(exciting orchestral music)
(gong rings)
Men of Shao-Lin, the 10 disciples,
five of them monks and five laymen,
are now prepared.
Their studies are complete.
Give them your instructions.
Buddha loves wisdom,
the true reflection,
the way of Shao-Lin
reflects that wisdom.
Remember that,
respect the way,
be true Shao-Lin.
Now you go out into the world,
always be merciful,
and practice kindness.
[All] Sir, we'll do as you say.
God's name be praised.
[Men] God's name be praised.
(gong rings)
(exciting orchestral music)
I will take you in to meet the abbot.
[Woman] Thank you very much.
Please.
(chanting)
Liu Shaoin, pleased to meet you.
God's name be praised.
So, you have come for your master.
Two years ago, Uncle Chang and myself
accompanied our master here.
We said then when the time was right
that we would return.
The time has come.
Mm, I have come to fetch you master.
Aye, times have changed.
The Ming has been defeated.
No, master,
the Ming cause is not defeated.
Everything is prepared, we await your return.
Oh?
Once you are with us
our armies will march on the road to victory.
And General Chang has been working all this time?
Yes.
The heavens are guiding our cause.
Abbot, I don't know how to repay you
for your kindness.
It was nothing,
I was merely doing my duty.
Shao-Hua, let us leave now.
No, their spies are everywhere.
They saw me coming here.
They'll be watching my return.
You cannot come with me,
but I have another idea.
I'll take the responsibility
for assuring you a safe journey.
Ah, good, then I shall leave here first.
On the second of next month,
we'll meet at Whitestone town.
(gentle horn music)
Chi-Yung.
Master?
Tomorrow you are to leave here.
You are to protect the master
with your life, if need be.
He's most valuable.
Take every precaution.
Do you understand?
I understand.
I'll take care of it.
Remember,
no matter what else is happening at the time,
you guard his life and make sure
he gets through to his destination
at all costs.
Yes, sir.
(grunts)
(yells)
God go with you.
Good luck, and take good care of him.
[Chi-Yung] Yes, sir.
Good bye.
Thank you for everything.
(exciting dramatic orchestral music)
(dramatic sinister orchestral music)
Excuse me, sir.
What's the matter?
[Man In Black] A pigeon from Shao-Lin Monastery.
Oh?
Show in the commander!
(dramatic orchestral music)
Sir, a message has arrived from Shao-Lin by pigeon.
Mm.
Dismissed.
Yes, sir.
[Chin-Hoo] Sir.
Mm.
Sir.
The letter tells us,
"King Chiu has left
for Whitestone town."
He leaves Shao-Lin at last.
They have harbored that traitor all this time
despite your requests that he be
handed over to you.
Now that he has left the temple,
it's our chance to strike.
I think we should stop him
from getting to Whitestone town
before it is too late for us.
(dramatic exciting orchestral music)
(dramatic sinister orchestral music)
(chuckles)
I'm glad you know your way.
We've been waiting here for some time now
for you to arrive at this crossroads.
But how did you know that we'd be coming?
It's the only way to Whitestone town.
That is where you're going, isn't it?
Mm.
Sir!
Charge!
(dramatic intense orchestral music)
Take him!
[Men] Sir, sir!
(yelling)
(thudding)
(swishing)
Don't let them escape!
Right, come on!
(swords swishing)
Come on!
(yells)
(swords clanging)
(thudding)
(groans)
(swords swishing)
(grunting)
[Men] Humbly, comrade.
My brothers.
[Men] Humbly.
The abbot didn't think it was going to be easy,
so he told us to go along in case.
I'm glad that you did.
That was most thoughtful of him.
Well, my brothers, are you coming with us?
No, well, we will go on ahead,
while you two make a detour to throw them off.
We'll see you later.
All right, good bye.
Good bye.
Bye, see you.
Thanks, come on.
Yeah, right.
(dramatic sinister orchestral music)
Forgive me, sir,
please, please.
Please, sir.
(smacking)
Ah, ah, no, no.
Oh, please, please, sir, please.
Brigadier Lan.
At your command, sir.
You lead the guard in attack.
They must be stopped.
If you fail, death!
Yes, sir.
Brigadier Ching.
You had better advise Brigadier Chow,
help is on the way.
He's to go to Whitestone town right away,
and wait for them to fall into the net.
Yes, sir.
Father, let me go.
I'm sure that I can capture this impostor Chiu.
Hmm, all right,
but your uncle's to go with you.
Yes, sir.
Commander,
all the monks have betrayed you.
They refuse to hand him over.
Supposing we were to threaten the abbot himself,
he will be forced to give up Chiu to us then.
It wouldn't cause us so much trouble,
and you could kill the two birds
with just the one stone.
All right, you go to Shao-Lin Monastery immediately.
Warn the abbot to call in all his monks.
Remember, I want that man alive!
(exciting orchestral music)
(hooves thudding)
(dramatic orchestral music)
My name is Chin-Hoo
from the commander's headquarters.
God's name be praised.
And what brings you to our monastery,
may I ask?
The commander orders you
to hand over Chiu.
Mr. Chiu left
here some time ago.
Then I must ask,
where are the 10 disciples
who have been studying here?
They have also left.
Their studies are complete.
They are not complete,
you must call them back.
They're to return immediately,
otherwise you will face the consequences.
(swords clank)
God's name be praised.
And what consequences are these,
could you explain?
Well, it's really quite simple.
Unless you call back the 10 disciples,
we shall be forced to destroy Shao-Lin.
Well you tell your commander
I refuse, I'd rather die than surrender.
God's name be praised.
(dramatic orchestral music)
Master, come on, let's go.
Right.
(logs clanking)
(dramatic music)
My friend,
are you trying to stop us from passing?
But gentlemen,
don't you know that all roads lead
to the same place?
And which place is that?
Why, to hell.
To hell?
Well, you must be-
- Yes, I'm your friend.
(gentle strumming orchestral music)
And if you don't want to go to hell,
you'd better go this way.
Stan-You.
Thanks for the directions.
Come on, we'll take this other path.
(dramatic music)
(grunts)
(yells)
This is a hard pathway.
I remember when he brought me to Shao-Lin,
two years ago now,
but I don't think we passed this way.
I want to get you to Whitestone town safely.
It doesn't matter how we get there.
Come on.
Right.
(water rushing)
(gentle orchestral music)
Some people have all the luck, huh?
How come we're sent out here on guard?
They must know that no one's coming this way.
Yeah, you're right about that.
Less spies to have everything,
they didn't need to send all of us
into the countryside like this.
Yeah, we're being picked on.
We should be back in the city.
(chuckles) You're too damn right.
- Hey.
- Huh?
It's your turn to carry.
But I've just been carrying it,
you've gotta do your part, too.
It's your turn.
It's yours.
Look, I'm finished.
I just told you no, didn't I?
All right,
I'll just leave it then!
Huh?
Hey, hey!
(gasps)
Help me, I'm being caught!
What's that?
(yells)
(water splashing)
(dramatic orchestral music)
(grunts)
Ai!
(grunting)
(moans)
(yells)
(groans)
(dramatic orchestral music)
Master, let's get moving.
Right.
[Chi Tong] Wait a minute.
What do you want?
Take a new road.
Don't go up the mountain pathway.
Nobody lives up there for miles around.
It is much better to detour
through Ching Fang Valley.
Tell me, who are you?
Blue Dragon White Tiger,
I'll see you later.
Hey!
[Chi Tong] Comrade, I am the 5th pupil,
Chi Tong.
(exciting orchestral music)
Father, we have returned.
Shao-Hua is there.
Shi-Ying.
Shao-Hua, welcome back.
How was the trip?
Fine.
Uncle Chang.
Shao-Hua, when will the master return?
The abbot sent his 10 disciples as an escort,
he'll be here soon.
Therefore, once he arrives,
then we can start our campaign.
Yes, everything waits for him,
then our country will return to the Ming.
[Both] Mmmm.
(dramatic orchestral music)
Good,
we'll give them a nice surprise.
(gentle orchestral music)
Shao-Hua, what's the matter?
Half a month has passed already.
King Chiu's still not here.
I'm worried.
Ah, he's well looked after.
Remember, he has an escort.
I'm sure he's going to get through all right.
What about you?
I've talked with your father,
but he became very angry with me.
What for?
Disloyalty,
my first duty should be to my country.
That's right.
But,
but you and I get on so well together, I thought-
- If you don't stop this,
I shall get angry with you.
Don't forget,
country comes first
before any love.
Understand, the Ming is in great danger,
Shi-Ying.
Ah, of course, I know all about that.
I don't mean to lecture you like this.
Now is not the time,
there's work to be done.
Oh, I realize, I do understand.
[Man] Sir?
Sir, master's here.
Oh, where is he?
[Man] Waiting in the old house.
In the old house?
Let's go welcome him.
What's he doing at the old house?
We agreed to rendezvous at Whitestone town.
Ah, maybe it's a mistake.
How would I know about that?
Well, is he there?
Come on.
Where is he?
(dramatic orchestral music)
All right.
How dare you harbor common criminals.
You're both guilty.
I ask you,
where is King Chiu hiding now?
You deliberately set up an ambush.
You dumb bastard!
(sharp thuds)
Shao-Hua, you go first, I can handle them.
Catch him!
(grunts)
(swords clanging)
(groans)
(grunting)
You're not gonna get away!
(moans)
Shi, I'm going!
(dramatic orchestral music)
All right, in there, men.
(swords clanging)
Uncle Chang, Uncle Chang.
What's the matter?
We've been betrayed.
Ting-Toe sold us out to the Ching, the damn traitor.
We can't stay here anymore.
We'd better get out of here quick.
But we are so near now.
All we need is Chiu.
We cannot afford to panic.
Ah, how about this?
I will move out to the north,
while you go down south to help bring Chiu.
Good.
Are you Brigadier Chow of Shin-Woo Ford?
Quite right.
Now I think it's time you die.
(sharp thudding)
(yells)
(grunting)
Fire!
(arrows swoosh)
(groans)
(laughs)
My friend, what is your name?
Buddha is my mind, I am the body.
Oh, Chi-Tong, it's me.
Brother.
I almost didn't recognize you.
Brother, strange things are happening.
I suspect there is a spy in the temple.
I've come to the same conclusion, brother.
What are we gonna do?
You better return to the temple to tell the abbot.
Remember, be on full alert.
Don't worry, I'll be careful.
May God go with you.
Right.
(dramatic orchestral music)
Hmm, who's there?
If you're a man, come and show yourself.
Why are you hiding from me?
What are you afraid of?
Stand up and fight like men.
(yells)
(swords clanging)
(clanging and swishing)
(laughs)
So you are one of the 10 disciples of Shao-Lin.
You appear to be strong.
Too bad you're going to die.
What is your name?
(chuckles)
Later, you'll find out.
(yells)
(chuckles)
(yelling)
(ax swishes)
(clangs)
(sharp smacks)
(grunts)
(groaning)
(yells)
(screaming)
My name is Brigadier Chow.
(groaning)
(dramatic orchestral music)
Mister, you must stop.
This is the Shao-Lin Temple.
Comrades,
it is Chi-Tong.
Ah, Chi-Tong.
[Men] Brother!
[Chi-Tong] Is the abbot about?
How can you be sure?
How do you know there is a spy?
If there is no spy here,
how did they know where to lie in wait for us?
They had information.
Oh.
It's bad Abbot.
We need to act now
before the spy betrays all of us.
It's strange.
Nobody except for the high priests
knew our strategy.
Also, how did the enemy
find out so soon?
It is puzzling.
[Chi-Tong] He used pigeons.
[Abbot] Oh!
(dramatic orchestral music)
[Man] Teacher.
Huh?
Teacher, something awful's happened.
And what are you in such a hurry a for?
The Abbot says we have a traitor here.
He is searching the whole monastery.
Oh.
Good, you go back first.
Yes.
(groans)
(dramatic orchestral music)
[Abbot] Where did you say you found him?
Well, Abbot, I found him down by the well,
and there's a dovecote there, too.
A dovecote?
(dramatic sinister orchestral music)
Also, Abbot, he was killed instantly
by a special kind of Chinese karate.
Oh?
Karate?
No, it couldn't be.
Isn't it true
that only the elders have learned Chinese karate?
Is one of them the spy?
This is a serious matter.
Don't jump to any conclusions.
We must make sure first of all
we have made no mistakes
before we name the spy.
We have work to do.
(exciting dramatic music)
Chi-Yung, I'm so tired.
I can't move another yard.
Come on, it's not safe to take a rest yet.
But I must take a rest. I
really can't go any further.
Surely we're safe.
Yes.
All right, you can rest.
(laughter echoes)
Oh, Chi-Yung, oh, Chi-Yung.
Uh-uh.
(yells)
(sharp thudding)
What are you doing here?
(laughs) I am leader of the guard,
Lan-Ching Yiu.
Huh, you're no better than a dog following us about.
(yells)
(grunting)
(chuckles) So, you think you're qualified
as a disciple of Shao-Lin?
Now, let's see how good you are.
(chuckles)
[Chiu] Chi-Yung.
Huh?
Chi-Yung, Chi-Yung, help!
(grunting)
(thudding)
(groans)
(dramatic orchestral music)
Chi-Yung, help!
Let me go!
Chi-Yung!
Chi-Yung, help me!
[Man] Out of the way!
Chi-Yung, make them let me go!
Here you go!
(clanging)
(sword swishes)
(grunting)
Comrade,
Comrade!
(yells)
Comrade, where is he?
They took him away.
I'll get him.
(yells)
You get away.
(sword swishes)
Oh, are you from Shao-Lin, too?
That's right.
Hee-yah.
(grunts)
(sword swishes)
(groans)
(grunting)
Mr. Chiu!
Mister!
Mr. Chiu.
Thank you for saving my life.
God's name be praised.
Mister, let's go and find my other comrade.
Excuse me, who is your other comrade?
His name is Chi-Yung.
Ah, Chi-Yung!
Master Chiu.
Chi-Yung!
Oh, friend.
Master Chiu, are you all
right? Brother, thank you.
Are you frightened?
No, this man, he saved my life.
Oh, so you've come along as well?
He was in trouble, so I helped him.
Then let us proceed together.
No, you go on ahead.
See you later.
Good, we'll see you soon.
(dramatic orchestral music)
Commander, a white haired fisherman
is also working for Shao-Lin.
Oh, fisherman?
In my opinion, he is most dangerous.
He fights like no man
I've ever seen before.
Commander, he sounds to me like
one of the disciples.
Even if he isn't, and we kill an innocent man,
he mustn't escape from us.
Father,
let me take care of him.
(dramatic orchestral music)
(darts whizzing)
(yells)
(chuckles)
You have been wounded by a poisonous dart.
In a few minutes,
you are going to die.
I don't even know you.
Why did you want to take my life?
(gasping)
What have I done to you?
I'm not your enemy.
(chuckles) Everyone who comes
from Shao-Lin Monastery
is our enemy.
(gasping)
(groaning)
(yells)
(dramatic orchestral music)
(groaning)
(all chattering)
(dramatic orchestral music)
It's here.
Let's get inside.
[Chi-Yung] Hold it.
Gentlemen.
Waiter, some customers!
Coming!
Do you want a meal or a room for the night?
A room.
[Waiter] All right.
[Man] Hey, waiter, over here, I want some tea.
Follow me.
Come on, let's go upstairs.
(customers chattering)
This way.
(dramatic orchestral music)
Hey.
Please.
Ah, hey, hey!
(grunting)
(groans)
Hello.
Waiter.
(dramatic orchestral music)
Please, go inside, mister.
Do you have any rooms here?
Oh, yes, sure, sure.
Ah, mister, please get inside.
Now, sir,
what can I get you to drink first?
[Man In Brown] Jasmine tea.
[Waiter] A Chinese tea!
[Man] A Chinese tea coming up!
(chuckles)
(dramatic orchestral music)
Mr. Chow.
Mr. Chow, an official visit?
(dramatic orchestral music)
Hold it!
Come down.
Mister, the leader of the guard,
Brigadier Chow.
What is your line of work?
Businessman.
And where do you come from?
From the south.
Oh, from the south.
(chuckles)
(yells)
(dramatic orchestral music)
(grunting)
(glass shatters)
(yelling)
(grunting)
(groans)
Take Master Chiu to the south.
I'll follow later.
Right.
(grunting)
(dramatic exciting orchestral music)
This way.
Quickly!
Look!
Master.
Soldiers.
Come on!
(yelling)
More soldiers, come on!
Hurry.
(intense dramatic orchestral music)
[Man In Red] There they are right below!
It's bad, the army's got us surrounded.
- What do we do?
- Once they catch up with us,
it'll be hard to get away.
Let me set up a kind of diversion.
You take Master Chiu away to the north,
then turn southwards.
We'll meet up at the Yom-Ting Gate.
At dusk in three days time, I'll be there,
so keep waiting.
Good, I won't leave until you come.
See you later.
Good bye.
Bye.
All right, come on.
(exciting dramatic orchestral music)
[Man] Come on, right here.
Don't let them get away!
Come on.
Quickly!
Come on, move!
[Man] He went that way!
[Man] Right.
(exciting dramatic orchestral music)
Boatman, boatman,
please help us.
Take us across the river.
What's all the hurry?
Oh, but, we're being chased
by a Ching Army patrol.
Huh, soldiers?
Okay, get in.
(dramatic exciting orchestral music)
There they are!
Come on!
[Man] Hey, boatman!
[Man] Hey, boatman, stop!
Get back here!
[Man] Boatman, come back!
[Man In Red] Boatman, stop!
Boatman, hey, come back here!
Bring 'em back, bring 'em back!
Come back!
[Man] Come back here!
[Man] Boatman!
[Man] Come back!
(all yelling)
[Man] You, bring it back over here!
Quickly!
Get back over here!
Boatman, how much will it cost?
(all shouting)
A dollar.
Huh?
(gentle orchestral music)
It doesn't cost you anything.
Good.
Thank you.
Boatman, boatman!
Come back over here!
[Man] Hey, boatman, bring it back over here!
(all shouting)
You son of a bitch!
Come away!
(exciting dramatic orchestral music)
Out of my way, dog!
Boatman!
Boatman, I left home to wander about!
To wander about?
I'm coming!
Hold it.
Huh?
(clanging)
(yells)
(dramatic orchestral music)
(yelling)
(swords clang and swish)
(groans)
(sword clangs)
(grunting)
(swords swishing)
(dramatic orchestral music)
Master, you don't need to kill him.
(sword clangs)
(grunting)
(groans)
(swords clanging)
gru
(grunting)
(yells)
(groaning)
(grunting)
(swords clanging)
(yells)
(groaning)
(grunting)
(yelling)
(breathing heavily)
(grunting)
[Man] The Commander in Chief!
(majestic orchestral music)
[Man] Master.
Father.
Master, we have tried to capture the traitor,
but each time the Shao-Lin monks interfered.
So we-
- So you ran back home.
Commander, the 10 disciples
broke through our blockade
and wounded our men.
I think we should send out
an entire army after them.
You should have realized
the 10 disciples are the most superior
fighting monks in Shao-Lin,
especially the man called Chi-Yung.
His kung fu's excellent, most talented.
(chuckles) Old man,
how many days have you been here?
Oh, 10 days now.
Don't you think they'll be missing you at Shao-Lin?
Mmm.
What do yo intend to do about it?
I see,
it's time for action.
You kill Chi-Yung,
and bring Chiu to me.
If you do that,
I'll appoint you abbot of Shao-Lin.
Oh.
Old man, do you agree?
I do.
I would like being the abbot.
It's a deal then.
Commander, the traitor Chiu
has escaped yet again.
He's heading south.
Our soldiers were unable to capture him.
Perhaps the old man
will be able to give us some help.
Mmmm.
Old man, Chi-Yung does not know
that you betrayed Shao-Lin.
Only you can do it, you must help us now.
(exciting dramatic music)
(gentle orchestral music)
(dramatic orchestral music)
Teacher!
Good to see you.
Good day.
How come you're here?
Right now, I have come here for King Chiu.
For me?
You follow me.
A priest!
Teacher.
I only want him.
Not you, get out!
What?
Teacher, why are you acting like this?
Orders of the Ching commander.
I must arrest him.
[Chiu] What?
Teacher, you've joined the Ching.
Teacher, I was given strict orders
to protect King Chiu.
With my own life, if need be.
I cannot allow you to take him.
You think that I will not kill you?
- (yells)
- Priest!
You must not kill him.
Well, all right, I'll go with you.
No!
Chi-Yung, thank you for your protection.
You suffered much,
but I don't want you to die.
If destiny ordains the Ming are no more,
so be it, I have done all I could.
Now, Priest,
I ask you to release Chi-Yung.
I'll come with you to the Ching commander.
Master, you are our anointed king.
Your subjects need you with them.
We will save you.
It's our duty, after all,
even to sacrifice our life.
(dramatic music)
God's name be praised.
Elder.
You've come at the right time.
Teacher.
[Chiu] Abbot.
Elder, let's go back to the temple.
Back to the temple to be punished?
I am not a common criminal.
Yang-Kho,
you cannot take me back.
Only in one's mind.
I know all that nonsense.
Don't tell me what is written.
(sighs)
I know, too,
what you really desire,
but it is not worth the price
you're prepared to pay.
Please, consider your soul.
Shut up!
I came to Shao-Lin as a child.
I learned Buddhist sutras everyday
and practiced kung fu.
It has been a hard life,
and what have I got from it in return?
I wanted to become the abbot of Shao-Lin,
but our master was prejudiced.
Do you think you are better than me?
Do you?
Answer me!
(sighing)
Elder, you do everything better.
(dramatic orchestral music)
You are quite right.
You should be the abbot.
Shao-Lin will become a strong foundation
under your leadership.
(sentimental orchestral music)
God's name be praised.
Hold on to the holy scepter.
Now you are the abbot of Shao-Lin.
(chuckles)
I am the abbot,
at last I am the abbot of Shao-Lin.
(laughs)
(dramatic orchestral music)
Elder!
(groaning)
Elder.
Teacher, Teacher.
I deserve it.
It's what I wanted.
Elder.
Good and evil exist,
only in one's own mind.
Who should realize this truth
will find peace
at last.
(gasping)
[Both] Teacher!
Elder!
- Elder!
- [Chi-Yung] Teacher!
God's name be praised.
Why hasn't Chiu come yet?
He should be here, it's getting late.
Come on.
(moaning)
Quickly.
Oh, brother, it's you.
Brother.
You've all arrived?
Where's Shao-Hua?
She went back first to the headquarters.
Oh?
Oh, Chi-Yung, we'd better be going.
No, there are too many soldiers about.
(dramatic orchestral music)
Uncle Chang?
Who are you?
I am the hunter home from the hill.
Where is Uncle Chang?
Ha.
He's gone where he won't come back.
And who exactly are you?
The official guard of the Ching Commander,
and this is the son of the commander in chief,
Lu-Shao-Wan.
If you hand the traitor Chiu over to us,
then we will spare both your lives.
I will never do it!
(swords clanging)
(grunting)
(groans)
(swords clanging)
(grunting)
(groans)
(swords clanking and swooshing)
(swords clanking)
(grunting)
(groans)
(swords clanking)
(grunting)
(dramatic orchestral music)
Halt!
Surround the place!
(yelling)
(yells)
(grunting)
(swishing and thudding)
[Man] On the left,
you search that way.
Brother, Mistress Lu is inside.
We'd better help her.
Brother, Mistress Lu is in danger.
We cannot stand here doing nothing.
Certainly we're gonna do something,
but first we must make sure our effort's not in vain.
When we strike, we must make it count.
I agree with you.
Our duty is to protect Chiu at all costs.
Of course, we'll have to leave her,
but we will come back.
We can't help her.
Right now, we'd better make sure
that Chiu is perfectly safe.
We left him outside the gates.
He could be in danger.
But-
- We must protect him.
We will come back soon.
Damn!
[Man] Make ready, quickly over there!
(dramatic orchestral music)
What?
How come he's alive?
Who is he?
The captain of the guards,
Lan-Ching Yiu.
Comrade,
when I was passing through the forests
I came across our brother.
He was-
- Brother, how was he?
He was dead.
Ah!
(somber orchestral music)
Brother, you two
go and look after Chiu at the city gates.
At daybreak, we will all meet again at Stone Hill.
[Both] Right.
(dramatic orchestral music)
After him!
(gasping)
(groaning)
(grunting)
Father.
(gasping)
My son, my son!
My son!
(intense dramatic orchestral music)
(yells)
(grunting)
(swishing)
(shouting)
(dramatic orchestral music)
(sighs)
(intense dramatic orchestral music)
(hooves thudding)
(yells)
(grunting)
(scratching)
(groans)
Today I'll make you pay for my brother's life.
(shouts)
(grunting)
(yells)
(dramatic orchestral music)
(groaning)
(gasping)
Huh, what?
I am Shao-Lin, too,
the 8th disciple.
My name's Chi-Tur, how are you?
Please excuse me for being so reckless.
Ah, pleased to meet you.
All of you Shao-Lin
have been so kind to me.
I don't know how can I ever repay you.
God's name be praised.
What we do is only our duty
out of our love for our country.
Please, think nothing of it.
You must go back at once,
otherwise they'll miss you.
You must not move away from this place.
I go now to contact my comrades.
Be on your guard.
Good bye.
(dramatic orchestral music)
(somber orchestral music)
My son,
my son.
[Man] Father, Father, Father!
My son!
[Man] Father!
Father!
My son, my son!
My son!
(sighs)
(sighing)
(footsteps thudding)
Commander, the traitor Chiu is here.
(dramatic orchestral music)
So I have you in my hands at long last.
Hmm.
Sit down.
Sir!
I don't want to.
[Chin-Hoo] What's that?
You dare to disobey the commander?
[Commander] Chin-Hoo!
Here, yes, sir.
King Chiu Chin.
You are the King Chiu Chin?
Aren't you?
What was your territory
now all belongs to me, it's mine.
You should learn to swim with the tide
or drown.
I haven't lost.
There is still hope.
And if you die,
is there still hope then?
(laughs)
If I die, my soul goes,
and the name of King Chiu Chin
becomes history.
Oh, you are history all right,
Chiu Chin, but I'm not gonna kill you yet.
Ah?
You want to humble me?
Is that what you intend?
You can still serve a useful purpose.
I want you to be the bait.
I want to crush the Ming,
especially the 10 disciples.
(exciting dramatic orchestral music)
Hold it.
Comrade.
Huh, Chi-Tur!
Comrade, it's too bad,
but Chiu Chin has vanished.
What?
Disappeared?
How did it happen?
It is all my fault.
I saw him wandering alone in the street.
I thought the soldiers would see him,
so I...
Damn it!
What are we gonna do now?
Where's Chi-Ming and Chi-Chin?
I don't know.
Come on.
(exciting dramatic orchestral music)
This way.
[Man] Oh, brother!
Hi.
Brother!
Brother.
We could not find Chiu-Chin
at all at the city gate.
He's disappeared.
I know it.
Chi-Tur told me already.
But what about Mistress Lu?
Kung-Chin-Hui has already left.
I'm afraid that she is dead.
Kung-Chin-Hui.
Who is he?
I don't know him.
He's the commander of Tong-Ping County.
He's a very tough nut, hard to crack.
Oh?
In the present situation,
and with Chiu disappeared,
I guess Kung is our only lead.
All right, let's go and find him, we'll ask him.
Good, I'll bring you to him.
(dramatic orchestral music)
(intense orchestral music)
Who is it?
Brother, he's the commander of Tong-Ping County,
Kung-Chin-Hui.
You're right,
and you're not gonna leave this place alive,
god damn you!
You will release King Chiu immediately.
You are nothing.
How dare you threaten me.
(grunting)
(yells)
(screaming)
(grunting)
(groans)
(yells)
(grunting)
(crackling)
(intense dramatic orchestral music)
(grunting)
(gasping)
(yells)
(grunting)
(groaning)
(yelling)
(grunting)
Three tiger attack!
(dramatic orchestral music)
(yelling)
(grunts)
(groaning)
(yells)
(yelling)
(groans)
(gasps)
(exciting orchestral music)