- Miss Eady?
- Mr. Christie?
Come in, do.
Blessed blackout.
Well, we'll have a
nice little cup of tea first,
come in the kitchen it's cozier in there.
Oh, that will be lovely.
Well...
I, I only just brewed up.
Mrs. Christie is out, is she?
She's, she's away,
up in Sheffield at her sister's.
- Oh sit down, Miss Eady do.
- Thank you.
Do you...
- you take sugar?
- No thank, no.
Thank you.
Well now...
- It's been bad, has it? The bronchitis.
- At nights. It's been bad at nights..
- Keeps you awake, I daresay?
- Oh yes.
Well, this is the stuff for you, Muriel.
You don't mind if I call you Muriel, did you?
- No.
It's very good of you
to go to all this trouble.
Oh, not at all.
All my doctor does is
keep giving me this cough mixture.
Well, there.
- Not many of them know about this stuff.
- Oh, it smells just like friar balsam.
Well yes, that's in it, it's a
mixture. What we call a compound.
I see.
Now, here is the little mask that goes over
your face.
- Oh, have you finished with your tea?
- Yes, thank you.
Fine.
And when it's over your
face you must breathe deeply...
so you take in all the vapors, you see.
You may feel...
just a bit dizzy.
- What's that for?
- Ah, that's the extractor.
It gets rid of what we call
the waste products.
Now then.
You put the mask over your face.
Lean you head back.
Lean right back.
Shut your eyes, close your eyes, that's it.
Shut your eyes. Now then.
Start your breathing then.
Breathe quite deeply.
Breathe.
- Smells a bit funny Mr. Christie.
- Yes, do you feel a bit dizzy?
I do, a bit.
Yes, well, that's
all the goodness taking effect.
Breathe Muriel, breathe.
No no Muriel, no. Breathe Muriel.
- No, no, no, no.
- No, no, no.
Breathe, breathe, breathe.
Breathe, breathe.
Muriel?
Muriel.
Ring the old bell then, shall we?
- Oh, it's not a bad district, is it?
- It's not bad.
Come on, come on.
Yes?
- We've...
- We come about the flat.
To see it?
We just want to look
it over, you know. See if it's suitable.
Yes well, you better come in.
Oh, that's my wife, Mrs. Christie.
They've come about the flat.
I'll lead the way.
I'll look after him.
The baby. While you're
looking at the flat, I'll hold him.
He'll be all right with me. What's his name?
- Geraldine.
- She I should say.
Yes.
Mr. Kitchener occupies
this floor, it's up one more..
- Just the two rooms, is it?
- Yes.
Well, it's not what
we're used to, you understand.
We used to have this
mansion flat overlooking the river.
- But we had to move out.
- Tim?
Oh gas, is it?
Yes, it works out less of a
expense, that's what we find.
Oh well, we're not too worried about the
money, the job I do, we don't have to.
- Oh, we'll take it.
- Oh Oh Tim, I don't know.
- Oh, do we get use of the garden?
- No.
- Well, I mean just to put the baby out.
- Well, I'd like to help you, but...
It's a question of the lease.
Once you surrender the right of way, I mean
it can take an act of Parliament these cases.
- Oh Tim, I don't know.
- There's another couple, very keen.
- Irish, as a matter of fact.
- No, we'll take it.
Well, you're doing the right thing.
Right, now you and Teddy
can have a nice sleep?
There's a good girl.
Now, you have a nice sleep.
- Mr. Christie...
- I thought you might like a...
- you did make me jump.
- A little cup of tea.
- Well, I just had one actually.
- Well, that's all right.
Thank you.
It's nice up here now.
Yes, it's not bad, is it?
I was in the police during the war, you know.
Were you?
We had a lot to do with medical stuff then.
Consulting.
I'm always on
hand for advice Beryl, if you...
Has Beryl gone out, Mrs. Christie?
- Don't know.
- I'll go up.
Beryl, it's me.
- Oh, I was looking for Beryl.
- She's...
- Oh, I thought it would be you Alice.
- I got you all the stuff for tea.
- Oh, thank you.
- Alice, this is a...
- Who was that?
- That was the ground floor.
Am I late?
- My tummy is been playing me up again today.
- Oh Reg.
Tim? Tim, might I...
- Might I have a word?
- Mr. Christie, why sure.
There was a gentleman at
the door for you today, he left this.
- What it say Mr. Christie?
- Oh yes, I forgot.
Well, there's no need to read it anyway,
it's about the payments on your furniture.
You're six weeks in arrears apparently.
- Not paid, you mean?
- No.
I didn't mention it to...
Beryl or worry her with that.
Well, she has the money
Mr. Christie, she has it every week.
I gave him 10 shillings out of my own pocket.
I don't want this house getting a name Tim.
Oh, that damn girl.
All right, don't you worry Mr. Christie,
you, you'll get that money back.
I'll be getting a new job
shortly, I shouldn't wonder.
They've asked me if I want to train as
a manager or as a managing director.
Or something, you know.
Yes, won't you have to learn
to read and write for that?
Oh, no, no, no. You have
secretaries, things like that, see?
Yes.
Well, as long as I get my 10 shillings back.
- Oh, that damn woman.
- Oh, and Tim, there was a young girl...
- in and out of here all day.
- Oh, I'm sorry Mr. Christie.
What's the matter?
Oh, hello. Hello little one.
What you've been doing today then, eh?
- Oh, where's Beryl?
- Oh, she's having a bit of a lie down.
She's not feeling too grand.
- What's all this then?
- I'm all right, I'm just having a lie down.
Now, what's all this about
the furniture money then?
The what?
You know bloody well what,
so don't give me all that.
The man was here.
Six weeks it hasn't been paid.
And I slave my guts out
for that money my girl.
So do I, four pounds 10 a week to feed you...
pay the rent and all the installments,
and buy everything for the baby...
and another one on the way.
Yes, that's right, another one on the way.
Oh we, we can't have another kid yet.
And that's exactly what we're going
to get unless I do something about it..
Do something?
- Do what?
- Oh, never mind what.
She wants to go to bed now.
- Do what?
- Tim, there are things you can do.
- Oh no, you don't my lady.
- Well, it's my choice, isn't it?
Anyway, I done it, I taken some pills.
What you think I'm lying here for?
Well, you didn't even
ask me, you didn't even tell me.
Ask you, do I have to ask your permission?
Yes, you bloody do.
And does she know about this?
- Now, leave Alice out of this.
- You knew about this, didn't you?
- No.
- Leave Alice alone.
She's staying here tonight to look after me.
- Oh no, she's not, I know her sort.
- What's that meant to mean?
Never you mind, I met your sort before.
Don't you worry leading her along.
No. Tim, now look what you've done.
Get out, and leave Alice alone.
I wouldn't touch her
with a bloody barge pole.
- Beryl, I think I'd better go.
- No.
- He can sleep in the kitchen.
- I'm not sleeping anywhere,
So don't you fret and I'm not coming back...
- so don't expect me.
- Good.
Bloody old cow.
No, I'm not the sort of man who can
make do with just one woman.
No? Go on.
No, it's in the family, see.
I mean, you take my brother, he's
paying out hundreds a year in alimony.
Well, thousands.
Mind you I'm fly, what you think
I got waiting for me when I get home?
The rent collector?
Rent collector, he's a bit
of a humorist, isn't he our Wally?
All tucked up nice and warm
in bed with the wife.
- That's what I said, the rent collector.
- I'll bloody hit you in a minute.
Go it, Taffy.
No, there's two of them see, there's Beryl
and this other little dark one, Alice.
Just lying there
waiting for it, crying out for it.
Three in a bed, eh? How about that?
You can have my old woman
if you like, that will make up the set.
Thanks very much Bub
I'll take you up on that one day...
I got enough to be going on with that.
Oh well, if you're traveling around like
me, you know, it's Brighton one day and...
Birmingham the next, you usually manage
to pick up a bit on the way, you know.
That's not all you'll pick up
if you go on like that lad.
Oh, no, no. These aren't scrubbers like you
might get man. Oh no, these is ladies.
Rich ladies. Well, you know,
get bore, they're wanting a bit of fun.
Elegant but passionate.
Come on you, out.
- Tim?
- Out.
Beryl wants me here, she may need me here.
I don't bloody need you here and it's my bed.
Don't wake her Tim, she's tired.
So I'm tired too, I'm tired of having you
around, so come on, you bloody get out.
And you just bloody leave us in peace.
And you get back in bed and keep out of it...
- just get on out of here.
- Tim, just for the night.
- She may not be well.
- Oh, and whose fault that, eh?
- Tim, be quiet.
- Go on out, hurry out.
- Let go of Alice.
- You take your hands off me.
- Don't you touch me like that.
- I have my bloody rights, haven't I?
Don't touch me.
- What's it Reg?
- That's the Evanses again.
Get off Tim.
Get off me, get that bloody here.
Take your hands off me.
You bloody touch me again,
I'm throwing her out.
Don't be so bloody silly.
It's my bloody house, isn't it?
- I got rights in my own bloody house.
- Let go me.
Now then, now then, now then.
What is all this about?
- It's all her Mr. Christie.
- Calm down, you just calm down.
Well, it's just because
I got Alice staying here a night.
- Staying the night?
- In my bloody bed.
- All right.
- And I'm meant to stay on the bloody floor,
- in the bloody kitchen.
- All right, All right.
There's no need for language.
This is an apartment for two persons.
That's quite clear in the lease.
- What lease?
- The statutory regulations.
Well, Alice is just staying
with me because I'm not well.
Never mind about that, I know the law.
Now then, you can't
be guaranteed security of tenure...
if you're overcrowded, that is a regulation.
That's right my girl, you put your
shoes on and go about your business.
- Why should she?
- It's all right Beryl, I'll go.
Any more of this sort of behaviour,
and out you go, both of you.
- I just want a bit of peace Mr. Christie.
- All right then.
Beryl.
Beryl, if you're not well you shouldn't
be larking around at this time of night.
You should see a doctor.
- Lovely day today Mr. Christie, ain't it?
- Very nice, yes.
Oh hello Beryl. How are you today?
- Oh, I'm fine, thank you Mr. Christie.
- Have you been to see the doctor yet?
The doctor? Oh no.
- Well, won't you come in a minute? I...
- Well, I got the, put the kettle on.
Well, sit down Beryl, do in the deck chair.
Well now, what is all this
trouble between you and Tim?
And don't try and tell me
there isn't any trouble.
No.
You're very young, you know.
Unexperienced and things which may seem...
great problems to you...
may seem simpler to an older head, you know.
But it's just that I,
I'm going to have a baby.
Yes, I see.
Tim, I suppose...
is none too keen
on this addition to the family.
No.
Well, I'm not either, I,
I took some pills yesterday.
- Pills?
- Yes, they didn't work though.
You see Mr. Christie, Tim
only gets 7 pounds a week. Well...
we can't afford another baby now.
No, I understand that.
I...
I do know people,
medical people, who could help you out.
But that would cost money, wouldn't it?
- Yes, that's, that's true.
- Yes.
That's true, I'm afraid.
They are very eminent men,
one particularly I have in mind I...
I used to assist him in his earlier days.
Studied with him.
It's quite a simple matter.
You, you mean you know
how to do it Mr. Christie?
Oh yes. Oh, that's not a problem.
I seen it done a hundred times.
Terminations we call them.
Had to learn about that in the police.
Well, I suppose you couldn't...
Oh, I...
I know it's against the law and everything.
Oh no, that's, that's all right.
As long as nobody goes telling
tales out at school. Sugar?
- No, I wouldn't...
- It's the moral question that concerns me.
I wouldn't tell
a soul Mr. Christie, honestly.
The taking of life.
- No matter how rudimentary.
- Well, it's not really.
I'd be ever so grateful Mr. Christie.
All right, I will.
Is such a weight off my mind.
Honestly, Mr. Christie, honestly.
When you think you could?
Oh, you think you could?
Well, you have a word with Tim tonight, eh?
- Yes.
- And...
Perhaps we'll be able
to fit you in tomorrow.
Yes.
What you doing here then Beryl?
Now then, now then.
I thought we go to the pictures.
- Oh, did you then?
- Yes.
Now, Mrs. Christie is
looking after Geraldine.
And you and I are going
to have a night out, Ok?
- Well, all right then, come on.
- Oh, the bus.
Here now.
- Did you like it? The film?
- Oh, it was all right.
- Didn't see too much of it.
- I like Gregory Peck.
He's Ok.
You know, you're a bit like him to look at.
- Good God girl, you hardly had one drink.
- No no, you are.
He's about 7 foot 3 for a start off.
I know but just around
the eyes, you look like him.
Mr. Christie was talking to me today.
- What? About last night?
- Oh no, he was, he was Ok about that.
He...
Well, he said he might be able to help us.
- About the baby, you know.
- Oh?
So what's he think he can do?
Well, he had experience of things like that.
- You mean getting rid of it?
- Termination it's called.
Oh, I...
No, I don't know about that, Beryl.
No, no. I don't think he wants
money or anything like that.
That's not what I mean.
Tim...
We can't have another
kiddie now, you know we can't.
Well I, I know I could always get a...
bigger job, pays more cash.
You know I could go to night
school, get qualified in something.
- What's he do, anyhow?
- I don't know.
Yeah.
All right, then.
Hey, mind the beer girl.
Tim...
Will you tell Mr. Christie it's all
right when you go down the stairs?
- I don't like it, Beryl.
- Oh Tim...
You can't go back on it now.
Ok, Ok.
Mr. Christie?
- Oh, there you are Mr. Christie.
- Oh Tim, come in, come in.
- Look Mr. Christie, Beryl has been tell...
- Shut the door, will you? Do you mind?
Oh, no.
Tim...
I dislike this business as much as you do.
- Well, I don't know Mister...
- It's just that I happen to...
had picked up this knowledge whilst I
was in training as a doctor, before the war.
Oh, I didn't know you did
all this medical stuff.
Oh yes.
Yes yes, unfortunately my
training was interrupted by a motoring...
accident and then...
- then the war came and...
- Well, I suppose...
I was browsing through
some of my medical texts...
Before you came in, as a matter
of fact, perhaps you like to...
Yes, well, I, I don't know
about all this stuff, see.
No, no.
But how you...
I mean...
How do you actually do it?
Well, that's something only
doctors and myself know about.
It has to be secret, you understand.
We couldn't have every Tom, Dick and
Harry going around doing it, could we?
No, no, I understand that, but...
I won't conceal the dangers from your mind...
The...
the stuff I use...
- one in 10 might die from it.
- Die?
Well yes, that's an acceptable
medical risk, that's understood.
Mind you, they
probably use too strong a dose.
If only you and...
Beryl had come to me earlier,
I could've done it without any risk at all.
I...
Oh, I don't know, I don't know Mr. Christie.
Well Tim...
if you haven't got complete
confidence in my ability...
No, no, I, I trust
you Mr. Christie, of course I do.
All right then.
Good lad. Right, well you cut
along to work, otherwise...
you'll be late. And Tim, remember...
- we've never lost a father yet.
- No.
Well, thank you Mr. Christie.
Ethel?
Ethel...
Ethel, I want you to
go to the office for me, will you?
See Mr. Steadman, tell him my back is been
playing me up and I shan't be in today.
Oh Reg, are you going to the doctor?
No, no, I'll be all right.
- I'll phone from the corner.
- No, you better go.
They'll want theses bills
of lading and invoices right away.
- Go get your coat darling.
- All right.
I'm ready Reg.
- Tell him I ought to be better tomorrow.
- All right.
- Yes, what's it?
- Mr. Christie?
- Yes.
- Builders.
Repair roof to outhouse, re-plaster
where necessary and make good.
- Now? It's not convenient.
- You are Mr. Christie?
You complained the landlord
about this outhouse.
Well I, I need to be informed in advance.
But look mate, I just take
my orders from the owners.
- It is just the, the wash-house, is it?
- Just the outbuildings, yeah.
You better come through.
Now, thank you very much.
I was just having a cup of tea.
Oh, back up here, on the right.
- This is it, the wash-house.
- Right.
All this lot will have
to come down for a start.
How long will take?
Oh, shouldn't take more
than a couple of days.
- Be careful, do you mind?
- Yeah, mind the paintwork mate.
And the priceless antiques.
Mr. Christie?
Are you?
- I got the builders in.
- Well, it doesn't matter.
Here we are then,
brought you a little cup of tea.
Oh. Thank you.
What are they doing, the builders?
Oh they, they won't disturb us.
- Baby asleep, is she?
- Yes, she's in the other room.
Right, that's well then...
we can manage in here then.
Just drink your tea and relax.
- Is it going to hurt?
- Just a little twinge but we can help that.
Open the window for me 6 inches, will you?
And perhaps you better pull down the blind.
Fast asleep.
Right.
Just pass me my bag, will you?
Thanks.
Oh, what's that for?
- Just a whiff of gas.
- Gas?
Like at the dentist.,
take away those little twinges.
- But that's poisonous, isn't it?
- Oh no. Not the way we use it.
Something we had to learn during the war...
for bomb victims...
that needed urgent surgery.
It's a chemically compounded filter, you see.
The liquid...
takes out the carbon monoxide or CO-2...
as we call it.
There. Right.
Right, just get scrubbed up.
- There isn't any cutting, is there?
- Oh, no no, no no.
I'm ever so nervous Mr. Christie.
Oh, there's no need to be, no need at all.
You have...
- undergarments on?
- Yes.
Well, just slip them off, will you?
- Oh, should I take my dress off?
- No, no, just the...
And then lie down on the quilt.
- Right down?
- Yes, just lie down and relax.
- You ready?
- Yes.
Is a good girl.
Now, just a little whiff of the gas.
You had gas before at the dentist, have you?
Well, you know what it feels like then.
You'll feel just a little
bit dizzy, I expect.
Right, now breathe deeply.
Breathe, just relax,
breathe deeply, close your eyes.
Close your eyes, that's a good girl.
That's a good girl.
Breathe.
Breathe, breathe Beryl.
That's it.
No., no, no, no, no. Quiet. Quiet.
Be quiet. Be, be quiet, quiet.
No, I don't want to.
- Please, please. Don't make me hurt you.
- No.
Please.
Oh, Beryl.
- Howdy dowdie do?
- Hey come on, come on.
Beryl.
Beryl?
If you don't want to see me,
you've only got to say so.
Beryl?
Mummy.
- Oh, hello Mr. Christie.
- It's bad news Tim.
It didn't work.
Well, where is Beryl then?
- She's upstairs on the bed.
- Oh, Tim.
Lying down.
Go on up, I'll come up with you.
Beryl?
She's got blood all down her chin.
That's the concussion I'm afraid,
she would struggle, you see.
Concussed her head against the bed head.
It's got sharp corners, that bed head.
Beryl?
She's not alive.
I told you it was bad.
- But you, you never said...
- One out of 10 die of it, I told you that.
Oh, Christ.
I'm sorry Tim, these things happen, though.
She should've approached me earlier.
Oh God, and she was only young.
Yes, it's a terrible thing but she's
about to be in hospital by now, anyway.
Doctors couldn't have helped her even.
Her tummy was septic poisoned.
All those pills she been
dosing herself up with.
- Oh God, Oh God, those damn pills.
- Don't, don't wake the baby Tim.
- What am I going to do?
- Come with me, come on. Come on.
Come on.
Sit down.
You'll get the doctor?
Doctors can't do much now, I'm afraid Tim.
Well, we got to do something,
police or something.
- Yes, you may be right.
- Well, that's what I think anyhow.
It will be criminal manslaughter
for me, of course.
Oh, God, I don't want to get
you into trouble Mr. Christie.
No, I'm not just thinking about me so
much, I'm not the only one involved.
You knew all about it, didn't you?
- Well, of course I knew about it.
- Well, don't get huffy with me my lad.
You knew about it, that's the point.
You're an accessory before the act.
Well, I done nothing.
Oh, God, I done nothing.
But you knew about it Tim, you consented.
That's all they will want to know.
All right, all right then, I'll...
I'll not tell them nothing, I'll just say I
don't know nothing and just keep clammed up.
You better go and see to the baby,
you can't leave her crying like that.
Poor old Timmy.
I could get you out of this if
only you didn't keep talking so silly.
I just don't know what to do.
Well, we could keep
quiet about it, couldn't we?
She's just lying there.
Well...
there are ways of...
disposing of bodies.
What? Not be buried, you mean?
- No proper service?
- What good would a proper service do?
Well, she want it, that's what.
And me too I, I want it.
You want it? She want it?
You want to be hung?
Is that what you want?
You better see to the baby supper,
she'll be crying for it in a minute.
They don't hang you for manslaughter anyhow.
No.
They do for murder though.
They will just think you killed her
in one of those fights of yours.
She's got that knock on the head.
The whole street knows about
the fights you have all the time.
The police know even.
- What do you mean? I...
- I mean...
you start going to the police or
whatever and I'm going to have to deny...
- I had anything to do with it.
- Oh, they'll know.
They will know from the operation you did.
Oh, no my lad, there are no
visible signs, not the way I do it.
All right then, all right,
I'll tell them and then They'll know.
Who you think they will believe Tim?
Everyone around here knows the stories you
come out with about your father being...
an Italian count and everything.
Oh, it's just storyfying,
everyone knows that.
Anyhow, he was an Italian, my father.
Well, he may not have been a
count, I don't know about that.
An Italian named Evans?
He are, it's just a name he used so as
people wouldn't know who he was.
Well, he was in this secret business see?
Well, that's why we were so rich.
He had all his money
in shares and everything.
Only he lost it, because
he was killed in the war.
So who are the police going to believe, eh?
You...
or me that was a special
constable for four years?
Well, me of course, me.
All right then Tim...
Well, you go to the police
and tell them, go on.
Off you go.
All right, I will do.
Well, they'll have to believe the truth.
Well, go on then, if you're going.
Well, I can't go now, can I?
I got the baby to feed and everything.
I'll do that, I'll do that
for you while you're gone.
Well, you tell me.
Tell me what to do and then I won't go.
No no, you got to do what you think's right.
Well, let's just shut the door and talk, eh?
All right.
- You're going to be guided by me?
- Yes, Ok Mr. Christie.
Right, sit down.
Now, first of all is
Beryl, I'll look after that.
I'll, I'll dispose of her.
I'll wait till I get a chance, you know the
the big manhole cover by the front door?
- Lay her to rest there.
- Oh, Oh, God.
- Is no time for you to break down.
- Yes, I know, I know, I'm sorry.
It would look better if you went away for
a bit. Right away, tonight, out of London.
- I don't.
- Listen to me.
Then I could tell people that you
and Beryl had gone away together.
And what about the baby? Geraldine?
Oh, she'll be all right.
It's very lucky, as a matter of fact.
There's a young couple over at Acton
I know who will look after her for you.
East Acton to be precise.
They can't have any of
their own so it's handy really.
So you just leave all her things packed up.
And I'll get them to come over
and collect her in the morning.
But I'll be able to have her back, won't I?
- I mean when, when all this has blown over.
- Oh yes, yes. Yes I daresay.
Right then, you get the baby fed.
Oh God Mr. Christie, and she was only young.
If she'd come to me earlier...
Come and give me a hand.
Grab her, grab her legs.
Let her down, let her down.
We'll put her in Kitchener place, the old man
is in hospital, he won't be back for days.
She'll be all right in there for tonight.
- Take this.
- What's this?
Wedding ring, sell it.
It will make her less easy to
identify, if they do ever find her.
Oh...
Now you get packed and
then get a night train anywhere,
And I'll get those
people over from East Acton...
first thing in the morning for the baby.
- You better go and finish feeding her.
- Yes Mr. Christie.
Go on, go on.
- Hello Auntie Vi.
- Tim?
Oh, what are you doing down here?
Come in, come in.
Carl, it's Tim.
Tim boy, what are you
doing in this neck of the woods?
Sit down Tim, take your coat off.
Well, me and the boss is touring
round trying to find new branches.
- Only the car broke down in Cardiff.
- There's tea, fresh brewed Tim.
- You still like egg and fried bread?
- Oh, smashing.
It will be a few days the car.
- Big end is gone, they said.
- How is Beryl?
We can put you up on the
settee in the back room if you like.
Thanks, Auntie.
How is Beryl and the baby?
Oh fine, fine. They've gone to Brighton
for a bit to stay with Beryl father.
I just been upstairs.
- He's gone.
- Tim?
Packed up and left.
His clothes and everything, scarpered.
And that's not the worst part.
What's the matter Reg?
You know what he's gone and done?
What?
He's killed the baby.
- I don't believe it.
- I'm telling you, strangled,
- If you must know, with his tie.
- He never do that.
Never mind what he
never do, it's what he's done.
He worshipped that child.
- When I think of all the things.
- Reg, what we going to do?
Nothing.
Hey, see what I bought Geraldine in Cardiff.
Did you go into the garage about the car?
Oh yes, yes, they say it will be
a bit. They will let me know.
There.
- Woolworth's I got it.
- Oh, it's lovely Tim.
Tim, your uncle and I wrote a
letter to Mr. Thorley on Monday.
- Thorley?
- Beryl's father.
- Oh, what you want to write to him for?
- Because a telegram this morning.
He said he hasn't seen Beryl
and the baby since the summer.
- What you want to go poking around for?
- But where is she Tim? What's happened?
I don't want to talk about it
and none of your business anyhow.
- She's, she's gone off.
- Gone off?
With some fellow, I don't know, do I?
- In a car.
- But what about little Geraldine?
Look, just stop asking
questions at me, will you?
- Now then Tim...
- Don't you now, then me she's...
She's gone off with some rich
fellow and that's all there's about it.
- Oh Tim, we're only...
- Never mind that.
- She's not that sort of a girl Tim.
- Well, I'm going out, I'm bloody going out.
Yeah, I think that's the number.
- Yeah, that's Ok.
- There's the record card.
- I...
- Yes sir?
Is there an inspector
or sergeant or somebody here?
There's nobody available at
the moment sir, can I help you?
I'd like to have a bit of a
chat with you alone like.
- All right.
- Excuse me sir.
Well now...
I want to give myself up
I disposed of my wife.
Now wait a minute.
Do you realize what you're saying?
Oh, I know what I'm saying. I can't
sleep for it, I want to get it off my chest.
She was expecting, see.
And we have one already.
Anyhow, I met this fellow in Ipswich.
He just come up to me in a cafe
and give me this bottle of stuff.
Why, I told her not to take it but
she said she was going to anyhow.
So I come home from
work and there she is dead.
She had the empty bottle beside her
and I didn't know what to do, so I got...
I, I didn't know what to do so 2 in
the morning, I got her downstairs...
and I opened the drain outside the
front door and I put her body...
down the drain.
And then I come down here.
You want to make a statement, in writing?
Well, I'll tell you about it
and you write it down, eh?
I'm not all that educated.
I can't do this reading and writing.
Yeah, that's what he said.
He's a bit simple, you know.
Yeah Ok. I'll have another go at him.
Yeah, goodbye.
Well now...
The drain where you said you put
your wife body, it's been examined.
There's nothing there.
Well, I put it there.
I see.
It's a manhole, is it?
I expect so.
Who helped you lift the lid off?
I did it myself.
Who are you trying to kid?
It took three men to lift it.
Well, I don't know about that, I did it.
I don't think your wife body
was ever down that drain.
All right.
All right. I only said that
to protect a man named Christie.
- Christie?
- Yes.
It's not true about the man in the cafe.
Now I'll tell you the truth.
She wasn't very good with money
I'm afraid, run up a lot of bad debts.
That was one of the reasons
they were always fighting.
This was their little domain.
- What's it? Just the two rooms?
- Just the two rooms, yes.
You'd only have to ask the neighbours
about the fights they had I'm afraid.
One of your chaps from the station had to
come round one night, as a matter of fact.
- You saw them go, did you?
- No.
No, they just crept off.
- Who has the flat below this?
- Mr. Kitchener, an old gentleman.
Worked on the railways.
Inspector you, you want to look
at his flat Mr. Kitchener, I expect.
Oh, yes.
Yes well, he's in hospital at
the moment so he'll not mind.
I just found these, sir.
They're all about the torso murder case.
Oh yes, a bit morbid about that case Tim was.
Kept all the newspaper cuttings.
Can't think why.
I thought he couldn't read.
No, he used to get Beryl to read them to him.
I better take a look in here first.
I, I just left the kettle
on in the kitchen, I'll just...
Shoo, shoo, go, get out, get out, shoo.
This is the back garden.
- Can't seem to get this open.
- It gets jammed occasionally.
Go and get the poker, Ethel.
Sort of bundle under the sink here.
What's that Mrs. Christie,
under the sink, you know?
Well take a look. It's a bundle of
something, you know what's in it?
No.
It's a tablecloth
or something, all wrapped up.
- Is that yours?
- No, I don't think so.
Well feel it, feel if you recognize it.
- No, I never seen it before.
- Take it out, let's have a look at it.
Weighs a ton.
Better cut the cord, if
you no objection madam.
No, not at all, it isn't mine anyway.
- There's another one here.
- It's a baby.
Did they ask Mr. Christie...
if he could get the baby back
from the people in Acton, do you know?
Well bloody hell, you going to
keep this up all the way to London?
At 11:50 AM today I found the
dead body of your wife Beryl Evans,
concealed in a wash-house at 10
Rillington Place, Notting Hill.
Also, the body of your baby daughter,
Geraldine, in the same outbuilding...
and this clothing was found on them.
Later today, I was present
at Kensington mortuary...
when it was established that the cause
of death was strangulation in both cases.
I have reason to believe that you
were responsible for their deaths.
Yes.
Right, then.
She was incurring one debt after another
and I could not stand it any longer...
so I strangled her with a piece of rope
and took her down to the flat below...
the same night whilst
the old man was in hospital.
I waited until the Christies
downstairs had gone to bed,
then I took her to the
wash-house after midnight.
Then I strangled my baby in our bedroom
with my tie and took her to the wash-house.
Sign there lad.
If you don't know how to write
your name just put a cross.
- I know how to write my name.
- Good lad, just sign there then.
Mr. Christie, I've got to suggest to
you and I do not want there to be...
any misapprehensions about it...
that you are responsible for the death
of Mrs. Evans and of the little girl.
Or if that's not so, that at
least you know very much more about...
those deaths than you've said.
That's a lie.
That is a lie.
Did you know that Mrs. Evans was
pregnant in November last year?
My wife told me.
Did you have any discussion
with her or Mr. Evans?
We understood from what Mrs. Evans
told my wife that she had been taking...
pills and various things
to procure an abortion.
Now, I suggest to you that a
little later you said to Evans:
If you or your wife had
come to me in the first place...
I could have done
it for you without any risk.
No, definitely not.
You remember him saying to you:
I didn't think you knew
anything about medical stuff?
No, he...
And that you said that you've been
training to be a doctor before the war?
No, that's nonsense.
You remember showing Evans
some medical books in your flat?
I've not got any medical books.
Except the St. John Ambulance handbook.
Did you show this book to Evans?
No, certainly not, it's an obsolete book.
I daresay it's obsolete
but did you show it to him?
No.
Did you not tell Evans that
you had been doing training in...
medical matters before the war and that you
stopped the training because of an accident?
No.
You gave evidence yesterday that during
the night of Tuesday, the 8th of November...
you heard a thud.
Yes.
It seemed rather loud.
It startled us, rather.
- It woke us up.
- This was about midnight?
Oh yes, it would be.
- You quite sure about that?
- Absolutely certain.
Do you remember giving evidence at
the Magistrate Court at West London?
Yes.
You never mentioned there this noise of
something very heavy being moved, did you?
- Oh yes, I did mention it, I'm certain.
- Well, perhaps it was not taken down.
What happened after the
sound of furniture moving?
I...
I went off to sleep again because of the
pain I was having with the fibrositis.
I was taking tablets, it was the
only way I could get to sleep.
I'm still taking them, as a matter of fact.
Are you still suffering
from fibrositis Mr. Christie?
Very badly my lord,
I was in severe pain all night.
I had to go to the doctor again last
night and he prescribed for me and...
gave me some pills to alleviate the pain...
but I was awake for most of the night.
Would you be more comfortable
giving your evidence sitting down?
- Well yes, I think I would my lord.
- Then you may.
Thank you.
Mr. Christie, yesterday you
remember Mr. Humphreys asking you...
if you had been in the police
force during the last war?
Yes.
But in fact you were a
constable in the war reserve?
Four years, yes.
But you are not, are you,
a man of good character?
Well, I have had some trouble.
I apologize for having to ask you
these questions but I'm afraid I must.
On four occasions you've been convicted
of offenses of dishonesty, haven't you?
- Three.
- Not four?
Then perhaps I had better put them to you.
Were you sentenced to...
three months imprisonment
in 1921 for stealing postal orders?
Yes.
Bound over for false
pretenses in 1923 at Halifax?
Yes, I remember that.
Nine months hard labor for stealing
material and goods in 1924 at Uxbridge?
Yes.
And three months also at Uxbridge
for stealing a motor car in 1933?
Yes, that's right.
Well surely Mr. Christie, you could
remember that four offenses for dishonesty.
Well, I, I had an idea it was three. I...
I just didn't, I just wasn't quite sure.
I see.
But what's perhaps more
important and relevant to this matter...
are there two other
convictions recorded against you?
Yes.
The first of these being
for violence at Halifax in 1923?
Yes.
And the second
when you were sentenced to six...
months for malicious wounding in 1929?
Yes.
Do you appreciate that the medical evidence
in this case which has been called...
is this woman was strangled?
I was informed of that, yes.
Not killed by abortion, of which there's
no sign whatever, but by strangulation?
Yes.
Now, a word about your character.
- What were you doing in the First World War?
- I was in the army in the First World War.
- Fighting for your country?
- Yes.
I, I was gassed, twice.
I was blinded for three months...
and I never spoke for three and a half years.
The last time you were in trouble with the
police for any offense was in 1933, was it?
Yes.
- Seventeen years ago?
- Yes.
In this last war,
in spite of your disabilities...
you served in the war
reserve police for many years.
- Is that right?
- Yes, I did.
And I was commended on two occasions.
Thank you, Mr. Christie.
What you doing?
I'm going to sleep in the front room.
Front room?
- On the sofa from now on.
- What's that in aid of?
Nothing, is just that I'm not
sleeping very well, that's all.
Now...
it is you who voluntarily go to the
police on the 30th of November...
after hearing about the telegram which your
aunt had received from Mr. Thorley...
your wife father?
That's right.
It was because your previous lies
were exposed by the telegram...
that you decided to go to the police, was it?
It wasn't because of the lies.
Then why did you suddenly go to the police?
Well...
I was getting worried about my daughter.
Are you saying that seriously to the jury?
That you go to the police
and confessed a murder...
because you're worried about your daughter?
With great respect, there
is no confession of murder.
He said, I have disposed of my wife.
I have put her down the drain.
It sounds very like murder.
All he said was he had put her...
it might well be her body, down the drain.
You made a statement to the police,
and this is the first you made...
Exhibit 6.
In which you talk
of meeting a man in a cafe...
and of how your wife took these pills...
and died of them and you found her dead.
Do you remember that statement?
- Yes, I remember that statement.
- That is untrue?
That is untrue, yes.
You then make a statement in
which you set out in some detail...
how Mr. Christie gave your wife
something which would cause an abortion...
and she died of that.
- You remember that one?
- Yes, I remember that one too.
- Is that one true or untrue?
- That is true.
Then you made a statement in which
you confessed to murdering your wife...
and your child, is that true or untrue?
I was told of my daughter
death before I made that one.
True or untrue?
- It is true I made the statement.
- Is the statement true or untrue?
Untrue.
And then that's the second statement you've
made to the police, in some detail...
- which is untrue.
- Yes.
So would it not be
right to say that you are a...
person who's prepared to lie or tell
the truth at your own convenience?
Well, why should I tell lies?
My life is at stake here.
Now...
we have shown that your story...
about Mr. Christie giving your
wife an abortion is nonsense.
Well, you are the person who alleges
Mr. Christie is the murderer in this case.
Can you suggest why he
should've strangled your wife?
Well, he was...
home all day.
Can you suggest why he
should've strangled your wife?
No, I can't.
Can you suggest why he
should've strangled your daughter?
No.
I didn't do it Auntie, Christie done it.
I didn't even know the baby was dead till
the police brought me in to Notting Hill.
Well, Christie said she was in East Acton.
Get Christie.
Get him here to see me, he's the
only one who can help me now.
Timothy John Evans.
The court has found you
guilty of willful murder.
And the sentence of the court upon you is...
that you be taken from this place to a lawful
prison and thence to a place of execution...
and there you'll suffer death by hanging...
and that your body be buried
within the precincts of the prison...
in which you shall have been last
confined before your execution.
And may the Lord have
mercy on your soul, amen.
The one thing that sticks in my mind...
is I'm in for something I haven't done sir.
You must remember Evans...
that we're not here to go into
the rights and wrongs of your case.
- This is purely a medical board.
- Yes, I know that sir.
See...
Christie done it.
You confessed at Notting Hill, why was that?
I broke down at Notting Hill.
I had nothing else to worry about
when I knew my daughter was dead.
Why you think your daughter was killed?
Well...
to be out of the way, wasn't it?
- I see, any further questions?
- No.
All right, thank you.
Come along then.
But Christie done it. I say Christie done it.
All right, all right.
Well, I don't know. He's not
an unpleasing little fellow.
Oh no, primitive sort of creature but
nothing abnormal, medically speaking.
- Rather nicer than average, I thought.
- Yes.
Nothing very much at all really.
Certainly no medical grounds for a reprieve.
Oh.
Supper is in the meat safe.
I should've thought you
could've got it for yourself.
I'm going to bed now.
I've taken a sleeping pill.
I'm going to Sheffield in the morning.
- Sheffield?
- To stay with Jessy and Bob.
You can't just leave me here.
I can't stand Jessy you know
that, she talks too much.
What am I meant to do then?
We no friends.
Not a soul set foot in this
house for two years nearly.
Not since the Evanses, we've no money.
- You haven't worked since I don't know when.
- I can't work, can I?
Not with my back and everything,
the doctor says I should be in hospital.
I know where you should be.
- What's that supposed to mean?
- You know what I mean.
Oh...
You don't mind, do you?
It's migraine.
- I get these terrible headaches.
- Very unpleasant. Oh, very unpleasant.
Mind you...
medically speaking of course, it's a very
interesting condition syndrome as we call it.
You're not a doctor, are you?
Well, now how did you know that?
Well, I should've say, I was.
- Was?
- Yes, I...
I did a favor for a friend, a lady friend. I
expect you understand. You know how it is.
Oh yes. Oh dear.
- Can I get you another cup of tea?
- No, thanks.
You sure?
Yes, well of course, they
won't do you any good, mind.
- What does though?
- Well, if only I was free to...
Honestly, I'd do anything.
You certainly do yourself
proud in here, I must say.
- My wife is away.
- I don't blame her.
You can keep that mattress for a start.
I've the whole shop running alive.
- What's that meant to mean?
- Bed bugs.
Look, this is mahogany, pure mahogany.
Oh, yeah? Ten quid the lot.
- What? For everything?
- Everything, but that mattress.
- That will walk out by itself.
- Ten pounds?
- Surely it must be worth 15.
- Not to me, it isn't.
- Why, I can't work I was wounded in the war.
- That's tough luck, squire.
Twelve is my top. Yes or no?
- All right.
- I'll have the van round up this afternoon.
One, two, three.
I was just looking through my papers.
Cuttings and things, newspaper cuttings.
Founds in all the papers a few years back.
Murder trial it was.
Dreadful business, appalling.
Of course, I was in the police once so I...
understand these things.
I have had a very...
varied life.
Funny really.
In all the papers a few years back and now...
Pig.
Well of course, if that's
the way you're going to talk...
It was what I expect, of course.
Ok, just dump it here.
- Really smells bad in here.
- We'll soon get it cleaned up.
Cliff?
Go and get the police.
What are you doing? Looking for work?
My employment cards haven't come through.
- Well, what's your name?
- John Waddington.
Have you got anything
on you to prove your identity?
- No, nothing at all.
- Take your hat off, will you?
You're Christie, John Reginald Christie.
I shall have to take you into custody.
Come along.