Putra Al Fatih. Annisa Santosa.
Santosa is my dad's name, sir.
Ilham Santosa.
How old are you guys?
-I'm 20.
-I'm 18.
Are you serious?
You really want to get married?
Aren't you still in school?
Ninis is still in high school,
but she'll graduate soon.
As for me, I'm not in high school anymore.
I'm attending college now.
Then who told you guys to get married?
-I myself.
-My dad.
I see. An arranged marriage.
Sis, there are laws
and conditions to get married.
First,
you must be a Muslim.
Second, the groom must not be
a family member of the bride.
Thirdly, there must be a valid custodian
present when the wedding vows take place.
Fourth, you must not wed
while undertaking a major or minor hajj.
Fifth.
You must not be being pressured into it.
You are here to get married.
Are you being pressured into this or not?
-Inshallah, no, sir.
-No, sir.
You two know each other well?
-Yes sir.
-No sir.
What is going on here?
How could you not know each other?
Please explain it to me.
Well, I don't know Putra that well, sir.
It's my dad who chose Putra
to be my husband.
But I'm sure and convinced
that my dad's choice
is what's best for me.
You said you knew her.
How did you get to know her?
I follow her Instagram account, sir.
Almost every day, I see what she posts.
I put likes on all her photos.
When she posts something,
I'm the first one to comment.
When she attends seminars with her dad,
I also go.
I sit in the front row.
For me, family is everything.
100% Halal is a book
based on my personal experiences.
With this book
I want to motivate you all
to get married young.
You must all know Annisa.
BOOK TALK: 100 PERCENT HALAL
ILHAM SANTOSA, WRITER
My beloved daughter.
I've been telling her
to also get married young.
Maybe someone here is interested.
Please see me first
if you're ready and brave enough.
From that moment on, sir,
I've never missed Mr. Ilham's seminars,
or any events attended by Ninis.
I got red marks all over.
How come you always get good marks, Nis?
I study.
You should have studied, too, Lit.
Lita, do you want to improve
your red grades?
Of course. How?
Put eye drops on your marks.
Instead of red,
they'll be clear and bright.
Archery trains us to concentrate
and focus on our aim.
-Understand?
-Yes, sis.
Thank you.
Sir.
My name is Putra.
I'm asking for your daughter's hand.
So, you see, sir.
I know everything about Ninis.
I know all about her family,
what activities she's interested in,
what her favorite color is,
her favorite food,
and also who her best friends are.
-Ouch!
-Lita!
You and your light, feather-weight figure.
Sorry, sir.
Hi, Nis.
Let me tell you…
Marriage is not like dating
where you break up and make up repeatedly.
No, sir. I never date.
Dad says dating opens
the opportunity to commit adultery.
That's why my dad asked me to marry young.
Let me explain.
There's more than meets the eye
in a marriage.
You have to think about
where you will stay after getting married.
We'll live in my house, sir. With my dad.
You, Putra.
How will you provide for your wife?
-I will…
-My dad will provide, sir.
He will help us out.
You will be the head of the family.
You have to provide
for the needs of your wife.
Inshallah, my dad will provide for us.
He will give guidance.
He will give examples as to how
to be a responsible head of the family.
You keep saying "my dad" Again and again!
Are you marrying your dad or him?
OK, fine.
If you're serious about getting married,
have you learned the prayer for the act?
Which prayer, sir?
The prayer for… you know.
-Which prayer, sir?
-The prayer for that act.
-What act?
Don't you get it already?
-The prayer for before copulating.
-Body cleaning?
Copulating. Not body cleaning.
How do I put this?
Ah, sis?
How do children nowadays say "copulating"?
You mean "ML," sir?
-Isn't that what you mean, sir?
-Ah, that's right.
Say, how come you know?
About the term "making love"?
Can it be that you…?
What a despicable thing to say, sir.
I'm a pure woman.
I'm protecting the honor of myself,
the nation, and the country.
I was just joking.
-You've never made love?
-Of course not, Rel.
To wrap things up…
Let me remind you not to forget
the prayer before copulating.
There's a prayer for that?
Yes. Listen.
Say with me.
In the name of Allah.
-In the name of Allah.
-"In the name of Allah."
-O Allah.
-"O Allah."
-Keep the devil away from us.
-"Keep the devil away from us."
-And keep the devil away.
-"And keep the devil away."
-From what You blessed us with.
-"From what You blessed us with."
-Amen.
-You're so deep into it.
-I can't wait to experience it myself.
Have you practiced
saying the wedding vows?
I have, sir.
Give me your hand.
Putra Al Fatih, I marry off
my daughter Annisa Santosa to you,
with a mahr of ten grams of gold jewelry
and a set of worship equipment
paid in cash.
I accept the marriage of Annisa Santosa,
daughter of Ilham Santosa,
with the mahr mentioned above,
paid in cash.
-Is it valid, dear witnesses?
-Valid!
All praise is due to Allah.
Not valid!
The marriage is not valid!
Do you agree?
Do you agree that
the marriage is not valid?
Let's continue, sir.
What's wrong, Grandma?
Mom, please don't act like that.
-Ninis is now Putra's wife…
-Shut your mouth!
I want Ninis to sleep with me tonight.
I insist!
It's all right, Nis.
You sleep with Grandma tonight.
Are you sure it's all right?
Yes, Grandma. Tonight…
I will sleep with you in here.
The night has come
Go to sleep, my dear
The prayer that follows
All through the night
Will put you sound asleep
And soothe your heart
Until the morning comes
And we welcome its light
Come in.
Wow!
Darling.
-Darling.
-What?
Just a moment. Let me go to the restroom.
OK.
Just a moment.
Come on, Lit, Rel. Pick up.
You're both about to sleep?
Help me out here.
What is going on, Nis?
Calling at this hour…
You're disturbing my me time.
What is wrong, Nis?
I haven't slept yet.
By the way, aren't you supposed to be
copulating?
Don't forget to pray beforehand.
But I'm confused.
I don't know how to start.
You're worrying
over such an unnecessary thing.
It's easy.
Just lie down
and stick your body onto him.
What are you guys babbling about?
Don't confuse me even more. Help me out.
Have you taken a bath?
Of course I have!
Have you brushed your teeth?
Otherwise,
your lovely time will be disturbed by
smelly breath.
Phew.
Lita,
what a big mouth you have.
Well, you can see
how tense Nissa is.
I don't know what to do.
You both know well
that I've never been around boys.
That's true. Remember what
Grandma Yos used to say?
"Put a distance between yourself and boys,
one and a half meters!
Don't stare into each other's eyes!"
Well, she said it for my own benefit.
Especially after my mom passed away.
Grandma Yos is so possessive.
I thought she'd get over it
once I got married,
but she's still possessive.
She still is?
Nis, are you all right?
I'm all right, darling.
See, guys…
Just go ahead. Change your clothes.
Don't forget to wear the lingerie
that I gifted to you.
Don't wear your typical sleeping clothes.
Go ahead. Change!
Are you serious?
Dead serious. Go ahead. Change.
Change!
They just hung up?
Lita, Aurel. Some friends you are.
3 MONTHS LATER
PREGNANT
-Ninis!
Congratulations. You did it!
By the way, how can you be pregnant?
Because she has a husband, of course.
She's so smart and yet clueless.
By the way,
how does it feel to be pregnant?
Spill and tell us!
Nothing extraordinary.
I've been feeling nauseous since yesterday
and weak, too.
It turns out they're signs of this gift.
Alhamdulillah.
Your post went viral.
That pic of your test pack
got 456,321 likes.
Wow, you know the numbers so well.
-Of course, I'm an expert.
-Oh my. Such a huge number.
-You should have a giveaway for the fans.
-Everyone's doing it.
Once again, congratulations.
Thank you, guys.
Cheers!
-Assalamu alaikum, Nis.
-Waalaikumsalam.
Are you really pregnant?
Alhamdulillah.
I'm so happy.
Yes, darling. I'm very happy, too.
Why didn't you inform me first?
I wanted it to be a surprise
until you were at home.
But then you found out already
from Instagram, didn't you?
Yes. I've asked for permission
from my superior
to take you for a checkup tomorrow.
You don't need to, darling.
I called Dad immediately.
We're on the way
to the hospital now to do the checkup.
Besides, it wouldn't look good.
You've worked there for just a few weeks,
but you're already asking for extra leave?
That's a good point.
You don't need to worry.
If I need anything, Dad is here to help.
-Right, Dad?
-Of course, dear.
I will always be there for you.
All right, then. I'll continue my work.
-Assalamu alaikum.
-Waalaikumsalam
What's the matter, bro?
Your face looks twisted all over.
Like a kite's thread.
You know, household things.
What's wrong with your house?
It's stilted?
It's not about ladders or things
in my house. Household stuff.
Wow. Sorry I set you off.
I can't say I have a household
to take care of yet,
but when it comes to women…
I'm an expert.
Let me share something with you.
As soon as you get home,
hug your wife from behind.
And bite the back of her neck.
Then, you take her to the roof.
And you spoon her.
You think my wife is a cat?
You and your twisted mind…
Oh, Putra…
Already in over your head
with just one wife.
What will it be like when you have three
like I plan to have?
Alhamdulillah. The baby is healthy.
OK.
Nurse.
Ninis…
You must be happy.
OK. Alhamdulillah, everybody is healthy.
In the first trimester,
please take care of her food intake.
Don't ever drink soda.
Then the baby will grow healthily.
And don't do hard activities.
OK, Doctor,
I will look after what she eats.
-I will monitor her activity, too.
-But don't get too possessive, sir.
Let her enjoy the pregnancy,
with full caution.
There's one more thing
I should remind you of.
During the first trimester,
the pregnancy is at its most fragile.
So, when you do the intimate activity,
do it slowly.
Don't get too aggressive,
for the sake of the baby.
Funny thing to say, Doc.
She is my daughter.
-She's your daughter? Oh…
-Yes.
What a great dad. He accompanied you
all the way here. Where's the husband?
Her husband's still at work.
That's why I'm taking her.
Very well, repeat what I said to him.
-We will, Doc.
-I will tell him.
-Assalamu alaikum.
-Waalaikumsalam.
How is it, Nis?
How far along is the pregnancy?
Alhamdulillah,
it's eight weeks old, darling.
From now on, you must--
Look after her intake and health.
One more thing.
Don't keep checking on her.
-Abort it!
-Astaghfirullah, mother!
What are you saying?
Ilham,
you're the evilest man in the world.
Grandma!
All this time,
I've been very patient with you.
Dad never makes mistakes!
He is the most responsible man
in this house.
The evilest person in this house…
is you.
You dare to speak up to me now?
Nis…
Your child is an illegitimate child!
Because your marriage is not valid
according to the religion.
Your dad here
is not your valid custodian,
don't you know that?
Mother, enough.
Grandma!
THE DEPARTED
YOYOH SUMARNI DAUGHTER OF SUDARMAN
I heard her last words, Dad.
Is it true that I'm not your daughter?
Morning, Dad.
I've made your favorite dish,
chicken soup.
Good morning.
Let me prepare it for you.
Thank you.
Where are you having
your seminar today, Dad?
Bandung.
For how long?
Two weeks.
That's quite long.
I'll prepare some snacks.
You can nibble on them during the ride.
Jakarta to Bandung is quite far, and
there's traffic jams to consider, too.
Have you packed your clothes?
I'll put them in your luggage.
Thank you, Nis.
-Please put this in the car.
-Yes, sir.
Please be careful, Dad.
Nis.
You're the only one I have left
that I love.
It will be like that forever.
-Assalamu alaikum.
-Waalaikumsalam.
Are you all right, Nis?
Yes, I am.
Nis, is this your real mother?
-I don't know for sure yet, Lit.
-She's pretty.
Just like you.
Looking back, my mom passed away
due to cervical cancer.
Maybe that's why they adopted me.
And the way Grandma Yos treated me…
was so different.
That's impossible, Nis.
Throughout her life,
Grandma Yos loved
and took good care of you,
even though she was overprotective
and a bit annoying.
That's what makes me confused.
Have you asked your dad
who your real parents were?
No, I have not.
I didn't have the guts to ask.
I'm afraid that if I ask that,
my dad will get sad.
And I've promised myself
not to make Dad sad and disappointed.
He's been very kind to me, Lit.
You're right about that.
But do you guys recall…
during the wedding vows back then,
Grandma Yos got hysterical.
She said your marriage was not valid.
Maybe that was a sign.
She wanted to reveal the truth
for your sake, Nis.
That is correct.
But we ignored her, right?
We thought that she was being possessed.
Maybe that's the case
because before she passed away,
she said that
my child is an illegitimate child.
An offspring of an invalid wedding.
She might be trying to do that.
Lita, what are you saying?
I'll slam your mouth shut.
I'm being serious. Listen closely.
I once attended a sermon.
One of the conditions
for a marriage to be considered valid
according to Islamic law
is to have a guardian present.
If your dad is not a valid custodian,
as long as you don't know the truth,
you're not committing a sin.
However, if you do know,
then your wedding is not valid
and you have to remarry,
this time accompanied by
a valid custodian.
With your real father,
an uncle from your real mother's side,
or a legal custodian you appoint
based on a request from your real mother.
If you and Putra don't do that,
you are both committing a sin.
Your marriage is not valid.
And that's exactly what Grandma Yos said.
It's not like you to be right.
Did you drink Zamzam water recently?
Such a nuisance!
It's you who drank hand wash water.
But, this is the real deal.
You must know and understand it.
Just so you know,
I often go to religious lectures.
What lectures? You attend
to catch the eyes of the boys there.
What are you saying, Rel?
Stop being a know-it-all.
But you're not wrong about the boys.
Oh, just quit it.
It might not be true about Grandma Yos.
Let's change the subject.
So, how is life after marriage?
Is it nice?
-Go ahead, tell us!
-You go get married and find out.
-Tell me how to start?
-You can attend lectures like I did.
See, she does attend lectures
for the boys.
She was searching for the best catch.
-You'll then do the introductions.
-Yes. We'll get introduced.
-All right, then, Miss Know-It-All!
-I know all the tricks in the book!
RUMOR SAYS
ANNISA SANTOSA'S MARRIAGE IS INVALID.
SHE'S HAVING AN ILLEGITIMATE CHILD.
DON'T YOU HAVE ANYTHING BETTER TO DO?
JUST BECAUSE YOUR LIFE IS MEANINGLESS,
DON'T MAKE SLANDEROUS COMMENTS,
ESPECIALLY TO PEOPLE YOU DON'T KNOW.
Nis! Are you all right?
What's wrong, Nis?
I want to look for my real parents.
We will do that.
Later, after our child is born.
Darling!
Our marriage is not valid.
Our relationship is not halal anymore.
We can't mix freely again.
What are you talking about?
Go back to sleep.
Darling!
What we're doing now
is committing something unlawful.
How could you say that?
We didn't know that your dad
was not your valid custodian.
If we don't remarry soon,
this child will turn out to be
what Grandma said it was.
So what is it you want?
I want to find my real parents.
I want to find my valid custodian so that
our relationship will be completely halal.
Then this child
won't be called an illegitimate child.
-Excuse me, brother…
-Yes?
Do you know which way
Suka Bobo village is?
Suka Bobo village?
Go across the road, then head straight.
-Over there?
-Yes. Straight ahead.
-Thank you, brother.
-You're welcome.
-Do you know…?
-I don't.
-Thanks. Excuse me, sir.
-You're welcome.
Excuse us, brother. Do you know this lady?
-No we don't.
-Thank you, brother.
Thank you.
SUKA BOBO VILLAGE
Excuse me, sis.
Do you know the lady in this photo?
-I'm afraid I don't know her.
-Thank you, sis.
Excuse me.
It's raining. We must hurry.
Assalamu alaikum.
What is it, brother? Can I help you?
It's rare that someone greets me
like that in this place.
I bet you went to an Islamic school.
-How many hours do you want the room for?
-Why do you have hourly rates?
You won't be able to do it
for 24 hours, will you?
If you can, be my guest.
There's plenty of rooms.
Brother, we are husband and wife!
Watch your mouth
or thunder may strike you.
Why are you getting so annoyed?
Here's the key.
The rate is 400,000 per night.
Here you go. Come, Nis.
So fierce!
At least he paid.
Oh, my…
This is because of
that Islamic school student.
I shouldn't bother him.
Better go back to bed.
How could that thunder come
all of a sudden?
What do you think you're doing?
-Get down from the bed!
-What is it, Nis?
Your place is on the couch.
I sleep on the bed. Alone.
How could that be? What wrong have I done?
We are husband and wife.
I'll move to another room
if you won't sleep on the couch.
No, don't do that.
OK, I'll sleep on the couch.
Here.
Nis, you're still my wife.
Why can't I touch you
just because of one new fact?
You know already.
Our marriage is not valid.
We cannot freely mix.
It's forbidden to intimately interact.
How long must I be in this situation?
I can't suppress it.
Until we remarry!
Fast if you can't suppress it.
Now I'm annoyed.
There's hardly any space to sleep.
No news is worth reading.
It's all fabricated.
A hoax.
No one is in favor of the people.
Brother?
-Brother!
-Oh my! Thunder again!
What is it, brother?
Do you know this lady?
No, brother.
OK, thank you.
Aye-aye, brother.
That's some kind of magic the guy has.
Thunder accompanies him everywhere.
Could he be a descendant
of a thunder warrior?
Mother.
Pretty child.
Lovely child.
-Your mom loves you.
-Excuse me, sister.
I'd like to ask.
Do you know the lady in this photo?
Let me see.
-What's her name?
-I don't know, sis.
How can that be?
One needs to know a name first
before finding the person.
All I know is that
she's a Jaipongan dancer.
You're kidding, right?
No Jaipongan dancers
will be hanging around in broad daylight.
You won't find one.
If you want to find meatball sellers
or tofu sellers, that's one thing.
But Jaipongan dancers
only come out at night.
Hey, cut it out.
As you can see, the father can only breed.
Later, he'll be nowhere to be found.
-Stop making noise.
-OK, sis. Thank you.
You're welcome. Wait a second…
If you want to see Jaipongan dancers…
See that place? They usually
hang out there on Saturday nights.
Check it out.
-Thank you so much, sis.
-My pleasure.
We'll go get ice cream later.
Go get your sister.
No need.
-Mineral water delivery.
-Hi.
Come in, brother.
-Why are you late today?
-I had so many orders.
Nis, let's call it for today.
It's raining.
You shouldn't get too tired.
Think of the baby.
It's OK. I can still walk.
Very well.
Get some rest. I need to go to the toilet.
-Astaghfirullah!
-Are you looking for someone?
Can I see who you're looking for?
Rinda Kumalasari?
You know her?
A Jaipongan maestro.
Can you take me to her?
Who was that man with you?
He's nobody. Just a friend.
I can take you to her.
On one condition.
What's that?
Don't come with him.
-All right.
-Come on your own.
Do you see the house on the corner?
Meet me there at eleven tonight.
I'm going now.
What was he up to?
I asked him about this photo.
Did he know her?
Darling, let's go back to the hotel.
It's getting late.
Let's find some girls,
and then we'll party.
There's one. Hey, sweetie!
Look, she's running.
Gosh.
Come in.
Please, come in.
Take a seat.
No need to rush. Let's chill first.
We'll have a good time.
Just tell me where Rinda is!
Behave yourself!
Don't you dare treat women
disrespectfully.
Women should be protected and guarded.
You got that?
I was just pulling a prank.
Please forgive my friend.
Take a seat.
Please, sit down.
Why did you tell me to come here?
I don't have much time.
Tell me where Rinda is!
Calm down.
You'll get high blood pressure.
Take it easy.
I think I've seen you before.
But where exactly?
You're the musician
with those absurd songs.
She's a fan of my work.
I told my friend to lead you here
because I need input
for my religious song.
Since you look like a religious person,
I'd like you to listen to my song.
I'm sorry, I don't have time.
My life is at stake.
I'll listen to your song later,
but right now
I need to know where Rinda is.
Hold on.
What business do you have with Rinda?
I'd like to learn to dance.
Who wants to learn
Jaipongan dance nowadays?
You should learn modern dance instead.
-What's wrong with Jaipongan dance?
-No.
Relax. Chill.
It's your human right to learn to dance.
Protected by the laws.
Go ahead. Learn to dance. Chill.
I'm just amused someone still wants
to learn Jaipongan dance.
Go ahead. Tell me where Rinda is.
OK, but you must promise
you will listen to my songs.
Rinda usually hangs around in the hall
on the eastern side.
Go ahead. You'll find her there.
Are you all right, Nis?
Calm down.
Calm down, please.
Nothing immoral was being done.
Everything is in order. Just chill.
Everything in order, am I right?
-Yes. Thanks for the information.
-Relax.
I'll be on my way. Assalamu alaikum.
Waalaikumsalam, pretty girl.
How silly of you, back then.
I was just trying my luck.
Nis, how could you leave
without telling me?
Please forgive me, darling.
Where are we going?
Tanjung flower
Greatly desired
Oh, my
The city of Bandung
The city of Bandung is very beautiful
Oh, my, Tanjung flower
It blooms and falls
We must respect
Respect women's honor
I'll get changed.
-Thank you, everyone. I'll be on my way.
-Thank you, sis.
Nis…
Sum…
Sumireh…
You're pregnant again.
Where did your husband go?
He's not coming back, is he?
Poor girl.
I bet your husband
has married another woman.
Poor girl.
Darling, dear…
Come.
Let's go in, Sum.
Sumireh.
Nis, why are we stalking her?
We should've approached her.
You should tell her who you really are.
It's not that easy.
For 18 years, I never knew
that I had a different mother.
She might not actually be my real mother.
I've been reconsidering.
Maybe I shouldn't be doing this.
What are you saying?
You've got this far and you want to stop?
Nis.
The person you've been looking for
is in front of you.
You really want to miss the opportunity?
You think that by talking like that,
you can help calm my uneasiness?
Help me find a solution.
To Suka Bobo!
Dominoes!
-Here.
-To Suka Bobo!
Nis. What are we doing here?
Last stop. We've reached the terminal.
We have arrived.
-Last stop. The terminal.
-Hurry up.
Wait for me.
-Ouch!
-What? How come…?
Why are Lita and Aurel here?
Don't ask too much.
Trust me on this.
-Come.
-Hey.
-There's Ninis.
-Hi.
Ninis.
To Suka Bobo. Bobo?
Dominoes!
Sweetie, going to Bobo?
Smart-ass! You should be working
instead of sleeping.
-So feisty!
-Cool it. Don't you dare!
This is my friend!
Anyone to Cibobo?
Your mother's place is still far, Nis?
-I'm thirsty.
-I have mineral water, Ta.
Here you go. Have some water.
Drink a lot of water.
-It's good mineral water. Natural.
-Thank you.
You can do it.
You can.
Assalamu alaikum.
-Waalaikumsalam.
-Excuse us, ma'am.
Does Miss Rinda Kumalasari live here?
Oh my God. Ninis' mom is so pretty.
Who is Ninis?
I'm sorry, ma'am.
What my friend meant is,
you resemble our lecturer.
Her name is Miss Ninis.
You are both pretty.
-Am I right?
-Right.
We're students
from the University of Jakarta, ma'am.
We're doing some research
for our field study.
Are you Miss Rinda Kumalasari?
I'm sorry. You've got the wrong address.
Wow. I wasn't expecting that.
You were so overzealous in asking.
That must've ticked her off.
-I didn't say anything wrong, right?
-Sure you didn't.
Two, three, four,
five, six, seven
and eight.
One, two…
Gosh, so many mosquitoes.
The mosquitoes here are so aggressive.
-They keep biting like crazy.
-You can say that again.
One, two, three…
-The bites have turned red.
-Gosh, it's raining.
That's it for today.
We'll continue tomorrow.
Go approach her.
-Go on.
-You wait here.
Ma'am.
I know your name is Rinda Kumalasari.
I'm humbly begging you,
please let us research in your place.
What are you going to do here?
We want to study.
If you want to study, do it on campus.
My place is not a campus.
Ma'am…
Nissa!
-Nissa!
-Go after her. Quick!
-Ma'am!
-Putra.
Putra, wait for us.
We've come all the way to see you
to learn how to dance, ma'am.
We've sacrificed a lot to reach here.
That's your problem.
-I really want to learn dancing.
-Jaipongan dance is an erotic dance.
Take a look at yourself.
But I really want to learn, ma'am.
I want to be like you.
You don't know
how I've waited 18 years
for this opportunity.
Come…
Bring her to my house.
Hurry.
What is wrong with your friend?
She's expecting a child, ma'am.
She's pregnant?
What is it?
And where is her husband?
-I'm…
-We don't know where the husband is.
That's right.
You mean to say…?
Ninis was abandoned by her husband.
Such a shameless guy. A despicable man.
Leaving after having fun.
Watch it.
Stop poking me. It hurts.
Very well. Your friend can stay here.
Let her rest.
You can all spend the night, too.
You mean we can spend the night here?
-Are you serious, ma'am?
-Yes. It's OK.
-Alhamdulillah.
Thank you, ma'am.
You're awake already?
Have some tea.
How far along is your pregnancy?
If you're in the first trimester,
you shouldn't get exhausted.
You shouldn't get stressed, either.
Otherwise, the baby will feel it, too.
Let's have breakfast.
The others have had theirs.
But you will teach us to dance, right?
On one condition.
Don't call me "ma'am."
Call me "sis."
Yes, sis.
DANCE SCHOOL
Jaipongan dance is a symbol
of women's resistance and liberation.
Because men can't be allowed
to step over women.
Ouch!
-What's wrong, Ta?
-You need to ask? I'm in pain. I fell.
Do you really have to ask?
-Get up.
-How could you fall?
-Stop grumbling and help me instead.
-You should've kept to easy moves.
Are you OK?
-I'm OK. I just tripped over.
-You want to keep practicing?
-Yes, sis.
-We'll do the easy moves.
-Try not to keep falling.
-We'll take it slow.
Assalamu alaikum.
How are you, Nis?
Waalaikumsalam.
Thankfully, everything's fine, Dad.
What about you?
You're through with the training?
Yes, I am. I'm in a coffee shop now.
But it seems that
I can't go home to Jakarta yet.
I have to go to Sukabumi.
I have an event there.
It's OK, Dad.
By the way, I'm not at home either.
How come? Where are you?
I've been in Majalengka
for the last few days.
-I'm taking dance practice.
-How come?
Why are you suddenly practicing dancing?
I don't know.
Maybe it's what the baby wants.
I'm also accompanying
Lita and Aurel in their field studies.
I am tagging along
and learning to dance at the same time.
Putra is here.
You don't need to worry.
I see. OK, then.
By the way, Nis…
I want you to join me at a seminar.
As co-speaker.
You can share your experience
about marrying young
and preparing for motherhood.
So others will be inspired.
What do you say?
OK. I'd like to ask my friend
to come and perform there.
She's a dancer? OK, you may.
But remember to look after your pregnancy.
Don't strain yourself.
If your mother were still around,
she would have made your favorite food.
You mean chicken in coconut gravy?
Yes.
But my longing for her
is fulfilled by being here.
Alhamdulillah.
Are you staying in a villager's house?
Yes. She's a dancer.
She's very kind to me.
I feel like I'm in my own home.
Glad to hear it.
Very well, take care.
Give my regards to Putra.
I have to go now.
-Assalamu alaikum.
-Waalaikumsalam.
Good morning, ma'am.
What a delicious smell.
You were saying?
I'm sorry. Sis.
I keep forgetting
because you are like my own mother.
If my daughter were still alive…
she'd be your age by now.
You had a daughter?
She might be happy in paradise now.
Your daughter passed away?
She was an unborn child.
Had she lived…
she'd have grown up
to become a beautiful girl like you.
-Let's bring the food inside.
-OK.
If I might ask you…
Where is your husband now?
The day of birth
should have been
the happiest day of my life.
I have never had a family before.
And that day, my daughter was born.
I was also supposed to have become
the wife of a person I loved.
I didn't even care that
people said I had an illegitimate child.
What mattered was, I didn't get pregnant
because of prostitution.
And I was not a prostitute.
I knew I was wrong,
getting pregnant out of wedlock.
But I made a promise to repent
and take care of my daughter.
So that when she was born,
she would not repeat
her parents' mistakes.
But fate had other plans.
My daughter passed away.
And he left, I don't know where.
The day turned into
the saddest day of my life.
You've made me sad…
Therefore you must look after
your baby well.
The baby will be
the most precious thing in your life.
But, sis…
Why did he leave you?
I don't know.
Maybe he found happiness
with another woman.
If I may ask…
What is your husband's name?
It's not important, who he is.
What is important is,
I'm not alone anymore.
There are children in the dance school
that I have to take care of
so they don't become sex workers
like their mothers.
-Come on.
-Yeah, wait a minute.
We didn't know you guys were here.
You're not interrupting.
Come join us to eat.
-Is it OK?
-Yes. Have some food.
Come. The food is ready.
-I want it.
-You want some?
Come, we'll eat together.
-Here you go.
-Thanks.
So, this is the place?
-It's beautiful.
-Nis.
Do you know what date it is today?
November 28th, I think. Why?
Too bad it's November 28th
instead of October 28th.
What's happening on October 28th?
October 28th is Youth Vow Day.
And I want to change it.
Change it into what?
I want to change it
to the day of the vow that I love you.
What are you saying? That's so cheesy.
You need to loosen up a bit.
Think of the baby.
He's stressed
because you're so uptight and tense.
Are you hungry?
I am.
-Let's have some fried rice.
-OK.
Two portions of fried rice, sir.
-Look, Rinda, a photo site.
-Come and take a photo here!
-Let's take our photos together.
-Take mine first.
Take our photos first
Then I'll take yours.
-You want me to take the photos?
-We'll take turns.
-Promise you'll take mine later?
-I will. Let's do it!
-Sis, strike a pose.
-One, two, three.
Rel, wait a second.
Sis, please put on a happy face.
A cheerful, funny, crazy face.
-I'm shy.
-Well, don't be.
-Look at her.
-Make a face like this, sis.
-Put two hands together,
-You'll look cute.
-One, two, three.
-Smile.
-It's in focus.
-Let me see.
-Like a real photographer's work.
-Let's share it on Instagram.
Yes, let's do it.
I'm getting more confused, darling.
Why is that?
Can it be…
that Rinda is not my real mother?
She said her daughter had passed away.
Well…
I have been asking the locals.
They give different answers.
Some say her daughter passed away.
Others say her husband took her.
I'm not that curious anymore.
Why don't you ask your dad directly?
It will be more solid.
I can feel
there's a big secret
that Dad has been keeping from me.
A secret that has left a painful mark.
I can see it.
And I fear I will reopen the pain.
I fear I will disappoint and hurt Dad.
Wow.
So many photos of Ninis.
My name is Ilham Santosa
May I know your name?
Rinda.
Smooth.
Drink the milk, Rin.
Drink it all.
You really sure you don't want ice cream?
No, thanks, I'm on diet.
Your body is so small,
and yet you're on diet?
Ta, look. Rinda is there by herself.
She's just sitting silently,
like someone with debts.
-Let's sit with her.
-Let's go.
-Hi there, Rinda.
-Sitting here all alone.
Let us sit with you,
so there's three of us.
-I mean, four of us…
-What do you mean by "four"?
You surprised me.
I wasn't expecting anyone.
I'm out for some fresh air.
-I see.
-What are you doing out here?
We just came from the stalls.
Getting some refreshments.
-You want some ice cream?
-No, thanks.
-You shouldn't have offered yours.
-This one's all I have.
Lita, Aurel, I want to ask…
Where is Nissa's husband?
Oh. You mean Putra?
I have no idea. He's probably gone
to the city to buy milk.
Milk for the pregnant one.
-Lita…
-What is it?
-Ta…
-What is it? Tell me.
You know…
It's OK.
You don't need to hide it anymore.
I know everything thanks to Instagram.
What is your real purpose in being here?
It's all right. Tell me.
I won't get mad even if you lied.
Putra is Ninis's husband, sis.
They got married young.
Her dad matched them.
A few days after Ninis got pregnant,
she realized
that their marriage is not legitimate.
Her dad, who gave her away at the wedding,
is not her real parent.
Does that mean Nissa is a foster child?
-Yes.
Her parents are not her real parents?
We'd been thinking
you were Ninis' real mother.
But it turns out
your daughter has died.
We assumed wrong.
-Didn't we.
-Right.
Where did you put the pendant?
I don't know.
Usually, I put it by the bed
every night after I wear it.
I've been looking all over for it,
though, and I can't find it.
-Nis, look at these photos.
-What photos?
Dad…
What does this mean, darling?
Maybe it's true what the villagers said.
Rinda's daughter is not dead.
She was taken by her boyfriend instead.
And the daughter… is me?
You mean to say…
I'm the child
of an illegitimate relationship?
That's impossible, darling.
My dad would not do
a cruel thing like that.
But you can see for yourself.
There are so many photos
of your dad in Rinda's possession.
Look! A photo of Grandma Yos.
It's impossible, darling.
Nis!
You can't keep on taking your dad's side.
If your dad was right and not lying,
he could've easily told the truth.
Why did he choose to hide it instead?
He doesn't dare
to discuss this matter at all.
Darling.
How could you be so impolite
as to accuse Dad like that?
Dad never lies.
He never disappoints me.
He has done a lot for me.
For us.
And what have you done for me and my life?
You never take me seriously.
And I can never be a husband
who makes you respect him.
Because I'm not your father.
You keep praising him,
and yet he couldn't tell the truth
to his own daughter.
Is that what your ideal man is like?
Just stop badmouthing my dad!
Or else…
Or else what?
What will you do?
You should think, Nis.
Why did Grandma Yos say
our marriage was not valid
in the middle of your pregnancy?
She was trying to save us.
She was trying to save you,
and the baby in your womb.
What have you done for her in return?
Your dad is human.
He could have made mistakes.
He's not an angel.
He might even…
have been a bastard in the past.
How dare you!
One, two, three.
And turn!
Four, five, six,
seven and eight.
One, two, three.
Four, five, six.
Seven and eight. Shift to the left…
Lina, what's the matter?
Sis, may I spend the night here?
-Stop crying…
-Come in.
Sis, my father doesn't know
that I'm here, does he?
Why shouldn't he know, Lin?
I'm afraid, sis.
My father gets angry with me all the time.
And my mom used to beat me, too.
You're safe here.
Be calm, OK?
Rinda and I are here for you.
OK?
Yes, sis…
Get some sleep.
The night has come
Go to sleep, my dear
The prayer that follows
All through the night
Will put you sound asleep
And soothe your heart
Until the morning comes
And we welcome its light
Whose song is that?
That's my grandma's song.
Every time I've gone to bed,
from I was a kid to adulthood,
she sang me that song.
She said that when I was in my mom's womb,
my mom used to sing it to me.
I can't stop thinking…
How could Lina's father hurt her?
She's still a little child.
Does this type of thing happen often?
Sis?
What's wrong with you?
My daughter…
You are my daughter.
I thought you were gone, dear.
It turns out you're still alive.
I remember that song very well.
I used to sing it during pregnancy.
Mom…
Am I… really your daughter?
And if I'm your daughter…
then who's my father?
Sir, don't forget. I've made
an appointment at eight o'clock tonight.
-With Mr. Robby.
-You've made an appointment?
Yes, sir.
What's wrong with you?
My schedule is full today.
So… should I cancel it?
Of course not. Once you make an
appointment, you must stick to it.
All right, sir. The event will start soon.
Please take a seat.
Where's my daughter
who has become an expert dancer?
Excuse me, sir?
Come to the briefing, and also,
we'll change your clothes.
Is that it? After all that has happened,
you'll just stay silent and leave?
Why, Dad?
Why have you been lying to me?
All this time,
I've been following your words.
I've done everything that you want.
But what have you really done to me?
You've shoved me into
the pit of sin that you dug.
What kind of a father would do that?
I'm pregnant, Dad.
You had the heart to lie
just for the sake of your image.
You are cruel. You're a hypocrite.
How could you do that?
Eighteen years ago,
you told me my daughter had died,
when in fact, you had taken her with you!
Why?
Answer, Dad! Answer!
Are you OK?
-Nis…
-Don't touch my daughter!
Don't…
Nis, be patient.
Nis. Are you all right?
Darling, forgive me…
All this time, I've never listened to you.
Forgive me
for not being a good wife.
Don't think about it, Nis. Don't be sad.
The baby will be sad, too.
Dad has been lying to me all this time.
He's been lying…
Take it easy, Nis. Calm down.
Please be calm.
Have patience, Nis.
All this time, I've made my penance.
Annisa, go change your clothes.
Have I lost all my rights
with regard to my beloved daughter?
The clerics have decided…
that…
if a child is borne out of wedlock,
the father loses the right
to give her away as her guardian.
That is stated in our religious law.
So…
what should I do?
Have some patience.
Reveal the truth.
My daughter. You look so beautiful.
I take after my mother.
I once told you…
that I wanted
to be the best parent for you.
I have failed.
I've let you down.
I've lied to you.
I've ruined your future.
I just want to say…
please forgive me.
Forgive me.
Rinda.
Please forgive me.
I never meant to lie to you.
At that time…
I was powerless.
I'm sorry, father. I acted out of bounds.
-I will take responsibility…
-Abort it!
Leave the girl!
Don't you ever see her again!
No, Father. I will take responsibility.
I won't add another sin to my conscience.
I want to marry her.
If you marry her, you are never
setting foot in this house again!
And you'll never be considered
as my flesh and blood again, either.
Got that!
Do not ruin my reputation!
It's a matter of tradition.
You can't marry someone of questionable
origin, don't you understand that?
-Do what has to be done, Doctor.
-Yes, sir.
I'm sorry, ma'am.
There were abnormalities.
We did our best, but…
-What?
-I'm sorry.
Doctor…
Look after her as best as you can.
Love her like your own.
Inshallah, ma'am.
Forgive me, Rinda.
Ilham…
A man's worth is seen…
when he has to decide
his destination in life.
Forgive me for what I have done, Rin.
Nis. Nissa.
Everyone is waiting downstairs.
Nis.
Come, Nis.
Annisa…
As women,
sometimes we have to make peace
with our disappointments.
But don't let anger reside
and grow in your heart.
You are a good child, dear.
Understand?
Regarding the role of the custodian,
it has been bestowed on me
as the magistrate guardian,
due to the fact that
the mother of the bride
has no male family members.
Is that true?
That's true, sir.
Let's proceed.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
Putra Al Fatih,
I hereby marry you to Annisa Santosa,
daughter of Rinda Kumalasari,
with a mahr of ten grams of jewelry
and a set of worship equipment
paid in cash.
I accept the marriage of Annisa Santosa
daughter of Rinda Kumalasari
with the mahr paid in cash.
-How is it, honored witnesses?
-It's valid.
Dad…
Dad, forgive me.
I overreacted.
I forgot about all the good things
you have done for me.
If Allah forgives the sins
of his servants who repent,
does a daughter have the right…
to hate and reject her father
for his past sins?
Forgive me, Dad.
Alhamdulillah.
Allahu Akbar.
O YOU WHO HAVE BELIEVED,
PROTECT YOURSELF AND YOUR FAMILIES
FROM A FIRE WHOSE FUEL
IS PEOPLE AND STONES
OVER WHICH ARE [APPOINTED] ANGELS,
HARSH AND SEVERE;
THEY DO NOT DISOBEY ALLAH
IN WHAT HE COMMANDS THEM
BUT DO WHAT THEY ARE COMMANDED.
[AT-TAHRIM - 66:6]
Are you sure you want to marry
at this young age?
Yes, sir.
Are you really sure?
Yes, I am.
Are you really sure about your choice?
You're doing it without pressure?
I'm 100 percent sure.
I was searching for someone
who can protect and guard me.
You're beating around the bush
too much, sir.
What's the matter? Is there a problem?
No, sir. No problem.
Have you learned the prayer by heart?
The prayer for that act?
I know it by heart.
I know it 100 percent, right, dear?
I see. That's good then.
You have experience, don't you, sir?