You Mo's daughter?
Yeah.
Okay. Well, I'm the housekeeper.
I'm here to pick you up.
What happened to 9 o'clock?
So, anyway, as I said, I'm Joel.
I'm your mom's housekeeper.
So, we'll probably be seeing a lot of
each other.
You excited to be moving back in with her?
She hasn't seen you in a while.
What's it been? Three or four years?
She's excited to see you.
Yeah...
It'll be a nice change-up from the two of
us.
It's just usually us.
I help her get the mail. Cook, clean...
feed the cat.
Sometimes we do fun stuff , like , go to
a movie or something.
Just to change it all up.
But, yeah, three people will be nice in
that apartment.
I'll bet you'll love the view. It's on
the twelfth floor, at the very top.
You can see for miles from that window.
All the way out to the parks.
You know, they say, when Mo gets on the
elevator, and she pushes the twelfth
floor button,
they say, "Oh, she's going to the
penthouse. Mo's going up to the
penthouse!"
So, what does "A" stand for, anyway?
Abigail?
Annabel?
Alice?
Not Alice.
Anna! Anna's a nice name.
Yeah, Mo wouldn't give you a bad name.
Do you ever shut up?
Okay.
I'll just say one more thing, okay?
She is thrilled to see you.
She's glad you're coming home.
I don't see how,
because you seem like the perfect doting
child.
Why should she need me?!
Well, here we are.
Home sweet home.
Well, it is for some of us, at least.
Need any help?
No.
Alright...
Do you know the way?
Yes!
Oh, that's good. She knows the way.
Almost beat you up here, huh?
It's not locked. You can go on in.
Here you go.
We're back, Mo.
Oh, great!
Well, hi, A.
How was your trip over?
It was fine.
That's good.
You got everything moved over?
Mmhm.
Well... That's good.
I'm sorry to interrupt. I'm just going to
get the rest of the boxes.
Okay. Great, Joel.
Wow!
All that red hair.
How long have you had it?
Awhile.
You must like it.
I do.
I'm going to have to get used to that,
but I'm sure I can manage.
You know, Joel's a great cook.
He could whip us up something for supper
tonight.
What would you like?
He also talks a lot.
Well, so do I. And you used to.
We just want to make you feel welcomed.
Why don't you...
take you're coat off? Make yourself feel
at home?
Good morning, A.
Do you like your food?
Joel's a really good cook.
I like it.
A?
It's fine.
You know,
We really haven't had a chance to talk
much
since you've been back.
I have nothing to talk about.
We've not seen each other for three years,
and you don't think there's anything to
talk about?
Do you think you'll like living here?
Wouldn't it be nice if we could,
you know, talk to each other?
I don't want to just sit here and stare
at each other night after night.
I just want to be left alone!
Some peace and quiet.
Well... That's not going to happen.
Do you feel like you're stuck?
What do you think?!
It doesn't have to be like that.
You can go places.
I'm sure Joel would take you somewhere.
You have friends?
They're welcome. They can come over and
take you places.
I can't just go out and have fun, like
other people my age!
Why not?
You should know.
I have help.
I can go places.
Sure beats sitting home alone all the
time.
Yeah, and what have you done with your
life?
I had you.
Well, thanks a fucking lot!
I want us to be close again. We used to.
My mom and I, we were close.
I want that for A and I, to be close
again.
This is going to be so hard.
Joel, do you think I'm doing the right
thing by having her come here?
I do.
I hope so.
I mean, I've always believed family helps
family.
Not just throw them out in the street, or
send them to a shelter amongst strangers.
We're family, we should be together,
but...
She comes over here, after she agreed to
move in with me, and she don't even want
to talk to me!
And when we do, we just have this huge
blow-up, and...
Hey.
All unpacked? Settled in?
Yeah.
Want me to take those for you?
Sure.
Got a lot of stuff. Lot of boxes.
Hey.
What's in those?
Hmm.
You know I've worked around them all
the time, and I have no idea.
Probably storage, or something.
You're free to look. It's your room, now.
And, good morning, everyone.
Sorry I'm a little late today.
Just had to have my coffee, you know how
that is.
How's everyone doing today?
Oh, you're looking a tiny bit droopy.
We might have to give you a little bit of
a cut.
But, it won't hurt. Don't worry about it.
I'll be very, very gentle.
It's so good to see everyone.
And, how are we doing with
our new friend, the fern?
Everyone say, "Hi, Fern!"
We've never had such a large plant before
but it's very, very nice to have you.
Of course, we're sorry about Mrs. Milton,
and that you couldn't be in her apartment
anymore, but she had to move...
Beach music! Our favorite! Come on!
Okay. Here we go!
That's good music.
Oh, it's wonderful music! Reminds me
of the Carolinas.
The Carolinas, huh? Reminds me of Koko
Head.
Oh, I know.
Okay, here we go!
I always want to hug you when we dance.
Well... good!
That is good!
Alright, ready for a little twirl here...?
Wow.
What do we have? It's impossible to walk
by this book without taking a look. I
can't believe it.
There's Ike. There's Patton. What are
they talking about?
Oh yeah! "The Race for Tunisia"!
"Command and Corps in Tunisia: Patton".
Who knew I'd be a history buff?
Who knew I would be so
interested in World War II?
But, then... shoot!
I got a grandfather who had shrapnel in
his leg from World War I,
and my dad flew B-17s over Germany as a
belly-gunner.
A belly-gunner...
Who the hell even reads the newspaper
anymore?
Who ever reads this?!
It's your bill! I'm tired of paying your
bills!
What bill?
It's not mine.
It is yours.
How could that possibly be mine?
It's from now! I just now got it in the
mail!
What about this?
This is all you, too!
That's not me! That's you! That's not me
at all! They're all your bills.
No.
I'd don't use that stuff!
Why do we have to have this conversation
every day? I don't understand!
Because every day you're ringing up bills!
No I'm not. Please.
Hey! Don't you...
What are you doing?
I was just checking it out.
Put it back!
Sorry.
Just because you're my Mom's housekeeper
doesn't mean that you can go through my
things!
Won't happen again.
I bet you don't even know what that is.
I bet you ten bucks that I do.
Alright, you're on! What is it?
It's you owing me ten bucks,
because that is a shotgun shell reloader.
How do you know what that is?
Because my grandfather used to own one.
You see, during the 1930s, during the
Great Depression.
They used to reload their own spent
shotgun shells with their own material
to save money.
So, they didn't have to go buy new ones
at the store.
Sound about right?
Just know not to go through my stuff.
I'll ask next time,
but from now on, maybe you can stop
acting like I'm as dumb as I look? Hmm?
You certainly are rude.
How was your day?
It was alright.
What did you do?
Not much.
You went out.
You must have done something?
I was just doing a little bit of...
bird watching.
Oh! That's exciting.
What kind of birds did you see?
Well...
I saw a Bald Eagle perched on a building.
That's neat! Don't see too many of them.
What else?
I saw a mother Robin tending her nest.
That's neat. I like Robins.
I saw a couple Sparrows kind of dancing
around each other.
Oh, that would have been fun to have seen!
But then, there were some really, really
aggressive Crows.
Yeah, Crows can be like like that, I
guess.
I really don't know too much about birds,
but
they're fun to watch.
So, where are we going first?
We're going to the bank.
"To the bank", and then what happens...?
Do we go to a show? Do we...
Uh! Help me, here. Help me, here!
Okay, give me your arm.
Sorry.
Well, come on!
Hi, there.
What the hell are you doing here?
I work here.
What have you been up to?
Nothing.
Just bird watching.
Not a lot of birds out, yet.
You would be surprised.
You would be surprised to know that when
I was taking the trash out a little
earlier,
I looked through one of the windows,
and I saw you down there in the park.
Your binoculars were faced towards the
building.
You want to tell me what's up with that?
Fine, you caught me.
I was doing some people watching.
You're spying on the residents.
I really wouldn't call it spying. It's
just more curiosity.
It's a breach of privacy.
Oh, as if they would even know.
What if you get caught?
So what?
There would be a lot of trouble.
I hate to break it to you, but I'm going
to have to do the five-year-old thing,
and tell on you.
You're going to tell on me?
To who? My mom? What's that going to do?
Yeah, I'll tell your mom, for a start.
And then, I'm going to tell the building
management, because they'll get a kick
out of it.
Fine! What do you want?
Oh, wait. You're going to bribe me now,
is that it?
Bribe me, so you can keep playing this
sick little game?
Call it what you want.
Okay. I've got something.
You can start being nice to Mo.
I mean, she's your mom, for Christ's sake!
And, she saved your ass by letting you
live here,
so I think the least you could do is open
up.
Fine. I'll try.
You promise?
I promise I'll try.
Deal?
Deal.
Hi.
Hey.
What are you doing?
The floor's uneven.
Have you ever realized that?
Really?
Hmm.
Yeah, I was having trouble with my
wheelchair, and I decided to try marbles.
I guess I never would have realized that.
Anyway, I wanted to bring this by.
I thought maybe you'd be interested.
My roommates, they can't stand it anymore.
They think it's...
cursed, or something. It gives them the
creeps.
It's a lucky cat statue.
The Japanese call it Ma... uh...
Maneki-necko.
That's it.
Interested in giving it a good home?
Sure. I'll take it.
So, still doing any... "bird watching".
I am.
Thinking about doing some night watching,
as well.
Okay. Spy at your own peril.
I will.
Oh, and....
I didn't know if you knew this or not,
but there's a community balcony you're
free to use. All the floors have them.
Might give you a good view, and you
wouldn't have to go into the park at
night.
Okay. Cool.
Thanks.
Sure.
Well, you're still here. That's a
surprise.
Never been anyone that was still here.
They're here, and then they're not here.
Why would I expect anything different
from you?
I shower you. Talk to you. Feed you.
And...
what do I get? Nothing. Nothing!
You're just... you're only plants.
Not just... you're not just plants.
You're the only thing that's stayed.
And listened.
You've been a part of me.
Everything, everyone goes... away.
Wait a minute! What are you doing?
I don't like your attitude.
Well, tough!
What is the matter with you?
I don't know what's the matter with me!
Alright. I'll try dancing again.
Ow!
You stepped on my foot!
I didn't step on your foot! You put your
foot over here, where mine was.
What? That's ridiculous!
I was doing my dance step, and you
screwed it up!
Me?
Yeah. You!
You're impossible.
Wait a minute! What about supper?!
Never mind supper. Fix your own!
I'll starve!
Remember?
You told me about that. I couldn't figure
out what you meant by The Battle of the
Bulge.
I later read about it.
Patton, and Montgomery, and Omar Bradley
headed up by a guy from Abilene.
My god.
If only I could see the two of you today.
That would be so beautiful.
You lived a good life. You were strong.
Lived in a one room house.
Twenty-by-twenty. Des Moines, Iowa.
All these guys.
All this "attack, attack" and "fall back" and...
Didn't have to be this way!
I'm done!
That was good.
Thank you.
Time to do the dishes.
Yeah, right.
Time for bed.
Come on. I've got you.
Hey, old woman. I love you. Thanks for
taking care of me.
Awe, you're a good boy.
Time to go to bed.
Do you know which apartment the EMTs
went to?
Yeah. B904. Ninth floor.
Isn't that the one with the old lady and
her son, or whoever it is that lives with
her?
Ed?
You know his name?
Yes, I know his name. We uh...
I've worked with him a couple times. Okay?
Why is it so important to you?
Did they say how she died?
Yes. They said natural causes. They think
she stopped breathing during the night
sometime,
and they found her in bed.
I don't think it was natural causes.
Oh, really?
Think she was murdered?
Yeah, I kind of... do think think she was
murdered.
And, what brings you to that conclusion?
I saw something weird last night. Okay?
You saw something weird during that
illegal activity that you call "bird
watching".
That's convincing.
I know what I saw, and she suddenly turns
up dead the next day.
A little weird, don't you think?
I think you're making it up.
Alright. You've got to stop doing that!
Alright, listen. I saw....
a lamp fall over. I saw a shadow, or a
silhouette, or...
it looked like it was-
Okay, look. You think you saw something.
Okay, you think you saw a lamp get
knocked over.
But, I think you're making it all up.
You're making it all up because you're
bored out of your little head.
You've been bored since you got here, so
it makes since to me that you're just
trying to cause a little fuss
for your own entertainment.
So I think you should drop it.
I know what I saw, and I know I'm not
lying!
What did you do today?
Not much.
Didn't go bird watching?
Eh, not so much anymore.
Why not?
There's only so much I can take of
aggressive Crows.
Oh.
Because I thought you were enjoying those
dancing Sparrows and that...
mother Robin?
So...
I know I haven't always been very
appreciative
of all that you've done for me.
I just want to let you know that I'm
going to try to do better.
I appreciate that. That's good to hear.
I know this hasn't been easy for you.
I'm sure it's hard, you know, after
living on your own, then having to move
back in with me.
I guess I got so used to being on my own
that...
I thought my world was going to crash
and I took everything out on you.
I can understand that. I know there's
been times I've been upset at a situation
and have taken it out on others.
Doesn't make it right,
but...
I can understand it.
I'm just glad that you're willing to want
to have a relationship again.
I'm willing to try harder, too.
And, I would very much like for us to...
have a relationship.
Find some interests, and be able to do
things together.
That would be fun. Have my daughter back.
Hey, where are you off too?
Ninth floor.
No you're not. No you're not. Get back
here.
Come on! I got to go!
I know what you're up to, and you're not
going down there.
You don't know anything, for sure.
And neither do you.
That's why you shouldn't go down there
snooping around like this.
It's not like I'm going to go up to his
door, and say, "Hi! Are you a murderer?"
That's what it sounds like you're doing.
No. I'm just going to knock on his door
and
chat with him a little bit. Maybe look
around when he's not looking.
I just don't think that's a very good
idea.
I'm sure you think a lot of things aren't
a good idea.
Well, yeah. I'm the only one who thinks
around here. Wait a second! Wait!
Okay. Okay, I think maybe I know where
this is going. Maybe... maybe.
Look.
If you're trying to do this to prove a
point to me, you don't have to do that,
okay?
It has nothing to do with proving a point
to you.
I just want justice for the old lady.
Do you think anyone should actually, you
know,
have to go through that. And just think,
"Oh, well, she just died in her sleep." ?
Would you want justice if it was your
relative?
Yes. If you put it that way, yes. And, if
that's what actually happened, yes.
And, okay, maybe you actually... I'll
take a leap here. Maybe you actually saw
something, and
on that note I'm sorry about the other
day.
Really?
Yes. Sincerely, I'm sorry. I... Look,
I blew up on you because...
It probably sounds stupid, but I've been
working in places like this for a while,
now.
And, you get to know older people. You
respect them a lot,
and a lot of them are just really
helpless, and you don't like the idea of
people killing them.
It just... it got to me, because I
thought you were making it up. It got to
me. So, I'm sorry.
This is why I need to do something. So
she can have some justice.
Okay. Alright, look. If you're so
determined to see this done, then...
then I'll go down there.
So how are you going to get in there?
It's not like I can just knock on the
front door and say, "Hi, Ed! Long time,
no see." You know?
And then snoop around as he fixes me a
cup of tea. It's not going to work like
that.
Yeah, he doesn't really seem like the
friendly type.
No.
We're going to have to get in there when
he's not home.
You mean, like, break in?
Sort of.
You know when I said I worked
with him that one time?
Mmhm.
Well, I was helping him move a bunch of
stuff into storage.
Took a whole freaking month. So, anyway,
I ended up keeping this, because the
whole thing ended on a sour note, and
he never asked for it back.
So, I guess you don't need to break in.
You can just walk in through the front
door.
Mmhm.
But, when? I mean, he's always there.
I think I have an idea.
I think that's right.
Okay, it's ringing.
No, no, no! You do it.
What?! Why?!
I don't sound professional over the
phone. I sound like a little girl.
Do it! Do it, do it, do it!
Alright, alright.
Yes, good afternoon, Sir. I am with
Denver and Strasbourg.
Yes, the uh, insurance company downtown,
that’s correct.
And I have a policy here that is worth
$50,000
in the event of such a death that we
heard occurred in your residence.
Oh, it was taken out about 5 years ago,
yes.
That’s right, $50,000.
Well, you see, it has to be, and I’m
sorry, this is rather inconvenient for
you,
it has to be claimed today.
Yes, it expires in a week, but, you know,
there’s a lot of paperwork to get through.
We have to get the ball rolling.
Again, I’m sorry it’s such an
inconvenience, but it is a...
lot of money.
Yes.
Okay, well, we appreciate your business,
and we look forward to seeing you.
Mmhm, buh-bye.
Did he buy it?
Yeah, he says he's on his way.
Good.
Okay. looks like he's falling for it.
Alright. You need to get down there and
find something.
Something? Like what?
Anything that could be used as evidence?
Something that looks out of place?
Alright. Easy enough, I guess.
How long do you think we should wait? You
know, to make sure he's out of the
building?
I'd say let's give him a bit. About...
ten minutes.
Alright. We'll wait it out for ten
minutes, then.
Oh, yeah, make sure you have your
walky-talky on at all times.
Keep the volume low, though. We don't
want to attract attention.
Right.
You're my look-out, so
you let me know ASAP if anything fishy
goes down so I can get out of there.
And don't you dare get caught.
And don't get caught. Right.
This is nuts!
Any of this junk could be evidence. Any
of it could not be evidence!
God!
Hey, Joel, come in.
Joel, do you copy?
For some reason he's back early. Come on,
pick up!
I'll be damned.
Dude, come on!
Joel, do you copy?
Oh, come on! He's on his way up there!
Joel, you need to get out of there!
He is coming up there right now! You need
to get out of there!
A?
A, you're not coming in very clear.
Can you repeat that? Over?
Oh, shit.
Joel! You need to get out of there!
He is coming there right now! Do you
copy?!
A, do you copy? Over?
Oh, shit.
Shit, shit, shit, shit, shit.
Close the door! Close the goddamned door!
Damnit, Joel! I thought he caught you.
No. He didn't catch me.
I didn't even see him.
He didn't see me.
That makes one of us.
What do you mean?
He saw me on the balcony.
Alright.
Well, I have some good news.
You just might be right.
Shit.
Yeah.
I don't see another way around it.
We're going to have to split up again.
You're right.
Alright, you take the stairs, I'll take
the elevator.
That way if he catches one of us,
then at least the other can go get help.
Okay.
We cannot lead him back to the twelfth
floor apartment.
No. That's got to be our number one
priority.
Okay. There's no time to waste.
I'll head towards the stairs. You take
the next elevator up, alright?
Alright. Good luck.
You, too.
Whew.
Joel?
B. 1. 2. 1. 1.
I tried to lead him away, but he knows
where I live.
Well,
I guess we have to go to the police.
But, I don't know what we'd tell them.
I mean, we show that to them, the first
thing they're going to say is, "It's a
piece of junk."
You know? They're not going to put that
to a killing.
Second, they're going to ask me where I
got it.
I can't tell them I broke into his
apartment and took it. I'm going to have
to say something like,
I dug it out of his garbage.
We have to do something, though. We can't
just let a murderer go free.
Yeah.
And if he is, in fact, a murderer,
I don't like the thought of him running
around knowing where you live, where Mo
lives.
He could hurt you guys.
Yeah, I know.
We have to figure something out.
I mean...
there's nothing to figure out.
We have to take our chances with the cops.
I'll go there right now.
I'll see if there's anyone at the station
who will take me seriously.
You stay here.
Keep the door locked. Keep an eye on Mo.
Hello?
Yes.
How did you get my number?
Fine, I’ll meet you.
Mom!
Mom?!
Look what I found.
Color!
Not that I don't love green. It's my very
favorite color.
But, I just happened across these,
and I thought we'd just add a little bit
of zing.
There's nothing wrong with zing, is there?
I mean, you're all acclimated as a new
friend, and now we have
some more new friends, I'm glad we waited
, though, until you felt more comfortable
, but
here's just a few more friends, and we
know how we love friends.
Alright, here we go!
Whoo!
Oh, I love it!
We haven't lost it, Babe!
These young people think they can dance.
Pssh. They can't dance.
Whoo!
Oh, this is so fun!
We knew it was going to happen. Yeah.
Well, Mom, it's a beautiful day.
We're going to enjoy this. We're going to
celebrate.
We're going to celebrate your life, Dad.
Just like that! Okay?
I was just telling Mom the other day,
when you came home from the service you
built...