[Narrator] This is Lagos
where dreams are born every few seconds,
and where the dreams
are crushed every few seconds.
In Lagos, you’ve got to know
what you want and grab it,
because if you dont,
there are 20 million
others waiting their turn.
Welcome to Lagos.
♪ If I was your best friend ♪
♪ I want you round me all the time ♪
♪ Yeah we could be best friends ♪
♪ If you promise you’ll be mine ♪
♪ You say, "I'm just a friend" ♪
♪ Either I is or I ain't your man ♪
♪ Hey girl, let's not pretend ♪
♪ one two, one two ♪
♪ If I was your man I would get it right ♪
♪ I would get you roses up
On Sunday and every night after ♪
♪ We could count the stars
And close the night chapter ♪
♪ Or maybe hit the road
And watch the lights pass ya ♪
♪ Let me elaborate ♪
♪ My queen in the making
Mama Dipped it in water ♪
♪ So no touchin' from satan ♪
♪ But now her soul aching
Tryna get her round a corner ♪
♪ Only cure she got is Smoking marijuana ♪
♪ If you need me, I got you ♪
♪ Don't stay back ♪
♪ What’s a best friend for
if they can’t keep you intact ♪
♪ Girl you're so
specific and I'm so terrific ♪
♪ This that talk
You might as well come on with it ♪
♪ We kick push, we glide
We been through this all the time ♪
-[female voice] Charlie!
-Teni!
-How are you?
-I’m fine, let me get aunty.
-[Teni] Aunty, Charlie’s here!
-[Charlie] Oh Josh, it's good to see you.
-Charlie, what's happening here?
-Yeah
-What?
-You've put on so much weight
[Teni] Aunty! Charlie is here!
Aww, mum.
Hi baby.
-Good to see you.
-How are you?
-I'm well, thank you.
-Good, how was your flight?
It was good. Mum,
I swear you look younger every time
Oh please stop lying to your mother.
[Charlie laughs]
This is my friend, Keme. Keme, my mother.
-Hello, honey how are you?
-Good thank you
-Good to see you.
-This is Josh, and Teni. Guys, Keme.
Josh, nice to meet you.
I've heard a lot about you.
Well, welcome to our home. Shall we go in?
-[Keme] Thank you.
-It's good to see you, honey.
-[Keme] Ohhhhh
-[music]
-Come in
-[laughter]
-Hey honey, see who’s here.
-Welcome home, son.
-It's so good to have you back son.
-It's good to see you, dad.
Ehhhhh!
Keme, come in, come in,
come in. Come meet my dad.
Dad, this is my friend, Keme.
-Keme.
-Nice to meet you.
[Mum] Have a seat.
[Dad] My dear,
get them something to drink.
Oh I will, yes.
Darling, go in there and get…
I got you your favorite meat pie.
-Yes!
-Get the meat pies and drinks.
-[Mum] I know you're going to love it.
-Keme
You’re in for a treat, man
My mum makes
the best meat pies in the world.
-Yea?
-Oh that's right, Charlie.
Your mother is a perfect cook.
You know she gets the basic ingredients,
and then creates magic
Haha, that's how I created this.
[laughter]
-[Charlie] Lollipop!
-[Lollipop] Oh my God!
[Charlie] How are you?
Ahhhh-ahhhh
-[both] It's so good to see you.
-[Charlie] Jinx!
-How are you?
-I'm okay
Now, you're squeezing the life out of me!
[Lollipop] Sorry.
So, okay, meet my friend, Keme.
My sister, Lola.
-Hey.
-Hi.
Nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you too, Lola.
[footsteps] [Temi] Meat pie.
[Keme] Oh okay.
-[Mum] That's it, very good
-[music]
Alright.
At least we can use this as
refreshment before... dinner is ready.
-[mum clears throat].
-[Teni] D'you want some juice?
[Charlie] This smells fantastic
No, no, no, no, just serve them.
They are the visitors [laughs]
Ohh, well, I'll serve my son.
Awww, mom.
-[Charlie] Thank you Mama.
-You're welcome.
And me.
Please don't forget me.
[laughter]
-[plates clinking]
-[phone rings]
So how are the wedding plans going?
-[Teni] So far, so good
-[Joshua] Yeah
Okay. Yes, That’s fine.
That’s fine, thank you so much.
Yea, alright. God bless. Bye.
-Hey, easy.
-Oh sorry. Hi
Hi, I wasn't expecting to
bump into anyone.
-Are you leaving?
-No no.
Not at all. I was wondering what
was keeping you out here.
So I came to check on you.
Make sure you were safe.
Alright, just kidding.
I wanted to stretch my legs
and I noticed you hadn’t
had some of the famous pie
and no drink either,
so I brought you some.
You do know stale
food can make you sick, right?
Okay, thanks for the nutrition lesson.
Are you a doctor?
No, not even,
just a concerned friend, I guess.
Right.
You gonna take it or what?
Oh yes, yes, sorry.
-Thanks. Yes.
-Yea?
-No pie?
-I had to…
-No [chuckles]
-Okay.
I had to step out to make a phone call.
The call must have been important.
-Yes it was.
-Was it business?
Do you usually ask these
many questions of people you just met?
The thing is, Charlie talks about you,
like, all the time.
So, in my mind, we're already friends.
Friends. [smacks lips]
There’s that word again.
Do you have a problem being friends?
-No comment.
-No... [sighs]
Spoken like a true lawyer.
Oh, wow. Okay, fine,
Charlie has really spoken about me a lot.
What about you? What do you do?
Err, this and that…
Alright, I'm an investment banker.
[inhales]
-I work on Wall Street.
-Wow.
You know I was thinking you were like...
-an actor or model or something like that.
-[chuckles]
Sorry, I didn't mean to laugh,
but you think i could pass for an actor?
What is it? My eyebrows,
or my perfect leading man looks?
Which one?
[sighs] Uhmm..
I’m gonna go back inside, okay?
[sucks teeth] Sure.
I’m hoping you're gonna get
to stay home a lot longer this time.
I hope so too.
-Hi, Lollipop.
-Oh, there you are. [clears throat]
I was beginning to
wonder where you guys went to.
-I needed to use my phone, to call, just--
-[Keme coughs]
[exhales]
[Keme] Right.
[mum chuckles]
[Charlie] Everything okay?
[lighthearted music]
Ejike! [door closes] How are you doing?
Mum, can you try knocking once in a while?
It's that thing that p…
[sucks teeth]
Come in mum, good morning.
make yourself comfortable.
[sniffs]
Did you sleep well?
I did, actually.
[sniffs] How was your night?
We thank God.
Your father called this morning,
but it was too early,
so didn't want to wake you up.
He was expecting your call last night.
Right, I actually meant to call him.
Sorry, I got in really late
last night and I was really tired.
-I'm going to Abuja.
-Okay.
You’re home,
I want you to come with me.
I will be fine
And besides, Charlie and I actually
have a couple of meetings here, so
next weekend.
And when are we going to get to meet
this your mysterious friend?
You'll meet him soon.
We're just a little
busy right now, that's all.
Hmm
Okay, so it's more
important to have these meetings
with your mysterious
friends than go and visit your father?
I did not say that, alright?
Okay, so when you finish
with your meetings, come to Abuja.
Okay. What's going on?
Come on tell me, why are
you so intent on me coming to Abuja,
What's happening?
Is it a bad thing to
go and visit your father?
No of course not.
But you literally just said,
he's busy doing his political stuff.
So why do i need to be there so badly?
-Okay.
Stay for your meetings.
I mean... [laughs]
You never listen to what I say.
Here we go.
I really don't know why I bother!
Okay, look. Mum, mum, mum!
Where are you going? Goodness.
Okay.
Okay, look, let's do this.
We will spend this weekend together
We will do some fun stuff
then you can go to Abuja on Sunday.
And when I'm done with
my meetings here, I...
I will come join you.
That's a good idea.
Oh, and I know the perfect place
to take you.
-Ohh!
-Oh dear Lord.
-This will be fun. [laughs]
-What did I get myself into?
‪[lighthearted music]‬
‪[door opens]‬
‪[door closes]‬
‪[bass music playing]‬
‪[exhales]‬
‪[bass music]‬
‪[water splashes]‬
[grunts]
[female voice] Good morning,
Brother Ejike.
I hope you are
enjoying your trip to Nigeria.
So far, so good. How far?
You are looking good.
Tunde is taking really good care of you.
Hmm! That one? Do I even get to see him?
He is always off to one
political thing or the other.
That's a good thing because it means
politics is actually working out for him.
Hmmn, well yes.
I guess he’s trying
to be like your father.
Hoping one day to become Senate President.
Yeah, that would be something.
But look, listen
I just had like the weirdest
conversation with my mum.
She’s trying a little too
hard to get me to go to Abuja.
I feel like there’s
something else going on. What is it?
Why do you think so?
Hey, come on, we both know that woman.
She doesn’t do anything for no reason.
-What's going on?
-[laughs]
Ah, I don't know.
-Come on.
-Come to think of it.
Maybe she wants to find you a wife
as you’ve refused to bring one home.
[Keme laughs]
-You guys are trying to find me a wife?
-Hmm-mmn
I can find a woman by myself.
Thank you so much.
Okay, then you better
hurry up and bring one home.
You know Aunty does
not take "No" for an answer.
Yeah, I can't even
deal with you guys, alright?
-I will see you later.
-Okay.
[grunts]
Don't bother coming to Abuja again.
He won’t even consider it.
Perfect.
Don’t worry about it.
I'll bring him over to Abuja next week.
-We'll see you there.
-[female voice ] Hello, Aunty.
Hello yourself.
Nma, haven’t I told
you to stop sneaking up on me?
I didn't sneak up on you.
I walked leisurely in.
[long hiss]
Did you see Sisi Toyin
when you picked up Kemi?
Uhhm no,
it was really early in the morning,
so she might have
been sleeping when I got there.
I didn't go upstairs, so I don't know.
Oh, that's okay.
I... guess I’ll call her later.
I can't make Bible study today.
I'm sure she wouldn't mind.
I mean she knows Charlie's around, so...
-Oh, speaking of Charlie,
-hmm-mm
His friend seemed like a... nice boy.
Yeah, he is.
I saw the way he was looking at you.
Mum, don't start jumping the gun now.
I'm not jumping the gun, and I’m
not saying anything that I didn’t see.
All I'm saying is,
I saw the way he was looking at you
and I bet you anything,
he’ll be here soon enough.
I'm sure he will be here soon enough, mum.
I mean, Charlie is his friend.
So yes, he will come back.
That is not what I meant, but never mind.
Trust me, he’ll be back.
Mum, you know I'm not
looking for a relationship right now.
All I want to do is focus
on God and my career, that's it.
Hmmn
Honey, you do
realize you’re only saying that
because... you haven't met the right
man yet?
When you do,
just like I did meet your father,
-Hmmm?
-Everything will fall into place.
You don’t have to be single to serve God,
you can serve him while married.
I did, and so are
countless women out there.
All you have to do is just
open your heart to the will of God.
All you have to do is just open your heart
to the will of God.
-Oh, stop.
-[laughs]
Ok mum, I've heard you.
["I Hear Say Dem Talk" playing]
You’ve literally been on your phone
since I got here, is everything okay?
Ah, I’m tired,
my cousin promised to call me
for a business proposition I made to him.
Oh, is this the cousin
you were telling me about?
The one that’s in the States?
When am I meeting him?
You’ll meet him soon.
He's quite busy at the moment.
He and one of his friends are
trying to set up
venture capital for businesses in
Nigeria, he can impact lots of Nigerians.
Wow! That is such a strange coincidence.
Charlie and his friend are
literally doing the same thing.
-Really?
-Yes. Maybe we should introduce them.
What do you think?
Probably after
Teni’s wedding or what do you think?
Yes, that’s a good idea.
So, what does Charlie's friend look like?
He's hot. Very hot.
Well, do I smell an attraction?
Kemi, am I not
allowed to just admire someone
without you thinking
that there is something there?
Okay, now give me the details,
full details.
I want to listen.
Well, he did make
a really good first impression.
Hmmph!
[male voice] Gala gala
["I Hear Say Dem Talk" playing]
&lrm;gala gala
[Keme] This is ridiculous, man!
It's like the one thing
about Lagos that never changes
You know we've been here for…
Look at that, we've been here for an hour.
And we’ve moved I’m pretty sure
about five meters. It makes no sense.
You would think that after all this time,
the government would
have figured out new modes of
transportation to ease
the congestion on the roads
-[phone chimes]
-Hold on
Err, ok, Pastor Ben just
confirmed our meeting
-So we’re good to go.
-Oh, awesome, awesome.
What about the Centre for Law
and Business? Any word from them?
Oh no, they confirmed yesterday
so we have two meetings lined up now.
-Great.
-Yeah, man
‪[knock]‬
[in pidgin] Sir,
please buy from me, buy, please.
-How much?
-[hawker] 100 Naira each, sir.
[Keme] Do you want something?
I'm not really hungry.
[Charlie] It's fine, I don’t mind.
-Let me ask you something.
-[Hawker] Okay, sir.
-Did you go to school?
-No, sir.
-[in pidgin] You never went to school?
-Yes.
How come?
[in pidgin] Sir, no money …
Look at my beards
[in pidgin] I haven’t eaten
since morning, sir. Please buy, please.
Do you have any Naira on you?
No, unfortunately not.
Err, hold on,
I should have some change somewhere.
Okay, just give me one.
[in pidgin] Emeka, bring a paper bag
for me.
-It's fine, keep the change.
-God bless you. Sir, thank you so much.
‪Emeka!‬
‪So what's this mystery man’s name?‬
-Keme.
-Keme?
Keme, sounds romantic. Lola and Ke--
Kemi! There is no by Lola and Keme or Loke
or whatever happening, please.
Okay, it’s fine.
So what’s happening tomorrow morning?
Are we still on for the market?
Yes we are. Bright and early,
so you need to be ready.
-So set your alarm.
-[sighs]
But Lola, please, why can’t Teni
just hire a professional wedding planner?
I don’t have to wake up
every weekend for this please.
Kemi, why are you complaining?
-You know, you like it.
-I don’t.
[laughter]
So how did it go at the market?
I hope you got all you wanted.
Oh yes, we did.
Lola has such an eye for beautiful stuff.
Must you give Lola so much credit?
You are as talented as she is,
if not more.
It's okay, mum,
I am confident in my abilities
and I do not have a problem
with recognizing how gifted Lola is.
But mum, where is this coming from?
I'm just tired of "Lola this, Lola that",
you deserve some credit too.
Ok, thanks for looking out for me,
mum, but I am super cool with Lola.
[laughs sarcastically]
I don't know how you can be.
After the stunt she pulled with Femi.
-She ruined your engagement.
-Oh come on, mum
we both know it wasn’t Lola's fault.
Femi is such a horrible person
Lola did nothing wrong.
Well, that’s not how I remember it.
It's fine, but I think we’ll...
agree to disagree then.
[car engines revving]
[door opens and closes]
-[Charlie] I'm sorry.
-What happened?
I'm sorry, sorry, I’m just coming.
The traffic in this town is... terrible
Third mainland was blocked.
We had to go through Yaba and Eko bridge.
Thank God for Lola who knows all the ways.
Well then, how is... Lola?
She's great, I suppose.
Yes, definitely.
Your sister is, she is something else.
Yea, I think so too.
Why do you sound like that?
Why do you have
that look on your face, Keme?
Alright, fine, fine.
Since we're here and we’re doing this
Yes, I've been actually
meaning to talk to you about this.
-Hmmn...
-I know it's kind of weird, but I like her
As in, I really like her.
You think she would
agree to go on a date with me?
Why don't you ask her?
Wait, you are actually cool with this?
No, I'm not.
-Oh my bad.
-[laughs] I’m just kidding, come on.
I can't think of nobody better.
[clears throat]
Hey man, I appreciate this, seriously.
-[chuckles]
-No, seriously.
-It means a lot to me.
-No problem, no problem.
-I won't let you down.
-Oh, no wahala.
-Let's get to business.
-Alright.
We are ready to see her now,
if you can just give her a ring.
Tell her we're here.
[in Yoruba] Iya Dundun.
Please, let me have
three wraps of amala, and meat.
-[Iya Dundun] Okay, how many meats?
-Uhmm...
Two each. Make it goat meat and beef,
okay?
Any ponmo?
These ones are ajebo,
they can’t eat ponmo, just--
No, no, no, I will
have some ponmo, thank you very much.
-[laughs]
-Why not?
Mehn, how's the…
-Thank you.
-[Charlie] Thank you, man.
How’s the wedding planning going?
-Maaan! It’s going good
-Yes.
I learned something very early on.
[Keme] What’s that?
The wedding belongs to the bride.
I simply do as I'm
told and we’re all happy.
So I hear.
And Lola is doing an amazing job.
Of course, she’s amazing.
I don’t know how she finds the time
to do all the things she gets to do.
It’s like she can out plan
any event planner in the world.
-[Charlie] That's crazy.
-I tell you what?
I mean, all of her creativity and style,
-Simple, but classy.
-Classy, yes.
she just seems like
that kind of person, you know?
She’s just that kind of person,
that's all.
-Hmm!
Why do you have that look on your face?
Hey, you think we didn’t see how
you were staring at her the other night?
Are you guys being serious right now?
I can’t say someone is incredible anymore,
I can’t just
compliment your sister in peace.
-[Josh] this is the food, let's dig in.
-Yes good idea.
So?
I could actually get into this.
-It’s actually pretty nice.
-[Keme] Not bad at all.
The amala is soft,
the soup tastes really delicious.
-[Charlie] It's pretty good, actually.
-Hmm!
Iya Dundun is the best.
So, guys, this is my business idea.
[In Yoruba] Joshua, buka?
You want to open a buka?
Listen up guys.
It is a bukateria par excellence.
[sighs]
What I’m trying to do is
blend the local traditional buka
with the modern-day fast food joint.
-That could actually work.
-Yeah.
Ah, who do we have here?
Ehhhh!
[Lola] Hello.
-Awww, how are you?
-I'm fine, thank you.
-How are you?
-I'm fine.
-Good to see you.
-Same here.
How are you?
-I’m okay.
-Good. Business is looking good.
-Thank you.
-Well done.
Thank you, thank you.
Ah, Auntie Lola!
Efe, I didn't know you were in town now.
-How are you?
-I’m fine o, I’m fine.
That’s good. How is the job search going?
You know Nigeria, my dear. If you’re
not connected with people in high places,
you can be sure,
your hope of getting a job is very slim.
But you know, we are children of God,
so Efe, your own case will be different.
[All] Amen.
Although, I just got a job
as a security guard to a politician’s
wife.
A friend of mine recommended me,
and I should start soon, by next week.
I mean... I just
I really hope they are good.
Not the one they’ll
come and turn you into a thug.
[both] Ah, God forbid.
-[Woman] Never, My son? Never.
-[Efe] God forbid
Just don't do that.
[indistinct shouting]
-Allow me to kill this evil child.
-Don’t you have shame?
You want to kill your daughter?
Why won't I kill her?
[Man] This girl is a demon child.
She is an Ogbanje child.
She has been taking
all my money to the coven.
And this same child has
been collapsing my businesses,
and everything that I put my hands into.
And you think killing your child
will solve your financial troubles?
Yes Madam.
At least no body will be
taking my money to the coven.
It's okay, thank you.
-I'll take her, you don't have to worry--
-You can have her.
What kind of a man are you?
[Man] Byebye!
Eh, what's this torture?
I don't know how you do it.
-Do what?
-Give, give, and give.
It is my Christian duty as a believer.
If I don't, who will?
This is what we are called to do.
Do you even know her name?
We’ll look for a name for her,
and have her dedicated in the church.
You know... What do you think
about Esther?
Esther, that's a lovely name.
The orphan who became a queen.
Madam Eloha...
it's so beautiful.
You’ve really outdone yourself this time.
Teni is gonna be so happy, honestly.
-Thank you.
-We thank God, we thank God.
I will get the reception
dress ready by tomorrow evening.
-Thank you.
-Okay.
And by the way,
when are we getting
the invitation to your wedding?
[laughs] Well... there is someone.
Yes, I met him through Charlie…
-Wow.
-And I think he likes me.
Wow.
-Do you like him?
-Yes.
Is he a born again?
Have you prayed about it?
In that case, what... are you waiting for?
Please just hold this one, okay?
Just use it to buy food and clothes
for the little one, please.
Thank you very much, Lola.
You’ve been very good to my family and I.
Thank you so much.
The Lord will replenish your purse.
Amen, amen.
-[Keme] Ready for this?
-[Charlie] Please...
[Keme] Bro, you have no idea
what is about to hit you.
-I get it.
-Thank you so much.
-When you're done boasting--
-No no no.
Just because I don't live here anymore
doesn’t mean I don't
know how whoop your behind.
One, two, three, come on.
[Charlie] Okay, Okay.
-[Keme] Keep going
-[light hearted music]
-[Keme] That's it.
-Hey.
[both] Hey.
-Let me get that for you.
-Oh, thank you.
That’s... really sweet of you.
[Lola] Great to see you again.
Great to see you too, Lola.
What's going on? You seem like you had
a busy day.
Really busy day. I had to pick up
the bridesmaid's dresses
You know, for the wedding.
-Right
-You're coming to the wedding, right?
Uhh, I will, yes,
if you promise to save me a dance.
Uhhmm...
I don't know because
it’s gonna be really hectic
with the whole wedding
and my friend’s not around.
So, it’s just, I don't know.
That’s too bad, because
that's my condition If I’m gonna attend.
-Uhhmm...
-Come on.
-Just one dance?
-One dance.
Seriously, one dance.
-[laughs] Okay, fine.
-Yes? Wonderful.
Now I can start
looking forward to this wedding.
And you my darling
sister has just been played.
You know he was going to
come to wedding anyway, right?
And who told
you that I wasn’t playing him?
[Lola chuckles]
Bye guys.
[Charlie] Keme!
-Right!
-Sit!
[Keme] Whose turn, whose turn?
What did I tell you?
Uhmm, I don't remember,
Mum. What did you tell me?
Didn't I tell
you that he was going to come back?
Really?
Alright, fine, mom,
you did tell me. You were right.
So... did he say anything?
Well, he wants me to dance
with him at Teni's wedding.
And?
-I agreed.
-You agreed.
Well, that's a surprise.
Sounds like you like him too, huh?
Mum, slow down, slow down.
Look, we're gonna take
this one step at a time, ok?
It's just a dance.
-Oh, I'm not rushing.
-Yes, you are .
I just figured [clears throat]
Take a date now and you never know.
[laughs]
-Wedding? Baby?
-Mum!
‪[mum giggles]‬
‪[laughs]‬
Ah! Wait, why did it get
quiet all of a sudden?
[Charlie and Keme laugh]
No, no, no, we are innocent boys.
Well Keme, I hope your parents won’t mind
that you’re gonna
spend time with us. For dinner?
Oh yes, that would be fantastic.
It smells really good.
My parents are in Abuja,
so they’re not gonna mind.
Oh great.
What... do they do exactly?
My dad works for the government
and my mum is a business woman.
Oh that’s nice.
What kind of businesswoman is she?
Mum, can you please
stop interrogating him?
You'll chase him away before dinner.
That’s what you call
getting to know someone lately?
-It’s interrogation?
-[laughs]
I won’t want to... run you out of here,
but I just want to remind
you that get your palates ready
My daughter is preparing a lovely dinner,
Sweet potato porridge with fresh fish.
That sounds very tasty.
I'm looking forward to dinner already.
Right? She's a great cook.
-[Mum] Right?
-Mum, yes, yes, yes, she is a great cook.
Sure.
She is. [laughs]
[laughs] My mum.
Hello Charlie, you’re welcome.
-And Ejikeme, you’re welcome.
-Nice to see you, sir.
-Good to see you guys.
-Thank you
Hello sir.
-So great to see you.
-Thank you.
And I'm so delighted
that you have a great interest in RILA,
-Helping us to promote RILA.
-Yes, yes.
You are welcome, do sit down.
Thank you for having us.
-Thank you so much.
-You are welcome.
We applaud what you are doing
-with the academy
-Yes.
And we would like to partner
with you to expand the courses
and maybe bring a few
campuses to the United States.
If possible, yes.
-[Charlie] That’s the plan
-[Keme] That's the plan
This is great, Charlie and Ejikeme.
Great news to my ears.
I must sincerely thank you,
because we have been looking for partners,
strategic partners, to help us advance
the cause of what we are doing globally.
[Both] Okay.
That’s actually perfect, then,
because we just felt that coming
now was a bit of the right time.
We’re really interested in the course
that focuses on building
apostles in the marketplace.
-Yes Yes Yes.
-Yes, we felt that that kind of thing
would really hit our target demographic.
Yes, we would like to, you know,
set up strategic meetings
with church leaders
across the United States.
-Great.
-And then have you come over
To talk in some of these churches,
-To share the RILA vision--
-Share the message.
-Yes.
-Beautiful, beautiful.
That’s great, because...
that is the major area of our focus.
We’re raising Christian
leaders who function in the marketplace.
And your coming is like the biblical
story of Aaron and Hur in the Bible.
-[Both laugh].
-that lifted up the hands of Moses
Yes Yes.
In battle until the victory was won.
Absolutely.
The Lord will greatly bless you
-[Charlie] Amen.
-for taking this step.
-Thank you so much
-Thank you.
So if it is alright with you,
we just wanted to run
you by a couple of the strategies
that we have for making this work.
-[Charlie] So, that was interesting.
-Yes, I think we’re making progress
Yes Yes. I think so.
Where's the driver?
I don't know, I have no idea.
He’s probably parked somewhere else.
You know how hard it is getting parking--
Alright, what are
you doing for the rest of the day?
Josh.
-I have to see Josh.
-Okay,
You guys have the wedding vows to make
-Yes
-Yes, I don't think I’m trying to do that,
-so you guys have fun.
-[laughs]
And I'll find something to do.
-Alright man.
-I'll just take a walk.
-Take it easy, huh?
-Alright.
[lighthearted music]
[Keme] Lola.
Keme.
Hi.
Fancy meeting you here.
Hey.
-What's up?
-I'm good.
What are you doing here?
I just finished a meeting with Charlie.
We had the RILA thing
so we just came from there,
but he had to go do something with Joshua,
for the wedding.
So, I'm kind of bored,
I was just strolling around.
What are you doing here?
Oh! My office is literally just there,
around the corner.
-Okay. Alright.
-Yea
Uhhm...
Do you want some yoghurt?
I don’t mind.
Frozen yoghurt.
Ok, alright.
What do we have here?
Alright, you can get the strawberry.
I think I'm gonna try... sweet kiwi.
Yea, that's me.
Thanks for the treat.
My pleasure.
No, I should be the one saying that.
I’ve actually enjoyed
spending time with you.
[clears throat]
-Likewise.
-Likewise?
Alright, I’ve enjoyed
spending time with you too.
-There we go, it wasn't so hard.
-[chuckles]
Uhhm...
So listen, you think
we can do this again, sometime?
Yes.
Yeah, because I’m trying
to get to know you a little better.
If you wouldn’t mind, I’d like to
take you on a date or two or three.
Let's start with one.
Okay. Alright, we can do one.
How about Sunday, after church?
Let's have lunch.
-It’s a date.
-Yeah?
-Yeah.
-Okay, perfect.
‪Okay...‬
What's happening?
Why do you have that look on your face?
All is well.
It's just that Otunba Ayodeji
has asked your father
to be his running
mate in the next elections.
Ok, that's… Dad,
Congratulations, that's amazing
But I'm pretty that the election literally
just ended. The next one is in four years?
Yes, definitely.
The election cycle runs
immediately. Four years, yes.
Ok, so he’s asked you to
be his running mate in four years.
Yes.
You see, we... have to
put this like in lock down,
so that he doesn't change his mind.
And that is why we have arranged for
you to marry his only daughter. That way,
two powerful families,
become a formidable dynasty.
[laughter]
Wait.
Come on guys, we're... joking, right?
Do we look like we’re joking?
Okay.
Let me umm,
Let me understand this.
You want me to marry someone.
As in actually "marry someone",
someone's daughter,
because you want to
secure a running mate postion,
four years down the line?
Oh no, son, son, son.
Don't take it like that,
it might sound weird
but you see, this is a family decision.
How is this a family decision, dad?
this has nothing to do with family.
This is about you and I'm sorry
but this is about
you and your ambition, that's fine.
You want to be
president one day, that’s okay.
But why do I have to
be the sacrificial lamb?
Oh, stop being so dramatic.
Nobody is trying to sacrifice you.
I mean, this is
an alliance of two families
for the benefit of both sides.
Okay.
I thought you would know me better by now,
but I can only marry somebody
that God has actually destined
for me, mum.
If I am going to get married
it has to be the will of God.
Ejike, I understand you.
You are born again.
-I am.
-And you believe in the... will of God.
-I do.
-But... so do I.
-So do we.
-So what are you saying?
We believe in the will of God.
and you have not seen this girl.
She is beautiful, elegant,
classy, and she is successful.
Look, I have her on my Facebook.
She’s on your Facebook?
Guys, can you can you…
Mum, dad, can you not hear yourselves?
It sounds like a bad comedy.
Can you please put that phone down?
She can be Miss world, Miss universe
Miss everything rolled into one,
but it’s not gonna happen.
[Keme] Ok mum, I'm sorry.
And dad, let me you ask for something.
Let's say I marry this girl, okay?
We actually get married and then,
four years down the line, Otunba decides,
"Hey, I need someone
more strategic as a partner."
then he dumps you. What happens to me?
I will divorce her immediately,
I'll pay for the divorce.
Wow! I love you both.
But sometimes I cannot deal with you.
You do realize these are
people's lives that you're discussing.
Oh, stop making it sound so evil.
Everybody does this.
But I'm not everyone, and neither are you.
So what do we…
Look, mum, dad,
Maybe this doesn't
make sense to you, I get that.
But I'm the son of
the most high God, okay?
And I have to at least
try to be led by the Spirit,
not the flesh.
So I... refuse to play these games
with you.
Did you just say you refuse? You refuse?
Who the hell do you think you are?
I am your father.
Now, these same
strategies you dismiss as games,
That has paid your fees
and made you whoever you are.
You will obey me!
-[sighs]
-[sad music]
Look, dad,
mum,
I love you both, okay?
I’m sure you both know that,
but you can't force me to do this.
Look, I'm 30 years old, okay?
And I haven't lived at
home in the last decade.
So, with all due respect, sir,
I don't have to do anything.
[music]
I can find a God-fearing wife
Nice and pretty, all by myself.
Thank you.
‪[upbeat music]‬
-[people cheering]
-[upbeat music]
What did you think of the show?
It was... interesting.
I do think some of
the girls should have been
a little more modestly dressed though
Well, that's how
these girls dress nowadays.
But the designer is very talented.
-Hi!
-Hi, Wande.
Hello, darling.
[mum] Hey!
[indistinct]
-Hi.
-Hey
I’m Wande, nice to meet you.
Hi Ejike. Sorry about that.
You know my mum?
Yes I do, I do.
-Okay.
-Yeah.
Oh right, you're the designer.
-This is your collection, right?
-Yes I am.
I hope you enjoyed it.
Yes, It was interesting, it was good.
-Oh.
-Congratulations.
Thank you so much.
[upbeat music]
Lola!
-How are you my dear?
-I'm fine, thank you, ma.
-I'm just trying to--
-Ah!
Auntie Nneka, this is Lola.
The daughter of Dr Deola Makinde's,
that I just introduced to you.
Good afternoon ma.
Your mummy just left. She left in a taxi.
She waited for a long time.
I know, I knew she would leave.
The traffic was so bad today, honestly.
-[in Yoruba] Ah, sorry.
-Thank you.
Okay, let me go.
-Salute her, ehn
-I will
[in Yoruba] Ah, my Yewande!
-My Yewande
-How are you?
I'm fine.
That was a beautiful show.
-Oh thank you.
-Oh yes.
Ejikeme, ah!
-How are you, my lovely
-I didn't know you were coming.
Oh, and thanks for
the perfume you bought me.
I was going to come to
the house personally to thank you.
You’re not supposed to
thanking me for stuff like that, Aunty.
I'm just glad you like it, that's all.
I like it. I’ll use it once a year
[all laugh]
Yewande, that was
a beautiful fashion show.
-Thank you
-And your designs
Very beautiful. Wonderful
Your parents must be really proud.
Well, my mum is ,I don't
know about my dad, he never has time,
he is always very busy politicking.
Hold on. Your dad is a politician too?
Yes, you didn't know?
My dad is Otunba Ayodeji.
Yes now.
Yewande, it was wonderful
-to run into you.
-[Wande] Oh, thank you.
-We’ve got to leave now.
-Okay.
-Sister Nneka.
-Yes, see you soon.
[human sound]
Auntie, it was good to see you.
-Yes, yes indeed, my dear.
-Wande.
-Yes, it was a pleasure to meet you
-It was a pleasure.
-Okay.
-Excuse me, just a second.
Mum, no, no, no.
Mum, how much of today was a coincidence?
What do you mean?
Why did you bring me here?
To watch a fashion show.
[sighs]
Look. It... was a fashion show
for charity,
and I know you love things like that.
Mum, I'm not joking.
OK, alright.
I just wanted you to meet her.
You know,
you refuse to look at
her on my Facebook page.
Can you stop with the Facebook…?
[sighs]
What you did was wrong, okay?
I wanted you to make an informed decision.
There is no decision to make.
I am not going to marry that girl.
-case closed.
-Oh, stop being so stubborn.
Case closed.
["'Carried Away" playing]
♪ Baby won’t you carry me, carry me away ♪
♪ Take me where you stay and maybe,
To your favorite place ♪
♪ Mama, just me knowing you here
Won't let me find my space ♪
♪ Baby, don't come here
Unless you taking me away ♪
♪ No more time for the new girls ♪
♪ There is a new dog in a new world ♪
♪ And I see too much to understand ♪
♪ And I see too much to leave a chance ♪
♪ Introduce you to my baby, we say
Number ten ♪
♪ Wait, hold up ♪
♪ You been acting all shy from the club ♪
♪ And I gotta understand,
Will you show up? ♪
♪ So precious, think to name
Your daughter, Alexis ♪
♪ Coming up now where the best live ♪
♪ Let's talk about
the future we will be best friends ♪
♪ When we get this ♪
♪ Maybe we can take a trip
To where I was at ♪
♪ Teach you about that type of love
One at a time ♪
♪ Tell you all about the stories
Trapped in my mind ♪
♪ He's checking my mind ♪
♪ And baby,
I can be a soldier, you put me in line ♪
♪ So will you carry me ♪
♪ Baby will you carry me from pain ♪
♪ 'Cos I could care for you baby ♪
So, that was a profound service?
Yes it was. Definitely was
The last two weeks... have been
some of the best of my entire life.
-You make me blush.
-Oh.
-[laughs]
-I'm being serious.
Just meeting you and
spending time with you,
Getting to know you... it's been amazing
And I just feel like i want
to take our relationship
to the next level,
if that's what you want.
What do you mean?
I umm...
I want to marry you, Lola.
[laughs] Umm...
Are you sure?
I mean we we’ve only known each other what
-Two weeks. I know, I know it's…
-Two weeks.
[sighs]
Let me ask you something
Are you sure about how you feel about me?
-One hundred per cent?
-One hundred per cent.
Then that's what we need.
I mean, I’ve just always believed that
if God is in something... you just know.
And... I’ve known
that you are the woman for me,
since the very first second I saw you,
at the house, with the meat pies
-and the drinks and everything
-[laughs]
I just knew.
I knew it too.
And every time I try
to fight these feelings,
for you, they just get stronger.
So...
Yes, I will marry you.
Yes Yes.
Wait, seriously?
-Yes.
-[laughs] Are you serious?
Hmmmnn....
Oh sorry, sorry. Am I squeezing you?
-You actually said "Yes".
-I can’t believe you asked.
I'm not sure what I was… Wait, wait,
now you are definitely
going to think I’m crazy, but...
I know I already seem really crazy, but
I already ordered the ring.
Okay [laughs]
Yes, I couldn’t wait for it to arrive.
So I'm just gonna give you this instead.
It belonged to my grandmother.
It was important to her,
so she wore it every day,
every single day until the day she died.
So, I want you to have this,
so you can wear it every day.
It will remind you of how I feel
about you.
-May I?
-Yes.
-Yes?
There we go.
-Yes, no, no, no, let people see it, yes.
-[laughs]
There we go, look at that.
I will cherish this every single day
for the rest of my life.
You should come over to my house.
We're having this
birthday party for my dad.
It's his 60th birthday,
so it’s like a big thing.
You should come as my guest.
Do you think I should actually come?
I mean, what will your parents say?
Do they know about me?
Oh, they'll find out when they meet you.
Look, I just want them
to meet you, you know?
Get to know you the way I have.
Come on, say "Yes".
Yes, I'll come.
-Yes, yes?
-Yes.
You have no idea how happy you’ve made me.
Ha! I’m getting married.
-I love you.
-I love you too.
[gospel music]
[water running]
Oh wow, it all sounds so exciting.
Hmm-nnn
And he said I should wear it everyday
as a token of his love for me.
Honey, it is beautiful.
Mum, you don't sound happy for me.
Oh come on, honey.
Of course, I'm happy for you sweetheart.
Why wouldn’t I be?
Honey, I’m just… [clears throat]
I just feel you're moving a bit too fast.
I mean, you’ve only known him what?
All of two weeks.
Look honey, I'm worried
we don't know anything about his family.
And every time we bring it up,
he clams up.
Even Charlie has no
idea what his parents do.
Mum, it doesn't matter.
He is the one.
Huh?
How can you be so sure?
Barely two weeks ago
you weren’t ready for marriage.
Now you are engaged.
Look, mum, I can't explain it, okay?
I just know. I can feel it, mum, I know.
He’s the one, mum.
Okay.
Well, call it a mother's intuition,
we know nohing about his family.
Please, can you just be happy for me,
please?
I will meet his parents
at his dad's 60th birthday,
and everything’s gonna go well.
And then you’ll be
able to meet his parents
and ask all the questions you have, mum,
All of them.
Okay, if you put it that way, honey.
Let's go.
Okay.
Lola, I need you to style me.
for what?
It's my Aunty's husband’s 60th birthday.
Oh, is that the one that’s
arranging a wife for his son?
Yes, I heard from the family grapevine,
That it’s already a done
deal and Otunba is even coming
with their daughter for the announcement.
Wow, okay, fine.
Let me see what I can do.
[clears throat] So, I’m actually
going to a 60th birthday party myself
-Really?
-Hmmn
And who is it?
Do you remember Charlie's friend, Keme?
-The hot guy now.
-Ahnahn!
Oh my God. [laughs]
I do not
remember him because I haven't met him.
But girl, that’s great.
I wish I'm coming with you.
No, please,
come and be going to
that your engagement party.
I'll give you all the gist later.
-What?
-And listen, if all goes well, I might
have a special announcement later tonight.
-What?
-Yes.
What? You need to fill me in, everything.
-No
-Let's go.
Wait, you need to give me everything
in detail.
-[Lola] You love gist, let's go.
-[Kemi] Of course I love gist
[dance music]
[Keme] Mum, you’ve outdone
yourself this time, seriously.
-Yes, this looks fantastic.
-Thank you.
[Keme] Listen, I invited
two friends over. I hope that’s okay.
Why didn't you tell me?
Mum, it’s two friends.
I had planned something
nice and intimate for your father.
[Keme] this is nice and intimate
Well, I guess two extra
people won’t do any harm
Thank you, thank you.
And are they the ones
that have kept you out.
for so long?
And, your recent good mood?
You do realize I'm
here on a business trip, right?
So obviously I’m not gonna be at home.
I have to go out and do things
and what’s wrong with having a good mood.
[Mum] I like your cologne.
-Mum, please, not today.
-[laughs]
-I think someone needs you over there.
-When did you start using cologne?
Mum, give me a break.
[Keme] When my friends come
You’ll get all the answers you need, okay?
But seriously, good job.
Thank you.
And please, no more surprises.
I have prepared something really
special for your father.
I don't want it to be ruined.
[sighs] Yes, mum.
[Keme sighs] thank you.
‪[background chatter]‬
-Hi again.
-Hi.
I just wanted to thank
you for coming to the fashion show.
It was really nice chatting with you.
No, absolutely, absolutely.
I had a good time talking to you as well.
You are pretty knowledgeable about
fashion.
Yes, I am.
I was just kinda hoping I’ll
get to know you better tonight.
No, thank you.
You wanted to...
Well, excuse me, Iet me get some drinks.
What's going on?
What do you mean?
Mum, why is that girl here?
Her father is here.
Should I tell him not to
bring his only daughter?
Mum, come on.
Look, I...
I hope you are not planning
anything embarrassing tonight, mum.
I resent that!
Do you think I'm stupid?
No one said you're stupid,
you don’t have to be so dramatic.
Sorry, sorry, sorry.
I wasn't trying to insult you, okay?
I'm just saying I... hope you've accepted
my decision.
And I hope you respect it.
Mum, I'm not marrying that girl.
[sucks teeth]
Mum!
[sighs]
Here you go.
-You got me one.
-Yeah.
Is everything okay?
Ahh...
Yea, everything is okay.
Listen, I... I’m not trying to give
you the wrong impression or anything
and I don't know what my mum has told you.
Oh my God.
[Wande] You're so uptight right now
you need to loosen up, okay?
Maybe after tonight,
the tension will disappear.
What's...
What’s happening after tonight?
[laughs] You're so funny.
You and I know what's happening tonight.
Am...
Am I missing something?
Look at... Sorry, can you hold this
for me?
-Ohhh
-Hey
You look amazing.
That necklace should not be hidden.
Let people see it.
-Bro!
-[Charlie] My man.
[both laugh]
-How are you doing?
-Thanks for coming through bro.
-No problem.
-Look at you.
-Looking all traditional
-Look at you, looking traditional.
What can I say, bro?
Mum, hi.
These are my friends.
This is Charlie, we work together,
and this is his sister, Lola.
[dance music]
Good evening Ma.
-Charlie.
-[Charlie] Ma?
Welcome to our home.
[Charlie] Thank you very much, ma'am.
Ejike has told us so much about you,
but he failed to mention your sister.
Yes, her name is Lola.
This is Lola.
-I met you.
-Yes Ma.
At the fashion show?
you were at the fashion show?
I was only there for a little while.
Just to pick my mum.
Oh. Okay.
Anyway, you should meet my dad.
You should meet my dad, yes.
-No.
-Come on.
You get them a drink, you know,
let your father finish with the Otunba.
And then we will do the introductions.
Excuse me.
How are you?
-We'll meet him later.
-Hey you,
introduce me to your friends.
-Ok, this is Charlie.
-Yes.
-Hey.
-Nice to meet you.
-Charlie, this is Wande.
And Wande, this is Lola.
Your father is the Honorable Chukwuemeka,
and you didn't think that was something
that you should have told me?
Yeah, look, I'm trying to be me, okay?
I don't want to walk
around town as Chukwuemeka’s son.
I don’t like that thing.
I see.
Nice to meet you.
Can I speak with you for a minute?
Yes, sure.
Well, look at you.
‪[suspenseful music]‬
We’re in trouble.
Ejike gave that girl the necklace,
mum’s necklace
What girl?
His friend's sister.
So?
Mum said that he should give the necklace
to the woman he plans to marry.
We cannot go ahead
with the plans for today,
Or else Ejike will
blow up and ruin everything.
How can I…?
Otunba is anxious to make a statement now.
Stall him, let me think about something.
[sighs]
Okay, hurry up, Nneka.
But I thought you said
you were working on him.
Yes, well, I am
I wasn’t expecting this girl.
Look, I promised to make
you president and I will.
I mean... we are so close now.
Nothing is going to stop us.
-[Charlie] This party seems cool
-Hey
Yeah, man. Thank you for coming.
Welcome to my little corner.
-Hey hey, please.
-Small.
Hey, please, we are a poor family
Keep saying that
At some point, you’ll
believe it. Keep saying that.
No, no, this is tiny.
-Kemi.
-[Kemi] Lola and Charlie.
Cuzzo.
-How are you?
-Hey.
What are you guys doing here?
-Is this the party you were invited to?
-Yes.
-Wait, this is your uncle's house?
-So he’s your--
-Ejike, my cousin.
Keme, Keme.
[Keme] Right, just one second.
How are you?
[Keme] I didn't know you were coming.
Yes, my full name is Ejikeme, Chukwuemeka.
I'll explain later.
Ok, you know what?
I don't know what's going on here,
but... wait a minute.
So Keme, if you're the only son,
then who exactly--
[Keme's dad] Uhhm
Thank you very much, friends and family,
Thank you so much for
coming to celebrate with me today.
I thank God for making me to see today.
-I am 60 years old, It’s not a joke.
-[guests clapping]
-[Keme's dad] My joy is double.
When I received
a splendid news from my son,
Ejikeme, before this party.
It is with my utmost pleasure--
[Keme] Dad, please.
And joy to announce the engagement
of my only son, Ejikeme,
-to Wande Ayodeji
-[guests clapping]
the only daughter of
Otunba Ayodeji, thank you.
Thank you, thank you.
It's not what you think.
[Keme] Hold on, hold on, hold on
let me explain to you
-Let go, I’m fine,
-It's okay.
What is going on here?
Mum, not now, please.
Ejike, don't be rude.
Otunba wants to
understand what is going on here.
Mum, that's his problem not mine, okay?
Can you get this girl out of my house?
-Lola!
-Let's go, let's go talk
Lola, oya, come and be going.
Charlie, go and drop her.
She's... not going anywhere.
Ok, mum, she’s here on my invitation.
-So she gets to stay.
-Lola, for the first time in your life,
don't make this about you.
Don't come and
cause trouble in this family.
Lola, we know each other.
You better leave now before I expose you.
[Charlie] Expose her?
This is the girl
you knew since she was a baby.
[chuckles] You don’t know her!
I know exactly who she is,
thank you very much.
You don’t know who she is.
Her M.O is to take other people's men.
How dare you?
This is all a lie.
What did she do to you that is so bad
That you’ll say such
hurtful things about her?
Why not?
That's how she met
Femi for the first time.
-Ah.
-Eh, immediately.
Femi started running
after her day and night.
The most painful
part of this whole thing is
this girl did not even like the Femi,
but.. she just decided to ruin
Kemi's life.
Mum, what has gotten over you?
Femi was just a horrible guy.
Stop defending her.
For once in your life,
hold this girl responsible.
Hold her responsible
for what she did to you.
Ejike Chukwuemeka, this is
the girl you want to bring into my family?
This prostitute.
Ah!
Mum!
[iKeme] Lola, wait!
-Mum, why do you--
-[in Yoruba] Kinni?
[Keme] Lola, wait, wait.
Sorry, sorry. Please.
Look, Lola, just let me explain, okay?
I am sorry about that, you didn't
deserve to go through that.
[crying]
Why did you invite me here?
I wanted my parents to meet you.
Look, I meant it when I…
Lola, I love you.
-You lied to me.
-I didn't lie, okay?
Yes, I omitted the fact
that I am my father’s son, but
-it's not a lie.
-An omission... is still a lie.
I don't know who you are.
You told me that you are someone else,
I don't know you.
I'm the same guy you met... The same guy
What does it matter what my last name is?
Who are you?
Please, I don't know who you are.
Who are you? And who is Wande?
And what does
she have to do with all of this?
Okay, hold up.
The Wande thing, that's
just my mum being crazy.
I'll explain later,
but... you are the only person
I care about.
Lola, I'm the same guy.
Ok, the same guy
that fell in love with you,
literally seconds after meeting you.
I am the same guy who’s
standing here asking you, begging you.
Forgive me... Please.
‪[exhales]‬
I need some... space.
Look, I need to understand
what's going on,
I don’t understand, I'm confused.
Look, I need some space, please.
‪[sniffs]‬
OK. Fine.
I'll give you space.
But I meant it when I said I loved you.
So, don't expect too much space.
I’m gonna go get Charlie to take you home.
I'm never giving up on us, Lola.
Never.
I'll be right back.
‪[footsteps]‬
[sighs]
What is the meaning of this,
Ejikeme or Keme,
or whatever your name actually is?
Bro, it's still me, okay?
I wasn’t trying to lie to anyone.
It's just that I don't like
announcing he's my father, that's all.
I was trying to distance myself
from my parents' name, that's it.
That’s all well and good but
all I care about right now, is my sister.
You told me you loved her.
Are you serious?
I mean that more than you’ll ever know.
And I do intend to marry her.
So why then are your parents announcing
your engagement to this person?
Who is she?
And what's going on here, Keme?
I have no idea what
happened back there, okay?
I was completely blindsided.
[sucks teeth] This is like the…
what… second time I’m meeting that girl.
I don't even know her like that.
I'm not going to marry her.
Well, Kemi says that the whole
family has known about this for months.
Why would your own family do this to you?
Yes, my family is crazy. Okay?
I don’t know how else to explain it, okay?
Otunba Ayodeji has asked
my father to be his running mate,
four years down the line,
which I thought would be crazy.
But hey, my parents
want to lock down the position,
so they want me to
marry his only daughter,
which makes no sense.
But that’s just how they think, okay?
They told me about it,
I said: "No'' obviously.
but they didn't listen, so here we are.
Trust me, I had no
idea that was gonna happen.
I promise you.
They must not have heard me
or they just didn't care
because... now, there’s this.
Keme, this is a nightmare,
and my sister is
caught in the middle of it,
fix it.
I know, okay. And bro, I promise you,
I'll sort all of this, okay?
better sort it or you'll answer to me.
‪[footsteps]‬
‪[car door opens and closes]‬
‪[car ignition]‬
I am really sorry about the other night.
I had no idea you were
not aware of the arrangement.
For what it's worth,
I think she means well.
Yes, she wants people to think that.
Look, I have to ask you,
why are you going along with this?
I mean, come on, Wande, you are young,
you are accomplished,
you are really beautiful.
You don't need anyone
to set up a marriage for you.
This is what I’m groomed for, okay?
Besides, it's way easier this way,
'cos I know who I'm dealing with
and it is clear
you are not after dad's money.
Errr, fair enough.
Do you really think I'm beautiful?
[chuckles] Wande, I think you are a
lovely person,
I actually mean that.
You are really beautiful,
but... I fell in love with
someone already, okay?
And I actually intend to marry Lola.
[sighs deeply]
I am sad, honestly,
because I really think
we could be good together.
But it seems she’s a nice girl.
She is, she is, she is.
She is amazing.
[purse lips] Okay.
Look, I'm glad we had this talk.
-Me too.
-Okay.
I'm sorry things didn’t work out.
No hard feelings.
Thanks for being honest.
-Okay, no problem.
-Okay.
I’ll see you around?
-Yes, good
-OK.
‪[heels clicking]‬
‪[keyboard clicks]‬
[door closes]
Hi Mum.
How did it go?
How did what go?
How did you find Wande?
Uhhm, she's a nice person,
‪[keyboard clicks]‬
but she is not the one for me, alright?
Mum, I'm sorry.
But you just said she’s a nice person
What more do you want in a wife?
Mum, we’ve been over this.
Lola, is the one for me, okay?
Can we please not do this? Please?
I really want to know
what this Lola has given you?
What kind of juju has she given you?
I want to know her native doctor’s name.
[sighs] I'm not even gonna--
How can you let Wande go?
I mean she's tall
she's elegant,
she is so well mannered. She--
-Hmnn...
-Did you do this?
-No, I did not!
-Mum, tell me the truth.
But you look so good together.
Mum, you have no idea what you've done.
‪[car engine revvs]‬
-[car door closes]
-Lola!
Lola!
‪[car door closes]‬
[Lola's dad]] Hey,
can I help you, young man?
Ah, sorry, sir.
I am...
I'm here to see Lola.
Lola. I see.
The woman you're about to marry
does she know
you are here looking for Lola?
Sir, I'm not getting married
to anybody except your daughter.
-Is that so?
-Yes sir.
Go home, son!
Leave my daughter alone.
Listen, listen, we are simple people.
-I know.
-And we just don't want your trouble.
-I know sir, let me explain.
-We don't want your trouble at all.
Daddy, please calm down. Please
[Keme] Hey,
can we... talk for a second?
Daddy, please, it's okay.
[purse lips] If you hurt my daughter,
[laughs sarcastically]
I will make
you regret the day you were born
‪[calm music]‬
Hey,
can we talk please?
[soft music]
I’m guessing you saw
the pictures online already.
I couldn't have
missed them even if i tried.
Every time I open up a page,
that's all I would see.
Congratulations.
-Let me--
-No, no, wait, Congratulations.
She is very pretty and
you guys are trending, so--
-Lola, just let me--
-No, hold on.
I saw all the hashtags.
What did I see? I saw Wajike, I saw
Okay, can you, please stop?
I'm not marrying Wande, okay?
I don't even know
who posted those pictures online.
My mother probably
had Something to do with it,
but the point is, that wasn't real.
So if you're not marrying her,
why would you let
someone take pictures of you like that?
That’s what I'm trying to explain.
All right, look,
she came over to see me, right?
We had a little talk and...
I told her my heart belongs
to someone else.
Okay, listen to me. She was leaving,
alright?
She just wanted me give me a hug, goodbye,
and someone decided to take pictures,
That’s what you saw.
It wasn't real.
-[sighs]
-Please
Listen, I don't know
what to believe anymore.
Believe me.
Alright, just say, "You will marry me."
Your parents won't even accept me.
I don’t care!
Honestly, I don’t.
Look, Lola, I love you. Alright.
And I know that you love me too.
You’re still wearing my necklace.
I do love you,
But is that even enough?
What is the point of marrying someone
that you can’t even build a future with
because the families won’t even accept it?
It's going to have to be enough.
Okay? Because I'm not going to stop.
I'm not stopping until you are my wife.
when I came to Nigeria,
I came to look for
businesses to invest in.
I didn’t come looking for a wife.
Obviously, God had other plans
because he led me to you and...
Look, Lola, God makes everything;
everything beautiful,
-In his own time.
-[calm music]
Keme, please don’t hurt me again. Please
[gate opens]
‪[car door opens]‬
[screams]
‪[muffled screaming]‬
Make sure that no body goes
out or comes in through that gate.
-You hear me?
-Yes sir.
And then I don't want to
see you inside here, okay?
Yes sir.
No, inside there
[in Yoruba] Fool... Get away from here!
Ah, aah. shior
Guess who's back?
Hey, uncle. [human sound]
How’ve you been?
[Charlie's mum] Hello, Darling.
How are you?
Good to see you, thank you.
-Hey you!
-How are you doing?
-Hi, Auntie.
-Hello Darling.
-How are you?
-I've missed you so much.
-You are so pretty.
-Thank you.
Uhm, where's Lola?
I have so much to tell her.
Uhm, Lola is... nowhere to be found
right now.
[chuckles] What do you mean, she’s nowhere
to be found? Did she go out?
Teni, Lola is missing.
Ok? We have no idea where she is.
[sobs]
How, how?
People don't just get missing like that.
Has anyone contacted the police?
Yes, Josh. We have but
there are no leads at the moment.
God is our lead.
He’ll bring my daughter back home,
where she belongs.
We just have to have faith, right?
Apparently she left a note with
Keme saying that she was leaving
and that no one
should come looking for her.
So that means she's alive, right?
[Teni] Yes?
We are very sure
that she didn’t write that note.
And Lola wouldn't just leave.
Also, there were so
many typos in the message.
Has there been any ransom
message or any ransom demand?
No. There is no other communication.
-I don’t understand it.
-[mum sobs]
-Who has my daughter?
And... what do they want to do with her?
How is Keme handling this?
Don’t you dare say that name
in this house.
D'you understand me?
Especially with what his mother
and himself put my daughter through
Mum, come on,
you know it's not Keme's fault.
He's devastated about all of this
as we are.
-Oh, please!
-I don't care what his feelings are!
The whole problem started
the day he laid his eyes on her.
Ugghh
I told you, I have no
trust in these politicians at all.
Oh, my baby.
-My poor baby, my poor baby.
-[phone chimes]
Hello.
-Yes.
-[somber music]
[somber music]
Ok, Ok... Thank you.
Thank you very much.
-[sighs]
-Yes?
-There’s been a lead.
-[mum] Oh go on, go on!
Go, go!
Stay with the family, okay?
-[Josh] Are you sure?
-Go quickly, go quickly!
My daughter’s gonna be fine.
‪-[car door opens]‬
‪-[somber music]‬
‪[car door closes]‬
‪[car horn blaring]‬
Yes, Efe, where are you? I can’t see you.
Yes, I am on the street.
I am here, I am here.
I’m the one waving my hand, yes.
-Alright, hurry up.
-Come on.
-Bros.
-What's the plan? What's going on?
They have her in the room at the back.
They asked me not to enter the room,
but when I was doing my rounds,
I saw that a window was open.
So I peeped and I saw
auntie Lola lying on the floor.
How do you know it's Lola?
Bros, I know auntie Lola anyday, anytime.
She has been so good to me and my family.
Immediately I saw her,
I called Auntie Kemi,
and she said she will inform bros.
Okay, we're just gonna have to go.
-Yes.
-And see what we can do.
How many people are in there?
Bros, there are three of them.
But Dele is their leader.
-Dele?
-Yes, bros, Dele.
Just go , I'm coming.
Bros, please do something.
No, no, no, just go open the gate.
‪[car door closes]‬
‪[car ignition]‬
Did I not tell you not to...
Ah ha!
-Eh, eh
-Where is she? Where is she?
Where's Lola? Where is she?
Arrggh!
-[Keme] Lola?
-The Lord is my Shepherd, I shall not want
He makes me lie down in green pastures.
[door opens]
[iKeme] Lola!
[Lola groans]
It's okay, it's okay,
I'm here. Help me get her up.
-[sobs]
-I know, I am here, I am here.
[Keme] I got you, let's get her up
come on.
[groans]
Listen, call your dad, and tell
him to meet us at his hospital. Ok?
‪-[inaudible]‬
‪-[somber music]‬
Lord, please, protect my daughter.
Bless her, O Lord.
O Lord, heal her.
[praying]
Bless the hands of the doctors.
Give them wisdom
and knowledge to treat her.
Amen.
O Lord, Let no harm come near Lola.
I can't just stay here.
Let me know when she is awake, okay?
I'm gonna go confront my parents.
[mum] Lord, we leave it in your hands oh
God, please.
I need to bring God in this.
Well, she'll be okay.
Oh...
Now Charlie, tell me
Where did you find her?
Well, It appears Keme’s
mum had Lola kidnapped
to keep her away from
him until after his wedding
to Otunba Ayodeji's daughter.
-What?
-She did what?
Why are these people like this?
Of course she did this
in conjuction with your friend,
Sisi Toyin.
What?
She fed Keme's mum
the how and where to find Lola.
Well, she met her match.
And she did this to the wrong woman.
-She will pay for this, honey.
-[Teni] Aunty.
No, and that Keme's mother,
oh she will pay for everything.
They’re gonna pay for
everything they did to my daughter,
Irrespective of
her husband’s political clout.
I always knew this.
I knew that her relationship
with that boy was a wrong one.
See, politicians can do and undo.
Yes, And they always
believe that they are above the law.
Well, they are not above God’s law, honey.
Why would she do this to Lola? Why?
[Lola's mum] Honey.
[dad] Lollipop.
Good to have you back with us.
Hey, baby.
They beat me…
[Lola] I was so scared I would never see
you again.
[mum] Shhhh, don’t say that.
We will never let anyone hurt you again.
I'm so sorry, baby.
I am so sorry.
I prayed so hard.
And then God sent me Charlie and Keme.
Praise God.
Why would anyone do this?
Why?
Oh honey, I love you.
I love you too, mom.
It’s okay.
I’m just grateful
that God brought me back to you.
So am I.
[groans]
It's okay, don't try to move.
Don't touch it,
don't touch it, Just leave it…
[Keme's dad] Ah,
here comes the prodigal son.
Look at you, moping around
the house because of a woman,
instead of sealing a simple family deal.
[mum] You know, I don't even know
how we'll face the disgrace of yesterday.
We were at Otunba's last night,
discussing the wedding
plans and he was so angry
that you couldn’t even bother to...
show up.
It took all the skills
I possess to pacify him and his daughter.
How could you do that to us?
It will be a wonder if
Otunba speaks to me again.
[dad] I don't know what got into him,
what possessed him,
he even went as far as telling Wande
that... he is breaking up with her.
Can you imagine?
[chair squeaks]
-What is that?
-What is this?
Look at it
What's it?
That is the woman that I love.
The woman that I'm going to marry, right?
Beaten up, kidnapped,
tortured … Because of you?
Did...
-Did you ask them to beat her--
-No!
I didn't ask anybody to beat her.
All i said was
that they should keep her until--
[Keme groans] Mum!!!
Until I could convince you that she had
asked...
you to leave her alone.
I wouldn't ask anybody to beat her.
-I didn’t--
-What's wrong with you people?
Who does this?
Dad, I'll send every single copy--
-Wait, wait, wait.
-of these photos.
Dad, dad, please, please,
These pictures are going out,
okay? Unless you do what I say.
If you don’t, let's see how
your whole vice-presidential ambition,
let's see how far that goes for you.
You want to ruin me, me, your own father?
Me, ruin you?
Your own blood?
Dad, you kidnapped someone!
Look!
Mum, dad, her parents
have been worried for days,
wondering where their daughter is.
Not knowing whether she's alive or dead
and I am supposed to be
worried about your... re... reputation.
your career,
that’s what is important right now?
What do you want us to do?
How about we put this
whole marriage charade to an end?
Can we do that? I am not marrying Wande.
I need you to
apologize to Lola and her family.
Mum, I'm being serious.
Ok, and dad, the people who did this,
I need them arrested.
[mum laughs]
I will never apologize to anyone
for looking after my family.
Ok, let's see how
you will enjoy... jail then.
Hey, hey, hey, stop bluffing there.
Ejike, now listen, let me tell you.
No security organization
in this country,
I repeat, in this country,
that will put, my wife and I
in jail! Do you hear me?
Alright, dad.
Let's put that to the test. Shall we?
Since you are the big man. Right?
Maybe you’re a big man here.
But let's see what happens
when they face pressure
from the international media.
Yes, because maybe you guys didn’t know,
but... Lola is a British citizen.
So let's see what
happens when the news gets
a story about a British
citizen being kidnapped, beaten
and almost killed in Lagos.
Let's see how that goes,
Maybe that will be a story then.
What?
-[Ms. Chukwuemeka] Dele.
-Ma.
What happened to
the girl I asked you to hold?
Err... Uhhm...
Mr... Ejike... came and saved her.
Ehnehn, and I’m
just hearing about it this morning?
I... had no... credit, ma'am.
And then I sent--
Shut up your mouth!
I pay you enough money to make sure
there's enough credit on your phone
How can I ask you to do something
and you just disappointed me?
I didn't... disappoint... you.
I didn’t, Ma.
It's Mr. Ejikeme, ma
It was Ejike who came--
If you had done your job,
he would not have found her.
How did he know where to look?
Ah, eh eh!
Insider information, I'm sure.
Oh, that's
your excuse for not doing your job?
Insider information.
No, no, wait, wait, wait.
Who beat her up?
-Beat her?
-Yes.
[both] Who beat her up?
-[Dele] Beat her?
-Yes.
I didn't beat her. It wasn't me.
-You don't know?
-No, sir.
You were asked to watch
and keep an eye on someone
and you’re telling me you don't know who?
Do you know how serious the issue is?
I know, sir. I didn't beat her.
[in Yoruba] True! No sir.
-Dele!
-[Dele] Ma.
How often have I told you
that you must always tell the truth?
I’m speaking the truth.
Ok, let me tell you exactly what happened.
I had running stomach.
Yes, Ma.
My stomach was making noises.
[Dele] So I ran to the toilet
and before I came back,
the girl had vanished.
It's... my stomach, ma'am.
You know what?
Deal with them,
ask Kunle to handle this issue.
I have to clean up all
this before It gets to the press.
-Please, sir
-I'm off to see Otunba
to tell him our own version
of the story before
he hears it from somebody
-Do you hear me?
-Good idea.
Deal with them
-No, as for you
-It's...
-you've lost your job.
-It's running stomach--
-No, ma, it's not me.
-And you,
I'm going to lock you up.
I will lock you up.
How could you have
let that happen to that girl?
I said, "Hold a girl,"
and you end up beating her
until she is totally unrecognizable.
[Lola's mum] Where is she?
Where is the spineless coward
who had thugs beat my daughter?
-You?
-Who is this woman?
-Dele, get rid of her.
-Ma?
-Out!
-If you touch me,
I will tear you to pieces this morning.
You dare hide behind your thugs?
Face me!
Face me like a woman!
So I can show you what it is
when cowards think they are above the law.
Madam, leave my
house before I get the police
to lock you up for trespassing.
The police?
After what you did to my daughter?
Lock me up?
You dare touch me one more time,
and I will show you why
they say that Nneka Chukwuemeka
is worth more than ten men. Your daughter
had bitten off more than she can chew
How dare you?
-Aunty, let's go.
-[Ms. Chukwuemeka] Rubbish
I'm begging you.
Ok guys take her inside.
What kind of a mother are you?
You would rather see your son unhappy
because of your political goals?
You don't know what you're talking about.
Get out of my house!
Take her inside. Stop! Take her inside!
What kind of woman is this?
I know I know, please, alright?
Oh my God.
Take her inside.
Get out!
Ah, get out!
[in Yoruba] Are you deaf?
[in yoruba] She asked you to leave
Ah, madam!
[sighs]
Let me see.
Congratulations.
I hope you are at
least happy with yourself.
Uhmm, I...
I can’t even recognize the person
seated in front of me right now, honestly.
Ejike, please.
Don’t look at me like that,
I am not a monster.
I’m doing the best I can for my husband.
Look, I didn't mean to hurt Lola.
Things just got out of hand.
Yes, but mum, but I kept telling you
I kept telling you I did
not want to marry Wande
it wasn’t complicated.
Why wouldn’t you just listen?
Mum, I love you, okay?
Always have, always will.
But I can't have
you interfering in my life like this.
It’s just not gonna work.
I'm sorry.
I won’t interfere anymore.
Forgive me?
It’s just one more thing.
I actually need you to go and
apologize to Lola and her family.
Mum, not one of those
manipulative apologies you give,
when you don’t want people to sue you.
I need a genuine one, okay?
For me, please.
I need you to help me make this right.
I need you to help me keep
the woman that I actually love.
Alright.
Well, I'll apologize, I'll grovel,
I'll cry to bring
the smile back in your eyes.
Are we good now?
There’s just... one more thing.
God, what now?
I need you to promise to rededicate
your life to Jesus.
Ejike, I don't know
what you're talking about.
My faith in God is just fine,
I am very active in church.
[laughs] How did
you come up with this ridiculous idea?
Mum, come on.
Let’s be serious here.
Not even you can
lie to yourself that much.
Surely, you know
that you’ve fallen so far from Him.
I mean, look at what your life has become.
Look at the things
you’re doing with your time.
Look at your face.
Who is this person?
What happened to that... prayer warrior?
You know, the one that raised me…
Mum, I became a Christian because of you,
You were my role model.
I wanted to be like
you, I wanted to have that relationship
with Christ the way you did.
I wanted to serve,
just because seeing you serve looked so…
I wanted to be like you.
How did you go from being that person to
whoever this is?
Son.
Politics is a beast.
You go in there with
high hopes of changing things,
of destroying the endemic corruption
that has paralyzed our country.
And before you know it
You’re making deals to
get things on your agenda done.
Very soon you realize that to survive
you have to get rid of your ideals
and jump into the swamp
where it is always dirty
And just like that.
You become what you have always despised.
You look at yourself in the mirror
and you don't recognize what you see.
But you console yourself that
you have got things done
And you just need a little bit more power
to get some more things done.
And then you’ll go
back to what you used to be,
but you never go back.
This is what we have become.
[sighs] This is our reality.
This is who we are.
Yes, but mum, it doesn’t have to be.
It’s not enough to just say: "Oh,
this is what happened,
and this is who I am now so that's it".
Jesus will always take you back, always.
His arms are just wide open,
just waiting for us to come back to him.
Mum look, it's possible.
You just need to …
You need to turn
your back on all of these things, okay?
on the world,
on all of these power hungry things
You’ve gotten yourself into. Just...
Just give it up, okay?
And come back to him and I promise you,
He will accept you.
Turn our backs,
turn my back on
everything we have attained?
Go back to who we were?
What does it profit
a man to gain the whole world
and lose his soul.
You taught me that.
That’s from you, mum.
Alright, you can do this.
I need you to believe that.
You can do this.
Mum, you've known Lola all her life,
and you know, she’s an amazing person.
How could you say
such horrible things about her?
But it's the truth. She destroyed your
relationship with Femi.
Oh mum, spare me! Spare me!
Femi went after her and she said "No" .
If not for Lola, I would have
married that miserable wretch.
You should be thanking
her and not using it against her.
It’s a pattern with Lola.
She did the same to Bisola.
Must she be the only
one that men must die for?
I'm only looking out for my cousin.
Oh mum, stop, stop, stop.
Your cousin is capable
of looking out for herself.
She doesn't need
anybody to look out for her.
Lola almost got killed.
If not for Ejike and Charlie,
Only God knows what
would have happened to her.
Wo, I don’t have a hand in that o!
Oh mum, you did!
You encouraged her!
You told her where and when to find Lola!
You are an accomplice in this!
You owe Lola and her family an apology!
You owe them a big apology!
Sisi Toyin!
-Sisi Toyin!
-Okay.
[Lola's mum] Open the door!
Don't tell me to stop!
Sisi Toyin!
Stop acting like a coward and face me!
Face me! Don't tell me anything.
She better open up this door and face me!
-I know you're upset.
-Let her face me!
[gospel music]
♪ Sing and tell
The world that you are great ♪
♪ Everybody sing ♪
♪ Heavenly blessed, your majesty ♪
♪ Speak of your goodness, all around
This must be a sign ♪
♪ Sing and tell
The world that you are great ♪
♪ Glory, glory to God ♪
♪ Most high ♪
♪ Creation speaks of your wonders ♪
♪ Telling all of whom you are ♪
♪ And by your name we say ♪
♪ Glory to your name forever more ♪
[drum beat sounds]
‪-[chatter]‬
‪-[local drum sounds]‬
‪[inaudible]‬
[local drum sounds]
‪[entourage singing]‬
‪[crowd clapping]‬
‪[singing]‬
[church organ music]
[Pastor] Okay, repeat after me, Ejike.
-This ring, I give you.
-As a demonstration.
-Of my abiding love.
-For you.
[Pastor] Amen.
[congregation cheering]
[Ejikeme] Beautiful.
Repeat after me, Lola.
-This ring, I give you.
As a demonstration of my abiding love.
-For you.
-[crowd clapping]
-[music]
[Pastor] Now they are kissing.
[crowd clapping]
Ohhhh!
-Alright, Mrs. Chukwuemeka.
-Me? [laughs]
Are you ready for this?
I like the way that sounds.
Ms. Ejikeme Chukwuemeka. I am ready,
Forever, always, with you.
-I love you.
-I love you too.
[music]
This is Lagos, the land of dreams.
Did you find yours?
In Lagos you’ve got to know what you want
because a lot can happen in a short time
Not much timeto spend in the city?
Never mind
All you need is just two weeks in Lagos
And you can make all
your dreams come true,
because this is Lagos.
[music]
♪ I hear say you are beautiful ♪
♪ I hear say your body na fire ♪
♪ I hear say you carry gather for waist ♪
♪ You dey kolo for head o ♪
♪ I hear say you follow Don Jazzy ♪
♪ I hear say you carry belle for
Jim Iyke ♪
♪ I hear that you are ♪
♪ I hear you you're a little princess ♪
♪ I hear you ♪
♪ I hear that you like scandal ♪
Subtitled by: Ayomide Otegbayo