When you're really into someone
one kiss is too much
and 20.000 are not enough...
Meet me at the office.
The boss.
Do you know who's that?
Cachito Vigil.
Coach of our Olympic champion
women's hockey team.
A motivator, a pep talker.
I never believed much in pep talks,
I always thought...
the "all together for a common cause"
was kind of a dated slogan...
Until yesterday I kept believing
it was everyman for himself.
But, then a motherfucker
like this one comes
and tells you about the piano.
There're those who play the piano,
those who move the piano...
Did you know, Juan,
that life is like a choir
and everyone is an important piece?
This guy motivated me,
took me to the next level.
To put it in three words,
I saw the light.
Suddenly, he makes two drawings.
Don't look.
So then...
You can look now.
He shows them to us and says:
"What's the difference?"
He asks!
- The smile!
- Or his sadness. Right?
Have you seen your coworkers?
Have you seen them, Juan?
- All sad, Juan. You too.
- Well yes, I'm getting a divorce.
That'd also explain your sloppy look
and lack of punctuality.
Don't let yourself go, Juan. Please.
- How long have you worked here?
- Three years.
I've been here 24 years, Juan.
Come in! Come in!
- Who left these on my desk?
- Guess who!
I did! Come here.
- What's the difference?
- One is...
Don't rush it. Take your time.
Don't say a word, Juan.
Let's see.
- His sadness!
- Ex-cel-lent!
Everyone's sad around here all the time!
- It's a downer!
- Totally!
In his case, he's getting a divorce.
but it's true for the rest!
This guy Cachito is a motherfucker!
He told us about relaxing workplaces.
Like Google, where they have
table tennis and playstations.
Luciana, Juan,
I want you two working together.
I want ideas to make this office
a better place.
- So Juan? It's on?
- Yeah. Sure.
- It's on, Juan, or not?
- Yes. it's on.
- I'm on your side.
- And I'm on yours!
"This time around
You're going to lose it all."
"I'll try to convince you
there's nothing else to wait for."
"This time around
I'd rather do it simpler."
"May the stars stop
sending signals of love."
"Pm going to choose just one
And this is my way of tailing you."
"Or would you rather I slowly
gave you these 20,000 kisses."
'This time around...
You thought about finding a husband."
"The updated version of a good scholar
is no good any more."
"And I this time
thinking about taking you far away."
"Up to the mountain
where even time can't find us."
"Pm going to choose just one
And this is my way of tailing you."
"Or would you rather I slowly
gave you these 20,000 kisses."
Here is some stuff I found...
Anything else you need, just...
Just...
- Just ring and I'll get it.
- Cool.
I still don't get how...
you're not devastated.
I don't know...
- How're you doing?
- I'm about to score with a chick.
But...
There's an issue...
She saw my posh side...
Shaved and wearing a suit.
- Tell me.
- I'd shave to testify...
...at the police station in a murder case.
- A murder case?
- The quick-mart around the corner.
There was a gunfight.
The cashier shot someone.
But this chick
is in another league, Juan.
- Dinner dates?
- Three.
- Laughs?
- Many.
- How many "I'm kidding"?
- None.
- Kisses?
- We start each day with a cheeky...
We end each date with
passionate kissing at her doorstep.
- Intercourse?
- Probably tomorrow.
It's weird anyway...
Every time we went out
I picked the place...
I had to educate myself.
I got recommendations, "Pierino",
"Setebaco", "Bodega 52"...
All very... classy places.
All 5 stars stuff...
I'm out of my element here. Still...
- it's weird...
- I'll be weird when it gets weird.
- How do you know you'll score tomorrow?
- Because she's coming to dine here.
What 5 stars delivery
do you have available?
No delivery.
I'm cooking.
Breaded meat and mashed potatoes.
Her favorite.
- You're cooking?
- Figueroa brings out the chef in me.
It's an easy dish.
- Turn the lights off.
- Sure.
"Happy birthday Claudita...
Happy birthday to you-"
C'mon on, turn it off...
Enough!
I divorced today...
Morning...
"They say inside of you
There are hurricanes without sea."
"Which is so deep
That is has no end."
"That there's a big ship
And that I'm inside."
"Fighting the tides
Singing this song..."
- How long was it?
- Three years with her.
I've been waiting for this moment
for two and a half.
- Cheers!
- Let's make a toast!
Look me at the eyes!
- He's separated.
My humble homage to an artist
who left a lifelong mark on me...
With ideals, with strength,
with courage, with braveness...
A guy who fell and stood up,
fell and stood up...
fell... and you stood up.
The past returning, the future
putting the present at risk...
Pure and sincere love.
To overcome our own limitations.
Think about it, Juan.
Your fears during those three movies.
Once you told me:
"Answers are everywhere".
That's why, on each of these walls,
I pay homage to the films
that marked my life.
Hey, this is really nice.
Are we going out to get pussy
or stay here all night?
- Are you busy?
- Yes.
Okay, let me read you some of the ideas
I came up with.
Juan...
It's so cool that you're a skater!
- Do you ride?
- Yes.
I'm Regular.
- I'm a goofy, very nice to meet you.
- I'm Regular.
Let's ride together one of these days...
Cut the bullshit and do some work.
"Invisible friend", "The crossing light",
"The love trampoline",
"The invisible window," "Where's the
mattress", "Rings, necklaces and pearls",
"3 papers-2 pencils and an rubber",
"Tag", it could be silent or musical tag,
or the inverted tag, "Hop on",
"The potato"...
Well! So many ideas...
- Let me make a note here...
- Please do, Juan.
I want to set the record straight...
I don't want to award myself any merit.
This is all Luciana.
All of them are your ideas.
Okay...
He's stuck at the idea of the divorce
and feels he hasn't contributed...
I see your point, Juan. Back at '89,
when I got my first divorce...
So, let's do something...
Pick three ideas and work on them.
Please.
I need one idea. One more.
One idea.
It's really important for me.
For everyone.
Last night I cried
while watching "Big Fish".
- Have you seen it?
- Yes.
Then that's all I have to say.
- Move your leg!
- Give me water.
In a second.
Here.
Who were you dating?
What was this guy's name?
Tomás, the musician.
- Was he a hit?
- You wouldn't have asked if he did.
- You were the one who liked this show... Curb?
- Yeah, I'm watching several.
- Tell me a bit more.
- About what?
About what you've been doing...
What have you been reading...
Whatever...
What shows you're watching...
I don't know, boss.
I never finished liberal arts...
I work sometimes...
I'm thankful for my folks being loaded,
although the price to pay
is my mom's constant nagging.
"When will I see a grandson?"
The boyfriend, the dog, the house...
So I picture my whole life as a comedy.
Ultra nagging parents,
an ex-boyfriend who ruined my life...
Some friends, cool people...
Like I meet you
waiting for the elevator,
Scene cut, and here we are...
Talking...
What's wrong with you?
Nothing, boss.
Just a pause for the laugh track.
So what's the benefit
of coming up with all that?
Your problem is you over-think it.
It's called "The Andrea Portela Show".
You're either into it or you're not.
Laughs!
In one episode, I arrive,
by mistake, at an event.
It's the annual gala of People's
magazine's 50 most famous.
I'm an outsider,
but I start staring at them all,
I start blurting my thoughts out
without filter.
That one is a homo, she is a dyke...
That one has no talent.
She's got implants and they don't
look good. I play the rebel...
The cool cat.
Do you know how it ends?
Everyone posing.
Me seated next to a nobody...
Clapping, but with a smile.
You're mental, Portela.
Immunity was over.
- Yes, yes.
- And the music is back.
It's a girl's game anyway...
"Wonder boy" and "Pac-land
are girl's games.
- "Boobble, Boobble."
- Yes.
- "Boobble, Boobble" is girl-boy.
- It's not!
- It's a gill's game.
- It's a girl-girl.
Those are all girly. "World Cup",
"Punch Out", those are manly.
Punch Out and it's joysticks...
I liked the black guy on stage 2
who had a resemblance to Apollo Creed.
- "Piston Hurricane"!
- That was his name?
Glass Joe, Piston Hurricane, Bad Bull.
- Very good!
- Bad Bull...
So you and Portela...
Fragala, right?
Portela!
I can't remember which one she was.
Power rack who thought
she was funny. Right?
The one who "some" thought
she was funny.
But she was not funny at all, man!
She had something...
What about you, guys?
I was doing really good
with this chick...
No sex yet... But well headed...
I was working my way past second base.
About three days ago,
we went to the movies,
on the way back we bumped
into a nerdy guy who works with her.
She introduced me as... "A friend".
Take a step back!
Friend zoned!
That's the end of it, boss.
"A friend" never has sex.
"First name" might...
Yeah! "First name" gets you there...
- "Family name" is a sure score.
- Yes!
- "Family name" is kind of pervy...
- Come here, "López"...
Yeah, there is something like...
- "Cute" is a death warrant.
- "Cute" never scores.
- Nickname! "Nickname" gets lucky.
- It depends on the nickname!
- "How are you doing, sir?"
- That's the same as "López".
We're back on the pervy path...
"Boss" is a winner.
"Boss" always gets the job done.
Yeah! That's master level!
So then let's stop using "boss"
among ourselves, dude.
- What's so funny, dude?
- What?
We're in the middle
of a tragedy here, man.
- What? Me? A tragedy?
- But it is a tragedy!
But it's funny, dude!
It's funny seeing myself here.
Two days ago
I couldn't picture myself anywhere.
Do you know where I was two days ago?
Owner's association meeting
at my building. The death star.
Do you remember
the garbage compactor scene?
That was me! Trying to fix my suit,
in a shitty state of mind...
The pits!
Now this is another galaxy!
This is Dagoba.
Yoda is here...
The bugs, my friends...
I'm taking out the ship
with my mind now.
- Get it?
- Cool!
You know what man?
Any chick I have to date,
...has to understand this.
- You farted, dude!
- No way!
- You farted, man!
- Get out of here!
- Portela?
- Goldstein.
- You farted in the square!
- Stop!
- Who is it?
- Goldstein!
Tell that motherfucker to text me back!
- Hey, Goldstein!
- Juan.
I crashed and burned
with Figueroa, Juan.
Then it was not going so well...
I thought it was...
I did everything right.
All I didn't do before.
Combed my hear, trimmed my beard...
The minute she stepped inside
I had to start working her.
- Really!
- I saw a shadow park on her face.
The shadow of doubt, boss.
She must have thought I had a crib,
one of those with a cool kitchen.
Since I have no idea what happened
I left something prepared.
Okay. I'm on my way.
I didn't touch a thing.
The untainted crime scene.
It looks like Martin Luther King's
untouched breakfast.
Okay... Let's see what we can read here.
- Tell me a bit more.
- I don't know what to tell you.
I was doing three things at once.
Cooking, entertaining...
...and working her.
- What did she bring?
- Nothing.
- She used this one.
- Nice.
She'd told me she liked singing, so
I downloaded some Rafaela Carrá songs.
- Did she sing?
- Yes. "Pedro Pe".
"The best of all Santa Fe".
- How much did you drink?
- Just that. Not much.
- Did she eat?
- Only a bite.
The worst breaded meat ever...
- How did she leave?
- Walking. I walked her.
- Why did you walk her?
- She lives seven blocks away.
Too close to take a taxi,
too far to let her go by herself.
The odd thing is,
when I was coming back home...
I zigzagged across an entire block.
Along Corrientes, from Pringles to Yatay.
- You zigzagged?
- Not an ounce of booze in my system...
You weren't drunk.
She gave me...
a kiss, and told me...
"Take Corrientes, it's safer".
- How was that kiss?
- A quick one, no tongue.
This quick?
No, it was rather like this.
She told me:
"Take Corrientes, it's safer."
And she gave me a last kiss.
- She gave you Freddo's kiss.
- Exactly!
The death kiss.
- How many glasses did she drink?
- Just that one.
- How many previous dates?
- Three.
- You always treated before?
- Yes.
Okay...
So you were...
Two dates away from her
peeing with the door open.
You said she brought nothing
and you always treated.
From that we can figure out
she thinks of the man as a provider.
You felt she had you
doing the hard work...
And then she filled your house
with signals. For example:
The glass. Her glass!
She probably took just one or two sips.
But left it very near the edge.
This shows... Insecurity...
Or a tragedy about to happen.
The napkin! Folded as if she hadn't
ever used it. As if she hadn't been here.
What about her singing?
- She wouldn't have sung if uncomfortable.
- Vanity.
Vanity!
That woman has no feelings.
She had you working,
but it was she who quit.
That woman wants to be maintained.
Probably to fulfill any of her whims,
being such an unfulfilled woman. Like gym.
That woman doesn't fuck!
She makes love.
That woman doesn't surrender her secret
because she simply doesn't have one.
And the same way she involuntary
left all these signals...
she also left another one...
One that defines her even more.
She also left another one...
Today you're disconcerted.
Something clicked inside of me.
I still can't understand what.
Figueroa is just like this mark.
This mark that is no longer here...
and her, who surrendered
a long time ago.
We missed you, Juan.
"Everything you find."
"Makes you surprise."
"The world is so wonderful
"Your eyes let you see it."
"And what's left of me?"
"If I doubt even with my heart."
"I must shout."
"That Pm a wizard."
"The 'mambo' genius.
who no one can beat at dancing."
The apartment is nice.
Kind of small, but nice.
It has a small balcony...
It's okay!
What do you want me to tell you, mom?
Let's dine and I'll explain...
We'll be more relaxed.
No mom! I'm fine.
Can you understand that?
I don't need a setup. I'm fine.
Do you want me to be okay?
"I wish I knew."
"What you say about me."
"When I'm not at your side."
"That makes you love me even more."
"And what's left of me."
"If I doubt even with my heart."
"I must yell."
"That Pm a wizard."
'The "mambo" genius,
who no one can beat at dancing."
We've to come up
with something more solid, dude...
The silent tag!
Yes! Running around the office...
Is an icebreaker,
we'll get more relaxed.
The office looks
like a school playground.
I don't really see it.
- No.
- It's done!
- I'll bring bags of ice.
- Bags of ice? What for?
What do you mean "what for", Juan?
For the presentation! What else?
To break the ice.
Totally! I forgot to mention
the "Musical Tutti Frutti"!
- Did I mention it?
- Listen. I have to go in here.
You know what?
I think Big Fish is the clue...
- You should think on that.
- You're kind of sleek guy...
But does he mean the movie?
Actual fishing?
Listen, I don't want to be rude.
I just don't think it's worth
the extra hours after work.
This isn't school homework.
- Okay. Are you upset for your divorce?
- It's not the divorce.
- You're not?
- No.
- What are you looking for?
- A colander...
This is nice.
- "Kneel".
- What?
"Kneel", Juan!
- Don't you know the game?
- No, I don't.
It's the same as the chairs game.
Only without chairs.
And without music.
Someone says: "kneel".
Everyone has to kneel
no matter what they're doing.
We can switch leaders every hour
and play it in the office.
It's nice... the colander...
Right? I like it...
- I'm your father... I'm your father...
- Give it back! I'm buying it.
Hold it.
- Hey!
- It works perfectly. Excuse me!
Hi. We're taking this one.
Can you gift wrap it?
- Your turn.
- Close City reactor control.
-250.
- Here's the cash.
- Come to daddy.
- He's about to brake his record. Will he?
Oh, no!
Can you turn
that fucking cell phone, Juan?
- I told you. She is a sex addict.
- Is Goldstein coming?
Goldstein is driven
by his new obsession...
Corrientes Street,
between Pringles and Yatay.
- Oh, what the fuck...
- Some bullshit about a romantic zigzag.
Hello!
I haven't make up my mind yet.
It's a weekend.
Can we talk on Monday?
A brainstorming breakfast?
Aren't you taking this too seriously?
No, you do it and then let me know.
Okay.
- Talk!
- And speak the truth.
- It's a work related call.
- Hold it there! Boss!
Where is Portela?
Argentine? Spain? Thailand?
Is she alive? Giving input?
Paying taxes? Doing Pilates?
She is only a fuck buddy. Although
she said she wanted to go out to dinner.
She actually pronounced the words?
- She mentioned it.
- Not the same thing.
She'd be the ideal woman if it weren't
that she is not the ideal woman.
Only that's the one
who thinks she is funny.
You're not bringing her
here again, Juan.
She's the one who says:
"I stop talking and here comes laughter".
She lives in French and Berutti, boss.
Luciana Portela...
She is not Luciana!
Which one is Luciana?
Luciana is the one who works with me.
Mommy's girl from the south.
Tag girl!
- It's a record! It's a record!
- Did you make love to her?
"Made love"? When did you start
talking like that, dude?
Did you make love to her?
Turn that fucking cell
off once and for all!
No! You listen to me!
Write down my email.
Email me.
Juanmarvel@gmail.
Okay.
Twins that don't look alike?
Isn't it scientifically impossible?
Not sure. That's the way
they introduced themselves.
The title rings a bell anyway...
- What was her name?
- Melina.
Melina?
And her sister?
I don't know. I barely remember Melina.
I was only 14.
- I don't know...
- Melina...
Melina...
Melina had sort of a crush on me.
But nothing ever happened.
Soledad.
Sole?
- Sole?
- Yes. I couldn't tell...
Oh no, dude! No!
We'd already made plans...
- I can't believe it, man!
- It's done.
Okay. It's all good.
Easy. Relax.
You're looking good.
I'd rather look good than feel good.
Hello!
What Melina? What Soledad?
Oh yeah! Come in.
- Welcome!
- Hi!
Come in. Goldstein,
a good friend. Meli...
- Sole.
- Sole, Goldstein.
- How are you doing?
- Good!
- Have a sit and a drink...
- I can't remember when you called...
This is not working...
- I have a game for you.
- Oh! The player!
- Do you remember? These two are crazy.
- Totally! I remember now.
- I didn't remember...
- Let me guess...
- You're coming up with it just now.
- I'm still thinking the last details.
Look at him!
He's on a journey right now...
Juan is on a journey
to his most glorious past.
When he was 14.
The "game master" we used to call him.
I can see you coming up with a new game.
You motherfucker.
You're there...
You were so cute, Juan.
The creator of "The shower test"...
now presents...
So a couple of days ago,
my friend Goldstein was heartbroken.
C'mon, dude!
And since this is a reunion for me also,
I worry...
and try to think what's best
to help him.
So I guess maybe it's going out
and meeting new people...
- That might be...
- No new people.
So, to the question
of what might salvage this night
- A double answer appeared.
- The double answer.
So what's the double answer?
Whatever works for Goldstein
has to work for us four.
And for the night.
What would work for Goldstein,
for us and for the night also?
Such a long question
doesn't deserve a short answer...
This is how the story goes.
Each one of you has to pick a name.
Men have to pick
between Héctor and Osvaldo.
Women, between Liliana and Graciela.
These four names
live in a parallel world.
And are waiting for four bodies
to come alive.
In this parallel world,
there's a safe mode to play this game.
- Please allow me.
- Explain.
In this parallel world, Liliana
and Graciela go to different rooms.
In this parallel world
there's a kitchen,
where Héctor and Osvaldo
wait for 5 minutes.
Who would have said! Your parallel world
is very much like this apartment.
From then on, we have 15 minutes.
- Turning the light on is forbidden.
- Totally forbidden.
That's the only forbidden thing
in the parallel world.
After the first 15 minutes,
Goldstein shouts...
- Fifteen!
- That's when the men switch rooms.
After a new 15 minutes,
Goldstein shouts...
- Fifteen.
- It's then that we gather here and debate.
Those 15 minutes in the dark
mean absolute freedom.
- Anything can happen.
- Have you played it before?
- Of course not. He just came up with it.
- Maybe we did.
The thing is, whatever happens
in the parallel world...
Stays in the parallel world.
Is this your way of proposing an orgy?
You call me after God knows how long,
just to get into a foursome
with my sister and I?
- Are you for real?
- You're missing the point...
Listen, I loved getting your call...
I really did.
I missed you all this time.
And all you wanted was...
The truth is I look at you,
and don't know who I am.
- I mean, don't know who you are.
- Let it go, sis...
- Thank you for this awful night...
- Melina?
Here.
A bit of magic.
- Here.
- "Kneel", Juan.
It's the best choice.
Give it some thought.
- It could be a lot of fun.
- A whole day with that?
- I think it's too much.
- But that's the thing, Juan!
If we only play it for a while,
it's a downer.
But if we play it for...
say ten hours!
Or eleven, or twelve
and 35 minutes and a half.
We're going to have a blast.
I still don't get it.
Check that.
- Poor guy!
- Terrible! That guy's sweater is terrible.
If I ever see you in a sweater like that
I'd fucking kill you.
- Did you bring salt?
- No.
That's good!
I dated for two years
with a guy that loved salt.
- He loved salt?
- He didn't just loved it.
He was a salt fanatic.
On our second date,
he took me to dine...
When I came back from the WC
the guy'd opened seven salt envelopes.
He had a pile of salt on the table
and was licking it with his fingertip.
When I marry, one of my dreams
is to re-enact the way I met my boyfriend.
Really?
How's that?
Like I tell it.
We both play our roles.
- You have to know the fairies...
- The fairies?
Yes, Juan! The Banfield fairies.
My friends.
They're really cool. Although...
They always get it wrong with boys.
Always.
Do you know who I have a crush on?
Arum?
w'.
Iv"?
- Yes! "V"! I have a crush on
I love "V".
I'm mad in love with "V"!
Even though I've never seen his face.
It's better this way? Right?
Just think about it.
I can...
Just get whoever I like and put him
inside of V. Put his mask on.
There you have. The two men
I like most together in one.
- It's the perfect man.
- Oh! Are you talking about V?
V of Vendetta?
The Comic by Alan Moore?
No... Yes!
I don't know who's it is.
- What are you doing today?
- I don't know yet.
Okay...
Do you dare come to Banfield?
Right now driving for an hour already.
We're going fucking somewhere with Juan.
This is bullshit!
Where are we going?
- To Banfield.
- Motherfucking Banfield!
- When are we getting there?
- I don't know...
- Who're we meeting?
- Luciana...
Cut the crap, man!
I think Luciana's.
Someone from work.
Juan's fucking secretary.
Yes...
So?
- Apparently she's got friends.
- She's got friends.
- Hold on. Who are them?
- She calls them "the fairies".
She...
Hold on. Let me call you back.
- Cut the crap, Juan. What "fairies"?
- "The Banfield Fairies".
- What "fairies", Juan?
- That's what she calls them!
- But how many are them?
- I don't know. Many.
- Call them then, I'm fucking lost.
- Okay...
- Chill out, man!
- But I've been driving for an hour!
My head is going to blow up!
I can't believe
the things I do for you, Juan.
- I'm calling now.
- Is it ringing?
Yeah, it's ringing.
Hey, Luciana!
- Give it to me!
- Hold on!
- We're lost.
- I'm not lost.
We just went by "Veneciana".
- Make a left here!
- Where?
Make a left now!
- See ya!
- Can't you see my signal?
- This one here.
- This one, Juan?
- Yes! This one!
- Okay.
- Lock your door.
- Okay...
- Lock your door!
- Yeah!
What are you doing, Nico?
Nico!
- What are you doing?
- You let me do it my way!
Johnny!
- How are you?
- Good!
- Your friend?
- Hey there!
- "Movie Buff", Luciana.
- Hi Luciana.
- Fine and you?
- Fine. What a nice house!
Super nice!
Mom!
This is Juan,
and his friend, Movie Buff.
- Good evening.
- Hi, nice to meet you.
Good evening.
Nice to meet you.
Allow me to tell you.
I can smell the peace inside this house.
And I can see it too.
As I witness, how you two share your mate.
Our Argentine heritage.
I took the liberty
of bringing this box full of candy...
Since I'm on the candy
distribution business.
- You shouldn't have bothered.
- Please. Help yourselves.
There they are...
Do it again. Do it again!
Kneel!
Kneel, you moron!
So, this are Juan and Movie Buff.
- Hello.
- She is Maru, the brown fairy.
Euge, the green fairy.
Romi, the pink fairy.
And Ari.
It's called "The Human Misery".
I want to make a short film
based on a game I was told about.
- We can all play a role!
- I want to be in it!
It's like role playing.
One plays the policeman...
Another is the killer,
the rest are victims.
The policeman needs to catch the killer,
before he kills his victims.
You play seated
and looking into each other's eyes.
You uncover the killer
by making questions.
The game is basically that.
I don't know why, but I have the feeling
it could be a good short movie.
- Yeah! Definitely!
- Let's all be a part of it.
I think mystery is a good-
I've never played it.
So I thought we could play it now.
- Yeah!
- Yes!
- Now! Now!
- Wait a second!
Are you telling me you want to make
a short film based on a game?
A game you never played?
Why don't you explain it to me?
It's like role game.
One plays the policeman.
Another plays the killer.
The rest are victims.
The policeman...
- The policeman?
- The policeman...
has to uncover the killer
before he kills his victims.
You play seated
and staring into each other's eyes.
You uncover the killer
by asking questions.
That's basically it.
I don't know why, but I have the feeling
it could be a good short movie.
- Totally.
- Yes. I'm totally sold.
Since I never played it,
I thought we could play it now.
It's excellent!
This is excellent.
- You need a bit of acting.
- Yes! We can all act!
If acting is required...
Movie Buff here...
Is an excellent retired actor...
- You're famous!
- Your face looked familiar...
Yeah! I thought I knew you
from somewhere.
Movie Buff had a one-man show
about Jim Morrison's last 48 hours.
"Who?
- Morrison's.
- Such a great actor.
To get in the mood, he used
to stand on his hands for half an hour.
- Really!
- C'mon!
It's true! I did.
- The play ended with Morrison dying-
- Who is Morrison?
- I didn't dare ask!
- Oh, sory!
- C'mon, Juan.
- Sorry...
I can't believe
you don't know who Morrison is.
The Doors? The band?
The Doors' front man?
He's knows too much about music!
Why don't you do
a part of the show for us?
- No, no!
- C'mon!
You dare do it in front
of three thousand and not six?
- C'mon!
- Okay.
Morrisey! Morrisey!
Nico, the Film Buff presents...
Morrison! His last hours.
At this moment my mind roams
the territory of the unknown.
Nevertheless they seem close.
The pigs.
The blood suckers.
The hookers, the thieves,
the blow, the shit.
An unstoppable feeling...
A light at the end of the road
guides me.
I realize that light is actually...
the end.
And the end is...
perhaps...
my only friend.
The end.
Excellent!
I have to say you were right, Juan.
- About?
- Tonight.
A while ago
tonight was a night to forget,
almost like that night
when we didn't have any water.
Suddenly this night is unforgettable.
The best night
in probably the last six months.
One of the top three for this year...
And Morrison...
Let's talk about Morrison
and about what happened to me.
The way I connected with the material,
the things I felt...
How everything flowed...
The way it makes me think...
About my friends, about what I do...
About...
Money and all material things...
The things that happen to me.
How I can't usually be the contrary...
To be in touch
with so many more things...
Luciana's family!
Let's talk about her family.
Extraordinary!
I mean: Extra-ordinary!
Meaning... more than ordinary!
And the fairies!
Let's talk about the fairies...
I know they're young...
That they have small titties...
That they're missing pubes...
But there's a reality
we need to discuss.
These girls want to fuck...
And I want to fuck.
If they want it and I want it,
we sit down, discuss it and do it. Period.
There's no sense in arguing...
HOW TO GIVE 20,000 KISSES
We only need to choose one.
We'll get along...
Juan.
Juan!
- Juan!
- Eow!
Beware of this girl.
I can't really get used
to the idea anyway.
Do you really think An'
will really make that short movie?
Of course!
Nowadays anyone can shoot.
Just get a decent image, build a couple
of plot-lines, add some narrative...
It still works, doesn't it!
- It still works. Morrison.
- Yeah! They were all hooked.
It's amazing!
I keep doing it as time goes by...
The audience is moved, I touch them.
The girls were all focused, watching...
I still need to fine tune
the summersault at the beginning maybe...
I drew a conclusion tonight, Juan.
Can I tell you something?
- You and Luciana are imminent.
- You think so?
- What's up?
- Fine.
- Was nice another day, isn't?
- Yes, was awesome!
Yes, What's about "the fairies"?
They're awesome.
You all seem like one.
Totally!
It's like the best qualities of each...
fuse into only one
and it seems the four of us make one.
Like Voltron.
Exactly! Like Voltron.
But you're the head.
I am?
- What about Ari?
- He's cool.
Cool? Ari is awesome!
It's like he's almost our best friend.
Besides... Can I tell you something?
I think he likes Euge.
He's a guy anyway.
He likes whoever likes him back.
He's changing all the time.
He is a good guy anyway.
He's a really nice guy.
I hope he makes the short movie.
It'd be fun.
Besides I...
Sort of I like acting.
Not professionally though.
- Did you know I wrote a story?
- Did you have a black book also?
No, I had a book were I used to write...
Stories, poems. They all sucked.
Eventually I stopped.
I also have a notebook
where I write poetry.
Really?
- I want to read it.
- No! No way.
What's your story about?
It might be usable
to do a short movie...
- A very amateur one...
- Totally!
- Lucy... In the sky with diamonds...
- How are you doing, mister?
- How are you guys doing?
- Just chatting with Johnny.
- Do you have plans for tonight?
- Not much.
But it doesn't mean
I'll agree to anything, anyway.
- Tell her.
- Let's hear it.
If you're in the mood,
we'll be at home.
Drinks... Music...
And if you're into it... Brownies!
We're going to sing a couple of songs...
Laguerra here,
is a killer guitar player.
I like it. Count on me.
Wanna come?
- Bring a couple of friends.
- Relax... Relax, okay?
I'll see what I can get.
They're so cute, right?
Now I want to love you...
till the end...
- Julieta!
- So?
- Thinner...
Very good!
The Office band is very good!
Hang in there... I have an idea.
Follow my lead.
So girls, do you know the game called
"The merry-go-round of love"?
No.
It's simple.
Each guy gets into one of the rooms.
Every girl then randomly
gets inside a room.
There we stay
until the girl gets tired, since...
only the girls can get tired.
They decide whether they stay or go,
us boys are slaves to your wishes.
When any girl is tired, she gets out of the room,
and gets inside the next room.
The girl in that room has to inevitably get out,
and head to another room.
And that's the way
the merry-go-round of love starts turning.
And what do you do in the room?
Whatever both of them want.
Talking.
Kissing, or nothing at all.
Way to go Juan.
I had you for an ass, but...
- How many rooms are there?
- Three.
- Three plus a bathroom?
- Yes.
Come in!
- Thank God!
- Really?
I was cool
with the fairies coming anyway.
- Really?
- Yes.
- How's that?
- Maybe...
Maybe what?
Maybe Laguerra was in the race...
Well, I don't know!
Not sure what I'd do
if Laguerra was in the race...
Who would've thought...
Remember about the short movie
I told you today?
- The short movie...
- Yes. What about it?
- I'll do it.
- Really?
- Yes. It's cool.
- Totally!
So... Would you like to be a part of it?
- Me?
- You.
- You mean me?
No!
- Really? How?
- Yes.
Well... You'd be the star!
Totally! Oh! I'm so happy!
I love it!
Thanks!
It's what I've always wanted!
I've always wanted
to act in a short movie.
I need to...
Wow!
Come in.
I have to apologize.
- I hope you don't blacklist me.
- Never, boss.
I want you to know this in-service I took
was the worst thing I've done ever.
It took me into
an over awareness state...
I feel bad all the time.
I see everyone sad, bored...
Tense...
But actually... It's really me.
It's me who...
This guy Cachito...
has you believing
everything is possible...
- When it really isn't.
- Don't feel that way, boss!
I feel anyway I fucking want to, Juan.
I'm sorry if I'm being blunt, Juan.
Here...
See these?
Remember these?
It's over!
Enough with the games.
Enough with originality.
When I was a kid...
I liked locking myself up in my room.
I grabbed the bottle of cologne...
I always liked to sing...
So we're going to start
the "Karaoke Casual Fridays".
And we're all going to sing.
We're all going to sing!
- So, Juan? Are you in the mood?
- Yes, I'm in the mood.
Juan is in the mood!
- What are you doing here?
- I don't know. I like it.
It's my favorite place in the office.
Hey...
I thought he'd like the "Kneel" game.
I thought we were
right on track but no...
- Will you let me come up with a rematch?
- Maybe we can go out this weekend?
- Would go come to Banfield?
- Yes.
Why not?
I can't make it this weekend anyway.
I have a ton of things to do.
My mind is going to blow up.
- So, I'll go.
- Hold on.
I want to give you something.
It's the story.
For the short movie.
I want your opinion.
- Okay. Bye.
- Bye.
Hello everyone.
What a night!
Good! That's what I want to hear!
It's not working.
The phrase
any girl doesn't want to hear.
Right? I bet it's not
the first time, darling.
You there, looking away.
"It's the first time this happens to me".
Don't pay attention to what
the MC said about me, I'm no diva.
Clearly I wouldn't be here light now
if I were a diva...
My name wouldn't be
Andrea Portela either...
I'd have a star name,
something similar to Gwyneth...
Or a very fancy family name.
So, today I left home as usual,
and almost got run down
by a kid in his skate.
Death by a skater running you down...
Is one of the saddest things
that can happen to you, isn't it?
Obviously upset, I yelled at him:
"You motherfucking brat!"
The kid stops,
turns around and looks at me.
A guy in his forties!
The jackass grabs his skate,
puts it under his arm,
he thinks he looks really cool,
approaches me and asks me on a date.
I look at him and ask him:
"So you'll take me to dinner
on your skate!"
I know the kind!
These are kids inside a grownup's body.
If they see you with some other guy
they throw a fit and question you.
But not with me, darling.
If you want the trendy skater shoes,
if you want your trunks
and your cap and skate,
you don't want me naked, darling!
You want a teenager.
A teenager that by the time she grows up,
is going to kick your ass so hard,
that you're going to need your skate
as a walker, darling!
Your ass will be so sore
that you won't be able to sit, you moron!
Go to kid-land, go to teenage-land...
Go to get-lucky-land!
Thank you! Good evening!
Go fuck yourself, motherfuckers!
Thank you for coming!
Evening! Thank you for coming...
How many couples...
You didn't have any better things to do?
And you're here all alone...
So, I was saying...
For some time now, I've been...
in a weird mood.
I don't know...
I'm kind of dizzy...
Luciana,
the girl who works with me...
Is totally different from me.
Nevertheless...
There's something about her...
That...
I can't read her.
I'm baffled.
I just can't...
She's totally different.
I think I...
I'm really into her.
Is it good?
You're crazy!
I'm crazy about you.
How?
I came to tell you this.
It was an impulse.
I made all the trip to tell you...
I don't think...
I'm crazy about you.
In the most complete sense of the word.
I came to tell you that.
I came to tell you that...
That any difference we may have...
...are the things that attract me to you.
I don't know...
You're... You're a riddle.
A riddle?
- Yes, look, before...
- Before your divorce?
Before my divorce.
I was living with a missus.
My life was monotonous, plain, linear.
Doing the dishes
was just doing the dishes...
Sleeping was just sleeping.
Eating out was just eating out.
Do you get it?
Nothing was an adventure...
I started to get desperate.
I started to say to myself:
"This isn't what you want".
"You're not doing yourself any good."
And...
One thinks he knows what he wants.
Until you come along.
Now I know even less than before.
But there's one thing I know.
You.
What you're telling me is so nice!
No one ever talked to me
like that before.
I don't know what else to say to you.
You don't have to tell me anything...
I felt the need.
I came here to tell you...
That's it.
Did you read the story?
I fell for a dumb-ass!
- Why? What happened?
- I don't know.
I don't know what happened,
but it's happening right now.
The Movie Buff warned me
and I didn't pay attention...
She is out of her mind!
I can't believe I have a crush on a girl
who doesn't know who Morrison is!
That unfinished kiss was a mind twister.
It infected my brain.
She is the opposite of Portela,
of the missus...
- Melina...
- No, it's not Melina.
- So there was an unfinished kiss?
- Yes.
What kind of kiss?
Like this?
No. Like this.
Wanna go for a walk?
So...
I took Corrientes on my way back...
Zigzagging...
True. You told me. Here.
I was clean at that time.
Specifically that night.
I hadn't used any.
A sip of wine only.
But I was zigzagging...
Really bad!
Right about here... I felt...
I mean, I know this street by heart.
I've walked it...
A thousand...
A thousand times that night!
As if...
The answer was somewhere...
Along this path. Understand me?
It's simple.
The only night I zigzagged...
was when I suited up.
- That's it.
- I wasn't myself.
Figueroa was an iceberg anyway,
but I have no argument because,
I didn't give her the chance
to meet the real Goldstein.
- The one who she loved.
- Was not me.
You remember.
Obviously.
It doesn't matter
if you fell for a dumb-ass.
if the girl you like
doesn't know who Morrison is.
That's not what matters.
Because in the end, the fact that she
doesn't know is what you might love.
But, never suit up.
Relationships are just what they are.
We can't ask them
to be any more or any less.
Or to be something they're not.
Because that leads to frustration.
We fear the ephemeral.
Do you understand?
And that's what makes us
search in every girl...
...for the love of our life.
How long have
we've been zigzagging, Goldstein?
Sometimes I feel the city is...
Like my house backyard.
Have I ever told you that?
- Not once.
- Toss it!
- You say they're coming for us?
- Toss it away!
Toss it away, man!
C'mon!
Run: man! Run!
Thanks, Lore...
Ernesto!
Figueroa!
Juan, a friend.
- Nice to meet you.
- Nice to meet you. Lorena, a friend.
Nice to meet you.
Bye!
Let's go.
"A friend told me
I'd find her some day."
"in a fashion shop
At the soda fountain."
"Dressed in wool gloves
and high heels."
"With a giant beside
Holding a miracle in her hand."
"He said some day
I was going to learn."
"That I can't touch
what I can't hug."
"it doesn't matter. I walked.
I thought. I decided to imagine."
"A silent mermaid
A mountain of enchantment."
"A cramp in my leg
makes me doubt."
"That my mermaid lives in the water
That mountains are not real."
"The cramp goes away,
I stretch and start to think."
'That I can't hug
what I can't touch."
"A dog barks at his owner
and bites his overcoat."
"And I get really sad
Even it's not my dog."
"This dog is like my dreams
and I'm the owner."
"Like a dog with no owner
Like the owner of the dream."
"I fall asleep thinking of mermaids
and start dreaming."
"That it's not convenient to dream
about what I can't touch."
Lu! Make it a little bigger, happier.
- Perfect! Camera?
- Rolling!
- Sound!
- Mark it!
- Scene 14, take 5!
Action!
Cut! It's a wrap!
"In the middle of horrible worlds
I meet her."
"Dancing a furious Mambo
A rhythm arrow."
"She pulls my bow tie,
I put on shoes and a tuxedo."
"I turn into Sinatra...
Into Captain Scarlet."
"I hug her hard
and in silence start to explain."
"That it's not convenient to dream
With what I can't hug."
This is what happened.
We finished the shoot
and went to a cosplay party.
It seemed like the perfect night...
Laughter, beer, dancing, joy...
It was great.
Luciana...
...was beautiful.
I felt that was the night.
Nico felt it too.
Is it me or this is the night, Nico?
Haven't I told you a thousand times
that you and Luciana are imminent?
Yes, man! Just corner her!
Tell her: "You're under arrest!"
You're the Lone Ranger, steal her heart!
Give her all your love.
Look her in the eyes.
You'll have her falling for you
in a second.
Do you get me?
Give me a hug.
But pay attention to her.
Look at her. Smile at her.
To infinity... and beyond!
At one point...
I was dancing...
and I started to feel alone.
There was no one around me.
And...
Suddenly I see Nico arrive...
His face pale.
And I ask him.
How long was the kiss?
"The world ends."
"And I wonder."
"If you..."
"Are aware."
"That I need,
to come back."
"There's no time anymore."
"To argue."
"No, there's no more time."
"Not even to lie."
"No more..."
"If I'm from heaven."
"And you're from the sea
We'll sure..."
"We'll explode..."
"We'll be the cause
Of a new Big Bang..."
"You and I."
Eight hundred bucks, man!
What the fuck!
Stop the car, Nico.
C'mon. Stop it.
Stop the car.
- I want to walk.
- Hey, Juan! Where're you going?
- So...
- Hey!
I know that guy.
- Hello.
- I know why you're there.
- You're about to take a decision.
- I don't know.
Could it be that the night
you proposed... the orgy...
That was just a game!
That night,
you didn't get to learn...
You were in front
of a professional baseball player.
What does that have to do
with anything?
Hold this for a second.
So you have a bit of magic too.
NO ONE FORGETS YOU
JUST LIKE THAT
By Juan
Subtitle ripped and corrected by luqui89
www.Clan-Sudamerica.net