Well, l'm off.
Everything alright, honey?
Yes.
l'll call you later.
Spaniards...
Franco... is dead.
My leaving
is of more benefit to Spain
than my remaining as president.
And I do not wish a democratic
system of coexistence
to be once again a parenthesis
in the history of Spain.
...and send them before closing.
Fine, we'll get to it then.
-What are you smoking?
-Pall Mall.
Pall Mall?
Where'd you get them from?
Testing, testing...
And you'll change your vote.
l assure you, that won't happen.
Since he resigned,
he hasn't been seen here.
And just when it comes time to vote,
he turns up.
Congress is in session.
This plenary session
has come together, as set out
in Article 99 of the Constitution,
to submit to a second vote
the proposal of the candidate
for President of the Government
as Leopoldo Calvo Sotelo.
Next, the proposal of
the candidate for President,
Leopoldo Calvo Sotelo,
who will take the podium
to again request
a vote from the Chamber.
17:41 MADRlD
JUNTA OF THE CHlEFS OF STAFF
At your orders, General.
Ladies and gentlemen of this Congress,
l take this podium
only to confirm what l said
in my investiture speech
and in the subsequent debate
to thank all parliamentary groups
for their contributions
and to ask the Chamber again
for the vote of confidence
according to Article 99
of the Constitution.
Thank you.
Yes?
Yes. Everything as planned.
You can locate me in Zarzuela,
as of 7 o'clock.
You know the King is changeable,
and even though he backs this,
l'd rather be with him,
in the Palace.
l don't trust Sabino.
Yes.
For any truly pressing matters,
call me there.
Gentlemen,
from now on there's no hesitation.
ARMY HQ
Orders will come at any moment.
Excuse me.
Yes?
-Pedro, I'm very worried.
-Why?
Damn. Because it's 57 past exactly.
The distance from my ''estate'',
worked out this morning,
was close to 1 hour.
But the ''foreman'' was going to
tell you when he was leaving.
l was told the ''variation''
would be at 25 past.
-At 25 past!
-So ends the contribution
from the Andalusian group.
Next, the President of the Chamber
will hand over to...
Sir, lgnacio and Miguel
await you on the court.
Good.
And don't forget that around 8
Landelino is coming
for the signing of the appointment.
Don't worry,
l'll finish them off quickly.
Especially Miguel,
he's got a weak serve.
...the most powerful sectors
of this country's oligarchy,
a policy that opposes
the interests...
Right.
You know what you have to do.
There's even a segment that says,
''We must turn round and go back''.
And another part of public opinion,
the majority in my judgement,
believes that little has been done,
little progress has been made,
that the structure of the State
must be changed.
General, Carres calculates
that they'll arrive at 25 past.
The vote will commence
with Deputy 114,
Antonio Garcia Miralles.
l'll go in first.
Bovis, stay in the courtyard,
with those on the first bus.
Vecinos, take the podium.
You know what to do.
Corthay, you come inside with me.
Gentlemen.
Guards!
This is in the name of the King!
For Spain.
-Long live Spain!
-Hurrah!
Santiago Carrillo Solares.
Nay.
C'mon, c'mon!
-Faustino Munoz Garcia.
-Aye.
Let's go! Let's go.
-Cipriano Garcia Rollan.
-Nay.
-Alfonso Guerra Gonzalez.
Take it easy, officer.
-Out of the way!
-Stop right there!
-Where are you going?
-Out of the way.
Halt!
By order of the King
and Valencian HQ,
we're taking over Congress.
Take it easy...
-For your own good.
-Armoured is about to arrive.
-Freeze!
-Stay right there.
-For the King!
-For Spain!
-Out of the way!
-Stop! Stop!
Out of the way!
Halt, you can't go past.
Get to one side.
C'mon, c'mon!
Victor Zero! Attention, Victor Zero!
A group of Civil Guards...
Put that away.
Whose side are you on?
-Pedro.
-Aye.
Enrique Mugica Herzog.
Nay.
-What is this? What do you want?
-On the floor!
-l'm Commissioner Oria.
-l said, on the floor!
On the floor!
-Everyone hold it! On the floor!
-On the floor!
Go up there.
My men, with me. Move it!
-Carlos Navarrete Merino.
-Nay.
On the floor!
Manuel Nunez Encabo.
Guards!
On the floor l said.
Guard, no one is to move.
A loud noise
has just been heard
in the Chamber.
We don't know what it was because...
One can see the police.
The Civil Guard is entering.
Everyone stay put!
Where are you going, Manolo?
Sit down.
-Who's your leader?
-Sit down, Deputy.
-Who's giving you orders?
-l told you to sit.
-Halt!
-Sit down!
l order you to hand over that gun!
Leave him alone!
Every stay put! On the floor!
Cease fire! Hold it!
Hold it!
You're going to hit one of ours!
Unplug that camera! Unplug it!
Give it to him!
On the floor! And stay put!
Sit down!
Go back to your place.
-l order you to be quiet, Captain.
-Sit down!
Shut up!
-Manolo, sit down.
-Sit down!
Leave him alone!
Manolo, please sit down.
Sit down.
Sabino, have you been listening
to the radio?
Yes, come up, please.
Put me through to State Security.
lt's only a charity event
for widows and orphans.
Perhaps you, Armada,
with your influence over the King,
could slip him a word.
Of course, General.
lf l may, General...
There are shots in Congress.
Shots? What do you mean?
lt's on the radio.
Some Civil Guards came in shooting.
lt looks like an assault.
Good God.
Olivenza, go straight to Congress.
Keep me informed.
Yes, sir!
Yes, Guillermo.
Yes, l heard.
Excuse me. Armada...
l'm leaving for Zarzuela, General.
l think right now,
my duty is by the King's side.
No, Armada. l need you here.
lf this is what l think it is,
we'll have to act under one command.
Yes, Guillermo.
l'll call you back.
Yes?
This is shameful, Alfonso.
What a terrible country.
Are they going to keep us
on the floor like rats all night?
Come on!
Keep your hands in sight!
Your little hands
where l can see them!
Everyone!
Everyone! You too!
And you! Get those hands higher.
l can't see them!
Just a moment.
Sir, State Security.
Laina, what's going on?
ls anyone hurt?
Just a moment. You see to it.
l can't now. Call back in 5 minutes.
Gentlemen, no personal calls.
We need the lines open.
Get my diary from my office.
And get Maria to make coffee.
You know what you have to do.
Please, talk to the deputies,
calm them down.
Excuse me, given the circumstances,
l refuse to exercise the presidency.
...highly disturbed by events...
What did you hear? A colonel?
They said, a lieutenant colonel.
Then the sound of gunfire.
...15 minutes later
Vice-President Calvo Sotelo,
in Congress...
Do you think it was gunfire?
The team phoned to say that
during the incident,
First Vice-President,
Lt. Col. Gutierrez Mellado,
was struck...
Next the caller said not to worry.
No, not a chance.
-Thanks, Paco.
-Sir...
One moment, Nicolas.
lnform me as soon as
you find out anything.
Where are Agustin and Jose?
Call Fernando and everyone
from the Fourth.
A crisis cabinet has to be set up.
Nicolas, please...
-Office of the King.
-Yes, in 5 minutes.
Laina says
they entered Congress in my name.
l cannot consent to that.
Have you located them yet?
Where are you going?
On the floor!
Sit down.
And don't get jumpy!
Tejero! Get Tejero here!
Valencia's on the phone for you.
-Where are the phones here?
-Down the end.
-General?
-Antonio...
Congratulations.
l heard it on the radio.
You were magnificent.
Thank you, General.
The building
has been taken as planned.
We have the government here,
a little cowed.
Yes.
But keep it all calm.
Wait until ''H plus 2'' arrives.
Good luck,
look out and get down to it.
General, now we can say it out loud.
Long live Spain.
Hurrah.
-Long live Spain, damn it!
-Hurrah!
-Long live Spain!
Okay! Great.
Sorry about the delay.
How are things?
Everything under control.
What about your men?
As agreed, l told them we're here
on manoeuvres. They understood,
-and they're at your disposal.
-lncredible...
My men were just incredible.
l was worried about you.
-There was traffic...
-Traffic?
On the Valdemoro exit.
Did you think l chickened out?
You?
You've got balls to spare.
Welcome.
-Thanks.
-Let's go.
What are they doing here?
Journalists, relatives,
even diplomats wanting to call
their embassies.
Throw them out.
We just want the people inside.
-l need a favour.
-Whatever you want.
You've got the gift of the gab.
Why don't you go in and say
something to calm them down?
You're not filming, are you?
Good evening.
Nothing's going to happen,
but we're going to wait for
the relevant military authority
to state what is to be done,
and what he has to declare.
So stay calm.
lt may be 15 or 20 minutes...
Unplug it or l'll kill you.
...or half an hour, no longer,
and the relevant authority,
military of course,
will determine
what is going to happen.
Nothing's going to happen,
so everyone stay calm.
Mr. Suarez, remain in your seat!
-As President of the Government, l...
-Mr. Suarez, sit down!
Sit down, damn it!
Guards!
General Milans sends us
his warmest greetings.
He has decreed a general mobilization.
What do we know about
the Armoured Division?
Relax. They'll be on their way.
BRUNETE ARMOURED DlVlSlON
Units of phase 1 of Operation Diana
waiting to depart, General.
What are they waiting for?
Move out at once.
Yes, sir.
What's Juste doing here?
Shouldn't he be in Zaragoza?
San Martin said he'd take him there,
on the excuse of manoeuvres.
That was what was agreed with Milans.
What's going on here?
l remind you that you don't command
this division anymore.
Look, Pepe, no one's disputing
that Armoured is under your orders.
But l'm here under orders
from Armada
and the King.
The King?
They ordered this operation.
That changes matters.
Continue the operation.
l'll confirm with Zarzuela
that everything's alright.
Talk to Armada.
He'll explain.
Stand to attention
when you address me, Commander.
Don't worry,
Pepe's one of us. l know him.
How could l miss all this?
You'd better be right.
l gave my word to Milans
that Brunete would come out,
and nothing or nobody
is going to stop me.
Follow my instructions.
That's right. Agreed.
We need a command
to keep the units under control.
We need to gather
the General Staff immediately.
Hello, Pepe.
lt's Juste.
-Tell me, how are things going there?
-All in order.
The first units are out
and the tanks are set to take Madrid.
What is this lunacy?
What is it? What's he saying?
The Armoured Division
is setting out to take Madrid.
All units to barracks immediately
and they're to stay there!
To barracks?
You heard.
I don't understand at all...
lsn't Armada there?
Armada isn't here, nor is he expected.
That certainly changes things.
Torres Rojas is here.
Torres Rojas?
He told me that Armada's there...
and you'd given the order.
-Sabino?
-Go ahead.
I don't know if I understand
what's happening.
They're to follow our orders
and stay where they are.
l have the King right here.
His orders are clear.
He says: Do not let your troops out
and do not listen to anyone,
not to Torres Rojas or to Armada.
-No one!
-l'll keep the units on stand-down.
But the officers are fired up.
It won't be easy
to maintain command.
All the best, Pepe.
Anyone who is not
a civil servant may leave.
Journalists, guests,
and Security Forces,
leave in an orderly fashion.
We don't have the 3rd,
and the 4th is engaged.
Are the Canaries secure?
Please tell them...
to call me at this number.
We must insist.
-What do we know about the 4th?
-lt's still engaged.
Keep at the ready.
-l'll put you through.
-We don't have the 3rd.
The 4th is engaged,
nothing on the 5th and 6th.
l've been trying to get on to him
for over half an hour.
l'll confirm it to you
as soon as l can.
l can't tell you.
He's to call this number.
Yes, he's here.
Armada!
lt's for you.
l know he's been talking
to politicians lately,
looking for situations
in the Constitution
that would legitimize
an crisis government
presided over by a military man.
-Obviously, Armada himself.
-lt was crazy talk.
The problem is that Armada,
in military eyes,
after so many years in the Household,
is linked to the King.
lt's possible he's convinced
some of the military
that a decisive blow
would be approved of by Your Majesty.
l know the Army.
Many of them
crave a return to the past,
but l've always
made it clear that their duty
is to the Constitution
over and above the King!
The Constitution...
A lot of them are still ruled
by Franco's testament.
And according to that,
they owe you obedience.
One must tread carefully.
Your Majesty, you should...
Let's go back.
l have to speak to
the Commanding Generals.
-Sabino, try to speak to Tejero.
-Very well.
l've got him.
Lt. Colonel,
l'm putting a call through.
Yes, go ahead.
This is Gen. Sabino Fernandez Campos,
General Secretary
of the Royal Household.
Yes. How are you?
Did you want something?
Did l want something?
Have you gone mad?
How dare you enter
in the King's name?
ln the name of His Majesty,
leave Congress immediately!
l only obey orders from
the Commanding General of Valencia!
-What did he say?
-That he only obeys Milans.
Milans...
lmpossible.
Jaime would never
rise up against the King.
But for the King, yes.
Guard, get me through to
the number l gave you before.
Milans is a good friend of Armada.
They fought
in the Blue Division together.
Get me Armada and Milans.
-Call the rest of the HQ's!
-We're on it, sir.
Guards!
Obey no orders but mine!
Who the hell is in command?
You men!
Get on the buses going back!
Juan, start moving, the unit
is to get here as soon as possible.
Then ''that gentleman''
has to be called.
He told me not to forget ''H Plus 2'',
that's when the unit has to arrive.
Give me the number
where l can contact you.
l'm here in the Congress Building.
Give me the number, damn it.
General Aramburu is here.
He want to take away the Guards.
Excuse me,
we have orders to obey
only immediate superiors.
lmmediate...?
l'm the Head of the Civil Guard!
Arrest him!
-You'll see who's in command here!
-Come with me.
You! Back on the buses!
Everybody on!
You're a disgrace to the Corps!
Here he is.
The great man.
General.
Give up, Antonio.
Put a stop to this madness.
-That's an order!
-l only obey orders
from the Commanding General
of Valencia.
-Careful!
-Drop the gun!
-Seize that man!
-l will not surrender, General!
One more step,
and l'll shoot you
and turn the gun on myself.
-This is over!
-No, no! General!
No, General.
lt'd mean a massacre. Let's leave.
Calm yourself, General.
The main thing now
is to set up a command centre nearby,
to keep an eye on them.
Excuse me, sir...
Yes. One moment.
Laina suggests that all Secretaries
and Sub-secretaries of State meet
to form a provisional government.
-What do you think?
-lt's a good idea.
That'll avoid a power vacuum.
Go ahead, Paco.
Gather as soon as possible.
Excuse me, Sabino.
Pascual, are you still there?
Listen carefully.
No, no, listen.
Don't do anything.
Remain in your barracks.
Don't you give that
''unique-opportunity'' line too!
That's a direct order,
do you understand?
-Go ahead.
-l've just spoken to Armada.
He denies any knowledge
of what's happening.
He insisted
on coming here to help us.
What did you tell him?
That he's more useful to us
at General Staff.
Good.
For greater security,
call the Somontes checkpoint and...
order them not to let him in
if he presents himself.
l've taken that liberty, sir.
-You're all journalists.
-Yes, sir.
Why didn't you say so before?
-Well...
-Fine.
Get going.
But the film and cameras stay here.
Madam.
-How are you?
-Fine.
l spoke to London.
My brother sends you a hug.
-Are the children alright?
-l'm trying not to let them worry.
Cristina and Elena
keep asking me what's happening.
And Felipe?
-ln his room.
-Tell him to come, please.
7:32 P.M. MADRlD
SPANlSH TV, PRADO DEL REY
Everyone stay put!
-Silence!
-Stay put!
Here they are! We've got to hurry!
We're taking control here.
No news.
Broadcast what you like, but no news.
ls that clear?
We've also ordered National Radio
to only broadcast military marches.
You!
Get me a transistor.
l want to check that
our orders have been obeyed.
Didn't you bring one?
l mean,
l don't have a transistor here.
This is a TV station.
We don't have ''transistors'' here.
How can that be?
Men, turn all this upside-down,
but find me a fucking radio!
-What do we know about Barcelona?
-Nothing, we know nothing.
-And Granada?
-Delgado Alvarez,
-we have his full support.
-His Majesty has to talk to them.
Seville...
The Captain-General
isn't answering the phone.
Merry Gordon.
Keep calling him.
And if they don't answer,
send them a teletype!
-Go ahead, Juanillo.
-Antonio...
There a many of us behind you.
lmportant people, very important.
Listen.
Military marches on National Radio.
-You don't say!
-Yes! Keep that morale high!
Guards!
Military marches on National Radio!
Keep up that morale!
Listen to them! Listen to them!
Let's get the ones l told you about.
Military marches on National Radio.
Alfonso,
military marches on National Radio.
Military marches on National Radio!
Guards!
Military marches on National Radio.
Chin up!
Adolfo,
they're broadcasting military marches
on National Radio.
You...
come with me.
Gentlemen...
Gen. Milans del Bosch
just declared a state of siege.
We shall read out the decree.
Don Jaime Milans del Bosch y Ussia,
Lt. General...
You two, come with me.
...Captain-General, 3rd Region...
Let's go.
...given the events
taking place
in the capital of Spain,...
You, follow me!
it is my duty to guarantee order
in my military region
until receiving instructions
from His Majesty the King.
l therefore declare:
Article 1 :
All civil service personnel
are to be militarized,
with the duties and powers
set down by law.
Contact with armed military units
by the civil population
is prohibited.
These units will repel
without intimidation or warning
all aggressions they may encounter
with the greatest force.
Similarly repelled will be
aggressive action against buildings,
water and light utilities...
All public and private activity
by political parties is suppressed,
similarly banning the gathering
of more than four people.
It is established...
that family groups
in their respective...
All state security bodies
will remain under my authority.
Similarly, I assumejudicial
and administrative power,
at the regional...
The rules will remain valid
for a strictly limited period
until instructions from His Majesty
or High Command are received.
For all this,
I shall finish with a hearty:
Long live the King!
Long live Spain!
On the right.
Go ahead, gentlemen.
You two, down the end.
Quickly.
Mr. Rodriguez Sahagun.
Next to the table.
You two, there.
May one enquire why there are tanks
in the streets? By what right?
They're only some units
returning from manoeuvres.
Manoeuvres?
Do you take me for a fool?
Withdraw those units at once!
And call Zarzuela,
the King's been trying all evening
to speak to you.
I will, General.
ls Armada there?
Armada?
General.
How are things in Valencia?
What the hell are you doing there?
You're meant to be with the King.
Of course, but...
l'll try to speak to him
sometime tonight.
Do so.
You have to protect the King
from bad influences.
And, if need be,
protect the King
from the King himself.
l'll do what l can.
Armada, why is everyone
asking me about you?
Since l've had some contact...
with politicians of late...
Armada, you and l are soldiers.
Let's leave politics
to the professionals.
They're doing a bad enough job
on their own.
l'm leaving for
the Junta of the General Staff.
l'm counting on you to
keep things calm here.
lt's an extraordinary night
for our country.
We're here at the Palace Hotel,
in front of Congress.
Meeting right now
are the Head of the Civil Guard,
Aramburu Topete,
and representatives of
the Police and the Army.
ln coordination with
State Security Forces,
they're trying to determine
what measures to take
at this crucial time.
Yes, Father,
l've just spoken to all the HQs.
lt seems it's an isolated incident,
only seconded by the Third,
but l've insisted that Gabeiras
maintain full control
of the Armed Forces.
What about the General StaffE?
They're meeting now.
A meeting of the Secretaries
has also been called
in order to establish
a provisional government.
Son, this isn't the first time
our family has faced this.
My father had to do it,
and your grandfather before him.
These are difficult times, Father.
But don't worry,
we'll get through this.
I'm sure you'll be up to it.
I know you hold Spain in your heart
and you'll defend her
with all your courage.
Majesty... Long live Spain!
Thank you, Father.
l know l can count on you.
l'll call back when l can.
Goodbye.
l want you to pay close attention
to what's going on today.
This is a very important day for us.
Take a seat.
Sabino! l need to address
the nation as soon as possible.
The people need to know
the Crown's position.
Castedo, go ahead.
Fernando. This is Sabino.
The King wants you
to send a crew to Zarzuela.
He wants to send
a message to the country.
No, tell him l'm in a meeting.
-Do you have people in your office?
-Yes.
Civilian or military?
The latter.
The latter, on UHF.
You've got military men
in your office?
That's right.
We'll do what we can
to get them out of there.
Alright.
Captain.
Quintana Lacaci on the phone.
l'm only here for my commander.
Hang up.
And if he calls again,
hang up again!
You and l fought in the War
on opposite sides,
but...
you might accept one from me.
l'd be grateful.
l wanted to give up smoking,
because of this damn bronchitis.
The situation is quite complicated.
There are over 50 tanks.
All the best.
50 tanks...
You have to put me in touch
with Milans, any way you can.
What did he say?
He won't speak to
Quintana or Gabeiras.
He refuses to leave.
He says he only obey orders
from immediate superiors.
lt's a detachment from Villaviciosa.
You've always been
on close terms with the Cavalry.
Have you got friends
in that detachment?
Yes, sir.
Those crews have to leave
the TV building.
Taping an image
is a top priority, Nicolas.
Alright. l'll see what l can do.
Thank you.
304, Herrero de Minon...
305, Ernest Lluc...
300...
Count away.
Like we counted on you,
while you people did nothing.
What are you talking about?
Over 80 last year alone.
They had wives...
...children...
And you never even went
to their funerals.
l stopped when the wives
looked at me the way you are now.
You didn't have the balls
to look them in they eye!
Listen to me!
l've spent many sleepless nights
searching for a solution.
A solution?
An iron fist.
There is no other solution.
That's why we had to intervene.
Because you didn't have the courage
to take steps.
lt's easy to be brave
when you're aiming at an unarmed man.
You unarmed people
are the most dangerous of all.
You only drag Spain down
with laws, from inside your offices,
while outside
Civil Guards risks their lives!
-Look...
-No, you look.
Who's to blame that we're here?
Are we?
We're not, that's for sure.
Sir, if you'll let me...
Are you sure, sir?
Yes.
At your orders, sir.
Get the men.
We're leaving.
l gather l'm now back in charge
of this establishment
and can broadcast what l like.
Do what you like.
Manises hasn't come out.
Brunete hasn't come out.
Anyway, sooner or later
you'll have to talk to him.
Majesty.
Jaime, what are you doing?
l'm trying to preserve order,
that's all.
At a time like this
one has to protect the monarchy,
protect the King,
and wait for events to unfold.
Protect me from what?
From whom?
Wasn't it you people
who started this?
Not at all.
This is a one-off, it's some zealot.
-Right.
-It's understandable,
given this country's situation.
The Army saw its duty as...
Jaime, you must revoke that
decree now.
Or l'll have to declare you
as being in rebellion.
Majesty...
Armada told me last night.
You spoke to Armada?
Sir, you'd have to see
the mood of the troops.
They're just waiting for you
to give the word
and they'll take to the streets.
Revoke that decree
or suffer the consequences!
Have I made that clear?
Yes, sir.
But I beg you,
try to speak to Armada.
lt seems that five politicians,
as well as Adolfo Suarez,
have been taken away...
Latest news.
Attention, attention,
this very moment,
at 9:03 p.m.,
we've received a note,
a communique from
the Ministry of the lnterior
informing of the establishment
of a provisional government.
Under the orders of
His Majesty the King,
and presided over by
Francisco Laina,
this government's aim is to ensure
the governability of the State.
Given the circumstances,
the Secretaries of State
and their Sub-secretaries,
have come together,
on the orders
of His Majesty the King,
to ensure
the governing of the country
in civilian hands
and it remains in close contact
with the General StaffE,
who are also meeting.
Gabeiras,
how are things going at General Staff?
We've just approved a declaration
supporting the Constitution
and established a single command
under your orders, Majesty.
Good. Good, good.
Another thing.
ls Armada with you?
No, l left him
in command at Buenavista.
Leave General Staff
and return to Buenavista at once.
-Keep me informed.
-Immediately, sir.
Armada is alone at Buenavista.
Tejero has the Congress,
l've got my tanks on the streets.
What are you doing in Madrid?
No one's being decisive here.
l can't see how it can be done.
You can't?
lt's being done!
Get some balls
and keep your word!
General, time's slipping by
and the linking of chains
you talked about hasn't come about.
l think the time has come
to try another way.
Let me retake the reins.
How can you,
if you haven't done anything?
You're not even in Zarzuela
keeping the King under wraps!
General, l think
l speak for all of us.
We have a unique opportunity
to put things in order.
lt seems even the King can't stand
this government anymore.
Have you been talking to Armada?
He gathered the officers together.
He says that the 2nd, 4th
and 5th are thinking it over.
lf Madrid moves out,
all Spain will follow suit.
lt's in your hands, General.
Go back to your posts!
Things haven't gone
the way we thought.
Excuses!
Don't give me excuses again!
You want to try it your way.
Go ahead.
Isn't that what you wanted
from the start?
Alright... l'll try to....
do something.
Alfonso, will you tell me
what the hell's going on here?
Milans just called.
He tells me...
Tejero seems very agitated.
He's afraid there could be
a massacre at any time.
He suggested that
l go to Congress
and...
propose a political solution
to the deputies.
And you refused.
l don't know...
lf with this l did
a service to Spain...
lf l went there under your...
direct orders...
A decision like that
isn't up to me.
The King would have to authorize it.
Give the wire some slack.
-Tape in.
-Connect it.
How are we doing?
-Well, Chus, what do you think?
-Perfect, Majesty.
Thank you, Nicolas.
Do you have everything ready?
How does it look, Pedro?
Just the last technical adjustments
and we'll be set.
Good.
Sir, l've just spoken to Armada.
He's on the phone.
Excuse me, today's been
a day full of calls.
Guards!
l've just spoken to Valencia.
The Second, Third, Fourth
and Fifth Military Region
have said yes...
to Milans del Bosch as President.
The Balearics are considering it.
This looks like a rescue operation.
Congress has no generator.
lt could just be a power failure.
-Please, stay put and keep calm.
-Go back to your place.
Guards!
lf there's a blackout,
and anyone brushes past
trying to get out or in,
open fire without hesitation.
Cover the access points!
Everyone stay sharp!
What's going on, Alfonso?
l warned you of the risk of
some excitable person doing this.
Now it's too late.
l need to know
what your role is in all this.
l'm just trying to intermediate.
l've just spoken to Milans.
He suggests that I go
to Parliament...
and propose a crisis government.
You want to be named president
by a Parliament
besieged by arms, is that it?
lt's not my desire,
but l'm ready to make that sacrifice,
if Your Majesty orders it.
-l think you've gone mad.
-We're talking about human lives,
not just those of politicians.
A civil war could break out again.
Your Majesty would be responsible...
Responsible for what?
You people are setting the Army
against me and all Spaniards.
You, Alfonso.
You,
my tutor.
These people are ready to open fire!
lt'll be carnage!
Sir,
may l go
and speak to Tejero in your name?
Look...
You don't have my support.
You may not speak in my name.
ln fact, l don't want to speak to you.
I'll put you on to Sabino.
Alfonso,
if you think
you can convince Tejero to surrender,
go and see him.
But in your own name.
Leave the Crown out of this.
Well, tell the King
he still has time.
You have to convince him.
For the love of God!
Everyone's waiting
for word from him.
And they'll get it.
General...
l just want to say
that l was forced to come here.
l was in the Traffic Dept.
washing a car,
when they gave me this gun
and told me ''Come with us''.
We know how these things start.
But not how they end.
We have here Gen. Prieto
of the Civil Guard,
one of the last people to contact
his friend, Lt. Col. Tejero.
How did he seem to you, General?
l know him very well.
At present he is not nervous.
He's out of his mind.
He's making no sense at all.
There he is!
Excuse me.
Attention, it seems...
Yes, General Armada,
along with General Aramburu
and other Army personnel
are leaving the Palace Hotel
and heading for Congress.
We can't make a copy here,
we have to do two takes.
Fine.
lt has to be filmed twice
and the tapes sent out in two cars
on separate routes
in case of roadblocks.
Alright.
At your orders, General,
we've been waiting for you.
General.
l'm sorry l'm late.
A problem came up,
but it's all sorted out now.
Don't worry, General,
we've been kept very busy here.
As Milans will have told you,
from now on
l'm taking charge of the situation.
l shall address the deputies.
There's no need
for you to accompany me.
Just a moment, General.
We have to talk this over first.
Tejero, we thank you
for your services,
and we know they'll be rewarded.
But don't make me
waste any more time.
A government must be set up urgently.
And what ministry would Milans
have in this government?
That's none of your affair.
But if you insist: none.
Milans is a soldier, not a politician.
No, General!
l thought we came here
to set up a Military Junta.
Now you give me
this politician stuff.
Let me go.
You're making a scene.
Come with me.
Turn off the extractors
to cut down the noise.
Turn them off.
Change the clocks so they don't chime.
lt's almost half past.
When you wish, Pedro.
Alright, sir.
-Are we ready?
-Ready.
Roll it, guys.
We're taping.
Rolling.
Whenever you wish.
On addressing the Spanish people,
briefly and concisely,
in the extraordinary circumstances
we are going through at this time,
l ask of everyone the greatest
serenity and trust.
We must proclaim
a Military Junta at once!
With Milans at the head.
A cabinet to take power
and declare a state of emergency.
That's what we have to do.
That solution is infeasible, Tejero.
At least for now.
We have to find
a solution, a compromise.
A government
with military men, of course, but...
inevitably, with politicians too.
What politicians?
Politicians from
the four main parties.
lf l can get into the Chamber,
l believe l can convince them.
This is the government list
l've prepared.
A communist in government?
ls that why we came this far?
There's no other solution, Tejero,
believe me.
What does it matter?
We give two portfolios to each party,
so they're happy,
but Spain will be in our hands.
Milans would never accept this.
Milans is in total agreement.
Confirm it. There's the phone.
...the Constitution,
voted for by the Spanish people,
determined, in its day,
through a referendum.
What do you think?
Fine. Fine, fine.
Now hotfoot it to Prado del Rey.
-Sir...
-Thanks, Pedro.
Thanks to you, sir.
Have them escorted at all times
until it's been broadcast.
-Yes, sir.
-Let's go.
Listen to me, Tejero!
Nobody, nobody talked about
a Military Junta!
Neither you nor l are politicians!
This is about putting things
in the hands of the King and Armada,
-so that they decide.
-General...
We did our part.
Now obey Armada
in whatever he requests.
That's an order.
l'm sorry, General,
but l cannot obey that order.
ln that case...
prepare for the consequences.
Do you think at this point
l'm worried about consequences?
Don't kid yourself, General.
This man's looking for
a cushy job,
even at the price of
carrying on with democracy!
Listen...
Could you do me a favour
and get my coat from my seat.
This cold is unbearable.
Something's going wrong.
They look anxious,
like they were being abandoned.
That makes them more dangerous.
You're tired, nervous,
and that stops you
from taking stock of
the situation we're in.
Even of your own actions.
lf you're worried about
your personal safety,
l have several Aviocars
ready in Getafe
so that you...
and any officers you may choose
can leave the country.
Later, once in government,
we'd process a pardon.
And...
...sure, there'd be a tidy sum
of money as a reward.
Thank you, General,
but flying makes we queasy.
ln the worst case scenario,
you'd be an exile in luxury,
respected and admired.
But if you hinder me
from addressing Congress,
you'll end your days in jail,
and forget about watching
your children grow up.
Look,
the only way out l accept
is a Military Junta.
lt's that, or l start
a martyr's massacre here.
l don't mind dying,...
but l'll take all of them
with me first.
l know you're doing this
in good faith, for Spain!
But l'm thinking of Spain too!
Or do you think
l love Spain less than you?
Don't make me laugh.
Any one of my men
loves Spain more than you.
And now,
if you will allow me...
BREAKlNG NEWS
The news up to this minute.
We can tell you that
in a few moments
you'll be able to hear the message
from His Majesty the King.
On addressing the Spanish people,
briefly and concisely,
in the extraordinary circumstances
we are going through at this time,
I ask of everyone the greatest
serenity and trust
and may they know that
I have given the generals of
the military regions, maritime zones
and air sectors the following order:
Faced with the situation created by
developing events
in the Congress
and in order to avoid any confusion,
I confirm that I have ordered
the civil authorities
and the Junta of the Chiefs of StaffE
to take all necessary measures
to maintain constitutional order
within existing legality.
Any measure of a military nature
that has to be taken
must have the approval
of the Junta of the Chiefs of StaffE.
The Crown cannot tolerate,
in any form,
actions or attitudes of people
attempting to disrupt by force
the democratic process
that the Constitution,
voted for by the Spanish people,
determined in its time
by referendum.
Mad. The man's gone mad.
He's threatening a massacre.
He's gone mad, Aramburu.
You can't reason with him.
l've failed.
l need to inform the King.
General.
Why don't you come with me
to the Ministry of the lnterior?
Laina would like to speak to you.
Yes, of course.
Gen. Alfonso Armada,
Army Second-in-Command,
has left Congress
just a few minutes ago.
Gen. Armada was negotiating
with Lt. Col. Antonio Tejero Molina
of the Civil Guard,
in charge of the group
still holding Congress
in their power.
No, that won't be necessary.
Thank you, see you soon.
l just spoke to Juste.
Commander Pardo Zancada,
of the Brunete Division,
refuses to obey.
He's mobilized a column
of military police
and is heading for Congress.
What do we know about him?
A zealot.
He often writes or El Alcazar.
The question is: could this be
the start of a chain reaction?
Juste can't guarantee that
there won't be more cases.
He says that moods are fired up.
-Examples like this do not help.
-What do you think?
After your message,
the HQs seem quieter.
But while Milans
refuses revoke the decree,
and with Tejero still holding
the government,
l wouldn't rule out others
like Pardos popping up.
Yes, Milans is the key.
The indecisive generals
will have their eyes on Valencia.
Even Tejero said
he'd only obey Milans.
At 1:40 in the morning,
jeeps with Army forces
crossed the security cordon
set up by the Police
and have taken up positions
facing the main gate of Congress
on La Carrera de San Jeronimo.
Thesejeeps arrived at Congress
with Military Police
from the Brunete Armoured Division,
and at 1:45,
they had donned helmets
and were awaiting orders
from Military Command
outside Congress itself.
l don't understand how you could
take these decisions
without consulting me!
No, no, Jaime,
you're not listening to me
and l'm sick of this drivel!
l order you to withdraw
those troops immediately!
And to tell Tejero
to stop behaving this way!
l swear, l'm not leaving
and l'm not abdicating!
You'll have to shoot me first.
l beg you to reconsider, Majesty.
Gabeiras, are you there?
Yes. l heard.
l have the Military Governor
of Valencia on the other line.
I'll give him the order, Majesty.
Send a telex to Valencia
with all the orders in writing.
Right away.
Are you alright?
Send that telex.
Caruana, direct orders from the King.
You have to detain Milans.
Your orders, Lieutenant Colonel.
Commander Pardos Zancada
of the Armoured Division.
l'm here at the request
of Milans del Bosch.
l have 70 men outside.
-70?
-70.
l expected a division.
They told me they'd send
someone higher.
The generals are thinking it over.
The Civil Guard always
takes the brunt of everything.
ln the end, we're left
hanging in the wind.
Look, Commander....
Do what you like.
The Civil Guard
can defend Spain by itself here.
-How did the conversation go?
-No, more of the same.
-Armada too.
-Yes.
He was going to make a botch of it.
A pile of shit
with politicians on top.
Carrillo and the Minister of whatever.
Just a moment, don't hang up.
l won't hang up.
This is a shitty time for me.
That's the way it is.
Nobody dares to step.
Okay, okay. Okay.
-Hey!
-Yes?
They tell me a regiment
is on its way there.
Villaviciosa is out, Antonio!
Villaviciosa and Pavia
are going to move out!
Hold out!
And tell everyone about this!
Hold out? Of course l'll hold out!
The radio is lying!
They've fucked us!
Of course they're lying!
Please, hold out!
-This victory is for Spain!
-Exactly.
For Spain!
This victory is for Spain!
Keep you chins up, up, up!
Men of honour will know
how to respond to this.
Juanillo, cut the propaganda!
Bloody hell!
Long live Spain!
Guards!
Pavia and Villiviciosa
are on their way here!
Keep your chins up!
Are you sure?
Do you trust him?
How could l not trust Juanillo?
Whose side are you on?
-How can you say that to me?
-And how can you say that to me?
-l'm just saying, think about...
-l don't think!
This is what we're here for,
to hold on, and die if need be!
lf you're not with me,
then get out.
Antonio...
General...
This is the hardest order
l've ever had to carry out.
But it comes straight from the King.
l'm very sorry, but l have to...
Take it.
Gunplay, you and l, General?
Not a chance.
You needn't pay heed to me,
but at least withdraw the troops.
And leave those brave men
in the lurch?
lt's a superior order.
l gave my word of honour
to those men!
Caruana...
How can we give Spain back
its dignity
if we can't behave with honour
amongst ourselves?
l was taught that
discipline comes before honour.
When what you hold most sacred
is destroyed all around you...
there are times when
you cannot obey,
you have to act.
At least you'll have
the consolation of having tried.
-Take me to Lt. Col. Tejero.
-That's impossible right now.
-Here he is.
-Antonito!
Camilo...
-What a surprise.
-Your Guards won't let me past.
What are you doing here?
l was nearby
and l'm just visiting.
But if l'm a nuisance...
How could you be a nuisance?
Give me a hug.
Thanks.
Come on in.
Ever been here before?
-No.
-l'll show you around.
These stairs go up to the podium.
Come.
This hall leads to
some fabulous rooms.
l keep the dangerous ones
separate here.
Guards!
Pavia and Villaviciosa
are on their way here!
General, a telex
just in from Valencia.
Milans has revoked the decree.
That means his surrender.
We hope now that nobody moves out.
What about Tejero?
The bastards have cut off everything.
l have to find out where
Pavia and Villaviciosa are!
Holy shit, we have to find
a fucking phone that works!
Holy fucking shit!
In short,
we want the unity of Spain, peace,
order and security.
And sign it with
a ''Long live Spain''.
You've moved me, Antonio.
l've taken it down.
lt'll be in the morning edition
of El Alcazar tomorrow.
People will hit the streets
in droves when they read this.
Don't give in, Antonio!
-This is for Spain!
-Of course it is, damn it!
-Long live Spain!
-Long live Spain.
And another thing, Juanillo.
l may not be able to call you again.
l've got Carmen on the other line.
-Carmen?
-Don't hang up.
Speak up so she can hear you.
How are you, honey?
Fine, baby, fine.
Antonio, promise me
there'll be no bloodshed.
Of course there won't be
any bloodshed. Don't worry!
Why didn't you tell me anything?
How little you love me.
Of course l love you, sweetie.
-Juan Garcia Carres?
-Yes, what is it?
You're under arrest.
-Carmen?
-Antonio?
Stop! Stop!
The well-known ultra-right leader
Juan Garcia Carres
was arrested this morning
at his home in Madrid.
National Radio Network.
9 minutes to 7 in the morning.
We hand you over to
another of our mobile units,
located in front of
the Congress of Deputies.
Luis de Benito...
As we previously reported,
Civil Guard forces have vacated
the Congress Building,
and have been replaced by
members of the National Police...
-Hello? Listen, l need...
-Are you Tejero?
Yes. Put me through to Milans.
lt's very important.
The General has retired
to his rooms.
What?
He's asked you to hand yourself in,
to negotiate surrender.
Guards!
Attention!
From the King on down,
they're all trash!
Trash.
What did they say?
He's asleep.
He's gone to sleep.
A nation of cowards.
They don't deserve our sacrifice.
COUP FAlLS
All that effort to change
Spain's image...
...and in the end, this is the photo
that'll go around the world.
Guards...
the time has come
to show that
in the holy name of Spain,
we shall sacrifice everything.
Yes, it's been a rough night.
We're tired.
lt's time for us to show ourselves
to be even more united!
We're going to turn this Congress...
into a new Alcazar...
a new Santa Maria de la Cabeza!
And like the men of
glorious Captain Cortes,
we will resist...
until ultimate victory is ours.
Who is ready to follow me?
Stand to attention.
Here he is.
Lt. Col. Eduardo Fuentes,
sent by the General Staff.
Fine. What do you want?
These are the conditions proposed
by Commander Pardo Zancada.
None of your men,
from lieutenant down,
will suffer any reprisals.
You will all leave for El Pardo,
and there, in your barracks,
without photographers,
you will surrender.
And l'll be the last
to leave the Congress Building.
Very well.
We can offer a pact of honour
on similar terms for the Civil Guard.
Look...
...for the good of my men...
l'd accept these conditions...
but l will, of course,
be the last to leave.
Over 20 Civil Guards
have abandoned
the Congress Building.
The Guards jumped from
a first floor window
of the Press OffEice section.
Tell Captain Munecas
l'm on my way.
lt's what must be done, Antonio.
It appears
to be Colonel Tejero
in Civil Guard uniform,
talking to another offEicer.
It seems they've seen the camera,
but aren't taking much notice of it.
Adolfo...
President...
With every passing minute
it's getting harder and harder
to perform our reporting duties...
Antonio Tejero Molina: sentenced to
30 years for military rebellion
and expelled from the Army
with loss of rank.
Served 15 years in jail.
Alfonso Armada y Comin: sentenced to
30 years for military rebellion
and expelled from the Army
with loss of rank.
Pardoned for reasons of health.
Served 7 years in jail.
Jaime Milans del Bosch y Ussia:
sentenced to 11 years
and 8 months in prison
and expelled from the Army.
Pardoned due to his advanced age.
Served 9 years in jail.
Ricardo Pardo Zancada: sentenced to
12 years for military rebellion
and expelled from the Army.
Served 6 years in prison.
Jesus Munecas Aguilar: sentenced to
5 years for military rebellion
and expelled from the Army.
Released from jail after serving
3 and a half years.
Juan Garcia Carres: the only civilian
charged with the plot.
Sentenced to two years,
he served 15 months on remand.