Dear god in heaven,
it's me, Frankie.
Look, I know I probably ain't
One of your favorite people
down here.
I done some bad things
here and there,
And I know I been asking
for a lot favors lately, too,
So maybe I used
most of mine up.
I know you probably tried
to help me out
With this lottery thing
tonight,
But the way
things are going,
It doesn't look as if
it's going to work out,
So i'm asking
for one more favor--
Please don't add insult
to injury here, god.
Please, i'm begging you.
I don't want to win
the lottery.
the lottery...
Hi. Name, please.
I'm Frank pesce.
P-e-s...
C-e.
Ok, here you are,
Frank. I'm julie.
Welcome
to the empire stakes.
Follow me.
I have you down for 6.
Where's the rest
of the family?
What?
Where's the rest
of the family?
It's only me.
Oh. So, what are you
going to do if you win?
I really don't know.
Come on,
tell me the truth.
Do you feel lucky tonight?
You have no idea.
Good luck, mr. Pesce.
Hey, how you doing?
Good luck to you, man.
Yeah, you, too.
Ladies and gentlemen,
mr. Memory lane himself--
Joe Franklin!
Ok. Thank you very much,
ladies and gentlemen.
The big moment has arrived
at long last--
The very first
new york state lottery--
The empire stakes,
with some lucky person
Receiving $6,200,000.
The very first
in new york state.
I know the excitement
has been mounting
And generating
and mushrooming
And snowballing
and escalating
And skyrocketing,
And the, uh...
Contestants out there,
The audience--
you're kind of palpitating
And drooling
and salivating
And getting ready now
for the moment.
The moment has arrived.
And the lucky, lucky
person is...
Mr. Frank pesce!
Tony Bennett:
♪ OH, THE GOOD LIFE ♪
♪ full of fun ♪
♪ seems to be ♪
♪ the ideal ♪
♪ mmm, the good life ♪
♪ lets you hide
all the sadness you feel ♪
♪ please remember ♪
♪ I still want you ♪
♪ and in case
you wonder why ♪
♪ well, just wake up ♪
♪ kiss the good life
good-bye ♪
Are you happy now?
Are you happy, god?
You had to do this to me!
You weren't happy
leaving me alone, were you?
Were you?
I'll kill you!
Aah!
I never wanted
the damn ticket!
Why did you
give it to me?
I get up every morning!
I'm fine!
I'm a nice guy!
I know I do
some things wrong!
I was perfectly happy
in my life without it!
You couldn't leave me
alone, could you?
What's going on
out here?
What the hell
is your problem?
Frank, is that you?
And you!
What the hell
do you want?
Get back in
there, lowery!
What are you doing?
Don't you know
that it's christmas eve?
A lot of good you ever
did me, you priest!
A lot of good
you ever did me!
I'm going to call
the cops on you, Frank.
I'm catholic!
I can do whatever
the hell I want!
Oh, tartaglia,
the atheist is here.
Bring him in.
Honey, I got to go.
Merry christmas.
Yeah,
I love you, too.
Say hello
to the kids for me.
Look, sergeant, you got
to let me go, all right?
I ain't got
a lot of time here.
This priest wants
to press charges.
You messed up
his manger.
Father lowery,
i'm sorry.
All right?
Well, all right.
All right.
But why did you
do it, Frankie?
Just let me go,
all right?
Look, I just
can't sit here
And bullshit
with you guys.
Uncuff him.
Great.
You know, Frank, I checked
on what you said.
Your brother is
a cop with the 1-8.
You got no prior record.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
You look like
a nice italian kid.
What the hell
are you doing
Throwing snowballs
at the church,
Scaring the priest?
It's christmas eve.
Don't you belong somewhere?
Anchorman on TV:
AND THE WINNER TONIGHT--
Frank pesce
of queens, new york,
Who will take home
$6.2 million.
When his name
was called
And he failed
to come forward,
Ushers discovered
that mr. Pesce
Apparently had left
the drawing ceremony.
At any rate, congratulations
to Frank pesce
Of queens, new york,
wherever you are.
Turn it off,
will you?
New yorkers are crying over more
bad economic news today.
Some say our city
is going down--
That's you?
Same guy?
Yeah.
And then you went and broke
windows in the church?
What are you,
some kind of mammalucco?
Yeah, well, it's
a long story, you know?
You're not going anywhere.
Neither am i.
Not until you make some
kind of sense out of this.
I swear to god,
The only way I know how
to tell this story
Is from the beginning.
I got all night.
You see,
I got this, uh...
I got this curse.
I've been lucky since
the day I was born.
It's like my mother.
She used to work
at lincoln hospital,
So that's where
I was supposed to be born.
But she went into labor
at a bingo parlor
A couple of blocks
from where we live,
So they had to rush her
TO BELLEVUE HOSPITAL
ON 29th STREET INSTEAD.
Actually, that was
my first stroke of luck,
Because on that very night
Lincoln hospital ended up
having a huge fire,
And the place nearly
burned to the ground.
1-7. Vito, where you--
1-7. Hold it.
603 is the combination.
60 cents.
10 cents a weigh.
No, the others are
straight action, shadow.
Straight action.
Madeline,
hey, huh, huh?
717 for $1.20.
Mr. Pesce?
Shadow, i'll get
right back to you.
Would you like
to see your son?
Come on, madeline.
Let's go see your brother.
Come on, come on.
Let's go.
My mom said
he always cried
When he saw us
for the first time--
My brother, my sister, me.
Come on!
We're going to be late.
I'm coming!
20 minutes from here
to radio city.
I got you a hot dog.
You don't want nothing?
I'm not hungry.
Come on, let's walk.
It's such a beautiful day.
All right, let's go.
Come on, we got
about 8 blocks, right?
Yeah, but
we're going to see
Student prince.
Come on.
When I was younger,
my dad used to always seem
Like this giant to me,
This guy who knew everything
about everything.
What are you
looking at?
That.
What's that?
What's that say?
Oh, that says,
"Today is president
eisenhower's birthday."
I want to get
my name up there.
I wouldn't want to have it
any other way, Frankie,
But only great people
get their names up there.
How can I get
my name up there?
You know, you got to do
something big, Frankie.
Big.
How big?
Very, very big,
you got to do.
How big?
Well, uh...
This big.
I guess every son
Wants to make his father
proud of him,
You know, so he doesn't feel
like a jerk for having you.
And I figured if I could get
my name up on that building,
At least
I could have left
Some kind of mark
on the world.
Frank, Sr.: MAYBE YOU'LL
SING LIKE MARIO LANZA.
You ever hear
of him?
Frank:
IN MY NEIGHBORHOOD,
There were, like,
2 ways to make it.
One's the right way,
And the other way's
the fast way.
And I got to tell you,
The fast way looked
pretty attractive to me
As a kid.
Wow, look at that.
♪ you went away
and left me a long time ago ♪
That's louie tucci.
He's the biggest wise guy
in the neighborhood.
He's poison.
Don't even look at him.
Yeah, but I still
like his car.
♪ but you can't come in ♪
You'd be better off
walking, Frankie.
Come on.
♪ I hear you knockin'... ♪
My dad could always
talk circles around everybody.
I swear, the guy
should've run for office
And been a politician.
There was this odd thing
goin' on
Between him and louie tucci.
I knew my father
couldn't stand him,
Yet they seemed to be spending
a lot of time together,
Especially when my dad
lost his trucking company,
Which i'll get to later.
Hi, Frankie.
Dad, you say
don't look at the guy
Because he's no good,
Then you hang
around with him.
You mean tucci?
Yeah.
Come on, Frankie.
It's business.
You in business
with that guy?
Never.
You see, Frankie,
I don't want to be
in business with him.
I don't want to spend
any time
With a guy like that.
That's why
you were with him?
Yeah.
Because you don't
want to be?
That's right.
You mean,
you spend time with him
Because you don't want
to spend time with him?
That's exactly right.
If I spent
less time with him,
I'd have to spend
even more time with him.
So if you spent
no time with him...
Then i'd be with him
constantly.
I can't wait
until I grow up, pop,
So I can know what the hell
you're talking about.
Get out of here,
wise guy.
Frankie!
Don't be late.
Mama's cooking
ciccia baste.
Yeah, dad.
Growing up didn't help.
I still don't know
What the hell
he's talking about.
Now, this luck thing
Kept on happening
time after time.
Like I remember one time
I was hanging out
with my friend jimmy vitello,
Whose father
was also in the mob.
In fact, he was the biggest
mobster in the tri-state area.
Come on.
Let's go.
Wow!
Can you believe it?
It was just
laying here.
Hey, let's take it down
to irv's and pawn it.
I'll give you $5.00.
$5.00?
Are you nuts?
Thing must be worth
A couple
of hundred bucks.
Yeah, don't be
a fucking stiff.
Ooh, what a mouth you got.
You kiss your mother
with that mouth?
Where did you
get this?
Huh?
God left it
for us.
Oh, well, I don't want him
coming around here
Looking for it.
Get it out of here.
Huh?
Irv, you know
who my father is.
We don't want to have
a little misunderstanding,
Now, do we?
Jeez, all right.
All right.
You're something else,
you know that?
Here.
10 bucks.
That's it.
Now get out of here,
little bastards.
Go ahead.
Now, to a kid,
this seemed very impressive.
All you had to do
Was mention
jimmy vitello's father,
And, boom, you got
whatever the hell you wanted.
So no matter how far
out of line jimmy got,
The cops never showed up
at his house.
However, a member
of new york's finest
Did end up
in our house.
My brother vito decided
to become a cop.
Personally,i think
it was like
Getting a wolf
to watch the chickens.
Pesce, vito.
But at least somebody
was doing something
For the family name.
Vallamone,
ronald.
Meanwhile I hung around
with a bunch of guys
Who were doing absolutely
nothing with their lives.
There was lenny nipton.
You know, we called him
needle nose.
This guy was
the definition
Of postnasal drip.
Hey, Frank.
You know something, Frank?
Girls love poetry.
Dig this.
Tomorrow and tomorrow
and tomorrow
Creeps, baby,
in its petty pace.
Then there was
dom the bomb.
♪ hello, Frankie,
how are you today ♪
♪ yeah, yeah, yeah, now ♪
This guy actually
thought he could sing.
What are you going to do?
I got to lose some weight.
I think
I got a gland problem.
Rocky sav
had a gland problem
Ever since the day
he was born.
Poor sal las benas.
He spit on everything in sight
whenever he talked.
And then there was
jimmy vitello.
Frankie boy, how you doing?
Want to make some money?
$10,000 cash, tax-free.
Frank, we had some pizza
the other night...
♪ and if you promise
not to run away ♪
Extra cheese, sausage,
pepperoni...
♪ 'cause i'm your... ♪
What cops?
...of recorded time.
♪ in town ♪
Forget about it.
While I was hanging
around in the street
Bullshitting
with my friends all day long,
My dad was out
breaking his ass.
Ever since he lost
his own company,
He had been working as a driver
for some other outfit.
So every day he had to take
the subway to penn station,
Then he would catch
a connecting train
All the way to union city
To drive a truck
5 days a week
Through city traffic.
The yankees
are going to win.
Get it out of here.
Yankees, big. All right?
Yo, Frankie!
No wonder the guy
had problems relaxing.
This city is going
to the friggin' dogs.
We got to
get out of here.
Yeah, yeah,
I seen that.
We need a house
out of manhattan,
A nice house
with our own lawn.
That's what we need.
You know, pop, it's funny
that you're saying that,
Because of what
I been thinking.
I can't wait
to hear this.
The way I got
it figured, right,
Is that the future
is in outer space.
Maybe I could
become an astronaut.
It's the last
frontier, pop.
An astronaut?
Well,
think about it.
Look, pop,
I could become
The first italian
on the moon.
No, don't laugh.
I want to--
I want to do things that
I never done before.
Oh, I see.
Why don't you try
going inside
And cleaning up
your fucking room?
Come on, pop.
I'm serious.
I got longings and
desires, like everybody.
Are you all right?
Is there little people
Going around in
your head, or what?
Are you
putting me on?
No.
See, because i'm talking
About reality here,
Frankie.
Reality.
You get it?
I'm trying
to move us to queens,
And you're
talking about
Picking up
fucking moon rocks.
Well, you know what
your problem is, pop?
Yeah, what's
my problem?
Your dreams
are too small.
Yeah. My dreams
Dean Martin:
♪ VOLARE... ♪
Frank:
ANYWAY, WHEN I WAS 18,
My father got his dream
and moved us all to queens.
He got his other dream,
too--his own lawn.
Every afternoon,
like clockwork,
He'd come home
and set up the sprinkler.
♪ no wonder
my happy heart sings ♪
♪ your love has
given me wings ♪
♪ nel blu de pinto
de blu ♪
So, what are we
eating tonight?
Shithead ordered
a couple of pizzas.
Could you watch
your language, please?
Where the hell
did he go, yonkers?
When did you stop
liking pizza?
It's a waste
of money.
But gambling is not
a waste of money, huh?
Who's gambling?
See me gambling?
I heard you took your son
Frankie to the track yesterday.
You couldn't buy him
A miserable hot dog
for a buck,
But i'll bet you spent
$400 on a horse
That came in dead last.
Go ahead.
Tell me i'm wrong.
Huh?
Do you see
my name on these?
You see my name anywhere
on these stubs, huh?
Oh, i'm so sorry.
That must've been
some other guy
Wearing your pants.
HOW MUCH
DiALBIA'S COST?
7 bucks.
7 bucks, huh?
You know it probably
cost 25 cents to make.
So?
I'm a man of principle.
And I ain't paying 27
times what it's worth!
That's so!
Not for nothing, pop.
Did you pay for this?
You making a joke,
Frankie?
My family could
start a fight
Over absolutely anything.
What's the weather
for tomorrow?
I heard
it's going to rain.
That ain't
what I heard.
What the hell did you hear?
Never mind, Frankie.
Where
did you hear rain?
Madeline, I heard it
on the radio.
The weatherman said
it's going to rain tomorrow.
Typical, vito.
You listen
to the radio.
They're
always wrong.
Hold it. Do me a favor with
the goddamn weather here.
With the weather,
with the rain, with mars.
Who gives a shit?
Who gives a shit
about sun and rain?
I do, pop.
You don't pay $10 to
get your hair done.
My hair frizzes
in the rain.
Vito: LISTEN, WITCH,
LEAVE YOUR BROOM AT HOME.
Don't go out.
Your hair won't get wet.
That was good one,
wasn't it?
Know what, vito?
I got a 2-seater,
So you can just jump
right on with me.
Fucking shit!
Who's going to marry you
with a mouth like that?
2 months later,
she married a sicilian guy
Named tony.
And tony didn't make too big
of a hit with the family.
Now, the vietnam war
was raging full force.
Guys from the neighborhood
Were coming home in boxes
every week.
We all got letters
in the mail
And had to go to
the draft board to sign up,
So we were about to do what
was right for our country.
You know,
I just developed
A theory on life.
Oh, yeah?
What's that?
Ok, listen, because
it's very complicated.
First you're born,
And you're like a baby,
a child.
And then you start
to mature a little
After you hit
your "adio-lescence."
Then you grow old.
And then
you grow older.
And then you die.
And that's it.
Rocky sav, no offense,
But that's the stupidest
fucking thing I ever heard.
Rocky:
ALL RIGHT, LAUGH,
But if you stop
and think about it,
It makes
a lot of sense.
Nearly a thousand
18-year-olds
From every part
of the city were there.
Getting a load
of these guys,
I figured we could win
the vietnam war
In about 15 minutes.
Quiet down!
Quiet down in here!
Hey, rocky, whoa!
When you going
to grow up?
Quiet down,
you shitheads!
Street trash
motherfuckers!
Marrone. This guy
looks tough.
Yeah, he looks
real tough,
Don't he, Frank?
Yeah.
Sergeant: ALL RIGHT!
As of this minute,
All of you here
Is now the property
Of the united states
government!
Now, if anybody here
Has been in jail...
Who is out on bail...
Please move to the right
side of the auditorium!
The whole fucking room
got up.
You got to be
shitting me.
Excuse me, sir?
Excuse me?
I really don't think
it's fair
That we got to take a test
that we didn't study for.
It's a goddamn
urine examination, boy!
I'm sorry.
I misunderstood.
I thought it was
something else.
What's your name, boy?
Pesce.
Frank pesce, sir.
You know, pesce
means fish in italian.
I don't give a good
god damn what it means!
I'm sorry, sir.
Is there something
wrong with you, boy?
No, n-n-not that
i'm aware of, sir.
You got
a high school diploma?
No, sir.
You ain't got no
high school diploma?
No, sir.
No diploma.
I think
he likes you.
Ok,
cover your left eye
And read line 7
on the chart.
"Tagglethorp."
Get out of here.
All right.
Pesce!
Frank pesce!
Where the hell
is Frank pesce?
Pesce!
Frank pesce, get the
hell over here, boy!
Yes, sir?
Did I not ask you
If you had
a high school diploma?
Yes, sir,
you asked me that.
I remember you
asking me that.
And what
did you tell me?
That I didn't have one.
According to my files,
You have
a high school diploma.
Well, yeah, I got one...
Just not on me.
You get the hell up there
and see the psychiatrist.
Move it, boy!
Get the hell up there!
You got 4 cards
in your hand--
I don't know
what I should do.
It's too early
in the game.
You don't want
to build it up the back,
Then you wind up
in trouble.
You going
to tell me?
Here comes
general custer.
Jesus. Come here, Frank.
I want to talk to you.
10 million guys are
tryin' to beat the draft,
And only you
can get away with it.
What do you mean?
You see this letter?
Know what it says?
It says the united states
government
Thinks that you are
a calculated risk.
Is that good or bad?
It means that they
think you are nuts.
So now the army knows
What the whole
neighborhood knows.
You're fucking crazy.
I'm very sorry
i'm letting you guys down
By not stepping
on a land mine.
What's so funny?
I'm supposed to go to all
my friends in the neighborhood
And say that
my son's nutjob--
That's why
he's not in the army? Huh?
You got to have
mental illness, right?
And i'll tell you
something else--
You're ruined!
You'll never get
a city job! Never!
Oh, excuse me.
I'll just get a rope.
I'll hang myself.
Mentally disqualified.
This reflects
on the whole family.
Frank:
SO I GOT OUT OF THE WAR,
But I knew it
was no accident.
It was my lucky star.
All right,
wait a minute.
I'm trying to figure
out what I got here.
What do you have
to figure out?
The Righteous Brothers:
♪ TALKIN' ABOUT MY DREAM ♪
Frank:
MY DAD WAS WRONG.
I did end up getting
a city job,
And it ended up being
The luckiest thing
to happen to me yet.
And it would show itself
in the face of maria rios.
♪ she's my groovy
little baby, yeah ♪
♪ little latin
lupe lou ♪
♪ ba ba ba ba
♪ a-shake it, shake it,
shake it, lupe... ♪
10 train
30.
Ma'am...
They call it
10 train
Because it leaves
10.
Oh.
You thought
that that
Was the number
of the train.
I see.
What an idiot.
No, no, no.
45.
Ma'am...
Trust me.
On my mother's eyes,
The train to pelham
30.
I don't care.
I don't care!
All right.
I tell you what...
Why don't you come
45,
And if the fucking thing
starts moving,
Jump on it!
Jerk.
Frankie,
you're bad.
You know you got
the most beautiful eyes?
Cut it out,
Frankie.
We're going to
get caught.
We're not going
to get caught.
Come on,
I own this place.
♪ whaah! ♪
♪ one more time ♪
♪ oh, come on,
come on ♪
♪ come on ♪
Frank, Sr.:
ALL RIGHT, LOOK.
I want to...
I want to make an announcement.
A family announcement here.
I'd like to congratulate
my youngest son Frankie, jr.,
Who bears my name,
for having been fired today.
Leave him alone.
What are you,
kiddin'?
You held that job
for what--8 months?
That's a record with you.
I'm pointing out
your progress.
Dad, I didn't
like that job anyway.
Besides, I got
a new angle on my life.
I can't wait
to hear this.
Yeah, me, too.
Shut up!
While I was
working there,
I was thinking,
you know,
I never had to look
at the board.
I always knew which
trains went where.
I knew every
schedule by heart.
You know what
that means, right?
Yeah.
You got a natural talent
for useless information.
No! It means I got
a good head for numbers.
Maybe I could be
an accountant or something.
That's a terrific idea,
Frankie.
You can't do that
on account.
On account of what?
On account of
you're a moron!
Oh, stop it!
If they make you
a detective,
Anything is possible,
you hard-on.
Hey,
don't curse.
Can I shoot him
for saying that?
Now, hold it. Hold it.
I got something
very serious to say here.
I've been thinking
about that lawn out there.
Bluegrass of kentucky--
what do you think?
I got a relative
in kentucky, pop.
Shut up! What
the hell is it?
It's the best
grass there is.
Grass is grass, pop.
You know, you don't know
a damn thing
About anything
do you?
Oh, marrone! Enough
with this lawn already!
Yeah, you're driving
everybody crazy
With that lawn.
Oh, yeah?
What happened, tony?
Got dressed
in a hurry tonight?
You left your shirt home?
Why don't you ask her?
She hasn't done
the wash in a week.
What?
What do you mean,
"her," "she"?
Her name's madeline.
And what is she,
your servant?
Oh, yeah, like i'm
not your servant?
That's different.
Ha. How's it
different?
It's different,
that's all.
Pop, could you just not
start tonight, please?
Ma, thanks
for the spaghetti.
It was great.
What is this, eat and run?
Where you going?
I'm going out.
Can't you tell?
Where you going?
I got a date.
With who?
With a girl.
Hmm. What girl?
Vito:
MARIA.
Who's maria?
You know the spanish girl
from spanish harlem,
The one you told him
to stay away from?
3 months he's
been a detective,
And already, he's
narcing on everybody.
Hey, he's right.
Ma, you know
where my gun is?
Frankie, I told you
to stay away from her.
Dad, she's
a nice girl.
Did you see my service
revolver around?
I'm late.
Look, I don't care
how nice she is, ok?
She's spanish.
She's a puerto rican,
And historically,
puerto ricans hate italians.
You go up to spanish harlem,
you're gonna get hurt.
Where's my gun?
Enough with the gun!
What, do I got to do
everything around here?
I got to find
your gun?
Maybe I should ride
in the car with you?
Dad, her brother jesus
Loves me like a brother,
all right?
Do what you want.
Bye.
Hey, jesus,
how you doing?
Quit fucking
with my sister!
Help me.
Help me!
Is this
a catholic hospital?
I'm a catholic.
If i'm going to die,
I want to die
in a catholic hospital.
Dr. Puccini
wants to talk to you.
It's nothing serious.
It's just a little problem.
He just wants to talk
to you just for a minute.
You all right?
Looks good, huh?
How are you, Frank?
What it is? I'm going
to be ok, ain't i?
God was good to you
on this one.
If you hadn't
received this injury,
We would
have never caught
This other problem
in time.
What? What is it?
I'm going to be ok,
ain't i?
X-rays show
that you have a tumor
On one of your ribs,
Right below
your stab wound.
A tumor?
That's cancer.
I'm going to have to go
in there and remove it.
What's with his eyes?
Mrs. Pesce: IT'S A LITTLE
CONDITION OR SOMETHING.
Condition?
It's funny.
No, it ain't funny.
This guy's going
to cut me open
And look inside of me?
One minute, he's looking
at the air conditioner,
The next minute,
he's looking at me.
Frankie,
you got to calm down.
You got to
take it easy.
This surgeon
is one of the finest
In new york.
He operated
on cousin ernie's lungs.
Cousin ernie's dead.
That couldn't be helped.
He died
of a heart attack.
His lungs were clean.
Announcer on TV:
THE NEPTUNE SOCIETY--
A simple, dignified,
low-cost alternative
To the high-priced funeral,
Wants you to spend
your money on the living,
Not the undertaker...
Oh, yeah, yeah.
Look at that.
That's one of dr. Puccini's
patients up there right now.
What are you
laughing about?
It ain't funny, man.
Now, i'm out of my mind
with depression.
I go see this nun on my floor
for a little spiritual advice
To help me
through all of this.
You know what she says?
Whatever is god's will
is god's will, my son.
The truth is,
that it was cancer,
But I ended up beating it
because they caught it in time.
Needless to say,
I recovered quickly.
Even though
we lived in queens,
I WAS ALWAYS
ON 29th STREET
'cause that's where
the action was.
Tony Bennett:
♪ JUST IN TIME ♪
♪ I found you
just in time ♪
♪ before you came,
my time ♪
♪ was running low... ♪♪
The club was run
by philly the nap,
The local bookmaker
Who smelled like he was
constantly sucking
On a clove
of garlic.
Philly the Nap:
YOU DIDN'T FUCKING BET?
How can you get
such great cards like this
And be so fucking stupid?
God protects
the dumb.
You got
lifetime protection.
How about this one, huh?
How does a guy get stabbed
up in spanish harlem
And have it turn into
the thing that saves his life?
The problem is,
you got the luck.
You were born with it.
The pitiful part is,
You don't know what
the hell to do with it.
Some people are born
with it,
And they know
what to do with it.
Now, if i...
There he
goes again.
Philly the nap,
a narcoleptic.
He would nod out
without warning,
And a second later,
he'd snap out of it.
How long
was I out?
3 1/2 weeks.
You're a wise guy, right?
And you...
Learn what to do
with the luck.
You got it.
Jesus, philly,
Take it downwind,
will you? Phew.
I don't want
that garlic.
Gloria!
What's up, baby?
How you doing?
Frank:
REMEMBER WHAT I TOLD YOU
About the right way
to make it
And the fast way?
The right way wasn't
working out too well for me,
So I decided
to try the fast way.
These heavyweight wise guys
Came up from mulberry street
To set up
a gambling operation.
They chose
the bakery next door
AFTER TALKING
TO BILLY DeWOLF,
The guy who owned it.
Stay
the fuck out!
Man:
HEY, BILLY, HUH?
Frank:
STILL BEING A JERK-OFF,
I went and looked for a job
as a guy at the front door
Instead of looking
for honest employment.
So I talked to jimmy about
getting a job there.
Look,
my name's Frank.
I was told
to talk to you.
Yeah? And by who?
I--i can't say.
You know somebody?
Yeah.
But--but I can't say.
Who do you know?
I told you,
I can't--i can't say.
What the fuck is his name?
Jimmy vitello.
You know, you should
never mention no names.
Never mention names
like that in this joint.
That's a bad thing to do.
Never, never, never say--
You asked me!
Am I nuts,
or did he ask me?
Frank:
ANYWAY, I GOT THE JOB,
And I had
enough money saved
To go in with vito
on a car.
Frank, Sr.: HO! HO! HO!
Who's going
to talk to the guy?
I'm talkin'.
This is bullshit.
You know what?
I want to order this car
before it goes out of date.
I'm going to order
the car!
Let him talk
to the guy.
Don't forget--white
with a white vinyl top,
A rear defroster,
am/fm stereo, tinted windows,
And a tilt wheel.
Vito, shut up,
all right?
FOR THE 200th TIME,
I know how
to order a car!
Just relax!
White with a white
vinyl top.
What's this?
This is not our car,
is it?
Yeah, it's the car.
What are you
talkin' about?
I told you
when you went in there,
White
with a white vinyl top!
The guy said--
I don't care
what the guy said!
I thought it was white.
We're partners on--
I don't want this.
I'm not going
to pay for it, either.
What's wrong
with it?
You stay there!
Come here.
Come here!
You stay over there.
Come here
for one minute.
Look, don't fuck around.
White with
a white vinyl top.
Come--
No. Stay there!
Dad, tell him
to stay there.
What is that?
This is our car.
Come here.
Mungo Jerry: ♪ CHH CHH-CHH UH
CHH CHH-CHH UH ♪
♪ chh chh-chh uh
chh chh-chh uh... ♪
Hey, mr. Pesce.
How you doing?
Everything
all right?
♪ in the summertime
when the weather is hot ♪
♪ you can stretch right up
and touch the sky... ♪
Punk.
Pop!
You know,
a man is judged
By the company
he keeps, Frankie.
That don't bode
to well for you, pop.
You're out here keeping
company with the crickets.
You're a smart ass, huh?
I'm still very capable
Of smacking the shit
out of you if I have to.
I mean, today you're
watching the door.
What are you
going to do tomorrow?
You going to hold
some guy down
While he hits them over
the head with a tire iron?
Dad, it's just
temporary, all right?
I'm saving the money up
So I can do
bigger things.
Yeah, like what?
I don't know.
Frankie, this is it.
This is all there is.
You get a job,
you make a living.
You meet a girl,
you get married,
And you have kids.
There's nothing else
to it.
Pop,
this can't be it.
What if I want to
do something else?
Like what?
I don't know!
Will you quit
asking me?
Look how miserable--
you're miserable.
You are.
You're miserable.
You know
what you got to do?
You got to
find yourself a hobby.
A hobby.
That's right.
You got to get something
That's going
to give you pleasure,
Like me and my lawn--
Get out!
You little bastard!
Have you gone
completely nuts?
Don't hit the cat!
The heat from his body's
burning a hole in my lawn.
Ha ha ha ha.
Isn't it a big difference?
What?
The bluegrass of kentucky.
Different nothing, pop.
I don't notice
any difference.
You don't notice
no difference?
No.
That's because you don't
have the eye, Frankie.
The eye.
What eye?
The eye. The eye.
If you had the eye,
You'd know
what I was talking about.
But obviously you don't
have the eye, Frankie.
Well, pop, I tell you,
I wish I had this eye,
Because then I would know
What the hell
you were talking about.
Well, i'm just listening
to a different drum, Frankie.
So now there are drums.
There's a lot of shit
happening out here,
I tell you.
That's right. The lottery
comes to new york. Take a look.
Yeah, yeah, you and
20 million other people
Seen that today,
all right?
There's always hope, kid.
Not for you, pop.
There's no hope.
Bullshit.
Hi, mom.
How you doing?
Perfect timing.
Get out of there!
What's the matter with you?
Go wash your hands!
You come in
bringing them germs
And sticking them
in the sauce like that!
Hey, out of my chair,
bub. Come on.
Who died
and made you king?
Just get out!
I have
to go to work.
I have a job,
Not like
some people I know.
Yeah? What are you doing,
Staking out
a slumber party?
Where's your father?
He's outside with
the bluegrass of kentucky
And the eye
and the drums.
Frankie, don't give him
a hard time today.
Why not?
He got laid off
from work.
He got laid off?
You heard her.
Would you go call
your father, huh?
Get off your ass
And go call
your father!
All right, i'm going!
That was serious.
We were just getting by
as it was,
And I knew that we were in
for some hard times.
Now, at the same time,
The neighborhood
was going nuts.
Everybody had lotto fever.
Me, I wouldn't have
anything to do with it.
Hey, rocky,
What you going to do
with your millions?
If you don't play,
you don't win.
That's original.
You're turning into
A freakin' rockefeller,
rocky.
Ha ha ha ha ha!
My father could have
probably supported
The new york state lottery
commission all by himself.
He was going
for the big one.
I know it ain't right,
But i'd been collecting
unemployment checks
While I was working
at the club.
It was lucky, too,
Because I picked labor day
to cash that check.
The banks were closed.
The pawn shop
Was the only joint
on the block that was open.
Hey, Frankie,
How are you?
Everything ok?
How's the family?
Good.
Your mother, your father?
Your beautiful sister?
Everybody's fine.
Look, I got to cash
a check.
You got an i.d.?
Irv...
How's my sister,
how's my mother--
You asking me
for i.d.?
Frank, i'm sorry.
That's the way it is.
You got to have
2 forms of identification.
You know
who my father is?
We don't want to have
a misunderstanding.
Hey, hey. Well, ok.
For you, Frankie,
i'll make an exception.
Jeez, thanks, irv.
But you got to buy something.
Minimum of 10 bucks.
I got to buy something?
Yeah.
What am I going
to buy in this place,
What,
a fucking ukulele?
I'm no chase manhattan.
Minimum of 10 bucks.
Irv, I swear to god,
this looks like
The same shit you had
here 20 years ago.
All right, give me
That piece of shit
binoculars over there.
Oh, yeah.
Hey, Frank,
these are beautiful.
Everything's beautiful.
He wants to sell it.
What do you think?
9 bucks.
Irv, come on!
I got to charge you 10.
No.
No, no.
Make up
the difference.
Give me one of them
lottery tickets.
Beautiful.
You got it, Frankie.
You got it.
Everything is a chore
with this guy.
You got a beautiful pair
of binoculars there.
Yeah, beautiful.
There you are.
All right.
1, 2, 3, 4, 5...
Today, irv!
Come on!
Come on, irv, huh?
Come on, irv!
Don't forget
the binoculars.
I ain't going
to forget them.
Cost me 9 bucks.
Ha ha ha ha!
Put it
on layaway.
That was it. I thought
it was such a waste of money,
I never told my father
I bought it.
And then it happened.
I was on the subway
sometime in november.
Holy shit.
I don't believe it.
I'm a finalist
in the lottery!
Right here! I'm a finalist
I'm not kidding!
I'm not kidding! Look!
Wait, wait, wait,
look at this!
Here! Here's the ticket!
I got a shot
at $6.2 million!
$6.2 million!
Yay!
Mom, vito, you'll never
believe what happened!
Mom, vito! Mom, mom!
I'm a finalist
in the new york state lottery!
Are you serious?
Yes! Right there
in the paper!
Oh, Frankie!
They laughed at
christopher columbus!
the wright brothers!
They laughed
at einstein!
Mama, they even
laughed at me.
But nobody's going
to laugh at me
After christmas eve
Because
i'm a finalist
In the new york
state lottery,
And i'm going to win
that $6.2 million,
And i'm going
to spend it!
And, honey, honey,
I'm going to buy you
a beautiful home
With a big lawn
for me.
Frankie, don't worry
about a career,
Not that you'll
ever get one anyway.
Read it, kid.
Answer that.
Who's on the phone?
It's madeline.
Madeline! Madeline!
I'm going to buy you
a washer, a dryer,
Every appliance
you ever hoped for.
Then--
She must have fainted.
Celebration!
Wine!
And what about you,
detective pesce?
What can I buy for you?
Pop, can I talk to you?
Not now. I'm busy spending
my money over here.
Honey, listen to Frankie.
Yes, my baby boy,
who bears my name?
That's exactly
the point, pop.
Yeah? So?
We both got
the same name.
I know. It's my name.
I gave it to you.
But it's my name
in the paper.
What are you trying
to tell me, Frankie?
Pop,
it's my ticket.
What do you mean,
your ticket?
I know. I know.
You don't think i'm going
to share it with you.
Is that it,
you greedy bastard?
It's my ticket. I'll buy you
whatever the hell you want.
You're a riot, kid.
You are absolutely a riot.
For a minute there,
you had me going.
Salute!
Ahh.
What's going on?
Honey,
it's Frankie's ticket.
Yeah, pop.
I went to irv's
to cash a check
'cause the banks
were closed,
And he made me
buy something.
So--so I bought
Binoculars
and a ticket.
You're telling me
you bought one ticket?
I got 8 million tickets
Sitting in
a shoe box upstairs,
And you bought
one ticket.
Yeah, well, pop,
You know, I mean...
I'm lucky.
Could I see
the ticket, Frankie?
Yeah.
You're going to win
This miserable
fucking thing.
You know that,
don't you?
Yeah, well, pop,
you know,
What's mine
is yours.
Yeah, likewise, Frankie.
I got nothin'.
Suddenly, everyone
was my best friend.
Congratulations.
Thank you very much.
♪ how many days ♪
♪ has it been ♪
♪ since I was born ♪
♪ how many days ♪
♪ will I die... ♪
He's a lucky bastard.
Frankie pesce is a finalist
in the state lottery.
Frank:
IT WAS REALLY RIDICULOUS.
I was 1 of 50 finalists.
Everybody was acting like
I'd already won the thing.
Would you bet on
a horse going for 50 to 1?
I wouldn't.
But my friends
were betting on me.
Zippas was convinced
I could do anything.
So he took us down
to mulberry street
To this real big
gambling joint
To see if I could
throw some dice.
♪ tell me why ♪
♪ he's a stranger
in a strange land ♪
♪ just a stranger
♪ tell me why ♪
♪ he's a stranger
in a strange land ♪
Throw the man
the dice.
Go, go, go.
That's too fast,
baby.
Place your bets!
180 grab.
A 9!
How you feel?
I feel kinetic.
Kinetic. I love that word.
I love that word.
All right. We're
going to show them.
3 coming up.
Place your bets.
100 says you don't
make that 9.
Come on.
All right.
A 4!
It's all right.
It's fine.
Let's try
once again.
400 on 9.
Come on,
Frankie boy.
Take their money,
baby.
Take their money.
Come on! Come on!
Hey, hey, hey.
Ain't that louie tucci
over there?
Don't offend him,
Frankie.
He's got his own
graveyard in jersey.
He'll cut your throat then
go out for calzone afterwards.
He don't give a shit, man.
Yeah, fuck him.
I have friends, too.
Hey, how you doing?
Roll the fucking dice,
will ya?
What's with this kid?
He got fucking palsy?
What, are you jerking
off? Let's go!
Relax now,
Frankie.
You can do it.
All right.
Come on.
Ho!
A 9!
Yeah!
Right here!
Let him ride.
Anybody got
any briasci?
Fucking s.i.
Fuck it up,
fat boy.
Then it happened.
I made history.
I was about to do
something
Nobody had ever seen
ever anywhere.
Incredible.
You see this?
Frankie, ba--
Get that fucking kid
outta here.
Gimme an ax, i'll chop
your fucking hands off.
Come on.
It's just a game.
He was really upset.
What are you looking at?
What, you think
this is a fucking joke?
Hey!
I'm just
playing some dice.
Come on.
Come here,
you cock sucker.
Come on!
Come here!
Fucking douche bag.
Hey! Hey!
Come back here!
Say good morning
to vinnie, dad.
Ha ha ha.
You think it's
a big joke, don't you?
What?
Hanging out
with the mob guys
And shooting dice, huh?
What the hell are you
talking about?
You're a legend
on mulberry street.
Frankie fish's kid,
the man with the golden arm...
You know, the golden arm
and head up his ass.
Keep it up.
Watch what happens.
Just relax, all right?
I'm having fun.
It's just recreational.
Ok, sonny, ok.
Don't get yourself killed
before the drawing.
Then you can do
whatever the hell you want.
Great. Thank you.
What the hell is
that smell in here?
Smells like old gym
sneakers or something.
It's pizza.
That don't
look like
No pizza
I ever seen, pop.
Just shut up
and have a slice.
Did you make that?
Did I make it? Do you see
your mother here?
Yeah, I made it.
It cost me a dollar
to make $1.00.
The shit you buy--
7 bucks.
Have a piece.
Come on.
The dough's a little hard.
What's wrong?
What's the matter?
Pop, pop, you get
better pizza in korea.
Who the hell made that,
michelin?
Put it in the trunk
and use it as a spare.
I'm going
to back to bed.
That's the worst pizza
I've ever had
in my life.
The only member
of our family
To appreciate
my father's pizza
Was vinnie.
Obviously, my father's
not the kind of guy
To sit around the house
like a normal person.
The boredom
was driving him crazy.
And remember,
the idle mind
Is the devil's
playground,
And in my father's case,
It was about to become
an amusement park.
Hey.
Where the hell are
you three going, huh?
We're going bowling.
That's right.
Bowling.
Bowling, huh?
You haven't been bowling
since christ left chicago.
Well, maybe
we'll go bowling
And maybe we
won't go bowling.
Maybe we'll do
something else.
But I figured
it would be nice
For a father
to spend the evening
With his sons.
Got a problem
with that?
You are
so full of shit.
Ah, faccia due...
I don't know.
With dad out of work,
Our money situation
was getting worse and worse.
The three of us decided
to get rid of the t-bird
For the insurance money.
Frankie, Frankie.
What?
Wait a minute.
Stand over there.
What are you
talkin' about?
Stand over there.
Turn around.
Come on.
Let's go home.
They found the car
completely untouched,
Except for the damage
my father had done,
Just where we left it
in the bronx.
See, there are times
When you don't want
to be lucky,
But that lucky star keeps on
shining no matter what.
Bowling, huh?
♪ the best things
in life are free ♪
♪ but you can give them
to the birds and bees ♪
To make matters worse,
We had a $500 deductible
on the car.
A broken windshield
cost 380 bucks
And 40 for the tow.
Now we had
to pay 420 bucks
To get the car back
in the shape it was.
We don't--
we don't--
We don't have $420!
Well, insurance
companies
Are not in business
to be taken
By stupid idiots
like you guys.
Oh, yeah? Yeah?
Idiots, huh?
The car really did
get stolen in the bowlin' alley.
I don't want
to get into it again.
Yeah, like
i'm 5'2" and blonde.
The car didn't
get stolen
Because
it's under his name.
You know him with
that lucky curse,
They'll find it no
matter where we hide it.
This is
all your fault.
You know what?
You're full of shit.
I'm full of shit?
Where you going now?
I got something
I got to do, all right?
I paid my cousin leo a visit
in budd lake, new jersey.
Together we figured out
a way to dump the car.
Leo, you stinking crook,
get over here.
Leo! What's the matter
with you?
You know, this stuff
really works.
Forget that shit.
Come here.
Let me
ask you something.
♪ money ♪
♪ that's
what I want ♪
♪ lots of money ♪
Get in there!
♪ that's
what I want ♪
30 days later we were told
to go to the insurance company
To pick up the check.
The month had come and gone
and no one had found the car...
As I was sure
would be the case.
Let's not look like 3
gaboons going in there.
Who says we look
like gaboons?
We look like a family
gonna pick up a check.
Look like a pack
of fucking wild dogs--
That's what we look like.
I'm going in by myself.
You wait out here.
You don't want us
to come in?
Frankie, tell him
what I said.
I'm sorry, mr. Pesce,
but it seems
That nobody's found
your son's car.
Aw, that's too bad.
You know,
my son Frankie...
He's been sick
for the whole month.
You know what
he says to me?
He says, "daddy,
losing my car
Is like losing
my brother."
I mean, the kid's
heartbroken.
Gee, you know,
I feel terrible
about this.
Listen...
Let me make
one more phone call.
Oh, no, no--
Maybe
we'll get lucky.
Yeah. Hi,
this is lucy sills.
I was wondering if
there was anything
New with case, uh...
"102169."
Thanks.
They're checking.
Yeah.
What?
Ivory gold mist?
Uh, no, no. Aqua velva.
Oh, no.
The car. Is it
ivory gold mist,
A ford thunderbird,
License plates
"my way"?
Yes. That's it.
Thank you.
It seems they found
your son's car
Over the weekend in
budd lake, new jersey.
Isn't that wonderful?
I'm so glad I checked.
Budd lake, new jersey?
Budd lake.
...bullshit me.
Automatic, my ass.
Budd lake, new jersey?
Are you fucking crazy?
What the hell
are you talking about?
They found the car
In budd fucking lake,
new jersey!
What a coincidence.
We got family there.
I don't think
the insurance company's
Gonna put that together.
Who'd you go with,
Your cousin leo,
that fucking moron?
You, come!
Drive the car!
Shut the fuck up,
all right?
Get in the car!
I'm getting
in the car.
I ended up selling
the car to my cousin leo.
2 days after the sale,
it got stolen.
But that money
didn't last long.
Now we were hitting
rock bottom.
Frankie,
give me the keys.
Come on, car keys.
Give me the keys.
I got to go out.
Gimme the keys.
I need them.
I'm going
to the garden.
Come on.
Come. Come.
Got any money?
What?!
You got some money?
I need some money.
Dad, not now.
Frankie, look.
I'm way behind here.
What do you got?
I've got $400.
Go get it.
No, dad. What for?
Frankie, I got
a feeling tonight--
I got a feeling
That I can't lose
on a fight tonight.
Please.
You're my partner.
We'll be partners.
Not again, dad.
It's the first time
I ask for money--
All right. I'm going
to get the money.
All right. Hurry up.
Come on.
Of course,
I got him the money.
Frankie, it's
in the blue sock
On the left side
of the drawer.
Believe it or not,
My father actually
won on a fight.
So I went down to the club
To stop him before
he did any more damage.
But philly said my father
doubled his money,
Took the 800 bucks,
put it on a horse.
He got it up to 1,100
And took off
like a bat out of hell
With johnny cake
and joe numbers,
Saying something about
going to yonkers raceway.
What are you doing?
I'm waiting for you.
Is your mother up?
Yeah. She's up.
Aw, christ. I'm
getting out of here.
Hey, what happened?
I lost 400.
Good.
Good. I was
really worried there.
Listen, pop.
Why don't you let me hold
the rest of the money?
There's no money, Frank.
I thought you said
you lost 400.
Right. I lost
the 400 bucks.
You had 1,100
when you left the club.
Yeah, I did.
That means you've
got 700 on you now.
No. I don't have
shit on me now.
How can you lose 400
out of 1,100
And not have anything
on you now?
I lost the 400 bucks
you gave me.
You lost $1,100?
No. I lost the 400
you gave me.
Then where's
the other 700?
It's gone.
You lost it all.
No.
Yeah.
Technically.
Technically?
What "technically"?
You had 1,100
and now you don't have shit!
That means
that you lost 1,100!
I don't count
the other 700.
Oh, you don't count it.
That money ain't real?
It's no good?
It doesn't pay the mortgage,
the gas, the electric.
Look, I don't count it
because it's their money.
You see, I gambled
with their money.
I lost your 400,
But their money
is their money.
You had their money
in your pocket, didn't you?
Frankie...
I'm out
of fucking work!
What the hell
do you want from me?
Besides, what the hell
are you worried about?
You're going
to win the lottery
And then hang out
on the street
And be a jerk-off
for the rest of your life!
How the hell do you know
i'm going to win that lottery?
Even if I do, it's
not included in my plans
I'm going to hang out
on some street corner.
I'm going to do
something with my life.
Yeah? Yeah, like what?
I don't know,
But i'm going
to get a real life.
And what am i?
A fucking
cartoon character?
Oh, shit.
F-Frank.
Frank.
I'm sorry what
I did to youse.
You listen to me,
Frank pesce.
Listen to me good,
huh?
I don't want
to hear this shit.
Just don't you die
on me, you bastard.
That's all. Not now.
Ma, relax.
You're not going
nowhere.
You're going
to get well.
to come home.
I want the house
To stink of them
rotten pizzas
You've been making.
I want you to see
your son Frankie
Just make something
out of his life.
Do you think
I want to live till 106?
I'm not kidding,
Frank.
I'm not kidding.
You and i,
we made a deal.
We made a promise
to each other
To live together
happily ever after.
Antoinette?
What?
Come here.
What did he say, mama?
He said, "keep the
cat off the lawn."
Hey, pops.
Be careful
with him, Frank.
You all right?
He looks good,
doesn't he?
He said
we ruined his lawn
While he was gone.
That's when I knew
he was all right.
He was back to
terrorizing everybody.
I went for the first
available job I could find.
And I got one
Over at sheldon toys
as a sales representative.
Listen, i'm from
sheldon toy company.
I got the greatest
little electric cars
You've ever seen.
These electric cars,
They're incredible.
The kids will go nuts.
You should order 20, 30
because the first day--
Bang! They're out
the door. I'm serious.
I'm not kidding ya.
How many would you like?
♪ you'll look so good
that you'll be glad ♪
♪ you decided to smile ♪
♪ pick out
a pleasant outlook... ♪
It was the best job
I'd had yet.
They even let me order
a company car.
♪ slap on a happy grin ♪
What's this?
It's my new car.
Yeah, white with
a white vinyl top?
It's a company car.
You order a car for yourself,
you get the right color.
Me and you go partners,
you get ivory gold fuckin' mist.
Why not take it to budd lake
and show it to your cousin leo?
Show him the car you shoulda
got the first time.
This car better not be
under my fucking name
With the insurance,
i'm warning you.
Hey, vito...
Looks good, don't it?
Come here
and say that, you fuck.
I'll give you
"looks good."
Come here.
Then about a week ago,
Jimmy vitello
said there was a guy
Who was real interested
in meeting me.
All jimmy would tell me
Was that it had something to do
with my lottery ticket.
Hey, pesce!
Get in the car.
I'm going.
Get in.
Brr.
Ha ha ha ha.
You?
Yeah. Why,
What's wrong
with me?
Well, nothing. I mean...
Last time it looked like
you wanted to kill me.
Naw. That was
just that night.
A lotta guys
get killed
Because people
are in bad moods.
You're a legend down
on mulberry street,
You know that?
What you did that night
with them dice
And everything
else lucky
That's
happening to you.
Got the lottery
ticket on you?
Yeah. Why?
I might be interested
in buying it.
Well, it ain't
for sale, you know?
For 10,000?
You want to
give me 10 grand?
Ain't that
what I just said?
Word is you got
a shot at this thing
With your luck
and all.
Maybe you do
and maybe you don't,
But if you want to sell
and do the right thing
And keep it
in the family,
Remember, i'm with you
and you're with me,
And everybody's
with us, capisce?
Hey, 2 minutes
I know you guys
And already
i'm in the family.
Well, you just
think about it.
These things
Have a way
of working out,
And i'm
easy to find.
I'm hungry.
Are you hungry?
Yeah, i'm hungry.
You hungry?
Absolutely.
I'm hungry.
Me, too.
I'm really hungry.
Get the fuck
out of here.
Frankie!
Frankie, come on,
wake up. Frankie!
What?
Wake up.
What?!
I really think i
nailed it this time.
Oh, no!
Get that out of here!
Not this morning.
Isn't it better,
what you're doing here--
Staying at home,
Away from
these mob guys
And all
those hangouts?
Watch, you'll amount
to something.
You keep your nose
to the grindstone,
And you're
gonna do better
Than that cop
upstairs.
I never heard you talk
like this before, pop.
Sometimes it takes
something like this
To open your eyes.
Frankie, I want to
ask you a question--
When you win
the lottery,
You're not gonna
use that as an excuse
To sit on your ass,
are ya?
I'll tell you
what I want to do.
What?
Don't laugh,
all right?
I'm not going
to laugh.
I think i'm going
to go to college.
How about that?
A college graduate
in the family.
You could
be a doctor.
Why don't you put
the cigarette out, huh?
She worries
about me.
No, no doctor.
What about a lawyer?
You be a lawyer.
Your brother can throw
everybody in jail,
And you can get them all
back out in the street.
Keep everybody busy.
Very funny.
Come on.
First he'd have to
arrest someone.
If he can
find his gun.
That's culture, son.
I forgot
to tell you--
Jimmy vitello
called.
What did he want?
Go down and see him.
Don't make him
feel bad, all right?
I got you, pop.
I got you.
I'll see you, kid.
Have a good one.
All right,
pop.
Get out of here.
I love
you can still sing,
Real good.
Come on.
May I say something?
Well, you know
I got a bad heart.
I know you got
a bad heart.
Well, uh,
you don't want to
Break it, do you?
Oh, Frank.
I would never--
Wait a minute, now.
Wait a minute.
Wait, wait, wait.
Excuse me.
You're crazy,
you know that?
Uh-huh. Uh-huh.
Can I have
this dance?
It would be
my pleasure.
Oh, Frank...
♪ please, won't you
think that I am ♪
♪ unforgettable ♪
♪ too ♪
I went to the club
To kill some time
before the drawing.
It was here that everything
started to fall apart.
Hey, Frankie.
♪ o come,
all ye faithful ♪
♪ joyful and triumphant ♪
♪ o come ye,
o come ye to bethlehem ♪
Well, in a couple
of more hours,
You're gonna find out
if you're a millionaire.
You know I wish you
nothin' but the best of luck,
You lucky
son of a bitch, you.
Thanks, philly.
Hey, richie,
Where's
my hot cider?
It's not hot yet.
You'll let me know
before I die, huh?
Where's Frank pesce?
Uh-oh.
Right here.
Not you, scumbag.
Your father.
Hey. Hey, hey.
Not in the club.
Your old man owes my
uncle a lotta money.
I'm talking to you.
What are you, deaf?!
What the hell are you
talkin' about? What money?
What money?
Hey! Hey! Hey!
You scumbag!
Ho, ho, ho!
What do you
take us for, jerk-offs?
Your father been ducking us
for 3 fucking weeks.
Not here.
Not in the club.
You're fucking
with him,
You're
fucking with me!
You don't have anything
to do with this, jimmy.
Bullshit, man!
You know why
we're here, philly.
You want to start
a war over this?
You come in my club
at christmas eve
And you start
this shit?
Get out of here!
We're coming
to your house tonight.
We're gonna give your
father a christmas present
He'll never forget.
Get the fuck
out of my club now.
Remember who you work for,
you fat fuck!
Get out before I cut
your friggin' nuts off
And have them
with my calimare!
What are you looking at,
you potato-nosed sucker?
He called me a fat fuck.
Guys, go sit down.
Have fun.
It's christmas eve.
Don, sing a song.
Do you know anything
about this?
Your old man's
into tucci for 10 grand.
10 grand?
And he's 3 weeks
behind, all right?
What is he, out
of his fucking mind?
How can he be
3 weeks behind?
Hey, I don't sleep
with your father.
How do I know?
He's got a mortgage,
he's got bills.
He's losing
his ass here.
Talk
to your old man.
You got to help me.
I ain't getting
friggin' involved.
I'll kill
that son of a bitch.
Jimmy, come on,
you got to help me.
Hey, I can't, Frank.
Why not?
I can't, man.
Forget it. All right?
Forget it.
Frankie, Frankie,
i--Frankie.
Fuck.
Oh, thank god, Frankie.
What happened to you?
We're almost late.
We got an hour and a half
to get to the garden.
I was scared stiff.
I thought you was hurt.
No. Everything's
fine, ma.
Where's dad?
He--he's upstairs
getting dressed.
Something wrong?
No. Look...
I been thinking...
I think that I should go
to the drawing alone.
Are you crazy? He hears
that, he'll go nuts.
Frankie, we been
Looking forward
to tonight.
I know, ma.
I bought a new dress,
for christ's sakes.
Frankie,
what is wrong?
No, ma. I told you
everything's ok,
All right? I just been
thinkin' about it,
And I think I should go
to the drawing alone.
That's it, all right?
Wait a minute. Wait
a minute, wait a minute!
This is the biggest
night of your life,
And you're going
to screw it up?
Shut the fuck up.
Don't tell me
to shut the fuck up!
Don't you guys ever
stop? What's going on?
Frankie
don't want us
To go with him.
You don't
want us to go?
Just a thought I had, pop.
Well, it's a bad thought.
Get it out of your head.
Let's go. It's gettin' late.
No, pop. Forget it.
I'm going by myself.
Come on,
Frankie.
What is it?
We put too much pressure
on you, am I right?
You're afraid
if you don't win,
We'll be disappointed in you?
Forget that shit.
Let's just go
and enjoy ourselves.
Whatever happens happens.
No, pop. This is
what's going to happen.
I'm going up to my room,
i'm getting my ticket,
And i'm going by myself.
Please
get out of my way.
What's the hell's
wrong with you?
You know what this
means to us.
This is the most
important moment
Of our lives,
for christ's sake.
No, pop,
it's not your moment.
It's my moment.
You leave this house
without us,
Win or lose,
don't come back.
With you setting
the example,
I stand a good chance
of losing.
What the fuck
did you say?
You heard.
Frank,
don't!
Are you calling me
a loser?
I'm not a loser!
Have it your way, dad.
All right!
You're a winner!
Is that what you
want to hear,
You're a winner?
What the hell did you do
that was so great
Except gamble away
everything you ever owned,
Including
your own business.
I stayed.
That's what I did.
I stayed for 35 years.
I stayed and raised
a family for 35 years.
I did anything
I had to do
To keep a roof
over our heads.
That's what
the fuck I did!
You stayed, huh?
Big fucking deal.
You stayed? That's what
you're supposed to do.
It would be better
if you left
Rather than put up
with your shit my whole life!
You squashed every dream I ever
had! It's not bad enough
You pissed your own dreams
against the fuckin' wall--
You took me down with you!
You don't know shit
about my dreams,
Not a fucking thing
about my dreams.
You think I gambled
my business away?
You don't know
What the fuck you're
talking about.
I loved my business.
It was the only thing
that I fucking owned!
I didn't gamble it away.
They took it away!
That's your fucking
big explanation?
It's the same
old shit, dad.
You know something, son?
We were doing
pretty damned good
Until you came along.
You know,
I didn't want you.
Your mother did,
And she nearly died
having you,
You sorry
son of a bitch,
And I borrowed the money
To keep you
and your mother alive.
Keep your fucking hands
off me.
I got down
on my fucking knees
And begged louie tucci
to give me the money
To pay off
the hospital bills,
And when I couldn't
pay it back,
He took control of
my company and my life!
You get this straight,
You ungrateful
son of a bitch,
I am not a loser!
You get your
fucking hands off me.
I'm not a loser.
I'm not a loser!
Oh, Frankie.
This ain't right,
Frank.
I'm not a loser!
I am not a fucking loser!
Please, Frank.
♪ fall on your knees ♪
Jerk.
♪ o hear ♪
♪ the angel voices ♪
♪ o night ♪
♪ divine ♪
♪ when christ was born ♪
♪ o night ♪
♪ divine ♪
♪ o night... ♪
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
What do you want?
I'm looking for tucci.
Do you know where he is?
No. He ain't here.
Who the hell are you?
I work for him. Want to
see my fuckin' resume?
I haven't got time
to screw around.
You can't see him. Who
are you? Come over here.
Look, my name is Frank pesce.
Tucci wants to buy
a lottery ticket that I have.
Couple weeks ago,
he offered me 10 grand.
Yeah, yeah, I know all
about that. Hurry up.
I'm freezing
my balls off.
I want to exchange
the ticket
For what
my father owes him.
But he's got to promise me
that he won't hurt him.
All right.
You wait here.
You wait right
here.
All right.
It sounds fair.
You got the ticket
on you?
Yeah. I got it.
Let's have it.
Buon natale, kid.
So that's that.
I guess tucci's
a very happy guy tonight
Because he won
6.2 million bucks.
But I saved my father.
Hey, I had to do
what I had to do,
You know what I mean?
Then I went down
to the gordon,
Check the results.
Lucky me, huh?
The rest you know.
I went crazy
down at the church.
You guys picked me up
and you brought me here.
Do what you want with me.
I just want to go home
And make sure that
my father's all right.
Go on home, boy.
Let's forget
it ever happened.
Tolan.
Yes, sir?
Give him a hand.
Take him home.
Anything else he needs.
Thanks, guys.
Frank...
You're no mammalucco.
Thanks, sarge.
God bless, father lowery.
Hey, Frank, want us
to walk you up?
No. I'll be all right.
Hey, Frank...
Merry christmas.
Thank you.
Hey, Frankie,
congratulations.
We heard about you
on tv.
This is my girlfriend
sheila.
She's been dying
to meet you, Frankie.
This is so great.
Oh, god bless you,
Frankie.
Mom, listen to me.
Mom, we got problems.
I got to talk to dad.
Where is he?
He's in the kitchen.
He's making a pizza.
We're having a party.
Everybody's here.
Yay, Frankie!
My hero is right here.
Yay!            yay!
Yay!
Ma, everybody's here.
Get rid of them.
Of course they're here.
What's the matter
with you?
I knew you were
gonna win!
The man of the hour
finally comes home!
Congratulations, son.
Yeah! All right!
Excuse me.
Oh!
What the hell
are you doin' here?
I thought we
straightened this out.
I don't know
What the fuck you're
talking about.
Excuse me. Excuse me.
Excuse me here.
Can I say something
here, louie?
I want everybody
to hear this.
Tucci, I can't borrow
money off you anymore.
You want to know why?
My son Frankie's
a millionaire,
And he's choosy
who I borrow money from.
There's something
I got to tell you.
Frank, you're not going to
ruin my moment, are ya?
I've been waiting
my whole life for this.
I'd like
to say something.
I said some bad things
To my son Frankie
earlier tonight,
Things that
i'm sorry I said.
Me and my kid,
we're big dreamers.
But my problem is
That most of my dreams
didn't work out.
And I think I stepped on
a lot of Frankie's dreams.
You know,
you get a little older,
You get harder
and you get harder.
Sometimes you forget
what's important.
But today...
One of my dreams
came true.
I found out why my son
Frankie was born.
What is this,
a fucking christening?
Where's my money?
Tucci...
You know what's in here?
Huh?
$10,000.
That's what I owe you.
Vito, give it to tucci.
Give it to him. Go on.
No. You don't
owe him anything.
Merry christmas,
pesce.
Likewise, louie.
What are you doing?
I owe him money.
Hey, hey!
You can't take that!
I owe it to him.
He can't take that money!
He can't take that money.
He loaned me the money.
I owed it to him.
I paid him.
Dad...
I heard that you
were in trouble.
So I gave tucci
the ticket.
You gave tucci
the ticket?
I gave tucci the ticket.
You gave him the ticket.
I gave him the ticket.
You didn't
give him the ticket.
Did you give him
the ticket?
Pop, for christ's sake,
Don't do one of these
in front of everybody.
I gave the ticket away
at the restaurant.
I gave it
to one of his goons.
I got a call
from philly the nap.
He told me what happened
at the club tonight.
You're my son.
I'm your father.
So I figured out
what you were going to do.
The guy you gave
the ticket to?
Big friend of mine.
Frankie...
You gave the ticket...
Back to yourself.
What?
We got it.
We got it!
You got the ticket?
Right here!
You got the ticket.
He's got the ticket.
Where...
Where'd you
get the money?
WHERE'D I GET THE MONEY,
THE 10 Gs? JIMMY V...
Am I good for the 10 g?
You got it, mr. Pesce.
This one
you're going to love.
Oh, no.
I can't eat that.
Come on.
Get in there.
Have a piece.
No! No!
Put her there.
God bless you.
Buon natale, kid.
You bastard.
What the hell did you say
to those guys in the car?
I wished them
a merry christmas.
Ha ha ha!
Thank you.
♪ peace on earth
and mercy mild ♪
♪ god and sinners... ♪
Frankie.
Hey, pop.
This is yours.
Frankie...
Did you know the first
time I saw you,
You made me cry?
What you did tonight
was great.
I want to thank you
for it.
It's just a good thing
That you're smarter
than me.
Uh-uh.
No, Frank, I ain't
smarter than you.
I'm just older.
You know you said
Some beautiful things
in there tonight.
But would you finish...
Saying what you
started saying in there?
What?
You know.
About why I was born.
I don't know.
Why don't
you go out there
And find out
for yourself?
From time to time,
I think back on rocky sav's
theory of life.
You know--you're born,
you grow old, and you die.
Maybe that's all
there is to it,
And we just keep
making it more complicated
Than we need to.
My father's gone now,
But I remember
how years later
When we were up at
the new house on glencove,
Overlooking his new lawn
of kentucky bluegrass
About half the size
of a football field,
I said to him,
"I guess there's a happy
ending for us after all."
"Happy ending," he said.
"I wouldn't have it
any other way."