# [ Hip Hop ]
# BOW-WOW #
WHAT'S UP, CATS?
GODDAMN.
IT'S A MOTHERFUCKIN' DOG HOUSE.
# IF IT AIN'T CHRONIC DON'T BLAZE IT U #
# AND IF IT AIN'T A CHEVY
DON'T RAISE IT UP #
# YOU KNOW WE KEEP IT BANGIN'
DON'T FAKE THE FUNK #
# SO ALL THE REAL NIGGAS
STAY GANGSTA'D UP #
# WE MAKIN' PAPERS SUCKAS
ONLY CLAIM TO TOUCH #
# BY STICKIN' TO THE SCRIPT
AND NEVER CHANGIN' UP #
# YOU KNOW WE KEEP IT BANGIN'
DON'T FAKE THE FUNK #
# KEEP IT REAL, MOTHERFUCKERS
STAY GANGSTA'D UP #
YO, WHAT'S UP, Y'ALL?
MY NAME IS ROBERT DOUGLAS.
Y'ALL CAN CALL ME ROB.
BORN AND RAISED
IN SOUTH CENTRAL LOS ANGELES...
LA-LA LAND.
GOT A COOL FAMILY, TOO.
MOMS, SHE'S
A BEAUTIFUL WOMAN.
POPS, HE A LITTLE CRAZY,
BUT YOU KNOW, THAT'S POPS.
I STILL LOVE HIM.
AND MY LITTLE SISTER,
SHE GET ON MY NERVES,
BUT THAT'S MY LITTLE SISTER.
THIS IS L.A.,
LAND OF OPPORTUNITY.
YOU CAN BE ANYTHING.
I COULD BE
A BASKETBALL PLAYER...
I GOT A KILLER "J."
FOOTBALL PLAYER.
I'M A FOOL ON THE BASEBALL
FIELD, TOO.
YEP.
BUT I THINK IT'S TIME FOR ME
TO SETTLE DOWN.
GET ME A NINE TO FIVE,
YOU KNOW WHAT I'M SAYIN'?
GO TO WORK,
WORK HARD,
COME HOME
TO MY BEAUTIFUL GIRL JUANITA.
THAT'S WHAT
I'M GONNA DO, TOO,
SOON AS I GET OUTTA HERE.
[ Buzzer Sounding ]
[ Men Chattering ]
# I STAY GANGSTA'D UP #
# 'CAUSE IT JUST
LIVES IN ME #
# AND WHEN I'VE SEEN ENOUGH #
# I GUESS THAT'S WHEN
I'LL BE SOMEBODY #
# ONCE SAID FROM WILLIE C
NIGGA, DON'T SPEAK ON ME #
[ Announcer ] CHANNEL SIX...
NEWS BEFORE IT HAPPENS. WITH
JERRY DUNPHY AND TRICK TURNER.
FROM THE DESERT TO THE SEA
TO ALL OF SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA,
A GOOD AFTERNOON.
BACK TO YOU, JERRY.
OUR TOP STORY
THIS AFTERNOON...
A CALIFORNIA MAN WAS SENTENCED
TO A MINIMUM OF 25 YEARS...
FOR STEALING A SLICE OF PIZZA.
[ Man ] DAMN!
A SLICE OF PIZZA?
WHAT KIND OF SHIT IS THAT?
NEXT IT'LL BE FARTIN'
IN PUBLIC.
ALREADY GOT TWO STRIKES.
YEAH, THAT'S RIGHT, NIGGA.
YOU ABOUT TO GET OUT.
BUT YOU FUCK UP AGAIN,
YOU GONNA BE RIGHT BACK
IN THIS MOTHERFUCKER,
WASHIN' MY DRAWERS
FOR THE REST OF YOUR LIFE, BOO.
WHY YOU SEX PLAY ME?
THE LAW PROVIDES THAT
THE PENALTY FOR TWO-TIME
OFFENDERS WILL BE DOUBLED,
AND THREE-TIME OFFENDERS
WILL BE PUT BEHIND BARS
FOR A MINIMUM OF 25 YEARS.
I DON'T CARE IF THEY'RE
CAUGHT ROBBING A BANK,
BURGLARIZING SOMEONE'S HOME
OR STRONG-ARMING
A SLICE OF PIZZA.
THAT'S RIGHT.
FUCK UP AGAIN, ROB,
AND THAT'S YO' ASS.
[ Thinking ]
EVERYBODY ELSE SEE THAT,
OR AM I TRIPPIN'?
[ Buzzer Sounds ]
MAN, I'M GLAD I'M GETTIN'
THE HELL UP OUTTA HERE.
FOOLS LOOKIN' AT ME
LIKE THEY WANNA KILL ME.
DAMN.
# [ Hip Hop Playing
On Stereo ]
HEY, SUNSHINE.
GET OUTTA MY FACE!
WELL, FUCK YOU, THEN!
YOU KNOW WHAT I'M SAYIN'?
FUCK Y'ALL!
[ Korean Man ] YOU DON'T COME
TO MY STORE NO MORE!
I'LL BLOW THIS MOTHERFUCKER UP.
YOU STAY OUT!
YOU GANGBANGER!
WORD.
YOU CRAZY, NIGGA.
[ Laughs ]
MAN, FUCK THEM.
THIS NIGGA, MAN...
UH, UH, UH.
T-BIRD.
WHY YOU DIDN'T GET AT ME
ABOUT THAT SHIT, DOG?
MAN, NIGGA, MAN,
I JUST GOT THROUGH
CALLING YOUR HOUSE.
MMM.
IS THAT RIGHT?
YEAH, MAN.
OH, SHIT!
AAAH!
AW, DAWG!
NEXT TIME YOU BETTER
LEAVE A MESSAGE, NIGGA.
WHAT'D I DO?
[ Whimpers ]
OH, WHAT'D I DO?
NEXT TIME
LEAVE A MESSAGE.
# [ Hip Hop On Stereo ]
[ Man ] I DON'T WANT TO
HEAR THAT BULLSHIT.
ALL YOU GOT TO DO...
IS TELL YOUR GIRL
TO BRING THE SHIT IN.
WHAT IS YOU TALKIN' ABOUT?
I'M NOT HAVIN' MY BRIDE
DO NO-THIN'.
NATHAN, YOU HEARD ME?
LOOK, IF MY GIRL
GET CAUGHT,
THEN THAT SHIT GONNA
FALL BACK ON ME.
THEN I'LL BE RIGHT BACK
UP IN HERE WITH Y'ALL
SORRY ASSES.
AND I'M NOT ABOUT TO WASTE
MY LAST STRIKE...
ON SOME PENNY-ANTE BULLSHIT
FOR ANOTHER NIGGA.
YOU FEEL ME, MAN?
YOU KNOW WHAT I'M SAYIN'?
NOW, YOU GONNA TELL
THAT LITTLE BITCH OF YOURS
TO BRING THE SHIT IN,
OR ELSE YO' ASS MIGHT NOT
MAKE IT OUTTA HERE.
YOU STILL GOTTA
WAKE UP TOMORROW, PUNK.
I KNOW.
BITCH-ASS NIGGA.
I'M GONNA STICK THIS NIGGA.
LET ME STICK HIM.
HEY, HEY!
WHAT'S GOIN' ON
BACK THERE?
DOUGLAS!
WHAT THE HELL
YOU DOIN'?
NOT DOIN' SHIT.
# [ Hip Hop ]
WHY THE FUCK
IS THE MUSIC SO LOUD?
DAMN, GIRL!
IT'S MINE!
# [ Stops ]
I DON'T GIVE A FUCK!
# [ Starts ]
DON'T START NO SHIT.
ANYBODY CALL ME?
YEAH.
- WHO?
- T-BIRD!
OH, WELL.
YOU FEED MY DOGS?
I WAS TOO TIRED.
I CAN'T BE ON MY FEET
TRYIN' TO FEED
THEM WILD-ASS ANIMALS.
CAN'T BE
ON YOUR FEET ALL DAY.
WELL, HOW ABOUT THIS...
[ Shouts ]
WILD-ASS ANIMALS.
LOOK AT THAT.
GET OFF OF ME!
WILD-ASS ANIMALS.
YOU GONNA SQUISH THE BABIES.
BABIES?
WHAT YOU MEAN, BABIES?
THIS BABY AND THAT BABY.
OH, I'M FAT? I'M FAT.
I'M FAT, HUH?
[ Laughing ] ALL RIGHT, MOVE!
WHY DON'T YOU
MAKE SOME TACOS?
[ Chuckles ]
[ Clears Throat, Spits ]
Y'ALL BETTER
EAT THIS SHIT.
COME ON!
COME ON.
I'M NOT SURE
IT'S ENOUGH.
[ Cell Phone Rings ]
[ Mumbling ]
HELLO?
[ Operator ] WILL YOU
ACCEPT A COLLECT CALL FROM...
[ Rob ] ROB DOUGLAS.
TO ACCEPT,
PLEASE PRESS ONE.
[ Dogs Growling ]
HELLO?
MAN, WHAT YOU DOIN'?
SOUND LIKE YOU OUT THERE
WITH THEM DAMN MUTTS.
NIGGA, MY DOGS AIN'T NO MUTTS.
THEY IS KILLERS,
AND THEY GONNA BE
ALL IN YO' BITCH ASS, NIGGA.
FUCK THEM DOGS, NIGGA.
AIN'T NOBODY THINKIN'
ABOUT THEM DOGS.
I'M THINKIN' ABOUT
SOME HOOCHIE-COOCHIE.
[ Laughs ]
- HEY, YOU GOT THREE-WAY, RIGHT?
- YEAH, YOU WANNA CALL
YOUR MAMA?
NIGGA, DIAL THIS NUMBER.
DAMN.
WHAT'S THE NUMBER?
213-555-7249.
STOP.
[ Dog Whimpers ]
# [ Hip Hop ]
[ Phone Rings ]
WHO'S THIS?
[ Rob ]
IT'S ME!
- WHERE YOU AT?
- WHAT YOU MEAN,
WHERE I'M AT?
I'M IN JAIL. YOU KNOW
I DON'T GET OUT
TILL LATER ON.
OH. WELL, I DON'T KNOW WHAT
YOU'RE CALLIN' ME FOR, 'CAUSE
I DON'T HAVE GRANDPA'S CAR...
AND I CAN'T COME
AND PICK YOU UP.
GIRL, QUIT TRIPPIN'.
YOU KNOW
I'M GONNA BE OVER THERE
AS SOON AS I GET OUT.
MY GIRL CAN'T WAIT
TO SEE A NIGGA.
I'M GETTIN' READY...
TO HAVE PUSSY ON MY MIND,
PUSSY ON MY FACE,
PUSSY ON MY BREATH.
HEY, I'M GONNA HAVE
ENOUGH PUSSY TO MAKE
A PUSSY POT PIE.
[ Chuckles ]
PUSSY, PUSSY, PUSSY.
MAN, PHONE CHECK, PUNK.
NIGGA, FUCK YOU,
PHONE CHECK!
HEY, I'M ABOUT TO GET OFF
THIS PHONE BEFORE I HAVE TO
FLASH ON THIS NIGGA.
TONE, BE AT THE PHONE BOOTH
BY THE TAXIS AT 4:00.
IF YOU AIN'T THERE,
I'M GONNA JUMP IN ONE.
JUMP IN ONE THEN.
DON'T BE THREATENIN' ME,
MOTHERFUCKER.
SERIOUSLY, DOG.
I AIN'T TRYIN' TO BE
AROUND THIS SHITHOLE...
A MINUTE MORE
THAN I HAVE TO.
JUANITA-BOO,
I'LL SEE YOU LATER ON.
- ALL RIGHT.
- SIMP-ASS NIGGA.
I'M GONNA
SEE YOU TOO, JUANITA.
[ Chuckles ]
TONE, MAN, PICK ME UP LATER ON,
AND DON'T BE LATE FUCKIN' AROUND
WITH THEM HO'S, MAN.
I'LL BE THERE. OH, SHIT.
THAT'S SOME HONEY
FOR TEDDY BEAR.
OH! OH!
[ Tires Screeching ]
HEY, HEY!
[ Honks Horn ]
I MEAN...
[ Scoffs ]
TEDDY BEAR.
YEAH!
SHE GONNA DEFINITELY
LET ME SPLIT THAT.
MM-HMM, SHE IS FINE.
HEY!
HEY, SUNSHINE.
[ Tires Screeching ]
I AIN'T MEAN TO BLOW
THE HORN AT YOU,
SUNSHINE.
COME ON NOW, BABY.
I'M JUST TRYIN'
TO GET ACQUAINTED.
DAMN. OH, YOU AIN'T
GIVE A NIGGA A MINUTE?
I MEAN, DAMN.
[ Sighs ]
TO BE HONEST WITH YOU,
I JUST LOST MY NEW JOB
BECAUSE MY BOSS
WAS AN ASSHOLE.
- OH, YEAH?
WHERE WAS YOU WORKIN' AT?
- THE Chick'N'Strip.
OH, YEAH?
I THINK I KNOW THAT NIGGA
THAT RUN THAT CLUB.
- UH, UH...
- CHUCK?
YEAH, CHUCK.
I KNOW CHUCK.
I CAN GET YOU YOUR JOB BACK
IF YOU WANT IT.
- YOU GOT IT LIKE THAT?
- I GOT IT JUST LIKE THAT.
- SO, WHERE YOU
ON YOUR WAY TO NOW?
- HOME.
YOU SHOULD LET ME
GIVE YOU A RIDE,
BECAUSE IT'S ALL KIND OF...
VICIOUS CRIMINALS
AND THUG-ASS NIGGAS
AROUND HERE.
I ONLY LIVE A BLOCK AWAY.
I DON'T GIVE A FUCK IF YOU
LIVE IN BEIJING, BABY.
# I'LL TAKE YOU THERE #
[ Laughs ]
ALL RIGHT,
BUT YOU CAN'T STAY.
# [ Rap ]
# POP THAT PUSSY, BABY
POP THAT PUSSY, BABY #
# POP, POP, POP PUSSY
POP, POP THAT PUSSY #
[ Coughing ]
# I WANNA ROCK, I WANNA ROCK
I WANNA ROCK, I WANNA ROCK #
[ Rob Narrating ]
AH, THE LAST TIME I EVER GET TO
WALK THIS CELL BLOCK.
I SURE AM GONNA
MISS THESE FOOLS.
HOMEY, I'M GONNA MISS Y'ALL.
HEY.
WHAT'S UP, BRO?
HEY, WHAT'S UP, MAN?
Y'ALL ALWAYS BEEN GOOD TO ME.
TODOS LOS DIOS, MAN.
SLAP THAT ASS
FOR TEDDY BEAR, BABY.
OOOH!
- OOH. OOH.
- AAH.
# GO, GO, GO, GO
GO, GO, GO, GO #
SLAP THAT ASS ONE MORE...
HEY, J.J., I NEED YOU
TO DO ME A FAVOR, NIGGA.
ROB GETTIN' OUT OF JAIL TODAY.
HE PROBABLY...
DOWN AT THE COUNTY RIGHT NOW,
SO AIN'T NO TIME TO WASTE.
I NEED YOU TO BE
IN THAT CORNER
FOR ME, BABY.
GO DOWN THERE AND PICK HIM UP.
I GOT CAUGHT UP
IN SOME BULLSHIT, NIGGA.
[ Moaning ]
DO THAT...
OH, SHIT!
DO THAT FOR ME, NIGGA.
GO DOWN THERE.
AIN'T NO TIME TO WASTE, NIGGA.
OH, SHIT. SLAP THAT ASS.
SLAP THAT ASS.
YEAH, JUST LIKE...
YOU'LL BE BACK,
FOOL.
HA!
HEY, COME HERE,
MOTHERFUCKER!
COME HERE!
HEY! HE SAVED YOUR ASS.
HE SAVED YOUR ASS.
YOU'LL BE BACK!
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
ROB HAS LEFT
THE BUILDING!
FUCK ALL OF Y'ALL
VERY MUCH.
I'M GONNA SEE YOU AGAIN, PUNK.
[ Moaning ]
# LET ME HEAR YOU SAY HEY
HEY, PEOPLE, HEY #
BACK, BACK, BACK DOWN.
BACK DOWN, BACK DOWN.
YES. YES.
MM-MMM.
TEETH, TEETH, TEETH.
YES. MMM.
# DOO-DOO BROWN
DOO-DOO BROWN #
# DOO-DOO BROWN #
# DOO-DOO BROWN
DOO-DOO BROWN #
# DOO-DOO BROWN #
HEY, GIVE ME MY PERSONALS.
I GOT TO GO.
YEAH. UH-HUH.
WHAT'S UP, MAN?
OH, HELL, NAW.
I DON'T...
NO, THIS A WHITE FUCKER'S.
[ Rob Narrating ]
FREE AT LAST. SUN SHININ',
BIRDS CHIRPIN', HOOCHIE CALLIN'.
EVEN A JOB AT McDONALD'S
DON'T SEEM SO BAD.
AS LONG AS I'M NEVER
INSIDE HERE AGAIN.
# [ Hip Hop Playing
On Stereo ]
WHAT'S UP, NIGGA?
WHAT'S UP, HOMEY?
WHAT'S UP, MAN?
WHAT YOU DOIN' UP HERE?
NIGGA, I CAME TO SCOOP YOU UP.
WHAT YOU THINK I'M DOIN'?
LOOK AT YOU.
WHAT THE FUCK
HAPPENED TO TONE?
MAN, YOU KNOW HOW TONE IS.
HE PROBABLY OUT THERE TRICKIN'
WITH ONE OF THEM HO'S, NIGGA.
# SEVENTY DEGREES IN THE WINTER
TROPICAL WEATHER VENDETTAS #
# 'CAUSE L.A. NIGGAS
BE ALL ABOUT THEY JETTA #
# HOOCHIE BITCHES IN B.G.'s
TOO BIG FOR THEY BRITCHES #
# CURVE SERVIN'
THEY DOUBLE UP TO GET RICHER #
# FUCK AROUND AND THEM NIGGAS
COMIN' TO GET YA
AND GET WITH YA #
# JUMP UNTIL SIX HITS YA
DON'T LET THE SUN SHINE #
OH, HEY, NIGGA.
MAN, YOU KNOW I JUST GOT OUT.
I GOTTA GO SEE MY P.O.
CAN'T FUCK AROUND.
THEY TELL YOU
YOU CAN'T SMOKE?
NO.
THEN, NIGGA, YOU BETTA
HIT THIS WEED, BOY.
SHIT. WORD.
GET ME IN TROUBLE
WITH SOME SHIT, NIGGA.
[ Chuckles ]
YEAH.
YO, I LIKE THIS NEW WHIP
YOU PUSHIN', MAN.
WHEN YOU PICK THIS UP?
AW, I JUST PICKED IT UP,
YOU KNOW.
THE MOTHERFUCKER
FLY, THOUGH, RIGHT?
RIGHT, RIGHT, RIGHT.
I'M GLAD I'M UP
OUT THAT MOTHERFUCKER, MAN.
I'M GONNA DO WHATEVER IT TAKES
NOT TO GO BACK TO THAT BITCH.
HEY, UH, WHERE WE
ON OUR WAY TO?
WHY, YOU IN A RUSH
OR SOMETHIN', NIGGA?
NAH, NAH, NAH.
BUT I WANTED TO STOP
AT THE PAY PHONE
SO I COULD CALL MY GIRL.
PAY PHONE?
CELL PHONE, BOY.
WHAT? WHAT?
[ Laughs ]
YOU A BALLER?
YO, NIGGA,
WHAT'S THE AREA CODE?
213, NIGGA.
RIGHT.
DO IT, NIGGA.
[ Mumbles ]
HEY, HEY, CHECK THIS OUT.
HEY. CHECK IT.
HELLO.
WHAT'S UP, GIRL?
WHERE YOU AT?
I JUST GOT OUT.
I GOTTA GO SEE MY P.O.,
THEN I'LL BE RIGHT OVER THERE.
WHERE HAVE YOU BEEN,
MOTHERFUCKER?
[ Chuckles, Clears Throat ]
HEY, LOOK, I'LL BE OVER THERE
IN LIKE AN HOUR.
I PROMISE.
ALL RIGHT. BYE.
MAN.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT THE HELL'S UP
WITH THESE WOMEN THESE DAYS.
NIGGA AIN'T OUT FIVE MINUTES,
ALREADY SHE THINK I'M FUCKIN'
WITH ANOTHER BITCH.
YOU KNOW HOW THESE HO'S IS.
LET ME SEE THAT LIGHT.
I COULD GO
FOR SOME NEW PUSSY, THOUGH.
[ Laughs ]
OOH, NIGGA.
AW, SHIT.
OH, SHIT.
THIS THE LAST THING
A NIGGA NEEDED, HOMEY.
WHATEVER YOU DO, NIGGA,
DON'T LOOK BACK, ALL RIGHT?
[ Siren Sounding ]
NIGGA, I SAID DON'T LOOK BACK!
WHAT THE FUCK, MAN?
FUCK. PUT THE SEAT BELT ON.
[ Cop ] DRIVER, PROCEED
TO THE NEXT EXIT...
AND PULL OVER
TO THE SIDE.
- WHAT, WAS YOU SPEEDIN'?
- NO, NIGGA,
I WASN'T SPEEDING.
- GOT YOUR
DRIVER'S LICENSE, RIGHT?
- YEAH.
THEN WHY YOU TRIPPIN'?
WE JUST SMOKIN' WEED.
IT AIN'T NO FELONY, RIGHT?
- MAN, JUST SHUT THE FUCK UP.
- NIGGA, JUST ACT LIKE NOTHIN'.
ACT LIKE NOTHIN, NIGGA?
I'M GONNA HANDLE THIS.
DAMN.
[ Policeman ]
DRIVER AND PASSENGER!
PUT YOUR HANDS
WHERE I CAN SEE THEM!
DAMN, CUZ.
THEY SWEATIN' US LIKE
WE DONE STOLE SOMETHIN'.
NOW, DRIVER.
WITH YOUR RIGHT HAND,
REACH OUT THE DOOR,
OPEN IT...
AND SLOWLY
EXIT THE VEHICLE.
WHAT'S UP
WITH THIS SHIT, CUZ?
YOU KNOW I GOT
TWO STRIKES ALREADY,
AND MY BLACK ASS AIN'T ABOUT
TO GO BACK TO NOBODY'S JAIL.
- [ Gunshots ]
- OH, SHIT!
MAN, WHAT YOU DOIN'?
[ Policewoman ]
SHOTS FIRED! REQUEST BACKUP
AT 110th AND FLORENCE!
[ Rob Shouting ]
NIGGA, WHAT THE FUCK
IS WRONG WITH YOU?
YOU WANNA DIE?
NIGGA, YOU SAID
YOU WASN'T GOIN' BACK!
I AIN'T MEAN IT LIKE THAT!
PUT YOUR MOTHERFUCKIN'
HANDS DOWN!
[ Whimpering ]
I'M GONNA GET 'EM
UP OFF US!
[ Stammering ]
GET UP OUT OF WHAT?
NIGGA!
OH, SHIT, NIGGA!
HOW THE FUCK YOU GONNA PICK ME
UP FROM JAIL IN A STOLEN CAR?
I GOT TWO STRIKES ALREADY!
YOU MUST BE OUT YOUR
RABBIT-ASS MIND!
OH, SHIT, NIGGA!
WHAT WE GONNA DO NOW, MAN?
WHAT WE GONNA DO NOW?
PLEASE, LORD...
SHUT THE FUCK UP! I'M
GONNA GET US OUTTA THIS!
WHAT?
[ Gunshot ]
OH, HELL, NO.
[ Muttering ]
FREEZE!
[ Panting ]
[ Gunshot ]
THROW OUT YOUR WEAPONS
RIGHT NOW!
- AAAH! OOOH!
- [ Policewoman ]
I GOT HIM!
- I GIVE UP!
- [ Panting ]
[ Yells ]
BIG OLD TITTIES.
HEY, MY ASS, MAN!
I'M GONNA DIE!
I FEEL LIKE I'M DYIN'!
PLEASE, MAN. MY ASS.
I'M GONNA DIE, MAN.
[ Police Radio, Indistinct ]
# [ Mariachi ]
¿QUE QUIERE?
I THINK
HE WENT THIS WAY.
OKAY.
[ Chattering In Spanish ]
I DON'T SEE HIM HERE.
LET'S GO. THIS WAY.
COME ON. COME ON.
ALL RIGHT.
LET'S GO.
# [ "La Cucaracha" ]
[ Shouts In Spanish ]
[ Crowd Cheering ]
[ Rob Shouting In Spanish ]
[ Speaking In Spanish ]
[ Groans ]
[ Groaning ]
[ Woman ]
SORRY.
¿QUE PASO?
HEY, WHAT'S UP,
HOMES?
ALL RIGHT, Y'ALL.
I'M GONNA GET UP
OUT OF HERE.
BEEN HERE TOO LONG.
I DIDN'T PLAN
ON STAYING THIS LONG.
DONE WORE OUT
MY WELCOME.
THANKS.
BE COOL, MAN.
- COME BACK AGAIN, OKAY?
- DAMN. HEY, HEY, HEY!
HEY, MAN.
[ People Chattering ]
ALL RIGHT.
[ Woman ]
ADIOS.
[ Man ] COME BACK
AGAIN SOON, AMIGO.
[ Brakes Hiss ]
# IT'S LIKE
YOU WANNA RIDE WITH ME #
# YOU DON'T EVEN KNOW
WHAT RIDE IS
IF YOU WANNA GET CLEAN #
# YOU WANNA GET DIRTY
YOU WANNA GO LEFT, RIGHT #
# THIS IS WHAT WE DO #
# WELL, IT'S THE KNOCKER #
# PARTY WHILE
I'M WINE DRINKIN' #
# MY RHYMES WILL BUST
A HALLWAY THROUGH
YOUR THINKIN' #
# FORGET THE STRATEGIES
WHEN YOU BATTLE
IT'S INTERNATIONAL #
# RECONCILE
PEOPLE TRY BUT THEY FAIL #
# [ Continues, Indistinct ]
[ Knocking On Door ]
WHO IS IT?
[ Rob ]
IT'S ME.
HMPH.
WHAT'S WRONG
WITH YOU?
WHERE HAVE YOU BEEN?
WHOA, WHOA,
WHOA, WHOA, WHOA.
NOW, I'M A GROWN-ASS MAN.
I AIN'T GOT TO BE
CHECKIN' IN WITH YOU.
OH, WAIT A MINUTE, NOW.
YOU AIN'T GONNA BE
PUTTIN' YOUR HANDS ON...
- [ Snoring ]
- MOTHERFUCKER,
I'M CALLIN' 911.
WAIT, WAIT, WAIT, WAIT.
BABY, BABY, BABY, BABY.
NOW, YOU KNOW
I JUST GOT OUT,
I'M ON PAROLE...
AND THE LAST THING I NEED
UP IN HERE IS THE POLICE.
NOW, I TOLD YOU
I HAD SOME BUSINESS TO HANDLE,
AND THAT'S WHAT I WAS DOIN'.
GIRL, YOU KNOW
I LOVE YOU.
[ Phone Rings ]
IT'S 911.
WELL, LET
THAT SHIT RING.
BUT IF WE DON'T ANSWER,
THEY GONNA COME BY HERE.
[ Nerdy Voice ]
HELLO? YEAH, NO,
THERE'S NO PROBLEM HERE.
I WAS TRYING TO DIAL 411,
MUST HAVE DIALED 911
BY MISTAKE.
YEAH. OKAY, WELL,
THANK YOU FOR BEING
CONCERNED, SERGEANT.
ALL RIGHT.
THANK YOU, CAPTAIN.
BYE.
GIRL, COME HERE.
WHAT'S WRONG WITH YOU?
YOU KNOW I LOVE YOU,
MISS YOU.
NIGGA BEEN
LOCKED UP IN HERE.
WILL YOU STOP?
GRANDPA'S GONNA WAKE UP.
I COULD SLAP MY BALLS
ACROSS HIS OLD-ASS LIPS,
[ Snoring ]
HE STILL
WOULDN'T WAKE UP.
HMM. YOU JUST
A GODDAMN LIE.
[ Spraying Aerosol Can ]
GIRL! DAMN,
WHAT UP WITH YOU?
HEY, WHAT'S UP,
BIG BRO?
SO, HOW LONG YOU PLAN
ON STAYING THIS TIME?
GIRL, YOU NEED TO SHUT
YOUR FAKE, YOUNG,
GROWN AUNT JEMIMA ASS UP.
GOT EYE BOOGERS DROPPIN'
ON THE GRITS AND SHIT.
PROBABLY AIN'T WASHED
YOUR FACE THIS MORNIN'.
[ Snoring ]
WHERE MAMA AT?
YOU KNOW
WHERE MAMA IS.
- UNC!
WHAT'S UP, UNC! UNC!
- [ Snoring ]
GODDAMN.
HEY! HEY!
WHAT? WHAT?
WHAT YOU GOT TO SAY?
WHAT YOU KNOW GOOD?
KNOW GOOD?
HEY, WHAT I KNOW GOOD
COULD BE DETRIMENTAL
TO YOUR HEALTH.
DON'T TRY THIS
AT HOME.
[ Breaks Wind ]
OH, DAMN, MAN!
YOU TRYIN' TO RUN A NIGGA
UP OUT OF HERE AND SHIT.
I'M TRYIN' TO COOK!
DAMN, NIGGA AIN'T BEEN
GONE A YEAR, COME HOME
AND CAN'T FIND SHIT.
NOT EVEN A PAIR
OF DAMN DIRTY DRAWERS.
WELL, IF YOU'D KEEP
YOUR SORRY BUTT OUT OF JAIL,
MAYBE YOU'D FIND YOUR STUFF.
HEY, BOO.
HEY, MAMA.
YOU ALL RIGHT?
WELL, THEN, COME ON.
MM-HMM.
OKAY, HOW LONG YOU PLAN
TO STAY OUT THIS TIME?
YOU KNOW, 'CAUSE YOU WASN'T
EVEN HOME THREE DAYS...
BEFORE THEM POLICE CAME IN HERE
AND BUSTED MY DOOR DOWN...
LOOKIN' FOR YOU,
AND I'M NOT GOIN'
FOR THAT MESS NO MORE.
MAMA, I TOLD YOU, I'M GONNA
STRAIGHTEN UP THIS TIME.
AIN'T GONNA BE NO MORE OF THAT.
I'M THROUGH.
YEAH, I HEARD YOU.
AND THAT'S THE SAME THING
YOU SAID BEFORE YOU WENT
TO JAIL THE LAST TIME.
I TOLD YOU, LAST TIME
WASN'T MY FAULT.
THAT WASN'T MY GUN.
GUN WASN'T YOURS?
WHAT DIFFERENCE
DOES THAT MAKE?
- A GUN IS A GUN.
YOU WENT TO JAIL.
- LET'S JUST LET IT GO.
SEE, YOU KNOW WHAT?
YOU WON'T LISTEN.
A HARD HEAD MAKE A SOFT BEHIND.
THE CALIFORNIA HIGHWAY PATROL
GOT INTO A...
AFTER PURSUING
A STOLEN VEHICLE
ON THE HARBOR FREEWAY.
ONE SUSPECT WAS SHOT
BY OFFICERS...
I'M GLAD YOU'RE HOME.
AND IS LISTED
IN STABLE CONDITION.
MAKE SURE YOU STAY HERE.
THE OTHER MANAGED TO ESCAPE,
BUT WAS CAUGHT ON VIDEOTAPE...
BY THE PATROL CAR
DASH CAMERA.
UH, MAMA, WILL YOU MAKE ME
ONE OF THEM FAMOUS
BREAKFASTS YOU MAKE?
BOY, WHAT ARE YOU DOIN'?
YOU ALREADY MADE BREAKFAST!
YEAH, WELL, YOU KNOW
HOW BEULA IS, MAMA.
GET FOR REAL.
[ Mama ] GET FOR REAL?
[ Rob ]
GIRL CAN'T COOK.
[ Gunshots, Shouting ]
THANK YOU, MAMA.
YOU KNOW I APPRECIATE IT.
[ Breaks Wind ]
OH, MY LORD!
- WAS THAT YOU OR ME?
- [ Phone Rings ]
- SUGAR, WOULD YOU
GET THAT FOR ME, PLEASE?
- [ Mumbles ]
[ Continues Ringing ]
HELLO?
YEAH, NIGGA,
YOU AT HOME,
EATIN' GOOD
AND FEELIN' COMFORTABLE,
HUH, MOTHERFUCKER?
YOU HEAR ME, NIGGA?
WHAT YOU TALKIN' ABOUT?
I'M TALKIN' ABOUT YOU LEFT
A LITTLE HOMEY ALL STUCK,
MOTHERFUCKER.
YOU A WANTED MAN,
MAN, I AIN'T HAD
NOTHING TO DO WITH THAT.
WE WAS SMOKIN'...
WE WAS SMOKIN' WEED,
AND THEN THE NEXT THING I KNEW,
ONE-TIME WAS BEHIND US.
WE GET PULLED OVER,
AND J.J. START BUSTIN'
LIKE A DAMN FOOL.
WHAT THE HELL
I'M SUPPOSED TO DO?
LOOK OUT THE WINDOW.
WHAT YOU WANT ME TO LOOK
OUT THE WINDOW FOR?
KNOCK, KNOCK,
MOTHERFUCKER.
IF ANYBODY SEE YOU
FROM THE HOOD, IT'S ON,
LITTLE MOTHERFUCKER.
YOU HEAR ME?
IT'S ON.
BETTER WATCH YOUR ASS,
MOTHERFUCKER.
[ Dial Tone ]
DAMN. NOW I GOTTA
DEAL WITH THIS FOOL.
WE HAVE LATE BREAKING NEWS
ON THE HARBOR FREEWAY
SHOOT-OUT...
- NOT THIS SHIT AGAIN.
- BETWEEN TWO SUSPECTS
AND C.H.P. OFFICERS...
ON A FREEWAY OFF-RAMP.
ONE SUSPECT WAS SHOT
IN THE BUTTOCKS.
DETECTIVES HAVE BEEN ABLE
TO ENHANCE THE VIDEO FOOTAGE...
WHERE YOUR SISTER AT?
WOULD YOU MIND?
OH, YOU KNOW WHAT?
I GOTTA GET OFF THE PHONE.
WE ROLLING.
[ Phone Beeps ]
JERRY?
DETECTIVES HAVE BEEN ABLE
TO ENHANCE...
- THE VIDEO FOOTAGE FROM THE
DASH CAMERA TO ESTABLISH...
- [ Belches ]
A POSITIVE I.D.
OF THE SECOND SUSPECT,
WHO IS STILL AT LARGE.
YOU JUST SPRAY IT ON.
YOU CAN'T EVEN TELL.
LOOK! LOOK!
WE ARE MOVING TO A DAY
WHEN THE FEDERAL GOVERNMENT...
WILL NO LONGER
DO STATES' BUSINESS.
THREE STRIKES, ROB.
I KNEW YOUR BLACK ASS
WOULD FUCK UP.
- THE F...
- THANK YOU EVERYONE.
THAT'S ALL.
[ Snorts, Swallows ]
- [ Belches, Breaks Wind ]
- EWW! DAMN, UNC.
YOU NEED TO LAY OFF
THE MEDICATION.
GOT YOU SNORTIN'
AND FARTIN' AND SHIT.
IT'S NASTY, MAN.
STEP IT UP!
GO FOR IT!
COME ON! FEEL THE BURN!
YEAH. SEE, NOW, THAT THERE,
THAT'S WHAT I'M TALKIN' ABOUT.
- MM-HMM.
- ONE, TWO, THREE, FOUR.
WORK IT!
ONE, TWO, THREE, FOUR,
FIVE, SIX, SEVEN EIGHT.
THAT'S IT!
PICK IT UP!
WORK IT!
WORK IT.
FEEL THE BURN!
GO FOR IT!
ONE, TWO, THREE, FOUR,
FIVE, SIX, SEVEN, EIGHT,
ONE, TWO, THREE, FOUR...
[ Fades ]
- [ Man ]
GO, GO, GO!
- [ Gasps ]
- [ Rob ] SHIT! OHH!
- [ Police Shouting ]
- [ Rob ] AAAAH!
- BABY, JUST GIVE IT UP!
[ Helicopter Flying Overhead ]
I'M GONNA GET
ALL YOU MOTHERFUCKERS!
AAAH!
I AIN'T GOIN' BACK!
BOY, WHAT THE FUCK
IS WRONG WITH YOU?
NOTHIN'. I...
[ Stammering ]
I HAD A DREAM.
YOU HAD A DREAM?
NOW YOU MARTIN LUTHER KING.
SEE, THAT'S WHAT
SMOKIN' THAT PIPE
WILL DO FOR YO' ASS.
TALKIN' ABOUT
YOU HAD A DREAM.
[ Continues, Indistinct ]
GETTIN' ON MY LAST NERVE.
WHAT YOU NEED IS A CHECKUP
FROM THE NECK UP.
WHO DRANK MY LAST BEER?
IT'S A DAMN SHAME...
A MAN CAN'T EVEN COME HOME
TO A COLD BEER.
YOU KNOW, ME AND YOUR MAMA
WAS TALKIN' ABOUT YOUR ASS
LAST NIGHT.
NOW, YOU KNOW IT COST ME
$275 TO GET THAT DAMN
DOOR FIXED?
NOW THE POLICE COME,
TALKIN' ABOUT THEY DON'T
HAVE TO REIMBURSE ME...
'CAUSE THEY GOT A WARRANT
OUT FOR YOUR ARREST.
WHAT KIND OF SHIT IS THAT?
HOW YOU GONNA PAY
FOR THAT, HUH?
I TOLD YOU,
I DIDN'T KNOW I HAD
A WARRANT OUT FOR ME.
WHAT YOU MEAN,
YOU DIDN'T KNOW?
I DIDN'T KNOW!
- YOU KNOW EVERYTHING ELSE.
- WHAT THAT SUPPOSED TO MEAN?
IT'S SUPPOSED TO MEAN WHAT I
TRIED TO TELL YOUR ASS LAST TIME
YOU GOT CAUGHT UP IN THAT SHIT.
HUH?
DON'T LOOK AT ME
LIKE I'M A FOOL.
WHAT, YOU THINK I'M CRAZY?
I JUST GOT OFF THE AIRPLANE,
NOT THE BOAT.
WHO YOU THINK YOU TALKIN' TO...
I DIDN'T KNOW WHAT
YOU WAS TALKIN' ABOUT.
THE BOY JUST SAID
THAT IT WASN'T HIS FAULT.
GIVE HIM A BREAK.
I'M GONNA GIVE HIM A BREAK.
I'LL BREAK MY FOOT OFF
IN HIS ASS.
DON'T TALK TO ME LIKE THAT!
I'LL FUCK YOU UP!
UH-UH, UH-UH. JUST...
DON'T TELL ME WHAT TO DO!
I AIN'T TRYIN' TO TELL YOU
WHAT TO DO, BABY,
BUT I'M SICK
OF THIS MESS TOO!
THAT'S COOL, THEN.
IF HE DON'T WANT ME HERE,
AIN'T NO PROBLEM
FOR ME TO LEAVE.
I DON'T KNOW WHY YOU KEEP
THREATENIN' TO LEAVE.
GET YOUR ASS ON OUT!
- LOOK, AIN'T NOBODY SAID
YOU GOTTA LEAVE.
- LET HIM GO INTO THE ARMY.
GO TO THE NAVY.
SALVATION ARMY.
HELL, I DON'T CARE WHERE HE GO.
JOIN THE JEHOVAH'S WITNESSES,
I DON'T CARE, AS LONG AS HE GET
HIS MONKEY ASS OUT THIS HOUSE.
NOW, WHERE YOU GOIN' TO?
YOU KNOW HOW ROUGH IT IS
OUT THERE IN THEM STREETS.
GONNA GO STAY WITH JUANITA.
KEEP BEGGIN' HIM TO STAY.
SHIT, LET HIM GO!
YOU DON'T HAVE TO PAY HIM
NO MIND. YOU CAN STAY HERE
AS LONG AS YOU'RE MY SON.
MAMA, MAMA...
I'M SORRY, BUT I GOTTA GO.
JUANITA, LOLITA, AQUANITA.
I DON'T CARE WHERE YOU GO.
SHIT. WHOO,
LORD HAVE MERCY.
# I GOT THE WHOLE WORLD
IN MY HANDS #
WAIT A MINUTE, NOW.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO
GO NOWHERE.
YOU JUST GOT HERE,
ROB!
[ Door Slams ]
I GOT ON
YOUR FAVORITE COLOGNE.
- WHAT KIND IS THAT?
- HARD-ON.
DIDN'T KNOW YOU COULD
SMELL IT, DID YOU?
[ Chuckles ]
HI. I'M HERE
TO BOND OUT RAY.
UH, WHAT'S
HIS LAST NAME?
RAY.
RAY'S HIS FIRST NAME
OR LAST NAME?
BOTH. RAY RAY.
[ Chuckles ]
LET ME CHECK.
DO THAT.
RAY RAY. UH, NOPE,
I DON'T SEE NO RAY RAY.
WELL, KEEP LOOKIN'.
HE'S IN THERE.
HE'S IN HERE.
WELL, IF HE AIN'T HERE,
HE AIN'T IN HERE.
I KNOW YOU AIN'T BLIND AND BALD.
HEY, WATCH IT.
LISTEN.
NO, YOU WATCH IT.
JUST FIND RAY RAY.
FIND RAY RAY.
DON'T CALL ME BALD.
HEY, HEY, HEY,
TIME OUT.
[ Both Arguing ]
PEOPLE, COME ON.
LET'S KEEP IT CALM.
LET A BROTHER HANDLE
THE SISTER'S BUSINESS.
I KNOW WHAT I'M DOIN', OKAY?
EXCUSE ME, MA'AM.
MY NAME'S DETECTIVE JENKINS.
IS THERE SOMETHING
I COULD HELP YOU WITH?
GET YOUR HAND OFF OF ME!
HELL, NO.
ARREST THIS BITCH!
YOU DON'T KNOW ME!
OH, HELL, NAW.
HELL, YEAH.
HELL, NAW.
SELLOUT!
OH, I'M GONNA SELL YOU OUT.
YOU AIN'T GOT TO CALL
FOR RAY RAY, BABY.
YOU ABOUT TO MEET HIM!
PUT HER IN THE HOLE!
Y'ALL SAW THAT, MAN.
I HAD TO GET HER.
I SAW THAT.
SHE COULD HAVE STUCKE
ALL IN MY EYE WITH ONE OF
THEM PRESS-ONS, RIGHT?
RIGHT? THAT'S WHAT
I'M TALKIN' ABOUT.
UP. GET UP. COME ON.
YO, WHAT'S
WITH THE CUFFS?
DAMO.
[ Computer Voice ] HEY, BABY,
WANNA SEE MY DIC?
SALDAMO!
IS IT A BIG ONE?
BIG ENOUGH
AND HARD ENOUGH.
SALDAMO? SALDAMO.
YOU GOT A POSITIVE I.D.
ON THAT SUSPECT
IN THE FREEWAY SHOOTING YET?
NO, SIR, CAPTAIN.
WE'VE BEEN HAVING TROUBLE
WITH OUR COMPUTERS.
I HAVEN'T BEEN ABLE TO ACCESS
THE MAINFRAME DOWNTOWN.
JUST CALL 'EM UP.
TELL 'EM TO FIX IT,
YOU KNOW?
- WE NEED THAT I.D.
- I'VE BEEN CALLING ALL NIGHT.
I CAN'T GET THROUGH.
- JUST KEEP TRYING.
- WE DID GET THAT DRAWING
FROM THE SKETCH ARTIST, SIR.
OH. LET ME SEE.
I KNOW THIS GUY.
OH, WAIT A MINUTE.
WHO DREW THIS?
SAMUELS.
THEY LOOK ALIKE, RIGHT?
YEAH?
LET'S GET
A NEW SKETCH ARTIST.
- YES, SIR.
I'LL GET RIGHT ON THAT.
- JENKINS! JENKINS!
WHAT?
JENKINS, OH, GOOD.
YOU'RE BACK FROM COUNTY.
YOU INTERVIEWED
THE OTHER SUSPECT, RIGHT?
I'M GONNA CHECK ON IT
FIRST THING IN THE MORNING.
KEEP ME UPDATED,
OKAY?
ALL RIGHT.
RIGHT AFTER
I TAKE A SHIT.
SHIT.
HELLO?
HELLO, JUANITA?
ANYBODY CALL FOR ME?
ANYBODY BEEN
LOOKIN' FOR ME?
WHY YOU TALKIN' SO FAST?
- ANYBODY LIKE WHO?
- JUST HAVE YOU
SEEN ANYBODY?
NO.
YES, I'M SURE.
YOU SURE?
COOL, COOL, COOL.
I'LL BE OVER THERE
IN A MINUTE.
- WHAT'S WRONG?
- NOTHIN'. ME AND POPS
GOT INTO IT.
I'LL TELL YOU
ABOUT IT LATER.
OKAY.
- ALL RIGHT, THEN.
I'LL SEE YOU IN A MINUTE.
- ALL RIGHT.
[ Woman ]
MR. CORTINO'S OFFICE.
WHO'S CALLING, PLEASE?
ONE MOMENT, PLEASE.
I'LL CONNECT YOU.
[ Phone Beeps ]
MR. CORTINO, YOU HAVE
A CALL ON LINE SEVEN.
MR. CORTINO?
[ Snoring ]
MR. CORTINO!
HUH? WHAT?
WHO IS IT?
IT'S A DETECTIVE JENKINS
FROM DIVISION 77.
DIVISION 77?
THANKS.
YEAH. I HOPE
YOU'RE CALLIN' ME...
ABOUT SENDIN' SOMEBODY
TO PICK UP THESE SHITBIRDS...
THAT HAVE BEEN
CLOGGING MY OFFICE
FOR THE PAST SIX HOURS.
NO, THIS IS DETECTIVE JENKINS.
I'M CALLING ABOUT ONE OF
YOUR PAROLEES.
HIS NAME IS
ROBERT DOUGLAS.
OH, YEAH.
THIS IS THE SUSPECT IN THAT
FREEWAY SHOOTING YESTERDAY.
- HOW COME YOU'RE JUST
CALLIN' ME NOW?
- THE BUCKET THEY WERE IN...
WAS REPORTED STOLEN
ABOUT 9:00 A.M.
OOH, THAT'S
NICE TO KNOW.
LOOK, I'LL TELL YOU WHAT. IF HE
CONTACTS YOU, YOU CONTACT ME.
RIGHT.
AND YOU'RE GONNA SEND
SOMEBODY TO PICK UP
THESE SHITBIRDS.
I'LL TALK TO YOU LATER.
MR. CORTINO, YOU HAVE
ANOTHER CALL ON LINE THREE.
YEAH, I GOT IT, AMINA.
JENKINS. I HOPE
YOU'RE CALLING TO TELL ME
THE WAGON'S ON THE WAY.
WAGON? NO, MR. CORTINO,
THIS IS ROB.
I MEAN, ROBERT DOUGLAS.
I DIDN'T EVEN EXPECT
TO CATCH YOU THIS LATE.
- I WAS GONNA LEAVE A MESSAGE.
- OH. DOUGLAS.
HOW NICE OF YOU TO CALL.
MAN, SHIT'S
BEEN ROUGH.
WHERE ARE YOU?
WHERE YOU AT? DON'T WORRY
ABOUT WHERE I'M AT.
I'M WHERE I'M IS.
OH, YOU'RE GONNA BE
A TOUGH GUY NOW?
YOU AIN'T GONNA BE SO TOUGH
WHEN THE GOON SQUAD
PUTS A CAP IN YOUR ASS.
MAN, I AIN'T HAD NOTHIN'
TO DO WITH THAT SHOOTIN'.
SO IT WAS YOU.
HELL, NAW. LOOK,
I CAN EXPLAIN EVERYTHING.
HEY, THERE'S
NOTHING TO EXPLAIN.
WE GOT YOU ON TAPE.
LISTEN TO ME, DOUGLAS.
THE BEST THING
FOR YOU TO DO...
IS TO COME DOWN HERE
AND TURN YOURSELF IN.
I GOT SOME GUYS ON THE BENCH
HERE YOU CAN HANG OUT WITH
'TIL THE WAGON COMES.
YOU DO THAT, AND YOU'LL
SAVE US ALL SOME HEADACHE.
YOU KNOW THE POLICE AIN'T
GONNA SHOW ME NO LOVE
IF THEY CATCH UP TO ME.
- IF?
YOU MEAN WHEN, DON'T YOU?
- I SEE YOU BEIN' A LOT OF HELP.
- I DIDN'T GET YOU INTO THIS.
- YEAH, AND YOU AIN'T DOIN'
NOTHIN' TO GET ME OUT, EITHER.
I TOLD YOU,
TURN YOURSELF IN.
- MAN, I GOTTA GO.
- HEY, HEY, DOUGLAS, WAIT!
- MAN, WHAT?
- LISTEN TO ME.
YOU KNOW THAT THIS
IS THE THIRD TIME FOR YOU.
[ Cell Door Slams ]
[ Chuckling ]
[ Cortino ]
FUCKIN' DOOFUS.
GOT YOUR PHONE CALL.
[ Dial Tone ]
[ Line Ringing ]
J.J.
[ Rings ]
HEY, THIS IS DAHLIA.
I'M NOT IN RIGHT NOW. LEAVE ME
A BRIEF MESSAGE AT THE BEEP.
HELLO?
[ Operator ] WILL YOU
ACCEPT A COLLECT CALL FROM...
[ J.J. ] J.J.
DO YOU
ACCEPT THIS CALL?
YEAH, YEAH, YEAH.
WHAT'S UP, DOG?
WHAT'S UP, LOC?
YOU STRAIGHT?
EVERYTHING GONNA BE ALL RIGHT?
YEAH, NIGGA
GONNA BE ALL RIGHT.
JUST TRYING TO RECOVER.
NIGGA ASS SORER
THAN A MOTHERFUCKER, THOUGH.
[ Laughs ]
THAT'S RIGHT, YOU CAUGHT
ONE IN THE ASS, HUH?
- DID IT HURT?
- DO YOU NEED... SOMETHIN'?
- HELL, NO, YOU CAN'T
GIVE ME NOTHIN', NIGGA!
- HEY, WHO YOU TALKIN' TO?
- SOME FAT-ASS FAG...
KEEP WALKIN' BY THE DOOR,
PEEPIN' IN.
BUT TO ANSWER YOUR QUESTION,
HELL, YEAH, IT HURT, NIGGA.
PLUS, I GOTTA SLEEP
WITH MY ASS IN THE AIR
FOR THE NEXT TWO WEEKS.
YOU KNOW I AIN'T
GONNA GET NO REST
IN THIS MOTHERFUCKER.
- DON'T TRIP.
YOU IN SICK BAY, BRO.
- THAT DON'T MEAN NOTHIN'.
GOTTA WATCH THE GUARDS
AROUND THIS MOTHERFUCKER.
YOU DOZE OFF,
THEY WIND UP HITTIN' YOU.
OH, I SEEN Y'ALL ON THE NEWS
THE OTHER NIGHT TOO.
YOU A STAR, BOY.
SAY WHAT? HEY, Y'ALL SEE
THAT PUNK-ASS NIGGA
IN THE HOOD?
NAW, I AIN'T SEEN
THAT NIGGA YET, BUT...
- WHAT'S UP WITH YOU
AND THAT NIGGA, THOUGH?
- MAN.
THE DETECTIVES COMIN' UP HERE
TO ASK ME ABOUT DUDE TOMORROW.
- YOU KNOW WHAT TO TELL 'EM?
- I KNOW WHAT
I'M GONNA TELL 'EM.
THEY TRYIN' TO GIVE A NIGGA
A DOVE WITH A "L"
FOR THAT SHIT.
- WHAT YOU GONNA TELL 'EM?
- I'M GONNA TELL 'EM WHATEVER
THE FUCK THEY WANNA HEAR.
THAT NIGGA ALREADY GOT
TWO STRIKES ANYWAY.
YOU KNOW WHAT I'M SAYIN'?
- THIS HIS THIRD ONE.
- MAN, THAT'S SOME COLD SHIT.
NIGGA LOOKIN' AT 25 TO LIFE.
- WHO HAD THE STRAP, THOUGH?
- NIGGA, I STAY HEATED.
- THAT'S RIGHT.
- BETTER HIM THAN ME.
THAT'S RIGHT.
[ Guard ]
TIME'S UP.
COUNT IN FIVE MINUTES.
HEY, MAN THE GUARD'S TRIPPIN',
ABOUT TO CUT OFF THE PHONE...
COUNT IN FIVE MINUTES.
DAMN, MAN,
THAT WAS MOMS.
YO' MOMS.
[ Laughing ]
WHAT?
- HEY, NO, DEP. HEY!
- IT'S... IT'S WINKY TIME,
BABY.
LET'S PLAY
19 INCHES OF FUN.
- ME AND YOU, RIGHT NOW.
- YOU BETTER SHUT YOUR ASS UP
AND GET UP OUT OF HERE.
- DO YOU NEED TO SEE IT?
- HEY, YO, DEP!
[ Rob ]
MIKE! MIKE!
MOTHERFUCKER.
WHAT'S UP, HOMEY?
MY SAHAB.
WHAT'S UP, WEEBLE?
WHAT'S GOIN' ON, MAN?
YOU COOL?
SHIT, NIGGA
JUST BEEN MODULATIN'.
RIGHT, RIGHT.
I SEE YOU LOOKIN' GOOD.
NIGGA ALL SUITED AND BOOTED.
EVERYTHING STILL
ROLLIN' FOR YA?
SHIT COOL, NIGGA.
I JUST OPENED
THIS BEAUTY SALON
FOR 'WEEZIE.
THAT NIGGA JUST STARTED
THIS RECORD COMPANY
CALLED SICWITIT RECORDS.
SELL 100,000
THROUGH THE UNDERGROUND,
THAT'S GHETTO GOLD.
IF I CAN GET
THAT SHIT POPPIN', NIGGA,
I'M STRAIGHT.
RIGHT, RIGHT,
RIGHT.
WHAT'S HAPPENIN'
WITH YOU, THOUGH?
I JUST GOT OUT.
OH, OH, OH, OH, OH.
CHECK THIS OUT. SMELL ME
ON THIS ONE, WEEBLE.
I APPRECIATE YOU,
SINCERELY, FOR DOIN'
THAT LITTLE OLD TIME...
FOR YOUR SAHAB,
PULLIN' THEM BULLETS,
YOU UNDERSTAND THAT?
YOU A REAL NIGGA, NIGGA.
IT'S THE LEAST
I COULD DO.
YOU THREW THE DAMN GUN
IN MY LAP.
THAT WAS QUICK THINKIN'.
BUT A NIGGA AIN'T
LIKE THAT SHIT.
I'M SAYIN', WEEBLE,
I HAD TO THINK QUICK.
THE EL ROYS WAS ON MY ASS.
IT WAS VERY VALUABLE
FOR ME TO DO THAT.
RIGHT, RIGHT.
BUT I AIN'T TRIPPIN', MAN.
BUT HEY,
WHY DON'T YOU LET
A NIGGA HOLD SOMETHIN'?
YOU KNOW WHAT?
I'LL TELL YOU WHAT?
TAKE THESE MARBLES
RIGHT HERE, WEEBLE,
GET BACK WITH YOUR SAHAB
WITH THE GYPSYNESS, AND I
MIGHT HAVE A JOB FOR YOU.
OH, NO, MAN,
I AIN'T FUCKIN' AROUND.
NO, NO, NO, NO, NO, NO.
THIS ANOTHER JOB.
GET BACK AT YOUR SAHAB.
I'M FLYIN' STRAIGHT NOW.
OKAY.
COOL, BIG HOMEY.
ALL RIGHT.
ALL RIGHT, WEEBLE?
ONE.
OH, SHIT. HEY!
CAN I ROLL WITH YOU?
GET BACK WITH ME.
LATER ON, WE GONNA GET
OUR CHANCE TO ROLL.
RIGHT NOW, I GOT THIS
COOL LITTLE OLD BREEZIE,
COKE BOTTLE SHAPE,
WAITIN' FOR YOUR SAHAB
AT THE COFFEE TABLE.
ALL RIGHT MAN. I'LL JUST
GET BACK WITH YOU LATER ON.
ONE LOVE.
YEAH! THIS JUST
WHAT A NIGGA NEEDED.
[ Engine Starts ]
# [ Hip Hop ]
[ Line Ringing ]
[ Sniffs ]
- HEY! THAT'S HIM!
- [ Phone Ringing ]
MAN, THAT'S
TRUCK TURNER, MAN!
MAN, THAT'S HIM!
HEY, NOW WAIT
A MINUTE, MAN!
NOW, YOU SAID
KILL A NIGGA.
THAT'S TRUCK TURNER.
LOOK, MAN, WHAT'S
THE MATTER WITH YOU?
WE GOT A JOB TO DO!
MAN, LOOK HERE, MAN!
COME ON!
[ Juanita ] WHO'S THIS?
[ Rob ]
HELLO, JUANITA?
YEAH, ROB.
WHAT'S UP NOW?
YOU BUSY?
NOT REALLY.
WHY YOU CALLIN' ME BACK?
YOU NOT COMIN'?
I WAS COMIN', BUT LOOK,
I NEED YOU TO MEET ME...
AT THAT HOTEL-EASY
THAT WE WENT TO
THAT PROM-EASY AT.
- WHAT YOU TALKIN' ABOUT?
- NEVER MIND, ALL RIGHT? JUST
MEET ME THERE IN 30 MINUTES.
- FOR WHAT?
- DON'T WORRY ABOUT
"FOR WHAT."
- JUST MEET ME THERE.
- WELL, I'M HUNGRY. AND HOW
AM I SUPPOSED TO GET THERE?
- ASK GRANDPA
CAN YOU USE HIS CAR.
- ALL RIGHT.
ALL RIGHT. HEY, STOP
AND GET SOME DRINKS.
- WHAT YOU WANT?
- YOU KNOW I GOT TO HAVE
THAT YACK...
WHEN I'M ABOUT
TO BREAK YO' BACK!
[ Laughs ]
OH, IS THAT RIGHT?
THAT'S MORE
THAN RIGHT.
- BYE.
TAXI!
WHO TOLD YOU YOU CAN
SMOKE IN MY CAR?
LET ME
HIT THAT SHIT.
JENKINS.
ROBERTS.
WELL, NOW, JUST CORRECT ME
IF I'M WRONG HERE,
BUT YOU DON'T HAVE
A LEAD ON THIS KID YET?
- I TALKED TO HIS P.O.
- UH-HUH. WHAT DID
HE TELL YOU?
HE DIDN'T TELL ME SHIT.
HE SAID HE HADN'T SEEN HIM.
SO, WHERE DOES THAT
LEAVE YOU?
WELL, I GUESS WE COULD
TAKE A RIDE THROUGH
HIS OLD NEIGHBORHOOD.
- YEAH.
- WORKIN' TOGETHER.
GOT YOUR FEET NAILED
TO THE GODDAMN FLOOR.
DON'T PAY ATTENTION TO HIM.
HE'S STILL UPSET
ABOUT THAT O.J. TRIAL.
HELL, I THINK
HE DID IT TOO!
DAMN.
[ Valet ] HELLO.
WELCOME TO THE HOTEL, MA'AM.
HOW CAN I HELP YOU?
[ Juanita ]
HERE. BE CAREFUL
WITH IT, NOW.
[ Valet ]
HAVE A NICE NIGHT.
[ Driver, Rob Laughing ]
[ Rob ]
RIGHT HERE. RIGHT HERE.
RIGHT HERE, DUDE!
[ Laughing, Chattering ]
I TOLD YOU THIS
IS SOME BOMB SHIT, DOG!
[ Valet ]
HI, GUYS. HI, GUYS.
WELCOME TO THE HOTEL.
ANY BAGS OR ANYTHING?
TAKE MY BAG, MAN.
HEY, MAN,
NO PROBLEM.
HEY, I'M GONNA
GET AT YOU.
ONE LOVE.
JOHNSON.
JUANITA JOHNSON.
ARE YOU SURE YOU HAVE
A RESERVATION WITH... US?
YES, I'M SURE.
MY MAN TOLD ME
TO MEET HIM HERE.
I'M SORRY, I JUST DON'T SEE
YOU OR YOUR MAN'S NAME
IN THE SYSTEM.
YEAH, WELL, THEN I THINK YOU
NEED TO CHECK A LITTLE BIT
DEEPER INTO THE SYSTEM.
WHAT'S GOIN' ON?
SHE TALKIN' ABOUT
SHE DON'T SEE OUR NAME
IN THE RESERVATIONS.
I DIDN'T MAKE
NO RESERVATIONS.
OH. YOU SHOULD HAVE
TOLD ME THAT THEN.
LOOK, I'M SORRY
FOR THE MISUNDERSTANDING,
BUT CAN WE GET A ROOM?
YES, SIR. YOU CERTAINLY CAN.
OUR ROOMS START AT $250 A NIGHT.
TWO HUNDRED
AND FIFTY DOLLARS?
WHAT'S WITH YOU...
BABY, THIS PLACE IS
ABSOLUTELY BEAUTIFUL,
BUT $250 A NIGHT?
JUST CHILL OUT.
TWO HUNDRED
AND FIFTY DOLLARS?
YOU HAVE THAT KIND OF MONEY,
ROB? 'CAUSE IF YOU DO,
YOU CAN GIVE ME 200...
AND WE CAN GO OVER
TO THE SNOOTY FOX.
THE SNOOTY FOX?
ALL THESE RITZY PEOPLE, YOU
TALKIN' ABOUT THE SNOOTY FOX?
CHILL OUT.
NEVER MIND HER, OKAY?
WE'LL TAKE THE ROOM
AND PUT 50 ON THE PHONE.
BABY, WHERE'D YOU GET
THAT MONEY FROM?
LOOK, DON'T WORRY ABOUT
WHERE I GOT THE MONEY FROM.
JUST CHILL OUT.
[ Mumbling ]
HERE'S YOUR ROOM KEY, SIR.
ELEVATOR'S JUST DOWN THE HALL
TO YOUR LEFT.
HAVE A GREAT DAY.
THANK YOU.
HEH HEH!
YOUR BAG, SIR.
OOH! BLUE 42!
HUT, HUT!
COME ON
IN HERE, GIRL.
OOOOO-WEE!
HA HA!
LIKE THIS, HUH?
WE GONNA GET BUSY
UP IN HERE, GIRL!
YOU STILL DIDN'T TELL ME
WHERE YOU GOT
THAT MONEY FROM.
LOOK, WOMAN, I DONE TOLD YOU
ABOUT QUESTIONIN' ME.
WE JUST WENT OVER THIS
THE OTHER DAY.
WHO YOU TALKIN' TO?
UH, HELLO!
I DON'T SEE NOBODY ELSE
UP IN THIS ROOM.
OH, SO NOW YOU TRYIN'
TO BE FUNNY, HUH?
YOU KNOW WHAT?
YOU AIN'T HAD NONE OF THIS
IN A YEAR.
YOU KEEP MESSIN' AROUND,
AND YOU WON'T GET NONE
FOR A WHOLE 'NOTHER ONE.
HEY!
I'M GONNA TAKE
A BATH.
LET ME COME TOO.
YOU BETTER KEEP
YOUR ASS OUT HERE.
QUIT PLAYIN'! JUANITA!
ALL RIGHT, COOL!
GO ON IN THERE THEN!
I'M JUST GONNA KK BACK,
RELAX AND ORDER ME UP
SOME ROOM SERVICE.
ORDER ME SOME TOO.
THAT LITTLE FUCKER AIN'T
ANYWHERE NEAR HERE, MAN.
YEAH, WELL, YOU KNOW,
IT'S JUST ROUTINE QUESTIONING,
MAN.
SHIT, HOME'S THE LAST PLACE
I'D BE IF I WAS
ON THE FUCKIN' HOT SHEET.
WELL, IF ALL THE CRIMINALS
START THINKIN' LIKE YOU,
THEY'LL FUCK AROUND
AND PUT US OUT OF WORK.
THEN I'LL HAVE TO
ARREST YO' ASS.
MAN, COME ON.
YOU KNOW I'M ON DUTY.
THEY DONE WROTE ME UP
FOR PULLIN' MY GUN ON THAT
CRAZY BITCH AT THE PRECINCT.
SORRY ABOUT THAT, MAN.
GOOD SHIT, THOUGH.
[ Pounding On Door ]
[ Rob ] GIRL, COME ON OUT!
I GOTTA TAKE A PISS!
[ Mumbling, Indistinct ]
YOU JUST IMPATIENT.
I'M TIRED
OF WAITIN' ON YOU.
JUST LIKE THEM OTHER PEOPLE
IN THE HOUSE, IMPATIENT.
THAT'S YOUR PROBLEM.
I'M NOT GONNA
FOOL WITH YOU, THOUGH.
NOT GONNA
FOOL WITH YOU.
# [ Whistling ]
[ Rings ]
SHIT, MAN,
THERE AIN'T
NOBODY HERE.
[ Sighs ] MAYBE THEY'RE
WATCHIN' JERRY SPRINGER.
[ Mama ] WHO IS IT?
DETECTIVE JENKINS
FROM THE 77th PRECINCT.
MA'AM, WE JUST WANT TO ASK YOU
A COUPLE OF QUESTIONS
ABOUT YOUR SON, ROBERT DOUGLAS.
HE'S NOT HERE.
WELL, MA'AM, IF YOU
COULD OPEN THE DOOR,
WE JUST WANT TO ASK
A COUPLE QUESTIONS,
THAT'S ALL.
YOU GOT A WARRANT?
NO, MA'AM.
THEN I'M NOT
OPENIN' THE DOOR.
ALL RIGHT.
WELL, THAT'S FINE WITH ME.
I'M JUST TRYIN' TO SAVE...
YOUR LITTLE BABY BOY
FROM GETTIN'
HIS FUCKIN' HEAD BLOWN OFF.
[ Door Opening ]
EXCUSE ME? UH, EXCUSE ME?
WHAT DID YOU SAY?
WE JUST WANT TO TALK TO YOUR SON
IF HE'S ON THE PREMISES.
HE'S NOT HERE.
MA'AM, DO YOU MIND IF WE SEARCH
THE FRONT OF THE...
DO YOU HAVE A WARRANT?
I SAID NO, BUT...
THEN I WOULD SUGGEST
YOU LEAVE THE PREMISES.
ALL RIGHT, THEN.
IF YOU HAPPEN
TO SEE YOUR SON,
CAN I ASK YOU TO TELL HIM
TO CALL THE 77th PRECINCT?
MM-HMM.
DO YOU HAVE A CARD?
YOU KNOW WHAT?
I LEFT MY CARD.
HMM.
BUT TELL HIM...
WHY DON'T YOU, WHEN YOU
GET A CARD, COME BACK?
OKAY, THEN I'LL DO THAT.
THANK YOU. THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
YOU HAVE A GOOD DAY.
AND BACK ATCHA.
YOU HAVE A GOOD DAY TOO.
CAN I SHOOT HER?
THESE PEOPLE, MAN.
MY NERVES, MAN!
# [ R & B ]
ROB.
I MISSED YOU.
I WAITED
A WHOLE YEAR FOR YOU.
I WAITED A WHOLE YEAR
FOR YOU TOO.
I DIDN'T EVEN JACK OFF
THE WHOLE TIME I WAS
LOCKED UP.
[ Juanita ]
OH, I'M SO PROUD OF YOU.
[ Sniffles ]
[ Dialing Numbers ]
[ Ringing ]
[ Both Mumbling ]
DOUGLAS.
[ Coughs ]
DOUGLAS RESIDENCE.
MAMA.
ROB?
[ Rob ] YEAH, MAMA, IT'S ME.
WHERE IN THE HELL ARE YOU?
IS THAT HIM?
PRINT ME OUT A LOCATION
RIGHT NOW.
[ Mama ]
POLICEMEN HAVE BEEN OVER HERE
LOOKIN' FOR YOU.
YOUR FACE HAS BEEN IN THE NEWS,
AND THEY SAY YOU ARMED
AND DANGEROUS.
MARINA DEL REY?
WHAT THE FUCK'S
HE DOIN' THERE?
[ Pops ] TELL HIM TO KEEP
HIS ASS THERE. DON'T BRING
THAT HEAT HERE.
JUST BE QUIET, BABY. THEY
LIABLE TO KILL HIM. THEY DON'T
CARE NOTHIN' ABOUT HIM!
WELL, THEY DON'T GIVE A SHIT
ABOUT US EITHER. TELL HIM
DON'T BRING THE HEAT OVER HERE.
BETTER GET JENKINS
ON THE HORN.
MAMA, CALM DOWN, CALM DOWN.
EVERYTHING GONNA BE ALL RIGHT.
I'M GONNA GET A LAWYER.
I AIN'T DO NOTHIN'.
CALM DOWN?
IF YOU DIDN'T DO NOTHIN',
WHAT YOU NEED A LAWYER FOR?
I DONE TOLD YOU
THAT THE POLICE HAVE BEEN
OVER HERE LOOKIN' FOR YOU.
NOW, Y-YOUR FACE
HAS BEEN ON THE NEWS MORE
THAN THE RODNEY KING BEATING.
THEY LIABLE TO SHOOT YOU
ON SIGHT.
- WHAT?
- YOU HEARD ME.
AND WHERE YOU GONNA GET...
THE MONEY
TO PAY FOR A LAWYER?
I SURE AIN'T
PUTTIN' THIS HOUSE UP
FOR HIS SORRY ASS.
AND... AND THIS GIRL
CALLED OVER HERE,
SAYIN' IT WAS
SOMETHING IMPORTANT,
SOMETHING ABOUT SOME TAPES.
SHE SAID IT WAS SOMETHING
THAT WAS LIABLE TO KEEP YOU
OUT OF JAIL.
NOW, BABY, WHAT IN THE WORLD
IS ALL OF THAT FOR?
WELL, WHO WAS SHE?
- DAHLIA.
NAME WAS DAHLIA.
- DAHLIA?
OH, DAHLIA! YEAH, YEAH, YEAH,
I KNOW WHO THAT IS.
DID SHE LEAVE A NUMBER?
YEAH.
- OKAY. YOU GOT A PEN?
- OKAY.
555-3555.
213 AREA.
ALL RIGHT, MAMA.
I'M GONNA CALL YOU LATER.
- LOOK, BABY, COME ON HOME.
- I'M GONNA CALL YOU.
I PROMISE.
ROB, JUST COME HOME, BABY.
I'M WORRIED ABOUT YOU.
NOW, I CAN'T TAKE
TOO MUCH MORE OF THIS.
I'M GONNA BE FINE.
AIN'T NOTHIN' GONNA
HAPPEN TO ME.
SOON AS I GET ALL THIS
STRAIGHTENED OUT,
I'M GONNA CALL YOU.
I'M WORRIED
ABOUT YOU.
I LOVE YOU TOO.
ROB, JUST COME HOME.
BYE.
[ Sighs ]
SHIT.
- AAAAAH!
- STOP FUCKIN' WITH ME!
LOOK, I TOLD YOU.
I WENT TO PICK HOMEBOY UP,
AND THAT NIGGA
WENT CRAZY, MAN.
HE WENT CRAZY?
HE HAD A GUN.
TWO GUNS.
WELL, THEN WHAT DID HE DO?
- NIGGA KIDNAPPED ME.
- SEE, I SHOULD HAVE KNOWN.
I SHOULD HAVE KNOWN THAT YOU
LYIN' LITTLE MOTHERFUCKER.
NOW, THE REPORT I READ
SAID THAT YOU SHOT FIRST.
HE SHOT 'EM, MAN!
I DIDN'T SHOOT NOBODY.
YEAH?
WHAT ABOUT
THE CAR?
YEAH,
THE CAR.
ALL RIGHT.
I-I DID THE CAR.
THAT'S WHAT I DO.
I STEAL CARS.
BUT THAT'S IT, SIR.
JENKINS, YOU GOT A CALL
IN THE CAGE.
WELL, WHO IS IT?
IT'S SALDAMO.
ALL RIGHT. KEEP AN EYE
ON THIS LITTLE SHIT,
AND I'M GONNA BE BACK LATER.
AH, GOT YOU!
- THINK YOU'RE A REAL
BAD ASS, DON'T YOU?
- NO, SIR.
I BET YOU AIN'T GONNA BE
SUCH A BAD ASS WHEN YOU'RE
DOING TEN YEARS IN SOLEDAD.
ROBERTS.
FUCK HIM.
FUCK 'EM BOTH.
WELL, COME ON.
ABOUT TIME YOU GOT UP
OUT OF THERE.
WHAT'S WRONG WITH YOU?
I GOTTA DO MY THING.
MM-HMM.
[ Phone Ringing ]
- HELLO.
- HELLO. MAY I SPEAK
TO DAHLIA, PLEASE?
THIS IS SHE.
THIS IS JUANITA.
ROB'S WIFE.
WHAT THE HELL IS YOUR NUMBER
DOING IN MY MAN'S POCKET?
- EXCUSE ME?
- BITCH, YOU HEARD ME.
BITCH?
I GOT YOUR BITCH, BITCH.
- YEAH, WELL,
DON'T BE CALLIN' MY MAN, THEN.
- I DIDN'T CALL YOUR MAN.
I CALLED HIS MAMA.
YOU CALLED HIS MAMA?
WHAT YOU DOIN'
CALLIN' MRS. DOUGLAS?
THAT'S MY MOTHER-IN-LAW.
WHAT? LOOK, I WAS JUST CALLIN'
TRYIN' TO HELP ROB'S ASS
GET OUT OF TROUBLE.
GIRL,
WHO IS YOU TALKIN' TO?
SOME HO NAMED DAHLIA.
WHAT'S THE MATTER WITH YOU?
HELLO, DAHLIA.
YOU BETTER TELL HER
WHERE YOU ARE.
YEAH, GIRL. WHAT'S UP?
MY MAMA SAY YOU GOT SOME TAPE
GONNA HELP GET ME OUT
OF THIS SHIT.
YEAH. YOU NEED
TO COME OVER HERE
AND SEE WHAT I HAVE.
YEAH. I CAN BE OVER THERE
IN LIKE AN HOUR.
OKAY.
YOU REMEMBER WHERE I LIVE?
YEAH, I REMEMBER.
UNCLE DAVE'S STREET, RIGHT?
- UH-HUH.
- ALL RIGHT. BYE.
WHAT THE HELL IS YOU DOIN'
GOIN' THROUGH MY SHIT?
YOU PROBABLY
DIPPED IN MY CHEESE.
WHAT THE HELL'S WRONG WITH YOU?
YOU SHOULDN'T HAVE BEEN HAVIN'
THAT TACK-HEAD'S PHONE NUMBER
IN YOUR WALLET.
AIN'T NOTHIN' GOIN' ON WITH
ME AND HER. SHE'S JUST TRYING
TO HELP A NIGGA OUT.
SIT AND WAIT FOR YOUR ASS WHILE
YOU GETTIN' READY TO GO OVER TO
SOME GIRL'S HOUSE IN AN HOUR?
YOU KNOW WHAT?
I NEED TO USE GRANDPA'S CAR
TO GO OVER THERE.
UH-UH. UH-UH. NOPE.
WHAT IS YOU TALKIN' ABOUT?
I NEED TO USE THE CAR.
AND HOW AM I SUPPOSED
TO GET HOME?
CATCH A CAB.
A CAB?
YEAH, USE THAT MONEY
YOU STOLE FROM ME.
OH, SO NOW YOU'RE TRYING TO
ACCUSE ME OF TAKING YOUR MONEY.
NOW YOU'RE TRYING TO ACCUSE ME
OF TAKING YOUR MONEY.
JUST LET ME USE THE CAR.
YOUR CAR, SIR.
OH, I GUESS YOU WANT
A TIP, HUH?
IT WOULD BE MOST APPROPRIATE.
STAY OUT OF DARK ALLEYS
AT NIGHT.
I BEG YOUR PARDON?
NIGGA, MOVE!
ALL RIGHT, MAN.
I GOT ALL KINDS OF STUFF TO DO.
STOP IT.
[ Tires Screeching ]
[ Laughing ]
NIGGA, STOP.
YOU ABOUT TO MAKE ME FART.
SHIT.
[ Laughs ]
MAN, I SLAPPED
THAT SKINNY MOTHERFUCKER
ON HIS NARROW ASS SO HARD,
I THOUGHT HE WAS GONNA
START SHITTING BULLETS.
[ Laughing ]
I CAN'T TIGHTEN YOU UP NOW.
WE ON POLICE BUSINESS.
YOU GOT A PIECE
OF THAT ASS TOO, THOUGH.
[ Laughing ]
LET'S TAKE CARE OF THIS.
[ Chuckling ]
GAW-W-WDDAMN.
[ Hisses ]
HEY.
WHAT'S HAPPENIN'
WITH YOU, NIGGA?
NOTHIN'. I WAS JUST...
I WAS JUST WHAT?
I WAS HERE WHEN...
FUCK THAT!
WHAT'S UP, WEEBLE?
HOW ARE YOU?
LONG TIME NO SEE.
I CATCH NIGGAS DOIN' THAT SHIT
ALL THE TIME. THAT'S WHY I HAD
TO MARRY THE BREEZIE.
YOU UNDERSTAND THAT?
I HEAR YOU, DOG.
THINKING ABOUT MARRYING MY GIRL
TOO, IF I CAN EVER GET HER
TO STOP TRIPPIN' SO DAMN MUCH.
LIKE THAT.
YEAH, I HEARD, NIGGA.
I HEARD, I HEARD.
YOU KNOW YOU'RE...
WHAT YOU DOIN' OUT
ON THE STREETS ANYWAY?
YOU KNOW YOU'RE HOT
AS A FIRECRACKER, BOY.
THEY GOT EVERYBODY
AFTER YOUR ASS.
MY GRANDMAMA SEEN YOUR ASS AT
THE MOTHERFUCKING POST OFFICE,
NIGGA.
MY GRANDMAMA
SEEN THAT SHIT.
AMERICA'S MOST WANTED,
CHANNEL TWO. CHANNEL SEVEN.
NIGGA, YOU HOT AS A FIRECRACKER.
- WHAT THE...
- [ Police Dispatcher ]
ROBERT DOUGLAS. BLACK MALE.
THAT'S WHAT I'M TALKING ABOUT.
YOU GOT MY SHIT ON FIRE.
THEY LEFT THE LOT YET?
YEAH, THEY GONE, NIGGA.
YOU GONNA HAVE TO TOUCH
THE GRAVEL, BUST A PATTERN UP
OUT OF THIS MOTHERFUCKER.
I'M OUT,
BUT THE REASON
I CAME THROUGH...
I WANTED TO KNOW
IF YOU KNEW
ANY GOOD LAWYERS.
CHECK WITH ME LATER.
I MIGHT HAVE SOMEONE
FOR YOU.
ALL RIGHT.
I'M GONNA HOLLER
AT THAT BOY LIBOWITZ.
COOL.
ALL RIGHT?
ONE, BABY.
ALL RIGHT. ONE.
ALL RIGHT.
[ Video Game Beeping ]
[ Dahlia ]
YOU KNOW WHAT?
YOU NEED TO FIND SOMETHING
MORE CONSTRUCTIVE TO DO
WITH YOUR TIME.
AND YOU KEEP HANGING WITH J.J.,
YOU GONNA WIND UP JUST
LIKE HE IS... IN JAIL!
WHY YOU TRIPPIN'?
I AIN'T TRIPPIN'.
I HEARD THAT SHIT Y'ALL LEFT
ON MY ANSWERING MACHINE
THE OTHER NIGHT!
YOU TRIPPIN'.
NO, I AIN'T TRIPPIN'.
I'M TRIPPIN',
AND I AIN'T EVEN DID NOTHIN'.
JUST STAY AWAY FROM HIM,
AND DON'T BE ACCEPTING NO MORE
COLLECT CALLS ON MY DAMN PHONE!
MAN, YOU TRIPPIN'!
NO, NIGGA, YOU TRIPPIN'!
TAKE YOUR ASS OUT OF HERE THEN!
AND PULL YOUR DAMN PANTS UP!
[ Dahlia Muttering ]
GET ON MY NERVES, MAN.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT, THOUGH.
FAT ASS. YOU NEED TO GO RUN
AROUND THE CORNER OR SOMETHING.
[ Muttering Continues ]
THEN THE NIGGA GOT THE NERVE
TO ACCEPT A COLLECT CALL
ON MY PHONE!
[ Laughs ]
BUST-ASS NIGGA.
# [ Hip Hop ]
[ Tone Humming ]
# [ Stops ]
[ Humming ]
HITCHHIKER.
SUNSHINE. HEY, SUNSHINE.
I MEAN YOU. DAMN, BABY.
SHIT!
[ Men Laughing ]
OLD BUCKET-HEAD BITCH!
[ Laughing Continues ]
FUCK Y'ALL!
HA, HA, HA! SHE'S JUST NEVER
BEEN WITH NO PRETTY NIGGA.
[ Chattering ]
HA, HA, HA.
[ Laughing, Chattering ]
[ Chattering Continues ]
WHAT UP, NIGGA. WHAT UP?
YEAH. WHAT'S UP, BABY?
HEY, MAN.
SMOKE THAT SHIT OUTSIDE.
HUSH, YOUNG BOY. I GOT SPERM
BIGGER THAN YOU, MAN.
WHAT'S UP, PARTNER?
MM-MM. HERE'S THE JOINT HAND.
WHAT'S UP, MAN?
WHAT'S UP, GIRL?
WHAT Y'ALL NIGGAS
UP TO?
OH, LORD.
WHAT WE GOT HERE?
IT'S FAT BOY DAY TODAY.
WE GOT FAT BARBERS,
FAT CUSTOMERS.
LITTLE PEABO BRYSONS.
FADE MY FUR, DOG.
MAN, DON'T NEVER SNATCH
MY HAT LIKE THAT.
WHAT'S HAPPENING, MAN?
SPACE COWBOY.
I'M GOIN' DOWN TO
THE Chick'N'Strip.
SEE SOME... HO'S.
ALL RIGHT. WELL,
GO TO THE Chick'N'Strip.
NIGGA, I'M GOIN'
TO THE CENTURY CLUB,
WHERE I GET FREE...
BOOTY.
I GET FREE BOOTY.
I'M GOIN' TO THE CENTURY CLUB,
MOTHERFUCKER.
WATCH HOW I SLIDE
UP INTO THEM HO'S.
SO WHERE IT'S AT?
IT'S OVER HERE.
COOL, COOL.
LET'S CHECK IT OUT.
SEE WHAT YOU'RE TALKIN' ABOUT.
MM-HMM. I'M GONNA PLAY IT,
BUT, SEE, FIRST,
YOU GOT SOMETHIN' I WANT.
MMM, A DEMO BUDGET?
THIS ISN'T A PRODUCTION STUDIO,
GIRL.
THIS IS VALUABLE
TO MY GODDAMN LIFE.
MM-HMM. I KNOW.
HEY, COME ON NOW, DAHLIA.
YOU KNOW I GOT A WOMAN.
SEE, I UNDERSTAND ALL THAT.
BUT WHAT YOU NEED
TO UNDERSTAND,
FOR YOU TO GET WHAT YOU WANT,
AHEM, I GOTTA GET WHAT I NEED.
[ Hisses ]
DAMN, Y-Y-YOU REALLY WANT
A NIGGA, HUH?
BOY, I DONE
HAD A CRUSH ON YOU
EVER SINCE HIGH SCHOOL.
O-O-OKAY, UM...
[ Clears Throat ]
WHY DON'T YOU JUST GO ON INTO
THE ROOM, KICK BACK AND RELAX.
AND THEN...
WE GONNA GET BUSY?
YEAH.
WE GONNA DO THAT?
MM-HMM.
MMM. LET ME SLIP INTO SOMETHING
A LITTLE MORE COMFORTABLE.
[ Snickers ]
WHAT YOU DOIN'?
UH, I WAS, UH...
DO YOU...
YOU REMEMBER WHEN THEY DID...
YOU REMEMBER THAT.
[ Laughs ]
I WAS... THIS GUY WAS...
[ Yelps ]
# HEARTBEAT
IT MAKE ME FEEL SO WEAK #
# THERE'S NOTHING I WON'T DO #
# ANYTHING YOU WANT ME TO #
[ Chattering, Laughing ]
# [ Hip Hop From Club ]
FUCK Y'ALL LAUGHING ABOUT?
YOU AIN'T MADE NO MONEY
ALL NIGHT.
CHUCK.
SHUT UP.
[ Chattering Continues ]
YOU SHOULD CAB IT.
# [ Loud Hip Hop ]
SHAKE THAT ASS!
SLAP IT!
SHAKE IT! SHAKE IT!
OH, GIRL!
SHAKE THAT ASS! WHOA!
SHAKE THAT ASS!
YOU KNOW WHAT?
I AIN'T EVEN GOT NO CONDOMS.
[ Giggles ] SHIT, NIGGA,
YOU AIN'T SAYIN' NOTHIN'.
I GOT A WHOLE BOX
OF SHIT HERE.
LET ME SHOW YOU.
ALL RIGHT. SHIT,
I GOT CONDOMS FOR DAYS.
NOW,
SEE THIS RIGHT HERE...
THE RIBBED TICKLER?
NOW THAT'S MY SHIT.
AND IF YOU LIKE
SOME OL' FREAKY,
KINKY SHIT,
THIS RIGHT HERE
WILL DO THE TRICK,
BABY.
AND IF THAT DON'T TURN YOU ON,
OH, I GOT SOMETHIN'
FOR YOUR ASS, HMM?
AND IF ALL ELSE FAILS,
MEET MY FRIEND BLACK CHARLIE.
MM-HMM.
I'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
POP THAT PUSSY!
POP THAT...
MAN, I BEEN LOOKIN' FOR YOU
ALL DAY. HEY, GUESS WHO AT
MY HOUSE RIGHT NOW.
NIGGA, WHO?
WHO, NIGGA?
MAN, ROB.
ROB AT MY HOUSE RIGHT NOW.
COME ON. I'M GONNA
ROLL OUT THERE WITH TONE.
[ Chattering ]
HEY, Y'ALL GOING TO GET
THE HOOPTY, RIGHT?
[ Vibrator Buzzing ]
YES, ROB. OH.
OH, THAT'S HOW I LIKE IT.
YEAH. YEAH, THAT'S
HOW I LIKE IT, BABY. YEAH.
[ Chattering ]
I DON'T GIVE A FUCK, MAN.
FOR REAL.
[ Chattering Continues ]
ANYBODY IN THERE, MAN?
ALL RIGHT.
[ Vibrator Buzzing ]
[ Dahlia Moaning ]
ROB.
[ Buzzing, Moaning Continues ]
SHH, SHH, SHH.
UH, UH, UH!
YOU DIDN'T THINK I WAS
GONNA CATCH UP TO YOU, DID YOU?
MAN, I... MAN, I...
DID YOU? DID YOU?
WHY YOU LEAVE LIL' HOMEY
ALL STUCK?
I DIDN'T LEAVE HOMEY NOTHIN'.
- YOU WERE SUPPOSED
TO PICK ME UP ANYWAY.
- YOU BETTER LOWER YOUR VOICE.
YOU WAS SUPPOSED
TO PICK ME UP ANYWAY.
YOU STILL LEFT
THE LITTLE HOMEY ALL STUCK.
HE IN THE HOSPITAL
WITH HIS ASS IN A SLING.
I TOLD YOU,
I AIN'T HAD NOTHIN'
TO DO WITH THAT, MAN.
HOMEY PICKED ME UP...
WHY YOU MOVIN' YOUR HANDS
LIKE THAT?
KEEP YOUR HANDS
TO YOUR MOTHERFUCKING SIDE.
MAN, HOMEY PICKED ME UP,
WE GOT PULLED OVER
BY THE POLICE,
HE GETS OF THE CAR
AND START DUMPIN'.
- I RAN. I MEAN, WHAT?
- [ Mocking ]
I RAN. I MEAN, WHAT?
I'M TIRED OF THIS SHIT,
NIGGA!
DAMN!
OH!
WHY THAT NIGGA DO THAT?
BLUE, CATCH HIM!
SHIT!
YEAH!
[ All Yelling ]
[ Yelling Continues ]
[ Tires Screeching ]
[ Siren Wails ]
DAMN, I NEVER THOUGHT
I'D BE HAPPY TO SEE THEY ASS.
GO GET HIM, ADOLF!
GO ON!
[ Officer ]
DISPATCH, 59-12.
PURSUING THE FREEWAY SHOOTER.
[ Panting ]
[ Growling ]
THIS MOTHERFUCKER'S FAST.
WE'RE GONNA NEED BACKUP.
SHIT! AH! SHIT.
SHIT.
[ Grunting ]
[ Growls, Yelps ]
[ Yells ]
[ Exhales Deeply ]
SHIT.
[ Tires
Screeching ]
[ Engine Starts ]
[ Siren Wailing ]
UNIT 12 TO DISPATCH.
I'M IN PURSUIT OF THE SUSPECT
IN THE FREEWAY SHOOTING.
[ Cop ]
TURN, SON OF A BITCH!
TURN! TURN!
DON'T BE YELLING IN MY EAR!
GODDAMN!
TURN!
HEY, LOOK. STAY DOWN.
I SHOULD HAVE SHOT HIS ASS
WHEN I HAD THE CHANCE.
COME ON, COME ON, COME ON,
COME ON, COME ON, BABY.
[ Sirens Wailing ]
HUH?
[ Phone Ringing ]
SHH...
HELLO? HOLD ON
FOR A SECOND, BROTHER.
I GOT THREE PEOPLE WAITING.
HOLD ON A SECOND.
YO, MIKE. IT'S ROB.
YOU GET THAT LAWYER FOR ME?
DONE DEAL.
I GOT THE BOY LIBOWITZ.
I TOLD YOU THAT, WEEBLE-IZATION.
COOL. I NEED YOU TO CALL HIM
AND TELL HIM TO CALL...
WHAT THAT FOOL NAME
WHO WORK FOR CHANNEL FIVE NEWS?
- UH, UH, UH...
- STAN, STAN WILSON, YEAH!
TELL HIM TO MEET ME
AT FIRST A.M.E. CHURCH.
TELL HIM I GOT A HIGHLIGHT
STORY ON THE FREEWAY SHOOTIN'.
TELL HIM TO MEET ME THERE
IN TEN MINUTES.
WHERE YOU AT NOW?
- I'M IN TRAFFIC.
- [ Tires Screeching ]
[ Jenkins ]
HOLD ON!
I'M JUST TWO SECONDS OFF
HIS STINKIN' ASS!
OOH, OOH!
I'M GONNA FUCK HIM UP!
OOH, I'M GONNA FUCK HIM UP!
[ All Yelling ]
[ Gasping ]
SHIT! OH, GOD.
- GET OUT OF THE CAR!
- FREEZE!
- PUT YOUR HANDS UP!
- GET OUT!
ALL RIGHT.
HOLD YOUR FIRE, MEN!
DROP YOUR WEAPONS,
COME OUT WITH YOUR HANDS UP
AND YOU WILL NOT BE HARMED!
I DON'T GOT NO WEAPONS!
[ Whispering ]
OH, SHIT.
LOOK OUT!
HE'S GOT A GUN!
[ Everyone Shouting ]
[ Gunshots ]
[ Cop ]
SAVE YOUR FIRE!
[ Shouting Continues ]
THESE MOTHERFUCKERS
IS TRYING TO KILL ME.
I'M STAN WILSON,
AND I'M COMING
TO YOU TODAY, LIVE,
BECAUSE I RECEIVED A PHONE CALL
FROM LEON LIBOWITZ.
MR. LIBOWITZ IS BELIEVED TO BE
THE ATTORNEY OF THE SUSPECT
IN THE FREEWAY SHOOTING,
ROBERT DOUGLAS.
DOUGLAS FEELS
HIS LIFE IS IN DANGER...
AND HAS AGREED TO COME IN
TO ME, HERE, TODAY,
OUT IN PLAIN SIGHT
OF THE VIEWING PUBLIC.
[ Dog Barking ]
SHIT!
[ Helicopter Blades Whirring ]
NOW, I'VE JUST BEEN INFORMED
THAT THE LOS ANGELES
POLICE DEPARTMENT...
IS PURSUING MR. DOUGLAS
ON FOOT.
CAN WE GO TO SKY 12
FOR COVERAGE?
BOB, ARE YOU WITH ME?
[ Bob ]
YES, I AM, STAN, AND WE'VE GOT
THE SUSPECT IN VIEW RIGHT NOW.
LOOKS LIKE THREE OR FOUR
L.A.P.D. OFFICERS ARE IN
FOOT PURSUIT RIGHT BEHIND HIM.
[ Stan ] HAVE YOU GOT HIM
IN SIGHT? CAN YOU SEE HIM?
[ Bob ] UH, NO, STAN.
IT APPEARS WE'VE LOST HIM.
THERE'S SOME DENSE SHRUBBERY
DOWN THERE.
WE CAN SEE L.A.P.D.
IN PURSUIT,
BUT FOR ACTUALLY SEEING
THE SUSPECT, WE'VE LOST HIM.
OKAY. THANK YOU, BOB.
WE'LL BE STANDING BY.
[ Rob ] THIS SHIT IS CRAZY!
[ Wilson ]
AS I SAID BEFORE,
THE SUSPECT'S ATTORNEY
MR. LIBOWITZ DID CALL IN
TO SAY...
MR. DOUGLAS DID FEAR
FOR HIS LIFE.
AFTER ALL, HE DID SHOOT
AT A POLICEMAN.
[ Sirens Wailing ]
AND NOW IT LOOKS LIKE
HE HAS GOOD REASON.
[ Chattering ]
MOBILE SWAT COMING IN,
AND THE POLICE COMING IN.
- LET'S HOPE HE MAKES IT.
- [ Dog Barking ]
- NICE DOGGIE. DOWN BOY.
[ Chattering ]
[ Man ]
MOVE OVER HERE! THESE GUYS.
WHERE ARE THEY GOING?
STANDING BY FOR ORDERS, SIR.
ALL RIGHT. RIGHT.
FIRST THING WE GOT TO DO
IS GET SOME MORE DONUTS.
[ Laughs ]
YOU HEARD WHAT I SAID, ROBERTS?
I SAID, "GET SOME MORE DONUTS."
[ Laughs ]
UH, YES.
I'M DETECTIVE JENKINS,
OFFICER IN CHARGE.
WHAT WE'RE DOING
IS A STANDARD SWEEP.
WE'RE GONNA LOCK DOWN
THE AREA IN ORDER
TO LOCATE THE PERPETRATOR.
[ Man ]
ALL RIGHT. I GOT IT.
WE GOT A CANINE UNIT OUT.
[ Announcer ]
CHANNEL SIX.
NEWS BEFORE IT HAPPENS.
FROM THE DESERT TO THE SEA
TO ALL OF SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA,
A GOOD EVENING.
JERRY DUNPHY HERE.
THE MAN WHO ALLEGEDLY
OPENED FIRE...
WITH AN AUTOMATIC WEAPON
ON TWO CALIFORNIA
HIGHWAY PATROL OFFICERS...
HAS BEEN IDENTIFIED
BY LAW ENFORCEMENT OFFICIALS...
AS LOS ANGELES RESIDENT
ROBERT DOUGLAS.
THEY'RE GONNA KILL MY BABY!
LOOK AT THAT!
I SEE IT.
THAT BOY CAN RUN, CAN'T HE?
RUN LIKE ME.
I USED TO BE A SUPERSTAR.
GO, BOY! HE JUMPED THAT FENCE
LIKE YOU, THOUGH.
HE'S GOIN' NOW.
THEY AIN'T GONNA CATCH HIM.
HE ALL RIGHT.
[ Cackling ]
POLICE CAN'T CATCH HIM.
THAT'S MY BOY...
WITH HIS SORRY ASS.
[ Dahlia ]
OH, ROB!
[ Vibrator Buzzing ]
OOH, ROB!
[ Newscaster ] IT WILL BE
COMPRISED OF POLICE OFFICERS.
[ Dahlia ] IT JUST HASN'T
BEEN THE SAME WITHOUT YOU.
[ zzing Continues ]
OOH! MMM.
THE SO-CALLED FREEWAY FELON.
FOR THE LATEST
ON THE FREEWAY FELON,
WE GO LIVE TO TRICK TURNER
AT THE FIRST A.M.E. CHURCH.
TRICK?
I'M STANDING HERE RIGHT NOW
WITH MR. LIBOWITZ.
MR. LIBOWITZ IS GONNA SHED SOME
LIGHT ON THE SITUATION FOR US.
MR. LIBOWITZ, WHAT CAN
YOU TELL US ABOUT THE ORDEAL?
AS I STATED TO YOU OVER
THE PHONE, I RECEIVED A CALL
FROM ANOTHER CLIENT OF MINE...
WHO ASKED ME
TO REPRESENT MR. DOUGLAS.
THERE'S NOT MUCH MORE FOR ME
TO STIPULATE AT THIS TIME.
[ Softly ]
MOTHERFUCKER.
BACK TO YOU, JERRY.
THANK YOU FOR THAT BIT
OF INFORMATION.
THE TWO-TIME FELON
WAS RELEASED ON PAROLE
MINUTES BEFORE THE SHOOTING.
[ Man ]
YO, J.J.,
YOU WATCHIN' THIS SHIT?
I'M PEEPIN' THIS SHIT, MAN.
I HOPE THEY HURRY AND KILL
THAT MOTHERFUCKER...
BEFORE I CAN STOP
SWEATING THIS SHIT.
YOU THINK THAT FOOL
IS GONNA SNITCH ON YOU?
NIGGA,
IT'S EITHER HIM OR ME.
WE ALMOST GOT HIM!
[ Tires Screeching ]
[ Grunts ]
SHIT.
NIGGA, GET IN! GET IN!
[ Rob ] HOW'D YOU FIND ME?
YOU ALL OVER THE NEWS,
MY WEEBLE-IZATION.
SUSPECT IS HEADING WEST
ON TAYLOR IN A GREEN S.U.V.
[ Rob ]
WHAT'S GOING ON, MAN?
THEY TRIPPIN', MAN.
THEY TRYIN' TO KILL ME
AND STUFF.
[ Sirens Wailing ]
OH, MAN, MAN, MAN!
NOT SOME MORE HELICOPTERS!
COME ON, MAN!
GO, GO, GO!
[ Man ]
BE ADVISED WE HAVE SPOTTED
SUSPECT IN GREEN S.U.V.
HE IS HEADED YOUR WAY
TOWARD THE COMMAND POST...
AT THE FIRST A.M.E. CHURCH,
OVER.
WE ON THE NEWS!
WE ON THE NEWS, MAN!
HOW WE GONNA GET AWAY
WHEN WE ON THE NEWS?
THEY KNOW WHERE WE GOIN'!
[ Mike ]
MAN, YOU HOTTER THAN GONORRHEA.
[ Tires Screeching ]
[ Cop ]
WE GOT HIM! WE GOT HIM!
[ Rob ] BE CAREFUL!
WE GOT HIM HEMMED IN!
THERE'S NO WAY HE'S GONNA
GET OUT.
[ Rob ]
OH, SHIT!
WHERE THE HELL IS HE GOING?
- BACK IT UP! BACK IT UP!
- HELL, MAN. SLOW DOWN.
SLOW DOWN, DUDE.
[ Mike ] DON'T TRIP.
I GOT THE LAWYER POSTED UP
LIKE A THUMBTACK...
WAITIN' AT THE CHURCH HOUSE,
WEEBLE-IZATION.
SO, MR. LIBOWITZ,
I CAN'T UNDERSTAND
FOR THE LIFE OF ME...
[ Horn Honking ]
[ Rob ] OH, SHIT.
I THINK YOU HIT SOMEBODY!
OH, SHIT.
OH, GODDAMN.
[ Man ]
GO, GO, GO, GO, GO!
[ Tires Screeching ]
HOLD YOUR FIRE!
DOWN, DOWN, DOWN, DOWN!
- [ Bob ] AND IT LOOKS
LIKE THEY HAVE THE SUSPECT.
- I'M DOWN, I'M DOWN, I'M DOWN!
[ Chattering ]
DON'T MOVE.
WE GOT HIM, GUYS.
DON'T MOVE!
HE'S DOWN.
HE'S FACE DOWN.
[ Bob ] YES, STAN, HE IS,
AND IT LOOKS LIKE THE OFFICERS
HAVE THE SUSPECT IN CUSTODY.
- STAN, BACK TO YOU
ON THE GROUND.
- [ Chattering Continues ]
[ Wilson ] HE IS ERECT.
HE IS STANDING ON HIS OWN
TWO FEET.
HE SEEMS NONE THE WORSE
FOR WEAR.
THE SAGA OF ROBERT DOUGLAS
IS OVER.
[ Chattering Continues ]
[ Man ]
I LOVE THIS MAN.
[ Gavel Pounding ]
YOUR HONOR, THIS GIBBERISH
ABOUT THE DEFENDANT FEARING FOR
HIS LIFE IS TOTALLY LUDICROUS.
APPARENTLY, COUNSEL
WOULD LIKE TO MAKE A MOCKERY
OUT OF THIS SITUATION...
- AND AMELIORATE THE CHARGES.
- AMELIORATE? WHAT THAT MEAN?
YOUR HONOR,
THAT'S PREPOSTEROUS,
NOT TO MENTION LUDICROUS!
COUNSEL, APPROACH THE BENCH.
I DIDN'T PLAN TO SPEND
THE WHOLE DAY IN HERE, YOU KNOW.
[ Breaks Wind ]
I STRONGLY ADVISE IF YOU HAVE
A POINT TO MAKE, MAKE IT.
LET'S GET OVER WITH IT.
I ALREADY LISTENED TO THE TAPE
IN MY CHAMBERS...
THAT CLEARLY PROVES
THAT MR. DOUGLAS...
IS NOT AT FAULT
WITH THE SHOOTING
THAT OCCURRED,
NOR DID HE HAVE KNOWLEDGE
THAT THAT CAR WAS STOLEN.
NEED I SAY MORE?
[ Breaking Wind ]
[ Grumbles ]
OOH!
GOOD GOD ALMIGHTY. SHIT.
YOUR HONOR, I WOULD LIKE TO HAVE
ALL FORMAL CHARGES DISMISSED...
AND TO HAVE MY CLIENT RELEASED
FROM CUSTODY IMMEDIATELY.
YOUR HONOR, I HAVE NO PROBLEM
WITH DROPPING THE CHARGES
FOR GRAND THEFT AUTO...
OR SHOOTING
AT A LAW ENFORCEMENT OFFICER.
HOWEVER, THE DEFENDANT DID FAIL
TO REPORT TO HIS PAROLE OFFICER
AT THE APPROPRIATE TIME,
HE COULDN'T DO IT.
WHICH IS A DIRECT VIOLATION
OF HIS PAROLE.
NOT TO MENTION THE CHARGES FOR
EVADING AND RESISTING ARREST.
I WASN'T RESISTING ARREST.
THEY WAS JUST WHOOPIN' MY ASS.
- YOU TELL 'EM, BABY.
- ORDER!
NOW, COOL WITH THE ATTITUDE.
I THINK WE GOT IT OUR WAY.
YOUR HONOR,
IF IT WOULD PLEASE THE COURT,
AND TO AVOID ANY DIFFICULTY
WITH THIS ARRAIGNMENT,
MY CLIENT HAS AGREED
TO ACCEPT THE PAROLE VIOLATION.
- DID HE?
- YOUR HONOR,
I CONCUR WITH THE MOTION.
VERY WELL. MR. DOUGLAS,
ARE YOU AWARE OF THE CHAOS...
YOU HAVE CAUSED
IN THE LAST THREE DAYS?
YOU ARE INDIRECTLY RESPONSIBLE
FOR ENDANGERING...
THE LIVES OF OTHERS
AS WELL AS YOUR OWN...
AND CREATING
A MASS-MEDIA HYSTERIA,
NEARLY STARTING A RIOT IN FRONT
OF A VERY PROMINENT CHURCH.
YOU HAVE ANYTHING
TO SAY FOR YOURSELF?
NO, MAN. I... HONOR...
Y-YOUR HONOR.
MR. DOUGLAS,
I SENTENCE YOU...
TO REMAIN IN CUSTODY
FOR VIOLATING CONDITIONS
OF YOUR ORIGINAL PAROLE...
FOR A PERIOD
NOT TO EXCEED 30 DAYS.
THIS WILL NOT COUNT
AS A THIRD STRIKE.
[ Sighs ]
THIS COURT IS ADJOURNED.
SON, WHEN YOU GET OUT THIS TIME,
HAVE YOUR ASS OUT FRONT.
I'M GONNA PICK YOU UP MYSELF.
MAKE SURE YOUR ASS
GET HOME THIS TIME.
YOU TAKE CARE OF YOURSELF, BABY.
[ Juanita ] I'LL WAIT
FOR YOU ANOTHER YEAR.
LOVE YOU.
I TOLD YOU
THIS WAS GONNA HAPPEN.
KNUCKLEHEAD.
YOU SHUT UP.
SHH!
[ Breaks Wind ]
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
I'LL BE ALL RIGHT, Y'ALL.
[ Breaks Wind ]
OH, BABY.
WHAT'S WRONG WITH YOU?
YEAH! GET...
[ Gates Slam ]
[ Buzzer Sounds ]
[ Slamming Continues ]
[ Chattering ]
PUSH-UPS, HOMEY.
HEY, HOMEY.
[ Speaking Spanish ]
OH, KITCHEN PUSSY'S BACK.
WHOA.
COME ON.
[ Spanish Continues ]
[ Buzzer Sounds ]
[ Gates Slam ]
#
HEY, J.J.
NIGGA, THIS IS FAIZ...
[ Laughing ]
[ Man ]
CUT!
[ Laughing Continues ]
OH!
HEY, J.J. NIGGA, WHAT'S UP?
THIS IS ROB, NIGGA.
CUT!
YOU SHOULDN'T HAVE LEFT
THE LITTLE HOMEY STUCK.
I TOLD YOU I AIN'T HAD
NOTHIN' TO DO WITH THAT.
LOOK, MAN.
THE POLICE PICKED US UP.
NO, WE WENT TO THE, UH...
McDONALD'S?
PAY NO ATTENTION TO HIM.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO LEAVE NOW.
BABY, JUST LET ME EXPLAIN.
STUCK. CAN'T GET OUT.
[ Laughing ]
[ Chattering, Indistinct ]
WHERE HAVE YOU BEEN?
HOLD IT, HOLD IT.
I'M A GROWN-ASS MAN.
WAIT A MINUTE, GIRL.
[ Laughing ]
WAIT.
CLOSED-CAPTIONED BY
CAPTIONS, INC. LOS ANGELES
# IF IT AIN'T CHRONIC
DON'T BLAZE IT UP #
# AND IF IT AIN'T A CHEVY
DON'T RAISE IT UP #
# YOU KNOW WE KEEP IT BANGIN'
DON'T FAKE THE FUNK #
# SO ALL THE REAL NIGGAS
STAY GANGSTA'D UP #
# WE MAKIN' PAPER
SUCKAS ONLY CLAIM TO TOUCH #
# BY STICKIN' TO THE SCRIPT
AND NEVER CHANGIN' UP #
# YOU KNOW WE KEEP IT BANGIN'
DON'T FAKE THE FUNK #
# KEEP IT REAL, MOTHERFUCKERS
STAY GANGSTA'D UP #
# IT'S GOIN' DOWN, MOTHERFUCKERS
LIKE THAT #
# SOUND LIKE BATTLECAT
BEEN UPSTAIRS WITH ZAPP #
# AND THE KNOCKIN' DON'T STOP #
# I HOPE NOBODY
DON'T CALL THE COPS #
# IT DON'T STOP, THE BEAT
WILL MAKE YOUR POP BLOCK #
# NO BETTER YET, THIS SHIT
WILL KEEP YOUR GLOCK COCKED #
# YOU THINK I'M TRIPPIN'
FOOL, I AIN'T BULLSHITTIN' #
# YOU BETTER READ UP
ON THIS SHIT TO KEEP
THE LATEST NONFICTION #
# WATCH OUT FOR THE FRICTION
THIS WEST COAST ALL MINE #
# AND FUCK ANYBODY DISSIN'
NIGGA, LISTEN #
# DOGG HOUSE STYLE
'CAUSE I'M A GANGSTER CRIP #
# C-WALKIN' HOLDIN'
ON THE EXTRA CLIP #
# NOW YOU WANNA BE A FRIEND #
# BUT YOU GONNA MAKE ME UNLOAD
AND SLAP THE OTHER CLIP IN
AND RELOAD #
# YOU WANNA GO TOE TO TOE #
# SET MY PISTOL DOWN
ON THE GROUND ON THE POUND
NIGGA, HELL NO #
# I STAY GANGSTA'D UP
'CAUSE IT JUST LIVES IN ME #
# AND WHEN I SEEN ENOUGH #
# I GUESS THAT'S WHEN
I'LL BE SOMEBODY #
# ONCE SAID FROM WILLIE C. #
# NIGGA, DON'T SPEAK ON ME #
# I WON'T STOP SO LET ME BE #
# WE ARE FROM THE STREETS
SOMEBODY #
# I'M A LONG BEACH EAST SIDE
MAD-ASS LUNATIC #
# GANG-BANG, SLAP-A-BITCH NIGGA
OUT TO GET A GRIP #
# ON THE GRIND, GETTIN' MINE
ASK THE HOMEYS ON THE NINE #
# TWO-OH, YOU KNOW #
# WE STILL OWN NIGGAS
WHO TALK BIG SHIT #
# REAL NIGGAS FEEL THIS
LET'S GET RICH #
# UNDER THE SUN
WITH THE YOUNG TWO ONES #
# TLCs AND ALL THE DPGs #
# DOWN FOR WHATEVER
WHOEVER WANNA SEE ME NOW #
# YOU'RE LOOKIN' LIKE ME
I GUESS YOU WANNA BE ME NOW #
# IT TAKE A WHOLE LOT
TO BE SNOOP D-O-DUB #
# YOU GOTTA PUT IT DOWN
AND ALWAYS STAY G'D UP #
# ALL-STAR SHOES
WITH THE G APPAREL #
# IF I FALL IN THE CLUB I MIGHT
BUST A PAIR OF STACY ADAMS #
# YOU NEVER CATCH ME
LOOKIN' R & B #
# I MIGHT BE IN A THREE-PIECE
SUIT LOOKIN' WAY O.G. #
# BLAZIN' AN OUNCE
WITH THE HOMEY CAT #
# A ROUGH DOG 'CAUSE I LOVE
PUTTIN' HUSTLERS ON THE MAP #
# I KEEP IT GANGSTER FOR SURE
THOUGH, LOC #
# AND ALWAYS GOT THE
MOTHERFUCKIN' DODO SMOKE #
# FOR ALL MY LOCS AND KINFOLKS
THIS IS FOR Y'ALL #
# LET ME GET SOME, DOG
LET ME GET SOME #
# BEWARE OF MY CLICK
WE HOPPIN' AND DROPPIN' #
# NOTHIN'
BUT THE GANGSTER SHIT #
# IF IT AIN'T CHRONIC
DON'T BLAZE IT UP #
# AND IF IT AIN'T A CHEVY
DON'T RAISE IT UP #
# YOU KNOW WE KEEP IT BANGIN'
DON'T FAKE THE FUNK #
# FOR ALL MY REAL NIGGAS
STAY GANGSTA'D UP #
# WE MAKIN' PAPER
SUCKERS ONLY CLAIM TO TOUCH #
# BY STICKIN' TO THE SCRIPT
AND NEVER CHANGIN' UP #
# YOU KNOW WE KEEP IT BANGIN'
DON'T FAKE THE FUNK #
# KEEP IT REAL, MOTHERFUCKER
STAY GANGSTA'D UP #
# GANGSTER, HA, HA
DOGG HOUSE #
# SOMETHING FOR THE 9-5
PLUS FOUR PENNIES #
# DOGG HOUSE, TRAY-DEE
GOLDIE LOC, YEAH #
# MY NIGGA BATTLECAT
ON THE BEAT #