We are currently on a family trip
If you need to reach us,
please call tomorrow
Be happy!
Open the door
you have the keys!
You wanted to go on a trip so badly.
What's wrong now?
You call that a trip?
It was hell
Get rid of that right now!
Shoot me. Shoot me.
Please make my day
Why aren't you picking up?
Are you still angry at me?
I'm sorry.
Hurry and pick up
I've done everything for you!
What are you unsatisfied with?
You are driving me nuts!
Pick up the phone!
Damn it!
Pick up the phone now!
You want to see me
go crazy again?
I want to talk, so pick up!
If you don't answer the phone,
I will go home right now
What are you doing
with all the doors open?
And can't you answer the phone?
I couldn't get any work done
on my business trip!
Why are you ignoring me?
Do I look that foolish to you?
Am I your slave?
What do I need to do?
Think it's easy to live this well?
I told you not to wear this!
Why do you keep doing
the things I hate?
I'm sorry
I don't know why I act this way
I love you
Please make me happy
Why? Why do you make
me feel so wretched?
For once let me do as I want to!
Think I'll devour you?
Am I some insect?
Just please hold still. Please.
What the hell?
Who's playing golf in my yard?
How'd you get in here?
Hello? Is this the police?
What are you doing?
Are you crazy?
Hello? My house is...
Hi, this is Oak Jin-Gon
I'm abroad right now
for a photo shoot
If you need to reach me,
please call 011-342-3464
Thanks
Hi, you've reached the home
of Ji-Eun and Hyun-Soo
We're in Hawaii now
for our three year anniversary
If you have something to say,
please leave a message after the beep
What the hell's this?
See if they've taken anything
Honey! Honey!
Who the hell are you?
What are you drunk idiots
doing in my home?
And why are you two
wearing our pajamas?
- Anything stolen?
- No
If you're not thieves,
then what are you?
Mi-Young, open your eyes!
Mi-Young!
Mi-Young, wake up!
Mi-Young, are you alright?
Mi-Young!
Mi-Young, wake up!
Wake up! Mi-Young!
Mi-Young! Mi-Young!
Mi-Young, wake up!
Please open your eyes!
We are off to Jeju island!
If you need to contact us
please call back in three days!
Be happy!
Dad, did you call?
Are you okay, dad?
Hello?
Hello...
Dad!
Father!
Who are you people?
What are you doing
in my father's home?
Where's father?
- Father!
- He's not here
- What?
You two.
Stay where you are
Come outside
Hello? This is the police, right?
Yes, I have a situation here.
Please come quickly
What did you do to the old man?
Sweetheart, you tell me
You killed him, right?
What's this?
I see you've broken into
many other homes
So you took pictures
as if it was your own home
Officer Lee, see if their owners
reported a burglary
Yes, sir
You two. What did you steal
from all these homes?
This punk needs to learn a lesson
Take the woman outside
Sorry to keep you waiting
He buried him secretly
near his apartment
What?
- Officer Lee!
- Yes, sir!
Take the CIS team
to his father's apartment
Open the lid
Father...
Father!
Doesn't look like
he was buried in secret
Father
Missing person report
This is you, isn't it?
Yes?
Yes, I understand
Illegal entry. Murder
Abandoning a dead body.
Kidnapping
If you have any others,
tell me now
What did you do to that woman?
What did you do to her
to keep her so silent?
Sir, he's clean
Also, I called some of the houses
he shot with the camera,
and they said nothing was stolen
Really?
- Bring her husband when he comes
- Yes, sir
You even have a college degree.
So why'd you break into their homes?
Sir, he's here
Tell him to come in
Lee Min-Kyu, right?
Yes
She's all yours
Son of a bitch!
Stop it!
Let go!
I'm gonna kill that bastard!
Let's go
Sir!
The autopsy results
have come out
it's not murder, it's lung cancer
What? Lung cancer?
- Are they sure?
- Yes, I understand
He was delicately shrouded.
Apart from a real ceremony,
He buried his body
better than any son could
He doesn't seem
like a bad person to me
- Wait outside
- Yes, sir
Well, you're free from
the homicide charge
So how was she?
You liked forcing her, right?
What are you looking at?
Don't smile
Your favorite plant over there...
I knew you'd come back
so I took good care of it
It looks healthy, doesn't it?
I've thought things out
and I'd been too much
I'll be good from now on
Okay, I won't if
you don't want me to
I've changed, you see?
Oh yeah, while you were gone,
I sent plenty of money to your folks
If it's that hard to withstand,
then do what you like
Isn't he being too harsh?
Smile again
Let go, you bastard!
Son of a bitch!
Sit down!
Prisoner 2904!
Playing games with me, you punk?
You scared me!
Try that again
Today, you go hungry
Don't pretend you're sleeping
I've been thinking about us,
and I feel like a real dumb ass
Was I that bad to you?
Tell me!
I never wanted to ask this,
but I have to
What did he do to you?
Did he do this?
He did this, but you stayed still?
Like this?
Like this? Like this?
Prisoner 2904!
You son of a bitch!
Why do you keep hiding?
Wanna disappear
from the world altogether?
If you pull that again,
I'll kill you
Can I help you?
Excuse me!
- You're cleaning it again?
- Hi, honey
Who is she?
I don't know
Let her sleep
Where have you been?
I told you to call me
if you go out!
Where have you been?
You're behind me, aren't you?
The human eye sees
within the 180 degree angle
so you're hiding
in the other 180 degrees?
But that's impossible!
You bastard!
You need more practice.
And take care of the shadow
and you'll have to calculate
the human mind, idiot!
You crazy bastard.
Even if you cover all that
what are you gonna do?
Let's move out of here.
First thing tomorrow
You're waiting for him
to finish his sentence, aren't you?
I'm right, aren't i?
A moving service please.
Hello?
What's with you?
Fine, then
let's wait together for him
I dare you to come,
you son of a bitch
Prisoner 2904! Your meal!
Prisoner 2904!
When I go in this time,
I'll kill you for sure!
You're behind me, aren't you?
Trying to escape?
Bastard...
You think you can play with me now,
don't you?
You fucking ghost
come out!
We have a laundry machine.
Why go through the trouble?
Hello?
The police?
Yes, I understand
That bastard is out now
Son of a bitch,
I dare you to show up
Tell me
Tell me!
Why'd you turn off your phone?
- Know how many times I've called you?
- I told you!
I told you many times!
My battery ran out
Rotten bastard
Think I'm that stupid?
Who did you meet?
What the hell's wrong with you?
Are you mentally sick?
You made me this way
Who's the girl who always
calls late at night?
Let's stop this
Did you just hear something?
- What are you talking about?
- Hold on
I think someone's in the house
Who cares whether
someone's here or not
- I'm the idiot for trusting...
- No, I'm certain someone's in here
- Don't play the psycho act with me
- Hold on
Someone's here for sure
So who's here?
I swear someone's here
I don't wanna hear it!
I don't trust you at all!
You see?
I told you someone was here
Oh my goodness!
You scared me
I did? So how was your day?
Good
Why didn't you tidy up the sofa?
I did this morning
But why is it so messy?
That's strange
Can't sleep?
Want me to sing you a lullaby?
I miss you, too
Wanna come over?
Hey, it's weird
It feels like someone's in my place
Yeah
Then hurry up
So who's in your place?
I didn't see anyone.
I just felt it
That's impossible
Am I just being too sensitive?
- Isn't this your work?
- You haven't seen it yet?
- Can I look at it?
- Yup
- Stop it
- Come on
- I thought someone was here?
- Let him watch
- What's wrong?
- I think someone's watching
I'm scared
You see? What did I tell you?
What is it?
Why'd you hang up an empty frame?
It's creepy
I think someone's here
could it be him?
He's bad luck,
that son of a bitch
Honey, stay still
What are you doing up?
I love you
What?
Honey...
Breakfast is ready!
What's made you so happy?
Stop smiling and eat
It's strange
It feels like someone's been here
since last night
What are you laughing for?
Are you that happy?
Don't open the door
to just anybody