- * YOU SAY THE SUN
* ISN'T ENOUGH
* SO I'LL BRING YOU THE MOON
* AND THE STARS ABOVE
* YOU SAY THE WORLD
* COULD USE SOME MORE LOVE
* SO I WRAP IT IN ROSES
* AND ANGEL DUST
* AND WHEN YOU CALL
* FOR ME TO MEET YOU
* I'LL COME RUNNING
* TO YOUR DOOR
* AND I'LL CALL YOUR NAME
* FROM THE STREET TO MEET ME
* ON THE SECOND FLOOR
* YOU SAY THE RAIN
* IT MAKES YOU HAPPY
* SO I'LL BRING IT POURING
* UNTIL IT FLOODS
* YOU SAY A GIRL
* IS NEVER EASY
* TO UNDERSTAND
* SO CONFUSED I RUSH
* AND WHEN YOU FALL
* I'LL TRY TO CATCH YOU
* AND WHEN YOU CRY
* I'LL KNOW WHAT FOR
* AND I'LL DRY YOUR TEARS
WHEN I COME TO MEET YOU... **
(FAUCET DRIPPING)
- HEY.
- OH, HEY.
WHAT'S UP?
- NOTHING.
I'M JUST GOING
TO RUN INTO TOWN.
WE NEED SOME GROCERIES.
- AH.
DO YOU WANT ME TO GO WITH YOU?
- NOT IF YOU'RE GOING
TO RUSH ME.
- JUST GROCERIES, RIGHT?
- MAYBE A COUPLE OTHER THINGS.
NEVER MIND.
- I'LL COME IF YOU WANT ME TO.
- NOPE.
- LOVE YOU.
(DOOR OPENS AND CLOSES)
(CHATTING)
(BEEPING)
- HEY.
- MARC.
HEY, HOW'S IT GOING?
- GOOD. FINE, FINE.
I THOUGHT THAT WAS YOU.
AROUND THE CORNER
ON THE SIDEWALK.
YOU DIDN'T SEE ME.
- OH, NO, I GUESS NOT.
- HOW HAVE YOU BEEN?
I HAVEN'T SEEN YOU IN...FOREVER.
- IT'S BEEN A WHILE.
- YEAH.
- WHAT BRINGS YOU
OUT THIS WAY?
- UM. BUSINESS, ACTUALLY.
YEAH.
I'M TALKING WITH SOME INVESTORS
ABOUT MY NEXT PROJECT.
IT'S ACTUALLY--
ACTUALLY REALLY EXCITING.
UM...IS DAVID IN TOWN, TOO?
- YEAH. HE'S BACK AT THE HOUSE.
- OKAY. YEAH.
SAME ONE?
- YEAH.
- OH.
AND DAVID'S...DAVID'S WELL?
- YEAH, HE'S GOOD.
HE'S...YOU KNOW,
HE'S THE SAME.
YOU KNOW DAVID.
- YEAH, YEAH, I DO.
- ACTUALLY, I TOLD HIM I WASN'T
GOING TO BE LONG, SO--
- OH, OKAY, YEAH, YEAH.
WELL, GET OUT OF HERE.
WELL, ACTUALLY, YOU KNOW WHAT?
WE-- WE SHOULD HAVE DINNER.
- YES. YES, DEFINITELY.
- YEAH.
- WHY DON'T YOU GIVE US A CALL
AND WE'LL PICK A DAY?
- CALL YOU?
- YEAH.
- OKAY.
ALL RIGHT, I WILL.
- ALL RIGHT.
- I GOTTA RUN.
- OKAY. YEAH.
ACTUALLY, WAIT, HOLD ON ONE
SECOND.
THERE'S ACTUALLY SOMEONE THAT
I REALLY WANT YOU TO MEET.
- LOST YOU.
YOU WALK SO FAST.
- SORRY. CATHERINE,
THIS IS JULIE.
JULIE, CATHERINE.
- NICE TO MEET YOU.
- NICE TO MEET YOU, TOO.
- JULIE AND DAVID...
- OH!
OKAY, YEAH, YEAH, RIGHT.
THE THEATER. UM...
MARC'S TOLD ME SO MUCH
ABOUT THE THREE OF YOU
AND THE THEATER.
SOUNDS LIKE THOSE WERE SOME
PRETTY FUN TIMES.
- YEAH, THEY WERE.
- JULIE WAS THE BEST.
SHE WAS JUST ALWAYS SO
COLLABORATIVE AND GREAT.
- MARC GETS SO WORKED UP WHEN
HE TALKS ABOUT THOSE TIMES.
YEAH, YOU DO.
SOUNDS LIKE IT WAS
EVERY ACTOR'S DREAM.
GREAT WRITERS, EXPERIMENTING,
PUSHING BOUNDARIES.
- (LAUGHING)
- JUST EXPLORING.
- YEAH.
YEAH, DEFINITELY.
(HONKS HORN)
(BOTH LAUGHING)
- I HAVE TO MEET DAVID.
IS HE OUT HERE, TOO?
- YEAH, HE IS. I WAS JUST--
- YEAH, WELL, JULIE SAID
THAT WE SHOULD JUST CALL.
- OH.
- YEAH.
- OKAY. GREAT.
YEAH, IT'LL BE FUN.
- YEAH.
- SO WE WILL--
WE WILL CALL YOU.
- OKAY. GREAT.
- ALL RIGHT.
- IT WAS NICE MEETING YOU.
- NICE TO MEET YOU, TOO.
- UM...
DO YOU AND DAVID EVER
TALK ABOUT THE THEATER?
- UM, YEAH, WE DO SOMETIMES.
IT WAS A LOT OF FUN.
- YEAH. THOSE WERE SOME
REALLY GOOD TIMES.
I JUST MISS THOSE DAYS IS ALL.
- YEAH. IT WAS
A LONG TIME AGO.
- YEAH. BUT NOT TO ME.
ALL RIGHT.
- * I SAID, OH
(HORN HONKS)
- YOU'RE COOL.
- THANKS.
- * YOU'VE GOT A SMILE LIKE
YOU'RE IN CONTROL *
* BUT THE WORLD KEEPS TURNING
ALL AROUND *
* JUST LIKE ANY OTHER NIGHT
- HEY.
WHAT ARE YOU GUYS
DOING RIGHT NOW?
(DOOR OPENS)
DAVID?
HEY.
- HEY.
- HA HA. WHAT THE--
- HE FOLLOWED ME HOME.
- HA HA HA HA.
- HOW YOU DOING?
- THIS IS A SURPRISE.
- SURPRISE.
- GOOD. GOOD.
WOW. THIS IS A SURPRISE.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING OUT HERE?
- HOLD ON. I WANT YOU TO
MEET SOMEBODY.
THIS IS DAVID.
THIS IS MY GIRLFRIEND CATHERINE.
- GIRLFRIEND?
- YEAH.
- CATHERINE, NICE TO MEET YOU.
DAVID.
- HI. NICE TO MEET YOU.
I HEARD A LOT ABOUT YOU.
- GOOD STUFF, I HOPE.
- NO, ALL THE BAD STUFF,
ACTUALLY.
MARC TOLD ME EVERYTHING.
- REALLY?
WELL, IT'S PROBABLY ALL TRUE.
- SEE? TOLD YOU.
- IS THERE MORE?
- YEAH, I GOT IT.
- I'LL HELP.
- I INVITED THEM FOR DINNER.
- OH, GREAT.
THAT'S GREAT.
- WELL, I SAID WE DIDN'T
HAVE TO COME TONIGHT--
- NO, NO, IT'S FINE.
WE LOVE COMPANY.
- OKAY, GOOD.
RIGHT ON.
- I CAN'T BELIEVE YOU'RE HERE.
- I KNOW.
- LOOK AT YOU.
YOU LOOK GREAT.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
HOW DO YOU STAY SO...
AND LOOK AT THIS.
- AH.
- YEAH.
- THAT?
- KEEPS GETTING BIGGER, YEAH.
YEAH, THAT.
- YOU LOOK GOOD, MAN,
YOU DO.
LOOKS LIKE, UH, YOU GOT
A LITTLE BIT OF COLOR,
AND THE GOOD LIFE IS TREATING
YOU WELL, SO...
- YEAH, IT IS. IT IS. I CAN'T
COMPLAIN. IT'S NICE.
- GOOD.
- IT IS.
BUT, I MEAN,
YOU REALLY LOOK GREAT.
WHAT, ARE YOU WORKING WITH
A TRAINER OR SOMETHING?
- WELL, I MEAN, I WAS, A FEW
MONTHS AGO FOR A THING, BUT--
- WAIT, THE ROMAN THING?
- YEAH, THE GREEK ZEUS.
- OH, GREEK, YEAH. WOW.
WELL, WHATEVER YOU'RE DOING,
IT'S WORKING. LET ME, UH, JUST--
- YEAH. LET ME TAKE
MY SHOES OFF.
- AH, I SEE WHAT TOOK SO LONG.
- WHAT?
- NOTHING.
- I WAS BORED.
- HA HA. THE CURE FOR
BOREDOM: SHOPPING.
- I NEEDED SOMETHING NEW.
- HMM.
- MARC HATES SHOPPING
WITH ME.
- I DO NOT.
- DAVID DOESN'T MIND,
AS LONG AS THERE ARE
OTHER WOMEN TO WATCH.
- EXACTLY.
YOU LOVE IT WHEN I LOOK
AT OTHER WOMEN.
- THAT'S WHAT IT IS.
- WHAT?
- DEPENDS ON THE STORE,
DOESN'T IT?
- WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
- YOU ARE SUCH A BAD BOY.
- OH YEAH?
- YEAH.
- OKAY.
- WHAT ARE YOU GOING TO DO
ABOUT IT?
- PUNISH YOU.
- OH, GOOD. CAN'T WAIT.
- BET YOU CAN'T.
- UH-HUH.
(KISSING)
I THINK WE'RE BEING RUDE.
DO YOU GUYS WANT ME TO HELP YOU
WITH SOMETHING OVER THERE?
- NO, NO, IT'S FINE.
I'M JUST, UH--
- YEAH?
- YEAH.
- GOOD? THIS IS FINE
WITH YOU GUYS?
- OH, MY GOD.
- YOU'RE SO BAD.
I GUESS WE'RE STILL IN OUR
HONEYMOON PHASE.
GOT TO ENJOY IT WHILE IT LASTS.
- TRUE.
- HOW LONG HAVE YOU TWO KNOWN
EACH OTHER?
- UM, WE MET ABOUT A YEAR AGO.
- YEAR AGO.
- BUT WE WERE WORKING TOGETHER,
SO IT KIND OF JUST, DIDN'T--
THEN WE RAN INTO EACH OTHER A
COUPLE OF MONTHS AGO, SO...
- THAT SOUNDS LIKE
A HONEYMOON.
- REMEMBER THAT?
- WHAT?
- THE HONEYMOON.
- UH. SO TIGHT.
- HONEYMOON.
VAGUELY.
- CAN'T BELIEVE
HOW LONG IT'S BEEN.
GOD, EVERYTHING HAPPENED
SO FAST FOR US.
ONE MINUTE WE MET, THE NEXT,
WE WERE MARRIED.
- YEAH. WELL, THAT'S DAVID.
HE KNOWS WHAT HE WANTS. DOESN'T
NEED TO MESS AROUND, RIGHT?
STILL THE SAME WAY, THOUGH?
STILL STUBBORN?
- STUBBORN?
- I DON'T KNOW.
- WHAT THE HELL ARE YOU
TALKING ABOUT?
- I MEAN, HE'S DEFINITELY
CHANGED A LITTLE BIT.
HE'S NOT AS, UH, I DON'T KNOW,
AGGRESSIVE AS HE USED TO BE.
- REALLY?
- WHAT?
- NO, I MEAN, IT'S NOT A BAD
THING. YOU'RE NOT.
- WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
- IT'S SOMETHING THAT COMES
WITH AGE. MATURITY.
- OKAY, SO NOW I'M AN OLD MAN.
- SHUT UP.
- NO, WAIT, NOW I'M AN OLD,
UNAGGRESSIVE MAN.
YOU SEE WHAT HAPPENS WHEN YOU
STAY TOGETHER FOR A LONG TIME?
MY ADVICE: DUMP HIM AFTER SIX
MONTHS. FIND A YOUNGER MODEL.
- DON'T GIVE HER ANY IDEAS.
- I PLAN ON IT.
- I'M SERIOUS. TRADE HIM IN.
- WHAT?
- HMM?
- WHAT DID YOU JUST SAY?
- I WAS KIDDING.
- THAT WASN'T FUNNY.
- DON'T.
- NO.
- NO?
COME HERE, LITTLE GIRL.
DADDY WANTS TO TICKLE YOU.
- NO, NO, NO, NO, NO.
- YEAH, YEAH, YEAH, YEAH.
- NO! DON'T. DON'T.
OH!
OH, MY GOD.
- OH, DADDY WANTS TO...
I'M SORRY.
I COULDN'T HEAR YOU.
WHAT DID YOU WANT TO SAY?
YOU WANT TO GET RID OF ME?
- STOP. STOP, MARC.
- DADDY NEEDS TO PUNISH YOU.
- NO, NO, NO. OH!
STOP. PLEASE.
- SORRY.
APOLOGIZE.
- OKAY.
I FORGIVE YOU.
WHEN YOU SAY YOU WANT TO TRADE
ME FOR SOMEBODY ELSE,
IT MAKES ME FEEL INSECURE.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
DON'T GIVE HER ANY GODDAMN
IDEAS.
- OKAY.
- I LOVE YOU.
- REALLY? YOU DO?
- THAT'S NOT WHAT YOU'RE
SUPPOSED TO SAY.
- OH! SHIT. I ALWAYS
FORGET MY LINES.
OKAY. I REMEMBER.
UM, I LOVE YOU, TOO.
- THAT'S PERFECT.
YOU WANT TO GO FOR
A WALK ON THE BEACH?
- YEAH.
- YEAH?
- WAIT.
I HAVE AN IDEA.
WHY DON'T YOU LADIES
GO FOR A NICE LEISURELY STROLL
ON THE BEACH
WHILE US GENTLEMEN PREPARE
THE FISH FOR GRILLING?
AND WE'LL MAKE A NICE BIG SALAD
AND, UM, UM...
WHATEVER THE HELL ELSE YOU GOT.
WHAT'D YOU GET?
- ASPARAGUS.
- YES.
WELL, WE'LL MAKE THAT, TOO.
HOW'S THAT SOUND?
- SOUNDS GOOD TO ME.
DAVID?
- UH, YEAH, SURE.
FINE WITH ME.
- LET ME JUST GRAB MY HAT.
- SOUNDS GOOD TO ME, TOO.
YOU GENTS WORK WHILE US LADIES
TAKE A LEISURELY STROLL.
- YEAH, AND JUST
TAKE YOUR TIME.
- I DON'T KNOW WHAT YOU DID TO
THIS GUY, CATHERINE,
BUT I'VE NEVER SEEN HIM SO
ACCOMMODATING.
- OH, REALLY, JULIE?
WHAT ARE YOU TRYING TO SAY?
ARE YOU TRYING TO SAY
I HAVEN'T ALWAYS BEEN
SUCH A NICE GENTLEMAN?
- NO, I'M NOT SAYING ANYTHING.
TRUCE.
- WHERE ARE YOUR GLASSES?
- IN MY BAG.
- SHOULD COVER YOUR FACE.
THERE YOU ARE, DARLING.
- THANK YOU.
- YOU'RE WELCOME.
NOW GO DO THE GIRL-TALK
THING.
- YOU'RE SO CHAUVINISTIC.
- YEAH.
- HE IS A--
- OW.
- YOU OKAY?
- YEAH. I'M FINE.
- OKAY. BYE.
- BYE.
- WE WILL RETURN.
- YES.
- DON'T BREAK ANYTHING.
- I WON'T.
SHE REALLY IS A HANDFUL.
- YOU SEEM TO BE MANAGING
PRETTY WELL.
- YEAH, WELL, WHAT THE HELL ELSE
AM I GONNA DO?
(GROANS)
HOW...HOW HAVE YOU BEEN?
- UH, GOOD. YEAH, YOU KNOW.
I CAN'T COMPLAIN.
LOOKING AFTER THINGS, TAKING
CARE OF THE BUSINESS.
- OH, THAT'S RIGHT.
THE RESTAURANT. FUCK.
I'M SO SORRY THAT I HAVEN'T BEEN
IN THERE TO TASTE IT,
BUT I HEAR IT'S GOING GOOD.
- IT'S ALL RIGHT.
IT'S GOOD. IT'S DOING WELL.
WE GOT A COUPLE WRITE-UPS WHICH
DOESN'T HURT THINGS, SO--
- OKAY, YEAH. SO YOU GOT, UM,
YOU GOT SOMEONE DOING
PR FOR YOU.
- OH, YEAH, YOU HAVE TO.
I MEAN, IF YOU WANT TO GET
WRITTEN UP...
- YEAH.
- BUT IT'S GOOD.
I MEAN, HOPEFULLY IT KEEPS
GETTING BETTER.
IT WOULD BE NICE TO BE PACKED
EVERY NIGHT.
- SURE. YEAH.
- HOPEFULLY. SOON.
WE GOT A REALLY GREAT CHEF.
I MEAN, HE'S REALLY GOOD.
EXCELLENT DISHES.
- WHAT KIND OF--
- HEY, DID YOU WANT
SOMETHING TO DRINK?
- YEAH. YEAH.
THAT'D BE, UH--
- WE JUST OPENED THIS
LAST NIGHT.
IT'S A LITTLE LIGHT,
BUT IT'S GOOD.
- OKAY.
- WE HAVE SOME BEER, TOO.
- NO, MAN.
WINE IS FINE.
- OKAY.
I'M SORRY. WERE YOU, UH,
GONNA ASK ME SOMETHING?
- UH, BEFORE OR--
- YEAH. I THOUGHT YOU, UH...
- OH, NO, IF I WAS,
I FORGET.
- OKAY.
- TO FRIENDS.
- YEAH.
- SHE SEEMS REALLY NICE.
- SHE IS. YEAH.
UM...
I MEAN IT.
I MEAN, SHE'S GREAT.
I MEAN,
LOOK AT HER.
- THAT'S GREAT.
- YEAH.
AND YOU AND JULIE SEEM
TO BE DOING GOOD.
- YEAH, WE ARE.
YEAH, YOU KNOW--
WE GO THROUGH SOME THINGS
SOMETIMES, BUT...
I GUESS IF YOU CAN, UH,
STICK IT OUT OR,
I DON'T KNOW,
MAYBE TOLERATE--
THAT'S-- THAT'S NOT--
I THINK YOU JUST COME TO REALIZE
WHAT YOU REALLY WANT,
AND IF YOU DO, THEN THINGS ARE
PRETTY GOOD.
- YEAH. THAT'S GOOD.
THIS IS PRETTY LIGHT.
- YEAH.
- BUT IT'S GOOD, THOUGH.
I LIKE IT.
UM...
OKAY. SO...
DID YOU WANT TO DO THE FISH
OR--
- YEAH, YEAH, YEAH.
YOU KNOW WHAT?
ACTUALLY, YOU KNOW, WE'VE GOT
PLENTY OF TIME.
WHY DON'T WE JUST GET
THE SALAD READY
AND THEN WE CAN DO THAT LATER?
- ALL RIGHT.
- UM, SO, LET'S SEE.
I GOT A...
UH...
HOW ABOUT IF WE GET YOU SET UP
OVER HERE? YEAH.
- OKAY.
- I'LL GET A BOARD.
SET UP.
MAYBE SOME CARROTS TO GET
STARTED?
ALL RIGHT.
THERE YOU GO.
UM. OH.
SOMETHING TO CUT IT WITH.
- YOU OKAY?
- YEAH. YEAH, I'M FINE.
I JUST, UH...
I'M GLAD YOU'RE HERE.
- ME, TOO.
- YOU KNOW, THINGS ARE, UH...
DIFFERENT NOW WITH...
YOU KNOW, IT'S JUST...
- YEAH.
NO, I KNOW.
(CHOPPING)
- DON'T LOOK AT ME
LIKE THAT.
- LOOK AT YOU LIKE WHAT?
- MARC, COME ON.
IT'S JUST--
- HEY, I SAID OKAY, YOU KNOW?
I UNDERSTAND.
- WELL, IT'S NOT THAT
I HAVEN'T, UH...
I JUST...
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
- NOT DOING ANYTHING.
- MARC, STOP.
- STOP WHAT?
- COME ON, REALLY.
- YOU NEED TO RELAX.
THIS IS WHAT MARRIAGE
DOES TO YOU?
- DON'T SAY THAT.
- I'M KIDDING.
(CHOPPING)
- YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND.
- WHAT DON'T I UNDERSTAND?
HEY, YOU'RE RIGHT.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
I WASN'T DOING ANYTHING.
- RIGHT. YEAH. YOU NEVER DO
ANYTHING, DO YOU?
- WHAT IS THAT
SUPPOSED TO MEAN?
- WHEN'S THE LAST TIME
YOU DID SOMETHING?
I MEAN REALLY DID SOMETHING
YOU FELT GOOD ABOUT.
- WHAT ARE YOU
TALKING ABOUT?
I DO THINGS ALL THE TIME
THAT I FEEL REALLY--
YOU KNOW WHAT? I THINK THIS
MIGHT HAVE BEEN A MISTAKE.
I THOUGHT WE COULD JUST--
- THINGS ARE DIFFERENT.
IT'S NOT LIKE IT USED TO BE.
I MEAN, WE'RE NOT--
- THEN DON'T DO THAT.
DON'T START ACTING LIKE YOU'RE
ALL BETTER THAN ME
JUST BECAUSE YOU GOT YOUR NICE
LITTLE FANCY BEACH HOUSE,
YOUR NICE LITTLE--
YOU KNOW, FORGET IT.
- WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
- I'M GOING TO GO
FIND CATHERINE.
- MARC, WAIT.
COME ON, COME ON.
COME ON.
COME ON, YOU KNOW ME
BETTER THAN THAT.
- YEAH, I THOUGHT I DID.
- COME ON, DON'T DO THAT.
YOU KNOW YOU DO.
I DON'T THINK I'M BETTER.
AND I'M HAPPIER HERE,
I AM.
YOU HAVE TO KNOW THAT.
COME ON.
TRUCE?
HOLD ON, HOLD ON, HOLD ON.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
- WHAT AM I DOING?
- WHAT DID YOU COME HERE FOR?
- DAVID--
- WHY?
- THIS DOESN'T HAVE TO BE
ALL DRAMATIC, OKAY?
I THOUGHT WE'D HAVE
SOME FUN, YOU KNOW?
REMEMBER FUN?
- YEAH, I DO.
- LOOK, LET'S JUST
MAKE DINNER,
WE'LL ENJOY OURSELVES,
AND CATHERINE AND I
WILL TAKE OFF, OKAY?
(SIGHS)
(CRUNCHING)
YOU KNOW ME.
YEAH, I TAKE WHAT I CAN.
BUT I DON'T BULLY PEOPLE.
IF YOU DON'T,
IT'S OKAY.
(CHOPPING)
- OH!
- HA HA! NICE SHOT.
- HA HA.
THANK YOU.
FEELS GOOD, MAN.
HAVEN'T PLAYED IN...
I DON'T KNOW HOW LONG.
- YEAH?
- YEAH.
YOU AND JULIE PLAY MUCH?
- NO, NOT REALLY.
SHE GETS TIRED.
- GOOD MORNING!
- MORNING.
- HOW YOU FEELING?
- UGH.
- CATHERINE STILL SLEEPING?
- NO, SHE, UM...
SHE WENT INTO TOWN.
SHE'S SEEING...
SHE'S SEEING AN OLD FRIEND.
- OH!
NICE HUSTLE.
- YOU READY TO START
KEEPING SCORE?
- (PANTING)
YEAH, SURE.
- YOU DON'T WANT TO?
- NO, IT'S FINE.
I SAID SURE.
- I HEARD WHAT YOU SAID.
- SO COME ON.
- NO, IT'S FINE.
THIS IS FINE.
- IF YOU WANT TO KEEP SCORE,
WE KEEP SCORE.
- WHAT ARE YOU TWO
ARGUING ABOUT?
- WE'RE NOT ARGUING.
MARC HAS THIS THING.
WHAT IS IT,
A PHILOSOPHY--
- YOU LIKE DOING THIS,
DON'T YOU.
- I'M ASKING.
- DOES HE DO THIS TO YOU, TOO?
- I AM ASKING.
IS IT A PHILOSOPHY?
- I DON'T KNOW
WHAT HE'S DOING.
- DON'T LISTEN TO HIM.
- TRYING TO EMBARRASS--
- DON'T--
- TRY TO--
- FORGET IT.
LET'S JUST KEEP PLAYING.
I DIDN'T MEAN TO
HURT YOUR FEELINGS.
I DON'T CARE ABOUT
KEEPING SCORE.
- FUNNY.
- NICE TO SEE SOME THINGS
NEVER CHANGE.
- DON'T PUT ME IN WITH HIM.
HE'S THE ONE.
I'VE CHANGED.
- THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
I WILL TAKE THAT AS A
COMPLIMENT.
I DON'T WANT TO CHANGE.
- I'M GOING TO TAKE A SHOWER.
PLAY NICE.
- STILL THE SAME.
- I DON'T THINK SO.
- (LAUGHING)
**
- * ANY TIME YOU LIKE
* WE CAN MEET AGAIN, BABY
* AND AS TIME GOES BY
* WELL, YOU MUST REMEMBER
* HOW IT FEELS TO LOVE
* WITHOUT CONDITION *
- DAVID WENT TO CHECK
ON THE BOAT.
- IS HE GONNA
TAKE IT OUT?
- NO, HE JUST LIKES
TO CHECK ON IT.
- I APPRECIATE YOU INVITING US
TO STAY LAST NIGHT.
- YOU BOTH HAD A LITTLE
TOO MUCH TO DRINK.
- (CHUCKLES)
- WELL, IT'S NICE HAVING YOU.
YOU CAN TELL DAVID'S
HAPPIER HERE.
YOU, UH-- YOU HEARD FROM
CATHERINE?
- UM, SHE LEFT A MESSAGE.
- DOESN'T BOTHER YOU THAT SHE'S
SEEING AN OLD BOYFRIEND?
- NO.
I GUESS YOU COULD SAY WE HAVE AN
UNDERSTANDING, YOU KNOW.
- HOW DO YOU MEAN?
- WELL, I MEAN...
SHE DOES WHAT SHE
WANTS TO DO,
AND THEN I DO WHAT
I WANT TO DO.
- (SIGHS)
SOUNDS SIMPLE ENOUGH.
- YEAH.
IT WORKS.
- (EXHALES)
IT'S GETTING TOO HOT.
- HOW HAVE YOU BEEN?
- WHAT WAS THAT?
- I SAID HOW HAVE YOU BEEN.
- GOOD.
YEAH, YOU KNOW,
THINGS ARE GOOD.
HOW ABOUT YOU?
YOU DISAPPEARED FOR A WHILE.
- YEAH.
- WHAT HAVE YOU BEEN UP TO?
CORRUPTING YOUNG GIRLS?
- UH, DON'T BELIEVE EVERYTHING
YOU READ.
OR IS THAT WHAT DAVID'S BEEN
TELLING YOU?
- NO, HE WAS WONDERING
THE SAME.
- COULD HAVE CALLED.
- TRUE.
YES, WE COULD HAVE.
- NO, I SAID YOU
COULD HAVE CALLED.
- I ALMOST DID.
- YEAH?
- WHEN I WAS OUT IN L.A.,
I RAN INTO SOMEONE
WHO HAD SEEN YOU.
- SOMEONE WHO?
- I THINK IT WAS FRANK?
- OH, REALLY?
AND HOW IS FRANK?
YOU KNOW, ACTUALLY, I DON'T
REALLY CARE.
YOU KNOW, FRANK'S THE KIND OF
PRODUCER
WHO COULDN'T PUT HIS MONEY WHERE
HIS MOUTH WAS, SO...
I JUST DON'T HAVE TIME FOR
PEOPLE LIKE THAT.
- I DIDN'T KNOW.
- SO WHY DIDN'T YOU CALL?
- I DON'T KNOW.
I WAS JUST...
- WELL, ISN'T THIS FUNNY?
- DON'T BE A JERK.
- I DIDN'T REALIZE I WAS.
YOU LOOK REALLY GOOD.
SORRY. MEANT TO SAY YOU LOOK
LIKE SHIT.
- (LAUGHING)
- MY BAD.
I WAS GONNA GO FOR
A LITTLE WALK ON THE BEACH
IF YOU'D LIKE TO JOIN ME.
- NO, THANKS.
MAYBE NEXT TIME.
- SURE YOU DON'T WANT TO COME?
- YEAH, I'M SURE.
**
* DO YOU REMEMBER
* WHAT IT FELT LIKE
* WHEN WE FELL IN LOVE?
* MY HANDS WENT WEAK
I LOST MY GRIP...*
* I CAN'T SEE ANYTHING...
* I'M SORRY
* YOU ARE MY REASON
- HEY!
- WANT A RIDE?
- SURE.
* YOU ARE MY ANGEL...*
- WHAT WERE YOU DOING?
- I WAS JUST CHECKING
ON MY BOAT.
- ARE YOU GOING TO
TAKE IT OUT?
- UM, NO. I MEAN, MAYBE.
I GUESS I COULD.
- I HAVEN'T BEEN SAILING
IN A LONG TIME.
I MISS IT.
- YEAH?
- YEAH.
AN OLD BOYFRIEND HAD
A LITTLE SCHOONER.
HAD THIS CUTE LITTLE PLACE ON
SHELTER ISLAND.
WE'D TAKE THE BOAT OUT JUST
ABOUT EVERY NIGHT,
JUST BEFORE THE SUNSET,
WATCH THE SUNSET
AND MAKE LOVE.
ALMOST EVERY NIGHT.
IT WAS FUN.
- SO, WHAT HAPPENED?
- WITH JOSH?
I DON'T KNOW.
IT'S A GOOD QUESTION.
WHAT HAPPENED?
I THINK...SUMMER ENDED,
AND I WAS MODELING AT THE TIME.
WENT AWAY FOR A FEW JOBS
AND...
I GUESS IT KIND OF JUST
FADED AWAY.
I DON'T REALLY
REMEMBER, THOUGH.
YOU KNOW, LIFE'S FUNNY
LIKE THAT.
IT'S SO HARD TO STAY IN TOUCH
WITH ALL THE PEOPLE YOU'VE MET
AND SPENT TIME WITH.
MAYBE-- MAYBE EVEN PEOPLE YOU'VE
SPENT SIGNIFICANT TIME WITH.
PEOPLE COME IN AND OUT
OF YOUR LIFE,
YOU GO IN AND OUT OF
THEIR LIVES AND...
IT ALL JUST SEEMS SO RANDOM AT
TIMES, YOU KNOW?
I HAD THIS ONE BOYFRIEND ONCE.
HE WORKED SO HARD TO FIND
THE MEANING IN THINGS.
IT WAS LIKE, EVERYTHING WAS
FOR A REASON.
HE USED TO ALWAYS SAY,
"WE'RE ALL HERE TO LEARN
SOMETHING."
YOU KNOW WHAT I SAID TO HIM?
"I DON'T WANT TO LEARN.
I JUST WANT TO HAVE FUN."
I NEVER EVEN LIKED SCHOOL.
I ONLY LIKED RECESS.
OF COURSE,
HE DIDN'T LIKE THAT.
AND OF COURSE, THAT DIDN'T STOP
HIM FROM FUCKING ME, EITHER.
I THINK MOST MEN
ARE THE SAME.
JUST LITTLE BOYS PLAYING
GROWN-UP.
- * I CAN STILL REMEMBER
SWEET MEMORIES *
* THE WAY WE BELIEVED *
- I THINK I'M GONNA GO
FOR A SWIM.
DO YOU WANT TO JOIN ME?
- MAYBE.
I'M GONNA CHECK ON JULIE.
- OKAY.
- JULIE?
(SHOWER RUNNING)
HEY.
- OH. HEY.
- WHERE'S MARC?
- HE WENT DOWN TO THE BEACH
TO TAKE A WALK.
- OH.
- WHAT?
- NOTHING.
YOU WANT TO TAKE
THE BOAT OUT TOMORROW?
- SURE.
- HEY, DID, UH, DID MARC GIVE
YOU ANY IDEA
WHEN HE WAS PLANNING
ON LEAVING?
- NO.
NOT HAPPY HE'S HERE?
THOUGHT YOU'D BE HAPPY.
- I AM.
IT'S NICE TO SEE HIM.
I JUST, UH...
I LIKE MY ALONE TIME.
- I THINK HE WAS UPSET
ABOUT CATHERINE.
- MARC? PLEASE.
NO, I DON'T THINK SO.
- I THINK HE WAS.
SHE WENT INTO TOWN
TO SEE AN OLD BOYFRIEND.
YOU DON'T THINK THAT
WOULD UPSET HIM?
YOU TWO HAVE BEEN FRIENDS
FOR HOW LONG
AND YOU CAN'T TELL
HE'S COVERING UP YET?
- COVERING UP?
I PICKED HER UP
ON THE WAY BACK.
SHE WAS JUST WALKING ALONG.
- HUH? WHAT?
- NOTHING.
I SAID I PICKED HER UP
ON THE WAY BACK.
- OH.
- I'M GONNA GO OUT
TO THE POOL.
- OKAY.
- HAVE YOU SEEN MARC?
- UH, JULIE SAID HE WENT FOR
A WALK ON THE BEACH.
- OH. THANKS.
- SURE.
HMM.
UH, HOW'S THE WATER?
- REFRESHING.
ARE YOU GOING IN?
- UH, MAYBE.
SO, UH, WHAT BRINGS YOU TWO
OUT THIS WAY?
- UM, NOTHING, REALLY.
RELAXATION.
LITTLE GETAWAY.
MARC SAID HE'S HAD SOME PRETTY
MEMORABLE SUMMERS OUT HERE.
- YEAH?
- YEAH.
WHAT ABOUT YOU? IS THIS
THE NORMAL SUMMER THING?
- UM, YEAH. PRETTY MUCH.
I MEAN, I POP BACK INTO
THE CITY SOMETIMES,
BUT FOR THE MOST PART,
WE STAY OUT HERE.
- MUST BE NICE.
SO HOW LONG HAVE YOU TWO
BEEN MARRIED?
- UH, FIVE...
ALMOST SIX YEARS.
- OH, WOW.
THAT'S A PRETTY LONG TIME.
- YEAH, I GUESS.
IT'S ALL RELATIVE.
- (LAUGHING)
YEP.
AIN'T THAT THE TRUTH.
SO, ARE YOU STILL WRITING?
MARC SAID YOU WERE
A GREAT WRITER.
- YEAH?
- YEAH.
HE DOESN'T SAY THAT
TOO OFTEN.
UH, THAT SOMEONE'S GREAT...
AT ANYTHING.
- WELL, THAT WAS
NICE OF HIM.
- HE'S A NICE GUY.
- YEAH, HE IS.
- UH, I WAS JUST GONNA
POP INTO TOWN
AND GRAB SOME GROCERIES
FOR DINNER.
- DID YOU WANT SOME COMPANY?
- NO, THAT'S OKAY.
ENJOY THE POOL.
- I'LL COME WITH YOU.
- NO, IT'S FINE.
I'M OKAY.
- I DON'T MIND.
- NO, I KNOW. IT'S OKAY.
KEYS IN THE CAR?
- YEAH.
- YOU NEED ANYTHING IN
PARTICULAR FROM THE STORE?
I WAS THINKING STEAKS
FOR DINNER.
HOW'S THAT SOUND?
- SOUNDS GREAT.
ARE YOU SURE YOU DON'T
WANT SOME COMPANY?
- I'M SURE.
MARC SHOULD BE GETTING
BACK PRETTY SOON.
I'LL BET HE'LL WANT TO
SEE YOU WHEN HE GETS BACK.
WOULDN'T STOP TALKING
ABOUT YOU EARLIER.
I THINK YOU'VE PUT
A SPELL ON HIM.
- YEAH, RIGHT. I DON'T HAVE
A SPELL STRONG ENOUGH.
- I'LL BE BACK.
- OKAY.
UH...
(WATER SPLASHING)
- UH-OH.
SOMEONE FEELING ADVENTUROUS?
(LAUGHING)
WHEN'S THE LAST TIME
YOU WENT IN?
- UH...
LAST SUMMER, I GUESS.
- LET'S SEE WHAT YOU GOT.
- (CHUCKLES)
OKAY.
- (LAUGHING)
- WHOO.
- VERY NICE.
YOU'RE SMOOTH,
LIKE A PROFESSIONAL.
- THANK YOU.
- SEEMS A SHAME NOT
TO BE USED MORE.
- YEAH, I GUESS.
SO, HOW LONG HAVE THE TWO
OF YOU KNOWN EACH OTHER?
- WE MET ABOUT A YEAR AGO.
- OH, THAT'S RIGHT. YOU SAID.
HE'S A GOOD GUY.
- YOU DON'T HAVE TO
SELL ME ON HIM.
I HAVEN'T MET TOO MANY PEOPLE
WHO GET ME AS WELL AS HE DOES.
IT'S NOT AN EASY THING.
- NO?
- MAYBE IT IS.
MAYBE IT ISN'T.
HAVEN'T MET TOO MANY PEOPLE
WHO DO.
EVERYONE'S SO HUNG UP ON ALL
THEIR LITTLE LABELS AND...
CATEGORIES.
I GUESS IT'S SAFER.
FEELS SAFER.
- THAT'S RIGHT.
YOU DIDN'T LIKE SCHOOL.
- YOU WERE LISTENING.
SO WHAT ABOUT YOU?
I TAKE IT YOU LIKE THE LABELS
THING.
- WHY WOULD YOU SAY THAT?
- I DON'T KNOW.
HUSBAND, WIFE.
THAT'S PRETTY BIG LABELS.
- YEAH, WELL, IT'S NOT REALLY
ABOUT THAT WITH ME AND JULIE.
- WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
- I JUST-- I DON'T KNOW.
I GUESS WHEN WE GOT MARRIED,
IT WASN'T ABOUT THOSE LABELS,
YOU KNOW?
- AND NOW?
- I SEE WHY MARC LIKES YOU.
IT HELPS SOMETIMES,
THE LABELS.
- YEAH?
- YEAH, SOMETIMES.
HELPS PEOPLE TO
KNOW WHAT'S WHAT.
- AND WHO'S WHO.
AND WHERE'S WHERE.
AND WHY'S WHY.
- (CHUCKLES)
- MARC SAID YOU WERE
A THINKER.
- YEAH?
WHAT ELSE DID HE SAY?
- HE ALSO SAID YOU HAD
PRETTY EYES.
HE WASN'T LYING.
HE ALSO SAID YOU WERE
A PRETTY GOOD ACTOR, TOO.
I BELIEVE HIM.
SO, ARE YOU STILL WRITING?
- UH, NO, NOT REALLY.
I GUESS I GOT SOME STORIES
ROLLING AROUND IN MY HEAD,
BUT, UH, I THINK
MOST WRITERS
ALWAYS HAVE SOMETHING GOING ON
UP THERE.
- WHY AREN'T YOU
WRITING THEM?
- UH, PEOPLE WEREN'T TOO
INTERESTED
IN WHAT I WAS WRITING.
IT GETS PRETTY TIRING BARING
YOUR SOUL
AND PEOPLE JUST AREN'T
GETTING IT.
BESIDES, I DON'T THINK
I NEEDED TO SO MUCH.
I WAS YOUNG, HAD A LOT OF
CONFUSION,
THINGS TO WORK OUT.
IT'S, UH, ONE OF THE THINGS
THAT WRITING IS GOOD FOR.
- SO NOW YOU GOT IT
ALL FIGURED OUT?
- MAYBE.
- WELL, MAYBE YOU COULD
FILL ME IN
ON SOME OF THE MYSTERIES
OF LIFE, THEN.
- SOMETHING TELLS ME YOU
ALREADY GOT SOME THINGS
FIGURED OUT AS WELL.
- MAYBE, BUT NOT EVERYTHING.
- IT GETS BORING
ONCE YOU DO.
- OH.
(LAUGHING)
IS THAT THE BIG SECRET?
- (LAUGHING)
- I HAVE TO TAKE A SHOWER.
TELL MARC IF YOU SEE HIM.
- SURE.
**
(SEAGULLS CALLING)
(WOMAN SCAT SINGING)
* I'M GONNA MAKE
A LITTLE HAPPY FACE *
* AND WANDER ALL AROUND
THE PLACE *
* THEN TAKE A SEAT
AND SIT TO EAT *
* UNTIL YOU PULL ME
OFF MY FEET *
* AND DANCE ME LOVELY,
SWEETLY, DREAMY... **
- THANK YOU.
- YOU'RE WELCOME.
- WHAT?
- YOU'RE VERY FOCUSED.
- I GUESS THAT WAS
ONE OF THE GOOD THINGS
I GOT FROM MY FATHER.
- COME ON.
- OH, NO, THANKS.
- YOU SURE?
- YEAH, I'M SURE.
- OKAY.
YOU'VE GOT A REALLY
NICE PLACE.
- THANKS.
IT'S BEEN IN MY FAMILY
FOR A WHILE.
MY FATHER BUILT IT.
- REALLY?
- WELL, HE DIDN'T DO
THE ACTUAL BUILDING,
BUT HE WAS INVOLVED IN
THE DESIGN AND ALL.
- OH, WOW.
IT'S NICE.
IT'S KIND OF...
CLASSIC.
- YEAH.
- UM, I'M SORRY.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT IT IS.
I JUST...
I JUST KEEP WANTING
TO LOOK AT YOU.
- OKAY.
- I KNOW IT'S NOT POLITE,
RIGHT?
- OH, I DON'T KNOW.
I GUESS I'VE HEARD
SOMETHING LIKE THAT.
- YOU'RE VERY PRETTY.
- THANK YOU.
COULD I ACTUALLY--
I CHANGED MY MIND.
- YEAH.
- THANK YOU.
- THIS IS NICE.
- HUH?
- THE WINE.
DID YOU PICK IT OUT?
- OH, NO. DAVID, HE'S A...
I TEASE HIM ABOUT BEING
A WINE SNOB.
IT'S GOOD,
HE KNOWS WHAT I LIKE.
- WELL, THAT'S GOOD.
- YEAH, IT IS.
- YOU KNOW WHAT'S
GOING ON, DON'T YOU?
- WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
- I MEAN WITH ME AND MARC,
YOU AND DAVID.
WE'RE FORMING MEMORIES.
I MEAN, IT'S PRETTY AMAZING,
RIGHT?
ONE DAY, WE'LL LOOK BACK
ON THIS AND...
REMEMBER IT EXACTLY HOW WE
WANT TO REMEMBER IT.
YEAH.
IT'S WHAT I SAID.
EXACTLY HOW YOU WANT
TO REMEMBER IT.
- WHAT DO YOU WANT?
WHEN YOU LOOK BACK ON THIS
WEEKEND,
WHAT DO YOU WANT TO REMEMBER?
- GOOD WINE.
GOOD COMPANY.
SOME LAUGHS.
- (LAUGHING)
SOUNDS LIKE A GOOD LIFE.
- I'M NOT COMPLAINING.
- YEAH, YOU DON'T SEEM LIKE
THE TYPE.
- NAH. I USED TO.
DECIDED IT DIDN'T HELP ME
WITH ANYTHING.
- YEAH.
**
- * GET CLEANED UP
* COMB YOUR HAIR
* STRAIGHTEN YOUR TIE AND I'LL
SHOW YOU WHERE *
* THE GIRLS COME TWISTING
ON BOTH SIDES OF ME *
* DOWN TO THIS LIFE ON
A DEAD-END STREET *
- (MUMBLING)
- * YOU CAN BUY HER
SOME DRINKS *
* BUT DON'T LOOK NOW,
YOUR BABY'S CHANGING SEATS *
- (TALKING, INDISTINCT)
- * YOU DO YOUR BEST AND GO
BOOM BOOM BOOM *
* BUT THIS WORLD KEEPS
TURNING... **
- BEAUTIFUL DAY.
- YEAH.
- THEY SEEM TO BE GETTING ALONG
QUITE WELL, DON'T THEY?
- YEP.
- SO WHO HAS THE
RIGHT-OF-WAY?
- OH, WE DO
WITH MOTORBOATS.
WITH OTHER SAILBOATS, IT'S
WHOEVER HAS THE STARBOARD TACK.
- AH.
CATHERINE TELLS ME YOU
HAVEN'T BEEN WRITING MUCH.
- YEAH, WELL, I HAVEN'T HAD
VERY MUCH TO WRITE ABOUT.
LIFE HAS GOTTEN
PRETTY SIMPLE.
I MEAN, GOOD SIMPLE.
- OH, SURE.
- I'M HAPPY.
JULIE'S HAPPY.
I DON'T KNOW. WE JUST DON'T HAVE
ANYTHING TO WORRY ABOUT,
WHICH IS GOOD.
IT'S NICE TO FEEL
THE SECURITY.
- SECURITY.
- YEAH. SECURITY.
- WELL, JULIE DOES
SEEM HAPPY.
- YEAH, SHE IS.
- OH. SPEAK OF THE DEVIL.
- OH, REALLY?
(LAUGHING)
- CAREFUL.
- HOW ABOUT FRED'S FOR LUNCH?
- SURE.
- I DIDN'T KNOW
YOU SMOKED.
- I DON'T...
I MEAN, NOT REALLY.
I USED TO, LIKE A FIEND,
BACK IN COLLEGE.
AND A FEW YEARS AFTER.
IT'S VERY ADDICTIVE.
- ORAL FIXATION.
- IT'S NOT.
THIS IS MY SECOND,
THIRD IN YEARS.
I NEVER TOLD YOU?
- NO, I DON'T THINK SO.
- WELL, WE GOT TO HAVE SOME
SECRETS, DON'T WE?
- I WAS--
I DON'T THINK IT EVER CAME UP.
FUNNY. IT WAS SO LONG AGO.
- I GUESS CATHERINE'S A BAD
INFLUENCE ON YOU, EH?
WHATEVER HAPPENED TO YOU
SMOKING CIGARS?
THAT WAS A REGULAR THING
WITH YOU, WASN'T IT?
- YEAH, IT WAS.
BUT I WAS ENCOURAGED TO QUIT.
BUT I CAN SEE THE RULES ARE
CHANGING NOW.
- I NEVER TOLD YOU TO QUIT.
- SUBTLE ENCOURAGEMENTS.
- I DON'T KNOW WHAT YOU'RE
TALKING ABOUT.
- YOU DIDN'T LIKE IT, RIGHT?
- YEAH, BUT--
- SO I QUIT.
I DON'T HAVE AN ADDICTIVE
PERSONALITY.
- THAT IS TRUE. YOU NEVER DID
GET HUNG UP ON MUCH.
SELF-DISCIPLINE?
- I DON'T KNOW. I THINK IT'S
MORE ABOUT HARD-WIRING.
- I FIGURED IT WAS ALL THAT
BUDDHIST STUFF YOU READ.
- YOU'RE A BUDDHIST?
- NO, I JUST READ SOME STUFF.
- AH. SEEKING ANSWERS.
- I GUESS.
- FIND ANY?
- JUST MORE QUESTIONS.
- YOU ARE A DEEP MAN.
- FUNNY.
- AM I?
- I NEVER TOLD YOU
TO QUIT.
- I GUESS IT WAS
MISCOMMUNICATION.
- I GUESS SO.
WHAT ELSE?
- WHAT ELSE WHAT?
- ARE THERE OTHER THINGS YOU
FEEL I'VE ASKED YOU TO CHANGE?
- I WAS JUST PLAYING.
IF I DIDN'T WANT TO QUIT,
I WOULDN'T HAVE QUIT.
- I NEVER WANTED YOU
TO CHANGE.
I HOPE I HAVEN'T SAID THINGS
THAT MAKE YOU FEEL LIKE
YOU'VE HAD TO.
- YOU THINK I'VE CHANGED?
I MEAN BESIDES BECOMING
OLD AND UNAGGRESSIVE.
- I DIDN'T MEAN THAT
THE WAY IT SOUNDED.
- YEAH, IT SOUNDED
PRETTY SINCERE.
- DAVID.
THIS IS FUN.
AREN'T YOU HAVING
A GOOD TIME?
- YEAH, I AM.
- WHAT'S WRONG?
YOU LOOK LIKE
YOU'RE THINKING.
I THOUGHT YOU SAID THINKING
WASN'T GOOD FOR YOU.
- YEAH, WELL, MAYBE
SOMETIMES IT IS.
- WHAT ARE YOU THINKING
ABOUT?
COME ON, WHAT IS IT?
- HAS HE SAID ANYTHING
TO YOU?
- MARC?
ABOUT WHAT?
- I DON'T KNOW, ANYTHING.
- (SIGHS)
WOULD YOU JUST RELAX
AND HAVE FUN?
SHE'S SWEET.
OBVIOUSLY THEY'RE IN LOVE.
MAYBE HE JUST WANTED TO
SHOW OFF HIS NEW GIRLFRIEND,
MAKE YOU JEALOUS.
- MAKE ME JEALOUS? PLEASE.
- WHAT?
- I THINK HE STILL HAS
A CRUSH ON YOU.
- ME?
- YEAH. WHY DO YOU THINK
HE TOOK OFF FOR L.A.?
I KNOW IT BOTHERED HIM WHEN
WE STARTED DATING.
- UM, YOU REALLY THINK IT WAS
ME HE HAD A CRUSH ON?
- YEAH. WHY?
HEY, WHAT ARE YOU SAYING?
WHAT ARE YOU SAYING?
- I...
I JUST DON'T THINK HE HAD
A CRUSH ON ME, THAT'S ALL.
YOU TWO WERE BEST FRIENDS,
AND I COME ALONG
AND STEAL YOU AWAY.
- YOU DIDN'T STEAL ME AWAY.
- YEAH. YEAH, I DID.
- WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
- LET'S STOP SOMEWHERE
ON THE WAY BACK
AND GETS SOME NICE CIGARS.
I WANT YOU TO BE HAPPY.
- I AM.
- GOOD.
(PLANE FLYING OVERHEAD)
- IT'S SO PEACEFUL
OUT HERE.
I CAN SEE WHY YOU GUYS
LIKE IT SO MUCH.
IF I LIVED OUT HERE,
I WOULD NEVER LEAVE.
- (LAUGHING)
- DID YOU COME OUT HERE
WHEN YOU WERE A KID, TOO?
- YEAH.
IT WASN'T SO PEACEFUL THEN.
MY FATHER WAS A...
WELL, FOR LACK OF A BETTER WORD,
A RAGE-A-HOLIC.
WE WERE ALWAYS WALKING ON
EGGSHELLS.
I DON'T KNOW HOW MY MOTHER PUT
UP WITH HIM AS LONG AS SHE DID.
- WHAT WAS HE RAGING ABOUT?
- I DON'T KNOW.
I NEVER UNDERSTOOD HIM.
NEVER REALLY GOT TO KNOW HIM.
I'LL HAVE TO TRY
WHAT YOU SAID.
REMEMBER THINGS THE WAY
I WANT TO REMEMBER THEM.
- (LAUGHING)
MIGHT AS WELL, RIGHT?
- YEAH, SELF-DECEPTION.
THAT WORKS.
- THINK SO?
- DON'T YOU?
- HE DIDN'T MEAN IT
LIKE THAT.
- BUT YOU'RE RIGHT.
WE REMEMBER THINGS THE WAY
WE WANT TO REMEMBER THEM.
MIGHT AS WELL FOCUS ON THE
POSITIVE THINGS, RIGHT?
WHY GET ALL BOGGED DOWN WITH
THE NEGATIVE STUFF?
- WELL, IT DOESN'T MEAN THAT
OTHER STUFF DIDN'T HAPPEN.
- THAT'S NOT
WHAT I'M SAYING.
- BUT MAYBE OUR PERCEPTION
ISN'T ALWAYS ACCURATE.
- HOW DO YOU MEAN?
- LIKE, THE OTHER DAY,
WHEN I WAS IN--
WHEN I WAS IN TOWN
SEEING MICHAEL,
HE WAS SAYING THINGS THAT I
THOUGHT WERE OUT OF FOCUS.
- HOW DO YOU KNOW WHAT YOU
REMEMBER WAS IN FOCUS?
- I DON'T.
(LAUGHING)
I MEAN, I GUESS I QUESTION IT
EVERY SO OFTEN, YOU KNOW?
JUST SLOW DOWN AND FEEL IT.
OR QUESTION IT.
BUT I DON'T THINK MICHAEL
EVER DID.
HE WAS ALWAYS SO SET ON WHAT
WAS RIGHT AND WHAT WAS WRONG,
AND MAYBE THAT'S WHAT
THE PROBLEM WAS.
I DON'T CARE WHAT'S
RIGHT OR WRONG.
I CAN GIVE A FUCK.
BUT HE JUST COULDN'T
LET IT GO.
HE JUST ALWAYS WANTED TO DEBATE
SOMETHING THAT I WAS DOING.
(CHUCKLING)
WHO CAN LIVE LIKE THAT?
- WELL, I GUESS HE CAN.
- YEAH.
- YOU WANT TO GO
FOR A WALK ON THE BEACH?
- SURE.
- YOU GUYS WANT TO GO FOR
A WALK ON THE BEACH?
- I'LL PASS.
- JULES?
- TOO TIRED.
- COME ON.
BOO.
HERE.
- NO, NO, NO, LEAVE IT.
- YOU SURE?
- SEE YOU GUYS IN THE MORNING.
- OKAY. THANK YOU SO MUCH.
DELICIOUS.
- HE SEEMS REALLY HAPPY.
- YEAH.
- SO WHAT PROMPTED YOU TO TAKE
THE BOAT OUT TODAY?
IT'S BEEN A WHILE.
- YEAH.
I DON'T KNOW.
I GUESS I JUST FELT LIKE IT.
- YOU FELT LIKE IT?
- YEAH. I FELT LIKE IT.
- WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
- WHAT, THE WINE?
I'M WRITING.
- YOU HAVEN'T TOUCHED THAT
THING IN...
I DON'T KNOW.
- YEAH. WELL, I GUESS I'VE BEEN
BUSY WITH OTHER THINGS.
- OTHER THINGS?
- YEAH.
THE RESTAURANT FOR ONE.
- DID, UM...
DID MARC ASK YOU
TO WRITE SOMETHING?
- NO.
HE ASKED IF I HAD BEEN WRITING,
WHICH MADE ME THINK.
THEN I REALIZED I HAVEN'T
WRITTEN ANYTHING IN
QUITE A WHILE.
- I GUESS MARC BEING HERE HAS
SOME GOOD POINTS TOO, HUH?
SO, WHAT ARE YOU
WRITING ABOUT?
IS SOMETHING BOTHERING YOU?
YOU GONNA WORK OUT SOME ANGST?
- MAYBE.
- MAYBE?
- YEAH. MAYBE THAT'S WHY
I'M WRITING.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
- NOTHING.
- REALLY?
WELL, IT SURE DOES SEEM LIKE
YOU'RE DOING SOMETHING.
- BUT I'M NOT.
REMEMBER?
THINGS AREN'T ALWAYS AS THEY
APPEAR TO BE.
- OH. WHO SAID THAT?
- ME. JUST NOW.
SO WHY ARE YOU WRITING?
- OOH. HA HA.
TO LEARN.
- TO LEARN?
- YEAH.
I GUESS THERE'S SOMETHING
GOING ON-- OH--
I NEED TO UNDERSTAND.
- SOMETHING'S GOING ON?
- OH, YEAH. YES, DEFINITELY.
- YOU NEED TO UNDERSTAND IT?
- UH-HUH.
(EXHALES)
- THAT'S GOOD.
- YEAH, IT IS.
- WHAT IS, UM,
MARC'S PHILOSOPHY?
- WHAT?
- THE OTHER DAY WHEN
YOU WERE PLAYING TENNIS,
ABOUT KEEPING SCORE.
- (MOANING)
UH, UH...
- WHAT? WHAT IS IT?
TELL ME.
- I CAN'T.
I CAN'T THINK RIGHT NOW.
- WHAT'S WRONG?
YOU WANT ME TO STOP?
- NO, NO, PLEASE DON'T.
PLEASE DON'T.
OHH.
- COME ON, WHAT WERE YOU
GOING TO SAY?
- OH. OH, GOD, I CAN'T.
OHH. I DON'T WANT TO
THINK ABOUT MARC RIGHT NOW.
- WHY NOT?
- (MOANING)
OH, YEAH, YEAH. OH.
OH, GOD.
OHH!
OH. OH.
(MOANING)
WHEW.
(LAUGHING)
OH. OH. OH.
HE, UH...
HE THINKS THAT, UH...
THE NEED TO KEEP SCORE IS
FOR PEOPLE WHO, UM,
DON'T UNDERSTAND THAT
WE'RE ALL ONE.
COMPLETELY CONNECTED.
THERE IS NO YOU OR ME.
THAT THE NEED TO DOMINATE AND
WIN IS, UH, AN EGO THING.
AND IF YOU TRANSCEND THE EGO,
YOU WILL SEE THERE IS
NO WINNING OR LOSING.
THERE IS JUST WHAT THERE IS.
- I DIDN'T KNOW MARC
WAS SO DEEP.
- HMM.
- AND WHAT DO YOU THINK?
- I DON'T KNOW.
I KIND OF LIKE THE GAME OF
DOMINANCE AND SUBMISSION.
(SPLASHING)
- OH!
HA HA!
(LAUGHING)
(SPLASHING)
OH!
(COUGHING)
(LAUGHING)
OH!
- GOOD MORROW!
- GOOD MORROW.
- (LAUGHING)
YOU UP FOR A LITTLE RUN
WITH ME TODAY?
- MM-MMM.
- YOU DID SAY SOMETHING ABOUT
GETTING RID OF THAT,
DID YOU NOT?
- OH, FUNNY.
- SMELLS GOOD.
GOOD MORNING.
- ARE WE BEING RUDE?
I'M SORRY.
- NO. GO.
I WAS JUST TRYING TO CONVINCE
DAVID TO GO FOR A LITTLE RUN.
- OH. I'VE TRIED, TOO, BUT--
- WHAT?
WAIT, GET OUT OF HERE.
- CATHERINE STILL SLEEPING?
- NO, NO, SHE'S AN
EARLY RISER.
SHE IS DOING YOGA
ON YOUR BACK LAWN.
- REALLY?
- YEAH. PRETTY MUCH EVERY
MORNING.
- WOW.
- OKAY, LET'S DO IT.
- YEAH?
- WOW.
- WHAT?
I'LL GO THROW SOME
SNEAKERS ON.
YOU'RE GOING TO TAKE IT EASY
ON ME, THOUGH, RIGHT?
- YEAH.
- GOOD JOB.
- LOOKS LIKE I GOT
A RUNNING PARTNER.
- VERY GOOD.
MORNING.
- AM I INTERRUPTING?
- OH, NO.
NOT AT ALL.
- PRETTY IMPRESSIVE.
- SHOULD HAVE SEEN ME
WHEN I FIRST STARTED.
IT'S JUST PRACTICE,
YOU KNOW?
PRACTICE MAKES PERFECT.
MY MOTHER USED TO
ALWAYS SAY THAT.
JUST LIKE THAT, TOO.
(LAUGHING)
I GUESS IT WORKED.
- LOOKS LIKE IT.
- YOU EVER TRY? YOGA?
- OH, NO.
WELL, ACTUALLY, ONCE.
WE WERE IN THE BAHAMAS AT THIS
RESORT-TYPE PLACE,
AND IT WAS MAINLY COUPLES.
THEY HAD THIS
BEGINNERS' CLASS.
FIRST THING IN THE MORNING
ON THE BEACH.
SOUNDED SO NICE, I THOUGHT,
WHY NOT, YOU KNOW?
WAS GONNA CHANGE MY LIFE.
I THOUGHT, I'M GONNA BE
A YOGA PERSON.
FROM THIS DAY FORWARD,
I WILL DO YOGA.
(CHUCKLES)
I WAS GONNA BE HEALTHY.
I WAS EVEN PICTURING ALL
THE BLENDED JUICE DRINKS
I WOULD HAVE EVERY DAY,
YOU KNOW,
ALL THAT KIND OF STUFF.
BUT I TRIED. I MEAN,
I KIND OF TRIED.
SOMETHING DIDN'T FEEL RIGHT.
I PRETENDED SOMETHING WAS
WRONG WITH MY STOMACH,
AND I EXCUSED MYSELF.
THINK I LASTED, LIKE,
FIVE MINUTES.
THE INSTRUCTOR IN THOSE PLACES,
THEY DON'T REALLY CARE.
I'M SURE SHE THOUGHT,
"OH, GOOD,
ANOTHER BEGINNER I DON'T HAVE
TO HELP," YOU KNOW?
- COME HERE.
YOU WANNA TRY?
I'LL HELP YOU.
- UH, THAT'S OKAY.
- BETTER DO IT NOW.
IT NOT GONNA GET ANY EASIER.
- THAT'S WHAT I'M
AFRAID OF.
- COME ON.
- OKAY.
- FEELS GOOD, DOESN'T IT?
- IF I COULD CATCH MY BREATH,
YEAH.
- OH, COME ON.
YOU'RE DOING FINE.
- OH.
NO, REALLY.
I GOT TO
OH, I GOT TO
CATCH MY BREATH.
OH. OH.
OH, JESUS.
- OKAY, ALL RIGHT. CALM DOWN.
CATCH YOUR BREATH.
- OH, MAN.
UGH.
THIS IS FUCKING PATHETIC.
I JUST RAN A MARATHON
A COUPLE YEARS AGO.
- THAT WAS, LIKE, SIX OR SEVEN
YEARS AGO, WASN'T IT?
- WHAT?
YOU'RE KIDDING, RIGHT?
- YOU FEEL THAT?
NOW TAKE A DEEP BREATH.
- (INHALES)
- AND EXHALE.
- (EXHALES)
WOW.
OH, I CAN'T BELIEVE
HOW GOOD THIS FEELS.
- HOW YOU FEELING?
- LIKE SHIT.
CAN'T BELIEVE THIS.
- WHY DO YOU RESIST THINGS?
I DON'T KNOW WHY THERE HAS TO BE
ALL THIS TENSION BETWEEN US.
DON'T YOU REMEMBER WHEN THINGS
WERE RELAXED?
I DON'T BLAME YOU, YOU KNOW.
JULIE'S A GREAT CATCH.
IF SHE'D HAVE PICKED ME,
I WOULD HAVE DONE--
- PICKED YOU?
- YEAH.
WHY NOT?
EVERYTHING COULD BE DIFFERENT,
YOU KNOW.
EVERYTHING COULD STILL BE
DIFFERENT.
THERE'S NOTHING ETCHED
IN STONE.
THE SIMPLEST OF THINGS CAN
CHANGE EVERYTHING, RIGHT?
THOSE ARE YOUR WORDS.
DID YOU FORGET THAT EVERYTHING
IS SO FRAGILE?
I GUESS YOU DID FORGET.
- THAT WAS YEARS AGO.
- SO WHAT'S CHANGED?
- WHAT'S CHANGED?
- YEAH, WHAT'S CHANGED?
- I'M MARRIED.
- JEEZ, LIKE THAT FUCKING
MEANS ANYTHING.
- YOU'RE A FUCKING ASSHOLE.
- THAT'S THE BEST YOU GOT,
HUH?
I'M AN ASSHOLE?
OKAY, YEAH, I'M AN ASSHOLE.
SO WHAT?
WHO FUCKING CARES?
DID YOU HEAR THAT, OCEAN?
I'M AN ASSHOLE!
DAVID THINKS I'M AN ASSHOLE.
YOU REALLY DON'T THINK
I HAD A SHOT WITH JULIE?
- WOULD HAVE NEVER WORKED.
SHE'S DIFFERENT.
- FRAGILE?
WHY DON'T YOU ASK JULIE
IF I EVER HAD A SHOT?
(MOANING)
- HEY.
- HAVE YOU SEEN, UH--
- SHE'S UPSTAIRS.
- WHERE'S MARC?
- YOU OKAY?
- YEAH.
I'M FINE.
HOW WAS YOUR RUN?
- IT WAS GOOD.
I MEAN, IT WAS OKAY.
I'M A BIT OUT OF SHAPE.
MARC KEPT GOING.
- JULIE WANTS TO SHOW ME
SOMETHING.
SHE JUST HOPPED IN THE SHOWER.
- OH. OKAY.
DID YOU TWO EAT ANYTHING?
- UH...NO.
- OKAY.
I'M GOING TO CHECK ON JULIE,
AND THEN I WAS THINKING ABOUT
POPPING INTO TOWN
AND GETTING SOME STUFF TO MAKE
US BRUNCH.
- SOUNDS GREAT.
IF I SEE MARC,
I'LL TELL HIM.
MAYBE HE'LL WANT TO TAKE
A RIDE WITH YOU.
- OKAY.
- AAH!
YOU SCARED ME.
- SORRY.
- THAT'S OKAY.
- MIND IF I JOIN YOU?
- NO. SURE.
- CATHERINE SAID YOU WANTED
TO SHOW HER SOMETHING?
- UH, NO.
IT WAS NOTHING.
- WHAT'S THE MATTER?
- NOTHING.
I DON'T WANT YOU
TO BE MAD.
- WHAT FOR?
- SOMETHING HAPPENED.
- THAT WAS SO GOOD, JULIE.
WHAT DID YOU PUT ON THAT?
- NOTHING SPECIAL.
COULD I?
- OH. YEAH. SORRY.
SO RUDE.
- SALT, PEPPER.
OH, SOME SPICY MUSTARD.
- THAT'S-THAT'S WHAT IT WAS.
MUSTARD, SPICY,
DELICIOUS.
- THANK YOU.
WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
- UH, I'M GONNA GRAB
A COUPLE CIGARS.
- I'LL, UH...
I'LL HELP YOU.
- SHOULD I OPEN
ANOTHER BOTTLE?
- SURE.
- ANY PREFERENCE?
- YOU ARE THE SOMMELIER.
- WHAT'S THAT?
- WINE SNOB.
ARE YOU OKAY?
- I'M FINE. WHY?
- YOU JUST SEEM LIKE YOU'RE
THINKING ABOUT SOMETHING.
- YEAH, WELL, I'M ALWAYS
- NOTHING IN PARTICULAR?
- I'M JUST TRYING TO DECIDE
WHICH WINE.
- OH.
- THIS SHOULD BE NICE.
COULD YOU?
- OOH.
- SO ARE YOU
ENJOYING YOURSELF?
- (SIGHS)
YEAH. YEAH, IT'S NICE.
ARE YOU SURE YOU'RE OKAY?
- YEAH.
I THINK YOU'RE THE ONE
WHO'S THINKING TOO MUCH.
- YEAH, MAYBE.
(SIGHS)
- (CATHERINE)
I'M SO GLAD.
- YEAH?
- YEAH, SURE.
- YOU KNOW JULIE MEANS
A LOT TO ME.
I'M NOT SURE WHAT WOULD HAVE
HAPPENED IF I HADN'T MET HER.
- YEAH, I-I CAN SEE THAT.
I GUESS WE'LL NEVER KNOW,
THOUGH, RIGHT?
- YEAH, I GUESS.
DO YOU REALLY WONDER WHAT IT
WOULD BE LIKE
IF SHE HAD PICKED YOU?
- YEAH, SOMETIMES.
BUT NOT AS MUCH AS IF...
YOU PICKED ME.
- JULIE COULDN'T HAVE
HANDLED IT.
- SO YOU DID ALL THIS FOR
JULIE, THEN, HUH?
YEAH.
TOWNHOUSE IN THE CITY,
BEACHFRONT ESTATE.
YEAH.
THE SACRIFICES WE MAKE
FOR LOVE, HUH?
THE BOAT IS THE CLINCHER,
THOUGH.
THAT'S REALLY NICE.
LOOK...
I DON'T BLAME YOU.
ANY ONE OF US WOULD HAVE DONE
THE SAME THING.
IT'S NICE NOT TO BE SO
AMBITIOUS.
IT LETS YOU RECOGNIZE
A REALLY GOOD THING
WHEN IT'S RIGHT IN FRONT
OF YOUR FACE.
- WHY DO YOU ALWAYS TRY
TO MAKE THINGS BAD?
CATHERINE'S A GOOD GIRL.
BUT YOU ALWAYS WANT MORE.
WHY CAN'T YOU JUST BE HAPPY?
- IT'S NOT TRUE, I AM HAPPY.
- YOU'RE HAPPY?
- I'M HAPPY.
(PASSIONATE MOANING)
- YEAH.
YEAH. YEAH.
OH, WAIT A MINUTE.
WHOA, WHOA, WHOA.
JULES.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
- WE WERE JUST GOING TO GO
FOR A WALK ON THE BEACH.
I WAS JUST GOING TO SEE
IF YOU WANTED TO GO WITH US.
IT'S OKAY.
I'M OKAY.
I WAS...
IT'S OKAY.
I LOVE YOU SO MUCH.
LET'S JUST HAVE SOME FUN AND
ENJOY OURSELVES.
WE'RE GONNA GO FOR A WALK
ON THE BEACH.
- OKAY.
- * I'M GOING DOWN
TO ACHERON *
* BUT YOU'RE PULLING ME BACK
* ACROSS AN OCEAN...
- NICE SEEING YOU.
- YEAH, NICE SEEING YOU,
TOO, MAN.
HEY, LET'S NOT BE STRANGERS,
OKAY?
- SOUNDS GOOD TO ME.
- SO GLAD I RAN INTO YOU.
- THANK YOU FOR EVERYTHING.
- DID WE EVER REALLY
HAVE A SHOT?
- I DON'T KNOW. MAYBE.
- NOT FAIR.
- DRIVE SAFE.
- WE WILL.
- WE'RE GONNA SURPRISE YOU
ONE OF THESE DAYS
AND SHOW UP ON YOUR DOORSTEP
OUT THERE.
- YOU BETTER.
- BYE.
- * SOMEWHERE DOWN THE COAST
* WHERE THE BLUE SKIES
ARE FOUND *
* THE SUN WHERE YOU STAND
* I'LL SEND YOU
A PHOTOGRAPH...*
- HELLO.
- ARE YOU UP TO A SWIM?
- YEAH. SURE.
THAT SOUNDS GOOD.
- YOU, UH, WANT TO TAKE
THE BOAT OUT TOMORROW?
- SURE.
**
- * I THINK YOU KNOW
HOW YOU MAKE ME FEEL *
- * LIKE A CHILD THAT'S
SPINNING IN THE BREEZE *
- * I THINK YOU KNOW
WHAT YOU MEAN TO ME *
- * IF YOU REALLY MEAN IT
* THEN I NEED TO SEE IT
IN YOUR EYES *
- * I THINK YOU KNOWN WHERE
I'M GONNA GO *
- * ANYWHERE I WANT,
I KNOW YOU'LL COME *
- * I THINK YOU KNOW
WHAT I'M GONNA SAY *
- * YOU DON'T HAVE TO SAY IT
* IT GETS IN THE WAY
OF EVERYTHING *
- * THERE'S A SONG
THAT'S PLAYING *
* AND THEY WROTE IT
JUST FOR YOU AND ME *
- * I'VE BEEN THINKING ABOUT
ANOTHER PLACE TO GO *
- * EITHER WAY,
JUST KEEP IT SIMPLE *
- * I'VE BEEN THINKING THAT
THE VERY BEST *
* IS IN-BETWEEN
- * THIS IS HOW OUR SONG'S
SUPPOSED TO GO *
- * WE MADE THE RHYTHM
SPECIAL *
- * TAKE A MOMENT,
HOLD IT OUT *
- * LET IT SING
* LET IT SING
- * I THINK ABOUT WHERE
WE'RE GONNA LIVE *
- * ROOM FOR TWO,
DON'T MATTER WHERE IT IS *
- * I THINK ABOUT
HOW THE TIME WILL ROLL *
- * WE MAY NEVER KNOW IT
* WE CAN'T COUNT ON WHAT
THE FUTURE BRINGS *
- * 'CAUSE YOU KNOW OUR SONG
KEEPS PLAYING *
* AND THEY WROTE IT
JUST FOR YOU AND ME *
- * I'VE BEEN THINKING ABOUT
ANOTHER PLACE TO GO *
- * EITHER WAY,
JUST KEEP IT SIMPLE *
- * I'VE BEEN THINKING
ABOUT THE VERY BEST *
- * IS IN-BETWEEN
- * THIS IS HOW OUR SONG'S
SUPPOSED TO GO *
- * EITHER WAY,
THE RHYTHM'S SPECIAL *
- * TAKE A MOMENT,
HOLD IT OUT *
- * AND LET IT SING
* LET IT SING
(VOCALIZING)
- * I'VE BEEN THINKING ABOUT
ANOTHER PLACE TO GO *
- * EITHER WAY,
JUST KEEP IT SIMPLE *
- * I'VE BEEN THINKING THAT
THE VERY BEST *
- * IS IN-BETWEEN
- * THIS IS HOW OUR SONG'S
SUPPOSED TO GO *
- * WE MAKE THEY RHYTHM
SPECIAL *
- * TAKE A MOMENT,
HOLD IT OUT **