Downloaded from
YTS.MX
Official YIFY movies site:
[Music]
Reporter: all right I just
need you to go ahead
and put this on just
put it on the lapel
perfect. I have it
turned on.
I just need to do this right here.
Abby: Like that?
Reporter: Yeah.
Reporter: well we want it turned
a little bit. How about
this side?
Abby: Do you want this?
Reporter: You can put it in the
pocket. That's fine.
If you want to put the cord
underneath and zip it up.
that should look
a little bit better
on camera.
Abby: Ok.
Reporter: Does that work?
Uh huh.
Reporter: Ok. Good.
Isn't it gorgeous outside?
yeah I love this the season.
it's my favorite.
Two cameras today?
yeah I'm gonna use
them for my reference
do you have any other
camera crew coming?
well unfortunately
with the news station,
they don't really
think that this is news.
I mean it kind I think it's too old... but
It kind of sucks. I think
there's still a story
behind it, so I want
to interview you.
[Music]
so I just gotta get
these cameras set up
Can you look straight
at the camera
I want to get a good
focus on your eyes.
okay. all right. looks good.
Let's go ahead and get started.
all right. so...
Can you tell me your name and how to spell it?
Abigail Turley [spells name].
but you can call
me Abby
that's what everybody calls me
[Music]
now tell me what it is you do
and a little bit about your
background
I work at a youth homeless
shelter right now
and I do do quite
a bit of um movie extra work.
I'm a background artist.
that's fantastic.
So tell me about that dog
oh this is Murphy
he's my my bodyguard
He's about 11:00, so
don't have too much time left
but he's been a good boy
he looks very sweet
and kind
yeah
[Music]
Interviewer: so I want to get
down to it...
before we get into your story,
can you tell me a little bit
about the murders?
Um... well I guess
the cops might think it is a
serial killer at this point
Just because of how many
people have been killed and
the methods that have
been used...
What do you mean by
different methods?
well there was one woman who was
strangled
with a rope and
Reporter: that's scary
with one guy there was there
was an axe involved
there was a gun
obviously he's me
there was bow and arrow.
there was a knife
Reporter: so... um. let's get
into a little bit
more of the other
people before we
talk about your story.
well I'd like to go
through all of the
different stories and just the
correlation and what's
happened to each one
one and then get to
your story.
does that work for you?
okay, yeah.
tell me what you know about
Cynthia Parsons
um Cynthia...
actually she was kind
of well-known in
the area just because
she owned like the
biggest real estate company
[Music]
[Sound of car pulling in]
I am her boss I am NOT
her babysitter.
We all have deadlines,
but we get it done.
You don't see me
crying about it.
ABBY: You would see her face
on all the busses...
driving by and like
the billboards and
stuff so that was
kind of a shock for
everybody just because
everybody knew
who she was and she
was just really pretty, and...
No. She needs to get it done.
Either have her step up, or be done.
I'm done.
yeah how'd you get
her shit together
[hangs up]
What the hell...
Megan... Megan, can you hear me?
I think someone's in my house.
there's a camera in my house
apparently this guy
broke into her home
and strangled her one night,
that's how she was found
Reporter: that's scary.
Abby: mm-hmm
Yeah... soemone put a camera in
my house.
Can you come?
Hurry, please.
Reporter: Do you think there's
a reason why?
Abby: well they didn't
steal anything so
either it was like
some personal mission
of theirs. they didn't
get the house they
wanted or I don't
know the offer
wasn't accepted... exactly
but I don't know she was really
well-liked so I have a hard time
believing she did
dirty business or
anything
Reporter: now what happened with
David Korman what
What can you tell me about that?
he worked as like a film grip or
something like that
and they found him...
I guess the day after...
the morning after he was killed
um... on a soundstage
he was he was actually
struck by an axe
I kind of know he
kind of had a shady past.
with like... I don't know.
I kind of know he
harassing women and stuff so
DAVID:
[Humming]
DAVID: striking!
Reporter: so so do
you think he had it coming?
Abby: yeah I
think I mean if you
believe in karma, I guess.
i probably shouldn't say that.
REPORTER: I don't know much
about that kind of stuff
okay
god oh sorry
production is on
soundstage a so the
[SCREAMS]
What are you doing? God dammit!
Reporter: So the moral of the
story is... don't harass women
well obviously.
Reporter: Yeah or Karma will
come back and get you.
It should.
And in his case it obviously
really
struck him the face.
[SCREAMING]
HELP!!!
SOMEBODY HELP ME!
[Music]
sorry
production is on
soundstage A
Anchorman: reports from the
coroner show she was
probably strangled.
Suffolk County authorities have
previously said the
cause and manner of
death of 34 year old
Parsons was had
reviewed the evidence
[Screaming from computer
speakers]
Anchorman: and said the findings
were consistent
with homicidal
strangulation.
[SCREAMING]
Reporter: Talk to me about
Jonathan Ackerman and what
happened to him
Jonathan he had
gone camping alone
I guess one weekend
and was found nearby
his campsite shot to death
[music]
I don't know like...
he had just been married.
just recently
maybe like a year
I don't know like
and a half, two years maybe
Abby: he was a nice nice guy
from what people
say and he owned and
operated a video
iproduction company.
I don't know what
kind of stuff they
made but they seem
like really nice guys
and you know some
coward just shot him
while he was camping
[Music]
Oh
ah
come on
[Music]
Anchorman: ...are confirming that
David Korman was the victim
of homicide at
the South Valley
film soundstage ont
October 15 2016 and
[GUN SHOT NOISE] ...when his
co-workers found his body.
[unclear speech] ...3 known victims.
Corman worked as a
professional film grip for the
soundstage for more
than ten years.
His wife told reporters
that he had gone to
work late evening
to prep equipment
for an early morning
shoot. Corman was...
Reporter: Now the next in
line was you.
do you see
any correlation?
I think at the time I
was an easy target
[Music]
I used to go runnin
in the same place
every day five six
days a week
it's pretty stupid actually
but and it's kind
of a secluded area
I mean why me nobody
else.... you know?
I don't have the answer for that
[Music]
Reporter:so tell me about what
happened when you
went through what
you did
well I just
got back to my car
and got a sip of
water to water and
Abby: I don't know I just
felt this immense
pain in my back all
of a sudden I'm not
I couldn't breathe. I couldn't
move I did I
I didn't know
what was happening
that was probably the
worst part of it
was just this
incredible pain out of
nowhere
I thought I heard
something behind me
and you know I was
trying to hang on to
the car. I was just
feeling like really
woozy and just and I
I fell down to my
knees I was just trying
to just maintain
because I wasn't sure
what my what was
happening to my body.
I looked kind of
back and I saw I saw
this guy just all
in black and he was
pointing a bow and
arrow at me.
and that's when it
kind of that's when I
realized that um he
shot me
did you see his face?
No.
why didn't
you see his face?
he was covered he
had it all covered
like a fucking coward
you know if you're
gonna shoot somebody
in the back
at least have the
decency to show your
fucking face to him
Reporter: yeah we can edit
that stuff out.
so just feel free to let
out what you need to
let out.
Yeah.
So he approached me and
shot me a second time
[Music]
and I I mean I felt
it but I was already
so much pain from
that first shot but I
don't know if I was
going into shock
But I was
just screaming for
help and nobody
nobody was around
obviously but....
[screams]
Reporter: Police remain
tight-lipped about a camper
who was shot near
the Wasatch River.
despite South Valley News Leader
requests matter the
long Warren County
Sheriff's Office local
state police nor
National Park Service
night yet provided
an incident report on
the shooting of 30
year-old Jonathan Ackerman
Jonathan leaves behind his
husband of two years
Justin Benton. Jonathan
owned and ran a
video production
company in southern Idaho.
speculation is
circulating about
whether this is the
third in a string of
murders in the South
Valley County
I looked back and he
had turned around
and he had dropped
his bag and that's
when I knew kind of a
survival mode just
kicked in you know
like I'm not gonna be
this guy's victim.
I'm gonna survive.
I'm gonna get out of here
yeah and so I just
reached for the
biggest rock I could
find that I had
this strength to grab
and just like my
brother showed me I
just took it and as
soon as the guy
turned around I just
clocked him as hard
as I could I mean it
was hard because I
had these arrows in me.
but um he fell
to the ground so I
know I got him really hard
I started to run away
but after that it
just kind of it's a
blur... um just
I what I was focused
on was...
"Abby, you've got to get out of
this. you're not going..."
"....to be a victim to this
guy."
sorry. can you edit this out?
Reporter: yeah, yeah definitely.
[Music]
Reporter: so, Emily Boone...
tell me what you know
about her um and
what happened to her
well that one was
weird because I guess
a bunch of people
in her neighborhood
had reported seeing
a drone flying over
her house or her
backyard in the hours
leading up to her
death or maybe after
she died I don't
know if they were
watching but yeah
[Music]
[Drone whirring sound]
Abby: and again probably
the same coward goes
up and stabbed her
in the back multiple times...
and just left
her there that's
where they found her
was in the backyard
Reporter: such a shame.
Anchorman: authorities have
been searching the
soldier summit
national park area for
the perpetrator of
ban odd attempted murder.
police were
called to the region
when a passerby found
Abigail Turrley
passed out off the
side of the road.
She was barely visible
behind some trees
Abigail was out for
a daily run in the
area when she was
assaulted by an
unknown assailant.
the person shot
Abigail twice in the
back with a bow and arrow.
One of the arrows
missed her spine
by two inches. Abigail
was able to escape
the assailant on
foot leaving her
vehicle in the area.
[Music]
Reporter: now let's talk about
Walter Carlson
Do you know him? what
happened to him?
I don't know Walter but
just like kind of
through the movie
business I kind of had
heard about him.
he was a documentarian
and he made like... I
don't know if you saw
"Social justice"
or "the same old"
[Music]
they think his body
was actually he was
killed somewhere else
and his body was
dumped at the South
Valley mall parking lot.
[Mumbling]
[Music]
His throat had been cut.
No. I'm not slating you tying
me up.
Hey! FUCK YOU!
Let me out of here!
Okay. Be gentle.
okay roll eight
scene six take one
Hey! Have you ever heard of
Soft Sticks, asshole?
I don't know it's
like none of these
people like had a
chance to fight back
at all... like there's
no blood under their
nails or anything, so it's
like this person just...
I don't know...
didn't even give anybody
a chance
to escape.
Reporter: so are you saying that
it was just cold blooded murder
in every single case?
yeah that's exactly what
I'm saying
Anchorman: Emily Boone 28 was
found murdered in her back yard
in her rural hometown of
Fountain Green.
She was stabbed several times
in the back and left outside.
she was discovered hours later
by her neighbor
police are searching
the area for the killer
and have asked
the locals to stay
alert and on the
watch for anything suspicious
there were three
sightings of a drone
flying in the vicinity
of Emily's home
close to the same
time as her slaying.
police speculate that
the drone may have
been used by the killer
to scout out the
area previous to the murder.
There hasn't been a killing in
over six months.
why do you think that is?
I don't know... I mean
you see those crime
docs where the
serial killer kind
of goes on a spree
and then goes into hiding for an
extended amount of
time and I mean it
could be something
like that where he's
just enjoying the
media coverage and
I don't know or maybe
he's scared he's
gonna get caught
[moaning]
Man: Ohhh... my head hurts.
[Music]
he's gonna come back
but honestly if he
comes out of hiding...
good luck.
Reporter: What does that mean?
I'm gonna be ready
for him
I'm going to shoot him
right in his face.
[moaning]
Reporter: So I see you've got
something right there
can I go ahead and
zoom into that?
The gun?
Reporter: yeah yeah so
tell me about it
this is my 9-millimeter
Glock I got
so I don't go anywhere
without it
Reporter: so you feel safe
with that then?
yeah damn right I do
Last time. I wasn't prepared
and
it's not gonna happen again
Who are you?
Reporter: Now.... here is the
burning question
do you see
any connection or
correlation with
all the killings?
Who are you?
Abby: you know I've thought
about it a lot and
the only thing I can
think of that kind of
connects us all is...
Man: What are you doing?!
like we were all
kind of in some
form of the movie business.
like I'm a
background artist
I think Emily was actually
an actress like
I think she did some
local local theatre
and like local stuff
like that and then
obviously Walter and
his documentaries
that he makes and
Dave he worked on
movies and I think
I don't know but I
think Cynthia might
have modeled it was
kind of the same thing
I mean it's kind
of a waste of a pretty
face if she didn't model.
WHO ARE YOU?!
Somebody help me!
Help me!
Abby: but yeah that was
the connection that I
came up with.
and that seems to make a lot
of sense.
Reporter: so tell me what your
recovery was like
in the hospital.
Abby: Oh god.
I was there for about
three weeks
they had to do two
surgeries
because the one arrow
the one arrow was
so close to my spine
so they had it....
that was kind of tricky
for them to get it out
without causing a
lot of nerve damage
the other one
was just kind of
more in the flesh so
that wasn't as bad
People always ask me if
they can see the scars
Absolutely.
let's go ahead and get a
close-up on this.
Reporter: Wow.
they're pretty big
Those look like some good
war wounds.
Yeah I mean
they're supposed to
fade but I kind of
scar bad.
Why are they so big?
um so the guy used like
razor arrows so they're
kind of they're
shaped like that
so when they go in
actually make that
same shape and then
to get them out they
had to cut further
around him mm-hmm so
I just yeah I mean
I'll have him forever
but at least it's on
my back so...
[choking]
Reporter: you're really lucky
that you made out.
Abby: Yeah.
I don't know, but I just think
just think there was
a reason you know
did the police offer
you any protection
yeah while I was in
the hospital they did.
because they
thought this was done
by the serial killer
they thought was
out there. they had
security at the door
like 24 hours a day
but as soon as I was
released kind of was
my responsibility
if I wanted further
protection so I mean
the first night they
did actually patrol
outside my house but
after that if I
wanted it, I had to
hire somebody so um
Reporter: that's tough
yeah and it's
expensive and kind of
invasive of your privacy so
I figure well between
Murphy and my gun
and other ways I can
protect myself like
I should be fine.
[choking]
Reporter: so this is going to
be on TV. a lot of
people are gonna be
watching this and
possibly the killer.
do you have a message for
the killer?
yeah
I.dare you to come after
me again. I dare you.
I'm ready and it's
not gonna end pretty
for you.
Reporter: wow that
sounds like quite a threat.
yeah
it's meant to be.
I survived for a reason.
Reporter: well I want to thank
you so much for
taking the time for
us to go ahead and
interview you and Ik
let you know when it
will be airing.
awesome. thank you so much.
Reporter: yeah thank you
yeah thanks especially
for telling your story.
I realize it
can be kind of hard
we'llll go ahead
and wrap up here
and then get out of
your hair
Okay
Wanna want to know the
stupidest thing about this?
how many people
have said,
[mocking] "oh you get a new
lease on life. make it count!"
"Oh Abby, what are you
gonna do with your
new lease on life?"
God.. no shit.
obviously I'm gonna
make it count
there's a reason I'm
the only one that survived.
who uses a
bow and arrow to
hunt somebody anyway?
what am i? a fucking deer?
What kind of a
dipshit thinks he
can get away with
killing this many people?
Reporter: Stupid piece of
German crap!
Reporter: [laughs]
Uh... no.
piece of shit
Who's a dipshit now?
hello everyone. thanks
for watching my movie.
I'll have you
know that this movie
is mine. I produced it.
I shot it. I edited it.
and I wrote the
soundtrack for it
and you may be thinking...
a found footage film
with a soundtrack?
yeah it has music
the reason why? music
makes a movie more intense.
I guess you
could call it a
found footage film.
but really it isn't.
I shot it.
and I'm delivering it.
I guess you
could consider it found
when you find it online.
[Music]
everything you watched
is real. you can
check the news stories
on the people you
saw in this movie.
the news stories will
match up with the
names and the images
you saw in this
film. now that I'm
finished shooting
I'll finish the Edit
and then I'll post
it on YouTube, Vimeo
and a few other
places. so you can
download it. I'll just
give the heads up
if you're one of the
few people watching this,
you're gonna
want to download it right now.
honestly,
after a certain point
you're not gonna
be able to find it
feel free to torrent
it, share it free
online on all the
other streaming
services and servers
because once the
public realizes what's
contained in it
it'll be taken down
immediately
it'll likely be co-opted
by the authorities
for evidence or
whatever else
[Indistinct talking on phone]
Lady: No, no. I'm in
for the night.
I'm having a little Chardonnay
and I'm out.
Just get him to sign that doc.
Yeah. And then we're done.
All right. See you later.
Reporter: Just couple of
technical things you should
note... I have titled
the movie 4K Killer
Now, the authorities
called me the
South Valley killer
I hate it when
authorities and news
stations give you a
title that you didn't
ask for and you
didn't want and they
have no idea of
your motive. I am NOT
the South Valley Killer
I was very deliberate
in what I did
wanted to record all
the killings and I
I wanted it to be a
really high-quality footage.
so I shot
everything in 4k
now that the footage
is being released
and the feature film
is available, I want
you to call me 4K Killer
Why 4K killer? well it's high
quality footage.
I shot it in 4k.
in layman's terms, 4k means
really high resolution.
I wanted the
picture to look good
for you guys
so that means all cameras,
cellphones, drones,
GoPros, everything I
used was shot in 4k
I mean you gotta have
high quality when
you have a feature
film and plus the killings...
you want to
get into that nitty
gritty detail. that way this
entertainment is
of utmost highest quality
I only want
to do the best so
that's what I gave you
[Music]
4K Killer: a bit of a
disclaimer. Some of the
cameras I used don't
actually shoot in
full 4K.
Lady: [coughs]
They were UHD
formats or Ultra High Definition
Lady: [breathes heavily]
a lot of people
mistakenly call it 4k and it's
technically not you
know there's about a
hundred pixels
difference
what we're used to seeing is
called HD or high definition
that means
the resolution or
actual amount of pixels is 1920
horizontal pixels
by 1080 vertical pixels.
UHD has
literally double that
resolution.
so 3840 horizontal pixels by
2160 vertical pixels
so the horizontal pixels are
actually 160 pixels short of
4k or 4000 pixels
But you know...
It's really close enough,
so people just say 4K.
and besides UHD
killer... that really
doesn't have the
same mm as 4K Killer
I don't know.
maybe they're both
stupid names but I'm
not letting the
media or other people
decide my name.
I decide that.
Lady:[gags]
[Music]
most of my GoPros
are GoPro 4's but
there was one scene
that I just wanted
that other angle and
aso I only had one
more GoPro 2 so
technically that's
only an HD and not UHD
I had to up-res it.
so I mean don't get
your panties in a wad
over it. I mean
it's not that big of a deal.
Lady: [gags]
so I'll be
officially releasing
my movie in u HD or
4k. so when you're
googling my movie to download it
definitely do not
download the HD version.
and seriously
do not settle for SD
I mean people
are gonna try to
compress it and I
mean it's just not
worth it especially
when you have the
UHD version available
and it's free okay
enough about that.
let's move on to the killings.
[phone buzes]
[Music]
make sure my hair
looks good. all right
okay. slate. eight
okay sorry I had to
head out. I mean my
phone dinged. I had
to get the camera
equipment back because
otherwise they charged
me for an extra day
and I mean
seriously this has
already cost me an
arm and a leg.
heh... arm and a leg
yeah I'm funny
no but seriously... camera
equipment is not cheap.
[Music]
okay anyway I wanted to show you
everything that I've
done so this is the mask.
I know it's kind of crude,
but you kind of get
kind of get the feel
of it. so initially
what I had done. I got
some burlap sack
and I put it under
so you couldn't
distinguish my eyes.
but dang that stuff hurts.
I mean it started
unraveling
it wasn't working and
then I got in my eyes
and started itching
my eyes then my eyes
got red and I don't need those
problems.
so I switched to this
handy-dandy pantyhose
and I mean it's
amazing you just
easily put it on and
then put it in the
mask and no one can
identify you
no one saw these
baby blues
but another part of my costume
was this bad boy
you see this? that's
my stomach
you may think, oh you could
look pregnant
no, It just made me look
fat so I wore the
stomach plus the
mask, so no one could
identify me at all.
so yeah I never
intentionally made
the connection with
all those that I
killed. they were
somehow apparently
linked to the film
industry. I didn't
know I didn't realize that.
but good on you,
Abigail for doing that.
Hey. Have you ever heard of
soft-sticks, asshole?
It just basically
comes down to--
they were in close proximity
to each other
you know a lot of
people... they operate
in patterns.
routines. so
I'd watch and I'd
observe.
and I'd see
if they fit my profile.
Abigail's detective work?
She obviously put some
heavy analysis and
thinking into this.
her conclusion was a
bit of a stretch
because they all
weren't involved in
the film industry
I mean apparently some
were but when you
start putting enough
time and energy
into figuring out
your killer or your
attempted killer, then
it kind of makes
sense how she came up with those
conclusions.
I suppose
you have to start
finding answers so
you don't go insane
but honestly the main thing that
connected them all...
they all lived within
100 miles of each
other. it was just a
fact of mere convenience
for me.
that's it. nothing more.
I selected them based
upon how often they were alone
I watched them. I
observed them.
I checked out out
their routines.
I couldn't have others
close by when I
was gonna kill them.
there are several
people that I watched
and then they just
really didn't fit my
profile. that's it.
plain and simple. one
thing I did find
funny is that a lot
of people gave me
motives that honestly
I just didn't have
they thought I was out
to get someone or
I had revenge or that
it was something
from when I was a
kid that I'm pissed off about.
what's my motive?
I wanted to make a movie.
and I did.
I made this entire movie.
I guess
I should give some
credit to those who
died. I did a
shit-ton of work so give
credit where credit is due
I tried to
be creative in my
killings and with
my weapons. it was
tough getting an SMG
and flying under
the radar. I figured
after Abigail got away,
that wasn't gonna
happen a second time
it just pissed
me off that it
didn't work.
Borja.
if you're watching this,
watch your back.
Cause I'm coming for you.
you sold me an
automatic that cost a
shit ton of money and
didn't even work
Fuck you!
Anyway... I release my movie
out to the world.
I hope you find it shocking
and entertaining.
and as good as a
movie should be.
I realized that my
face is going to be
out there.
but I can guarantee you will
never find me.
This project took a lot
of patience on my part.
to bring everything
together.
It's been a lot of work
but it's my
contribution to the
art world
Thank you.
[Music]
All right. Dang, I'm good.