He can get you out of me whenever
dead whiskey Harold MacGREGOR!
If there exists a hoþ of whiskey,
that you're you, Alastair MacGREGOR!
See how you talk! Nobody has said
ever think of MacGREGOR's hoþ!
With  better!
I have the pleasure of being first!
What you saw?
- 200 head.
- Why?
Some horses minunaþi.
And in the home are only few old people.
Let's go!
Veniþi with me after all!
Haideþi!
Bonjour and Welcome!
I think you are însetaþi.
Want a little water?
Thanks, Mama, but do not want water.
We want the horses yourself.
But we sell horses at the fair animals.
The thing is that ... we do not want
I bought. We want to take.
Well, about this need to talk
soþul with me.
Harold!
I seek some hoþi horse!
Just a moment, please.
Coming.
Whiskey and glory!
Hooray for MacGREGOR!
Hooray!
Descãlecaþi!
Adãpostiþi you behind the rocks!
Try not to waste you gloanþele.
On how much ...
It was my glonþul and do what I want with it!
Give me that cigar once, Mamie!
Pacat ca bãieþii are plecaþi,
you could help.
We can handle ourselves, and,
you know better, unaided.
Take care, Kenneth, that you're not
the carousel.
It's easy to humanize the girls are!
Courage, Johnny, it's yours.
Vai of those who neglect
purity of the soul!
Not even Lord miles
can not save from hell!
Mila Lord helped already
avoiding to become a real priest.
It was Lord miles, but my dad ...
that he wanted to get money
of pocket to send me to the seminar.
You can keep teaching
fair in town.
Forgive them, because do not know what I mean.
I come!
I can you show me
how to tame it a horse.
Lãudãrosule!
I do buy a whiskey
residency if you are more than a minute!
If we want to get þarc,
it is better to get behind the house.
Pedro! Detour on the way!
Jane!
Give me a hand
to move it.
Sorry.
Nice shot! On time
Geronimo's not a shot you and a.
Let 'me and you will see that crowd
that mucous and no one to come in the house.
At least not live.
Râdeþi, râdeþi.
Maybe I'll enter the house,
but will þarc sure.
I e, þarcul!
We hotãrâþi time to do something?
- Queen Ana!
- Sure!
Queen Ana, right!
Blessed are you, boys.
If I be us ...
You must have great patience.
- Gale! Uiþi what is most important.
- He is right.
- Come on come on!
- Hold.
Grãbiþi you!
Indian vase and Dorothy ii!
And how much it cost!
Only to be once it was.
Ana Regina not you never grow old.
Hold.
It is better to straddle.
I can take them by surprise.
You can get immediate
þarc of animals. Let's go!
Strike this is my MacGREGOR.
Last time you have pulled it þii mind?
E Queen Ana!
Whiskey and glory!
Hooray for MacGREGOR!
The goddamn gun
I'll never get on track.
There's only one thing
to do: to attack the group.
- We next house and killed them all.
- Do we get home next?
But fuck like mad!
Half of us to die.
Yes, but if you go back to horses
tonight, we'll kill Santillana.
Means to attack the house choose
the lower river, too?
Distanþaþi you and to my
I exit out everyone!
If you matu Dorothy would find
that it was broken vase ...
... we would never forget.
- Leave now damn vase.
Friday and gentlemen orii that.
Hey, MacGREGOR!
We have some guests!
Courage, boys, otherwise you kidnap
wives!
Dispose of weapons and predaþi you,
otherwise we fire house!
I'm sorry, my dear,
but I think he said to us.
Courage, hotãrâþi you!
We are old, sir,
rãcim and easy.
I think a little heat
we'll use for the bones.
Go!
Bãieþii! Friday bãieþii!
Alastair, your concerns!
- On windows, quick! Damn it!
- Now it Friday and reinforcements.
- Johnny! You are hurt?
- Go, I have nothing.
Rest in peace.
What is ludicrous? We have done
very well and without you.
Better stingeþi fire.
Otherwise skip dinner tonight.
Come on, do your work!
Hi, Mom.
Hi, Gregor.
Did you eat?
Put your handkerchief that cold.
I'm sorry, Johnny ...
but I think it is better to stay
home and to help the elderly.
- You know that the road is long and tedious.
- No need angel.
Yes, I need you, you know.
But to stay anyway, if
those guys that will appear again.
Those guys certainly
not-and will make appearance.
And anyway, once vânduþi horses,
will not have anything that you take.
And even evening
spuneþi your prayer.
- Goodbye, Kenneth.
- Do you care.
- Bye, honey.
Goodbye, mother.
- Bye, Indian and ica.
- When you think you'll întoarceþi?
In four days you should get
Las Mesas with the horses.
A day to sell them,
two to get back.
Yes, one week.
Do not understand why you must go
to Las Mesas ...
when San Diego's closer.
San Diego is closer to us
but also of Santillana.
- And it is better not to risk.
- But we always went to San Diego.
- Once in the life and Alistair are right.
- And once in the life you have confidence in us.
At Las Mesas is more secure.
And it pays better.
- And now it is and rail ...
- Nonsense!
At least five dollars in addition
for each horse.
For me, this argument
put an end to any discussion.
Even the half of U.S. dollars
should end any discussion.
Subtitling = =
Florin-Bratianu-Constanta
- Look and Las Mesas.
- Nice place.
It remains to be seen.
Now that we put the horses in þarc ...
... hopefully to us and buy some.
- And that we pay well.
- And money ice.
Anything else?
You would like to find a girl?
I feel that this is not too
how to have fun.
It's a strange atmosphere. One of us
would have to remain with the þarc horses.
Let's take a look.
Rail we brought
hoþi than here.
one I go to Dallas.
This is not fair, it's a racket!
What kind of proposal I do
- Horses that I grew, I never steal!
- But who told you something?
But  is a price and inos ru!
- Hello. Here's your whiskey.
- Thanks.
I'm in here or it's supposed to be
a deal for animals?
No, not in the eli.
It is a deal of animal.
- This is the last price.
- No, Crawford! No! No and no!
Than to accept your conditions, better
eat them all on! One!
- Stevson is right!
- Stevson in the ealã!
Who shot?
I, and erifule. Stevson out gun
and had to defend myself.
Take away from this.
Hey, a minute!
But the man had a gun,
how was it out?
- Keep your mouth, Dick! Do not meddle.
- It's the first time when veniþi here?
Yeah, so's I got recently.
To deal.
Be welcome.
I saw horses.
Beautiful animals.
Crawford is interested in them.
Don 't you, Crawford?
Sure I'm interested.
And bãieþii ã and are very nice people.
- You hear how many heads you have?
- 200.
- Give them 1,000 dollars.
- I said 200 horses.
And I said, 1000 dollars.
200 horses with one $ 5,
make 1000 dollars, right?
Yes.
Well.
Agreed.
1000 dollars for nutreþ.
But for animals as I have?
Dude, in Las Mesas, I am
who buy.
And nobody else.
The fixed price that I am,
and that it supports are too.
Got it?
Take your money and go with God.
Mind if we issue?
- Hooray for MacGREGOR!
- Hooray!
Omorâþi sure between you wild!
In the end I sing
real music.
Be careful, Gregor!
Just felt the need.
Mine is!
Sorry that I gave the bounce, but ...
You are beautiful.
I hope to have the chance to see you again.
My name is David MacGREGOR.
And I'm Barbara Othorn.
Goodbye.
It was a real pleasure.
Stop it! Hands up!
Hands up, I said!
How many move you!
Haideþi!
Take their guns.
Melee, aggression ...
dislocation lines and the public know ...
... and yet incalculable damages.
- Inches, and here you have time to make sure lines.
- Yes, but I was provocaþi.
Us must get that mulþumiþi
he used no guns, and erifule.
- This is a city still.
- Still a cemetery.
It's a luxury room.
Faster!
- And that should be the eriful?
- We closed for few punches.
Do not you seem exaggerated?
A erif and so intensely
are not found throughout the west.
And yet I was worth.
During the melee of hand
certain meetings ...
A woman?
An angel.
- Let's you better look out.
- Sit still, and erifule, sit still.
Let's go.
Dislocation lines and the public know ...
I feel like laughing.
- I say so ...
- No, not about the lines and public tea ...
... and no melee.
They just wanted us to get
of road.
- And why?
- Like to take our horses.
Clearer than that ...
Maybe gre º esc.
But here I feel the smell of Santillana.
If the way you say, why not back
the road, and as soon as possible?
Maybe you were right the elderly.
It was better to go
to sell horses in San Diego.
And now what?
Must do in any way. Unless,
your imagination what the vote says the elderly.
Peter.
See if the door's resistance.
Well.
Here is nothing to do.
Keep an eye on our buddy.
Daþi me a spur.
- Who has a piece of string?
- I think that is me.
That's good?
Keep you here, you here.
Pull.
Work!
But it can be and better.
Warning!
My involvement and that he did a hungry ...
I a. Enough so.
Haideþi!
Good night.
I thank you, Virgin of the Pillar!
I thank you!
Haideþi, boys!
At þarcuri!
Þarcurile Here!
- But are empty!
- Blestemãþie!
- Have disappeared.
- Tâlharii!
- I told myself.
- Will pay for it!
And when you Think that you venisem here
close to good business.
Now who is back home
without animals and without money?
- Old'll kill us!
- I say so ...
Traces are still fresh.
I should be away.
Let's go!
- Water and ii!
- No, not here.
Be carefully, boys.
Could be a trap.
I never saw anything so when the Indians
chyrykawa buried the hatchet.
Descãlecaþi!
Damn it!
Forgive me.
I thought that you're a water and.
Blestematule!
Hey, boys.
Veniþi to see.
My father tried to arrange them in a colony are
to be opposed to Crawford.
I think Crawford has done that?
I do not know, it's hard to say.
Those who attacked us ...
... were not men.
Are secure.
It was a powerful banda, were many.
Certainly came from the border.
- As those who have attacked our farm.
- It could be same i. Now is clear.
- Santillana?
- Yes, Santillana ...
- He came up here.
- What are the Santillana Crawford?
It should be about, Rosita.
Do you have any plan, Gregor?
Just to say that I have an idea.
To stay here yet.
It's a place where no one can find us one.
Dick ...
Come back to you old.
Line up the them and explains the situation.
- I just have to go?
- You are the lowest.
And you won 't get too certain.
You others, aranjaþi little house,
you can even sleep in it.
And what you gonna do?
I'll give up a getaway to Las Mesas.
I am curious to see how it has failed
escape us.
I think I'll be back
with much clearer ideas.
But Santillana, you can not
Think you are up to you something.
I was always loyal to you.
I hope this for you, Crawford. Moreover,
if you reconcile with science, as saying ...
n you want me to refuse hospitality.
And if you do not want to come with you?
Few had ienþa to the INCON
contradict me, and have paid dearly.
You can inform you of the old
Carson and his daughter, Rosita.
You are sure of the power, right?
I have not any reason to be? Time
that I brought only a small escort.
I knew that I am among friends.
Straddle horse, Crawford!
One can have a pleasant conversation together.
Come on, Crawford.
Goodbye, and erifule!
I can send you my instructions.
Haideþi, boys!
Step that must be repaired,
otherwise one that hurt someone.
This is the Rio Pecos.
This is his lair Santillana.
Here, five hours away on horseback,
us.
And here in Las Mesas, Crawford steals
animals, the way it has done and with us.
When they go beyond the river ...
and the pred of Santillana,
they sell. Is that clear?
Crawford and it's spit.
Crawford must bear
any condition ...
even if a deal with the stran dinþii i.
Because when one gives
increased animal which opposes ...
Santillana ... intervenes with force,
while the eriful ...
... shall ensure that nobody
not be punished.
- I say that you ...
- A perfect organization.
And we what?
Sit and look lini sure?
Yes, but not outside.
I have to go into banda.
See, dude, you tried
I go to the nose.
And I don 't like to be taken to move to.
You had my trust and you betrayed it.
And now, Crawford, you'll pay dearly
for this.
So, who wants to follow your example,
will think six times before to do.
I didn 't go nose, Santillana.
I just gave all animals
the fair in Las Mesas!
All 200 less horses that
did you removed the night of þarc ...
while the eriful to keep it cooler
on their owners.
I do not know anything about horses that!
This is the truth!
Minþi Crawford! You wanted to go atragi
and me in this affair.
But I do not betray my friends
especially for a partner like you.
Enough talking!
Let's start the show.
Today!
- To be clean!
- Yes, excellence.
Rollick and them. In a place like this
not how to have fun.
And when ive the chance ...
My time was different. That
yield more than five minutes.
I'm glad.
I'm glad to have a partner like you.
If we associate, we can do
more traffic than the animals.
And then put the animals.
There are other ways to us îmbogãþim
quickly and with less effort.
Fat is not wake up.
Definitely not worth a damn.
Very bad! Very bad!
Men for anything!
It would be better to go.
I want to get to Las Mesas dawn.
I transmitted to you as the tile.
Goodbye, friend.
Bon voyage.
And to give signs of life
as soon as possible.
This is something that Crawford
he can do.
- Polished up my shoes! Faster!
- Yes, excellence.
Whiskey.
Huh? What's the big idea?
When so many guns around ...
it is better to get rid of greutãþi.
Someone i could come a little draw.
It's a prudent and a.
You're right, buddy.
It's healthy, right?
I like people prudenþi.
But I'd like to know ...
what a guy here
so cautious that you?
I know that people searching Santillana,
and I'm here to enlist.
That's only if you offer
is convenient.
If not, this is fun anyway.
It's already something.
And as a thought to offer Santillana ...
a cautious guy like you?
Much.
Because you see, I have left
gun because I am scared of you ...
but because they are a little nervous
and he's like someone here ...
... and to lose life.
- Listen, pal.
I like your jokes.
And I do not like strangers.
So I delete it as soon ...
if you do not want to give you a lecþie!
- But I really want to get a lecþie.
- What?
I think that always
something you learned in your life.
And if someone wants to give me
a lecþie not refuse.
Get out of here!
Stop it!
Do not shoot against a man
unarmed.
You should you know it, Miguel.
- What are you, gringo?
- You are Santillana?
I heard that you're in search
pricepuþi people.
With fists good, gringo,
but the gun where you left?
Put down that gun.
When you enter the house of friends,
leave it to the wardrobe.
Otherwise I would too dangerous.
- I like you, gringo. How you name?
- Thompson.
Kid Thompson. If you kill me,
receive 150 dollars.
But live you'll get more profit.
But Thompson is not in prison
from Yuma?
She ... in Yuma.
- Santillana here?
- Yes, it's up.
money for miners' wages go
morning at the Bank of Saint Antonio ...
and will be împãrþiþi Saturday.
We have two days available.
Okay.
- Miguel, go and get my bank plan.
- I'm going soon.
Takes only a minute.
No, Santillana ...
tonight, no.
Look  bank plan, Santillana.
Okay.
You need to create a false alarm
far from town.
In such a way as eriful
and his men to go.
will give a kick on Friday.
We'll get there early-the-morning,
least after the opening bank.
route will be it.
Look . See
A  and it will compel the director
to open the safe.
contact people to be prepared.
Yet that's all. You can go.
Why did you close?
Open!
Who is with you
What 's happening?
You fucking bitch!
- But why? What I did?
- I'm wondering?
Destrãbãlato!
Where did you hide?
- Rosita!
- Who?
I know right!
If you give him, I do bucãþi!
Are you crazy?
Damn!
Forgive me, but it was an impulse
stronger than me.
Nice way to greet me.
Now understand why you wanted
so much to get in the banda.
And I, as a poor,
I worry for you.
Do not say shit.
You better tell me, why are you here?
Why do not you and Dick?
Listen, Gregor ...
I know you ride as good as you.
And here, dressed so, to give a
less than one suspect in man.
You are crazy! You must go back
immediately to the farm.
I want to revenge my father,
trying to understand.
Last night I did it succeed to sleep.
Felt that it should be
next to you and run.
But if you do not want me ...
Not that you want.
But you must send
an urgent message fraþilor mine.
Be very careful. This
ita succeed depends on my plan.
- Good day, Mr. Director.
- Bonjour Smith.
- Bonjour, Barner.
- Good day, Mr. Director.
- Bonjour, Calaghan.
Bonjour, Mr. Director.
- Good day ...
But you who are you?
My name is Santillana, sir.
I think you have already heard of him.
Money wages for miners are
in your safe, if not me-no he.
Mr. Santillana would
to withdraw staff.
Please, open it.
Daþi you off now.
We can handle ourselves.
You do not want to take it?
Courage. Ready soon.
Barbara ...
Come on!
No time to lose!
Yes, wine.
But she, who more reviews now?
And erifule! And erifule!
What disaster! Hurry!
We pierduþi!
Santillana's banda! Thanks
God's erifule! You are here!
- But you are not the eriful!
- Sure it's not eriful!
And no I suggest you call him
if you want a glonþ headed!
But you who are you?
What?
My name Santillana.
I think you heard me.
I want the money that is
in your safe!
But money is not safe.
No more, I want to say.
Were furaþi all! All!
Bandiþii what they left.
And then, you are not Santillana!
My friend, I love jokes!
Hey, you!
Come here!
- I ...
- Shut up!
Get in!
What means this?
Where is the money?
How where they? In pockets
Santillana's! I told him that they stole!
There is no dollar here.
I go everywhere.
Not even one U.S. dollars!
Santillana took everything!
Nice surprise.
I do not knew that two of Santillana.
Vamos!
We started well.
I always go to
your business?
Me I like the bread tigat
today.
I never saw any
atâþia money.
- You should put them in a safe place.
- Let's put the bank.
But who are you?
What want?
Sir, iertaþi me,
But the question they put us.
- You ... Who are you?
- I judge Garland.
Old Carson was
best friend of mine.
On his daughter, Rosita,
I saw a nãscându is.
- I just died and she?
- Rosita's okay, the lines you know.
A So you
are judge?
I am judge of Las Mesas.
More names than facts.
Because the law do now bandiþii ...
... how Crawford, as Santillana,
and how are you.
Like you, yeah!
I recognized immediately!
Nelegiuiþii who are devastated
half of the city.
Rosita!
- Hi, Rosita! What news do you have?
- Hello, boys!
- What is Gregor?
- Okay.
May we broke a robbery
de Santillana's.
- Great!
- What is it?
Rosita!
Rosita ...
You are more beautiful.
Tell me, how come?
And what cauþi with bandiþii ã º tia?
There are some special bandiþi,
'll see.
Your honor,
I would like to talk.
And then I think that'll intraþi
and your in our banda.
Damn! Let us cherish!
I fell into an ambush!
What is happening?
Who shoot us?
Who want to be?
Or have those who robbed the bank.
But this time we'll pay it.
Acoperiþi me!
Carramba!
Why!
Thompson is a real devil!
- Look at him!
- Yes, but I'll never succeed eascã.
Boys! To draw to protect us
mate! Fire!
Þopãie, Greg! Þopãie!
Bastards!
- Dick, you stay here!
- Hi Gregor him from me!
- Want to finish at once?
- Hey, Greg! How goes?
- Okay. And you?
- Everything is fine.
- And my mother?
- It was a little cold, but now is better.
Rosita goes with what?
You engaged?
Want to stop saying shit?
That girl is dead after you
I bet with your head.
What if you did not?
Hey, Greg!
What?
It's a load of silver bullion
Santillana that brings them in Mexico.
Why!
Here on the our.
- Dispose of arms and hands up!
- Without the mecherii!
Damn, what happens?
- Come on down!
- Later, Gregor!
And greet her Rosita
from me!
Let us hurry, boys!
To take charge in a safe place!
Blestemaþii!
What beautiful show!
Are a bunch of spineless.
I put about 20 on the run alone.
We came from one percent.
They come at once.
Like it out of Earth.
We fought, but you were too
Next, you have to see how.
Were more than one percent, I say!
And probably have killed many
of them.
Lots!
And where are they?
Well, they succeed in it to take on everyone,
both morþii and the rãniþii.
He wants you to be in your skin
When I povestiþi this to Santillana.
Santillana! Santillana always!
Let him try to do the job!
Fool!
It's the last chance that you have!
May do me any inconvenience
and he said to you!
All happens only
when Thompson came!
Idiot!
All should be like him!
Come on, name them in!
Intraþi!
Dullness good thing!
Daþi When in trouble, I am the
protects you. Just me!
And when the riot colony you know,
call to Santillana.
If you need to acoperiþi
escrocheriile, who chemaþi?
On Santillana!
And I ask you to do my run
orders with a minimum of inteligenþã.
And I discover the traitors
which is among you. Too much?
There's an area in banda
we break plans.
There are some bandiþi, right?
Means that your business, and erifule!
Anyway, I have in mind a blow
we will cover all losses.
And this time do not allow gre and eli.
- Is everything okay?
- All right, yet.
Hopefully that will be you next.
With all the gold you transport
you are more scared than those at hand.
- Tell me about it?
- Hello!
Hands up! Stop the train!
I told you to hold back!
You three open wagon with gold!
Hurry! Daþi people down!
Ajutaþi us to get gold!
Who shot?
Now it's two people no longer wake up.
David, let it start.
We are ready.
What
Barbara! Barbara!
Gentlemen and Othorn time!
I'm that guy from the salon!
I recognize you?
Miss Barbara's time!
Stop it! Stop it!
- Jim, what happened?
- No idea.
I'm going to see what happened.
Warning, arrives!
Who shot at you our?
Better target our fraþii.
Get in, Peter!
Congratulations, boys.
You did good job.
And you.
Ãstuia I'll use
little fresh air.
And now what will you tell
Santillana's?
Me? Well, as I received
a blow to the head.
Take the train to Vallee, you will get
gold can not bother anyone.
And what are you doing?
And in them, right? A so when others arrive,
'll find me here next to him sprawling.
Remember how to proceed.
Go! Good day!
Goodbye, Gregor!
Good day!
Pleasant rest!
First silver ...
... then gold mining company,
plus money from the bank in San Diego.
Dearly beloved, in my warehouse
that almost no room.
If we continue so we have a
Reserve more than Federal bank.
While his Santillana
will be completely empty.
But our pockets and
are empty, Judge.
You can get daþi $ 10
for a good lunch.
Oh no! We are not bandiþi.
I did one I'd like to be in place
poor ...
which will lead to Santillana
this news.
Better words are, otherwise you'll put
wounds on a layer of melted sugar.
Zaharul burn wounds ...
... and like it very much
ants and ro ii.
I will eat alive.
You are încãpãþânat, you?
Sugar!
No! Ready, go!
I speak! I say to you all!
But it does not torture!
But you who are you?
Daughter of an honest man
You have killed you!
I say whatever you want
if it cruþi life.
- No, Rosita!
- You come with me.
Get it here!
Ants can not wait May
today.
Thanks for the information.
I hope for you to be true.
Meat 's too beautiful
to the SFA and iem whip.
You have only mângâieri.
My and my people.
Pãziþi is good! Tomorrow resume
fun with the whole family.
Rosita, what have you done?
What did you say? What did you say?
- Gregor ...
- Say it!
I told him everything. How to take
by surprise ... to my farm.
What could you do?
But all will fall with
Santillana in his hands!
Without even to defend,
without-and aware of, understand?
Understand what you did, nefericito?
I just know that ...
.... that you're still in your life.
24 hours of life or more
less does not change things much.
Tomorrow I'll die anyway
while you ...
Gregor, sometimes several hours worth
rather than whole life.
No ...
It's not right ...
An exit to im here.
I had an idea.
Look at him.
I have got all.
What do you do?
I do not know. I know only that and my
should be there.
Friday and me with you.
You know what you wait if you catch?
But you can find free help.
Why invent this
just to eject me.
No, it's a matter of life
and death.
You must go. If you stay with me
would be a vain sacrifice.
If you need to die,
I want to die and I with you.
Hard încãpãþânatã's you!
You know what? Here, the scoþieni,
women never discuss!
Good luck, Rosita.
No! No, Santillana! No!
I do not have any guilt!
You let you escape a prisoner.
And this is coming at me
it pays to life.
To be a lecþie for all.
It's useless to search on the motherfucker.
And anyway, single
no one can do anything.
Ramon! Take up the rest of the family.
Prepare them a warm reception.
- Good evening.
I'd like to confess me.
It is very urgent.
A wait, son. I'm going to call him
the parent Fulcenzio.
Thanks much.
annual Virgin Festival
of Guadalupe. Fireworks.
Faster!
Santillana wait!
- We are almost done.
- Go and prepares the prisoners.
It's time to light the fire!
Haideþi! Prepare yourself!
Can I give the signal?
I'm here, boys!
Fugiþi!
David! Take that you little!
Let us cherish in!
What do we do?
Înconjuraþi house. We attack at dawn.
high heavens!
Lucky that the judge had
treasure with him when we got caught.
What would have been disaster.
All efforts and dangers that
I passed, would have been unnecessary.
Mark, how many gloanþe you have left?
We have a total
only about 70 gloanþe.
Economy must do.
Economy!
For 15 generations we all economy.
I recommend to make a scoþian
economy is almost an insult.
Not sure supãraþi. I wanted to say ...
Each impui and should cãturã
nimereascã to a man.
- Friday!
- There they are!
Fuck you, to come.
E banda whole.
- Haideþi, Take it!
- Okay.
At your seats!
And Wait I come!
You do not care you expuneþi.
And do not forget ...
I try not  irosiþi gloanþele!
Vamos!
Them!
Damn fucking!
I finished gloanþele.
Watch out, Greg!
He left two gloanþe.
Do not fiddle.
As we have told the elderly ...
Hector strãbunicul at Waterloo,
before he died ...
sang of bagpipe
and led the final assault.
Shame you do not have a bagpipe.
In lack of something better,
and it goes.
Peter is right.
Muzicuþei's sound like
like a bagpipe.
So sweet ...
... and so removed.
But I do not sing!
Our elders!
Whiskey and glory!
Hooray for MacGREGOR!
- What do we do?
- Omorâþi them all!
Vamos!
- After me!
- Atacaþi them!
This time it's mine!
Come on! Come on!
Excellent, Mamie!
God rest it.
Veniþi after me!
Them!
And you've just said
do not waste you gloanþele!
Save me ... Take me with you.
Don 't leave me. I beg you!
Blestematule!
You bitch!
Santillana!
Gregor!
Gregor ...
I forgot to tell you that each of
Thank you pãgubiþii that ...
were back in possession of their assets ...
decided to leave as a Reward
to you in sign of recognition tinþã.
And everything together,
makes a nice amount.
And so we got back, and horses,
and money.
Father, bring your mind that I
have to base my family.
Well, that'll make you a loan.
This is my part time
þinem according to a toast.
Good idea, Judge. We barrel and the
this old whiskey for 20 years.
What do you like sheep?
Let him drink, of course.
Bullshit! The Whiskey That's my
and no one to touch him!
I'd like to see
Who prevents you to go.
Why do not I stop?
Let it go. Are boys,
have fun and they little.
- Why?
- A little move that makes good.
Good evening!
Garland judge here?
I am his granddaughter.
I was told that you find here.
- Barbara!
- Uncle!
- God to save Scoþia!
- But the father, the whiskey that is mine!
Hooray for  MacGREGOR!