Do you really want to break up?
I did empty the wardrobe,
did you think I was just
getting them dry cleaned?
We're adults,
you should've just told me directly.
It's exactly because we're adults
that not everything
has to be so direct.
I'm not wealthy
and I'm not very smart,
but I know exactly what I want.
"77 Heartbreaks"
"Heartbeat Shutter"
He's always out drinking
with his friends,
and he's a reckless driver.
How can I not worry about him?
I know, is it so hard
to make a phone call or send a text?
Eva's father had a wish,
which is for his daughter
to find a good husband.
Mrs Lui, I did think about marriage.
The happiness I'll give you
will definitely make up
the 77 times I broke your heart.
I hope you can forgive me
one last time.
You'd already closed the file,
yet here you are again.
You're just torturing yourself.
I left that notebook out on purpose
for you to see,
and I guess this is what
that girl left out on purpose
for me too.
Look...
I was in a mess, I don't have...
Leave me alone!
"77 Heartbreaks"
That's a definite no.
- You look gorgeous!
- How's this one?
No way!
So ugly.
Cheers!
It's too tight.
One, two, three!
"77 Heartwarmings"
Solicitor Eva Lui!
Are you ready to go?
White already comes with
so many styles, it's hard to pick.
Men are no different,
they come in all shapes and sizes.
- Afraid of picking the wrong one?
- No.
I'm not ready.
You're usually so decisive,
but now you're just
throwing out excuses.
If you do pick the wrong one,
just get a divorce.
I'm moving heaven and earth
to put together this wedding
just so I can get divorced?
According to statistics,
11.61 million marriages were
registered nationwide last year.
Meanwhile,
there were 2.32 million divorces
and a 20 percent increase
in divorce rate.
Which also means one out of five
marriages end in divorce,
and there is another divorce
happening every three minutes.
Based on the cases
our firm has handled,
these are the top ten reasons
for divorce.
He doesn't love me anymore.
That's right,
I don't love her anymore.
We haven't talked in over 40 years.
He never gave me a cent
to raise these kids.
- Don't play with that.
- Isn't he useless?
An irresponsible,
useless piece of trash!
I won't get alimony
if I don't get divorced,
and how will I have
a steady income then?
Let me tell you, lady.
A family unit can only
buy one home in China.
Baby, if we're both single,
then we can buy another home!
So we can each have one!
She's changed,
she used to be thinner than me!
- She abuses me.
- Shut your mouth!
No sex!
I don't know why we got married...
In the past year, our firm's offices
in Hong Kong, Guangzhou and Shenzhen
saw business double.
However, this is also
the tragedy of our generation.
"Adam Cheung"
"We held hands for the first time
8 years ago."
Come in.
Daisy says when you get
to the airport in London,
there will be a driver
waiting for you.
She's truly a winner at life,
even her kid's one-month banquet
has to go international.
Why don't you fly out early
with me anyway?
Oh, I know.
You don't want to be on
the same plane as NT Tang, right?
Hi, Mr Tang.
I'm Eva.
Hi there, you can just call me NT.
He's already pretty nice
for a nouveau riche.
Plenty of girls would jump
at the chance of marrying him,
and you would've been set for life.
What are you doing?
Even your phone still misses Adam?
You guys have split
for a year already.
"Saving"
Good thing that
you back-up the phone regularly.
Be yourself, be happy!
Be yourself, be happy?
I wish too.
Be happy...
Excuse me, it's time to close.
Sorry.
Miss.
In lightning speed,
we've transferred your phone's data.
Take a look.
How do I unlock it?
The factory setting for this phone
is like the M shape,
just make an "M" to unlock it.
If you have anything
against the word,
you may as well change it
when you get home.
Go online and see if it works now.
Perfect, all done.
"Why are you still single?"
Why are you still single?
Because I love myself the most.
I overthink things
and it's hard to love someone new.
Because I can't handle
another betrayal.
Because I don't want to
sacrifice so much for someone else.
Freedom!
- Another bottle, handsome?
- Thanks.
"Adam Cheung"
"We held hands for the first time
8 years ago."
I'll treat your mother better,
I won't drive drunk and buying
those raisin cookies anymore.
All the mistakes
I made in that book,
I'll never make them again.
Believe me.
Once, I had the love of a lifetime,
- but I didn't treasure it!
- Oh, forget it.
You guys broke up a year ago,
you don't have to
act brokenhearted forever, right?
Right now, you ought to be happy.
You've just escaped
a maximum security prison.
Just because of leaving
a bottle of beer behind,
you don't have to go back
in the cell for it, dummy!
One of this, please.
- Me, too.
- Thank you.
Where's Francis?
I guess his wife
didn't grant him a release then.
You have to understand,
having the freedom to watch football
is some kind of bliss.
We used to be happy, too.
When we watched games at his place,
Eva used to take such good
care of us and served us drinks.
She even made us instant noodles
whenever we are hungry,
and no to mention
that crispy chicken!
So delicious!
As if to have a friend
with a girlfriend
that can cook as well as her,
do you know how hard it is?
Look, we're here to watch football
and other ball-shaped objects.
What a ball game!
- Thanks, guys.
- You're the real winner.
Such a nice ball game.
- You didn't even take a peek?
- They were spilling out.
- You can keep them.
- Sure.
You pulled a prison break?
No, my wife and her mother
are away visiting family.
Good thing that
I didn't have to go with them.
So once I dropped them
off at the airport,
I came straight here
to see you rascals.
It's really been a while, rascal.
Yeah.
The last time I saw you,
you were just a little fat.
- Now you've really blown up.
- Get off, man.
Dude, you just wanted a girl, right?
Why did you get married?
There are so many dating apps
out there.
What I mean is,
you can't give up
all the functions on your phone
for a single app.
But I really do love my wife,
and I gained weight
because I'm happy.
And I enjoy being ordered around,
what do you care?
Second half's starting soon,
so shut up.
We've already lost
in the first half.
They'll catch up in the second half,
that's what makes the game
so exciting, right?
He lost 77-0 to Eva
in the first half.
- You try catching up!
- Come on.
It's your fault
for getting caught red-handed.
The very night
you split up with Eva,
you brought a girl home.
- You deserved what you got.
- I don't agree.
He was drunk,
and he was technically broken up
with Eva at the time.
Girls always expect you to go
through a mourning period like them.
If you bring a girl home
within the first 7 days,
you're disrespecting the dead!
Drink up and shut up.
Drink up, you two.
You're talking too much.
You know, I use an apology app
on my wife all the time.
You should take a look.
That's absurd!
Mom, I'm back.
Welcome home.
How are you feeling today?
Is your stomach better?
What about you?
You can't skip your medication.
Those pills are making me drowsy
all the time.
What have we done to deserve this?
Me with the depression
and you with the stomach problem.
You really should move,
and live in
a more comfortable place.
What for? This is my home.
Some tasks are a little hard
without a man around, that's all.
Everyone uses those
T5 energy conserving bulbs now,
these fluorescent lights
are old and hard to buy.
I asked your dad to change them,
but he refused to.
Got it.
Mom, dad's been gone for so long.
If you need to cry,
you can do it in the living room.
It's so stuffy in the kitchen,
women don't have to
suffer like this anymore.
I'm not suffering.
I told you,
I may have married the wrong man,
but I had the right daughter.
But you've devoted your whole life
to your husband and daughter,
you ought to do something
for yourself and be happy.
I'm happy if you're happy.
By the way, I'm going
to the UK and see Daisy tomorrow.
I won't be around
to take care of you,
so you should call up your friends.
I don't need friends,
they're so annoying.
There's bound to be an exception.
Well, there's one.
But I haven't seen him in decades,
and I don't even have his number.
It's easy
to find someone these days,
give me the name
and I'll find him for you.
It's that easy?
His name is Tsang Po-wah.
Tsang Po-wah?
Well, never mind.
It's been decades, I don't even know
if he's still alive.
Remember to bring
your stomach medicine.
Alright, I got it.
Need anything from the UK?
I have to spend
my money somewhere...
"Sorry App"
I'm sorry, Eva.
This is so stupid!
Let's go that way.
We're trying to find our way,
this isn't a maze.
- You can't just guess a way out.
- Let's just go!
Let me help you,
or you'll hurt your hip again.
Did you bring your passport?
You know how forgetful you are.
Of course I did.
Wait, no way!
I told you, you're always like this.
It's not your first time missing...
I knew you'd throw a tantrum.
We're in a rush, stop playing!
Let me help you.
- Thanks.
- Okay.
"Chats"
"Speak now"
"Tap to stop"
Eva.
Do you know what today is?
It's not the anniversary
of our first meeting,
nor the anniversary
of the first time we held hands.
It's the first anniversary
of our breakup.
In the past year,
I keep feeling like
I've lost something,
which feel like I've lost myself.
I don't know what I can do to
make you forgive me the 78th time,
but if you do give me
one more chance,
I won't let you down.
Next, please.
"Plaza Premium Lounge"
- Hello, Miss.
- Excuse me.
My phone's out of battery,
where can I charge it?
We have a temporary charging
station inside.
- Great, thank you.
- You can go in now, Thank you.
- Marvel!
- Sorry...
It's okay, she's harmless.
This is for you.
Thank you.
I remember you, you're Melody.
Marvel is now in a rush.
We should go now.
Marvel, I have some bad news.
My parents are getting divorced,
what should I do?
How can I go on like this?
How can I be happy again?
Yours, Melody.
Thank you.
I didn't know girls still do
knitting these days.
This is for a special person.
A special one?
Oh, for your kid, right?
No...
For my friend's kid.
You must be very patient
Kind and old school.
You must be very neat
and sentimental.
Me? Sentimental?
You look sad
holding the paper heart over there.
You mean the origami?
I shouldn't say this,
but you look familiar.
Sir, flight HW77.
Last call for boarding.
- Oh, I gotta go.
- Thank you.
Oh, my phone.
Bye...
Thank you very much.
- Mrs Lui.
- They're writing parking tickets.
It's okay.
I've seen your car around
a few times.
I really don't get
how you young people think.
Once you lose touch with someone
back then, it was for good.
But it's so easy to find people now,
you can just make a call
or find them on the internet.
This is useless
to sit around doing nothing.
Mrs Lui!
"Eva's phone"
Hello.
What's going on?
Everything's in Thai.
My phone.
Bye...
Thank you very much.
No way...
Eva.
Do you know what today is?
It's not the anniversary
of our first meeting,
nor the anniversary
of the first time we held hands.
It's the first anniversary
of our breakup.
In the past year,
I keep feeling
like I've lost something...
"Happy 100 days"
This is for you.
This is lovely, did you knit this?
That's so thoughtful.
It's not like people
who is giving gold accessories
that I don't even know
what I'm supposed to do with them!
- Hi, ladies.
- It's beauitful...
- Hi, baby...
- Hi...
Do you mind if I steal the princess?
- Hi.
- Of course, that's a good idea.
- Is that alright?
- Let daddy have our little princess.
Yeah, thank you.
- Hi, sweetheart.
- Go to daddy.
- Bye.
- Thanks, daddy.
Bye, Daisy.
I'm amazed that
you had the time to knit the hat.
The baby's head is so small,
I got it done on the plane.
So?
Have you located my phone yet?
Not yet.
If your phone is off,
there's no way to track it.
Maybe he's still on the plane.
- What should I do?
- How did you mess that up?
How did you switch your phone
with a Thai guy anyway?
So I guess you can call this
a "Tom Yum Phone"!
That's a terrible joke.
Was he trying to steal your phone
or steal your heart?
- What are you talking about?
- Steal your heart.
Hey, look at this.
These photos are pretty cool.
- Let me see.
- What's that?
- That looks familiar.
- Is that's the Star Ferry Pier?
- Oh, "A Brokenhearted Dolphin".
- How do you know?
And this is "Lazy Afternoon",
that's the name of the piece.
The guy who made this
is named the Space-time Intruder.
Even to this day,
no one knows who he is.
But he's already intruded
over 35 cities
and left 890 intruder pieces.
There are 75 in Hong Kong alone.
How did you not know this?
I don't care who he is.
Putting stickers
on buildings like that
is against the law.
He's only in trouble
if he gets caught,
and who is just conquered Central
last week.
Maybe the phone doesn't actually
belong to that Intruder guy,
but just a fan of him instead?
It doesn't matter.
If he's handsome,
then this is awfully romantic!
Think about it.
The same phone model
with the same pattern lock.
It's fate.
That's fate, I totally agree.
I've looked into this.
Of all lock patterns on this phone,
there are 389,112 possible ways.
For two people to have
the exact same lock pattern,
this is just destiny.
The lock pattern
was the factory setting,
and the very destiny
that you're talking about
only happened because
I didn't have time to change it.
I have an idea.
Why don't we check on the messages
of this Tom Yum Phone?
No way, it's an invasion of privacy.
Sorry, ladies.
I think our little baby
just made a mess,
could you give me a hand?
I have to go upstairs.
- Sorry.
- See you later.
Hello, Eva!
I'm fine, thank you.
She didn't say "How are you?"
It's been four whole seasons
since we last met,
I'm sure that
you've missed me very much.
Excuse me.
I'll wait here for you.
- Why are you calling my phone?
- Hello.
- Eva, Adam is looking for you.
- Hello?
- Ask him what he wants.
- She'd like to know what you want.
Hello, what is it?
What's the matter with you guys?
The Thai guy called,
and says he can go to Hong Kong
to switch the phones back.
Really? When?
He didn't mention about it,
but he said he'll call again.
Eva, Adam says
that your mother's in the hospital.
Okay, thank you.
You won't be able to get on
a flight tonight, it's full.
The ticketing agent says the
earliest flight back is tomorrow.
It's done, let's pack up
and go to the airport.
Miss Lui.
This rose is from
Mr Tang's winery in Champagne,
Chateau du Tang.
This rose is called "All My Loving",
It's grown exclusively
at Mr Tang's rose garden.
This is a 77 percent cocoa
dark chocolate,
the latest from
NT and The Chocolate Factory.
- You can leave while you're done.
- Yes, sir.
Eva, guess what
this chocolate is called.
It looks like...
"A melty tear",
like a melting teardrop.
I'm romantic, aren't I?
I'm sorry, Mr Tang,
for having to fly me
back to Hong Kong.
I'll pay you back for the flight.
If I make you pay me back,
then I'd be really sorry.
You're so much poorer than me.
Money is of no object to me,
I value my time
and effort far above that.
Just take some time
to focus on the now,
and get ready to enjoy
the entertainment I've prepared.
Are we watching a movie?
I like watching movies.
I don't talk when I watch movies.
Brilliant minds think alike.
The best entertainment
is chatting with me.
So let's chat,
and you may start now.
- Then, why don't we tell jokes?
- Good idea.
Once, I bought some expensive
caterpillar fungus
and I asked my domestic worker
to cook it.
She brought it over to me,
but I'd actually bought it
for the dog.
I can't believe that
she had no idea, isn't that funny?
Your turn.
I don't have many...
That's hilarious!
That's a good one.
It's fun to tell jokes.
But I'd like to talk to you
about some romantic things,
do you know what GDP stands for?
- Gross Domestic Product?
- Good answer.
Let me tell you a story.
Once there were two economists
named Adam and Smith,
they were taking a stroll together
when they spotted a drop of dog poo.
Adam says to Smith,
"If you eat it,
I'll give you a million dollars."
Smith really eats it,
so Adam gave him a million bucks.
Then, they kept on strolling until
they spotted a drop of cat poo.
This time, Smith says to Adam,
"If you eat it,"
"I'll give you back
your million dollars."
So Adam eats it,
and Smith really does return
the million bucks.
Well, that's dumb.
No one made any money,
but they both ate poo.
But that's not how economists think.
It's true that no one ate money
and both of them ate poo,
but the GDP went up by 2 million.
Everyone feels richer for it.
I'm such a romantic, aren't I?
I'm sleepy,
I'm going to get some sleep.
You really look like my dead mother.
Not when your eyes are opened,
but when they're closed.
She looked just like that
when she died.
She didn't toss around,
and breathed less.
Then, her heart stopped, too.
Your husband died
such an unjust death!
How can you die so early?
Our flat isn't
even paid off yet, son!
Sit down...
- He, he's dead now!
- What will we do about the flat?
- Eva.
- Where's Mom?
Come with me.
- Mom.
- You're back already?
- Are you okay?
- I'm fine.
What did the doctor say?
He says it's a spell of anaemia,
but I think it's better
to get more tests.
- Thank you, Adam.
- You're welcome.
Thank my family's domestic worker
for this.
When my mother was in the hospital,
she made soup for her, too.
Thanks.
- I'll get you some water.
- Let me.
The doctor is coming
on his rounds anytime now,
so you can talk to him directly.
Hey, sit down.
Adam always hangs
around downstairs waiting for you,
but he didn't want you to know.
He brought you to the hospital?
- I'm fine.
- You should lie down.
Would you like dessert?
We have two choices,
blackcurrants cake and macaron.
Definitely not
the blackcurrents cake,
you don't eat processed fruits.
Two macarons, please.
- Sure, two macarons.
- Thanks...
How did you lose your phone?
It's unbelievable,
good thing you knew to call Cat.
Two macarons, thank you.
- Thanks...
- Enjoy.
Have mine too,
I know you like it.
So, how have you been?
My father and stepmom moved back
to Vancouver for retirement,
and he sold his shares
in the law firm to his partners.
You know me,
I never liked working
in my dad's firm.
Besides, mergers and acquisitions
work isn't for me too.
That's good, you can keep
teaching kickboxing then.
I already am.
As long as you're happy.
But I'm also trying new things.
Like what?
Sorry...
I'm interrogating you like a mom.
Never mind, go ahead.
It's been forever since someone
asked me questions like these.
Sorry, it's time for last order,
would you like anything else?
I'm full.
- The check, please.
- Sure, thank you.
Thanks.
Are you okay?
Just some gas,
I'll be fine after I take my pills.
Say, did you receive
my text message?
What message?
Never mind.
Is there any doubt?
I'm 100 percent sure that he wants
to win you back with that message.
He's been on probation for a year,
it's time to absolve him now.
Feelings change, but people don't.
What will you do, Eva?
Nothing,
I'll just take the world as it is.
- I want to see a happy ending!
- No way.
Adam should've known better,
am I right?
It's good to stay single,
live worry-free
and you can go anywhere you want.
You're just boring,
I'm going to ignore your opinion.
I have the longest CV
when it comes to relationships,
just trust me on this.
Oh, shut up already.
You think you're a judge?
Court...
- The trial is in session.
- A trial?
Are you kidding me?
Silence!
Your Honor,
I object to our Plaintiff
getting back with the Defendant.
In the words of Albert Einstein,
"A woman who repeats
the same mistake"
"will suffer the same fate,"
"no matter
how many times she tries."
When did Einstein say that?
Your Honor, I hold evidence
proving that the Plaintiff still
misses the Defendant.
Even your phone still misses Adam?
I wanna help my Best-friend-forever
to pick a wedding dress.
Objection, I don't want to wear
another bridesmaid dress!
Besides, I don't get
why people still get married.
Your Honor,
evidence shows that there are plenty
of great guys waiting for her.
For example,
my crazy rich boss, NT Tang.
Everyone, for the Plaintiff.
Money is not
the most important thing.
The most important thing is
that modern women have a choice,
it's no crime to be single!
Yet, a lot of women
search day and night,
only to still end up with scraps.
Let's hear some objective facts
from the Plaintiff.
We have to consider the
Plaintiff's best interest.
I see her in the office every day,
I'm the only one
who truly understands her.
- No, I understand her the most.
- I understand her so much more.
Silence!
Or I'll disbar all of you.
Eva Lui, what do you
have to say for yourself?
I want to tell the world
at this moment that you, Eva Lui,
taught me all about...
Love!
I, Eva Lui, want to tell the world
that the only person I love
is my mother.
Lin?
Is that Lin?
Po-wah!
Are you Po-wah?
I've been looking for you
for 40 years!
You haven't changed one bit.
- Your eyes are just getting old.
- No way.
I just had the cataract surgery
last year, and I am good now.
We've both grown so old.
I'm so happy.
If we hadn't come in
for maintenance at the same time,
we wouldn't have met again.
Just a coincidence, that's all.
To be honest, after losing touch
all those years ago,
I never found another girlfriend
as compatible as you.
- How have you been?
- I've been well.
I have a daughter,
she's all grown up now.
She's a lawyer.
Here.
I'll show you.
She's awfully pretty.
Like you.
This guy is the boyfriend
she's always arguing with.
Why did you pick him?
My mother made the call.
I went on a lot of arranged dates.
Out of all the guys I met,
he's the one
that looked the most like you.
Did he treat you as well as I did?
For better or worse,
we had a life together.
It went by in the blink of an eye.
He's passed away now.
I don't know
how long I'll last, either.
Don't say that.
Hong Kong women have the longest
life expectancy in the world,
which even longer than the men.
What are you in the hospital for?
I'll give you three choices.
I'll buy you an ice cream
cone if you get it right.
A, the three highs.
B, a stroke.
C, cancer.
Don't joke about that,
I can't handle the shock.
I'm easygoing
about my own mortality now,
I just miss my friends.
I worked as a tour guide
for 40 years.
I've been all over the world
and I've seen all kinds of things.
You're lucky,
I just convince myself
I've been to a place
after seeing it on a travel show.
You've led a fortunate life.
The only regret is
I couldn't marry my first love.
Look at how old we are,
no point talking about that.
How did you end up in here, then?
I fainted on the street,
the doctor says it's anaemia.
The tests are taking forever.
Do you have diabetes?
If you don't,
let's go get an ice cream gone.
The convenient store
in this hospital
has that Apollo brand
that we used to love,
how's that sound?
You're so nostalgic.
The old is new again, come on.
Where do you live now?
- Not far from here.
- Is that so?
- Hey, Adam.
- Sorry.
What's up?
Your ex-student is over there.
When I paid the tuition fee,
you guys said
that it can be refunded.
- No...
- So what should I do?
Should I report you
to the Consumer Council?
Company policies state that
a refund is only possible
under special circumstances.
According to our records,
you've never called
to make a leave of absence.
It's your trainer
that doesn't want to train me,
I didn't even have a chance
to take a leave of absence.
- Let me handle this.
- Sure.
Sorry,
there was a long line at the ATM.
Your refund, please count it.
I threw away the old one.
Clearing your debt?
How's your Eva?
We almost got back together,
but your contact lens
case ruined it.
I returned her notebook to you.
And that contact lens case?
Did you leave it behind on purpose?
I don't know.
Even if I did,
you should've known it wasn't Eva's.
Blame yourself for being dumb.
Without a backup phone like me,
how would you know how much
you missed your primary phone?
All your memories, social media,
everything important in your life
was in that primary phone,
after all.
You were even crying "Eva..."
when you were drunk.
Anyway, be careful
meeting people next time.
I really hate you,
but I really like you, too.
Still got my phone number?
I've deleted it already.
I'm heading back now.
It's okay, I still have your number.
"5th, 77 Heartwarmings"
I have good news.
I'm going to marry Mandy,
whom I've only known for 3 days.
Sorry, I'm still in love with her.
"Message from Anon"
"Anon"
"Loading"
"77 Heartwarmings"
Marvel, get some rest.
We'll head to the airport
in three hours, okay?
Sure, see you soon.
Dear Melody,
if you want a happy ending,
it depends where you want to
stop the story.
You can always start a new scene
and give it some happiness.
If you believe in it,
your dreams will come true.
Melody is your name,
let's play a joyful tune
in your heart.
From Marvel.
"Tom Yum Goong"
"I'll be in Hong Kong tomorrow"
"Let her know
what you're doing right now"
"I'm waiting for a job interview,
I'm a little nervous"
"I want to go to your place
to pick up some things,"
"is it okay?"
"You can come home anytime."
"NT Tang"
"I want to tell you"
"that what I'm doing right now"
Eva, what I'm doing now is called
Shitali Pranayama yoga,
it means cooling breath.
The key is in the breathing,
so the nostrils are
really important.
Come on, closer.
You must find this interesting, Eva.
I'll show you how to do it.
Press on the right nostril
with your left index finger
and breathe.
One, two, three.
Then press on the left nostril
with your right index finger.
Let go of your left hand,
then breathe.
One, two, three.
The last step is a little hard,
you have to
take your two index fingers
and press down
on both your nostrils,
then even curl up your tongue.
One, two, three.
Mom.
You're here.
What's with all the ice cream?
Sweets make me happy,
and I had a nice dream last night.
What happened?
I dreamt your wedding.
You know, you had a beautiful
wedding dress on.
Just when I was about
to reach out and touch it,
that nurse woke me up.
No, I can't do this.
Marvel, please don't be upset.
You read the script?
It's ridiculous.
The father dies, the mother dies,
the son dies, the daughter dies...
I die, everybody dies.
Exactly, we all die in the end.
Ginny, you better
talk to the studio again.
This is no use,
the studio won't change the script
nor will they change
the contract we signed.
It doesn't matter
where we are heading to,
there is only one map
to the journey of life
and it lives within our hearts.
"Stage 2"
"Move of the day"
"Have dinner with her"
Welcome home.
You're into gaming now?
And you're reading
psychology books too?
Don't have much else to do.
It's not like you to be this neat.
Why do you sit on the floor
instead of the sofa?
It's easier for work.
Like this.
- What's going on? Where?
- A cockroach!
Under the monitor.
The neighbor didn't put the lid on
the trash bin again!
Stay off my keyboard!
Off the keyboard!
- Go away...
- Not my book!
- Don't be scared.
- Help me!
Good thing you were here.
I was scared, too, but look at you.
You were freaked out,
so what else was I supposed to do?
Do you think it's really dead?
Wait, what are you doing?
It's a bookmark now!
Can I borrow your bathroom?
It's your home, too.
I'll give it an ocean burial.
Then I'll go steam the fish.
Did you see
how well he cleaned the place?
Of course he did,
because you're not around.
It means everything you did
were in vain.
There was a lot happening
in his family back then.
There was his dad's divorce,
then his mom got sick.
He was so upset,
how could I bother him?
And now, he's got nothing better
to do than to play games.
That's called passion.
People need to have hobbies,
you know.
That's not what you used to say.
Don't say I didn't warn you.
When a man wants you back,
it's natural that
he'll show you his best side.
Once you're hooked,
he returns to his old ways.
I don't get why
you're always so negative.
You didn't come back for your stuff,
but wanted to see if other girls
left anything in the bathroom again.
I don't have time to argue with you,
a steamed fish is best served hot.
Hey, what were you doing
on that bridge?
What?
Dinner's ready.
Let's give this a try.
Say, how did your interview go?
They said
that I gave the best answer.
What was the question?
Imagine.
There's a blizzard outside
while you're driving home,
and there are only
two seats in the car.
The blizzard's getting worse,
then you drive past a bus stop.
You know that the bus only comes
once every three hours,
and there are three people waiting.
The first person
is your best friend.
The second person
is a sick old lady.
And the third person
is your dream girl.
Remember,
your car only has two seats.
If you were the driver,
how would you choose?
Knowing you,
you'd drive your friend.
Nope.
Maybe the old lady?
You did drive my mother
to the hospital.
Not the dream girl, right?
You'd fail the interview
by answering that.
Then what did you say?
I...
Excuse me.
- Hello?
- Hey, want your phone back?
Of course, it's very important.
- Do you know any good lawyer?
- Yes.
I need your help,
please come to
Wan Chai police station.
Okay, I'm coming.
Sorry, I have to go.
- Is everything okay?
- I am sorry.
What's wrong? Do you need a ride?
No, I'll just get a taxi.
Thanks for the dinner.
Bye.
Be careful.
- You can go now.
- Okay.
- These are your belongings.
- Yes.
Sign here.
- Where's my...
- Thank you for bailing me out.
Where's my phone?
Oh, yes, sure.
I need to work tomorrow.
If I couldn't get out,
I'd be in big trouble.
You're already in a big trouble
in the first place,
that's why you couldn't get out.
Where's the lawyer?
Me.
Eva, please charge me.
May I have your business card?
Sure.
So should I bill Space-time Intruder
or Marvel?
You watch my movies?
Come on, your phone advertisements
are everywhere.
Will you keep my secret?
Which one?
You mean the real identity
of Space-time Intruder?
Or the arrest of
the Thai movie star, Marvel?
Listen, I can't let anyone know
about my secret.
It would be damaging to me,
my clients, my agent and my fans.
So you're asking me
to shut up about your mistakes?
I'm hiring you as my lawyer,
we can sign
a confidentality agreement about it
and you can charge me
double or triple.
Okay, I'll consider it.
Bye.
Hey, one more thing.
I think you should
go back with that Adam guy.
Wait, you checked my messages?
Adam's messages are sincere,
please don't ruin the happy ending.
You have no right
to intrude my privacy,
and please stop telling me
what to do with my life.
You know nothing about me,
nor anything about him.
It's none of your business,
I'm not even a fan of yours!
Cool, no one talks to me
like you do.
Adam, a student's waiting for you.
Again?
I already gave her back her money.
It's a new student,
he was here before we opened.
Thanks.
His name is Marvel,
he doesn't speak Chinese.
- Hi.
- So you're Adam?
Yeah, and you must be Marvel.
How do you know me?
We have a common friend
on social media,
so I want to get to know you.
Nice to meet you.
- Where are you from?
- Thailand.
- Do you know Muay Thai?
- Yeah, a little bit.
But I practice kickboxing more.
Let's try.
Sure.
I know him, he's a movie star!
No wonder he looks so familiar.
He doesn't look like
he's here to learn.
He's here to pick a fight.
Show me your kickboxing.
Show me your Muay Thai.
You're not looking for a teacher,
you're looking for a contender.
It's not easy
to find a contender like you.
Same here.
- See you next time.
- Sure.
You haven't changed one bit,
who is still eating too slow.
You haven't changed, either.
Still eating too fast,
and getting it all over your mouth.
Ice cream melts, doesn't it?
Every ice cream cone
is like a race against time.
And who won?
Well, you see?
In all my years
of traveling around the world
and meeting different people,
no one's ever beaten time.
That's why you should savor it,
make it worth your while.
Lin.
We'd agreed to elope back then,
why didn't you show up?
My family was against it.
We can't be selfish.
Since then, I'd miss you
whenever I eat an ice cream cone
and wherever I go.
There's an ice cream shop in Okinawa
that I'm dying to show you.
- Take me there when I'm better.
- Sure.
Why are you so late?
I was supposed to take my mom home,
but she got a headache.
So I stayed with her
while the doctor checked on her.
It's that bad?
I don't even know
if she really has anaemia,
she told the doctor
totally different things.
Anyway, she needs to do more tests
in the hospital.
Like Spider-Man says,
"With great power
comes great responsibility."
But I'm the opposite one.
With great responsibilities
come great power.
I'm not Spider-Man,
I'm just a normal human being.
There are three surprises
for you today.
Congratulations.
For what?
I've done some checking for you.
"Move of the day, send her flowers"
This is an app called
"77 Heartwarmings",
which is huge right now.
Let's see who sent them.
NT Tang.
Adam.
Anon? Who's that?
- Hello?
- Eva, call from the police station.
- Please put it on hold.
- Sure.
Get me the template
for the confidentiality agreement.
- Sure, give me the client's name.
- It's confidential.
You and your secrecy...
Cut!
This is
the confidentality agreement.
Let me explain, first...
You shouldn't sign anything
before you understand
the terms and conditions.
I trust my lawyer.
I appreciate that,
but reality is not like movies.
You're the only person
who knows both sides of me.
Anyway, they won't press
any charges for now.
So you're my lucky star.
But still,
the way you do art is illegal.
I won't bail you out next time.
"Understand".
It means "I understand".
Let me walk you out.
When I'm on set,
it feels like
I'm traveling through a time tunnel.
People only live once,
but you can live as many lives
as you want.
You have different roles, too.
A lawyer,
a daughter and a nice girlfriend.
Let me clarify.
I'm a lawyer, you're right.
I'm a good daughter, I guess.
But I don't have a boyfriend.
I guess you haven't gotten back
together with that Adam guy yet?
So he's the past,
welcome back to the market.
Chances of us being together
in this space and time,
this is destiny.
You want to
intrude space-time with me?
Are you asking your lawyer
to break the rules?
Life is about breaking rules
and knowing who you really are.
I'm going back tomorrow,
and I don't know
when I can see you again.
You can text me anytime.
This is not a good tool
for communication,
it's not the way
we should stay connected.
Then what?
The shadow of your smile,
the apple of my eye.
You're the sunshine of my life.
Perhaps you need to
break from reality.
Cat, please help me send
Barrister Tong's contract
to the Guangzhou office today.
Yeah.
Also, I won't be in
the office today.
Call me if anything comes up.
Okay, bye.
I have to go.
Bye.
Hey, I'll come back for you.
It seems like a dream,
we have to wake up somehow.
At least not now.
I don't want to get hurt again.
You won't, I promise.
You're here early.
You're early, too.
Don't you have work?
- What's wrong?
- Nothing.
Nothing? Tell me.
Mrs Lui.
We can't hide it from Eva anymore.
- What's wrong, mom?
- I'm fine.
- Tell me.
- It's nothing, really.
Adam.
We didn't tell you
because we didn't want you to worry,
but the doctor have just came by...
He confirmed that Mrs Lui has...
Brain cancer.
Can it be cured?
Whether it can be cured or not
and how, it doesn't matter now.
Everyone dies eventually, right?
You can't say that!
I'm your daughter,
how could you hide it from me?
You should've told me.
It breaks my heart when you cry,
so don't cry.
Alright.
- It's alright...
- How could you do that?
I'm fine, it'll be okay.
Don't be like this, it doesn't help
to be worried like this.
I just want my mom
to live a happy life,
but now she's running out of time.
I don't know what to do,
my mind's a total blank.
I'll go through this with you.
Take a leave of absence
from the firm,
so that you can spend some time
with your mom.
When my mom had cancer back then,
I met some brilliant doctors.
I'll contact them for you.
All these years,
your mom treated me like a son.
I'll do all I can for her.
Thank you.
Do you want me to go up with you?
By the way,
this is some stomach medicine.
Recommended by my doctor friend,
try it.
"Incoming call, Eva Lui"
- Hello?
- Hey, Eva, how's it going?
- Everything's okay.
- I just hope you're okay.
Marvel.
- Let's forget all these.
- Why?
I'm here for you.
I'm sorry, bye.
Eva?
"Incoming call, Ginny"
Marvel, good news.
The studio approved
the happy ending you proposed.
Oh, I see.
Thanks, Ginny.
Nurse!
Where's Lin?
Which Lin, sir?
The one who was at this bed before,
is she okay?
- I'm not sure.
- She came in for a dizzy spell.
Please, tell me where she's gone.
I'll help you find out.
I bought her an ice cream cone.
Please.
- I'll check for you.
- Is she okay?
"Saint Teresa's Hospital"
I told you to stop crying,
You're so pretty when you smile.
So smile for me, will you?
"Po-wah"
"27 missed calls from Po-wah"
Oh, the poor thing.
It can't get that off.
And it can't even walk now!
It's just too stupid
to be cute, right?
"Po-wah"
"I'm worried about you,
you won't answer..."
"Do you want to delete your
conversation with Po-wah?"
"Delete"
All my life,
I've only done
whatever people want me to do.
Can I finally
call the shots this time?
I don't want to keep
switching hospitals,
nor keep switching doctors anymore.
I'm in pain.
This is torture.
Eva.
- This is for you.
- Really?
This is beautiful.
It'll take forever
to fold all of these.
"He broke his leg,
he needs a cast..."
It's not that many,
just 3,000 of them.
- 3,000?
- We'll fold it together.
You can even write on them.
Let me see what you wrote.
"I felt a shock the first time
we held hands, as the legends say!"
"On our first trip,
he forgot his passport!"
"He got his driver's license
for the first time!"
Say, did you receive
my text message?
What message?
I don't know what I can do to
make you forgive me the 78th time,
but if you do give me
one more chance,
I won't let you down.
I have the same dream every night,
that my daughter
would have a romantic wedding.
Will you make
that dream come true for me?
Go ahead and have another dream.
- Come on, hurry up!
- You naughty girl!
- Alright, go have your dream.
- Hey!
- Are you okay?
- Can you give me a hand?
I'm coming in, then.
It's gorgeous.
Adam.
Did you know that one out of
five marriages end in divorce?
My parents are one of them.
I don't mean to force you,
I don't want you to do this
because my mom...
I want to do this.
After our breakup,
I thought that maybe
I had too many impractical fantasies
and expectations for you.
Maybe I read too many fairy tales
with princes and princesses,
maybe I should be more like
the people around me.
As well as lower my expectations,
so that I wouldn't be disappointed.
You don't have to do that.
If you feel uncomfortable
after the wedding,
you can choose all over again.
Fulfilling your mom's wish
is the most important thing now.
Okay, look at this way.
Look at each other now, good.
Another one.
One, two, three.
Too many red balloons!
One, two and swing!
Isn't it adorable?
- You two look great together!
- Look at this.
You're really great together!
The perfect match!
Honey, that's a beautiful dress!
Doesn't my daughter look pretty?
"Eva and Adam's Wedding"
"Marriage is between two people,"
"but a wedding involves
the whole world."
The bridal car's okay,
fast and furious!
"Flower shop is okay."
"Make-up is okay."
"The wedding venue is set."
Please give me a job, period.
Except for arranging seating.
"How's this backdrop?"
"Discount from my friend,"
"35 percent off."
I say again, period.
Don't force me to wear that
bridesmaid dress, exclamation mark.
"Love you all."
Excuse me.
I'm flying
out on working holiday tomorrow.
Come out for a drink
with me tonight, send me off.
I'm getting married in a few days.
Oh, to Eva?
Yeah.
You've got better taste
than her, then.
Anyway,
thanks for sending the link
of that "77 Heartwarmings".
I didn't do it, why would I do that?
It wasn't you?
Have a good marriage.
If you get divorced, call me.
Here you are.
- Your fan letters.
- Thanks.
It's so cute.
- Drink mine.
- Thank you.
Back here for filming?
I hope it's not for
another Space-time Intrusion.
I came back for you.
Marvel, my wedding
is in a couple of days.
So...
You decided to give the audience
a happy ending?
As you said,
life is about breaking the rules
to find who you really are.
Which means life and love
are conflicting.
Every movie has an ending.
But why does it end here?
The audiences.
The wedding's not only for me.
Your case is closed.
If I were you,
I would change the ending.
But I'm just a simple girl,
not a Space-time Intruder.
Thank you.
Mrs Lui, wait here.
You look beautiful today.
What are they doing?
Adam and I have a surprise for you.
That's your mother.
Look at this one,
she is so beautiful!
This is for you.
Thank you.
We've lost a lot of time.
Therefore, today,
in front of
your daughter and Adam...
I'd like to ask...
Will you marry me?
I do.
I've picked a dress for you, Mom.
Look.
This dress looks like
the wedding dress in my dream.
You'll look beautiful in it.
Thank you.
Thank you all for attending...
Wait, don't get married!
Stop the execution!
You again?
Don't mess things up here.
- You look familiar.
- Last time...
I'm not getting married,
so just sit down and be the VIP!
Eva's mother is getting married.
- Have a seat.
- Congratulations, Mother-in-law.
What mother-in-law?
Not true!
Let's start.
Thank you for attending
Mei-lin and Po-wah's wedding today.
This is Lin,
she doesn't have many hobbies.
Her only hobby
is taking care of her daughter,
but she's never asked her daughter
to take care of her.
Women in her generation
never asked for much.
As long as their families stay
together and stay happy,
they'll feel content.
All these years,
Lin's responsibilities
outweighed her own happiness.
Lin didn't ask for this,
but as your daughter
and your wedding's witness,
I hope that
for the rest of her days,
she'll find the happiness
that she deserves.
Tsang Po-wah.
Do you agree
to be Chau Mei-lin's husband
and make her happy?
I do.
Chau Mei-lin.
Do you agree
to be Tsang Po-wah's wife
and make him happy?
I do.
Please exchange wedding rings.
I hereby pronounce you
husband and wife.
Enjoy your life,
don't worry about me.
You have to enjoy your life, too.
My mom's in your hands now.
Sure, don't worry.
Be good to my daughter.
I will, don't worry!
- It is none of your business.
- Hey, boss...
- I'll sponsor your honeymoon!
- What is it?
I've never seen my mom
had a smile that sweet.
No matter how old a woman is,
there's a young girl living inside.
Stephen Hawking once said that
even he can't fathom woman.
Are we that hard to understand?
You sure are,
but I'll try my best to learn.
Let me show you something.
You still have this thing?
What "thing"?
This jar is called
"The Stars from you".
Who knows how long ago,
I put the jar away
and stopped folding the stars.
Since then, I stopped
remembering the good things.
It's true, people seem to
always remember the bad things.
You should keep it from now on then.
Take out a star once in a while,
then open it up
and remind me of the good things.
Sure.
Did you send this app to remind me?
Didn't you send this
to remind me to win you back?
"Anon"
Anon?
Who is it?
It's confidential.
I think you should
get back with that Adam guy.
You checked my messages?
"Type a message"
"77 Heartwarmings"
"Message from Anon"
What is the app telling you to do?
"Move of the Day"
"Invite her to do something
she has never done before"
Invite her to do something
she has never done before.
What haven't I done before?
You teach kickboxing here?
Yeah, come on in.
I keep forgetting to ask you.
For that blizzard question
at the interview,
what was the answer you gave?
My answer was...
Giving the car key
to my best friend,
so that he can drive the old lady
to the hospital.
Meanwhile,
I can stay at the bus stop
and wait for the bus
with the dream girl.
Love is an instinct,
but it takes some learning, too.
You're into gaming now?
And you're reading
psychology books too?
Faster...
One, two!
"Using a Code Editor"
"Backers by Adobe"
Let's start.
Here.
Come on.
Just go easy.
There's something in here.
Did the app tell you
to do this, too?
No, I told the app to do this.
"Move of the day"
"Eva, will you spend your life
together with me?"
Adam, we have every confidence
in your creativity and leadership.
This "77 Heartwarmings" app
that you created
has been greenlit by our company.
Whoever you want to hire for this,
we have your back.
Each of your answers has
its own set of reasoning behind it.
In my case,
there's someone very special
who changed my life.
She taught me
how to be more caring
and understanding.
She made me
a better version of myself.
"Confirm"
"Pending publication"
5, 4, 3, 2, 1!
The app's published!
Yes!
- Congratulations, Adam!
- Thank you, guys.
We've worked so hard on this!
This app is going to be a hit!
"Heartwarmings Exam Preparation"
I really want us
to be together again.
But that's not
the only reason I developed the app.
I want those people
who bury their heads in their phones
to look up
at the people beside them.
"77 Heartwarmings",
I developed it
to remind people how to...
Love.
Eva Lui.
This guy may have moved you
77 times,
but he hurt you
77 times before, too.
Is this the so-called
happy ending you want?
Can I have a little more time?
We've got plenty of time.
"Will you kiss me?"
"Will you hug me?"
"What if I never know the answers?"
"Will you need me?"
"Will you love me?"
"Have we the chance to be together?"
Eva, look.
"Cherish my heart"
"You're the sunshine
of my most gloomy life"
"The only bright light"
"Perish my soul"
"When you're away"
"When you're gone out,"
"out of sight"