Thank you.
Thank you so much. I'm so excited
to be here tonight.
My name is Richard Gage, AIA. I've been
a practicing architect for 20 years
and I'm a member of the American
Institute of Architects.
I became interested in the World Trade
Center high rise collapses on 9/11
after hearing the startling conclusions
of a reluctant 9/11 researcher,
David Ray Griffin, on San Francisco
Bay Area's KPFA radio, Guns and Butter
with Bonny Faulkner in March of 2006.
This has changed my life radically and
launched my own personal and professional
quest for 9/11 truth, inspiring me to
found Architects and Engineers
for 9/11 Truth,
which now numbers hundreds of architects
and engineers who are demanding
a real investigation into the
destruction of these buildings.
I'm employed with a San Francisco
Bay Area architecture firm,
which by the way has no affiliation
with my work in 9/11.
Like many other architects though I
designed numerous fire proofed
steel frame buildings in my career, including
these 3 and 10 million dollar gymnasiums
and the day to day construction
administration services for this
$120 million high school in
San Ramon in California.
I'm now working on a 400 million dollar
project in Nevada with almost 2 million
square feet of retail parking structure
and fire proofed steel framed mid rise
office space with over 1200 tons of
steel framing all together.
I'd like to start by thanking each and every
one of you for being willing to consider
the very difficult subject of the
destruction of the World Trade Center
and its staggering loss of life on 9/11.
Just as architecture and engineering
projects are sometimes joyful,
sometimes quite difficult, this particular
project has proven to be
extremely difficult.
Not difficult in terms of reaching
conclusions but difficult in terms of
the implications of those conclusions and
finding people who are open minded enough
to be willing to hear the facts about these
building collapses, check out every fact
that we point out.
Because it's extremely important that we
know the whole truth about this event.
After all, it served as the pretext for the
invasion of 2 countries in which already
over a million people have perished.
Also as the pretext for the loss of many of
our own cherished liberties here at home
in the United States through
recent legislation
such as the Patriot Act, the Military
Commissions Act and the forthcoming
Senate Bill 1959, the Violent Radicalization
and Home Grown Terrorism Act
in which many of us can be named
a terrorist and have no right
to an attorney or trial by jury.
Another 9/11 could happen again if we
don't dedicate ourselves to finding out
exactly what happened and why, and to
bringing those actually responsible
to justice.
What do I mean it could happen again?
Well, basically we're promised another 9/11
by members of the Congress, the media
and the Bush administration
with official statements such as this;
"The next attack will make
September 11th pale by comparison",
"a nuclear weapon in the middle
of one of our own cities",
"a nuclear terrorist attack on
the U.S. could be imminent",
"weapon of mass destruction
- this summer or early fall",
"it'll be much bigger than 9/11",
and Michael Chertoff, "a gut feeling
that attacks were imminent",
last summer without any evidence
or facts suggesting that.
These are among the many reasons that
we must peer into this painful part
of our recent history, to reexamine the
relatively new physical evidence from 9/11
which we have not seen in the main stream
media, and to find out why for instance
a 2006 poll by the New York Times and CBS
reveals that 28% of Americans believe
that the Bush administration is lying,
and not just about Iraq,
but about the events of 9/11.
And Time Magazine reporting that 36%
of Americans consider it likely
or somewhat likely that government officials
either allowed the attacks to be carried out
or carried them out themselves.
And an even more recent poll from Zogby
in 2007 finding 51% of Americans
want Congress to probe the president
and the vice president about 9/11.
Of even greater concern, another poll that
year by Scripps Howard Ohio University
which found that a shocking 16%
of Americans  believe
that the World Trade Center Twin Towers
were brought down by explosives.
NIST, the National Institute of Standards and
Technology, claims they found no evidence
for explosive demolition at
the Twin Towers.
Later they admit that they've
never looked for it.
How can you find what
you're not looking for?
Well, architects, engineers, scientists
and many others looked for it
and it was not hard to find. We've been
speaking about it for 2 years now,
in over 3 dozen cities in a
dozen states and in Canada.
We're proud to be part of the
international 9/11 Truth Movement,
which is growing by millions
every year.
We now have hundreds of architects
and engineers for 9/11 Truth
demanding a real investigation.
This is our website.
You can find on the right side the bullet
points of information that we're going to be
going through today,
it's AE911Truth.org.
On the left side you'll see the Power Point,
you can step through it at your own pace
because you may not have time to follow
and  read all the text and absorb
the information that we're rapidly
going to be going through.
You can also watch the DVD on the left side
and you can purchase the DVD online.
You can sign the petition after you find
yourself convinced that this evidence
is something worth looking at.
Let's get something clear from the start.
The ever growing number of architects
and engineers for 9/11 Truth
are not
conspiracy theorists.
We're building and technical professionals
looking at the science based
forensic  evidence in the destruction
of these high rises on 9/11.
As Joel Hirschhorn, PhD says:
"First, let the technical truths emerge.
Then, if necessary, cope with the inevitable
conspiracy and other questions".
Tonight we're presenting to you the
technical truths, the evidence found
for  the explosive demolition of all 3 World
Trade Center high rise collapses on 9/11,
the iconic Twin Towers and
the mysterious Building 7.
9/11. Just the utterance of it brings us
right back to the terror filled morning.
We were subjected to
these shocking attacks,
killing thousands of Americans,
destroying cultural icons.
These 6 years have given us time to
step back and examine these events
more objectively.
To step back from the shock
induced trance really, to evaluate
the relatively new evidence that has only
come out in the last couple of years,
and to reexamine these 3 high rise
collapses more objectively.
Let's begin with an overview of the events
of that morning in order to start us off
on the same page, looking at
the jets and the impacts
and how this myth developed.
On September  11th we learned that
4 passenger planes were hijacked
and taken radically off course.
Within an hour 2 of the planes were thrown
into the enormous steel towers
at the World Trade Center, creating fires
and eventually toppling them.
Dazed by the news the American public
soon believed that the fires in the towers
had burned so hot that they caused the
steel  frames of the buildings to give way.
A myth developed fed by official sources
trough the media to a bewildered audience.
Elements of the myth; the impact of
the airplanes, gallons of burning jet fuel,
steel melting, the buildings failing
and suddenly imploding.
In a mere 10 seconds 110 stories hurdled
earthwards, pulverizing into dust.
Right from the start on the street
itself the official story was born.
come out of nowhere and just reamed
right into the side of the Twin Tower,
exploding through the other side,
and then I witnessed both towers collapse,
one first and then the second,
mostly due to structural failure because
the fire was just too intense
We need to look for these kinds of people
and these kinds of events that are
the first ones interviewed by the main
stream media, planting the official story
in the minds of people.
The myth bled into the FEMA report
and was echoed by the experts.
It was the combination of the impact load
doing great damage to the building,
followed by the fire,
that caused collapse.
Well, let's take a look at that.
What we do is to apply the scientific
method which many of us learned
in 7th and 8th grade.
It's the best way yet discovered for
winnowing truth from lies and delusion.
The simple version looks
something like this.
We formulate a question;
how did the Twin Towers collapse?
We perform research,
we make observations.
We construct a hypothesis;
we have an idea how it collapsed.
It collapsed by fire. It collapsed by
explosive controlled demolition.
We make some predictions and we test
those predictions and those assumptions
with experiments, objective, verifiable,
repeatable experiments.
We analyze the results and
we draw conclusions.
And if those conclusions are found to be
corroborated by the evidence we report it
in an open, transparent manner, where
our experiments and our findings
can be repeated.
If it is not found to be corroborated
we think and try again and construct
a new hypothesis with new
observations, new research.
Buildings are destroyed by a number of
different forces, each of which have
very different and
identifiable characteristics.
For instance, fires affect buildings quite
differently than controlled demolition.
Fires, by their nature, tend to creep from
place to place as they run out of fuel,
moving to fresh, new fuel sources,
leaving the burned down area to cool.
So when collapses do occur, and by the way
you'll note that they've never occurred
in over a hundred examples of very hot,
very large and very long lasting fires.
Buildings tend to fall over,
they fall asymmetrically,
they're burned out on
one side organically if you will.
It's a natural process.
They don't fall straight down
through the path of greatest resistance.
Let's listen to Jonathan Barnett
from FEMA talk about what fires
are expected to do in steel buildings.
The way in which steel framed
buildings behave in fires
depends on their construction.
In this test, done by British Steel in 1995
a large amount of typical office furniture
was burned to see what would happen
to the heavy steel beams
that supported the ceiling.
When steel is bare, when it heats up it
gets weaker. It's not that it melts in a fire.
In fact, normal fires aren't
hot enough to melt steel.
Even if you were for example to
use an unusual fuel like kerosene
you cannot achieve temperatures
hot enough to melt steel.
But what happens is that it
starts to lose its strength.
And as it's loses its strength
it starts to sag,
it becomes softer and sags and
can no longer support load.
This was the largest test of
its kind ever conducted.
It showed how unprotected steel can be
distorted, even by a normal office fire.
But as is typical in steel buildings
the structural beams only slowly
and progressively warped and sagged.
There was no chance of a sudden collapse.
In over 20 years I have not seen until
recently a protected steel structure
that has collapsed in a fire.
So what was the cause of the
devastating, explosive failure that
happened to the World Trade Center?
These particular buildings collapsed.
They follow the path of least resistance
Or they fell over.
You can see that the building
structure holds the building together
in some recognizable form.
The structural elements have not been
dismembered from each other
and their concrete has not
been pulverized into dust.
They follow the path of least
resistance, which is generally over.
These buildings exploded.
Witnesses hear sounds of explosions,
they see flashes of light.
There's thick, billowing and enormous
pyroclastic clouds of pulverized concrete.
The expansion of the gasses very quickly
produces this cauliflower-like formation
that we see in the smoke.
This is a controlled demolition. Let's
focus on this type of destruction first.
We have hundreds of examples from
all across the country from which to make
our comparison because it's the most
commonly used method to demolish
high rises.
This is what a high rise looks like when
it's being demolished with explosives.
Controlled demolitions can be
engineered in many different ways.
Normally the purpose of a controlled
demolition is to remove a structure while
avoiding damage to adjacent
structures and to do so economically.
Typically a tall building like this is
demolished by placing thousands of
cutter charges throughout the columns
and beams in the building and then
detonating them in a very precise order,
starting with the interior structures
and then progressing outward,
synchronistically timed, floor by floor.
Destroying the interior columns
allows the unsupported weight
to pull the exterior inward.
Destroying the building from the ground
up allows the weight of the building
to be harnessed to do much
of the destruction.
So the result is an implosion producing
a vertical, symmetrical collapse
at free fall speed into a consolidated
rubble pile that's broken up
and ready for loading and shipment.
Now this is a feat that only a handful of
companies in the United States
can accomplish.
Let's look at some of the key
characteristics of controlled demolition.
First we have a sudden onset of
destruction at the base of the structure.
We have straight down, symmetrical
collapse into its own footprint
because demolition waves
remove the column support
resulting in a free fall speed,
virtually, through the path
of what was the greatest resistance,
thousands of tons of structural steel.
We have a total dismemberment of
the steel structure, so it's loaded
and ready for shipment.
We have minimal damage to adjacent
structures, sounds and flashes
of explosions, heard and seen by witnesses,
enormous clouds of pulverized concrete.
Squibs sometimes, explosive charges
that go off at the wrong time.
Chemical evidence of cutter charges.
These are all fairly typical and they
go to show us direct evidence
of explosive destruction.
Now, the interesting thing is that
not one of these typical characteristics
of controlled demolition can be
explained or accounted for by fire,
let alone all ten of them.
Typically we have government
documentation, expert corroboration,
foreknowledge and video documentation
all of which supports
the hypothesis of controlled demolition.
Providing proof beyond a reasonable doubt.
Let's take a look at World
Trade Center 7 now.
It was 47 stories tall, what would've been
the tallest building in 33 of our states.
Half the height of the Twin Towers,
dwarfed only by its proximity to what was,
for a couple of years the
tallest buildings in the world.
It was not hit by an airplane.
It was the 3rd World Trade Center
high rise to collapse on 9/11
at about 5.20 in the afternoon.
World Trade Center 7 was hit
by debris from the North Tower,
you can see it being pelted here,
and it sustained about 8 fires,
according to NIST, on various floors.
This is the World Trade Center 7,
47 stories high, don't be confused
by the shadow from this building.
Here we have the 13th and 14th floor fires
and the 7th floor fire on the North side
of the building, the opposite side of the
building that was pelted by the North Tower.
Curiously enough, the Securities and
Exchange Commission was operating
out of this floor which lost thousands
of files related to hundreds of cases
it was actively pursuing against Wall Street
companies like Enron and Worldcom.
So we are looking for an investigation that
goes well beyond the buildings, of course.
Now let's take a look at the evidence
of World Trade Center 7 and see
how it stacks up against the typical
features of a controlled demolition,
starting with is there
a sudden offset of destruction?
Let's listen to this emergency worker.
We were watching the building (WTC7)
actually cuz it was on fire
The bottom floors of the
building were on fire and
we heard this sound that
sounded like a clap of thunder
turned around- we were shocked
to see that the building was ah,
well, it looked like there was a shockwave
ripping through the building
and the windows all busted out
it was horrifying
About a second later the bottom floor caved
out and the building followed after that
we saw the building crash down
all the way to the ground
we were in shock
A sound of a clap of thunder?
A shock wave ripping through the building?
And windows busting out?
And then the building coming down.
Do we have a straight down, symmetrical
collapse into the building's footprint?
Let's listen to Dan Rather narrate this
collapse for us as we take our first look
at the collapse of Building 7.
What you're seeing are high shots.
Now here were going to show you
a video tape of the collapse itself.
Now we go to video tape of
the collapse of this building.
It's amazing
Amazing, incredible, pick your word.
For the third time today
It's reminiscent of those pictures we've
all seen too much on television before
when a building was deliberately destroyed
by well placed dynamite to knock it down.
What, Dan? Deliberately destroyed by
well placed dynamite to knock it down?
Dan never repeated these
words after this first day.
In fact, we didn't see this building
coming down after 9/11.
Let's take a look from West Street.
Maybe we haven't quite
understood yet what's going on.
Well, I'm not quite convinced yet, let's
take a look in this side by side comparison
with a known controlled demolition
on the right.
Did the building fall into
its own footprint?
Petty much so, a little bit of
overlapping into the street,
I could've done a much better job myself.
A tidy rubble pile nevertheless.
Do we have demolition waves and how
do these remove the column support?
Well, here's a floor plan of Building 7.
Now, to bring a building smoothly,
symmetrically into its own footprint
without falling over, what we have
to do  is remove the core columns
because what we want to do is to bring
the  outside of the building in on itself.
This involves a high degree of
precision that fire is not capable of,
being an organic process.
We're told by NIST in a December 18th
update meeting that we attended via telecon,
that there's virtually no influence
in the collapse from the debris
from the North Tower or the damage
caused by it, or from the diesel
that may have been
spilling out of the diesel line.
Why? Well, the East penthouse is the
first part of the building to collapse
a few seconds before
the global collapse.
And so NIST is now targeting column nr. 79.
And so that's where they
say the collapse initiated.
Do we have a free fall speed of collapse
through the path of greatest resistance?
Let's listen to David Chandler.
We can measure the downward acceleration
of Building 7 by video frame analysis.
I used a magnifying glass to place markers
on the corner of the building on each frame.
From this we can get a
data table and various graphs.
The slope of this graph indicates
acceleration which is shown here to be
about minus 10.279, plus or minus 0.6.
Free fall in a vacuum is
minus 9.8 in these units.
That falls within the margin
of error of this measurement.
In other words, the rate of fall of
Building 7 in the first few seconds
is indistinguishable from
free fall in a vacuum.
What are we talking about?
You can see, second by second, the building
gaining downward momentum.
You can plot the drop distance on the graph
of time and it fits the free fall curve
almost perfectly.
What does this mean?
That the columns had to
have been removed, and removed
vitually simultaneously, on each floor,
synchronistically timed,
so the building had no resistance,
virtually, on the way down.
Do we have a total dismemberment
of the structure?
We had a 47 storey skyscraper, compressed
to 4 stories. How does this happen?
This building had some moment
resisting frames on several floors.
That's where the beams are welded
very rigidly to the columns.
Do we have sounds of explosions?
Here's Craig  Bartmer from the
New York Police Department.
And the whole time you're hearing
thoom thoom thoom thoom.
So, eh I think I know an
explosion when I hear it.
I was real close to Building 7
when it fell down.
That didn't sound like just
a building falling down to me
while I was running away from it.
There's a lot of eye witness testimony
down there hearing explosions.
I didn't see any reason for that
building to fall down the way it did.
And a lot of guys should be
saying the same thing.
How about Kevin McPadden,
former Air Force Special Operations
Search and Rescue?
He came back over with his hand over the
radio and what sounded like a countdown.
And at the last few seconds he took
his hand of and you heard 3.2.1.,
and he was just saying
"just run for your life",
and then it was like another 2 or 3
seconds, you heard explosions
like BABOOOOMMMM,
like a distinct sound.
It's not like when with compression,
like booom booom booom,
like floors that were
dropping and collapsing.
This was like BABOOOOM,
like you felt a rumble in the ground,
like almost like you wanted
to grab on to something.
That, to me, I know that was an explosion.
There was no doubt in my mind.
OK, thank you, Kevin.
Do we have enormous clouds of pyroclastic
smoke from the pulverized concrete?
Watch the concrete entrained in the air
racing down every street in each direction
at 35 miles an hour, this incredible volume
of pyroclastic dust and folding itself.
It takes incredible quantities of heat
to create this kind of action.
A lot more heat than these 8 various
fires that were on these floors.
Do we have pools of molten iron?
Let's start with the South Tower now.
This section applies to the World Trade
Center Twin Towers and Building 7.
We're told by NIST that this substance
must be melted aluminum from the airplane.
But melted aluminum looks
like melted aluminum, it's silvery.
It doesn't glow in day like conditions.
"As of 21 days after the attack,
the fires were still burning
and molten steel was still running", says
World Trade Center structural engineer
Leslie Robertson to a conference of
structural engineers on October 5th 2001,
one month after 9/11.
"Fires burned and molten metal
flowed in the pile of ruins
still settling beneath my feet",
says Sarah Atlas.
What do the first responders and demolition
contractors say about molten metal?
"Saw pools of literally molten steel."
"Molten metal, beams had
just totally been melted."
"It was dripping from the molten steel."
"Steel flowed in molten streams."
"They're finding molten steel."
"Seeing the molten steel."
"Uncovering red hot metal beams."
"Molten metal, red hot
weeks after the event."
"Molten steel at the heart
of the tower's remains."
"Molten steel beams."
"The streams of molten metal
that leaked from the hot cores
and flowed down the broken walls."
"Molten metal dripping from a beam."
"The end of the beam would
be dripping with molten steel."
And this structural engineer,
Abolhassan Astaneh-Asi from Berkeley
cites and documents:
"I saw melting of girders in
the World Trade Center."
"Still so hot that molten metal dripped
down the sides of the wall
from Building 6."
"Debris past the columns was
red hot, molten, running."
"A fire truck 10 feet below the ground
that was still burning 2 weeks
after the Tower collapsed, its metal
so hot that it looked like
a vat of molten steel."
"Pieces of steel, still cherry red."
One of the more unusual artifacts to emerge
from the rubble is this rocklike object
that has come to be known
as the Meteorite.
This is fused element of steel, molten steel
and concrete and all of these things,
all of them fused by the heat.
And architects and engineers,
people who work with steel, welders,
have just never seen the level of
destruction and the level of deformation
of this material in our lives.
These cooled meteorites are not
aluminum because aluminum doesn't rust.
It's not a melted airplane.
What does the gentleman in charge of the
clean up at World Trade Center Ground Zero
have to say about molten metal?
Mark Loizeaux, the president
of Controlled Demolition inc.,
told the American Free Press that in
the basements of the World Trade Center,
where 47 central support columns
connected to the bedrock, hot spots
of literally molten steel were discovered
more than a month after September 11th.
These incredibly hot areas were found at
the bottoms of the elevator shafts,
down 7 basement levels.
The molten steel was found 3,
4 and 5 weeks later,
when the rubble was being removed.
He said that molten steel
was also found at WTC7.
The highest temperature was at
the East corner of the South Tower
where a temperature of 1377
degrees  Fahrenheit was recorded.
The molten steel in the basement was
more than double that temperature.
What are we talking about here?
Here is Building 7, at A and B,
and here is the North Tower
and the South Tower.
These hot spots are
1340 to 1370 degrees.
These are the temperatures
of the hottest office fires.
There was no fire on the surface
of Ground Zero after the collapses.
What are we measuring here?
We're measuring the molten metal
that was seen by these first responders
4, 5, 6 stories down below in the
basements that were surely at least
twice or 3 times these temperatures.
What's the problem with that?
Office fires, Eager says, 1200 degrees.
NIST claims 1800 degrees, for which
we have no evidence for office fires
of that temperature
in the Trade Center Towers.
But for something salmon or lemon
colored it's 15-18 hundred degrees.
And structural steel doesn't even begin
to melt until 2700 or so degrees...
We're missing 1000 to 2000 degrees
of temperature, heat energy required
to produce this stuff.
Where is it coming from? We'll be
taking a look at a possible suspect,
thermite, which reaches
temperatures of 4500 degrees.
Molten metal flowing off this substance
held in the jaws of this backhoe.
Now, let's listen to John Gross,
lead engineer of NIST,
tell us about the molten
metal from his perspective.
I'm curious about the pool of molten steel
that was found in the bottom of the Towers.
I am too, please tell me about it,
have you seen it?
Well, not personally, but eye witnesses
there found huge pools of molten steel
beneath the Towers and some scientists
don't think that the collapse
of the building could have
melted all that steel.
A physics professor analyzed
some of this steel, Steven Jones,
and he found evidence of thermate residue,
which would explain how the buildings
collapsed by means of
pre planted explosives.
So, have you analyzed the
steel for these residues?
Eh, first of all let's get back to your basic
premise that there was a pool
of molten steel.
I know absolutely nobody,
no eye witnesses said so,
nobody who's produced it.
You'd get down below and you'd
see molten steel, molten steel
running down the channel rails,
like you're in a foundry.
Like lave from a volcano.
Out on the rubble I believe
it's still 11oo degrees.
The guy's boots just melt
within a few hours."
This is how it's been since day one.
It's unbelievable,
this is 6 weeks later,
and as we get closer to the center
it gets hotter and hotter.
It's probably 1500 degrees.
We've had some small windows into what
we thought was the core at some point
and it looks like an oven,
it was just roaring inside.
Just a bright, bright reddish, orange color.
Underground it was still so hot that molten
metal dripped down the sides of the wall
from Building 6.
I know absolutely nobody, no eye witnesses
said so, nobody who's produced it.
What is the problem here?
We have plenty of eye
witnesses that have produced it.
Somebody is lying. I'm going to leave it up
to you to make your own conclusions.
"The last fire was not even extinguished  for
3 months after 9/11." Tom Manley says:
"You couldn't even begin to imagine
how much water was pumped in there.
It was like you were
creating a giant lake."
Well, thermite contains its own source of
oxygen, it burns just as well under water.
How about chemical evidence though?
What produced all this molten metal?
And what is thermite anyway?
Thermite. An incendiary used
by the military, thermite is a
compound of iron dioxide and
aluminum which, when ignited,
sustains an extreme heat reaction,
creating molten iron.
In just 2 seconds thermite can reach
temperatures over 4500 degrees Fahrenheit,
quite enough to liquefy steel.
We know that open air fires cannot
burn hot enough to melt steel,
but metal had melted at
the base of the towers.
Appendix C of the FEMA report
describes sulphur residues
on the World Trade Center steel.
The New York Times called this
the deepest mystery of all.
Sulphur slightly lowers the melting point
of iron, and iron oxide and iron sulphite
had formed on the surface
of the structural steel.
Sulphur used with thermite is called
thermate, producing even faster results.
NFPA 921 is the guide for fire and
explosion investigations. Was it used?
They say: "Unusual residues could
arise from thermite, magnesium
or other pyrotechnic materials."
At a crime scene, where this was an
example of, did NIST used this guide? No,
They acknowledged they didn't even
look for such evidence. But others did.
Dr. Steven Jones performed chemical
analysis on the previously molten metal.
He did some background research,
again, part of the scientific method.
Thermite would create a characteristic
burn pattern with a white ash,
a white yellow hot liquid metal and
intense white reaction zone seen.
It would also leave behind
chemical evidence.
Common elements such as iron,
aluminum, copper, calcium, silicon.
Unusual elements such as fluorine and
manganese left behind also in the residue.
These elements here.
He's sent a sample of this 40 pound
chunk of previously molten metal
from one of those 'meteorites'.
He finds that it's predominantly iron so we
can rule out aluminum from the jet plane.
It has small amounts of
aluminum, sulphur and potassium.
And manganese and
fluorine in abundance.
The manganese is from the potassium
permanganate, commonly used
as an oxidizer in thermite.
Fluorine is also used in sol-gel
type thermite charges.
So these appear to be
the thermite fingerprint.
Let's take a look at what else dr. Jones
found in the slag from this memorial
at Clarkston University.
He performs his x-ray fluorescence
on this small piece of slag and finds,
once again, iron, sulphur,
potassium, manganese, calcium.
Gel explosives are a super thermite,
tiny aluminum particles in iron oxide,
in this sol-gel, they can be
cast into shape, like clay.
Lawrence Livermore Labs did research
on this and this invention offers
"a thermite based apparatus
for cutting target materials."
You pack the thermite in here and you ignite
it and it comes out and it's forced through,
melting the structural steel
element in fractions of a second.
Almost as effective as high
energy explosives, RDX and C4
which are more common in
classic controlled demolitions.
If sol-gels were used they would
leave behind a very unique signature,
1,3-diphenylpropane.
And in fact EPA finds one molecule
in their toxilogical studies
at levels that dwarfed all others,
1,3-diphenylpropane.
Erik Swartz says "we've never observed it
in any other sampling we've ever done."
But is there evidence of
thermite in the WTC dust?
Dr. Jones received no less than
4 separate samples of WTC dust,
some of it from an apartment across
the street, Janet McKinley's apartment,
where the windows blew in and filled
her apartment with a foot of this dust.
Another sample was found like 10
minutes later on the Brooklyn Bridge.
Well, he takes it and put a magnet over it
and he finds that there are small particles
that come up to the magnet. Some of
them are angular, some of them are round.
They look like this.
In fact, he calculates by the weight of
the amount of these spheres that he finds
in the dust that there must have been
about 10 tons for all of the dust
that was available.
They're about a 16th of an inch in diameter,
the largest ones, and most of them though
are smaller than a human hair. What
could produce such an incredible array
of microspheres?
Well, if you had thousands of cutter
charges going off in the columns and beams
throughout the building and they're
under this incredible pressure,
what you would see
is something like this.
Tens of thousands or
millions of tiny droplets.
What's the shape of those droplets?
When a liquid is dispersed like this its
surface tension forms itself into almost
a perfect sphere.
In the case of molten iron
those droplets cool and they fall,
along with the dust, everywhere.
He compares the spheres to
a known thermite experiment,
performed by John Parulis in Nevada,
which finds the same spheres.
In fact, we do another X-EDS
and we find in the microspheres
the same kinds of evidence.
We have iron, manganese, and, in the
case of this known thermite signature,
it matches basically.
In other words, we have a controlled
experiment to compare the results against.
And for those who know how to read
these graphs such as dr. Jones and others,
this is pretty much an exact
match indicating that this is
the signature of thermite.
Dr. Jones is not the only one who
finds these iron rich microspheres.
The EPA finds them in all the dust and
the toxilogical studies that they're doing.
They have no idea
where they came from,
they don't report the results other
than just a tiny bit, they're curious.
They sweep it under the rug. It has
only one possible formation and that is
from liquid molten iron
under extreme pressure.
RJ Lee finds the iron rich microspheres
on top of the Deutsche Bank building
in their toxilogical studies.
Is this what corroded the tops of these
cars, this atomized thermite cooling?
Manganese was also found in
large proportions, very toxic stuff,
from the city's Chief Medical Examiner,
very very concerned about it.
Dr. Jones concludes that given the mix
of trace metals present in these
high concentrations in the dust
such as zinc, copper and manganese
and the formation of
iron rich aluminum spheres
it's clear that significant aluminothermic
reactions occur and he can
reverse engineer this and suggests
to us that there must have been
in the thermite mix powders of
aluminum, iron oxide, copper oxide,
zinc nitrate and
potassium permanganate.
Well, would there possibly be any
unignited thermite pieces in the WTC dust?
Indeed he finds it.
It also comes up to his magnet
from the dust samples.
Many chips.
This one is a 16th of an inch long,
red on one side, grey on the other.
The red side is composed of tiny
iron oxide particles and aluminum.
In fact, he does an X-EDS
on this stuff too.
And he finds a little bit of sulphur, more
aluminum, lots of iron and manganese.
Compare that to the traditional thermite,
it's also a match for unignited thermite.
This stuff is not made
in a cave in Afghanistan.
The Lawrence Livermore Lab came out with
papers only a year or 2 ago about this stuff.
The particles, being so small, allow for
almost instantaneous ignition between
the 2 chemicals, the aluminum and the iron
oxide, producing very explosive results.
Los Alamos Lab and Lawrence Livermore
Lab have produced these results.
Then he continues his study and finds
additional chips that are partially ignited,
with spheres embedded in them,
indicating that the source of the spheres is,
for all intents and purposes,
identified very clearly here.
Partially reacted thermite.
These results are documented
in a peer reviewed journal,
in the Open Civil Engineering
Journal, volume 2.
'14 Points of agreement', he calls it,
'with official government reports on the
World Trade Center destruction', because
it turns out that there is much in common
between the NIST report, the FEMA
report and the work that we are doing.
And of course there's a lot of disagreement
as well. But dr. Jones is an optimist.
So we're going to look
for the points of agreement.
He has also documented this in
'Applying the Scientific Method',
which is on our website www.AETruth.org,
also on
www.JournalOf911Studies.com.
With dr. Jones and his small team of
scientists, through EDS, XRF and WDS,
identifies the components of these spheres
and chips predominantly iron, along with
aluminum, oxygen and silicon,
1,3-diphenylpropane,
the results coupled with the visual
evidence, he says, at the scene such as
the flowing hot liquid metal
providing compelling evidence
that thermite reaction compounds
were deliberately placed
in both WTC towers and Building 7.
Verify the results please.
This must be repeatable,
there's lots of dust out there.
We encourage anyone who has any
samples of this dust to email us at
WTCdust@AE911Truth.org so that we
can get repeatable samplings done.
We need a lot of this.
Now all of this is direct evidence of
explosive destruction in Building 7.
We're going to jump back
to only Building 7 now.
None of these characteristics can be
explained by fire, let alone all of them.
Why? Well, buildings are
protected from fire.
High rise steel frame buildings in particular
have 2 and 3 hour fire protection,
designed to allow the
occupants to escape a fire.
But even after, in fires that are
much longer than 2 hours, larger,
these buildings have not collapsed.
Why? Let's take a look.
Here's New York, 1970.
Burned 6 hours over 5 floors.
Los Angeles, 3,5 hours
over 5 floors.
Philadelphia, 18 hours over 8 floors.
Caracas, Venezuela, burned
17 hours over 26 floors.
Not one of these fires brought
these high rises down.
In fact, no high rise steel framed building
has ever been brought down by any fire.
Yet relatively small, randomly placed fires
and a whole lot of smoke is to have brought
this skyscraper, Building 7,
down in 6,5 seconds
after burning in just that afternoon.
How about this FEMA report
and these investigations?
Well, we have 4 investigations,
starting in 2001 with the ASCE,
the American Society of Civil Engineers.
We're told that these are volunteers but
these are not your average PTA volunteers.
These guys earn 10 million dollars annually
average between them working for
the Defense Department with their expertise,
mainly on blast resistance of buildings.
Then we have the FEMA report in 2002
which finally got some funding,
600.000 dollars.
Compare that to the 40 million dollar
effort to find the source of those stains
on Monica Lewinsky's dress.
This is easily the 3rd worst
structural failure in modern history.
It deserves a far greater
response and resources.
In 2002 we had the Silverstein/Weidlinger
report, responsible for reversing
the theory of FEMA, which came up
basically with the 'pancake theory'
or the 'zipper theory' where one truss
pulled away from the columns
and then caused the others to pull away
and that chain reaction went around
and then the floors
'pancaked' all the way down.
We'll talk about that.
Silverstein/Weidlinger report was
responsible for changing that theory
because if that were true it would've
been the bolts that broke and therefore
Larry Silverstein, the overall owner of
this complex would not have been paid
his 5,6 billion dollars that he's been
paid on the insurance settlement.
Why? Because that would've
been the building's fault
instead of the terrorists' fault.
So we had to have another theory.
And the new theory states that the
trusses sagged, pulled in the columns,
they blame the persistence of that
connection, and then the columns buckled
and then the whole
thing came down.
Either way, it's something that we're
going to be looking at very critically here
in a moment.
Then we have the NIST investigation which
took over all of these investigations in 2005
and came up with a 3 year,
20 million dollar effort.
We'll take a close look
at NIST's work.
These experts, who worked on these
buildings, all worked from the FEMA report,
or most of them, into the Weidlinger
report and into the NIST report.
These are not independent investigations
by any means whatsoever.
Let's listen to what FEMA did
conclude because it's interesting.
"Evidence of a severe high temperature
corrosion attack on the steel, including rapid
oxidation and sulfidation with
subsequent intergranular melting."
Very interesting.
Remember, office fires don't melt steel.
What melted the steel?
Sulphur formed during this hot
corrosion attack on the steel.
Here is the intergranular
melting documented for all of us.
Thank you.
Capable of turning a solid steel girder
into Swiss cheese, like this former column,
wide flange column from the
structural steel in Building 7.
Now they document this very carefully
in their appendix C. Listen to this.
"Gaping holes, some larger than a
silver dollar, let light shine through.
A one inch column being reduced
to half inch thickness, its edges curled
like a paper scroll, having been
thinned to almost razor sharpness."
This was the flange, curled up on itself.
This is the web of that wide flange column.
NIST swept this entire appendix C
under the rug and we do not have it
in the official report today.
Listen to this though.
"The collapse of WTC7 had a small debris
field as the façade was pulled downward,
suggesting internal
failure and implosion.
The specifics of the fires in WTC 7 and how
they caused the building to collapse remain
unknown at this time "
What? Unknown?
"the best hypothesis (fire + random
damage-then complete collapse)
has only a low
probability of occurrence"
Wait a minute You spent 600.000
dollars of our tax payer money and
over a year investigating this and
your best hypothesis isn't even right?
What do you do when your hypothesis
is not corroborated by the facts?
You go back and construct a new
hypothesis. In FEMA's case, punt.
And that's what they did.
They say "further research,
investigation and analysis are needed
to resolve this issue."
But unfortunately, for those hoping to
resolve the issue, much of that evidence
had already been destroyed.
About 99% in fact.
By FEMA!
Before the report came
out in May of 2002.
Let's listen to what real investigation
should've been performed.
Normally, when you have a structural failure,
you carefully go through the debris field,
looking at each item, photographing every
beam as it collapsed and every column,
where it is in the ground,
and you pick them up very carefully
and you look at each element.
We were unable to do that
in the case of Tower 7.
Why? Because all the steel was
removed before the report came out.
In fact, 800 truck loads a day.
Easily the 3 worst structural
failures in modern history.
250 Pieces were saved
"Crucial evidence that can answer the
questions is on a slow boat to China",
exclaims Bill Manning, editor in chief of the
125 year old Fire Engineering Magazine that
brings together fire protection
engineers to communicate with each other.
"Showing an astounding ignorance of
the government officials to the value of a
thorough scientific investigation.
The removal and destruction of
evidence must stop immediately."
"Commission a fully resourced
blue ribbon panel to conduct
a clean and thorough investigation"
is what they were calling for.
If the evidence contradicts
your fire hypothesis, destroy it.
That's where our tax dollars are going.
How about the 9/11 Commission
which was tasked with giving us
the fullest explanation?
No. Not one sentence in the 571 pages
of the 9/11 Commission report even
mentions the destruction of WTC 7.
Is this one of the reasons perhaps
that senator Max Cleland
resigns from the Commission citing:
"It's a national scandal.
The investigation is compromised."
How about expert corroboration?
How about Danny Jowenko,
27 year controlled demolition expert?
"It starts from below, they've
simply blown away the columns.
It's controlled demolition.
A team of experts did this.
It's professional work,
without a doubt."
How about Hugo Bachman, professor
emeritus, chairman of the Department of
Structural Dynamics and
Earthquake Engineering Swiss
Federal Institute of Technology?
In my opinion the building, WTC7,
was, with great probability,
professionally demolished."
How about Kamal Obeid with Architects
and Engineers for 9/11 Truth,
a structural engineer?
"A localized failure in a steel framed
building like WTC7 cannot cause
a catastrophic collapse like a house
of cards without a simultaneous
and patterned loss of several of
its column sat key locations
within the building."
Does that sound like fire?
No.
How about this fire and protection
engineer once again, Jonathan Barnett?
We were surprised that
tower 7 collapsed.
We being the team that investigated
what occurred on that day.
Building 7. Do we have any
foreknowledge of its destruction?
"We're moving the command post over
this way, that building is coming down"
says Chief Nick Visconti.
Well, there was some
structural damage, as we've noted
and they were concerned about it.
"By noon or one o' clock, they told
us to move from the triage site,
up to Pace University a little further
away because Building 7 was going to
come down, or being brought down"
says Indira Singh, interviewed
by Bonnie Faulkner on KPFA.
"Did they actually use the
words 'brought down'?"
"Yeah, that's what they said, we're
going to have to bring it down."
This involves volition. Listen to these
construction workers walking away
from Building 7 and this
police officer caught on CNN.
Keep your eye on that
building, it's coming down.
The building is about to blow up.
Move it back.
We are walking back as the building is about
to blow up. Flames and debris coming down.
Keep your eye on that building,
it's about to come down.
The building is about to blow up.
Flame and debris coming down?
How do they know? And how about
Kevin McPadden, what did he say?
And at the last few seconds he took
his hand off and you heard 3, 2, 1
Countdown? Does that
imply foreknowledge?
Do fires bring buildings
down to countdown?
Unlikely.
In fact, the BBC announces the collapse
20 minutes before it happened.
It's true. Jane Standley is here
announcing it. She says:
"The 47 storey Salomon Brothers Building
close to the WTC has also collapsed,"
and there it is standing behind her.
The BBC apologizes for this grievous error,
citing the confusing events of the day.
But does that make them psychic?
Unlikely.
Is there some kind of script that's
handed out like the guy on the street
at the Twin Towers who had all the answers?
I believe we've shown that Building 7
matches all of the features of
controlled demolition in the classic sense.
Is it likely that Al Qaeda could
have had access to this building
which had to have been one of the
most secure outside the Pentagon?
We have to ask ourselves that question
a few times because, if they didn't,
then who did?
This is as far as we go.
You need to go farther.
And there are resources at
your disposal to do just that.
I will point them out after we
look at the WTC Twin Towers.
Because as clear as the evidence is for
the destruction of Building 7 by explosives,
the evidence is even more clear
in the case of the Twin Towers.
When you look at it with a new pair
of glasses and look at the forensic
science based evidence.
Let's get introduced here.
Some call it the 'crowning achievement
of the International Style',
this  pair of buildings.
Others ' heartless modernism'.
In fact, architect Robert Stern calls it
'gigantic dumbness'.
It's 2 squares extruded, just to
the point where they become
the highest buildings in the world.
Well, either way, no matter how you feel
about these buildings, they did have an
innovative structural engineering, led by
John Skilling and his aide, Leslie Robertson,
who helped Minoru Yamasaki preserve
the simple sculptural purity of his forms.
And you can compare this building
to the elegant Art Deco
of the Empire State Building and come
to your own conclusion about design.
But it did eclipse the highest building in the
world in 1976, just for a couple of years
until the Sears Tower outgrew it.
The structural engineering innovations were
quite extraordinary, lending the award,
the engineering project that
"demonstrates the greatest
engineering skills and represents
the greatest contribution
to engineering progress in mankind" by
the American Society of Civil Engineers.
Let's take a look at what we achieved.
We have 60 foot spans.
We have a perimeter structure that's like
a tube structure and this inner core.
Let's take a look at it.
Most high rises up to this time  were built
on a dense grid of steel or concrete frames
all the way throughout the building
in a 20 or 30 foot grid.
The Twin Towers were built as a
tube structure with a very dense,
strong mash of steel surrounding the
exterior and acting as a baring wall
which resists the lateral loads, earthquake
and, in this case, particularly, wind,
hurricanes of up to 140 miles
an hour it was designed to resist.
This perimeter structure was 14 inch
columns, 3 foot 9 inches on center.
Inside was this core, a dense
grid of 47 immense box columns,
4 inch thick at the base,
2 inch thick at mid height.
Prefabricated floor assemblings, 22 gauge
steel decking, over which was poured
reinforced concrete and held up by
29 inch deep open web steel trusses.
All of this, by the way, was completely
pulverized, this floor structure, on 9/11.
We'll take a look at that.
Now these trusses were bolted to the
perimeter columns and the core columns
with these 5/8th inch bolts which we
talked about the different theories about
what happened to those bolts.
Now, this is a structure within a structure.
This dense core structure would have
remained standing 1300 feet
in the air if this surrounding,
less strong floor structure
were to have collapsed around it.
In fact, the perimeter structure would
have been left standing for a while until
its lack of support gave in.
This is the core columns, 52 inches
by 22 inches along the long edge,
almost solid steel at the bottom,
continuously welded from the bottom
all the way to the top.
Now, any 1800 degree fire would
have almost immediately conducted
throughout this 100.000 ton heat sink.
That's the reason there's been no
collapse of steel frame high rise fires.
Because it's steel.
Hold a spoon over the stove,
see how long you can hold on to it.
Almost instantly you'll
be forced to let it go.
Let's take a look at the structural imperative
that was given to John Skilling.
John Skilling and Les Robertson were
the structural engineers who designed
the streamlined steel frames
of the Twin Towers in the 1960'.
Because a wayward army bomber flew
into the Empire State Building in 1945,
the Towers were built with
skyscraper crashes in mind.
We had designed the project for the
impact of the largest airplane of its time,
the Boeing 707.
That is, to take this jet airplane,
run it into the building,
destroy a lot of structure
and still have it stand up.
The building was designed to have
a fully loaded 707 crash into it,
that was the largest plane at the time.
I believe that the building could probably
sustain multiple impacts of jetliners because
this structure is like the mosquito netting
in your screen door, this intense grid,
and the jet plane is just a pencil
puncturing that screen netting.
It really does nothing to the screen netting.
A very robust structure in fact.
The forces coming down routed themselves
around, they arched around the opening
created by the airplane.
In fact, Eager says: "The towers
withstood the initial impact of the aircraft,
this ability to withstand the initial impact is
hardly surprising" given the robust nature.
We have the North Tower being hit at 8.46 in
the morning and about 102 minutes later,
after fires travelled around the floors and
up the floors, in the case of the North Tower,
the building did collapse.
The South Tower was hit about 15 minutes
later and after only about 56 minutes
it collapses as the fires were
in fact diminishing severely.
Skilling noted that he designed the towers
to take a hit from a Boeing 707 traveling
600 miles an hour.
When he was asked if he
considered  plane crashes he cites;
"Our analysis indicated that the
biggest problem would be the fact
that all the fuel would
dump into the building.
But the building structure
would still be there."
This is FEMA's theory.
We have the sagging of the trusses
and the pulling away from the column and
then the subsequent pancaking down.
Again the trusses, one after the other, 6 foot
8 inches, every truss disengaging from the
perimeter wall, which would have to be,
at the rate that these buildings fell,
that would have been at the speed of
sound, the disengagement from one truss
to the next, all the way around
the building, and then the next floor
and the next floor and the next floor.
So, NIST turns it around and blames
the persistence of these connections
pulling in the columns,
causing the columns to buckle.
It's generally more difficult for people
to understand that the Towers were
a controlled demolition because it was
so outside our frame of reference,
we'd never seen anything like this.
So this, combined with the shock,
kept us from being objective.
But if you were to plan a fire induced
collapse as a result of airplanes
you'd start the explosions at
the point of jet plane impact.
So in WTC 2 and 1 we have all of
the key characteristic features
of controlled demolition but with
some of these key differences.
We have the beginning of detonation
at the point of jet plane impact,
not at the base of the building.
In addition we have not an implosion
but where everything is being exploded
outside the footprint.
We have squibs or these mistimed
explosions that occur 20, 40
and even 60 stories down below.
And, as we've already discussed, the
evidence for thermite in the molten metal
and in the dust,
in the iron rich microspheres.
So let's take a look, starting
with the sudden onset.
What is the evidence for
this and how is it produced?
It's produced by these sounds
and flashes from the explosions.
Now, the city's Fire Commissioner, Thomas
von Essen, requires all of his EMT's
and fire fighters to record their
experiences, about 500 of them
and in 12.000 pages as it turns out,
collected from 2001 to 2002.
The New York State Court of Appeal
overturns the City's request to hold on
to this information against the
law suit by the New York Times.
They failed and why was the City
holding on to this information?
Was it because 118 of these fire fighters
witnessed sounds and flashes
of explosions?
"We felt the ground shake. You could
see the towers sway and then
it just came down."
"All of a sudden the ground
just started shaking."
"It shook my bones."
"Shortly before the first tower came down
I remember feeling the ground shaking."
"Somewhere around the middle of the
World Trade Center there was this
orange and red flash coming out.
Initially it was just one flash.
Then this flash just kept popping all the
way around the building and that building
had started to explode."
"like on television they
blow up these buildings.
It seemed like it was going all the way
around like a belt, all these explosions."
"Pop pop pop, that's when I
heard the building coming down."
"Saw a brief number of  light sources
being emitted from inside the building
between floors 10 and 15."
"I saw low level flashes."
"We actually heard the pops, you know,
you heard the pops of the building."
"It was blowing up on all 4 sides."
"With each popping sound it was initially
an orange and then a red flash came
out of the building and then it would just
go all around the building on both sides."
"I saw flash flash flash and then it
looked like the building came down."
"I thought the terrorists planted
explosives somewhere in the building.
That's how loud it was,
crackling explosive."
Well, you can hear that
explosive in this video.
Yeah. Here's one of the guys
to tell you I'm OK, alright? Hold on.
You wanna call your mother?
Does that sound like a fire?
Or collapsing floors?
None of these explosions are
a part of the official story.
"Another loud boom at the upper
floors and then there was a series
of smaller explosion swhich appeared
to go  completely around the building
at the upper floors."
"Before it came down
I saw low level flashes."
"Flash flash flash and then it looked
like the building came down."
"Did you see any flashes?
I said yeah, I thought it was just me.
He said no, I saw them too."
What did these guys experience?
You saw
Floor by floor it started popping out.
It was like they had detonators,
as if they were planted
to take down the building,
boom boom booom boom boom
All the way down.
How about the news reporters,
what did they say?
They tend to tell the truth, as we
pointed out earlier, on the first day.
And then we don't hear that truth again.
What happens to it?
Anybody who has ever watched a building
being demolished on purpose knows that
if you're going to do this you have to get
at the under infrastructure of a building
and bring it down.
The entire building has just collapsed
as if a demolition team set off
When you see the old demolitions
of these old buildings,
it folded in on itself and
it's not there anymore.
At 10.30 I tried to leave the building
but as soon as I got outside I heard
a second explosion and another rumble
and more smoke and more dust.
I ran inside the building, the chandeliers
shook and again black smoke filled the air.
Within another 5 minutes we were covered
again with more silt and more dust.
And then a fire marshal came in
and said we had to leave because,
if there were a 3rd explosion
this building might not last.
A huge explosion now,
raining debris on all of us,
we gotta get out of the way!
And all of a sudden there was this
big explosion. I don't know if
Just like you've just seen.
That's what we went through
before we came out of the building.
There was another big,
big explosion in the other tower.
Now watch this gentleman as he
experiences the North Tower collapsing
and ask yourself this question.
Is his reaction justified by witnessing
what we're told is a gravitational
collapse which happens to be about
1700 feet away from him?
People were just standing around
talking to each other, not even..
Oh my God
Do you know whether it was an
explosion or a building collapse?
To me it sounded like eh,
to me it sounded like an explosion.
There was a huge explosion.
Chief Albert Tury told me he was here after
the events that took place this morning.
He tried to get his men out as quickly
as he could but he said that there was
another explosion which took place.
And then, an hour after there was
another explosion in one of the towers here.
According to his theory he thinks that there
were actually devices that were planted
in the buildings.
It just went like BABOOOM,
like a bomb went off.
It was like holy hell
coming down those stairs.
And then we finally got to the bottom, we
were coming out, and another explosion
sent everyone flying.
Like the sound of gun fire,
bang bang bang bang,
and then suddenly 3 big explosions.
I was about 5 blocks away
when I heard explosions, 3 thuds,
and I turned around to see the building
we  just got out of tip over and
fold in on itself.
We heard reports of secondary explosions
after the airplanes impacted.
Whether, in fact, there was something else
at the base of the towers that in fact were
the coup de gras to
bring them to the ground.
As we were getting our gear on
and making our way to the stairway
there was a heavy duty explosion.
Again, none of these explosions
are a part of the official story.
Now, compare these explosions to
a known explosion on the left here.
Upward, outward, arching streamers,
pyroclastic volumes of dust,
symmetrical display like a mushroom.
Does it look like a
gravitational collapse to you?
How could explosives be placed at the
WTC Twin Towers with 50.000 occupants
not knowing about it?
Well, this is the floor plan.
Let's enlarge it and take a closer look.
We note that the core structure, the columns
of which are immediately adjacent to almost
all of the elevators,
at the lower levels certainly.
If you had access to the elevator hoist way
and you could hack through the 2 layers
of ¾ inch gypsum board protecting the
building from a fire rising up through it,
you would have access to the core columns
and beams and no one would see you.
How about an elevator modernization which
we know was going on the nine months
prior to 9/11?
Yes, Elevator World,
March 2001 documents it.
In fact, they were in the
middle of this modernization.
ACE Elevator had the contract.
We're not conspiracy theorists but it's pretty
obvious that somebody needs to be asked
some very key questions.
There are people who noted that
the elevators were locked in turn
and that there were guards placed
at these locked elevators
during the modernization.
Of course you'd have
to have access to security.
Securicomm was brought in.
Who sits at the board of Securicomm?
Marvin Bush, the younger brother
of George Bush.
Let's have somebody ask
them some questions.
Wireless detonation is common in the
industry, you don't need miles of wire
and you can detonate them
remotely with great flexibility, in fact.
Well, but is there a precedent?
NIST tells us that it couldn't have
been a controlled demolition because it
it didn't start at the bottom.
That's where most controlled
demolitions start with buildings.
Let's take a look and see if
there's another way to do it.
The words of a senior blaster.
We blow the basement,
all the columns in the basement.
Then we crack it up at
the top to get it started.
We go every other floor,
all the way down.
Every explosive has a timer on it,
that's why it's 'controlled'.
When the columns go, each floor goes
down and impacts the one below,
and keeps going.
Mark Loizeaux is president of a
company called Controlled Demolition.
You don't have to go to the top floor,
you can go almost anywhere
in the structure and, given the right
circumstances you can release
all that stored energy, converting it
into what's called kinetic energy,
that's energy in motion, and that's
what brings the building down.
Well, here's a 3 storey, top down
controlled demolition, let's count them.
One , two three.
Now these are high energy
explosives, C4 and RDX.
Very loud booms and very visible flashes.
Perhaps the reason thermite was used
is because they don't have as loud
of these explosions like
these high energy explosives.
And they don't have these
flashes that they do either.
Here's a 20 storey, middle
down controlled demolition.
You can start demolitions
from anywhere you like.
Let's look at the North Tower now.
What I want to point out to you is that
you're going to see some explosions
up at the top of the building, curiously
enough and what's going to happen is this
entire section is going to telescope, such
that half of it, its upper half is destroyed
before there is any movement
from the jet plane impact down.
Let's take a look.
Here's the first evidence of explosions,
and then over here,
and then the collapsing.
Of course, the violent clouds which are
emerging even prior to the collapse.
We're going to take a closer
look after this second look.
A new fuel source which might
well be jet fuel that wasn't burned
that's getting new oxygen.
Let's take a look now closer up.
Right away we're seeing
clouds forming up here.
Wait, the collapse is
supposed to be down here.
We have asymmetrical
damage to this building, right?
The plane went in one side, and yet
this completely symmetrical collapse,
we'll use quotes from now
on and let's keep going.
And one more time.
Belts, just like the firemen saw,
all the way around the building.
The antenna falls about 12 meters first,
before anything else falls,
indicating core column damage
first, not trusses pulling away
from the perimeter columns.
Now take a look at this, from the
same tower, from the bottom,
noting the violence underneath
the mushroom cloud.
The collapse is supposed to be
occurring way up here, but down below,
as you'll see in this second run,
incredible quantities of squibs,
explosions bursting out, and on the 3rd
time I'd like to direct your attention
to this racing series of explosions
down the right side
and the corner of this building.
About 40 stories below
the collapsing building.
It gets painfully obvious
after a while, doesn't it?
Note these multiple nodes of
these independent explosions,
it's a little different then the North Tower.
But it's still incredibly the same after a while,
after all of these explosions developed.
Do we have a straight down,
symmetrical progression of collapse
outside the footprint?
We had a 207 foot wide building. FEMA
tells us, and you can see in this document,
that we have a 1200 foot debris field,
equidistant around each tower.
Asymmetrical damage, symmetrical
distribution, all through the site in fact,
and beyond.
Do we have squibs or
these mistimed explosions?
Some believe that these might be
appropriately timed explosions, whatever
In all the videos of the collapses explosions
can be seen bursting from the building
20 to 30 stories below
the demolition wave.
Here.
And here.
Now, NIST tells us that these
are puffs of air being produced
by the collapsing building pushing
air down the hoist way like a piston,
it's gotta come out somewhere, right?
Well, first of all these are not puffs of air,
they're pulverized building materials.
And they occur at a 160 to 200 feet,
some of them, per second.
These velocities are
propelled by explosives.
20, 40 and 60 stories below, how
can a piston be producing all of that?
And in fact there are these focalized
ejections that occur half way
between the corners of the building.
Also, say that this was the
open office space, 60 feet long,
the elevator hoist way is over here,
the piston is going to shove the air
into this room, it's going to fill the room
fairly uniformly with air pressure
before it breaks any windows, right?
And then it might break several but
not these focalized, pin point accurate,
geometrically precise,
violent ejections.
No, it's extremely unlikely.
But let's look at a couple of them.
As the South Tower begins to explode we
track 2 squibs near the bottom of the frame.
They shoot out quickly at first, then slow
and merge with the rest of the rest
of the dust cloud.
Using the first few data points
we see the first squib shoots out
at 44,98 meters per second
or about 100 miles per hour.
Doing the same for the second squib we
get a speed of 56,3 meters per second
which works out close to 126 mph.
126 mph of almost instant ejection velocity?
Does fire create that?
Do we have a near free fall pace through
the path of greatest resistance?
Let's take a look.
Galileo's law of falling bodies calculates
the time in which an object will travel
a certain distance in complete free fall.
Distance, D, equals 16.08 times
time in seconds squared.
The South Tower was 1362 feet tall.
1362 equals 16.08 times 84,7
or 9,2 seconds.
The Twin Towers came down
at nearly free fall speed.
What are we talking about here?
Let's just try to put this in perspective
with this storey problem.
We have a 15 storey building which we
hold with this crane over 95 stories
with nothing but air.
No resistance, right?
Just air resistance.
Next to it another 15 storey building held
over a 95 storey building with, say,
80.000 tons of structural steel in it.
Now we're going to pull the levers on
these cranes and drop them both at once.
I brought a 95 storey
building with me today
and we're going to just
test this theory of NIST.
I've got 2 15 storey buildings.
We've got 80.000 tons of structural
steel in this one right here
and we've got air resistance here.
So let's try it, OK?
We'll put them both up here, we'll
even give a little impact load too, OK?
Ready? 3, 2, 1
Oh my God! The one without any
resistance under it hit the ground first.
At virtually free fall speed.
This doesn't take much, does it?
What happened over here?
The building above, it met resistance
through the energy of deformation
it came to a halt.
In fact, you'll find on our website,
www.AE911Truth.org ,
that Ken Cutler and Gordon Ross produced
these papers and they show and calculate
that in fact the building's downward
momentum would have been almost
immediately arrested.
Then where is the 15 storey building that
was driving this building down to the ground
at free fall speed?
In the first 2 seconds you saw it reduced
half of its mass, it was blown outside,
it couldn't have been used to influence
the downward progression of the building.
In the next 2 seconds, after 4 seconds
totally, it's destroyed itself.
There's nothing crushing the building.
It's tearing itself apart at free fall speed.
And it's dismembering the steel structure.
In fact, the leading edge of these mushroom
clouds are full of perimeter columns,
aluminum cladding and other steel.
Let's take a look at the South Tower
in terms of dismemberment.
See what's going on here.
South Tower is on your left.
It was hit lower by the aircraft.
And, as you can see, its descent,
its rapid destruction starts there and
it begins to tilt to the left.
Now in fact, it disappears in this cloud.
We would expect to see this building,
which is already tilted at 22 degrees and
continuing its angular momentum,
off center of the building below it.
How can it crush it symmetrically at
free fall speed if it's already off center?
We don't see it either mangled up in some
heap at the bottom down on the pavement.
It's been completely dismembered.
Let's take a look from below though.
Because I'm not quite convinced.
We have asymmetrical damage and yet
there's this symmetrical destruction
occurring underneath the cloud, all the
way around the building like the firemen saw
even though this top mass
is already fallen over.
Free fall speed.
It doesn't make sense to me.
The steel framed structure
was completely dismembered.
There are no large chunks of building.
Only those shards that we saw
of the perimeter structure.
Does it look like a
gravitational collapse to you?
Do we have lateral ejection
of structural steel?
Let's take a look.
Now let's take a look at the
collapse of the Twin Towers.
We're seeing explosions rather than
implosions, a first in demolition history.
A sequenced rumble becomes a
roar as debris is thrown outward.
The damage is not contained.
Windows are blown from
neighborhood buildings.
What kind of energy enabled this?
Would fire hurl metal and
concrete sideways into the air?
Here a chunk of steel was blown
400 feet wedging itself deep in WTC 3
on Vesey Street.
A FEMA photographer taking pictures
of Ground Zero wondered why
so many steel beams were
jutting from neighborhood buildings.
What shot pieces of the Towers
all the way across the street?
In fact, the portions of the tower that
had the greatest structural members,
the sky lobbies and the mechanical
floors, had their perimeter units
thrown farther than the perimeter
wall units from the upper floors,
because they're higher they
should have gone further, right?
No, these perimeter units landed
on the Winter Garden, 600 feet away.
Let's take a look at the physics of this.
Girders weighing several tons were found
600 feet from the base of the North tower.
How fast they were ejected
depends on where they originated.
If they came from high in the building they
were thrown outward at about 50 mph.
If they came from lower down
the speed had to be even greater.
Gravity alone cannot account for
such high lateral ejection speeds.
In fact, let's take a look at a
couple of these specific ejections.
Using special software we can analyze
motion on video clips frame by frame.
I've placed markers on each frame
so we can track a particular projectile.
From the markers we can get a
data table and plot various graphs.
The data shows that the objects that we
were tracking were shot horizontally
at over 70 mph.
The energy needed to hurl a 4 ton
girder at this speed is comparable
to the energy needed to hurl
a 200 pound cannonball 3 miles.
What about those floors,
those pancakes?
If this is a pancake collapse we're
looking for pancakes down below.
This is a 7 storey lobby.
There's about 2 or 3 stories of stuff in there.
We'll take a look at that stuff but
what I'm looking for is 110 floors
with this kind of metal decking underneath
4 and 5 inches thick of concrete.
An acre in size, each of them.
110 acres of these.
How many floors do we
find at the bottom?
Not 50, not 10, not even 1.
We don't even find metal
decking down there.
Or concrete. There's hardly any
macroscopic chunks of concrete.
What happened to the metal decking?
What happened to the concrete?
Tom Patrezza  brought
these floor decks out.
"6000 of them", he says. "I couldn't
believe it. Not one floor panel",
he notes when he comes
back to help the clean up.
Pancakes occur in pancake collapses.
Enormous pyroclastic clouds
of pulverized concrete?
Where is all the concrete in fact?
Let's listen to Jeff King.
One of the most significant things to my
thinking that indicates that this could
not have been the sort of collapse
that we're told it was is the presence
of the dust clouds.
And as you've seen in the pictures, I'm sure
all of us have seen more than we would like,
there were very very large clouds of
very thick dust that enveloped the area,
that crossed the river, that made
it almost all the way to New Jersey
from the pictures that I've seen.
This type of flow is something
that we're familiar with in physics.
It occurs in only 2 situations
that we know of naturally.
One is in volcanic eruptions where a large
amount of material is suddenly exploded
into the air and basically
forms small particles.
Thank you, Jeff.
How about New York governor Petaki?
And you look and you see
that there's no concrete.
There's very little concrete.
All you see is aluminum and steel.
What happened to the concrete?
The concrete was pulverized.
When I was down here Tuesday it was
like you were on a foreign planet.
All of Lower Manhattan, not just this site.
From river to river there was
dust powder 2 to 3 inches thick.
The concrete was just pulverized.
And how about this fire fighter?
You have two 110 storey office buildings.
You don't find a desk,
you don't find a chair.
You don't find a telephone,
a computer.
The biggest piece of a telephone
that I found was half of the keypad
and it was about this big.
The building collapsed to dust.
And this dust made it almost across
to New Jersey, across the river.
Thick, billowing, laying a carpet of 4 to 6
inches thick around Lower Manhattan.
Pulverized to 100 micron to 10 mille
particles, almost like talcum powder,
some of it.
It's very very fine.
Where is the grinder that produced this?
90.000 tons of it.
In these clouds that expanded 10 times
the volume of the buildings themselves
in just 30 seconds.
Now the available gravitational potential in
the whole building was about 110.000 KWH.
That's basically the weight of the building
times its height above the ground
evened out.
But the expansion of these clouds has
been calculated to require about 10 times
that energy in heat which
produces that expansion.
So we have a problem here.
In fact, the gravitational potential of
the entire building needs to also produce
4 other heat sinks.
But first, we have a 15 storey building,
this part of the gravitational potential alone,
it's converted all of its gravitational
potential into kinetic energy.
They can't do anymore work.
In other words, it can't fall at
free fall speed and then also crush
80.000 tons of structural steel.
It can't fall at free fall speed and also
grind up 90.000 tons of concrete.
It can't fall at free fall speed and
create by friction or anything else
these several tons of molten metal
seen by the first responders.
The energy doesn't add up.
We're talking overall about 50 times the
gravitational potential energy of the building
to produce all of these phenomena.
How about the victims?
In April 2006 New Yorkers were
distressed to learn that bone fragments,
human remains from 9/11, had been
found on the roof of the nearby
Deutsche Bank Building.
And how in God's name did
those fragments get there?
And bone fragments less
than a centimeter long.
How could they be so small?
700 bone fragments half an inch long found
on top of a skyscraper across the street?
Think about that one.
There's 2.749 victims but only
300 whole bodies were found.
20.000 pieces of bodies found, 6.000
small enough to fit into a test tube.
1.151 victims completely unaccounted
for, in other words,
no pieces large enough to get
any DNA from, vaporized.
200 pieces were matched
to one single person.
Can fire and gravitational collapse account
for this massive pulverization of people?
We talked about the iron microspheres.
We talked about the chemical
evidence of thermate in them
and in the slag and
the ends of the beams.
And we talked about evidence of thermite
and unexploded thermite in the dust itself.
All of this is direct evidence
of explosive destruction.
And none of it can be
accounted for by fire.
Let's have dr. David Ray Griffin
sum this one up for us.
These facts taken together render the
likelihood of the official theory
essentially zero.
In fact, each of the 10 phenomena,
the likelihood of them occurring
without explosives being used
is by itself essentially zero.
But let's be generous and suggest
that maybe there's a 1% chance
that these things could occur.
Virtual free fall speed, straight down,
enormous amount of dust, 1% chance.
But when you figure up the probabilities
down when you say how many that
2 of them occur, 3 of them occur, by the
time you get up to 10 of them occurring
without explosives, you're talking
about the likelihood of on in a trillion.
So we can say that the official theory
about the Towers is disproved as thoroughly
as any such theory could possibly be
whereas all the evidence can be explained
by the alternative theory according to
which the Towers were brought down
by explosives.
The official theory is therefore
an outrageous theory whereas
the alternative theory is, from a scientific
point of view, the only possible theory.
Thank you.
How about that FEMA report?
What does Fire Engineering
Magazine say about it?
"FEMA investigation is a half
baked farce", Bill Manning says,
"that may already have been commandeered
by political forces whose primary interests,
to put it mildly, lie far afield
of full disclosure."
"The structural damage from the planes
and the explosive ignition of jet fuel
in themselves were not enough
to bring down the Towers."
How about that NIST report?
We got 20 million dollars and 3 years.
What happened with our tax dollars?
Their task was to determine how
and why WTC 1 and 2 collapsed
and how and why WTC 7 collapsed.
Let's look at their objective.
"The focus of the investigation was
on the sequence of the events,
from the instant of the aircraft  impact to
the initiation of collapse for each tower.
For brevity in this report,
this sequence is referred to as
the 'probable collapse sequence'.
It doesn't actually include the structural
behavior of the tower after the conditions
for collapse initiation were reached and
collapse became", they say, "inevitable."
Wait a minute. You're going to spend
3 years and 20 million dollars
and you're going to model every turbine
in the airplane and you're going to stop
the entire investigation before
the real action begins, right at the point
where the truss was sagging
and pulling in the first column
and you're just going
to stop your analysis?
How many engineers did you
have working on this?
And what are you concluding?
They have 10.000 pages in this report.
This is the half page that explains
everything after that.
No analysis.
Let's see their conclusion.
"The structure below the level of collapse
initiation offered minimal resistance
to the falling building mass at
and above the impact zone."
Structural engineers do this every day.
This is not rocket science.
You have the known weight
of this building mass.
You have what are known columns
below it in order to resist it.
You put the building up there and
you let it go in your models
and you calculate what the resistance is.
Why didn't they do it?
Could it be because they knew darn well
that it would not have collapsed at all?
What was the report title?
'Final report on the collapse
of the WTC Twin Towers'.
They probably should have called it
'Final report on the initiation of collapse'.
They also cast doubt on their own theory.
They say to us in a letter to our request
for correction which several of us
applied for and have yet
to see adequate results from:
"We're unable to provide a full explanation
of the total collapse of the Twin Towers."
Thank you.
We think so too.
Prompting Jim Hoffman to write
'Building a better mirage,
NIST's 3-year, 20 million dollar cover up
of the crime of the century',
in which he documents numerous
unfounded assumptions.
He documents that it's
a mountain of distraction.
They'll never read all this stuff.
TNRAT, they'll never read all this.
10.000 pages.
1.000 pages modeling the airplanes.
And, as I mentioned, only half a page
on their core presumption, classic,
progressive collapse.
How can it be classic if it never
happened before in history?
As if some initiating element in a steel
framed building caused the rest of it
to ever collapse.
He documents the startling omissions and
outrageous lies, which you'll have to go in to
yourself if you have a little more time,
and the fudged computer simulations.
They document these unrealistic scenarios
C and D, and the realistic scenarios A and B.
A and B didn't make the buildings collapse
so they crank up the airplane speed.
They reduced the strength of the structure.
They increase the fuel.
They do all of these adjustments until
they get, in the more unrealistic scenarios,
which they're actually fairly open about,
to get the computer model to collapse.
Structural engineers rail against NIST
because they refuse to show
the visualization.
It's a black box, you cannot
download any of this data.
This was a public building, or at least
before 3 months prior to 9/11
it was a public building, and it
should be a public investigation.
Clearly it was a public event prompting their
former chief of their fire science division,
dr. Quintiere, to call for
an independent review.
"Let's look at real alternatives that might
have been the cause of the collapse
of the WTC Twin Towers."
Do we have any whistle blowers?
Yes. Kevin Ryan, fired from his job for
making public the fact that NIST hired
Underwriter Laboratories to perform tests.
And these tests showed that the building
should have remained standing.
In fact, there were 4 mock samples of
35 foot spans, two 17 foot spans and
two 35 foot spans with fire proofing just like
in the Twin Towers with the floor decking.
Now, there's 2.000 degrees of fires put
underneath this assembly, per ASTME 119,
and twice the amount of load that was
known to have been in the Twin Towers.
What happens?
None of them fail.
These are the 4 tests.
The steel temperatures were
over 1.100 degrees average.
Foot note nr. 3 documents
that no failure occurred.
In fact, there was only
3 inches of deformation.
What does NIST do with
this experimental data?
They throw it out and they claim
that there was a 42 inch sag,
10 times the value that resulted
from the experiments!
Do we have expert corroboration?
Well, here's Van Romero.
"It's too methodical to be a chance result
of airplanes colliding with the structure",
this explosives expert says.
"After the airplanes hit the WTC towers
there were some explosives, in my opinion,
inside the buildings that caused
the towers to collapse."
Van has withdrawn these statements
after receiving a sizable grant
from the federal government.
Mike Taylor, a demolition expert:
"It looked like classic controlled demolition.
The collapse of the WTC towers
mirrored the strategy used
by demolition experts."
How about this structural engineer,
Ron Brookman?
"Explosive clouds of dust
and debris moving horizontally
and vertically upward as the collapses
of WTC 1 and WTC 2 are just beginning
does not look anything like a heat-induced
gravitational collapse mechanism.
"Why complete collapse of the
Twin Towers became inevitable?
Why would all 110 stories drop straight
down to the ground in 10 seconds,
pulverizing the contents?
None of the official reports address
the issue of total collapse.
William Rice, structural engineer, also with
Architects and Engineers for 9/11 Truth:
"The prevailing theory would have us
believe that each of the Twin Towers
inexplicably collapsed upon itself crushing
all 287 massive columns on each floor
while maintaining a free fall speed
as if the 100.000 or more tons
of supporting structural steel
framework underneath didn't exist."
How about David Scott,
structural engineer with AE911Truth?
"Near free fall collapse
violates the laws of physics."
You can memorize that one.
How about Scott Grainger, fire
protection engineer with AE911Truth?
"All three collapses were
very uniform in nature.
Natural collapses due to
unplanned events are not uniform."
How about Ed Munyak, with us today,
fire protection engineer?
"The fires were very weak, oxygen starved
as evidenced by the black smoke.
Steel temperatures were low.
All 3 WTC collapses have no resemblance
to any previous high rise fire."
How about Matthys Levy,
who later joined the FEMA team?
If you've seen many of the managed
demolitions where they implode a building
and they cause it actually to fall vertically
because they cause all the vertical columns
to fail simultaneously, that's exactly what
it looked like and that's what happened.
That's what happened?
What happened Matthys,
after you joined the FEMA team?
Did you look for controlled demolition,
your initial hunch?
No.
Neither did this gentleman, Ronald
Hamburger, who also joined FEMA
after saying:
"It appeared to me that charges
had been placed in the building."
Never looked for controlled demolition?
How about foreknowledge of
these 2 buildings?
FEMA was on site with
their exercise 'Tripod 2'.
They had "hundreds of people from FEMA ,
the federal government,
from the state, from the Office of
the State Emergency Management .
They were getting ready for a drill in down
town Manhattan for a biochemical attack."
This is per New York mayor Giuliani.
Tom Kenney from FEMA says:
"We arrived on late on Monday night,
went right into action on Tuesday."
Coincidence?
Maybe.
Mayor Rudolph Giuliani:
I went down to the scene and we set up
headquarters on 75 Barclay Street,
which was right there with the police
commissioner and the fire commissioner,
the head of Emergency Management,
and we were operating out of there
when we were told that
the WTC was going to collapse.
Who gave you that warning?
Did you warn the firemen and women?
We have plenty of video evidence,
you've seen.
And this suggests all the features
of a classic controlled demolition
with those exceptions which are
atypical of classic controlled demolition.
None of these features can be
accounted for by fire.
Let alone all 10 of them.
We have supporting evidence.
This all goes to support the
hypothesis of controlled demolition.
It's proof beyond a reasonable doubt.
If you're with me so far
you have big problems.
It's much easier, given our human nature,
to go right into paralysis and take
no action because the implications
of this are absolutely staggering.
We come up with these kinds
of questions which are valid.
"Our government wouldn't do this to us!"
Well, were not saying your
government did this to you.
Somebody was responsible for this.
Somebody, somewhere on the inside,
we don't know how high up it goes,
we don't know how wide it is.
"I would've heard about it by now!"
You are hearing about it now!
I didn't hear about it until 2 years ago.
"It couldn't have been kept
a secret that long!"
Well, the 'Manhattan Project'
had thousands of people ,
it was kept quite a secret
for a very long time.
"I'm not an expert in controlled demolition!"
Wait a minute, neither am I. But you are
the jury and you have an obligation
to make a decision.
Guilty or not guilty is typically the decision.
In this case explosive
controlled demolition or fire.
You have to take this information,
process it through your brain
and come up with a decision
and then a course of action.
I'm going to help you
with the course of action,
the decision is a little more difficult.
And don't do this:
"It's too horrible.
I don't even want to think about it!"
"I didn't even see this stuff tonight."
The worst form of denial.
You avoid the debate, go back to sleep
and become a part of the problem.
And it is a huge problem in America.
America is asleep at the wheel.
Very few of us know about this.
You've got to get motivated with this
information and take action based on
your response to this rational,
scientific, forensic based information.
Work through your fears.
Yes, there's fears.
If this happened to us then
it could happen again.
Then who's in control?
Who did I vote for?
There are a heck of a lot of questions.
We have disbelieves and mindsets
that are contrary to our acceptance
of this information.
There's no way to get a
handle on it for a lot of us.
I'm a Reagan Republican.
Consider what I had to go through.
We got to get informed and inform
every other architect and engineer
that you can find and
everybody else that you know.
Support a new investigation.
Support these people who are
demanding a new investigation.
How about 200 9/11 survivors and family
members, 110 military intelligence,
law enforcement and government officials,
170 distinguished professors,
110 entertainment and media professionals,
all endorsing a call for
a new probe into 9/11?
Visit www.patriotsquestion911.com
and look for Andreas von Bulow,
the former Defense Minister
of Germany who says:
"This is unthinkable, without year-long
support from secret apparatuses
of the state and industry."
How about Francesco Cossiga who says:
"The disastrous attack was planned
and executed by the American CIA."
How about Yukihisa Fujita,
travelling around the world today,
prominent senator from Japan,
demanding a new investigation?
And Paul Hellyer, former Minister
of National Defense of Canada:
"I would like to see a much tougher,
more in-depth inquiry.
We have to try and get at the truth."
What happened to the truth? Let's take
a look at this quote from William Colby.
Maybe it can shed some light:
"The CIA owns everyone
of any significance in the major media."
That's a heck of a statement from
the former director of the CIA.
What does it mean?
It's documented in many places,
including Project Censored, dedicated to
bringing all of us the 25 most censored
stories from the main stream media.
Why did we not see the truth about 9/11?
Well, it appears as if our government
lied to us about the building collapses.
The 9/11 Commission Report reinforced that lie.
FEMA and NIST justified it.
And the corporate media repeated
it and they hammered it in.
We really didn't have much of a chance.
We've shown here today that explosives
were used to destroy each of the 3
WTC high rise buildings on 9/11.
And it's known that it takes months
of planning to set up and engineer
and place these explosives.
Do we think that Al Qaeda had access
to these highly secure buildings?
So, unfortunately, this is just
the beginning of a disturbing
but very essential journey for you,
back into the nightmare of 9/11.
The evidence you've seen tonight is
just a small fraction of the vast body
of information that the 9/11
Truth Movement has assembled.
The questions raised are numerous
and ominous that must be answered
in a new investigation.
I encourage you to discover the
evidence that I have not had time
to bring to you tonight.
It will take thousands, perhaps millions of us.
Each one of us in this grass roots
movement has an ultimate responsibility
to take the information that we
have provided and disseminate it.
Get the DVD, loan it to everybody you know.
You must become a truth bearer.
Email the AE911Truth.org link along with
a statement saying "CHECK THIS OUT"
to every architect and engineer you
can find and everybody you know.
We will turn heads in
the halls of congress.
Check out the other great DVD's
including '9/11 Mysteries'
which you've heard several clips from
tonight, and some great books
by David Ray Griffin including 'The New
Pearl Harbor' and his latest book
'9/11 Contradictions'.
Check out 'Loose Change,
2nd edition and Final Cut',
there's some great
information available there
and go to www.journalof911studies.com
and Steven Jones' website www.stj911.org .
Demand a real investigation.
Call and write your elected representatives,
write your local television stations,
radio stations, news papers.
Call in to talk shows, write to
national TV and radio networks.
Tell everyone you know.
Ask questions, demand answers.
Sign the AE911Truth.org petition.
Sign it, demanding a new investigation.
Stand up and be counted.
There's nothing to fear but fear itself.
Everyone can sign, architects
and engineers and all else.
We have several categories of people.
Millions of people are studying
these matters, they're called
the 911 Truth Movement.
For the average person and for everyone
that has looked into this to any degree
there's no shortage of information,
evidence that, of course,
the buildings were blown up.
Why is it so difficult to get
people to simply just look?
There is difficulty. I mean it's not
even easy for me as an architect.
I've been studying this for 2 years.
So, when people aren't
open to this, I hear that.
Sometimes they are and it's refreshing.
What you need to do is
get one of these cards.
We provide it.
You've got hundreds of architects.
We stick our necks out on the line for you.
Let them call us conspiracy theorists.
All you have to do is say that there
are a couple of hundred, 400 now,
architects and engineers
demanding a new investigation.
What do you think?
You're not saying "hey, I'm a conspiracy
theorist, here's my conspiracy". No.
Blame us and ask them:
"What does this picture look like to you?
I'm just curious."
9 times out of 10 they'll say
"it's an explosion, it's a mushroom.
It's a volcano."
It's incredible the responses that you'll get.
Support us by becoming
a sustaining member.
You can make a difference.
We are a non-profit organization that
has our hands tied for lack of funds.
We need to get the word out
to the building professionals.
For 10 dollars a month, as little as that,
you can become a sustaining member.
Architects and Engineers for 9/11 Truth are
at the apex of the 9/11 Truth Movement.
Why? Because we have those who have the
necessary credibility to raise eyebrows
and gain attention.
We need to get the vinyl banners,
the DVD's and brochures in the hands of
the real heroes of the 9/11 Truth Movement,
the people willing to get the message
out on the street.
www.wearechange.org,
www.truthaction.org ,
Project for a New American Citizen,
these folks need your support.
We need to act.
The power of truth is greater
than the power of the lie.
So get informed and begin to
let the truth speak through you.
Get informed through our website,
we've got all the information you need.
Sign the petition here.
Follow the red arrows.
Become a sustaining member here,
it's real easy.
Given the numerous warnings of far worse
terrorist attacks and war plans against Iran
that are in place we
need to do something.
Speak out, because a time comes
when your silence is betrayal.
Thank you so much for your attention today.
Subtitles and synchronization
by Erick van Dijk, Holland
for a transcript, email me at
erickvandijk@hotmail.com