AUGUST 1944
A BAG OF MARBLES
Everything is the same.
And yet...everything seems smaller.
Or I've grown up.
But how long has it been now?
Two and a half years?
Is it for today or for tomorrow?
This is my favorite marble...
Come on, Grouile!
Stop bugging me, I'm concentrating.
- Shit.
- Still wrong.
You are too incompetent.
Come on, we're gonna be late.
Keep your marble.
Stop crying.
Come on, hurry up.
We'll be late.
I'm not crying.
Yes, you are right. You don't cry.
It is not just because of its
technological superiority,
that Hitler's army is advancing rapidly.
Excuse me for the delay.
You'll see me after class.
So not by the
technological superiority,
but mostly thanks to the
morality of the German people...
who believe that their
destiny is to lead Europe.
That's not from
yesterday or today, is it...
Already under Karel... Zerati!
Give me that piece of paper.
Come on little boy...
"I hold my mistresses,
even those of others."
Very funny.
But full of mistakes.
Did you write that?
- Bah. ..
- He's stupid enough to to pass it on,
but not smart enough
to write it down, sir.
Silence. Silence.
You will write out
50 times the motto of the Maréchal.
And do not forget the "S" after "celles".
Come on, Zerati. To your place.
Here!
Do you want another one?
I got you.
Right on your ass!
Take this !
Just wait...
- Get your guard up.
- You, you gonna stick one?
You're dreaming, mosquito.
Look. I have an idea.
Could he choose?
To cut?
Haircut?
Albert!
Take care of Monsieur.
Hello.
What can I do for you ?
They haven't seen anything...
Cut my hair.
With pleasure. Take a seat.
You're welcome.
Go ahead.
We'll take your coats.
Short on the neck?
Please. And a trim
on the left for my colleague.
No problem.
He does not speak French well.
He understands a little, huh?
Yes.
But you speak very good French.
Not really. But I will
try it to speak better.
That is only a matter of time.
I'll be back later.
Until next time, Mr. Levi...
Mr. Léviyard.
It's okay.
It's on the house, Mr Léviyard.
Are they yours,
the two little boys?
Yes.
The older ones too.
These little rascals are always
ready to make the 400 shots.
Ah, the war...
Terrible business, isn't it?
It depends for whom...
It's because of the Jews.
Here. Nice and short.
Satisfied?
Thank you.
- Do you like it?
- Yes. Very good.
Know, gentlemen,
that here, in this salon,
everybody is Jewish.
Oh, I almost had it.
Come on, get into bed.
No no! In bed, kids!
We stop acting like idiots.
Let go of your brother. Stop!
Go to bed.
Yawohl, My Commander!
- In bed. No whining.
- Yawohl!
- That's right, yes.
You want to act like your brother.
Calm down, darling.
Your father told me
what you did today.
Don't do that again, okay ?
Those Germans
are not here to laugh.
Ja! Sehr gut!
Sehr gut!
Did you laugh?
Yes.
You had them by the nose.
Yes. You're too strong, Papa.
It's not a matter of strength.
You answered them.
The question is what can you do about it.
Maybe soon, you can't
say nothing more.
Perhaps.
But in the meantime, we
are "dignity, justice and pride",
As your grandfather used to say.
grandpa Jacob.
In bed !
Aren't you too old for that nonsense?
No.
No? Well, me neither.
Stop! They have to
go to school tomorrow!
Stop!
But you're crazy?
MAY 1942
Come on, Grouil. Come!
If Maman sees us
smoking, we're in shit.
Why do you say "us"?
The Jewish star has 6 points,
the size of the palm of your hand
with outlines in black.
It is made of yellow fabric and in
black the letters JEW are written on it.
It must be clearly visible and
worn on the left side of the chest
firmly sewn to the clothing.
Listen, Maman.
Penalties:
Failure to follow this order will be
punishable by imprisonment and fines.
This can be extended
with or being replaced by...
admission to a Jewish camp.
Do you know what that means?
There's nothing more we can do,
don't go out anymore.
We don't have to stay here.
We'll ask Papa what he thinks.
It's like a medal, isn't it?
They mark us, like
in the Middle Ages.
Shut up, Henri. That's enough.
Mother, listen to me.
Albert and I made our decision.
We'll leave tomorrow.
Where to?
You're not gonna leave like that.
Do you think they are taking revenge
for what happened in the salon?
No, I don't think so.
Especially you:
keep your head up.
Hey, he's also a Jew.
Good, see you later.
He is Jewish...
You don't have to frequent it.
Why are you looking
at me like that?
I didn't know you were Jewish.
So what? What does it matter?
That changes everything.
- Oh yeah? What then?
- That means you're a Youpin.
A Youpin.
It is you who have crucified
the little Jesus.
That's it, it was I
who crucified him,
- Asshole.
- Asshole yourself.
He denies it, with his Jewish blood.
What's wrong with my blood?
Is it not the same as yesterday?
It's because of the Jews
that the Germans are here.
- Take that back.
- In your dreams!
That's what you deserve.
Well, mosquitoes...
Do you want to fight?
Because hitting is what I prefer.
Is that Youpin causing problems for you?
Who's a mosquito now?
Gentlemen, come on!
In a line!
Go inside!
I want to speak with you.
In my office!
I hit him with my right.
Not really, no...
I can defend myself.
Wait, Joffo!
- Well, are things getting better?
- Bof
Show me your star.
Here, I'll trade it for
my bag of marbles.
What are you talking about ?
Your star, I trade it
for my bag of marbles.
Are you sure about that, Zerati?
Yes, I told you.
I like it, your star.
Look, there's plenty in there.
Good. Okay.
But I warn you, be careful.
It's not just a star.
It is also a target.
Do not worry. Thank you.
See you tomorrow.
Hey! Go ahead.
Give it back.
You made a great deal.
Come on, Grouille.
Otherwise we're gonna get banged up again.
Hello 'pa.
Hurry up, mother is waiting for you.
Maman! I don't have any homework today.
Sit down, kids.
Come on, eat up. It's going to get cold.
Is there a problem?
I will tell you a story that happened
to grandpa Jacob and me.
A long time ago,
in our village in Russia,
There were riots against the Jews.
There were called "the pogroms".
It became very difficult to stay.
My father came to talk to me.
He told me that I had
to leave, alone,
To save my life.
And that's what I did.
And today...
Is it our turn?
Yes.
And when?
Tonight.
Henri and Albert left this morning
for the free zone.
They will be waiting for you in Nice,
at my friend Saul Levine's house.
And why don't we stay together?
Because that's too dangerous.
We would be noticed.
It's better to separate.
No one will be suspicious
of two little boys.
- And you ?
- We'll leave tomorrow.
Time to close everything.
Next week, we'll all be in Nice.
Good?
So, look...
You're going to the free zone
via Hagetmau.
This is the safest route.
Find the ferryman in Hagetmau.
He works in a restaurant
with blue shutters.
Beware, there are many scammers out there.
Papa made a list with the stations,
the tickets,
points of passage and the appointments.
Memorize it by heart.
No one should see you
with these papers. Never. Okay ?
I'll put it in your bag.
That's 200,000 francs...
for trains and buses.
You will leave Austerlitz railway
station directly to Irun.
- Did you write that down?
- Yes.
Give me that.
The most important:
You must swear to
me that you will never say
to anyone that you are Jewish.
Under any circumstances.
We must be proud of who we are.
But today, it is too dangerous.
And it's not cowardice.
I swear.
Promise.
Jo.
Are you Jewish?
No.
- Are you a Jew?
- No.
Never answer when someone
talks to you in Yiddish.
Tell me you're a Jew.
I know you're a Jew.
Tell me the truth.
I know you're Jewish!
- Are you Jewish?
- No.
- Yes, you're Jewish.
- No !
- I know you're a Jew!
- No, I'm not Jewish!
Excuse me, Jojo.
Sorry.
Better take a slap that hurts...
than you lose your life
because you are afraid of a blow.
Do you understand, my Jojo?
I'm not a Jew.
Come on.
Come on, get dressed darling.
Come here.
Come.
Come on.
I love you.
Lets' go.
No nonsense, eh?
Hey.
Don't worry. With this money
I'll buy you a ton of marbles.
For real?
You're dreaming, dude.
Come on, come on.
It will be fine.
Train to Dax,
is about to depart.
Please move away from
the edge of the track.
There is no room left.
The children...
Let the kids go first.
It's full.
Excuse me.
Sorry. Thank you.
Sorry.
Excuse me.
Excuse me, can we sit here?
Of course.
Thank you.
Excuse me.
- Do you think they are fleeing like us?
- How would I know?
I dunno.
We're going to Dax.
And then to the south.
It had started. We had left.
Our first night without parents.
What exactly were we fleeing from?
Jo. Jo, wake up.
We have a problem.
Honey, hurry up.
What is happening ?
Where is everyone going?
I don't know. There are many
jumping out before stopping.
Come.
Paper...
Psst.
We have no papers Father.
If you radiate fear, they
will notice. So don't be afraid.
Thank you.
Identification card!
Eat that.
Follow us.
Stay calm.
Your papers.
Papers.
I don't understand German.
Fritz!
She's for you.
Is there a problem, sir?"
- So, grandma, come with me.
- Papers?
Go.
Thank you.
Identification card! Now!
Papers.
Yes,
I have lost a lot of
weight, but it is me.
Faster!
"Gott mit uns."
God is with you.
That is beautiful.
With us all, by the way.
Hey, kids?
The children belong to me.
Good. Thank you.
Paper?
We're going, we're going.
You come with us.
- There must be a mistake!
- You have to come.
Let me go.
No, I do not want to follow you.
What are they doing
with that grandmother?
Nothing for you to concern yourself with.
Quick or we'll miss the bus.
A moment please.
Thank you Father
that you lied for us.
I didn't lie. All children
in the world belong to me.
That's all. Go now.
Hurry up.
Hey, psst.
Don't trust anyone, okay?
And smile a little.
You don't get apples every day.
Good luck.
Come on. Let's go.
We're following them.
There's still a spot in the back.
Follow me.
Come on, come on.
Did you see it? There are
many people in that restaurant.
Did you see ? They are
also looking for the ferryman.
If we stay here we're
sure to get caught.
Hey, you looking for a ferryman?
No, I'm fine.
The ferryman comes here at
eight o'clock to pick up people.
His name is Bronchet.
He asks 10,000 francs per person.
20000 francs!
Ergh... yes.
With me, it would be cheaper,
but you're not looking for a ferryman.
How much would it cost?
Just for example...
Let's say...
1000 per person, without negotiation.
And with negotiations?
See you later, Parisians.
We can pay.
Well, what do you know?
Good. You give me half now
and the rest on arrival.
Agreement concluded.
Good.
I will continue with my delivery
round first, then I'll poke a trout...
and we'll meet on that corner
of the street when night falls.
We're not leaving now?
Oh no.
That's too dangerous.
Okay, see you later!
- My name is Raymond.
- Hi, Raymond. Me, it's Jo.
That man was nice, isn't he?
- "Hey Raymond, I'm Jo."
- That will cost us a thousand marbles!
You're joking?
We just saved 18,000.
We're better off here
than in Clignancourt, huh?
Yes, we certainly are.
- I'm going to pee.
- Yes.
Come on.
Come on little one. Come!
Watch out. The Germans!
- I got you.
- Shit.
Your cock is circumcised, isn't it, 'little boy'.
- "Jew, you are."
- You're stupid.
You pissed on it.
Come on, come on.
No, no you're not wiping it on me.
It's almost dark.
What the hell is he doing?
There's no one here anymore.
He went to poke a trout,
didn't you hear that?
And what does that mean?
It sounds disgusting.
I have no idea.
We got ourselves conned by Raymond.
Papa had warned us.
Quick!
Don't move.
Get down.
Look...
They're searching everywhere.
We'll never get out of here.
- I want to see Papa and Maman.
- Calm down.
This is not the time to cry.
We'll wait a little longer.
Damn it.
Hey Parisians! Are you OK?
Come with me.
Go.
Come on, little one.
Come on!
Be careful.
Stand up.
Hey! Psst. This way.
Father Bronchet's been caught.
It had to happen eventually.
He transfers twelve at a time.
They make too much noise.
Please.
We're lost.
Come. Come.
Come down!
I'm with my wife and my mother.
Our ferryman has abandoned us.
I beg you to help us.
It's 1000 per head.
The little one is free, but...
I don't want to hear him. Good?
Very good.
Thank you sir.
"Sir"?
He's funny...
Come on, it's okay. Pass it over.
Go.
Do you see that barn over there?
It's open. The farmer is aware.
Go in. You can sleep on the straw.
Thank you.
Hey, are we in the free zone there?
"In the free zone"?
You've been there for 10 minutes.
- Is that all? Was it that easy?
- Are you disappointed?
I told you.
With me, no danger, and no Germans.
In the free zone...
Free from what exactly?
Are we free to be Jews?
We're free to sleep, dummy.
Twenty kilometers on foot,
wear out, wear out...
it wears out your soles.
Twenty one kilometers on foot,
wear out, wear out...
it wears out your soles.
Twenty two kilometers on foot,
wear out, wear out...
it wears out your soles.
Twenty three kilometers on foot...
- Are you limping?
- No, it's nothing.
- Your foot hurts.
- It's nothing!
Show me. Sit down.
Shit.
You can't walk with that anymore.
It is not worth insisting.
Come on, come on.
Grab your bag.
I'll take you on my back.
Go.
Do you know your feet stink?
Your ass stinks.
But thanks anyway.
That's normal, you're
my little brother.
I would carry you to the end
of the world, if necessary.
Come on, get off. You're too heavy.
- Until the end of the world, huh?
- Oh, you're getting on my nerves...
- What? Are we lazy?
- No, it's my brother...
- My brother is too tired to walk.
- Come on, get in!
Go ahead, get up.
Okay, here we go!
- That's Adolf.
- What are you going to do with it?
What did you think?
We'll make him bleed.
We make black pudding from his blood.
And then rillettes and bacon.
And of course meat.
Turn around, Adolf.
That's her ass.
You don't think that she's
going to shoot at us, huh?
Adolf, kaputt!
Maurice and I changed our route
to avoid highways.
It was too good to be like
that, to travel freely...
like we've never done before.
We ended up forgetting that we
were running away from something.
There were no parents, no school,
And above all, no one
to tell us what to do.
Watch out, little one.
That's not for girls.
We meet all sorts
of people on our journey.
Some more fun than others...
But everyone was afraid.
You could see it in their eyes.
Even though everyone
was pretending.
Oh, look there!
Wow.
I can not believe my eyes.
How blue it is!
Look. We've finally arrived.
Hey boy, you're losing your coat.
Thank you sir.
Hey, I'm taking a picture!
Come on, I don't bite.
I eat you alone...
Come on, you take
your time. The beauty...
Those Italians are more
relaxed than the Germans.
Come on, let's find our parents.
Turnips or Jerusalem artichokes?
Jo.
The beautiful fish!
Hello. Are you looking for something?
Mister Levine's hair salon, please?
It's right there.
Hello.
Oh, the children! Great.
Albert!
Look.
It seems that happiness
passes faster than sadness.
We were finally all together.
The rest did not exist.
He still needs his Maman and Papa.
Especially his father to dry his hair.
You're not cold?
Okay darling ?
Never again do you leave me like that.
Never again. Promised.
Never again.
I was afraid.
We too were afraid.
When you have children of your own,
you will understand.
I'm so proud of you, son.
So proud.
I will always be there in your heart.
Always.
You are crazy!
Go. Watch out.
Watch out.
No.
No no no.
No no. No !
3 MONTHS LATER...
Oh shit.
You could help me, instead of laughing.
I have better things to do.
What shall we do now?
Let's go to the beach.
Is that all?
It fell out.
And the other?
Fallen out. If you don't understand,
trading is not for you.
Tomorrow I need tomatoes.
- Impossible.
- But why?
On Mondays, the Italian
soldiers give me some olive oil.
I trade that for soap,
that I exchange for sugar,
that I exchange for flour,
that I trade for cigarettes.
To find tomatoes for a week,
messes up my organization.
I understand nothing.
If you don't understand,
trading is not for you.
And five.
What are you going
to do with all that money?
I have an idea for that.
Ciao, Marcello!
Too long. Tell Albert to
trim the back of your hair.
Roman, did you know that Jo will
eventually will buy the Excelsior Hotel?
- Were you still at the market this morning?
- Yes.
And school ?
It's Thursday, Papa.
- You don't miss school, do you?
- No, I won't.
It's not possible.
Stop speaking Yiddish.
How often do I have to say that?
Relax, Roman.
Enjoy the beautiful sun.
Look at these two crickets.
The war isn't over yet.
You never know.
You see everything in black.
I see everything in black.
I said nothing.
No, he did not say anything.
I distrust everything.
I hear terrible stories
about the camps.
We're in no danger.
The Italians are soldiers, not killers.
Tell him, Marcello.
That's true. We don't
kill women and children.
No, you certainly don't kill women.
You break their hearts.
What do you want too?
I love the charm of the French.
Their seriousness turns
me on. Come on, play!
Belote, rebelote and profit!
What do you say to that?
Well done, Papa.
Orders in Italian
What's the matter ?
Mussolini was arrested.
- It's chaos in Rome.
- What's going to happen?
We're going back to Italy tomorrow.
- The holiday is over.
- Yes...
Seriously...
Does it mean the war is over?
No. That means the
Germans are coming.
Don't tell Maman.
Do not spoil her surprise.
Okay.
- More cake...
- No, take some pie. There is enough.
But what is this ?
Is that for me ?
Yes.
What is that, then?
But you're crazy...
You should not have done that...
I didn't do it, it's from the boys.
From you? Jo.
This is not for you,
it's for me.
I miss hearing you play.
But I don't know how to play anymore, darling.
Of course you do.
Go.
You know... My father
gave me my first violin.
I played...
And you recited poems.
Poems?
Which poems?
Poems of love. Hey?
Love Poems!
Here.
That's what we want to hear!
Oh no.
Yes, yes, yes.
Yes, yes.
I don't remember them anymore.
And I want to hear your mother play.
Go ahead, darling.
Police ! Open up!
Hide yourselves, children!
Don't open it.
Mrs. Joffo? We have a
summons for Henri and Albert.
I'm not Mrs. Joffo.
We're not at 6, rue Pairolière?
I beg you, think.
We don't have a choice.
- I'll stay alone. Go now.
- Stop!
I've had enough of this...
Hide yourself.
Think of the children.
It's the police!
Go ahead, go.
Open up! It's the police!
We heard you.
I'm coming.
What are you doing ?
Yes?
Henri and Albert Joffo
Live here?
Yes.
But they're not here.
I am their father. Can I help you?
There is a call for the CLS,
the Compulsory Labor Service.
They are expected
tomorrow at this address.
Very good.
I will give it to them. Good night.
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
Wait.
Did you play the violin?
Not at all.
No, not me. I took a nap.
He took a nap.
- Are you making fun of us?
- Absolutely not.
Are you alone?
I don't know. I was sleeping.
Show me your papers, sir.
Hurry up.
Let's go. Let's go.
Sir.
Was that Jewish music we heard, huh?
- Jewish?
- Yes, Jewish.
Yes or no?
- I don't know.
- Is there a problem, honey?
- Hello, sir.
- Sir wonders...
how I'd rather go to sleep
while you play the violin. Me too...
Wait a minute, wait a minute!
Do you play?
Yes I do. See!
Don't you like music, sir?
No, he likes music,
but not Jewish music.
Ah... okay.
Oh, I understand. But I'm
Russian and I'm proud of that.
And my maiden name is Markov.
I am a descendant of the
Imperial Romanov family.
It is insulting to say that
I play Jewish music, sir.
Yes...
You pass the CLS papers
to Henri and Albert.
- We'll do that.
- Good. Have A Nice Day.
- Thank you.
- Madam...
We gotta get out of here.
One two. One two. One two.
One two. One two.
There's plenty to do.
Here, take your brother's...
You are the boss now.
You promised we would stay together.
I didn't think you would be liars.
Calm down.
There is no other way.
If we could, we would stay with
you, but we have no choice.
I don't want us to separate.
I want to go back to Paris.
Stop it, Jo.
For us it's difficult too.
I want to be with you.
That's enough, Jojo.
Pull yourself together. If we all start
crying, it will be useless.
We cannot stay together.
It's too dangerous.
You have to move forward
now and don't look back.
We must go now.
We will meet soon.
Come on, come on.
Come.
Come on.
Is this a camp for collaborators, sir?
It is a government camp for minors,
So he is a Petainist.
Do not worry.
Most of the people here
are not really Catholic.
But they pretend.
You're Catholic, aren't you?
- Of course, sir.
- Yes.
You will find out for
yourself who you can't trust.
It's pretty obvious.
Gérard, would you like to give a tour?
Follow me, toads.
Every morning we
get up at six o'clock.
Hey! Here's a small gift.
- What's that for?
- For your ears.
Go upstairs to the dormitory.
We have to be on our guard here.
Never say that you're Jewish.
We're not Jewish.
That's what I thought.
We're not, either.
Didn't you understand?
There are no Jews here.
"Schmock."
Do not worry.
We are among us.
Watch out for Gerard and his gang there.
He's a real cunt.
I already understood that.
And him?
Him? He's Ange.
A foreigner. From Algeria.
Are you talking about me, or I'm dreaming?
Hi, newbies.
You come from Africa?
From Africa. He thinks I'm out
the jungle come to the elephants.
I am from Algiers.
And why are you here?
Actually, you see...
I was at my brother's in Paris,
And during this time the
English landed in Algeria.
- And thus?
- So I'm stuck in France.
And besides, my brother met
a girl. Then he put me here.
So you miss your parents.
Frankly, not at all.
My father is always behind
me and calls me a donkey.
Donkey here, donkey there.
I've had enough of that.
Oh, are you okay, chicken?
Donkey, huh?
Follow me.
SEPTEMBER 1943
We raise our heads.
One two. One two.
One two.
I'm telling you, the
Krauts are everywhere.
They need their quota of
Jews to take to Germany.
There is panic in Nice.
We're better here.
- How so? Are you Jewish?
- I? No. How so. You?
No.
I am.
Just kidding.
Boy, you should have seen your faces!
That's me: the best.
Attention !
What happened ?
Is he crazy? He almost hit us!
Shit.
I'm sorry, but with the mud and rain,
it doesn't slow down.
In addition, the steering
wheel is on the right.
But it's okay. You can eat puree.
Puree yourself! Here!
Come on.
Puree, you yourself.
Just go.
Stop. Here, take that!
No !
Bring it back!
This way. Come on, we're hurrying.
Come on!
What's the matter ?
Have you heard the new one?
Catch the Germans, Jews everywhere.
Eventually they will arrive here too.
So what?
Aren't we Catholic?
Yes...
Joseph Joffo, resident of Clignancourt,
right in the Jewish quarter...
They just have to watch
you take a piss to confirm.
- The penis?
I'm not a kid anymore.
What do you call that?
Bah... The "zboub".
"The 'zboub'."
Who told you that ?
- Angie.
- The Algerian?
Yes.
We just say we
come from there too.
From Algeria?
Well yeah. The same
story he told.
The journey, the
landing, everything.
Yes, that's a good idea.
They won't be able to check.
You're not that stupid are you...
Hey Joffo, move your ass over here!
Okay Algerian, show us what you
have in your belly.
Next one!
Hey, Joffo!
If we tell that, where do we live?
- Rue Jean-Jaures 10.
- What about Jean-Jaures?
Because there's always a
Jean-Jaures street and it's easy to remember.
The rest remains as it is is:
the house, the drawing room...
Papa is a hairdresser,
Maman plays the violin.
Then we cannot make any mistakes.
Come on. Come on!
You're not too stupid, either.
Come on, you follow.
We accelerate!
Come on!
- Ouch!
- Let's practice it.
Where do you go to school, 'little boy'?"
Rue Jean-Jaurès.
In the same street where...
- What is your mother's name?
- Anne Marie.
- And your father?
- Roman.
That's good.
Come on, let's go.
I miss them.
Me too.
It's not normal,
that we don't hear from them.
Maybe they're
suspicious of the phone.
I want to see them.
- We don't know where they are.
- So what? I want to see them!
We're accelerating a bit here.
Guys, tell me, do you
have family in Nice?
- No, let's go for a walk.
- Walk around?
Are you going to the Promenade
des Anglais to see the girls?
Yes that's it.
Don't say stupid things,
that he doesn't believe.
You don't have to be
ashamed when you look at girls.
In a few years they will be looking
at you too. You're good looking enough.
Watch out!
That's sensational, isn't it!
Wow! Go on.
We're gonna look at the girls!
WE WILL WATCH THE GIRLS!
WE WILL SEE GIRLS!
This is not the market...
I need two minutes.
Wait for me. I will return.
Wait here, huh?
I'm counting on you.
Shh.
It's not funny. Open your door.
How do you do that?
Don't you know how open a door?
- Don't you get tired of doing nothing?
- No...
He's been gone for a while.
What the hell is he doing?
He said to wait.
Come on, stay.
You're waiting for me.
Above all, you do not move.
I'll tell him we're going
to the market on foot.
Jo.
Are you okay?
- Okay, okay.
- Sit up.
You promised not to move.
I'm sorry.
Children! You say nothing.
Quickly.
Meyer, Martha.
Hurry.
There's one more coming.
Dreyfuss, Louis.
Goldman, Gabriel.
Epstein, Doris.
Goldman, Mordecai.
Abel, Adele.
Walk! Walk!
Abou, Gabriel.
Saul, Levin.
It's Levine.
Goldfarb, Michael.
And do you see Maman and Papa?
Usually, I begin by asking
name, first name and religion.
But here I am lost.
Why all these false papers?
Are you Jewish?
No.
Are you not a Jew?
So...
You are a resistance fighter.
No.
We slaughter all resistance fighters.
These are the orders.
In German:
He is a resistance fighter.
Unless you are Jew...
No.
Yes, I am a Jew.
Is that what you want to know?
I am Jewish.
And also a resistance fighter.
Jew and resistance fighter.
Kill me if you want.
It will not change anything.
You will not win the war.
You have already lost the war.
I am Jew and resistance fighter.
And I shit on you!
Stop!
He is a resistance fighter.
Next.
Name, first name, religion.
David Cohen, I'm a Jew.
Next.
Name, first name, religion.
Listen, we have nothing to do with all this.
We are from 'Moissons Nouvelles'.
Name, first name, religion.
Maurice Joffo, Catholic.
We just went with Ferdinand to go shopping.
It is a mistake, sir.
- We have nothing to do with it.
- Is that your brother ?
Yes, it's my brother Jo.
Jo... Like Joseph?
Yes.
Our mother's name is Marie.
I see.
So you're not a Jew?
No, I already told you that.
Stop! We are Algerians!
Catholic Algerians.
We'll start again.
Are you Jewish?
No.
No!
Stop!
Let go of me.
To the medical examination!
You say you are Catholic?
Yes.
Yes, in Algeria we do
this as a precaution.
Otherwise adhesions will occur.
Yes sir.
They circumcise everyone's 'zboub'.
The Algerians, the Catholics: everyone.
Even the Jews.
That I do not know.
There are not many Jews there.
I've never seen one.
On my word: that is the truth.
Sit down.
My name is Rosen.
Know you what that means?
No.
That you are pink?
No, I am a Jew.
So you can tell me, to me,
That you too are Jews.
- You are Jew, but we are not.
- We are Algerian.
That's why our 'zboub' is circumcised.
So, Jewish or not, you
know what you have to do.
Guard!
It's medical, not religious.
Please...
Go.
Next.
I will always wonder why the doctor...
had saved us.
While every day he had
to condemn hundreds.
On the Rue Jean-Jaures, as
I have already told you.
The name of the school?
The primary school in Algeria.
The Jean-Jaurès school, I think.
That's all ?
Well, yes, I think.
I didn't pay attention to it.
It's just the school, isn't it?
Friends at school?
Yes a lot.
Zerati is my best friend.
He is very good with marbles.
Zerti...
Zerati.
He is good with marbles.
- And what games do you play at school?
- Everything.
Playing tag, hide and seek,
thief with redemption...
with marbles...
there are many:
marble pit, bowling, target shooting...
the hole, the pyramid...
What have I done?
Listen to me, little one...
I know when someone
is not telling the truth.
And you lie.
And your baptism?
Where was it?
At the great church of Algiers, surely?
No. Here in Nice, at the Buffa.
Mama wanted to have the family there.
That's why she preferred it here.
Very good.
That should be easy to verify.
A pass for 48 hours!
You have two days to get your
baptismal certificates.
If you're not back within 48 hours...
I send your little brother
on the next train.
Do you understand?
I didn't know what to say.
I don't know of any
churches in Algiers.
If it turns out you can't
make it, then don't come back.
One alive is better
than two dead, I think.
Do not say that.
I will return with false papers.
It's mission impossible.
Save yourself.
Shut up.
I will be back.
- Jo. Something wrong?
- I am tired.
It has been going on for a week.
I'm fed up with this bullshit.
- I want it to stop.
- Listen to me.
- As long as there's hope we hold on.
- Hang on, Jo.
Maurice Joffo!
Listen to me.
I will return. Do you hear me?
I'm coming back for you. Promise.
Maman...
No, leave me alone!
Maman.
Leave me alone!
Maman !
Papa...
Jo.
Papa ?
No, not really, Joseph.
Papa, I didn't say anything.
Do not say anything. You have
been delirious, but you are saved.
Sulfonamides have been effective.
Dr. Rozen?
You are lucky.
Meningitis is often fatal.
And my brother? Maurice?
- How many days have I been here?
- Two, three days.
You are cured,
that is the most important.
Yes. That's how it is.
That way I can board
the train in good health.
Listen to me carefully.
I'm the one who's going.
I'm going to get on the
train with everyone else later.
It's better that way.
You know, Joseph,
Sometimes we do things in life,
which we are not always proud of.
Here.
You held her tight in your fist, like that...
So...
Throughout your delirium.
You were attached to it.
That's all I have left from before.
If you keep fighting...
then keep your life in
your fist like this one.
Then you'll be fine.
What's the use of living?
It's a matter of chance.
It's stupid.
Stupid.
Stu...
Joseph...
Death did not want you twice.
That means you have a
good reason to live.
Do something with your
life, Joseph. Be proud of it.
Come on, you owe me that.
Goodbye, Joseph.
These are fakes.
Not at all, I assure you.
The Archbishop can testify that
these are authentic certificates.
I do not believe you.
Why ?
I recognize the truth when I see her.
And when I look at you...
Do you know what I see then?
The certificates of the priest
from Buffa, I gave to the Krauts.
I alerted Subinagui too.
He's coming for us.
And... Papa and Maman?
The salon is closed.
It does not matter.
We'll get out of here and
we'll find them one day.
Why do you bother about them?
They are Jewish.
- I put my hand in the fire.
- It's obsession.
But that doesn't change anything.
They lie.
And you too.
The Archbishop
The Archbishop does not want two
children judged on mere assumptions.
He will inform Rome.
You don't want it do you?
Have a pontificate against you?
Certainly not now.
We shall see.
Understood!
Hey brothers! Go get
me tomatoes from the garden.
I don't understand
why they won't let us go.
Come.
You see that vegetable garden?
It's very easy to escape from there.
There's more to that.
Here, there?
Really, very easy.
Maurice... look.
You vouch for their
innocence, don't you?
Did you see ?
Yes.
Let's go ?
We're going, on three.
One...
Two...
Three, go.
Watch out!
There's a soldier.
It's a trap.
Thank you, Father.
You saved our lives.
Mr. Subinagui!
Hello, children.
Thank you, Father.
You were brave.
I only did my duty.
Go in peace, my children.
Come on. We must not hang around here.
Jo.
Farewell, Father.
Go. Go.
What are you moaning about...
Papa !
Where is Maman ?
Your mother is with her sister,
And your brothers, in Savoy.
I stayed to find you.
What is that ?
Better a slap that hurts,
rather than never see you again.
Papa promised us we
would meet in Paris
Once the war was over.
But, for now, it was too
dangerous to stay together.
Maurice?
Jo. Jo, wake up.
Your Maman's on the phone.
Hi Maman ?
It's me.
"My darling, are you okay?"
You have to leave right away.
Your father has the
same illness you did.
Meningitis ?
Worse than that.
Hello?
I understood that she was
talking about Papa's arrest,
But I no longer had tears.
They were replaced with anger.
Again, we had to flee.
I can carry you, if you want.
Rather die.
I'm the big brother.
I'm the one who carries.
We were in touch
with the others lost.
But that wasn't a big deal.
Because if Maurice and I
had already arrived there,
then Papa sure would be.
Everything was going to be fine.
You had to believe in that.
While waiting for the end of the war,
Maurice and I had a job.
Just like Maman told us to do.
Any job.
Maurice worked in the
largest restaurant nearby...
and I was a delivery person for
the bookseller, Ambroise Mancelier.
You see, Joseph,
you won't learn anything
at a public school,
because public school
has become like a girl...
What characterizes the great minds,
is to have an ideal.
And there aren't 36 things to do.
No, there is only one thing to do for Europe.
And they are three great minds,
my dear Joseph, that Europe has made:
Louis XIV,
Napoleon Bonaparte
and Philippe Pétain.
"I keep my promises,
even those of others."
Oh, that's beautiful...
Congratulations, my little Joseph.
My son.
Here. Bravo.
Look.
You do good work every now
and then, in the Militia.
MILITIA EXPORTS 20,000 JEWS
It's just the beginning.
France for the French, Papa.
Wait a second boy...
You sleep under my roof and have been
working with me, for almost six months.
So you're part of the family, right?
Yes sir.
Your parents must miss you,
being so far away from you, in Algeria.
Yes, a lot.
As of today, you will eat with us...
but from Sunday you will also share
in something that is very dear to us...
the Holy Mass.
I understand that you are not
very devoted to the mass.
It is time you did as our Christian faith teaches.
Yes.
Thank you, Mr. Mancelier.
Newspaper!
'La Gerbe', 'La Proche',
'Je Suis Partout'!
'La Gerbe', 'Le Petit Dauphinois',
'Je Suis Partout', the newspaper!
Who wants the newspaper?
Let's see, little one.
Oh no, thank you.
'La Gerbe', 'Le Dauphinois'!
'Je Suis Partout'!
La Gerbe. The newspaper ?
The Dauphinois!  La Gerbe!
I'm everywhere!
Good morning, Ms. Loca.
Oh! Sorry.
My brakes are not working.
I take the  Gerbe.
La Gerbe ?
Yes.
Thank you. Have a good day.
The Vichy newspaper, Mr. Julien?
La Gerbe ?  I'm everywhere ?
Over my dead body.
Here, keep your newspaper. Is he
still always so stupid, that Mancelier?
Always.
Hello. Here, the newspapers.
Hey, Jo!
Shh.
The penguin flaps its wings.
The Penguin
- What is this?
- The penguin flaps its wings.
Encoded messages for the Resistance.
The ghost doesn't talk.
Good. I'm going because
Mancelier will call me.
By the way, how is she,
the girl of the collaborators?
Why do you want to know that ?
Still in love with
your little Francoise?
What does that mean?
5 months that you look at her?
Has she talked with you or not?
I'm making progress...
And you, your entrance into the Resistance,
are you making any progress?
Don't start on that.
Do they send you coded messages?
Yes
"Françoise has hair on her legs.
I repeat: Françoise has..."
You're really miserable!
The Militia!
Maurice, hide everything.
You send the message.
Hold on.
Lets' go.
Its good.
Jo, give that to sir Jean
in the factory. Come on!
Nobody moves.
You stay here.
Maureler, hurry.
- We are here.
I'll take the floor.
Search it all.
Show me.
What have you got in here?
What are you hiding?
Remove your hand.
What's this ?
Empty your pockets.
- Me ?
- Yes, yes, you.
I have the impression that you are
a rat and are hiding something.
Go away. Here's your marble.
Don't come here anymore.
Understood?
So what?
What are you doing here?
With what right do you
come inside people's homes?
Who is he?
The newspaper delivery boy.
He wants to talk to Mr. Jean.
What do you want to say to him?
Paul, at the Hotel du Commerce,
gave me something for him.
What does Paul look like?
Pretty big, round glasses,
hair brushed to the side.
Give me the message.
I have to give it to Mr. Jean.
I am Mr. Jean.
Go.
Come on, hand it over.
It's him, give it to him.
Take over.
Follow me.
Close the door.
There is water in the gas.
"The Chamois of the Alps jumps."
We've been waiting for that for a while.
Congratulations, little one. Well done.
Maryse will tell you if
we ever need you again.
Come on.
Attention, Francoise, it's hot.
Yes!
Yes !
Hello. I'm sorry for the delay.
You lost yourself in the attic?
- Shut the door, please.
- Yes, excuse me.
What are you doing here?
Well, Mr. Mancelier...
- You get out.
- Leave him alone.
It was Papa who invited him.
And here is the beast!
- There you go.
- Joseph, at the table.
Sit yourself next to Raoul, over there.
I raise my glass... to all mothers
And to all the women who
will bare children in their bellies,
for the France of tomorrow.
Happy birthday, ladies.
Thank you.
"You are the inspiration of
our Christian civilization."
- Who said that?
- Marshal Petain, papa.
Exactly.
How can we treat "sold" men
who glorified Mother's Day?
My God, help the Marshal to resist.
And Adolf Hitler.
If one had allied himself to him in 1936,
with Franco and Mussolini,
England would not have fired
and Europe was ours.
Anyway.
And we did not?
Because our government had become rotten
by Jewish vermin.
Hitler did a good job.
There's no other way.
Be up to the challenge.
In any case, we're going to
exterminate them, these rats.
They may hide in their holes,
they will all go through it.
In the meantime, help us to drink.
My brother, he's a jerk.
He is anti-everything.
Anti-republican, anti-communist,
anti-capitalist...
Antisemitic.
That too, yes, more than anything else.
He thinks like your father.
Well yeah.
They're the same, those two.
I, too, think like my father.
Who is your father?
You never talk about him.
Well, that's my father.
You are mysterious,
you and your brothers.
True, we do wonder what you hide.
That, "we"
Me and my girlfriends.
Francoise. Listen.
I have to tell you something.
I don't have the right to say it,
but I can tell it to you.
Because I trust you.
Are you sure you're okay?
Yes.
Well, go ahead. I'm listening to you.
I am...
Do not worry, I get it.
Come on.
Come quickly. Quick.
Hurry up.
Go up the stairs.
Hey, you.
The.
It's my brother.
Aim.
Fire!
Freedom,
Equality, Fra...
Take them away.
Fortunately they did not take you,
the Resistance.
You might be dead now.
Imagine having to tell our parents?
And Henry and Albert?
It's the English.
No, it's the Americans.
You know what that means?
We'll see them soon.
Death to the Militia!
You will pay for all
those who have died.
Death to the collaborators!
Band of bastards!
You want to give France
back to England? Cretin!
The English are the historic enemy.
Not the Germans.
Species of imbeciles!
What are we going to do ?
It's Waterloo, we lost.
Be careful Françoise,
that glass will cut you.
The little one, Ambroise,
must be protected.
You must take Françoise
to my sister's house.
Your daughter, your mother, your sister!
I do not care !
I know what it's like
to leave, you know.
Everyone in my family had
to leave at one time.
My father said, "Do not look
behind you when you walk.
"Otherwise we break our mouths."
I'm sure you're like your father.
It's not true !
Joseph! Joseph!
What's happening now?
Misery...
Paris is liberated!
Attention. Paris is liberated!
Attention.
Paris is liberated!
Attention
Read the newspaper! Paris is liberated!
The newspaper! Paris is liberated!
Paris is liberated! They left!
They're gone, Jojo.
They left.
They're gone, it's over.
Look, they're going to Paris.
Go get your brother.
My dear fellow-citizens,
today is a big day.
We are finally free!
Sleeping with the Germans!
Treacherous!
Jo!
Maurice!
Do you believe it?
No. It's finally over.
Come. Cars are going back to Paris.
- What?
- There's room for us.
Go get your things.
We're going back.
No, I cannot.
Go yourself.
I'll meet you later.
You're sure?
What would you do?
We're free, are we not?
We're free, yes.
Tell our parents I'm
coming and I love them.
Are you going to cope, all by yourself?
And you?
You're gonna get away without me?
Come on, go find her.
Francoise!
No. Stop! Stop!
Stop! Stop!
Stop! He hid a Jew!
What are you saying ?
Is that true Jo ?
It's true.
That bastard would never hide a Jew.
I swear to you.
And who then?
Me.
I am Jewish.
I am Jewish!
I am Jewish! I am Jewish!
Did he know?"
Of course he knew.
Nevertheless, he is a collaborator.
He did it so he would
not be suspected.
We're embarking.
Go to the hole,
and wait for the judge.
And Marcelle, we'll
shave her head anyway.
Thank you.
Where is she, Francoise?
Francoise, wait!
Francoise!
Papa?
Papa!
Maman!
Maman, Jojo is back!
Maman, it's me!
Jojo!
Maurice, your brother is here!
Papa.
Papa, do you remember?
You told me that when
a good man dies,
a star in the sky lights up,
and one had to keep hope.
Well, that's true.
You're here, papa, and
you'll always be.
In April 1944, Anna, Albert and Henri were arrested
in their flight, then interned in the Drancy camp.
Due to a lack of trains,
they narrowly escaped deportation.
The Red Cross released them shortly before
the Americans arrived in August 1944.
The family was thus able to return to Paris.
Roman, brought by convoy no. 62 to Auschwitz
in November 1943, never returned.
In 1945, Joseph and Maurice took over their father's hairdressing salon
with their brothers, thus perpetuating the family tradition.
They still live in Paris, surrounded by their children and grandchildren.
Subtitles: Eclair Media