How's the situation over in
Phnom Penh?
A lot of personnel changes.
The situation can still be
considered stable.
Sir, you can't take my money
I know that is my fault
The money is very important
to me for saving a life.
Can you give it back to me?
Thank you.
What's up?
Cheung Chi-Mun
You're free to leave prison.
Mark
I was supposed to pick you
up at the airport...
Instead you picked me up at
prison
Where's Dad?
Uncle's waiting for you at
the drug store.
Yesterday I almost lost my
life at the airport.
If I hadn't paid them off,
we'd be meeting inside the
prison.
When those customs officers
see money,
their eyes light up like car
headlights.
Mark, you went through a lot
of trouble for me.
Pedicab
It's a good thing they like
money.
Otherwise you'd still be
rotting in jail.
Bye-bye
"Bye-bye"
Is that "goodbye" in
Vietnamese?
They don't know what you're
saying
In Hong Kong, what do you
hear about the war?
We've got a piece of news
black-out, don't know a thing
The radio and newspapers
all report...
...the Viet Cong are very
close to the city.
The situation is terrible.
It's good you've come back.
Help me persuade Dad.
He's not convinced that the
situation is bad.
You said there's a news
black-out here.
How can anybody know what's
going on?
The city looks peaceful
enough.
Mun, didn't you apply for
Uncle's visa?
The line outside immigration
goes on forever.
You get nowhere without
bribes.
The Chinese have been here
for decades.
Asking them to shut down
their businesses...
...is worse than killing
them.
Why do you think I worked
in the black market?
Only to get him a passport.
And it all came to nothing.
Which one of us gets them?
They're yours
Hello
How are you?
War mongers, go home
Let's make a fast turn
The pedicab's broken down.
- Get off and push
Great
Chicken buttocks
Pat, get the soy sauce.
Uncle, here's some wine.
I put Chinese wine in a
foreign brandy bottle.
Almost got confiscated in
customs.
Drink up so it won't go to
waste. - Yeah
You're clever to put the
wine in a brandy bottle.
Mainland Chinese products
aren't allowed in.
You've to remove the label
or change the bottle.
Did you go to Mainland China
to see your Dad?
How can I go there now?
It's chaos there with the
Cultural Revolution.
Even if I went, I wouldn't
know how to find him.
We've been separated for
over ten years.
Uncle, I bought this at the
China Products Store.
This is good wine
Delicious
Pat
Not fish sauce. I hate fish
sauce.
I want soy sauce
The black stuff
Get going
Soy sauce.
Who's that kid?
At New Years when the Viet
Cong entered Hue,
he was separated from his
parents.
I took pity on him and took
him in.
When I asked him his name,
he just stammered.
I didn't understand what
he said.
So I call him Pat.
Dad
What was Dad gabbing about?
We need money to get Dad
out of here.
I was already arrested by
them once.
A second time would be very
dangerous.
But there's a war going on.
It's dangerous no matter
what you do.
Anyway, nothing ventured
nothing gained.
Who are you looking for?
My ex-boss went to Thailand.
When I was in prison, Chung
told me of new buyer.
Miss Chow Ying-Kit.
I'm familiar with Saigon.
May be I'll recognise this
Chow.
Which one of us gets her?
She's mine
She's responding
Not the reaction we hoped
for
Are you Cheung Chi-Mun?
Hello, Mr. Chow
Hello.
This is my cousin Mark.
Let's go over there.
Mr. Cheung, you've just
gotten out of prison.
You're fast at making
connections.
What's your connection with
Bong?
Chung introduced me.
Chung?
- Yes.
I can tell the soldiers
outside...
...to use you for target
practice
What's the matter?
They're looking for Chow
Ying-Kit.
These two guys are friends
of mine.
Let me talk to them.
It's Ok.
Leave
Does she know us?
This is your territory. Why
ask me?
You're looking for Chow Ying
Kit?
He's "10th Uncle", the boss
here.
I'm Chow Ying-Kit.
Bong is a complicated
fellow.
He doesn't need you for
the black market.
There's lots of other ways
to make money.
Why choose this path?
You've been in prison.
If Bong cheats you...
...and you're arrested again
You'll never see HK again.
I've done business with
Bong twice.
He could have betrayed me
long ago.
You say that Bong's
complicated.
In this business, aren't
we all?
Mr. Cheung.
You're an outsider.
We're all Chinese.
A piece of advice for you.
Don't get involved in things
you can't control.
Good-bye.
Miss Chow.
Please don't blame us for
our ignorance.
He's an overseas Chinese.
We're doing this for my
uncle.
You know now these old
Chinese are.
They struggle all their
lives to get ahead
If I can't get them out of
here,
and they stay, what is it
all for?
So I've come back to take
them to Hong Kong.
I don't want to gamble like
this.
You've seen this country.
Everyone gambles.
Including this war.
Nobody knows what tomorrow
will bring
Our gambling chips...
...are being played by
others.
We have no control over who
wins or loses.
Not even a choice over
whether to play or not.
If this were our own place,
we wouldn't need to leave.
Everyone here tonight is
escaping.
To leave or to stay,
it's all a gamble.
You're very capable.
If you don't serve as the
casino's banker,
we won't even have a chance
to gamble.
You said that all of us are
Chinese.
Try to see it from our
perspective.
Tell us what to do.
According to my usual
practice,
I never conduct business
here.
As to the time and place,
I'll have someone contact
you.
What are you doing?
I'll have someone contact
you.
Don't bother. I'll answer it
It's just the phone Why so
anxious?
It's Mun's girlfriend.
Asking him to have a last
fling.
Then what are you so nervous
about?
Me?
Waiting for your girlfriend,
too?
Mun and I met that girl at
the same time.
So part of the fling should
be mine.
I'm going over now for my
phone fling.
His Dad and I used to be
just like that, too.
It's hard to escape the
tender trap
What are you laughing at?
You don't even know what
I'm talking about
Take your dinner
Let me have the phone
- Come on
Hello, Miss Chow.
Hello?
Hello? Hello?
Why isn't she saying
anything?
She already hung up.
- Playing tricks on me
What's up?
Tonight at 8:30 at the
Alhambra Theatre.
Miss Chow, it's getting late
still want to wait?
This car's from the Foreign
Ministry.
They wouldn't dare to do
anything rash.
Don't try anything
We have a permit from the
Foreign Ministry.
Bong, Bong. - You haven't
stopped the car yet
Mum Mum
Hello
We've been waiting for you
a long time.
This is Hung.
Please excuse us for being
late, Miss Chow.
Miss Chow Ying-kit is the
buyer I told you about
This is my cousin, Mark.
Miss Chow, this is Bong.
Pleased to meet you.
Let me help you with this.
Move out of the way Over
there
You, too. Hurry up
Have a smoke.
Let them conduct a thorough
search.
Have some gum and then
search him.
Come on
Hurry up
Go where?
Upstairs.
Make a thorough search.
Search upstairs.
Mark, stay here. II'll stop
Bong from getting away.
Don't go there. It's too
dangerous.
The army is on its way up.
Sooner or later we'll have
to make our escape.
Cover me. I'll get the gold
back.
No bullets left
Take a jump, Mun
Forget about the money.
Let's get out of here.
What about Miss Chow?
How's Miss Chow?
Over there
Mark
Mark Mark
Mark, are you Ok?
Very proud of yourself,
aren't you?
Did you see Bong's
expression?
You certainly earned your
commission.
Otherwise, why go to so much
trouble?
I worship you more than any
other woman on earth
Miss Chow,
Let me return this to you.
I hope I didn't get your
lipstick dirty.
I forgot all about it
I'd never thought you'd take
such good care of it
Old songs always make for
great listening.
Proof that old things are
better than new ones.
Do you agree with me?
"10th Uncle"
What are you trying to say?
I think you still remember
Mr. Ho.
He made you what you are
today.
Could you ever forget him?
Ho disappeared in Holland
3 years ago.
I miss him very much.
If it weren't for him,
I wouldn't have the success
I have today.
You don't have to remind me.
What is Ho's relationship
to you?
More than ten years ago,
when Ho was just starting
out,
he came into the bar one
night.
I was singing in the bar
at the time.
I thought...
just one man against ten...
I acted on impulse and
grabbed a knife.
I saved his life.
Afterwards,
I travelled the world with
him.
We were together a long time
He was not only my lover,
but also my confidante.
Now,
his enemies are out to kill
him,
so he's disappeared for 3
years.
Do you know what it feels
like...
...too lose someone dear?
The dearest person to me is
my father.
I don't know what's happened
to him.
Nobody knows if he's alive
or dead.
All these years, everything
I've done...
has been for my uncle and
my cousin Mun.
I don't dare have any hopes
for myself.
I only know...
the bigger the hopes,
the greater the
disappointment.
Actually, hopes are just
a big gamble.
If you lose, it's very
painful.
I'd rather not even try.
Before, when I was poor...
I just wanted to make it
big.
Now,
I have money, position,
everything but a close
friend.
It's hard to make it to the
top, but impossible to
go back.
There are many things, I can
look back & observe,
but I can't go back.
Since you don't expect too
much,
you should be happier than
me.
It's been a long time since
I talked so much
Really?
- Yes
Later on, please don't cry
What's the use of going back
In 1997 Hong Kong will be
handed over to China.
We'll just have to come back
here.
Vietnam has been at war for
many years.
The situation here is no
worse than before.
Uncle, it's 1974. 23 years
until 1997.
That's a long time.
Might as well go back for
a look.
Yeah
Let's go.
It's all a matter of fate.
Everthing is pre-ordained.
Mark, the taxi's waiting.
We're carrying a lot of cash
Will customs give us trouble
Don't worry. Kit knows those
guys.
She'll arrange matters for
us at the airport.
The signboard has been here
for over 20 years.
I can't bear to leave it
behind.
Pat
Be careful
The camera
Turn off the lights
I almost forgot we weren't
coming back
Uncle, I'll pack it for you.
This money for you. Don't
waste it.
I'll come back when things
have settled down.
Take good care of your
your health.
Don't forget to close the
windows at night.
Wipe away the dust when you
have time.
It's up to you to take care
of this big place.
On clear days, take the
medicine out to dry.
We're running out of time,
Dad. Hurry up.
The taxi meter is running.
Let the medicine get mouldy.
Why are you so reluctant to
leave this shop?
I'll get you a new one in
Hong Kong.
Does he even understand what
you're saying?
He understands more than you
I looked at the sign,
and he knew to take it down.
Why didn't you take it down?
So what if he took it down.
Now it's up to me to get it
to the airport.
Let's go The plane won't
wait for us.
Why are you so impatient?
Go by yourself.
I'll tell Pat to hang it
back up.
I'm not going.
I went to a lot of trouble
to get your exit permit
Don't make all of us miss
the plane
If you still have
instruction on the medicine.
You can write a detailed
letter from Hong Kong.
You have no sentiment for
the past
Ok, I'm going.
We've reached already.
I'll go in and get a luggage
cart. - Be careful
This signboard has given me
lots of troubles.
Be careful with that
sigboard.
Mun
It's a pleasure to see you.
Where's Mark?
He went over there to look
for you.
Kit, we've a lot of US
dollars on us.
Will we have any problems?
- I'll find a way.
I'm mun's Dad.
Uncle, I'm Chow Ying-kit.
Miss Chow.
- Nice to meet you.
I'll go look for Mark.
Mun, is she the "last fling"
Dad, what do you mean by
"last fling"?
She's going with us.
Don't jinx us by saying
unlucky things.
Wait for me here.
Kit
What's the matter?
There are a lot of new
people in Customs.
Don't worry, it'll be Ok.
I'll take a look to see
whether I know such people.
Get in line first.
Don't push
Don't take too long. Time
to board the plane.
Officer, have a drink on me
Trying to bribe me?
Just what do you think you
are trying to do?
Get out of the way
He has heart trouble
Don't push him.
Dad
Uncle
Don't ruin it
Dad
Uncle
Hurry Help him sit down.
- Dad, where's your medicine?
Dad
Uncle
Mun, hurry up.
Passengers on Flight 175,
please board immediately.
I'm afraid I won't make it.
You'll make it to Hong Kong
for sure, Uncle.
Attention, passengers on
Flight 175,
please board the plane
immediately.
Dad, I found it. Take your
medicine. Hurry
You'll be fine once you
swallow it.
Dad, how are you?
Dad
He took our passports
Take care of him
Mark
Don't
Get up Acting to be pityful
Come on
Get up Acting like a dog
Dad, you're alright?
Come on Come on
We'll all die together.
Get up
Mark?
Hit me Hit me
Come on
He's... He's repacking the
suitcases.
Can we go?
Very soon We'll be back
in Hong Kong soon.
Kit
You're Ok?
Fine
Better get on the plane
fast
What about you?
I have to stay behind as a
witness.
Uncle
Go with your mind at ease.
You won't have to be
subjected to this anymore.
We accussd the Customs
officer of corruption,
so I have to stay here and
be a witness in court.
We'll all meet again in
Hong Kong.
Take care
You, too.
Hurry up and get on the
plane
Due to the Watergate
incident, the U.S. Congress
has requested President
Nixon's resignation.
According to observers,
after Nixon resigns,
the situation in Vietnam
will be worsen.
But the South Vietnamese
government emphasizes
they have confidence in
current situation.
And will continue their
liberal economic policies.
Next Monday, the President
of Vietnam
will convene an emergency
meeting...
...to deal fairly and
impartially...
...with the serious problem
of corruption.
He pledges to the National
Council...
...that the government will
be cleaned up.
Get out of the way
Stand to the side
Reuters reports a fierce
aerial attack...
...on South Vietnam last
Sunday.
Casualty figures are still
unavailable.
Due to the current
instability in Vietnam,
many Vietnamese boat people
have arrived...
in Hong Kong during the past
few days.
The Hong Kong government
and the UN...
...are conducting
discussions over ways...
...to humanely solve the
refugee problems.
I told you they were
finished
It's a good thing we left
when we did
So what? We still lost our
home
Cousin Mark, if there's
anything I've done wrongly,
please forgive me
Don't be silly I got mad
just now. Don't bother me.
You'll be getting hungry as
you don't take dinner.
Have a bowl of soup, please.
Thank you.
Vietnam is in chaos.
I wonder how Kit is?
I hope she's OK.
We still haven't had any
news about her.
Cousin Mark
There's a car outside with
a flat tire.
You want to repair it?
Let me take a look.
Hey, friend Which tire
is flat?
Mun
Mun Look who's here
What's the matter? Can't
fix it?
Tell him to leave it here.
Look who's come
Who?
Kit
I thought I'd have to go
to Saigon to find you
Mark and I talk about you
all day and night.
I mussed your hair
Great The family has been
reunited.
Uncle
Dad
Mun goes to the airport
everyday to wait for you.
Mark, take her things inside
Uncle, she has her own home.
How can you ask her to
move in here?
Lt'll happen sooner or later
Sorry. I've sweaty palms.
How do you know the night
club manager?
Our company has shares in
this place.
Evergreen invests in
everything
Excuse me, boss woman
Six, seven, eight
Sit down
Don't be bashful. Sit down
Let me introduce you. This
is my cousin, Mun.
Mark, let's just sit and
chat.
No need for so many
hostesses.
Silly In this kind of a
place,
how can you not have
hostesses keep you company?
Kit, you're the boss here.
Why so few hostesses to
serve us?
You're not a very good
friend
Mr. Cheung, Miss Chow.
Mama-san.
This is Baby.
Baby, take a seat.
Maggie
This is my cousin, Mun.
Hello
She is Tina
Tina, Hello
Flora
Hi, Flora
Come on. Take a seat
Drink Drink
Mark, we're leaving.
Let's go.
Boss, tell Mama-san that I'm
very happy tonight.
I want her, and her... to
join me for a late snack.
Thanks.
Drink Drink
Find out what Mr. Cheung
desires,
and put it on my company's
bill.
Thanks a lot.
You can treat me whenever
I come here.
Have a good time. I'm
leaving now.
Kit, I'll take you home.
Oh, so Mr. Cheung is a
friend of Miss Chow's.
Miss Chow.