Now, don't you say a word.
No matter what the employees say,
don't apologize,
or make excuses.
This is harder for you
than it is for them.
Don't mistake that.
- Good morning.
- Yes.
Good morning.
Attention!
I'm Murakami, business consultant.
For this company to survive,
we will hire an accounting agency.
It is unavoidable to ask you all
to leave this company.
Pay check and
arrangements for insurance...
will be made later.
What is this?
We know it's a difficult time.
But why 'it's the consultant
to tell us?
Instead of you?
We've work for you
all this time together.
Huh? Say something!
Satchan, let's go.
- Come on.
- Wait!
He betrayed us.
Don't say that.
Ayako, come.
- Coming.
Ayako, well.
Good morning, gentlemen.
Thank you for coming here
all the long way so early.
President has a message.
Gentlemen here today are all over 50.
You are all in responsible posts...
and your effort made this company
what it is today.
However,
in the midst of this recession,
business are closing.
Even large companies.
For our survival, we need to carry out
a major restructuring.
The board decided to request you all
to voluntarily step down.
This decision was difficult.
But this is the only way to survive.
We ask for your understanding.
If you accept and step down, we will
provide additional compensation pay.
If you do not accept,
you are welcome to stay.
But your post will be outside duty.
Please decide by the end of May.
The human resources manager
will give you more information later.
Thank you.
Stop passing the buck!
Yeah!
"Six months later"
April 6th, rain, later clouds.
Mom's starting school.
Mon in her white clothes,
dressed pretty to school.
Now, everyone, introduce yourself.
Hashimoto.
I worked 35 years
in an insurance company.
2 years to retirement,
but they made me step down.
So I'm here.
I ran a factory in Arakawa,
doing sheet metal work.
Business failed
and closed last spring.
So I'm here to start over again.
I ran a bar,
price became business over quality.
Banks refused to lend,
eventually I ran out of money,
so I quit.
Studying at my age is hard,
but I'll try my best.
My name is Kim Yong Su.
Okay to call me Kim.
I ran a small store
selling electronics,
then a large store opened nearby.
Business turned bad and...
I had to close my store.
I live with my grandmother...
but her pension isn't enough.
So I'm here.
Now the only lady here, Kojima.
I'm Kojima. Only lady here.
The interviewer said
physical work maybe hard,
but I'm quite strong.
I'll try to do as well as you all
for next six months.
Takano.
My name is Takano.
Hata.
I'm Hata.
Parent company cut cost,
which hit us and I had to leave.
So I'm here.
Rain stopped later.
I hate rain.
Because the newspapers will get wet.
Hanzomon, Hibiya, Marunouchi.
Do subway have tunnels?
North or south hemisphere?
Behave!
Tommy, are you okay?
I told you,
not to ride in the middle.
I didn't.
Okay?
Aunt, Tommy fell from the bicycle.
Again?
We delivered the newspapers together.
Thank you.
Take your bicycle.
Ken, stay for dinner.
I have class. Gotta go.
Say "hi" to mom for me.
Are there tunnels in Paris?
Special dishes today.
"Itadakimasu"?
Itadakimasu.
You could always say it.
Remember Tommy?
Mom is going to school tomorrow.
You have to eat breakfast on your own.
My own.
Yes. Kobayashi will come at 10...
to take you.
Mom will come home at 5.
Come home at 5?
Toast for school! Cheers.
Cheers.
Tasty? Look this is textbook
for studying. Very hard.
Is boiler English?
Yes.
Why written in Katakana?
Maybe Americans can't read Kanji.
Itadakimasu.
- Yes?
- It's me.
Oh hi.
Hi Tommy. Dinner done?
- Done.
- Not yet.
Good. I brought some Tempura.
Yes.
Looks delicious. Thanks.
How was school?
Never thought I'd go back at this age.
All the pains. One after another.
I'll probably get by like always.
Come in.
No I can't. Good luck.
Thanks.
No sauce, no mayonnaise.
Tasty?
I'm not young,
I don't need anything fancy.
Just a secure job,
with stable employment.
Not part-time,
not temporary, full time.
Just enough money for me and my son,
to make living,
I take hard work.
Those jobs, up there...
cleaning job for woman over 45,
all part-time or temp.
I need security. Help me.
What about vocational schools?
Vocational schools?
If you finish the degree,
offers better chance.
How much does it cost? Expensive?
It's free.
And with allowances.
Here is a building.
Sorry for my bad drawing.
Before, most of you worked in...
this section of the building.
When you graduate...
and work in a building,
this section,
where the big boilers and
transformers are,
will be the section where you work.
Remember that you're not...
in offices with ties,
it's different.
You get paid much less,
maybe half or even a third.
Takano,
please change your clothes.
My clothes?
As I have said before,
you will be working in...
Fine.
Maintenance is literally the base.
As you study this course,
tell yourself that you support...
the safety of building
and its people.
You are older,
your memory maybe half or a third,
you have to work harder.
It's hard...
but do your best
and finish this course.
I'll do it.
Let me, I like serving.
Terrible tea.
I'll bring better tea.
- Some tea?
- No thanks.
This is fire tube boiler.
Currently most common type of boiler.
This one uses gas
but crude oil is common.
Now, we will use this boiler for class.
This is the tiling classroom.
In here, we learn
about electricity.
Building's transformers and boilers,
freezers, and operation of
automatic controllers.
Tomorrow,
class schedule will start.
There is a lot to learn
in a very limited time,
so please prepare for class.
Class dismissed.
Takano,
we are deciding...
our turns for cleaning,
can you stay while we decide?
Cleaning? Why do I have to?
Why? Because it's our classroom.
Go ahead. I have plans.
It will only be a few minutes.
Finance section?
I'm Takano, Arai manager's friend.
Is he in?
What time will he return?
Okay. I'll call later.
Tell him I called.
Say, that Takano,
he probably used to boss around.
And a lot of money at retirement.
It's open.
Let's go for a beer.
I have to cook for my son.
Then, Kim.
I can't drink.
Come on. Take care.
- Thanks.
- Bye.
Bye.
Ouch!
In the middle, always telling you.
Don't run in the middle, keep left.
Left side of the road.
You have to cooperate.
Cooperate or it's autism.
Have to cooperate.
If not, it's autism.
If autism, it's dreadful.
Have to cooperate.
Behaving, behaving.
Are there tunnels in Argentina?
How many tunnels?
Are there tunnels in Brazil?
How many tunnels in Columbia?
In a long tunnel. In a long tunnel.
Hello?
Tommy just came back.
Wet from rain,
taking a bath now.
Old newspapers? What?
I'll be right there.
Tommy did something again.
Tommy, I'll be out. Be right back.
Phone doesn't stop,
20, 30 so many calls,
they're really upset
about old newspapers.
Big trouble. We're redelivering.
Yamamoto, leave that, go now!
What to do?
I'll go and apologize.
- What?
- Let me.
Excuse me. Yomiuri Shimbun.
My son delivered old newspaper
by mistake.
I'm really sorry.
Who is it?
Excuse me. My name is Kojima,
my son delivered old newspaper
by mistake.
I brought new newspaper.
Leave it in.
I'm very sorry.
Excuse me. I'm Kojima,
my son delivered old newspaper
by mistake.
I'm very sorry.
I'll tell him not to.
Your son?
That mumbling boy?
He's handicapped.
He scares my kid,
disturbs his study.
Does he have to work?
He can go to institutions, can't he?
Yes, but he wants to work.
He is treasured at work,
worked over a year.
I will tell him to keep
his mumbling down.
Sorry.
Why no poop? No poop.
Try, no poop.
When will I poop?
After dinner. You can poop.
If no poop comes, what will happen?
Then have milk.
Have milk. Will I go poop?
Why? Tommy just did
what he thought was best.
Don't deliver wet newspapers.
Why do people say things like that?
In such a mean way?
Like this child is no good
for this world?
Eat, then big poop?
Lots.
"Correct reason,
for setting the major axis...
of elliptical manhol
in direction of...
the boiler tube circumference."
This is a common exam question.
Any one? Hashimoto.
Stress to the circumference...
is double to that of axis.
Therefore it's safer.
Question?
What's "stress"? Is it pressure?
Back in page 39.
Power to pull and bend things
with pressure.
Wrong units. "cm2", and "mm2".
Just remember "stress".
Now, on the types of tubes.
There are 5 types
chosen depending on the use.
Exam question. Kojima.
Yes.
Read?
"Smoking pipe".
I first thought so too.
It didn't make sense.
It means "fire tube" here.
These are in the boiler water...
filled with gas.
Water tube. Water is inside,
combustible gas is outside,
used in water tube boilers.
Hello? Finance section?
Is Arai manager in?
I'm a friend of his. Takano.
Is he in? Thank you.
It's me, Takano.
Sorry, I called many times.
You busy?
Did you talk to the president of
Marui Securities?
What? What about my age?
Before, you said it was okay.
Why now it is a problem?
You should have told me earlier.
Arai, can we meet for a minute?
I know you're busy, just a few...
Hello?
Wow!
Takano. Are you there?
I just saw him walking out.
It's his turn to clean today.
Does he know?
Hello? Is Arai manager there?
I called several times,
Takano, a friend from school,
In meeting...
Please, it's quite urgent,
can you...?
You can't. Fine.
Tell him that...
Takano will never call again!
Thanks!
Takano.
It's your turn to clean today.
You forgot?
I had plans.
Why didn't you tell us then?
"Self-ism" is not good.
Such word doesn't exist.
Can't you talk nicely?
Why don't you mix with the others?
Why should I?
No rule.
Unpleasant guy.
We don't care if you don't,
but don't disturb others.
When we were complaining,
Kojima said
she will clean on your behalf.
Go thank her.
Let's go now.
I cannot forget, I love him.
Old song.
Reminds me of good times.
I had my love.
Really?
I'm very sorry. I will do it.
Don't worry.
Can you do it?
No problem.
Wait, wait!
Look. Wash inside first,
then squeeze.
Not so hard!
Give me that. Like this.
Step on the pedal,
then squeeze by gradually releasing.
Takano, take off your jacket.
Right.
Roll up your pants. It's wet.
Right. And my sleeves.
- Right.
- Rough.
Leave it to me.
Thank you.
Know where to put the mop?
Yes.
Next to the toilet.
Goodbye.
That guy is just selfish.
Common guy nature.
Wonder what his wife is like...
Jerks like him
often have beautiful wives.
Dumb women.
Yamazaki Metal 930 yen,
buy 20 million.
Got it.
Turn out Yamazaki Metal,
sell two million.
803 yen. Sold?
Barge is strong.
Sell.
Meeting at 6?
Sold? Thanks.
Sawako Kojima.
"Common exam question."
You came?
You told me to.
How?
On bicycle.
How's mom?
Bad business, bad mood.
You hungry? Eat.
You're eating this? Pitiful.
Nagashima manager has 7 pitchers...
Dad, you remember
Nagashima playing?
Yeah, went to see his games.
Remember when he quit?
I was 26.
I became manager that year,
so I remember clearly.
Wanna drink?
Underage.
He hits! To the left field!
He hit!
Big one to left, but... stopped!
What!
Hajime, that freshman year,
you said you want to become a chef.
Yeah.
I said, you should go to college
no matter what,
and you cried in fury.
Uh-huh.
I shouldn't have said that,
I regret now.
The value of people
isn't just college education.
Don't become a white collar!
That's why you called me
to come here?
You only live once, so treasure it.
Too late to regret at my age.
Listen, I also have a lot of things
that I want to say.
But I'm not saying it.
So quit lecturing.
What do you want to say?
To say that you also were a victim?
Dad, stop drinking.
Makes me miserable.
That hill? Thanks.
Hello.
Hi! Why are you here?
You forgot your textbook.
You can't study during the holidays...
without the textbook.
So you brought it for me?
I like bicycling around.
So I just stopped by.
Goodbye.
Thanks a lot.
Sawako, invite him for tea.
He came a long way.
Takano, wait. Hey, Takano!
Yes...!
I was surprised.
Wondered why you were here.
Did I disturb you?
No, I wanted to study and
I need the textbook.
Didn't know you were kind.
Me?
You always look sullen in class...
and you never talk.
Thought badly?
We were saying,
you probably bossed around before.
- Really...
- Please.
Tell me why did you quit?
They condemned employees over 50.
I was so enraged.
So I resigned in anger.
I thought, heck,
there are other companies
that need me.
Big mistake.
You couldn't find any?
Unemployment office
introduced that school.
So that's why you're studying...
with other unemployed from
dinky company like me.
I was hung over
on the first day of school.
You looked gloomy.
You remember?
Of course. You were late.
I also remember
being surprised to see you.
Just kidding.
- Is Mr. Kojima out?
- He's there.
He died 10 years ago.
My son is home.
What if I poop on a Shinkansen?
You can't do something like that.
We have guest. My school classmate.
Nice to meet you.
Tommy, say hello.
Hello. Where is America?
Uh...America?
Are there tunnels in America?
Tunnels?
I don't know why he's interested in
tunnels and caves.
He's been like this since he was a kid.
choo-choo-choo
Tommy
How many tunnels in Sanyo line?
I got you ice-cream.
What if I pee on a frying pan?
We have a guest.
Itadakimasu.
He was a healthy pretty baby.
Never dreamed that
he was handicapped. Please.
When did you?
When he was 2.
Something's wrong.
Words were clear but...
Didn't take me in.
No eye contact,
and didn't hold me.
When I took him to hospital,
doctor said,
"typical case of infant autism".
I see.
It was a hot day.
On the way home,
my face was wet from sweat and tears.
He's grown so much since,
same thing everyday,
except our age.
Do you worry?
About the future? Yes.
But I know I will die someday and,
I think he will somehow find a way
to live on his own.
Optimistic.
I never wished...
him or myself to be dead.
Except, once I thought,
if we could die together,
that'll be okay too.
On a cable car in Zao,
Tommy got scared, went berserk,
I wished the cable to break
and let us fall together.
When I came home and
told this to my husband,
he got very angry.
He was in tears with rage.
That was the first and
the last time I saw him so angry.
Parents' feelings.
I...I have a spoiled son.
No. Actually I'm the one,
I'm spoiled.
You're up?
- Sorry.
How many tunnels in Tohoku line?
Tohoku line.
I'll find out later.
How many tunnels in Argentina?
Argentina. I'll find out that too.
You're so earnest.
I liked trains.
If I'm 68, how old are you?
68? You're 16 now?
What day is Saturday plus Saturday?
Saturday plus Saturday?
That's a hard one.
Which bus goes to Tokiwadai
via tunnel?
Good bye.
Thank you today.
See you in class.
Yes. Takano,
don't be late for class.
Always late. Not thought well of.
I drink to sleep, a bad habit.
I stay up late,
can't get up by myself.
Your family?
I'm living alone, we're separated.
Then, I'll call you in the morning.
Will you? Bye, Tommy.
Bye. Rocket in Mars.
Explode, bang!
Beautiful sunset.
Many birds flying into sunset.
Mom said. "Tommy, if we had wings,
we'd fly away with them."
Are people with wings human?
Hello?
Morning! Get up!
Yes, yes. Thank you.
Now look.
To check if water level scale...
is working correctly on boiler,
shut steam and water cock.
Morning.
Takano. You're early.
This first.
I see. Then, drain cock.
Right, after draining, steam cock.
Check steam, then shut.
Water cock, check water, shut.
Shut drain cock and done!
Not yet. Open steam, warm up tubes,
open water.
Check water level.
Done.
- Impressive, Kim.
- Thanks.
Grave as a tax collector.
Hi.
Everyone, good news!
A grandchild was born to Cho.
- Congratulations!
- Morning.
Kita, from office? Why?
Mr. Nomura called,
he'll be late for a while.
I'll be his substitute.
Tell us a joke.
You know my major?
So, it has been 2 months,
since you came.
Any comments or complaints,
about your classes?
Please voice out.
Yes.
Anything?
Sure.
I...I don't understand anything.
It's too fast.
All the jargons,
enthal-pee, etc. Slips me.
Incontinence?
Thought studying will make me smarter.
Yes.
But the more I study,
the more confused I am.
I feel more and more stupid.
I agree.
It's really not funny!
I understand. You're tired.
And the weather's getting hotter.
Cheer up! Let's talk about...
something else about "tools".
Electricity and boiler.
These are one of many
tools we created,
in order to better our lives.
Chalk, black board,
table, chair, car, train, etc.
are all "tools" of ours.
You know our ancestors are apes.
2 or 3 million years ago,
our ancestor got on two feet.
Grew tall. Remember the diagram?
By standing, our hands were freed.
Free hands.
I can throw. Or swing sticks,
throw these stones..
Use of "tools",
made us different from animals.
Sticks and stones lead
to civilization.
Then we found fire.
Life rapidly improved.
With fire, we made iron.
Later, over 200 years ago,
James Watt invented an engine...
to convert steam pressure to power.
In other words, "boiler".
Your topic.
So you ask yourselves,
"Watt's boiler"?
Everyone is listening.
It was the dawn of modern technology.
I just wanted to say
what you're learning...
is the essence of it, the end.
I feel cheated.
Interesting.
If all classes were as fun.
But don't ask that in exam.
Good morning.
Enjoy your class.
Let us start. Page 27.
Boiler maintenance. Article 24...
He will be on his way.
Here's the map.
What's gotten into you?
You're unemployed, why "schooling"?
Told you, it's for work.
I need to have some skills.
Will that ensure you a job?
I don't know.
See! I'm saying it's unlikely.
Consider your age.
You're over 40. Get married.
I'll arrange someone for you,
I've been looking.
This person.
He's a friend of my father's.
You wanted to tell me this?
He's a nice person.
His wife died a year ago.
He needs someone.
I told him about Tommy.
He said one of his relatives has,
you know..."slowish" child.
So he's accustomed.
Isn't he nice?
Look, he's the second from the right.
Little thinning.
Auntie, thanks, but...
What's look?
Appearance only matters
when you're young.
When I met uncle,
I thought, "yuck!"
But I gradually got used to him.
It's all about money at your age.
He seems to have savings.
- Excuse me.
- Customer!
I have to go to a meeting.
Stay longer. Uncle's late.
Have a seat.
It's August. Wear lighter clothes.
They are on cheap sales.
Coffee for me.
- Yes.
Here, your dad's keepsake.
It was in the cabinet.
Wanted Hajime to give you.
How's work?
Bad. Bad sales. Banks don't lend.
I fired a girl.
- Find a job?
- No, not yet.
You're still going to that school?
- Summer holiday now.
- Excuse me.
How's Hajime?
Cramming school.
Is he okay?
Hajime is far more capable
than you think.
- You just don't know.
- I see.
Retirement pay.
This should cover all mortgage,
and leave you change.
Use it for Hajime's school...
Takano speaking.
How's it?
Tell them I'll be there.
Say hi to Hajime.
Okay, I'll call again.
- Oh, hi!
- What are you doing?
Uh...just eating doughnuts.
Surprised to see you.
Tommy, Mr. Takano.
Hello Tommy! Hot, eh?
Will you die?
Surely, the heat is killing.
Sometimes, he says strange things.
When's your funeral?
Mine? Maybe soon.
Who'll come to your funeral?
Important people,
like Prime Minister.
Stop kidding around.
Tommy! Hi!
My friend. Remember her?
- Yes, hello.
- Hello.
We bumped into each other.
Not to beach. Scary.
I'll be there for you.
We're off to the beach till tomorrow.
Beach...sounds great.
Sorry, we have to go.
See you. Enjoy it!
- Good bye.
- Let's go.
- Come on Ken.
Antares, Scorpion...
So long.
Come to the beach with us.
- What?
- You have plans?
No, no.
Then come!
- I'm not wearing pants.
- What?
I mean, swimming pants.
Tommy's swimming!
Hey, he's swimming! You okay?
You know, Tommy likes tunnels.
I know.
Grand opening!
Oshima tunnel opened!
Euro tunnel opened!
Yes! It opened!
Ken, Tommy has a love?
- He does.
- Who?
Tommy, you like Yuki?
No I don't, I don't.
When he says no, he means yes.
Tommy's handsome.
He was pretty as a girl baby.
Really. What about your love, Ken?
Me? Appropriately.
Tommy, here that? "Appropriately".
Father is probably necessary for boys.
Let's go swim Tommy!
Yes let's go Tommy!
Hurry!
It's not scary, come.
Let me see Tommy.
Pegasus, Pegasus.
Pegasus.
Tommy likes constellations.
- Yes.
- Why?
It never changes.
Never betrays him, never ever.
Unlike people.
Why moon? It wane and wax.
It's been repeated
for millions of years.
He loves the moon.
It doesn't betray him either.
- Tommy, watermelon.
- Yes.
Touch head?
What? You like my hair?
You can touch it.
Tommy, I told you not to bother her.
It's okay. I don't mind at all.
He wants to touch beautiful hair.
I think I understand...sort of.
Peculiar.
- Stop it.
- Tommy, Tommy, stop.
Mommy's going
to sing for you. Ready?
Ai-Ai, Ai-Ai, little monkey.
Ai-Ai, Ai-Ai, on southern island.
Ai-Ai, Ai-Ai, with a long tail.
Ai-Ai, Ai-Ai, little monkey
An old song.
- You know this song?
- No.
You were probably busy working.
Kids' TV program song,
very popular.
Baby Tommy, responded to the song.
So when he got alarmed,
and went berserk,
we sang this and it calmed him.
Right, Sawako?
I once dressed like the singer
in the program.
Tommy loved it.
He wanted me to wear it
all the time.
If I didn't he would go berserk.
So again I ended up doing "Ai-Ai".
Few hundred times!
Remember, when we went to a store,
Tommy must have wanted a toy,
he suddenly started hollering.
So at the cashier, you stated "Ai-Ai",
everyone around was shocked,
but you had to keep on
dancing and singing with all might.
I was so hit by that,
brought me tears.
I'm so moved by your story.
I can't speak. So let me sing.
When the summer is over,
I will be gone.
When summer comes back, so will I.
I don't like babysitting,
for crying babies,
because I get blamed
for making them cry.
Didn't know his character..
- You mean Takano?
- Yes.
Come on, he's typical,
estranged by family by
just devoting to work.
Once retired,
don't know what to do.
Just like Tommy, his head is blank.
- May I?
- Come in.
- Where to?
- To see stars.
Will you turn off the light?
- Yes. Good night!
- Good night!
Great summer.
Rape flower, blossoms, camellia...
Hey, they're making fun of us.
What's so funny? Stop laughing.
Why do they...
dye their hair?
Feed enthalpy,
divided by calorie equals 539.
Equation of capacity
To memorize,
Ge=Gx(h2-h1) divided by 539.
Very important.
Now, boiler handling.
Common exam question.
Mr. Saito!
Kojima. Police called.
Your son had an accident.
Go now. This hospital.
Yes...yes.
To Akabane.
Go fast! Speed!
Hear me?
Wait! Use this.
- Thanks.
- Now, go! Go!
That was a good move.
Money helps.
Unemployment allowance.
Really used wisely.
Tommy, Tommy!
I am his mother.
How was the operation?
Everything went well.
Thank you. My son is handicapped.
- Yes, we know.
- Thank you.
W...Where am I?
Tommy, you ride on
the left hand side.
Not in the middle of the road.
Or you get hurt like this.
Left side.
Will you die, will you...
You're asking, "will I die"?
You're okay, doctor said there
is nothing wrong.
You won't die, okay? Never.
Not hurt, not hurt,
not hurt, not...
No, it doesn't hurt.
Big boy. Strong boy.
There are other people,
we have to keep quiet.
- I'm leaving.
- Thank you.
I was with him...sorry.
Don't, it's not your fault.
Take care Tommy.
Russia, which way?
That way, far away.
- Bye bye.
- Thanks.
My son's name is Tomio Kojima.
He has difficulties to communicate,
and may cause you inconveniences,
I ask for your understanding.
May I take your temperature.
Not hurt! Not hurt!
Shirt...pajama...
I'm back.
I go home by Saturday?
Not hurt! Not hurt!
Big boy.
Tommy's brave. So strong.
Not hurt! Not hurt!
W...Where am I?
Damn it, can't sleep!
Sorry to disturb.
I came about my son.
Come in, we wanted to know.
Please. When speaking to him,
please don't use childish words.
It might feel like you're talking to a baby.
But he has his 16 year-old pride.
Please treat him like an adult.
It's difficult for him
to express himself,
so sometimes
he might do absurd things.
But please try to see his needs,
before you scold him out right.
I'm really sorry for all the trouble.
We understand.
If he does something right,
please praise him for it.
Although not overly.
You know?
Of course.
That's what child raising is.
Yes? We'll be there.
Room 307, drip is done.
Hi.
You came for me at this hour?
Go home and sleep tonight,
I'll watch him,
many more days ahead.
Thanks.
I'll pick you up tomorrow morning,
sleep till then.
Studying?
You came?
I didn't know which hospital,
thought I'd see you here.
- How's Tommy?
- He's okay.
- Good.
- Thanks.
Come in.
It's late...
Come on, come in.
Let me. Tired?
- I'm glad you came.
- Good. Good work.
Tastes so good.
What?
I was imagining you buying this.
As is.
Ah. Mr. Saito wished you well.
Today's class was especially difficult.
I'll teach you.
I got I after someone taught me.
Sleepy? Let's stop.
- I'm fine. Teach me.
- Page 125.
You asked about
the number 539 calories.
At reference point?
Correct. 539 calories
at reference point.
You have to memorize it.
- You okay?
- Yes.
Example question.
Take notes as I read.
Feed enthalpy h1,
is 18 kilo calories.
If G is 3500kg per hour,
in boiler at pressure of 5kg per cm2,
what is the correct scale evaporation?
Here, vapor enthalpy h2,
for 5kg per cm2 is 657.9 kilo calories.
Answer 1 is 6578...
Kojima?
Dear everyone, I appreciate,
everything you have done for me.
My son's wounds are healing well.
Have you started looking for jobs?
Hello. Air-conditioner maintenance.
How is job availability?
TV news and newspapers
always talk of unemployment
and closures, it worries me.
Will the time come,
after working day and night,
to see peaceful retirement?
Will it ever come?
I wonder as I see the elderly
in hospital. It kills me.
Pink circles mean exam questions.
How was school today?
Morning exercise. Weather was good.
Afternoon class was difficult.
Lunch was catered. Very tasty.
Sounds like Tommy's essays.
Went to restaurant.
Drank juice. Tasty.
Train was fun.
Oooh God. Will I get better?
I'm fed up.
It's Autumn skill festival soon.
I'm hoping to go back before that...
to catch up with class.
See you then, all the best,
Sawako Kojima.
September 7th, clear sky.
I went to mom's school.
Nobody was in uniform.
Is it really school? Or factory?
- They're here.
- How are you?
Love, my love, burnt up
and turned the sky crimson.
"Until death,
I'll never leave you."
He "whiskered" to me.
My love season.
Love, my love, burnt up
and turned the sky crimson.
Terrible.
My wife and daughter.
- Tommy, my son.
- Hello.
"Morning coffee, together,
just two of us."
He "whiskered" to me.
My love season.
Ready? Smile everyone!
Peace!
"Morning coffee, together,
just two of us."
Onizuka was mad.
"I hate you!"
"Morning coffee, together,
just two of us."
Thanks for the ride.
Tommy, visit us again.
- Good night.
- Bye, Tommy.
You forgot.
I wished it was just the two of us.
I'll see you tomorrow.
On the road, not in the middle.
Keep left on the road.
Left side, left...
September 16th, clear sky.
Mom's exam day.
She said "I'd fail anyway."
If she'd "fail anyway",
why take it?
Poop mom?
Why no poop mom?
Poop not yet?
I was studying.
Air contaminants are...
SOx, NOx and dust.
symbol is...
SO2, sulphur trioxide is SO3,
Nitrogen monoxide is NO,
nitrogen dioxide is NO2
You memorized all?
Before me? I'm the one who's going.
Thermal Knox, fuel NOx.
Helper will come at one.
Then go to therapy with you.
I go at one.
Be home in evening, okay?
Okay.
I'll pass. Maybe not.
Can't beat men.
- Can't.
- Bye.
No...
Done? Bye.
Uh-oh.
Why yellow rain?
Hi Tommy!
How long is Shintanna tunnel?
Express.
How long is Kanmon tunnel?
I've learned that in school.
A bit over 1km?
Crib, Crib. You, crib when?
That again?
Don't say if before people,
Mom never cribbed.
I...I just saw it by accident...
Boiler, Sawako Kojima.
Express mail?
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
Tommy, I passed!
Banzai! Banzai! I passed!
- Behaving.
- Tommy, thanks!
No screaming!
I cry when I'm sad,
mom cries when she's happy.
Maybe there's something wrong with her.
Hello?
It's me. I passed.
2nd class boiler exam.
Hear me?
Congratulations. Great job!
Thanks.
- I wanted to tell you first thing.
- Good.
Thought I would fail.
I've been telling myself that...
I will try again.
I'm crying in joy.
Sorry, I'm babbling.
- How about you?
- I failed.
- What?
- Just kidding.
I passed also. Barely.
You scared me.
I'm not used to you joking.
Let's celebrate.
- When?
- Tonight?
I can't. Club meeting for parents
with handicapped kids.
Is hair sweet?
So when?
What about Friday after
the graduation ceremony?
Do you have time?
Yes, I have time the whole day.
Just two of us that night, okay?
- Yes, just two of us.
- Good bye.
When the summer is over,
I will be gone.
When summer comes back, so will I.
September 25th, clear sky.
Mom's graduation.
Mom's slow but she can graduate,
maybe because she studied.
Tommy, I have an important plan,
that's why I'll be late.
Don't you understand?
Mom will be late.
Yes. Eat by yourself
and go to sleep.
Sleep alone.
Mom will be late, but
promise to come home.
Promise.
- Understood?
- Yes.
Okay. Bye.
Mom not coming home!
Gone, never see her again.
Tommy.
Mom not coming home!
I will be late,
but I will come home.
Please understand.
It's a happy day for mom,
a special day.
Gone.
You want that?
Mom not coming home!
You want me to go away?
Mom going away?
Gone?
Not coming home?
Onizuka, ever amorous attire.
I will give out the diploma. Senda.
Yes.
Health is important,
take good care.
- Thank you.
- Congratulations.
- Kudo.
- Yes.
Congratulations.
Glad you found a job.
Are you happy?
Yes.
- Shimada.
- Yes.
Cooperation is important.
Please keep it in your mind.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
- Kojima.
- Yes.
Biggest challenge is
prejudice and discrimination,
but I'm sure you'll make it.
Be happy.
- Thank you.
- Congratulations.
Takano. Where's he?
I called but, no answer.
Sleeping in again? Ikeyama
Yes.
You're not young,
cut down on drinking.
Ah, yes.
Going for a drink tonight?
- Just briefly.
- Congratulations.
Thank you.
- Kojima.
- What?
I'm really impressed.
Honestly, I thought you'd fail.
You were crying on the way home.
I said we can take it...
together again,
you cried more.
- It's all past now.
- Yes.
With your help,
I found a job and feel relieved.
Thank you.
Everyone, a toast...
for the only lady, for Kojima.
- Congratulations.
The red sunset on school building,
Cheerful voice from shade of elm,
High school seniors,
Even if we part,
Class friendship lasts forever.
Hey, something wrong?
- Nothing.
- Feeling okay?
Is it your day?
So hard for a woman...
If I'm 68, how old is mom?
When's your funeral?
Someday I'll die, so when I do,
do a funeral.
Funeral.
Tommy has to do it for me,
you thank everyone
for everything they did for mom.
Caves in America?
Go to the other room,
leave mom alone.
If you put plaster on penis,
what happens?
- Hello?
- Me, Takano.
What happened?
I thought you had a stroke
or something.
So worried. Where were you?
I wanted to call,
but didn't have the time.
It's difficult to tell you,
my wife attempted suicide.
We found here,
before it was too late.
Her business went down,
she was probably stressed.
Sorry, for ruining our date,
really sorry.
Everything is under control,
I'll call in a day or two.
We can celebrate graduation...
- No, we can't.
- Why?
Stay with her.
I don't know here,
but I know she needs you.
Don't ever call here.
Forget about me. Please.
Good bye,
thank you for the past 6 months.
Full moon and crescent moon.
Full moon is covered by clouds.
Crescent moon is covered by clouds.
I won't cry...
Dad, mom wants some juice.
Get me some sake.
Sake? In a hospital?
I'm tired.
Said you quit drinking,
where's your will-power?
You get addicted.
I said go get it!
Obey me! Go!
Excuse me. Bulb change.
Thank you. Excuse me.
- Kojima.
- Yes.
Head office called...
about your health check up result.
Call them back.
Okay.
I get called every time, my liver,
they always say,
"no alcohol, and quit smoking".
Building management center.
Yes, yes, please hold.
Mrs. Sawako Kojima.
Please come in.
Yes.
- I'm Dr. Ito.
- I'm Kojima.
Did you have a check up
for breast cancer?
Yes.
One more time. Raise your arms.
Thank you. Put it down.
This stiffness.
You never felt it?
No.
In some cases,
husband finds it first.
I don't have a husband.
Pardon me.
More tests are necessary.
Yes.
Ready in 12 minutes.
- 28 more seconds.
- I'm home.
12 more seconds.
Sorry I'm late.
I'll cook dinner.
Nikuman, nikuman.
You cooked nikuman?
- 12 minutes.
- Thanks.
Oh, hot. Hot! Be careful!
Tasty nikuman.
Looks good.
Mom use mustard. I don't.
Mustard hot.
- Not hot.
- Steam is nice.
Mom has cancer, breast cancer.
You may not understand,
but it's serious.
I went to the doctor.
He suggested me to bring my family,
but I told him I'm okay by myself.
Sorry for not taking you
as my family.
But mom's not scared.
Mom is very brave and strong.
Even when I found your disability,
dad suddenly died,
lost my job,
and broke up with Takano
I came over it.
Mom's okay, not scared a bit.
Right, no big deal.
Pacific Building maintenance?
Hi, Hashimoto. It's me, Inoue.
Hi. I'll be quick.
Our friend Kojima,
will have operation.
Breast cancer. She has no family,
so we all go,
see her and cheer her up.
Great. The hospital is...
Akabane General Hospital.
Breast cancer operation.
Poor thing.
We're going to see her,
and cheer her up.
How about you?
What? Next Monday, 1 o'clock, okay.
I'll be there.
I'll tell Onizuka.
- Auntie.
- Operating today?
Why didn't tell me?
I'm your only aunt.
I worry about you always.
I'm your family.
Stop crying, auntie.
I'm not dying.
You're right,
you get well after operation.
All well. Boobs are...
only important when you're young.
Later, they're useless.
When you get well,
I'll find you a man.
Who accept one boob.
Will there be any?
Yes, there will.
Tunnels in Denmark?
Tommy, you've grown.
When will you die?
How unpleasant!
Who'll come to your funeral?
Hello. Anesthesia preparation.
Hello doctor, I'm her aunt.
Please help her doctor.
- Lie down.
- Sleep well?
Probably not.
Taking blood pressure.
Consent taken?
Yes, confirmed.
Who are you?
We're her classmates.
We came to visit.
- Kojima.
- Yes.
I can only tell you, good luck.
Wish I had more vocabulary.
Now, be strong. I'm here.
I'm not much use.
Yes, you are.
We didn't age for nothing.
He's right.
You worry about nothing.
Thank you.
It's me.
Hello.
It's Cho. Hello.
You okay?
Hey, your...
Your wife, did she get well?
Good. That was worrying me. Really.
Kojima, snow.
Life passes in a blink,
we're just like a momentary star.
Without blinking,
even reluctant to breathe,
we want each other.
When are you disappearing?
When are you leaving me behind?
Where are you going without me?
Even if your reflecting mirror,
doesn't have a song to praise you.
I will praise you,
about you unknown to you.
That humble life...
may be criticized by some.
may be judged useless by some.
But I will praise you,
about you unknown to you.
People are beasts
without fangs, poison or thorn.
Just given tears, to be pained.
A naked beast.
I will praise you,
about you unknown to you.
Life passes in a blink,
we're just like a momentary star.
Without blinking,
even reluctant to breathe,
we want each other.