What do you want me to say, Bruce?
He broke into our offices this morning,
accessed our files, our computers.
Do we know what?
Well, we can assume everything.
This is a major liability.
You're telling me.
Renaldo, now!
Vamos, vamos! Let's go!
Okay, okay!
Does the army know who he is?
Yeah. Francisco Francis.
Come on, come on.
Just keep walking, keep quiet, okay?
- Renaldo!
- Mama!
No, Renaldo!
Renaldo!
She's dead, Renaldo.
Come on, come on, come on!
Come on, come on, get inside!
Let me out!
No, no, no, no!
I don't care what General Aguila
is doing right now!
I want you to put him on the phone, now!
Let me out right now! Let me out!
It's Tony Green from ClearBec!
Let me out of this car!
Jesus Christ...
Did you ever hear about
the great transformation?
Yeah, I think... What was that again?
It started about 300 years ago in England.
With the turning of public lands
into private property.
It changed the way we think,
the way we view time
and land and water and even people,
turned them into units,
commodities to be bought and sold
and therefore exploited.
Yeah, but what is bought and
sold is constant.
That's never gonna change.
You know what, Sarah?
That is absolutely incorrect.
Society needs to approve of the things
to be turned into commodities
before they can be bought or sold.
People can be bought or sold, correct?
And that did happen.
As horrific and diabolical
as that may sound, it's a fact.
Yeah, and still slavery
happens in some countries today.
Regrettably true.
But why is it that in Western society,
we no longer buy and sell people?
Because it's immoral
and it's wrong in all aspects.
Well, is it wrong to sell water?
What about air?
Would it be wrong to sell air?
Air! Come on, man!
I mean, you can't sell air.
No?
Well, what if you can't afford it?
There's lots of people all around the world
that can't afford much water.
- And what happens?
- I don't know.
They die.
Is it so farfetched, Sarah?
You can sell water,
but you can't sell air? Think about it.
I'll take the next caller.
Hello, this is Jack Begosian,
you're on the air.
The name's Charlie.
Hello, Charlie. Good morning.
Morning. I want to know
when we're gonna talk about the real truth.
What truth is that, Charlie?
About the aliens
taking over the White House.
The aliens taking over
the White House?
You know you know it, Jack.
You mean illegal aliens, Charlie.
No, you're making light.
Extra-terrestrial beings
are a real threat to our way of life, Jack.
Only if you exchange
bodily fluids with them, Charlie.
I'm not, are you?
No.
Then we're doing our part.
Thanks for calling.
Last call.
Hi, this is Jack Begosian,
you're on the air.
Hey, man,
it's Van from Oakland.
Hello, Van from Oakland, California.
Thanks for the call.
- A question, Jack.
- Yes?
Why did you quit?
Why did I quit what?
The agency, dude. Everybody knows.
Why did I quit?
Yeah.
Well, Van, when you
can't effect change from within,
I mean positive change, you have an
obligation if you're at all conscious,
to get out and try other things.
That's what I'm doing.
Other things?
You mean, like ways to effect change?
Yes.
You think people want to hear the truth,
man, but they don't.
They want sound bites,
celebrity gossip, scandal, you know.
This is true.
The news doesn't have
to be truthful anymore, just entertaining.
Nice!
You know, our values are eroding,
our morals...
What are we doing here, man?
The real question is,
what are we really after?
Is there some ultimate end,
or are we just into some sort of endless
pursuit of nothing more than pleasure?
What do you think?
I believe there's meaning
to it, to our lives.
That's what I believe.
Meaning? Like what?
I haven't learned that answer yet.
Well, keep up the good work
until they shut you down, dude.
They're not gonna shut me down, Van.
Yeah, they will.
The CIA is suing you, right?
Rumors.
And I hate to break it to you,
but the CIA does not sue.
What do they do, then?
They have several other options.
But I'd welcome my day in court.
Do you think they would? Think about it.
Thanks for the call.
One last thought.
Sometimes it seems
like a bleak picture.
But it really isn't because
the basic nature of mankind is good.
And if you don't believe me,
go on the subway,
on the bus at rush hour and take
a good look around, look at the people...
Black, brown, red, yellow, white.
They're all coming home
from an honest day's work.
And they don't do it for the money
because their jobs are
paying them very little.
But they do it for their families.
They do it for the ones they love.
And you can see it,
and you can feel it.
You can see it in their tiredness,
in their resignation,
and you can feel it
in their commitment,
their commitment to their families.
This is Jack Begosian. Good night.
Good morning.
And can you make reservations
for Clare van Huysen and I,
at that new French restaurant for two?
You know the one.
At 2:00?
No, for two at 1:00.
But the ribbon-cutting ceremony
at the hospital won't be over by then.
- It won't?
- No.
I'll make it 2:00 for two.
Okay, perfect. Thank you.
Yes, ClearBec is very pleased
we've funded this new wing dedicated
to children's cancer research.
And in addition to this wing,
ClearBec has also funded
a hospice for the out-of-town parents,
which will allow them
extended stays with the children
during ongoing treatments.
So, thank you, everyone.
To our future, the children.
Miss Swinton,
how much is ClearBec paying
to the South African government
to privatize their water system?
Miss Swinton!
Does your company still intend to sign
this deal despite the mass protests?
Miss Swinton. Miss Swinton, stop!
Back!
Your company killed my family,
killed my entire town,
poisoned them,
then shot the survivors.
You will remember them.
I presume
I have your attention now, Miss Swinton.
My country
and many others in South America
are in the war for water rights.
Who knows of this?
Few, as it is not happening
in New Orleans or New York.
The noise you hear is gunfire.
Children, women and men are being
gunned down outside Tayca, Ecuador.
I recorded it, saw it.
Inagua, a local subsidiary of ClearBec,
your family's company,
installed a water purification system
for Tayca and the surrounding area.
The system did not purify.
Just the opposite.
A very bad form of typhus
emerged in the town.
Francisco Francis broke into
the Inagua office.
ClearBec's own report stated what
was happening and how they were involved.
You can't help them.
We have to get out now.
There is always
something you can do.
The dead are the dead.
We can help
the ones that are left.
But look at what
you have in your arms.
Francisco, I can't live
without you again.
We're together forever.
Forever.
The army, ClearBec's partner in Ecuador,
moved into my town
and quarantined the area.
They had orders to find Francis
and kill any residents
that were trying to get out.
No one knew what to do
with the sick and the dying.
Then the soldiers began to get sick.
They began to execute everyone.
Question, Jack. Why'd you quit?
I thought I answered that question already.
Yeah, but I want the real reason.
I stopped believing in lies
including my own.
ClearBec has provided you
quality water products
for over 50 years.
ClearBec stands for
integrity, value, quality.
Your body is over 70% water, over 70%.
You deserve the best water possible.
The kid was my assistant last summer.
Okay? How the hell
did he get to Toronto?
Whatever. He just blew his brains out
in front of my sister
at a press conference, Tony.
Okay, Bruce. You should never have
authorized the use of force here.
- I didn't.
- Then who did?
General Aguila.
He said he had no choice.
That's bullshit! I saw it happen.
It was murder, Bruce.
Aguila is a general
for the Ecuadorian army.
He's not an officer
or an employee of ClearBec.
We are not guilty of anything.
I am saddened and disgusted
as to what happened down there,
but we are not to blame.
Yeah, so, then, what?
- Damage control.
- Damage control?
Yes.
Do you understand
that it was more than just a few villagers?
It was hundreds of people, Bruce!
Even though ClearBec is innocent,
we can't let our South African partners
find out what really happened
down there, all right?
It's best for the company.
Tony, I'll call you back.
Call me back!
How are you?
Jesus, are you all right?
What happened in Ecuador?
I am so sorry you had to see that.
We pulled a file on that kid.
He was a nutcase.
He was working for
an anti-government rag magazine.
He infiltrated our Ecuadorian offices.
I listened to a tape he left for me.
A tape?
What did we do down there?
We have interests in
Ecuador, you know that.
- Interests?
- Yes.
A boy doesn't
blow his head off over interests.
We're an international company.
We can't possibly
make everyone happy all the time.
It gets complicated.
It's best if you don't get involved.
Don't get involved in our own company?
The company that our father built.
Morgan, you do lunches,
you do ribbon-cuttings,
you do fund-raisers,
you do bad marriages.
Wow.
I'm sorry.
You should go home.
Clean yourself up, okay?
Sorry.
What happened in Ecuador
needs to be contained, Doug.
Believe me, Bruce, I know that.
None of these events
can be traced back to ClearBec at any cost.
Right.
Now, Tony was shaken up,
but I think he will be all right.
But from what I just heard,
I'm afraid your sister might be a problem.
What are you suggesting?
Morgan needs to be deflected.
Goldman Brothers, line two.
You gotta take it.
Bobby, how are you?
How the hell
do you expect me to get this closed?
Have you seen what's
coming up about ClearBec
since that kid blew his brains out?
That kid was a nut-job, Robert.
The press is all over it, Bruce.
It's completely killing the financing.
We have to close by the end of next week.
Otherwise, South Africa pulls out.
That's the scheduled close.
You want to close by the end of next week,
then our fees just doubled.
Does that mean we're not playing squash
on Saturday?
You'll have a new deal memo in an hour.
I want it signed and executed back today.
Fine.
And if anything else like
this happens, Bruce,
we're out of this deal.
Bye-bye.
I have no idea how many were killed.
Hundreds.
They burned the bodies, the evidence.
But some got away.
I did, before they infected people
who survived.
And I pray that
Francisco Francis made it out.
Francis is a great man.
They jailed him, beat
him, tried to kill him.
But he keeps rising up!
He is witness to what happened.
He will tell the truth.
If he is alive, you must help him.
May God have mercy on you
if you don't.
Jason, I made you
your favorite breakfast.
If you're not gonna eat it,
then you might as well go to your room.
What's going on?
I don't know.
He's not eating, just staring at the clock.
What's wrong with the clock?
Nothing.
Since when is he not eating?
A couple of days.
How come you haven't told me?
I've been trying to.
You don't know, he's so
frustrating, I mean...
Karen...
You were the one
who wanted to move out here off the grid.
I know.
And deal with his issues.
I can't do it by myself.
You are not by yourself.
Yes, I am.
You're here, but you're not here.
I feel it, and Jason sure as
hell feels it more than I do.
I know.
You need to spend some time with him.
Quality time.
Jack...
Just be with him.
Spend more time with your son.
Please.
Bruce, listen to me.
I've been thinking about this, okay?
Please, we gotta help these people.
We can't just leave them.
We have to call in World Health.
They can contain the typhus.
Tony, if we call in the WHO,
that's like sending out a press release
saying that ClearBec
caused the typhus outbreak.
If that happens,
the government of South Africa
will pull out of the deal for sure.
You think the South African deal
justifies what Aguila did?
No, I don't, but he said
it was a disaster beyond imagination,
that what he did was the only way
to contain the typhus outbreak.
And you believe him, right?
We have a company to run.
I have shareholders to report to.
Now we have to do the right thing.
What the hell happened
to our filtration system down there?
The river flooded, okay?
That's what happened.
But we've tested for that extensively.
The sewers backed up
and then rats were infesting the town.
The market will crucify us
if this ever gets out.
I don't know, man. I don't know anymore.
I just... You tell me,
what's the official story?
The truth.
He broke into our filtration plant
and sabotaged the system.
That's what caused the typhus outbreak.
The army came in to apprehend him,
Francis and his men fired back,
the army returned fire.
There were casualties, end of story.
Have they gotten to Francis yet?
Yeah, he's hiding up in
the mountains somewhere.
All right, Tony.
You do whatever you can
to help those people down there.
But please keep a lid on it.
You wanna go help me
stack some firewood?
Come on.
I heard you crying last night, Mommy.
Why were you crying?
Because Mommy saw something
that made her feel sad.
My sister called me.
She said she's being followed.
She's been online trying to figure out
what really happened in Ecuador.
- You tapped into her computer?
- Yes.
I never authorized you to do that.
Well, I apologize, Bruce,
I didn't think you'd object.
She's on our system
and we have responsibilities.
We both have to answer
to the Board of Directors.
This is the flavor of the week.
She'll lose interest in a second.
I don't agree.
I think this really has her going.
She made an appointment
with Tom Delmonte about this.
- Her lawyer?
- Yes.
I think we should call in Torrance.
I don't know.
There's a lot of things in this situation
which could use special handling.
We should call in Tor now.
Did you listen to the tape?
Yes.
Were you able to make arrangements
to send money to the boy's family?
I'm sorry, we couldn't locate
any relatives at all.
I need to find out
what happened down there.
ClearBec does have legitimate
interests in South America, Morgan.
Look, the boy stuck a gun into his mouth
and blew his brains out in front of me.
I think something ugly is being covered up.
And I think that you
should not get involved.
Can you find me someone
to send down there?
You're serious?
There's one of our investigators
in Washington that might be helpful.
I could speak to him.
- I'll get back to you.
- Thank you.
It's Calder. We have a situation.
ID number?
237418665.
I understand your
South African deal's in jeopardy.
That's why I'm calling you.
Well, you should have called earlier.
We have some problem areas.
And I think Morgan Swinton
may be one of them.
She and Bruce really close?
Well, they're siblings,
but if push comes to shove,
I imagine Bruce will do what he has to do.
Send me what you have on this.
Send me everything.
I was in South America a long time,
I never saw anything like this.
It's a serious mess.
We have to make this disappear.
Yeah?
Doing much these days, Jack?
Not really.
Some civilian wants something checked
out in Ecuador, good money.
You take it.
Still got a price on my head down there.
Take a flight, look around, fly back home,
file a report, pick up a nice check.
What's the matter?
- I don't think so.
- You can't outrun it, Jack.
You ought to know that by now.
I don't like you, Clive.
No. You don't like anybody
who knows what you did.
Come on, let's pick this up, come on.
You forget it was for a good cause.
It wasn't for a cause.
It was for vested interests.
Take the job.
I got a family now.
You're marking time.
I've already hung up, Clive...
Hey, you're leaving earlier and earlier.
I have a lot of work to do.
I listen to your show every night, Jack.
Do you know that?
I lie in bed and I listen to it
until I fall asleep.
It's the next best thing
to having you beside me.
I'm always amazed
at how much you give to complete strangers.
It's part of the show.
I wish you'd bring more of the show home.
What is it, Jack?
What are you looking for?
Like the show says.
Yeah...
Well, maybe the truth is right here.
You were always
the smartest girl in the room.
I gotta go.
Jason ate a little bit with me today.
Just a little bit.
I don't care what you say!
I think it was stupid.
I disagree. It wasn't stupid.
It was an impassioned choice, a sacrifice.
My father always told me there is nothing
worth laying your life down for.
I disagree.
You don't know what you're talking about!
What is life without freedom?
You're still alive.
Is freedom worth dying for?
No, it is not!
That's the question.
This is Jack Begosian. Good night.
And good morning.
Jack?
Jack Begosian?
Yes?
I'm Morgan Swinton.
Yes, I know. I saw you on the news.
You have a moment?
I need to talk with you.
The village was quarantined
and many people,
perhaps hundreds, died or were executed
for corporate protection.
ClearBec may be implicated.
I need someone to go down there
and find out what happened.
And you come highly recommended.
I'm told you're very familiar
with that part of the world.
I've already said no.
And I'm asking you to reconsider.
There may be survivors,
witnesses to what happened.
If there are, I need you
to bring them back here.
- And then what?
- I'll go public.
I'll stop them from doing
that deal in South Africa
because you know
what they'll do down there.
Bleed it dry.
They'll be left trying to
suck an elephant through a straw.
I'll pay you very well, Mr. Begosian.
Fifty thousand before
you travel down to Ecuador.
If you come back
with witnesses, another 200,000.
All expenses paid,
including private air travel.
Wasn't your father
the founder of ClearBec?
Yes.
Then why are you doing this?
My father taught me everything has a price,
but not everything should be for sale.
Ever seen a boy
blow his brains out in front of you?
Unfortunately.
ClearBec was a good company,
Mr. Begosian.
Listen to this recording.
It mentions a name, Francisco Francis.
That name mean anything to you?
A very bad form of typhus
emerged in the town.
Francisco Francis broke into
the Inagua office.
ClearBec's own report stated what
was happening and how they were involved.
They had orders to find Francis
and kill any residents
that were trying to get out.
No one knew what to do
with the sick and the dying.
They began to execute everyone.
I was offered $250,000
to take a job in South America.
$250,000?
Who would offer you that?
Her name is Morgan Swinton. She's a major
shareholder in ClearBec, the water company.
Her father founded the company
and her brother, Bruce, runs it.
It's been a long time
since you've been out in the field, Jack.
You don't have to do this.
Listen to me.
There was a name on the CD.
There was a name mentioned.
- Francisco.
- Who?
Francisco Francis.
He was responsible for organizing
a peasant revolt in South America.
They were protesting
the privatization of water and land rights,
and industrial pollution.
He became
quite militant
and he was labeled an eco-terrorist.
You knew him.
If he's alive, and if he's in trouble,
I need to help him.
Why?
Lowe him.
For what?
You know I can't tell you that.
It's best you don't know.
My God, what did you do down there?
Just think of the money.
Look, if you... If you need to do this...
I need your blessing.
Then do it.
Do it, but don't do it for us.
It's the same thing.
Okay.
This is Jack Begosian.
Somewhere along the line,
we decided to turn the seven deadly sins
into virtues. Greed, gluttony, anger...
Hello?
Yes, this is Jack Begosian.
We're on.
Thank you.
Don't thank me yet.
I need the 250 up front.
All up front?
Yes, for my family,
and any unforeseen expenses.
My advice is to keep a low profile
and stay away from your brother.
My brother would never harm me.
You can't guarantee that.
I'll get back to you to
finalize arrangements.
- Did you get my list?
- Yes.
I arrive in Quito tomorrow.
Who are you working for now?
Myself. Got to go...
- I'll call you.
- Okay.
What's the matter, champ?
Come on, walk me to the truck.
I wanna talk to you.
Come on.
Can you get the door for me?
Okay, Dad.
- You got it?
- Yeah.
Good boy.
Come here, I want to talk to you.
Okay.
You know, Daddy's gotta
go away on this trip.
So you gotta be the man
of the house, right?
You gotta take care of Mom, all right?
And no matter what happens,
you're gonna be my son forever.
Right?
Nothing could ever change that.
And I’m gonna be your dad forever, right?
Yeah, forever.
Now, look.
See this?
Look at that. Who's there?
Me and Mom.
You and Mom, that's right.
And I'm gonna
have you guys with me all the time.
And I'm gonna place you
right here next to my heart, okay?
I have you with me all the time,
then nothing can ever happen to me.
This is Jack Begosian.
Somewhere along the line,
we decided to turn the seven deadly sins
into virtues. Greed, gluttony,
anger, avarice...
Mr. Begosian has been
instructed not to answer that question
for the sake of national security.
This is a matter of national security!
I am instructing you to
answer the question!
I will remove Mr. Begosian from this
hearing before I instruct him to answer.
Did you He under oath, Mr. Begosian?
Don't answer that question, Jack!
The CIA has no standing in this hearing.
Please answer the question, Mr. Begosian.
Did you He under oath?
Yes.
I lied.
Welcome to Quito, Mr. Shore.
Come on up.
I got something to show you.
Thank you.
Welcome to my home. Come on in.
Close the door.
Miguel said you might need
a little bit of protection, so...
You pick.
Come on, let's get out of here.
I'll give you a good price.
Let's go.
What's your hurry?
I'm gonna get you there on time.
Give me the keys.
- You don't want me to drive?
- No.
I'm your guy.
- Get in the car.
- Good!
That way, I can keep drinking.
You're lucky you know my friend Miguel.
He says you two worked together before.
Says I can trust you.
He said I could trust you.
I'm very good at what I do, my friend.
So, you work both sides, then?
Yeah, but only one at a time, okay?
A man of principles.
I'm a professional.
You pay me, I work for you.
And I'm the only one
that knows where they're at.
I got smugglers that work
the mountains for me.
And they see a lot of things.
Tell me this one thing, then.
What?
Francisco Francis, is he alive?
For now, yeah.
I arranged a back-up
vehicle like you asked.
It's up by Esmeraldas.
It's the old slave town.
It's gonna be a quick extraction.
We find Francis, we're in and we're out.
I know you have a plane waiting.
But what if Francis
doesn't want to go with you?
What then, my friend?
Then he won't survive.
South Africa has over 50 million people.
We'll be running the entire water system
and we're in negotiations with Greece.
- Greece is going to privatize water?
- Yes.
Look, I've been
hearing nasty rumors about ClearBec.
Our reputation as an international provider
of high-quality water service is impeccable.
Yeah, right, I'll send you my story.
Send it to me before it goes to print.
Thanks, Wayne.
You're late. You have docs to sign.
I'm not signing anything
until I get some answers about Ecuador.
Wouldn't mind a coffee, though.
Tracy, coffee, straight up.
Morgan, this deal with
South Africa is huge.
We are going to own
every drop that country's got.
Wow. That'll certainly drive up
the profits, won't it, people?
Come sign these...
That'll be my arm.
Hang on.
All right, all right, all right.
When was the last time
you brought the kids up to the lake house,
like Dad did with us?
I want you to listen to me.
I have power over your bank accounts,
your estate and your stocks.
That's the way Dad set this up.
And I can have that changed.
No, you can't.
You can't.
Your well-being is inextricably linked
to the well-being of ClearBec.
You have to sign these papers.
You need to sign these papers.
No. You need me to sign these papers.
I have to have a cup of coffee.
Thank you.
Yes?
Morgan just hired Jack Begosian
to go to Ecuador.
Morgan's hired someone
to go to Ecuador?
Not just someone, Jack Begosian.
Who's Jack Begosian?
That's correct, General.
I'm sending you
an extensive file on him right now.
Jack Begosian?
That's correct.
- I understand, Mr. Calder.
- Thank you, General.
The army is controlling access
to the area where my men have seen him.
Give them a little bit of money
and they'll let us move through.
Slow down here.
Just let me do the talking, okay?
I know how to handle these matters.
Listen. If he asks who I am, tell him
I'm a Canadian nature photographer.
- Do you have a camera?
- No.
That can be a problem.
Commander, how are you?
Listen, he's a Canadian photographer.
We want to go up the hill.
To take pictures of the
beautiful Ecuadorian landscape.
Ask him how long
it would be on foot to the bird sanctuary.
Bird sanctuary...
A day and a half.
Ask him if he would be so kind,
if we leave him our jeep,
and let us pass through on foot.
He says yes.
Okay, tell him,
"Thank you very much,"
and come get your stuff.
Thank you.
Get them out of the road.
He's dead.
It's okay.
Are you from Tayca?
No, all the people
in Tayca are dead.
The sickness
killed almost everyone.
Morning, Bruce.
Some liabilities close to home
have developed.
- With my sister?
- No, Tony Green.
- Tony?
- He's going to the press.
He already set up a
meeting with a reporter.
Are you crazy?
You can't do that!
You cannot shoot soldiers here!
This is General Aguila's area!
- And then you leave a witness behind!
- Too late.
Yeah, too late, too late for me! I'm toast!
General, three of our men
were found dead near Gauinee.
Their bodies were brought
down to the side of the road.
Efficient.
What an asshole.
That should be our man.
Find him and keep me informed.
Yes, General.
Top of that ridge. That's it.
They're up there.
- Past the ridge?
- Yeah.
What are you doing? What?
I don't climb at night.
I wish...
Good evening, Mr. Green.
Would you mind terribly
if I called you Tony?
Or would you prefer Antonio?
Yeah, I would prefer you call me
by my goddamn name.
I am Anthony Green, American.
Now cut me loose, chief, will you?
Who was your meeting with, Mr. Green?
I had no meeting.
My meeting's with you.
It's our understanding you were scheduled
to meet with a member of the press,
unfriendly to our cause.
Yeah, your cause...
That's what you call it?
It is my duty to protect my country,
Mr. Green.
Okay, let me tell you something
about your understanding.
It's based on a misunderstanding
because I didn't meet with any reporter.
What an unfortunate answer,
Mr. Green, as we say...
For I have already met with the reporter.
This only confirms
our suspicions about you.
No. No, no, no.
My men will take care of you from here.
The reason this has happened
is because too many people
have too much,
and too many people have too little.
So this is not over by any means.
I agree with you.
Hey! Hey, man!
I am an American. I'm an American!
You can't do this to me!
Yes, General?
Your associate seems to be missing.
Well, if you find him,
have him give me a call.
I will.
We have located your Jack Begosian.
There is $1 million for you
if you could dissuade
Francisco Francis and Jack Begosian
from leaving Ecuador.
Mr. Calder,
I believe they're worth a million each.
I think you're right.
This is Jack Begosian, you're on the air.
I was hoping
we could talk about eternity, Jack.
In what sense?
Do you think that
there's some aspect of ourselves
that lives on, beyond this life?
Yes, in the example we leave.
What do you mean by that?
In the example you leave behind,
good or bad,
that's what's remembered.
How do you want to be remembered, Jack?
Well, I've done some things
that I'm not proud of.
And will never be forgotten
that are
impossible to forgive.
But I'm trying to do my best
to make amends and catch up
and do my part.
Thanks for the call.
You all right?
Hold on.
Put your gun down.
Put your gun down!
Hey!
You'll get your money
by next Friday, Quako.
I must tell you,
if this is forced to referendum,
we cannot deliver on our agreement.
If this is not settled next Friday,
it may well go to referendum.
Rest assured, we'll be closed next week.
My associates and I
have always felt ClearBec
was the most qualified company
with which to work.
Good.
But we've been hearing
some very unfavorable rumors
regarding ClearBec in Ecuador.
It's nothing to worry about.
There are many companies
we can do this deal with, Bruce.
Rest assured we'll be closed.
Good.
We'll be awaiting your payment.
Roberto Shore de Canada.
What is your real name?
Jack.
Jack Begosian.
What brings you to these mountains,
Jack Begosian?
I came looking for the survivors
of the attack at Tayca.
Why? To what end?
The people I work for,
they want the world
to know the wrong that was done here,
and the people who did it, charged.
That's never gonna happen.
ClearBec pays millions and millions
of dollars to the politicians here.
They can be stopped.
Okay. Well, I admire your spirit.
Were you at Tayca?
Yes, I was.
There was a massacre there.
I'm aware.
What brought you there?
My father lived in Tayca.
We were visiting him when the typhus broke.
I went to the offices of Inagua
to get some answers.
I got none.
So I broke in at night
and I got many answers.
They say that I poisoned the water.
They say that I attacked the army.
Neither is true.
It's a lie.
I believe you.
Let me help you, Francisco.
Thank you.
So, how do you know my name, Jack?
You were the founder and leader
of La Vida Campesina.
I didn't lead them well.
The movement almost died underneath me.
I learned that nothing grows
out of the barrel of a gun
but violence.
And that Mao was wrong and Gandhi is right.
You said you found answers
when you broke into the offices of Inagua.
ClearBec's filtration system
is what caused the typhus.
You have proof?
I have their records. I downloaded them.
I have them over here.
Then come with me.
Be a witness against ClearBec.
Tell your story.
Francisco...
Come with me.
I don't trust him.
We don't know him.
It's fine.
I'll tell him.
My wife, she doesn't trust you.
I know.
She thinks that our family won't be safe.
Is your family safe here?
How long can they live like this?
How long can anyone live?
The answer's always the same, until we die.
Come with me.
We will stop ClearBec from doing what
they did here in other countries.
How do you know they'll listen to us?
You have to trust me.
Francisco...
You must trust me.
You must trust me!
Forgive me.
I lost control.
I had to do it.
I lost my family.
I share your pain.
I understand your pain.
I put my trust in you.
Thank you.
We need to move now.
Get your family out!
- Mama!
- Mia! Mia!
Go, go, go!
Come on, come on.
Mama!
Jesus, are you all right?
Are you both all right?
Listen to your mother.
I have to go back.
Yes. Go.
Come on, let's go! Let's move! Move...
- I can't. I gotta go back!
- What?
He has to go back.
He has to help
them or else they'll die.
He must not go back up there.
Please, please, take care of my family.
If something happens to you,
the truth will not get out.
She has truth.
Keep moving downhill.
- Jesus!
- Mama!
It's okay, it's okay.
Here you go. You ready?
Yes.
- Shoot to kill. Got it?
- Yes.
Wait for my first shot.
Okay, get them out of here!
Get them out of here!
Francisco! Your family, let's go!
Let's move!
Francisco, we gotta move!
It's all clear up there.
Okay? Rest up a little, lie down.
Francisco.
May I sit for a moment?
Of course.
There's something you need to know.
What?
I worked for the CIA in South America.
I see.
I'm the man responsible
for sending you to prison.
Well, then...
I'm indebted to you.
I don't understand.
When I went to prison,
it changed the way I thought.
I wrote this book, Presence is Born.
I published it under a pseudonym.
You wrote Presence is Born?
Yes.
That book was very successful.
It was a best-seller.
Yes, I gave all the rights to that
book to la Vida Campesina.
You regret that?
No.
La Vida Campesina
is 150 million people strong.
It's a movement of peasants and farmers
who are fighting,
unlike me, peacefully,
for the integrity
of their land and their water,
and for the needs of all their children,
and the children to come.
Do you have children?
I have a boy. His name is Jason.
"You will be my son forever and ever."
I wrote that when my son was born.
Nothing will ever change that.
Nothing.
I'm sorry, my friend.
It was a gift.
It was a gift to me.
We need to move on.
I have a vehicle waiting for us up here.
Give me your hand. Come on.
Francisco, let's go!
We have to get out of here!
Francisco! Francisco!
The people down here regard you a hero.
They call you Francisco Francis.
I was born in San Francisco.
You received your Ph.D.
in Environmental Studies.
You came down here
with Greenpeace to South America,
and now you're serving
11 years in a very tough prison.
Yes.
How did you become involved
in the South American water wars
that resulted in you becoming incarcerated?
How could I not get involved?
It became illegal for farmers
to collect rain water
because ClearBec owned
all the water rights in the whole country.
That's like saying, "I own God."
Do you have any regrets
about what you did, and being here today?
I regret the violence.
I regret
not having enough knowledge
to make the proper choices
that would have helped the people.
I regret that.
Hello?
Hello, can you hear me? Hello!
Mom, it's for you.
Thank you, sweetie. Thank you.
Hello?
Yes, this is Jack.
I've found Francisco Francis.
Yes. Is... Is he...
He's alive. Listen very carefully.
I need you to call the number I gave you.
Tell them there are four people coming in.
I'm gonna text you the names,
confirm you receive them,
forward and delete. You got that?
And... And...
Hello?
Jack?
Yes?
Well, looks like
you're gonna get your money's worth.
When that plane lands,
we've got to prevent Begosian
from bringing Francis anywhere where he
could cause any more damage,
because, Bruce, if we
don't, we are finished.
We've gone too far, Doug, too far.
Bruce, listen to me.
Francisco Francis has many enemies.
Violent people
who will stop at nothing to eliminate him.
They hired an assassin, Tor.
The assassin will kill Jack Begosian
and Francisco Francis.
Our security will kill the assassin
because they're there protecting Morgan.
And Morgan will still be a liability.
Am I your enemy now, Bruce?
No, but...
What you're doing will
bring down ClearBec, Morgan.
Maybe ClearBec deserves
to be brought down.
You're forgetting
all the good that we have done.
You're forgetting those
thousands of towns and villages
that we provided water
for that otherwise wouldn't have had it.
You're forgetting about all the lives
of the children that we saved.
No, I'm not.
But I'm not forgetting
about Ecuador either.
I'm sorry that that happened, I am.
But you're forgetting
to look at the big picture.
We have to move on,
we have to move forward.
There's just too much at stake.
Too much what?
When is it enough, Bruce?
I can't believe that
you of all people would say that.
Do you remember
what Daddy used to say?
"It's never too late
to do the right thing."
Bruce? Goldman Brothers on two.
Robert.
I thought you'd like to know you're funded.
You have the $2 billion dollars
for your South African friends.
Thank you.
Yes?
Hello?
Are you there?
We're funded.
What do you want me to do, Bruce?
What about your sister?
What do you want me to do
about Morgan, Bruce?
Okay.
We'll pinch them just past the
clock tower outside the airport.
Tor, you'll take
the kill shots from the roof.
Okay. We gotta get out of here.
- How was your flight?
- Pretty good, thank you.
Good. You owe me one, Jack.
Yes, sir.
Our subjects are Begosian,
Francis, and Morgan Swinton...
They're on their way.
Got it. We're green.
Everyone, we're green.
Go to the roof.
When Tor takes them out,
I need you to kill him.
Plant this cell phone on him,
there's 43 calls to Aguila.
That should be
a good enough connection.
- Yeah.
- Go.
Is this your service, Jack?
Is this your mission?
I guess you can call it that.
Tor... Jack Begosian. Take the shot.
Tor, take the shot.
What the hell's going on? Take the shot.
Ecuador, Ecuador, Ecuador!
Everybody, down!
Tor has turned.
I repeat, Tor has turned!
Ven, take him out!
Stay down, stay down, stay down!
Take your family out!
No! Francisco!
No!
Calder, you son-of-a-bitch!
Everybody, out! Let's go, go!
Let's go! Go, go, go!
Get in! Get in, quick!
I got it! Let's go!
These are the pledge holder agreements.
- I'll get Raymond to notarize.
- Just get out.
And Goldman wants to be included...
Get out!
...Front Street, amateur footage...
...armed with automatic weapons,
began a gun battle after a
near-collision between two vehicles...
Yes?
Bruce, this is salvageable.
Francis is the only one whose testimony
can possibly hurt us in court.
He's in the hospital.
I will personally pay him a visit.
This is not acceptable, Doug!
Bruce, I will protect our company,
our employees, our shareholders, and you.
I will fix this.
Francisco Francis, an eco-terrorist...
As the majority shareholder
in ClearBec,
I promise a full investigation
into what happened in Ecuador.
Thank you. Thank you, all.
Go. I'll talk to you later.
Black, no sugar.
You listened well.
Thank you.
Why'd you do it?
It's hard to find good
radio talk show hosts these days.
The wind, it blew in your favor, Jack.
You know, it's not over.
While Calder's still
walking around out there.
You call it.
Heads or tails?
Yeah, this is the account number: 3714826.
Yes, sir. How can we help you?
I need a 6-5, please.
Departing when, sir?
It should be ready
for wheels up in about three hours.
Yes, sir. Destination?
I'll call back.
What the hell?
A golf bag, really?
You think we can't handle this, Jack?
There are a thousand ways to spin this.
Francis is a terrorist.
You're lunatic fringe, Jack. You know that?
You hear me?
You made shit like this disappear
a hundred times.
What, you think we can't?
Well, we can.
We can, Jack!
Let me tell you how this is gonna work.
Before your skin starts to blister,
you're gonna smell something.
You're gonna smell your hair
and your eyebrows as they begin to burn.
Then your eyes are gonna ooze.
They're gonna run
like broken egg yolks.
I know what you did.
I saw what you did.
You're not...
You...
You are not better than me, Jack!
We are exactly alike!
Take a look at yourself, Jack!
I know who you are!
Excuse me, sir.
Did you say "golf bag"?
You heard right,
in a golf bag outside the house.
His name is Doug Calder.
He's the man responsible
for the shoot-out today on Front Street.
This is Jack Begosian,
and for those of you just tuning in,
you are listening to
the new daytime version of The Truth.
Today I have with me,
the great honor to have Francisco Francis,
the founder of La Vida Campesina movement
who brought to light the atrocities
committed by ClearBec in Ecuador.
Francisco, the floor is yours.
Thank you for having me, Jack.
The reason that the ClearBec incident
is so horrible
is that it exposes the lengths
to which corporate interests will go
in order to protect themselves.
Absolutely.
We'd like to hear your thoughts.
Next caller, please.
Hello, this is Jack Begosian.
You're on the air.
- Hi, Jack. This is Jeff.
- Hello, Jeff.
What's gonna happen to ClearBec now?
Well, Morgan Swinton
Is the major shareholder In ClearBec,
and she has promised
to pave a new moral path for the company.
Her brother, Bruce Swinton,
has been indicted
for conspiracy to commit murder.
The guy's already out on bail.
He's got all the money in the world.
You know how the system works, Jack.
No client's guilty until
they run out of money.
Well said. Thanks for the call.
You know, Jack, I think
that the important thing to realize here
is that the water deal
in South Africa has been stopped,
just as it was stopped in Paraguay,
just as it should be stopped everywhere.
We are talking about a natural resource,
a natural resource that
should be controlled
by the government for the people,
not by the private entity whose major
interests are to maximize profit.
We have individuals who can't even
afford to buy a piece of bread,
and now they won't even be able to
afford drinking a glass of water.
This is something that cannot occur.
This is something that we have to stop.
You're listening
to Francisco Francis on The Truth.
Next caller.
I just want to know
what the hell makes people like Swinton
step over the line the way he did.
We all have demons, each of us.
Come on! Bruce Swinton was greedy!
He just wanted more and more.
It's not only about greed.
It's about many things.
Fear, selfishness...
Are you excusing him, Jack?
Is that what you're doing?
It's just not that simple. I'm not
defending him, I'm not excusing him,
nor am I excusing myself.
You know, Jack, sometimes we do things
that are difficult for us to let go of,
surrendering control, even of the thought
that we can judge or forgive ourselves.
All the things we've done,
the things we carry in our past,
they only add up to this moment.
Hi.
Where are you?
I'm at the lake house.
Even violence, non-violence itself
is not the absence of fighting the enemy.
It's the ability to fight the deeds
of the enemy, not the human being.
The lake house?
And I know that what you have done
has opened up a road
to save thousands and thousands of people.
God, we used to come here a lot
when we were kids, didn't we?
Yeah.
It's a little chilly, but
it's beautiful as ever.
You taught me how to swim there.
You brought light
to a situation that was in the dark.
Bruce, I'm on my way.
You've saved countless amounts of people
and for that I'm very,
very thankful to you, Jack Begosian.
Morgan...
Yeah?
I'm proud of you.
Don't...
Bruce?
At the end of the day
all we can do is search for the truth,
learn from it
and most importantly, defend it.
So on behalf of myself
and Francisco Francis,
I am Jack Begosian
and you are listening to The Truth.
Good night, and make it a good day.
- Thanks for having me.
- All right.
I, myself, I'm going home and that's...
That's a good place to start.
Beyond the ideas of wrong-doings
and right-doings is a field.
I'll meet you there.
Original Subtitle by Dorothea
Join Subtitle by Ian091280
Ngayogyokarto Hadiningrat,
Rebo Kliwon, 20 Februari 2013
Original Subtitle by Dorothea
Join Subtitle by Ian091280
Ngayogyokarto Hadiningrat,
Rebo Kliwon, 20 Februari 2013