How many beds
are there in this flat?
A couple, I guess.
Is this not your home?
No.
So, you're not the romantic that
stuck the stars in the ceiling?
No. That doesn't
mean I'm not a romantic.
Do you always like
to do it on the floor?
It was a spur of the moment.
Yeah, well, my back hurts.
It doesn't happen too often.
For the moment,
you can rest assured.
But wait, does that mean
we can have an uncool?
Onto bed, of course.
Let's see, I need some
time to recover first.
No pressure.
Do you at least know
where the shower is?
- A thing in here for you.
- Thank you.
Would you mind if I take this off? It's
starting to bother me a little bit.
To where's you feel
most comfortable?
Good.
That's where I'd have
to keep it on all evening.
It was just a game.
Good excuse to
show off my purchase.
Don't get cocky.
I like you more like this.
Is that a compliment?
Yes, can I tell?
Thanks.
Undercover celebrity
or secret service agent?
Intergalactic seducer.
You're going to have to show me an
intergalactic seducer certificate to prove it.
Fuck, I left it at home.
All jokes aside, what do you do?
Don't you want to
keep our lives secret?
We could come up with a fictional
identity for each other.
We don't know anything
about each other.
So? Don't you find it fun to explore
a different version of ourselves?
I don't know.
Sorry, sometimes I get a
little carried away by my idea.
No, no, no,
don't apologise, it's fine.
Marcello.
Yeah.
You remind me of the Delta Beta.
Do you like old black
and white movies?
Masterpieces never grow old.
That's true.
Well.
I can't wait to hear more about
your career as an aerospace engineer.
With pleasure
but first we toast...
- ...to artificial satellites
- To the sweet life.
I didn't realize how late it was.
Time flies in my company.
Maybe I should change
your name to Modest.
M.M. Marcello Modest,
the best of the best.
I've created a monster.
Do you have to wake
up early tomorrow?
No.
I'm asking you because,
you know,
by now your carriage's already
turned back into a pumpkin.
Are you asking me to stay?
Yeah, okay, yeah, I'm yet to
determine your profession, so...
Great.
Chocolate shop owner.
Could be offended.
No. No, I didn't mean anything
by it. I didn't...
That's the door
I'm seriously, I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to...
I'm only winding you up.
Arsehole.
I'm sorry,
what did you just call me?
How dare you call
me an arsehole?
You come to my flat
and you call me an arsehole?
Which isn't even my flat anyway.
- Okay, now it's me that's starting to....
- Leave it.
Wait here,
I'm gonna get something.
Guess what's inside.
Viagra's and poppers.
What a perverse mind.
Can I?
It's beautiful.
Where did you find it?
In a flea market in Istanbul.
The gentleman who sold it to me,
who, by the way, had the thickest
moustache I have ever seen,
told me that it dates back to
the times of Sultan Murad III.
No.
Legend has it that a nobleman
gave it his favorite slave
with the promise that should the number
three come up three times in a row
he would free him.
The master however
was in love with the slave
so every night he would pray that
he wouldn't throw three threes,
so that he would
never abandon him.
It is rumored that
the dice was enchanted
because his wish came true.
The slave remained by his side
until his death.
- And you were persuaded.
- I couldn't resist.
It's a bit of a sad
story though, isn't it?
You know, the slave
never gains his freedom.
Well, maybe
he was the one
who was really free.
While
his master was a slave
to the love he felt for him.
If you say so.
Listen, Mr Skepticism.
How about we put
the legend to a test?
How?
We play a game.
Each face of the dice
corresponds to an action
that we must perform.
And who decides the actions?
We do.
Okay, I'm in,
but under one condition.
You can never back down.
You must always do
what the dice says.
Obviously,
I told you it's enchanted.
Okay, perfect.
Okay, so.
Number one,
tell an uncomfortable truth.
- We start strong.
- This is no joke.
Number two...
Do something the other
one likes.
Sold.
Number three, invite a third
person into the apartment.
I can already see your sinister
intentions.
What? Sinister intentions are all
in the eyes of the beholder.
I'd be very careful
of the eyes of the beholder.
Four,
do a hundred push-ups.
No, actually, no.
I don't want that one.
Um...
Decently blindfolded.
And I am the pervert.
Nope.
You're just silly.
Number five,
leave the apartment.
Fuck, the game gets tough.
But what happens
if it's your turn?
Well, you're leaving anyway.
It's me who rented
the apartment.
Yeah, fair enough.
And six, sex.
So predictable.
Well, at least we think
of it the same way.
So, here's yours.
Thank you.
I asked for it.
How's she?
Well, believe it or not, I am
not the new kid in the block.
Yeah, you're a true nerve man.
Yep.
That's it.
Okay, you can stand up now.
Can I trust you?
Okay.
Okay, this way.
To the left, keep going, here
we are, and a bit to this way,
and now to this way, and
now this, here we are.
And we need to come this way.
So, your first task will be, no not that,
you will have to prepare the spritz.
Seriously?
Come on,
it's not that difficult.
Okay.
Let's put this down.
Yeah.
Start with that.
Go.
Is this dry?
Yeah.
Go.
Go, go, go, go, go, go.
No.
That's it?
And then this one now.
Go.
Okay.
Yes.
Yeah.
Here.
But enough.
And then that one.
Wait.
Open it.
Okay.
There you go.
And go for it.
Enough, enough, enough.
Put it down.
That's it.
Did I make a mess of it?
Let's say that it
looks quite boozy.
Yes.
Okay.
Drink.
You're gonna need it now.
That's a good thing.
Yeah.
We'll start with a bang.
Come on.
I don't know anything about you.
You've got a wide choice.
Okay.
When I was in college,
still young and handsome,
I worked as a cam
boy for a while.
Are you kidding me?
I swear.
Well, my parents didn't
want me to study literature.
They said it was
a useless degree.
I, of course,
decided to do it anyway.
So that's where your passion for
playing with dice comes from then.
I hadn't thought of that before. Well
I see that you're quite the expert too.
Well sometimes I went to CAM websites
and I remember seeing the roll the dice option
that determined what the model would do
next. I just never got what I wanted.
What was that you wanted?
These cuts were really good.
Did you ever meet
any of your fans?
No. Most of the time
I didn't even have to undress.
It's, er, there are many,
many people in the world
who just want the attention
of a handsome guy.
Such a generous soul.
Ahem.
Matcha Lumote.
Were you never embarrassed?
And what? When you're in a locker
room, don't you see dicks around you?
Yeah, but it's different.
Are you afraid of a hard time?
No, actually I think of myself
as more of an enthusiast.
Are you expecting someone?
This late.
No please, let me go, let me go, I can
explain, I can explain, I can explain.
Yeah, I am really curious to know why you've
come to our flat at two in the morning.
You're crazy! Do you want
me to die of a heart attack?
And you, what do you think
you're doing with that?
Who the fuck are you?
Why do you have keys?
I'm Maria.
The cleaning lady!
I'm gonna call the police.
No! No, no, no! Police!
I wasn't here to steal, I swear.
And what did you want to do?
Are you Italian?
I've lost my wedding ring.
When my husband found out,
he kicked me out.
He thinks I've got a lover.
And you expect
us to believe you?
No, no, no.
That's the truth. I swear.
They wouldn't let me
go home until I find it.
And you want to sleep here?
No! Do you listen
to me when I speak?
I just want to find my ring
and save my marriage.
Come on,
let's start looking for it.
What?
Really? My gosh, thank you,
thank you, thank you.
Okay.
Damn!
Shit!
Excuse me, but you can't.
What the fuck is going on?
No!
In summary.
'Sta disgraziata,
lost her ring while cleaning.
I have rented this apartment.
And you are interrupting
my date with him.
So I kindly give you ten minutes to
find it and then you have to evaporate.
Understand?
Open your eyes.
Do you still love me like this?
You're gorgeous.
I mean it.
What do you think?
Be honest.
It's not so bad.
It's so sweet of you, Barry.
Well, let's see if you'll
soon be embarrassed too.
Again?
The truth, the whole truth,
and nothing but the truth.
Strawberries make me sick.
Strawberries.
Yes.
They have this shape that
looks like an irritated tongue.
They are watery
almost all the time.
And the damn green stalk.
I don't think that counts
as an uncomfortable truth.
Of course it does,
it's a nightmare.
Every time I buy a fruit salad,
or they serve a cake,
or even when I order a cocktail.
I find it there, impaled
on the edge of the glass,
and I'm forced to
remove them meticulously
in front of everyone.
And people stare at me
as if I were committing
some sacrilege.
I think that's a
bit of a stretch.
See, you're discriminating
against me too.
Okay.
And what about
the other berries?
No, I've got a fairly good
relationship with the others.
Okay.
The berries in particular.
Okay, let's switch to the tea.
Your turn.
Okay, but last lap for tonight.
Okay.
Yes!
On the bed this time.
Okay.
Slowly, slowly. My god, I'm so
sorry, I'm so awkward, I'm sorry.
It's okay, don't worry.
No, no,
I really can't get used to...
Do you really have the strength
to get dressed and go?
I mean, if you insist.
Goodnight.
Good morning, Mr. Fetishist.
No, I...
It's okay.
I've seen worse.
I thought you'd left.
I can't until the dice say so...
Come on.
I can't find the bread.
How did you sleep?
Well, thank you.
Your concert induces sleeping.
I don't snore.
You must have dreamt it.
Anyway, I wanted to tell you that it's not one
of my habits to have sex dates with strangers.
Usually...
I don't see anything
wrong with casual sex.
What I mean is there are people out there
that are more or less comfortable with it.
Me...
I don't like sharing my intimacy
unless I feel a connection.
What made you change your mind?
Full disclosure,
yesterday I was furious.
A guy I liked disappeared
all of a sudden without
any warning. He was telling me how
much of a wonderful person I am,
how he really liked me. I guess
I was trying to punish myself for
falling for it.
Not that bad for a punishment.
Let's talk about serious things.
Is it bad or good?
You know it's so bad
I have a boyfriend.
Okay.
I didn't tell you before because
I didn't know that was the case.
No, of course. Don't worry.
It was not a simple decision,
but...
Little by little we realised that there
was space in our lives for other people.
If it works for you. I don't
judge others on their choices.
Yes, it worked.
Have you ever had any
experiences of this kind?
Not until now.
- Hi!
- Hello!
- Max, is it?
- That's it. Max.
Hello.
Toilet?
Down there to the right.
Hello, handsome.
How are you? I'm Max.
Nice to meet you.
Hi.
I'm sorry, I'm sorry. I just need to
go because I drank two liters of detox.
Moody.
Feel free.
Thank you.
But then, I'm all yours.
Interesting choice.
Guys, let's put on some music.
It's like a morgue in here.
Silence, silence, silence.
I love your beard, cat.
It's so... soft.
So Max,
what do you do for a living?
Nothing interesting, obviously.
I mean...
I mean, in the sense,
it doesn't matter.
Tell us anyway.
Are we here to fuck or to lounge?
We enjoy a little
conversation before the action.
Okay.
Okay, I see, I see, I see.
You're intellectual ladies.
Anyway, thank you so
much to share this hotness.
We were playing a game.
Do you want to participate?
Yes.
Okay, what should I do?
You roll a dice and depending
on what number comes up,
you take an action.
Mind you, it is a magic dice.
Magic dice?
Interesting, I love it.
Give me the dice.
I can't believe it,
bullshitting people like this.
Sorry, rules are rules.
Fuck your rules.
Fuck your rules and fuck you.
Fuck you.
Fuck you too.
Maybe next time.
Fuck you.
You shouldn't.
Or just put a hand inside it.
Fuck the dice.
- Saved by the dice.
- But we cheated.
Yeah, but it was a matter
of survival, did you see?
For a moment there,
I feared the worst.
I'm a big girl.
I swear, I was about to explode.
You were just jealous
because all the attention was on me.
I would have gladly
left him to you.
You invited him...
You have a penchant
for muscular cardio.
We all want a trophy so we can
brag about dating a hottie.
I don't know. I generally
prefer other types of beautiful.
The uniqueness,
the mental connection.
However,
if Max hadn't opened his mouth,
you would have fucked
him without a problem.
Probably.
What?
No.
Maria will be happy.
Do you like this kind of music?
Can't I say anything?
Concentrate.
Have you ever listened to
the neighbours through the walls?
Sometimes.
Fortunately, we're not
close to a bathroom, so...
Silly.
I would worry more about
what the neighbours had earlier.
And I help out.
Once, as a kid, a friend
of my mother's came on to me.
Are you sure you want
to talk about this?
I was brushing my teeth as
he walked in to take a shower.
I remember he was wearing some
ridiculous pea green pajamas.
I quickly finished rinsing my mouth, and I was
about to leave, and he called me back.
Can you pass me the shampoo?
Something like that.
When I got closer, I saw
that he was touching himself.
For a moment, I watched him. I had
never seen an erect penis before.
Then he asked me
if I wanted to touch it.
I just knew that
something was wrong.
I dropped the shampoo
and ran away.
It was nothing terrible.
But I still think
about it and...
I feel guilty.
Why?
You didn't do anything wrong.
My silence.
I told myself that it wasn't
worth ruining his life.
He's always been nice to me.
But a few days later, he quarreled with
my mother and I never saw him again.
But over time,
I started thinking...
...what if he molested
some other kid?
Couldn't have stopped him.
You're a victim.
You're not at fault.
I never know.
- Well...
- Listen...
- Sorry, you go.
- No, no, please.
Let's see if another
hot session comes up.
Can't we just do it?
I like the risk.
Sooner or later
it had to happen.
But what if I want to stay?
- It wouldn't be fair.
- Why?
The reason why it was so intense is
that we knew it would be over soon.
Right.
Are you so terrified
by the future?
Well, I haven't felt so good with someone
in a long time, so thank you, really.
And the same goes for me.
Goodbye, Marcello.
Wait!
I have an idea.
We meet here
on exactly the same day
in the number of years
that the dice sets.
I don't see much sense in it.
I'd love to see
you again someday.
Find out how we've changed.
They created Facebook
for things like that.
I'm serious.
I didn't have time to knock.
Come in.
Are you going somewhere?
No.
Yes, the supermarket.
I needed something.
No, no, no, no, don't worry.
I can go with another time.
Three years.
Fuck.
Don't tell me.
You look good.
Thanks.
Just a few more grey hairs.
You'll soon become
a respectable daddy.
Not funny. By the way,
you're not that far off either.
Would you like a drink?
On spritz's? Blindfolded?
It's coming.
Cheers!
Am I wrong or is there big news?
Congratulations!
Thank you.
- How long?
- Two years now.
It's a bit lucky.
I realised I needed someone
to sleep by my side every night.
And you?
I'm single again.
Shit.
I'm sorry.
C'est la vie!
I thought you weren't coming.
I had my doubts,
but the curiosity was too much.
Well, I'm glad you made
the right choice.
Listen, do you still
have that famous dice?
Of course I do.
I know that's actually
what you're here for.
Okay, you got me.
It was my turn,
if I remember correctly.
Dice doesn't do foreplay.
So, shall we go to the bedroom?
Does your husband
agree with all that?
Let's just say that, in very rare cases,
we allow ourselves some exploration.
Well, I am flattered that you've
chosen to take advantage of it with me.
Don't you want to
explore with me?
Even better than
I remembered it.
- Yeah, even if different.
- What?
How to explain it?
It's more of a sensation.
I have the sensation
of sinking with sweat.
- Shower?
- With pleasure.
You go in first.
Thank you, such a gentleman.
There you go.
Shit, sorry. Apologies.
Come here.
Seriously, come on!
You know, I've never understood
that thing you Italians use.
The sole and high purpose
of the bidé is to wash your bum.
This is how it works.
Open the tap.
Make sure the water
is not too hot or cold.
You sit down on it.
You apply soap.
I'd recommend a delicate one.
You rub your tushy with water,
nice and suave.
Give it a rinse. Close the tap.
Stand up. You're done!
Nice and fresh!
It's already the best part.
I am ready to explode.
Um, are you going to
continue excavating?
I don't remember
you being this scrotoclastor.
Stop trying to
act all intellectual,
you're using big, obscure words.
Tomorrow.
Okay.
So, are you going to sleep here?
If I'm not one too many.
Of course not,
it's just that, I thought...
I don't need a
permit to sleep over.
Okay, great.
- What time is it?
- 10h00.
Let's go.
Aww, she's Samira.
Hello.
Hi.
Okay.
You didn't need to show the world
that you're little ass there.
But I need to prepare people
because mine is much more beautiful.
No, it's much more hairy.
I didn't need to know that.
So, everything in order here?
The girl who replaced
me seems quite a stoner.
Don't worry,
nothing out of place.
No wedding rings.
Don't remind me.
What a panic that day.
Thank you again
for saving my life.
How is everything
with your husband?
He's great.
Thanks so much.
He's like a little lamb now.
Although I'm a bit
jealous of that tiny pest
who steals all the attention.
You're awful.
What about you two?
I still don't
understand one thing.
Are you together or not?
No.
That's a shame.
You look so good together.
Yeah, well, um,
circumstances are...
Sorry, sorry, sorry.
I'm a meddler.
No, really? I didn't notice.
Sorry.
She's already a heartbreaker.
Yes.
Holy shit,
we need a diving mask here.
Okay, so this is a recipe my aunt
used to make us as a child,
so please don't mess it up.
Feel the carrots.
I never had any
talent in the kitchen.
Didn't you have
a chocolate shop?
Right,
I was almost forgetting that.
Well, it's never too
late in life to learn.
It only takes a
minimum of commitment.
Don't do that.
You what?
So?
No.
You will not be allowed to give
this with kisses, Mr. Modest.
Okay?
Come on.
Okay.
Good?
Stop it.
You're throwing it all together.
For what?
Don't recycle.
No.
Seriously.
Come on,
it's not the end of the world.
No, just thousands of dead animals, we end up
polluting our waters and drinking microplastics.
I didn't think you were
such an environmentalist.
It's not a question about being an
environmentalist, you're smarter than this.
Well, now you finally have an excuse to
flaunt your moral superiority over me.
And what the fuck is
that meant to mean?
Nothing, nothing.
No, no, no, no, no, sorry.
I don't do it to feel superior.
If you wanna play victim,
choose another topic.
Okay, okay, you're right.
Let's set it here, please.
Sorry about before.
Okay.
Do you want us to keep playing?
I haven't been well lately.
One morning I woke up
and I couldn't move my right arm.
I thought it was just a cramp,
but it didn't go away.
The doctor ran some
tests and it turns out
that there is a
shadow on my spine.
Wait.
What the fuck are you saying?
I'm awaiting
the results of the biopsy.
I'm sorry,
I can't imagine what...
I should have told
you right away.
Don't be silly.
I didn't know how you'd react.
There's nothing
to be ashamed of.
Or you'll suffer.
Isn't it funny?
Nobody sees pain unless
you choose to reveal it.
I'll see you then.
Hello boys.
Hello, Steve.
Where are those faces?
Don't you like my costume?
Yeah, very original.
Meet Marcello Modest.
Hi.
Nice to meet you.
So, how did you two meet?
Wasn't it an orphan's tastings?
No, don't listen to him.
We met a couple
of years ago online,
but I got engaged before
we had the chance to meet.
Unfortunately, we never
got past the big, big stage.
Can I try it?
Yeah!
Why are you dressed like this?
I sent you a message.
I was at the parade today,
remember?
Jesus, it's hot in this thing.
That's normal.
It's a demon from hell.
We were playing a game.
Do you want to participate?
We throw a dice to decide which actions
to take. I'll give you an example.
Okay, so two means that Marcello has to
do something that we like. Any ideas?
How did it seem to you?
Weird, but good.
Like I was breaking down
some sort of invisible barrier.
I didn't understand that goal.
OK.
What's your interpretation?
I don't know, it felt like a mix
of yoga and group dynamics.
I think you should stop trying to analyse
everything and just focus on what you really felt.
Okay, it's my turn to play.
Yeah, yeah it is.
What are the other rules?
One, inconvenient truth.
Two, you've already seen.
Three, invite someone else over.
Four, do something blindfolded.
Five, leave the apartment.
And six, fuck.
Yeah?
Um, if you're not
comfortable with any of that,
we can change one of them.
No, I'm okay with that.
Okay.
I'm curious.
What the hell, Steve?
Leave the apartment? Yes, these are
the rules. Okay, alright, but not right away.
Don't worry, I'll take this opportunity
to see my sister, she lives nearby.
So, you two make the most of it. I'm sorry,
I was pleased to meet you, I hope to see
you again one day.
Sure, daddy.
Too bad,
I was starting to like him.
You were giving him daggers.
Who, me?
Yeah, you were looking
like a jealous boyfriend.
Well, can't deny that
the focus was all on you.
Aw, poor Marcello.
Thinking about it, after all,
the spiel of the body
and the emotions
should have given him
a good shag, at least.
Wow, you should have
thought about that beforehand.
Sucker!
What the fuck are you doing?
Crazy.
Hello.
Yes, it's me.
Yeah, absolutely.
Okay.
So...
But is it certain?
Yeah, sure. When?
No, don't worry.
Alright, see you on Monday.
Bye.
What's happening?
Marcello?
My name is not Marcello.
Marcello doesn't exist.
I need chemo.
Everything's gonna be okay.
You're strong as a rock.
Look at this.
- Sorry, I, erm...
- No, are you kidding me?
Come on,
let's go lie down for a bit.
No, I prefer to keep playing.
I really don't think
this is the right time.
Really, I don't want
to think about it now.
I understand that, but...
I am serious. I want to play.
I'm sorry.
Marcello, don't be childish,
it's just a game.
The games are over
when one loses, no?
Come on.
Your husband will
be waiting for you.
What's my husband got
to do with anything of this?
Marcello, please stop.
Just talk to me for a minute.
Marcello, please.
Turn the lights off
when you leave.
For fuck's sake, please stop.
Stop!
See you again in two years.
If I'm still around.
Please, don't say that.
Marcello...
Fuck.
Fuck!
Wait,
we don't even know our names.
Shut up.
You're so nice, dawg.
Stop trying to change things.
We didn't speak the first time.
I forgot the condom in the bedroom.
I remember our first meeting
differently.
The stars in the ceiling
aren't there anymore.
I often thought about you
during the treatment.
I imagine telling you
how my day was.
The jokes to the nurses,
the crap I ate,
the progress I made,
the things that scared me.
I thought about you too.
I was really worried.
I'm pissed off with
the way you behaved.
I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to hurt you.
I was afraid.
Of what?
To screw everything up,
like I always do.
You'd just got fucking married.
I thought, if I leave now,
he won't suffer.
You're a compassionate arsehole.
More or less.
Love stories end
one way or another.
You would have guessed that my marriage
would have fallen apart so soon.
I'm sorry to hear that.
It is what it is.
The truth is that we have
no control over our lives.
Maybe that's why
I can't stop playing.
We should keep playing
until the dice says so.
No compromise.
No responsibilities.
Even if we end up
hating each other.
I'm interested to see what will
happen before we get to that point.
Won't the owners get angry?
I am the owner.
What?
Yeah, they made me a good offer.
I liked the place.
Congratulations
when do you move in?
I've actually been
living here for a while.
I cannot believe it.
I was tired of wondering.
I needed to stop and take root.
Well we need to
fucking celebrate.
Let's see what the dice says.
We have to celebrate.
I am terrified of dying before
I've done everything I want.
But you can't. No one can.
I want to read all the books,
visit all the countries,
see all the movies.
- I want everything.
- You want too much.
I don't care. I'm here.
I exist.
And as long as I'm alive
I have the right to dream.
I have the right to
pursue happiness.
And you? What do you want?
To listen to all the records,
cook all the recipes,
fuck all the men,
I want everything too.
Well, I want to try and get
as close as possible.
We have the power to try,
until the end.
We have the duty to try,
Can you believe we're
still seeing each other
after all these years?
It's definitely only
because of the dice.
Screw you.
Did I tell you I was
suffering from panic attacks
every time I had
to take the bus?
Can't you talk about
silly stuff for once?
Like, I don't know,
candles that smell like vaginas.
You're not very subtle when
you want to change the subject.
Do you really want to
talk about panic attacks?
No, of course not.
I remember all the names
of the people I've slept with.
Impressive.
Yep.
Well, except for mine.
Yeah, but that doesn't matter.
You'll always be my Marcello Modest.
Enrico.
That's my name.
Really?
No.
I can't with you.
I really can't.
Okay, so let's see. What was
the name of your third boyfriend?
Adam. I was 19 and he was
older than my father.
Yeah, at that point I didn't
think I deserved love.
And you were terrified
of taking the bus.
Yeah, exactly. What a mess?
I know it sounds stupid, but...
... I thought everyone would abandon
me when I found out I was gay.
Well I wish I'd been there to tell
you that you were so fucking wrong.
You can be nice when you want.
I can indeed.
I just feel like I have so much love in my body
and yet there's so little in the reality around us.
Let it all out.
Let it flood everything.
Where's the dice?
Did someone by mistake take
the dice that was in this box?
I'll repeat it, who took
the dice that was in here?
What's wrong?
Do you know where the dice is?
No?
Well, it must be somewhere.
Shit.
Marcello, calm down.
Where is my dice?
- Where is my dice?
- Marcello, stop it!
Shit.
Shit!
Marcello, stop it!
Stop it!
You hit it, tell me the truth.
Me? Are you crazy?
- Who took it then?
- I had no idea!
- You did it!
- Are you listening to yourself?
- Take it out!
- I didn't take your fucking dice!
Stop it! You're hurting me!
Do you really need the dice
after all these years?
I don't know. I think...
I think I was afraid of losing you.
I know it has to happen.
It's inevitable.
If it's you the one who decides
to leave me, and not the dice,
I don't think I could bear it.
I'm sorry. I don't think
I can do this anymore.
I don't think I can stay with someone
that wants to run away from themselves,
who wants to run away from me,
and the whole world.
Do you understand
what I'm saying?
How did you get to this point?
I don't know.
We got tired of playing games.
You stay here with me.
Forever?
Subtitles
LAPORT INC.