(TYPEWRITER KEYS CLACKING)
THE VOICE: Once upon a time,
not so long ago.
(CLOCK CHIMES)
(CAT MEOWS)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(HEAVY BREATHING)
(SHRIEKS)
This is the story of me.
Jack.
There I am,
absolutely shitting it.
I'd been carrying a carving knife around
with me for three weeks
due to an irrational
fear of being murdered.
(PUFFS)
I couldn't sleep at night.
As soon as I got into bed
I started seeing killers.
(EXHALES)
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
(PUFFS)
These killers were
the subject of a series
of plays I had been
writing for television.
The nature of
the project necessitated
research into heinous
Victorian criminals.
And I had unwittingly
familiarized myself
with all the famous hackers,
dosers and severers of the 19th century.
Faces that would have
frightened the Ripper.
Many a long night I spent there,
drenched in thoughts
of bloody murder.
(THUNDER RUMBLES)
I became particularly disturbed
by a man I called
"The Hendon Ogre."
A maniac from North London who had
boiled the arsenic out of flypapers
and introduced the result
into his lodger's broth.
I'd lie awake for hours
thinking of the brute,
terrified someone was slipping
arsenic into my diet.
In the mornings I'd inspect grapefruit
and milk bottle tops,
looking for evidence
of interference with syringes.
Trivial events became vital cues
in the detection of my assassin.
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
If the telephone rang at 4:30,
I'd look at the clock and say,
"It was 4:30 when the telephone
rang that fateful evening.
"How could anyone
have known at the time
"how important that telephone call
was to become?"
My situation became unbearable.
I suspected
everyone and everything.
Innocent passers-by.
Creaks in the corridor.
Bumps in the night got so bad
I started plugging my head shut.
But I'd soon have to get up and check
for killers in the bathroom...
In the kitchen...
In the fridge or in the hallway,
where they kept a low profile,
crawling about in the shadows,
lurking behind creaky doors.
(DOOR CREAKING)
(YELLING)
Bloody windows! Bloody drafts!
(PANTING)
(WHISPERS) Oh, God.
(SCREAMS)
(GASPING)
This fear that I
would be murdered
all began sometime before...
At lunch to be exact.
The day I saw my
literary agent...
Newspaper?
Clair De Grunwald.
- Thanks.
- No problem.
She'd arranged to meet me
at a respectable establishment in Soho.
VENDOR: You like a newspaper?
Shall I bring sir the wine list?
Uh, yes, okay.
Pleasure.
JACK: "The body was found
in the East End of London,
"but the Hanoi Handshake
"is the unmistakable
calling card
"of a Vietnamese gang killing...
"According to one
unnamed police source,
"downtown Hackney,
also known as Little Vietnam,
"is now a bloody jungle
"of organized crime.
"The missing fingers
have yet to be found."
VENDOR: Newspaper?
Whoa, hey, no...
It please, I'm...
CLAIR: Jack!
- Clair.
- Under the table already?
It's not even 12:00!
No, I...
I'm sorry, I'm afraid
I only have an hour.
I've got to go and
meet Ragsie Lawrence.
Remember Ragsie,
the dancing dyke?
She's just been made
Commissioning Editor at the BBC.
Can you believe it?
Never underestimate a hunchback.
That's what I say.
Darling, are you going to stay there
all through lunch?
No, sorry.
Anyway.
Mmm.
It's good timing for us
because I can tell her
how busy you are
with all your murders.
- (STAMMERS) Up to my elbows.
- Good.
Do you have a title?
Uh... Decades of Death.
Chilling.
Yeah, well, if you want murder,
then Victorian Britain
is the golden age.
I think murder's lost its
sense of theater, really.
I mean, you know,
what do we have now?
- It's just like kids...
- Mindless violence?
Exactly, yes.
I mean killers don't put any thought
into their murders anymore.
Take Long Ear for example.
Have you heard of Long Ear?
Can't say I have, no.
Terrifying Polish plumber who
hacked off a Frenchman's head.
He disposed of the limbs
down the sewer,
but he couldn't think of
what to do with the head.
So, eventually he utilized
his gas-fired crucible,
filled the nose and mouth
with molten lead,
slung the whole thing
in the river.
Can you imagine? (CHUCKLES)
I'm sorry, sir. This is a non-smoking
restaurant. Thank you.
Are you ready to order, madame?
Do you know what you're having?
Um... Oh, I think I'll just have a beer.
I'm not very hungry.
One beer.
This is my treat, darling.
Oh, well, then I will have the chicory salad
with asparagus, croutons,
chorizo and poached egg...
To start, followed by the salmon
and leek fish cake
with mushy peas, chips and chive cream.
Thank you.
Lovely.
You see, why people
love a good murder...
I began to tell Clair about
my good friend, Professor Friedkin,
author of an influential paper
on the criminal stare.
An ocular condition
that instantly identified
a madman.
MAITRE D': Monsieur?
(GASPING)
(SCREAMING)
Jack?
- Jack?
- Yes.
- Sorry.
- Are you all right?
Yes. I'm... Yes, I'm sorry.
(STAMMERS) I, um...
What was I talking about?
The book. The criminal stare.
Oh, yes, yes, yes,
the criminal stare.
Um, yeah... I've, um, I've trawled through
hundreds of these photographs.
And, um...
Um, when you kill someone, when you...
When you take a life,
you acquire these awful eyes,
you know, like a...
Like a shark or a chicken.
How frightful.
Yeah, but it's...
It's not just a horror show.
You know, I've realized
that's not just
the reason I have to write this.
Oh?
No, it's a detective story,
you see, about how
they become killers.
You know, how do they get there?
What fills them with the need
to victimize and kill?
Why choose mass murder?
Why not become a writer?
Yeah, well actually, writers
and serial killers are very similar.
They're practically brothers.
What is it Hemingway says, um...
"What do you need to become a writer?
An unhappy childhood."
It's the same thing
with serial killers.
Whatever happened
to the hedgehog?
What?
He had to cross the road
and go into the woods.
But he was afraid.
Harold the Hedgehog?
Harold the Hedgehog!
Dear little chap.
Whatever happened to that story?
You never finished him.
He nearly finished me!
He wrecked my marriage, prickly cunt.
No, he did, Clair!
I'm sorry, the stress of it.
He fucking drove
Catherine out of my life.
What do you want to
talk about him for?
Darling, I'm just thinking you need
to earn some money, that's all.
This death thing
could take a while.
Timmy the Tortoise
can't pay the bills forever.
I don't want him to.
I didn't mean to become a children's author.
It was a terrible accident.
It was your destiny.
Look, why not rattle off a little
bedtime story? Hmm?
Timmy Goes to the Seaside, perhaps?
- Oh, God.
- Or Harold?
How did it start?
"Once upon a time there was
a hedgehog called Harold
"who lived in a bush."
(LAUGHING)
Or Little Johnny Rabbit?
The world is dying for another
Little Johnny Rabbit.
Johnny Rabbit is dead.
So is Timmy.
So is the fucking hedgehog.
They're all lying in the middle of the road,
covered in blood.
I killed them.
Tell that to the kids.
Darling, we're going
to make this work.
Just try not to worry too much.
And take care of yourself.
You know me better
than anyone, Clair.
Yes, I do.
You're a workaholic
and you're sensitive.
I don't want to see you go over the edge
like what's-his-name.
(GASPS)
JACK: Clair's concerns
about me proved justified.
Three weeks on and Long Ear's head
was playing on my mind.
(FLOORBOARDS CREAKING)
Life was hellish but it was just about
to get a hell of a lot worse.
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
Come on then, you bastards!
(YELLING)
My knife!
(PANTING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(YELLS)
(CRASHING)
(GASPING)
(VOICES WHISPERING)
(WHISPERING STOPS)
(CHUCKLING)
You mad bastard.
(CHUCKLES)
(URINATING)
(STOPS)
(URINATING FITFULLY)
(PSYCHEDELIC ROCK PLAYING)
(SCREAMS)
(GASPING)
(PUFFS)
(EXHALES)
Oh, I got an hour.
(SIREN WAILING IN DISTANCE)
The flying eye.
Oh... Someone's on the loose.
(TELEPHONE RINGS)
"It was 5:00 when the telephone
rang that fateful evening."
- (DOORBELL BUZZES)
- Shit, I could...
CAROL SINGERS:
♪ We wish you a Merry Christmas
and a Happy New Year ♪
Hello?
Happy Christmas.
ALL: Happy Christmas.
What do you want?
We're singing carols.
Yeah, I can see that.
Well, ain't you gonna come out
and hear us then, bruv?
No, I can hear you perfectly well
from up here. Thank you.
Blud, we've been out here for ages
and no one's given us nothing yet.
Well, honestly,
I think you should
perhaps work on your repertoire.
Our what?
Look, I'm sorry.
I can't help you.
Good night.
But it's for Save the Children.
Kids who ain't got no food,
Nintendo or nothing, bruv.
GIRL: ♪ We won't go
until we've got some
ALL: ♪ We won't go
♪ We won't go
until we've got some ♪
All right! All right! All right!
Just wait there,
I'm coming down.
Yes.
(GASPS)
BOY: You gonna open up this door then,
or what, bruv?
Um... I tell you
what I'm going to do.
Um, I'm gonna put some
loose change into this sock
and then I'm gonna feed it
through the letter box.
Did you get that?
- BOY 2: Is it clean?
- Is it what?
BOY 1: Is it clean?
Is the sock clean, bruv?
- (DOG BARKS)
- Well...
It's not box fresh,
if that's what you mean.
I... Do you want
this money or not?
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
(WHISPERS) Oh, God...
Who are you?
- BOY 1: Still there?
- Yes! Yes!
I am. Just stand back.
Okay, stand back.
Um...
Christ, can't you
see I'm not in?
Um... Okay. Get ready.
I'm opening my flap.
Here it comes.
Gently does it. Gently.
(TELEPHONE CONTINUES RINGING)
(SHOUTS) God in heaven,
will you just fuck off
and give me some peace?
Hey, wait!
Come back.
Oi! What about my sock,
you little... Thieving little...
You.
- You did this.
- (TELEPHONE CONTINUES RINGING)
You wanna hear my voice,
you sick fuck? Hear this.
(WHISPERS) Hello?
(FAINTLY) Hello,
it's Clair here.
Hello?
- (LOUDER) Jack, it's Clair.
- Clair!
Why haven't you been answering?
I've been calling for hours.
I thought you
were a wrong number.
Well, listen,
I've just had a very excited
man on the phone.
- Have you?
- Yes.
He's read your treatment
for Decades of Death
and he's very
excited by your ideas.
He wants to meet
you tonight at 8:00.
Oh... I see. 8:00?
Darling, he's off
to New York tomorrow
and it's imperative
you see him before he leaves.
Why is it imperative?
Because he's Harvey Humphries.
Harvey Humphries? Who's he?
Head of Scripts.
Clair look, can I... Can I see him when he
comes back from New York?
Because I've not been sleeping
very well and, um...
Jack, he's genuinely excited.
The arrangements have all been made.
Tonight, 8:00, 100 Humbolt Mews.
100 Humbolt Mews, 8...
That's in one hour
and 47 minutes.
Wear a suit, please.
I don't have any suits.
Well, wear a clean shirt then.
They're all dirty.
I'm down to my last sock.
Then you'll have to go
to the launderette, won't you?
(LAUGHS) What?
A launderette? Are you serious?
Of course I am.
What's the problem?
It's just, you're...
You're asking a lot, Clair.
Okay? I don't...
I don't do launderettes.
All right! Never have done.
Never will.
It's no place for a man like me.
I mean, exposing
your most intimate
articles in front of
complete strangers.
Oh, stop it,
you're being ridiculous.
You know me,
Clair, I'm sensitive!
I've never even
bought toilet roll!
All right enough!
Jack, I've worked very hard
getting your script to the right people
and I'm afraid
there's no interest.
I didn't say anything because
I didn't want to disturb you.
But that's the reality.
I can't see any other options...
It's Humphries or bust.
- I understand.
- Good.
Call and let me know
how it goes, darling.
JACK: And so it was that I first
came to hear the name
Harvey Humphries.
I had sat in every Head of Scripts
department in London
listening to these twats full
of white wine and arugula,
but I'd never heard of this man.
Harvey Humphries
of Humbolt Mews.
I didn't like the sound of it.
The name seemed innocent enough,
but there was something
about it that jarred.
I thought it might be the
Harvey-Humphries-Humbolt bit
that was worrying me,
but I had a friend called Garry Gordon
who lived in Garrick Street
and he'd never
caused me any problem.
No, it was something stronger than
just a repetition of the "H".
It was more
a sensation of having
heard the name Harvey Humphries
in some unsavory context.
Harvey!
It was the "Harvey."
Harvey was the middle name of
Dr. Hawley Harvey Crippen,
the myopic Yank
who'd spent all night
in the basement of 39 Hilldrop Crescent, N5,
separating his wife.
He'd done her in lime.
Crippen had come from America.
Harvey Humphries
was going to America
within hours of completing
his business with me.
Was Humphries
related to Crippen?
Farfetched as it might seem to
others, it was not impossible.
Crippen was an American. Yes.
And so was Humphries.
Surely it was more than a coincidence
that a man going
to America should be excited
by a title like Decades of Death,
and have the middle name
of one of the most
famous killers of the lot?
No.
No, no, no, no. Facts like that
are beyond the realm
of coincidence.
(HUMMING)
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
(CONTINUES RINGING)
Hello? Who's that?
Speak up, I can't hear you...
Oh! Oh, no, Clair's
not here just now.
This is Irene.
You want what?
Harvey Humphries.
Do you know of a man
called Harvey Humphries?
Think carefully before you
answer please, Irene.
A man's life may be at stake.
Ooh, I'll have to
think about this.
Uh, hold on a minute, love.
Well, can you tell her to call Jack back
regarding Harvey Humphries?
Tell her it's a matter
of life and death.
Life and... Life and death?
Yeah, yes, yes.
Tell her that. Exactly.
- Thank you.
- Ooh, right. Will do, dear.
Okay, okay, okay,
be rational, be rational.
Clair was obviously
not in her office,
so she must have
telephoned you from home.
That's clear. But seeing as you don't
have her private number,
and she's ex-directory,
there is no way you can call her back.
I have to trust that it was Clair,
and that she meant no malice.
After all, she has
no reason to wish me any harm.
She had no way of knowing
that she was sending one of her clients
to meet a man
related to a murderer.
Only a highly suspicious, paranoid cynic,
or someone like me,
with a... With an eye
for clues and patterns
could possibly connect the dots,
could see the truth
staring him in the face.
That Harvey Humphries is in fact
Hawley Harvey
Crippen's grandson!
Ha! No more questions,
Your Honor!
(SHRIEKS)
(HELICOPTER WHIRRING)
Right, that does it!
Where's the super glue?
(GRUNTS) Right!
You've done nothing
but terrorize me for weeks.
And I've had enough!
I've had enough!
Take that, and that,
and that, and that.
Take that, take this, take this.
(GRUNTING)
Take that! You didn't
expect that, did you?
Well, expect
the unexpected, mate!
(DOORBELL BUZZING)
God, that's quick.
(DOORBELL CONTINUES BUZZING)
Hello?
Anyone home?
JACK: Yes? Hello?
Uh, are you
the gentleman in Flat 3?
Who is this?
Community Support Police
Officer Perkins, sir.
Good evening.
How can I help you?
Oh, no cause for alarm, uh,
just a routine call, sir.
Uh, some of the kids
over on the estate said, um,
said you might be
in some distress.
How interesting.
And, uh, what might I
be distressed about?
Well, I have no idea, sir.
Are you in any distress?
No, I'm fine, thank you.
I'm just about to do some washing
and then I'm going to go to bed.
Oh, well.
Just so you know, we're out
on the beat if you
ever need assistance.
I'm just across the road.
Jesus Christ.
Sorry, sir, sorry I was
just checking you were...
I'm... Yeah, well,
I'm very sorry to bother you, sir.
Uh, I'll let you get
back to your laundry.
Policeman, my ass!
He was looking for something.
What was he up to?
Jesus, nowhere's safe.
Okay, Humphries,
you want my script?
You can have it! If it means I finally
get paid some decent money
and get the hell out
of Hackney. You're on!
Right, where's my wardrobe?
I'll show you, Clair!
I'll show you, Catherine...
Exactly what I am capable of!
(GASPS)
Jesus Christ!
God!
These aren't clothes.
This is refuse.
I might as well
take it into the garden
and dig it in around the roses.
I'd do anything for a break right now,
but not the launderette.
Not for Humphries,
not for any other man.
Why should I?
I've got everything I need here!
I've got water, I've got soap,
I've got drying facilities.
I can do this, Jack.
No more sleepless nights.
No more scuttling around in the dark.
We'll meet this monster head on.
Well-armed and well dressed.
It's a quick thrash
in the tub for you,
my lovelies,
then into the dryer.
Right.
A good 15 minutes on
regular nine for the socks,
five minutes less for the pants.
And we'll play the shirt by ear.
Now that's cooking with gas!
Okay, here's how to play it.
When you get to the meeting,
refuse to sit down.
Refuse all drinks and cigarettes.
Certainly all food.
The meeting will be
conducted standing up.
And if he leaves the room to make a call,
you go with him.
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
I'll have a pretext
for everything.
I could take an apple
or an onion into the meeting.
Yeah, that'd work. I could use it as
a circumstance to show him my...
Carving knife!
(GROANING)
(PANTING)
Come on! Come on!
(GRUNTS)
Ow!
Fuck!
What the fuck am I supposed to do now?
Cut my fucking hand off?
JACK: (IN AMERICAN ACCENT) That's correct,
Officer. When I saw the knife,
I simply defended
myself with the ice pick.
I have no idea how the pick got stuck
in the back of his neck.
Well, I put him in
the bathtub because
the blood was staining
my Persian carpet.
(GASPS)
(DOOR CREAKING)
(SCREAMING)
(GROANS)
I'm not dead yet, you bastards.
(SIGHS)
Come on, Jack,
we can still do this.
Against the odds.
We can still beat them.
Now, as I remember,
this thing has some seriously deep pockets.
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah.
I can hide a knife in there.
That's like Loch Ness in there.
Yeah, you could
hide a whole fucking
submarine in
there if you want to.
I just keep my coat on
and my hand on my ha'penny!
Okay, don't let this guy
psych you out, all right?
You're a writer, Jack, remember?
You can just outwit this
two-bit Hollywood gangster!
Gangster?
Say she didn't throw it away.
Please, please,
please, please, please.
Be in here,
be in here, be in here.
Where are you? Where are you?
(GIGGLES) Uzilicious.
My definitive
gangsta rap compilation.
Yeah, yeah!
I remember I wooed
Catherine with this shit.
If it still works.
♪ Ass, tits, cunt, pop, motherfucker... ♪
- Good times, old friend. Good times.
- (TAPE REWINDING)
If you can get
me through college
you can get me through anything.
(SYMPHONIC MUSIC PLAYING)
♪ I drop a old school beat
(RAP MUSIC PLAYING)
♪ Yeah, yeah
Yeah, you wanna read my script, bitch?
♪ You wanna polish my script?
♪ You wanna polish my script, motherfucker?
Is that what you're saying?
♪ What's up, bitch?
♪ You wanna polish my script?
♪ Wosh!
Polish this, motherfucker
(GUNSHOTS)
♪ I'm gonna step up to a man
called Humphries
♪ Wipe that shit up, dawg
just like cream cheese
♪ Up all night, y'all
Rockin' the mike, y'all
♪ Smoking my pipe, y'all
Motherfucker ♪
JACK: (ON TAPE) Yeah, yeah,
Catherine this jam goes out to you.
It's real, true dat
from the heart.
I just want to say you're my girl
and, uh, I love you.
Shut up! Shut up! Fuck!
(SIGHS)
Who are you
trying to fool, Jack?
You're not a G-man,
you're a tit!
(SNIFFS)
What's that smell?
Smells like... Burning garbage.
(YELLS)
Not the socks! Not the socks!
Ahhh! Damn it!
(GROANS)
(SCREAMS)
Ow! My eyes!
Oh! (GASPING IN PAIN)
Oh, God, the pants have gone up.
CLAIR: Then you'll have to go to
the launderette, won't you?
(COUGHS)
JACK: (LAUGHS)
A launderette, are you serious?
CLAIR: Of course I am. What's...
Then you'll have to go
to the launderette, won't you?
Then you'll have to
go to the laundrette.
go to the laundrette...
(JACK SCREAMING)
(CHEERING)
(PARTY HORNS HONKING)
- (TELEPHONE RINGING)
- CHILD: Cake! Cake!
Okay, let's cut the cake.
Dad, can you answer that?
It's Mr. Goofy. He's lost.
Mr. Goofy? Is on my office line?
Right, here we go...
Hello. This is Dr. Friedkin.
You've got to
help me, Dr. Friedkin.
Jack? Is this Jack?
I can't take it anymore. I...
I'm gonna buckle. I swear to God.
Well, it's my
grandson's birthday.
A phobia of launderettes?
No, Jack.
That's a new one to me.
Wait a minute, I'm confused.
Which case study is this?
It's not a case,
Dr. Friedkin. It's me!
I'm the problem. It's me!
Okay, okay, calm down.
Just calm yourself.
Jack, I want you to
take a deep breath.
Now, inhale
and exhale. That's right.
Fill your entire body.
Imagine every cell being rinsed clean
with life-giving oxygen.
Do you have any clues
where the origin of this phobia lies?
I've had it all my life.
I've tried to get on top of it.
I went to a wash house
when I was at college,
but I was just so terrified I accidentally
trapped my load in an O.O.O.
An O.O.O.?
Yes, an "out of order" machine.
I was in there
with about six months'
of unimaginably
sensitive material.
The room gathered round and
engineers were called,
it was a nightmare!
No, no, no Jack,
I sympathize with you,
but as unpleasant as
the experience may have been,
it cannot have been traumatic enough
to create such a phobia.
It's ruining my life.
Look, I can help you,
but you must be completely honest.
And you must trust me.
Close your eyes, I want you
to take another deep breath
and imagine you are sitting here
with me now in my office,
having a consultation.
Think of my office
like a space capsule.
From here we can go
anywhere in the universe,
in space and time,
by the power of our mind.
To your childhood,
to your dreams.
THE VOICE: Can you
see the little hedgehog?
Frightened little hedgehog
lives in an old
hedgerow by the...
And can you see the spider?
Clever spider.
Waiting in the shadows.
And Mrs. Ladybird?
And Mr. Rabbit?
How about old farmer...
(BEEPING RAPIDLY)
(SCREAMING)
Did you have a happy childhood?
What is your earliest memory?
The orphanage on fire.
(SCOFFS)
You're being facetious.
No, I'm not, really.
The orphanage
I was in caught fire.
Uh, November the 5th, 1979.
Somebody let off a Roman candle
in the dormitory.
Luckily no one was hurt.
You're an orphan?
I'm sorry, I didn't...
My mother abandoned me
when I was five years old.
She just packed me a little suitcase for me
one day and disappeared.
How did it happen, Jack?
It's all right
to feel vulnerable.
These pajamas aren't helping.
Try, Jack.
Try to go back.
The only memory I have of my mother
is of a book she gave me.
Um, fairy tales,
I suppose you'd call them.
With these awful
talking rodents.
(STAMMERS) Truth is,
it doesn't bother me.
I don't miss my mother,
because I don't remember her.
I just... I'm sick of
these irrational fears.
Like the bloody launderette.
It's stopping me from living my life.
Well, you can do
something about it.
You're not a child anymore.
I once treated a girl
who had a phobia of bananas.
(LAUGHS)
When this girl came to me,
she was so pleased with herself,
because she'd been able to overcome
her phobia to the extent
that she could sit in the same room
as a closed banana.
It had to stay closed, unzipped,
or else she'd go
completely psychotic.
But the point is,
open or closed,
she had not made the connection
between her phobia and her fear.
Of bananas?
No, she was afraid
of something else.
A past trauma.
Something far more
threatening than a mere banana.
Do you understand?
It's like a movie screen.
She projected her
fear onto the banana,
because looking directly at her trauma
was too terrifying.
It was a projection.
Onto a piece of fruit?
Exactly.
Her banana's no different
to your launderette.
I also have a reoccurring nightmare.
About an eyeball.
What sort of eyeball?
The giant, floating kind.
Sort of Eye of Death,
watching me.
All fears and neuroses can be traced
back to our early childhood.
To the first
terrifying recognition
that we are alone in the world.
When a young child is abandoned,
it has no concept of time.
No understanding that things can get better,
that there is hope.
For a child, Jack,
mother equals life.
Take away the mother, and the child
is literally swallowed by death.
But, I didn't die, did I?
(CHUCKLES) No.
You lived to experience
your own death.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
That's some scary shit,
Dr. Friedkin.
It's the primal trauma
we are all trying to forget,
to bury in our subconscious,
but it inevitably finds expression,
either in dreams, or fears,
or infantile fantasies.
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
DAUGHTER: Dad? How much longer
are you going to be in there?
Just finishing up, sweet pea!
I'm sorry, Jack.
We have to end now.
I don't know how to
thank you, Dr. Friedkin.
Perhaps as a teenager you were
subliminally
drawn to that O.O.O.,
because somewhere deep
in your subconscious, you recognized
that you too are
"out of order." Broken.
You don't work anymore.
The primary defense mechanisms you relied on
to get you through childhood
no longer support
you as an adult.
I'm sorry?
You're fucked up, Jack.
You need therapy.
Ah, well, I haven't got time.
I've got a meeting in about an hour.
You must return to
the scene of the crime
and retrieve those unwashed articles
locked in the machine.
Release your raw,
true inner self.
Begin a new life,
free from fear.
Fear of death.
(CREAKING)
The irony is, we must all
journey through Hades
before we can reach our heaven.
Dr. Friedkin, I think it's time
I faced my banana.
(GRUNTS)
(PANTING)
- (YELLING)
- (HORN BLARING)
(PUFFS)
(RAP MUSIC PLAYING)
(MUSIC STOPS)
It's all right, mate.
It's all right.
JACK: What the fuck.
Everything all right, sir?
Yes, yes,
I'm, I'm fine, thank you.
Looks like you're
in a bit of a hurry.
Yes, well I have
an appointment...
With death.
Excuse me?
I mean with the launderette.
(STAMMERS) I'm going
to wash some socks.
There's no crime
in that, is there?
Not that I'm aware of, sir.
Good.
Well, I'll be on
my way then. Good night.
Good night.
JACK: Keep it together,
keep it together.
It's only a banana.
It's not him you're afraid of.
It's only...
(GASPS)
Okay, okay. Stick to the plan.
If I move fast, I can get
in and out in half an hour.
That leaves just 20 minutes
to change and get a taxi north.
No room for error.
"Everything Automatic.
One, open the door.
"Two, get the clothes in.
"Three, shut the door and have
two pound coins ready.
"Four, place the money
in the slot.
"Five, push your slot in!"
Great!
How do I manage it?
I've managed to create
a bad impression
and I'm still in
the fucking street!
Okay, okay, you can do this.
You can do this!
(EXHALING)
(PUFFS)
JACK: Looks like my lucky day.
Only four people and
no visible infants.
There, look, the atmosphere's
easing a little.
I'm blending in.
Okay. So far so good,
I'm already up to number three.
"Shut the door,
have two pound coins ready.
"Four, put the money in.
"Five..."
Shit!
These signs are older
than the machines.
What do I do now?
Heavy soil.
(MACHINE WHIRRING)
Jesus. It's over.
All I have to do now
is stand in front of it
until the things came out clean.
(CELL PHONE PLAYING
JINGLE BELLS )
(SPEAKING VIETNAMESE)
JACK: I need to check out
those drying machines.
Interesting...
It appears the technique
is to open the door
and grab the dry
things as they fly past.
That must be so more heat gets
concentrated into the bulkier items,
such as woolens, while at the same time,
anything fragile,
such as bras, are spared
unnecessary exposure.
I'll have to remember that
for my shirt.
Wait...
Something's wrong.
I'm spinning
without a problem, but...
Mine's different to the others.
What is this?
I can't afford a hitch.
Excuse me...
Mine hasn't gone white yet.
What hasn't?
My washing water. Look.
You didn't put no soap in.
I thought the machine did it.
Machine don't put own soap in.
You have to put soap in.
Where your soap?
I haven't got any.
It says,
"Everything is automatic."
See number six.
"Add detergent."
No.
What am I going to do?
It's not going
to get washed is it?
Not without soap.
JACK: I've done it again!
How is it possible
for me to keep
putting things
into washing machines
without getting them clean?
Look here.
Have you got any soap?
Soap in slot machine. £1.
(SPEAKING VIETNAMESE)
Here. Soap.
Thanks.
(SPEAKING VIETNAMESE)
Not now!
You cannot put soap in now,
you've missed your cycle!
You wait.
Will, will you tell me
when to put the soap in?
No. I'm in hurry to go home.
So am I.
You haven't been here
since 8:00 this morning.
What've you got in there?
A shirt and some socks.
That's it?
No...
There's a pair in there as well.
A pair?
A pair of underpants?
Is that all you put in machine?
I'm allowed to, aren't I?
You can put in a handkerchief,
for all I care,
but I think it's a criminal
waste of water.
(LAUGHS)
Sorry, how right you are.
In fact in a funny way, crime
is the only reason
I'm here. (GIGGLES)
I'm going home.
It's 7:30.
JACK: Well, actually it's 7:20.
But uh, if I'd been here
since 8:00 this morning,
I'd have started lying about a lot
more than the time to get out!
We'll miss out the drying.
Yeah, I agree.
JACK: I've missed my cycle.
Will it still get clean?
I'm gonna have to chance it.
I'm cutting it fine as it is.
And why do I seem
to be the only one
with a machine that
refuses to stop spinning!
Those two are
beginning to annoy me.
Especially the one in the rollers,
who looks like Caligula.
She's obviously the ringleader.
What the hell are
they staring at?
I mean, I imagine they live
pretty mundane lives
here in these launderettes,
but even so.
(WHIRRING STOPS)
It's over. I'm free!
Get me out of here!
(PSYCHEDELIC ROCK PLAYING)
Oh, no. A beautiful girl.
That's the last thing I need.
It's bad enough shifting underwear
with these louts.
Now I'm going to have to do it
with her watching.
Better be discreet,
it's down to the dryers now.
I'll just hang back here,
hope the beautiful girl
doesn't notice my presence.
She's trying to block
my view of her dryer!
What does she think I am?
A peeping Tom?
Jesus. The size of that.
I've never seen anything like it.
And another! That thing must
have Dunlop written on it.
Oh, thanks. Thanks very much.
That's just downright impolite.
Listen, darling, I don't want to look
at your fucking underwear.
It might excite
the gentlemen in your life,
but as far as I'm concerned
it's about as sexy as a couple of buckets,
which is what it looks like.
I look like something
out of a horror movie!
All those little
ruptured blonde hairs...
My head looks like
a Swede's scrotum!
Ahhh!
JACK: No wonder
they've been watching me.
They're justified in everything.
I look horrifying.
I'm a monster!
What to do?
I've still got half an hour.
I could go to the service station,
get some big sunglasses.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, could work.
Yeah, motherfucker. Hood up.
Right, I've got to get
out of here. And quick.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
A bit of dampness
never hurt anybody.
(GASPS)
(WALTZ MUSIC PLAYING)
Forget 'em.
They're lost forever.
Just get the sock and the shirt.
(WOMAN CLEARING THROAT)
Excuse me.
Are these yours?
No.
No. Nothing to do with me.
Um, are they yours?
They're his.
I saw them come out.
Excuse me. What's your name?
John. My name is John.
Then they are yours.
It's embroidered
inside on a little tab.
Yes, yes, they are,
they are mine, yes.
I, I um, I lent them to somebody
a long time ago.
I'm not sure how they got
into my wash actually.
- Don't you want them?
- No!
No, no, no, thank you.
Well, I don't want them.
Throw them in the bin, love.
Well, yes, thank you,
you've been very kind.
(GASPS)
Look out! He's got a blade!
(SCREAMS)
It's not what it looks like.
I'm not going
to hurt anybody. Really!
(SCREAMS)
I'm, I'm... I'm a professional writer.
For television.
Don't, don't, don't go.
Call the cops!
- Call the cops! Call the cops!
- Please!
Stop! Stop! Stop!
(GROANS)
Go! Get! Go, go, go!
Ahhh! Where's the cops?
(DOOR CLOSING)
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
CALIGULA: Go that way!
I'm gonna go down this one.
(GASPS)
(GRUNTS)
Half past.
I've still got 20 minutes.
SHEENA: Back off.
Please, I can explain.
Let me out! I can explain.
No way! Go on, stay back!
Look, I know I look weird,
but I'm a writer.
I don't normally look like this,
and I certainly don't
wanna use this knife!
Now please, I have a really
important meeting.
Not interested,
mate, okay, and I said,
"Back off."
There's must be
another way out of here!
(CELL PHONE PLAYING
JINGLE BELLS )
SHEENA: Jen!
(DIALING)
They're coming, they're coming!
Hang on. I can hear the sirens.
SHEENA: Hurry up. Hurry up.
He's trying to get out.
Come on, Clair!
Come on, pick up, pick up!
Come on, Clair! Pick up!
- Pick up!
- (SIRENS WAILING)
Oh! Come on.
(GRUNTS)
(SIRENS CONTINUE)
Oh.
You say he threatened you?
I'll say. He's sick as pig!
(KNOCKS)
Stand by. We've got a nutter.
SHEENA: Hurry up!
He's trying to get away!
Okay, stand back!
(INDISTINCT CHATTER OVER RADIO)
Roger, about to
apprehend said knife man.
Over.
PC: Positions.
SERGEANT: Follow!
Follow! Follow!
- WPC: I'm in.
- PC: Right.
I can't see him.
Dryers clear, Sarge.
Dryers clear.
WPC: Hatch clear.
No visuals.
No visuals. No visuals.
Where is he then?
CAMERA MAN: Is this
the right launderette?
WPC: Covered!
PC: Stay still! Stay still!
Stay still.
SERGEANT:
Right, sonny. Drop the knife!
Now! Drop the knife.
Step forward!
Hands up where we can see 'em!
I'm not here to hurt anybody.
I'm a professional writer.
Drop the knife,
don't give me no mumbo.
Mumbo?
Mumbo jumbo.
Oh, well, it's stuck.
You heard the Sarge, drop it!
We want the knife, bitch!
Be my guest!
Tase him.
Ow!
- (ZAPPING)
- (SCREAMING)
(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)
WPC: This way please, sir.
All right, back off, sonny,
back off. Out of the way.
Help him get that off, will ya?
I can't take him anywhere
with that thing on.
Okay, this way, sir.
Sir, "You do not
have to say anything.
"Anything you do say
may be given in evidence."
He wants locking up, that boy!
Lock him up and
throw away the key!
JACK: It's not me
you should be after.
It's this bastard
in North London.
Harvey... That's blinding.
All right.
Filming for Beat Cops, mate.
It's gonna be on TV.
Anything you wanna say to
the viewers of Beat Cops, mate?
No. Go away.
This is my life, you know,
this is not some excuse for cheap TV.
Ow!
All right, you're
being very brave.
Bugger off, sonny.
You've got what you want.
Sarge, look...
I set fire to myself
before I came out,
and then accidentally glued
this knife to my hand.
- You threatened those ladies.
- I didn't!
They say you did.
I really didn't, please can you tell them.
I didn't, did I?
No. He just sort of
"got it out."
Well, he can tell us
all about it down the station.
Right. He is done.
Okay.
(WHISTLES) Everyone!
It's all over. You can
go back to your homes.
Safety has been restored.
SERGEANT: Thank you everyone.
See you later.
Load him up.
Wait! I'm innocent.
Look, I've got
a meeting this evening.
Tell him I'm safe!
That's enough, sonny,
or I'll do you for resisting arrest.
I'm a victim of circumstance!
(HELICOPTER WHIRRING)
SERGEANT: All units,
Mare Street! Go! Go! Go!
Sarge, Little Vietnam,
big trouble.
Right.
What do we do
with, er... Paddington?
Take him with us.
Chuck him in the back!
Hey, no way, I've got a meeting!
Come on then! Shake a leg!
Follow that chopper!
PC: Oh, for God's sake.
Mirror, signal, maneuver!
SERGEANT:
Mirror, signal, maneuver.
WPC: Shut up!
I am driving this truck!
(SIREN WAILING)
Looks like they let you go after all.
You're free.
Free.
It's fate.
I'm facing my demons.
And I'm winning.
(LAUGHS)
I'm free!
Come on, stars!
Give me your best shot!
I'm ready!
Let's do this!
Oh! (LAUGHS)
- Evening, sir.
- Sorry, Officer.
Something funny, sir?
No. I'm, I'm just happy.
Happy?
Are you drunk, sir?
No, I'm a writer.
Oh, yeah?
Yes, uh, I'm just
on my way to meet
a Hollywood movie
mogul, actually.
You're kidding?
Yeah, he's very interested
in buying my script.
About, uh, serial killers.
You don't say.
Oh, are you all right, miss?
Did you, um, did you get
your laundry done?
No. Maybe another night.
Oh, well. Well,
good night then, miss.
Night, sir.
(SHOE SQUEAKING)
DR. FRIEDKIN: You must return
to the scene of the crime
and retrieve those unwashed articles
locked in the machine.
Release your raw,
true inner self.
Begin a new life,
free from fear.
JACK: Okay, okay, I got this.
Dr. Friedkin, one banana signed,
peeled and...
(DOOR CREAKING)
(PSYCHEDELIC ROCK PLAYING)
(BEEPING)
(MUFFLED SCREAMING)
(GRUNTING)
(MUFFLED) Oh, my God!
What happened?
(MUFFLED) I don't know!
Where are we?
We have to get out of here!
Yes! Yes!
(SHOUTING UNINTELLIGIBLY)
Huh?
Oh, my God, what happened?
How did we get here?
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
I was... I was
walking down the road.
Yeah, I was walking down the alley
and I heard a noise, and...
Oh, God, I feel sick.
Oh, my God, I have to let
my parents know I'm here.
They'll panic, they'll panic.
I don't want them to panic!
- (MUFFLED SPEECH)
- What's that?
(MUFFLED) I can't breathe.
You're gonna heave?
- I can't breathe.
- You can't leave?
I can't breathe!
Oh, you can't breathe!
I'm so sorry!
(COUGHING)
Thank you.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
They must have drugged us
and dumped us here, the bastards.
Who? Who did this?
The Vietnamese mafia.
Think about it.
Look around you,
we're still in the launderette.
This must be some
sort of safe house.
They must have caught me
snooping around and thought...
(VIETNAMESE ACCENT)
"Let's tie this one up,
and dump him in the cellar."
Oh, my God.
No, no, no, no, no. It doesn't add up.
It doesn't add up at all.
They might have suspected me
of being up to something,
but you were on your way home.
You were no threat,
no threat whatsoever.
What are you saying?
It must have been premeditated.
We've been abducted
by a crazed psychopath
whose sole intention
is to terrorize,
torture, and terminate
our existence.
No.
What do you mean, no? No!
I refuse to believe that.
What about... Mistaken identity, huh?
This, this could all
be a practical joke!
A joke?
Are you out of your mind?
No, you're... You're paranoid.
You're jumping to conclusions.
Lady, there is
a time and a place for
accusing a man of being paranoid
and this is not
fuckin' one of them.
Help! Help us, please!
Help! Please!
BOTH: Help! Help!
Please, please!
Somebody help us!
- Hel...
- (THUD)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
Listen!
Somebody's up there.
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
What do we do?
(SANGEET SOBBING)
Mummy...
(DOOR OPENING)
(JACK WHIMPERING)
MAN: Hello?
What's going on
down there, then?
Oh, oh, mate.
Are you all right?
Mate, I have never been so happy
to see a, a, sup...
Community Support
Police Officer.
Yes, Community Support
Police Officer in my life.
Quickly, untie us!
- Come down, please!
- No, no, shit...
No, no, no. Don't, don't, don't.
Go, go back up.
- Go back. Get some help. Get some backup.
- Right.
But we're trapped!
We are trapped!
- He can see that!
- Don't leave us!
Look, if they come back and he's here,
they'll get him too!
- He's police.
- He's not even armed.
Look at him. They haven't even
given him a fucking whistle!
Listen, mate, go
and get some help.
Get some men with
guns and the dogs.
And some dogs with guns.
And a fucking helicopter.
Just go! Go!
(DOOR CLOSING)
Oh!
On second thought,
I think I'll just
stay here with you.
Very cozy. Just the three of us.
The criminal stare...
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
What's he doing?
JACK: I'm afraid
this is one very sick
Community Support
Police Officer.
PERKINS: Very good.
You know, you...
You can't beat these
old machines for
sheer craftsmanship.
Front loading,
motor power,
elegant design.
Oh, admittedly,
they don't spin as fast as
the modern machines do,
but so what?
As Mahatma Gandhi said,
"There's more
"to life than simply
increasing its speed."
And looking at this washing machine,
you'd have to agree with him.
I mean, it's a bloody
work of art.
I said it's a work of art.
Don't you agree?
Yes, it's very nice.
Right, well, uh,
take comfort in that.
Because it's the last thing you're going
to see before you die.
If, if you both look closely,
you'll notice a pea
green flashing light.
Which means that while you
were both sleeping,
this machine has
already passed smoothly
through the stages of
pre-wash and main wash.
And is now completing
the last rinse.
(CLATTERING)
Ow.
This will shortly be followed by
the magnificent "Final Spin,"
at which point
the cycle will end,
the light will turn red,
and I shall have the pleasure of
sending you both to a better
and, one would hope,
cleaner world than this.
You fucking maniac.
I was just gonna go home tonight
and catch some telly...
But when you mentioned you were a writer,
about serial killers,
I thought, "No.
"No, this is meant to be.
"This is fate."
JACK: What do you call yourself?
What's that, mate?
What do you call yourself?
The... The Spin King? The Laundry Man?
No, I'm the Hanoi Handshake!
That's me.
After I kill you,
I'm going to chop your fingers off
and pin it on
the Vietnamese lot.
Why?
Why are you doing this?
Oh, well, it's complicated.
You see, this launderette
used to belong to my grandmother.
That is before the whole neighborhood
went to pot.
Pol Pot.
No, the uh, the boat
people elbowed her out.
Broke her heart. Killed her.
So, uh, I'm on a rampage.
A rampage of vengeance.
Oh, I... I see.
Well, anyway...
That's not important now, though.
What is important...
Is that I've got the key,
and no one knows we're here.
So then, if you don't mind,
I've just got to, uh, quickly go upstairs
and sharpen my knife.
Sit tight, kids.
And remember, when the light
goes red, you're dead!
(BEEPING)
(WHIRRING)
Hmm.
The rinse is ending.
(LAUGHING)
Oh, that's it then, isn't it?
Not only am I not gonna make my meeting
with Harvey Humphries tonight,
I'm gonna fucking die! (SOBBING)
Hey, stop it!
You mustn't lose hope.
There's no hope.
We're dead.
There is always hope!
I was abandoned
in a launderette as a child.
I couldn't speak for six weeks,
I was so afraid.
I've come full circle.
I'm alive, alive to experience
my own death.
It's destiny!
No!
(FAINTLY) No!
Listen, your mother,
she gave up on herself, not on you.
You don't make the same mistake.
We can do it together.
Come on, we have to
try and reason with him!
There's always hope.
I don't even know your name.
Sangeet. My name is Sangeet.
Sangeet.
That's a very beautiful name.
Sangeet, do you think
if all this blows over
you and I might perhaps
get some dinner or...
(CHUCKLES)
That's the spirit, John!
(DOOR OPENING)
Hey, call me Jack.
( THE FINAL COUNTDOWN PLAYING)
Those about to die,
we salute you!
What's wrong?
Not your cup of tea?
But how can you not like this?
This is top-notch.
This is classic rock.
Uh, no.
Technically, this is
80's hair metal.
What?
(MUSIC STOPS)
Right!
I'll have you know that
that track was number one
in 25 separate
countries in 1986.
Twenty-five!
Now I think that
qualifies it as an
all-time rock classic.
Don't you?
Yeah. Well, we,
we had different childhoods, mate.
While, while you
were jumping around
in your bedroom
to men in tights,
I was, I was keeping it fresh, you know,
rolling with the brothers,
you know what I'm saying, y'all?
Dusting off my AK-Motherfucker.
Well, you missed out!
You don't know what
you're talking about, anyway.
I used to lie
over there, on my bed,
with my headphones on,
and I, I'd just disappear
into my imagination.
Gran always said I had
a very vivid imagination.
I could be anyone.
Sometimes I'd, I'd be this um...
I'd, I'd be this rock star,
half man, half elf,
with this great mane of golden hair,
down to my waist,
and all the girls'd be yelling
"Oh, Tony, let me touch it,
Tony, please let me touch it!
"Just let me touch it."
This, this was your bedroom?
Eh?
You had a bed down here?
Oh, oh, mate...
Me and this
launderette go way back.
You see, my mum died
when I was quite young
and I didn't have
any other family,
so I was sent to
live here, with my gran.
At the launderette.
She took me in, bless her heart,
and looked after me, but...
After a while, she decided there wasn't
really enough room
for two people
upstairs in the flat.
So she made me a room down here.
Down in the cellar.
It was... Well...
It took a bit of
getting used to...
But she only locked the hatch
very late at night.
And I was allowed out,
to see the people coming and going.
To watch them wash.
You!
Oh, Tony, you poor thing.
What do you mean? "Poor thing"?
You were abandoned, Tone.
Mate, I had this whole
massive bedroom to myself!
This is a cellar, Tone!
It's a cellar!
Yeah, but...
Yeah, but look, it's Dickensian!
Well, how big was
your fucking bedroom?
That's not the point.
Jesus, what kind of woman
keeps a child in a cellar!
Hey, don't you say
a word about my gran.
My gran was a very
special person.
That's the kid talking.
Look, any mother, even a twisted
hag bitch of a mother
is better than no mother at all.
Come on, Tone.
You were dumped!
Alone! In a cellar!
Yeah, all right, thank you very much,
Sigmund Freud!
You're the one
tied up in a basement.
I'm the one feeding the press!
Baffling the police!
I'm conducting the whole thing
like an orchestra.
I'm like the... The Andre Previn
of serial killers!
Mate, I have studied serial killers,
and you are not it, okay.
A serial killer is
practically an artist.
Hey, I'm all about
elegant design.
Tell 'em, Gran!
I am an artist, aren't I?
I'm like a sculptor,
sculpting in crime!
Don't tell me you've got your bloody
grandmother down here too!
Well, of course I have!
I'm a serial killer, aren't I?
It's been done, mate!
Can't you come up with something
a bit more original!
I did the Hanoi Handshake.
The part that sounds like
two Vietnamese gentlemen
in a public convenience!
He's right. It does, actually.
(IMITATES VIETNAMESE ACCENT)
"Oh, Daddy, can I give you a handshake?
"I give you
handshake long time!"
Please, have some
bloody respect, will you?
(WHIRRING)
That's it.
- Spin's started.
- (SANGEET SCREAMS)
No! No! No!
No! No!
PERKINS: Shut up!
Shut up! Shut Up!
Try making fun
of this, dead man.
Say hello to my bowie knife.
I call him Dave.
David the Bowie Knife?
Sounds like a character from
one of my old stories.
Dave doesn't like you.
He's telling me to do it.
I'm gonna do it.
Tony!
(GROANS)
You can't reason
with a serial killer.
(PERKINS GROANS)
Oh, Jack!
Just go, go, go please go,
go, go, go on. Go get help!
Hop! Hop! Hop! Hop!
Hop! Hop! Hop!
Run!
(SCREAMS)
Sorry. I am sorry.
(SANGEET SCREAMING)
JACK: No, Tony.
PERKINS: No, I can't let you go.
I'm sorry. I'm really sorry.
This is how it has to end.
Tony, please leave her alone!
Sorry, mate,
she saw me with you.
- No turning back now.
- Jack!
Jack, do something, please!
What? What?
You're a writer, aren't you?
Tell him a fucking story!
A story?
Right, this is it.
(STAMMERING) No, wait, wait.
No, she's right, she's right.
- Let me tell you a story.
- A story?
Yes, please, please.
It's uh, it's a dead man's last wish.
Ah! It's a st...
Story to, to, end the cycle.
Well, how long
is it going to take?
Not long, it's very compact.
- Cause I haven't got long.
- Neither have I.
(BOTH LAUGH)
Oh, all right, dead man,
but make it good,
cause it's the last thing
you're ever going to write.
- Yeah, yeah.
- No pressure, though!
(LAUGHS)
Okay. I have to start
right at the beginning.
Once upon a time...
There was a hedgehog,
whose name...
A hedgehog?
Yes. Yes.
You're, you're about
to die, and yet you
want to tell me
a story about a hedgehog?
Mate, please just bear with me.
Okay, you sitting comfortably?
Once upon a time,
not so long ago,
there was a hedgehog
whose name...
Was Brian.
Brian lived in a cave,
deep in the forest.
A dark and terrible place,
called the Wyrd Wild Wood.
After dark, the forest would
echo with howls and screams.
And sometimes it
seemed to Brian as if
even the moon
conspired against him.
But the more afraid Brian became,
the angrier he got.
(GRUNTS)
Until, one night,
frightened out of his wits,
he turned himself into
a terrifying monster.
He put on weight,
painted his face,
and started insisting on being addressed
as Balthazar the Berserker.
But then a strange thing happened.
Brian received
an unexpected visitor.
"Come any closer,
and I'll scratch your eyes out,"
he snarled angrily at
the flickering eyes in the trees.
"Brian?" whispered a voice.
"Is that really you?"
"Who the fuck are
you calling Brian?"
said Brian, as menacingly
as he could manage.
"Why, Brian, it is you!"
It was Harold, his brother,
last seen by the road,
walking with mother...
A long time ago.
He said, "I'm so happy I found you,
Brian, old chap.
"I've been terribly lonely,
and fancied a chat."
But Brian had crossed that road
and never looked back.
He'd erased the memory
and his soul was now black.
"Harold, mate.
I hate to be blunt.
"But look in the mirror,
you prickly idiot.
"You're a worthless,
pathetic, snivelling fool.
"I'd rather spend time
with the worms in my stool."
And with that he chased him into the trees,
and over the dells,
screaming, "I'll eat you for supper,
or meet you in hell!"
(INSECTS SHOUTING IN ALARM)
But fate intervened
and Brian got lost.
And to make matters worse,
there was a treacherous fog.
"Hello?" he cried,
"Is anyone there?"
But no one replied
and Brian got scared.
And that's when he saw
he wasn't alone.
A small crumpled body
was lying in the road.
(HONKING)
"Why didn't you leave me?"
said Brian, "and just let me die?"
"You're my brother," said Harold,
"how on earth could I?"
And that's when they
heard the pitiful cries
of a very small hedgehog
whose mother just died.
And suddenly Brian
just started to blub,
he picked up the babe
and gave it a hug.
"This little thing, you know,
reminds me of us,
"left all alone,
when Mum caught that bus."
"The spell has been broken," said Harold.
"It's time to break free.
"You're not really a monster,
you're a hedgehog, like me."
(PERKINS SNIFFLING)
I tell you what that...
That is a beautiful story.
So I... I suppose
they adopt the...
Adopted the baby hedgehog. Yes.
Oh, mate.
It's symbolic, you see,
they discovered their true selves.
They were able to go back
and start again where they left off,
before the trauma
of losing their mum.
I tell you, that was my life,
right there in that cave.
I'm not a monster, am I?
SANGEET: No.
You just need some help.
I'll let you into a secret.
I'm not even
a proper serial killer.
That Vietnamese bloke,
the one in the marshes,
I didn't kill him.
What?
No, he must have
tripped and fell.
He was dead when I found him.
Yeah, but the fingers,
the Hanoi Handshake?
Oh, yeah, yeah. I did do that.
Well, otherwise, he was
just a bloke in a ditch.
Oh, her.
It's just a mannequin.
I found her in
a bin outside Topshop.
So you're not a killer, then.
You're like me.
We were both abandoned.
We're the same.
We're like...
Yes... Brothers.
(CELL PHONE PLAYING
JINGLE BELLS )
Uh, no, it's not mine.
I just, I picked it up.
( JINGLE BELLS CONTINUES)
(MUSIC STOPS)
(DOOR OPENING)
(SPEAKING VIETNAMESE)
Brother?
ALL: Help!
And so Harold and his
long-lost brother Brian
lived happily for
some time afterwards
in the old hedgerow,
beside the churchyard.
And remember, no matter how dark
and scary those woods may seem,
there's always
a way across the road
for a hedgehog
who's brave enough to cross it.
- Thank you.
- (AUDIENCE APPLAUDING)
- Hey.
- Hey, hi.
You look fantastic.
Thank you.
That was a wonderful story.
DR. FRIEDKIN:
Congratulations, Jack.
A perfect synthesis of
Jungian and Freudian thought.
Harold's lost self is recovered,
whilst acknowledging the important role
that the false self,
the defense mechanism,
played in surviving
the terror of abandonment.
Well, it's all credit to you,
Professor Friedkin.
Next book, Harold must address
his destructive oedipal complex
and help Brian with his tendency
towards malignant anal hoarding.
Darling, I've brought someone I think
you should finally meet.
Harvey Humphries.
You.
You never came to
see me, did you?
Oh, you are a very,
very, naughty boy.
Harvey's still very interested
in Decades of Death, Jack.
Maybe you two can get together
and uh, discuss it later?
THE VOICE: Can you see...
The spider?
And the farmer in his field?
Can you see the lovely ladybird?
And what about the little
frightened hedgehog?
SANGEET: Jack? Jack?
Are you all right?
Uh, yes, sorry.
Hey, what about that dinner
you promised me?
(WHISPERING)
Um, I'll get back to you,
okay, on the whole thing.
I'll think about it. I will.
- Call me.
- Absolutely.
(SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
THE VOICE: Once upon a time,
there was a hedgehog called Harold,
who one day set
out on a journey.
When he reached
the far side of the wood,
he came to
a large flowing river,
dancing with speckled light.
Without a moment's hesitation,
Harold threw himself into the water.
The current
carried him far away...
And he was never seen again.
Morning. Morning, you two.
Morning, madam.
Right then.
(BRAKES SCREECHING)
What a fucking...
Twat! Cock!
Fucking dickhead! Wanker!
- (BRAKES SCREECHING)
- Ooh!
(SYMPHONIC MUSIC PLAYING)
JACK:
♪ I drop a old school beat ♪
(RAP MUSIC PLAYING)
PERKINS: Churning nicely.
JACK: Get ready,
I'm opening my flap.
PERKINS: Front loading.
DR. FRIEDKIN: No, you lived
to experience your own death.
CLAIR: Never underestimate a hunchback.
That's what I say.
JACK: There is a pair
in there as well.
GRANDE DAME: A pair?
JACK: A bloody jungle
of organized crime.
Push your slot in.
Push, push, push, push.
SANGEET: Are these yours?
SERGEANT:
Standby, we've got a nutter.
WPC: We want
the knife, bitch! Bitch!
AFRICAN LADY:
He wants locking up, that boy.
Lock him up and
throw away the key.
JACK: This is a cellar, Tone.
It's a cellar.
PERKINS: Yeah, but...
JACK: Yeah, but, look,
it's Dickensian.
PERKINS: Hey, don't you say
a word about my gran.