The plane went down in that area.
Poor Ghentar.
Sometimes I ask myself if we'll ever
rid ourselfs of those b#s*t!rds.
They don't waste any time, here they come already.
The only thing that works here is the police.
Halt!  Stop that ship!
Your life in Ghentar is going to be hell.
Don't worry about me Pablo, I'm accustomed to danger.
Besides, the bottom of the sea is like my second home.
The fish here aren't dangerous,
it's General Lorme's men you should avoid.
If we've gone to all the trouble of getting you from
Marselles it's because we need you here.... alive naturally.
The inhabitants of Ghentar die easily,
but I'm not from these parts.
I won't give General Lorme's men that satisfaction.
That won't be easy,
General Lorme probably already knows who you are.
Inspector Sirdar, I've come to inspect your documents.
Pablo and the American are onboard.
- We must act carefully.
General Lorme doesn't want international incidents.
- I think they'll try something tonight.
Richard, do remember the password.
- Yes, of course.
I'm starting to enjoy all this spy business.
'American tea, with mint'.
- And served in a clean cup.
If something were to happen to me, remember to
contact Gotar's followers at Bar Claveles.
Gotar? .... Who's he?
He's our leader.  But beware,
that's a hot name here in Ghentar.
Here they come.  It's time to separate.
What now?
- I'll take care of Pablo, you get the other one.
Take this, you may need it.
I really am sorry.
Where did he go?
- That way.
Your face is hard, even though you look like an idiot.
I'm over here.
You must find Botul, he'll guide you.
Look out!!
Wait, don't shoot.  The General want's him alive.
Stay on your right.
Ok inspector.  Steer right ... a little more.
Nothing yet inspector.
He can't be far, keep on looking.
- Yes sir.
Full speed, we'll find him if the fish haven't eaten him yet.
There he is.
Are you sure?
- I haven't drunk tonight.
I can't see him.
- Me neither.
He was just here now, I swear it.
This isn't the best way to make introductions,
but you're not very hospitable here in Ghentar.
Only with suspicious night drifters.
What if I told you that I fell off a boat.
Yeah, a police boat.  Inspector Sirdar just passed through here,
and then you climbed on board.
If that what you're worried about little man,
that can be explained very easy.
I'm only passing through here, and I'm no friend of Sirdar.
Why don't we talk about this boss.
- That's more like it.
This is the best lure I've ever had.
And it seems to me that you're also a fisherman.
In effect.  It appears to me that the sea in Ghentar is very rich.
But I don't think that lure will be of much use to me.
I'm looking for 'rare fish'.
- Good luck to you then, would you like a drink?
Why not?  'American tea, with mint'.
But American tea isn't served with mint.
Why not?  If the cup is very clean.
You're the man Pablo was bringing in.
Why didn't you say so before?
Tomorrow we'll take you to Claveles Bar.  Where's Pablo?
I'm afraid Pablo won't be joining us.
Another victim for Lorme!
Stupid imbeciles!
- It's not easy finding a plane wreck at that depth General Lorme.
The plane can't be too far, it had barely taken off from Ghentar.
How is it nobody knows exactly where it fell!?
- In the same spot where they're searching your exellence.
Still no results, idiots!
They've found a tyre at 30 mt, it's only a matter of time.
A tyre!  A tyre!  It's the strong box I need to get!
It needs to go to a safe place.
Do you have any idea what this means?
I won't tolerate this any more, this is the last warning!
But your excellency...
- I won't accept any more failure!
If they don't recover the documents I'll have you all shot!
I've given you all the men you asked for..
and you let it slip through
your fingers all because of that, that...
Richard, Richard Jason
That Richard Jason son of the devil.
And where are those dumb-asses that were going to arrest him?
They're under punishment.
Tell your men this is only a warning. Understand?
Let them know that General Lorme doesn't joke.
- Even so, inspector Sirdar is still our best agent.
If that's true, I can just imagine what the others are like.
And tell Sirdar that next time I'll punish him if need be.
I want that man here now.  Do you understand Coronel!?
Yes Sir, we'll put up checkpoints in all the city.
If he tries to make contact with the rebels...
... we'll catch him.
Look!
If anything happens to us, go to Bar Claveles,
your American tea is getting cold.
A thousand pardons.
Hey you American!  This way.
Hey babe.
- Hey, what are you doing?
Can I get you anything special stranger?
We have all sorts of liquor.
- Yeah, i noticed.
But I must confess, babes like you also make me dizzy.
I'd rather some 'American tea with mint'.
But American tea isn't made with mint.
However, if you want it done that way.
The girl made a mistake, American tea can also be
made with mint.  And even tastes good sometimes.
As long as the cup is clean.
The tea is ready.
- Not now, we'll have it later...
... together.
Relax stranger.  Who sent you?
I was told that the tea here was good.
But this place seems more like a boxing gym.
Who gave you this address?
- Friends.
Who's friends?
That depends.
We'll make you talk.
Hold it!  What are you doing, he's a friend!
You must forgive them my friend.
Ghentar is full of spies.
This is our man.
Pablo's man?
- Exactly.
Please forgive us stranger.
But you need more than a simple ID card to make contact.
It was my job to introduce him,
but inspector Sirdar was on our trail.
It's now clear that Lorme knows you're here.
This will make your job much harder.
Good, now that I've passed the security check,
would you please be kind enough to tell me what my job will be.
Because so far all I've had is a bad introduction.
Aren't you an ace frogman?  That's why you're here.
Do you have a habit of being obscure,
or do I need to talk to Gotar to get the full story?
Don't even mention that name,
nobody can see our leader.  I'll be giving you the orders.
What is it?
This is the north-east.  Clearly the transmittor is in the sea.
- I'd swear it was here.
Were're sure it's out there, but it's hard to locate.
We need to test it out there.
How far is it?
- It's hard to say, we need another man.
Ok, let's go.
Massage recieved.  Keep contact.  Did you hear that Noemi?
Let them try again.  This must be the right spot.
Of course Noemi, when plane fell I was fishing right here.
It almost fell on me.
It's encrypted.  We may not be able to locate the transmittor.
It's been transmitting the last two days.  They're in the sea.
- You keep on searching.  - Call the boat.
Clearly Gotar's men are trying to beat us to it.
- Sr, there's no answer.
Nothing sir.  That plane must of desintergrated.
- Try again, search deeper.
Here HQ,  waiting for your orders.
Suspicious fishing boat at Punta Blanca.  Check it out.
- Then it must be that one over there.
A wing!  That means we must be...
Yes, It's possible that the current hasn't pulled the wreck
down too far.  The bottom of the sea there is 200 mt.
Don't worry, the American is expensive, but he's worth it.
We can't trust him.  If he sees those documents.
- He's up to his neck now.
And he's knows he can't play games with us.
Let's get away.  Shut down the radio.
We only poor fishermen.
- So there's no rebels onboard.
Search the boat!
There must a man down there.  Finnish him off!
It's only rotten fish.
- It's actually quite fresh.
Why don't you take some.
- Let's go!
So you didn't find anything.
- Just a nasty cold.
It looks like we've got campany.
It's better if we cut the ropes.
Hey Botul, don't people die of old age in this country?
That's not easy.  These guys shoot first and ask later.
I just want to save my boat.
I love her like my sweetheart.
I agree, we should treat her as she were a woman.
How odd, they're giving us a warning.
Listen, what would happen if they arrested us?
Nothing too bad.  Worst case, they'd just shoot us.
And the boat?
- It would be confiscated and taken to the fort's dock.
That's terrible.  You love this boat.  We must save her.
You escape with the boat.  I'll try and stall them.
We'll meet again soon.
Don't let him get away.  We'll follow the boat.
There's no point trying to escape.  Give youself up, it's better.
Welcome Mr Jason.
General Lorme is anxious to meet you.  We've been
expecting you for some time. Would you be kind enough.
It would be rude to make him wait now, don't you agree?
Fear not my dear, sooner or later I'll come and save you.
Have you recovered your memory Mr Jason?
Or perhaps we need to try a little harder?
- Continue.
I've already told you, I've lost my ID papers onboard.
I've been robbed.
We know that story, tell us something we don't know.
For eg. what were you doing on that boat?
I just hired any boat.  I'm an underwater fisherman.
You didn't run into two police frogmen by any chance?
No, why?
Were they supposed to ask me for my fishing licence?
Unfortunatley they're now dead.
And under very strange circumstances.  Isn't that odd?
If would be better if you talk now Mr Jason.
We know the rebels hired you to find a plane.
As a professional frogman your ears are of great value
to you.  How much are they worth to you?
My ears are good, but I can't say the same about yours...
since you haven't understood a word of what I've said.
Our divers found the plane cabin empty,
someone must of beaten us to it.
Well Mr Jason?
A plane at the bottom of the sea?
What's that suppose to be... a riddle?
It's possible he's telling the truth General.
The explosion may have thown the box anywhere..
although not very far, and a man like this can be of
help to us... as long as he's willing to reason.
You're a great psychologist captain.
Very well, I'm willing to be reasonable.
Very good Kim.  This time you've hit the mark.
And good for you too Mr Jason.  Now you're starting to be
reasonable.  We'll pay you well, more than the rebels did.
I'm moved when I hear you speak of money,
but unfortunatley I can't accept.  - Why?
I like living in this disgusting world,
but if I work for you, the others will want to kill me too.
I don't want to contradict you General,
but I don't think you're very popular here in Ghentar.
You'll be under our protection.
- And who protects you?
I've heard the people speak of revolution.
I've read Gotar's declarations.
Shut up!  You westeners beleive anything.
Gotar is only a name, and nothing more!
It's only a cheap trick to gain power.
You don't like to be contradicted, right?
I suggest sending him to The Mines Of Paradise.
A few days there will do him well.
Not a bad idea Captain.
You deserve a promotion.
There's nothing like 'Paradise'.
Where's the American?
- He's doing his duty Captain.
I want you to give him special treatment.
- I'll take care of it personally
Back to your post, you hear!
Can't you see I'm trying to help this poor man.
- Don't argue you imbecile!
POW!
You're too nervous, let me calm you down.
ARRGH!
SMACK!!
Back to work!
So, has our American calmed down?
- Can't even hear him.  He must be 'well done'.
Well now...
Have you finally decided to work for us?
Your hands are best suited for swimming,
not for breaking stones.
I must confess that our divers found nothing.
Or can we assume... that you've beaten us to it.
I thought we had nothing left to talk about Captain.
That's a real shame.  I was hoping to take you with me.
Whoever called this place The Mines Of Paradise
had a strange sense of humor.  Even hell is cooler than this.
Leave him!
Let me make a confession.
It's about time you talked.
You have the worst beer here in Ghentar.
You damn traitor.  Take him away!
We'll see in a few days if you still feel like joking.
All our state treasure is in enemy hands...
Do you know what this means!?
Begging your pardon, but it's likely the diamonds are still in
the sea. When we arrested the American the boat was empty.
Did you hear that Coronel?
And I'm suppose to be paying you to think of that.
Move it!  Get me the American,
we have to make him talk whatever the cost!
So they've finally let you out of that 'cooking pot'.
I was lucky,
they just didn't have as much patience as I did.
Listen, you've proven to us that you're a brave man.
We believe you can be trusted.
Let me make you an offer.
We're planning a break out.
Do you want to be in on it?
Why not, I wasn't planning on growing roots in here.
Good, that makes four of us.
But we need more to improve our chances.
We must act fast.  I'm an impatient character.
There's a fabulous treasure waiting for me in Ghentar.
A women eh?
- Huh, yes.
If I don't hurry I may never see her again.
You know what women are like.
Now listen carefully guys.
I have an escape plan, it can't fail.
It's all up to us now.
We'll be out of here in no time.
Do you all agree?
Then listen carefully.
So the American wants to break out?
- I overheard the whole thing Captain.
We should of let him cook in the pot longer.
- We need him alive, you know that.
Shall I put him under survailance?
That guy's capable of anything.
No, let him be.  Let's pretend we know nothing.
Leave him alone?
- Of course.
First of all, nobody has ever escaped from here anyway.
Besides, I've just received special orders...
From General Lorme.  Very interesting orders indeed.
Corporal, I'm going to find a pick.
I've got the dinamite, get ready.
- Yes.
You!  Where are you going?
- To the carriages  - Ok, pass.
To the truck!  Let's go, quick!
Rat-tat-tat-tat
Son of the devil!  Cowards!
Rat-tat-tat-tat ... Rat-tat-tat-tat
Hahahahah!
B-O-O-M!!
That bird won't fly no more!
- If only that pig Lorme were in it.
Now we must face the desert.
We have to leave the main road.
But without food and supplies we can't get very far.
If we're going to die, let it be far from this place.
Wait, maybe those two dead men
have something that we can use.
Stop it!  This is no time to start fighting.
With this sun we'll never make it, it's madness.
But if we keep on going,
we could be at the sea by tommorow.
Are you crazy?  Even if we stayed on track,
it would take at least three days.
We can't walk in the day.
We'll travel by night.
During the day we'll stay in the shade.
But we don't even have water for two days.
Then we'll have to lower our rations.
- We have no choice, our chances of survival are bad.
Let's go!
Finally, you're awake.
I'm just curious, is this the final judgement
or are we in the pre-chamber?
What's your name darling?
Well, well Mr Jason.
I see they've been taking good care of you.
You got that right captain.  The service here is
much better than in The Mines Of Paradise.
You, leave us.
What a shame...
Now that I've found the real paradise...
You'll send me straight back to hell.
It's evidently clear that the 'Mines' treatment
hasn't worked on you.
The trip here by helicopter was very long.
I can assure you Captain that my trip here
was much less comfortable than yours.
Why do you take so many risks?
You're a shrewd man...
And shrewd people never take risks without a motive.
Well, you see captain,
I've got my professional dignity.
Gotar pays me and I can't switch sides...
even if you threaten me.
Now you're being unreasonable.
- You should be tourist guide.
And organise lovely excursions to The Mines Of Paradise.
You disappoint me Mr Jason.
So much idealism... when it's diamonds you're after.
Diamonds?  What are you talking about?
I thought it was only some documents.
And naturally you'd only give these
documents the rebel leader.
Yes, exactly, only to Gotar.
But just like a fish, I prefer the sea to the desert.
Have you ever met Gotar?
- No, he doesn't like publicity.. That is, if he really exists.
Would you like a cup of tea Mr Jason?
- Yes.
With some mint leaves.
American tea isn't served with mint...
even if the cup is clean.
So you must be Gotar... I mean, the real Gotar.
I would never of guessed it.
And neither would General Lorme I suppose.
Good, now we can show all our cards.
Where are the diamonds?
Lorme's men found an empty box.
Give me a break Captain,
don't you people in Ghentar believe anying?
I didn't find anything, just a plane wreck.
That plane was shot down under my orders to prevent Lorme
from sending them away.  It's the treasure of my people!
I understand, however this is the first
time I hear anything about diamonds.
For the last time Jason, where are those diamonds?
- And me?....
Where am I?
- Captain, it's the radio.
Take him inside.
- Follow me.  -I'm coming.
We hear you, this is free Ghentar radio.
It's the boat command.
Gotar here, speak Noemi.
Understood, I'll be there right away.
- What is it?
We've been discoverd by Lorme's police,
And our attempted assault has failed.
You're coming with me Mr Jason.
You're worth too much to us.
You prepare the jeep, and give him a uniform.
Traitors!  So you wanted to take over the fort.
A brilliant plan.  But you should've know better.
Democracy, freedom.. after all they're just words.
Do you know what I do with traitors?
I shoot them all!
I don't need a blindfold.
You're going to meet Gotar in hell,
with or without the blindfold.  Make it quick!
Be carefull Mr Jason.
General Lorme would very glad to get his hands on  you.
Don't worry about me Captain,
I never fall from the frying pan into the fire.
Sargeant, come here!
General Lorme has orderd a blockade,
we have a curfew.
A curfew?
Thanks sargeant.  Get back to your post.
You blend in well with that uniform.
- Yes, and so do you.
Botul!  What you doing here?
- Quick, let's go.
How's it going American?  - Botul, you old fox.
I'm so glad to see you.
Hey, watch your mouth.
I'm not allowed to fraternize with prisoners.
Tell me Botul, do all your revolutions go so well?
You better pray this one does.  If things get ugly,
you'll go straight back into Lorme's hands.
He's not kidding.
- Everything will be ok.
And you shouldn't worry about it.
Very soon you'll be reunited with your dear boat.
I doubt it.  Lorme's men have confiscated it.
Confiscated?  What for?
Who knows.  Right now it's rotting away
in the fort's dock.  My poor little boat.
In the fort?  -Yes that darn fort, with all those
canons.  I would need to be a fish to see my boat.
A fish?  What do you mean by that?
- Well, you see...
Only a fish could get in though the
underwater rocks without being seen.
Now you've just found yourself an American fish.
I give you my word Botul...
you'll see that boat again.  - Really?
I've just had a brilliant idea.
And I'm sure Ghentar's new leader will aprove.
Come on.  Row.
Welcome aboard my dear Mr Gotar.
We're very glad to see you.
Would you be so kind as to raise your hands.
You weren't expecting us, right?
Boys, we've made a good catch.
General Lorme has chosen a special death for you.
After your death, Gotar will only be a name,
forgotten and lost, Captain King...
Or should I call you Gotar, if you prefer?
She's very lucky...
The General likes beautiful women.
Take her away!
Lock them up!
- B#s*t!rds!
Burn everything!
B#s*t!rds.
So much for the revolution.
I never thought it would all go up in smoke.
Don't worry, we won't be cooked alive.
See all this dynamite here..
When the fire gets here, Boom!
That'll be the end of us.
Dynamite, eh.  Heaven doesn't want us just yet.
Hey Botul, where's that dynamite?
- Inside that box.
Make it quick, the fire is almost here!
Hey Botul, do you have any matches?
What for!?  This whole place is on fire.
Ok, just a second.
Hurry up!  Get back!
If you know any prayers, now's the time to say them.
Allah is great and merciful, please remember your servant..
- Get yourself in here!
B-O-O-M-!!
Look, your Gotar has gone down into history.
I had no other choice.
How unfortunate that the American
will be the one who gives Ghentar her freedom.
The American is a devil in the water.
He's the only one who can pull it off.
Yes.  Besides, I couldn't send my people to
the slaughter house under the fire of those canons.
But I don't feel good risking his life.
He offerd himself willingly by saying:
"You paid me to open a box, but now I'll open you a fort".
The men must be ready to attack once they hear the explosion.
Now get ready!
I hope luck is on Jason's side, he's our only hope.
Halt!
Don't you reconize me soldier?
- Give the password!
Here goes..
POW!!
A man came from over there, then hit me by suprise.
He went that way. - Sound the alarm, let's go!!
Mr Jason, you seem to have more lives than a cat.
I hope they last me untill I retire.
- General Lorme will decide that.
I believe in divine fate.
Anyway, we'll all be paying him a visit any moment now.
SMACK!!
AAAARRRH!!!
$$$$
K-A  B-O-O-M-!!!
He's done it!  Give the signal to attack!
Inspector Sirdar!  I sure am glad to see you.
Where have you been?
- Trying get out of this hell.
I agree.  I've come to save my poor little boat too.
That's great!  Boats like this are hard to find.
Were are you going American!?
Give me a hand.
This is no time for games.
Back off!
Back off or I'll shoot her.
Give me the rudder.
- Ok.
American, where are you going?
The city is that way.
Our future is that way.  I bet you didn't
know that your boat was also a strong box?
A strong box?  Listen American, are you speaking in riddles?
It's the treasure of Ghentar!
- Let's say that it was, now it belongs to us.
No, we can't do this!  Think of our country,
of our new found freedom..
And you just think of a hotel next to the beach,
surrounded by charming blond babes.
Don't be a fool my friend.
These stones never belonged to the people.
They were in Lorme's pocket,
and they would of ended up in Gotar's pocket too.
You're right!  We can't permit these stones
to fall into the hands of the oppressors.
I am, a sincere democrat..
and with diamonds, even more so!
You sons of a crazy cow!!
There's nothing we can do.  It's at least 150 mt deep.
What a shame, for a moment I thought I was a rich man.
- And we were, how disgusting!.
After all the effort I've done, I'll only be a poor old man.
Do you have a cigarette?
This should be enough to pay for our travel expenses.
- Where are we going?
To find another country in need of a revolution.
hahahahah!!    (crazy laughter)
The American is leaving with Botul.
We've lost all the diamonds,
but we've gained our freedom.
subtitles by alomaco