When will Yair show up?
Where is he?
A film by Gilad Goldschmidt
You’ve reached Yair.
Please leave a message.
Yair, it's Dafna.
Where are you? We all waited
to celebrate with you.
I'm worried. Call me back.
Vitali Friedland
Daniella Wircer
Guest Stars: Pavel Tsitrinel
Lucy Dubinchik
Casting: Sigal Ginzburg
Costume Design: Rona Doron
Production Design: Yoel Hertzberg
Soundtrack Design: Yossi Appelbaum
Chief Recordist: Maxim Segal
Original Music: Issar Shulman
Assistant Director: Yulia Shifter
Production Manager: Amir Ringel
Cameraman: Uri Ackerman
Editor: Shimrit (Shish) Ronen
Screenplay: Ori Ravid.
Uzi Weill. Gilad Goldschmidt
Producers: Mosh Danon
Yifat Prestelnik
Directed by Gilad Goldschmidt
Sashinker sorry it's been so I’ong.
but before your mother died.
to send these things to you.
Kisses. Aunt Ina.
How do you say I love you’ in
Russian? -It s prettier in Hebrew.
Yair, everyone here thinks
you're talented and devoted.
sometimes insanely so.
I would say.
Presenting the new leader
of the Shunra’ troop.
Green Chariot
Sasha?
-Yulia.
Qh. sorry, now its Yair.'
I got mixed up. Yair.
What are you doing here?
m returning a book to your dad.
mill h'i Nin
but he's not home.
What are you doing here? You
haven't been here for a long time.
...It s good you came to see him.
Just because we broke up doesn t
mean I can t see your father.
He:s got class. -Yes. well...
-Try him at work. -Thanks.
Dafna
Are you happy there
I'm... I’m in a hurry.
Sasha, your friends miss you.
Your father, too.
Bye. -Bye.
Come on, come on. come on.
slowly, slowly, slowly.
a little more... Stop
Great. Turn it off.
I didn't know they were paying
you to be a traffic cop.
I haven’t seen you for months.
and the minute you appea
you start up. -Sorry. I’m kidding.
et it.
Choose a car:
Mercedes. Bianchi... -What?
It s cold! Let s sit in a car.
Well then. Bianchi.
You don’t know how to live.
we ll sit in the Mercedes.
Well, what happened?
Nothing happened.
Whats the occasion? -No occasion.
nziun hd nnN pint ‘zdi
Still, you’re here on a Saturday.
late at night. Is something wrong?
Nothing s wrong, really, it's
just that... Aunt Ina...
sent me a package with some
of Mom s things.
And?
-And in it was...
What was in it?
Oh... Gold.
Christians wear crosses
Of course Christians.
who else. Moslems?
Don't you see. Dad? -What?
I mean... was Mom...
...Christian? Not a chance!
Your mother was a Jew. A Jew
So that's why you came?
How about a simple visit.
doesn't your world value that?
No... It s not just that.
Then what else?
I'm getting married. -What s that?
Getting married. -Great. Sasha
Is she Jewish?
She’s from our youth movement.
...I'm just kidding.
Let s see what we have here...
We should celebrate, no?
Don’t worry, it's my friend s car.
It's Kosher.
Cheers. -Cheers.
Yair, it s Dafna.
I'm worried sick about you.
You disappeared, you didn't make it
to my parents, to the activity.
I've been trying to reach you all
night... Call me back.
Then whose necklace is it?
Dad. I have to know.
What does it matter?
Did it belong to Mom? -No.
Dad. tell the truth. -What truth?
About the necklace, about Mom.
What do you want to hear?
The real truth.
or your religion's truth?
What does that mean? -Your mothe
was a Jew. A true Jew. you see?
She wore a Star of David, even
at times when it was dangerous.
She insisted you be circumcised.
when that too was dangerous.
Your mother was a true Jew.
I don’t understand what you're
saying, is the necklace hers?
No. -Thank God. Then whose is it?
Her mother s, your grandmother.
Then she wasn't Jewish. If Grandma
wasn't Jewish, neither was she.
Don't you understand?
-I understand.
I understand that you want to let
your religious teachers decide
who your mother was.
You should be ashamed of yourself!
Sasha! Yair
Blessed are You. Lord.
King of the world.
who gives the rooster wisdom
to know day from night.
Blessed are You. Lord.
King of the^world. who...
didn’t make me a Gentile.
Blessed are You. Lord. King of the
world, who didn't make me a slave.
world, who didn’t make me a woman.
Blessed ar(e You. Lord. King of the
world, who-opens blind eyes.
Blessed ar,e You. Lord. King of the
world, whoclothes the naked.
Blessed* are You...
Where have you been?
-I'm sorry.
I was just... -Do you have any
idea how worried I was about you?
I m really... -You don’t show a
sign of life all day. nothing.
I'm sorry. -'Sorry!
My family waited more than an hour
for you to show up for the meal.
I don't know how many
messages I left for you.
And then you just show up in the
morning saying you're sorry.
You see. I went to see my dad.
-Since when is your dad
in the picture? Couldn't you call',
couldn't you answer your phone-?
You re 100 percent right, it's
just that... suddenly...
i realized i hadn't told him about
us. I felt bad, i had to tel him.
I was so worried about you.
-I'm really sorry.
but still, it s my dad.
He deserves to know about us.
Was he happy to hear it?
-Very. We even drank a toast.
Very nice. Without me.
It's not fair.
I should have been there.
He said that too. He won't approve
until he meets you.
So nothing happened.
-What could have happened?
I don't know,
something doesn't seem right.
The whole story about your dad
has nothing to do-with yesterday.
after all. you didn't drive
to Tel Aviv on the Sabbath.
Is it about me? -No...
it has nothing to do with you.
You have nothing to worr.y about.
-But I am worried.
I want to help.
-No. Dafna.
It's something I have to do
on my own.
It will be fine.
It's no big deal.
That's the thing, it is a big
deal. -But I didn't know anything.
I have to resolve this
immediately, today.
Get together whoever you need.
I m here. Let’s do it.
Kid. I understand your problem,
but it's not that simple.
First of all. there's a test.
-What 'test? I study at Yeshiva.
I go through three pages of Talmud
a day. -Good. It’ll be easy then.
I ll take you in to see
Rabbi Struman.
he will set a date
for your test.
and if. God willing,
you pass the test...
Hold on. were you circumcised?
-Of course.
A rabbi came especially from
Moscow. -Excellent.
So you only have to dip in the
Mikveh. That’s the procedure.
By the way. at which Yeshiva do
you study? - Ohr Yitzhak."
' Ohr Yitzhak,' I know it.
Hold on. it's in Jerusalem, what
are you doing here in Tel Aviv?
What does it matter? I m Jewish.
I keep the commandments...
You keep the commandments...
suggest you re-open the Talmud.
Why do ,you say that?
Because if you're such a scholar.
you should know that for now.
you re forbidden to keep the
commandments. -Forbidden?
-Sure, especially the Sabbath.
What? -Come on. I thought
yo'u were a Yeshiva student.
you were a Yeshiva student.
Does Maimonides ring a bell?
A Gentile who keeps the Sabbath'
...is punished by death.'
-Excellent. Punished by death.
You are forbidden to keep
the Sabbath for now.
You don’t, have to go overboard.
As-Sabbath comes in.
light a cigarette, or write
something, then you're fine.
Eat
After all. King David was a
descendant of Ruth the Moabite.
It is. written: Ammonites and
Moabites may not become Jewish.’
Are you with me?
If he fell asleep and slept
all1 Sabbath, he deserves death
If who falls asleep?
-The Gentile.
What Gentile?
What are you talking about?
Maimonides. Laws of the Sabbath.
But we re studying laws of widows.
Besides, who^will kill him.
the religious court-?--------
Kill who? -The Gentile
who kept the Sabbath.
Why would a Gentile keep Sabbath,
is he crazy? -Forget about why.'
Why. is keeping the Sabbath
a hobby?
Sasha. Yair.
I can t find you anywhere.
Why don’t you answer
m very worried.
We have to talk.
We ll find a solution.
Please call. I love you.
Quiet! We re going on the trip the
day after the Shavuot holiday.
We ll be visiting the
immigrants camp and the beach.
They’ll explain everything
there. Any questions?
What time do we come back?
-I told you. at ten.
How much is the trip?
-Where have you been?
Everyone paid a month ago.
now you remember to ask?!
150 shekels.
Sasha, what about my parents
permission? -I told you
I’d talk to them.
You don't have to nag.
Excuse me a second.
Will you tell me what s going on?
-Nothing.
Wait a. second! What happenecb to
you in there? What s going on-?
We aren’t married yet. right?
-What’s that supposed Co mean?
That I don't have to report to
you about everything I go through.
You know what? You don't
have to do anything for me.
Sabbath begins
Sabbath ends
...He raises the dead
with His word.
The Hol.y God. there is none
like Him.
He lets his people rest on
His holy Sabbath day-
for this is his will,
vj e will s e rw e him with
fear and trembling.
and we will thank His name
every day. always.
with essential blessings.
The Lord of thanks and peace...
Peace upon you. ^attending angels,
heavenly angels.
from the King of Kings.
the Holy One. blessed be He
Peace upon you. attending angels,
heavenly angels.
from the King of Kings... -Dafna
It s all right. Leave her-alone.
Come in peace, attending angels,
h'eavenly angels.
from the King of Kings,
the Holy One. blessed be He.
Come home.
Yes?
Hey.
Yair isn’t here? -I think he
went out. Is something wrong?
Do you know where he is?
-He is hardly speaking.
but I think he went out with
his father. -His father.
Dafna. keep me posted, okay?
-Byei;
Too bad. It s delicious.
Have you told Dafna?
Sasha, understand, in-the end.
what's important is what-s inside.
You don’t have to be-a-gehius
to see who you really are.
Who am I really?
I can t answer that for you.----------
t just hurts me to see you
suffering over nothing.
For you it s nothing, for me it-s
everything. -Okay, it-s important
to you. -Yes. -Really important-?
Yes. -Then stop pitying yourself*
Do what they ask.
They want to test you? Pass it.
lik.o miz,L z,adnuc r,l z,r?ia
It won't cost you anything.
Yair, explain what the Mishna
is. please.
You must have heard of the
Mishna. -I’ve heard of it.
Y:ou must have heard of the
Mishna. -I've heard of it.
d^be glad if you went right
to your-'Jhardest questions.
I d be glad if you went right
to your hardest questions.
No need, just answer.
We asked you about the Mishna.
. No heed, jusj answer.
We-asked you about the Mishna.
Is that a 11 ? - T h e n w h a t s the
difference between Biblical-
and Rabbinic >? -Is that it0
—•Pell us^what Mukfze is.
and Rabbinic ? -Is that it?
-Tell usVvhat Muktze is.
And don't Jorget the Mishna.
The early commentators have three
ways of understanding Muktze.
Maimonides holds that
it is from the Torah.
Maimonides* holds that
Later commentators show he bases
this on the^concept of rebirth.
Some early commentators disagree
and say that it s Rabbinic.
and the evidence is in the
Mis'hnaic- tractate -Beitza. ’
Oh. I forgot, you also asked me
what "the JMish na is.
Well. 4he M1 s h n a was written by...
-Okay, we don't need-the details.
Well, the Mishna was written by...
-Okay, we don’t need the details.
we just want to see if you know.
-Of course I know.
we just want t'ox see/if you know.
-0f course I know.
Yair, you seem very angry.
No one is forcing you to convert.
Are you sure you want to?
-Do I want to...
Are--you .sure you want to9
-Do iVvant t6\.—
- Krupitzki-
Yes. y.es° Can I help you
Hello. -Hello
I m Dafna. Are* you Yair's father?
-Ah. Dafna. my daughter-in-law.
Please come in.
Is Yair home? -Not yet.
he should be-here soon.
Even better, we ll have time
to get to know each other.
Please come in.
You passed, buddy. God bless you.
Now you only have the ritual bath.
You can come...
»
You can come..
Oh. great, on Shavuot eve.
It's a symbolic date.
What a sign from God.
It s a symbolic date.
What: a‘-signMfrom God.
Ruth the Moabite. I know.
Please.
Thank you. -You're welcome.
Do you play?
-Me? No. I don’t get near it.
Then whose is it?
-Sasha s. I mean Yair s.
He didn't tell me he played.
-He didn't?
That s how he is. Discreet.
You have to.twist his arm.
-Especially lately.
It doesn t matter.
That-s what I'm here for.
Look, second place in the
piano competition.
Harkov Piano Competition
Alexander Krupitzki. 2nd Place-
This is Yair at his piano
lesson. He-s seven here.
Look how serious he is.
Ever since he was little I told
him. don’t be like-Pierre Bizohov.
6e like Andre Balkonski. alive
• t	r-
Are those your relatives'?
-In a way.
That's Tolstoy.
It's War and Peace/
He once knew it almost by heart.
-Another thing he never told me.
Where is he?
-He’s on an errand.
I don’t interfere.
-Who is this?
Friends of his.
You probably want to be alone...
-No. it's all right.
What did you talk about?
-- -Nothing.
In fact it .was very nice..
saw pictures, of your family-,
your friends.
You don t understand.
-Ik understand^ver-y well.
What do you understand?
-That hdon:t Jknow-you at-all.
You could at least have been
brave enough to be honest.
instead you disappear all the
time and make me chase you.
Wait a second.
If you decide you want to leave,
it's all right
This belonged to my grandimothen.
my mdther-s* mother. —
I need air
I understand.
You don't understand anything.
You can't begin to understand.
It takes more than a piece, of
metal to make me give you up
sea. Tihat S'the only thing
missing-in Jerusalem.
Will you eat with us
on the Shavuot holiday?
Aren't your parents mad at me
-They do what I tell them.
Okay-.
You didn't-, even, tell me you play
piano. -I don't
That was years ago,N when my mother was still alive
Sb what do y.ou have’left.,ijust
theuMikveh-(rituab bath')-?
lbs not so simple. -Why. you just
have to dip. In andudut.
And what Kapperisi a_ft'er I dip?
Suddenly I m a' Jew-?-Like magic?
being> under water
tor a few seconds-?
That s how it-is. according to. .
-And1 everything I felt, studied...
and'prayed’. 'Was; it< all a lie?
Don’t think abdut-it-so much.
Do. y,6u want me to come with yjau
to the Mikveh-?
It's nothing complicated.
You say
"I take upon myself the yoke
of Torah and the commandments.'
you dip. and then you make
the blessing over the Mikveh.
You should be happy. You’re
getting a new soul, a Jewish soul.
What about the old one?
-Excuse me?
My old soul, the gentile soul, the
one being replaced by a Jewish
one. What happens to it? Does it
come with me? Does it stay here?
Don t you care that a soul is
lost? -Yair... -You take a guy
who gave everything
to become Jewish.
then you suddenly come and
tell him. you’re not Jewish.
Excuse me. mister, that's not the
point. -That's the whole point.
Yair, it's a lot more complex.
It doesn't work like that.
You add a dimension to your soul.
-Leave him alone, he's crazy.
That s right. I'm crazy!
Crazy for getting up every
morning to pray and lay Tefillin.
Crazy for never touching my
girlfriend, who I left
to study Torah day and night
at Yeshiva. But I'm not Jewish.
I love my soul.
So when does he plan to
try again? -I don’t know.
try again? -I don't know.
He won t talk about it.
sure he ll* be all right.
I'm shure he'll be all right
Give him time.
I d rather we d'idn t brjng up
the-subject at all.
I don't want him to know that
you know, okay-? -Fine. firFe.
I made the quiche you like.
-Thank you. -Bon appetit.
Let-my*father.‘do that, okay?
In our .fam iky. that’s the
father-s j^bv -Please.
I ll go get another bottle opener.
Mom. can I have some too?
No. sweetie, not now.
Cheers
i get it
A' Gentile touched y.our wine, a'n'd
now your holy wine is impure.
Thank you very much, really.
m sorry I touched) your wine.
But I can make up for it easily.
Would you like me to ’turn
something on for you?
You don't even
have'to say anything.
Is it too dark for y,ou.?
I ll turn on a light.
Is it too hot?' Let s turn on
the air conditioner—
Is it too hot? Let s turn on
the air-conditioner-.
Is it a'I H l I e boring?
I ll turn on some music.—
After all., I have to, desecrate,
the-Sabbath. holidays too.
No problem. The boiler,
the-microwave. just say the word.
l am a Gentile.-
I must-desecrate the Sabbath.
Yair.
Happy holiday, where to?
Dafna
-Cheers*
Yulia! Yulia!
Yulia!
Hey. look who I brought.
Hi!
Our little monster came back.
Make your move already.
Come on. kid. tell us.
How is it with your religious
pals? is life easier now?
No. Not at all. -Ask him
if his religion allows him
to hang out with his friends.
Leave him alone.
Is he allowed to speak Russian
Back off. We love you.
Pay no attention. It s from love.
Tell him religion has nothing
to do with it. It s just me.
Did you hear that?
Stas, pass the silotka.
Bon appetit.
I missed that taste.
Tolstoy - War and Peace
Count Andre was happy, so he
didn’t see Pierre s suffering.
Yes. yes. yesterday I suffered.
but I don-t regret it.'
(From War and Peace )
Hi. Gidi.
-Hi. Dafna. what s up?
There's a problem.
Let me guess: Yair?
He’s not coming.
-I see.
Well. I could use a sunny day.
-Thanks.
Sasha, play something. -No. no.
Play. play.
I haven’t played in ages.
The piano is like a bicycle.
you never really forget. Come on.
Sashka.
You're such a...
Remind us of the smell of snow.
Hush, the mice are sleeping.
the hedgehogs fell asleep.
bear cubs, bear cubs and children.
they all sleep until sunrise.
All but a green chariot.
Rushing, rushing in the heavens.
in the silvery expanse.
Six horses galloping.
in red and green caps
floating over the land.
on the windowsill.
a black crow.
You can't catch the chariot.
for Spring travels within...
I forgot how beautifully you play.
Thanks for taking me there.
You re welcome.
Have you ever been with a girl?
No.
Are you okay? -I’m a Gentile.
Gentiles are allowed.
I wasn't asking about that.
What's wrong
I don't want you to hate me
if we sleep together
you'll never forgive me.
Sasha, sometimes you have to
go away in order to return.
Return? To what? -To yourself.
Thanks. Yulia.
Hello. Dalna?
I hoped it would be you.
-Yes. it's me. it's met
The old me or the new me?
Both.
I'm comming to you
Hello. Dad?
I'm fine. -
Stop worrying about me
all the time-.
But... I have a strange
favor to ask.
We are all just...
That s how you say I love you'
in Russian.
I love you. -I love you.
There should have been a hug here.
It will be all right soon
Sooner than you think.
What are they doing here?
what is this?
A house full of girls, everything
we have is pink. -What?
They came especially for you.
Go and dip.
Come back to us new.
New and old.
Go. Sasha. Go. our Yair.- -