Many, many years ago…
with the hardness of chert stone,
by breathing soaked plasma…
a human heart was born.
And it started to march.
Step up, step on.
Its harness was made of
pure teutonic flesh.
Step up, step on.
It was suffocated by sulphates.
The platelets were short of oxygen.
We, platelets, ask for oxygen and
to slow down the drive of time!
Geez, which one forgot to turn off
the TV this time?
Who will pay for all this?
Who always gets grief for
the thing being on at night?
Mr. manager, what are you doing here?
I'm checking the employees' kimeteeping.
Didn’t everyone here agree
to increase their efforts?
What will you tell me?
Well, what should I?
I had pains last night
and now I overslept.
- I don’t watch porn, unlike someone.
- Really!
What kind of man you take me for?
They say you’re a huge skirt chaser.
- Me? Who says so?
- Someone living…
Mrs. Maštálková, think hard,
who told you?
Come on now,
it’s important.
- Someone important? - The Gossip’s
being told, the water’s running.
Someone important…?
Could it be someone important?
Someone important or…
Someone important?
It could mean a good deal.
Mrs. Maštálková,
You know, for such calumny…
you could well be… imprisoned!
You mean nowadays?
OK, let’s admit, nowadays no.
But in passed times… yes.
Man, look at this.
You’re still here, Mrs. Maštálková?
I’m leaving.
You got up early today.
You’re kinda pale.
Like after a sleepless night.
Get up!
Get up, I say!
Hey maestro! Move!
Damn, I besmirched myself.
Now, come on!
- An invitation to a graduation party.
- Where was it?
- Are we going?
- Dunno, you didn’t study…
You promised to
give me a lift to work.
I have no time now.
Have to shave…
So come on, lass.
If the kind way doesn’t work
the mean one will have to.
Now…
Here you go.
Put your feet away.
So are we going to the party?
I’m not sure.
Like I said, you didn’t study.
Promises are wrongs.
Geez,
this is just like marriage…
Another thing you’ve promised me.
OK, lass.
I’m not going to the party anyway.
Swear…
on our love.
I swear on our love…
this is beating for you only.
- And not for our baby?
- For our baby?
What do you mean?
Nothing.
So nothing?
You won’t give me a lift.
Bye then.
Damn.
One always has to worry about something.
Good late afternoon, Mr. Dědek.
When will you finally learn to
be on time to work?
Sorry, I wonder too.
Oh, you wonder?
We shall have a talk about it.
No entry, working for the director.
- Hi.
I’ve brought work for you.
- Those perished sheep?
- Yep. And Hlaváček wants it soon.
- Do you want coffee?
- Yes.
What are you doing?
Making slices macro-biotically .
Oh…
- And mineral water, if it’s cooled.
- I only have siphons here.
At least something.
The water is terrible anyway.
But beware,
bubbles are also unhealthy.
So what? It’s scientifically proven
anyway that we will die.
I’ll take a look at you…
At you I’ll take a look.
What does it remind me of?
This perhaps?
Here’s your drink.
I sent someone for the mineral water.
Well, it’s all prepared
in a kinda clumsy way,
- But still it seems like "VPN".
- Oh yep.
The new one worked on it.
She’s not skilled yet.
Say…
Today I’ll need to leave sooner.
You can’t, muffs need to be controlled.
- Damn.
- How do you do.
I’ve brought the mineral water.
Where should I put them?
To that… What’s it called?
Put it… I don’t—
Somewhere to that-.
What’s it called?
Well, put it somewhere…
You’re free to go,
I’ll manage here somehow.
Jiřina.
- I wanna drink!
- Have this. - Not this.
Two more Becherovkas, please.
I wanna dance.
Come on.
- May I have a dance?
- Yep.
Great stuff, isn’t it?
- Danke.
- Bitte.
- Sie sprechen deutsch?
- Klar. Ja, sicher.
Wir kennen fast
alle deutsch sprechen.
- Ja.
- Ja, gut.
Sturm und Drang,
nicht war?
Dichtung und Wahrheit,
mein Liebe.
Dichtung und Wahrheit.
Wait, where are you heading?
- Where Will Pepe invite us now?
- I’m insolvent, ladies.
Was machst du den hier, Mensch?
- Ich hab dich noch so lange nicht
gesehen. - Na ja, sehr lange.
Das ist mein Freund Pupi.
- Look, some foreigners there.
- From the west.
From where else, silly?
Schönes Mensch, nicht war?
Entschulding.
- Watch out, Jiřina’s looking for you.
- Man, we better hook it.
Du bist ein sehr lustiger Kerl.
- Speak german, I have 3 chicks here.
- Great.
Well, girls come on.
I have…
- Herzlich Willkommen!
- I introduce you to Herr Dědek.
- Horst Bucholz.
- This is Maruška.
- Kateřina. - Guten Abend.
Horst Bucholz, mein Name.
Where are the Germans, girls?
Aber das ist so
schönes Überraschung!
Also kann ich alle einladen
zu meinen Tisch?
Also gehen wir.
Pupi!
Pupi, Wait.
Heute Abend ist so schönes
Wetter, nicht? Donnerwetter.
Come on, where are you?
Eindringen, nicht war?
Is Herr Franc here?
A separé is ready for him.
Separé, für mich?
- We have to go.
- Separé.
But hurry up,
we can’t understand a word.
Never mind, we’ll make ourselves
understand, nicht war?
- Prosit! - Prosit!
- Prosit!
Come on!
What are you waiting for? Buzz off!
Bitte.
- Das Wein schmecken.
- Prosit!
- Es schmeckt gut.
- Ich auch.
Ich bin sehr glücklich.
Ich auch.
Danke schön.
Wie ist es tschechisch?
Děkuju (thanks).
Dě-ku-ju.
Das ist eine Lampe.
Wie ist es tschechisch?
Well, lampa.
Lampa.
Und das ist ein Luster.
Wie ist es tschechisch?
Lustr too.
Auch Luster.
Und das ist ein štokrdle.
Wie ist es tschechisch?
Štokrdle too.
Štokrdle Also...
Goddamn.
Das is ist kein Kruzifix.
- There’s gonna be a spot.
- Das ist kein Fleck.
Aber das sind boobs!
Boobs? You speak Czech?
What did you expect?
I’m a pure candid Czech.
You cheater!
You’re already done?
Man, I had no idea that
“forwards” in german is “vorwärts”.
I used it on him, man.
- Mein Blut. Pupi, harmed…
- Ruhe!
Das Leben ist so schön,
nicht war?
Heute abend und morgen
ist der Tante urlaubs Leipzig.
Und unsere alte Kerl
aus Karl-Marx-Stadt.
Mon cheri...
Es mir tut so leid.
- Does it hurt?
- No, it’s OK.
Wasser. Ich muss für Wasser gehen.
Ich bin gleich zurück.
Sitzen und warten.
Sit and wait. Ich bin
gleich zurück. Ich gehe für Wasser.
He’s probably going to the restroom.
Look, there's Netík.
- Who?
- A crazy professor.
A phenomenal asshole.
- He’s heading here.
- With his whole family.
- What will we do? - Let’s not give
a damn. - Sure.
What impertinence!
Válová, Přibylová,
I don’t know the third one.
What are you doing at our table…?
Drinking our wine!
Hearing the tower-clock beat,
we don’t give a shit.
And chaps drink, drink and drink…
Booze - nothing to lose.
Come here, make me disappear.
Drink this
to make peace.
Hey, stuff your love.
- What’s up?
- An inspection’s here.
- Is this all?
- Yes.
- What’s inside those boxes?
- Chicken too.
We’ll take a look later.
- And where’s your storeroom?
- In the back. Where else?
What are you doing?
Come on, help me.
If you touch me… !
I’m done!
I’m not gonna be anybody’s fool.
- Take your hands off!
- Pick it up immediately.
Bring the stuff
from the car inside!
That is a 55 kg surplus.
There's no mistake.
I counted it three times.
Mrs. Manager, stop it, will you?
Such a young man.
One would expect you
to be understanding.
But I understand you, don't worry.
But you must understand me as well.
So this is finished here.
Next-door, it’s also all written down.
Think he’s noticed?
Damn!
We’ll have to give him another one.
Wait.
Oh, what’s this?
- Your coat is all dirty.
- Never mind.
- May I? I’ll make it clean.
- No need. - I have some petrol.
OK, as you please.
- Better make it two.
- But then he’ll have three.
I’ll take one away from him.
Excuse me…
Don’t stay here. The chicken will
disappear before I leave.
Of course…
Mrs. Manager!
Come here.
Give me your signature.
You’ll pay a penalty for those bills.
And as for the chicken…
I hope,
you won’t cause many problems for me.
We’ll see,
sign it here.
Oh, this damned job…
- So can we go on?
- Sure.
Simultaneously, the expenditure
of forage was observed…
- Got it?
- A minute
It’s so hot here…
…for the production…
of one egg.
- Of what?
- Egg.
Or as the case may be…
of one kg…
of egg material.
No entry! Working for the director!
- Tschüss!
- Hi, What brings you here?
- Keep cool. What are you writing?
- A dissertation.
Aren’t you through with it
for a long time?
But this is for
the director’s daughter, see?
- Hanička, Could you make coffee for us?
- Sure.
- It’s her? Nice chick.
- Hey, watch out, will you?
Shit, where could the hag have put it?
- What makes you so nervous?
- I tried a trick with chewing gum.
Seems it didn’t work.
So I will have to do with
one thousand.
- How much do you earn for this work?
- Come on, it’s for the director.
Then I would dump it.
Well boy, it’s our times.
First I wanted to work on it
by myself. But whatever.
It’ll help the girl to get through.
And me as well.
- Have a cigarette?
- Yep.
- Oh, look at this…
- Look!
That’s it!
One… and another…
Honesty pays well.
The thirst is huge…
The thirst is huge, my life’s dwindling
away, lemme daydream pleasantly,
…listen to the nightingales, sing along
and drink.
Merci.
Oh, too salty.
- It’s your first time here, isn’t it?
- We met before?
I knew you even as a kid.
You’re my star. Believe me?
- Me not that old.
- So you don’t believe?
Let me show you something.
Come on, it’s not far.
You speak french?
Is this me?
This is not me.
No way, it’s not me.
- It surely is you.
- It isn’t. - Really. - No.
Just take a good look.
- It’s not me.
- A good look!
Like that?
Like that…?
Not me at all.
What do you think?
Like this she similar.
A bit.
I'll show you…
because sitting like this…
Not completely me. Is it?
To catch it it mustn’t show interest.
The pray will then let itself be seized.
It mustn’t show interest.
That’s it.
The pray will let itself
to be seized by it.
I must give this a try soon.
There’s something for you.
Some free dates at the big hall.
Put it here.
Are you angry?
No.
Because of yesterday?
Because I didn’t dance with you?
What are you writing?
Nothing for you.
Come on…
- So František is angry…
- Leave me alone.
Well, after you change your mind,
you can invite me tonight.
I’m afraid I can’t.
Where’s the will, there’s a way.
Hot, isn’t it?
Enough! I’m going home.
I’m going home!
You won’t find me here.
- Comrade director, how do you do.
- Where…
- Where are you heading?
- Nowhere.
- I mean, for some posters.
- Well go ahead.
When you’re back come to see me.
- Know why I’m here?
- About those damaged chairs?
That also, but mostly about the
performance of those…
dirty musicians and singers.
People, wake up.
You know the situation.
There was even a consultation
in the cultural department.
And it’s all your business.
- You are responsible.
- Those boys got a rating.
Leave me alone with your rating.
It’s a club for youngsters
in the first place.
Their opinions are still forming.
We can’t play them such dirty music.
Can you see what it could cause?
Be happy that it’s been settled
this way without more sanctions.
- Hell, what way?
- Keep calm, sit down.
It’ll only be canceled, nothing more.
The place’ll be used as a
campaign center. That’s it.
Perhaps you’ll be allowed to play
there now and then.
What’s this here? Show me?
- It’s only… - Only What?
- A performance we're working on. - Wait
Another and another people get in.
Here you go, it’s nice.
Fine start.
Another and another people get off.
Get off? God, off what?
- Anywhere.
- Wait.
Don’t get off after the sound signal.
Oh, from the subway, you should
Have said. It’s not wrong then.
Don’t get off.
It’s clear as a day.
Don’t get off and hurry to leave
the door way.
He can’t see the rear-view mirror,
didn’t make it.
He collapsed from the drive of our time.
Wait a minute.
Collapsed from the drive of our time.
What does it mean?
- Well. - What?
- Nothing, I don’t know…
- Couldn’t take it anymore.
- Now, who couldn’t?
Who do you mean, comrade?
Nobody, dunno.
Dunno! "Dunno" but still he writes.
He writes not knowing that everything
needs a clear ideological basis.
What’s wrong with your brains, sonny?
We also used to do theater plays,
and what kind!
We chose nice plays to
make people laugh.
And not to make them collapse
from the drive of time.
Here, it has to disappear…
- Now, like this.
- We meant something else.
Else! Everyone must think something else
Everyone must think the same way…
something else.
And not this… “These days don’t
differ more than eggs”.
What? The thought must be clear
and understandable for everyone.
The thought must be clear and
understandable for everyone.
Don’t laugh, gentlemen.
I stand for revolution.
But no one volunteers to execute it.
That’s the main dilemma of scientific
revolution.
- 3, 2, 1!
Another and another carnival float
appears.
- Everybody asks…
- What will you be like, vodka?
What will you be like, polar bear?
Wait, gentlemen.
Know this one?
There.
General paralysis proceeds.
Don’t drink, when you can’t
handle it.
Chocolate Betty and her ensemble
enter.
- Here. - Want one of them,
František?
Me?
Are you sure?
Don't worry, it’s gonna be OK.
- Have some cash? - Why?
- For the bog.
Hurry up.
- Geez, you’re so slow. Gimme.
- Wait. - It’s OK.
- If someone leaves, let me know?
- What?
- Let me know, if someone leaves.
- I’ll take care.
- Františkek! - Here he is.
- You are here?
Why weren’t you at the
banquet last night?
I guess it’s too square for me…
You made a mistake.
You may have made contacts with
very important people…
Don’t underestimate it. Though I admit
this place is much less boring.
Oh, even Brazilians are let in?
This is just terrible.
I say, it’s quite amusing to
watch folk amuse themselves.
- Come on, will you? Hurry up.
- Who do you speak with?
- With you indeed, asshole.
- I beg your pardon.
It’s preferable not to respond
to such trash, Mr. director.
- WTF?
- Will you lemme go, damn it?!
Nelly, come here.
“Digima lezina veroni.”
Gypsy baron, it’s me,
every gypsy girl knows me…
Where’s Janinka?
I’m madly in love.
Everybody come here,
let’s go for coffee.
- As you please, Mr. baron.
- I’m in love.
- This thing’s surely gonna
fall apart. - Janička!
Hit the road.
And now, gentlemen?
Let’s go to ours.
- I’m gonna get some sleep.
- I’m gonna get some life.
I’m going to the office.
Have to take some posters there.
I have to go there too.
Need to take something there.
Yep, take something there,
how kind of you.
- Kind of him, isn’t it?
- Don’t forget, boldly and rough.
For the lady in 360.
A bottle of mineral water on ice.
- Get on the table.
- How? Where?
- It’s dangerous.
- Get on me.
- Not that way, the other way.
- Like this?
I’m afraid.
I’m afraid!
Bob Saint-Clar was eluding Karpov’s
hands with natty, feline steps…
and then he undressed her,
boldly and rough…
Hey, slinger!
Excuse me, I would need…
- I’m not sure…
- Take it off, come on.
Here’s my coat.
I knew it was you.
Yesterday.
Bravo.
Go on.
Well…
Go on, sporty!
Come on now!
Piss off, bastard!
Hey, where are you?
Damned…
Where is it, man? The coat!
I’ll kill you!
Let’s raise our song,
our flag will wave forever.
Hooray, hooray, hooray!
My love, it’s a bead of dew
at the bottom of bloom.
My love, it’s a
wedding gift from forest elves.
- My love…
- What’s happened to you, moron?
Where you easily brake your neck,
there I took off my hat.
God, where are your glasses?
Those beautiful sun glasses?
Really.
Aren’t they important as hell?
Can’t you see,
the reflection of infra-red shine…
on coherent layer of snow…
is as dangerous for eyeballs as…
…a window opened in January for
a patient struck with bronchitis?!
So shut it, you moron.
- How many horses does it have?
- Divide its hooves by four.
A hoof here, a hoof there…
The second day passed for the
ninth time.
- Hoof there…
…hoof here
The mirror reflections burn in the sun.
My heart caws out from
the body's frame…
…And the evening rises…
…My forehead in the line…
…And the command: castle…
…My command: direction-
Forgot the ninth thing in the second day
-Through bush he hears a strong sound
The hooves beat unreason.
A hoof here, a hoof there.
- The cymbals ring…
…in the grotesque of the night…
Only kettledrums yell about my death!
- Here we go, assholes.
- Get off, final station!
Look, our salami’s been eaten.
We’ll never get this outta there.
Look!
Czechoslovakian television.
Over there, artiodactyls!
Hoof here,
Hoof there, jerks.
Struggling through the path
around Cotter Creek…
here comes Florián Targonelli.
The cap reinforces the mind
jumping at little joys.
The hooves beat unreason.
Gee-up, boys!
Nice horses.
Nice yes, but never stand behind them.
No worry, animals love me.
Geez, what kind of swines do you have?
Your joy - a little fairy of unease.
And I fall dazzled by its blackness.
Well, dear audience,
a hoof here, a hoof there…
doesn’t pay well.
Peaks and valleys, black forest…
I haven’t seen my dolly yet today.
I haven’t seen my…
There’s a dolly!
Come on, move!
You can do it.
Come on now! Come on!
Come on, only a little longer!
- Move!
- Hop, hop, hop...
- I book the Fisher-skis-chicks.
- I book Rosignole-ones.
- I book Bohemia-ones.
- Dědek, there go Bohemias.
Move, come on!
Come on, 5 seconds left…
I guess.
Move!
We can’t go on like this, boys.
Let’s get into action.
That is action Z -
- the rearrangement of the fence.
Move on.
Oh, I see…
Look, there she’s coming.
Here comes the first one,
a Fisher-snow-lady.
Move on!
Come on, hurry up!
Hey, my darling is coming.
Harry up, Dědek.
Before the next one arrives.
Come on.
We must arrange it now.
- Watch out!
- It’s nothing serious, young lady.
Everything’s gonna be all right.
- Man, have you gone mad?
- Nothing’s gonna be all right!
Everything’s spoiled, ruined!
- It’s too late for everything.
- It only seems like it.
The sun will rise again.
Have a little look at me.
Come on, give us a smile.
There, it becomes you.
Here comes fernet.
Shall we dance?
Order something for me,
I’ll try it with Petra.
May I have a dance?
- Stop it! - What are you doing?
His meal is getting cold!
You castrated cuckolds!
You braindead mug!
Fecal asshole!
Mountain bastards!
What’s up…?
Pepe, open up!
Pepe, be reasonable!
They’re only pretending.
It’s all arranged.
Pepe, please!
Let me be! I’m an invalid!
- Lemme be!
- Act better, dilettantes.
You cuckolds!
It’ll end in no time. Let’s hide
meanwhile. Cover your ears.
Stop it, moron!
Lemme be, assholes!
- I can’t take it… - Take what?
It’s nothing but an act.
- I have to open it.
- Come to bed. - No.
- Look, such poor acting.
- I’ll open it.
Why should you?
Stay here.
Damn it!
- Oh, he’s bleeding! - Tasteless.
Where’s Dědek with the ketchup?
- Doesn’t he look like you.
- Which one?
- Why, the red one.
- Looks rather like you.
- Hardly—
- Man, What a mug.
- But he really looks like you.
- You think so?
- Sure, your brother in America.
- Funny guy, aren't you?
- Petruška, we do also amateur theater.
- You said “we”?
- Especially Franta, I mean.
- That’s better.
And when’s your opening?
I’m not sure yet
when he finishes it up.
You make it up yourselves?
Ourselves, really.
And then František writes it down
in his office, doesn’t he?
Naturally by peacock plume.
Ouch, you asshole.
It’s the theatre d’auteur, see?
Kind of hyperbole,
Kind of parabole…
Something utterly new.
Something unreal,
something unrepeatable,
overstatement, gag, satire…
Kind of… experimental.
Something utterly new.
Oh, the freedom.
The liberty.
The relief.
An utterly new theater.
Jesus, I hear something.
Wait!
- My dad… Jesus Christ! - Dad, really?
- Come on, get dressed.
Hide, we can’t be found here
like this.
- You’re still up? - Hi.
- Guess what I’ve brought for you.
Some wax, see?
For your skiing.
Something wrong?
- How do you do.
- What are you doing here?
- A pal’s here for watching the VCR.
- VCR my ass!
And she’ll get a cottage
from her father…
This could be sold for some 150 or 200
thousand, even with a hen house.
- You’re an asshole.
- She’s not silly enough to come.
And what about Jiřina?
Whatever. He’ll put her with
this cat in the same bed.
Let’s wait only 10 more minutes…
then off we go.
You’ll be sorry one day,
- when you know life.
- Shut up!
- Damn…
- Try the doorbell, chicken.
I won’t get the serial here.
At worst, you’ll be
attacked by a piece of wax.
Piss off from the bell, man!
I won’t be told what to do!
I’ll do what I want!
Well, some paprika would come in handy.
What’s the red stuff in there?
No kidding, man.
Is he throwing up blood or what.
Is he perhaps yellow?
Stop it, you…!
Go for the X-ray
first thing tomorrow.
Of course.
Don’t eat, drink or smoke…
And as doctor said:
Don’t forgot the diet.
And don’t cheer up after
first sign of relief.
Don't worry, I’m so sick that I’ll
obey everything. Goodbye.
- Oh, hi.
- ciao.
You’re back already?
What a mess in here.
- I was looking forward so much.
- You don’t say.
- You weren’t?
- I was but I’m sick.
You don’t care about me at all.
Not even telling me where you were.
You’re still god knows where.
Saying nothing to me.
- How was it? Was there some snow?
- Yep, lots of snow.
Could you make for me
an herbal tea? It’s in that bag.
So you’re sick?
Our Pepíček doesn’t feel well?
So, to the bed… now!
Let’s do a little massage.
- Lemme be, please, I’m sick.
- Smiling is a cure, give us a smile.
I’ll get isotopes…
And now you’re like this.
Who do you think?
- He gave me this address.
- What…?
Well.
So, here it is.
- There’s no-one there.
- You know where they are?
They went to the storeroom
for some flags.
Or maybe to the hall.
Mr. manager, are you there?
Geez, someone’s in the corridor.
Is there an electrical fuse?
- Don’t go.
- I have to.
We need a fuse, comrades are there
in the dark.
The doorkeeper has spare keys.
He could come here.
Wait. I’ll get dressed.
- Let’s go… wait.
- Mr. manager, hurry up, will you?
- Wait here.
- Like this?
Hide yourself, I’ll lock it.
- To where?
- To there.
What’s up? Coming…
I’ll be back later.
Come on.
I must be dreaming.
Dreaming, Mr. manager?
You weren’t sleeping, were you?
No, comrade manager.
I was cleaning up in here.
It’s a great mess in here though.
But you've found the flag we need,
haven’t you?
- There in the back.
- Oh, I can see it.
Shall I get it out,
comrade manager?
I’m not so old I can't
do it myself, am I?
Here it is!
Man, that’s funny.
Dear comrades,
we must realize,
Where we stand and…
What our goals are.
See the motto for today:
We must protect the peace
at any cost.
No worry, one of them may have
left since then.
Don’t leave me, please.
- Sometimes she's so mean.
- Don't worry.
Easy.
Watch out.
Jiřinka, We have come.
I brought a pal with me.
Don’t be angry with me, please.
If I had known…
We need to take a rest in the
living room, come on.
With this cat in the same bed…
- Where are you going?
- Let go!
- You're going nowhere.
- Let me be!
Nowhere, I say!
You have to explain this.
I’m not gonna explain a thing.
- What do you mean, not a thing?
- As simple as that.
- Now, what do you think?
- I won’t talk about this.
- Huh, you won’t talk about this…
- I won’t.
Gimme the keys!
How dare you?
It’s the keys to my motorbike.
- You have no right.
Let it go. - The keys…
This means, either her or me.
Do as you please,
you hysteric.
So you call me hysteric?
You… call me… hysteric?!!
This means…
I go… OK.
- I'll take this.
- Just take it.
- I'll take this too.
- Oh, not me!
Not me!
Stop trotting around, dammit.
No one needs the scene you’re making.
- No one needs the scenes I’m making!
- That’s right.
You should calm down finally.
It’s not funny anymore.
- Here, you got it.
- You bitch.
Man, I can’t believe it.
Go to her, please.
Jiřina, wait!
Take it easy!
- Don’t touch me!
- Why are you like this to me?
- I’m not guilty of that.
- Not guilty?
- See, you could hurt yourself.
- You're all guilty, I hate you.
You saw that, he hit me.
And in front of that bimbo.
I’ll kill him.
I’ll do something to myself…!
Do something, a good idea.
Coffee for instance.
Coffee is ready.
Jesus, Hanka.
Jesus, what’s the time?
Jesus, Jiřina…
Jesus, Hanka…
Jesus, wait! Jesus Christ!
Jesus Christ, just don’t go apeshit.
- Hanka, please, don’t be angry.
- I’m not angry at all.
I’ll explain everything.
Don’t explain anything,
please, Mr. Doctor.
Don’t call me Mr. Doctor, geez.
Calm down, please.
Let me be, please.
Got work to do.
Easy, you’ll make everything fall here.
I guess, you’re a bit better
at playing chess.
What do you want?
- I’d like to have more games with you.
- Oh, please!
I mean chess.
Oh, chess.
So you want to play sports.
Play sports then.
But you’re not gonna play with me,
you fatso!
Viruses whirl in the swirl of life.
They whirl in the swirl of blood.
We, the outcasts of outcasts,
believe in death.
Oh no!
I, a strong lymphocyte,
led by the radar of the heart,
came from the empire of
stop-angina and aspirin
to exterminate that insect
with chromium wings,
to put an end to bacillus.
If bacillus are there, they won’t be.
But we, viruses, changed by swirling
into hybrids carved into the heart.
So a gun will help.
I bring victory, firing
with both hands.
- He really wrote it himself?
- So what?
I had no idea he was so…
…what?
You don’t mean potent, do you?
- How was it?
- Good, wasn’t it?
Now dear friends, let me invite you
to a lavish dinner.
Well, great.
If not for bacillus, we couldn’t
even scoff properly.
- Petra, I feel sick. - Come on.
- Don’t resist, come on.
- Fernet is healing, whatever
you're feeling. - Shut up and go.
- Hurry up.
- Wait up!
What will our pretty guy have?
Fernet with vodka, a big one.
Get it ready.
Alps down, now knock!
Bring it to the table.
- Fernet.
- No, I won’t drink.
Why? He can’t drink.
He’s not well.
It’d make him sick, huh?
- I don’t feel like it!
- Ouch.
- Cheers then.
- Cheers.
I’m not sure.
- Cheers. - Cheers.
- Here you are.
What is it "Chateaubriand"?
Do you know, František?
Chateaubriand.
That’s the stuff which,
put among your dresses,
when you then wear the dresses,
will also make you smell
like Chateaubriand.
Right, for anorexia
a diet is the best.
I mean vice versa,
for a diet is anorexia the best.
Mr. waiter
I’ll have storks with poppyseed.
- I beg your pardon…
- I mean the pepper stake, OK?
Thank you, how kind of you.
Aren’t they funny chaps?
I do envy your theater.
If you like,
you could try it too.
I think, you would be a boon.
You really think that I could?
You want a theater, huh?
Then watch this play.
What a nice flame.
Petruška,
here’s to our friendship.
Let’s have a little play.
Why not?
Has he gone mad?
- Let’s flame.
- Stop it!
I’m not a piece of meat!
Is the skinny guy perhaps drunk?
Let’s all do a play.
What do you think?
We'll all set the world on fire!
The first actors enter,
so come on,
If you feel like a play,
it’s gonna be cool!
Juvenile first! Right?
Now what?!
Beware, a fire! But he who wants to
set one must burn himself.
Don’t we like one another!
I don’t want to see alcohol any more,
a shame to society.
- What’s up? - I came to meet my
buddy you caught last night.
You think you can come whenever
you like to?
- What’s his name? - Josef Málek.
- Málek. Wait a minute.
- Thank you.
- Pick up the cap!
- Hit me and you’ll have to pick me up!
- In the name of law, pick it up!
- No point, let it be.
- All right.
As I see again and again,
alcohol is frigging mean.
Calm him down.
That Málek’s been brought away.
To the infection department,
so don’t bother here and go home.
If you don’t want to be dragged down,
don't drink another one.
But it’s getting better,
isn’t it?
Your liver is still enlarged,
but it seems to have stabilized.
You need to help it.
How can I?
You need a bigger will for health.
Parties aren’t good.
- I was ill with it too.
- Glad to hear it.
What do you mean?
You seem to have recovered.
It’s our early days in theater.
About 13 years old then.
And Pepe, when did he go in with you?
When we began to study, I guess.
- It’s Pepe. - There’s a poem
František composed to this.
Two jerks walk through the morning dew
and desire lays about them.
Why did you study veterinary
when you like theater?
- Well I was fond of animals.
Look… - You made this?
- No, my dad brought it to me.
And here’s a tiny one. - A tiger!
- Or rather cow…
- Why, it’s a bull.
You’re a bull.
This is an ox.
Then what is this?
Tell me.
Say again…
Why did you study veterinary?
Well, you know…
I said it before.
I was fond of animals, My dad
always brought me to the country.
But then, when you see it right
in front of you… in praxis, see?
It’s terrible.
And you have to act
like it’s all normal.
Playing theater you pretend too
but it’s fun at least, see?
Look, the TV for instance.
It amuses the whole nation.
Only, we mustn’t let people fight
one another.
You know, to read the report isn’t the
same as to see it with one’s own eyes.
What about my folks?
Do you get on well with them now?
There were some arguments…
But it’s all right now.
At the start it was hard for
both the factory and us.
Rather not talk about it.
But you helped us a lot.
Now we only need to
produce those 161 bottles.
I, a lymphocyte…
…strong…
Again, do it form the start.
I, a strong lymphocyte, came…
…led by the radar of the heart. Again!
The heart.
You know what it is, don’t you?
- I, a strong lymphocyte, come form…
- What kind of coming is this?
How does a lymphocyte walk?
- Dunno.
- With a sword!
But I don’t have one.
- Imagine that. Act like you do.
- With sword…
- A strong lymphocyte…
- From the start? - No, go on.
I, a strong lymphocyte, come
form the empire… lead by…
- Lead by the radar of heart.
- By the radar. - From the start.
I, a strong lymphocyte,
come from the empire of lymphocytes…
Now, what lymphocytes?
Of Stop-Angina, isn’t it?
- Stop-Angina. - Yep.
- What’s that? Don’t get it.
What do you mean?
Take off the helmet and come here.
Imagine this is a bed
and now you must lay into the
role, see?
You must live the role.
Theater, it’s a hard job.
You have to keep pushing.
- Now what? Do you want to act?
- I do.
You have to lay further back,
we can’t rehearse like this.
Imagine summer, a beach…
It's hot there, you have to take off…
Losing your mind?!
No, losing my weight.
Pepe’s prowling the place,
Pursuing Petra.
Petra, please go…
There’s nobody here…
- Hi.
- Hello, notary.
- What’s this party?
- An engagement.
- Jana’s going to marry the director.
- Where’s Petra?
At work. Where else?
Are you jealous?
You're having a party too, boys?
What’s wrong with you?
Don’t get mean because of me.
What’s up?
First, I wanted to assign you
as the father…
But I didn’t because it occurred to me…
Hey, where are you going?
- Where’s he going? - So you
even had something with Pepe?
Oh, only once at that dance.
- What dance?
- The one all three of you were at.
Huh, so even with Dědek.
What’s the big deal?
Everyone should have fun
before they grow old.
Well, what do you think, boys?
Congratulations.
It came all of a sudden.
By the way congratulations to him
as well, he’s a candidate.
Me?
Oh, your memory…
It’s getting worse.
Sometimes it’s better that way.
Isn’t it, Janinka?
And you must drop by someday.
We are like a family now.
Geez, I shrunk.
Do you know how
a fission chain reaction occurs?
Theoretically like this:
Imagine: When this neutron meets
the nucleus of uranium 235,
Something incredible happens.
Watch.
The nucleus, placid until now, vibrates
And immediately divides itself
into two parts of the same weight…
And two or three free neutrons.
Why did I come to you anyway?
Can you explain?
I am what I am.
We have just witnessed a
nuclear reaction.
- The free neutrons made by the fissure
- But why are you doing this?
Why are you ruining yourself?
You’ve been ill, you have
to take care now.
And why?
Will you tell me one reason
I should take care?
Me for instance.
- Come on, you weren’t even awaiting me.
- …amount of electricity
goes adrift… - What do you mean?
I’ve been waiting here the whole night,
I also need to do something.
Something that I like.
…first atomic bomb was
dropped on Hiroshima.
I guess, you like too many things!
I didn’t know you don't like anything
Could one do anything but
go mad in this jungle?
…enabled by this reaction.
I didn’t see you trying to
resist anything.
Resist what for god’s sake?
And with who?
It’s only riffraff all around.
It’s a hard one then.
- Petra… Petruška, please.
…to make the wheels of a steam turbine
spin we need coal.
- You are the only one left.
- Lemme go, please.
- …fission chain reaction.
- Better undress and wash off.
God knows what you’ve
been walking through.
- Are you offended?
- No.
I’m kinda sick.
I gotta go.
Go then.
Go to work like a good girl.
And bring some beer!
Sick. I feel so sick.
What have you stuffed into me?
Are you Josef Málek?
I'm here to inspect you. Show me
your sick note, please.
- Are you not in bed?
- Doesn’t it do that I’m home?!
I hope you go for walks
as doctor recommended?
Wait, look up.
Not like this!
Jesus, Your whites are so yellow,
you need a hospital immediately.
- Where’s your phone?
- I don’t have one.
Here. I’m going to order an ambulance.
But I just came from the hospital.
Damn.
I’m very  honored to have been elected…
As a chairman of the SSM
for our enterprise.
Especially now, when such huge tasks
are imposed on us.
I believe, in the period to come,
we will manage to improve…
the whole course of our organization…
and to strengthen its membership base.
Of course I realize the burden
I will bear…
in our time of scientific revolution…
but it can't be helped, dear friends.
We must work harder,
Harder, harder.
We all must unify!
So what, are we playing on?
- Mate.
Such a fool's mate, you greyhound!
How about another game?
Old maid?
Really!
Well, that means
three losses for you.
That's three ones.
- Mommy, please.
- How do you do.
Why are you bringing this?
Am I not on a diet?
But don’t you have a visitor?
There’s a letter for you.
Here, young lady.
She’s so thin and you offer
nothing to her.
There’s no place to put it down.
Oh, thanks.
- Some coffee?
- No, mum.
- Bring nothing, please.
- I’d like to…
- You’re kind. Thanks.
- Did I say—-
- Beware, young lady. He’s a
bit of a scoundrel. - Thanks.
What is it?
Smells like hospital.
Must be from Pepe.
Is it that bad Mr. doctor?
We think it’s jaundice.
- How come they didn’t know sooner?
- We’re not sure even now,
but we are waiting for the test results.
- I’ll be stuck here for ages, huh?
- Well, for some time.
His tongue hangs out,
he can hardly breath.
Even the dark ground had mercy.
It moans: he’s thirsty, he rambles.
Imbue him fast.
Or he dies and so do you.
The hidden breast of mine
springs now towards the thirsty.
Now, I have an inspiration.
I feel like a drink.
My chest is burning,
The churches are falling into ruins
above me. I feel like a drink.
A good one, I will use it.
A hole in the brain like…
like what?
Like the whole of…
Africa!
Silly!… Well, actually…
Not so silly.
- Hello? - František?
- Yes, speaking. What’s up?
Are you free?
- No, just working on a anti-alcohol
motto. - Of course.
A Career. Some of us must do it.
Hallo.
What brings you here?
I came.
All those celebrations around
and you’re alone here.
So I dropped by.
Hope you can eat this.
Well, how are you?
You’re the last one I’d expected.
Aren't you glad?
Oh, I am…
Let’s spank our mean Pepíček!
Please, I don’t feel like this.
I’m sick.
And there’s also something for
Pepíček…
from Jiřinka.
This beats for you only.
I heard that before.
You don’t believe me?
Look. What it says is true.
No one cares about you any more, huh?
Calm down now.
A changing station!
- What are you doing?
- Puff, it’s just a faker.
You’ll kill him!
The one who won’t obey and doesn't
take the prescribed cures properly,
I will operate… Nurse!
- What do you wish, master?
- My instruments!
Here.
Oh, udders!
These fallen angels are always
restraining.
Where’s the archangel with
the operating wagon?
Our comrade St. Nicholas…
He also collapsed from the drive
of our time.
Damn, it’s falling.
What do my bright eyes see?
Our patient’s eyes are bloodshot.
Close your eyes or you’ll bleed.
Wait, you demoniac furies.
March to the chimney!
Angel, a drip-feed, please.
I, as your doctor, prescribe you…
this marvelous medicine.
Stop it, he can’t drink this.
Give it to me.
If he doesn’t volunteer to
go to heaven,
he’ll be forced to.
- Well, well…
- No, no!
Oh no!
Oh, he’s heartless, has no heart.
Now give him the kiss of life.
Call Dr. St Bernard from Cape Town…
to do the heart implantation.
And what is it down here?
Oh my, look at this.
Oh, udders!
Do the catheterisation immediately!
- Don't worry!
- Quiet!
Let’s sign suspicious areas.
Lungs, appendix.
Appendix. Triodenum.
Leave the hairs alone!
What kind of angel are you?
And nutrition!
Nutrition!
Don’t kick!
Take your nutrition. Come on,
give him mash.
Silence!
Hey, this isn’t what I agreed to.
He’s seriously ill!
Somebody may come to scold us.
Oh yep, he’s seriously ill.
Then we must drink to our frail health.
Of course, champagne!
Oh, we forgot this.
AIDS diagnoses!
Cheers!
Chairs.
Nurse, take blood from us all!
Jesus, really, I’m not sure…
He who signs on with the
devil will know.
Strangle the hands of us all, angel,
like this.
And examine, learn, examine, learn.
So, have a good time.
She’s locked us in.
And she has my keys.
What will we do?
We’ll have to sleep
together here then.
Oh, really!
Sorry, we can watch
VCR for instance.
- Or we can go run-skiing.
- Oh my, what an idea!
- He doesn’t trust you?
- Why shouldn’t he?
He’s capable of anything.
I can’t imagine what I would do
in his shoes.
For I have never met anybody before
who cares about my feelings.
- But I’m boring you anyway.
- You’re not, go on.
But whatever, everyone is always alone…
no matter if he’s round, square…
- or furnished with hooks like me.
- Don’t talk like this.
After all, I think…
the most lonely is the beauty,
because it’s so unique,
so striking,
so fantastic,
that simply no one dares…
- How are you, Mr. Málek?
- Not great. - Give it to me, nurse.
Turn it off, please.
ALT decreased a little,
bilirubin is almost in the normal
Let’s have a look at it.
Wow, this is great!
This is so great!
This is really great!
- Now, I cut off my zipper.
- Oh, you have stripped pants!
- Funny indeed.
- Do an elephant.
Huh, elephant…
- And lion, catch me…
- Just laugh at me, you-
Wait till I catch you,
You’ve never seen an elephant
like the one I’ll do!
A donkey!
You have also stripped pants.
- Milánek… - Watch out, mother.
- Do you need something?
No, I’m all right.
- Milánek…
- Watch out…
- Lemme go. - You are…
- Stop it.
Do a lion.
- What?
- Don’t be so noisy.
Couldn’t we even watch TV?
I would chuck this all up
and move out!
Where?
Dunno, doesn’t matter.
Anywhere out.
- Try to stand on my own feet.
- Not so simple, see.
Why not place an advertisement?
A livestock specialist and a vet
searching for a job with flat.
Nothing for me.
…will increase your charm.
Kohn was the first to vomit,
Ábeles second…
Your rickshaw, Mr. Duke!
It looks kinda different here.
Who cleaned it up?
You, Petra?
Why are you standing, sit down?
You’ve had a hard time,
now it’s gonna be all right.
- Won’t you take it off?
- I won’t.
You shouldn’t smoke.
Well the home is the home.
Feuer?
Even I think it won’t be so bad.
I dropped the diet.
The main thing is a good mood!
I nearly forgot,
I’ve brought cakes for you.
Oh, really.
Why not feel well…
When God gives us health?
I can’t eat this.
How about taking him along
to cinema tonight?
Fanda will surely be able
to get one more ticket.
What Fanda?
She must mean me.
I'll get the ticket,
no problem.
I must go to bed early.
Cinema is out of question.
Anyway, can’t he watch the VCR?
To hell with the VCR.
Or you know what?
There’s another way to…
cheer him up!
- Is Pepe here?
- Jiřinka comes to greet you.
Move over.
Well gentlemen,
I was in the hospital…
And the nurse, who had sampled
our blood,
told me,
that one of the tests is positive.
- In what way?
- AIDS positive.
But whose one?
They’re not sure,
two test-tubes were broken.
Wasn’t it signed?
If one’s positive,
it must be mine.
Clear as a day.
I have all the symptoms.
But if you have it,
She must have it as well!
You fuckin’ bastard!
I’ll kill you, I’ll kill you!
You went to each boozer,
screwed each whore!
I’ll kill you!
All of you!
If I have it,
You all will!
- Lemme be!
- Stop it, he didn’t hurt you!
- Let him be!
- Lemme be!
He didn’t hurt you!
Don’t be ridiculous, you loser.
You surely have it too!
You’re all the same!
- You as well, All the same!
- Stop it, Jiřina!
Fanda, wait!
You’re bleeding.
Franta, where are you going,
Take it easy.
Never come to see me again.
Never!
- But wait! - Let me be.
Didn’t Jiřina make herself clear?
František.
- Don’t you understand? - What?
- It’s a matter of life now!
- But you’re bleeding.
- Don’t touch me! - Wait.
The disease Pepe has is contagious.
You recoil from me?
It’s incurable… and mortal!
You think I have it too?
Or what?
It isn’t possible, is it?
Am I not perfectly healthy?
I feel fine.
I’m sure I’m not ill,
see?
You don’t need to worry.
Let me be!
- It’s that you don’t love me,
right? - Don’t touch me.
Did something change?
Everything’s changed, see?
Everything’s different!
- Nothing is valid anymore.
- I hate you.
Well, I think I'll go.
Bye.
You won’t need this, will you?
So I'll drop by, someday?
- Sure you don’t want this?
- Just take it. - Thanks, bye.
Jiřina, Wait… Please!
- What?
- Give me a minute, please.
Easy. Anyway, you don’t
have to worry at all.
How comforting
when it’s you who says so.
See… Pepe never wanted to
be a father.
- So what?
- He mustn’t have relied only on you.
- Speak even louder, goddamn it.
- He surely always used contraceptives.
- Don’t be pathetic, you asshole.
- Wait, I have to ask you something.
I mean it! Stop please.
You know, the last time we saw
each other…
Could you tell me what happened?
I can’t remember a thing.
I’m not gonna console you,
you coward.
Blood… the bitch!
Bitch…
Oh, I had no idea,
you can sprinkle in such a lovely
way, Mr. Málek.
Buzz off, you old hag!
I don’t care a bit about you,
you sleazy earthworm!
- Is Hanka here?
- No.
She isn’t!
- How come?
- She had a visit, will be right back.
- Was it friend or a relative?
- I don’t know.
A kind of hotshot, see? There’s always
one around a young beauty.
Please…
Man, You’ll kill yourself at work.
It’s not your business.
You have no right to do this!
- We can make a deal. - I’m done with
you. - Don’t be hysteric.
- Let go. - Look, this is
serious business, See?
- You promised to let me be.
- He’s a huge moneybag, see!
- What’s wrong?
- I don’t want to anymore!
- It’s the last time, see?
- No!
You don’t want us to tell
the sucker of yours, do you?
Let him be!
I hate you!
Let him go!
I’ll find you, bitch!
- There’s blood on you.
- Where? Wait, damn.
- Here, I'll clean it.
- No, don’t touch me!
- Why?
- It’s dangerous.
- It’s been found out some of us
have it. - What?
- AIDS?
- Maybe me.
Or me, huh?
What will we do?
Jesus, what will we do now?
What will we do? Jesus Christ!
What will we do?!
We have to do something, Milan!
Come on, it’s all useless.
Nothing matters anymore.
What do you mean, useless?
You don’t believe me.
I knew you wouldn’t.
I worried so much.
So much…
That you would leave me.
And what’s the worst,
I still love you.
Please. Let’s leave! Outta here!
You can’t escape this.
Where could you escape this?
Where?
What do you wanna do? Where?
It’s all useless anyway!
Nothing matters at all!
Nothing matters!
I’ll give it all up!
But I don’t want to!
- Everything’s useless!
- I can’t stand this uncertainty!
Next one, please.
It’s you?
Yeah, it’s me.
- You're leaving?
- Going home.
- Wouldn’t it be better to find out?
- What for?
You would be certain.
Certain that I have it?
I’m not interested.
It’d be fair for others at least.
Look who’s talking!
Jiřina, is it you? Jiřina!
- Hi, how are you?
- Well, and you?
- Well also, you coward.
It’s good. - It’s good, good!
- It’s negative!
- It’s good!
- Negative!
Banzai!
It’s negative!
- What are you eating?
- Rice mash. Want some?
No way.
I have to lose some weight, bro.
I thought you stopped the diet.
Well yeah but I came to you
to say good bye.
- I’m going with Hanka to Šumava.
Did I tell you? - That’s great.
We’re gonna get married. Really.
Hanka is a great girl.
She set up everything.
Even the terms.
I hope you’ll come.
Man, you look better now, know it?
Really!
- What’s wrong?
- Nothing.
And I guess you’ve gained weight.
What do doctors say?
Still the same.
“Diet”, “take care of yourself” etc.
I hate always going there.
No wonder, but…
You need a change, anything.
Why not come to see František and
have a good-bye party?
Come, we’ll have some fun again.
Stop it, come on.
- It’s just so interesting now.
- I can see it.
Even art reached the
cul-de-sac?
You’re terrible.
You’re all terrible.
Everything is terrible.
Or a love drama perhaps?
I wouldn’t laugh if I were you, man.
- You’re involved too.
- Me? In what?
The director canceled the engagement,
Jana’s pregnant.
- So it’s yours.
- Or yours.
- If Janička told the truth.
Here it is…
Me…
and a child?
My child?
You think,
that I could have a child?
We don’t know who’s the father yet.
What’s worse, the director requested
Jana’s test and…
found out Jana’s AIDS positive.
The child as well undoubtedly,
so we’re all involved!
But not me, no way!
Hanička get herself tested and
Jiřina is also po… I mean negative.
Me, no way.
They’d have it both then!
We’re gonna get married!
We're going to the country!
We're going away!
Settle this stuff with one another,
gentlemen!
I don't give a damn.
Have a nice day, ciao!
So it’s your fault, you bastard.
Get the fuck outta here!
Damn, we’re all involved.
Even me. Me!
But why the hell me?!
Come on, now what?
But it’s nothing.
No one’s ever died because of
a tiny drop of blood.
- It hurts!
- Be quiet!