Well, Steve?
What happened?
A car accident...
I can't bend it.
I don't bend it anymore.
How did it go for you?
-I'd say it went well...
They left us in peace.
We did everything as planned.
Boris as well, though...
He chose a really nice house.
But the idea to reunite here,
at the end of the carnival...
Worked out well.
It will be easier to leave
without being noticed.
It really is beautiful.
But Boris...
Where is he?
What a way to receive guests.
Why are you here, beautiful lady?
Good evening, gentlemen.
Great, here's another one.
(?) of women.
And Boris?
-He's dead.
He's dead?
-Yes.
A viral infection.
I'm representing him, I'm his wife.
Sorry, I'm Boris' widow.
-And the valuables?
Entrusted to me.
Klaus, from Hamburg...
Albert.
-From Marseille.
Boris told me about you.
Steve, from London.
Carina, from Tangiers.
-I came, Omar is in hiding.
We know, he told us.
Thomas, Dutch.
Juan...
I'm not Dutch,
I'm Spanish.
My credentials,
and the key...
We played poker.
Me, and our friend Thomas...
He lost and I won.
But how exactly did you win?
It's not important.
-Good, we're all here.
And who is she?
-Jeanine...
My fiancée.
But who gave you permission
to bring her?
Permission?
I have more right to be here than you.
And she's with me...
If you don't like it (?) for you.
-That wasn't the deal.
We had to come here alone.
-I don't have to answer to you.
No, you have to answer to
all of us in the group.
You make me die of laughter.
Your group?
You're dealers...
The ones they send to
carry out the jobs...
I did all the work.
You weren't there that night...
And you're here for the poker.
But I was there...
And if they caught me I couldn't
even give them your names.
You may well be big diamond dealers...
But you can't say anything to me,
only Boris can.
But it seems like he's dead.
She says so.
Or the boss.
But he's out of the game now,
and he's been paid.
You've took part in this robbery because
you're an expert in strong rooms...
Like the one in the Amsterdam bank.
If this was about contraband,
drugs or money...
We'd have left you to your nightclubs,
to your women.
Okay, I'm useful to you because I
knew the bank of Amsterdam...
In that case...
Take me as I am.
Yes, yes...
Nice discussion.
But what do we do with her?
That's right, what do we do?
Omar says we must hurry...
He says luck is like the wind,
it changes.
Send her away.
-Alright, we must eliminate her.
Albert, Albert!
Or we can trust her.
-Trust her?
It's very dangerous.
I don't like these jokes.
I couldn't care less about your tastes,
stop acting like a fool.
You seem like a band of
fools to me...
Leave Janine alone and let's think
about where we can find Boris.
Boris is dead.
-Dead? What if you killed him instead?
It's all very simple, my dear Albert...
Outside in the park,
there's a lovely tomb...
You'll find Boris in there.
Outside in the park?
(?) in a park.
Right, but what were you expecting?
A beautiful funeral ceremony...
With a notice in the paper,
and a band?
Don't talk rubbish, the important
thing is I've got his key...
So we can go to the safe.
Lead?
-Yes.
Yes...
Lead.
-It was the boss' idea...
He knew how to do it.
-Nice.
How long has it been since
the Amsterdam job?
Eleven months.
And in all this time no one
thought about Boris...
To get him to blow it open?
-Yes, bravo...
Do you think the boss is an imbecile?
He couldn't put his hands on the
diamonds for fifty years.
Radioactivity...
There's a cavity lined with uranium.
Only our six keys can open it.
Here's Boris' key.
Gentlemen, yours.
I warned you not to try
anything funny.
But I've got it.
I've got it.
Let go of me.
What were you thinking, Albert?
We don't have time for your riddles.
I tell you I had it.
-What are your intentions?
Now you're exaggerating.
You're taking a big risk.
Let go of me.
I'll find it.
Even if it's under your skin.
-Stop, cut it out.
You're an asshole.
And Jeanine?
I haven't hidden it.
I swear.
You'd better pray to God I find it,
because I give you my word...
I'll kill you.
Damned French.
No.
Let go of me.
Albert.
Jeanine!
You're hurting me.
I don't know anything.
Let go of me,
I haven't got the key.
We'll see.
-I swear I haven't got it.
Don't touch me.
What has she got to do with it?
I had the key...
Jeanine can't have taken it.
Leave her alone.
You're pigs.
But you'll pay for this.
Everyone's against me.
Let go of me.
Do you see that I don't have it?
He had it.
Albert had it.
You also knew it was in my
cigarette case...
So where is it?
I don't know.
I...
...don't know.
-Enough.
Gentlemen, your rooms are upstairs...
Call me if there are any developments.
Child...
I won't allow you to make a fool of us.
What do you want in return
for the key?
What do you want?
If you plan on having fun,
look.
No, Steve.
Give them to me.
You can't Klaus...
I'm begging you.
No, Klaus.
You can't do this.
I'm begging you.
I'll go crazy.
Please, Klaus.
This is the price of your key.
Well done, Steve.
I'm sick.
Cover yourself.
You know who took it, right?
How did it happen?
Who took it from me?
It wasn't you.
I know.
Did they hurt you?
Help.
Help me!
Who took it?
Tell Klaus to give it to me.
I need it...
I can't stand it.
Give it to me.
-Out with the key.
I can't find it anymore.
I had it in my cigarette case...
We'll have a good look for it tomorrow,
outside in the park...
When I got out of the car,
perhaps...
I had it.
I had it!
Steve, make him give it to me.
Have you hidden it?
-No...
Why did I come all the
way here then?
Make him give it to me,
I'm begging you.
You know me, Steve.
You're my friend...
You know I'm not a thief,
we worked together...
You remember don't you?
Steve!
You weren't a drug addict then.
-Klaus.
Stop.
We're wasting time here.
I've already taken precise measures...
And you, Steve?
My part has already been
sold in London.
And you?
Juan.
Do you have any suggestions?
The safe must be opened.
Good, and how?
With a magic wand?
All we need to do is create a
mould to create a new key.
Klaus, why didn't I think of it before?
And you believe that if it was
possible to make...
...a mould...
We would've trusted Boris
to look after the safe?
I'm not interested in what
Boris could've done...
I've made moulds before,
I'll open the safe for you.
Give it to me.
Very well, I believe you.
Here it is.
The light is hurting me.
Stop it, Juan.
Stand up.
My child...
You have something to tell us, right?
What do you want to tell us?
Come on.
Still nothing?
You're still stuck on this idea
of making a mould.
Steve.
You have to give it to me.
Klaus.
Klaus, where are you?
I'll make the key for you.
We'll get the diamonds.
I'm begging you.
Klaus!
Happy carnival, grandpa.
Who is it?
-Callagan.
What if Albert didn't kill himself?
Then it means there's a murderer
amongst us, right?
Do you ever use your brain?
I'm starting to feel tired,
this should've been over in a few hours.
But here we are...
We're all stuck in this
damned mess...
With a key in my hand and a dead
body on my conscience...
It really doesn't leave me
feeling enthusiastic.
Nervous?
Perhaps you went too far with Albert?
His suicide might complicate
matters for the worst.
If it was suicide...
Why didn't he pull out the key?
-I'm certain he didn't have it anymore.
We'll never know the truth.
Do you have any ideas?
-No, and you?
We risk being stuck in here
for a long time.
If you really want to know,
I'm starting to miss Boris...
Maybe we'll never open that safe.
Albert's gone.
If we manage to open that little box...
We'll have to divide into five parts.
But no mistakes, you're the expert
and you have to be impartial...
Understood?
I'm falling to pieces.
I can't stand this any more.
I'm leaving.
-And what will Omar say?
Do you want to decide for him?
-Then let's do something...
There must be a solution,
what are we waiting for?
The sixth key.
I get the impression it's here.
You don't have two by any chance?
Stupid.
I must get in contact with Omar,
he'll to me what the hell I should do.
I'd like to make a call.
-There aren't any telephones here.
No?
And in the village?
I think so.
-I need someone to accompany me.
No!
-Carina.
Are we prisoners?
I asked for a telephone
and there isn't one.
There isn't one because
we don't need it.
I asked to be taken to a public
telephone and she said no.
We're inside a china cabinet, yes...
And anything can send
this all to pieces...
Let's try not to make any
brisk movements.
Who did you want to talk to?
-That's my business.
I'm free to talk to whoever
I want to, no?
Good day.
Biscuits, brioche...
Chocolates and cream.
Then I wasn't mistaken...
You're also greedy.
A man's shirt?
It was his.
Where will they put him?
He's downstairs in the garage,
he doesn't have anymore worries...
He doesn't shout anymore.
He was luckier than us.
How could he?
He was so scared of dying.
Would it be indiscrete to ask you
if you've made any alliances?
Who with?
With Anna.
And if I were?
You seem to be very close to Steve.
We were discussing the situation.
-Yes, yes...
A lot of discussion,
but no one has any good ideas.
Who owns this villa?
Boris bought it.
It's that tomb that doesn't
say much to me.
Boris wasn't my husband.
But it's as though he was.
What was he like?
He was somone who liked me.
I'm starting to have my suspicions.
Do you think you know who
has Albert's key?
Not yet.
I'm thinking about Boris.
He wasn't your husband...
You could have killed him...
He might not be dead.
It is possible I could
have killed him...
You can even think it.
But if you think he isn't dead...
Open it.
Now I disgust you, right?
It's always like that after.
You all have the same reaction.
Just say it...
I won't feel offended.
You won't be the first to tell me.
But you women always get it wrong...
You should be disgusted with
drug addicts, the weak...
Like Albert.
Albert, what a guy...
I don't know what your
friend was thinking...
But if I manage to find (?)
What have the others done?
-They haven't done anything...
That's the problem.
They don't think, they don't move...
They wait.
They spy on each other.
I'd like to provoke them.
What if the others killed you?
-With what advantage?
It's Albert's key that's missing.
Tell me something...
Did you see anyone follow
Albert into his room?
Did you hear anything?
-No...
All I heard was his scream.
Do you think someone killed him?
If that's the case then
we're all in danger...
I want to leave.
Hello?
I killed Albert.
You can come.
I'm thinking of leaving tonight.
Over and out...
You can talk.
Boris, Steve, can you hear me?
Omar.
Listen to me.
Listen to me!
I'm the boss.
I have some good news for you...
It's pointless looking
for Albert's key...
I have it.
Albert, you're very distracted...
You left without it.
You didn't pay me properly...
And you treated me even worse...
No one has ever treated
me so stupidly.
I prepared all of the most
sensational robberies...
The pounds from Glasgow,
the Third Reich's treasure.
Omar, Steve, Boris...
Listen up...
I want half of the diamonds.
This is the price of Albert's key.
Jeanine!
-I'll return tomorrow morning...
It's your radio!
It's yours, isn't it?
-No, it was Albert's.
Talk!
You know something.
I don't know anything.
-I'll kill you.
(Second Arf')
It's a miracle you're still alive...
But don't count on my help if you
keep looking for trouble.
Give it here.
Don't you know everyone's
looking at you?
What are you doing here?
His cigarette case.
He loved it so much.
I'll leave tomorrow and
this will all be over...
Forever.
-Worried?
No, just a strong desire to leave.
I'm not one of your kind.
I don't have any right to anything.
I'm leaving.
(?)
Your happiness doesn't ring true.
Do you like my clothes?
Anna lent them to me.
Don't I look like her?
(?) extraordinary
There must be another fountain,
where you can't hear the water.
Yes, come on.
Steve.
Water, water.
This place is very beautiful,
don't you think?
A place to fall in love.
But it's also a tomb, of course.
Who knows if anyone has ever (?) in here?
A dead fish.
Your stick is dangerous.
People like us must always think
defending ourselves.
Scared of fish?
I am sometimes, as well.
And this helps me to be
a little less afraid.
Where is the key?
I don't know.
Klaus would have killed you...
I was the one who stopped him.
But you're working with the boss.
Where is the key?
I'm sorry but I don't know.
I don't know.
Why don't you ask Albert?
If I find out the boss doesn't
have the key...
...and it suddenly appears,
we'll make a good couple.
A good couple?
But I like to run.
I don't know.
Jeanine.
Klaus.
-Come in.
What do you want?
-To make a decision...
We shouldn't take any more
risks than necessary...
We'll get caught.
I don't feel safe here.
Who is going to think of us?
They forgot about us for months.
The people outside are having fun,
and soon we will too...
You'll see.
-Yes, yes...
But in the meanwhile we're
risking a lot.
Time is passing and nothing
is happening.
What are you thinking?
We're all in a hurry.
If we accept the boss' proposal...
-No.
Why not?
Let's discuss it with the others.
Don't forget that the boss always
has some interesting business...
And we'll give him half of
the diamonds...
And he'll help us.
-No...
The diamonds are here,
and they belong to us.
With everything we've
spent to get them...
Would you settle for half?
I just want it over with.
The boss came here to tell
us he has the key...
Fine.
He'll come tomorrow morning...
And he'll give it to us without
taking any of it.
And then we'll leave.
-Are you sure?
The boss knows what he wants.
-Me too.
What are you going to do?
Do you have to back to Tangiers?
Why don't you come away with me?
Let's see what happens
tomorrow morning...
And then I'll decide.
Is there are decision in the air?
I was thinking about having
a chat about it.
I'm listening.
What do you want to do?
Do what?
-With the boss?
Tomorrow morning.
When he comes here.
Kill him.
Another dead body.
And what if the boss...
...is only bluffing?
Imbeciles...
Am I an imbecile as well?
The boss isn't one to risk his own life.
Imbeciles.
What do you think about Steve?
I don't like the way he does things,
I get the feeling he's hiding something.
I don't know how to say it.
Despite that stick, he seems a lot
more trite than he appears. (?)
Boris didn't like him either.
-Right, Boris...
I'm not convinced about
his death either.
Sensations, sensations.
Let's finish this...
Let's throw the boss a party,
we'll get that damned key...
And we'll keep his fifty percent.
Boris is dead...
As for Steve,
he's just a two bit crook.
We must act.
The time has come to do something.
I'll take care of everything
tomorrow morning.
I'll get you the key tomorrow morning,
you'll see.
Aren't you going to ask
me why I'm here?
I'm not the curious type.
And I'm always very discrete
with the ladies.
But here...
It's better to stay informed.
So...
Insomnia?
-No.
Nervous?
Then you're interested in my key?
-Not at all...
I'm looking for an ally.
An ally?
Against who?
Against Steve.
Against?
And why?
It's dangerous.
Jeanine is dead.
Steve killed her.
No, listen to me...
I figured out it was him and he knows.
He'll kill me as well.
It was him...
He found out Jeanine had hidden
the key in her hair clip...
And he killed her.
-Jeanine, the key...
How come you know all this?
I'm on guard, Juan.
I see everything.
I saw Steve leave his room and
go into Jeanine's room.
Then I spied on him.
It was horrible.
Poor thing.
Poor thing?
Why?
Deep down she was a fool.
As a woman and as the
boss' accomplice.
He had her and the key in his grip.
Now I understand why she begged
me to take her away from here.
Of course.
She had to deliver the key to the boss.
So Steve has found the sixth key...
And now you're scared.
Why didn't you tell Klaus?
Are you insane?
He'd kill us all.
Or Carina?
-She's hysterical.
I decided to trust you.
You're one of those who find
solutions reasoning.
Now, you and I know what happened...
The diamonds.
If you knew how many there are,
and what they look like....
It makes your head spin.
It makes you go crazy just
thinking about it.
Boris said there was a pair...
A pair...
With an inestimable value.
Inestimable value.
Do you want Steve to have it all?
Or Klaus?
You must go to the garage.
The controls for the safe are in there...
And wait for a while.
We'll all come...
Or Klaus will come.
Or me...
Or Steve will come.
With me.
Are you so sure?
And what if they kill you first?
No...
My key is hidden there.
They won't kill me.
Not until I've accompanied
them to the safe at least.
And you'll be waiting for us.
Juan, I trust you.
I knew about Steve.
He's diabolical.
If only you'd seen him.
I'd really like it if you
arrived with him.
Come on...
We won't argue to divide the diamonds.
We might also decide not to split them.
The diamonds will keep us together.
Remember, in situations like this...
The smart ones are the ones
who come out on top.
And we're the smart ones here.
It was easy.
You're infernal.
But how much will this game cost us?
A few people.
Well?
Come.
Juan has left us as well.
And we have his key...
Whose idea was it to electrocute
the handles?
Boris?
And Jeanine?
I'll go and have a look.
Jeanine.
She's asleep.
She's in a deep sleep...
She has her head under her pillow,
I think she's taken a sleeping pill.
I'm going up.
Let me know...
If anything happens.
Steve, Jeanine is dead.
I'm scared, I'm going.
There someone here who
wants to kill us.
And you have no idea who it could be?
You must give me your key immediately.
-Then it's you.
I want your key.
Let go of me.
-Give it to me.
The key.
-Have mercy, Steve!
Where are you, Steve?
Are you hiding?
Steve, where are you?
Answer me.
Where are you?
-I'm here.
In Boris' place.
I threw him in the bottom of the lake.
Come forward.
Or do you need your stick?
I don't need it anymore.
I'll kill you.
We have the same intentions, right?
Yes.
Where are you?
Come out.
You killed all of them, yes?
But where are you?
-I want the keys, Klaus...
I want all of the diamonds.
Then come and get them.
Of course, I never leave
things unfinished.
And now what will you do?
You've wasted your six good chances.
And you gave me the seventh.
Klaus.
You were working with
that dirty scumbag.
You damned whore.
I was an idiot.
An idiot!
Let go of me.
-You wanted to set me up.
But your little princess act won't
do you any good now...
Understood?
-It wasn't me, it was Steve...
He wanted to kill them.
-Who do you think you are?
Anna.
Have you calmed down?
Do we want to discuss it?
It was him I was waiting for, Steve.
Not you.
He's been terrorising me since
the day Boris died...
He killed him,
just like Juan, Jeanine, Carina...
All of them.
To keep the diamonds for himself.
I've got nothing against you, Klaus.
That's why I didn't shoot.
You don't fool me.
In that case I'll tell you that
you must deal with me...
Whether you like or not.
-I just told you that you don't fool me.
You must be crazy.
I'm not crazy.
The safe...
...is locked behind an electric fence.
And only I can disable it.
Have you already forgotten Juan's face?
But what are you frightened of?
I'm getting changed.
We're going to the safe.
-And the keys?
I have all of them now.
I took them from Steve.
I only need your one.
My one.
So?
Are we going to stick together?
Or shall we split it?
Let's go to the safe.
You want to talk about it after.
Okay.
Now, if you don't mind...
Get my car from the garage.
To end up like Juan?
Take it.
Don't you understand it was
him I was afraid of?
Not you.
I said let's go to the safe.
-And I told you to get the car.
We'll need to get away from
here as soon as possible...
You and me, Klaus.
Here's the key.
Come on.
Go.
I'll get ready then I'll join you.
We'll go to the safe together.
We've arrived at the last scene...
And only you and I remain
to act it out.
Go.
What is it?
-Hurry up.
I'm about to start the engine.
Okay.
I'm ready.
Anna, the door's closed.
Maybe it's a loose contact?
Maybe.
Can you open it from outside?
Come here.
Yes.
Klaus.
-Tell me.
Don't you hear anything?
-What should I be hearing?
Death.
I'll open that damned door.
Here they are.
And you?
-I'm leaving.
Go ahead.
-One moment...
Just one thing.
A request...
To see them.
To touch them...
I've heard so much about them.
Fakes.
Very good ones...
Very.
But fake.
I suspected as much.
There are two strong rooms in
the Amsterdam bank...
One of them has the real ones,
and the other one...
The fake ones.
Now I'll explain why the police
didn't look too hard...
They were fake.
Fake diamonds.
What a pity.
It happens.
Farewell.
Amateurs.
I'm the boss.
I'm on my way...
I always keep my promises.
Are you ready?
I'm through with talking...
Understood?
I want half of the diamonds.
Steve.
Albert.
Where are you?
Klaus.
Thomas.
Boris.
Albert.
Steve.
Klaus.
You've finished.
Can we go?
But these aren't mine,
they don't fit.
Of course.
These ones are real...
I broke yours.
Real?
Hello?
International insurance company?
This is 'operation insurance policy'
03140...
The diamonds have been recovered.
Did you encounter any difficulties?
-No danger...
All I had to do was say
they were fake.
Okay, we're on our way.
-Fine...
I'll stay with the diamonds
until you arrive...
Because there's a guy who is
demanding half of the loot.
But I think he'll stay up there.
You've done a great job.
Thank you.
Sorry...
Give me the diamonds,
I'll go and put them back...
You wait here for me.
Subtitled by the Eiffel Tower,
Paris, France...
September 2009
www.italianfilmtranslation.com