Jesse, dinner's ready.
Jesse, dinner's ready. Come on!
Jesse? Jesse?
Jesse, where are you?
Sweden, Finland,
Iceland, Germany,
England, Italy,
Spain, Portugal.
Okay, now I will list the last
ten U.S. presidents in order.
Donald Trump, Barack Obama,
George W. Bush,
Bill Clinton, George H. W. Bush,
Ronald Reagan,
Jimmy Carter, Gerald Ford,
Richard Nixon--
Richard Nixon was impeached.
No he wasn't, Mom!
He resigned.
Hold on, let me finish my list.
Richard Nixon,
Lyndon B. Johnson.
Jesse, so what are
you doing exactly?
I'm working on my 12
days of Christmas list.
Last year, Dad told me
that if I did everything
on the list, I could have
whatever I wanted for Christmas
and this year, all I
want for Christmas is
for Dad to come home.
Oh, Jesse,
we've talked about this.
You know that Daddy
isn't coming home.
I know this is hard for you,
and I know you may not
understand what happened,
but I need you to know
that Daddy's gone.
No, Mom, he's not gone.
He's just not here.
I know that if I do everything
on my list, he'll come back.
Here.
I wish it was right, Jesse.
I wish it was, but...
just come on.
I think dinner's getting cold.
It's always cold, Mom.
Dad's a better cook.
Ha-ha, funny.
You know what else is funny?
What?
You didn't notice
that I lost a tooth.
You did?
From karate?
No, Mom, I'm ten years old.
It just fell out.
You silly goof.
Come on.
Good.
I'm not a psychologist,
but I do know people's minds.
I need to in order to get
the results that I do.
What did you say?
That's not in the
holiday spirit.
I doubt you would succeed
with that kind of campaign.
Why? Because throwing ice
balls at kids eating
your competitor's
candy is not that nice.
Jesse, go easy on him.
I wasn't talking to you.
Look, I gotta go.
I'll come up with a winning
marketing plan, I promise you.
Just no ice balls.
I'm done.
Ah, Jesse, where's the teacher,
instructor...
You mean Sensei.
Yes, Sensei.
Where is he?
First of all, it's a she.
My Sensei is a woman.
I hadn't noticed.
I know.
Well, where is she?
I told her I need
to go it alone.
Go it alone?
Yeah, I have to earn
my black belt on my own
and I have to do it
by Christmas day.
Uh, what?
Jesse, a black belt
by Christmas day?
And teaching yourself?
Yep, read my list.
Christmas is only
five days from now.
People will think this is
greed and hatred, it's not.
It's just that things
need to be even.
They can ask why but,
they'll never understand.
The people that hear
about it on the news,
they won't understand.
Only those that come here
tonight will finally see
what it's like,
what it's like to be destroyed by someone you thought
was exactly like you.
Tonight, this town
learns what it's like
to be afraid.
Mom?
Mom!
-Mom, Mom, Mom!
-What is it, Jesse?
What's wrong?
I had a terrible nightmare.
There was this scary
man on a screen.
I didn't know what
he was talking about.
Then there was
a clown with a gun.
A clown?
Yes, and a woman.
Jesse, why did you dream
of that? Do you know?
It was a theater...
the theater where Dad
was when he disappeared.
But Jesse, you've never
been in that theater.
Felt so real.
I feel like I was there.
I know. Sometimes
bad dreams feel real.
But it was just a dream, okay?
You weren't there.
Please go back to sleep.
Can you stay here for a while?
Sure, okay, I will.
Oh, my God.
All right,
pass 'em down,
pass 'em down.
Y'all keep 'em upside down now.
Don't talk about it, all right?
Just pass 'em down.
Pass 'em down.
Everybody pass these
down, keep 'em upside down.
Don't talk.
I want everybody
to think Christmas
because I have something
for you little critters.
I can call you critters, right?
That ain't one of them
forbidden words or something?
Nah, critters is okay.
But how 'bout I
call you my elves?
Oh no, how 'bout my reindeer?
Yeah, you're all little reindeer
but without the horns
'cause I don't like horns.
They kinda remind
me of that devil guy,
and he ain't very
Christmassy, is he?
Okay, if you answer
my question correctly,
then you might get
an extra five points
on your paper as
a Christmas gift.
All right,
all you little reindeer,
y'all are out celebrating
with your boss.
You're in a bar.
You know,
celebrating with the boss,
that little chubby guy,
ya know?
Little red suit
with a beard, Santa?
Santa has had a whole lot
of beer to drink tonight.
In fact, he's just plum wasted.
All you little reindeer,
y'all are pretty
kicked to the curb too,
ya know what I'm saying?
Now, all of a sudden, you,
you are Rudolph
the red-nosed reindeer.
And that red bulb on your
nose, it just explodes
because you had
a tequila shot that just
didn't agree with you.
Now, that explosion is
so loud that it causes
some drunk guy to fall off
of his bar stool over here
and all of a sudden,
a big ol' brawl ensues,
and everybody's
just fightin' kinda like
in one of them movies, ya know,
where everybody's just fighting
for no apparent reason?
All these surfers
and these greasers
and don't ask me
why there's surfers
and greasers in this bar.
Okay, they just are along
with all you reindeer.
And all of a sudden ,
Santa just broke a chair
right over some greaser's head
because the greaser
was about to hit you,
Rudolph the red-nosed reindeer!
The greaser was about to hit
you with a whiskey bottle!
Everybody get it?
All right.
Raise your hand if you
think Santa is guilty
of aggravated assault.
All right, raise your
hand if you think Santa
has committed a simple assault.
Okay, now who thinks
Kris Kringle is
guilty of reckless endang--
The answer is
none of the above.
Do I know you, young man?
Santa Claus is
guilty of nothing.
He acted in defense of another.
He was protecting
his friend, Rudolph.
You're correct.
You are absolutely correct!
Are you Jesse?
So, your husband's a lawyer?
Look, it was really nice
that your kid interrupted
my classroom.
He's really smart, by the way.
-But Mrs. Uh...
-Abby.
I don't really
know why you're here.
It's kind of one of the
hazards of those online
appointment things.
You don't really know why people
make those appointments with ya.
If ya have a legal question,
why don't you just uh...
How did you know that
my husband is a lawyer?
Just a little deductive
reasoning based on
your son's answer to my
question in my class.
Look, I'm sure that you have
a whole lot of things to do.
It was really nice to meet you.
I'm sure there's got a
lot of Christmas shoppin'
still to go for that smart
little young man of yours.
But I think it's
time for you to go.
How did you know
my son's name?
Good guess.
I don't think so.
Now, you let Jesse come
and interrupt my class
but why didn't you have
him come in here with us?
When I was 16,
I went to a psychic fair
and got a reading.
You know what that is?
Yeah, I...
The psychic told me
that I would get married,
have one son, and that my
husband would go on a journey
that would be of a
major concern to me.
When I asked her for more,
she looked unhappy and then,
refused to tell
me anything else.
That psychic was you.
Look,
I don't know who you are 'cause
I don't remember you, OK?
But nobody around here
knows anything about my
psychic past stuff.
Now I don't even know
how you found me.
How did you find me, by the way?
Everyone in my profession
says I'm a very
resourceful woman.
And what profession is that?
Why don't you guess?
-Marketing.
-Yes.
Oh, dang!
You see?
No, no, I don't see.
I mean, I do see but
I don't wanna see, OK?
I used to help police.
They wanted me to help
them find missing people
and you know what I found?
I found a bunch of dead bodies.
It's all I could see and I
don't wanna see a bunch of
dead bodies, OK?
You have no idea what it's
like to see dead people
and ugh, it's just creepy and
it creeped me out so much!
I didn't wanna do it anymore.
So I paid my way through law
school by doing all those
stupid little psychic fairs
and you just happened to
find me out but I think it's
time for you to leave, OK?
Because I don't want
to remember any of it.
I don't!
I just wanna do something happy.
I wanna do something with kids.
So, Allison, I paid my
way through law school
and I just had this vision.
I saw myself in a
classroom with kids
and that's what brought me here.
The spirits brought me here.
I need you to tell me if
my husband is alive or dead.
And I told you I
don't do that anymore.
I don't want to see dead bodies.
I really think it's time
for you to leave, OK?
You know.
What, is it 'cause
I'm having nightmares?
Your son is having
nightmares too.
Did you know that?
It's all about his
Daddy's disappearance.
It's really not a
fun thing to see.
You really have no idea!
Oh.
That's why I'm sensing clowns.
Oh wow, I'm really sorry.
I'm really sorry for you
and I'm sorry for your son,
but I can't help you, OK?
-I really can't.
-You still have it.
It's like a
terminal disease, OK?
It's not a fun thing.
I'm sorry.
I'm just kinda known as the
wacky professor around here, OK?
Sorry.
This is not exactly
what I asked Santa for.
It was Bob's.
The police found--
Found it in a
alleyway, I know.
They found it in a alleyway
right behind the theater.
Oh, that tragedy.
He pulls his knife
out and he's using it
in self defense.
Karate.
What?
Karate, I don't know.
Uh... yeah.
Jesse's trying to get
his black belt in karate
by Christmas Day.
He thinks it will
bring his father back.
It might.
You think it will?
No, I didn't say that it will.
I said that it might.
Sorry, like I said, I can
get a little scattered, OK?
Everybody around here
thinks I'm scattered.
I'm just known as that little
wacky law professor here.
I really, I'm really
sorry for you.
I'm really sorry for you.
I can't help you.
My home address
is on the back.
So you can return the knife.
I have to take
Jesse to karate now.
He's already on his green belt.
-What's this, Jesse?
-It's on the list.
It's all about karate
now and you know,
getting my black belt.
But we can paint this later
like Dad and I used to.
Ah, I'm really no good
at this kinda thing.
Hey, the pizza's here.
It's not even cold!
We will haunt these victims.
We'll haunt their
minds, their dreams,
even the very land
they walk on.
And our victims won't hate us.
They'll become us.
Dad!
There's no
constitutional issue here.
People are permitted
to carry guns,
but only in very
specific circumstances.
Dad!
-Dad!
-Jesse, wake up.
Wake up, honey.
I just saw Dad, I'm
telling you, he's alive.
I need to get that black belt.
I don't want you to get hurt.
Mom, I'm tough.
I don't mean by karate.
Mom, I'm already
on the blue belt.
Dad will be coming home
soon when I prove that I
earned my black belt.
That's what I'm
talking about, Jesse.
Getting a black belt is not
going to bring back Daddy.
These are just
dreams you're having.
Then how do you
explain my dreams?
I saw you got some
newspaper clippings
about what happened.
That's why you're
having these dreams!
But why didn't you tell
me exactly what happened?
Because you're
so young, Jesse,
and I really didn't
think you needed to hear
all the horrible details
they write in the newspapers.
Then why didn't you tell
me Dad was at the theater
trying to make a constitutional
argument about guns?
How did you know that?
That wasn't in the news.
Gravy speaks Christmas.
No, no, it's not just
a Thanksgiving thing!
You have roast
beef on Christmas.
So you have gravy.
A whole chicken,
you put gravy on it.
What, prime rib?
No, that's au jus.
Au jus is a whole
different thing.
Uh huh, yes.
Yes.
Yeah, now you're thinking, OK.
And I can pull that off
by making Santa Claus
stir the gravy and then pour
it right over the turkey
for Mrs. Claus.
That way, we kill two
birds with one stone!
It's not just women in
the kitchen anymore.
And turkey gravy is hot
on a cold Christmas day.
OK.
Now let me go, I have
someone sitting here.
Seems like
it was just yesterday
that you were in high
school living next door.
You're graduating college?
Grad school actually, yeah.
-Oh my.
-Holiday break, of course.
You know, it was perfect
timing when you called because
I really need cash for presents.
So, I'm gonna pick
him up after school,
take him to karate and what not?
And maybe make him a snack
when you bring him home.
I work late a lot but ever
since his father went missing,
-I've just
-I am really sorry, Abby.
I remember your husband Bob.
He was a really cool guy.
Thank you.
It must be really
rough on Jesse.
I think it is.
I mean, it definitely is.
He's been obsessed with
completing this list of goals
that he set for himself.
I think they were all things
he used to do with his father.
They used to do a lot
of things together
that I wasn't a part of, ya
know, because I'm at work a lot.
I mean, me and Jesse have done
our own things together too.
I understand, Abby.
Um, he's had
these dreams, Sarah.
And some of it is rather
amazing, almost mystical.
But now, he's obsessed with
teaching himself to be a
back belt in karate,
by Christmas Day, no less.
And he thinks if
he gets a black belt,
it'll bring his father back?
Yeah, how did you know that?
I studied child
behavior and psychology.
It's a coping mechanism.
Reliving and doing all these
things that he used to do
with his Dad, earning his
missing Dad's approval
in a way so that
he'll come back.
And when he doesn't?
Well, what did your
grief counselor say?
-Well...
-Oh, you never got...
Jesse's a very smart kid.
He's determined, working hard.
He's fine.
He doesn't need a therapist.
Right, I shouldn't
have said anything.
No, no, you're
not the first one.
But we're doing just fine.
We're both strong and busy.
There's always so much
that needs to be done.
I mean, I'm sure it
works for others,
but not for Jesse, no.
Does he have any
dietary restrictions?
Timothy, kick him.
Kick, kick.
Fast.
Deeper, deeper.
You tapped him out again.
Stand up.
Applesauce is
amazing these days.
It's the new Jell-O!
You can get it with
maple syrup, cinnamon--
Are you kidding me?
Of course!
-I can market applesauce
with jalapenos.
I'm sorry, I have
to call you back.
Bob?
Where are you?
Who is this?
Where did you find this phone?
So, the Grinch suddenly
has this need for redemption
and he really wants
to be punished.
Maybe he just wants some
of that camaraderie thing
that prison brings
with all the prisoners
after all them years
of being alone up there.
Anyways, he strolls into
the Whosville DA Office
and he confesses to grand
larceny, trespassing,
and criminal mischief.
Only, there ain't
no criminal charges
been filed against him.
So, what is the responsibility
of the prosecutor?
The green guy, he even
brought in a whole bunch
of the stolen goods, like a
whole bunch of Christmas toys.
Class dismissed.
Um, that's it?
Yeah, that's it.
You're even gonna get a
little extra bonus for it, OK?
So, go home, it's
almost Christmas.
Go home for clown's sake.
OK.
Merry Christmas.
Merry Christmas to you too.
I'm sorry,
I'm looking for someone.
The needy people
won't start coming in
for about an hour.
You could start
dishing out this.
Oh uh, no, obviously
I'm not here for the...
I thought you said
people weren't arriving
for about an hour.
I guess they came early.
So you can name all the
presidents and you know all
the capitols, but what
I'm really impressed with
is this birdhouse.
Are you gonna paint it?
Yeah! With my dad
when he comes home.
Well how 'bout
with your mom now?
She's busy a lot.
She doesn't do
that sort of thing.
Wanna help me
practice my karate?
I would be honored.
Are you Jay?
Do I look like Jay?
I'm sorry, I don't
know what Jay looks like.
Do I look like aJay, hmm?
Um sure, why not?
Jay's a pretty common name.
J's a letter of the alphabet
and I don't think I
look like a letter.
It's also a bird,
as in blue jay,
and I'm not blue.
Do I look blue to you?
Huh, are you trying
to call me blue?
How would you like it
if I called you W, huh?
I don't, I uh, I'm
just looking for Jay,
the guy who owns
this restaurant.
Ya know, if you
haven't noticed,
today this place is set up to
feed people less fortunate,
people not like yourself.
We usually do this twice
a month, but this month,
we're doing it four times
because it's Christmas
and Jay, that blue bird
guy you're looking for.
He sold this spot to
me over a year ago.
It's mines now.
Oh, I'm sorry.
He said to meet him here.
Heh, yo, hold up, babe,
hold up, hold up.
I was just kiddin' around.
I was just joking.
Jay! Yo, Jay!
There's this chick out
here to see you, man.
Hey, he still owns this place.
He and I are best friends.
I'm just here helping him out.
Had you shook,
though, didn't I?
Hi, I'm Jay, and I apologize
for Sam's sense of humor.
I'm Abby.
You have my husband's phone?
You're Bob's wife.
I've heard so much about you.
Yeah.
One of the regulars
found it under the booth.
How did you know Bob?
Bob used to do free
legal work for us.
He was so generous
with his time.
Used to stop by
every now and again
and serve food if we had
nothing else for him to do.
Of course, that was
a long time ago.
So you haven't
seen him in a while.
No, not since the...
ya know?
Since the theater shooting.
Yeah.
Is everything all right?
But how could his
phone have gotten here?
I'm really sorry.
I don't know how long
it had been here.
Hello?
Professor?
What do you mean the knife
wasn't used in self defense?
Wait, wait, wait, you're
not making any sense.
Where?
So what's the meaning
behind all these belts?
Well, they all
start with white.
That signifies the beginning
or birth of a seed.
A white belt is a beginner
searching for knowledge
in the beginning
of life's cycle.
The yellow belt symbolizes
the first beams of sunlight
which shine upon the seed,
giving it new strength
with the beginning of new life.
Knowledge is germinating.
An orange belt represents
the growing power of the sun
as it warms the earth to
prepare for new growth.
The body and mind are
starting to open and develop.
The green belt signifies
the growth of the seed
as it reaches toward the
sun and begins to transform
into a recognizable life.
There is strengthening
of the mind
and refining of techniques.
A blue belt represents
the blue sky
as life sprouts from the earth.
The light feeds the life
so it can continue to grow.
Additional knowledge
and power are obtained.
The purple belt represents the changing of the sky to dawn.
Here, there is
great advancement.
It takes longer to get
through purple belt
than all the previous belts.
Wow.
Well what about all
the other belts?
Ugh, I'm only up
to a purple belt.
So can you cut a kid a break?
The remaining three belts
are red, brown, and black.
The red belt signifies the
red hot heat of the sun.
Life growing strongly towards it
but red is a sign of danger.
And a fighter, well, he can
become dangerous with his
knowledge and his
physical ability.
So, he has to be cautious
and red is next for Jesse.
Do you wanna know
about the brown belt?
The brown belt, well, it
represents the ripening
of a seed.
It's sort of a
harvesting process.
And a fighter, he's gonna
wrestle the longest with
gettin' his brown belt because
the next stop is greatness.
And that greatness
is the black belt?
Yes.
And with the black belt
comes profound knowledge
and that's knowledge that
he can pass on to others.
OK.
I'm interested but I'm confused.
Why are we at Jesse's
karate school.
Same knife.
I don't understand.
It just came to me right
when I was in the middle
of a lecture because that's
when things seem to come to me,
at the most inappropriate times.
What does any of this
have to do with my husband?
In my vision, Bob was
not holding this knife.
He wasn't even lookin' for it.
He wasn't even aware
that he had it.
Um, your visions are making me
more tired than those women.
Who are they?
What relevance do
they have to Bob?
Abby, psychic
vision isn't 20/20.
It's not like ya' know, well
it's kinda like nearsightedness
but only in my case,
it's like bifocals.
I was wrong, I was wrong.
I don't like to admit when
I was wrong but I was wrong.
Bob was not using this
knife to defend himself
in that theater.
He was using it
here to teach women
how to defend themselves.
This is a self defense
class for women.
This is where this
knife comes from.
Bob was using this
to teach these women
how to defend themselves
and he just left with it.
He forgot he even had it on him.
No, this doesn't make sense.
Maybe the powers of the
universe are trying to
teach ya something, Abby.
Maybe guide you to learn a
little bit about your husband,
things you didn't even know.
Maybe even surprise you.
Not like bad surprises
or something.
It's not like Bob had a whole
'nother family or something,
-you know, like that.
-You're wasting my time.
Hey Abby, your husband
was a black belt.
What?
Then live, you attractive
geniuses, and live large!
Hello out there in Crazyland.
I'm Graham Palace, owner
of the Palace Theater chain
and, of course,
this classic theater.
As my lovely daughter told
you, this is the crown jewel
in our empire,
and the place we end up
spending most of our time.
What she didn't tell you is
that today is her birthday.
Dun dun!
Everyone say happy birthday.
No, no, no, no,
that was terrible.
One more time.
All together.
Happy birthday!
And Aurora, as your
birthday gift in front of
all these wonderful people,
I'd like to give you
this Palace Theater.
I cede full control over
to you to finally do
all the things with it that
you've been yapping about
all these years.
So get ready.
You clowns, you two-faced hags.
She's got big plans
for this place
and she's the smartest,
most driven person I've met
and that says a lot.
I love you, Aurora.
And I know you'll be great.
But remember...
I will be watching you.
Tell your mother.
Then...
..you must remain silent...
...until Christmas Day.
That's the day you
earn your black belt.
Hey, hey, another dream?
The woman who
owned the theater.
-Aurora Palace?
-Yes.
What about her?
She was very close
with her father too.
How do you know that?
Because I saw him
speaking to her.
He gave her the theater
as a present on the night
of the shooting.
On the night Dad went missing.
On Christmas Day last year.
Yes, it was her birthday.
She was the only person
to survive the shooting.
It was a miracle
on her birthday.
On Hisbirthday.
Christmas wasn't
your father's birthday.
That's not what I
was talking about.
Jesse, what does
Aurora Palace's father
have to do with Daddy?
Dad has a Christmas
gift for me this year
like Aurora's father
had for her last year.
What makes you think this?
But I have to earn my
black belt like Aurora earned
the theater.
Jesse, what makes you
think this, what is it?
Mom, I have
a message for you.
I have to remain completely
silent from now
until Christmas Day and
focus on only one thing,
getting Dad back.
He says he needs
to earn getting his--
Earn getting
his black belt before Christmas
in order to get his daddy back,
and now he doesn't wanna talk?
How could I have not
known my own husband
had a black belt in karate?
Well, I sense that he
was trying to tell you,
but you're just
too busy to listen.
Is this what the spirits
are telling you?
That I was neglecting
my husband or something?
No, right now,
the only spirits that are
talking to me are
in those bottles.
Look, you are a very
successful businesswoman
and you're a pretty
average mother.
I'm more than
an average mother.
Maybe, but you do need
to pay more attention.
And I worked very
hard all my life.
Yes, you work hard
but you also had a pony.
You went to private prep school.
You even had a sweet
16 coming out party.
And you went to Yale and
your parents paid for
absolutely everything.
You had a very lavish wedding.
Ya' had an even more
lavish honeymoon
and you get a new
car every two years?
Whoop-de-doo.
Ouch! She's batting 1,000,
and the crowd goes wild.
Now, your husband John...
Bob.
That's what I said.
No, you said John.
Robert.
Robert, he had to work for
every single thing he has.
He had to pay his own
way through law school
just like me.
Do you know that he
used to tutor kids
and he even worked
as a bartender!
Yay for bartenders, whoo-hoo!
And he worked
as a bouncer in a bar.
That way, he could hobnob
with all the right wizards.
Do you know what though?
He never, ever once
forgot where he came from
or who he was.
How am I doing so far?
Score two.
Bartender, can we get
another one of these for me
and one for my very privileged,
poor little rich friend.
She's paying.
I know that Emma
laughed at me.
Never hated me or
schemed against me.
They thought nothing of me.
And before I knew it,
I agreed with them.
Now I feel different.
Now I'm something, something
strong that can't be
laughed at and ignored.
I am an instrument of power
and now my judgment matters.
They can try and judge me and
neuter everything in my life.
And relax, thinking they
have safety in numbers.
These spirits sure
bring out the spirits.
What is it?
I just keep, I'm having
the same visions as Jesse.
I keep seeing that
clown nut job.
You saw him?
That's who my son's seeing in
his dreams, James Whitmore?
Yeah and he's
seeing his Daddy too.
May I ask you something, Abby?
Why was Bob there?
There for a meeting?
Did he have a big speech?
Why was he there?
Yeah, yeah, to talk about guns
and constitutional
rights and stuff.
The girl who owned the
place had some kinda
three-tiered event,
a few friends first,
then a meeting and
then a big party
with the guys dressed
like clowns and the women
in some kinda wild makeup.
That's how he got in.
He just blended right on in
and nobody even noticed him
because he was dressed
up like a clown.
If you read the newspapers,
you would know that part.
I don't have to read
the newspapers, Abby!
I'm just seein' it!
Just seeing it!
I don't wanna see it.
Dad, Dad!
Everyone thinks that
the newest thing is crazy
up until they fall
in love with it.
Jesse, it's OK.
It was only a dream.
Oh man, no wonder you're
having nightmares.
Sarah, where are you?
Uh, coming, Abby.
Was I a bad wife?
No!
Why did he have to go to
that stupid crummy horror film?
And that theater birthday party?
And give a speech.
Well maybe he loved
horror films, Abby.
Yeah, yeah,
yeah, you're right.
He did love horror films.
How did you know that?
You told me that
when you came in.
Well, I love to make
arguments and give speeches.
I didn't know that
he was a karate man
and a homeless people helper.
So weird.
If I had
come home that day,
maybe he wouldn't have
gone to that theater.
Maybe you both would've gone
and Jesse would have no one.
-Cheers?
-No.
No. I wouldn't have gone.
I hate horror films.
So close, so close.
Ya know what, why don't you
take a swig of that coffee.
Pretend that it's a high
ball or whatever you were
just drinking over at the bar.
How did you know
I was at a bar?
Bottoms up, Abby.
No, no, no.
Oh yeah, good.
Uh yuck.
It's coffee!
And that's why you
earn the big bucks.
Can I get ya anything else?
Mmm, why the heck not?
You're all right.
You know that, Sarah?
Thank you, I try to be.
I try to be all right too.
Wish I was.
You will be.
You have to give yourself time.
Time to cope, maybe even grieve.
There's no deadline
on this Abby.
It's Christmas.
It is... almost.
I just want Bob back.
What about his father,
-a certain criminal?
A man responsible for
probably many deaths.
So then, why should he worry
about letting his father go?
He couldn't be expected
to do everything right.
He couldn't be loyal to
everything all at once.
I'll never let my
father go.
Mr. Palace, you are
right and wrong
in what you are saying.
My father was not a criminal.
He didn't kill anyone.
There, you are wrong.
But you are right in saying
that I can't be loyal
to everything at once.
My loyalty is with my
father only and now,
Mr. Palace, I need you to give
me a totally correct lesson,
a very private one too.
That's the only kind I do now.
Katarina, can
ya give me a minute?
You left your daughter
Aurora right after you
gave her the theater.
You didn't do it on purpose
though, I know that.
But, you are in a
beautiful place now.
How is New Jersey?
It's not warm
like where you are.
It's cold and it's scary.
Aurora knows for sure
where you are but I,
I don't know where
my father is.
Focus.
Streamline it.
James Whitmore was the
Security Officer at my school.
He was also the security
officer at your movie theater.
Me and Aurora have a bond.
Why would Whitmore wanna take
our fathers away from us?
Think
about what you need.
I need to get my father back.
-Sounds simple.
-No, it's not simple.
I need to defeat
Whitmore, but how?
Do you remember how
I taught you to fight?
Our creed?
You never taught me
how to fight, Mr. Palace.
We never even met!
But somehow, I understand
your creed, our creed.
It's loyalty, unconditional
loyalty to the ones
that we love.
Then live it.
Modify your officer in
every way that you can,
in every aspect of his life.
The only way I can modify
Whitmore is by getting
that black belt.
There is a powerful
force guiding me to it.
My father was always my teacher
and I was always the student
but now, my father
is my student.
I must guide him home.
Your owe your
student your loyalty.
And remember, you can't
be expected to be loyal
to everything all at once.
Hey Abby, so today,
all applesauce, right?
-I told you it's the new Jell-O.
-Perfect.
So we meet in ten in the
Eisenhower Conference room.
I thought it was the
Grant Conference room.
You're mixing up your
generals who became presidents.
Right.
Yeah, don't mix
up your applesauces.
-I won't.
-Good,
'cause there's
a big bonus for this one.
Oh, nice picture
of your hubby!
How 'bout a little
holiday spirit, hmm?
Uh, what's that?
Oh, just junk that my
students brought in to me.
I know, I know, it's just yuck.
That is not the way
to get a good grade.
Ya know, if they'd have
brought a bottle of wine,
a little spiked eggnog, maybe
even some glitter makeup.
Uh, we're not
drinking buddies now.
Oh, God, no.
You are a total downer
and the worst wingwoman.
Do you know guys just repel
against crying mommies
like bungee jumpers.
I get the message.
We're on track to figuring
something out together, I think.
But if you don't mind, I have an
important meeting to get to.
I had another vision, Abby.
I was thinking about
your visions this morning.
While all hungover and
with a pounding headache.
It seems you're seeing
things about Bob
and what happened that night.
But I came to you to
figure out if he was alive,
like Jesse's saying.
Not much in the evidence
the police found
and not much in your
visions is telling me that.
I saw your husband, Abby.
Like in the flesh
or in your head?
I saw where he
would be this morning.
What does that mean, Elizabeth?
You just called
me by my first name.
That means we're bonding.
I think I made a
mistake coming to you.
Nothing against you,
Elizabeth, but I started buying
into Jesse's dreams.
And I have some belief
in psychic abilities
and in your ability
specifically.
But, Bob isn't coming back.
I brought his picture here
to work with me because...
I'm fully accepting that
he's not coming back.
And I need to get Jesse
to realize that too.
Maybe Bob is just
coming to Jesse
to try to get to you ya know,
in some afterlife thing.
I don't know.
Yeah, maybe or
maybe you and Jesse
are seeing things from the past
or maybe you're just
both good investigators.
We can definitely look at
all options, just later.
Right now, I have to get to
that meeting in this world.
Stairs, where's those
stairs when you need them?
You wanna talk about
meetings and careers?
Not now, Elizabeth,
another time.
Oh come on, don't you
wanna know why I really
gave up the psychic
biz to be a lawyer?
-Nope!
-Er... Law Professor?
No.
'Cause it's a doozy.
No, but I'm sure
that won't stop you.
-Love to chat, gotta run.
-Come on.
Oh no.
Isn't it supposed to be the
Eisenhower Conference room?
How did you know?
I was eavesdropping.
God.
-I saw my fianc die.
In a vision.
I saw how we were
gonna get married
and he was gonna die.
I've never really even talked
to anybody about this before.
I loved him so much,
Abby, that I gave him up.
You didn't marry him?
No, I didn't marry him.
I didn't wanna see him die.
I figured if I gave him
up and didn't marry him,
then he won't die and
the spell will be broken.
Did it work?
I don't know.
Maybe.
He wouldn't speak to me anymore.
He didn't even
wanna stay in touch
and how could I blame him?
I broke both of our hearts.
I mean, part of me doesn't
even wanna know if he's...
alive or dead,
I don't even know.
I just threw myself into
law school so that I could
become a law professor
and for some people,
law school would be
complete torture.
But for me, well,
it was a release.
I'm sorry.
I'm very sorry, but I have
to get to that meeting.
Really? You really wanna
give up your husband
for some stupid bonus?
I don't know what you mean...
and that's not fair.
Take it back!
Whatever it means, take it back.
I can't.
I can't take back
what I see, Abby.
Don't you see that you're
losing your own son?
Why are you doing this to me?
Why today?
Maybe I'm the three
ghosts to your Scrooge
and you are a Scrooge, Abby!
Yesterday, that
was Christmas past.
Today, it's Christmas present.
Where did
you see my husband?
You saw Bob here
at your college?
Yeah, this is definitely,
definitely the place.
A gazebo?
That's a beautiful
Christmas tree.
Sensing something?
No, I'm cold.
It's freezing out here.
Look, Elizabeth, this
place is nice and all
and festive but why
would Bob come here?
You're here, ain't ya?
You brought me here.
No, no, no, the
spirits brought us here.
Really Elizabeth?
You have my mind going back and
forth like a ping pong ball.
Really?
My ghost of Christmas present?
This is definitely the place.
I know this gazebo.
I know that Christmas tree
and that nativity scene.
I even know that
tree right there.
Bob was definitely here.
Oh, God, this seat is so cold!
Bob was standing at that tree.
When?
Yesterday, today?
Two months ago?
I don't know, he's
just standing there.
He's tired out from something.
Tired?
Okay.
It was the day
before the shooting.
And he's here with a
whole lot of other people
and I have this sense of
pride and accomplishment
-from him for something.
-Putting lights on the
Christmas tree?
You are not helping matters.
I'm not sure if
you are either.
He wanted to
tell you something,
something about this place.
Tell me what?
I don't know. He was gonna tell
you when he got home,
when you got home from
work but you were late.
You're always late,
you're always at work, why?
It's always been
very busy at work.
You should've
made the time, Abby.
Bob always made the time,
didn't he?
Yeah, okay.
He was better at the work life
time management stuff.
He wanted to tell
you about this.
He wanted you to see this.
Why?
Beats me.
That's it?
I'm cold,
I'm going to the car.
You dragged me here and
now you wanna get in the car?
It's got a heater.
I must be nuts.
You're nuts and
the car's locked.
You locked the car?
Abby, we're at a nativity scene.
Ain't nobody out here
and you locked the car?
And you think I'm the one nuts?
Did you drop something?
Found something.
Car, heat Abby, car!
Come on, open the door.
Is it not opening?
No.
Oh, my God.
Heat, Abby.
Come on, I'm cold.
It takes a while.
Oh no.
What is it?
Another vision?
Yes.
Oh come on, give me a break.
I'm cold and she doesn't care.
She just wants to get
back to the office.
I care.
Are you sure, Abby?
'Cause I don't really know
where this is taking us.
Lead away.
Okay but fair warning Abby,
the psychic GPS stuff,
it goes all over the place.
There's like wrong turns
and then there's U-turns.
I don't know.
Let's hit the road, Jack.
Please just stick to
calling me Elizabeth, okay?
I don't like the name Jack.
It reminds me of
the creepy guy from
"Jack and the Beanstalk,"
and I don't like
fairy tales in general.
Like "Hansel and Gretel,"
creepy!
-Who makes up that mess?
-Gotcha.
Seriously,
kids don't even like it.
Creepy people, oof.
Creepy, creepy.
-Hiya, hiya, hiya!
Hiya, hiya!
Well, definitely not how
Bob would've done it but,
I'm kinda good at this.
Nah, this is terrible.
It's terrible.
Jesse, come in here.
Jesse?
Jesse!
Look, Jesse.
I painted it.
I painted the birdhouse.
Oh, so you're
happy I painted it.
Purple, one of my
favorite colors.
You've earned a lot of belts.
I'll fix it later.
One more belt?
Brown?
Then it's the black belt?
Uh, Charles, what are
you doing at my desk?
What happened?
You missed the entire
meeting yesterday.
Sort of a family
emergency thing.
What is that?
It's awful.
I painted it for my son.
You should keep
it at the house.
Charles, what do
you want from me?
What do I want from you?
Well, Janice had to
do the entire pitch.
Well, that's good!
So the presentation was made.
This is your project.
Remember, "Applesauce
is the new Jell-O."
-That was your idea.
-Janice is more than competent.
I'm sure she handled
it perfectly.
That's not the point.
My work was in there, right?
And the client is happy?
You can't miss
critical meetings.
It's a tough time.
It's Christmas.
Holidays are rough
for lots of people.
Like me and my son?
How many other people lost
their husband last Christmas?
It's just that usually,
you're the most...
"work-is-first person" I know.
You know, you're
absolutely right.
Can I ask you a question?
Of course.
Have you ever felt like
you missed something?
Like what?
Like life?
Shake hands.
So, Frosty the Snowman,
he's completely had it by now
'cause of all the salt
and the sand coming up.
And the soot's blackening
his pretty white coat.
It's bad enough that some
big ol' blackbird came along
and chomped off part of
his carrot nose to eat it
and he lost one of his
black pieces of coal
out of his eye.
So now he's got one eye and
half a nose and his whole body
is meltin' faster
than it should.
See, salt and sand is
hazardous waste to Frosty.
But, for the community,
the salt and the sand
is really good.
It's good for keeping the
streets and the sidewalks safe.
So, does Frosty have a
legitimate valid lawsuit?
Now I want you to put
your thinking caps on.
Come on, I need some
Christmas future advice.
It's Christmas Eve day
and I'm right in the middle
of an important lecture.
What Professor lectures
on Christmas Eve day?
And who to?
Well, these students are
in North Sentinel Island.
It's that island off
of India, ya know,
where they shoot people
with bows and arrows.
Not sure what their
Christmas plans are.
What are your Christmas plans?
Sorry.
What'd you do that for?
I'm trying to teach
them international law
and they are a real
lawless bunch, you know?
You started this.
You have to help me finish it.
I hope I have
this number still.
Nope.
Ow!
You managed to direct me away
from a very important
meeting and it did me good.
I feel like we're close.
You feel like we're close?
I love that.
Ya know, there are
times I'm afraid.
Afraid I'm making
the wrong choice,
going down the wrong path.
Just need to hold this,
fire it at the firing range
a few times.
It reminds me of what
you've taught me.
What did he teach me?
Who?
James Whitmore,
what did he teach me?
What did he teach you?
I don't know, the
guy's a crazy idiot!
You're stronger than
all of us put together.
Aurora, Daddy's little girl.
I need you to figure this out.
Daddy, help me to help you!
We can start to help.
You must watch for
yourself, Aurora.
You all must watch
for yourselves.
Unless he stops us.
Some is as it
seems, some is not.
This is me and this is real.
But if I'm not here,
not exactly here,
then I'm not real.
Aurora, you woke up.
Thank God.
Oh!
Abby, I need some whiskey.
I need bourbon or I
just need a drink now.
What?
What did you see, Elizabeth?
I saw a whole lot more than
I wanted to see, believe me.
Is that... that
Aurora lady,
was she in the hospital
after the shooting?
Yeah, I think so.
She wasn't shot but I think
she went to the hospital, yeah.
Why?
'Cause I saw your husband
there with her in the hospital.
That can't be.
He disappeared with Whitmore.
Like seconds after the shooting.
I don't know, it's just
like a big old jumbled mess.
I don't know if it's from
the past or the present
or the future or maybe
some... other place.
What it does tell me though,
by seeing a vision of
Bob in the hospital,
it tells me that he's alive.
You think he's alive?
You really think
Bob could be alive?
Yes, I do.
I really do think he's alive.
But uh, we need to
go back to that bar.
We need to go back to that bar.
The Christmas future is there.
And I need a drink.
Okay.
You gonna go to
the bar with me?
Of course I'm gonna go!
All right, well you're buyin'.
Okay.
Those Sentinel Islands students
that you cut me off from,
they're not like the
rest of the world.
The government doesn't
even let you get within
50 miles of them and they
don't even tolerate outsiders.
We've been here nearly
an hour, Elizabeth.
My days at a bar on
Christmas Eve are long gone.
I wanna get home to
Jesse but you said
my Christmas future is here.
It might've been my Christmas
future, not yours Abby.
Mark?
Elizabeth?
Mark, you're alive?
Of course I'm alive.
You upset me, but uh...
you didn't kill me.
Mark, it's been
almost 20 years!
My apologies for
breaking up the reunion.
But let me guess,
you're Mark's ex fiance?
Yes, and you're his wife?
Mark told me that
you were psychic.
No it's just that obvious.
Well look, it is Christmas Eve,
so, excuse me for
being rude but uh,
we gotta get home to our son.
Huh, lot of people seem
to be saying that lately.
Well, bye.
Merry Christmas.
Yeah, Merry Christmas,
Elizabeth.
Merry Christmas to y'all.
That was your ex fiance!
He's alive, that's great news!
Not for you!
What?
Why?
Bartender, two Johnny Walker
shots please, immediately!
In my visions, I always
saw that Mark was dead
and that Bob was alive.
Mark's alive, I can't
even believe he's alive.
But if Mark's alive,
then that means Bob,
he's probably...
This is terrible.
I mean, it's happy
for you but it's,
it's not what I was
expecting for me and Jesse.
We can start to help.
That sounded like Bob's voice!
That's exactly what I
heard Bob say in my vision.
Bob?
Bob!
What, what is it?
Oh, the women's room occupied?
I'm so sorry, we thought
you were someone else.
Abby, I want you to know I'm
really, really, really sorry.
My visions, they ain't perfect.
And I think I'm just seeing
all of the good things
that Bob did and maybe that's
what he wanted you to see,
all the good things and
he wanted you and Jesse
to know that he's
OK wherever he is.
I do know that he's definitely
watching over you, OK?
What you've done for me
and Jesse is wonderful.
I haven't done anything.
Bob isn't coming back.
I know that now.
Yes, he is here.
He's left us with something
so very special, his love,
to us and to so
many other people.
And you truly helped
me realize that.
And you helped me realize
that my life with Jesse
is so much more important
than anything else.
There was nothing more
important to Bob than Jesse.
I am so happy that
you see that, Abby.
And I want you to know
something else.
You really are a good mama.
I do see that. I want you
to know that.
I may be just a little
bit jealous 'cause I
don't have a kid,
but I do see that you
are a very good mama.
Would you like to
come by to my house
for Christmas Eve dinner?
I can promise you
it will be good
because my parents made it.
Really appreciate that
invite more than you
will ever understand,
but I actually do have a family.
My mama and daddy are
here from West Virginia.
So I'm going home to them.
Well, would you be able to
come by tomorrow afternoon
when Jesse's scheduled to
get his self-dealt black belt?
I could use all the
support I can with that.
I will absolutely be there.
I promise you.
Thank you, Elizabeth.
Merry Christmas, Abby.
Merry Christmas, Elizabeth.
Come on, let's go home.
Your mother and I are
very proud of Jesse, right?
Awe, that's so sweet.
I mean, honestly,
I don't know how he does it.
Plus the energy that he's
putting into this project.
Ah, amazing.
Clearly we all need the
amount of energy Jesse has.
My God, he's got
so much energy, that kid.
I don't know where he gets it.
People used to, though...
They did, I know, right?
It's so funny.
When you break this board,
you'll speak?
Do you want me
to hold the board?
I would like to
hold the board.
How 'bout you, Professor, would
you like to hold the board?
Me?
Oh no, no, no, no, no.
Looking at Jesse,
he might break my fingers
along with that board, mm-mmm.
That's what I'm talkin' about.
I think a man needs
to hold that board.
What do you mean?
A woman can hold a board
just as well as a man.
Mom. Dad.
I'm going to hold
the boards for Jesse.
OK, Jesse, you're supposed to
break this with one hit, right?
So give it your best shot.
Way to go, Jesse!
All right, Jesse! Way to go!
My dear God!
All right!
Way to go, Jesse! All right!
Dear God!
Dad, Dad!
You escaped!
I knew you would!
I did. I escaped.
Well, OK,
guess I was on target.
I'm home! I'm home!
Come here.
You did this for me, didn't you?
I did so that you
would come home.
You're a black belt, Jesse.
You're a black belt.
You earned it.
Come here.
It's a miracle.
It's a true Christmas miracle.