(¶ "Troubled Mind" by Arko ¶)
¶ Oh, troubled mind ¶
¶ You make love
so hard to find ¶
¶ Oh, troubled mind ¶
¶ I don't want to look behind ¶
¶ You may be strange ¶
¶ You were born and raised ¶
¶ By usual hands of
need and praise ¶
¶ And now set your mind ¶
¶ You'll be my slave ¶
¶ And I'll be kind ¶
¶ Oh, silly mind ¶
¶ You make me feel ¶
¶ Drunk and fine ¶
¶ And stains that
were once you ¶
¶ Are today only wine ¶
¶ Oh ¶
- Mom.
It's Christmas again.
(soft music)
- [Shivaani] Kabir?
- What's the point in knocking?
You don't have to do all this.
- You shouldn't
eat all this stuff.
- I like this stuff.
- Why didn't you eat the
food that I brought for you?
I brought you fresh food.
Because you don't like it?
- I never said that.
(water running)
Shivaani, I said don't do that.
- You can't live like this.
- Like what?
- Like this.
- I said I'll get to it.
Just let it go.
- [Shivaani] You know your
mother would have never--
- Shivaani.
- She wouldn't.
- Come help us.
- I think you both have
this under control.
- He prefers to supervise.
- Except when it's time to eat.
You used these dishes.
Help wash them.
- Uh huh.
- Okay I'm coming.
It's just that I am stuck
in this dimensional time warp
that slows down time.
- Smart ass.
- I am almost there.
- Why don't you practice the
song you're gonna sing tonight?
- But Kabir is stuck
in a time warp.
- Yes, so he has to watch
without criticizing.
- [Mom] Oh, you're right.
- I can still hear you guys.
¶ Boy of mine ¶
¶ Although my heart is aching ¶
- Okay, okay.
Stop, stop, stop, stop, stop.
I'm here, I'm here, I'm here.
Stop, stop.
Come on, you're not gonna
really sing like that tonight?
Are you please?
- She's teasing you.
- I will if you're stuck in
a dimensional time whatever.
- No, seriously don't
do that. Please.
- Seriously come on.
- All right, what do you want?
I said don't do that.
- Are you going into the city?
- Yes, I am.
- And?
- And what?
- What are you gonna tell them?
- What we discussed.
- So you're going back?
- Yes, I said yes, Shivaani.
- What time is your appointment?
- God, Shivaani.
What do you want?
- Seriously what do I want?
- You know what I mean.
- No, I don't know
what you mean, Kabir.
- Well then just let it go.
- Look, we all
loved your mother.
- Shivaani, please.
- You've got--
- Got to what?
- [Shivaani] Nothing.
- No, tell me what I need to do.
I'm already going
back to med school.
What more do you want me to do?
- How about living together?
How about being normal?
- Shivaani, you're the one
who told me to move here.
- I didn't know that
you were gonna live
in your mother's house forever.
- It's only been a year.
- It's a long time, Kabir.
I seriously think you
should start thinking
about selling this house.
- Shivaani, don't you dare tell
me to sell this house again.
- Don't I dare?
- Yeah okay 'cause I'm
done talking about that.
- [Shivaani] Where
are you going?
- [Kabir] I need some space.
- Look, come to
the party tomorrow.
- I don't want to.
- If not for my sake,
then come for my parents.
- What does this have
to do with your parents?
- If you don't come,
then everybody's gonna
ask them where you are.
It'll put them in a spot.
It's not fair to them, Kabir.
Try to come.
Come say hi to everybody.
Okay?
I'll see you later.
(cell phone ringing)
- Hey, how's it going?
- [Catherine] Are
you gonna come by?
- I told you I have
that party tonight.
- You're gonna be at the
hospital today right?
- Yeah, I'm gonna
be at the hospital.
- So, come by after.
- Catherine, listen.
- Only for a sec.
I wanna give you your Christmas
present before I leave town.
- Okay all right.
Only for a second.
- Awesome.
Text me when you're coming.
- Yeah okay.
All right.
(soft music)
- Hey KB.
- [Kabir] Hey Paddy.
- Oh, give me that.
This Shivaani's cooking?
- Yup.
- How come you just
give this stuff away?
How you doing, man?
- Okay.
Paddy, that's disgusting.
- No, it's delicious.
- No, how could
you eat like that?
- Like this.
Wanna try one?
Here try.
Try some.
- Oh no way.
- My fingers are clean.
You can try one.
- Paddy, I know for a fact
your fingers are filthy.
- What?
- [Kabir] You don't
wash your hands.
- Of course I do.
State law requires me to.
- Paddy, I've seen you
come of that bathroom
without washing your hands okay.
- You get some alcohol
on your fingers,
you don't have to wash it off.
Why are you so squeamish anyway?
- Med school.
You don't wanna know
the things that I know.
- Ignorance is bliss, my friend.
Believe me.
- What?
- You're all dressed
up and looking nice.
- So?
- Well, I just haven't
seen you look like.
- Like what?
- Look like you for a long time.
What's the occasion?
- I've got that
meeting at school.
- Oh, you think
they'll let you back?
- What does that even mean?
- I don't know.
Maybe they filled their quota
on good looking doctors.
You saw Shivaani.
Any improvement?
- [Kabir] In what?
- Getting back together.
- No.
Not happening.
- Seriously?
Do I have to tell
you what it means
when a woman brings you food?
- Yeah, tell me what it means.
- It means she loves you.
- Maybe she's doing what
she thinks a wife would do.
- No, she's doing
it because she wants
to get back together with you.
- Okay Paddy, let's drop it.
- Okay.
All right.
Hey, you coming to the party?
- No.
- No?
- [Kabir] No.
- [Paddy] Why not?
- Paddy, what were we
just talking about?
- About Shivaani.
- Okay, I'm gonna go.
- Hey, hey, hey,
hey, hey, hey, hey.
Just cheer up, man.
It's Christmas okay.
- I don't care if
it's Christmas.
- That was your mother's
favorite holiday.
- What do you know
about my mother?
- Are you serious?
- Yeah you think Christmas
was her favorite holiday.
- Yeah, I know it was.
- Well you don't know anything.
- Hey, hey, chill out, man.
- [Kabir] You chill out, Paddy.
Fuck off.
(¶ "Troubled Mind" by Arko ¶)
¶ In separated chambers ¶
¶ Our hearts collide to meet ¶
¶ We burn so we remember ¶
¶ That burning can be sweet ¶
¶ So sweet ¶
¶ Don't waste this
time being sorry ¶
¶ Time and people go ¶
¶ Your soul is all I'll carry ¶
¶ Your face is all I know ¶
¶ You like to win ¶
¶ You like to fight ¶
¶ Is one true love
worth all your might ¶
¶ Or may we play
my favorite game ¶
¶ Of lose and find ¶
¶ Of lose ¶
¶ And find ¶
¶ Oh ¶
¶ Oh troubled mind ¶
¶ You make love
so hard to find ¶
¶ Oh troubled mind ¶
¶ I don't want to look behind ¶
- Looks like you've
been out for a year.
You just left after
your third semester.
Do you think you're
ready to come back?
Mister Bakshi?
- Sorry what?
- [Administrator]
I understand it was
your mother who departed.
- [Man] Your mother.
- What about her?
- [Man] She collapsed.
- [Administrator] Mister Bakshi?
- What if I'm not ready yet?
- Well, we usually
don't allow students
to be gone longer than a
year, even for bereavement.
We have to consider the
impact such a long absence
would have on your studies.
This curriculum is designed--
- Couldn't I apply for a
longer leave of absence?
- There's a lot of paperwork
you'd have to submit
and there's no guarantee
it'd be granted.
- When would I have
to make that request?
- I don't think that's
such a good idea.
Sometimes it's--
- Ma'am, when would I have
to apply for the request?
- As soon as possible.
Right after the holidays.
- Hey, Bodhisattva. Huh?
- Sorry what did you call me?
- Can you help me
ease my suffering?
- [Kabir] Hey.
Don't click somebody's
picture without asking.
- Or without paying, huh.
- I'm sorry.
Asking would've
ruined the moment.
- Yeah, you mean it
would've ruined your shot?
- Yeah, I--
- No, you don't do that.
Okay?
(soft music)
- Ow.
- Watch where the
fuck you're going.
- Hey fuck you.
- Fuck you.
- [Mom] Kabir.
- Ouch.
Ow Mom, what the hell?
- This is Christmas.
- (laughs) Look who's returned.
- Hey listen.
Did you see where she went?
- Who?
- The girl, the photographer.
- [Kabir] Where is she?
- She went that way.
- That way?
Hey.
Hey, hey, hey.
- Hey.
- Listen.
I wanted to apologize
about earlier.
- It's okay.
I think it was my fault.
- Oh no, no.
It was my fault.
It's Christmas and I
should be nicer to people,
especially to people visiting.
I assume you're not from here.
- I'm from Kenya.
- Oh Kenya.
Hey, you followed me here?
- I had my picture taken, too.
A lady's gotta eat, huh.
- Here.
- Thank you.
- You got your money.
You can go now. Thank you.
- Hold on.
There is something
special between you two.
No, no.
Really.
Just take a moment and
look at each other.
- We can go.
- No really.
Just take a moment and
really look at her.
Just look at her for a moment.
You too, miss.
Take a moment and
really look at him.
- Okay come here.
- No, no, this is silly.
- Come on, just take a moment.
(soft music)
- [Homeless Woman] That's it.
- Okay anyways, this is enough.
- What about you, miss?
Do you believe in karma?
- I do.
- Come this way.
Just come on, come on.
Thank you very much.
Have a good day.
Come, come.
- Merry Christmas you two.
- Well, it was nice meeting you
and I suppose she won't
follow us around anymore.
- She's a strange woman.
- She's a crazy woman.
- But I think she means well.
- I think it's better you stay
away from people like that
because the city can be
pretty dangerous sometimes.
- [Kioni] What's your name?
- My name is Kabir.
- [Kioni] Kabir.
- Well, my friends
call me KB sometimes.
- Which do you like?
- Whatever.
- I like Kabir.
Is it Indian?
- Yes it is.
And what's your name?
- Kioni.
- Kioni?
You're on vacation?
- Kind of.
- Kind of?
- I applied to film school here.
I just finished my interview.
- And how'd that go?
- [Kioni] Pretty good I guess.
- Yeah, I guess you never
really know about those things.
So Kioni, do you know
where you're going?
- I wanna see more of the city.
I wanna see the
Christmas decorations.
- Okay, so you should
take the train uptown
because there's a
lot of beautiful
Christmas decorations up there,
but you don't wanna go that way
'cause you might bump into
the homeless lady again.
If you want, I can show you
another subway entrance.
- Can I walk?
- From here?
- [Kioni] Yeah.
- No, that's too far.
Listen.
Since you're a visitor
here, if you want,
I can show you a few
interesting places.
- That'd be nice.
Thank you.
(gentle music)
(camera shutter clicking)
- Whoa, you really like
all these buildings.
- Never seen anything like them.
- Never?
- I mean we have tall
buildings in Kenya,
but the architecture's
different.
Not where they're
altogether like this.
(camera shutter clicking)
- But you keep taking
pictures of all of them.
- I know it's silly.
(gentle music)
- Well I've never really
thought about the buildings.
I mean, there are
famous ones in New York
like the Empire State Building,
the Flatiron Building,
the Chrysler Building, so many,
but it's not like I thought
about the buildings.
- [Kioni] Why not?
- [Kabir] They're
just buildings.
- You see a building.
I see a story.
- [Kabir] You see a story?
- Sure.
Each one has a story.
- That reminds me of my
first year in medical school.
- You're a doctor?
- A med student.
During my first year
in medical school,
I lived in the student housing
in a building on Park Avenue.
- Nice.
- No, not nice.
Not nice.
It was an old rundown building
that must have been
housing medical students
for like 200 years or something,
but what you just
said made me realize
that all the students
who ever lived there
must have had stories
and conversations
and revelations about
their time there.
- And all the people made
friends then fell in love.
- And lost their minds
in their studies,
but no one would
ever know walking by
unless they were a
part of that story.
To everyone else it'd
just be another building.
- Or another story.
¶ Mozart's "The
Marriage of Figaro" ¶
Show me the pictures
you took of me.
Show me, show me, show me,
show me, show me, show me.
- Okay, look, look.
- Thank you so much.
- I'm married.
- Ummm, Okay.
- Sorry, I don't
know why I said that.
I don't know why I said that.
Forget it.
- It's okay.
I'm not trying to
come on to you.
- No, no, I know, I know.
That's why I don't
know why I said that.
I-- I didn't mean to
make it all awkward.
Listen.
- Really it's okay.
- Listen, ummm...
Okay, the thing is my wife
and I recently separated
and haven't been living
together for some time.
So, I just.
- Hey we're just hanging out.
Okay?
You don't have to
explain anything to me.
- Okay.
- You're kind of
a dork you know.
- A dork?
- Total dork.
- Why?
What?
- A girl kisses you on the cheek
and you get all
flustered and blush.
- That's not fair okay.
You surprised me.
- Sure, sure.
- You wanna sit here?
Do people give gifts
in Kenya on Christmas?
- Some people do but the
focus is also on community
and celebrating the birth of
Jesus, which the churches do.
My family had a
tradition of eating cake.
- You know, my family
is not Christian,
so for us Christmas was never
about the birth of Jesus.
- Are you Muslim?
- No, not Muslim.
Not really anything.
I mean, my parents were Hindus,
but at home we never
really spoke about it.
- So what do you
do on Christmas?
- I never really
liked Christmas.
- You don't like Christmas?
- You know if it was
more about religion
than about gift giving
maybe I would but--
- [Kioni] But?
- My mom raised me alone.
My dad died when
I was very young
and we never really
had much money
and so I never really
liked Christmas.
I would hate that
after the holidays
when all the kids
came back to school,
they'd show off all
the amazing gifts
that they got from Santa Claus,
and I'd just tried
to hide the fact
that the most
amazing gifts I got
from Santa were new
underwear and socks.
- Those are good gifts.
- Well, I see that now.
You know, that my mom
was being practical
and only got me
things that I needed,
but you know as a kid,
it hurts when you realize
that you got all the things
you got because you're poor.
Everything during
Christmas revolves around
how much money you have.
The more you have,
the better it is.
- That's true about
everything though, isn't it?
- Yeah, but for kids it's not.
They don't know any of that.
As a child I could have a
stick and call it a sword.
You know?
I could have a cardboard
box and it'd be my castle
and I'd be the kind
and I'd be happy.
- So why is Christmas
any different?
- It's different because
one day you realize
that Santa Claus is
actually your mom
and what you get
has nothing to do
with how good or bad you are,
but about how much
money you had,
and that's when all the
realities of life hit me.
- You realized this as a kid?
- I was 10 years old and my
dad had been gone for sometime
and that particular year my mom
got a fake plastic Christmas
tree instead of the real one
and I remember when that
happened, I was so angry.
I was so upset, I cried
and I yelled at her.
I mean, that moment
ruined Christmas for me.
- Why?
- Because I knew we got a
fake plastic Christmas tree
because we couldn't
afford the real one
and all the illusions
of Christmas came
- I think we can all relate
to feeling like
money's a problem,
but you look like you're
doing pretty good now.
- Don't judge a
book by it's cover.
- Let's get something to eat.
I'm hungry.
I wanna try New York pizza.
- You haven't had
New York pizza?
- No.
- Oh okay, let's go.
Pizza?
- [Kioni] Yes.
- [Kabir] You have to try it.
New York pizza is the best.
- That was really good.
- Told you.
- The first Christmas
movie I remember seeing
was the "Miracle
on 34th Street".
The color version, not
the black and white one.
- I saw the black and white one.
It's about that old
man who plays Santa
in the department
store and pretends
to be the real Santa Claus.
Wasn't there something
about a house?
- Yeah.
The little girl
wants her dream house
for her family to live
in and by the end,
they get it and it's a miracle.
- Yeah.
I sort of remember that.
- It had a huge impact on me.
I was orphaned
really young and I--
- You're an orphan?
- Yeah, my parents died when
I was eight but I wasn't--
- I'm so sorry to hear that.
I feel like such an asshole.
I've been talking
about being poor
and about all my problems.
So sorry.
- No, don't worry about it.
I realized long ago that
my life is my journey
and it's just as amazing
and difficult as anyone else
that's on the planet.
- [Kabir] When did
you realize that?
- It's kind of
connected to that movie.
To all Christmas movies.
Those movies were fantasy.
Like the idea that you could
ask for whatever you wanted
and just get it, that's amazing,
and I totally fell for it.
I didn't really
understand who Santa was
until after my parents died,
and so my first
Christmas without them,
my first in the orphanage, I
used to write letters to Santa
and I'd wish for a
house and a family
and I'd cry when
it didn't happen.
- How can you still
like Christmas?
I'd hate it if I were you.
- All those hopes and wishes
and unanswered letters to Santa
revealed to me what
I want in life.
The dreams of a child are basic,
but they're the backbone of
who we are when we grow up.
- But what if you don't
get any of those things?
- I already have those things.
We have everything we
want all our lives.
We just have to change
our perspective.
I wanted a family
growing up and I had one.
The kids I grew up with.
The women who raised me.
The lady from my church
who helped me get here.
They're my family.
And I've always had a place
to live and food in my belly.
I may not have my mom and
dad anymore, but I have them.
I'm blessed.
- And you're willing to leave
all that and come to America?
You wouldn't want to stay back
and help the kids
in the orphanage?
- But I will.
Coming here and
continuing my education
is the best thing I can
do to help my people.
Once I'm done with
school, I can go back
and help other people
tell their stories
and while I'm here, I
can meet people like you
and tell them about Kenya.
- Kioni, I must say
you're a very brave girl.
- If I was brave, I
would've gone ice skating.
- No, I said brave not crazy.
- [Catherine] KB?
- What time is it?
- It's ten after eight.
- Oh no listen...
I'm late.
I was supposed to be home
by nine to sing with my mom.
She's gonna be upset.
- Nine?
You've plenty of time.
Just stay a couple more minutes.
- No listen, listen.
I can't.
I can't miss this.
- Well.
At least open your
gift before you go.
Here.
- Wow, it's beautiful.
- That is just the
wrapping, knucklehead.
Open it.
- I don't know why I'm
feeling so nervous.
- What are you nervous about?
- How about I open
this when you get back?
- No.
No, open it now.
Come on.
- But I feel bad.
I didn't get you anything.
- Well it doesn't matter.
Open mine.
- Catherine, listen,
how about we both open
our gifts together
when we see each other next?
- KB, you are killing me.
- Listen.
I wanna do this right.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
Look at me.
When you're back from
the holidays, let's
- Do what for real?
- Be together. You and me.
- And what about your wife?
- No wife.
- No wife?
- I think it's time
I called it quits.
- You mean leave her?
- Is that okay with you?
- Seriously?
Are you sure you don't wanna...?
- I want this.
I wanna be with you.
Okay?
- Yeah.
Okay.
- Hi.
Hi, I'm Catherine.
- Hello, I'm Kioni.
- So how have you been?
I haven't seen you since--
- Yeah, I've been all right.
- Did you leave school?
- No, I've been on leave.
You know the bereavement.
My mother.
- Your mother, yeah.
- How've you been?
- Good.
I graduate next semester.
We've all been going crazy
trying to get placed.
Are you a med student?
- No, I've applied
to film school.
- Oh, that's great.
I tried to call you
like a million times.
I was just wondering.
I mean, I just was hoping
that you were okay.
- Yeah, I've been okay.
- That's good.
That's great.
And Shivaani, she's okay?
- Shivaani's great.
Shivaani's been good, yeah.
- Well, it was so
good to see you.
- It was good to see you, too.
- I'm getting married.
I don't know why
I just said that.
I guess I just
wanted you to know.
- I'm happy for you, Catherine.
Congratulations.
- Thanks.
Okay.
So, Merry Christmas.
- To you, too.
- Merry Christmas.
(gentle music)
You've been pretty quiet
since we ran into Catherine.
Everything okay?
- No, it's just this night.
I mean, not this night,
but this night last year
when my mother died.
- Yeah?
- I was going to leave my wife.
- To be with that
woman? Catherine?
- Yeah.
- But then your mom died.
- What happened?
(soft music)
- Kabir, where you been?
- What are you talking about?
It's only nine.
- Your mother.
- What about her?
- [Man] She collapsed.
They think it was
a heart attack.
- She had a heart attack.
- [Kioni] I'm so sorry.
- My wife's family has
this annual Christmas party
and my mother and I
were supposed to sing.
- Sing?
Like karaoke?
- No, this song.
But I was with Catherine at
her house while my mother...
You know, I think I killed her.
I think that killed
her, you know.
Sounds ridiculous, right?
- No, it doesn't.
(gentle music)
[Kioni] For a long time I
thought I'd killed my parents.
- Why?
What happened to them?
- Car accident.
(gentle music)
- [Kabir] How could you
think that was your fault?
- I don't know.
It's what people think.
Maybe if I'd done this or done
that, they'd still be alive.
That's not true.
It's beyond our control.
The question you've got
to answer is what's next?
How do I go on
without this person?
- Easier said than done.
- Why were you with Catherine
that night instead
of your family?
- I don't know.
- Yes, you do.
(gentle music)
- [Kabir] Making me follow
traditions from India
when I was raised in America
is like having a
split personality.
It drove me crazy until I
finally said enough is enough.
- [Kioni] You mean by
being with Catherine?
- [Kabir] Yeah.
- [Kioni] But when
I kissed your cheek,
you told me you're married.
- [Kabir] I don't
know why I said that.
- [Kioni] Because in your
heart, you're married.
- [Kabir] Yeah, maybe.
(gentle music)
- [Kioni] What was the song?
- [Kabir] The song?
- [Kioni] The song that you
were gonna sing with your mom?
- [Kabir] You wouldn't know it.
My mom picked it.
- [Kioni] Oh, let's go there.
Can you sing it?
- [Kabir] Now?
- [Kioni] Yeah, come on.
- [Kabir] No, it's too cold.
- Don't be a dork.
- [Kabir] I can really sing.
- [Kioni] Hold on.
Let me take a picture.
Sure you can.
- [Kabir] I can.
- [Kioni] Then let's hear it.
- [Kabir] No, I've
got a better idea.
- [Kioni] What's that?
- [Kabir] Dyker Heights.
- [Kioni] What?
- [Kabir] Oh you're
going to love this place.
(gentle music)
- [Kioni] This place is amazing.
- Yup, it's American
Christmas on steroids.
- I knew people put up
decorations, but this is unreal.
- Like a fairytale?
My mother used to
love this place.
She'd come every year.
- You don't like it?
- I don't know.
It's just another way
for some rich people
to show how rich they are.
- But you could also say
it's pretty magical, right?
- That's what my
mother used to say.
"It's so magical."
Anyways.
(gentle music)
How did the people of
Kenya react to 9/11?
I heard the response around
the world was very... mixed.
- I think most people mourned.
I was pretty young but I
remember seeing the images
and they stayed with me.
It was the first time I'd ever
really thought about
the United States
and the first time
I ever saw New York.
All those tall buildings
and I remember thinking,
who would wanna destroy
something like that?
It was very confusing for me.
(camera beeping)
- [Kabir] What's the matter?
- My memory card is full.
- Did you take
that many pictures?
- [Kioni] I guess so.
- [Kabir] What is
that like a thousand?
- I don't know.
I'll have to buy another one.
- All right, I'll give you one.
I have some at home.
- You're a photographer?
- My mom was fond
of photography.
Are people racist in Kenya?
- People are racist
everywhere, I think.
- I know but after
9/11, it got worse.
- Worse?
- Yeah, I mean you know
when I was growing up,
there were always these jerks
who were making fun of me
because of my skin color.
You know, brown.
Whatever.
But after 9/11, it seemed
like I was the terrorist
and that was really
confusing to me
because I had no idea
why they were saying
such mean things to me.
- Do you resent white people?
- Do I resent white people?
- Yeah.
I can see how some people,
especially in this
country, could resent them.
- No, I mean, I get what
you're saying, but...
If my friend Paddy doesn't
resent white people,
then I see no reason why I can.
- Who's Paddy?
- Paddy's like an uncle to me.
He gave my mother a
job as a bookkeeper
after my father died.
So he's pretty much had
a hand in supporting us
and taking care of us.
- Is he Indian?
- No, Paddy's African American.
He was born during the
Civil Rights movement, too.
He's much older than me.
But he's seen a
lot of crazy stuff.
- Racist stuff?
- Yeah but you know
even with all of that,
he's remained such a positive
person his whole life.
If I had to pick, I'd say
Paddy's the kindest
person that I know.
- What?
- I don't know.
I was a real asshole
to him today.
- To Paddy?
What happened?
- I actually don't
know what happened.
I just bit his head
off for no reason.
- But if he's kind as you say,
he's probably
already forgiven you.
- Yeah, maybe.
- But you should
tell him though.
- That I'm sorry?
- That you're a jerk.
Click.
You have some nice
Christmas decorations.
- They're my mom's.
- So they've been out for...?
- Since she passed, yeah.
- Can we turn them on?
- The lights on the tree?
- Yeah, come on.
Come on.
(gentle music)
How do we turn them on?
These are really
nice decorations.
- Yeah, my mom used
to make ornaments.
Like this one.
- That's really nice.
- People used to gift her
ornaments all the time
because they knew how
much she loved Christmas.
Like this one.
This one's from Paddy.
It's been a wonderful day today.
- It has been really nice.
(gentle music)
[Kioni] What was her name?
- My mom's?
- Yeah.
- Aasha.
Aasha means "hope" in Hindi.
That's a pretty name.
Merry Christmas, Aasha.
- Merry Christmas, mom.
- Kabir?
(Door slams)
- Shivaani.
Shivaani, wait.
- You disgust me.
- Shivaani, it's
not what you think.
- No, then what is it?
- She's just a friend.
She's from Kenya.
- I don't care where
she's from, Kabir.
- [Kabir] Just come
inside, Shivaani.
It's not what you think.
- You know, when you dishonor
me, you dishonor yourself.
You dishonor your mother.
- No, you're misunderstanding.
- I spend a year being
patient with you.
To give you space to go
through all your stuff,
but the truth is that
you were just like this
even before your
mother passed away.
You don't see me.
You only see yourself.
I'm done, Kabir.
- Done?
Done with what?
Shivaani, where you going?
Shivaani, listen to me please.
- You know I didn't
want to marry you?
- You didn't?
- Well, I thought it
worked for our parents,
so why wouldn't it work for us?
I mean it sounded better
than all the dating apps
and all the other nonsense.
It was such a mistake.
- No.
No, Shivaani, it
wasn't a mistake.
- I'm not finished.
Maybe I'm not a trophy
but I'm not a mat
that you can just
walk all over me.
I'm a strong and
capable woman, Kabir,
and I won't be
disrespected like this.
I'm done trying
to make you happy.
I'm done trying to
make you notice me.
Or to make you feel
loved and cared for.
I need those things for myself.
- I understand that.
That's what I'm saying.
This is a good start.
- I'm really done, Kabir.
- [Kabir] Shivaani,
I think we need
to talk about this please.
- Please.
Let's just go
through the holidays
and then we'll get a
divorce and you can go back
to whatever... life you want.
- No, no, no, going back okay.
I've had a bad year.
That's it.
Just come inside.
- It's too late, Kabir.
- Shivaani, I realize I
have wronged you okay.
I know that but
please understand.
You have to know that I--
- You think I don't know?
I don't need your confession.
- Then I don't know
what else to say.
- That's it then I guess.
- No, Shivaani.
Don't go like this.
Come inside.
We can talk.
- Goodbye, Kabir.
(gentle music)
- Everything okay?
- Not really.
- I feel like I should go.
- No, no you stay.
It's okay.
- I don't wanna
cause any trouble.
- Any trouble that
I'm in is my fault.
- Still I should get home.
Can I still get the
memory card please?
- Oh yes.
Sorry.
One second.
I think it's...
Here.
- Thanks.
Is there anything on it?
- No, I don't think so.
- If there is, I'll
send it to you okay.
- Okay.
Yeah.
Kioni, did you wanna
grab some breakfast?
- Silly man.
(gentle music)
- Hey everybody, Mister
bah hum bug is here.
- Hey Paddy.
Meet my friend Kioni.
(camera shutter clicking)
- Oh Jesus, man.
What'd you bring the
paparazzi up in here for?
- I'm an anthropologist studying
the primitive habits
of New Yorkers.
- I'll take it as a compliment.
Where you from?
- Kenya.
- Kenya?
Oh, we have a Christmas special
for folk from Kenya today.
Food and drinks on the house.
- On the house?
- [Paddy] Yeah.
- He means for free.
- You hungry?
- [Kioni] Starved.
- I'm going get you
a Paddy special.
- Oh no, you don't want that.
- KB, you love the
Paddy special, man.
Come on.
- Paddy, it's not even special.
It's french fries,
eggs, salsa, gravy,
and God knows what else.
- [Paddy] It's delicious.
- I'll try it and
an Irish coffee.
- Irish coffee?
- [Kioni] Yes please.
- You know that's
got whiskey in it?
- That's the Irish part right?
- Okay, okay, okay.
She's dangerous.
Okay.
- Yeah, I'll have the same.
- Two Paddy specials.
- Thank you.
What?
- Food ain't gonna
make itself, man.
- Oh come on, Paddy.
Not right--
- But you know where
the kitchen is.
Get cooking.
Come on.
- All right sir.
- And make it three
Paddy specials
if you want one for yourself.
- [Kabir] All right captain.
- So when did you
meet Mister Charming?
- Yesterday in the city.
He showed me around.
- What did he show you?
- I'm kind of obsessed
with Christmas,
so I made him show me
all the Christmas stuff.
- He showed you Christmas stuff?
- Yeah.
We've been all over.
We even went to Brooklyn.
- Dyker Heights?
- Yeah, it was amazing.
- Yeah, sound like the place.
You take any pictures there?
- Sure, but they're on
my other memory card.
I can show you the
picture I took of you now.
- Even better.
- Okay.
(soft music)
- Yeah.
- What's this?
- What is that?
Where'd you take this picture?
Hey, what's taking so long, man?
- It's coming.
It's coming.
Paddy, listen,
I wanna talk to you
about yesterday.
- About what?
- I wanna apologize, okay?
I didn't really mean to
say all those things.
- You wash your hands?
- Yeah, of course.
- Liar.
Aww, man that's disgusting.
- [Kabir] It smells
like fresh roses okay.
- You're gonna burn the food.
- I got it.
Listen, I'm just
saying that I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to say
all those things.
I was just in a very bad mood.
- [Paddy] Really?
- Yeah.
- You wanna make it up to me?
- [Kabir] Sure.
- Come to the party tonight.
- Party?
Shivaani's parents?
- [Paddy] Yup.
- No Paddy, I don't
know about that.
Listen, I had a fight with
Shivaani this morning.
It was just a mess.
- You just apologize because
you're gonna come to the party.
- Come on, don't do this to me.
- Man, but you disrespected me.
You disrespected Christmas
which is the same thing
as disrespecting your mom.
- Okay now that's a stretch.
- You missed the
party last year.
Don't miss it this year.
- That's just not fair.
- It's not about what's fair.
It's about what's right.
Good?
Hey, don't burn my food.
And don't spit in it either.
All right, I know you.
(gentle music)
- You wanna grab breakfast
tomorrow morning?
- I'd like that but let's not
have the Paddy special okay.
- You don't like that?
- No, not really.
- It wasn't good.
- It was horrible.
Gravy and salsa?
- I warned you.
- You should've tried harder.
- Listen I hope this
isn't a goodbye.
- No, of course not.
(gentle music)
- What do you think
about this tree?
This tree's about nine, 10 feet.
What do you think?
Yeah?
- You know, it's
a little too big.
- All right, well I got
more trees out here.
Come on.
Have you been here before?
- [Kabir] No.
- No?
Watch your step over here.
I know it's a little bit muddy.
Sorry about that.
So what size tree
you looking for?
- Don't know.
- Don't know?
So I'll give you an example.
Like for this tree right here,
if you wanna know
the size of it,
it's right here at the bottom.
Take a look.
It says five, six foot.
Is that something
you're looking for?
It's a little bit much larger.
- That's the one.
- That's a good choice.
I'll take it to
the front for you.
- Yeah.
- Tie it on your car?
- Thank you, yes.
- Let's go.
Okay.
(¶ "Troubled Mind" by Arko ¶)
¶ Oh ¶
¶ Don't waste this
time being sorry ¶
¶ Time and people go ¶
¶ Your soul is all I'll carry ¶
¶ Your face is all I'll know ¶
¶ Oh, oh ¶
- You would've loved
this tree, Mom.
(soft piano music)
- [Shivaani] You shaved.
- Yeah.
I wanted to talk to you
about what happened earlier.
- It's okay, I understand.
- You understand?
- Paddy explained
the situation to me.
He told me about your
friend from Kenya.
- You know, you're right.
About what you said earlier.
I don't know what's next.
- We don't have to talk
about it right now.
- Just.
Please.
- Okay.
- I don't know what's
next but I do know
that letting you go
without trying harder
or doing something about
it would be a big mistake.
Shivaani, you
deserve to be happy.
And if being apart is what
makes you happy, then okay,
but I'm not sure
that's what I want.
You said I only see myself.
And I hate to admit
it but it's true,
but I swear Shivaani
I wanna see you, too.
I really wanna see you, too.
- Thanks.
Thank you for saying this.
But I can't give you
an answer right now.
- Yeah, I know.
- Maybe after the holidays.
- Okay.
- Hey.
I'm glad you came.
- Me too.
(soft piano music)
Hey.
I thought--
What are you doing here?
- Paddy invited me.
- Oh he did, huh?
- He said there's
going to be something.
- Some what?
- He just said that
I should be here.
- [Paddy] Hey, is everybody
having a good time?
Are you having a good time?
- [Crowd] Yes.
- That's more like it.
Listen, can you all join me
in this room over here please?
This next room.
Come on, come on, come on.
I like the walk.
That's good, that's good.
Hey everybody.
Last year as you all know
we lost a dear friend.
Aasha.
Aasha Bakshi.
And if you recall last year,
she sang this beautiful song
and we thought in
honor of her memory.
Well just watch for yourselves.
All right that's good,
that's good, that's good.
Okay we're good?
Okay Aasha, take it away.
- Merry Christmas everyone.
This is a beautiful song
that my son really loves.
We were supposed to sing it
together as duet tonight,
but since he's not here,
he will just have
to watch the video.
- Come on.
- Please.
¶ Boy of mine ¶
¶ Although my heart was aching ¶
¶ I seemed to know
that you'd want to go ¶
¶ Pride in your manhood waking ¶
¶ Boy of mine ¶
¶ Although my heart was aching ¶
¶ I seemed to know
that you'd want to go ¶
¶ Pride in your manhood waking ¶
¶ I'll be here ¶
¶ Waiting here ¶
¶ 'Til at the glad
dawn's breaking ¶
¶ I'll hear you say
you're home to stay ¶
¶ Dear little boy of mine ¶
¶ [Kabir] Mom of mine ¶
¶ Mom of mine ¶
¶ It's Christmas
and I'm waking ¶
¶ I'm here to stay ¶
¶ There's no place to go ¶
¶ Pride in the merry making ¶
¶ Mom of mine ¶
¶ I'm here to stay ¶
¶ There's no place to go ¶
¶ Pride in the merry making ¶
¶ Mom of mine ¶
Merry Christmas, Mom.
You are a tricky man.
- Hey, it wasn't me.
It was her.
- Kioni?
- [Paddy] It was all her idea.
- But how did you--
- It was on the memory
card you gave me.
- I don't know what to say.
Thank you.
Thank you, Paddy, and thank
you, Kioni, again. Okay?
- Sure.
- And now I want you to
meet some of these guests.
All right come on.
After both of you.
(bright music)
- You look different today.
- Why different?
- There's a saying in Swahili
(speaks in foreign language).
- What does that mean?
- The letter from the heart
can be read on the face.
- Is that what you see?
A letter from my heart?
- I see your heart
is happy again.
- It really is.
- A gift... Because we
know each other's secrets.
- I will grab your luggage
now and thank you for this.
So I hope we see each
other again some time.
- We will.
I'm sure of it.
- And I wish I had
a gift to give you.
(camera shutter clicking)
- This is enough.
- Sweet.
You take care.
- Bye.
(gentle music)
You're blushing.
- No, I'm not.
- Dork.
(gentle music)
- And Merry Christmas, Kioni.
- Merry Christmas.
(gentle music)
(¶ "A Well Lit Cafe"
By Little Red Church ¶)