Blood leaves the body.
Where does it go?
Deep down
to the other side of the world
leaping out into a heart
that's been waiting for it.
A PLACE IN HEAVEN
Do you know a Rabbi Simcha?
Simcha Mintz, he used
to live here...
Last time, everything you gave me
was full of fat.
You bring me the fat on Sunday,
I'll replace it, on the scale, okay?
If I checked everything with
a microscope you'd be waiting a week.
But it's a good piece.
Everybody under this roof
is going to get what they want.
Two kilo head.
Young man, you're cutting in line.
- People, please.
I'm looking for a Simcha Mintz,
Rabbi Simcha.
Does he live here?
Yes, you step out, take a left,
then take a right, alright?
Out of the store, take a right,
you'll see a blue drawing on the wall.
Take a left, up the stairs,
it's 8 Ezra street.
Second floor,
the door on the right.
Yes, Avram...
You're a real computer.
So, did he find you easily?
Who found me?
The fellow that was here yesterday.
It was you who sent him?
Did I do something wrong?
No, no, no.
Everything happens for a reason.
He was a little excited.
I thought I'd help him.
It's a long story.
You honor me, Rabbi Simcha.
Your stories are like
the wisdom of sages.
Hey,
this helmet is worthless,
got the American ones?
That's all we've got.
It was in the fifties,
Palestinian fighters crossed
the border and we'd strike back.
Wild West.
Full magazines?
Yes sir.
- Water?
First Aid Kit?
Bambi was like a father
to those soldiers...
They knew his operations
were the most dangerous
but they loved him no matter what.
Good to see you.
How's the wife?
- Better.
You sure you want to come?
Yes, sir.
No... no... no...
This Bambi,
where did he get the name?
A girl on the base
saw the movie Bambi.
She told her friends that the
commander
looks like Bambi from the movie.
The guys started joking around
and when he came over,
they called him Bambi.
And that's how he became Bambi.
Everybody forgot his real name.
And he liked his new name, Bambi.
Blessed an thou, Lord, our God,
Who has sanctified us
and commanded us to slaughter.
I'd wait for him every time
he went out on a mission.
I was a cook.
They're back!
He was like King David.
He'd come back from the battle with
one thousand Philistine foreskins.
Proof of his victory.
How many?
- Ten.
A squad of ten?
You got them all?
- They're all here, I've got proof.
How should I know
where you got those genital from?
Why are you looking at me?
I... No reason.
- Each time, no reason?
You're like the great heroes
of the Bible.
You shouldn't envy us.
We die quickly.
But the best place in heaven
is reserved for you.
Where is this heaven of yours?
It's not a place.
It's in the next world.
How was it... good?
Very good, yeah.
Come and see me later.
- After the food. I'm hungry.
Take care.
So, what is the next world?
What's over there?
- That's where the souls go.
How?
When the spirit leaves the body
it returns to its father
the Lord Almighty,
and he decides where to send it.
Heaven or hell?
Yes.
Why does he want me
by his side so badly?
You risk your life to save Jews.
That's the highest virtue.
You're jealous of me.
Yes.
I am jealous of you.
Take it.
Take my spot.
Take it, I'm giving it to you.
What do you want for it?
Is this a flea market?
It's like in Genesis, when Esau
sold his birthright to Jacob.
The Jewish law says it can be sold...
- How much are you paying?
A hundred liras.
We need a contract and witnesses.
- Alright, write up a contract.
Rabbi Simcha, people are
waiting for food here.
I'll write up a contract.
- OK, I'm not going anywhere.
Two copies,
one for me and one for you.
What's that?
- He's selling his place in Heaven.
Erase that, I'm not interested
in your hundred liras.
Your scrambled eggs deluxe.
Write it instead
of the hundred liras.
And make it red hot.
the way I like it.
Scrambled eggs deluxe...
Red hot...
Also write:
'every day for a month'.
What does this have to do
with the fellow looking for you?
The fellow is the son.
Bambi's son?
Bambi's son.
He became religious.
Bless the Lord, he did.
Yesterday, a terrorist
shot his father at the hotel.
And what can a good son do?
Look for you, so he can buy
back his father's place in heaven.
He came to cancel the contract
after forty years.
Would you look at that,
the boy is standing here,
his heart is torn,
and I am deaf and blind to his pain,
dealing with Boris's fat.
Did you give him a good cut?
That's important too.
That's the beauty of creation.
The Lord Almighty gives you
a part to play, and you do it.
You do your part and you leave.
It's all over in a bang.
All the best.
Ayala, tell me,
why do you keep running from me?
- Running?
I don't know.
Scrambled eggs deluxe...
It's the last one.
You want some?
Here you go.
I need my father's blessing.
Alright.
Let's go?
Let's go.
Haven't you got women of your own,
you've got to have my daughter?
I want her to give me a son.
What's that?
Cheers.
I had four children.
Three boys and a daughter.
I lost the boys when we walked
from Yemen to Israel.
The first had a fever for days
and passed away.
The second ate something bad that
a woman gave him, and passed away.
The third fell and never got up.
I just looked away for one second...
We came here just me and her.
Her son is like my son.
His father must be God-fearing.
That means obeying
the commandments.
He's scared the soldier...
I'll obey the commandments.
That easily?
You have to know how.
You have to learn.
To show perseverance.
Let him be, rabbi.
I'll learn.
I'll persevere.
Are you trying to fool me?
Many have tried and failed.
That's the wine talking, rabbi.
Shut up or leave!
Are we children?
I want to see it with my own eyes.
You'll live here and work.
I'll pay you what I give an Arab boy
I'll give you food and a bed.
It's the first rain now.
Till the first rain next year.
Let's see you obey
the commandments and work.
I'm in the army,
how can I work here a year?
You want the army?
Your wish is your honor.
But don't come to this house again.
It's not how we do things here.
Goodbye, rabbi.
Three dignified men from synagogue
asked to marry her to their sons.
What makes you better than them?
If I meet your terms,
you swear you'll give her to me?
My word is like an oath.
You swear you'll give her to me?
I swear.
Quiet.
Two, four, six, seven.
It's called "tefillin".
Why does a Jew bind his arm
in these straps every morning?
To remind himself each morning
right when he gets up
that there is someone above him.
You bind yourself and become free.
Now hold this with your finger.
Yes, hold it down.
Now the "tefillin" for the head.
"Let's go, my beloved,
to meet the bride,
"And let us welcome
the presence of the Sabbath."
"I will betroth you to me
with Righteousness and with justice
"And with kindness and with mercy."
I'm clearing your shit hole.
I got a job from your dad,
every Friday morning,
so it won't smell
during your Sabbath blessings.
You left me a lot of work this week.
Let's run away.
I promised.
I can't.
Ahmed... Ahmed...
Your great Egyptian president
knows how to make noise,
but during wartime,
he runs away.
He's all hot air,
nothing but talk.
Not true, he can also run away...
like a bunny.
Only thanks to your prayers
our army wins. Let's go.
Reading about your
army in the paper?
Just the headlines. ( in Arabic)
Is it worth missing a war
for a girl's cunt?
Fuck your army.
Blessed are thy
that dwell in your house
Blessed is the people
of whom this is true;
blessed is the people
whose God is the Lord.
Can you manage in the field?
Huh?
- Can you manage in the field?
God Willing.
We'll find someone...
It's harsh here in the winter.
I should have done some work,
fixed the ceiling,
let you into the house on Sabbath.
Thank you.
You are like a son to me now.
I wanted to ask something of you.
After I leave this world,
say the Kaddish prayer for my soul.
Every memorial, at synagogue,
so my soul can rest
in the next world.
You don't have to believe it,
just say the words.
We had a deal.
I gave you everything you wanted.
I have nothing left to give you.
Measure for measure.
You too won't get what you want.
Goodbye, father.
Goodbye.
A rich family used to live here.
It's beautiful.
An Arab village is a beautiful place.
It's so close to the border,
you can see Jerusalem's walls.
You're worried about
Jordanian snipers. Show me.
Watch out.
An Arab pacifier.
That goes to the baby's mouth
and the bell tells where it is.
I'll keep it.
For luck.
Here.
From here to here,
it's only two meters, see?
From here to here.
That's where they can fire at us.
- That's enough.
We can bend over.
Every time you come here,
you'll bend over?
Why not?
And when we have a child?
When our child is born, all this
will already be part of Israel.
You see, all this.
We'll have a son,
no matter what he said,
and he'll play here,
in this yard.
Go to sleep, little one.
She's sleeping.
You're going back to base tonight?
It's OK, I like driving at night.
I wanted us to try this month too.
I'm glad you called me over.
Are you worried about me?
I want you to have
what you want, to be happy.
It's OK. It took us 5 years to get
pregnant,
another 5 don't scare me.
It only means we'll be happier
when it happens.
Yeah...
And this time it'll be a boy.
Why shouldn't it be?
No reason.
Give me one reason.
What your father said
doesn't trouble me.
It's nothing, not even nonsense.
It's going to be a boy.
I deserve it.
Good, I think he'll like it.
Turn around.
Who knows why, mama...
The Zebra wears a pyjama?
They say there's going to be a war.
What needs to be will be.
Forgive him, father.
Look at how the older one
holds her sister's hand.
Good girl.
I have forgiven him.
But it's not for me to decide.
I'll be gone in a little bit.
No, no... it's true.
Every man has his time.
But who will say the Kaddish prayer
over me? Just the gravedigger.
Talk to him.
Tell him that if he prays
for my soul
I will do what I can from up there.
To get him what he wants.
The doctors say I can't give birth
again, that it's too dangerous.
You believe the doctors
or your father?
You.
Good girl.
I'm sorry, daddy.
Enough, enough, sweetheart.
- Sorry.
If I had chosen your husband,
would you be hugging me like this?
So in the end I've won.
Is there anybody from the family,
who can say the Kaddish prayer?
No one?
May his Great Name
Grow exalted and sanctified.
Amen.
In the world that
He created as He willed.
May He give reign
to His kingship in your lifetimes
and in the lifetimes of the entire
Family of Israel. Now say: Amen.
You're mad at me?
Yes.
Why don't you go back to the radio?
They need people there now.
I'm sick of working in the radio.
I want you to have a baby
with another woman.
One cinnamon,
one raisons and cheese.
Don't let it get cold.
Wait...
There you go.
A paratrooper's officer
here with us...
Does this mean there won't be a war?
There will be.
And we're going to win. -Oops.
That's okay, it's nothing.
It's fine.
Good, just one second.
We'll swap it. Bon Appetite.
You'll be pregnant again.
Hey,
daddy loves you.
I read that in America they can
find out if it's a boy or a girl.
An ultrasound.
Listen.
It flew off.
I'll make it to the birth,
I promise.
Go into the synagogue, say
the Kaddish prayer for his soul.
It's not a Yemenite synagogue,
is that okay with him?
Alright.
If it's so important to you.
It's nonsense, it's not a big deal.
But not today,
when I get back.
I promise.
Grab the other hand...
Something's stuck here.
Just the legs...
Take it to the jeep
put it with the other bodies.
Don't leave anything behind,
get all the pieces.
Need some help here.
Soldier.
Soldier, hey.
What's your name?
- Asaf...
Asaf, listen to me.
Asaf. Look at me.
Asaf, look at me.
We've got to get all of him,
there are more pieces left.
Alright.
There is more of Asaf...
- Alright, don't worry.
We'll get all the pieces home.
And what is your name?
What is your name, son?
Me?
Nimrod.
Nimrod...
Do what I say
and I'll get you out of here.
I promise to take care of you.
I want to get out of here.
You want to live?
Look at me.
Alone, you don't stand a chance.
You'll die.
Sir, sir.
- What do you want?
We'll leave him here, we gotta go.
- Get out of here.
Sir, he's shell-shocked.
He's done.
Go away! - Our men are going
to start running away.
Where are you from, Nimrod?
- Haifa.
What do you want to
do when you get out?
Here... take it...
I have a girlfriend.
What's your position in the tank?
Loader, sir.
You'll be my loader.
I'll take care of you.
Deal?
Good.
And after that, son
we'll go home.
Sir...
someone from command.
Prince, this is Bambi,
leaving for the oil axis in five.
Do you copy, over?
Move now, the Syrians are advancing,
there's nobody left over there!
Go slow, slow. Take your time.
You're my boy, you're my son...
Let's move, keep your eyes open.
The cannon is gone, right?
Yeah, goddamit.
Give me a light.
Then the tank is worthless.
- Yes.
This tank goes home.
Okay.
Who's wounded, Moti?
- Yes, Moti.
Get him on the busted tank with two
healthy soldiers. They're going home.
Who should I take?
I want to go home.
No, you stay with me.
Erez, you and your driver.
You get on the busted tank.
You're going home.
I'll take the good tank.
- Yes, sir.
We're heading out.
Yes, sir.
Give us their ammo
before they leave.
Here, son, hide it.
Watch over me, watch over me,
I'll be with you forever.
The Syrian have a battalion up there,
maybe more.
Maybe forty, fifty tanks.
You saw the Syrians today.
They fight like lions.
I want to see that you're better.
Yes, sir.
Out.
Go on, son, take command.
Give the orders properly.
You know how long it's been
since I was in a tank?
Danny, break right, hard.
More, more, that's it. Stop.
One Bambi, this is Bambi,
we're hit, over.
Where are we hit?
There's a lot of smoke.
They hit Rami's tank.
- Rami, what's going on?
Rami, talk to me.
Anybody, Mussa, Gadi,
What's the driver's name?
They're all dead.
They're all dead because
they're idiots. We're not!
We won...
Son, we won.
You were good.
We won...
We're hit...
- Put him down here...
Mom...
The bandage... undo it...
Gently.
What's going on...
Lean your head back, son... yes...
Mom... Mom...
Nimrod... Nimrod...
Stay with me...
Let's get out of here already.
Mom... - No, Nimrod, no...
Here I am, talk to me...
Talk to me! Talk!
Nimrod!
He's dead! Let's get out
of here before we get hit again.
Dr. Shekter.
You're the general's son.
He's in a meeting now.
I know, I'm going into
an interview with him.
You'll be his new secretary?
Maybe.
Your dad's?
- Yeah.
Alright, put it on.
Thanks.
Call back command,
they're waiting for an answer...
The new girls are here.
Should I send them in?
There's no need.
Sit down.
I'll take her.
Get her trained for the job
No problem.
Prince, wait up for me,
we'll have lunch together.
Defend yourself...
You hit it, yeah...
You got it, you got it.
Tomorrow morning they'll announce
that your dad's the Chief of Staff.
Tomorrow morning.
Dad, dad, Nimrod's coming down.
Enough. Leave dad alone.
Dad.
- Enough.
Nimrodi, Nimrod, Nimrodi,
Come on, you have to go to school.
Where's your backpack?
You need a sandwich!
Ahinoam, make him a sandwich.
- Not now.
Dad, what's wrong? Dad.
Nimrod!
Here's the sandwich.
- Can't you add some butter...
Sandwich bag.
"Evidence of War Crimes in the 50s"
"General Samuel ( Bambi) Elifaz
Suspected
Of Cutting Off Enemy Genitalia"
Napkin.
Put it in your backpack.
Your lunch is in the fridge.
What are you doing?
Boy, give that paper back.
The blood from our fingertips
has to make it to the heart.
But it's got a long way to go,
so the heart helps it.
The heart is like a big pump...
Why'd you hit them?
No reason.
You hit for no reason?
Look at me.
Is it about me?
No, they were cheating at a game.
They were cheating, I told you.
They were cheating at a game.
You're not an animal.
Learn to restrain yourself.
Like you restrained yourself?
That's the way it was back then.
They did it to us and we did it back.
What's a "disgrace"?
Papers are nonsense. Get in.
Are they going to kick
my dad out of the army?
No one can do that to your dad.
Who's better than your dad?
Your dad was the hero
of the 73 war...
They're all shit, they're jealous.
Alright, you'll ride up front today?
I'm going in.
Are you happy?
Why?
We have more time together.
Yeah.
Disgraceful.
Nimrod... Nimrod...
If anybody makes fun of you,
you tell them your dad is
going to be the Prime Minister.
You tell them one year...
One year from now,
you'll be moving into the PM's house.
You remember I showed
you where he lives? -Yeah.
One year!
I promise!
I don't want to...
Enough, what do you want?
"We hereby agree on transferring
"Samuel ( Bambi) Elifaz's
place in heaven
"to Simcha ( Rabbi Simcha) Mintz"
Nimrod...
Nimrod.
For the 1973 War Anniversary
conference Reception, take a right.
There's food and drink, enjoy...
Hello, welcome.
For the 1973 War Anniversary
conference Reception...
I'm second on the panel, you see?
Take the room's voucher,
and fold it up, in your pocket...
Come.
Hello.
There's refreshments, want some?
There he is, the Minister of Defense.
He used to be my soldier.
- Bambi, I got you a meeting
with the President's cousin...
He works out of the Congo...
- Not now.
I want you to meet him,
he was my soldier.
I could have been in his place today.
- Sir, stay back please.
It's okay, I know him. David!
- Sir, please.
It's fine, I'm staying back.
David.
Hello.
- Hello.
Leah Belkin, nice to meet you.
- Nice to meet you.
You don't know me,
but we're connected somehow.
Nimrod's mother.
You remember?
We never got a chance to speak.
He was one of my soldiers.
When I came to console the
family I was asked not to come in.
It was a bit fresh, you know.
So, you're here to speak
at the conference?
Yes.
It's an important conference,
It was an important battle.
I was a part of it.
Yes, it was an important
battle for me too.
Before it I had a life.
And after it, I didn't.
You've got nothing to say?
You're thinking, let this crazy
lady make a scene and then leave.
It's a pain that never leaves.
I know.
You don't know.
I heard his best friend, Asaf,
was killed by his side
a few hours beforehand.
- That's true.
But if I'd left him in the field,
he wouldn't have made it.
How would you know?
Are you God?
At least he would have had a chance.
Mom, come on.
I won't leave you.
Wherever you go I'll chase you.
Whenever you fall,
you'll know it was me.
I know important people.
Not everybody's your pawn.
- Mom, let's go...
Look at that, they're using
rounded clubs.
What good is that?
You need an angle, a square.
Beat the Palestinians
to break their bones.
Here, honey, it's sweet.
In Russia they'd do
"Boom Boom" to them all.
Mistake.
Today, wars are fought
on this screen.
Round clubs, square clubs,
it all looks the same on TV.
I'll talk to him.
Rabin was my Company Commander.
He's not an idiot like the others.
I'll talk to him.
Fools, fools.
You need angles, squares, triangles.
Why aren't you eating?
Idiots.
I'm done.
He's mad at you.
- He'll get over it.
Everything passes.
Samuel?
Hello.
Your father was worried.
Is everything alright?
Are you mad at me?
No.
You're allowed to be.
Your sisters are mad.
How do you know?
Because since I've been here,
they stopped coming by.
I'm not mad at you.
You know, it's no good living
with someone who's mad at you.
I'll talk to your father,
he'll let you have your Bar Mitzvah
like your friends.
If I'll ask him, he'll agree
Even though he hates religion.
I know how much it matters to you.
I've seen you do that thing,
with those black straps on your arm.
I don't want you
to ask anything for me.
You're angry at me.
I'm not.
I feel sorry for you.
I saw you in the pictures they sent him
from Russia with other girls.
But he chose me, didn't he?
A beautiful woman
is a good thing.
Samuel, come here, baby...
Come to bed... Come...
It's a problem, you can't get
into any of the good units.
There are good positions
with intelligence units too.
You can't have a military career
unless you come from an elite unit.
What's this medical note you got?
A murmur.
Something in the heart.
I was worried they'd find out
I'm color-blind.
Don't worry about the murmur,
I'll take care of it.
It's a blackout, the entire block.
You know, I never told you,
a few years ago...
I thought about leaving it all,
going to Africa,
I wanted to see what this
making money thing is all about,
I wanted to cheat myself,
like dying and taking a pill
against the pain...
Then I thought of another option,
I'd go into the office
of the Minister of Defense...
I know that it was him behind it all.
I put together a whole file...
I never talked to you about it.
I wanted you to grow up clean.
I thought of going to his office
with my gun,
to the Minister of Defense...
Security never disarmed me...
When we were in the room together,
after they served us coffee
and all that,
I'd pull out the gun,
look him in the eyes and shoot.
Prison is not a factor.
I care about what they'll say
in 50 years, in 100 years,
what will people think
when they hear the name Bambi...
The lights are on.
I'm sure it would have put me
in a very good spot.
Only a man who's been horribly
wronged would do something like that.
That was the other option.
Then I looked at you.
Tell me, maybe you know,
how does a baby become a boy,
and then a teen, and now a man.
Is this a miracle?
Is that what it's called?
That was my strength.
Watching you grow up.
That's how I knew
I had something better.
I've got you instead of a gun,
you see?
You're done? Want a cigarette?
Take it, take it...
What's wrong, Nimrod?
- I can't breathe, my heart.
Get the doctor.
- What's wrong?
I twisted my ankle.
Your ankle? You said
you can't breathe...
It's just an ankle,
calm down.
Stretcher.
Careful. Careful.
Tie him down.
We need one more man to make
ten for the prayer. Anybody?
Medic.
When are you back with your unit?
You look strong already.
The army doesn't think so.
They're on to my murmur too.
Watch out, it's hot.
Eat, eat the meat.
Leave those weeds alone.
Salt...
If it was up to me,
instead of a month off
from the army,
I'd put you in jail.
Strapping "tefillin" in an ambush...
Your commander should be deposed
for not putting you there.
Salt.
Run for Prime Minister again
and you can depose them all.
I got one good thing out of you.
If not for you,
your mother would be here now.
A pot-bellied 60-year-old lady.
Thanks to you, I have this.
Eat her food.
- I eat kosher. I don't eat pork.
I want you to get off the pill.
I want a son.
Let Nimrod read it.
Go ahead, his honor.
- Go ahead... go ahead.
You got the bad knife, Rabbi Haim,
Would you like to switch?
- No. As long as the salad is good.
I found a match for you.
It's been on my mind for a while.
She's born-again too.
It's good for your
spiritual connection. Hold on.
Thank you, Rabbi Haim.
- I should be thanking you.
He who brings a match together
in Israel has a place in heaven.
Did you know that?
Can I get to know her first?
Meet her?
Of course,
that's the way to do it.
But not to doubt and babble.
What would one or two meetings
tell you anyway?
You'd know if she's beautiful.
Well, she is beautiful.
Are you happy to know that?
Yes.
No.
It scares you.
Be happy.
A beautiful woman is a good thing.
Shall we set up a meeting?
No... you're right.
I don't need to see her first.
Alright, but we'll wait, a year.
"And they seemed only a few days
to him" as with Jacob and Rachel.
Get the salad ready
and call the guys, alright?
You're here,
I was about to leave.
I'm here.
How are you?
- Bless the Lord.
Good.
Need anything?
Money? Rent?
- I don't pay any money here.
In the morning I clean the
synagogue instead of money.
I like this place,
it's what I need.
Not bad at all.
At your age, I lived in places
that made this look like a palace.
If it wasn't for your mother,
I would still be a savage.
Leave mom out of this.
Come over.
Come over sometimes.
If the problem is a kosher kitchen,
we'll make a kosher kitchen.
You think it's that simple?
You know how many commandments
you have to learn for a kosher kitchen?
We'll get disposable plates,
we'll order catering.
We'll make do.
- It doesn't work like that.
If a non-Jew touches wine,
it's no longer kosher.
If she's there, nothing can be kosher.
- Then don't have wine.
You want me to come,
then she needs to leave.
First time?
Yes.
I thought maybe...
Before you were born again.
No.
And you've been with a man?
I have.
Don't worry, it'll be fine.
We can do it later too.
It's a commandment,
you can't postpone a commandment.
Let alone this one.
It's the first commandment
in the Bible.
Should I turn it off?
It's beautiful, I love it.
Everybody's adding levels,
but this house hasn't changed.
Families grow, you have to build.
God Willing, we'll need to build
another story too.
When I was a child, I had a wall
like this by the house.
I'd stand there for hours
with a ball.
Toss it and catch it,
toss and catch.
I don't know how the wall held up.
When we have a child,
he'll play against this wall too.
God Willing.
We have to ask whose shed this is,
if we're allowed to use it.
Are you happy?
Yes.
Excuse me, my ball fell into
your yard, can I get it?
Of course.
Thanks.
Why?
In the Bible, Nimrod rebelled
against the Lord Almighty,
so if I change my name,
it might set me on a new path.
Sit.
The Sages say that Nimrod wore
"Adam's coat of skins",
his great-great-grandfather's.
This coat could not be pierced
by any sword.
Bullets of a gun were like
watermelon seeds to it.
The Sages tell that one day,
Nimrod went out to the field to hunt,
and met the evil Esau there.
Evil meets evil.
Nimrod said to the evil Esau,
that everything in the field was his.
There were savory foods there,
like deer and elk.
But Esau would not give in.
He said, who do you think you are?
So they decided to fight,
winner take all.
But Esau was no fool.
He said to Nimrod,
that's not fair,
let's see you fight
without the coat.
Nimrod, who had the coat his whole
life, thought its strength was his.
He forgot it was all from the coat.
He tossed it aside,
and Esau jumped on the coat.
And with the coat,
it was an unfair fight.
This is your name.
Whoever named you,
named you hard.
But whatever you do with it,
that is up to you.
Why are you looking so miserable?
Did you get your period?
- Yes.
Then say you got it.
Say, I'm not pregnant.
I got it.
So you got it.
You got it last month too.
Two months ago, three months ago.
We'll wait as long as it takes.
No.
I want a separation.
Now.
If you hadn't gotten it,
we'd keep going, have dinner,
go to sleep.
We wouldn't be fighting,
You wouldn't have said
that you want a separation.
I would have said it at some point.
When?
Tomorrow.
Then say it tomorrow.
It's hard, being with me?
- That's not the problem,
Sometimes things start out hard,
then they work out.
Why shouldn't things work out
for us in the end?
Because from the first moment,
you've treated me like an enemy.
From the first glance
on the alter.
Yes, it's true.
And why do you think that is?
I don't know.
Tell me. What's my problem?
I believe it's all about the family.
You haven't told me anything,
but I'm sure
that growing up without a mother
means something.
Do you ever listen to yourself?
It's psychology.
There's no such thing.
There is good in the eyes of the Lord
and bad in the eyes of the Lord.
I'll tell you why I didn't
want you from the very start.
Should I say it?
How can someone want a whore?
From the first moment,
I saw who you were.
Don't touch me, I'm on my period,
I'm forbidden!
Hello.
Your father isn't here.
Come in.
Will he be back today?
No, he's in Tel Aviv,
at his conference...
Come here...
Where's my dog?
He couldn't hear, couldn't see.
We had to put him to sleep.
Come, let me give you some food.
Just a bit.
Eat, no one's watching.
My child...
An old lion...
what does he feels
right before the end?
Surprise?
Because the end,
though inevitable,
must also be a surprise.
Is that it?
Is it over?
And then, the summaries.
What did I get done?
What did I never get to?
What was true?
What was a lie?
No...
My wife is pregnant...
Let me go to her...
No...
Take a right and then a left...
Cancel the contract.
I'll go to my Rabbi,
you'll be disgraced.
No Jew will talk to you.
Cancel this contract!
You've got a place
in heaven, anyway.
It's mine, he gave it to me.
You got a place in heaven,
so why?
Dad... dad... daddy...
Blessed are you, Our Lord,
King of the Universe,
By whose Word everything
comes to be. -Amen.
Your father.
If you love him this much...
It's good...
I have no children, you see?
Tea?
When I was a child
I'd face this window
and stare for hours
at the buildings, the sky.
I was interested to see what people
were doing inside their houses.
Nimrodi, your friends
from the Yeshiva are here.
One minute, okay?
Drink your tea.
It'll get cold.
I'm sorry.
Peace be upon you.
Upon you too.
Where is the master?
- Here.
Master.
There you go, Rabbi Simcha,
give it to the cats, alright?
It's good against the mice.
You can carry it all?
All the best. - All the best.
What can I get you, Rabbi Daniel?
Hold up, hold up.
Let us walk together.
It's better this way.
Let's walk.
Say, what did you have
to fear of the next world?
It's a long story.
Have we got time?
Looks like we'll
be there in just a bit.
Let's start.
If there's time, fine.
If not, that's alright too.
In Poland, during the war,
right when the Nazis came
the Polish seized the opportunity.
Two of them came into our house.
I knew one from the streets,
the other was a blond man.
My father and I
hide under our beds.
In a minute or two,
they took everything.
The menorah,
candlesticks, everything.
Put it all in a sack.
Suddenly, I had to sneeze.
I held it in, held it in hard.
The Polish men were already
on their way out...
But the sneeze came out first.
A big, loud one.
The Polish men stopped,
they looked at each other
and ran back in.
And then my dad,
the big hero,
came out, wiping his nose,
as if it was him.
The Polish men grabbed him.
One held him, the other held a knife,
and they cut his eyes out.
My dad was screaming,
and they were laughing.
He had a high-pitched voice.
I was already a big boy,
as tall as I am now.
I could have helped him,
but I didn't.
I didn't move.
That's it.
So when my day will come.
Will come? It has come.
In a few moments
we'll be facing heaven's gate.
If I'm let into heaven, all is well.
If I'm sent to hell,
I'll show him the contract. Here!
We could use a breeze.
Are you worried?
You have nothing to worry about.
What is the next world?
It's your children.
If you have a good son,
you have a place in heaven.
Shall we?
And your story, what about it?
For my father
Director and Writer
Yossi Madmony
Producers
Moshe Edery, Leon Edery, David Mandil
Alon Moni Aboutboul
Tom Graziani
Rotem Zisman-Cohen
Yossi Pollak
Keren Berger
Sophia Ostritsky
Sasha Avshalom Agarounov
Gabi Amrani
Michael Aloni
Director of Photography
Boaz Yehonatan Yacov
Editor
Arik Lahav Leibovich
Production Designer
Miguel Merkin
Sound Designer
Alex Claude, Daniel Meir
Music
Ophir Leibovitch
Subtitles:
Cinematyp Studios Ltd.