Reached? All good good?
You here would be even better
This rotten party will take the whole night
Kababs are excellent. I’ll get you some?
It’s my Tuesday
Ya, tell me
Yes, it was all so dirty
I've cleaned up the kitchen
and one room
When you come tomorrow,
you do the outside. Ok?
Yup, that adjacent room is shut,
but I'll lock it from this side
Yes, I'll eat. You also eat
Would their party food have fallen short
had they let you have some?
No, silly! I'm just saying
Ok then. I'll lock up properly
and go to bed. Bye
-Who’s that?
-Open the door
- Hey, sweetheart
Open the door
Open quickly
Who is it?
How does it matter?
Just open the door
We’ll have fun
Come on, open the door.
Just this once
Will you open or not?
We’re both all alone. Open the door. We’ll have fun
I won't stay long
You can clap your hands and do this on the street
Now that you’re in a building your conduct has changed?
Hello, Shahrukh?
Where are you?
Anil is with you too, right?
Yes, please come soon!
Take the left at the basti,
you'll get here in five minutes
Yes, please hurry up
Fine
I see. Calling your admirers?
Am I not enough?
Open up!
Open bitch!
Are you going to open or not?
I’ll see how you stay here
I’ll be watching you
Stop your drama or I’ll get you thrown out of
this building back onto the street
A Place of Our Own
RESTROOM
Brother, has that other girl gone?
Ages ago
She forgot her purse
Read this notice
YOUR BELONGINGS ARE YOUR RESPONSIBILITY
Is there a number?
-Now, what should I do with this?
-Told you, leave your phone number
Didi, tea?
Where are you?
Please try to come quickly
Yes, I’m sitting in Raj's shop. Come soon
RAJ SWEETS AND RESTAURANT
-You’ve come
-Tell me
I was so scared last night!
What if he had got in?
Hey, it’s ok
I couldn't sleep all night, left
that place first thing this morning
I don't want to go back there
How many places can we
give up on?
Come. Let’s go and tackle him
Sir, the whole area’s like that.
Full of students
Vacant in the morning,
gone by evening!
You could check out Nehru Nagar
I'll get you the best house.
You have Gupta's word!
Fine, I'll get there soon. Okay!
No one actually entered, right? It’s not
like anything happened to you
Oh, will we wait till it happens?
How can we stay here if it's not safe?
And you told us it was an empty, locked
room. So how did that guy get in?
How would I know?
Only you can answer that!
What’s that supposed to mean?
Well, you people know all sorts.
Must have been some pal of yours
-Would we invite people to harass us?
-So I would? Huh! Talking rubbish!
This building never had
these problems before
Decent people live here
But these comings and goings of yours
have made the building unsafe
Right, this building is full of decency!
Everyone is decent, except the two of us
And most decent of all –
last night’s intruder!
Who told him I'm alone here?
And how did he get the key?
So you... are... accusing... me?!
Enough! Give back the keys and get out!
“Get out” means?
It means vacate the place.
I don't want to rent this flat to you
-Look, we are just talking!
-No, you are accusing me!
Enough, now pack up your stuff and get lost
Hey Gupta!
We have paid a deposit, the rent,
and your commission too!
Talk too much,
and I’ll see you behind bars!
Fine, give me your account number,
you’ll get your money back
You took cash, give us cash back.
We don't have any account numbers!
You don't have a bank account?!
What sort of a shady racket do you run?
Hey! What do you mean, shady racket?
I have messaged you the account
details, just transfer the money
Fine! It’ll happen.
Look at the arrogance!
Get going now!
Just look at their arrogance!
What’re you doing here? This is
still our place. Get out!
Come to be entertained? Morning show’s over.
Out! Just leave my home!
I'll call you later
Gupta ji has sent me
-Where is Gupta ji?
-He's gone out on work
He hasn't transferred the money yet
What’s that account number
you gave? Who's Harish?
Tell him, whoever Harish may be,
just transfer the money there
You people and your shady deals...
And if it’s such a hassle,
let him pay us back in cash
Big Brother, can you back up a bit?
-Does she know?
-No, she doesn’t. Shush!
Follow us on your scooter
-Where are we going?
-We are going. Come
What? Why is she calling?
Yes, what?
Why are we going towards Rahul Nagar?
Just follow us
How often have I told you
not to use the phone while driving?
You'll end up at the police station
or the hospital, I'm telling you
Fine. I'm coming
-Should I stop?
-No, keep going. She'll come
Now why’s this one calling?
It’s ok, I have earphones
I'm at work ! It'll take me
a couple of hours
Khala, why does every new boy run off?
Now listen. Just call Neelam,
she'll manage all your work
There's no problem
with the ingredients!
You haven't got the hang of it
yet, that’s all
Believe me, aunty!
Shahrukh miyan, move aside
I'll call you back, I'm driving
This is to see the road, not to see one’s face
“Watch the road” – really?
Pull it off and chuck it then!
It’s not here for your use
-What does she do?
-What?
Where does she work?
-She's a counsellor at an NGO
-Is she very educated?
-Yes, she’s a graduate
-Wow!
Why, what did you think?
No, she seems educated,
that’s why I asked
Why have you brought me here?
At least we have a place to keep
our stuff and live for a month
I got the keys from Chandni this morning.
She’s gone to Jabalpur for some shows
You see this weather? That, plus
your tantrums - I’m fed up of both!
Are you just going to stand there,
Shahrukh miyan? How about a hand?
Aren’t you coming?
Then guard the stuff, ok?
Salaam!
-Here you go, good morning!
-Good morning
Slept well? Were you
dreaming of someone?
Who?
Don't you like the house?
After all that happened,
you still brought me here?
After all that happened, she still
let us have the house, be thankful!
Where would you be roaming otherwise?
I see! We’re supposed to spend
our lives being thankful?
So when the cop slaps us
should we be grateful he didn’t
beat us with his stick?
“Be thankful”, she keeps saying!
Where did this cop come from?
This is different from that, sistah!
And if you insist on not being indebted
we are paying her a month's rent
I see? You're right
So now she wants rent from us?
She didn't ask. I felt we should pay
Look, now don’t stretch this too
I didn't do anything wrong
She’d become so bossy.
How long can one take that?
So I refused to give her a sari.
Was that such a big crime?
Refusing a sari for the Bhujariya festival
is a very different thing
None of us have easy lives, no?
And how long will you
hang on to old grudges?
Let it go and hurry up now
Isn’t this a rather fancy colony?
Well, we can at least try.
And now I can afford the rent
Hmmm, “rent”! Fly too high and
you’ll end up flat on your face
Do I look okay?
Don't you have smaller earrings?
We're going to office!
Listen, lend me your scooter today?
I'll also check out a couple of places
After you drop me to office,
go wherever you wish
Just remember one thing
Pick me up on time
Ok madam, as you order
Let's go
Hurry up!
Wherever you go, look for
a house in a good area
We don't need a good area.
We need a roof over our heads
We'll look for a good area later, okay?
But still, try to find in a good area
-Here’s your office.
-Pick me up on time, don't be late
-Ok, as you say
But you meet me out here,
else I’ll push off alone!
Alright, just be on time
-What time should I be here?
-5.30
-Ok.
-Ok. See you. Bye.
-Hi, good morning!
-Hello, good morning!
-How are you?
-All right, and you?
-Not so good
-Why?
I was up all night
on the phone with a client
She has been outed to her family
They are pressurising her
so much that she’s feeling suicidal
So I was on this call all night
plus I have four sessions today
And I'm already exhausted!
I too have four sessions today,
one client’s coming from quite far
So I might need to spend
a long time with them
So let's kick off the day with
a strong cup of tea. Want some?
-Absolutely!
-Coming up
I just ran into Roshni.
Still looking for a place?
-If you hear of anything, let me know
-Will do
If you’re done with this file,
shall I put it away?
-So what time is that client coming?
-Any time now
-Sita, make me tea
-Tell Sandeep
-I don’t like his tea
-Sandeep, make tea for Sir
-Make it nicely with, ginger
-And use your head. Not the kind workers drink!
Oh, Sandeep bro! Make a couple
of aloo parathas today?
-Laila?
-Yes sir. I'm Laila, she's Roshni
Pankaj Parwana, that’s me.
I’m a writer.
Why were you standing outside?
Waiting in here is no problem. Great
view, and they serve excellent tea
Waiting someplace for 10 minutes
is very different for us and for you, sir
-Why’s that?
-They might not have let us in
It's only because we were
with you that we could enter
-Seriously?
-Yes!
What world are you living in?
India is a democracy!
Every human being
may come and go freely
Besides, we had to fight
to gain our freedom, madam!
You can’t get your rights
without fighting for them
Weren’t you going to show us a room?
Yes, but I don't have the key
right now. No big deal!
I'll get the key
and we'll coordinate
I'll call you and we'll fix
another time to see it
-Tea?
-Please
Three cups of tea!
Dinesh called me a couple of days ago.
He was telling me about you
About your troubles with
trying to rent a house
Yes
And he also told me how you got
your job with great difficulty
Masters in Social Work, right?
Very impressive!
I'm a very curious sort of guy,
I’ve long wanted to meet people like you
I had seen some of you
passing by on the streets
But...er...never had the opportunity
to properly meet any of you
-Sir, smoking is not allowed
-Come on, what are you saying?
Can we at least drink our own water?
Sheer robbery!
Go to any restaurant, hotel, theatre
you cannot carry your own water!
You have to buy it,
they're selling even water!
So did you know
right from childhood?
Know what?
Er...I mean...your condition
...about being different
Different?
We all know ourselves, don’t we, sir?
But it's a bit difficult
to explain to others
Er...when did your parents become
aware of your condition?
Excuse me, sir. This is not
a "condition", this is our reality
Quite right
As we grow up, parents
eventually realise the truth
Whether they accept it or not
That’s it! This is exactly
what I wanted to know
Whether your parents accept it or not.
Because I’ve heard that their gangs...
er...come and kidnap the children
And you people don't want to live
with your families either
I don't know who you are talking about
but I was turned out of my home
We are on our own because
our parents don't accept us
If they do, society, relatives,
make our lives hell
So that's why you join the gharanas (houses)
I hear there’s a lot
of exploitation there as well
They have a strong hierarchy too?
Sir, shall we first talk about
what we face in the outside world?
Let us sort out the internal matters
of the gharanas (houses) ourselves
-So you’re a counsellor?
-Right
I have heard your community engages
in dubious activities...
Meaning, unsavoury stuff...
Aren’t we here to discuss
renting a room?
Yes
-Then what’s with all these questions?
-No, look, I am not judging anyone!
-Why are you bringing up these things?
-Er...I just wanted to know...just by the way
Please excuse me for a minute
He’s just wasting our time. Been over an hour
Sorry, I had to take that call
How about asking before taking a photo?
-Of course, sure!
-Delete it!
-Come on, it’s just for my own records!
-No, delete it right now!
There’s no need to worry!
There, it’s deleted
We are leaving.
Let us know about the house
Sure
What was that? Who was that?
I thought he'd be genuine
Genuine! He was a genuine bastard!
Come on, have some genuine tea
Ma’am, I got to know at the Public Toilet that my purse is with you.
Where should I collect it from
I’ll let you know
-Whose message is it?
-That same girl
-What’s she saying?
-About that purse she forgot
Hasn't the weather become pleasant?
Shall we make our home on that island?
Someone called Preeti will come.
Please give her this purse.
-When will she come?
-By 6pm, she said
Just ten more minutes.
You can give it to her yourself
Excuse me! Do you have my stuff?
We spoke on the phone
Yes, here. Please check it
-That’s okay.
-No, no...just check anyway
Thank you so much
-Will you join me for a cup of tea?
-Certainly!
Why don’t you go in too?
You know me, don’t you?
I do, Preeti
Oh! Now I get why you were so hesitant
You know each other from before!
-Do you still live there?
-No. I left
Why? I heard you were
getting married. Did you?
-No. That’s why I had to run away!
-Oh my my!
Your old area seems to be full of runaways!
This one, you, who else?
And did you run away on your cycle?!
-You look very nice now
-Thank you
I always knew you were different
And I always knew you'd run away
from home rather than marry!
-Looking for someone?
-Actually, a friend was to come
Ah, here they are.
Meet my friend Sandy
-Hi, I’m Roshni
-I’m Laila
NEW HOPE
Social and Mental Health Counselling Centre
-Were those two clients tested yesterday?
-They were
What about the 4 o'clock meeting?
Had to postpone it, they called.
I'll let you know as soon as I hear from them
-Hi Roshni!
-Hi
-How are things?
-All well
-Is Laila here?
-Yes, inside
-Did you find a place yet?
-The search is on
Don’t worry, all the best!
-Do try as well!
-Absolutely!
-Ok Bye.
-See you!
How much longer, man? Look,
I took off early from work
Anyway, you said 5.30,
and I said I’d get here by 6!
We'll wait another
ten minutes, that’s all
Fine
-What did he say?
-Just being difficult
Let's wait another ten minutes,
then we'll leave
Sorry, I got late too
I had finished, but the boss called
to say guests were coming
Chicken would be served
That too, slow-cooked in the clay pot,
not in the pressure cooker!
For their own tasks they’re all modern,
but expect traditional labour from us
I keep telling you to start
something of your own
Yes, you have. But is it
that easy, my friend?
Think we’ll get one of these nice rooms?
And the balcony, perfect to drink
evening tea, when it rains!
(sings a Hindi film song)
-Not that one!
-What shall we sing then?
(sings another Hindi film song)
You're the ones looking to rent?
Follow me
-Who is it?
-Madam, I’ve brought tenants to see the house
-Who?
-Those two
How often must I tell you
not to bring such people?
I said I wanted a proper family
But madam, the place has
been vacant for so long!
Let it stay vacant, but
we won't rent it to these people
Give it a try at least
- Ok Madam
- Next time make sure it’s a family
Begumpura, the city
No grief or darkness there
Yes, Jannat?
How will I manage alone, sis?
Listen, I have never done this sort of thing
No, I feel a bit nervous
What if something goes wrong?
Good idea, I’ll ask Roshni
But see if you can get someone else
Okay then. Bye
What new trap is this now?
Oh, that was Jannat. She has to be
in Sagar, for some case
Will you go with me on Friday?
I told all of you earlier, I’d rather
stay away from stuff like this
Please, just this once
Brother, listen. Boss is
leaving right now
Open the gate only after we’ve left, please
Yes, I’ll handle  it
Didn't I say to park at the bend
and give me a missed call?
Why are you parked right here?
-Sorry, will this cause a problem?
-Let's go!
-But what’s the matter?
-They keep an eye on everything
Here, see this. How does it look?
Like a wedding card!
What is this?
You’ve put in veg biryani?!
Aren't you ashamed?
Your aunt agreed to this?
Lots of kids come to the
coaching class there
Chowmien, biryani – they relish
that stuff, they’ll lap it up!
Then there are all those Vegetarian
Tuesdays and Fridays...
-A ‘Veg Tuesday’ is sitting right here!
-I see!
-Khala cooks all this?
-Sure she does
-Did you bring my clothes?
-Here you go
I've told Khala to hire a couple
of helpers to get it all ready
I suggested a partnership
to this one, but she isn’t agreeing
-Whose partner are you making her?
-Khala's. Business partner
I don't want to be anyone's partner.
No time. I work two shifts already
-Sure, you have mighty ships sailing!
-Inshallah, that too will happen!
What a posh hotel!
-Shall I bring you their menu card?
-Sure, not that it’ll be of use!
-Pick us up on time, at 5
-I'll be around, don’t worry
Where’s the washroom?
When we try to obtain caste certificates,
they want records going back 50 years
-Are you Laila and Roshni?
-This way, please
We exist without documents
or govt benefits
For how many generations
will this carry on?
That’s what we want to ask
both, govt and society
I have put before you
the truth of our lives
Forgive me if we said
anything to upset you
Thank you, Suman
Many of us were unaware of those
complex bureaucratic and legal issues
And now, friends, we move to our next
session
Our panelist Laila ji is here,
along with her friend Roshni
We extend a warm welcome to them!
Do join us on stage
Laila and Roshni will speak of
transpeople’s challenges and struggles
Greetings!
My name is Laila
and I am a transperson
Thank you all, for giving me
the opportunity to speak here
I was asked to tell you about
the challenges we face in our lives
I don't know where to begin!
We are always kept out -
of society and from its progress
Take ration cards, identity cards, admissions
Or scholarships. Why aren't we included?
When people encounter a group
of us begging on the roads...
they say, "Look, these people
have come again to beg!"
But have you ever wondered what
brings them to the street?
I’d also like to tell all of you
that we suffer violence every day...
at the hands of our families,
on the roads, at workplaces
Now that’s never become a major issue
The daily murders of transpersons
don’t make it to the news media
Sometimes when a woman is raped and killed,
people hold candlelight vigils
But nobody’s ever lit
a single candle for us
Looks like we run out of candles
on such days
So all I want to say is
that if we have your support
we can make rapid progress, and
transform society's attitudes –
show we can be productive at work,
have jobs, not just clap for alms
Thank you, Laila! I’d like
to reassure you...
that we are all with you
on every front
Now I open this session for questions
But before that, Roshni,
would you like to add anything?
So please ask your questions
one at a time
You have a distinct culture, with
its own separate space in society
When you come to our homes,
we are happy to give you some money –
when the groups come,
for different occasions
So my question is - do you feel
this culture ought to be preserved?
This culture is also a creation
of society at large –
the same society that has kept us
separate, we didn’t keep it separate
We haven't kept aloof, it’s society
that thinks of us as different
This is not a culture
It is a burden we carry,
placed on us by society
Perhaps we will have to lug it
until you too come forward to change things
-Hi Didi!
-Hello!
-I really liked what you said.
-Thank you!
-A friend wants to speak to you
-Yes, sure
He will be so glad to meet you
-Will you meet him?
-Sure, we will
Could I have your phone number?
You know the medical store
by the hotel?
-Should we talk to them?
-Ask and see?
Yes, come soon
-Come on!
-Ask!
-Hey! Coming with us?
-What?!
-You available? Oh, she
seems educated!
Stop right there!
This is what you have been taught?
Is this what you learn in college?
Or from your parents?
Come back here! I’ll teach you
your first lesson!
Hey Sixer! You'll teach us?
Why are you tangling with these
insolent brats? Let’s go!
You are always ready to fight
anywhere, with anyone
-Let it go. They’re just kids!
-What do you mean they’re kids?!
Anyone can simply come along
and insult us
Don't we look human to them?
And didn’t I tell you to be on time?
Will you never understand?
Do not ignore my miserable plight
Averting your gaze, weaving excuses
I cannot bear this separation, beloved
Why do you not hold me close?
Why?
Consider it payment of fine from
the entire male community
Even if you drove us around your whole life,
it wouldn’t make up for all the abuse
But let it be –- I won't burden you
with the debts of all men!
Two enchanting eyes
with their hundred deceptions
Have you never used these abuses?
I have! That's why
I’m feeling so terrible
I’ve seen how it takes just one word
to cancel out someone's life
Good! If you’ve understood that,
our pain has been of some use.
Now get going!
Nobody cares to tell my beloved
of my state
Like the burning lamp, each part volatile
I turn into a whirling celestial being
No sleep for my eyes, no peace for the body
Neither do you come, nor send your address
No peace for the body
No sleep for my eyes
No sleep for my eyes, no peace for the body
Neither do you come, nor send your address
Do not ignore my miserable plight
Averting your gaze, weaving excuses
The longer you look, the more
you’ll feel like calling
Let it be!
Look, friends!
This is the very sari that
drew a wedge between two fond hearts!
That built a wall between Laila and Chandni!
How did your meeting go
with that woman yesterday?
I was a little late,
so couldn't meet the doctor
Laila ma'am, there’s someone
waiting for you outside
-Who? Ask them in
-They insist on speaking to you outside
-How are you?
-Fine, how are you, Sis?
I’m fine too. Who’s come with you??
-Elder brother
-Right. And he wouldn’t come in
-So how's everyone at home?
-Granny’s very ill, Sis
-What’s wrong with her?
-Her blood pressure. It’s shot up again.
She misses you. Keeps saying your name.
Okay, I'll come tomorrow
-You'll come for sure?
-Yes
But...
I understand
Sorry, Sis! But please come tomorrow
-For Granny’s sake
-I will
Don’t delay, Sis. She has
very little time left
Yes, I'll come
When are you returning
the rest of the money?
You had taken 15,000 as
advance, rent and commission
So what if the name is different?!
I’ve sent it from my number, right?
You can keep that 4000 too!
Hi Preeti! How are you?
She’s on a visit home. She'll be in
a bad mood for a while when she’s back
A picnic? Sure, make a plan!
Hi! Remember I told you
about my friend?
Pick it up, pick it up, pick it up friend!
Pick it up
Soaring from this side to the other
Go off beat and sing your song
Pick it up, pick it up, pick it up friend!
Pick it up
Swing from one branch to the other
Like a bird hop from one tree to the other
-Hey!
-What’s the matter?
Come with me! Looks like
something's happened to Roshni
What?!
I’ve been dialling her number for ages,
but she's not answering
Somebody's been beaten up
at her employer's. I got a call
-I have a feeling it’s Roshni
-Her phone’s still off
Let’s go, quick!
-Where?
-In here
How did all this happen?
Sir got to know today.
Then things really escalated
They dragged and hit mercilessly
Many of his friends were with him.
All very drunk
But how did they get to know?
TRANSGENDERS IN THE CITY
-We should file a police report
-No point
That's right. The Superintendent
of Police was there too
Let's go to the hospital first.
We could go to JP hospital
-No
-Why not?
Not there. The cops will ask endless questions
and then poke fun at us
Then where?
Let’s go to our usual doctor
Shahrukh! Get me a strong painkiller,
the pain is unbearable
-Ouch! Not that arm, that's gone
-Sorry!
-You could have called me
-The phone is in a worse state than I am
Shahrukh, would you get my bag?
Look at this! They’ve carried
such a huge article
They might at least
have used a better photo
Here, read it!
We should file a case against them too
How could they publish this
without permission?
Are our lives some exhibit?
He's advancing his career,
and getting us thrashed!
This happens to us all the time
This is so wrong!
And he’s written such rubbish!
If I get my hands on this
‘Pankaj Dubey Parwana’, I’ll show him!
Go see, it must be Shahrukh
Sandeep?
Oh, it’s you! Please come in
-So you’re colleagues?
-Yes, that’s right
Do sit down
-Feeling better?
-Feeling better and freer too!
I was so afraid for you that day
Such a big crowd they were.
The violence is one thing, but
the humiliation is unbearable
Those educated officers,
how filthy they are inside
How can you beat someone up
so brutally?
And so shamelessly, in front of
his wife and kids?
And the wife and kids
were just watching it happen
Have they no shame either?
I feel like quitting,
but can’t afford to
Oh, you shouldn’t have
One has to keep one's mouth shut
They are really terrible people
You have your own compulsions.
Working there is its own punishment
You take care of yourself too
They're going to file a case
against you, maybe theft
The case should be against them!
Under Sections 354 and 325
-You seem well-versed in law!
-I know a little bit
What proof do we have?
And who'll believe us?
We've been to the police before.
Always in vain
There’s no harm trying.
I know a few lawyers
No point, we've tried it all
It's time for my shift.
I’ll have to leave now
-If I can do anything, let me know
-Sure
Oh, he's sent me my video!
-Now this we can give the cops!
-First, let's make it viral
-What’s the use of that?
- At least the truth will come out!
-What if they still file a case?
-They'll do that anyway
Post it on your Human Rights group too
I seem to have forgotten the key!
Great! Like this rain wasn’t
bad enough already. Now hurry!
It’ll take just two minutes!
Auto drivers will never learn,
especially the ones in Bhopal!
-Right, break my other arm too!
-It’s just in the next lane
What matters is Khala’s agreed.
You can take it from there now.
You finally pushed me into this partnership!
Well, I got you the house too.
What's the problem?
Not for free, right?
It's a 70-30 partnership.
Your Khala is quite shrewd!
She's looked after the business
alone since we were kids
She has to be shrewd!
And at heart, Khala’s okay. So she
scolds and has a temper. No big deal
You’re quite sharp yourself! It could
well become a 50-50 partnership in time
Just stay on good terms with Khala
That’s all fine, the house is good too.
Let’s just hope “madam” approves!
It's your job to convince “madam”.
Oh, there she is!
-Where were you two?
-Picking up the keys
-You can close your umbrella
-We are enjoying the weather!
-Fine, keep enjoying it!
-We will!
And you’re also roaming about
in your raincoat
Can the nominee be someone
other than a family member?
If not, I don't want any insurance
And who is this "Harish"
you’re referring to?
There's no one by that name
Please don't call again
Thank you for sharing your house
For the things in the past, sorry!
-How are you?
-All right
I am very ashamed about that day.
I hope you can forgive us
You know what he’s like
when he’s drunk
You’ve witnessed it all
After drinking, he’s come to hit me too
-Are you working anywhere?
-No
-Should I put in a word somewhere?
-Let it be
After your video, an enquiry has been
instated against him
It had to be done
-Take it back
-What?!
If he’s suspended, our lives
will fall apart
-Sumit's studies, his entire future...
-And what about me?
Am apologizing for that. And if you want
I’ll get him to apologise too
Look, I’m speaking to you as a woman
You think of yourself as a woman, right?
Surely you can understand my pain
And what about my pain?
Now that you’re in trouble,
I have become a woman to you
Are we the same? Would this
have happened to you?
And you were standing right there!
You are a part of this
You lied as well. Never told us
about your caste, or your…
Anyway, I don’t believe in all this
But in his home you can’t
even cross the threshold
And you made your way
into my kitchen!
If I had told you,
would you have hired me?
I am what I am. This is
your problem, not mine
Let it go now.
Just forget and forgive
He still wants to file
a case against you
But I’ve stopped him. I said
I would persuade you
But if things go any further,
you will truly be in trouble
Even I won't be able to help you then
Are you here to save me,
your husband, or yourself?
-Everyone
-That is not possible
Joshi madam, it’s time
you decided where you stand
I’ll keep fighting. I’m not
scared of you people anymore
Do what you will!
I would have made you tea,
but you now you won’t drink it, will you?
Khusrau, deceived, seeks the right
Of redressal on Judgement Day
I will save these curses against my soul ...
Till I come to an agreement with my beloved
I will save these curses against my soul
Hey Shahrukh,
have you spoken to Khala?
Of course, I’ve asked her!
-So they’ll be staying here?
- Yes, they will
-What will they do here?
-What do you mean?
Whatever people do in their
homes. Eat, bathe, sleep!
Are you the ones
who’ll be living here?
Shahrukh, have you asked Khala?
Of course! Can I give out the room
without Khala’s permission?!
-What will you do?
-Live, just like others do
-Let me know if you need anything
-Thanks
-All of you will live here?
-Yes
-Shahrukh, have you asked Khala?
-Of course we’ve asked Khala!
-And what will you be doing here?
-The same things that others do!
-Here, have some water
-No, I’m fine.
-If you need anything, do tell me
-We will
Listen!
What?
Joshi is going to be suspended!
Nothing will happen.
They'll save him in the end
Do you like our home?
At last we have a place of our own
After searching the whole city
we’ve ended up next to a drain!
Close your eyes and imagine
we’re sitting by a river
I don't want to live in a dream world
To carry on the fight,
one needs a strong foundation
But that’s okay. We’ll continue
our struggle from here!
Begumpura, the city
No grief nor darkness here
No worry nor regrets
Nor any ownership
No fear of transgression
No pity, nor devastation
Now have I conceived such a land
Where wellness is eternal, my friend
Begumpura...
A never-ending reign prevails
None second, nor third, but equal all
Thriving, living, prosperous
Ever content, each resident
Begumpura...
Where one may roam as the heart may please
Where the strictures of ancient law books cease
Says Ravidas, the free tanner –
All those who are willing to live here are our friends
Begumpura...