25.000
The model's on a scale of 1/25,
but has to be imagined life-size.
The walls will be lined
with insulation.
Lighting will be permanent.
No switches.
I'll also have a mechanism
to slowly rotate the whole.
So while I'm sleeping,
when my brain's stopped,
my body still moves.
The brain doesn't stop
during sleep, Mr Keller.
Just a manner of speaking.
But how'd you define it?
Is it a cell?
A shelter?
A crypt, perhaps?
As it doesn't exist,
I don't know what you'd call it.
A way of shutting out
the world, no?
Maybe...
In any case, the world...
Yes?
The world?
So, what's your motivation
for this work?
I can't do anything else.
And, the modules,
in particular...
Why white?
I dunno, I like white.
I like silence,
things well done.
Outside,
I find all is dirty, mediocre.
There, you could gaze at the wall
for days, and after, maybe talk.
It might be possible.
If beauty comes
we need a place to greet it.
If we don't prepare
nothing can happen.
That's more or less
what I've always done.
I used to enclose objects
in white-painted boxes,
wrapped in cotton-wool.
Now I'm sick of boxes.
I want something big.
In which to put what?
Something beautiful.
Bruno!
What the hell is this?
Don't take my plastic
for your fucking car.
What's this fucking mess?
What should rot outside.
Not my stuff!
Are you crazy?
That's the best of furniture!
Top quality workmanship!
They don't make furniture
like that anymore.
I hope not.
Hope not...
Open this door.
Bruno!
Mind your tongue!
That was my father's furniture,
made to measure, saved hard for.
So put it back
where it fucking belongs!
You're eating late.
Yeah, a lot of work.
Don't want to know
how your father is?
Need the bag?
- What?
- Can I take it?
What's all this?
Might I know what's going on?
Nothing.
I just changed my mind.
I was getting pissed off
with the models.
And so?
So, nothing.
This'll be my third-year project.
But I'd just like to...
add one last little touch...
It'll be called:
"Wet Summer, Wet Paint"!
Did you ask for permission
to do this?
Where'll your classmates work?
- Dunno.
- You don't know.
Are you out of your mind,
or what?
You just cleared
their work out without...
Listen, Bruno,
this may be a "Fine Arts" school,
but that's just not on.
Already, you swan in and out
as you like.
You prepare projects
and then you...
I what?
My idea's still the same.
Sorry, but we can't let you do
just anything.
This isn't just anything.
Look, if you continue,
they'll expel you.
You understand?
Yeah, I understand.
You're not alone.
I'm through.
I'm outta here.
You don't have to take it
like that.
I'm out,
that's what you want.
We never asked you...
to be... a model pupil.
I'm outta here,
that way everyone'll be happy!
It's a put-on.
You like it too much.
A put-on?
I've no money,
no home,
no one to help me...
Call that a put-on?
I don't know what to say...
Maybe it's better that way.
But if you need money,
I may have a solution.
Landscape gardening,
a bit of interior decoration...
Pays well...
But it's up to you.
I can put in a word.
Enough!
That's enough!
Where's the furniture?
What furniture?
What'd you do with it?
That furniture
had to be taken apart
to get it in there,
now where is it?
Yeah, I know the story.
Now get off my back.
Don't piss me about, Bruno.
If you sold that furniture
I'll call the cops.
Fuck and damn!
To hell with your furniture!
It sucked, made me wanna puke.
You little shit!
Little shit!
I want you outta here.
Do you hear me?
I want you fucking out,
as of tomorrow!
Who'll put me out, you?
Me, and the cops, if need be.
Cheers.
You swine!
Take that back!
You take it back!
Let me go, you bastard,
all you can do is hit!
Know what I did
with your lousy jewelry?
Me and Raymond went whoring!
We had our dicks sucked
by a prize hooker!
Bastard!
Know what it means
to suck dick?
- You pig!
- Filthy bitch!
What's going on?
You shut it, brother-in-law!
Get back in your room.
Do you hear that slut?
The fucking nerve!
This here is my home.
You don't like,
beat it!
- No, I don't like it.
- Then ship out!
I don't like it one bit!
Pick that up!
Shut your fucking mouth,
crazy bitch!
Yeah, beat it!
The Keller brothers,
two bloody alcoholics!
So who'd want you, bitch?
You stink of drink!
It was me who started this?
Who was picked out of the gutter
at 4 a.m.?
Who was it? Who?
You bloody drunks!
She hits the sauce
at nine every morning!
What's your fucking brat
up to now?
I'm out of here!
I'm leaving!
Go ahead and fucking leave,
bitch!
I'll go get the cops,
you hear?
That's what I'll do.
April 1992
My name is Elise Gardet,
I'm 7 years old.
Follow the light with your eyes.
That's right.
- Are you ready?
- Yes.
So tell me about that day.
Where are you?
I'm in my room.
Follow the light with your eyes.
You're in your room?
Yes.
Your mom, is she with you?
No.
So tell me what you see.
I see his car...
It's blue.
No, red.
It's red.
Red? Are you sure?
Yes, red.
Stay with that.
Is he there?
Yes.
He's come inside?
What's he doing?
I don't know.
He's shouting.
Do you know why he's shouting?
Breathe deeply.
What's happening now?
Where are you?
In the corridor.
Stay with that.
- What are you doing?
- I'm hiding.
Where? In your room?
No, in the bathroom.
What are you feeling?
Are you hot, cold?
No...
And the man,
can you see him?
What's he doing?
I don't remember.
Concentrate, Elise.
He's crying.
He's crying?
Yes.
Stay with that.
And then?
He left.
She's better.
More attentive,
willing too,
but it'll be long.
I know.
How do you intend...
Think you'll have enough time
to devote to her?
If you feel you need to talk,
any fears, questions,
whatever, feel free.
It's important to talk,
because it's important for Elise.
And for me,
to make progress.
Yes, I understand.
I thank you.
But I'm okay...
So far, I'm bearing up.
Fine.
I also wanted to say,
though this doesn't depend on you...
But as long as the killer
is at large
Elise won't rest easy.
You understand?
- Had any news about the...
- Yes.
The target was
a certain Doctor Gardet.
Gardet? Like you?
He lives quite near us,
I even went to see him.
Yes, I know...
A shady doctor, say the cops. Bogus
prescriptions, a lot of cash...
I've a PhD in nuclear physics,
so I put "Doctor" in the directory.
The cops reckon
the murderer mixed us up.
Obviously some junkie.
It seems so...
You don't know what it's like.
No one does.
Those who haven't been through it
just don't know.
- I think I can imagine.
- You can't.
I too lost the woman I loved
in difficult circumstances.
- But I didn't come to talk of...
- They suspected me.
So, you're my alibi?
Didn't picture you like that.
- How then?
- I don't know.
I thank you
for what you've done.
If you'd not seen me
on the train that day...
You'd have done the same for me.
No, you saw me,
but I'd never have noticed you.
I take that train every day and...
Seems I've still a lot to learn.
No, it's nothing.
Don't let such things get to you.
I think your daughter wants you.
Number 1.
Okay, number 2.
Number 4.
Again.
It's him.
Number 1?
No, it's him...
He's the same.
Who's the same?
Who's the same, pet?
He's the same.
This is pointless.
Happy? Now what?
What else can we do?
- That's enough!
- There, see?
It's easy to know who she is.
Dead easy.
11 YEARS LATER
I think it's better like that.
I'll remove the hook.
Yes, that's nice.
- Very nice. Like it?
- Yes, lovely.
How is that?
Elise?
Elise!
Could you fetch madam
the beige ones?
How's that?
A little higher.
And there?
A bit higher on the right.
Don't move.
Did you do the photos?
No, just the hanging.
Like it?
What's your name?
My name's Elise Gardet.
I'm 18 years old.
Can I call you?
Okay.
Who's speaking?
I can't hear you.
- "Is Elise there?"
- Who's speaking?
- "Is she there or not?"
- What for? Who are you?
Are you calling
from that car?
Who are you?
What're you doing?
- Waiting for the bus.
- Nonsense, I saw you.
Three buses have already passed!
Really?
Still here in 5 minutes
I'll call the police.
Go ahead, call them.
I will, I'm warning you.
Why don't you just piss off?
This is your local police...
Hello, Police.
Anne...
Why do you feel
constantly watched?
- Is she asleep?
- Yes.
I really love her, you know.
I know.
I feel watched,
because someone's always watching.
You must stop thinking that.
He won't return.
Not 11 years after.
He's most likely dead
of an overdose.
Yes, true.
Him, perhaps.
But the others?
What others?
For years, Anne believed
the killer would return.
For me.
To look for me.
She trusted no one.
She chose my school, my friends,
what I should read, watch, eat.
She says men are dangerous
and that I'm fragile.
But I'm sick of it,
sick of being protected,
of not being allowed to forget.
I met him yesterday.
For him, I'm not a victim,
a child to be protected,
I'm simply there.
I am as I am
and that's enough for him.
For me, that's all that matters.
Anne thinks I meet Marion
at lunchtimes.
If she knew I were seeing him,
God knows what she might do.
It's beautiful.
Yeah, it's nice.
But don't look at what's in it.
You need to see it empty.
For the light, the space,
all this whiteness.
When it's empty,
I'll be here.
Why are you doing that?
Yesterday,
he took me up Castle Hill.
He told me
each tree is a world
and between each world,
lies water.
That one day he'd teach me
to swim between the trees.
Taking his hand,
he was trembling.
He said it wasn't death
which scared him
but that glut of bodies in the
earth, which the earth doesn't want.
Sunday again.
Stuck at home again.
Bored again.
Thought a lot of Bruno.
All the time.
Of what he said to me.
I was proud,
vain and dumb...
That's all.
I felt I was succeeding,
yet I was fucking up my life.
I only realize that now.
Why did I do that?
Why did I have to tag "Doctor"
onto my name?
You think it's normal
I still feel guilty?
Anyone'd feel guilty
in your situation.
Like it or not, it was you
who led that man to your home.
You led him there.
So, call it vanity, arrogance,
whatever you will...
your wife is dead,
and that...
Where our acts lead, we know not.
If we did, we'd do nothing.
But as that's no solution,
we get up, we do,
only each time striving
to be a bit more careful.
We reflect,
try to behave correctly.
Avoiding the seven deadly sins?
Why not? Perhaps.
In any case,
a tragedy like this shows us
why Vanity is one of them.
Don't you think?
Your daughter's asleep.
Is she staying?
Okay.
He said he'd a place for me
in his project.
I think those were his words.
What're you doing?
Not well?
Why's everyone leaving?
Whose place is this?
Belongs to Italians.
Folks with money to burn.
They only use it 2 months a year.
What a waste!
Why don't you use it?
You have the keys.
I would, if I were you.
Finished up at the shop?
Yeah.
This door will be walled over,
to put shelving here,
here...
I'm no stone mason.
And shelves will look dead ugly.
Should leave these walls empty.
Sorry, Bruno,
but no one asked you.
The owners want this walled up,
so that's that.
Are you listening?
Easy does it!
That's it.
Right, heave away!
Kamel, bring the truck!
So are you doing this job?
Yes or no?
You sleep naked now?
You're pathetic...
Dress, you'll be late.
She knows it's you.
Who?
In the shop.
She says you're a dirty thief.
Why dirty?
I'm not dirty.
Even if you were,
it'd be all the same to me.
Perfect.
No, Elise, don't get in!
It's filthy inside.
I'm not walking home.
Come on, out!
- It's not my car.
- I'm cold, I wanna go home.
- Come on.
- I'm late!
It's not mine,
we'll take the bus.
Come on!
Kamel?
Sorry, didn't know you were here.
Bruno, what're you doing here?
I came by to work.
- But I'll be on my way.
- What's going on?
- You've no business here.
- Sorry...
I just felt like working.
Up you go. I'll be off.
Have you stolen something?
No, nothing.
I just came by to work.
Then let me pass.
Let go of me!
Just go back upstairs.
Back upstairs, please...
Please, go back up.
Let go of me...
Go upstairs.
I'm leaving.