$IT
2 Some kind of a smile
J Twisted upside up until I fall down
J To the ground
J Sky is painted in pixels of blue
J And once again
IS 1 think of you
2 My hands are made of childish games
J The kind of thing we used to play
2 Now I'm old, my future's told
J Maybe I'll find love
J When I'm done
J You have got a hold on me
J Take my lungs so I can breathe
2l feel this sound might drag me down
J But I am louder than the voices now
J You have got a hold on me
J Take what's left and let me be
2l think it's time to see that it's through
J To get distance from you
J Without a doubt
21 find myself becoming one in the crowd... J
- Okay, just breathe...
- You're on next Reuben.
Okay.
Now remember, just take
your time and don't rush it.
I-1-1'll give it my - my - my - my - my best shot.
Yeah, sure you will.
J Rising dawn
J} My past is gone
JIt's never enough
S You have got a hold cn me... J
It groans! My heart!
It moans passionately.
It aches, arches and breaks.
It groans compassionately.
My heart!
My love!
At the finish, as it was at the start!
Just get out! Just get away from me! Just get! Get!
2 To get distance from you &
What the hell were you thinking?
Are you serious?
"Groans compassicnately"?
- No, what it's supposed to mean is --
- It doesn't mean anything, Blake.
Now, just get out. Just get out!
I have a show to run, get cut!
Reuben!
Get your arse out there!
That was Blake Rhodes with his rendition of...
...Hate Attack.
Coming up next; we have "Feathers
From A Thousand Li Away".
Apassage from "The Joy Luck
Club" written by Amy Tan,
and performed by Reuben Heywood.
Fuck!
The... The cld woman remembered a ss - a swan
she bought years ago in -in-in-in -in
- in Shanghai for a foolish sum.
"This bird," boasted the market
vendor "was once a duck..."
"...that stretched its neck out in hopes
of - of someday becoming a goose."
...And now look, it - it - it
-it's too beautiful to eat."
So the woman a-a-and the swan
sa-sa-sa-sailed across an ocean...
...m-many thousands of Li wide,
str-stre-stretching their necks toward America.
On her journey, the woman coced to the swan;
"In America, I will have daughter just like me"
"but over there no one will say her worth is
measured by the loudness of her hushand's belch."
"Over there she will be too full of Coca-Cola
to ever swallow any sorrow and over there -- "
"80 - s0 the woman a-a-and the - a-and the sw -
and the swan sailed across an ocean..."
[laughter and confused chatter]
Uh, apologies, ladies and gentlemen.
We appear to be having a
technical issue backstage.
Uh, but please remain in your seats,
our next performer will be on momentarily.
(muttering) What the fuck is going on?
L can't interpret under these conditions!
The last line he said needed subtitles!
I can't understand a word he says!
This is amateur theatre!
It's supposedtobea-a-a-a-a-a-a..
...asafeplace for somebody
who has a speech impediment!
I'm sorry, Reuben, but that's simply not true.
What about Blake? He was unintelligible!
At least he was speaking English.
L 'am speaking English!
I've your script in front of me and
I could barely understand you.
Can you understand me now?
He was speaking English the whole time.
I don't know why you had to cancel
his performance halfway through.
I could lip-read him the whole time.
Oh, that's not what you said befere!
Look! I have a show to run, so just
sort this out amongst yourselves.
- What about my play?
- Learn your lines better!
L know my lines!
Oh, you could have fooled me!
Um, don't mind her. She's a bit of a linguist.
She has no patience for miscommunication.
But you could lip-read my
performance, couldn't you?
Um... ll can now.
What?
Sorry. I just... stretched the truth a little bit.
I mean, I can lip-read them, but I
didn't like how they were treating you.
I thought I'd help you out a bit.
So you couldn't lip-read - you
couldn't lip-read my performance?
Sorry.
You locked really invested, though.
Thanks...
I'm Derek. My sign name is "Derek".
Reuben.
- Sorry?
- Reuben.
Reuben? It's nice to meet you.
Thanks.
Um...
Wanna get out of here?
What?
Do you want to get out of here?
$IT
[REUBEN] I don't know to
compete with those people.
Are you lip-reading me?
Yeah... Well, I try.
Right. Yeah...
You know, "a flower; it doesn't think
about competing with its neighbours...
...itjust blooms."
It's... hard... to... bloom...
when... you... have... a... st--
No, no, no! Tell me.
Try.
Okay.
A stutter is like, um...
...my words are, um.
...fabric...
...going through a machine.
And at random times, it just gets... jammed.
And it misses stitches.
Right...
I think that's the same for me when
I'm trying to learn new words...
...except that it's more of a, um...
...hearing impediment.
Um...
Are you profoundly deaf?
Yeah. Profoundly deaf.
Wow.
Yeah, it doesn't stop me, though.
L mean, I'm doing a political
science degree at uni right now.
That's impressive.
Yeah. Who else better than me to lead
the LGBTQIA and deaf rights rallies?
But do those overlap?
They do for me.
Yeah. The arts is just a...
...it's a form of therapy.
I think it's a way of helping people
regulate their mood and expressions.
It's healthy.
Doesn't help me with my stutter.
You know...
You can do anything if it has purpose.
I'm - I'm writing a play called
"The Burden of Being Me", it's...
...kinda based on my life and I think it has purpose.
But I take it up to the theatre and they won't
show any part of it. It's discrimination.
Egotistical thespians and
their overwritten musings.
Big deal. You don't need them for your validation.
Don't I?
Not if you say your work has much purpose.
Derek...
Call me Derek.
Um...
I'love your attitude and your... world view.
And I want to get to know you better.
Can I see more of you?
Is that a line?
J [Up-tempo music] &
S 1 don't wanna sit in again with you baby tonight
Jldon't wanna love, I don't wanna fight
J 1 don't wanna have to tell you all the things I know
J 1 don't wanna stay but I don't wanna go
J 1 don't wanna be the lover in your arms
I don't wanna be the one to keep you from harm &
What are you thinking?
Have you always been deaf?
Yep. Have you always had a stutter?
No, actually... Um...
I was an only child.
Are you...? Are you still an only child?
Yes.
But, um, when I was 3, uh, my mother
had twins and, uh, they were stillborn.
Oh my God.
I'm sorry to hear that.
She was pretty cold towards me after that.
Towards everyone, really.
I don't think anyone... feels rejection
as much as a small child, you know?
What about your dad?
He's a math teacher and she's a proofreader.
So they're very astute in finding fault and...
...taking it upon themselves to fix things.
That would be you, I take it?
Didn't get much better after that. Um...
I wore glasses, had a stammer, so...
...I was bullied a lot at school and
wasn't one to really fit in, you know?
What's wrong?
Don't take it the wrong way...
...but, I find that when...
...guys share their sob stories on the first date...
...it's ared flag.
Itisn't a sob story.
Like you being deaf. I have had to cvercome
and it's made me who I am.
Yeah, but there's a difference between
fitting in and belonging.
What's your sob story?
I need you to look at me so I can lip-read you.
Oh, sorry. Um...
What's your sob story?
Not really a sob story...
. but...
...Well, I...
...bulked up just a little bit.
Just to, you know, get attention from guys.
Yeah...
Hearing guys really don't know
how to flirt with deaf guys.
They just think sign language is all
"ugh, lock at me, I'm a spastic!"
You know, but...
It's amazing that you can create
meaning cut of these hand-shapes.
Like, if you put it here;
That's "silly". Or, "fuckwit".
Or "available".
Or "stubborn”.
It's amazing.
So, silly... available... stubborn.
I'm all three of those things!
Convenient!
Yeah... No one has ever really
learnt my language, so...
L know what it's like to be misunderstood.
So, how doc you find the
confidence to go intoc politics?
Hm? Sorry?
How do you find the confidence to go into politics?
Well, I find that...
...if you've got something to say and nc cne's
listening, change the way you campaign.
What do you mean?
Well, that play you're doing;
Why not turn it into a film?
I can't turn it into a film!
Films cost millions of dollars to make.
And who would I get to direct it
and edit it and... l don't know... gaffer it?
Well, if you are as motivated
as you say you are, you'll manage.
Yeah. And I've always wanted to do a bit of acting.
But I just never had the opportunity.
Because you're deaf?
Well, it's...
All the... there's no captions or
interpreters at workshops or theatres.
And that's a problem because you're deaf?
It's because I'm deaf that I
want to doit. I want to try.
Then you should.
If I'turn my stage play into afilm...
...I'd love to have you as my leading man.
Aww.
That's sweet of you.
Yeah.
But... you know, it can't just be the both of us.
All right? So...
Get all of this negativity and self-doubt...
Cram it into a ball. Cram it tight.
Throw it all the way over there.
Make a wish.
If you could pick anyone...
...any actor to be in your
leading role, who would it be?
Million dollar question.
Everything...
...Is stolen.
There is nothing new, there is nothing original...
...there are seven deadly sins,
there are seven days to the week...
...and there are seven basic
plot points in storytelling.
Douglas. Seven plots, peints. Go.
- Uh... Comedy, tragedy... rags to riches...
- The quest, rebirth, overcoming
the monster and voyage and return.
Good. Good... Now...
Every story, every idea, is just areactiocntoa
stimulus that comes before it.
Sometimes they work, sometimes they don't,
sometimes they overpower the competition...
However...
When you think about it,
there are only so many combinations of notes
that go into making the symphony that...
...eventually some tunes start to sound the same.
Some stories resemble other
stories with common elements...
But, sir, the writer is always
responsible for the manuscript.
In the context of film, the
writer always owns the work,
they just sell the rights to film it, don't they?
Hmm.
Interesting theory. Let's test it. Let's make a scene!
Okay...
- Uh, name? You've got a name of character?
- Geoff.
- Geoff, Geoff, Geoff -- what's Geoff doing?
Uh, he's in court.
- He's in court. Geoff's in court...?
- For manslaughter.
Okay, Geoff's in court for
manslaughter. What's the cutcome?
Uh, he gets, uh...
- Executed. Nice.
- Yeah, executed.
Lovely. Lovely work. Geoff's in court for
manslaughter and he gets executed.
We've created a story. Okay?
But with so many people contributing...
...who owns it?
That's why you guys are so
important to this industry.
You write up the contacts, you draw
up the clear lines of distinction...
...between the author and the
production company and above all...
...you protect your own work.
- But, sir?
- Gareth.
Gareth. How do you know all this? You're an actor.
L'am not a producer. I am not a lawyer.
L 'am, however, married to the best
entertainment attorney in Australia.
And they say showbiz marriages don't last!
Well, here is a clear example of when both parties...
...are passichately respectful
for what a contract represents.
All right, moving on...
"Dear Sir,
"Thank you for alerting me of the
litigation between our clients...
"...inthe matter of copyright infringement,
"allegedly contained in the product of my
client's screenplay, entitled 'From The Ashes'.
"As I understand it, the accusation
herein is that my client's work...
"infringes on your client's
screenplay; entitled 'Dust To Dust'.
"However, I am well-versed in
twentieth century literature...
"...and American poetry, including
the works of Maya Angelou.
"The excerpt provided in your complaint regarding
my client's alleged use of your client's prose,
"contains a word-for-word extract of
Ms. Angelou's poem 'Still I Rise', specifically;
"You May Write Me Down In History
With Your Bitter, Twisted Lies,
"You May Trod Me In The Very Dirt,
But Still, Like Dust, I Rise."
"This passage is evident in the work of both our
clients and I advise you to take heed of this.
"I have already contacted my client with a severe
warning to the ramifications to reputation...
...should potential allegations
be made against him,
or myself, by way of association,
"due to my role as his legal representative.
"I suggest you direct a formal letter of similar
content to your client, post-haste.
"Unless you would rather wait for the
executor of Ms. Angelou's estate...
"...whom I have alerted to be
in touch with you, regarding
this misappropriation of her works.
"The choice is yours.
"L suspect this is the conclusion
of this matter between our
clients and there should be little need for...
"...any combination of the four
of us to communicate further.
"I trust you will rescind and correct any and all
allegations made toward my client...
"...and refrain from bothering me further.
"Yours sincerely, Mrs. Lillian Donahue,
"Entertainment, trademark and
intellectual property attorney, LLD."
[door unlocks]
Hey, Lily.
Ugh, I'm exhausted.
How was your day?
Six solid hours, pontificating back my degree toc a
dozen dead-eyed university students...
Not exactly where I thought
I'd find myself at this age.
You?
Ch, the usual.
Intellectual property.
Copyright infringement.
People confusing the role of a
solicitor for that of an attorney.
Same old, same old.
Hm, same cld, same old.
Sounds a bit close to home.
You know, it occurred to me today,
that I was 27 when I got my first AFl award.
Best Australian Actor in multiple genres,
year after year and now I've lapped that age and...
...it occurs to me that in your 50s...
...the only roles you can count
on getting are the ones that
threaten to muffin-top your belt buckle.
You're still all right, mate.
Still geod looking. I love ya.
L want to blow your mind.
Look, no, Lily...
I'm just not in the mood.
Ch, come on!
You promised.
Gareth.
What?
Gareth, my cycle's been irregular...
- ...more than usual.
- Well, that's a turn-on!
"Hey, Honey, I'm staring down
the barrel of menopause...
"...we should be going at it like we're 19 again."
Gareth! This is serious!
My time's running cut.
And we've waited long enough already.
Not this again!
What kind of man turns down a
marathon of sex with his wife?
Lillian...
It's not the right time to have kids.
I'm not ready.
- You've been saying that for years!
- It's too soon!
But you're teaching now.
Take a look around you, Gary.
It's not like we're below the poverty line.
Lillian, my career has taken a nose-dive
and I'm not finished with it yet.
"Only those that can't do, teach."
I haven't finished doing.
And that's the end of it.
You still have plenty of
opportunities ahead of you, Gareth.
But I don't.
Aw, Lily, come on.
Come on, Lillian. Come on, come here.
L hate seeing you like this.
Look...
Just give it some time.
You know, it'll be worth the wait, won't it?
Hey?
$IT
So when you want to count, you count out here.
One, two, three, four, five.
But if you want to say how old you are,
you do it off your nose.
- So, I'm 257
- Yeah. That's right.
So, want. Don't want.
Comfortable. Not comfortable.
Good luck. Bad luck.
- It's all in the expression.
- Ch!
So, go good, bad.
- Yeah. Pretty simple.
- Okay, um...
Did... you... get... the sign... for... stutter?
Oh yes, yes.
Stutter.
Yeah. Talk, block.
Talk, block. Okay.
Um, I reckon... Uh, children...
uh, should have, um...
regular... uh, bullying... classes.
What, to teach them how to
bully? Or how to be bullied?
No, neither, neither. Um...
More how to... um, uh, combat a
bully... um, and how to not be one.
This is breaking my hands!
Don't worry. You're just breaking them in.
Okay? Just keep practising.
- Okay.
- Don't worry.
So, what can I get you guys?
C-c-could I - can I - ¢c-c-c-could I
havea-sa-ac-ac-aca-...
...C-could I please havea-a-ac-aca-
...Acoffee please?
Coffee?
One coffee? Okay.
Should I crder for you, next time?
I don't want anybody to ever speak for me.
Ohreally? Is that why we're together?
So you can learn a bit of sign language?
- 1s that what our relationship is based on?
- No, no, no, no, no.
I'm with you because I find you fascinating.
L want to learn how to exude
confidence the way that you do.
And I want to get enough Auslan skills so I can...
...get over my speech
impediment by just going mute --
No, no, noc! Bullshit!
Seriously, that's like...
...the dumbest thing you could say.
You've got the skills, you
just need to keep practising.
That's easy for you to say, you den't have a stutter!
Well, I'm deaf, you know!
And I have to deal with that.
It's not easy for me to say anything.
You know?
L just...
...make do with what I've got.
And you can too.
You know? I want you to be able
to speak confidently, for yourself.
That's what matters.
Show me, Derek.
L will.
$IT
2 Your body's in a chair, across from me
J But your mind is in the sky above the trees
2 Just floating
2 So lonely, yeah.
2 You tell me that you love me, truthfully
J But empty words have got no use for me
2 So showme
2 Just show me, yeah.
2 Well, your shirt is all stained
2 From the heart on your sleeve
IS You talk a gocd game and I wanna believe
J But if you really wanna prove your love
J Then just show me
J Do youremember when we met?
2 We were such a flaming wreck
J The fire never died when our
bodies would collide in the night
2 §till, I smell the smoke
JInthe words that leave your throat
J Buried deep inside
2 s the fire still alive
J 1 don't wanna hear your reply, no, just show me
2 Well, your shirt is all stained
from the heart on your sleeve
IS You talk a gocd game and I wanna believe
S But if you really wanna prove
your love, then just show me, yeah
2 And the well is all drained
from your buckets of words
JIt's time to listen up, if you wanna be heard
2 If youreally wanna prove
your love, then just show me J
I was just saying, I can transmit my
knowledge through werds and gestures.
- That's interesting.
- Yeah, it's amazing.
- Hi.
- Hey, how're you goin'?
Well, well, well.
What are you deing here?
I heard that Emily kicked you out of the troupe.
L wasn't kicked out of anything.
It was a mutual understanding.
Well, more like a mutual misunderstanding.
What do you want, Blake?
Who is that beefcake?
He's off-limits.
Well...
So is the theatre, as far as you're concerned.
Nice to meet you, Helen Keller.
What was that about?
We...
Um... need to go!
We need to go?
We need to go!
What's wrong?
That man, um...
He's, uh, from the, uh...
...theatre. He's one of the, um...
...the bullies.
And we need to go!
Okay...
Excuse me, can I borrow that?
Thank you.
Derek! Come on!
Wait a minute.
Let's see...
[strums guitar]
You know how to play guitar?
Sure.
It's an acquired skill.
Like speaking in a different language
or dealing with bullies.
But how?
It's just muscle memory.
Like, I know this is, uh... let's see...
L think. I mean, I feel it.
But I can't hear it. Like...
I don't even know if it's properly tuned.
And I know this is A.
And, um...
"Mary Had A Little Lamb".
J [Mary Had A Little Lamb] J
Pretty easy.
See...
You know you're available.
And you're stubborn.
And you know how to tell bullies
to shut the fuck up and piss off.
You just need to trust that
your confidence is in tune.
$IT
2 And at 21, I'm not quite a man
2 Hell, I ain't no boy, no more.
Jl've been stuck inside this cruel, hard world.
Jl've been kicked around, I've been left for dead.
Jl've been sick and tired, I've been Heaven-sent.
So, um, when I finish my degree,
I'll be, um, working in social justice...
...uh, particularly for the deaf
community and, um, deaf education.
Very admirable.
L teach maths at the local high school.
That's one of my favourite subjects.
Favourite subjects? You shouldn't say
things just to impress my parents.
Oh, seeing you interpret for
him is impressive enough.
Ah! They're here, Roy!
I'll see you both in the lounge room.
Hey.
They like you.
That's good, I like them too.
You know...
With me signing to you all night...
...I think they are starting to
think I'm becoming mere, um...
...aca--
-- demic.
Yeah, but Auslan's not academic.
No, but it's, um...
...ad-different language. It's like...
...binary.
You know, um, and-and they love their, um...
Ar...
tic --
--ula... tion...
...and...
...cor--
--rect --
-- ness.
They're all right.
Well, yeah, but...
They're too academic...
...for their own good.
And mine too.
You're perfect.
I'm far from perfect.
That's you.
You think I'm hollow and transparent?
No.
Because you're well-rounded,
and you're beautiful.
That's me?
Exactly.
J You'll be Thelma and I'll be Louise
2 We'll escape this horror, easy as you please &
And that's me?
That's right.
My mum is going to love you!
[FAYE] Sketch the oval of the face.
There should be six constant vertical lines...
...intersecting at the apex of the head,
hairline, eyebrows, nose, mouth and chin.
This gives the dimensions of the head.
Duplicate another oval of the same size
and turn it ninety degrees.
This gives the third dimension
of the skull, creating its depth.
Follow the sternccleidomasteid...
...inthe direction of the face and
carry it through to the clavicle.
The ear has a triangular bone structure,
with the node in the centre
having a direct line to the nose.
The eyes should measure three times
across the width of the face.
Draw a circle for the eyeball
and surround it with a hexagon.
This creates the points of the eyelids.
Uh, now, where was I?
Uhm...
Don't draw a mouth, draw lips.
But don't be seduced by large lips and large eyes.
Oh, Reuben, I'm sorry.
This must be going way over your head.
No, it's fine. I'm just really taken
in by the dynamic in the room.
It's a bit overwhelming, isn't it?
L can't even...
...what do you call it? Finger-spell, yet.
No, but you're getting there.
Maybe if I had more time to teach you.
Well, I never get the chance because full-time
carpentry keeps my hands full, literally.
Well, I'll teach you to sign with a hammer
and a saw in each hand, then.
All right.
The important thing is communication.
Nothing breaks down a
relationship faster than alack of --
-- alack of communication.
My dad.
Um...
I found that, uh...
...with my stutter, um, and being with, uhm,
Derek these last few months...
...that, uh, my...
...sighing has improved and
my speech is improving too.
So, I was, um...
...before, thinking cf becoming mute and now...
But you could think about changing your...
...your barrier into something more
meaningful and purpeseful.
You know, somebody could
really learn from your story.
Yeah, uh, do you have a sign-name yet, Reuben?
Did-did you just... call me a loser?
Um, no. It's, uh, it's colloquial...
...for learning. It's kind of
like, um... like shorthand.
Shorthand?
That's very apt.
L was stunned the first time
Courtney invited me over.
I mean, talk about encountering culture.
[FAYE] You mean counterculture, don't you?
No, I mean, it was like stepping intc another world.
And it was anything but silent. All these...
...gestures and things happening and
suddenly everyone just bursts out laughing.
Yeah, he said it was a little bit like
walking around and everyone's listening...
-...to acomedy podcast on headphones in public.
- Yeah!
You know what I'm talking about.
And... Auslan's quite a talent.
Uh-uh, no, it's a skill.
No, but talent is something your
born with. And it can't be taught.
It's always inside you. It just needs a bit of a Polish.
Polish.
I've...um, when I was in speech therapy, I - I heard
that if you need to correct
someone's words like that,
it means that they, um, learned it by reading.
Qch, I like that.
[MYLES] Wow, that's deep.
[FAYE] Well then, speaking of talent...
I received a letter today from
the Australian Disabilit...
The Australian Disability and Arts Society.
They've received my submission.
Ch, Mum! That's fantastic news!
Good of them to let you know that it arrived.
But there's more!
They've shortlisted me for
one of their annual grants.
- Aw, Faye! Congratulations!
- Yeah, Mum, that's fantastic news!
- Thank you.
- What's the grant?
Fifty grand!
Wow! What would you do with that?
Ch, probably...
...fall off my chair!
[FAYE] Reuben...
Maybe you could, um, submit that play
of yours during the next round of submissions?
But I don't consider my speech
impediment a disability.
Disability or not, you've got talent.
Well...
You must be a good man because
you passed the first - the litmus test.
The neighbour's dog didn't bark at you as
you walked past, up the driveway.
Derek?
Does your...? Do you like...?
...think in sign language?
Like, do the voices in your
head, like, sign to each other?
Well, my thoughts don't stutter
if that's any difference.
Yeah, but I always thought, like, a speech
impediment was caused by...
...anxiety or like an intellectual kind of... thing?
I've always thought that once people
start seeing themselves as a victim...
...that's that they become.
L only ask because the three of us could
all apply to the ADAS Fund.
A playwright, a carpenter and a deaf politician.
I'm an activist.
[FAYE] More like a crusader.
L know what you're thinking.
"Silly Myles, a tradie can't be a writer."
But a creative mind is a creative mind.
He's got a point there.
What's the idea?
Picture it;
An epic, sweeping historical
drama about carpenters.
[FAYE] Hm, sounds biblical.
It's called "Gone With The Window".
It's about this little
renocvaticn/construction company
run by this cbnoxiocus chick
named Charlctte G'Hara, right...
Well, Charlotte's got this burning crush on this
delicate lesbian named Ashleigh.
Ashleigh is going out with this
prissy little twit named Melanie
and this guy, Brett, or whatever...
...comes along and declares his undying
love for Charlotte and she's all like, "nah".
And it's set in this epic crisis, like the GFC.
So, everyone's going bankrupt.
So, Brett and Charlotte join forces and employ
abunch of slaves to burn down half the city.
Which Brett and Charlotte
will then make a fortune on,
when they're hired to rebuild everything...
...whilst underhandedly helping people
claim on their insurance policies.
Melanie and Ashleigh, though, decide to sell their
big plantation to Brett, in exchange for his sperm.
Melanie gets pregnant through IVF
and Charlctte decides tc drop a
palette of cinder blocks on her
head in exchange for the chair.
What do you reckon?
[Faye laughs]
You know...
When Derek was little...
...the neighbours were selling a litter of puppies.
Of course, Derek was drawn to the runt of the litter.
L discouraged him, saying that
the runt was special and...
...and it shouldn't be taken away from his mum.
He locked up at me with those
big green eyes and said;
"Mummy, am I a runt puppy too?"
It nearly broke my heart.
It was then I knew I had a choice;
I could either protect him from the world...
...or be there to pick up the pieces
when the world was done with him.
L chose the latter.
[FAYE] Derek has areal sense of right and wrong.
And for better or for worse, it keeps
him frem mixing with the wrong crowd.
Matthew was heavy-handed.
He was anti-Auslan and pro-surgery.
Cochlear implants are a real point of
contention with the deaf community.
And when both of Derek's attempts failed,
Matthew concluded that his son was defective.
[REUBEN] Why? He's so articulate and he...
he can express his intelligence
at every opportunity.
[FAYE] That comes from building him up.
Confidence accumulates over time,
until a person can make it on their own.
As you can imagine, it doesn't take very
much to knock somebody down.
[REUBEN] Is that why Derek has such an
interest in political and social agendas?
[FAYE] I think so. Turning negatives inte
a positive is the key to survival.
You know, when I'm with Derek
and - and - and I'm signing...
...I've my... my confidence back.
L could have used these sKkills
tc give up och my speech
impediment altcgether and not
have to worry about it again, but...
...I've found that since I've met Derek,
I've sort of resolved the problem.
But... when I'm signing, I'm so
much more charismatic and clear!
And I think; this would be a really
good second act for my screenplay.
L was thinking it would be about a guy
who gets through his speech impediment...
...with his deaf partner using
Auslan and the deaf community.
What do you think?
And I suppose you'd like to, um...
...give in tc Derek's aspirations as an
actor and make him the lead role?
Yeah!
Look...
One-hit wonders like Marlee Matlin
come and go in a flash with the deaf community.
But, if Derek concentrated his energies into...
...human rights, activism, deaf-awareness...
...like Helen Keller...
Now that's a real purpose.
No, Faye. That's real hypocrisy.
How can something so... strong...
...beso...
...gentle and expressive?
Work it out yourself, man!
[Reuben exhales deeply]
Could you hear that?
Yeah, I felt that!
Can you feel that?
Yeah, I can feel that!
L can feel that, too.
$IT
[REUBEN] Are you sure he - he - he - he...
he wants to meet with me, not
just read the screenplay...
.on -on -on his cwn?
[DEREK] Den't worry. Relax.
I'll be with you every step of the way.
G-G-G-Gareth!
You must be Reuben.
G'day.
Yeah, uh...
I don't normally take, uh, unsolicited calls, but...
Uh, I guess it's all, um,
eh-uh-uh, very su - very sudden.
Yeah, yeah, whoa. It's okay.
Actually I was honoured
that you, uh, thought of me.
Uh, sit down, sit down.
- Okay.
Tell me about this idea -- are you a, uh, a student?
- Writer.
- Ch, a writer?
My wife works with a lot of writers.
She's a copyright lawyer.
She's also my own personal legal rep.
I don't do a thing unless she's put her stamp on it.
Oh.
Have you got a copy of the script?
Yeah! Um...
Uh, this is Derek. He-he's deaf.
Oh, hey. Gareth Dona...
Sorry.
I'll leave it up to you to keep him up to speed.
Right, uh...
"The Burden of Being Me"
Interesting title.
Thank you.
What's it about?
Um, us. It's, um...
It's, uh, the main c-character,
uh, Robin, he's, um...
He - he - he - he - he's based on me, he wants
to be atheatre a-a-a-a-actor and he, um...
...he has this, uh, this-Th-Th-this-is --
Look!
-...this stammer...
- Hang on, hang on, hang on!
You - you don't have to be starstruck
around me. I'm just a regular guy.
L wasn't... was 1?
I-1-1 have a stutter, that's what
you're picking up on, but...
...l get that when I'm crdering a cheeseburger.
So it's not like it's really about you at all.
Have you tried speech therapy?
Yes... but, um...
Nothing is better for me than when I'm signing.
[GARETH] Then, why haven't
you been signing all along?
I-1-1 dunno. It's weird.
Uh, "Burden", is this... your only project?
Have you got anything better?
It's my life story, so it matters the most to me.
And it - it's about masculinity and assertion
and courage and self-esteem, belonging --
And self-indulgence!
No...
They say "if you want to be a filmmaker,
you need to write about what you know".
L thought you said you wanted to be a theatre actor?
That's more the character.
Ugh, okay!
You're going to have a lot of trouble with this.
Why?
You can't expect to be a director and have a stutter.
People will lose patience.
What?
You also have to be open
and prepared for criticism...
...at all times, if you want toc
survive in the film industry.
I don't think that's true.
Take any career outside of the arts and they're
not open to that much scathing review and criticism.
Like, take, uh, a teacher or a doctor or a lawyer;
People can either be taught or not taught,
treated or not treated, trialled or not trialled...
...but the point is that nobody can tell me whether
I'm good enough to be an actor or a writer.
You really are a wordsmith, Reuben.
You didn't stutter cnce through that.
Which means when you're passionate
about something, all that stuff goes away!
Which is why I'm interested
in being part of this film.
Really? Oh, thanks, Gareth!
So, the main characters are Robin and Drake...?
Have you cast anyone?
Us.
Who's producing?
I don't actually have a producer as yet...
But if you know anybody...?
I've not actually produced a movie befere,
but I think "Burden"...
...has the makings of a...
...atopical and a very profitable film.
It's a... a story about two...
...characters who are LGBT and disabled --
-- disability's a great thing at the moment.
It's right in vogue! Spot on.
So, hypothetically, how would you produce it?
What? Me, personally?
L would run it by my wife, Lillian.
We would doc some preliminary
proposals for the funding bodies;
The Australian Screen Fund,
The Film Finance of New Scuth Wales...
...The Sydney Screen Company.
I've got some, uh, contacts. You know?
Wow, you've got some really deft skill.
It's called being professional.
Perfect!
All right!
I'm excited to get started!
Uh, can I keep this?
- Sure.
- And can you...?
...email me a soft copy?
Thanks, Gareth. Yeah.
Talk to you later!
Thank you!
What does that mean?
He thinks he's king shit, doesn't he?
He-he-he's a famous, uh, film... person.
He-he-he's trying to impress us.
No, it doesn't.
That man...
...wants to support my film.
We should be happy about this.
Come on.
How is it?
Lillian!
Oh, sorry!
What's it like?
It's very engrossing!
Any, uh, juicy roles for a
distinguished actor like myself?
Um...
Yes.
The role of Shane.
He's the estranged father of the deaf guy.
He doesn't sign, but...
...ch,it's interesting!
- Good, good, good.
More suitable for me, if he doesn't sign.
But, he also gets jealous of Robin!
For having his son's emotional priority.
It's a very well-crafted story of the male ego!
Excellent.
This could be the big break I've been waiting for.
I've, uh, taken the liberty of giving a
friend of mine the script.
She's a - a proper writer and proofreader, so...
My mum's a proofreader.
Did she read the script?
No, but it's still my story.
Hmm.
Well, it's just as well I had it professionally
proofread. There's some notes.
Uh, Gareth, I don't like - I don't want people
re-re-reading my-my-my-my screenplay.
Reuben!
L can't understand a word you're saying.
L don't want people reading my
screenplay without my permission.
Please don't go spreading it around.
Look, it never hurts to get a second opinion.
And you are really going to have to get
used to people criticising your work...
...if you want to be in this industry.
Haven't we - haven't we
already had this conversation?
Look, she has noidea!
Oh, what do you mean?
She - she says here "cut out the bubble scene"!
Let me see...
Yeah, look. Right here, in her notes. It says...
"Not a believable exchange between characters".
That's how it really happened, though!
Well, doesn't it matter? Does it serve a purpose?
Have you even read the screenplay?
Itis clearly a-a-a-a visual metaphor,
showing the characters' united resolve!
Of course I've read the screenplay, Reuben!
Do you think I'd be putting this much work into
something that I didn't understand completely?
Anyway, we're getting off track.
And-and right here, she says;
"It's too dry-wit with dialogue. It
isn't how people really speak."
She's gone through it, saying
"Ha!" and "LOL" all over the place.
Who does that with - with proofreading?
It's just her opinion, Reuben.
You don't have to nitpick it.
But she's gone through my entire
screenplay and nitpicked it!
She's a professional writer.
She's won awards for her work.
So what? This isn't her writing!
The funding bodies look favourably on projects
that have award-winning people attached.
The tighter you edit it, the more
chance you stand of making the film.
But I'm the writer.
Then why didn't you edit it?
L did! But she's gone through it with a chainsaw!
That's how you edit!
You have to be savage and cut a lot out.
But that's my job, as the writer. And how about --
What happens when I'm directing it?
Huh?
I'm directing this film, aren't 1?
- Are you?
- Yes!
What makes you think you know how to direct?
- My plays!
- It's not the same thing, Reuben.
Of course, it's the same thing!
L don't need to imagine the story,
like some other director would, I have lived it!
Ugh, so you keep saying!
Ugh!
Perhaps you're too close to the story.
Your - your - your decision making process
can be influenced by your emotional connection...
...to the finer points.
I really think you should reconsider...
...before taking on such a heavy
responsibility without some experience.
I 'have all the experience that I need.
And I never asked for this critical analysis from
somebody who has no idea about it.
Oh, oh, welll Ch. I won't tell her you said that.
Was it you, Gareth?
Ch, Reuben!
I 'have far better things to do with
my time than to fix your screenplay.
Look, about the legals...
Your, uh...
Your mum didn't proofread the screenplay,
because you said it's based on her?
So how many people in the actual script are real?
Quite a few.
Who?
Well, there's me, because it's
my story, and Derek and --
Yeah, yeah, I mean is -- is it your original work?
Of course.
Have the names and distinguishing
characteristics been changed?
Yeah, what are you getting at?
Well...
I need to get Lily to draw up contracts
for the people mentioned to give their approval...
...for their likeness and characters
based on them to be in the movie.
That isn't necessary at all.
At all.
Okay. Will your mum sue?
- Why would she sue?
- Defamation. Slander.
- I'm not slandering my own
mother in my screenplay.
- You never know!
No, I know. Nobedy is going to sue anybody.
It's called being prepared, Reuben.
Speaking of which...
I've, uh, done, uh, a script
breakdown for the budget.
I didn't think it would be this much.
No. Of course, you wouldn't.
This is how it's done in the professional industry.
I've done this budget the proper way.
Why are Derek and I only "proposed cast"?
Well, the funding corps are
going to want name actors, you know.
We probably should get some big names.
Is that why you're on here?
Well...
You want me to act and produce, don't you?
Well ye-yes... but there's no little
asterisk next to your name.
Ch, Reuben!
I'm a known actor!
You know...
Giving me top billing makes this project
far more attractive to distributors.
That should be your focus!
My focus is on the integrity of my screenplay!
And that bubble scene has to be in it for the plot!
We're not harping back to that, are we?
[exasperated cry]
You must be Reuben Heywood!
I read your script. It's very well done.
Well, thank you very much. I'm glad you think so.
Are you talking about the bubble scene?
Yes, but --
I thought it was inspired!
How did you come up with that?
It just sort hap-happened that way, I guess.
I was very eloquent with bubbles that night.
It's brilliant!
- The bubble is the perfect metaphor!
- Thank you! Thank you!
It's weightless, it can't be lifted by 100 men!
And it's too fragile. Imagine
100 men trying to lift at it!
[REUBEN] I was thinking if there were bubbles
coming through the frame
it would be really artistic...
[LILLIAN] Excellent!
$IT
I already did!
Nice to see you're keeping your
cool in this weather, Courtney.
Can you come and help me sort
those paint tins, out back?
I'm busy. Ask this couch potato.
Derek's had exams all week.
Well, ask Reuben. I can't remember the last time
he wasn't hanging around like a bad smell.
Reuben's off helping that actor
friend of his become a producer.
Shows fine leadership and equity.
Your hairdressing business might have
done better if you'd had a mentor.
Ch yeah, a mentor half my age and with
a speech imp -- a speech impediment!
Oh, shut up!
Oh look, what's burrowed into your mood today?
What does that mean?
Ugh, Mum!
She could never take a joke!
Is this a joke, Gareth?
L was looking at the Australian Screen Fund...
...and it clearly states that
they don't support projects
where one entity is the writer, director or actor.
So...
We could bump you intc a
cameo somewhere, but you
and your boyfriend just can't write your own roles.
Both of us? But what about Derek's role?
Well, he's never acted. We
don't even know if he can act.
L know he can act, I've seen him do it.
Reuben, nepotism is not a good thing.
Coming from you?
And - and nobody in here is even noted
as being good enough for Shane.
Ch, what? You don't think I can play the part?
- No, I --
- Who have you got in mind?
- Well, nobody but --
- Reuben! Do you want my help or not?
L'just think it would be more authentic if
Derek and I play ourselves. That - that's all.
Okay...
Well...
You won't get the funding and then you'll have
to make the film with unpaid acters and crew...
...who can walk off at any time.
Is that what you want?
- No! It's just --
- Look, Reuben!
If you do it my way...
...this film is going to make you a lot of money.
I don't want a lot of money, I want the catharsis.
That's not how business works!
This is show business.
You need to put on a show.
And to do that you need to go cut and
big name actors with lots of razzle dazzle,
not some kind of glorified home movie
with you and your boyfriend making cut.
- That's not what it is at all!
- You've gotta make money! You've got to!
You've got to reach large audiences!
You've got to cross cultural divides!
Qch, coh!
What if we make one of the characters Chinese?
- No!
- Why not?
Because the film isn't about that. It's about people
wi-wi-wi-with disabilities a-a-a-and who are deaf.
And...
Because the leads are LGBT
it's already an encrmous
cultural standpoint. And it's -
it's already relevant and topical.
You don't need to shoehorn in
every minority just to tick boxes...
...and the peint is, people will come
to a film for a good story.
It doesn't matter who the actors are.
You've clearly never made a movie before.
- No, I haven't but --
- And the ASF know it!
Excuse me, I'm trying to speak here!
Okay.
I'm listening.
No, you're not!
You're just... waiting for me
to finish so you can argue!
Huh?
Huh? What kind of uneducated belch is that?
Reuben! Life is too short for your stuttering!
Your patience is too short!
Ugh, now you're talking shit. I have to go to work.
- But, Gareth I was --
- No, Precious!
I don't want to hearit!
And no one else does either! I am working my
butt off for his film that's so important to you!
- But, Gareth, this is my --
- And this how you repay me?
- This is my life story --
- Get out!
- Gareth! Fuck!
I've been in the film industry longer
than you've been alive, Reuben!
I've seen the plight of gay and leshian people...
...I've been to third world countries and
seen the slums and the poverty there...
...but people help those people, Reuben,
because they're grateful
for everything they have ...
- No, Gareth! No!
- ... unlike you!
You think you-you-you can do w-w-w-w-whatever
you want h-h-h-here can't you, Gareth...
...but you can't! Because you
don't have any disabilities...
- Spit out, mate!
-...youaren't LGBT...
...and you don't have any poverty.
Because, lock around you, Gareth!
James Cameron wasn't on
the fuckin' Titanic, Reuben!
Yet he made one hell of a movie about it!
With big names! With big money!
The way it's supposed to be made!
You know how he made it?
Hm?
He filmed it in Mexico.
Using the local unemployed.
You see, it's not about altruism...
...it's about the fuckin' money! Now, get cut!
$IT
J But a part of me mourns
2 What will never be born
J Forever, my favourite regret
J He's gentle and kind
2 And totally blind
J To not see the life we could lead
J And he
J s destined to be
2 My favourite regret J
[MYLES] So, your mum drew that?
Mmhm. Little bit of a Derek shrine up there.
He looks like a surfing Jesus.
That's what he is. That's who he is.
She must care about him a lot.
She does, she does. I think she's always
been pretty worried about him. You know...
Deaf baby and everything.
But, I getit. You know, I think he needs support.
And I think it's hard for anyone
to have kids these days.
Let alone have a deaf kid, or grow up deaf.
Crazy...
Do you...?
Do you think, maybe, cne day...
Further down the line, of course,
like... you'd want kids? At all? Like...
Like, further down the track...
Do you see yourself...
having a little Courtney or a...
Alittle Man-Courtney?
- Alittle Man-Courtney!
- Alittle Man-Courtney?
Um... Yeah. No, I would. I would like kids...
But, I don't know. Again, with Derek...
Like, Dad was deaf so...
...I'think it's hereditary and...
You know, marriage and kids and
everything sounds really good, but it's...
...kinda stressful as well.
Yep.
Do you want kids?
Maybe.
Maybe, eh?
J Take what I've got
J Putthe restin abox
IS Addressed to the stars in the sky
J And soon
2 Up there with the moon
My favourite regret
J Forever, my favourite regret J
What are you deing, Gareth?
You're nearly through it!
Yes, it's quite an easy read.
Aside from some spelling and
punctuation here and there, it was...
...actually quite polished.
Are you sure this is the same version
you gave the original proofreader?
- Mmhm.
Don't do that.
You're a grown man, Reuben.
Mum...
Why didn't you have more
children when you had me?
When a woman has an abortion,
or a miscarriage
...or a stillbirth...
...the womb knows.
And the next baby would sense that.
Imagine growing in a place that lacked safety,
surrounded by worry and fear all the time.
Do you think that's why I have a stutter?
Don't be silly.
I never had an abortion ora
miscarriage before I had you!
When I was growing up, I would snuggle up to
you on the couch and you would never hug be back!
L knew it!
When I reached that scene, I nearly saw red!
I'm only building a character based on what I know.
No! You don't know the first thing about what a
woman goes through when she has a stillbirth!
Let alone when it's twins!
And... I'm sorry if that disqualifies
me from being Mother of the Year!
Mum! I was only basing a stage
play, based oh my own experience!
Look right here.
See this?
This is a comprehensive list of
everything that you are entitled to...
- Oh, come on!
- ... and which the world owes you!
Mum, I was just --
[door slams]
Reuben, stop!
Now, why did you go and
write that play about us?
It wasn't for you!
Stop.
Didn't you think that we'd find out?
It wasn't for you to find out,
it was for my own catharsis as a writer!
For the amateur theatre people,
which you never come to see anyway!
- Ortoseeme--
- Just slow down. Take a breath.
No, Dad! It was for me, not for you!
L guess - 1 gu - 1 guess I'm not
a good enough writer, am 1?
Reuben!
2 I've been down
S On my luck cut here, lately
JI've been broke
J Beaten and bruised
2 I've been lost and confused
2l den't know which path to take
J She walked out like a scene from a movie
J She stopped
J She turned and she said, yeah
2 While I stood right there
2 Mmm
2 Just holding her gaze
J 1 don't want to sleep...
J ... by myself tonight &
Hm, Gareth?
Shh.
2 Just lie here with me
J Stay by my side &
What have you got your pants on for?
Um...
Your insomnia playing up?
Mmhm.
Yes.
Did you sleep well last night?
J Stay by my side &
Then you won't be needing your pants.
J Stay here tonight
J Stay by my side
J Stay here tonight, ooh
2 Just stay by my side &
$IT
[LILLIAN] Now!
Ugh, now!
Now?
[Gareth exerts himself]
$IT
[inaudible]
[ringtone]
Reuben Heywood.
[GARETH] Ruby, it's Gareth. How're you doin'?
[GARETH] You haven't been
answering your phone...
...I thought, maybe you've
been screening your calls.
Uh, I hope our little quarrel
last week didn't upset ya?
No, I've been, um...
...job hunting.
[GARETH] Oh! Oh, uh, that's not going to distract
you from the film tee much, is it?
[GARETH] Hey, I could get another director, or...
[GARETH] ... in fact, I could bump an A.D.
in to direct, if you can't handle it.
N-n-no. It's fine...
I've got it.
Okay. Cool, yeah, great.
Great. Listen, um...
I need you to change one of
the roles to suit Shelley Astor.
[REUBEN] In "The Burden of Being Me"?
Yeah, she just cleaned up at the Young Talent
Music Awards and there's murmurings...
...that she's looking for film
roles. What do you think?
But why for this film?
I mean, it's a story about two gay guys
and Shane, who you're playing.
There's just no role for her.
Eh... doesn't matter. We change a role to suit her.
I think a heterosexual romance has
more marketability anyway.
That's fine but what about the story that I wrote?
Reuben, you stumbled into the film
industry because you got rejected...
...from amateur theatre.
I have all the practical skills
to make this film properly.
You, pardon me for being blunt, do not.
I know how professional films work.
I've won the awards.
Believe me, I know better, okay?
Are you crying?
Geez, Rubes.
Next time you find your balls,
make sure you stick 'em on harder, ckay?
Oil Lily?
Lil?
Oi, Lil.
You'll never guess what just happened.
I heard. That was nasty.
What's the matter with you?
L just had my period.
Oh!
Well, so, that's a good thing, right?
Because you thought you were...
...hitting the... change?
Until this morning, I thought I had missed it.
Exactly!
And until this morning, I was happy because...
...I thought I was pregnant.
This again!
Yes! This again! My body's a ticking clock, Gareth!
Well, maybe you're having trouble conceiving
because you're so stressed about it.
That's not fair.
Well, it's still true.
We're having trouble conceiving!
L wish you'd start to realize
how important this is to me!
Lil, do you even think it's fair,
we have a child at our age?
L want to be a mother.
Well, great! Just. Not. Now.
I've given my soul to this marriage and all I'm
asking for is a little physical compensation.
Huh! Little?
You're talking about ancther human being.
Don't you want to leave a legacy?
I've got an idea.
Oh, yeah?
Yeah, you draw me up a contract for Reuben,
giving me full rights to the script...
...inall territories, in perpetuity.
Oh, wow. That's a big call. Will he accept that?
Well, he'll have to if we stand a chance of getting
this one last movie made. And then...
We can stop racing the clock...
You can have your baby...
And I get to go out on top!
L see!
What about compensation?
Compensation, for --
Ch, Reuben! Yeah, uh...
10% of the budget should
cushion the little princess.
So, what you're saying is...
As long as you get what you want,
I can get what I want?
I'd like nothing more.
At least what I want won't take a miracle.
2l am all of everything
Jlam east and west
[knock at door]
2l am wind and I'm the sea
2 Oh, it's I who loves you best &
- Myles! What a surprise!
- Hi.
You should have called. Courtney is out with Derek.
Oh, I - I know. I wanted to speak
to you when she wasn't here.
Sounds serious, come in.
You know I love Courtney, so much.
Yes, anybody can see that.
And I know she's had a really hard time this last
year with her business failing and everything...
But... l was thinking now
might be the right time to...
Faye...
I would like to ask Courtney to marry me.
Far out! And you want my blessing?
And to ask a favour.
Yes?
Well, Courtney's probably going to want to have
the wedding in Bali or Vanuatu or something...
...and I realize, not everyone's equipped to do that.
So I was thinking, we could
stage a surprise party here;
invite all her friends, some photographers...
...and I could propose in the middle of the party.
That scunds absclutely inspired, I love it!
- Also. ..
- Mm?
Having now met Matthew, I don't
suppose he'd like to make either journey.
No, I'm afraid Matthew's quite set in his ways.
Well, I was thinking that I could
setup alive video stream to him...
...with your permission, of course.
So, it would be like he's here, but he's not here.
Would I have to interact with him in any way?
No, it'd just be like he's watching
asurveillance tape.
Of his daughter's wedding propesal?
Pretty much, yeah.
Myles Bradford!
You are a gentleman and a scholar!
And a solicitously brilliant romantic!
I'd be pleased to help you crganize the party and...
I wish you and Courtney many
blessed years together!
Thank you.
Thank you! Thank you, Faye!
J When you're at the end of an end
2l am all of everything
Jlam all of everything &
oh, Lily!
Sorry, I didn't see you there!
I have the contract you asked for.
Thanks, Hun.
What were you deing?
Uh, just... learning to sign.
L'just think the romantic lead would be
a better role for me if I aged him up a bit.
Oh...
So, you'll be giving up the
role of Shane for the role of...
...Rebin, but... making him older?
I'm geing to combine Shane
and Robin into one juicy role.
I think it'd be better then.
- For the film, you mean?
- Yeah, yeah.
So, you'd be playing the role of the guy
with the stutter, but making him straight...
...and also aging him up?
That's actually quite compelling.
L can see you making a comeback
with a role that complex!
Are you actually going to make him
ahomophobe, the way Shane is, as well?
Ch, nah, I'm gonna get rid of that bullshit.
L just think it'd be better if...
...the audience identified with the character,
and far better if they could
understand what he was saying, if...
...he was a straight guy,
that got tongue-tied.
So, what makes him so "tongue-tied"?
Ah!
Wait, you can't just do that!
Well, when I have full veto, I can.
I can do whatever I want.
You want a baby, don't you?
Yes! But...
Yes, but what?
Well...
I think it's the...
...dynamic of the guy with the stutter and
his deaf partner that give the film its, um...
...its social commentary and
its, um... moral compass.
Yeah?
And the girl. As lovely as she is...
...could...
...could be his, um... his sister? You know?
...l suppose I could do that. But...
I don't even know if Shelley's going
to do the role. I guess I could ask her.
Aw, it would really boost my
star-power if we collaborated, though!
Ooh! Imagine that. Wow.
But why on this project?
"The Burden of Being Me"
is a such a powerful and dynamic story.
Why not collaborate with this, um...
...Shelley Astor...
...oh something you actually care about?
Something about a beautiful
singer that shows off her big...
...voice! You know?
Lily! You're overloading my brain!
Can't you see I'm trying to rehearse?
Now, go away!
The truth doesn't need to be "rehearsed".
[ringtone]
Hello?
She is?
Oh, my God, that is fantastic -- no.
Thank you. When? Oh, uh, where - where? Where?
Yep, yep. Oh, ckay. Ch!
I'll be there. Thank you.
Thank you! Thank you so much!
Okay, bye now!
Bye!
Who was that?
Shelley's agent!
She wants to meet and talk
to me about doing the film!
Oh!
Good morning, Mr. Donahue!
I'm... I'm such an avid fan.
No, I am a big fan. Really, truly.
Sit, please. Sit, sit.
Um, my publicist is over there by the bar...
...ll was hoping we could get a drink shortly, or...?
Yeah! Well - well... Absolutely!
Anything! Look, anything you want. I'm just so...
...excited to have the opportunity
to work with you. It's...!
Yes! Now, tell me about this film of yours.
Did you know that this is the
sign for shell? As in Shelley?
I'm a singer, Gareth.
The deaf are hardly my target demographic.
Ch, no, no, no.
That's just it!
L'am inspired...
...tointroduce you to the silver screen...
...inthe most unpredictable
characterisation you could think of;
As a singer...
...who falls in love with a deaf man!
Ah, that's... that's fascinating!
Are - are you writing or directing it?
Well, I'm... I'm definitely producing, but, um...
...l could write and direct, I suppose.
You haven't written it yet?
Oh, yeah. Yeah, it's... I've written it.
It's just, uh, I need to make seme, uh...
Just... minor adjustments.
Oh! Right, okay.
It's, uh... You look lovely, by the way.
Oh, thank you.
I really love the album too! It's just...
Thanks! I'm pretty excited about it.
Reuben!
My good man!
Ay, thanks for coming around.
I know how you like to communicate...
...with text and email but I can't
stand all that crap, besides --
-- time is of the essence. I think I've
finally solved our little problem.
Come onin, come on in!
Reuben...
...meet Peter Raymond.
He's going to play the role of Drake in
"The Burden of Being Me"!
But that's Derek's role. He needs to be deaf.
He is deaf!
Isn't that great?
Lily found him.
Well, actually, his disability support worker...
...uh, hired Lily to prosecute the
drama school, when they wouldn't...
...change the course to suit his needs.
But she's very good. She won, of course.
Oh, I've got some paper work for you to sign.
But, why?
Think about it, right. The
deafness in our script is good...
...but having a character...
...that's deaf and has cerebral palsy
just knocks it out of the park!
For originality, den't you think?
What about my character?
The one w-w-with the stutter?
Oh, yeah, yeah, I want to talk to you about that one.
I 'haven't told you yet, so brace yourself.
I've managed to secure Shelley
Astor to play the role...
...of Robyn. Robin, witha Y.
But Robin's my character!
What, no, no, no, no! Not anymore.
She's a singer who falls in love with a deaf man...
. only, his estranged father, Shane, gets in --
But-but-but-but you're playing Shane!
Yeah, yeah, I'm playing Shane.
He tries to break them up, their romance,
because he's a- he's a jealous dad.
But don't worry, I've...
I've written him just as, uh, nasty and as
relatable as you originally intended.
No, you haven't! You've just
hijacked my whole story!
Uh... What do you think?
[loud thumping]
Hey, hey! Don't cut me out of this conversation!
You, see... Reuben...
Able-bodied actors get Oscars for playing
characters like Peter with authenticity.
We've got the real thing!
- And Shelley Astor?
- Yes! And Shelley Astor!
But that's another complication!
Why would you want to complicate things?
Complications?
You think Peter is a complication?
In this instance, yes!
It's still a love story involving a deaf man!
You've got to be more grateful for what you've got
and you've got to be more
flexible with your rigid ideas.
I don't believe this!
Oh, okay, you're just butt-hurt
that's not a queer love story!
Is that what's got your goat? Hey?
Not at all! Gareth!
Reuben!
Let me give you some advice, ckay?
Make the changes to the script.
Sign on the dotted line.
And then let's make this movie
that's sc important to you.
Okay?
Okay...
Okay!
It's no accident that the face
is the same size as your hand.
Perfect for face-palming.
But, I'm reading through the contract
and Peter has a point.
This film could get a lot of praise
and recognition for its uniqueness.
[ringtone]
It's Gareth.
Hello, Gareth?
Reuben!
Yeah, yeah, how are ya?
Yeah, ook, lock, have you signed that contract?
You mean the one where I sign over
100% of the - of - of my story to you?
No, I haven't signed it.
Well, shit, Reuben. What are you waiting for?
We've got Shelley Astor on board...
...we've got all the proposals for
The Australian Screen Fund...
...The Film Finance of New South Wales,
The Sydney Screen Company...
...they're all ready to go.
Do you want funding or not?
Why am I signing over 100% of
creative control to you, again?
That's how it's done.
The writer grants the producer full veto rights.
The funding bodies pay the budget to the producer
because they're reliable and bankable...
...and promise a return on their investment.
It's industry standard. Trust me.
But...
But Derek says I should have it
checked over by a professional.
Well, yeah, how soon can you do that?
No! No, no, that's... uh, there's not encugh time.
You've got to sign it and scan it, now!
Reuben, I have to deliver the contract by...
. dpm.
Why 4pm?
Well, look, it's something about...
...submissions. I dunno. It's...
They probably want the information so they can
collate it before the end of business day.
I haven't told you befere, Reuben,
because I know how you hate...
...getting stressed about these things.
But I can't wait any longer.
You have to sign it, right now!
I really don't like making demands on people.
Okay, but I must insist.
Trust me.
You don't need to read the fine print.
There's no time for it, anyway.
Besides, it's just a standard agreement.
The real agreement, like I said...
...is between you and me.
So, what is "our agreement"?
[GARETH] Oh, geez, Reuben, we've been over this.
Look, our agreement is;
That we're going to make your
story into a film. Have it your way.
Your cast, your choice of crew...
...and at the end of the day, we split it 50/50.
And I promise you...
...that all that bullying and rejection that you
grew up with with culminate
into the biggest and best...
...that all that bullying and rejection that you
grew up with with culminate
into the biggest and best...
... trlumph of your life!
...triumph of your life!
What did you say about... Shelley Astor?
And Peter Raymond? And the investors? And...
.can I still use Derek?
You want this, don't you, Reuben?
Think of all those bully's
taunts. Count up all the times
you've been teased for your stutter...
...or wearing glasses or
being a sensitive little soul.
You wanna make this movie, don't you?
You want to show those turkeys up, don't you?
What are you waiting for?
We're on a deadline, Reuben!
We only get this chance once and everything
is in perfect alignment, in this moment!
Shelley is a massive star!
And you've got me!
Who's going to help you, Reuben?
What's going to happen now...
...if you don't trust me?
Okay.
Okay?
Okay...
I'm sending you the contract now.
[GARETH] Good bey, Reuben. Talk to you later.
L see you really twisted his arm on that one.
It's all a bit... really... Darwinian, isn't it?
Did you even mean a word of what you just said?
Oh, Lillian...
You can't maintain a nice garden without
spreading a little bit of bullshit around.
L see.
Look, Hun...
I'm net normally insensitive, but when I am...
...he'll get over it.
[ringtone]
Hello?
Reuben, hey! It's... it's Doug.
Um...
Look, I'm not sure how to break
this to you, so I'm just genna...
...Il glanced at the contact you sent me.
And...
...well, I'm kind of having trouble
understanding why you signed it.
What do you -- what do you mean?
Well...
Did you even read it before signing it?
Why?
It's just...
I mean, I've never seen anything like it.
The contract is so heavily
biased in Gareth's favour.
It's like...
It's like you've literally signed your life away.
He said it was standard industry practice
for a producer to have full rights to a film.
Hm, well, there's truth in that, but...
I mean, there's nothing in there
about upfront compensation.
There's a...
...aclause that alludes to "10% of the budget",
but you don't have a budget in place yet.
And...
...then it goes on to say that the
producer has complete and utter jurisdiction...
...to change and edit whatever
he wants at any given time.
What does that mean for me?
Well, it means that you'll only see your 10%
if Gareth produces the film you've written.
He won't.
He means to change the entire thing.
Yep...
...that's pretty clear in the
language of the contract.
Do you think he'll keep you on as a writer?
Maybe...
Reuben, you should have read this thing.
I know you and you take people at face value.
You want to trust, but...
Man, you've signed a deal with the devil.
- This is why I need you to help
with the fees, so you can...
- Oh my God!
...l don't know what's more stupid.
The terms of this garbage...
...orthe fact that you signed it!
- But Mum, I --
- Having read your original screenplay...
...I thought it was in quite horrible taste to base
those characters on your father and l.
- Maybe if you --
- And this! This is precisely what happens to films...
...based on nasty intentions.
- Maybe if you --
- You end up signing contacts like this!
Maybe if you took more interest in my writing,
you'd understand I had to --
No, no. Stop, look. All right,
we're not in a position...
...to fund your legal fees.
- But, Dad!
- No, no, you're going to have to
take this cne on your chin. Okay?
It's time you grew up, mate.
We're rehearsing. What do you want?
L want to perform in this year's showcase.
Are you kidding?
Did you forget that you walked out on us?
No, I remember... I'm actually making a
film about it, in case you hadn't heard.
No, I heard.
Word gets around.
So, who did you get to play me?
Nobody, because the film isn't being
made, anyway. At least, not with me.
- What do you mean?
- Emily, we're waiting for you!
Ch, Reuben.
Where's the boyfriend?
Shut up, Blake. The only thing uglier
than your haircut is your personality.
Uh-uh-uh!
Reuben.
Come on, man. That's not the way to make friends.
Pfftl F-f-f-friends? Wh-w-w-wh-with you twe?
Look, what are you doing here?
He only wants to burrow back into the theatre
because he's been kicked out of his own film, Emily.
- What?
- Yeah!
That interpreter, Felicity, told me!
Ch, she heard it from some, uh,
deaf actors Reuben's boyfriend knows.
Apparently, they were all thinking of boycotting it...
...until it dawned on them that there
would be more deaf characters...
...and that they could be in the
same film as THE Shelley Astor!
Oh my Geod, are you for real?
You know what, guys, just forget it. I'm resigned te
being the victim. I'm pretty used to it!
- Ugh!
- Reuben!
Look. If you actually have
a showcase idea in mind...
- ...I'minterested to see what you have.
- Emily!
Seriously, Blake. Shut up.
Come on.
You've rehearsed? You're all prepared?
L -1 have rehearsed.
And I'm not nervous at all.
Good. You are prepared, though?
You've learned your part?
I'm ready, I'm ready.
- Okay. I'm sure you'll do fine.
- Mum, please, you're making me --
Are you all ready for next Saturday night?
Aw, I wouldn't miss it. I'm so excited.
Oh, it's going to be a beautiful
surprise proposal party.
I'm happy to help.
Uhm... Actually, um...
Hm, yes, what?
No, but I expect it'll be scmetime soon, why?
Hm, wow! Very ambitious.
And I suppose that the lead role
would be perfect for my son?
No?
You want me to invest in it?
My arts grant?!
The one that I earned through my art-making
practice! The one that I competed for!
Please, Faye. It's a film about the deaf. And - and...
...it has Auslanin it and it showcases the
community you've made feel such a part of...
I'm sorry, Reuben. The answer's no!
Uh, good evening ladies and gentlemen
and welcome to this evening's showcase.
Our show will be commencing
in just a few minute's time...
...soif you could all please
make your way to your seats,
please ensure that all mobile
devices are switched off,
and I hope you have an enjoyable evening.
Thank you.
[applause]
Melody's bosom heaved with blunt regret,
as she stood on the peak of the Irish moor.
Her corset strangled her aching heart,
as the icy wind stroked...
...through her thick, chestnut hair.
She knew...
...there was an omen in every moment.
She that this was her moment to choose.
Satisfaction...
...or sacrifice.
Love...
...or loneliness.
Life...
...or death.
[applause]
That was Blake Rhodes, with his reading of...
..."An Omen in Every Moment", by Edith Keegan.
Next up, we have...
"Feathers From A Thousand Li Away"
Apassage from "The Joy Luck
Club", written by Amy Tan...
...and performed by Reuben Heywood.
{muttering to self)
Hopefully, it won't be as shit.
"The old woman remembered a swan she'd bought,
years age in... Shanghai for a foolish sum..."
2 [gentle Oriental music] &
The old woman remembered...
...aswan she had bought years
ago in Shanghai for a foolish sum...
..."this bird," boasted the market vendor...
..."was once a duck that stretched it neck out
in hopes of someday becoming a goose...
...and now look, it is too beautiful to eat!"
So the woman and the swan
sailed across an ocean...
...many thousands of Li wide...
...stretching their necks toward America.
On her journey, the woman coced to the swan;
"In America, I will have a daughter just like me...
"...bul over there, no one will say her worth is
measured by the loudness of her husband's beleh.
"Over there, no one will look down on her...
"...'cause I will make her speak
only perfect American English.
"And over there, she will be too
full to ever swallow any sorrow.
"She will know my meaning,
because I will give her this swan.
"Acreature that became more
than what was hoped for."
But when the woman arrived in the new country...
...the immigration officials
took the swan away from her!
Leaving the woman fluttering her arms...
...with only a single swan feather...
...fora memory.
And she had to fill cut so many forms that...
...she forgot why she left Shanghai
and why she'd come in the first place.
Now the woman was old.
And she had a daughter who
grew up speaking only English...
...and drinking more Coca-Cola than sorrow.
Foralong time now...
...the woman wanted to give her daughter
the single swan feather and tell her;
"This feather might look worthless...
"...butit comes from afar...
"...and carries with it, all my good intentions."
And so the woman waited...
...year after year...
...until she could tell her daughter this...
...in perfect American English.
[applause]
Hello, may I please speak to
Gareth Donahue, please?
Oh, excellent. Great, how are you?
Good, uh, good.
My name is Courtney and I'm calling
from the Australian Screen Fund.
Yeah, yeah, I just have a
couple of questions to ask you.
L haven't submitted anything yet.
[COURTNEY] Uhm, they're
just preliminary questions.
Uh, yep, sure. Go ahead.
Okay, great! Um, question one...
What the fuck is wrong with you?
Reuben, you little shit!
Don't you dare call here again!
- Is something wrong, Gareth?
- Shut up, Lillian!
[phone rings]
What?
Gareth, do you even understand how much
bad karma you're bringing on yourself?
Rubes, you know I don't believe in that crap.
No, you wouldn't believe in that,
'cause you don't believe in yourself, either.
You just take other people's ideas, as your own...
...and give them no credit for it
-- or reward for their hard work.
You just smudge intricate
details into some bland cliché,
devoid of any authenticity or sincerity...
...and all in the name of grubby
money and unregulated power!
Oh.
Oh, okay, what are you gonna do about it? Huh?
Gotothe papers? Start a smear campaign?
L will take you down for defamation so hard,
you will leave a crater in the pavement!
You think I would give you
that kind of satisfaction by
naming names and giving you that kind of notoriety?
What do ya want, Rubes?
An apology? Huh?
You're not gonna get one.
Oh, I know, some uninterrupted time to tell me off!
Well, I'm not listening!
You said yourself I can bombard you over
the pheone like nobody else can!
L can talk over you like a radio signal!
No! You can pull the wool cver my eyes...
...and you can fool other people inte
following your leadership with your...
...slick sales pitch and big promises --
I can just keep geing forever if you want, Ruby.
It doesn't really matter, 'cause
I'm not gonna be listening.
Ha! Keep talkin', buddy.
-- And you can take my story and you can change
the names and the genders and
the careers and the motivations...
. and you can give my character
an accent or a lisp or...
...a-a-an enlarged tongue, or no tongue or...
...false teeth or no speech skills at
all, but you can't silence me, Gareth!
Or my truth about what a horrible,
vicious shake in the grass you are!
[clears throat]
You've been listening to my
private phone conversations!
L somehow feel strangely invelved!
Oh and I suppose you agree with him?
Every incredulous word!
Look at yourself, Gareth!
You're turning into a menster!
Aw, are you scared of me, Lily?
Uh, of you? Christ no!
I'm scared of whatever it is that
makes me support you...
...and your nasty little secrets!
Those nasty little secrets bought
this house and everything in it!
Well, I despise this house
and I loathe everything in it!
There's the door.
How am I supposed to enjoy the tainted
reward for the suffering of other pecple?
You really expect me to share
in the spoils of your delusions?
It's never bothered you before!
Well, it's always bothered me and maybe
if you paid a little bit more attention...
...you might understand that!
I don't need this shit.
[phone rings]
I tell you, if that's Reuben... I'm
gonna throttle the little prick.
Ooh.
[phone rings]
Hey! Shelley!
How are you, beautiful?
You did?
Who'd you get?
Ch, I love her!
That's box office, right there!
2 [groovy music] &
[general chatter]
Hey, Reuben! I'm glad you could make it.
Are you kidding? I wouldn't miss it for the world.
I'm so excited to see Myles propose!
I know, it's very exciting.
You know, I've realized something.
You're a little runt.
Pardon me?
Do you remember when Derek first introduced us?
And ... Itold you the story
about when he was little and...
...him wanting a puppy and
how I had to explain to him
that the littlest and weakest
one was the most special?
So, I'm the weak little outcast, am I?
No, you are the one chosen by nature
to face the toughest of obstacles.
And with that, you gain the
most strength and support.
Well, thank you, Faye. I'm really feeling it now.
Maybe this will help;
It may seem worthless...
...butit comes from my heart...
...and it carries with it, the best of intentions.
How can you afford this?
Ch! Worst case scenario,
I'll just have to use crayons instead of paints.
It's a balanced risk I'm willing to take.
- Thank you.
- Gimme a hug.
So, when she gets here, are we all
going to hide and surprise her?
No, Mum.
You just... wait for her to walk in and
I'll kneel down on one knee and propose.
Simple as that.
There's charm in simplicity.
What's geing on?
Quiet everybody, Myles is
going to propose to her now!
[gasping]
Um...
Yeah.
What he said...
Will you?
[thudding on counter-top]
What?
Would...
Okay, goon... Ask me.
Courtney Shanahan...
...will you marry me?
I've... been waiting... for this
moment since I was a little girl...
Yes, of course!
Of course I'll marry you!
[awkward clapping]
Reuben, do you even
comprehend what you've done?
Oh, lock Faye, just leave me the fuck alone, will ya?
L feel bad encugh already!
That's it, just fuck off, you stupid bitch!
He told your mother to fuck off.
No!
You fuck off!
[shocked murmurs]
And Reuben, you can consider
that cheque null and void!
Reuben!
2 All my strings are being pulled
J Towards you
2 Mmm
J I haven't felt this torn in a while
J} Maybe never at all
2 If you think there's something
J Darlin', please let me in
J Cos I'm fighting with myself on this one
2 And I can't win
2 Theroadis long and my heart is tired
21 wish that I could find socme peace of mind
IS You were so big on honesty
J But, baby, honestly
21 don't know what I've done
2 If you think there's something
J Darlin', please let me in
Hello?
Reuben...
J Cos I'm fighting with myself on this one
Derek's died.
2 And I can't win
2l can't win
J When I've lost so many times
JIfl don't even know what's mine
2l can't win
S If you won't even let me try
2 If you think there's something
J Darlin', please let me in
J Cos I'm fighting with myself on this one
JAnd I can't win &
[JULIA] It's ckay...
[Reuben sobs]
J [ethereal music] &
[soft chatter]
You really have some nerve.
How am I supposed to go on sighing now,
when every gesture reminds me of Derek?
And after all he did for you
and your speech impediment
and you're prepared to just wash
your hands of him? Literally?
I 'have lost the only person
who ever loved me for me.
That's not my preblem.
You really should have let me
put my screenplay in with him.
It could have been cremated too, then.
And you're thinking about your screenplay now?
Of course I am.
That screenplay was the manifestation
of my love for Derek and the gift that he gave me.
Without it, I've got no semblance of him.
So, you tell me, Faye...
That's what he would have wanted.
[GARETH] Shelley, I swear, the funding is coming,
we've just to put it in the next round.
No, I know. I-l know I said
we'd have the funding by now,
but I can't be responsible
for what the funding bod --
Oh, wh --
Hey, hey, don't take that tone.
I'm deing this for you, okay?
The least I expect, is that you show me the s --
Well, cancel the tour! We've got a movie to make!
No...
Shelley, hey, baby, this role is perfect for you.
That's why I want you, and only you, lead the film.
Please!
Shelley...
Don't give up oh me. Okay,
look, look. Just let me level --
Yes! I need you, the funding --
What do you mean I'm all talk? How dare you?
Oh!
Oh, what? So you're quitting?
Uh, well, you just remember
who my legal rep is, okay?
Oh yeah? Well, we'll see about
that! Look, Shelley, shut up!
L can't deal with you, right now!
And you'd better be ready for the legal ramific --
Shelley!
L know, right?
Gareth, you're just going to have to give up
on that film. Just drop it, okay?
No, Lily.
I'll just find another star. I've got connections.
I can make it work!
L own it.
I can do what I want with it.
And thanks to you, it's legal and binding.
Hm, thanks to me, you're geing straight to Hell.
What on Earth are you talking about?
What the fuck's this?
Remember Reuben? The stuttering
playwright we slapped in the face?
Well, his deaf boyfriend died last month.
And Reuben's pouring his heart out
in a stage play in honour of his memory.
Well, I'm not respensible for that!
You'd better have a look at this play.
If he's using anything from "Burden”, we'll sue him!
You stole that man's baby!
The same way you begrudge me of mine!
Oh, for crying out loud!
He gave it to you to surrogate
and nurture and bring to term!
And you just snatched it away
and now, because of me...
...there's been an enormous miscarriage of justice!
Well, no more!
No more what?
I'm sick of your nonsense, Gareth!
I'm geing to give Reuben his film back.
You will do no such thing, Lily!
Gareth! You are a lowly, despicable dog!
You have the gall to insult that man's integrity
and his commitment to his work...
...even when he's suffered such a significant loss?
Lily, you're getting a bit upset.
You're a bully!
You're a coward, you're a thief
and you're a -- argh, a bully!
I've done nothing illegal!
You've done nothing ethical, or even fair!
- Oh, apparently, I stole someone's baby!
- From me!
You stole my chance at
having children! And now this!
Reuben's created this script cut of nothing!
He crafted it out of complete
belief in himself and the whole time...
...you've just been sitting there like a spider,
waiting to devour it!
You know that film belongs to Reuben.
And you can't just run off with somecne's
life force and say it's your own!
I don't have to listen to this shit!
Oh, yes you do!
And you will!
You are absolutely, batshit mad! Do you know that?
When we got married, I wanted to have children.
You said wait. So, I did!
L waited years for you to build
your career and I built mine.
Waiting patiently for you to say it was the right time!
L stamped and signed over
all your dirty, rotten deals.
I 'hung off your arm at every pompous,
self-indulgent awards ceremony.
But you...!
You just take all the energy and take over and...
You are the cancer to the
fulfillment of decent people!
Well, fuck me drunk!
Didn't you marry poorly!
You conned us both out of cur chance at happiness!
Those two were in love!
- It's not ab--
- The same way we were in love!
It's not about love!
It's about doing it the correct way.
Oh, and I suppose your way is the correct way?
Exactly!
You're really going to claim expertise on this?
Yes!
You're going to hijack Reuben's story;
The autobiography of a gay playwright,
with a stutter, who learns to sign...
...only to lose his deaf boyfriend 50 years
too soon -- and somehow -- you're geing to have...
...superior knowledge on the subject, over him?
Weren't we talking about
parenthood a moment ago? Huh?
For Christ's sake, Lily! Pick
a complaint and stick with it!
L 'am not responsible for your happiness!
You are solely responsible for my unhappiness!
All right, now you're being pathetic.
You're pathetic!
Oh!
What are you gonna do, huh?
You're gonna ruin me?
Divorce me?
What will you have then? Huh?
No children. Not even a potential father for them.
Exactly, so tell me what I have to lose!
Me!
Lillian, you lose me!
Aw, well, good fucking riddens!
No wonder we can't conceive a child.
You're incapable of conceiving an original idea!
Where are you going?
Get back here!
I'm going to restore hope back to
the life of a fellow human being!
Something you wouldn't understand!
You can't save the world, Lillian!
Ng, but I can save one man's last semblance of his!
Those contracts still stand!
Aw, yeah? Well, sue me!
Goddamn it!
Fuck!
J [peaceful acoustic music] &
Private rehearsal, sorry!
What do you want?
I... just want to extend...
...my deepest sympathies..
...and most sincere regrets.
Thanks.
So, how are you?
Devastated!
Thank you!
I've been thinking a lot about Gareth.
And how he's rewriting your script...
...to fit Shelley and Peterin...
...which would give no reason to credit
or compensate you, for your contribution.
I've had on my mind a lot lately, myself.
Well, you know you can do the same to him, right?
What?
Even without changing the premise.
You can't copyright history.
What about... intellectual property?
It's your story.
Gareth might own... an account toit...
You, meanwhile, have the actual
memory and experience.
Change the names, rearrange the plot and
you've got yourself a whole new "Burden”.
I'll say.
Well, unlike Gareth, I've actually read
"The Burden of Being Me".
You're a very talented writer.
Who clearly has vivid insight into what he loves.
L did have...
. until he stole it.
Just because Gareth owns the
title and the deeds to that story...
...doesn't mean he has a claim to the...
...title of the film or deeds therein.
Don't you see?
If someone wanted to create a reality TV show on...
...celebrities wanting to beat each other up.
They could have just as easily
have called it "Star Wars".
Um...
I'm pretty sure that would
be legal action, right there.
There's always loopholes. Trust me.
Derek once said, um...
"Love all but...
...trust few."
I'm pretty sure that was Shakespeare.
What would I know?
I'm just - just a thespian.
Do you mind if I just watch you rehearse?
Okay.
Peter, I know I'm not very
good at finger-spelling, but...
...I'm-1'mtrying my best, so cut me some slack.
Um... go - go ahead.
Peter, please don't quit.
Go ahead.
Stopped keying? What - what?
St-stop -- operator, wh-what does it -- ?
Oh, he... he hung up?
Uh, thanks... Um...
Oh, yeah, uh...
Stop keying.
Go ahead.
[group laughter]
Merry Christmas!
Reuben...
I've got something for you...
Just that I thought that I'd
invest in my son's legacy.
The runt puppy that...
...turned into a swan.
A creature that was more than
anybody could ever hope for.
$IT
Call it!
Twenty-seven, take one!
Action!
J Take what I've got
J Putthe restin abox
IS Addressed to the stars in the sky
J And soon
2 Up there with the moon
- [applause]
- I My favourite regret
J Forever, my favourite regret J
Thank you all for coming tonight.
Now that you've seen my feature film,
"The Purpose of Being Me"
You'll see why I need to thank some
people in the audience tonight.
Not - n-not just those who... uh... supported and...
...loved me throughout the whole ordeal, but those
who were challenging and bullying me throughout it.
'Cause it's thanks to you that I had to...
...strive for excellence. To...
...overcome and prove you wrong.
And I would hope that this film will help
others to pursue their creative endeavours...
...in whatever form they may take.
Even thought the words I have to say
might have trouble getting out sometimes,
what l... want to say should
not be lost in translation.
Because actions speak louder than words.
[applause]
$IT
2 Some kind of a smile
J Twisted upside up until I fall down
J To the ground
J Sky is painted in pixels of blue
J And once again
IS 1 think of you
2 My hands are made
2 Of childish games
J The kind of thing
J} We used to play
2 Now I'm old
My future's told
J Maybe I'll find love
J When I'm done
J You have got a hold on me
J Take my lungs so I can breathe
J I feel a sound might drag me down
J But I am louder than the voices now
J You have got a hold on me
J Take what's left and let me be
2 I think it's time to see this through
J To get distance from you
J Without a doubt
21 find myself becoming one in the crowd
J Then who's to blame
J When the winter winds pull me away
J And where we stay
J We will remain
J The rising dawn
J} My past is gone
JIt's never enough
J You have got a hold on me
J Take my lungs so I can breathe
1 feel a socund might pull me down
J But I am louder than the voices now
J You have got a hold on me
J Take what's left and let me be
2 I think it's time to see this through
J To get distance from you
J The ice is thin and the cracks still show
J You have got a hold on me
J Take my lungs so I can breathe
J I feel a sound might drag me down
J But I am louder than the voices now
J You have got a hold on me
J Take what's left and let me be
2 I think it's time to see this through
J To get distance from you
J From you
2 To get distance from you &