Oh! This looks yummy.
It's a part of my plan
so you miss me a lot, a lot, a lot...
You don't need a plan.
I'm already missing you.
- Oh, yeah?
- Yes.
Oh, you are missing me already.
Hey, I will miss the plane.
- You can't leave me like this!
- They won't wait for me!
Honey, I don't know
when we'll see each other again!
Don't get mad.
No, it's fine.
Look, it's your mom.
No way, I will call her later.
- Pick up, c'mon.
- No.
- You know what?
- What?
Since I'm traveling
to my parents' wedding anniversary...
- Right.
- So...
...I will ask them for money
so I can come see you.
- So I can go as soon as possible.
- OK, stop talking or you'll jinx it.
OK!
Oh, I can't wait to be there.
- I'm going to pack.
- OK.
- Do you need anything?
- No.
- Are you sure?
- Yes.
Do you need help?
- We'll talk, OK?
- Yes.
Deal.
- Phone me when you get there.
- Of course.
I will miss you. A lot.
- A lot, lot, lot...
- We'll keep in touch.
Here you go.
- Do you have everything? Passport?
- Yes!
- Yes, yes, I got it.
- You sure?
A SKELETON IN THE CLOSET
Manuel Lieto?
- That's me.
- Come in.
Thanks.
Mom, I passed! Tell dad.
Honey, I passed, so I am going to move
up my trip to Villa Mercedes.
I love you a lot.
Are you going to Lieto's?
Yes.
The best pasta in town.
Are you their son?
One of them.
The sportsman?
No, that's my younger brother.
Ah, you're the oldest?
Mhmm.
Hey, is he still in Europe?
Yes.
He's the man, right?
He must be getting all the ladies.
Yes... you can drop me here.
Left or right?
Right, please.
What do I owe you?
Two hundred.
- Thank you.
You're welcome.
- Have a good day!
- Thanks.
What happened?
What are you doing here?
Hi!
You came!
I thought you were coming on the weekend!
No, I'm here.
So do we have an alarm now?
Yes, there has been
a lot of break-ins here lately.
- We forgot to tell you.
- It's okay.
- Are you guys OK?
- Honey, dad could have picked you up...
- How did you get here?
- It's fine, I took a cab from the station.
What's up, dad? Did they break in here?
No, no. Just around the corner,
we are just a bit scared
but nothing happened.
So, you get up and it goes off?
N'), no!
That is only if you open the door
or touch the windows.
Oh, I can't believe you are here!
I just wanted it to be a surprise!
I'm sorry about this ruckus.
It's a beautiful surprise!
- Manu is here!
- Shh, mom!
- How's school?
- Good.
Good, I had some days off so...
- Also, I passed my exam.
- Yes, your mother told me!
Manu, what are you doing here?
Hi!
- How are you?
- Did you have to be so loud?
I'm sorry, okay?
That's some foul-smelling breath, huh?
Yummy!
Oh, I brought the thing for you.
- Did you bring me something?
- Nothing.
Wake Facu up!
I can't believe he didn't wake up
with all this ruckus.
Can I skip school today?
- Can she?
- No.
- C'mon, please.
- C'mon.
So we can catch up, mom.
- No.
- C'mon.
No, she missed a lot.
She is on the verge already...
Fine. Wait for me.
We'll have breakfast.
Yes, sure.
This is so nice!
It's so nice to have you home.
I could tell something was up, you know?
- As if I had delivered you myself.
- Oh yes, sure.
Just yesterday
I told Dora to fix your room.
- It's clean and ready.
- Really?
- Yes.
- Well, thank you.
- OK, I will settle in then.
- Okay, honey.
I left a bag there
with some stuff that's mine...
It's old.
Don't touch it.
C'mon, guys.
I'm running late to the factory,
I have to go to the municipality...
- Let's go!
- Hold on!
- I'm having breakfast.
- Will you pick me up from school?
- Okay.
Yeah, sure. What time?
1PM, but be there earlier!
- I will walk there.
- No, c'mon!
Facundo!
Coming! He doesn't even
let me have breakfast.
Kiss mommy.
Oh!
- Bye, fag.
- Hey... what?
Hey, watch your mouth!
Every morning is the same thing.
I'm so tired, I swear.
- Do you want more?
- Yes, I'll grab one.
It's so great to have you here, son.
I'm so hBPPY-
I'm also happy, teacher.
25 years now...
The house is celebrating.
Although I have to tell you...
It's a mess.
I don't know why I got into this!
But it's fun!
I mean, it's the perfect excuse.
Are you nervous?
A little.
You are right. We have to celebrate.
I don't know...
Hey, mom...
What's up with dad?
Why does he have to go
to the municipality?
Oh yes, it's because
some people over there might be...
...well, they will sponsor
Luisito's match.
Is Luis coming?
If everything works out...
Manu, baby!
Hi, Dora!
- How are you?
- It's good to see you!
Likewise! You look so pretty.
I have some old lady issues but I'm okay.
No! You look beautiful.
Your mom told me you were here
but I couldn't find you.
- I was getting settled...
- You look great, kid.
Well, thank you.
I bought all the ingredients
to make the sauce you love.
Oh, yummy!
And maybe for a little dessert.
- You have a sweet tooth, kid.
- Yes, but only for your desserts.
Oh yeah, sure, charlatan.
- Listen, this is laundry.
- Okay, I'll take it.
Okay, thank you.
I'll get it.
Hello.
Yes, who is this?
Laura! It's been a while, how are you?
This is Manuel.
Fine.
My mom is not here.
No, I don't have a clue.
I can tell her you called.
Ok, I'll tell her to call you.
Okay. Bye.
Oh, at last!
- Hi!
- I was so sick of class!
Well, I'm here now.
- Thank you for coming.
- Why wouldn't I come...
when you were the only one
who was happy to see me?
Of course.
- How was it?
- Look at him...
Who is that?
- Martl'n?
- Yes.
Manuel?
- Teach.
- Long time no see!
- How are you?
- I'm good.
- You're good?
- Uh-huh.
- Visiting your sister?
- For a little while, yes.
That's great.
Okay guys, good to see you.
Oh, he is so hot...
- God, Clara!
- He is just so hot...
I mean it, look at him!
He only gets hotter by the day.
I don't have a chance though...
Why? Did he finally come out?
Not here, obviously.
But you can kind of tell and...
I think he used to date a former student
who apparently moved to Mendoza.
Maybe if I finish school
he will notice me.
- Yeah, right. You think?
- Yes!
What? Is he your teacher now?
Yeah, he is my literature teacher.
I don't understand anything
but when he turns around
and writes on the blackboard...
- That pant fits him in all the right...
- Okay, enough!
- I guess you're all grown up, huh?
- Shut up, you used to do the same!
No way. Wait... Facu?
He has PE.
Oh, bummer.
The teacher was so cool,
he even remembered you!
Yes, well, your brother is unforgettable.
As if! What did you do?
I wrote a great paper
on “Platero and I", that's what.
That's why?
“Platero is smooth, hairy,
so soft you could almost say
he is all cotton, no bones."
- He is talking about a penis...
- God Clara, c'mon!
It's true!
F I have to leave I
I I have to escape from you!
I1 have to forget)'!
fAnd start over."
fBecause your love is the target."
IYour love is the fire that's burning mel'
fBecause your love inadvertently."
fSheds the poison that's killing me."
fAnd now I know what could have been!
II don't want to see it,
I don't want to have it."
IAnd now that I've decided to stop losingl'
fl'm telling you
and you'll have to understand."
JTve had your poison!
f1 've had your love and also your fire!
!I've had your life
and I don't want it anymore.'
II have to choosef
I1 have to feel again!
f1 have to search!
ffor a way to escape.)
fBecause your love is the target."
IYour love is the fire that's burning mel'
fBecause your love inadvertently."
fSheds the poison that's killing me."
fAnd now I know what could have been!
II don't want to see it,
I don't want to have it."
IAnd now that I've decided to stop losingl'
fl'm telling you
and you'll have to understand."
JTve had your poison!
f1 've had your love and also your fire!
!I've had your life
and I don't want it anymore.'
- I've had your poison, poison, poison!
- Mom!
- I've had your poison...!
- Could you knock first?
Oh, you used to say that to me always!
Golden saying:
“Knock before you come in...
- Well, I'm embarrassed.
- How could I miss that show?
Oh, “I've had your poison"!
That song was so cool.
You kept everything for me.
- It's all brand new.
- Listen...
I did all this... okay,
Dora helped me a little,
but I think this is all of it.
Look what I found.
What is that?
- This folder...
- No!
Do you remember?
How could I forget if I saved it for you?
But did we go together
to the Gran Rex theater...?
Exactly, we went to Buenos Aires.
(BOTH) When daddy took Luisito
to the tournament.
I swearl had forgotten...
Oh, I don't know.
- It's true, we went together.
- It was so long ago! We had so much fun.
That was a fun weekend, right?
- Look at this.
- Oh, Nati is so cute...
I can't believe it.
I can't believe
you saved all of this, mom.
How could I not?
- You're in good shape!
- Right?
I loved it.
So, listen up Manu,
I was considering having the grandparents
over for dinner, is that OK?
- Yes, of course.
- Yeah? So you can all meet.
- They really want to see you...
- Yes, that's OK mom.
Of course.
And that way
we can have some time together.
- I wanted to ask you something else...
- What?
- Come with me to the supermarket.
- No, no, no!
- C'mon!
- I don't feel like running into anyone.
I know you don't like it
but I want you to come with me.
C'mon...
I've had your poison, I've had...
Fine, alright, I'll join you.
Fine.
Hold on, let's see.
I don't remember if I saw this.
Oh, can I take one of these?
- So we have something sweet.
- Of course, son!
Take what you want.
Put it in the cart.
So honey, tell me,
how is everything back there?
How is school? Tell me everything.
Fine, everything's fine.
I'm studying so I brought some books
with me so I can read ahead...
Good!
So, actually I want to
talk to you guys about that.
Are you dropping out?
No, not quite but...
Phew!
That's good, because your dad and I think
these days are ideal for you to study.
You don't have to cook,
you have a maid...
Wait, let's get these chickpeas
so I can make some hummus.
Yes please, you make a mean one.
Oh, I've missed this.
Hi Rosa, how are you?
- Good.
- Good!
- Do you know who that is?
- No.
Don't you remember?
She is the mother of Facu's classmate.
Oh, she keeps going on and on
about her kids.
How her kids are the greatest thing ever,
and this, and that...
Do you know who their kids are?
- The oldest one...
- Yes?
- He's a cokehead.
- No way.
- He is a junkie.
- How do you know?
Honey, everybody here knows.
It's an open secret.
- Why do you care?
- Let's get milk.
Facu is always asking me for it
and I don't want to come back here.
OK.
Pick anything you want, seriously.
I already told Dora.
She's so happy you are here.
She wants to cook for you,
you know how she is.
But I had to
write her a list
because she can't remember
anything anymore. It's terrible.
She looked fine to me.
What?
- Are those low-fat?
- Yeah, both of them.
Oh, okay.
She is old, you know?
She is quite old.
Yes, I'm serious.
She can't clean
the ceiling anymore.
What if she falls and breaks a leg?
I mean just imagine.
If she sues we will go broke.
She can't bend down either.
There's a thick layer of dirt
on the kitchen floor.
But what can I do?
Poor woman.
- That's that. I can't kick her out.
- No!
You can't kick her out!
Well, no. I mean, it's a possibility.
Oh, I need this.
I mean it's not a possibility,
but I've been talking with your dad.
I don't think you should do it.
She's been with us for so long.
- Of course, and we all love her...
- Right!
But, you know...
I also don't want to get
into any trouble...
Wait, I didn't bring any deodorant.
Oh, okay. Yes, I use this one...
What else?
Uhm...
Oh, wait!
We are walking around
and I actually have a list...
We need...
- So mom, how is dad?
- We got this...
Uhm...
Your dad?
Fine. He's fine!
I mean, he is working a lot...
He's exhausted.
You know, the pasta shop
takes a lot of work.
But he's fine...
He's nervous.
Because when Luisito comes over
he deals with the club stuff...
Well, actually I was talking about me.
How is he with me, I mean..
Not fine...
He's hurt, Manu.
Why don't you talk to him?
I'm trying. I want to,
but I don't know,
he doesn't seem happy
with me here.
What?
What are you on about, Manuel?
He is your dad.
He adores you. We love you.
It's just that we didn't see you again
after that night.
You dropped the bomb
and left us all in shock...
...and then you disappeared.
What did you expect?
And now suddenly you are here,
three days earlier...
Look, that was the worst
Christmas eve of my life.
- Do you think it was easy for me?
- It was not easy for anyone.
Why did you come earlier?
Your father and I had already
ruled out you coming.
We always have to force you,
we have to call you...
And now here you are.
Is there something going on?
- No...
- Please, son, trust your mom. Tell me...
No, mom!
There's nothing going on.
I do want to talk
about something with you,
but nothing serious.
You are dropping out.
Of course, yes...
I knew it!
Seven years in Buenos Aires and
only three years of college?
- Oh, Facu, it's not right...
- It's Manuel!
Okay, Manuel.
It's not that easy, mom.
I want to tell you about
my plans with Méximo.
- Maximo?
- Yes, my boyfriend is called Méximo.
Okay, shh. Enough.
- Let's talk back in the house.
- No!
- Let's talk at home...
- Mom, I want to talk right now.
Is that so hard?
In the house.
- Here you go, love.
- That's six...
Thanks.
This is nice, right?
- And the aromatic plants over there?
- I love them.
- Stunning.
- Mom, dad.
Hi, son.
Can we talk?
Yes, of course.
- Here, I'll go.
- Okay.
What do you need, son?
- Nothing, I wanted to talk.
- Do you want one?
Yes. Thank you.
What?
Money. You need money.
You are beating around the bush.
You could have just asked for it
and save yourself the ticket here.
- That's it, right?
- No.
Are you dropping out?
No, dad, it's not that. Listen...
...I want us to talk
about what happened on Christmas.
No, son, no.
No, now's not the time.
Your grandparents are coming.
It's OK.
- But it is not OK!
- It's all good, Manu.
- It's all good, Manu!
- But it doesn't feel like it's all good!
- Don't...
- Dad, you don't treat me like you used to.
What? Son, please, c'mon...
Let's change the subject...
Tell me about your career.
Or should I say,
this walk you are doing.
C'mon, son.
- Dad, Luisito is online! Come here!
- Luisito!
- Let's go!
- What? No.
- You're keeping that?
- Yes.
- But... bring it...
- Just go. Go!
Okay, son, be good!
- Yes.
- Behave, okay?
Oh did it...
- Message him! C'mon!
- Wait... What? The sound is off.
No, no. Message him. Tell him:
“We are all here. We love you..."
- God, mom, he already saw you.
- Okay!
A m, A LOT!
- No, no. Don't write that, Facundo!
- God!
Come on, man!
- Manu, come closer so he can see you.
- I'm here!
- Say hi!
- Dora!
- Come here, Dora.
- Come here.
Luisito is going to be so happy.
Say hi!
Hey, let's eat, the grandparents are here.
What were you doing?
Nothing.
I was reading my old journal.
Let's hear something.
Listen:
“Today I watched “Mufieca Brava...
It was a great episode.
Natalia is amazing...
You wrote that?
Isn't there something more interesting?
Well, let's see...
Dear God, you were obsessed with Nati...
So what, I liked her!
Look at this:
“Today I played tennis. I ran a lot.
I am training for
the Rio Cuarto tournament."
That is so lame!
You were probably lying.
Hey, can I show you
my dress for the party later?
- Yes.
- You haven't seen it yet.
- No.
- Yes?
Of course I want to see it.
Wait!
What?
You are not wearing a bra.
- Why are you staring? No!
- You're so cheeky!
Shut up!
Don't make me talk about the Sua'rez,
they are my best customers.
They buy pasta
Monday through Monday.
Poor Sua'rez.
Poor Mari. That woman can't cook,
that's why they eat pasta everyday...
So, what about Luisito?
What do you know about him?
He is the only one missing here.
Luisito is in Europe.
Training hard.
We will have him home
for a couple of days.
- Yes!
- That's great!
He will stay a bit longer
because he will play a game here.
That's fantastic.
I would love to see him play.
Yes, and you will.
Of course, dad.
What is wrong?
Why are you huffing?
I want to go to my room.
C'mon, Facundo.
Honey, your grandparents are here.
Don't be rude.
Fine, go. If you are going
to put that face on...
- Just go.
- Mom!
- No, seriously.
- You didn't let me do that.
Come back for dessert, okay?
Did you hear grandma?
Come back for dessert!
That's not fair.
So, should I get to the gossip or not?
Yes, get to it, grandma.
Do you remember the Manriques,
who lived in front
of your grandmother's house?
How could I forget?
I don't remember.
I don't remember the Manriques.
You only remember
what's convenient for you.
It's the truth, dear!
You don't know what your grandpa is like.
- Okay, spill, mom.
- Gossip.
- Gossip?
- Gossip!
So, they came and went a few times
and now they are going back
because they had a child in Spain.
But with a nasty problem:
Their son turned out to be limp-wristed.
Do you get it...
That's life.
So this boy was in a relationship
with this very wealthy businessman,
a millionaire.
Well, the old man dies.
He was much older than the boy.
So Manrique's boy inherits a fortune.
Manrique is out of a job.
They own nothing.
He asks his son to help them
and he refuses.
But you know...
We all know these people
have a social problem
and most homosexuals
are very resentful and very vindictive.
Just watch TV,
look at their ways, everything.
They are always seeking revenge.
And not helping his parents
is this boy's vendetta.
These are complicated issues...
I don't know, grandma, I don't...
...you shouldn't generalize.
I am not, I'm simply commenting
on what happened to Manrique.
Why comment then?
If they were mean to him,
well, screw them.
What do you expect?
You are not a mother yet.
One day you will understand you would
give your life for your kids.
So they can be mean to you
and you have to be good to them anyway?
No, but he turned out like that.
What do you expect?
- Uhm, Manu--
- He didn't “turn out like that", grandma.
Yes, he did. In time, you
will think it over and say:
“Oh, my grandma was right...
- I hope I die before thinking that.
- No, you won't die.
Hey, Clara...
Manu, I brought tiramisu for you, my love.
You know you are my favorite
and you love my tiramisu.
But this one has...
Hi, baby.
Hi Manu, sorry I was a bit late.
It's okay, don't worry.
I just logged in.
How are you?
I'm doing good.
Where are you?
In the bathroom.
This house is crowded.
Privacy is a little difficult
to get.
I'm not used to being
with so many people anymore.
How are you?
What's going on there?
You didn't respond
to the picture I sent you.
Oh, I was just surprised...
...that you were
already there with your folks.
Yes, I wanted to come a bit earlier
so I could speak with them
about the money.
Oh, right...
What's going on there? It looks cloudy.
Is it...
Is it very cold?
Yes, today is not the nicest day.
Yeah, it's a little cloudy.
Yes...
What is that painting behind you?
Oh! It came with apartment.
You have no idea how badly
I want to be there, baby.
I want to be with you, hold you...
I found a great jacket for the trip!
Since it's cold there, I started looking
and found a great one.
- Let me show it to you.
- Hold on, Manu. Stop...
I wanted to talk to you about that.
Oh listen, according to my calculations
I think I could be there in about a month.
- Actually, that's--
- But wait, because I also thought
that if my parents give me the money
maybe I won't have
to look for a job either.
The thing is, I wanted
to talk to you about the trip.
What?
Well, I'll make this quick and easy
so I don't beat around the bush, okay?
Listen...
You are like...
...my story in Argentina, okay?
And I'm here now, and...
...I'm sort of meeting people,
experiencing new things,
making new friends...
...and if you come here...
...that ends.
I don't want you to come.
Come again?
I don't want you to come here.
Maximo, are you breaking up with me?
Sort of.
What do you mean, “sort of'?
You're either leaving me or not.
Answer my question! Don't act stupid.
Okay. Yes. Yes.
I'm breaking up with you, yes.
Manuel, hurry up, dude!
1 need to go in!
Son!
Do you know how long it's been
since we used that machine?
You are kneading ravioli!
Yes, I felt like it.
Oh, that's so nice!
It's been a long time since I made these,
so I hope they turn out OK.
You have your grandmother's gift.
Luisito arrives tomorrow.
- Really? Already?
- Yes.
How soon.
Well...
Mom, can I leave these to you?
- Yes, of course!
- Can you handle the rest?
Of course!
Thank you for these.
- Okay... they're done.
- Yummy!
I'm going to lay down
for a minute, okay?
- Are you okay?
- Yes.
- Yes. I'm just tired.
- Okay...
Clara, I came here to be heard
and for you to solve this.
- Yes, OK Gladys. What I--
- Mom, calm down.
- Calm down?
- I just need you to calm down.
This is not what we agreed to.
You are not keeping
your end of the bargain...
Clara, I came here to talk,
let me speak...
- Gladys, please--
- You need to understand.
1 do understand you, Gladys!
So how can I calm down when you
are not keeping our agreement?
- Please
- Mom, listen to her...
1 know we have an agreement.
But we have different timings...
Where are you going, fag?
What are you doing?
- You can't go in there.
- Oh no? And why is that?
If I can't go in, you can't go either.
But you are 14 years old, kid.
- Why are they here?
- I don't know.
Who knows.
If you talk to me like that
I will never unblock you
and you will always have
to call me to the landline.
No.
Oh, wait. I think
my brother's listening in on us.
Manuel!
What are you doing
listening in on me?
- I wasn't.
- Yes, you were.
- You can't spy on me!
- Well, what do you want me to do?
- To not spy on me?
- Okay, fine...
- Also, you owe me a conversation.
- What?
Yes.
About what?
- You said we could talk.
- Listen to me for a second.
What? You never tell me anything.
- Would you listen to me?
- What?
- What's going on with Laura and mom?
- I don't know.
You don't you know?
What are they doing here?
Laura's mom comes over sometimes.
Maybe they remained friends.
- Friends? Why is she here?
- I don't know.
- Are we going to talk or not?
- No...yes.
But I'm talking
and you won't answer.
I want to talk about us.
- I want to talk about you.
- What do you want to hear?
- About Buenos Aires...
- No. Tell me about mom and Laura.
- Why is she here?
- I have no clue!
Could you tell me about your boys?
- What do you mean by “my boys”?
- You know.
- What are you going on about?
- Move over.
Actually, your brother is rather picky.
You're picky. Yeah, right.
I'm not some floozy
that hooks up with everyone.
I'm sure you are
C'mon, tell me more!
- I don't know what you want to hear!
- Everything!
About what? I'm your brother,
I don't know what you're going for...
Well...
What?
Sex.
- No, we won't talk about that.
- Yes.
- No, we are not having that conversation.
- Why?
Because I'm your brother
and I have nothing to say...
Oh, don't be like that.
No, well...
You do it and I do it.
We're both adults.
As an older brother, it is
your responsibility to give me tips.
- Is it now?
- Yes.
Who do you want me to talk to?
Mom?
I don't know.
Maybe with your friends?
Of course I talk about it with my friends
but it's not the same.
- How come?
- Your experience is more useful to me.
Are you shitting me? Useful?
My experience is useful?
Obviously!
I mean, you have it and you suck it.
You have the best of both worlds.
- Well, you are right about that.
- See?
- C'mon. Let's share experiences.
- Wait, hold on...
Are you in a relationship?
Sort of.
What do you mean?
Who are you dating?
You don't know him.
Also, why does that matter?
Well, first of all: I should know him.
- Second of all...
- Are you my bodyguard now?
You have to ask me
for permission to date someone.
Excuse me?
Of course, you should
always ask your oldest brother.
- Not anymore.
- Why not?
- Will you give me some tips or not?
- OK...
Teach me...
- Teach me to give great blowjobs.
- No, you are insane!
- Why not?
- Because you are crazy. How could 1...? No!
- Come on!
You are my little sister, I can't!
I'm old and so are you.
- Precisely.
- Oh God...
You should feel proud that
I will know how to do it properly.
Well, let's see...
Have you tried with food?
No...
- How?
- Okay, there is an infallible trick
which works every time: a mint.
- What do you mean a mint?
- A little pill.
Sorry to interrupt the talk
between the fag and the slut
but dinner's ready.
Could you
knock on the door first?
- Shall we?
- Hold that thought, OK?
Seriously, don't forget.
Because you always do this.
Come on, stop it.
So how does the mint work?
Like so.
- Pass the cheese.
- Shall we start?
This looks amazing!
Did you knead these, Clara?
Me?
- Yeah.
- No! Manuel did.
Really, Manu?!
These are amazing.
You have to go train
the cooks at the factory.
It's not a big deal...
- They are not so great.
- Yes, they are!
You were always a very good cook, son.
You need to own it.
Oh wow! Let's hear it
for the ravioli maker!
Of course! Of course.
- The master of ravioli.
- They are amazing!
- Amazing.
- I'm sure you bought them.
Yeah, right.
You are going
to make these again, right?
Luis will be very upset he missed this.
Right!
- Luisito likes the ones with ham...
- Yes, he will go nuts over these!
Mom, did you know
the best ham is from Spain?
Well, whatever!
He won't care about the ravioli.
Nevermind the ham. The important thing
is that your brother made these.
Also he is used to his brother's cooking.
Then I also want
a special dish just for me.
- Okay, I will cook for you too!
- Squash ravioli!
- Okay, done.
- Customer's choice.
What's wrong?
Facu?
- What do you care?
- Hey, wow!
Don't be rude.
- So I am rude?
- Yes, don't talk to your mother that way.
You are going to teach me manners?
What's going on, son?
- Okay, enough...
- Stop it. Don't disrespect me.
- Stop it.
- I am OK, not that anybody cares.
- Honey, I asked both of you.
- No, you asked him.
Okay, okay!
So how are you? Tell us.
Yeah, how's school?
How's school?I got a D.
Let's talk about something else.
You got a D?
Are you okay?
Way to change the conversation, huh?
- I'm okay.
- What did you do today?
Not much. I did a couple of laps.
Like around town with the dog.
Next week you
are going back to college, right?
In theory, yes.
You have to hurry up with that, son.
I want you to give me
some tips for the factory.
I want to make some renovations.
- Should we head there one of these days?
- OK.
- Fine. We'll see.
- That's great. I'd love that!
We can offer your services.
- Should we hang up a sign?
- No.
Manuel Lieto. Architect.
- What? No!
- Why not?
Because he is the ravioli maker.
Oh, funny! Mom, first of all,
I haven't graduated yet.
- Exactly.
- Second of all, why all this circus?
- Then hurry up.
- Could you renovate my room?
Yes, and once you start practicing,
you will need those clients.
So that promotion will come in handy.
- Meanwhile, practice with your sister.
- Do the bathroom!
- Yes, the bathroom!
- And a closet!
Are you insane?
What? You moved out.
I get your room.
What are you doing here, fag?
What are you doing,
coming in like that? Ask first.
- This is my storeroom.
- Hey!
-“Your"storeroom?
- Yes.
Isn't that funny.
Hey.
- What do you want?
- Listen...
What's going on with Luisito?
Is everything okay?
- With Luisito?
- Yeah.
Yes, fine.
What could be wrong?
I don't know, something's off.
Do you know something?
No, dude.
What is wrong with you?
Hello?
Hi, is Laura home?
Who E looking for her?
A friend.
No, Laurita is not here.
I'm a former schoolmate.
Nevermind. Bye.
Laura.
Hey, Manuel, how are you?
- I'm good.
- Well, this is a surprise!
How long have you been in town?
I got here a few days ago.
Do you need anything?
Yes. I want to talk to you.
What's up?
Could you tell me what's going on
between you, your mom and my parents?
Nothing, why?
I don't understand your question.
The other day I heard you all
talking in my house,
and now I found out
we are paying for your healthcare?
Nothing's wrong.
They are helping us out.
Really? My parents
don't just help out people.
Manuel, I have to go.
No! Laura, please.
Tell me.
I can help you.
Manuel, don't you realize
what's going on?
Healthcare. My mom.
Your parents.
Me. Your brother.
Don't you get it?
Are you pregnant?
Wait. Laura!
You're a little out of shape.
What's up?
No, I'm not.
I run everyday.
I'm not used to
playing tennis anymore.
Even better.
I'll be gentle.
I want to beat you.
Yeah?
You are on top.
Well, there's no match for me here.
Everyone in this club is a wimp.
Do you know who is very good
but ignores me?
- Your brother.
- Facu?
He's a genius.
Have you seen him play?
He's got a gift.
He's got Federer's handback.
It's amazing.
The thing is he is
slacking off all day.
He doesn't want
to practice with me.
He's young-
Besides, isn't one tennis player
in the familiy enough?
Your sister could also
have a good career.
There are almost no
female tennis players in this town.
- Shall we?
- No. Wait.
Could we go to the bar
and talk a little?
Talk? Yes.
Can we talk in the car?
I have to be at work by six.
- Come on, let's go.
- OK.
Dad...
I would like to have
a good relationship with you.
I feel like ever since Christmas,
something broke between us and...
...I don't know.
Just now, while we were playing,
we seemed disconnected,
and it didn't use to be like that.
Hold on.
- Honey!
- Yes, what's up, Clara?
Luisito is here.
Oh!
Oh, that's wonderful news, honey!
Thank you!
TH see you later!
OK. Change of plans, Manu.
I'm heading back to the club.
I want to finish
coordinating the match.
What match?
I'm organizing a match
so the Secretary of Sports
can watch Luisito and maybe help us
sponsor him in Europe.
And while we're at it,
we throw a match for the kids around town
who are stuck, to encourage them.
It's a nice idea, right?
So they know if they want
to be an athlete, they can.
There's a lot of drugs here.
So Luisito will inspire them?
Right, yes. Who better than Luisito
to inspire them?
Drop me off here.
- What?
- I want to get off.
- Wait, why?
- Because I want to get off here.
- I'll take you home.
- No need. I'll get off here.
But... Fine, I'll drop you off
but what's wrong?
- Nothing. We'll talk later.
- Just tell me--
Nothing.
Please, tell me you became a reader
thanks to my lessons.
Teach.
"Teach"? You graduated
a long time ago, am I right?
About seven years ago.
That's a lot.
How are you?
I'm good.
Taking a walk around town.
I noticed the bookshop
and I wanted to get a book.
And you, sir?
You are killing me.
First "Teach" and now sir?
Could you address me as you?
Look, you make me nervous.
Sure, okay.
So...
- You are walking around?
- Yes.
Yes, I'm visiting my family.
There are family events.
That's great.
Did you read that one?
No, but it looks interesting.
It's good. It's about
an Italian restaurant in Mar del Plata.
OK, if you recommend it
then maybe I'll take it.
Do you like cooking?
Let's say...
I have my ways.
Take it.
- No, but...
- Take it, really.
I can pay for it.
You can thank me with something tasty.
Homemade, of course.
OK, but I can pay for it,
it's no big deal.
I am the owner.
That's nice.
Loaf cake?
Perfect.
Leave it, miss.
I'll do it. You don't put salt or oil
in it and the kids hate that.
Oh, Dorita is schooling you!
Your brother is here.
- Yes?
- Yes. Go say hi.
- He is settling into his room.
- Already?
Yes, he just got here from San Luis.
Good thing the flight was on schedule.
Aka'!-
That's it.
Manu! Bro!
How are you?
- I'm good.
- Long time, no see.
Mom told me you were in town.
- Are you OK?
- Yes, I came here for a couple of days.
- Great.
- How are you?
Good.
We are all here.
Great!
So it would seem.
Like the good old days.
So you are on a diet?
You mean this?
- Eating healthy?
- Shut up.
My big brother.
This is nice.
Are you coming to the match?
Oh, I don't know.
I don't think so.
Maybe I'll stop by.
I only came here for mom and dad's thing.
I didn't want to
do a lot of things.
Well, but it's just a match.
If you get bored you can leave.
Fine.
Maybe I'll go.
What's up, kids?
- Hi, dad.
- Hello.
Two things:
First. We decided since Luisito is here,
we're going to do a new family photo.
- Okay.
- Second thing.
Tonight. Party in the club.
For you, Luisito.
- For me?
- Yes, of course it's for you, dear.
- But why?
- Why? Because you are here.
I got some big names.
The head of the Municipality,
the Secretary of Sports...
Hey! The Secretary is coming to see you.
But I came home to relax,
not to do a parade.
I want to spend time with you.
Rest up. Take a walk.
Go to your party.
Eat like a pig.
Son, one thing
doesn't cancel out the other.
You can do all that and still
attend tonight's party in your honor.
And the picture will take one second.
Don't make this hard.
It's your mother's wish.
You too Manuel, please don't start.
I didn't say anything!
And that's dad.
Welcome home.
Manu!
What are you doing here?
This circus is for you.
I don't want to be there.
They talk to me like I'm Nadal.
They touch me...
It's all very fake.
Do you want?
Why are you smoking that?
It's okay. It's just grass.
You have a match
to play tomorrow.
That match is some crap
dad put together.
You know him.
He put this together
so the Municipality will sponsor me.
So they pay the hotels,
the training sessions.
Bullshit.
Exactly.
If dad finds out
you are smoking this he will kill you.
How are you doing?
How is Europe?
I'm great.
Barcelona is amazing.
The buildings, the architecture...
...the streets.
And the sea is so beautiful.
You should come with me!
You would love it there.
Sometimes I think
I'd like to stay for good.
Don't say that out loud.
Mom might die if she hears
her baby will move
to Barcelona forever.
That's true.
And how are you doing?
Not great.
I broke up with my...
With your boyfriend?
How did you know?
I never told you.
We all know.
I have known for a while now.
It's okay by me.
You are my brother
and I love you.
And about the breakup:
You are handsome guy,
you will find another guy.
Especially living in Buenos Aires.
There's a million people.
Yeah, I don't know...
Who knows.
I hope so.
What about Laura and you?
That's over.
But, I mean...
Did something happen
the last time you saw each other?
No, nothing happened.
We just decided to take different roads.
We thought it was for the best
if we both did our own thing.
I don't know. If you are here,
why don't you talk to her?
Isn't she coming tonight?
I didn't tell her.
Also, she knows I'm in town.
She must have heard
and still she didn't text me.
If I were you, I would talk to her.
At least to ask her how she's doing.
What for?
I'm not sure.
- Did you hear that scream?
- I did.
I think it was Flavia.
Nothing happened.
Something happened.
It did because she saw you.
- What happened?
- Nothing!
- I'm telling you what I saw, sin
- She's exaggerating.
Get in the car now, Clara!
Get in the car!
And you, punk,
get the hell out of here!
- Get in the car!
- Honey, go.
Get in the car!
You ruined your brother's party.
Do you get it?
No more scandals.
All of you, get out. Go home!
You too. Get out.
Please.
I am going to ask you for a favor.
I need what happened
to remain between me and you.
- It's very important to me.
- No problem, sir.
I appreciate it.
We want to award this trophy to Luis.
Or Luisito,
as we all call him,
for gracing this place
with his presence this afternoon.
Thank you.
Thank you so much.
A little longer.
Share some words.
I want to thank you
for sharing this afternoon with me.
I'm happy to be back in the club
that saw me take my first steps.
I lived a lot here
and made a lot of friends.
I would love it if someday
we could do an international tournament,
under this administration.
So thank you.
Who is it?
Manuel.
Manuel Lieto.
Oh! I'm coming!
- Hello.
- Hi.
- How are you?
- I'm good!
You're good?
Come on in.
- Excuse me.
- Yes, please, come in.
Aka'!-
Here we are.
It's bitter.
- Perfect.
- Great.
- Will you do the honors?
- Sure, thanks.
- It's orange and cinnamon.
- It looks amazing, I love it already.
- Do you like those?
- Yes, I love it.
- And nuts.
- There's some nuts as garnish.
- Nice detail.
- It's a family recipe.
Are you sure you didn't
buy that at a bakery?
You think so?
Of course not.
You'll see.
Hold on.
- Let's switch.
- There we go.
This is nice.
I'm happy to see you again.
Tell me more about you,
your life in Buenos Aires, I don't know...
Are you in college?
Yes. Architecture.
- Awesome!
- Yes...
I think it served more as a way to escape
than anything else.
I was tired of Mercedes
and I needed to leave.
That's OK, I get it.
I'm glad you got out.
For me...
I think a lot about leaving.
But I also feel like
I have a job here and...
...once you get old,
you have other concerns.
- Well, you're not that old.
- Oh, but I am.
But you seem
to be doing good here.
I'm doing fine.
But it's just... fine.
Because here, I mean...
...I would like to live in a bigger city,
where nobody stares at you
where they don't gossip so much.
Well, that's exactly why
I grew tired of Mercedes.
Everyone has an opinion or a comment
and you're always running into someone.
And the truth is...
I don't like that.
I... don't like that
I can't be myself.
- And did you find yourself?
- I think so.
At least you searched for yourself.
That's the important thing.
I'm glad I ran into you.
It's been so long, right?
I see you...
...older. Well, you were a kid.
Well, I graduated seven years ago.
Right.
YOU 3Y6 more mature.
You are handsome.
- Very.
- You are very handsome too.
Just gray-haired.
It looks good on you.
- I like them.
- I shouldn't dye them?
- No! They will gossip if you do.
- Yes!
Is this okay?
- Yeah.
- Okay.
- Oh, that's the doorbell.
- Oh, no!
Do I have to go?
Unless you want to stay for
a private lesson in syntactic analysis.
No, I'm good.
Coming!
Can we talk?
Sure.
What's up? Do you have
more pointers for me?
Did you know Laura is pregnant?
- Do you want to see my dress--
- Hey!
So you know she is pregnant.
Yes, of course I do.
Does Luis know?
No Manu, how would he know?
They can't keep this from him.
It's his son!
I don't know. Mom told me
if we tell him now...
...he won't want
to go back to Europe.
And that this is his breakout year.
And she is a little bit right.
No, she is not!
Are you both insane?
- What's wrong with you?
- Well, I don't know!
I don't know what
to make of this.
But if you don't want
any more drama, shut up.
My thing last night
was enough drama for now.
So, how are you?
To be honest, I guess
I'm a little pissed.
Why?
Because.
Also he won't text me back.
He will write back.
He must be shit-scared
with all that yelling.
Yeah... was that necessary?
I mean, you know dad.
Mann.
Hey.
What are you reading?
This new book about a restaurant.
You are really into cooking.
And you?
- Are you OK?
- Yes. I was walking around town.
- Do you know who I ran into?
- Who?
Remember my friend "Butter" from school?
- The short brunette one.
- Oh, yeah.
We were talking and he told me
he is going to be a dad.
No way!
Really?
Well, that's good news, right?
Not really.
I was shocked.
If they told me I was going
to be a father at twenty three
I don't know
what I'd do.
Well, I don't think
it would be such a big deal.
I mean, wow!
What about Laura?
You didn't run into her?
You are all about Laura lately.
Is she your favorite in-law?
I'm sorry, but we broke up.
No, I mean...
...I liked her, I always thought
she was cool. That's all.
Her mother is crazy.
Well, all parents are crazy.
Just imagine
what she must think of ours.
No, you don't get it. Her mom
is on another level of crazy.
She is deranged.
So, do you
want to go back already?
Is it obvious?
No...
...but I mean,
you do live there now.
- Yeah--
- I, for one, miss my apartment.
Maybe.
And you?
Are you going back?
Will you stay there?
I'm not sure.
Sometimes I think about
moving back here.
But, you know, things can be
pretty boring here.
It all depends. Maybe if I would meet
someone here I would stay.
Right.
Hi, Manuel!
How are you, Juancito?
- I'm good!
- I'm here to pick up something for my mom.
- Yes, that would be your lunch.
- Yeah.
Hey, your dad is in the back.
Do you want to come in?
No... No, I'm good.
I'm in a hurry, it's okay.
Oh, yum.
Hey, you know what?
We need a picture
of the six of you there.
- Yes.
- Don't you agree?
You might be right.
That's a good idea!
A good idea indeed.
How are you, son?
- Hi.
- We could take the photo at the party.
- Sure.
- That would be nice.
I'm glad you came.
I want to show you something.
Okay.
I'll leave this here for a second.
This is what I was
telling you about:
Humidity. Humidity. Humidity.
That spot is new
and I think it is getting bigger.
Also, everything looks very deteriorated.
I think we could
use this as an opportunity...
...to renovate the entire shop.
We make it better, more modern.
- Yeah...
- Are you up for it?
Up for what?
What do you mean?
For you to do it, son!
You mean
I would do the renovation?
But of course! Who else?
No, dad, no...
...I don't do renovations.
I prefer to do things from the ground up.
To start from zero.
Oh, you only take ground-up projects?
But renovations are
an important part of your career, son.
Yes, but...
...to be honest, what you call “modern"
to me is outdated.
This placed should be demolished
so we could start over.
I would go for something
more contemporary, you know?
A cool, New York vibe.
Very Italian, but cool.
Oh, okay.
Fine, whatever you say.
If a client comes in
and offers you a job like this,
you should take it, son.
Because you will have to
earn a living somehow.
You will have to earn
your daily bread somehow.
Why don't we have a talk now?
Didn't you want to talk to me?
About how I don't love you,
was that it? Let's talk.
- Now you want to talk?
- Yes.
- Should we do this or not?
- OK.
I'm tired, dad.
I'm tired of being
the black sheep of the family.
You are always pointing out my mistakes.
All the time...
I mean, I think you do that
because I am gay.
Because I like men.
That's not true, son.
- Oh, no?
- No, it's not true.
I don't care what you choose
or what you want--
But it's not a matter of choice.
It's what I feel.
That's fine.
I'm not worried about that.
I just want you to be happy, son.
And you don't look happy.
That worries me.
I want you to be happy.
I just offered you the chance
of doing a renovation,
something related to your career.
And you turn it down?
You look down on it?
I don't kid, I'm worried
life will pass you by...
...while you try to become someone.
I want you to do something that
makes you happy and earns you a living.
But something you enjoy doing, kid.
Something that makes you happy.
And you? Are you happy?
Is this your passion?
Look, I put a lot of effort
into everything I did.
I put my heart and soul into his, okay?
And no one ever offered me
a renovation.
That's not true. You are wrong.
What you're saying is not true.
Hi! What are you up to?
How are you, Luisito?
How's it going?
- I'm good, you?
- Fine.
Listen, why don't you go to...
...just grab the car and...
-...and pick up the kids from school, OK?
- Sure.
Thanks.
Do you want to come with me?
Yes, I have to do
a couple of things... but OK.
Mom.
Manu!
Did you go see your dad?
- Yes.
- And?
And I talked to him.
And how did it go?
Did he tell you about the renovation?
Oh, I would love you to do it, honey.
It would be great.
Oh, honey, I'm so happy
the six of us are all together!
Having my four puppies home.
I'm very happy-
- Mom--
- I'm so into this!
I really got into gardening.
It is a new thing.
I don't know if I told you already,
I can't remember.
I can't remember what I tell you and
what I don't anymore, but I'm so excited.
It's very soothing, you know?
I met a woman who does
the most amazing things.
You would die if you saw them! Really!
It's funny because her name is Rose,
-and she teaches a group of women that--
- Mom, listen to me.
Yes, son, I'm listening.
You're acting weird.
What's up?
I'm not acting weird!
I'm not okay.
I'm not okay because I'm not okay
with you guys, alright? I need you.
My boyfriend dumped me and
I haven't talked to you since Christmas!
Well, we are not okay either.
I already told you, Manuel.
Stop bringing that up!
Enough, goddammit!
But dad told me
he has no issue with “that”.
He told me he only cares about my future,
my happiness, my career.
My asshole boyfriend dumps me
the minute I get to Mercedes--
I care about your future too!
I care a lot!
I do, a lot.
But let me tell you about Maximo.
That's what I need to talk about!
I have already accepted you, son...
I already told you. I do.
But I can't handle it.
I can't handle you telling me
what you do in bed. Please don't tell me!
Mom, I don't want to talk about sex.
I want to talk about love.
Love? Did you say love?
Love is what I feel for your dad.
What he feels for me.
Love is a family project.
That is love!
You are insane.
Are you hearing yourself right now?
What about
what you are doing to Luis?
Not telling him he's going
to be a father? Is that love?
I beg of you... Shut up, Manuel.
Please, son, don't say a word
of this to anyone.
Son!
- Martin.
- Manuel, how are you?
I'm good, and you?
Were you waiting for me?
Uhm, yes... I felt like seeing you
so I decided to wait for you.
Alright then.
Are you OK?
Not really.
- Do you want to come in?
- Yes.
- I'd like that.
- Come on.
- After you.
- Thanks.
I'm so sick. Everything's a mess.
Really? It's that bad?
Well, don't worry.
You are here now.
It's over, OK?
- Yes, but you know what? I feel--
- What?
- I feel my parents are never gonna change.
- Uh-huh?
Yes. They don't even try to accept me.
- But my brother can do no wrong...
- Yeah?
I mean, he knocks up his girlfriend
and it's no big deal: they pay for her
medical insurance and that's it.
My dad is suddenly
worried about my future.
What is up with them?
Well, who knows.
Look, do you know
what the important thing is?
That you make yourself clear.
If you are uncomfortable here you have to
go to the city where you are okay
and they will come to you
and you will mend your relationship.
- OK?
- Oh, that's easy to say.
- What if they don't come?
- Then they are not worth it.
Here's the deal:
There's a three-year period, okay?
That's what they say.
Three years.
If in three years they don't accept you
then they never will.
So? What do I do?
What do you mean?
I have a lot of time left
before that but...
...if I leave I won't see anymore.
No way, you will see me...
...we can still see each other.
The important thing here
is that you are well, okay?
That you are well.
But that's enough
about parents for now, okay?
Can you think of something else?
Or better yet, don't think.
Had to leave. Had a great time.
Thanks!
Yes, who is it?
Is Laura home?
It's me. Who is it?
It's Manuel.
Manuel... I can't talk to you.
My brother is in town.
We need to tell him.
I know he is here.
I'm not telling him.
Laura, please.
He is a good person, he will take care
of his child and it will be for the best.
My parents don't realize that.
Goodbye, Manuel.
Manuel, have!
Laura, I beg of you!
Don't be a bad mother!
Leave or I will call the police.
Laura!
Manuel, is that you?
Son, where were you?
I didn't sleep here.
I won't explain myself.
I don't live here.
Okay, okay...
I don't want to fight.
I'm your mother. You are home.
You didn't come home.
I was worried, that's all.
Next time just give me heads-up.
- Okay, fine.
- Alright.
Look, I was just trying out
the dress for the party.
What do you think?
- Is it too much black with the shoes?
- No, you look nice mom, I like it.
- You do?
- Yes, it's nice.
I have to go to the salon
and do so many things.
- I don't know why I'm doing this...
- No.
I can't seem to enjoy this, I swear.
I can't enjoy you, or Luisito.
- I can't...
- Hey, calm down.
You are celebrating 25 years of marriage.
OK, that's not common.
So enjoy it.
Take this chance to treat yourself.
Just think if it weren't for this,
Luisito and I wouldn't be here.
Yes... that's true.
I'm sorry.
Forgive me, son.
I'm sorry if I said something
that upset you.
It's a sensitive subject.
And you know me...
I get very...
I say things without thinking.
Mom...
Relax, OK?
I know this is very hard for you.
I get it, really, but
I also need you to understand me.
It's a process,
but I want us to go through it together.
Hey, it will be OK.
OK?
But I want you
to promise me something.
What?
That you will solve
this issue with Luisito.
Mom, what you are doing is not normal.
Okay, I promise.
It got out of our hands!
I can't imagine what will happen
if your brother finds out.
Relax.
- Did you see my parents?
- No.
Thank you.
No! Mine has alcohol in it.
Fine...
This sucks.
"This sucks?" How old are you?
We have to celebrate.
Celebrating is good.
What do you want me to celebrate?
This is so boring.
- Hey punk, what's new with you?
- What do you mean?
- What are you going to study?
- Oh... It's always the same with you all.
Turns out you are just
like mom and dad.
- No, well...
- You can't talk about anything else.
What do you want me to ask?
You never talk to me.
You laze around all day...
- Fag.
- Asshole.
- Hey, have you seen mom and dad?
- No, why?
Don't tell me they are
going to make an entrance, please.
No, why would they make an entrance?
They are arriving late
to their own party.
Whatever...
Why are you drinking?
- You are going to get smashed.
- It's just that I'm hungry!
Okay, I will go into the kitchen
to see what's going on.
Can you get me something?
Some cheese and bread?
I will see what they got.
Dora!
How's it going?
Bad.
We are missing
half of the ingredients,
the food is not here
and they are just told me...
Please, we need to do something Dora.
This is a mess.
We run out of food,
I can't believe it.
Did you just figure it out?
We need to solve this, Dora.
Should I send for some of our pasta
so we can serve some pots?
Goddammit! I hired a catering service
especially to avoid sewing pasta.
- Can you believe this?
- Relax, dad. I got this.
Dora, what ingredients do we have?
- We will figure it out.
- We got this...
I love this!
It's delicious.
You have a talent for this, kid.
You should do this for a living.
- You think?
- Absolutely.
It was a pretty basic thing, though.
We had tomato, bread and arugula,
so I made some bruschettas.
Well, I wouldn't have thought of it.
I mean it, son.
You saved us.
Tonight, you saved us.
- I'm going to say hi to Lore.
- Sure.
Lore!
Hi Martin, this is Manu.
I'm fine, I'm at the party.
It's a big boring but it's okay.
Do you want to meet up later?
Oh... OK.
Don't worry, it's okay, really.
See you later. Bye.
Well, let's toast to my daughter,
Clara and her husband, Luis.
It's wonderful to celebrate as a family.
Thank you, mom.
Thank you, Mom.
I want to extend our toast to my kids,
especially my son Luisito,
who came back especially
to share this night
which is so important to us.
I'm delighted you are here.
Thank you, dad.
Your father is right.
It must be hard being away from us all.
I also want to make a toast.
Here's to Facu, Clari and me.
At the end of the day,
we're also your kids.
Excuse me everyone,
I forgot about our star.
He can't help himself.
He just has to be the star of the night.
My son, Manuel, prepared
those delicious things you are eating.
He might never build skyscrapers,
but he sure can make appetizers.
Ok honey, this is not the place
or time for that joke, okay?
- Here's to...
- I'm not joking.
Here's to Luisito.
I toast you.
I toast my kids.
I'm also your son, dad!
'QM...
"Skim!
I'm you son,
whether you like it or not.
And I think we should also toast
the achievements of my brothers and me.
Did you say achievements?
Here's to our kids.
No.
No, I'm sorry
but he has no right to do this to us.
Luis, here's to my kids.
Because they are our family.
Mom is right.
Let's toast the family.
Why don't we also toast
the new member of our family?
Shut up, Manuel.
- Here's...
- Shut it, Manuel.
...to Luisito and Laura's baby.
Who will be born soon.
He is making us all...
...aunts, uncles
and grandparents!
What?
Shut up, dude!
Dad?
- What was that?
- I just blurted it out.
You can't just blurt that out!
I know but, did you see
how dad was bullying me?
So that's your excuse?
I'm sorry! It was the first thing
that came to mind!
He is going to kill me.
He will kill me...
- You hate me, right?
- No, why would I hate you?
No, this is not about you!
This is about them.
I'm sorry...
Did you know about this?
I'm sorry.
- He is going to hate us.
- Come on, hurry up.
Hey, brother.
We wanted to know
how you were doing.
How do you think I am?
I don't get you!
I don't get any of you.
Least of all mom and dad.
- You seem to be all against me!
- No, we are not against you!
I mean...
...I did what I had to do.
You needed to know what was going on.
Yes, don't be mad at Manu.
You need to understand us too.
You come here and suddenly
you are the perfect son.
You needed to know.
It wasn't the time or the place, but...
-...would you rather not know?
- You guys hate me.
- No
- No!
I hate what mom and dad do to you.
They point out my every mistake
but you are the perfect son.
But...
...that's not my fault anymore, Manu.
That's on them.
Yes, you are right but...
...by making those differences
they pit us against each other.
And personally,
I don't like feeling that way.
Okay. Thanks.
So, what are you going to do?
Right now I don't know.
I want to see Laura.
- I think that would be good.
- Yes.
I also want to go back to Spain
and see what happens there.
You still have time
to make up your mind, relax.
Oh baby brother, relax.
I'm sorry.
I was wrong,
I shouldn't have spoken back there.
I'm truly sorry.
I'm not OK.
I'm going through a rough time...
...and I ended up hurting you all.
I apologize to the both of you.
I'm sorry too.
I needed to know this somehow.
And it's good to know
you don't hate me.
How could we ever hate you?
You could come home
more often, that's all.
- And bring chocolates as a present.
- Oh, you are so right!
What are you doing up there?
Please, get down.
No! I'm sick of you two, dad!
Oh guys, please come down!
So you can keep on shouting at us?
Wait a minute. We're coming.
Guys...
- What?
- It's over. Let's go down.
It's over.
Let's not make more of a spectacle
of ourselves.
Yes, who is this?
It's Manu.
What's up?
Are you busy?
Yes...
Yes... a little.
Can I come in?
I'm busy.
OK. It's fine, I get it.
I wanted to tell you
I'm leaving first thing tomorrow.
- Oh!
- So, I wanted...
...I wanted to see you
and spend the night together.
Oh...
Uhm, I...
I can't right now.
It's impossible, no.
- Oh. ..
- I can't.
I really can't...
But hey! Well...
-...I'm sure we'll meet again.
- OK.
- I hope you have a safe trip back.
- Okay.
Hey, wait up!
- What?
- What is wrong with you?
Come again?
I told you I'm leaving tomorrow
and you are just going to let me go?
I mean... don't you care about me?
Excuse me?
Dude, I'm telling you
I'm leaving tomorrow,
that we might not see each other
for who knows how long
and you don't care.
You just let me go.
You won't ask me what happened,
if something happened
to me or my family...
I mean, what is wrong with you?
Lower your voice.
Uhm...
There's nothing is wrong with me...
I think you are very confused, Manu.
Everything's fine.
More than okay.
We had a great time...
...but that's all.
Nothing more.
So that's it?
Yes, that's it.
Have a safe trip.
Manuel!
That damn alarm!
What happened?
We set it because we thought
you were inside the house.
- I want to get out of here!
- No!
I'm sorry, dad.
I'm sorry about today, really...
No, kid, why are you apologizing?
I'm sorry I'm a fag.
I'm sorry.
No, son!
I have fought against it all my life.
I needed...
...I needed to accept myself but...
...all I really cared about
was that you hear it from me.
So it would be okay.
So you wouldn't suffer.
We... we love you, son.
Me and your mom, we screwed up
a lot of things, didn't we?
I'm sorry.
The thing that upsets me
is that sometimes you're not happy.
You don't seem to be happy.
I want you to be happy.
I feel like I'm running away
all the time and I'm tired.
I'm exhausted.
You are very brave, honey.
You are so brave.
I can't do this anymore, mom.
Remember when you were a kid
and you came to the factory?
You used to love it!
Then you decided to be an architect.
What happened, huh?
I always wanted to be like you, dad.
Always.
Choosing Architecture was an excuse.
To get away, to run away.
I don't know, but I'm tired.
I'm tired of running away.
I want to be happy here,
with both of you.
- Yes, honey. Yes.
- I want to be near you.
Yes, of course, my dear son.
And...
...and so it will be.
And so it will be.
I love you both.
We love you too.
We love you.