Shave him bald.
You're lucky to get a free haircut.
Whose are you, little one? Eh?
A Strip of Uncut Wild Flowers
Who is your father?
Nobody. I was brought
by the wind, ownerless.
Written by Oles Gonchar & Yuri Ilyenko
from novel "Brigantina" by O. Gonchar
DP
Andrey Vladimirov
Art Director
Sergey Brzhestovski
Original Score by  Eduard Artemeev
Sound Design by R. Bisnovata
Produced by
Mikola Vesna
Cast:
Yurko Madzhula as Porfiry Kulbaka
Olekseiko Cherstvov as Gena Butkevich
Head of the Special School:
Regimantas Adomaitis
Ludmila Efimenko as Marisa Pavlovna
Zinaida Slavina as Oksna Kulbaka
Yuri Mazhuga as Trituzny
Directed by
Yuri Ilyenko
- Good afternoon.  - Good afternoon.
- Well, I brought him.
Stop it!
Hello, sir.
Here is your linen. Wash up,
disinfect yourself.
And for what do you
need the body scrub?
I'm looking for someone
to rub my back.
Well, I can do it.
I'll run from you too.
We'll catch you.
I'll run anyhow.
Even if you chain me.
Take your hands out of your pockets
or we'll sew them up. Stand straight.
Look me in the eyes
when I speak to you.
You've shaved me, but who cares?
You're forbidden to hit me.
Look, how much things you got,
And you're surprised you were
sent here from the special school.
Probably you got on
everyone's nerves.
You're a bad element, young man.
Do you love your Mum?
Don't know. Probably not?
I'm aiming straight for your eyes.
What is that? Take it out.
Which eye: the left one
or the right one?
Will it make you feel better?
Will you be happy?
Just because I'm here,
I can't play jokes?
You should stand up
if an elder comes in.
I'm the head of the reformatory.
Trituzny Anton Gerasimovich.
Yeah, I know,
run there, run here.
It's good that you
believe in immortality.
Take a brush, some paint.
Paint over it, for
you and for others.
We're into do-it-yourself.
The nail.
What nail?
The one you used to
scratch the wall.
Oh, you're even afraid of a nail.
We had a boy,
before you.
He swallowed a nail.
He wanted freedom that badly.
One can swallow the devil here.
We are in charge.
We don't hide our rules.
Do you think you've
tamed me? Do you?
There's a certain man out there
in the world: Uncle Ivan.
You should know...
...the moment word of my
treatment reaches the navy...
...there will be a 180-degree
turnaround. You'll see.
Porfiry, hold on!
Where did you hide him?
Have you really locked him up?
I'll bail the boy out.
Here is your receipt.
You don't know him.
He's like fire.
Such a helper will
come in handy.
Such a life is for him:
one of courage and risk.
Hold on, Porfiry, hold on.
I'll be there in a moment.
I must deal with some poachers.
It's a pity you're not here.
When I grow up...
...I'll become a defender
of birds and fish.
And for fishmongers like you,
there will be no mercy.
Kulbaka, stop it.
Hello, kids!
Don't get up.
Here you are, our juvenile
detention class. Newcomers.
Children, show me your hands.
Now she'll find out who
gets their pockets mixed up.
Between what belongs to them
and what belongs to someone else.
And what do you have here?
Did you mark yourself?
He was born with it.
He's a bad element.
You're a real comedian.
What got you sent here?
Where are you from?
I'm from Kamyshanky.
It's on the Kazakh side.
Why are you here?
I ran away from home,
dropped out of school.
I slept in boats, in attics.
And what else?
Why did you fall silent?
Tell her how you hooked a fish.
He's our juvenile poacher.
It's a type of cadres we have.
Who hooked what?
When did I hook anything?
It's a lie.
Who accuses me?
What does he mean, "hooked"?
It's when the fish is grabbed
through the ribs with a hook.
It's a barbaric method.
But no one will confess...
...though we can see
the truth in his eyes.
So he's a juvenile poacher?
- Yes.
How could you hook a living
creature through the ribs?
Don't you think it's painful
for the little fish?
Don't you think your lies
are painful for me?
And if he really didn't hook
it and isn't a poacher?
How can you cast
suspicion on him?
As for you, ma'am,
don't protect me.
Maybe I did hook it.
Maybe I've robbed
people's nets.
What happened?
Go on, defend him.
Was he arrested at the port?
He was.
And did he sneak off to
the beach this summer? He did.
And did he steal from
unsuspecting fools?
This is also a lie. Unless
you saw it, don't say it.
It's a lie. It never happened.
Never mind. Calm down.
We believe you.
Listen: there's no
smoke without fire.
You're a real saint.
Maybe you're descended from
a tsar of Kiev Rus, or...
Why are you suddenly
my character witness?
...from their roots...
Yeah, an heir, a scion...
...or maybe just son
of a single mother.
So maybe you, the
adults, can explain:
What is a son of
a single mother?
When I have never seen my
father with my own eyes.
What do you think, I was
born from the Holy Spirit?
Maybe the stork brought me?
Or I grew in a cabbage patch?
I've been branded with a hot
iron: "Fatherless Oksanych."
And now I have to live with it
everywhere in your wide world.
As you can see, he is
like a boiling kettle.
Such a boy won't perish.
He could catch a
wolf by its ears.
You should apologize to him.
Why?
You know very well.
My dear friends...
At first you won't
be used to this.
You may find it boring.
But when your term is over,
you'll feel rather different.
My dears, just promise me...
...you'll be disciplined,
and don't forget hygiene.
Marysa Pavlovna, go
on with the lesson.
I shall invite the committee
back for another class.
Anatoliy Ivanovich, after you.
As for you, Anton Gerasimovich,
please come see me after school.
Can you tell me, please,
where does Oksana Kulba work?
There she is.
Good afternoon!
I'm your son's teacher.
He would not obey me
even when I'd use a belt.
How do you expect him to obey
when you look like a schoolgirl?
Though nowadays, even
schoolgirls become mothers.
Your son ran away.
He's at your house right now.
I think it would be better if you
brought him to the special school.
Rather than the superintendent,
who's sitting in the bus.
Think about it.
- Porfiry, my dear!
- Mother!
My dearest son!
My darling! My sun! Honey!
My sweet! You're back!
- Have they released you?
- I've released myself.
Have you run away
without permission?
And there was such a chase!
I jumped to the window, from
the window to the ledge...
...from the ledge to the roof,
from the roof to the tree...
...from the tree
to the fence...
...and up there was a guard
with a rifle, with dogs...
...and with spotlights.
And I jumped on him.
You're my little dreamer.
What guards are you
talking about? What dogs?
Oh, you're so skinny!
This dog would have torn
anyone else apart.
But it didn't even bark at
me. It only licked my cheek.
You see, mom, all dogs love me.
Yes, they do, my dearest.
Mother, ma'am, just
don't give me back.
My son, you've made your bed.
Now sleep in it. It's fair.
I'll quickly run off to work.
I'll ask to be let
off for the day...
...and then we'll
go there together.
- Mother!
- What?
Ma'am, can I ask you something?
Mother, who is my father?
My dear son.
You have never
asked me about him.
Please never ask again.
Your father is a good person.
He never hurt me.
You were born from the
truth, not from a lie.
From the truth, my son.
Not from a lie.
Wait for me here.
I'll be back soon.
Ships, break off the anchors...
Fly through the world,
this oasis of silence.
And I'll spread my wings...
And only my shadow
will glide over you...
I'm free on my land, like a wind.
Like waves, like a bird
with celestial reach...
And only my shadow
will glide over you...
You won't catch me!
Catch me, I'll run anyway...
...to embrace the sun and rain.
Like a leaf, I'll blow
away among the stars.
And only my shadow
will glide over you...
You won't catch me!
You won't catch me.
The way is clear.
Porfiry, my dear, eat the cake.
I've baked it myself.
Drink the tea, my dear.
Sonny! Porfiry.
When you were little,
you loved me very much.
Here are your papers,
Porfiry. You're free.
Happy sailing!
Lay aft.
Raise the anchor.
Some here have asked me,
"Do you love your mum?"
I don't answer silly questions.
Period.
I do love her.
But it's none of your business.
Period.
Good afternoon!
Do you have any
stowaways aboard?
Even a mouse couldn't slip by me.
Wake up! Let's grab
this little bastard.
Get him!
Get out! Run over there, quickly!
Stand still!
Porfiry!
Comrades! Comrades!
Leave the boy alone.
Stand still! Do you
think it's a game?
What's the matter?
Piss off. Come on, get out!
It's not like he killed
anyone. Let him be.
He didn't have a knife, did he?
And what is it?
Pull yourself together!
Why are you breaking
children's hands? Butchers.
Let the child free.
Why are you twisting his arms?
Look at your fat face.
Twist your own child's hands.
Let's go, Porfiry.
I won't give you to anyone.
I'll take you to Kucuegury,
to be raised among lizards.
Where's this intern girl?
Do you know what you
get for running away?
Punishment cell, no
more than three days.
I glad you know.
Get out.
Okay, go.
- To the punishment cell?
- To the bedroom.
I'll manage without your pity.
I'm going to the punishment cell.
You're going to the bedroom,
to the spot you ran away from.
Kulbaka!
Look what your running away has
brought us. Look at the windows.
Yeah, and where did he run?
Right behind mama's skirt.
It's terrible!
It's the 20th century, and
we're still chasing people...
hunting them.
It's meanly.
I don't want to live.
After this, how can I believe it
possible to destroy meanness...
...cynicism, deceit?
How can I look into his eyes?
Tell me?!
If you could only see
how he stared at me.
Tell me, is there a solution?
Because I can't see one.
It's very bad, if
we've broken him.
If he won't have it in
him to run away anymore.
Yes, to run away.
Even if it's strange to hear
on the school director's lips.
Are you planning a
new breakout for him?
Why new?
Do you think that we've got him
back? We've only caught him.
Now we must truly bring him
back to us, to the people.
Porfiry! I envy you so much.
You're so brave. I wouldn't
be able to do it.
Weren't you afraid at all?
My grandfather's
name was Porfiry.
Mother gave me the
name in his honor.
Grandpa had 2 Orders of Glory.
There would be a third,
if he hadn't been injured.
Grandpa always said:
"Courage drinks honey."
My father is also brave.
He was a pilot during
the war. A fighter pilot.
He made ram-attacks.
Also, I didn't run behind
my mother's skirt.
I went to the sea,
to Uncle Ivan.
He was really fearless.
Be careful!
Hello.
- What are you doing?
- I'm building a fence.
Do you know how to mow?
If you'll put all the hay
I've mowed into the haycock.
Excellent!
Here you go.
Guys! Do all of you
know how to mow?
And how!
Okay.
This way.
So, Anton Gerasimovich,
shall we relive our youth?
We shall.
Why are we leaving a strip?
That won't do.
This strip of grass is...
...a strip of uncut
wild flowers.
It will be like a firm
fence for our camp.
We must have a heart,
Don't you agree?
I want no part of this business.
I have a heavy hand, it's true.
I got along without compassion.
Life hasn't spoiled me.
But I raised my children
right. They're not bums.
One is a harpooner, the other a
drilling foreman in the Caspian.
My son has earned two Orders.
It turns out my pedagogy
is worth something.
What is this?
What is this,
I ask you?
I think the summer camp ought
to be built in the schoolyard.
Pupil Butkevich!
Your father has come.
Gena!
Father has come.
Have you gone nuts?
Run to your father, or
he won't come anymore.
Let him go. Let him
not come again.
But you were saying
he made ram-attacks.
Gena, you must understand,
he's your father.
A traitor, he's a traitor!
Yes, I know he doesn't want me
visiting. He wrote me about it.
But I had to come, to hear a
word, to take a look at him.
I wanted it for some reason, so
here I am. And what a reception!
He thinks I betrayed him and
his mother, by marrying again.
His mother died in a crash. He
says I traded him for a stepmom.
It all began with that. Now he's
with this gang of hooligans.
I fought, did everything I could
to improve his surroundings.
I moved away from the capital.
I was a chair in architecture.
Do you think that it's easy
to sacrifice such a position?
But the sacrifices were in vain.
Again came the black marks on
his record, the vagabondage.
What he was lacking?
Maybe just pigeon milk.
But he didn't even want to see me.
I know very well this problem
has existed for centuries.
Education is an eternal problem.
But why is this problem mine?
My son didn't want to see me.
He turned away from me.
You're professionals, so tell me:
why more and more problem children?
There have to be some reasons.
But what should I do?
I have entrusted my only child's
education to you, strangers.
For us, the generation of
battlefront destitution...
...we hope to see our kids, who
grow among beauty and comfort...
...become spiritually beautiful.
He didn't even want to look at me.
I've refused him nothing.
I even brought a gift.
Tell me it's just a teen thing.
Maybe he will grow out of it?
Or have I lost him forever?
I've brought a gift for him.
It's a boat.
A very expensive gift.
Is there any way to win
him back, to break the ice?
I understand everything, I do, but
is he really convinced I'm his enemy?
Tell me, please.
Why did you come?
Do you want to traumatize
him even more?
What am I to do?
You know very well that
after your previous visit...
...he spent a week
in the clinic.
And what am I supposed to do?
Go away, and don't come
back until we call for you.
Here, like in a hospital...
...we deal with the injured,
the traumatized.
Even if they're rudely
called "offenders."
Regarding your present,
don't even show it to him.
"SPECIAL SCHOOL"
"MOTHER"
Gena, go look for Porfiry.
No! I said it's not allowed!
How did they let you in?
Let me see my son.
Come in.
I want to see my son.
You should drink less.
I don't drink at all!
Come over here, please.
What do you have here?
What are these?!
So what? He's been smoking
since the third grade.
And this is honey.
My precious son. My happiness.
"WE'VE WORKED, NOW
LET'S HAVE A REST."
What is it?
The bosses are making
a movie about us.
Nope, can't find him anywhere.
Go, look again.
The main event in today's
program is the sack race.
First prize will be mine.
There's nothing you can do.
Cake!!!
No, a roasted chicken.
Even better.
Better for me.
I like it roasted.
Ready, go!
Quiet, lads, be quiet.
The winner's speech.
Open, open the gates for me!
I'll sack-race all the way home.
Please, take it.
Hey, you! Actors.
You'll get soaked!
Lads, run away from
the stage. Run!
We're firemen. We have
no fear of water.
Well done, well done!
Cherry Troopers! Line up.
Faster, faster.
Attention!
To recap yesterday's results:
Pupil Kulba was the winner
of the socialism competition.
Kulbaka, take three steps forward.
Congratulations!
Today, he'll be awarded with a
transitional leader's jersey.
- Help yourself!
- Thank you.
Take more. It's not enough.
Enough.
Kulbaka, join the line-up.
Congratulations to all!
The leaders of the "Steppe Giant"
sovkhoz are pleased by your work.
And now, back to it. Keep it up!
Break it up.
As you were!
Why are you still shod?
Take off your shoes.
Hey, little workers!
Come here, come, come.
Feast your eyes upon your work.
What happened?
Shame on you!
Only the top layer is
covered with cherries.
What do you call this?
It was returned by the cannery.
This hasn't happened
for centuries!
Whose work is this?
Confess! Whose work is this?
It's your work. Why are
you silent? Tell me!
It's not his.
Whose then?
It's his. The striker's.
So it's you, the
striker. Come here.
He didn't do it.
What were you talking about,
esprit de corps. For shame!
Take off the shirt.
Don't touch me, don't!
Get on your spots!
You've eaten your fill.
No sweets for you.
You'll sing all day long.
Don't touch me.
Sing, all of you, so I can see
what your mouths are busy with.
No cherries. I told
you, no cherries!
Sing, all of you!
Well, Valery Ivanovich...a
mass escape from the garden.
And one of the ringleaders
is your little Kulba.
I warned you.
You should put the camp
in the school's backyard.
Put the tents behind the wall.
There's plenty of space.
The yard is big.
Let them live right out
there the whole summer.
You won't have my agreement
for your herbaceous border.
Valery...
Keep silent!
On your spot, quickly!
It's my error. Mine.
Why did I have to send
this blockhead with them?
He only causes conflict, and
embitters them against us.
He must be kicked out at once.
Hello, sir.
Hello.
Valery Ivanovich, I've bad news.
Herders found a dead man in a
car on the steppe. Heart attack.
We found out that he came
here to visit his son.
He is Gena Butkevich's father.
Here is his keychain,
with his son's picture.
Where is Gena Butkevich?
He hasn't come back yet.
I solemnly beg you,
don't tell anyone.
The kid shouldn't hear about
this through the grapevine.
I'll talk to him myself.
Okay.
There are three more who
have not come back.
We should send for a driver and
go straight to Kulbaka's home...
...and wait for them
'til tomorrow morning.
They won't allow an old man
like me to sleep today.
Take a rest, Anton Gerasimovich.
What do you mean, "take a rest"?
This time, you stay
here at the school.
The search party already left.
What's the meaning of this?
Don't chafe, Anton Gerasimovich.
Sir, it'll be night soon.
These people are younger than us.
Also, she's a teacher. A pedagogue.
I don't meddle in pedagogy.
I'm head of the administration.
I know whom I'm dealing with.
Those three are real masters. They
could teach a rabbit to set fires.
What they need is a jail,
and you've pampered them.
Take a rest.
Eat.
Just think of it, falling behind
and getting lost on a field trip.
Never mind, the guys will come
to have dinner. They'll help.
They've worked up a good appetite.
They're waving their spoons
like oars in a boat race.
What did I tell you?
Hunger will drive them here.
Should we arrest them now or let
them fortify themselves first?
Let them fortify themselves.
They still have a long time
to walk across that steppe.
What do you mean, "a long time"?
'Til they understand on their own.
They're coming. Run!
- It's not funny. She thinks
we were killed. - Killed.
- She fired into the air.
- You bet she did.
Of course she did. Who wants to suffer
all through life, to be a murderer?
There are archaeologists
working on the steppe now.
Let's join them.
I heard they're hiring
teenagers for odd jobs.
It could be interesting.
To swing a shovel all day?
Only fools and horses work.
It's better to go my brother's.
He's well-settled over there.
He cooks shashliks [shish kebab]
and chebureks [turnovers].
He bakes pastries
as big as bast shoes.
Express train!
Serpent. I hate it!
You haul vacationers to the sea.
Mamas' boys are fed with cakes.
Take that...right
between the curtains.
Have you seen this?
While someone was sack-racing
for a roasted chicken...
I grabbed something.
A real gun.
Give me the money.
Your hands are shaking, as if
you were stealing chickens.
Uncle Vanya, where are you?
Hold on, Porfiry.
I'm here. Hold on!
Two of us won't manage.
Guys! Help!
We're with you, Porfiry.
Cover it with sand.
Look, a picture.
It's not a picture,
it's a sculpture.
No, lads, we're hallucinating
due to hunger. It's a mirage.
- Hey, uncle, lend me
your boots. - Take them.
They're too small.
Watch out! A car!
The flower bed grows for me.
Do not touch it, don't!
Are you the one who planted it?
It's a pity I don't have my Finnish
knife on me...but we'll meet again.
Beast. He dares threaten me.
What's the matter with you?
Why are you laughing?
Hold on. Hold on.
Hold on. Why are you laughing?
He didn't even notice it.
What do we need it for?
That skunk wanted to rob
a cash-desk with it.
What now?
We should make for the coast,
go to Uncle Vanya.
He can make use of us.
It's said, the inspector's son bit off
a poacher's finger defending his dad.
I could also have
done it, couldn't I?
I couldn't bite off a finger.
Do you think Uncle Vanya will take us?
Of course he will. You still don't
understand what kind of man he is!
Listen to this:
One night, one autumn...
...some poachers were catching
fish with nets in the bay...
...when suddenly Uncle Vanya
emerged from the reeds...
Then one of them fired a rifle.
But Uncle Vanya wasn't scared,
and jumped into their boat...
They were strong, like two bulls.
They threw him into the water.
But he stubbornly climbed back in.
They hit him with the paddle,
but he kept hanging on.
His iron fist found the teeth
of first one, then the other.
They pressed him from two sides,
hit him on his ribs, his head.
But he smashed the big galoot in
the teeth, again in the teeth.
The other attacked with the paddle,
but he hit him in the teeth too.
They kicked and hit him in the head,
the liver, the ribs. But he hung on.
They threw him into the water.
All rise. The court
is now in session.
We now call the witness Kulbaka.
I recognize you.
And you too.
All of you.
You thought I had drowned?
Here I am, and I won't give you
poachers, you skunks, a break.
The verdict is delivered.
Shave off their hair!
My son, what are you doing to me?
I've had to get by all alone.
I've suffered enough with you.
I'm ashamed, son,
totally ashamed.
What am I to do, darling
Porfiry, my only son?
I'm alone with you. Why are
you not listening to me?
You're my sprig, my baby,
my lovely child.
We have not overlooked them.
It's good that we caught
at least one of them.
I mean, it's bad.
They arrested him as he tried to
rob a stall. Here's the telegram.
Has he got a gun on him?
What gun?
The starter pistol is missing.
I'd completely forgotten it.
It always stays in
my iron cabinet.
I remember it went missing
after the sack race.
Do you remember what a commotion
happened when the rain began?
In short, I have no excuse.
But it means those
two have the gun.
Look who's talking. I was
chasing him 10 years ago.
I've written reports on him,
and he should know better.
Neither Porfiry nor Gena
could do such a thing.
Why can't you understand that
they'll come back on their own?
That's the most important part.
If we seize them again, like
before, we'll lose them forever.
I beg you, give them
another three days.
If something happens, which it
won't, I will take the blame.
With your educational methods, you
won't be waiting long for that.
It concerns you too,
with your "iron cabinet."
They'll be caught without us. The
investigation's already open. I called.
How long will we sleep here?
Here, eat it and don't grumble.
I'm sick of those cucumbers.
Where's your Uncle Ivan?
He'll come tomorrow,
for certain. You'll see.
Enough, now, I'll tell you
what's going to happen.
It's not going to happen
the way you've laid out.
A boat will appear in the morning,
and in the boat, Uncle Ivan.
Uncle Ivan will get out and say:
"Porfiry, get up. Do you hear me?"
And you'll tell him: "Sir, we've
been waiting for you for two days."
He'll answer: "I know, I came just for
you. You overslept, you waiter-fors."
And we'll ask him: "Uncle Ivan,
please take us with you."
"Sir, we'll help you,
to build fires, to choose nets."
And he'll answer: "Well, boys,
I'd love to have helpers."
"But don't you think it's better
to go visit your mom first?"
"She's probably desperate,
her son is again on the run."
"Go, you know the
way. It's not far."
"Do you want me to send both
of you back where you belong?"
"I wouldn't do that. You have your
own heads on your own shoulders."
"You can decide for yourselves!"
"Remember, boys, the greatest
victory is that won over yourself."
"Do both of you understand me?"
There are other fish in the
sea, besides Uncle Ivan.
Gena, just take it easy.
We can move further along.
I bet my father has come and
is waiting for me over there.
Do you want to run away from me?
No, not at all.
And if they catch us with the gun?
Let's throw it away.
Okay.
That's that.
Let's get on a freight train,
and let them chase the wind.
He'll get put on trial.
Who?
Our gym teacher.
Why?
For losing the gun.
What do you suggest?
Fish it out and take
it back to the school.
Bring it back ourselves?
No, just throw it over the fence.
Well, why couldn't you
have said that before?
Nothing.
It's too dark down there.
Here it is. I found it.
You know, Gena, to be honest
I don't have any Uncle Ivan.
I knew that a long time ago,
but why did you lie to me?
I didn't mean to. You have
a father, but as for me...
This is it. Let's crawl away.
What about the gun?
It's in the staff room, on
the table, like we agreed.
Cinema! Cinema!
What's the hurry?
Let's watch the movie.
OK. We won't be able to
go to the cinema soon.
But after the movie, we're
immediately scooting away.
Porfiry, you know, our director
is just like your Uncle Ivan.
The spitting image of him.
The whole time you were telling me
about him, I pictured our director.
Here we are!
THE END [subs by Spartak2005,
edited by adimond]