Don't move!
This won't do, Mr. Adel.
Lower your voice, Sayed.
- We're in intensive care.
- Really?
We're in intensive care?
Nobody told me!
If so, why are you here?
Visiting hours
aren't for another 45 minutes.
What difference will 45 minutes make?
Nobody will notice.
They will notice, and I will get
into trouble and be punished.
Please, go sit in the waiting area
until visiting hours.
Okay, Sayed. Okay.
That would be great, sir.
Get me
the "x-bex-fistin" injection, quickly!
Why are you staring at me? Hurry!
Don't be scared. Don't be scared.
You look like a complete wreck.
Do this so God can bless you,
and you can be healed.
Come on. Slowly, slowly.
Dear God!
Did someone get the number of the car
that hit him?
- It was a train accident.
- Did someone get the train number?
Open up!
- Go ahead, Doctor.
- Open up quickly!
Go ahead.
There is no God but Allah!
Really, Adel?
What if they caught you?
Why would they catch me?
I'm dressed like a doctor.
What is a doctor
other than a coat, stethoscope and cap?
And good looks!
Plus, a one-hour visit
isn't enough, Abeer.
I can't get enough of you.
But you know what? You look better today.
You're glowing. Your face is smiling.
I'll tell the doctor
to move you to a regular room.
He comes at seven o'clock, right?
What time is it now?
Why are you asking about the time?
Where's your phone?
Did you damage it again?
No, I swear I didn't.
I switched it off and left it at home.
- Why did you switch it off?
- Who calls me besides you?
You're the only one
who calls me and checks up on me.
The phone is just an annoyance.
And, honestly,
I only like you annoying me, you beauty.
I really miss home, Adel.
We're so close, Abeer.
We're so close.
The doctor reassured me, I swear.
I promise, as soon as you're better,
I'll take you on the back of the Harley.
- Did you really get a motorbike?
- I'm picking it up tomorrow.
- You did what you wanted.
- I'll tell you what, Abeer.
It's been my dream
since I was 20 years old
to ride a Harley with the big handles,
take a pretty girl behind me
and go to Ras El Bar.
That was 40 years ago, Abeer.
How about we go to El Gouna now?
Yesterday,
I found you an amazing pink helmet.
A pink helmet for me?
I want to see your size.
This is too much, Mr. Adel.
What's this? Sorry, I didn't realize.
I will go and come back.
No, it's nothing. Come back.
I'm putting eyedrops in for her.
Oh, eyedrops, yeah.
Mr. Adel, don't you think it's a bit much
what you're doing every day to come early?
And, Mr. Adel, excuse me,
but I'm in nursing.
You can hide all you want,
but I'll find you out.
- What do you mean?
- The prescription.
How about you let me in tomorrow
with no issues,
and I'll get you a free gym membership?
In that case, we have a deal.
Why didn't you say that earlier?
Okay, but leave now.
You've already had an extra ten minutes.
Please. For my sake.
Give us another five minutes.
All right, you've got another 15 minutes.
But no eyedrops!
- Good morning, Grandpa.
- Listen, Metwally... Good morning, Yousef.
I got your sweets. Don't nag.
- Did you get a strawberry lollipop?
- It's in the bags.
Listen, sir.
I want you to submit
my service extension request
and have it on the minister's desk
tomorrow morning.
Is that clear, Metwally?
I know how smart you are.
Why are you speechless?
You got it? Yes.
In the drawer on the left,
there's a pack of papers.
Take three, as I know you'll make
a mistake when writing down the request.
Dad, why didn't you get plums?
- Plums?
- Uncle.
Not you, Mr. Metwally.
The pears you brought yesterday
aren't Khashabi ones.
I like Khashabi ones. You know that.
Metwally, have you got the paper?
Go inside, like this.
What Khashabi?
Khashabi…
Metwally, I don't want you
to just write down the request.
I want you to take
an import and export number
when you're handing it to the officer.
Why, sir?
So that, God willing,
listen to me, Metwally…
- What's up?
- …when you hand it in, he won't say
- he didn't submit the request.
- What's up, Dad?
Hi, dear. How are you?
Not you, Metwally, you idiot.
- Take this.
- What's this, Dad?
The phone you said
couldn't be repaired. Turn around!
Turn around!
I don't want to hear the words
"Get me a phone" again!
Disgusting. What a disappointment.
It turns out I have sons, Mr. Metwally.
It's none of your business.
I can extend my service as I wish!
I tell you what, Metwally.
I have put up with you for 40 years.
Put up with me for once, and do as I say!
- Hussein!
- Dear God!
You came in with your shoes on?
I just mopped the apartment!
- I didn't realize.
- What do you mean?
What's the use of those glasses?
I clean, and you dirty it up?
God forgive you.
So, mine are glasses and yours are lasers?
You should write on the door,
"Don't enter until I finish cleaning"!
Grandpa!
Take it easy on the boy!
Take this!
He was annoying me on the stairs.
- "Give me the sweets!"
- Come, dear.
- Goodbye, Metwally.
- Have you lost weight?
- Dad, my dear.
- Yes?
I know that sweet look.
I want 50 dollars to get V-Bucks.
Is the "Alpha Box"
something they asked for at school?
- No, it's for the PlayStation.
- Seriously?
Don't speak that way!
God give me strength!
Boy, do you know that back in the day,
if I asked my father for 50 dollars,
he would have said I was a spy
and reported me!
- Get away from me!
- Come here, Boudy.
What does your dad have to do with us?
Are you just going to keep
harassing the boy?
You know what? Give it to him.
I'll deduct it from his allowance.
Now that's clever thinking!
You son of a…
Al Ahly club! How great they are!
What are you doing?
- I'm watching the match.
- Match?
You left me to go watch the match?
We didn't utter a single word
to each other throughout dinner.
And at home you run to the TV?
My dear. Dinner was wonderful,
and the steak was amazing.
Would you prefer us to talk
and let the steak get cold?
We didn't talk during our last dinner,
the one before that or the previous one!
So it's a dinner problem.
We should sleep on an empty stomach
and not bother with dinner.
I'm not joking.
Why don't you talk to me?
- I have nothing to say, Sherine.
- Every day?
You have nothing to say,
Azaizy, every day?
Why didn't you talk?
Whenever I talk to you,
you give such ridiculous responses.
"Yeah… of course… mmm."
All right.
From now on, I'll add words
so that you don't get bored or fed up.
Like, "No way!", "Really?", "Oops."
Stop being so cold and answer me properly!
Sherine, what do you want?
- I want a divorce.
- A divorce?
Don't, Sherine.
Don't keep bringing up that word.
It could really destroy us both.
I don't want anything at all! I'm fed up!
What's this? Four girls, Shohdy?
I only went to the bathroom
for five minutes.
You underestimate the five minutes,
Oksana.
A minute away from you is like a year.
- Oh, really?
- Yes!
Come, come, don't be upset.
Come, have a seat.
Are you still upset?
All right, all right.
I will get my assistant in Soma Bay
to get the villa ready,
and we can go
and have a super wild weekend, okay?
And we can get married there.
Not that wild.
Oksana, just so you know,
no married people are happy.
Would you like it
if your dear Shohdy wasn't happy?
- No.
- Okay, then.
Marriage is a must.
Okay, we'll have this weekend,
and then marriage.
- Okay?
- No.
Because what's halal is nicer, I'll wait.
"Because what's halal is nicer,
I'll wait?"
Oksana, haven't I told you a hundred times
not to watch Radwa El Sherbiny?
You're still watching
Radwa El Sherbiny, right?
Here, drink this.
Actually, this won't do.
Wait, I'll get you something.
Wait.
Gino, give me something
that will stop me from seeing straight.
Both me and her.
"Because what's halal is nicer,
I'll wait."
What a traditional girl she's become.
I have a soft spot for black-and-white.
You see?
Gorgeous!
You've got me
going around in circles after you!
How did you find me?
Very easily.
I've spent seven hours going around
all the lowlife places you could be at.
I've committed so many sins, Mr. Shohdy.
May God forgive you.
This paper needs to be signed.
Choose your timing, Mostafa. Tomorrow!
Tomorrow won't do.
Take it. Tomorrow won't do...
Get out of the way.
- Trust me, Mr. Shohdy.
- Hold this.
Mr. Kumar won't let
the tour group leave India
until we transfer the money.
That won't happen without a signature.
Mostafa, are you aware
of what you're talking about and where?
Tomorrow, Mostafa. Don't be a pain!
- Do you know her, Shohdy?
- "Her"?
She is one of my employees,
but she's completely dense.
Poor thing.
Please, mind your own business,
because this man has worn me out!
Mr. Shohdy,
I am not prepared to lose our staff
because you won't sign!
- Besides, Mr. Kumar...
- Don't be a drag, Mostafa.
Work is for the workplace.
This is a place for dancing.
- You want me to sign?
- Of course.
- Dance, then!
- What do you mean?
I won't sign unless you dance.
These are my work clothes.
My dancing clothes are at home.
Well, I've got it into my head
that I want you to dance
in your work clothes.
- If I dance, will you sign?
- I promise.
- Okay. Can I borrow her from you?
- Yes.
- Here you go.
- Thank you.
I will dance with you.
Take it easy. Take it easy.
You are a master
Of style, suaveness and elegance
From an educated family
This mango is nice, Uncle.
- But it's not from Ismailia.
- From Ismailia?
- No.
- Just eat it and shut up.
- Fine.
- Hussein?
How is Abeer, Adel's wife, doing now?
I really don't know.
I keep calling Adel. He doesn't pick up.
His phone is switched off.
Let me try him again.
Slurp it up.
Just keep it down
so I can call the man on the phone.
- Hello?
- Hussein.
Who calls someone at a time like this?
Sorry to bother you so early.
You fool, it's the afternoon!
Oh, really?
I have no idea what time it is,
or what day it is.
I don't even know where I am.
Tell me, is there any news on Adel?
Do you know why his phone is off?
Oh, really? Is it still switched off?
Wait a minute. Wait, wait.
Azaizy is calling me.
I'll just take this call.
Wait. Be patient. Calm down.
I don't need a headache from Azaizy
right now.
Be patient.
Here, genius, take it.
Make this phone call a…
- "Video contrast."
- You mean a "conference call," Dad.
I knew that. No need to show me up
in front of everyone.
Good morning. How are you, you idiot?
Hello, hello, hello, Sir Azaizy!
Come and join us for mangoes.
You're only inviting me because you know
I won't come, you imbecile.
Why don't you come? What's keeping you?
The last time we actually met up
was three months ago.
What do you mean, "three months"?
We met last Ramadan, you moron.
Last Ramadan was three months ago.
Now you know
who the moron is, you imbecile.
Hussein, why didn't you tell me
Shohdy was on the call so I could hang up?
Calm down, boatman,
or I'll come over and sort you out,
as usual.
Come over here, and you'll be leaving
with no pants, as always.
You always did like to see me
with no pants, you dirty thing.
You guys are hopeless. Tell me,
is there any news on Adel?
He hasn't been seen for about ten days.
Come on guys, let's show a little respect
and ask after the man's wife.
Come on, Shohdy!
This is the fifth time
I've told you we should marry,
and then I wake up in a hotel with you.
That won't do.
Put it on speaker and say
you're talking to your dad. I'll save you.
Let me go now, so I can help her forget
what she saw yesterday.
Give her two sleeping pills so she
forgets the fiasco she saw yesterday.
Go, you moron.
You sons of…
So you do know how to talk?
And you know how to laugh
with your friends.
I also know how to swim without arm bands.
And when I walk, I don't fall flat
on my face anymore. I've grown up.
And I learned how to talk, okay?
Very funny.
God help me.
- How are you, Abu Sid?
- Hi, Mr. Adel.
- I'm fine.
- Here is your gym membership.
If you let me in,
you'll be a world champion.
If you don't let me in,
I'll punch you so hard,
I'll send you flying!
Let me in.
Mr. Adel, we tried to contact you,
but your phone was switched off.
My condolences.
This is the cycle of life.
We are all going to die.
The Lord opens the doors of heaven
before her.
So she returns to that land
where there is no death, only eternal joy.
So we may pray…
Where is Adel?
I couldn't see him outside.
Check it out, Captain Azouz has arrived.
What, you saw me and
couldn't hold back your laughter?
Let me in on the joke, you imbeciles.
What are you wearing?
Who comes to a funeral in that suit?
Get lost.
You are privileged to be able to sit
with Captain Azaizy, you imbecile.
Stop it, stop it.
Pull yourselves together.
People are watching us.
Respect yourself.
This is not the time for joking.
- Enough.
- This won't do.
Enough.
This suit has one of those
long sailor telescopes, right?
Pull it out and find Adel for us.
- And you're giving me grief?
- Enough, enough.
What's going on? Have you lost your minds?
The Lord is with you,
go in the safety of Jesus Christ.
Very nice fabric.
Thank you, guys.
May you be well.
May God bless her soul.
We wanted to be with you and Adel
at the burial.
But we only found out through Facebook.
So, where is Adel?
I am very worried about Adel.
He hasn't spoken to anyone
since the burial.
His face is hollow and different.
He even switched off his phone
and didn't come to the funeral today.
Oh, no. I will send him a message
on Facebook and see if he responds.
- There is no God but Allah.
- Mohammed is the messenger of Allah.
Honestly, I'm afraid
he will go into a depression.
I hope you'll stand by him these days.
May this be the end of the sadness,
God willing.
I'm sorry.
Because...
Of course, we have to stand by him.
Once again, I thank you.
May you be well.
Go ahead.
What are you laughing at
in front of the man?
One of his ladies
probably sent him a photo or a joke.
Shame on you.
Show me.
Show me with all your cleverness
what you're going to do about Adel.
Nothing.
We'll take him on a nice trip
for a couple of days
and entertain him at my villa in Soma Bay.
Who's coming with me?
I'll come with you, dude.
I was going for two days
with Sherine anyway.
But you know it will be a drag.
I'll go with you
and use Adel as an excuse.
First, find out how to convince Adel.
You think he'll go with you
when he didn't even attend
his wife's funeral?
This matter requires special tactics.
Leave this one to me.
Condolences, Adel.
Thank you.
Go ahead.
Be strong, Adel.
Be strong, brother.
May God give you strength.
Strength is for God.
What are you doing?
Why are you
all cooped up by yourself in here?
It's not good for you.
I know Abeer, may God bless her soul...
That's enough, Shohdy. I don't need this.
All right, look.
I want to ask you something.
What is it, Shohdy?
Even though the timing isn't right,
I want to ask you to come with us
for a couple of days.
- We can have a change of scenery...
- You're right. The timing isn't right.
Forgive me. I won't be able to come.
Adel, I'm not asking you, I'm begging you.
I'm begging you
to fulfill the last wish I have
before I die.
- What?
- Yes. You heard me right, Adel.
All the doctors have said
that my days are numbered.
And there aren't many left.
There aren't many left.
Yeah.
Not many...
Shohdy!
You won't die! You won't die!
And the doctors will turn out to be liars.
- Liars!
- That's enough, Hussein.
Don't do this to yourself.
- Tell me what you want to eat or drink.
- I want mango.
Mango?
Calm down. Calm down.
Don't do this to yourself.
- I can't, Shohdy.
- Calm down, Hussein.
Calm down.
- What do you think?
- Disgusting.
Disgusting?
The guy was about to give me an Oscar.
- He went to get me a mango for my acting.
- What Oscar? What mango?
Who asks for that?
You might as well have asked him
to make fried eggs with pastrami!
Calm down, Hussein. Calm down.
Don't do this to yourself.
Thank God. Thank God.
I'm afraid
I couldn't find mangoes, Hussein.
- Are persimmons fine?
- Yeah, that will do.
Adel, please tell me that you agree
to come with us to Soma Bay?
You have to come, Adel.
That's enough, Hussein. That's enough.
Calm down, Hussein. Have some persimmon.
- Here, my dear.
- Thanks, mother-in-law.
You're welcome.
- Mother-in-law.
- What?
I noticed that my father-in-law brought
two plates of prickly pear yesterday.
I would be grateful
if one of those plates came out now.
Have something savory first,
then have something sweet.
I can't keep up with your stomach, Son.
Mom, have you seen my swimsuit?
You're going to wear a swimsuit?
You'll look very weird.
Weird…
What swimsuit?
Are you going to Crazy Water?
Sorry, but...
What do you want a swimsuit for?
You always go swimming in your underwear.
I'm being serious.
Do you know how to swim, Uncle?
Should we get you Yousef's arm bands?
Are you done?
Are you done with your funny comedy act?
Or are there still more silly stories?
- Where is the swimsuit?
- All right.
Get out, get out, get out.
What's up?
What? What's up with you?
The company said you were traveling.
Tell me how!
- By car.
- By car?
What about the work that's piled up?
When will you take responsibility?
You have a company.
You have a company and staff
who are stressed out.
We're going through tough times,
and you're traveling!
Enough of this!
Why do you talk to me like this?
Are you dumb?
You're right, Mr. Shohdy. I'm sorry.
I'm afraid for the company.
If you leave without signing
the contracts, the company...
Give me the contracts.
I'll sign them and be done with it.
- All right.
- Give them to me.
If I didn't know
that you did all the work in the company,
I'd have fired you ages ago
and had some peace.
You're nothing without me.
What did you say?
- What did you say?
- I said without me, you are...
Thank you! Thank you! What is this?
This beautiful signature was the issue?
This tiny squiggle was the issue?
Thank you. Thank you.
Where's the invite to?
I'm going to show my friend a good time
for a couple of days.
Adel. You know him.
Yeah. What's wrong with Mr. Adel?
- His wife.
- She is a grumpy old woman.
She's always bringing him down.
- She died.
- So that she could bring him down!
See how they think?
They'll do anything to bring us down!
"I'll die, but at least
I'll bring him down!" God help us!
You're dumb, right?
You're dumb, not normal.
His wife passed away.
May God bless her soul.
Sorry. May God bless her soul.
By the way,
I'm trying to get ahold of Mahi,
who looks after the Soma Bay office.
I want her to prepare the villa for me.
I call her, and her phone's turned off.
How I can get ahold of her?
Don't worry. I'll come with you.
- Why would you travel with me?
- To find her.
Can't you do that here?
I can, but look at this coincidence!
What a coincidence!
- What?
- I was going to the bus station right now
to catch any bus going to Soma Bay.
- Really?
- I swear, God forgive me.
- No way.
- I swear!
You want me to come with you?
You want to go with me?
As you wish. You choose.
You're being ridiculous.
I've figured you out.
You want to come with me for a free trip.
I got you.
I do want to come for a free trip.
Forgive me, Mr. Shohdy,
I want to see the sea.
I haven't taken a day off
since I was promoted a year ago.
I need to be close by. If I need advice,
or a signature, I know where to find you.
It won't work out.
In order to convince Adel to come with me,
I had to tell him I was ill
and in my final days.
It won't look good if I'm thinking
about work during my final days.
We can tell him anything.
Just take me with you!
Please, take me with you!
Are the contents fragile?
Do you have any electronics, blenders?
Any china, cashew nuts?
Cashew nuts?
- Who is this funny comedian, Shohdy?
- Mostafa. He's with me.
- Thank you.
- I'm his son, by the way.
Welcome.
My heart is with you, my dear.
My dear Azaizy.
It's okay. That's how it is.
The precious ones leave,
and only the disgusting ones remain.
- May God honor you, Azaizy.
- No, Adool, honestly.
It's all right.
The good people leave us very early,
in the morning.
When did she die?
My dear, take this.
- You. Come.
- Me?
Yes.
- Yes?
- Put this in the trunk.
- Why don't you put it?
- What is this rudeness?
Why don't you choose proper drivers?
He looks like a driver,
but he's an employee of mine.
Employee? I'm the office manager,
Mr. Shohdy!
An office manager? So what? What did you
manage before that, a chest of drawers?
What drawer are you sitting in
at the office, in case we need you?
Am I supposed to answer?
What is this silliness, Mr. Shohdy?
Enough, Mostafa.
He's your dad's age.
My father is much cooler than him.
- Boy!
- Take the bag and get into the drawer.
- What drawer?
- Get into the car.
Wait, son.
- Take this.
- Stop! Why are you getting on my case too?
Why don't you give him 20?
- Should I give him another five?
- Come on, guys. Let's get going.
Where are you going?
- Give me the keys. I'm going to drive.
- Why?
Because you drive so slowly,
we won't arrive until after tomorrow.
Azouz, go sit in the back.
What do you mean
"sit in the back," Shohdy?
Me and Adel are in the back.
Sit him beside you.
- What about me, sir?
- I'm not sitting in the front or the back.
I'm driving,
and you're sitting next to me, Hussein.
Where will I sit? I'm not here
to see you off. I'm going with you.
Your father...
Don't mention him,
or I'll bring up your mother!
- I'm not sitting on his lap.
- I will drive!
We don't want to bother you, Adel.
Shohdy, I will drive.
Let's just stop these childish antics.
No, Adel, Shohdy is right.
You might crash the car
while daydreaming about Abeer.
Give me the keys, Shohdy!
Come on, come on.
What are you doing?
- I'm sitting in the front.
- Why? I'm sitting in the front.
I don't know how to sit in back.
I have to sit in front.
Go and sit in the back
like I told you.
- No, I'm sitting in the front.
- Fine, sit in the front.
We're not little kids, Azaizy.
- Azaizy, I want you. Come here.
- What?
I want you, but away from Adel.
Away from Adel. Let me tell you something.
What a strong move, Shohdy.
Get in.
- Petty children.
- They are truly petty.
Because they want to sit
in the front, right?
You've left your drawer.
Where are you going?
What's going on? Wait, wait...
Guys, wait a minute.
Mr. Shohdy, where am I gonna sit?
Mr. Shohdy, I'm coming with you!
What is this song you're listening to?
This, Mostafa, is our song.
A song from our generation.
It was all the rage back then.
So, this was a trend back then?
"Was a trend"? It is still a trend.
Still?
Mostafa, get me some water
from the icebox.
Sure, Mr. Shohdy.
Mostafa, check if there's
a Diet Coke in the icebox.
Who's the Diet Coke for?
Who do you think, my mother?
It's for me, of course.
How is it for you?
You decided to go on a diet today?
Or did your doctor say, "Eat
whatever you want, but have Diet Coke"?
What do you mean,
"Eat whatever you want"? Rude.
- Mostafa.
- What, Hajj?
Make me a cup of tea, please.
You'll find a packet
with some tea and sugar there.
Cut from the edge, as there's no spoon,
and pour it out like this.
Why are you so obsessed with me,
Hajj Hussein?
How can I make tea
when I'm squashed up like this?
You have so much space in front of you,
you could have a tea party!
Do you think it's normal
to raise your voice?
Quiet down. I'm trying to send a message
to Mahi. Her phone is switched off.
Where's the water, Mostafa?
All right, Mr. Shohdy. I'm alone
in the kitchen and no one's helping!
Ah, Sabah's mother, every man's dream.
Sorry for the question, guys.
Did you make a hole in the wall
to look at the maid?
Yes.
We were children, Mostafa.
Twenty to 21 years old.
- How were you children at the age of 21?
- In our days, a 21-year-old was a child.
The most hijinks
came from this man driving the car.
He used to get up at the crack of dawn
and go sleep at Mr. Shohdy's house.
He would peep through the window,
and he had...
- The binoculars...
- That belonged to your dad!
And he was the smart one!
Do you remember, Adel?
I can't take it…
Adel?
Sorry, guys. I wasn't paying attention.
Why don't you put something on,
like the radio? It's a long trip.
Sure.
What does it mean?
It means I won't see you again, that's it
I won't touch you, I won't tell you
About anything that's bothering me
What does it mean?
Leave it. It's nice!
He left me and went away
All the pain
He left me, I got ill
And then I was at peace
At peace
Why did you leave me?
It looks like it's going to be
a wonderful trip.
I honestly don't know what to do.
Beware of the direction of the wind
so there's no splash back.
You've grown up, Shohdy,
and you're urinating like a man now.
I'm the one who's surprised.
How are you urinating standing up, Hana?
Pull yourself together, Shohdy,
before I come over there and slap you.
Are you embarrassed by your name?
Adel, please stop talking about
this subject.
Sorry, guys,
but I've always had the problem
of not understanding
my dad's friends' jokes.
Is your name Azaizy or Hana?
His name is Mr. Hana Al Azaizy.
And his wife's name is Sherine.
So, it's Hana and Sherine.
Shohdy.
I swear, if you don't wrap up
this subject, I'll go back.
I don't know why you're uptight.
The man is explaining it to him, Hana.
I mean, Azaizy.
Even you are mocking me, Adel?
You should be depressed right now
given the terminal stage you're in.
- Are you an idiot?
- You're the reason!
Enough!
Don't be upset.
The name Hana
is a very beautiful and popular name.
Thank you, sir.
The first girl I dated
was also named Hana.
But she was a little shorter.
Do you like that?
You let a worthless child mock me?
Why say that, Ms... I mean, Mr. Hana?
That's enough, that's enough.
Mostafa, let's go. Come on.
Hussein, come on.
Where are you getting all this water from?
Hussein, are you urinating or showering?
I can see lots of shower gel.
- Zizo.
- Get in, get in.
This won't do. Wait.
Son!
Son, this won't do!
- How are you, Yasser?
- I'm your valet, Essam.
Oh, yeah, Essam.
- Essam, where is Mahi?
- I don't know, sir.
Get the bags out
and fill the car up with gas.
Me, me, Mr. Shohdy!
And get Mostafa down with the bags, Essam.
Go ahead, go ahead.
Of course, you'll find it's dusty
as I haven't been here for ages,
like I told you.
It must be dusty, then.
But this won't stop us
from having an awesome weekend!
What's this?
Shohdy, didn't you tell me
that your mother died?
- Yeah.
- Is that her, God bless her soul?
No, that isn't her, God bless her soul.
Are you sure of the address?
This might not be your villa.
What do you mean, you imbecile?
- I just unlocked the door in front of you.
- Maybe it's not your key.
- Then whose key is it?
- The villa's key.
- Nice one.
- Zizo, don't annoy me! What's going on?
What's this?
Oh, my goodness!
- Oh, my goodness! Who are they?
- What's going on, Shohdy?
Did you get a communal villa?
What do you mean "communal"?
I don't know what's going on.
What are these people doing in the water?
- Yasser?
- It's Essam, Mr. Shohdy.
Oh, my goodness! What is this?
- And why are they sleeping on the floor?
- I don't know.
What's going on, guys?
Good morning. Welcome to Masoud Center,
"Unlimited Containment."
We have fully comprehensive care.
We also have elderly care
given by the best doctors
for geriatric diseases,
such as joint stiffness, Alzheimer's,
Parkinson's, incontinence.
- The robes are for the women.
- The robes?
- We also have a massage that ends with…
- Stop. Be quiet.
- Where's Mahi?
- Mahi?
You know the owner, Mahi?
She's not here, sir.
Are you Mr. Masoud, her father?
No, he's Mr. Shohdy, her aunt.
Zizo, this isn't the time for it.
Where is she?
She's at the marina.
Do you know the Shohdy Tourism Office?
- I do.
- Well, she closed it
and turned it into the Masoud Yoga Center.
She is in so much trouble!
- I'm going to destroy her life!
- Then I'm coming with you.
Adel's glass.
- Good afternoon, sir.
- Good afternoon.
Welcome, sir.
You were saying the massage ended with…
Then Shohdy cut you off.
What does it end with?
Sauna and jacuzzi.
What did you think it was? I don't get it.
I understood jacuzzi and sauna,
the other way around.
- Isn't that right, Hussein?
- Of course, Zizo.
We are always looking for happy endings.
Here, take this drink.
Oh, my goodness! What is this?
Wait, Shohdy. You're gonna die too soon.
This is unbelievable! Where is the car?
- Yasser.
- His name is Essam.
Essam! Where is the car?
- Didn't you tell him to go and fill it up?
- Oh, yeah.
- Hey, you, come here.
- Yes, sir.
- Drop us off.
- But this isn't to your standard, sir.
What does that have to do with you?
Drop us off!
Shohdy, it would be better
if we wait for the car.
I can't, Adel.
Something is gonna happen to me.
- That was a really bad move.
- Take it easy, take it easy.
- Why won't you go?
- Go where, sir?
- Take us.
- Take you where?
Shohdy Tourism Office, do you know it?
You mean the Masoud Yoga Center?
- Has it become that popular?
- Very!
- She is a despicable woman, Adel.
- It's all right...
Something is gonna happen to me.
Let's go!
It's better if we wait for the car.
What's wrong, sir?
- Where are you taking the guys?
- What's wrong with taking my kids out?
Didn't he say
it was none of your business?
You're right. Sorry.
It's better if we wait for the car,
Shohdy!
One more time, we'll take a deep
breath together with our arms raised…
And the other side…
Mahi!
I need you here.
I'm sure...
I need you here,
or I'll ridicule you in front of everyone.
Okay. Carry on, please.
Do what we just did one more time.
Good morning.
- How are you, Mr. Shohdy?
- How am I?
I'll lock you up for what you've done.
Why, Mr. Shohdy?
What did I do? You'll lock me up
because I got your business booming?
My business?
Then what's this "Masoud Yoga"?
That's just a slight renovation.
Because I felt
that the name was more creative.
- And the villa?
- You went to the villa?
You mean the old people's home.
No, Mr. Shohdy,
it's not an old people's home.
It's a healing center.
- Oh!
- And, by the way,
your office is exactly as you left it.
It hasn't been touched.
I just used the rest of the space.
Thank you! Thank you very much
for leaving my office closed.
Calm down, calm down, Shohdy.
I am trying to help you.
I've been trying to calm him down
the whole journey.
And your responses are really infuriating.
Look, right now,
get those people out of the villa!
Right away. Today!
I can't do that, Mr. Shohdy.
They came through a tourism company.
If I kick them out, they'll lock me up.
And if you don't get them out,
I will lock you up!
Mahi didn't do anything wrong, Mr. Shohdy.
I mean that Mahi did what you taught us.
I taught you to scam people?
No. You taught us
to think outside of the box.
You taught us to not stop working.
You taught us that when tourism is slow,
we shouldn't take it easy.
Exactly! Exactly!
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
- What else did he teach us? I forgot.
- He taught us... He taught us...
He taught us to forgive.
And to forget yesterday.
And to think more about the days ahead.
Forgive me, Mr. Shohdy, forgive me.
- For my sake.
- Come on, Shohdy.
And, Mr. Shohdy, don't forget
that Mahi was the most beautiful...
I mean, smartest one in the company.
I used to tell the staff,
"Mahi is the smartest one of us all."
You sent her here
to get the business going.
And there!
She got the business going for you!
It's okay, Shohdy. Don't worry yourself.
It's only a matter of days,
then you'll be bidding the world farewell.
You won't be sad over a villa.
You're completely right, Sheikh.
I forgot about that issue.
Look.
If I didn't have guests with me,
I would have made a lot of trouble.
Please, finish what you're doing.
Then come and see me
so I can tell you off in peace!
Maybe.
What were you saying?
Is Shohdy dying?
You know what, Doola?
The girl has gotten really pretty.
She wasn't like that at all.
I guess being by the sea and doing yoga
do very nice things for your figure.
That's all you're good at.
Let's see what we're going to ride.
Come, son, come.
- What's going on? It's you again?
- Your servant, Hudhud, from Asyut.
Weren't you on the tricycle a minute ago?
When I finish my shift at the supermarket,
I do safari trips.
You want to come with me?
- Go, go.
- Where?
- Take us.
- Where to?
Where we came from!
Why didn't you call me?
Give me the chance
to put things in order before he arrived?
- You weren't exactly answering my calls.
- Mostafa, are you still...
The past is over!
Not the past, I'm talking about today.
I called many times. Your phone was off.
My phone is broken,
and I will pick it up tonight.
Just my luck.
What brought you here?
What brought me here?
Coincidence. I went to get some papers
from him in Cairo, and he said,
"Mostafa, you're a good guy.
Come with me to Soma Bay."
I told him, "I can't. I have work."
He said, "You have to be with me
by my side for everything that happens."
I said, "All right, I'll come, then."
Wow, looks like you've really progressed.
You've also really rounded out...
I mean, really progressed.
I mean, the yoga and this Masoud Bay.
Anyway, I need to get back to my class.
So, see you later.
All right, I'll wait for you
in the villa tonight.
When you come for Shohdy
to tell you off, like you agreed.
Didn't you agree…
- Bye, Mostafa.
- Bye.
- One second.
- One second, one second.
Is there something wrong?
Of course, I wasn't expecting us
to all be sleeping together in one room.
And especially not in this room.
So, right from the start, let's be nice.
I don't want any teasing.
Teasing?
Rats are nothing to be ashamed of.
Exactly. You're a lifelong friend.
There's enough space for everyone.
Go in. Don't worry, go in.
Shohdy, I don't want you to get worked up.
You're a sick man who's dying.
An office is an office.
Isn't there a sofa?
- It's an office. Of course there's a sofa.
- Okay then.
- Come on!
- Please, come in.
Come in.
What are these disgusting things, Shohdy?
- Are you a sadist?
- I knew the teasing would begin.
Go ahead.
Did you want to say something too? Say it.
No, I promised you I wouldn't tease you.
I'll just laugh.
- Shohda.
- Yes?
Do you enjoy being tied up?
It's not me that gets tied up, Hussein.
- Then who?
- Nobody gets tied up, Hussein.
It's just decoration,
a vibe, atmosphere, ambience.
Ambience!
Shohdy, is this also "ambience"?
No, Azaizy, they hold on to that
for the road bumps.
Like on the metro.
Forgive me, brother Adel.
The last time I saw something like this
was in those German films
that guy would translate for us, remember?
The "Oh, yeah" ones.
That's all you can manage? "Oh, yeah."
German films. Get off that pole!
- Fine.
- You know how much that pole costs?
That's enough about the poles, Shohdy.
We want to see how we're going to sleep.
I'll tell you how.
This chair turns into a sofa.
Very nice! This chair is mine.
Sorry, Adel.
I'm not used to sleeping next to anyone.
You guys can tumble around on there
and sleep as you please.
But this chair is for me.
Oh, yeah, Shohdy.
I had one like this at home.
It had a nail so that it wouldn't close.
Yeah, you're right.
It has a nail so it doesn't close.
- Where is it?
- Look for it.
- Where's the nail?
Hello. What's this?
God forgive me.
What is this room, Mr. Shohdy?
Is she looking at hell?
Mostafa, I swear to God,
if anybody at work finds out
about this room, especially that pole,
I won't fire you, I will lock you up.
- Understood?
- Don't worry, Mr. Shohdy. Don't worry.
What exactly do you do in here?
Are you filming "50 Shades of Shohdy"?
Guys, where are we going to sleep?
I'm dozing off.
- I'm going to sleep on that sofa.
- That sofa is mine.
It's obvious you haven't taken me
into account for the sleeping.
Fine. I'll take this cover
and go find somewhere downstairs.
Boy!
- Come here!
- What's wrong?
- That's rude.
Are you old enough to joke around with me?
I'm sorry.
Put the cover back.
So rude.
If you ask, you can have anything.
- Okay, can I ask if I can take the cover?
- No.
Azaizy.
Straighten out your head
so you can sleep properly.
The nail, Shohdy.
The nail for the bed, Shohdy.
- You want the nail?
- Yeah.
Give me your hand. I'll give you the nail.
My back, Adel. My back.
Give me your other hand
so I can give you the other nail.
- Here's the other nail.
- Thank you.
- Put the two nails next to each other.
- Is that the nail?
Yes, sleep, my dear.
Thank you, Adel.
Nail... Thank you, Adel.
Where should I sleep?
What's this?
Say a prayer, Hajj!
What are you doing?
You! Have I become
an old person's punching bag?
Hi. How are you?
What is he doing?
Thank you.
Goodbye.
Mostafa?
- Mostafa.
- Mahi.
- Sorry. I didn't see you.
- Hi.
- How are you?
- Fine.
Have a seat.
What, has Shohdy gone to sleep?
They've all gone to sleep.
Are you still upset?
I was upset until I saw you.
What? I'm talking about Shohdy.
Yeah, Shohdy's still upset.
You've been exposed!
Don't worry. Come over in the morning,
tell him a few words. He'll let it go.
Yeah, I'll do that.
To be honest, I wanted to thank you
for what you said this morning.
You're worth it.
No, really, you're a great guy.
Not that word, please.
The last time you used that word,
you later accepted an offer to come here.
You said, "Sorry, Mostafa.
I want to build my future first."
And I haven't seen you since.
- You still remember?
- Remember?
I can't really remember.
That was around four years ago?
- No, it was last year.
- What?
Oh, yeah. You're right.
I was then promoted
to Shohdy's right-hand man.
It was last year, indeed.
You came for Shohdy, right?
Go home and come back tomorrow.
What is this apathy, son?
Yeah.
Okay.
- Can I ask you something before I go?
- Ask.
Did you really come here by chance
because you can't leave Shohdy?
Or…
What would I leave work and come here for?
Okay, bye.
Bye.
Because you're an idiot.
Idiot, idiot.
And what's this?
What? Have you not slept yet?
- Who can sleep with these mosquitoes?
- Yeah.
You could have gone for a walk with
what's-her-name who was just with you.
What? Could you see me?
Yeah. To be honest, I could hear you.
Did you hear everything?
- You're rude.
- Very.
You were a complete Goliath.
- Mr. Adel.
- I swear.
Didn't you come for her?
Why are you pushing her away?
Because she's getting on my nerves,
Mr. Adel!
She knows I want her, that I came for her.
She's playing games with me.
You saw and heard everything.
I'm trying to get her.
Get her? You're an idiot!
- I'm leaving.
- Sit down, boy!
They are all like that, Mostafa.
They want someone
who makes them feel loved.
Who can't live without them.
Yes.
If she agrees to be with me,
I'll make her feel that way all the time.
Why aren't you with her?
Because her hair goes reddish brown
in the sun.
What's wrong, Mr. Adel? Pay attention!
She's not with me
because I'm not her priority.
She doesn't see me at all.
She's put me in her Plan B,
after her work and her future.
- I'm C.
- You're actually an F.
- "F"?
- Yes. It's your fault, Mostafa.
You're the one
who has to show yourself to her.
If she doesn't mind, in principle,
then you keep trying again and again.
You won't lose anything, silly.
You're right. I won't lose anything.
Right. Go rest inside
because of the mosquitoes.
Tell me everything. I'm by your side.
- Can I sleep in your spot?
- Upstairs? No, are you crazy?
Upstairs is for adults only.
Find a sofa downstairs to pass out on.
Sofa?
Hurry up! Hurry up!
What's this?
Have you not jumped yet?
What patience…
You have the right…
Can I know what jerk did this to me?
What kind of prank is that, Shohdy?
Shohdy? It has nothing to do with me.
He probably walks in his sleep
and does strange things.
Stop joking around and uncuff me.
I want to go to the bathroom.
Why don't you go to the bathroom
like that?
Shohdy, I swear to God, I'll beat you up.
You're handcuffed, son.
- Okay, give me a kiss and I'll uncuff you.
- Give him one.
Where do you want me to kiss you?
Let me think about it.
I'll get back to you.
Shohdy, pull yourself together!
Isn't the chair you made me
sleep on enough? My back is destroyed.
Because you're selfish, and you
latched on to it as soon as you walked in.
And it turned out to give the worst sleep!
Okay. Enough joking around, please.
Where's the nail for the chair?
I told you I don't know where the nail is!
And I told you from the minute we arrived
that I haven't been here for ages!
- Good morning, Mr. Shohdy.
- Hi, Mahi.
Is this Mahi who tricked you and
turned your villa and office upside down?
She's pretty.
You see?
You made some lowly boatman ridicule me!
Do you like that?
Shohdy, don't take it seriously.
She's a stranger. It's rude.
Good morning.
I introduce myself to you.
Captain Hana Al Azaizy.
- Hello.
- What's going on?
- What?
You mean this?
No, nothing. My arm was in a cast,
and then I took it off.
But I found myself feeling very tired.
I went to the doctor, and he prescribed
these for me. They really help.
Can you uncuff me?
I came over last night,
but Mostafa told me you had gone to sleep.
Where is Mostafa, anyway?
Of course, you have to ask about Mostafa
so he can defend you.
But you made a mistake
and must be punished.
Okay, can I have a word with you
on the side?
Of course, dear. Go ahead.
I won't uncuff you, then. Stop it.
Go ahead.
- Mahi, you must know that what you did...
- Please, before you say anything…
Here you go.
- What's this?
- $15,467.
- For what?
- Your percentage from the business.
I considered you a partner, so that's 50%.
Mahi, do you know how much I pay
to fill up my car?
You probably don't even know yourself.
You go to the gas station
and tell them to fill it up, that's it.
- Right?
- Right.
- So, do you forgive me?
Okay.
But you weren't like this at all.
If I knew staying here would've made you
like this, I'd have come a long time ago.
Made me what?
Smart.
Come on.
Come and have breakfast with us, Mahi.
Thank you, Mr. Shohdy,
but my yoga class starts in an hour.
- So I better get going.
- All right, then.
Could you please get my boat ready?
I want to take these kids out tomorrow.
- Tomorrow?
- Yeah.
Mahi, did you sell the boat?
Of course not!
No, Mr. Shohdy,
I could never do that to you. It's just…
that the Swedish group
are coming back with the boat on the 20th.
After that, it's yours!
It is mine!
- What will I do with you?
- I'm sorry!
What will I do with you, you disaster!
I won't do it again.
Okay, get us a boat ready.
The best boat for the best, Mr. Shohdy!
Go on, go…
How sweet.
Wow.
Mahi seems nice and good-natured.
Azaizy, she's your daughter
who is Sarah's age, right?
No, Sarah is much older.
- Have you seen, Selim, Sarah's son?
- No.
He's around her age.
Guys, where's Hussein?
We're gonna be late.
What for? Are they taking the sea away?
What's this?
Hi, guys. Let's go.
I'm going on holiday!
Adel, come.
No, I don't want to. You go.
Shohdy!
Mahi.
- Good morning.
What's going on?
Did you come to tell me good morning, or…
And what are you wearing, Mostafa?
Since when do you dress like this?
I'm always used to seeing you in a suit.
This is Mostafa's cool outfit.
Did you just come to show me your outfit,
or were you going to say something?
What outfit, Mahi?
First of all, I came to say that I…
lied to you yesterday.
I didn't come here by chance.
As soon as I got the opportunity
to see you again,
I couldn't stop myself.
I left everything and came.
And then, as soon as I saw you,
I forgot all the sadness,
and everything you did to me.
And I told myself,
"God can turn things around."
Why don't we open up
the topic of "us" again and reconsider?
And, to be honest,
I came to tell you that…
I haven't forgotten, even though I tried.
I really tried, but…
I couldn't forget you.
And specifically,
when you left the company.
It would come to me sometimes.
Not always, but sometimes…
"Why don't you go?"
And I would start thinking…
You know, take... I'm going!
No, wait.
Keep going. Finish those two words
you were saying.
Two words?
I wasn't planning on saying all this!
I thought when you saw me in this, you'd
take me in your arms and that'd be it.
How about
we have dinner together, tonight?
I'll calm down, put my thoughts together,
and we can talk in peace.
I'm afraid I can't.
I'm leaving.
- Wait.
- I already prepared myself.
I'm not shocked or anything.
- Can you wait?
- You're all the same!
Wait!
Listen!
Tonight, I'm working. I have work tonight.
So, tomorrow would work?
Yes, tomorrow works.
Okay, great.
But it will be lunch and dinner.
Lunch is on me, dinner's on you.
No, sorry, that won't do.
Call me old-fashioned, backwards.
I don't care.
Lunch is on me, dinner's on you.
Dinner! What, am I gonna pay for a yogurt?
Okay, bye.
- Wow!
How I long for a date,
but the palm tree is too tall…
Oh, mother.
Play with me!
No, I have to be at the meeting.
Don't stare. Otherwise,
that guy she's with will notice.
Look as though
you're gazing out at the sea,
and then peek
out of the corner of your eyes.
Good idea.
Like this?
- Is that the corner of your eye?
- I'm not wearing sunglasses like you guys.
Question.
Are girls that pretty
because of makeup or because of clothes?
So, if your wife wore the same clothes
and the same makeup,
would she look like that?
She'd get shouted at!
No, no.
It's a must.
What a scumbag. He left the girl.
Heartless guy.
What a failure.
He left her
to someone who would appreciate her.
Calm down, Wizwiz.
- What's this crazy guy gonna do?
- What do you think? He's gonna get her.
How is he gonna get her
with that double chin of his?
I'll bet you 800 pounds
that she'll shout at him.
Why not make it 1000?
That's a lot, Doola. He's not worth it.
And back to the matches of the past!
The big player who is back from abroad
is approaching!
This is the phase in which
he tries to suss her out.
Today's match is amazing.
The rocket is in front of him.
He has the ball. He passed the test!
The rocket took the ball from him
and smiled!
He is getting closer!
She is getting closer!
Where are those 1000 pounds?
First of all, it was 800.
- Second, I'm requesting VAR.
- You have the right to.
How is it going, you cosmopolitan?
Can I play the next game?
No way!
By the way, I'm Shohdy's friend.
- We're one and the same.
- What are you doing?
- I'm playing.
- With who? Do you know them?
- What are you looking at?
- The match.
- Because it's really hot.
- It's on fire.
What's hot and on fire?
Are you messing around?
Wait a minute. You should watch
how you're speaking
and who you're speaking with.
Who are you? You look like
you couldn't take a fight.
Fight with who? Are you out of your mind?
Or are you looking to show off
your muscles?
You better wake up and get it together,
or you won't like what's coming.
Take your hands off me
so I don't push you.
Don't take your t-shirt off, Adel,
I beg you.
What's going on?
Where is the manager of this place?
He took her and left.
What do you need the manager for?
I'll be his sponsor.
Calm down. What are you going to do?
He's trying to scare us
with his muscles, Hussein!
I've been training in boxing
since before you were born!
Don't overdo it, Adel.
Your words don't match your body.
- It's not about the body, Shohdy.
- Then what is it about, Doola?
- Come on, Azaizy.
- Check it out.
That guy is bringing some heavyweights
and coming towards us.
It's gonna be trouble.
What do you say, Doodoo?
Shall we carry on?
No, I'll leave him to learn his lesson
another way.
- Shall we go?
- Let's go…
Come here, Grandpa!
Where is the nail for this sofa, Shohdy?
My neck is going to break!
Hold tight, I've sent for some painkillers
from the pharmacy.
That's enough with all these noises.
Azouz, you've given us a headache.
What's the problem, Shohdy?
The man is in pain.
Why can't you just pull yourself together?
This is unbelievable!
And, you, hurry the pharmacy up.
Let's get this over with!
Wait. I'm getting the number of a dealer
who apparently has some really good stuff.
What are you? Satan?
Alcohol by day and weed by night!
And then there's the girls!
I hope you feel better, Zizo.
The medicine is here! Nobody move.
I'll do everything from here on out.
I will sweep, mop and cook.
But you stay resting because of your neck.
You didn't tell me,
did you want a boy or a girl?
Do you think I'm pregnant?
Go, go!
- It's over between us now!
- Go.
I hope he feels better, sir.
Hudhud?
Are you a driver or working in a pharmacy?
What's your deal?
I'm full of skills but out of luck.
What matters
is that you earn your living with honor.
Wow, Hudhud. An example for the youth.
Mostafa, bring the painkiller!
Coming! I'll give him the painkiller,
then pay you.
- Do you know the guy who sells sweets?
- He is my darling!
Hurry up.
Good news, I hope.
Hello, who is this?
Selim Al Nohly gave me your number
and said that you have good stuff.
Yes, sir. Where should I come to you?
- Do you know Masoud House?
- Of course I do, I'm in it!
- What do you mean "in it"?
- I'm here now.
Sir Shohdy!
You're a dealer too, Hudhud?
And in my house? I'll lock you up!
Why, Sir Shohdy? I'm your darling.
- Show me what you've got.
- Of course.
No, Adel, the cream you put on stings.
And the painkiller isn't doing anything.
- Take it off, Adel. I can't handle it.
- Azaizy, you only took the painkiller.
So it hasn't had the chance to work yet.
And this cream is magical…
I'm sorry, Azaizy.
- What's up, Adel?
- I messed up.
I bought a cream for hernias,
not for sprains.
They're both the same color.
You've given me a hernia after the sprain!
You guys stay.
I'm tired. I'm gonna go back.
- Why are you tired, Azaizy? What's up?
- I can't.
I brought you here
so I could give you a fun excursion.
- And here we are.
- No, I don't want to.
Fine, that's up to you.
Hi, Shohdy!
Oh, dear.
Go on, Azaizy. Leave.
What do you mean "leave"?
There's no going back. No surrender.
Take this.
- Come.
- Oh, dear.
Come on, you boatman. You scumbag.
- Come on. Don't be scared.
- I'm not scared of the yacht.
Welcome to Mermaid Yacht!
What are you doing here, Hudhud?
I'm the captain of the yacht.
Are you the only driver in this place?
Whoever has God on his side
can do anything!
- Come on, Adel.
- No, I'm not coming with you.
Don't give me a hard time. I'm not coming.
I'm going to stay in the villa.
- Fine, I'll stay with you.
- You guys go and have fun with...
- You have fun.
- Adel, enough of this mother's talk.
"You guys go and have fun and play
while I prepare your lunch."
Let's go.
Fine, I'm staying with you, I'm not going.
Bye, Shohdy!
Oh, boy… did you see that, Adel?
Why don't you loosen up, Adel?
- I'm loose.
- No, you're not loose, Adel.
This isn't the Adel we know.
The Adel we know would have had us
getting into hijinks on a trip like this
and made us stay up all night.
Adel, may God bless Abeer's soul.
She was sick, and now she is at peace.
And you should thank God
that it came on gradually
and wasn't a surprise.
Thank God. May God bless her soul.
God bless. May God bless her
and have mercy on her.
But you, how long will you stay
like this, my friend?
- Until I go up to her.
- Dear God!
What's up, Adel? What have I been saying
since this morning?
Adel, do you remember when my father died,
and I shut myself away?
And I left work
and everything went downhill for me?
You're the one who came and told me,
"Shohdy, you can't do this.
There are so many things to live for."
Everything I'm telling you now
is exactly what you told me. Remember?
This isn't you, Adool.
We can't take more misery.
I tell you what, Adel.
Don't be upset with me for asking.
Would you think about marrying again?
No, that won't work anymore.
- You can't get married anymore?
- No, no.
No, it's not what you think.
- You mean you can't get married at all?
- Well, not "at all."
Then I'll tell you "Rest in peace."
Get up.
Come on. Let's find something to eat.
I don't know what to feed you.
- Feed me some trotters and I'll show you.
- No, the mood is ruined now.
- It's ruined? Completely ruined?
- Completely!
I also want to develop the safari tours.
So it's not just barbecues
and beach buggies
and people sitting around a fire.
I feel there are better ideas.
- There should be more revamping.
- Yeah.
Enough about work, Mahi.
Why have you become
so enthusiastic all of a sudden?
Will you spend the rest of your life here?
Maybe. I haven't really thought about it.
I guess it didn't get through to you.
I'll explain.
Do you think you might find a decent man
that would relieve you
from all this work and let you stay home?
We'll see
when that decent man comes along!
He's come all this way,
and you're giving him a tough time!
All right, all right.
Where have you been, Mostafa?
I've been looking for you
since this morning.
- I'm here, Mr. Shohdy.
- What do you mean?
Are you here on holiday?
- What's happened, Mr. Shohdy?
- Never mind "what happened" and "Mr.".
This won't do.
You kept insisting on coming with me,
so we said two days would be fine.
But we can't both stay away
from the company.
Who is gonna get the work done?
Go ahead, now,
and sort out the price list
for our trips to Luxor and Aswan.
Send them to Rana, the secretary.
- Okay?
- Yes.
Okay. I'll call you tonight.
Mr. Shohdy, we were actually talking
- about the development of the company.
- I'm not worried about anything
or the development of the company.
I feel very reassured.
By the way, this yacht is very small.
I'm not used to being the captain
of such a small yacht.
I captain large boats.
And I've been all around Europe.
I've been to Malta, Greece, Cyprus.
I've been to every street, alley and path
in Europe.
By boat!
Good. That's an advantage.
But you're gorgeous, gorgeous!
Go easy.
Girls aren't good for your blood sugar.
What do you want? Let me have some fun.
Don't ruin the day, son.
The day will be wonderful.
What's this? I haven't had the chance to…
What's this?
What happened, Captain?
The boat stopped.
I think it's out of gas.
Didn't you fill it up before we left?
Of course! I filled it up
according to the itinerary of the trip.
And you've been going
round in circles for six hours!
You didn't give the boat a rest
or park it anywhere.
Why didn't you say
we needed to rest it for a bit?
Because some things are felt, not spoken.
And every time I came to speak to you,
you ignored me.
What does this mean?
It means
you are dinner for the fishes tonight.
You're going to die here tonight!
Wait!
Dear God!
I'm having a panic attack.
Help me!
If I get an attack and start dying,
then give me CPR!
Don't worry.
I'll call somebody to rescue us.
- My phone has no network.
- There's no signal out at sea.
I have a signal.
Just to let you know I'm special.
Hussein, I'll call Adel. Don't worry.
Adel's phone is switched off.
Call Shohdy.
No! I'd rather die than call that jerk!
- Hi, Shohdy!
- Shohdy!
You should have let Hudhud be the captain.
You're a disgrace to boatmen!
I could have come back swimming.
I just didn't want to leave
Hussein and these poor girls.
You're being arrogant, too?
You know what?
I won't give you the tank of gas
until you apologize.
I swear to God, I'll make this boat
run on sugarcane juice
before I apologize to a jerk like you!
Guys, stop these childish antics!
- This is unbelievable.
- You can see, Adel.
Azaizy, tell him "I'm sorry"!
Let's get this over with!
Okay.
I know how to make him come.
Say something to him, girls.
- Please, Shohdy!
- Please!
Ouch, he's hitting me
right where it hurts.
He says he captains boats.
He can barely cross
the canal in Mariouteya.
Stop. I don't like the coals too hot.
Mariouteya and the canal.
That's enough, you joker.
Guys, it's really hot up here.
Hussein, stop being so stupid, please.
Haven't you heard people say,
"What is this heat? Are we in a sauna?"
- This is the sauna, Hussein.
- Really?
I thought a sauna was a hot country,
like Aswan.
There is actually a country called sauna.
Sauna Land. But this isn't it.
I made this sauna in the house,
specifically so we can smoke
this fake cigarette
in this stuffy room and get really high.
- Zizo, light it up.
- Zizo?
I'm not into these games.
I'm better than that.
- Here, take it.
- You tough guy!
Take it, Hussein.
If he takes a puff,
he'll be completely knocked out.
Shohdy, if you want to smoke that,
smoke it yourself. We're not into that.
Speak for yourself!
You know what? You guys are no fun at all.
I won't have any either then.
Here it goes.
Guys?
I have a big problem.
I can't breathe or move my arm.
That's the benefit of the sauna, Hussein.
It opens up the pores
and completely loosens you up.
See how loose I am?
Loose…
Zizo, are you going cross-eyed?
Oh, God…
It's an app I found on my phone
that I make videos on.
It drives me nuts. It drives me nuts.
Why don't you show us, Azaizy?
- No, no, no.
- Please, show us.
For my sake.
Show me!
I'm the one who discovered it.
Don't say that you already know about it.
What's this?
Mostafa, when was the last time
you danced?
I dance all the time!
I was dancing two days ago for Mr. Shohdy.
- You were dancing for Mr. Shohdy?
- Yeah, so he could sign papers for me.
He made you dance for him
to sign something?
You've never danced
so he'd sign papers for you?
- Of course not!
- He told me the whole company does that.
He's a sick man!
Okay, okay.
Let me show you some new dance moves.
So next time, you can dazzle him!
Come on!
Mahi, why don't you think about
coming back to Cairo with me?
I don't like to think when I'm dancing.
You don't want me to quit dancing, right?
Did I ask you to quit medicine?
I'm being serious.
I want a serious answer from you now.
I don't want to feel
suspended in the air, Mahi.
Don't be mad, but I feel like
you're not thinking about the subject.
- Who said I'm not thinking about it?
- Are you being serious?
- What have you decided?
- I haven't made a decision. I'm thinking.
And I told you before,
this decision isn't easy for me.
I have to consider things.
Mahi, you don't have to sit down
and calculate everything.
There are some things that you just feel.
Who told you I don't feel anything?
Really? How do you feel?
Tell me what you're feeling.
- I feel, I feel...
- Just tell me.
I feel that I'm happy.
- You swear that you're happy?
- Yes, I feel happy.
Okay, hang on. This could go somewhere
really nice that I hadn't planned for.
Do you feel happy in general,
or when you think about this topic?
When I think about
this topic specifically, I feel happy.
- Really?
- Yes!
Why didn't you tell me?
Come on. Let's celebrate happiness!
Come on, then.
Mostafa! Mostafa!
Nice one, Azouz!
May all be well.
- Sorry, Sahsah.
- I'm gonna have a cigarette.
Since when?
One while I'm on holiday.
Guys, I feel like we're too old
for all this silliness.
What do you mean, "too old"?
You know what?
This trip has proven to me
that we are still little kids.
Yeah.
- I want to get your opinion on something.
- Talk.
I'm thinking of getting engaged.
- Stop being silly.
- Is marriage silly?
Why are you looking to get married
when you're about to die?
A couple of days of pleasure.
Besides, you guys lived your lives
and got married and had fun.
You yourself used to always tell me,
"Think about marriage, Shohdy."
Remember?
And maybe when I get married,
I'll have fun?
Being happy is not guaranteed.
Why are you saying that?
What happened with Sherine, Hana?
The strange thing is
nothing is happening.
It's silence, Adel.
It's like there's no dialogue left.
We have nothing to talk about.
What silence? You don't stop talking here.
You're right.
That's what's driving me crazy.
I can't seem to solve it.
I never meant to do that to her.
Maybe,
there's just nothing left to talk about.
Maybe I got bored of her,
especially after the kids
grew up and left home.
I don't know.
It requires effort, Azaizy.
You have to think the way she thinks.
Look at things from her point of view.
What questions does she ask you
that upset you?
The same questions.
"Where are you taking me out to tonight?"
"What would you like to eat tonight?"
Let's just go wherever!
Let's eat whatever!
It's been the same questions for 30 years!
You're a fool.
When she asks you
where you should go out tonight,
she wants to take you
somewhere you'll enjoy.
But when you tell her "anywhere,"
you make her feel like
going out is pointless.
Like she's not important to you.
Take care of her, Azaizy.
Answer her questions.
Let her feel her worth.
By the way,
she doesn't care about your response.
She cares about your interest.
It really makes a difference to them.
God bless you, Adel.
My problem isn't with silence.
What bothers me is the noise.
"Dad, the fridge is empty."
"Dad, the plumber."
"Dad, pass by the dry cleaners."
"Dad, won't you get me some Eid clothes?"
"Dad, Eid money. Dad!"
The kids treat me like…
I'm a Visa card.
An ATM…
Something that buys things for them.
That's it.
You know…
today,
today is my birthday.
It's fine.
Nobody called me
to wish me a happy birthday.
They do that to me every time.
I swear!
Even when they remember me…
they'll bring me a white cake
because they're the ones who like it.
I like chocolate cake.
Happy birthday, you jerk!
How old are you, Sahsah?
Sixty.
You're really old.
I'll have to call you Uncle.
Sixty years old?
You're about 30 years older than us.
- How did we become his friend?
- I don't get it.
Hussein,
I am going to make you
the biggest birthday party
you have ever seen.
Happy birthday, my dear!
Thank you. Thank you all!
I don't know what to say to you
or how to thank you.
- Just say thank you, no big deal.
- Thank you, no big deal.
Okay, hero, make a wish.
There's no better wish
than to live with my wife and kids.
May God give them strength and health
and a hard time like they give me!
You are annoying!
- You ruined my surprise!
- What surprise?
We miss you, Hussein!
The house is awful without you.
It has no feeling or taste.
I went to renew my passport.
Send someone to bring me over to you!
We really miss you, Dad.
We wish you were here
so we could celebrate like every year.
But we're happy that you're happy
and having a change of scenery.
Happy Birthday, father-in-law.
Happy birthday, Mr. Hussein. Beware,
you'll have another one when you're back!
What's wrong? It was made by the person
who put your birthday together.
What person?
When we talk to you,
do you just blabber nonsense?
Hussein, did you understand
what Boudy said to you?
Since when have I ever understood him?
He said "Don't forget to bring me a bike
on the way back."
The bike, of course.
Wait a minute, the phone's ringing.
What bike? Don't annoy me!
Boudy, tell me your mother
about your answer machine telescope…
Mahi, I need you for something.
Come over here.
How are you doing?
How is it going with her?
She's still giving me a hard time.
But the latest is that she said
she's happy and is still thinking.
Very good! If she said she's happy
and is still thinking, then we're close!
Yeah, we are. But he should stay away.
What does he have to do with you?
He's all talk. I'll deal with him.
Don't you worry.
Hi, Sherine. How are you?
I found this funny,
so I thought I'd send it to you.
I miss you.
I want to tell you something else.
Don't ever be upset with me.
I love you.
I love you, I love you, I love you!
I love you!
You know what, Mahi?
I'm very happy
that you managed to settle here
and adapt to this place.
I have decided to live here.
Live here how, Mr. Shohdy?
Move here.
I'll live at Masoud Center.
"Unlimited Containment."
But after you tidy it up, of course.
Mahi.
I want you to tidy up the villa for me.
Furnish it, arrange it all to your taste.
And we'll be next to each other!
What do you think?
I think this is a great idea, of course.
You being here
will help us develop the business.
Mahi!
The thing I noticed most about you
is that you're smart.
Given that you're smart,
then you understand and I understand.
And I understand
that you're not one for messing around.
That's why I'm talking seriously.
Let's get close.
Let's stay together.
And don't worry about the business at all.
Wherever I am living,
my business will be there by my side.
What do you think?
That's if you agree, of course.
- It's very hard...
- No, don't answer now.
Take your time.
I'll go to the toilet and come back,
and you'll have thought about it.
I think that's plenty of time
to be able to make a decision, right?
Have you thought?
Thought? About what?
Our topic?
What? I beg you, Mostafa,
this is not a good time.
Can we talk about this tomorrow?
Not tomorrow. Not the day after. Now.
Now, Mahi, please.
If you want an answer,
I honestly don't know!
Mostafa, can you leave?
Leave me some time to think.
Fine, Mahi. Don't stress yourself out.
I also don't want to stress myself out.
I get it.
You told me
you wanted to pursue your career first
and then see about marriage.
It's clear
that you saw both things as one.
I don't mean anything bad.
That's smart of you. Well done.
I used to always say,
"Mahi is the smartest one of us all."
Mostafa, why aren't you dancing?
- I have a headache.
- Headache?
Go to my villa, go into my bedroom.
You'll find a great pill for headaches
in the drawer of the bedside table.
Take one.
It'll will make you feel much better.
I'll do that.
Either way, the party is dull.
I hope you feel better.
Mostafa, where are you going?
- I'm going back to Cairo.
- Why?
Did Shohdy throw more work at you?
I've quit working for Shohdy.
I can't look him in the face again.
Sorry, Mr. Adel.
But your friend is a selfish man.
What would you like to drink?
Excuse me, Mahi.
I'd like to have a few words with Shohdy.
You're happy like this, right?
Yeah, I'm very happy.
Aren't you happy, Adel?
What you're doing isn't right, Shohdy.
I don't know why you insist on taking
something that doesn't belong to you.
What is it that's not mine?
- Mahi.
- Yeah, yeah.
We'll talk tomorrow then.
Leave me tonight.
No, I won't leave you, Shohdy.
Because you seem completely wasted!
What?
Do you think
she's one of those ladies that you know?
You date her for two months,
then dump her?
No, Shohdy. This girl is different.
Bravo!
It's because this girl is different,
that's why I want to marry her.
Don't I have the right to get married?
Of course you do.
But you know,
you're aware that Mostafa loves her.
What does that have to do with me?
If he likes her or not, he can get lost!
Did I force her?
- Yes, Shohdy, you forced her.
- No!
You want to mislead her,
dazzle her with your money and position.
And you know exactly how ambitious
this girl is and what she wants!
But what I don't understand is,
what are you trying to prove?
Are you trying to prove
that you're such a devil
you can get a girl your children's age?
What do you want out of life, anyway?
I don't want to die alone, Adel.
I want to have a home, Adel.
I want to have a bed.
So that when I'm away from it
for two days, I miss it.
Adel, do you think that when I…
get to know a different girl every day
that it makes me happy?
No.
I get to know a different girl every day
for companionship.
I'm scared of dying alone, Adel.
I'm scared that I'll die,
and you won't know about it
until my body starts smelling.
I think I have the right
to have people that take care of me
and will keep remembering me
like you remember Abeer.
Don't you think
that would be better, Adel?
Rather than having them go to
Hamdiyah Shazliya to have a cup of coffee,
lick their lips,
and say God bless his soul.
Have you understood what I want, Adel?
You're right, Shohdy.
You're right.
I was the first one
to tell you to get married.
But not this one, Shohdy.
She's not the one for you, my friend.
What do you mean, "not this one"?
Are we in the supermarket?
Where we can walk and choose as we please?
Shohdy, the world won't stand still
over one person.
Well, what is this?
Are you the one saying that the world
won't stand still over one person?
When all that's happening here is for you!
To bring you back to life
after what happened to you with Abeer.
Please, Shohdy.
Don't talk about Abeer when you're drunk!
Because I don't like what you're saying.
I don't want to lose you as a friend.
- We'll talk later!
- No, Adel!
I don't want to talk at all!
And whoever doesn't like it
can bang their head against the wall!
- Don't talk like that, Shohdy.
- Have some respect, Adel.
Adel, what's wrong?
Take note of what you're saying.
- Come with me.
- Stop it, Azaizy.
He's talking badly to me.
Are you drunk?
Is everyone gonna keep asking me
if I'm drunk? I'm not drunk!
- You'll get everyone on our case now!
- That's enough, Azaizy!
What's wrong?
Ouch…
What is this foolishness, you moron?
- We're sorry. It wasn't his fault.
- Wait. It's you again?
If you guys can't handle your alcohol,
why get drunk?
Come on. The man's not feeling well.
It wasn't his fault!
- If you can't handle it, don't get drunk!
- Dude!
Move!
Dude!
- Shohdy!
- Here you go!
- Come here!
- Shohdy!
Adel! Ambulance!
Adel, Shohdy isn't well! Shohdy!
Ambulance!
Your phone, Hussein.
We want to check up on Shohdy.
Hussein, your phone!
I must have dropped it during the fight…
How are you, Adel?
I know that your phone is switched off.
Which is why I sent you this message.
So you can listen to it whenever you want.
I just wish you picked up.
So I could tell you how happy I am.
And that I was happy with you
my whole life.
What did you do today?
Even though
I know what you're going to say.
You'll tell me, "What is there
to do in life without you here?"
There are many things in life, Adel.
There are friends and relatives.
And all the people around you
who love you.
Who always want to see you happy.
There are the happy moments,
and the wild ones
that are priceless.
All these things,
I want you to live them.
So when you come to me in heaven,
and I ask you what you did,
you won't tell me, "I didn't do anything."
Oh, yes. Adel,
don't ride the Harley without a helmet.
But not my pink helmet.
Take care of yourself, my love.
I love you so much.
Goodbye, my love.
Azaizy.
Shohdy!
- Are you okay?
- I'm fine, thank God.
Go to hell!
What's going on, Azaizy? Are you crying?
Call me Hana, since I'm crying.
Take care of yourself, Shohdy.
We're not young anymore.
It's all up to God, Azaizy.
God bless.
- Azaizy.
- Yes, my dear.
I want to confess something to you.
But I don't want it
to affect our relationship.
Take this, Azaizy.
Keep this with you and take care of it.
This is the nail for the sofa.
You had it all along?
You let me sleep on the sofa
and break my back and neck?
Hold it. Don't be embarrassed.
What should I write in the report?
Should I write that two 60-year-olds
beat up five burly men?
- It's not about age, sir.
- Or body.
It's obvious
that it's not about age or body, father.
Sir, there was a slight misunderstanding
that will hopefully be resolved.
But one of our friends is in the hospital.
And we want to go check up on him.
What's he doing in the hospital?
It must be the fight.
No, sir. A heart attack.
There you go. These are the illnesses
that suit your age.
Okay. I suggest that you do
a reconciliation report.
No, sir! We want them
to spend the night in jail.
You see, sir! He's starts it each time!
- I'm itchy, son. What's wrong?
- Leave him be.
As you like.
But that's not to your benefit.
You see what this guy looks like?
What are they gonna say?
That two old people... Pardon me...
Beat you up and wiped the floor with you?
How will you walk around the place?
How will you take pictures in the gym?
It's ruined.
- Right?
- Yes.
Shohdy, my dear. You missed it!
You missed your brother Hussein
beating all those kids up!
How about Adel?
He gave those kids a proper thrashing!
A real boxer!
Not to that extent, Hussein.
We don't want to exaggerate.
Such confidence! Oh, Adoola.
How are you doing, Mr. Shohdy?
Feeling better?
Much better, Mahi.
He's a monkey, as you can see.
- What could possibly happen to him?
- Have some respect.
He was just crying his eyes out
in front of me. Should I tell them?
He was crying, saying,
"I'm nothing without you, Shohdy."
"Call me Hana."
The nurse is called Hana.
I don't know why he's crying.
It's only a matter of time
before he'll have to say goodbye anyway.
No, Adel, we…
played a prank on you.
I'm not going to die.
I mean, I'm not dying.
Who are you playing a prank on, you fools?
I figured you out
the minute you came to see me.
But I thought I would come with you.
Or hide, and use you to keep me warm.
Who am I gonna find besides you guys
that'll put up with my sadness
and take my worries away?
Who asks for mangoes
when their friend is dying?
What?
I was furious, guys.
- Hello.
- Hi.
I'm sorry you're not well, Mr. Shohdy.
I ran over when I heard what happened.
You're a good guy, Mostafa.
- Are you okay?
- I'm fine, Mostafa. Much better.
Now that you've checked on him,
why don't you let him rest for a bit?
Yeah, get going. Let me rest.
Mahi, I need you. Don't go.
I hope you feel better, Shohdy.
- I hope you get better, Shohdy.
- Thanks, Hussein.
If you need anything, we're by your side.
Go ahead.
Mahi,
in the pocket of this jacket is a box.
Get it for me, please.
Open it.
Hussein.
Does Shohdy have hemorrhoids?
From a long time ago.
That's a shame.
I really wanted to do something for him.
We all wanted to do something for him.
Congratulations, Mostafa.
Thank you, Mr. Shohdy.
Thank you very much, Mr. Shohdy.
Thank you for this huge gift.
It's true. There was no need for it.
It's too much!
What are you thanking me for?
It's nothing.
It will be deducted from your salary.
What do you mean? I won't pay this off
even if I worked for my entire life.
- It's fine, Mostafa.
- Take it off. We don't accept gifts.
Deduct it from my salary, Mr. Shohdy.
It's no problem.
That's fine, then.
Why are you looking at me like that?
She's going to wear it. Why my salary?
You're a very sweet couple.
What a disgrace!
Before I let you go,
I have a quick question.
Does that silver thing over there
belong to the bride or the groom?
She's my uncle's wife.
- Your uncle's wife…
- May God bless his soul.
May God bless his soul?
You should have said!
- This is very delightful!
- Mr. Shohdy!
- Just leave him. He won't come back.
The last hotel I stayed at served pasta
for breakfast, lunch and dinner.
- Even Saleh, my assistant...
- You told me this story before.
You don't like it when I'm quiet
or when I talk?
No. I like you when you're talking
and when you're quiet.
But you can only talk
when I tell you to talk.
Can I talk now?
No.
They're lovely!
- Hussein.
- Yes?
Why don't we get up and dance like them?
Have some respect! Don't say that.
Why? Am I not desirable?
Just clap. Desirable?
Of course you're desirable, my love.
I meant, dancing here is by appointment.
We'd have to have come two days earlier
and dance to the right
and left of the bride.
And then choose the position we like.
Did you know
Hussein wanted to bring his cousins too?
What's up? What did I miss?
- Where have you been?
- I was getting the surprise ready.
- Have you done it?
- Of course.
I'm going to make this wedding light up!
You'll see! Look!
Subtitle translation by: Nadia McKinney