A STANGER IN TOWN
SUPREME COURT BUILDING
Washington, D.C.
The Honorable Court is now adjourned
until Thursday the 10th day
of December at 12 o'clock
Good afternoon.
The fruit to under
spare all right but
the left real one is
causing me great anxiety.
Switched minor well getting of the year
out there I should be very disappointed.
You know, that grandson of
mine is most unusual infant.
At 5 weeks he holds up
his head without support.
Yeah, I'll show you snapshot.
Goodbye Grant, have a good vacation.
Happy holiday Josephus.
-  Thank you gentlemen. Thank you.
Mr. justice.
- Well?
If we have a word with you
justice Grant, just a few questions?
I stopped answering questions,
when court recessed
about three minutes ago.
What do you know man...
- Comin, comin. -  Here at all.
Well gentlemen?
-  Justice Grant
We understand you declined to
preside at the Danville investigation.
There's some speculation
as to your reasons.
Well, believe me I had long hard
year I'm tired, I'm going hunting.
Miss Gilbert, would you
put this in my bag, please.
bBecause that referred
to you last week
is a terrible
temper justice Grant.
How do you feel
about that? - I'm flattered.
And this tomb miss Gibert.
-  Where are you going for your hanting?
Well there are plenty
of docs, and nowhere reporters.
When you are leaving?
-  A moment after you do.
Good day, sir.
Miss Gilbert, what is this nonsense
What does this resignation mean?
I think it's obvious, sir.
-  if it were obvious I wouldn't
ask the question, would I?
Justis Grant, I've been
with you for two years.
And no time you aspect
satisfaction with my work.
Miss Gilbert, you can learn
more law here in a week
than you can anywhere else in a year,
and that's all that should interest you.
I don't feel that
I have to constantly
remind you that you're
a brilliant young woman
and that you have a fine future.
Now if there isn't
anything else, can I go?
Oh, you wanted to look over
the Hill and Try an opinion, sir,
they won't be back for
the premature till next week.
Oh, yes they'll need some revision.
But I don't want
to hang around here.
Perhaps I can bring a
ot to you it can process, sir? (?)
That'd be fine. No, no, no,
you need a vacation too.
From me.
- I don't mind it at all.
Miss Gilbert are you
heaping coals of fire on my head?
I wouldn't dream of it, sir.
Oh I'll wire you
before I come. - Thank you.
Miss Gilbert. - Yes, sir? - No one
must know I'm going. No one.
I want to get away
from courtrooms... investigations,
lawyers... black robes everything.
Everything bath ducks.
Hundreds and hundreds
of beautiful ducks.
Gvik, gvik, gvik, gvik
gvik. gvik, gvik, gvik, gvik.
Hey, you!
Wait a minute.
I'm Orrin Todds. Game
inspector. Let's see your license.
yeah just like I thought
Stranger in town, ain't you?
Ths license ain't legal.
Well, I just bought it
yesterday at the state capital.
Yeah I know mister.
But this is Crown port.
You got to have
acomport stamp on there.
Well I didn't know that.
I'll get one tomorrow.
Are they ain't going
to do you any good today?
No I could haul you into court and
let the judge slide we'll fine on you.
But say wear and
tear on my tires for
the cell you one right
here it only cost you five bucks.
You know the five bucks
is just for the stamp.
I usually get a little
something to my trouble, too..
Well, you don't understand
I'm giving you a break, brother.
Yeah, I never pay off
twice brother. Come on.
Look, let me explain it to you.
Your Honor it's not as though
my client we're trying to evade
his financial oblation.
Tom Cooney is a member of
this community for many years.
And all that time his honesty and his
responsibility has never been questioned.
now he intends to make good
the payments on these flowers,
but he's been sick
unable to work.
Now if the court could
just grant him an extension.
The law doesn't
recognize good intentions.
I shouldn't have to remind
you of that, mr. Adams,
you're supposed
to be a lawyer.
But your honor am I not... am I
not justified in asking the court's
indulgence in this case?
If you take Tom Cooney
spawn tools away from him,
you take away his only
means of earning a living.
Mr. Adams this is a court of
law, not an employment agency.
Tom Cooney signed
an agreement with
Vincent Blaxton of the Crown
port auto and supplies company
This agreement stated if he
missed a payment on those plows,
Mr. Blaxton could
take them back.
Is that right mr. Cooney?
- Well, yes Your honor but...
All right, judgment
concelor against Thomas Cooney.
But it... it was just one payment.
If you give me a chance to...
I don't care whether
you say is fair or not.
It ain't!
- Get him out of here.
Come on Tom, this isn't gonna help.
- I know it's not gonna help.
Nothing's going to help in town
like this. - Officer. - Come on.
Let go on me.
- Come on. Looks like you
just lost yourself
another vote cellar.
I know ain't right.
- Come on. I know ain't right.
Crown Court versus Joe
Grant. Step up Joe Grant.
Name?
- Joe Grant.
Shooting ducks
without a Crown port permit.
I didn't get a chance to shoot.
- You were going to.
Of course I'm going to, you fool.
I so I bought a state license.
We also require a Crown
port license mr. Grant
An ignorance of the law is no excuse.
100 $ or 30 days.
Which one of you
gentleman do I pay? - The clerk.
Should have bought it for me in the
first place, save yourself a lot of the bill.
I assume that this
100 $ will permit me
to resume my hunting
without further interference?
Your assumption is wrong.
You still need a Crown port stamp.
And an officer enforcing the
law is not interference, mr. Grant.
As a judge I advise you
to be careful of your words.
Next case.
Crown port vs. Burton
Line. Step up Burton Line.
Hi, Tom.
I'm sorry it turned
out that way.
Yes, that's the only
way twitter turned out.
No I thought we had a chance
but I guess you should it know.
What you gonna do no?
- Arms no good to me
without the tools to work.
Quess I lose it. Bank will start
yelling for its money pretty soon.
No Bill. Sometimes it just
morning man can stand.
I got things something to do.  If I
can only... Yah, I know Tom. I know.
But, why don't you come
by the office later on
we'll talk about it, huh?
Hello, boys.
Shave, Boomer.
Right here poor
Tom Cooney lost his case.
Yeah, he'll probably
lose his farm now, too.
It's a shame, c, c, c, c.
You know Homer that's wha I like
about the fellas around your shop?
They enjoy the good things of life.
a guy who can't meet his mortgage,
or poor farmer geting dawn hs plaws.
Say had a Cooney real shot, Roy.
Maybe banker to extend
an honest man land credit,
or a judge' to give him a break
Talk like that isn't going to
get you any votes, Adams.
I can afford 50 cents
a guard to get yours.
Just the shave.
-  Sure, mr. Strange in tawn?
Aim just stay long?
- Long enough to get a shave.
Great little town, isn't it old timer?
Yeah, judge Harkley really
gave you a welcome didn't he?
And our constable Orrin
Todds that's... that's Homers cousin.
He's all law and order regular
minute man isn't he, Homer?
Uh, how many minutes did it take
before he tried to shake you dawn?
That's a shame. Ever notice how a
fella who can't make a living in a town
always tries to run it down
you know mr... Grand isn't?
- Yeah. -  Mr. Grant,
might be fun to bust up one
of the constables little rackets.
How about being a guinea pig
et me turn this into a test case.
Mr. Lane case save list
Jason wouldn't take it.
Was two bucks to
vote in it for him.
How you are boys?
- Hou you mr. mayor?
Out there is very much of
weight home were? - It will, mr. mayor.
Hello there my worthy opponent.
I'm sorry about Tom Cooney I
hope he doesn't go to pieces over this.
he's really got something
good this is always.
You know, it's a funny thing about
some fellas are unaware your firm
everything goes wrong for.
-  Hiya Tom, you looking for me?
I'll be ready in a minute.
- Yeah, mr. mayor...
if there's anything I can
a little ready cash or something...
I don't want charity...
-  I can't change the law, Tom.
You the mayor.
-  but I'm not a nursemaid to
every man in town
who can't take care of himself.
Alright Tomy that's
enough. Now beat it.
Keep your hands of him.
-  Let him alone, Blaxton.
Oh.  - No, no,
this is all my fault.
I wish you hadn't had to do that funny
- he said coming to him for a long time.
Our boy is turning
into an awful radical.
You could sell that for the speech
he made accept the nomination.
let's kind of talk is never
going to make a miracle, boy.
It's too bad. Nothing I like better
than to see some bright young fella
came along who would take my place.
But Bill Adams? -  Take a man
to feel your she was mr. mayor.
Darrell dropped in this morning.
He said to give us regards.
What's my Bill?
- Just a shame? - Yeah.
50 cents
Hey mr. , bill is 50
cents, not a quarter.
Guess she made
a mistake, friend.
No, you made the mistake... friend.
you pick the wrong
customer that time limit.
This fella ten years every
sip the better on me
WAY NOT TRY
BILL ADAMS
MAYOR
BILL ADAMS FOR MAYOR
CAMPAIGN HEADGQUARERS
Come on in old timer.
- thank you.
Well going stood
in boats? -  yeah.
That's a rather interesting
model. Sees the Columbia.
A square rigged for master.
Nice work. -  Oh,
and here's a nice one.
This is a parking team.
Form a square rigged the other
mass for an average, rather unusual.
For sail?
- Oh, no, no, no, no.
No, they're not that good
it's only a hobby, just just for fun.
I see you're running for mayor. - Yeah.
- Sort of a hobby too just for fun?
No, not quite.
mayor Connison, you
saw him in the barber shop...
he and his boys been running
this town for a long time.
Make it pretty tough for anybody comes
up against them. - Yes I get it as much.
A lot of people been getting
tired of it. I have much time myself...
the Army's going to grab
me in a couple of months,
but I thought I might at
least get the ball rolling
and for once give them a fight.
-  but not too much of a fight.
Something you want
to see me about mr. Grant?
In the barber shop mr. Adams
you mentioned the fact that you
might like to make a test case of my fine .
Yes, yes I think
you've got a case. - You do.
How would you go about it ?
Well, we... - lost the law requires
a stamp. I didn't have one.
no no but I think I
could work out an appeal.
An appeal? On what
grounds? Was the fine illegal?
Oh, no, no. They had
a right to fine you.
the fact that I was
unfamiliar with the law.
Well, that's no
excuse obviously. - Obviously.
Then what would you base
your appeal on mr. Adams?
The fact that it's Tuesday
and the sun is shining?
Look, I haven't had much
time to give it thought.
But I can figure out an angle there
must be one lying around somewhat.
Oh, yes I'm sure there is.
In the meanwhile you can
always make a living as a carpenter.
Hiya, Bill. Oh, you're
busy? - No Charlie, come on in.
Mr. Grant, Charlie Craig
my campaign manager.
How you do, sir?
- Hi.
Any new votes Charlie?
- Enough to fill a dog's ear.
Say I just heard about Tom
Cooney. - Yeah, he's taking it pretty hard.
I'm the same kind of
note he did so it don't look,
so good for that
tractor mine either.
you couldn't get me a couple
of weeks performance could you?
I'll try charlie
but there's no use,
of peeling the black stone over
the way he's got his business set up
his hopping on my tail wouldn't
burn me if I hadn't had so much
trouble with that tractor.
every time I needed a spare
part I had to send for myself
Blaxton never carried him in stop.
- Did Blaxton promise you such service,
No, there's nothing in the
contract about providing service.
Has Blaxton lived up to all his
legal obligations a seller of the tractor?
No, sir. You sound like a
lawyer yourself mr. Grant.
Yes, well, I was
about 20 years ago.
well maybe you could
give Bill here ponder it to.
Anyway I'm glad to met you.
Be seeing you mr. mayor.
I'm going out and see if I can
educate a few votes for you.
Well, mr. Grant since you'll
have some knowledge of the law,
you probably decided there's
nothing much I can do for you.
Well, what about Craig, what
are you going to do about him?
What can I do for him?
With Hartley on the bench?
You saw what
happened to Tom Cooney.
You can't blame
that on judge Hartley.
You went into that courtroom without
a defense, that's why you got whipped.
Well, and I guess to get
whipped again. - I guess you will.
You're not much of a
fighter, are you mr. Adams?
Except in the barber
shop brawls. - Oh, stop it.
You can't fight brass
knuckles with spitballs.
The trick in this town is either
to play the game their way,
and I haven't the
stomach for that,
or to be as smart as they are.
- The trick mr. Adams is to be smarter.
What does that wind up your
business? Are you going to stay
and give me the first private lessons
how to win friends, and influence judges?
No mr. Adams, I'm not.
Those lessons have been
written and very well written in
books like this,
and all the others.
And somewhere in one of
them, there's a lesson mentioning
that in any transaction
between a seller and a buyer
there are laws governing
the behavior of both parties.
But I doubt if you can keep
afloat long enough to find it.
You know mr. Adams I've seen
you in action now as a lawyer
as a candidate for
mayor and as a shipbuilder.
And if you'll take my advice
you will stick to shipbuilding.
There's a great
future in it for lawyers.
Excuse me, sir, for breaking
in like this, but I think I found it.
Yes, yes that covers it.
You've said you haven't
practiced law for 20 years
imagine remembering
a thing like that.
Have you had dinner mr.
Adams? - No thanks, not hungry.
I... I think this will
cover it. It should work but...
I've been batted down
by those guys so often,
I quess I haven't
to much cofidence.
How long have you lived
in Crown port mr. Adams?
For 28 years with time out
for colleagues in law school.
Never established
residents in any other state?
No.
- Are you sure in that?
Well, of course.
Oh,  we... we went to Mexico for a
few months when I was seven, but...
Did you file an income tax
returns on 1939 and 40?
Well, sure.
I didn't pay anything in 1940. I
didn't earn enough, but I filed a return.
And your figures were honest,
correct and would their investigation.
What? Well of well course they were.
- Oh, you getting nervous mr. Adams.
I'm not nervous, I'm really... - Ah,
yes, yes, you are you flustered
you're raising your voice
Why shouldn't I raise my voice
you must God has accused
me of falsifying my income taxes.
I've accused you
of nothing mr. Adams.
Now look I don't know
what you have on there,
but I want to tell you...
- Take a look.
It's... it's an old trick that
Justice Brandeis used to play.
I read about it
in Colliers once.
You see, it's an
unfortunate fact mr. Adams
that every man, even
you and I, has done something,
that he doesn't want
anybody to know about.
Now you can make him think
that you're holding in your hand
the skeleton in his
closet.. - You've got it.
Well let's say at least you've got him
squirming... nervous... worried as you were,
but if that man happens to
have a really guilty conscience.
your full name is
Vincent Lee Braxton? - Yes.
Tell me mr. Braxton,
what does the Z stand for?
Do I have to answer
that, Your honor?
What can be your objection,
surely you have nothing to hide.
Well, the Z...  well,
Z stands for Zeffir.
It's a family name.
Zeffir? Means a
little wind I believe.
Quiet.
Mr. Braxton, you're the owner and manager
of the Crown for Taran company? - Yes.
The sole owner?
- Well, sure of course.
No silent partners?
- No. Well of course... (?)
Then, you're
not the sole owner.
I didn't say
that I just say...
You sound very
strange to me mr. Blaxton.
You don't know whether you
own your own business. - I object.
That question is irrelevant, immaterial,
and calculated to confuse the witness.
Objection sustained.
Counselor will restrict himself
to the facts very on this case.
Mr. Braxton... the company sells most of
the used cars and tractors in this town.
Almost a monopoly, isn't it?
-  I do the most business
because I sell my
stuck at lowest prises.
that's not monopoly. That's...
that's the American
Way of life.
Tell me mr. Braxton...
carry spare parts for
your customers? - Sure.
You have in stock at
this moment piston rings for
Well mr. Braxton?
- Well, no. I don't.
Oh then you don't carry all the spare
parts your customers might need.
Well, I can always get
them if they need them.
Yes, but sometimes your customers
have to wait. - Sure, it takes two weeks.
If I ain't got them,
how can they have them?
The intelligent engine mr.
Braxton, and an honest one.
one which will require the court to
enter judgment against you in this case.
Will counselor explain that
statement. - Certainly,  Your honor.
Motor vehicle laws nineteen
nineteen chapter 174 section 52.
The sale of any automobile
or any other automotive vehicle
is void unless the dealer
carries in stock at all times,
and on demand parts that may be
needed to repair particulary vehicle.
Will you let me
see that reference?
Counselor would
seem to be correct.
You put it over, Bill. Say
will take your Tom cloony too. (?)
You're telling me.
Oh, mr. Grant.
Sorry, I thought
you were going hunting.
All the ducks are inside today. I
see you winged a couple yourself.
Oh it's nothing really big.
Who am I kidding. I'm so tickled
I feel like a combination of Superman
and a member of
the Supreme court.
and really I... I don't know
how to thank you, mister Grant.
Oh, no need to my boy. First time
I've enjoyed a courtroom in here.
Hey. Thank you
You know what this stuff is?
- No mr. Grant, he wouldn't.
William this is American money.
Good old fold of money.
You know what you can do with this
stuff? You can buy things that you need.
You get it? - And what
I don't get is, where you got it?
For Z and bikes and get tram warm some
arts and unloosen a couple of purse strings.
The boys have kicked
in for your campaign fund.
You know what we're going
to do with this beautiful stuff?
we're going to get some
posters printed great, big ones.
They kind of look you're right
straight in the eye and call you around
Why get frightened so Adams
does win one rotten little case.
Do you know what that case
cost me? - You can afford it.
you'd scream like a
stuck pig. - Stop it, stop it.
Seriously Jim, you don't see
Adams it's really competition.
Whoa, staying a Stan now no,
but if a lot of people start thinking of
Bill Adams as the people's champion.
Well... - Jim there was
nothing else I could do.
I can give you boys the edge
when it's a question of interpretation.
but not when the laws like
they're in black and white.
Oh, I'm not blaming you, judges.
Just something to start
thinking about, that's all.
You think we'll have trouble?
Well, now look boys.
On second thought, we may be
getting all steamed up for nothing.
Yeah, but suppose he opens a
lot of old cases like Tom Cooney's.
I think you've got
something there Zeffir.
We'll just have to show
the boy that is wrong.
MISS LUCY GILBERT
SUPREME COURT BUILDING WASHINGTON
YOU WILL SE MET AT STATION...
SEE YOU LATER AT HOTEL
PLEASE REMEMBER
I' AM DUCK HUNTER
RETIRED LAWYER AND THATS ALL
JOE GRANT
Miss Gilbert?
-  No.
- Yeah?
That's better.
That's much better.
I'm Bill Adams, mr.
Grant asked me to meet you.
Yes I know. - Let me
take that. The cars over here.
Is it... you think we should
try to scoop some of that up?
No, I guess not.
Huh, well...
everything seems
to be under control.
Would it be all right with you if we
went to your car now? - The car?
Oh, no. No, yes right here.
Sorry to get off to such a bad
start. I'm not always so clumsy
Oh! My hat!
Don't worry we'll... we'l get it.
How long have you
worked for mr. Grant?
Two years. - A credit
character, isn't it?
Quite. -  You know, I
was very surprised,
when he told me his
secretary was coming dow.
I had an idea the
old boy was retired.
The old boy is ... retired.
Where is he now, mr. Adams?
He went over to well bridge
this morning do some hunting.
He oughta be back soon.
What's going to drive
you around the town but...
I guess you want
to get cleaned up now.
Yes, I think I will. -  I'll
take you straight to the hotel.
BILL ADAMS FOR MAYOR
IT'S UP TO YOU
A NEW BROOM SWEEPS CLEAN
You are raning
for mayor? - Mm-hmm
Surprised? - That's putting
it very mildly, mr. Adams.
Won't make the most of it lady
because that's likely to be the only
surprise you'll get in this tawn.
Who's the girl with
Adams? - Don't know.
What difference does it make?
I'd like a room,
please buy the day.
No baggage? - Which is...
- yeah. - I don't register
women without
baggage in my hotel.
Henry, show this lady out.
-  But you don't understand.
Yes, I do.
- Why you...
Please, mr. Adams,
let me explain.
I am honest.. - Beat it.
- Take your hands off her.
Oh, yeah?
Nice work, pal.
I tell you you can't do this.
Look facts my face, mister.
Come on, officer.
Hey, officer.
Hey, sergeant!
Sergeant, I want
to use that phone.
Will you please keep
quiet, Your honor.
Just trying to get us
out of here, you know?
Why don't you think
of that before you got a... (?)
Look I'm very sorry this
happened, but it isn't my fault.
I suppose I started the fight.
You sure did all
right once it got going.
Ho, ho, ho, what a
gal, and what a wallop.
Yeah miss G. you're
really some scrapper.
Say Roscoe Swade asked
me to call you a judge,
we've got Bill Adams in here
with a dame salt and battery.
How long do you
want us to hold him here?
Oh, just let them
stew for a while, sergeant.
Adams will probably
want to get in touch with me.
And... oh, he does, huh?
Well, I'm out of town.
You can't reach me anywhere.
That's right.
Overnight.
Will you have a chef prepare a couple
of these for tomorrow night's dinner.
And I'll have my key, please.
What... what room
did you put miss Gilbert?
Gilbert. Gilbert. There's
no miss Gilbert registered.
Well, that's... - Anything
wrong mr. Grant?
Why yes, I was expecting
my secretary today.
Mr. Adams went to met her.
Your secretary?
-  Yeah, miss... miss Gilbert,
miss Lucy Gilbert have
you heard from? - No.
No. Not exactly, well that is she
was here, but... - Where is she?
Well mr. Grant, you see,
we had a little trouble.
Where is she? - She's
with Adams in the county jail.
Well you get them out
of there and fast. - Yes, sir.
Yes, sir, right away. Buddy
get me judge Hockley, quick.
Yes, sir.
Good evening mr. Grant.
- Well, good evening miss Gilbert.
I'm sorry I couldn't
meet you at the station.
So I'm I, sir.
However, mr. Adam seems
to have made your introduction
to Crown board quite spectacular.
Well it amuses you both.
-  Of course it was quite forvoa.
Ha, ha, ha, I'm sorry.
Sit down, miss Gilbert.
You, uh... seemed tired.
What... what happened?
- Well when I said the boys were...
we're playing with brass
knuckles I wasn't kidding.
Look, I win a case from Blackston,
that makes a good
impression around town,
so I walk into Swade's hotel,
Rosco says something provokes a fight,
and I land in jail that's the
way Crown courts run mr. Grant.
I hope the fact that as Gilbert
was involved won't upset you.
The fact that miss Gilbert was
involved upsets me a great deal.
It strikes me that Swade
Carlson and company are...
just been a little too high-handed
- Well, you can't fight the city halter.
As candidate for mayor
that's what you're doing, isn't it?
Well I suppose I am, but employees
are starting to play rough.
Well of course if they play too rough
you can always go back
to your ship building.
Yes, I guess I could.
But right now I'm
going to go home,
get some sleep miss Gilbert and
I have a date in court tomorrow.
Good night miss Gilbert.
Don't hold me against
comport. Good night, sir.
You know perhaps
you'd like to go over them.
I gather somehow that you're
not very much drawn mr. Adams
My personal reactions to
him aren't important, sir.
Well I wouldn't be too hasty.
He attacked too much trouble.
He certainly does. His
whole approach is wrong.
He shuts his eyes
and waves in and slugs.
But he has good stuff.
Do you think it wise to get
involved with his problem?
After all, you are
on your vacation.
Oh, I'm not involved I'm
just trying to give the boy a push.
Come in.
May Iturn your bed down, sir.
- Oh, yes, yes, certainly.
Good night mr. Grant.
- Good night.
Oh.
- Pardom mua.
Good night, miss Gibert.
Kind of skimpy, isn't it? - They
just ain't long enough, none of them.
I keep it telling mr. Swade.
Well, thy have to do it.
Good night, sir. Hope
you rest well. - Thank you.
THE MAN WHO WON'T SELL
THE PEOPLE SHORT
JIM CONNSON
Wrong number. - Mr. Adams
wake up. This is mr. Grant.
What? Wait a minute.
Yeah?
Want me to write?
- I said get any of your clothes
get two yard
sticks. Yard sticks.
Come right over here and
register for the night of the hotel.
I'll tell you all about it when
you get here. But get here.
Rright.
Halllo, Roscoe.
Give me a single room next mr.
Grant. - How lot? - I'll pay in advance.
What's the matter, Roscoe?
you don't seem happy to see me?
I... a have my baggage too.
Why should he sleep
here with yard sticks?
He's got a place of his own.
Hello? Get me miss
Gilbert's room, please.
What do we
started? - Shhh.
Why should he want to talk to
her in the middle of the night?
I don't know.
It's Grant.
Yes mr. Grant.
Yes, sir. Right away.
He wants a bellboy right away.
He wants to send
something to mr. Gilbert's room.
They're up to something,
I know they are.
Henry.
Take this yardstick
to miss Gilbert.
Yes, sir. Oh, mr. Swade
send with his compliments.
My compliments to
mr. Swade. I don't eat fruit.
DO NOT DISTURB
Thanks. - W... wait
a minute miss.
I got a bowl of fruit for you.
Mr. Swade send with his compliments.
My compliments to
mr. Swade, but I lost my apetit.
I couldn't see nothing.
They blacked out the room.
Number, please. (?)
She calling Grant.
Yes, miss Gilbert?
7 and a half.
Same here. And the others?
Two and a half.
- That daz it.
Maybe it's a cod.
Oh, don't worry
Roscoe. I'll be back.
Suites hotel?
Give me mr. Grants room.
Mr. Grant, you were
absolutely right. It's nine and two.
Yeah, I'll be back in a minut.
Oh I think mr. Swade it's going
to be a little sorry tomorrow
that he's bringing
those charges against us.
Good afternoon miss Gilbert, mr. Grant.
You're looking very beautiful miss Gilbert.
Really? I didn't sleep at all.
Probably nervous exhaustion,
due to the unfortunate
experience you underwent yesterday.
Ever spent any
time in jail mr. Swade?
Ever been sued for false
arrest mr. Swade? - Miss Gilbert,
I made up my mind to
drop the complaint against you.
Well, what about the complaint against
mr. Adams? He spent a few hours in jail too.
You've got nobody but yourself to
thank you started it kidding Henry.
I'll forget you hit me.
- He didn't hit you. I did.
Well I'll forget that too, but...
- But six hours in jail is something
I wont forgetting
mr. Swade. I think 5.000 $
Well I had thought of 10, but
- No, I think five is enough.
Oh don't worry mr. Swade.
I'll see that the money goes
to a good cause
I'll invest in war bond.
Court is now in session.
Judge Hartley presiding.
The case of Swade
versus Gilbert and Adams.
Judge I move you
through my complaint out.
The complaint against
miss Gilbert? - Yes. Adams too.
We settled advise himself.
How's alone?
- Yeah.
Well, case of Suede versus
Gibert and Adams dismist.
You can thank miss Gibert for getting
you off so easy. - Thank you, Lucy.
Oh Roscoe, just a minute,
Roscoe. We're not quite true yet.
As Joe said the papers
are mr. Swade.
Rosco Slade.
- what are you toking about?
I took it if I drop my suit against
you you've got yours against me.
Relax Rosco, this is another suit.
Your Honor, I find that in
the management of his hotel,
mr. Swade is in violation
of several important laws,
What are the charges? - I brought
the evidence with me, Your honor.
The hotel laws of this
state 1909 section 52.
All sheets provided in all hotels
hostelry skins or lodging houses
shall be a minimum of
nine feet in length.
7 and a half feature, Your honor.
All pillowcases shall be
a minimum of three feet.
Two and a half feet, Your honor.
There should be a minimum distance
between all twin beds of two feet.
Now, the beds in my room
with the swayed hotel
were scarcely half a
foot apart, Your honor
I couldn't bring them in
evidence but I have witnesses
who can testify
as to my veracity.
Let me see this
reference. - Certainly.
You'll be sorry for this.
You wait and see.
Will the court law
in the defendant
the threats and intimidation
are punishable by law?
Quiet mister Swade, and you
don't tell me how to run my court .
The law provides a fine
500 $. - Up for each offense.
Are you prepared to face these
charges at the present time? - Yes.
You plead guilty?
Yes.
- And pay the clerk.
Nice work, counsellor.
Half hour recess.
Well this couldn't by any
chance be a little gift for mr. Swade.
I thought we might end
our celebration in style.
What what vintage is
that miss? - California 1938.
Here, I'll do it miss.
Tell I'm an amateur
the bottle resents me.
Well, it stopped anyway.
Gil. -  To the next
pair of Crown pause.
Yes, who's learned to
use his head and law books.
Oh, to my rooting section.
I think you're on
the right track counselor.
You keep the connaissance
busy on the little things,
and they won't have
time for the bigger one.
Nieder would I.
Mm-hmm. Well I think I'd like to
do a little hunting in the morning
if you can keep your life
Kaylee quiet for one day.
Well I'll try. Lucy might keep
an eye on me, that woul'd help.
I'll be responsible for him, sir.
Starting with breakfast.
Well... - I... I think Lucy would
probably like some more coffee.
Yes, I would.
It'll just keep you awake.
- Well... - Good night.
Good night.
-  Good night, sir.
More coffee?
I suppose you're
a wonderful dancer.
Yeah.
- I'm awful. - Good.
Well magnesium cerium.
May I have a sampl? - Sure.
Hey, I'm not so
bad, am I? - You fine.
I guess the trouble is I just never
liked to dance before. - Neither did I.
You know Lucy, Crown ports
not such a bad little town,
it's got a lot of nice people.
You've just seen the worst side of it.
Like you?
- Mmhh.
Know what, I mean
Lucy is, well...
can you see yourself
living in a town like Crown port?
No pretty delegates.
Very. Practically nothing's
happened to me since I met you.
Yeah. You know no but
seriously sometimes I have home
days of peace and quiet.
Well, we've been
together for several hours,
nothing very
spectacular has happened.
Not near enough has happened.
Let's get out of here.
Sorry.
Sometimes we have old days of
peace and quiet? Good night mr. Adams.
Or that that ate
the breakfast still stand?
Morning Harry.
Well, the golems Adam.
Oh, no. Oh no. Mr. Grant said
you would look after me today.
What he says goes
easier boss, you know?
I've had breakfast
with you. - Oh, yes
but I need much more looking
after than that, much more.
What the hell?
- Wait, Bill!
Hey, I've been trying
to find you. Look.
Hey, what's going on here?
What do you think you're doing?
You're being invicted.
Here is your notice.
Come on boys, don't
take all day. - Okay, boss.
Because of the lumber I keep
around the places attracted termites.
How do you like that?
- It's fantastic.
Look Look, can't you
just wait until I call rigid
and get this thing fixed up?
- Sure you can call them,
from Wade's office, but
won't do you no good pal.
He sign the notice
himself. Okay fellas, left it.
Yeah, but... but at least
you can leave my stuff here
until I can get
another office.
Sorry. Orders.
Well, what difference
does it make to you?
Whereis a telephone?
- Over there? - Thanks.
Listen, stop reading
me the Constitution?
I'm just following orders. - All
I'm asking you to do it. Hello.
Hello. Is this the Andrews building?
Give me the superintendent, please.
Miss Gilbert. Miss Gilbert
I've been looking for you,
mr. Grant. They're evicting Bill.
Evicting Bill? Well, what's happened?
- Something about termites.
Yeah. Just drop my
things to the hotel, will you?
Now, follow me.
Who's responsible for this?
- Seems that Roscoe Swade
has a pal name Hart Ridges
happens to be my landlord, also
happens to be one Connison's boys.
Oh, so Roscoe gives heart
a call and here I am.
Don't worry though
I'll get another office.
Hello? Hello this
is William Adams.
Yes, I want to rent
an office. What?
Oh no vacancies. - Can't
we discussing this today?
Well I don't know.
- Wait! Be careful with that.
No vacancies,
at all. I see.
Not an office in
town, not even a loft.
Oh, those boys
think of everything.
Connison? Are you sure? - Who
else? Still corner for anybody else.
Who is Adams?
- You mean, mayor Adams?
I'm Bill Adams.
What do you want?
Electric company. Got
ordered to discontinue service.
Efficient, don't they? You can find
the box in the back. - Okay, thanks.
What's a minor mr. mayor?
Can't you pay your bills?
You shut your mouth.
- I'll shut yours before.
No, no, Tom no, that's
what they want us to do.
So let's not do it. - Why not use my
citting as temporary headquarters?
Oh, well, that's not
awfully nice of you,
mr. Grant, but I could't
accept. - Why not, Bill?
You not gonna let them to
put out of business, are you?
Where's Bill Adams? - Oh mr.
mayor you got a little company.
There you know I'm going to let
hey boys bring out a
couple of more chairs.
I'm Adams, what do you want?
I'm invincible to mayor thought
you might need some help.
Will you send my compliments right
back to the mayor, and telling him...
You tell me a countess and I'm staying
right where I am out on the street,
and before I'm through
I'll have him out here with me.
Ah,I bet you get so far.
- You bet I'll get us so far.
If goddess wants know what I
mean coming to come down here
and I'll try explaining
it to him personally.
Ha, ha, ha. - Ladies and
gentlman, please, please.
Just give me a few minutes
until I get my new office set up.
What, you... you mean clog
it on the streets? - Sure, why not?
Will end my shingle
on that lamppost.
They'll be here two
hours. - I know that, sir.
But this time
Connison gone too far.
He's giving me more
publicity than I ever dreamed of.
I may be here only an
hour but it'll be a good one.
I'll get you in office. Now keep out
of trouble. I'll be back in a few minutes.
Oh, that's about
right for the desk?
Oh, no I think it's the
Caddy corner. - Okay lady.
Oh, let me take those.
- Watch this.
Oh, yeah.
- Excuse me!
Who did that?
- Tom Cooney.
Come on, get him.
Wont volonters?
- Thanks, Fred.
Bill, stop it!
How is he, nurse?
- yours coming along alright.
Can we see him now? - I think
so. - You fellas wait. We wiil right on.
That'll do mr. Grant.
- Oh, thank you.
Well, where's mr. Adams?
- How you feel mr. Grant?
Better take it easy for no.
- No, no, I'm all right.
We're is miss Adams,
in my secretary?
Well he's in jail, and
she's trying to get him out.
Oh, Lucy. - Did the
doctor say if it did?
Oh yes, I'm fine. Where's Bill?
- Still in jail. I've tried everything
They're holding him
for a 15.000 $ bail.
In finding for riot.
- This is outrageous
We'll have to find
judge Hockley. - We try to.
And he couldn't
be found as usual.
You can find him
at connaissance rally
About an hour from now
out, there on the platform.
Shoot hs big maut of.
- We'll find him before then.
It's no use, mr. Grant.
It's all soda, it always do.
Yes, but they took one stitch too
many this time they always do to.
Come on.
Do you think you sai?
- I've got to get the boy out of jail.
I'm glad you feel that way, sir. -  yes,
well let's not keep judge haki waiting.
I want to talk to you that ugly. - sorry
I haven't any time to give you right now.
I'm afraid you'll
have to find time.
Say you... - Judge Harkley,
acting on my rights as a citizen,
I demand that you swear
out warrants for the arrest
of Ridges, Swade, Blaxton
and mayor Connison.
You are crazy.
On what charges?
Conspiracy abuse of
public
office inciting to riot.
I suggest that you come
to the jail with us now
and release mr. Adams
and sign those warrants.
We'll need a couple of more
warrants too for some hoodlums,
I have their names.
- You are crazy.
You can't push away into my
house in order to be around.
Do you realize I can have you
arrested for disturbing the piece?
All of you. - Aaaah.
- Let's just postpone that judge.
Ladies and gentlemen, would
you excuse us for just a minute.
Ladies and gentlemen, I have persuaded
judge Hockley to change his mind.
He has kindly consented to release your
candidate in time for the rally tonight.
I didn't know how you got it.
- Oh, that's not their say. (?)
What's the deal mr. Grant?
You know something about him?
No, on the contrary. He
knows something about me.
CONNISON FOR MAYOR
TRIED AND TRUE
Ladies and gentlemen
I mean my friend.
For a long time I've been
hoping a man would come along,
a young man because
like I always say
the future of our great country
belongs to the young folks,
who could take over and
give us old folks a chance
to sit back and
take things easy.
Well, this year
I said to myself,
Jim, maybe this Bill Adams is the fella,
but he dashed my hopes
and prayers to the ground.
I saw that he's not the
man we've been waiting for.
That is nothing but an
agitator a troublemaker
start up neighbors
against each other.
He said he'd be here tonight.
I wish he was.
I hope that when
I got up to talk,
he'd be here on
the platform with me
to debate with me the
issues so close to our hearts.
Well, Adams, if you think you're
gonna break up this rally you're crazy.
Did you let him out?
- Mr. mayor, I... uh... well,
chief Perkins here he is...
he's got a warrant for your arrest.
And for the arrest of
Blaxton, Ridges and Swade.
Take your ands f me!
- Jim, I couldn't help it.
Honestly you just
better come up along.
Attention, please, everibdy.
My friend. I never
thought he'd dare do this,
but you can see for yourselves now
to what lengths
this radical will go
to sabotage a piecefull
miting of the people.
But I am calling his bluff.
I'm going to make him bring
out witnesses to prove this.
As mayor of this town I got
a right to call a special hearing,
and I do so the issues will be clear
when you go to the polls to vote tomorrow.
We'll be sorry you
were the Scot of this.
Better remain with
us mr. Hartley.
We wouldn't want you to
prejudice the mayor's testimony.
Any place therefore.
I find seets.
That Adams birch gets lucky
ain't got a thing on the mayor. - No?
Find a seat and sit dawn.
Mr. Grant, I still don't understand.
Order. Order. This hearing
will condor
Judge Harkley, my friend,
I'm not on trial here.
Bill Adams has made
accusations against me
he's had a warrant sworn
out for my arrest
This is a hearing to show you that
he has no proof of anything he says.
But he's trying
by a cheap trick,
to win election, he can't
win by fair play. - Judge Harkley.
Mr. mayor you'll have to moderate
your tone. This is very irregular.
That was I'm very ugly.
Mr. Connison it's true that
you are not formally on trial here.
You asked for this hearing, to demanded
by what right we had you arrested.
we're here to tell
you and to accuse you,
of conspiring against men
who honestly opposed you
of inciting a riot with reckless
disregard for human safety
of abusing the office to
which you have been elected
by the people of this town,
and these accusations we
are prepared to prove.
I hate to see the whole boy
get himself involved like this.
Don't worry about
the old boy now darling.
Mr. mayor, mr. Grant has
obtained two sessions from these men
they have told mr. Grant
that acting on your orders
they started the riot this morning
in order to make
possible mr. Adams arrest.
They have sworn to
these facts.
Because of this mr. Grant was able
to demand a warrant for your arrest.
Mr. Grant swore out a
warrant from my arrest?
A man who doesn't
even live in our town.
I mentally old fool who does nothing
but shoot ducks,  and start trouble.
Jim don't say that.
- I'll say anything I please.
I demand to know who
who is this man is.
Who is this Jo Grant?
- Jim, do yourself a favor.
Don't ask that.
- It's all right, judge Hockley.
Mr. Connison, it's not Joe
Grant, it's John josephus Grant.
Where are you from Grant? - Washington
D.C. - Jim, please no more questions.
Mr. Grant... - Shut up. I'll
ask all the questions I please.
By what right, and what do you do
mr. Grant? - Mr. Connison and I am a judge.
An Associate Justice of the Supreme
Court of the United States.
Mr. Connison, you have asked by what
right I have interfered in this situation.
You still want an answer?
JusticeGrant, would you
cared of it... - No, no, no. thank you.
Bill. Bill. - Just throw some water
on him, Lucia, he will be all right.
Your honor, mayor Collison,
it's only right that you
should know why I, a stranger
become involved
in your affairs.
Believe me it's not because I
am a Justice of the Supreme Court.
It's because like
all of you here
I am a citizen of this country...
that is no little honor...
men of 40 revolutions
have died to we call citizens...
and as citizens, we carry
a burning responsibility
it means that when we
elect men to public office we...
we cannot do it as
lightly as we flip a coin.
It means that after we've elected
them we can't sit back and say...
our job is done what they
do now doesn't concern us.
That philosophy of indifference
is what the enemies of
decent government want.
If we allow them to have their
way to grow strong and vicious
then the heroic struggle which
welded thousands of lovely towns like
this into a great nation means nothing,
then we're not
citizens, we're traitors.
The great liberties
by which we live
have been bought with
blood the kind of government
we get is the kind
of government we want
government of the people by
the people and for the people,
can mean any
kind of government
it's our duty to
make it mean only one kind
uncorrupted, free United.
I believe mayor Connson
that I've answered your question.
Now as soon as court adjourns I'll
meet you back here in my chambers.
What's the matter mr.
justice? You seem nervous.
Oh, no, no, no, not at all.
How about you, mayor Adams.
Have you the ring?
The United line sir? - Well, I
autorized the past and I learning. (?)
Hello there Grant. I'm
glad to see you. - Thank you.
You're looking fine as you have
residing. - Oh best I ever had. (?)
Subtitle by suadnovic