It's as if I'm alone on a stranger planet
I have to go on living alone.
On this planet.
Alone.
3,000 yen.
But that's my engagement ring.
Then, 3,500 yen.
This happened because I depended on
somebody else for my happiness.
I'll never depend on anybody.
I won't believe in anybody.
I'm going to live alone. Alone. Alone.
Oh, no. I'm going to cry.
Come on, don't cry. Don't cry.
I'm not Ionely at all.
I'm going to live...
Alone?
You waiting for somebody?
Want to come over here?
Only if you want to.
But things taste better
if you eat with others, right?
Are you sure?
Yeah. Of course it'll be on me.
I'd be glad to.
A STRANGER OF MINE
Miyata.
Yes?
I hear you live in
a pretty cool apartment.
Uh...Well...I guess...
Do me a favor.
Let me borrow your place tomorrow.
What?
I have a date.
She's 24 and a nurse.
Oh.
Let me use your place.
Come on. Only for 3, 4 hours.
Oh.
I want to be able to say,
"You want to see a movie at my place?"
You have a DVD, don't you?
No, I don't.
- A PlayStation 2?
- No.
Oh.
Oh, well. Anyway, I beg you.
I'll buy you dinner.
Well...
Okay? I'll come over tomorrow morning.
What? In the morning?
Yeah. She's working tonight
so we're dating at noon.
Draw me a map, OK?
I'll drive there. Thanks.
6,852 yen? Seriously?
Hello?
Hello? It's me.
Oh, Kanda. What's up?
Can you come out right now?
Let's have dinner.
Now? I just came home.
Then just come as you are. I'll buy.
Nah, I'm tired.
We need to talk.
Talk? Why are you whispering?
Uh...I'm working right now.
I'm tailing someone.
Then do yourjob.
When you finish, come over. I'll cook.
It's kind of important.
Come out right now. To the usual place.
What's so important?
It's about Ayumi.
"MIYATA TAKESHI"
Hey.
Don't "Hey" me. You're late.
Oh, sorry.
Have you ordered?
What is it?
What? Oh, yeah.
What?
Ayumi's getting married.
You met her?
Yeah. I ran into her today,
and we talked a bit.
She seemed well.
- Is that all?
- Huh?
- That's it?
- Yeah.
Excuse me!
Did she say anything about her stuff?
Her stuff?
Her stuff is still at my place.
Oh. Nope.
Throw it away.
I can't do that...
She asked me to send it
to her new address.
Listen, she dumped you and left.
She can't complain about it.
Throw it all away.
And throw that pitiful soggy
hope of yours away with it.
I'm not hopeful.
Really?
Did you call that girl the other day?
What girl?
That girl we had drinks with in Shinjuku.
With short hair.
Said her dad looked like Woody Allen.
Akemi.
Yeah, Akemi. Did you call her?
No.
Why not?
I don't know her number.
Why didn't you ask her?
You liked her. You said she was nice.
Well, there was no timing.
There is no timing!
You make your own timing!
Listen, you better take
phone numbers seriously.
Whether or not you know
that 11-digit number
separates total strangers
from acquaintances.
You threw away all possibility
because you "didn't have timing."
You should be devastated.
Let's go pick up girls.
Huh?
Pick up girls.
Coffee, please!
We're not kids in college.
We're going because we're not kids.
Don't be ridiculous. We're too old.
Then how're you gonna
meet girls from now on?
Huh?
You're still hopeful about life.
"lf I live a normal life,
someday I'll meet somebody."
"A gorgeous girl will appear."
"I can't be alone
for the rest of my life."
That's you. Just like a high school kid.
Listen. I'll make this clear.
Once you're over 30,
"Destined" or "Natural" encounters
or "Start as Friends and Gradually
Fall in Love" will never happen.
There are no more proms or homecomings.
If you don't do something,
you're going to stay Ionely.
Forever. I mean it.
You should be dreading
the impending crisis.
But we've never picked up girls before.
That requires...
well, talent and technique.
No, it doesn't.
You don't need technique to meet girls.
Alone?
You waiting for somebody?
Want to come over here?
Only if you want to.
But things taste better
if you eat with others, right?
Are you sure?
Yeah. Of course it'll be on me.
I'd be glad to.
Excuse me! The menu.
Right away.
What do you want?
This is Miyata Takeshi. I'm Kanda.
I'm Kuwata Maki.
Maki. Nice to meet you.
- Hello.
- The hamburger steak here is good.
- Oh, really?
- Huh?
- Oh, yes.
- You like hamburger?
- I'm going to the toilet.
- Huh?
What's wrong?
I'm sorry. I'm fine.
- Are you finished?
- Oh, yes.
Um, do you want to order? A hamburger?
A hamburger.
- One hamburger steak set.
- Yes, right away.
- I'm sorry.
- No...
- Am I weird?
- No.
Huh?
Hello?
Where are you?
I'm...working.
Working? What about her?
Her? Do what you should.
What I should? What do you...
Look, I'm hanging up.
Good luck. It's your chance.
He's gone?
Yes. He went to work.
- At this hour?
- Yes.
I'm sorry.
He invited you over for me.
I mean...I recently... Well,
actually, about 6 months ago,
I broke up with my girlfriend.
And, well, it sort of
devastated me and...
I was pretty depressed...
He figured it would cheer me up
if I talked to a girl.
So he suddenly
struck up a conversation with you.
So, um... If you want to leave,
I understand.
Of course, the dinner's on me.
But I don't think he'll be coming back...
Where do you live?
I wonder if the train's still running?
- I don't live anywhere.
- Huh?
- Um...are you not interested in me?
- What?
Uh, sure, I'm interested in you.
I'm not very attractive, am I?
Uh...of course you're attractive.
I was engaged. Until yesterday.
I found a menthol cigarette butt.
With lipstick on it.
In his car. Not the ashtray.
It was between the
passenger seat and the door.
I found it.
Oh.
Menthol.
I wish I hadn't.
Um...do you like sweets?
I just remembered, this place has stuff
like cakes and nata de coco.
Yes. Shall we?
Yes.
Thank you... I'll have nata de coco...
Um...
You can cry, you know.
You can cry.
I'm sorry,
it's quite far from the station.
No. Um...are you sure it's not a problem?
Not at all.
In fact, I'm kind of glad.
Oh, I don't mean "glad" in a weird way.
You can sleep at my place
instead of a hotel.
Oh, by "sleep" I mean,
just sleep, sleep and stay over...
- Do you understand?
- Yes.
Yes. I'm alone, anyway...
Sometimes, that guy Kanda
drops by, but that's it.
- It's nice having a guest.
- Yes.
Oh, I don't do things
like this all the time.
Spending the night
with a man I just met...
- Oh, yes.
- Yes.
Um...do you want a ride?
It's still some ways off.
Oh, then I'll drive.
Mr. Miyata, please get on.
- No, no.
- Please, please.
- I'm not sure...
- It's all right.
- Please.
- Well...
Hold on.
- Excuse me.
- Let's go!
- I'll drive.
- No. You're letting me stay...
And you bought me dinner...Oh!
I'll kill you!
"HANDYMAN YAMA-CHAN"
I'm sorry.
Uh, no... Are you OK?
- Let's walk.
- Yes.
- That was scary.
- Yes. I'm sorry.
It's all right.
- Please.
- Thank you.
Slippers, slippers.
Um, I don't have slippers.
That's no problem.
Excuse me.
Please use this room.
Yes, thank you.
- Do you have things to wear?
- Oh, yes.
- I'll sleep in the other room
- Oh, I see.
Will you take a bath?
Yes. I'm sorry.
No...
Um...I'm really sorry...
This room is empty, anyway.
I mean, my old girlfriend...
Ayumi.
Yes.
We actually only lived
together for a week.
She left right after I bought this place.
Why?
Hmm?
Why did she leave?
She suddenly told me
she loved somebody else.
I hear she's getting married to that guy.
That's terrible.
Well...she couldn't help it.
She couldn't help it?
Yes, probably.
It's a matter of feelings.
We didn't sign a contract.
Do you still love her?
Yes, I do.
Anyway, please feel free to use this room.
You can think about...
I'm sorry.
No, it's all right.
I'll go get the bath ready.
Yes.
Um...Which bath salt do you want?
"Smooth Skin Beppu Spa" or "Hakone Spa"?
Excuse me.
I'm sorry. I know it's late.
How've you been?
- Can I come in?
- What? Now?
My stuff is still here. I came to get it.
Does it have to be now?
Yes. Not everything.
I just want to get what I need.
I'm sorry.
Oh, I'm really sorry.
I'll go right away.
Don't you think you're a bit selfish?
You betrayed him
and left without your stuff,
and now you're back go get it?
Do you only think of yourself?
Think about other people's feelings.
It's none of your business.
- I'll go now.
- What?
Thank you for everything.
Where are you going?
I'm sorry.
When you find what you need, leave.
I'll throw the rest away.
Good-bye.
You don't have anywhere
to go at this hour.
I'll stay in a hotel, so I'm fine.
But...
I think...
that I really shouldn't spend the night
with someone I just met.
And...I don't think she
just came to get her things.
What?
I mean, coming for
her stuff at this hour?
It's not natural.
She probably wants to talk to you.
Talk to me?
Maybe she came back.
That's what I think.
That can't be...
"That can't be true?" I don't think so.
Because a nice man like you...
I don't think is easy to forget.
Please just go home now.
You still love her, don't you?
No, I don't
But you said so before.
I loved her before, but I don't anymore.
Don't go.
Can it be anybody?
If you think she'll be yours,
you'll fall in love with anybody?
We just met.
You know nothing about me.
It's not right.
Thank you for today.
Watch out!
Your phone...
Give me your phone number.
My phone number?
Please.
I might never see you again...
for the rest of my life...
So please give me your phone number.
Since we did meet.
We just met.
I know nothing about you.
But I want to see you again.
Am I weird?
Give him your number.
Uh...Can I lie down?
Sure.
Your contract still has some days left over.
What will you do?
Oh, god...
"KANDA YUSUKE"
Hi, there.
Hi.
"KANDA DETECTIVE AGENCY"
Please?
I'll take black.
Oh, you want some, too?
No, forget it.
Is Miyata doing okay?
You want to know?
Sure.
Liar.
He bought that castle of an apartment,
so he's not doing great. The loan...
I developed them, but I can't give
them to him. He's devastated.
But compared to the others,
I suppose he's doing better.
What do you mean?
I checked up on you.
Because I heard you vanished.
I checked up on you
to discover where you were.
You were suspicious from the start.
I was curious about you.
I knew it.
You suspected me from the beginning.
You're 33 years old.
You were older than him.
5 years is a lot to subtract.
Why did you go after Miyata?
There are lots of rich
old men out there, aren't there?
Not really.
The police are after you.
But you didn't take any
money from Miyata. Why?
The deposit for the apartment...
He bought that damn
apartment with his savings.
So you kissed him good-bye.
And I know you were
a detective. I was wary.
So, what are you going to do?
What?
You know everything about me.
You knew where I was.
That's the problem.
I don't mess with yakuza...
Asai Shinobu...He's the boss, right?
I don't meddle with a mafia boss's woman.
So, why are you here?
I need help.
Ask Mr. Asai to help you.
I ran away from him.
I didn't know he was a yakuza.
He told me he ran a company.
He deceived me.
I always had a bad feeling...
If you mess around with yakuza,
you won't live long.
I'm not messing around.
That's why I'm here.
Help me escape.
Why should I...
I want to go overseas.
But my passport's still at Miyata's place.
You can get it, can't you?
I'll pay you well.
When did you run away?
Today. I came straight here.
You didn't know where I lived.
How'd you find out?
I had your card. You didn't answer
my call so I came directly.
"KANDA YUSUKE, DETECTIVE"
- You called...from your cellular?
- Yeah.
Give it to me. I'll erase the record.
I don't have it.
What?
Well, it was his cellular.
If I have it, he'd call me.
He's not home yet.
So you're helping me?
Why do you think I let you in?
If you caused any trouble,
you'd involve Miyata.
He knows nothing about you.
You didn't tell him?
Of course not.
He's depressed enough as it is.
- Oh.
- "Oh?"
I don't want you causing trouble
and becoming headline news.
I don't want to see him hurt anymore.
- 1,000,000 yen.
- What?
I'll help you escape for 1,000,000 yen.
Okay.
You idiot, don't touch this money!
Why not?
- You're giving it back.
- Huh?
You think the mafia will let anyone
get away with its money?
They'll come after you with a vengeance.
What'll happen then?
They'll do a betterjob than the cops.
You'll never get away.
You're gonna return that money.
Then, you have a chance.
Looking for somebody is pretty expensive.
If they get that back,
they might let you go.
No.
Look, you don't have a choice.
I could just turn you in,
or call Asai right now.
You're rolling in money.
I know which banks you have accounts in.
1,000,000 yen isn't so bad.
All right.
OK. Let's go.
What?
Your passport. I have a spare key.
Come on.
Now you tell me.
- You idiot!
- Ow!
Hide your shoes.
- I haven't taken them off.
- Hurry up!
I need the light.
You should change.
You're too conspicuous.
What? No way. That outfit's so dull.
- Miyata gave you that.
- Yeah.
Found it.
Hey.
In exchange for the 1,000,000 yen.
Change. I'm going to the toilet.
6,852 yen? Seriously?
Hello?
Hello? It's me.
Oh, Kanda. What's up?
Can you come out right now?
Let's have dinner.
Now? I just came home.
Then just come as you are. I'll buy.
Nah, I'm tired.
We need to talk.
Talk? Why are you whispering?
Uh...I'm working right now.
I'm tailing someone.
Then do yourjob.
When you finish, come over. I'll cook.
It's kind of important.
Come out right now. To the usual place.
What's so important?
It's about Ayumi.
You feel like coming out now?
I have work to do, so come right now.
Hey!
Hurry up and change.
I told you, I hate that outfit!
I'm paying you 1,000,000 yen,
so buy me something.
What are you doing?
Leaving it at the office.
Hey, are you really gonna give it back?
Of course.
Are you?
You can ease up on that left tit.
The money's going.
Flat chest.
"8F ASAI TRADINGS, INC."
Who are you?
Bike delivery.
Oh. How much?
Failing on the first day I introduce you.
Yes.
I've lost face, you useless jerk!
Hey! Come back, you!
You don't have to count it.
My passport.
Now we'll take the bullet train to Osaka.
You should leave Tokyo.
- I'll go alone.
- Huh?
If I have my passport, I'll be fine.
But...
That's hush money, right?
- Are you sure?
- Yeah.
Oh...well, be careful, then.
You got what you wanted.
Money.
You said noble things about Miyata,
but you found out so much
about me and let me in today
because you smelled cash, right?
Then why?
He's my best friend from junior high.
You found out all that
about me because of that?
It's expensive to find people, right?
You wouldn't understand.
I do understand.
Then why didn't you go to the cops?
Because, if I made a big deal over it,
Miyata would find out about you.
You liar.
You planned on blackmailing me someday.
What women like you
think about is so sad.
What people think about, you mean.
Just admit it. I would have done
the same if I were you.
If I were you, I'd have killed myself.
I really do like men like you.
See ya.
Hello? Oh, sorry, I'll be right there.
Hey.
Don't "Hey" me. You're late.
Oh, sorry.
Have you ordered?
What is it?
What? Oh, yeah.
What?
Ayumi's getting married.
You met her?
Yeah. I ran into her today,
and we talked a bit.
She seemed well.
I'm Kuwata Maki.
Maki. Nice to meet you.
- Hello.
The hamburger steak here is good.
Oh, really?
- Huh?
- Oh, yes.
- Do you like hamburger?
I'm going to the toilet.
You...
Good evening...
Good evening.
If you mess around with yakuza,
you won't live long.
Here.
I'm sorry. Thank you.
Yes. Says he was hired and
deceived by a girl named Ayumi.
Yes. He had 1,000,000 yen in new bills
Yes. Yes. I understand.
- To the office.
- Yes.
Um...let me explain...
Shut up! The boss will hear
you directly, so sit sill.
Um...can I get dressed?
No. When we kill you,
we have to dismember you,
so taking it of again is a hassle, see?
Miyata... Who is it?
A friend.
A friend?
A classmate from junior high.
Answer it.
Hello?
Where are you?
I'm...working.
Working? What about her?
Her? Do what you should.
What I should? What do you...
Look, I'm hanging up.
Good luck. It's your chance.
What's his chance?
No, um...
That was blatantly suspicious.
Uh, there's no connection...Really...
Well, do your explaining later.
Your life's at stake.
Yes, I'll do my best.
Bad connection.
Think of anything?
What?
An explanation.
No...
You should be thinking desperately.
Your life's at stake.
Yes.
Um...
Shut up until the boss comes.
Shiver there for now.
Hello, sir.
- Bring him in.
- Yes, sir.
- Go eat something. Good job.
- Thank you.
Now.
Mr. Detective, you know how much
it costs to get rid of someone?
We can do the killing. But we have
to hire someone to dispose of the body.
You know, a commissioned agent.
Pretty expensive.
And there are always risks.
If one of my men is caught, I have to
look after his family, and that's costly.
Honestly speaking, no man is
worth killing for that much trouble.
Oh.
But we yakuza have "face". Face. Get it?
...Yes.
You disgraced me.
If I let you get away with it,
I'm not a yakuza. Get it?
Yes...
Oh, forget the pretext.
From now on, you work for me for free.
I can use a detective.
And this money is mine.
You can go now.
Really?
Well, I searched your place.
I found this.
You do pretty good work.
You forget about this.
This is between her and me.
You can go.
Oh...thank you.
Well, then...
Oh, and this briefcase you brought...
These aren't mine.
And this was inside, too.
"KANDA YUSUKE, DETECTIVE"
So you didn't know?
I thought so.
I didn't think you were that stupid.
Then...the money...
I'll ask her now. She seems to have
lots of accounts, so I can't wait.
Did she say anything about her stuff?
She asked me to send
it to her new address.
"MIYATA"
- Oh, it's you.
- Sorry.
What do you want?
What?
Where's her stuff?
Oh. I threw it all out this morning.
I'm over her. Just like you said.
Did the garbage truck come already?
Yeah. A long time ago.
Hey, I have something to show you.
Ta-da! That girl last night's
phone number. I asked her.
I really felt like patting
myself on the back for this.
A guy has to do what
a guy has to do, you know?
But the way I acted last night was maybe
the "real" me.
Maybe that's who I really am.
Running a yakuza family
in this recession is tough.
This office costs 800,000 yen a month.
The electricity, 60,000 yen.
Feeding 8 men, 1,000,000 yen.
The phone bill, about 150,000 a month...
What? Who cares?
Money for ceremonial occasions
and such costs up to 2,000,000.
How much is that in all?
So, after subtracting the
necessary expenses from the profit
my own salary is just
over 1,000,000 a month.
But the boss can't live shabbily.
I have to eat and dress well
and date a gorgeous woman.
Image is everything.
Not everybody is here with
dreams of "Iove and duty"
Only the smell of
money'll attract people.
You can't tell?
Thanks, Yama-chan.
Sorry for making you do this.
No.
Oh, could you bring more paper after all?
Certainly.
I could use another 30,000,000 yen.
Yeah.
Excuse me. The new guy is here.
Oh. Let him wait.
Yes, sir.
OK, come in!
Excuse me.
Hi.
My name is Fujimoto.
How old are you?
I'm 19, sir!
Oh. The girls like you, right?
Yes! I mean...not really.
Are you hungry?
Yes.
We'll go out for dinner soon,
so let's talk then.
Yes.
Excuse me.
He saw them?
He saw them.
Yeah.
Excuse me. Ms. Yoko is here.
Oh, let her in.
No, make her wait a sec.
I'll be going then...
Oh, thanks a lot.
Okay, let her in!
It's my first time at your office,
so I'm kind of nervous.
Yoko, what do you want to eat?
Chinese?
Oh, Chinese? Sure.
Wait a sec.
Oh. I have to use the bathroom.
Sure, go ahead.
I want to fix my makeup,
so it may take some time. Go on ahead.
OK. We'll be right over there.
- You wait for her.
- Yes, sir.
Thanks.
Yes.
If you work hard, you can get anything.
Yes, sir!
Let's go, then.
"ASAI SHINOBU"
Where were you?
I...I was told to go buy cigarettes...
When I returned, she was...
I'm sorry!
What happened?
The money in the safe...
Look for it!
You move, too!
Yes.
Oh.
I'm sorry. We need more men.
Shall I call for help?
Idiot, do you want to make a fool of me?
Use just our men.
And don't make it a big deal.
Yes, sir.
Oh! Hey, when you find her,
bring her straight to me.
Don't ask her anything.
Yes, sir.
Who are you?
Bike delivery.
Oh. How much?
Hey! Come back, you!
What's wrong?
Someone brought this. Isn't it yours?
Oh!
Guess he brought the money back.
You chase him, too!
Yes, sir!
"Phone call, Boss! Phone call, Boss!"
Boss.
Yeah. Did you get him?
No, we lost him.
Oh.
Look, the money's back, so don't
make it a big deal. I'll ask around, too.
Tell the others to be
quiet about this, too.
Yes, sir.
Its open.
Thanks, Yama-chan.
Anytime.
"KANDA DETECTIVE AGENCY"
"Phone call, Boss! Phone call, Boss!"
Hello?
Oh. You have some nerve.
Did you see the card?
Yeah.
He has the cash! He's at a restaurant
called "Adesso", so get him.
What do you mean?
You took off with the money.
He made me do it.
He has all the money, so get him, quick.
Did you touch the money?
No. I just gave it to him.
Oh.
Then I forgive you.
Come back. Where are...
That's right.
Go get him right now. Do it quietly.
And when you get him,
don't make him talk. I'll do the asking.
Keep him quiet until then.
All right? Not a word.
"YAMADA Setsuko"
"KUDO Mika, Nurse, 1st Surgical Department"
"8,000,000 yen."
"13,000,000 yen. 12,000,000 yen."
"4,000,000 yen"
Oh.
Yes. Says he was hired and
deceived by a girl named Ayumi.
Oh. He's probably just a crazy drug addict,
so shut him up.
Yes.
Did he have anything? Like...money?
He had 1,000,000 yen in new bills.
Are they real?
Yes.
Oh...
Wait at the office.
Keep him quiet until I get there.
Yes. I understand.
Miyata...
So she didn't take anything from him...
Oh, hello, Yama-chan?
I need to ask another favor.
- Please.
- Thank you.
Slippers, slippers.
Um, I don't have slippers.
That's no problem.
Please use this room.
Yes, thank you.
- Do you have things to wear?
- Oh, yes.
- I'll sleep in the other room.
- Oh, I see.
Will you take a bath?
Yes. I'm sorry.
No...
Um...I'm really sorry...
This room is empty, anyway.
I mean, my old girlfriend...
Ayumi.
Yes.
We actually only lived together for a week.
She left right after I bought this place.
Why?
Hmm?
Why did she leave?
She suddenly told me
she loved somebody else.
I hear she's getting married to that guy.
That's terrible.
Well...she couldn't help it.
She couldn't help it?
Yes, probably.
It's a matter of feelings.
We didn't sign a contract.
Anyway, please feel free to use this room.
You can think about...
I'm sorry.
No, it's all right.
I'll go get the bath ready.
Yes.
Um...Which bath salt do you want?
"Smooth Skin Beppu Spa" or "Hakone Spa"?
Excuse me.
It's none of your business.
- I'll go now.
- What?
Thank you for everything.
Where are you going?
I'm sorry.
When you find what you need, leave.
I'll throw the rest away.
Good-bye.
Hey.
I'm devastated. You said you loved me.
No, this isn't...I...uh...
Can't think of a good lie so suddenly?
Even a pro like you.
You're some woman.
So that detective blackmailed you?
Two for one stone, eh?
Blame it on him and take the money.
I really do have an eye for people.
People who are loyal to
their desires are attractive.
OK. From now on, we're business partners.
A talented actress like you
needs good management.
I can write out a contract if you want.
I'll take 10,000,000 yen
as registration fee for starters.
Pretty cheap, right?
Aren't you Ionely by yourself?
It's sad being alone.
I have to go on living alone on this planet.
I can go on living alone.
He seems to be a pretty decent guy.
A clumsy and straightforward guy
like that is sincere.
He'll probably do his best
to make you happy.
Huh?
It's false?
No...
Maybe she made a mistake.
She didn't make a mistake. She lied.
A lie? That can't be true.
It happens.
Women do things like that.
Maybe this is an 8 and not a 6.
Give it up. It's false.
She wouldn't do such a...
Women do.
You've learned a lesson. Give up.
At least you brought yourself to ask.
Now get over it.
She made a mistake.
Come on...
She's not the kind of person who'd lie.
You sound like a kid in junior high.
Why do you trust someone
so easily and so completely?
She's not like that.
You live on another planet by yourself.
Hurry back to Earth.
No.
This is an 8, not a 6!
That's a 6!
"The number you have dialed
is currently not in use."
"Please check the number and try again."