Stone, scissors, paper.
Qu Ran, go!
Go!
Stone, scissors, paper.
Qu Ran, go!
This was the courtyard of our neighborhood
And these were our happy days in the '70s
Qu Ran was the prettiest girl in the neighborhood
Every boy wanted to be on his best when she's
around
I of course was no exception
I won
You cheated
Stand there! Stop! Get him!
Stand there! Stop!
Get him!
I won't cheat again
Let go of me please. I won't cheat again.
Hou Jia, I won't cheat again. Please let go of me
Hou Jia, go see your father
Go see your father
Hou Jia was the head boy of our neighborhood
We went to the same kindergarten, grade school and
I didn't know what happened in his family that day
But all of a sudden I felt a sadness.
It's because I was afraid,
and also because ofHou Jia
Mom
Mom, are you okay?
Mom, get up
You came fifth! That's something!
What are you doing?
I am your cohort in crime
Let's go
All the boys adored Qu Ran. She had that quality.
But she only liked me
Every time I rode past my school mates with her on
my back.
I just felt so great.
She's always talking non-stop.
Sometimes..
I really didn't hear what she was saying.
I just felt that she was very happy
Hou Jia has always been nice to me since we were
children
But as we grew up, that feeling changed.
It's become somewhat ambiguous and uncertain.
Back then I really liked to go to school
Because I wanted to see him.
And I knew when I looked at him
He'd be looking at me
Don't say anything
I know it. You haven't done it.
Why is it so hard to get my medical bills
reimburse?
I'm giving up
My lips are coarse from reminding you
How many times have I told you?
You tell me, how many times?
Every time you make me worry.
Then there's my salary
Easy on the salt.
You don't even go pick up my salary
How are we going to survive without my salary?
Such a simple thing, why is it so difficult?
Mom, I'll go when I have time. Stop bugging me
What else can I do besides bugging you?
I'm home
Mom, I'm home
You're late again.
But never as late as dad.
Mom, where's my brother?
He went to see a soccer game with some friends
Hey, have one
Wash your hands
So people go to college to watch soccer games.
I wish I could start college tomorrow
You're pretty confident, aren't you?
Look at your grades
You have your father and I worry sick over them
Relax.
I'm great playing catch up.
Ranran, what is Hou Jia's exercise book
doing on your desk?
We're friends, and friends help each other out.
Why him? Don't you have other friends?
We live in the same building.
And he's the best student in math, physics and
chemistry in our class
He's so smart. It's amazing.
Even the teacher don't understand
Mom, how come he's so smart?
I'm telling you, keep your mind on your studies.
I always keep my mind on my studies.
What's for dinner?
Dad, you're back.
Brother went to a soccer game
We're just waiting for you.
No, don't wait for me again
Ranran's busy, let her eat first.
I can get the water.
I've counted it. You can count it again.
Both your mom's salary and medical bill
reimbursements are here
Thank you.
I hate going to my mom's office.
Don't worry. I can go for you.
Let me.
Hou Jia, is Dong Da your first choice?
Of course.
What happens ifl don't get into Dong Da?
You want to apply to Dong Da? You're dreaming!
Then I'm not applying to Dong Da.
I'll apply to a second-tiered school with you.
You'll be brilliant there.
Whatever. "Dong Da" is definitely
my first choice anyways.
Mom.
I'm home.
Let's have noodles. Noodles are quick.
I've already eaten, you go ahead.
Mom, you're upset.
I'm late coming home because
I went to get your reimbursement.
I know. Xiao Ma from the union told me
when he came with the rice.
The money's here. Count it.
Put it over there. Did you hand in
your college entrance exam form?
Yes, and like we agreed,
I didn't apply to an out-of-town school.
Actually you should apply to a couple of them.
Like Beijing and Shanghai.
I'm sure they will accept you.
I'm going to the bathroom.
I'm not applying to an out-of-town school.
How will you manage ifl were gone?
I can find a maid or go to an old people's home.
Or I can go with you.
I've had quite enough with the building.
Where're you going? You should be studying,
there's no much time left.
You're asking me? Where are you going?
I can't study anymore. I'm going crazy.
I want to go to the examination hall.
I don't want us to get lost and
be late on that day.
Us?
I'll come to get you and we go together.
My dad said he's taking me.
But he's not picking me up, we can come back
together.
Right? Right?
The college entrance exam came and went.
Hou Jia came first in our school and second in our
district.
I did so-so and could only get into a branch
campus.
As we waited for our admissions notice to arrive...
We did all sorts of things to relax.
It looked like we wanted high school to go on
forever.
The truth was we didn't want to part.
It's agreed. We go to the countryside
when we get our admissions notice.
Mom.
Mom, I got into "Dong Da".
Mom, you're upset.
I know you will.
Mom, where're you going?
To the office to get my salary.
Take me downstairs.
I'm going tomorrow. I promise.
I'm going out for a minute, I'll be right back.
Didn't you hear me?
Take me downstairs.
Mom, what's the matter with you?
All my friends' parents are so happy
that their children get into college.
Everyone's celebrating.
What's the matter with you?
Hou Jia.
You're different.
Your father...
Committed suicide.
I never told you because I was afraid it'd affect
your education.
And I'm suffocating to death for it.
You're going to college.
You'll have friends...
From all over the country.
You can make friends...
With whomever you want.
I don't have an opinion.
And if you want to leave this town...
I can go with you.
Mom.
What are you trying to tell me? What is it?
You can't go out with Qu Ran.
Why?
Why isn't he here yet?
Qu Ran, what's the matter with Hou Jia?
I don't know.
I told him three times that we're meeting at six.
He didn't change his mind, did he?
If something had happened, he'd have told me.
You're home.
You haven't forgotten, have you?
What is it?
Is your mom all right?
Are you okay?
I'm fine. I just don't want to go.
Then who are you upset with?
Don't ask, just go.
Go where?
I don't care. Just don't come to me again.
Why?
You asked me why?
Why don't you ask you father?
Ask him what he did to my family.
You should turn in early.
I never saw my mom got so angry.
It's been ages and I didn't remember much about my
father's death.
But to my mother, it's always been a curse.
I just can't believe that Qu Ran was involved.
Not to say figuring a way to deal with it.
I just know...
Qu Ran would be so heart broken.
Brother, can I ask you something?
Can't you see I'm busy?
One quick question.
Shoot.
Hou Jia's father, I mean...
How did he die?
Who's Hou Jia?
He lives downstairs. We're in the same grade.
When he was in junior 5, the police arrested
his father and h killed himself.
That's ancient history. So?
Does father have anything to do with it?
That's ridiculous. Says who?
His mom forbids him to go out with me.
Why do you want to go out with him?
Who the hell is he anyway?
Son.
Are you thinking of getting a new bike?
Get something nice.
After all it's "Dong Da".
I've been asking around.
In our neighborhood...
You're the only one...
I've asked Auntie Wang to find me a maid.
It's 50 yuan a month, plus room and board.
You just concentrate on your studies
and don't worry about me.
What's that supposed to mean?
Hou Jia.
Are you pushing me around because
I don't have anyone to talk to?
Then tell me what happened.
What else do you want to know?.
Your father died and left us
to fend for ourselves, isn't that enough?
But what does it have to do with Qu Ran?
You are such a loser.
Mom.
You scolded me.
The greatest satisfaction...
Of my life,
Is that both of you...
My two children...
Are going to university.
One in the arts, and one in the sciences.
Your mother and l...
Will never stand in your way,
But only do our very best to help you.
That's what we did...
And that's how we'll continue.
As for Qu Ran's question,
My answer is:
I have never framed or hurt anyone.
Not in the past, not in the present...
And never in the future.
Then why did Hou Jia's father kill himself?.
That's a matter for grown-ups. It's none of your
business...
And I don't need to discuss it with you.
All right. It's settled. Let's eat.
Come. Let's eat our dinner.
Don't bring it up again.
Let's eat.
Since you don't want to come clean with it...
Then you must be hiding something.
Ranran.
That's no way to talk to your father.
You're going too far.
Starting today,
If that Hou Jia came to see you again...
You just slap his face.
Hou Jia.
If...
My family ever did anything to hurt your parents,
I can apologize to your family...
On their behalf.
My father didn't want an apology.
He's dead.
My father said he hadn't done anything.
No, he had.
Hou Jia.
But I haven't.
I know.
But...
Ranran.
How can you do this to us?
Are you going to eat your meals
in your room for the rest of your life?
Unless you tell me...
What that was all about.
It was perhaps...
Qu Ran's apology...
That made me realize
I was probably in love with her.
I wanted to get away from her.
I was afraid of seeing her,
But I was really waiting for her.
If not...
Why does Cupid hold in his hands...
Not roses...
But bow and arrows?
Only when you love someone...
Will you behave like that.
I don't hate Hou Jia.
And I don't hate my parents.
At that time I just didn't understand...
Why is it that the people who tortured me most...
Were those that I loved most dearly.
I started college with that question in my heart.
Qu Ran, let me give you a ride.
You're running late.
Why do you always look so unhappy?
I'm okay. It's just that college life
isn't exactly what I imagined.
Join us. Let's go out and have some fun.
I guarantee you'll be so happy.
That's what we do best.
I don't fancy skipping classes like you guys.
Of course you shouldn't make it a habit.
Never, not even once
But it's also a regret...
I have never been late for school in my life.
Everyone knows the story ofRomeo and Juliet.
But that was the first time that
I read the entire play.
Their love moved me to the deep.
And our experience was so much like theirs.
The play was to me like a beacon.
Sun Yifan.
Here.
Li Chuanzi.
Wang Song.
Here.
Qu Ran.
She's not here.
Lu Baocai.
Here.
Zhao Pengjing.
So this is the play.
'Tis but thy name that is my enemy.
Thou art thyself,
Though not a Montague.
What's a Montague?
It is not hand, nor foot,
Nor arm, nor face,
Nor an other part belonging to a man.
O, be some other name!
What's in a name?
That which we call a rose
By any other name would smell as sweet.
So Romeo would, would he not Romeo call'd,
Retain that dear perfection which he owes
Without that title. Romeo, doffthy name,
And for that name which is no part ofthee
Take all myself.
My name, dear saint,
Is hateful to myself
Because it is an enemy to thee;
Had I it written,
I would tear the word.
He jests at scars that never felt a wound.
But, soft!
What light through yonder window breaks?
It is the east,
And Juliet is the sun.
The play seems to have been written for us.
It's waited for us for several hundred years.
You mean...
We must persist. Is that right?
Eat.
What about you?
I'll eat at the canteen.
C'mon, eat with me.
Those were our happiest days.
We stayed out of our families' ways.
And we didn't think about the future.
We were in love and
we wanted to be together forever.
We wanted to prove that children
of feuding families can get together.
And their union can resolve hatred.
Qu Ran always said,
Ifwe were to give up our love
for our fathers' quarrels,
Then we're no different from Romeo and Juliet,
For death ofthe heart is just
as sad as death ofthe body.
Watching the gently falling rain...
Ah, walking in the rain. Isn't that romantic?
Beautiful rain, how I love this precious rain.
Let me give you a ride.
Why don' you teach me?
Sure.
Look straight ahead. I'm going to push you.
Hey, slowly.
Hold me, and don't let go.
C'mon, go.
Xiao Lan.
Xiao Lan, Hou Jia.
Hou Jia.
I'm giving you a push.
Have some water.
Thank you.
Mom.
This is Li Zinan, your brother's girlfriend.
How do you do?
I'm Qu Ran. Welcome to our home.
Oh, both the girl and the boy are here.
It's a happy occasion.
Sit down.
Don't stand up.
Ranran.
Here. Let me.
Please don't eat in your room this evening.
Look how happy your father is.
We don't want people to laugh at us, do we?
Mom, don't worry. I understand.
Qu Qiang. I lost one of my stockings.
I just washed them.
It must have fallen downstairs.
That's my only pair.
Qu Qiang, go look for it.
I go over there.
Ranran, lend her a pair of yours.
But I don't have any long stockings.
Have a candy.
What about my stockings?
They are a present from my aunt in America.
It's not here.
It's over there hanging on
your classmate's window.
I'll get it for you.
Hou Jia.
Hi. I think we dropped something on your window,
May I go inside and have a look?
Sure.
Thank you.
Our family does not have anything that belongs to
your family.
Mrs. Hou, is Hou Jia home?
Is that any ofyour business
whether he's home or not?
Our family does not have anything that
belongs to your family.
Mrs. Hou.
Qu Ran.
He jests at scars that never felt a wound.
My mother, she...
Are you okay?
Qu Ran.
Come, let's eat.
Enjoy the dishes. Eat.
Eat.
Hou Jia, you are not keeping your promise.
You're still seeing Qu Ran.
Don't think that I don't know.
You should really tell me the whole truth.
Tell me what actually happened.
Mr. and Mrs. Qu, I should be going.
Have a little more.
I'm quite full already.
See her off.
No, please don't.
You didn't give your brother face,
and you didn't give us face.
Dad,
Ifwe'd really done something terrible
to the Hou family...
Could I apologize to them?
I don't think it's fair that...
We should bear your burdens.
Ranran.
I'm telling you again.
I've never done anything against my principles or
conscience.
I don't owe anyone an apology.
As for the question ofyour emotional
involvements,
I'm sure...
You are capable ofhandling them.
You are so smart...
In so many things.
You will have a bright future.
However...
If you spend too much energy on these things,
You'll end up despising yourself.
But you still haven't told me...
What actually happened.
Were you in any way involved...
In Hou Jia's father's death?
Someone read...
The letter that Qu Zhiheng wrote
to frame your father.
They were squabbling over a position, and he
framed your dad.
Your father was arrested and he killed himself,
and Qu got the position.
What did he accuse father of?.
Was there no investigation into it?
What're the results?
I'm an adult now. You got to tell me the truth.
What's the purpose? You father died.
You won't forget it, will you?
But what does it have to do with Qu Ran?
That's something between you adults.
You're not to marry her
even if she's the last woman on earth.
Don't even think about it.
Not even over my dead body.
Uncle Qu.
I've always had a lot of respect for you.
That time we went on a field trip.
You came to pick up Qu Ran...
And ended up collecting all the kids
from our building.
The six of us crowded into the back ofyour car.
It was so much fun.
I'd like to know...
What happened...
Between our families.
Could you please tell me?
Hou Jia.
You don't have the right to ask me this question.
And I am under no obligation to answer it.
If...
you don't want her to be sad or get hurt,
You put an end to your relationship.
That's what a man should do.
First we go to Beidaihe, then Shanhaiguan...
Visit the GreatWall from the other side
and come back from Gubeikou.
Not bad. Sounds like a terrific trip.
I get sentimental when I'm by the sea.
I'll miss you.
I'll miss you too. You've brought so much joy
to my college life.
Hou Jia, what are you doing here?
This book here...
Came from your school library.
I should be returning it. You're graduating.
I already paid the fine.
It's five times the original price.
Let's go.
Qu Ran.
Who is he?
He's from the same class and the same department.
We've been friends
and now we have to say good-bye.
I've returned all the love letters...
To their authors in person.
They called me a stiff.
I'm not like you.
Hou Jia, what's the matter with you?
You came here to tell me that?
I haven't seen you in ages.
Do you know how much I miss you
and think about you?
It's the film...
Romeo and Juliet.
Our experience decided our hobby.
We became big fans of Shakespeare,
Especially the different interpretations
ofRomeo and Juliet.
Theater, opera, books, stills, etc.
Every time we looked at the two protagonists...
We thought we were looking at ourselves.
When we found ourselves losing
all sense of directions...
We always turned to the play
to look for each other.
Qu Ran.
Let's just keep walking...
To another city,
And never come back.
Let's ask for a transfer to another area.
I'll follow you wherever you go,
To a place where no one knows us...
And where we don't need anyone.
So long as we can be together.
There are so many places that we can go to.
Where do you want to go?
To Shanghai.
To Beijing.
To Dalian.
To Guangzhou.
Let's go to the south.
Ifyou gave up your work here
and went to another town with me,
Your family will hate me.
Hou Jia, please keep your promise.
I'm so afraid that you won't keep it.
Like Zijun in Lu Xun's story Sad Departing.
You should have a wonderful life,
but I can't bring you happiness.
How do you know I won't be happy?
We cannot give up our family.
And we cannot change ourselves.
Hou Jia.
Even if we'd fight, break up, regret and die...
Right this minute I want to go with you.
Mom...
I think...
I want to find a job elsewhere.
No, we don't agree.
Mom, just think that you'd never
had me for a daughter.
You can give up your parents,
but I won't let you throw your life away.
Mom, what do you want me to do then?
You're an adult, you should know.
You have to make a choice...
Between Qu Ran and l.
If you want me to go with you, that's fine.
But if you choose Qu Ran...
I'll go join your father.
Mom, what are you doing?
I'm going to your school,
and I'm talking to your school authorities.
Mom.
Talk to anyone you want.
I'm not going even if it's the best unit.
Then I also tell you,
you are not going to have your way.
Mom.
The story on the stage does not change.
But the story of our life gets re-written
over and over again.
Hou Jia asked me...
Is giving up life or giving up hope more horrible?
I knew what he meant.
I've always thought about that myself.
I even thought...
Perhaps that's another kind of happiness.
No.
I won't let you die.
There's peace after death,
and people can stop hurting each other.
Here?
Ranran, what happened?
Ranran, say something.
Ranran, Quiet, quiet
Ranran
Whose parents are you?
The name's Qu.
What's going on?
Sign here.
Please come over here to read the statement.
Ranran, what happened?
He...
Did he...
Did he rape you?
After all these years and
you're still using this word...
And this time on my son.
How much more do you want to destroy me?
Mom.
You go on home. Take the No. 54 bus.
Please read the statement.
Ranran.
Did Hou Jia rape you?
Qu Ran, I want to hear you say it.
Mrs. Hou...
I beg you, please don't torture him any more.
I love Hou Jia.
We didn't do anything wrong.
Stop this.
Let's go.
Qu Ran will never enter your home...
Even if she has to grow old and
die in her own home.
Qu Zhiheng, you heard it.
My son did not rape your daughter.
You're trying to frame us.
I'm going to the courts...
To sue you.
Hou Jia.
We're leaving.
Ranran, let go.
Did you hear me? Let go of your hand.
That's enough. You all leave.
Get out ofhere. What a mess.
To have that once in a lifetime experience...
Is good enough for me.
Your father became friendly with
a young woman in the office.
At that time I was busy at work and
on a short fuse.
Actually nothing really happened.
But later on there were all these rumors...
About that woman getting pregnant.
Qu went to speak with her
on behalf of the organization.
In the report he said the woman was raped.
Your father was put into custody,
and killed himself before the trial.
Why did he kill himself?.
He was too taken by surprise.
He felt betrayed and was desperate.
He was betrayed by someone he liked.
Later on I went everywhere looking for that woman.
I wanted to ask her who made her say that.
I never found her;
instead I got into a car accident.
Mom, please stop.
I don't enjoy talking about it.
It's not something to be proud of.
But you insisted on getting involved with them.
How can I put up with that?
The reason that I'm still living is you.
Your father wronged me.
He's dead and I'm still carrying his burden.
Out ofthe blue Hou Jia decided to go abroad.
For his career and his mother.
I was also looking for changes.
Separation was painful,
and staying together was also painful.
If not more painful.
Hou Jia, when do you arrive in Beijing tomorrow?.
What time is your flight?
I may stay there for one evening.
You're the first person
in our class to go to the US.
We'll be right after you.
I gave my mom your numbers.
Please take care ofher.
Don't worry, we'll call her.
I don't know what to bring you.
They say American food is sweet,
and you may not be used to it.
I really don't want to leave like this.
I'm okay. I only want you to be happy.
No matter what happens...
You must let me know.
If there's a way...
I'll send for you.
Don't say anymore.
I thought we have an understanding:
Nothing will change ifwe don't talk about it.
Nothing will ever change
ifwe never say a word about it.
The days slipped away quietly in expectation.
Father always wore a worried look on his face.
Hou Jia and I wrote furiously to each other.
He told me that
He'd collected over a dozen editions
ofRomeo and Juliet in different languages.
The days went by, and that was our link.
Romeo and Juliet die for their love.
We die for our love with each other's solitude.
Thank you.
Have some watermelon. Thank you.
Cool you off in this hot weather.
That's so true.
Mom.
Ranran, look who's here.
Ranran.
Mrs. Feng, how are you?
How are you?
It's been ages. You're all grown up,
and so beautiful.
Hey, leave my bag alone.
Ranran, Mrs. Feng is here about your business.
Sit down for a while.
Mrs. Feng, please make yourself at home.
I have to work.
Sure.
Ranran.
I really have to work.
Please sit down.
Have some watermelon.
To cool off.
Thanks
This watermelon is great. Right.
Have some water.
Thank you.
I've brought with me a photograph. Here.
Seoul, scattered showers, 15 to 25 degrees.
Beijing, scattered showers to overcast,
12 to 17 degrees.
Ranran, Mrs. Feng rode on the bus
for two hours to visit us...
To talk about your business...
And you wouldn't even sit down with her.
I have nothing to say to her.
Mom, it's only clothes for the child,
don't fret over them.
He's a fine boy, has a master's degree.
And all his siblings are doing well.
What does it have to do with me?
You're not getting any younger,
when are you going to grow up?
We're not obliged to serve you.
You just can't go out and hang yourself on a tree.
To hang myself or not, that's my own business.
What do you mean that's your own business?
Look what you did to our parents!
Look what you did to this family!
When the nanny arrives,
you get ready to move into the sitting room.
Shut up.
This is my home, and Ranran will always
have a room in this home.
If need be, I move into the sitting room.
Mom, eat. I'll make some more.
I shouldn't have said that.
It's just that...
I worry about you.
Brother...
How come you can be with the person you love and l
cannot?
Ranran...
I'm not asking you to do anything for anyone...
Just for yourself.
Oh...
Not even thirty...
And you already have white hair.
Qu Ran, come look at Hou Jia's picture.
I just got it in the mail.
That's nice.
What about my line to Boston?
We're very busy today, please wait another minute.
Line to Paris, booth number 3.
The story that begins with
a bang ends with a whimper.
For the first time in my life,
I felt lonely, like I've been dumped.
I decided to stop contacting Hou Jia,
afraid that he'd confirm that ending...
That he'd tell me things that
I didn't want to know.
Baobao, say Happy new year to grandparent
As well as auntie. Don't forget!
Baobao, here.
She always gives you the biggest red packet.
Stop giving him so much money. He's just a kid.
I make my money for him anyway.
Baobao, you be nice to Auntie Ranran
when you grow up.
When Baobao grows up,
he'll buy a country house for his grandparents.
I'll buy one for Auntie Ranran.
Buy what?
A country house.
Let's get one.
Why?
For Baobao.
I don't think he doesn't want it.
Then I want if for myself.
It's so cute.
I want two.
My son said when he had money
He'd right away find me an apartment
with an elevator.
I said let's wait until
you came back but he insisted.
Where is she moving to?
I don't know.
Goodbye.
Come visit me when you have time.
Yes, of course.
You all come.
Stone, scissors, paper.
You cheated. Get back.
Ranran.
What do you think about these earrings.
Let me get you a pair if you like them.
Bangkok, thunderstorm, 25 to 33 degrees.
San Francisco, sunny, 13 to 22 degrees.
London, overcast, 9 to 19 degrees.
Karachi, sunny, 27 to 35 degrees.
Moscow, showers, 4 to 16 degrees.
it's been two weeks since I returned to China
and I haven't visited Qu Ran
I was afraid that she's moved on
But somehow I felt I should go to
that show with Qu Ran
Why am I coming to see this show?.
Why can't I cut myself offfrom this story?
Perhaps I've given up having expectations.
It's just that waiting has become my life.
Stop looking for it. It disappeared ages ago.
There's a stamp of Qu Ran's stamp on that book.
You must have thrown it out.
The maid does the cleaning up.
I cannot remember everything.
You may forget other things,
but certainly not that book.
You took it out form my chest.
It's for you own good. Do you hate me for it?
How can I feel warmth?
All I wanted was to come back early
and take care of you...
To make you happy and healthy.
Why do I want to live long?
To look at my son stay single
for the rest ofhis life?
I heard Hou Jia came back.
He's been gone six or seven years, rights?
Seven years.
What're you two going to do?
That's ancient history.
Let's don't bring it up again.
Do you have any plans for yourself?.
Dad, sometimes I really want to get married.
But you know, these things...
I'll just stay with you and mom, make myselfthis
piece of junk useful.
I'm going to the hospital tomorrow for my report.
I'll go with you.
No, your mom can go with me.
I went back to the building
of my youth and childhood
Nothing has changed.
Qu Ran wasn't home.
I only saw her mother and left my card.
He left a business card,
but I didn't have time for him.
Mom.
Ranran.
Your father's report came out.
It's not good.
It's my fault. I made him suffer.
Stop this nonsense.
Your father said he didn't want an operation.
My father's illness made me realize
how deeply I'd hurt him.
Hou Qia came to see me but
I didn't have any time for him
Dad.
Oh.
Time for your medicine.
Ranran.
Give Hou Jia a call.
He's always busy.
Just to get together, for old time's sake.
Hello.
This is Qu Zhiheng. My cancer's terminal,
and I don't know...
Ifl could still have the opportunity
to apologize to you in person.
If possible, please have Hou Jia
come over to my house...
There's something that I'd like to say to him.
Do you still remember that day when
you confronted me in the courtyard?
I shouldn't have behaved like that,
I do apologize.
It was so long ago.
Please don't make it difficult for yourself.
Hou Jia, I've done Ranran harm.
My biggest sorrow...
Is to see my daughter...
Year after year,
Lose her youth...
Until she's turned into an old maid.
I, as her father...
Had ruined her chance for a happy life.
Uncle Qu.
If you could accept my apology...
I wish you and Ranran would get married.
This is a letter that I wrote to the organization.
It stated that...
Out of concern for the girl...
I had indeed told her that...
If she was forced into it,
then she was only the victim.
So I was responsible for your father's death.
If your mother finds it necessary...
She can take this letter to the organization and
request them to re-open the file.
Why don't you invite Qu Ran
to visit your new home?
What's wrong with you? The phone's ringing.
Qu Ran.
It's me.
How's your mom?
Is she okay?
Give her my regards. You take care of yourself.
Try to spend more time with her.
Yes.
There's something that
I've always wanted to ask you.
What is it? Please
All those years we were separated.
Now we can see each other again,
but we're not. Why?
My father has died;
and you know how much I'd hurt him
But Qu Ran... he...
Hou Qia, we can never meet
the departed again, ever.
I started living by myself.
I didn't see or call Qu Ran.
At that time I thought:
Shakespeare's love story has brought us together
so many times before.
Now there's a new scenario,
can we still get together?
Somewhere, somehow....
Will she and I brush past calmly?
Excuse me. Please wait.
Right, that's it.
C'mon, don't lag behind.
It's pretty good.
You should also try it on when you time comes.
What are you doing here?
Let me go say hello to a friend.
Qu Ran.
You're...
It's my colleague.
Is it?
She wants to rent a wedding gown,
especially that one in the window.
I thought...
She looks older than you.
It's her third marriage.
Sir, buy a flower for the lady. Thank you.
Buy a flower please.
Happy Valentine.
Young people today celebrate Valentine,
I guess that's fashionable.
People are living better and
there're more festivities.
Right.
We've been left behind.
It's only lovers who are not married
that celebrate Valentine.
In any case, for the occasion...
I also brought you a small present.
What are you doing? Look at our age.
I've always worried that you'd give up.
All these years it's been torturing me.
Nothing will change ifwe don't talk about it...
Nothing will ever change if
we don't ever say a word about it.
Qu Ran.
Let's get married.
I want to make you happy.
To live with you in the same building...
That was once my happiness.
To live with you in the same city...
That's also once my happiness.
To be alive with you at the same time
in this world...
That will be my happiness.
Happiness...
Is a feeling from deep inside your heart.
Hi, this way please
Stand over there a bit.
Get close to each other.
Right.
Look this way.
We're doing the first set.
Don't move.
Look this way.
The bride...
The bride please smile.
The bride please smiles again.
Look this way.
Ready...