Provided by explosiveskull
https://twitter.com/kaboomskull
Keep her steady, Willie!
Bastard's driving
like a bloody madman.
Beast of a storm
brewin' up out there.
Perhaps a sign of God's
distaste at the injustice
being served here.
An innocent man shouldn't be
subjected to this cruelty.
If I hear one
more word about you
being a so-called innocent
man, young Mr. Whittock,
I'll shove this pipe so
far up your back crack
you'll burn your bastard
tongue chewing me 'baccie.
Innocent?
How do you figure that?
You admit to
murdering the bugger.
They caught you in
the act, Mr. Whittock.
I never said I killed a man.
I said I killed a monster.
That transformed into a
man after he was deceased.
Yes.
Yes, yes, very convenient.
This monster of yours appeared
as a man to everybody else.
Just in time for the
lord and lady to discover
you'd decapitated their youngest
and most beloved nephew.
The thing was gonna
tear me limb from limb.
I had no choice.
That boy was a bloody pansy.
But he wasn't a boy
when I killed him.
I don't know how to explain
it, but I know what I saw.
What, what else do you suggest
gifted me this vile injury?
Rambunctious lover no doubt.
A woman did this to me?
I've had far worse done to
me in the throes of passion.
Almost lost me left bollock
during a vigorous affair
with Drusilla Douglas,
God rest her soul.
Went blind with
syphilis a month later
and fell down a wishing well.
She'd have to have
been pretty giant,
with the claws of a
lioness to do this.
Well you're an
ugly git Whittock,
and no doubt she was
a bit of a gargoyle.
We'll see what the
judge has to say.
Judge Thaddeus is a
cruel and impatient man.
He shan't be doing with
your whingeing lies.
I have all the papers
signed by all the witnesses.
Tomorrow morning you'll hang,
and I'll be glad of
the peace and quiet.
Me too, from
this wicked world.
Why the devil have we stopped?
Willie!
The horses are
spooked, Councilor.
They won't go on.
Well, whip the bastards
until they're un-spooked,
or I'll be forced
to come up there
and give you a whipping myself!
I got a court appearance
to attend tomorrow.
The storm is
getting worse, sir.
We must seek shelter
for the night.
Let's continue at
dawn when it's safer.
There's nowhere
to stay, Willie.
I know these woods, sir.
There's an old inn not far.
We turn off here.
Better to get there
before dark, sir.
Folks have been known to go
missing, whole groups of 'em.
Oh, very well.
Onwards!
No funny business from
you, you understand?
Thank you.
Best kept in a safe
place, don't you think?
Jesus, you're a
welcoming fella.
My name is Parish
Councilor Horrace Raycraft.
This here is my
coachman Willie Ryder,
and this sniveling delinquent
is a criminal I'm escorting
for his court trial.
Storm's preventing us
traveling any further tonight
so we was hoping you could
give us accommodation.
Three rooms, is it?
Just the two.
This one stays with me.
I can't sleep chained to
you, you smelly old bastard-
Please stop doing that.
What's his crime?
Murder.
Self defense.
Tomorrow he'll be executed.
Until then, he's
my responsibility.
I suppose you want
to come into the warm?
Wipe your boots on the way in.
Jesus, Willie, look
at this wallpaper.
I've left patterns
in me chamber pot
less grotesque than this.
Open a window every once
in a while do you ol' chap?
Let the odor escape.
Aha, unexpected guests.
I'm Martha Hogwood.
Welcome to the Three Claws.
Horrace Raycraft, and
this here is my coachman,
Willie Ryder.
Willie Ryder?
Why yes, he's the
finest in the county.
Pleasure gentlemen.
Now, don't let brother
scare you off, will you?
He's a little mentally-impaired.
It hadn't gone unnoticed.
Vincent and I manage
the inn together.
It's been our family
business for generations.
And a very fine establishment
it is, too, Miss Warthog.
Hogwood.
Precisely.
Well, I'll show you
up to our guest rooms,
if you'd care to follow.
Oh, Vincent, you'll take care
of their horses, won't you?
Their horses?
Yes.
Put them in the
stable out back.
I can do that, madam.
No, no, it's no trouble.
Vincent can manage.
Come on up.
You haven't seen a young
lady on your travels,
have you anywhere, gentlemen?
One of our guests
left this morning
without settling her debt.
Haven't passed a
soul, I'm afraid, madam.
I'm afraid we're almost full
tonight, but you're in luck.
Just the
two rooms for us.
This murdering
scoundrel stays with me.
Murdering?
It's incredibly brave of you
to keep yourself attached
to a potentially violent
criminal, Mr. Raycraft.
Call
me Horrace, please.
One must be very courageous
in this profession.
Protecting vulnerable
ladies such as yourself
from the many vulgar
miscreants of society.
I'd be worried he'd sever my
arm from my body and escape.
What's that?
Wouldn't be difficult.
Dislocate the hand from
the wrist in the night
while you were sleeping.
Here, perfect lodgings
for your coachman.
I'm afraid the bed's a tad
lumpy since our last guest,
Lady Stillinfleet, died in her
sleep of a perforated bowel.
Thank you, madam.
We have the Reverend
Pankhurst of Hilperton
staying just across the hall.
Oh yes, we're very
particular about our guests
here at The Three Claws.
Oh, Minnie!
All done here, Miss Hogwood.
Shut the pissin'
door ya daft wench!
Oh, Jesus Christ, you got
mess all over the bed sheets.
Minnie is our
resident lady of the evening,
available to our guests at
just two pounds a night.
Minnie this is Mister Raycraft.
Uh, Parish Councilor Raycraft.
You like what
you see, Councilor?
I'll admit I've
got more than a slight tingle
in me nether-giblets.
Maybe Minnie can give you
some relief later tonight, no?
Please don't.
I'm sure that can be arranged.
This is your room at
the end of the hall.
Here, take this.
Hide it with the rest.
Victoria hasn't returned?
She's not coming back.
Something must have happened.
God help us.
She'll never make it back now.
There are bad things
in the woods, Jane.
We should have gone with them.
So what am I to do?
I can't go out there.
You promised to leave
before the blood moon.
It's almost dark!
I can't, Minnie.
The Three Claws will
not be safe tonight.
They've planned to have
them filled with guests
on the night of the blood moon
as if their lives
dependent on it.
Whatever they are up to,
I know it can't be good.
The new guests, they
brought transportation.
You could help me steal it.
He's the parish councilor.
You will be arrested
for thievery.
If I'm to believe
what you say,
perhaps I've no other choice.
Believe me,
Jane, for his sake.
Have been dealt with?
Under shelter for now.
He's the parish
councilor, Martha.
They're expecting him
in court tomorrow.
He's not some lowlife that
people will easily forget.
What do you suggest
we do then, brother?
We cannot break our pact.
They'll come looking for him.
The inn must be full.
These fools are a
gift from the storm.
Wheel their carriage
into a ditch and burn it.
Make it look like they've
steered off the road.
Nobody will suspect us.
And the horses?
Perhaps they'll
serve as an appetizer.
Jane, quickly!
♪ So we'll roll the
old chariot along ♪
♪ And we'll roll the
golden chariot along ♪
♪ So we'll roll the
old chariot along ♪
♪ An' we'll all hang on behind ♪
♪ Oh, a night with the girls
wouldn't do us any harm ♪
Bring in the girls!
♪ Oh, a night with the girls
wouldn't do us any harm ♪
♪ An' we'll all hang on behind ♪
♪ So we'll roll the
old chariot along ♪
♪ An' we'll all hang on behind ♪
What madness is this?
Get outta my face,
you filthy, drunken pig!
You grumpy git,
you!
Cheer up, have a drink, get
settled in for the storm.
Aye, she's a brutal bitch.
And a blood moon
to go with her.
All the devilish ingredients
for an evenin' of sinister
and supernatural happenin's.
Pour yourselves
summat strong, boys,
and pray we make it
through till morning.
I'll be surprised
if he makes it
through the next 10 minutes.
So wrinkles, you got a name?
Horrace.
Horrace the hideous.
I'm Bernard Bagley,
and this is the Reverend
Gilbert Pankhurst.
Aye! Of Hilperton!
What about your attachment?
Archibald Whittock,
charged with murder.
Tomorrow he'll be
sentenced to death.
Then you should drink, boy.
Celebrate your last
night of livin'.
Do you always get
this drunk, Mr. Bagley?
I have to on a
night like this, son.
Calms me nerves.
Frightened of a
little storm, are you?
It's not the storm
that frightens me.
It's what's out
there in them woods.
You don't know where
you are, do you, lad?
This is Grittleton Marsh,
and there are legends
of Grittleton Marsh.
Its ancient woodlands
which spread for miles,
and the wicked beasts
who dwell within.
See one, I did, when
I was just a short lad.
And for me left eye, it was
the last thing it ever saw.
They're out there, wolves
like you ain't never seen.
Tall as men, and
strong as giants.
Wolves, you say?
Not just any wolves, foul
beasts crawled up from the
gizzards of hell.
What a load of
superstitious codswallop!
I said I seen them, sir!
Through the
bottom of a bottle.
There may well be
wolves in these parts,
but not as you describe them.
The only thing dangerous
within 50 miles
is this murdering ratbag.
And I've got him
under my guardianship.
Then here's to you, brave sir.
Sleep tight, Councilor.
Sweet dreams, Councilor.
The councilor wants to
see you in his room tonight.
I've already taken payment.
Ah ah, you'll get
your half tomorrow.
Now make sure you wear him out.
I need every man in this
inn sleeping like the dead.
But it's so
late, Miss Hogwood.
Maybe I'm worn out.
Don't forget who's keepin'
a roof above your head,
you ungrateful gutter whore.
Now do as you're told!
The only reason why
men come to this pigpen
is to spend a night with me.
So perhaps it is I keeping
a roof over your head.
You know tonight's a
special night, Minnie.
We pay you well to
draw 'em in, do we not?
Was that not the arrangement?
Everything must go
according to plan,
otherwise you will not
like the repercussions.
You don't scare me.
It's not me you
need to be afraid of.
Go on lovely,
like you mean it.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, that's
the spot, darling.
That's it!
Jesus, oh,
Oh, yeah, yeah.
Oh God, yes, yes, yes, yes.
Yes, yes, oh.
Oh, Jesus Christ!
Stop your moaning
and go to sleep.
You're
rusting me saw.
It's hardly getting
through the bone.
You gotta put
your back into it.
I am, woman.
I am.
Pass me the head.
Don't let it drip everywhere,
you're gonna stain
the furniture.
What's that noise?
Somebody's there!
Lord, look upon me
with eyes of mercy.
May your mighty power w
into every inch of my body
and into the depths of my soul.
Guide me and give me strength
to make it through
this dark night.
Somebody's awake.
Did they see us?
Oh, Miss Hogsbottom, absorb
me in your pillowy bosom.
Mr. Raycraft.
Mr. Raycraft, wake up!
Oh, snuck in for a ride on
old horny Horrace have ya,
you saucy minx?
Jesus wept!
Your breath stinks like piss!
Please Mister
Raycraft, listen!
It's the innkeepers.
They've killed
Willie, butchered him!
Butchered?
They intend to murder
us all, I heard it.
They're chopping the
guests into pieces.
What the bloody hell?
Why you little rascal,
you're trying to escape!
No!
I mean, yes, I was, but-
- Right, that does it.
Oh, you dirty little bastard.
It wasn't altogether
pleasant for either of us.
I warned you.
Now shut up, old
man, and listen.
Calm down.
I saw with my own
eyes those incubus
dismembering your coachman,
and plotting aloud
to do the same to us.
Poppycock!
Go and see for yourself.
I'm not lying, sir.
Dismembered you say?
And you came back
to warn me, did ye?
It's an unlikely story.
Just because it's
an unlikely story
doesn't mean it isn't the truth.
Promise to believe me,
or I'll go ahead and
prevent your suffering.
It is the merciful thing to do-
- Oh, whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa, whoa,
hold your giblets.
Just pass me the gun, lad.
We'll go and see if Willie
really has been murdered.
Fine, but I'm keeping the gun.
Oh, you bugger.
Vincent, what are you
doing with the head?
I thought you had it.
I told you to
chuck it in after the legs.
Shh!
Did you hear
something, brother?
Upstairs.
Was there something
you needed, Mr. Raycraft?
Miss Hogwood,
I'm placing you and your
brother under arrest for,
for murder, and I must insist
that you come peacefully
with me to the magistrates'
court immediately
or I'll have no choice
but to use deadly force.
And how do you plan to
take us away, Mr. Raycraft?
We've butchered your horses,
murdered your coachman,
and there's no getting away
from the Three Claws tonight
nor any night!
My gun, Archie!
Quickly lad!
Jesus woman, you could have
had my bloody head
off with this.
Get off me you
fucking mad bitch!
Jesus!
Shoot her, Archie!
Get this made bitch off me!
No, her!
Sorry!
Come here sweetness, we're
dismembering the guests.
What's all this
bastardin' racket?!
I'm totally shagged
and barely had an hour
of me beauty sleep!
Fine!
Be as loud as you want,
but I'm leaving this stank hole
first thing in the morning!
Archie!
Archie, where's me pistol?
Help me untie these knots!
Sorry, lad.
Thank you.
I'm sure you'll think of
some way you can repay me.
Actually, I've got
something specific in mind
which involves all three of us,
and they ropes may
come in useful.
Get out of the way!
Horrace!
Hurry up, man!
You're stressing me out!
Martha!
My Martha, no!
Vincent Hogwood, I'm
placing you under arrest.
Archie, tie him up!
What did I miss?
These two scoundrels thought
they could get away with
murdering every last
one of us in our sleep.
What reason, exactly,
I only shudder to imagine.
Luckily, I saw through
their dastardly scheme
almost the minute I
stepped through the doors
of this unholy hovel.
All evening I lay in wait to
outsmart this foolish pair.
And when heard a
disturbance in the night,
I did what I had to, and I
saved every single one of us
from certain death.
You didn't save
your coachman, though.
You let them chop
him up into pieces.
Aye, chopped to pieces!
Well yes, I had to confirm
me theory was correct.
But now you've
got no coachman-
- All right, Windy Wallace,
let's not interrupt.
You owe me your lives,
that's what matters.
You're all gonna
die, Councilor,
a far more grizzly
and petrifying death
than what my sister and
I would have granted you.
You don't know what you've done.
You do not frighten
us, Mr. Hogface.
It's not me you need to fear.
All our lives, my sister and
I have kept an agreement,
an agreement with the vicious
beasties of these woods.
Unlike any creature you've ever
seen or heard of, Councilor.
Half man, half wolf,
all bloodthirsty rage.
For generations we've kept
a pact that's protected us.
A truce between man and monster.
What sort of pact?
Every blood moon,
when the inn is full,
we make an offering.
All the guests of
the Three Claws,
all the lowlifes and drunkards,
hiding from their
damnable pasts.
They all die at our hands.
'Til the next blood moon,
the beasts leave us in peace.
Well, how often's
a blood moon?
- Every three, four years.
- Six, seven months.
It's a small price to pay
for a life free of fear,
or dread of being
disemboweled by their claws,
or devoured by their teeth.
Well, we have Willie,
and we have your sister.
There's an offering.
It's not enough.
Six bodies for three
beasts, that's the deal.
There's three
of these savages?
And you'd better not
let them go hungry.
Well, there's you.
That takes it up to three.
They'll come here
with a vengeance.
Well, perhaps it's all
just deluded superstition,
Mr. Hogwood.
You and your sister are
a truly demented duo.
Perhaps there's no other
explanation for your blood lust.
What if he's telling
the truth, Horrace?
What if they are out there?
I've seen 'em.
They exist.
Then we send an
offering, like he says,
and pray it will suffice.
Fine.
You can chop her into bits
and we'll make the
bloody offering.
Do it, man!
Not me own sister,
Councilor, please.
Do as he says, Vincent.
I'm sorry, Martha.
Eww.
Ooh.
Thank God you found us.
We couldn't have
left the rest of you.
Here.
This might sting.
Sorry.
It's all right.
Thank you for taking care of me.
It's the least
I could do, sir.
Archie.
Whittock.
Jane.
It's a pleasure.
What are they going
to do to him down there?
I'm not sure.
Arrest him.
They should kill him.
Like he killed those horses.
What?
There's no way
of escaping here.
We will have to wait until
morning and head out on foot.
Where are you heading off to?
She's on the run.
From whom, if you
don't mind my asking?
My parents.
Those who know me back home.
Archie, if I show you something,
do you promise to
keep it a secret?
Jane, no.
I can trust him, Minnie.
Perhaps he can help us.
You have my word.
My God.
It's yours.
He is.
His name's Edgar.
What's he doing in
the bloody wardrobe?
Hiding.
No inn would have me.
Not with Edgar.
And I can't risk anyone
finding us or following us.
Where's his father?
There's no father.
Just a cruel man
from a cruel night.
Men.
I never asked for
this child, Archie.
Now that I have him, nobody's
gonna come between us.
He's all I have.
Shh, it's all right.
It's all right, Mommy's here.
Please forgive
me, oh mighty beast,
for this is all I could
bring, oh ancient one.
The inn is full
as you commanded,
but these guests are
not so easy to kill.
I am old, master, and we have
served you for many years.
But I can't deliver
on our promise.
Go, feast on them.
Take our inn for yourselves,
but I beg of you, spare me!
Please, spare me!
Have mercy, master!
Have mercy, God!
I don't think
he's coming back.
Is that you, Mr. Hogwood?
Did they accept me offering?
That'll be a no, I reckon!
Run, men!
We meet again,
bastard hound of Satan!
Oh, bugger that!
There's more of 'em!
No!
It's not gonna hold!
Take cover, lads!
What was that?
Stay here.
I go and look.
No, I'll go.
Hide the baby.
I think I just shat me pants.
Minnie?
Don't make a sound.
Hide.
What is it, Minnie?
You wouldn't believe
me if I told you.
Shoot him, Horrace!
Get away from me you
ugly son of a bitch!
Oh no!
Not my eye!
Oh God no, my eye!
My eye!
Bernard!
Oh, Bernard!
It's too late.
He's gone.
Help me!
I'm still alive!
Well, there's nothing
we can do for him now.
Aye.
God rest his soul.
Someone come
and shoot the bloody thing!
Don't!
It'll be suicide.
Eat me!
Come and eat me!
It's all right.
We're safe in here.
Archie no!
No!
Archie!
Now we're safe.
What happened to you?
Don't ask.
What devilry is this?
Seems Bernard's tall
tales were true after all.
These were once men.
There's two dead,
one still out there.
No doubt he'll be
back to finish the job.
And we'll be ready.
Aye.
Barricade all the
doors and windows.
If we can make it just one
more hour 'til sunrise,
'til the blood moon sets,
then we may survive.
Minnie?
Oh God!
She's gone.
You did what you could, lad.
Jane.
Oh my God, Jane!
It's all right.
We're all right.
Thank God.
Where's Minnie?
It got her.
What the hell is that?
You can't bring a baby
into a place like this.
Are you mad, woman?
I didn't know it
would be set upon
by flesh-hungry wolf monsters.
Werewolves is what they are.
Men who turn to beasts
under the spell of the moon.
That is exactly what I
killed back in Eddington.
Now do you believe me?
We need
your help, lad.
We need to barricade the place.
They'll be back for us.
Will you be all right?
Yes.
Go.
Shout if you need me.
Thank you, Archie.
♪ As I was a-walking
one morning in May ♪
♪ To hear the sweet birds
sing aloud from the square ♪
♪ I espied a young damsel,
so sweetly sang she ♪
♪ Down by the green bushes
she chanced to meet me ♪
♪ I stepped up to her
and thus I did say ♪
♪ Why wait you my fair
one so long by that way ♪
♪ I'll buy you fine beavers
and a fine silken gown ♪
♪ I will buy you
fine petticoats ♪
♪ With the unce
to the ground ♪
♪ If you prove loyal
and constant to me ♪
♪ And forsake your one true
love, I'll be married to thee ♪
Gilbert Pankhurst.
Help me.
No.
Let me in.
No, don't listen, man.
It's just the
walls talking again.
Let me in.
Bernard?
Horrace!
It's Bernard!
He's alive!
He can't be.
What's happening to him?
Oh, God!
He's turning!
He's become one of them.
Minnie.
Oh no!
Jane's alone up there!
Reverend, guard the entrance!
Bernard it's me, Gilbert!
You can't even remember Gilbert?
Have you come back for your rum?
You drank it all
ya daft bastard!
No, no!
Minnie?
How is she?
Incredibly hairy.
Oh, that don't
seem like Minnie.
Run!
Over here!
In here!
You can hide.
He can't reach you in there;
it's too small for him.
Archie!
I don't see what
choice we have.
Hurry!
Oh my God!
Don't come out 'til
both beasts are dead.
Go, lad!
No, no, no, no, no!
If you're looking for your
arm, you just missed it.
What's that?
I'm not sure.
A mouse?
It's a big mouse, Archie.
A rat, then?
It's not a bloody rat.
That'll learn ya.
Bitch, go on, die!
And to think I fucked you!
You're still a
filthy, drunken pig.
Oi!
It's all right, sweetheart.
Mother will be back soon.
Archie!
Thanks.
No, no!
Archie!
Don't you even think about
it, you big, hairy bitch!
Archie.
Archie, wake up.
Wake up!
We did it!
We got the last one.
It bit me, Jane.
No, no, no, no,
no, you'll be e.
I'll clean you up.
I can feel it, the bite,
the hunger, controlling me.
No, no, no, no, no.
No, don't leave me.
Don't leave me.
"I will strengthen
you and help you.
"I will uphold you with
my righteous right hand."
Archie!
Get back, it's begun!
I'm sorry, lad.
No, don't!
Look at him; he's been bitten!
He's gonna turn into
one of them beasts.
We done what we could.
Step away from him, Councilor.
It happened to Bernard,
it happened to Minnie.
You're going to
slaughter us all.
I swear I'm gonna blow your
head off if you shoot him!
You'll damn us all!
No, he's right.
It's all right, Jane.
I'm turning.
I won't be able to stop myself
from killing.
And when the sun
comes up soon what then?
You'll change back,
you'll be Archie again.
I have no idea.
But I have to find out.
I realize we haven't
known each other long,
but I'm not ready
to say goodbye.
Nor I, Jane.
Oh Christ.
It's happening; go!
Don't hurt him!
Just run, Jane!
We've gotta leave this inn.
Damn ye lad!
Damn ye!
Reverend, we need to leave!
Help me move this furniture.
Quick!
No, Archie.
It's us.
It's me, Jane.
I know you're in
there, somewhere.
Fight it, Archie.
Remember who you are.
That's right, Archie.
It's me.
Spirit of Jesus come upon us!
Fill us with holy anger!
Wrench us from all desires
that breed violence!
Compel us with the
fury of your love!
O Lamb of God, grant us peace!
Jane.
Promise you'll
write to me, lad,
let me know how the two of
you are getting on, will you>
The three of us.
Of course we will.
Anything you want,
just ask old Horrace.
And on the next blood moon-
- You'll lock me
in the county jail.
Just for the night, lad.
That should give those
scallywags a bit of a fright.
Oh, and before I forget,
the witness reports
and warrant for your arrest.
No hard feelings.
Provided by explosiveskull
https://twitter.com/kaboomskull