Riot police, sons-of-bitches...
Riot police, sons-of-bitches!
You sleeping here or coming home?
- Whatcha got?
- Good shit.
- One gram, 10 euros.
- One.
Wait for me here.
Didn't you see me?
Hey, fuckin' Fascist,
can't fight alone?
Get in the car.
Get in the car!
You guys feeling tough?
Bring it on!
Listen, I'll tell you just once.
Never come here again pushing
this shit around families and kids.
- Carolina!
- Daddy!
Don't move.
What is it?
What the fuck are you sayin'?
Shut up.
How much did you fuckin' drink?
Let us through, it's our right.
It's our right to go to Rome!
Get back!
Close ranks!
You have to stay back.
Hey, cut the spittin'!
You piece of shit!
Open!
That's Carletto's seat.
And that's his twin's.
When Carletto gets here,
I'll get up.
Nice goin', rookie!
First day on the job,
- you cracked two workers' heads,
how do you feel? - Great.
- Hey, bro'.
- Hey, guys.
- Wanna hit?
- No, thanks.
What's up with him?
Hi, Mom.
Couldn't you get assigned
to another unit?
It pays best.
What the fuck's this?
What do they want?
To put us out on the street
like they promised.
But they forgot the other promise:
To give you your own place.
..At the port, heading for Rome,
they were stopped by the police.
The demonstrators
are asking for urgent measures...
- Your Unit is getting more popular
everyday. - Get off it, Maria.
Where's he going?
We said no going out for a month.
You try telling him.
He ended up at headquarters for
brawling, he can't do what he wants.
He doesn't listen to me.
Look, be around the house more,
maybe you can get it in his head.
Okay.
I'll go shower.
Stop, you'll wake the building.
- What's this mean?
- Didn't you get the letter?
- I want a separation.
- Miriam,
this is my house, hear me?
And Carolina's my daughter!
- If you love her, be more careful.
- What do you mean?
- That supermarket thing.
- That again?
Which adds to the crap
you've always given her and me.
Don't make me repeat it,
open this fucking door, let me in.
Open this door!
- Carolina!
- Say hi to Daddy.
- Daddy's little girl, hi.
- He's sleeping elsewhere...
I was in the south curve,
but I had better tickets.
At a certain point, I see an opening
between the barriers and I say:
"I'll go through there", but
as soon as I do a riot cop comes,
he grabs me, says I can't be there.
- He grabs you?
- Yes. He yanks my arm hard,
- almost broke it.
- And what did you do?
I try to explain I have a ticket
and that he's hurting me,
but he doesn't even let me finish,
first he yells to shut up,
then he hits me in the mouth
with his helmet,
and this is the result.
- Is the officer who hit you here?
- Yeah.
Could you point him out?
He's sitting there.
I remind the court the defendant
is not new to this,
he has more than five suits pending
for aggravated assault.
Maybe it's about time
you dampened your exuberance.
Mazinga, you not only suck,
you're deaf too!
- Didn't you hear me?
- Only one guy deaf here.
I might be deaf, but I see good.
- Then see about fuckin' off.
- Yes sir, Chief, sir!
You look like my Grampa
with that body! Look here.
- Know what makes us different?
- 300 grams of brain, Carletto.
Zone diet, a balance of carbs,
fats and protein,
40-30-30.
You trim down like a sonofabitch
and fat disappears.
That's where
your grams of brain went!
Laugh, Nero, but I'm in the Zone.
Good, then take my advice:
Stay there.
What's wrong,
you worried about the hearing?
I'm pissed off.
Me and Nero
are witnesses, you know.
Three cops against a poor
sports fan. Not enough of us.
Not many but the right ones.
What's going on, huh?
I have two kids!
Is this any way
to put people out on the street?
Hey, no answer? I'm not invisible!
- You have to leave here.
- I'm not budging.
See to this, I'm going upstairs.
You heard him? You have to leave.
- It's useless telling me.
- Sir, please!
You can plead to the Virgin Mary,
I'm staying in my home.
- It's not your home.
- Yes, it is,
all my things are here,
so it's mine.
- Get up!
- Let go of him!
Right now.
That stuff's mine.
What are you doing?
It's my stuff!
Since it's down on the ground now,
your home is down there.
Rookie!
I mean you, what's your name?
- You must have a name.
- Costantini Adriano.
You won't get the job done
by attacking people.
Does kicking people out
seem like a job?
City Hall is kicking them out,
it's our job to limit damages,
you almost did some!
If you attack one, a revolt
breaks out and 100 get hurt.
Destroy him psychologically,
that way you resolve the problem
and no one gets hurt. Just use this,
with this, you'll get results.
Nice words. Can I go?
- Am I dismissed, Sir?
- Go, go.
He doesn't want to learn,
let it go.
Can't.
- Your mother's house?
- It's still occupied.
You got a job?
You're not around any more.
Adriano Costantini, Mr. tough guy?
- Adriano Costantini, that's all.
- I say Mr. tough guy.
- And if I don't like it?
- Your problem.
- Who the fuck's this?
- Relax, Gabriele, it's okay.
- Sure?
- Sure.
- See you around.
- Bye.
Why are you here?
- What do you want?
- I'm here to do you a favor.
- Meaning? - You work on a team,
you have to fraternize.
- Fraternize.
- With the older ones.
Don't worry, you'll be back
before midnight... Cinderella.
This is Carletto.
Anything you wanna say to him?
You know where we're going?
Me and him
have nothing more to say.
- Open up.
- I thought I'd forgotten something.
- That'll teach you to be
a tough guy. - You bastards!
Open up!
- Have a beer.
- That gives you a pot belly.
- Drink it.
- You nuts?
Then I have to eat half a kilo
of broccoli and string beans.
I told you, 40-30-30.
- I hear you, drink the beer.
- No, you don't understand.
- I'm good like this.
- I see that. Yeah, really.
Why the silence?
Adriano-Costantini-that's-all,
do you hear me?
- Open it.
- Wait a minute.
- What if he's suffocating?
- He's acting.
Relax.
You call this fraternizing?
- We wanted to see how you think.
- Another sermon?
You're no street kid now,
you're a riot cop,
- you wear a uniform. - A riot cop
always obeys his commander.
They said that times
at the Academy.
You don't fucking get it,
he's not your commander,
he's your brother,
he teaches you to live.
You're wrong, I'm an only child.
Cut the crap, kid.
A riot cop's worthless alone.
He makes sense only in a team.
You're part of a team,
or you're nothing.
Now you're part of the team.
Good, I want you pissed off
for the stadium on Sunday.
We're counting on you.
Now who'll fuckin' drive?
Not me.
Riot police, sons-of-bitches...
Don't look down,
stare at them in their eyes.
It's nothing serious.
Hear me? It's nothing serious.
Get your hands off me!
On your feet.
Open your jacket.
Nothing.
Come on!
Your jacket.
Sit down.
- You, stand up.
- No.
You have a badge
and I have a ticket.
- Stand up.
- I said no.
Put the club down,
leave him alone!
You shit, you're hurting him!
What the fuck are you doing?
- He wanted to take my club.
- Piece of shit!
Shut up or it's my turn.
Wait outside.
Shut up. Open your jacket,
take the scarf off and shut up.
Let me see you, do I know you?
Got a record?
- No record.
- Hand over your I.D.
Listen to me.
That guy took your club
and bashed you in the face.
In getting it back,
you exchanged a blow or two.
Nero and me will say
we couldn't get there in time,
end of story.
I have to say some bullshit?
Now it's not bullshit.
A draft can kill you
What the fuck do you want?
Sit down.
Shit.
You found out who gave me
this gift?
It wasn't the Neapolitans,
we didn't find a thing.
What's the difference?
He was knifed.
Good evening.
We managed to stitch up the
ligament, with the right therapy
you'll walk without a limp.
But can I go back to work?
I don't know yet,
it was a serious lesion,
- you'll need patience.
- Just what I don't have.
- Try to find some.
- Good bye.
Think about getting better,
not work.
She's right.
Think about getting better.
I'll find those guys,
it's a promise,
we'll take care of them together.
Bye, Mazinga.
Think I didn't hear your friend?
Giancarlo?
It's turned off.
Hi, Elisa. Listen, make sure parents
park in the right areas, not...
- On the walkway, I know.
- Then do it, or cars can't move.
- This isn't a public school.
- Okay, Professor.
It's important.
- Professor of what?
- Who knows, what's the difference?
- You have a shitty job.
- Look who's talking.
What are you doing?
That's a mini-block of fats.
Open for the lady.
Forget it, on your salary
you couldn't even pay for her gas.
Know what tuition is
for this school?
What's the matter, does it piss you
off to be caged up in here?
Shouldn't it?
Is this what we wanted as kids?
I just wanted to see
the Roma Team.
Well, now you get in free
at the stadium.
- How's Mazinga?
- A bum deal.
Does your cousin still
hang around with hooligans?
- My cousin's a jerk.
- That's why I asked you.
Okay.
I'll see if he knows anything.
She's kicking me out
and thinks she's right?
Counselor, I'm not signing anything.
Nothing.
Just think,
those guys are colleagues too.
I wish they'd drop
by the Unit someday...
Costantini, what's the difference
between you and them?
- The leash?
- Stop playing tough guy.
Why are you a cop?
And why exactly a riot cop?
You don't even know that?
Turn your brain on,
so you can answer me.
Get your hands out of your pockets,
stand straight, if you can.
Put your beret on.
If you don't respect the uniform,
how can others?
So?
What's his cousin say?
It was Romans hiding as Neapolitans,
they're the ones who did this
to you.
Now I just have to find them.
And when you do?
What do you mean?
If you're worried about your leg,
it'll get back to normal.
How do you know that?
You're a fucking cop,
not a doctor.
Your leg hurts? I'm sorry.
But these things pass,
what doesn't is who we are.
Get better fast, damn you.
Joint custody of your daughter,
500 euros a month in alimony
and the house goes to your wife.
Any questions?
If there's nothing else,
you can sign.
- Please, don't send us away.
- Get up.
Don't send us away! Please!
- I'll do whatever you want.
- You have to get up.
- I'll do whatever you want!
- Knock it off.
Now you've pissed me off.
Tone it down.
Our problems stay at home.
Are you all right?
It was nothing.
Please, get up.
We're following the vote-count
of the second local elections ballot
in this long spring of elections
with some important differences...
Hello.
- I'm here to meet Enrico Mancini.
- He's in his office.
Adriano! Come here.
- How are you?
- Fine, you?
Sorry for the mess, the election
campaign's in full swing.
You disappeared.
The party still needs guys
like you.
I'm with the police now, riot unit.
Really? How come?
But it suits you,
you always had a mean punch!
Why did you want to see me?
The city wants to kick
my mother out,
they're throwing her out on the
street, she has nowhere to go.
I mean, she has a place,
they assigned her welfare housing,
but it's occupied by illegals.
When will our mayor
ever kick them out?
Pretty soon they'll be giving them
the right to vote.
That's why I called you, maybe...
You could give me a hand.
A hand?
You're not asking a favor,
you're demanding a right,
your mother's right
to her own home.
The wind's changing, people
are tired, they want security,
they want to take back
the motherland.
We'll win this time
and with the new mayor
you won't have to ask any favors.
I spoke to Santini,
head of personnel.
I don't even know
if I'll get my leg back, Maria!
Want to keep doing riot control?
I'm a riot cop, are you ashamed?
You're a cop yourself.
Right, you don't have to be
on the street
- to be a good cop.
- And where should I be,
- warming some chair in an office?
- I might be warming a chair,
- but at least I'm trying to raise
my son. - Meaning?
You don't even see he's not around.
That's new? He hasn't come once
since I got here.
For days now, he hasn't
even come by the house.
- What do you mean? Where does
he sleep? - I don't know.
HATED AND PROUD
STOP WITH IMMIGRANTS
ITALY FOR ITALIANS
Recreation's over,
we're going home.
Tomorrow you even go back
to school.
Take your hands off.
- Who the fuck are you?
- Who are you?
He's a riot cop.
- One that beats up guys at the
game? - I can beat you up here too.
Okay!
Get out, this is our house,
cops aren't welcome.
- Don't you like my face? - I don't
like servants, guys like you,
instead of defending Italians,
you fight kids at the stadium.
So you defend Italians?
A bunch of skinheads
screeching like monkeys?
No, I'm doing your job,
making sure this doesn't become
a mosque.
This is our house,
and if you're not Italian,
you'd better go back home.
You convinced me,
in fact, we're going home.
I'm staying here.
Hear that?
Now get out,
this is no place for you.
Servant!
- Yo, Cobra. - They still haven't
kicked you out of the country?
They don't make assholes
like me any more.
- And him? - Filling in for Mazinga
for a few days.
- Adriano, this is Mustafa.
- Pleasure.
He's kinda dark, but...
he's a brother too.
Know the rules?
Never say I'm a cop,
because moonlighting's illegal,
and if I see anything strange,
I tell Cobra.
No commotion.
Don't worry, he's a good kid.
I'll bring her back for dinner.
Be good.
- You're sure you wanted ice cream?
- Yes.
- Then why not eat it?
- I'm waiting for Mommy.
I think you're bored.
- You're bored, right?
- A little.
Carolina,
want to see where Daddy works?
Yes.
Want to?
You do?
Hey, friend!
- Give one cigarette?
- I don't smoke.
Then give money to buy
one cigarette.
Give some money,
some coins to buy one cigarette.
Give me some money?
Are you deaf?
Besides being a nigger?
Nigger, give me money
to buy cigarette.
Go home, no? A few coins!
Coins to buy cigarette.
Come on, nigger, some coins,
to buy cigarette and go away.
Thank you, nigger.
Cobra did this, Daddy's friend,
remember him?
He's good at drawing, isn't he?
When Daddy goes to work,
he dresses like that.
What is it? I can't now.
I have Carolina, how can I?
Okay, on my Wall...
Sicilian,
are you good with kids?
I'll leave her with you for an hour.
You got better eyesight,
does it say toilet here?
- Don't think so. - Then why's
this asshole pissing here?
- He's talking to you.
- What have you got here?
- If I pissed where your kid plays?
- What the fuck do you want?
- Come on, clean up the park.
- Me?
I said to clean the park.
Go on.
Clean up, then fuck off
to your own country.
You missed that.
There's a bottle cap,
don't you see it?
I'm back here tomorrow.
This park's gotta shine!
If you're here, I'll kick your ass,
never come back.
Do I pick this up myself?
Complaining?
They're buying tickets home.
Take back our motherland, fuck 'em!
You kick two out,
a hundred come back.
- Better two than nothing.
- Want to beat them all up?
Yeah, all of them.
When was this picture taken?
About when you started jerking off.
In Genoa, at the G8 summit in 2001
we're from the Seventh.
- Seventh what?
- Seventh Unit.
A team of 70 real men,
brothers who had just one ideal:
Clean the shit out of Italy.
- Italy. Not two drunks in a park
- That again?
Why, isn't it true?
If politicians hadn't screwed us
with that G8 Diaz school story,
this country would be
different now.
When a drunk Romanian
or a fucking hooligan insults you,
he's insulting the State
and you should arrest him.
Now what do they teach
in the course on public order?
- You have to be attacked
before you can intervene. - Get it?
They teach you to bow your head,
respect the shits.
- That's why I left.
- Why don't you tell the truth?
A rock broke your eardrum
at the Roma-Inter game,
and you cracked two heads
and attacked your superior.
You didn't leave,
they kicked you out.
Diet over?
What really happened
at the Diaz school?
The biggest fuck up of our lives
It was a massacre.
I'll be right there.
- Fuck!
- What is it?
I left: Carolina at the barracks.
What is it?
Still the G8 mess?
No.
I'm sorry you weren't there today.
But I don't give a damn, really.
I have other things to think about.
What do you want?
Ever thought about
giving it all up?
Give in? Never.
Tell me something,
how much fun was it today?
How much did you like
cleaning up the park?
- Lots.
- And so?
Would you give it up?
No.
Can I show you something?
That's it...
third floor, where the bike is.
Which one's your mother's?
Where the fuck's he from?
Want to ask him?
- Who is it?
- Is that you, Rami?
Yeah, who is it?
I was just wondering,
with this name, where are you from?
Who are you? What do you want?
Be polite, don't answer
a question with a question,
that's how we do it here.
'Cause in your country?
He's talking to his wife,
Ramina's there too.
Put your wife on!
Damn you.
If you not stop, I call police.
Here's some bad news.
I am the police.
Where are you from?
- Where are you from?
- Tunisia.
- How long have you been in Italy?
- One year.
Do you work legally?
Have you got a work visa?
- What do you want from me?
- You don't work legally
and you have no visa,
so you can't stay here.
Right?
- Right?
- I not do anything wrong.
Can you stay in Italy or not?
No.
- Are you still there?
- I'm here.
Go back to bed, it's late.
My apologies to your wife.
Let's go,
your politician friend
will get him out, right?
Stealing from your own home?
Go ahead, this stuff's
worthless anyway, right?
Like your father.
You know what I do
day and night to give you a future?
At best I'm being hit
by rocks, spit, insults,
and at worst,
I can even get knifed!
Knock it off! You don't do
this work for me, you like it,
you like playing war,
beating people to death.
Want to beat me? Go ahead, beat me.
Take your rags and get out.
Fuck off, get out.
Mr. Sartoni says I broke
his two teeth for no reason,
he was doing nothing,
and someone seems to believe it.
Keep to the facts against you.
Think I like beating people up?
I enjoy it?
You're wrong.
Before deciding
who's innocent and who's guilty
you should at least ask yourself
what the riot unit does.
Every Sunday
we face people like Sartoni,
who, in the best of cases,
spit on you,
but when they're real pissed off,
they throw everything at you.
And a good riot cop
has to stand there, immobile,
protecting himself with his shield.
Then, when the fans get
even more pissed,
then and only then,
if the commanding officer authorizes
us, we can we defend ourselves.
At that point, you're in a battle,
all you can think of
is how to get home alive.
There's just one way to do that,
stay clear-headed.
But in those moments
your heart's pounding,
your adrenaline spikes,
you think your head will explode,
you hear nothing,
you only have your brothers
next to you.
Your brothers
are all you can count on.
That's what happens
at the stadium on Sundays.
An ugly black page
for soccer in Sicily.
It all happened
in the final minutes
of the 40th derby,
Catania-Palermo.
Violent clashes broke out
outside the stadium,
clashes which caused
the death of a police officer.
Chief Commissioner Filipino Raciti
was hit in the face
by a homemade explosive,
he was taken to Garibaldi Hospital
and died there. Unfortunately,
news just in a moment ago,
it seems there's another officer
from police headquarters in Catania
who's suspended between life
and death at this moment...
A colleague is dead.
A brother.
It's useless crying,
it's time to be pissed off.
Tomorrow we all go
to the Ministry of the Interior,
to talk with the Minister,
to say we don't like dying
like dogs!
Let him go out on the streets
to be killed.
It's our right,
you'd better let us go inside.
Better if you go back to the
barracks and no one gets hurt.
If I order a charge, they'll be
scraping you off the floor.
Think you're the only ones pissed
off for the death of a colleague?
Let us talk to the Minister!
If things are better for everyone,
they are for you too.
We're the police,
it doesn't work that way.
We have to watch
our colleagues die on the streets?
Officer, mind your place.
What's the deal?
Put a delegation together
and you can go talk to a supervisor.
Two of us are going up,
and they'd better listen!
A colleague died,
and no one gives a shit.
They look at you, nod,
make promises.
What did you expect?
Think a dead cop
could change things?
Know what I say?
I'm fed up with the Minister,
my son, this job
this fucking leg
that's not getting better.
The doctor said
I'll limp for the rest of my life.
- What are you saying?
- Just what I said.
- What is it?
- A court order,
suspending visitation rights
with your daughter.
But I signed separation papers
that say I can see her.
Before you abandoned her.
I left: her in police barracks,
the safest place in the world.
What can a father do
to get his rights?
My daughter's 8 years old
and has the right to have a father,
the law says so, and a father
has the right to see his daughter,
it's the law. Unless
he's a criminal, but I'm not,
I'm a cop, a servant of the State,
paid to defend everyone's rights.
But who defends mine?
As a father, I have no more rights
you've taken them all away,
like I'm a criminal.
Actually, worse,
because when people come here
wanting to attack you
for stealing from them,
that's when you want me down here,
saving your asses,
defending your rights and of the
damned people who voted for you!
But I can't see my daughter,
because I'm not a cop then,
I'm a criminal.
But that can't be,
either I'm always good for you
or I never am.
So if I'm never good for you,
you can take this uniform back.
Get dressed and get out.
Kick me out.
Get your hands off me
or you'll ruin your pretty suit.
Yesterday evening,
just after 8 p.m.,
Giovanna Reggiani was attacked
as she walked along the path...
Giovanna Reggiani walked
this path every evening
and it's here she was tortured
and raped by a young Romanian
from a gypsy camp
about 100 meters away.
A gypsy camp located
in an area City Hall
had promised to clean up.
Councilor candidate
Enrico Mancini says
the city had already activated
evacuation procedures.
It's time to think seriously
about the Roman outskirts.
We're standing in front
of the Regina Coeli prison,
just arriving is the defense
attorney for Romulus Mailat
the 24-year-old Romanian...
You're a piece of shit,
you bastard! You gotta die.
Listen, we have to clear out
Reggiani's murderer's gypsy camp,
get ready.
No messes, Cobra.
You're defending them
instead of protecting us?
You should kick them
out of this country.
Turn that way, you clowns!
Clowns? Step back.
You came to see the show?
You forgot how to maintain order?
They're calling from everywhere,
anger's growing,
if you don't get these Romanians,
there'll be hell to pay.
- Who says?
- The ones who are pissed off.
The ones like you, me, them!
Don't yell, I can hear you.
These Romanians do
what the fuck they want,
we need to show them
this is our motherland.
- It's our home.
- Right!
Ma'am, a euro,
a euro for a sandwich.
I didn't like your show
outside Parliament, not at all.
Article 48?
I'm not crazy.
A psych visit will decide that.
You're on suspension
for the time being.
You can go.
If you wanna dance,
I can help you too.
- Why are you here?
- Am I bothering you?
What the fuck's this guy looking at?
Did I spoil the party?
You say you're with our kid
but you're screwing him?
- What?
- Want to screw my wife, Cuba?
- You're wrong.
- I'm not wrong at all.
What are you doing? I work here,
want to get me fired?
Is it revenge?
Take it out on yourself,
not on me.
Look at you,
you like playing crazy.
It makes you feel important,
the master of the world!
What do you and your friends say?
"Take back the motherland".
But this isn't your home
and you're not crazy,
you're just a poor asshole.
I really fucked up.
You earn 1,400 euros a month,
with overtime it's 1,800,
you do a few jobs off duty
and get to 2,000.
You go to Cuba, you're rich,
you meet a girl at a disco,
you tell her you're rich,
she loves you, you marry her,
but when you come back
you're still making 2,000 a month
and you each have nothing to say.
You go back to being a fucking cop
and a Cuban whore.
But he shouldn't have had a kid.
What do you want to do?
Nero's a brother,
brothers make mistakes,
but you don't abandon them.
- He hit his wife!
- You don't abandon brothers.
Ever.
- You've seen a doctor?
- What did you come for?
- To fix this thing.
- It can't be fixed any more.
Miriam,
Nero made a mistake, but...
the two of you have
to resolve this
just between you.
Talk to each other and
things go back like they were.
I say this for your good,
and especially for your daughter's.
Who are you to talk about
the good of my daughter?
You just don't want your friend
to go to jail for beating me.
He has to, his place is in jail.
Nero's already in trouble, if you
report him now, he'll lose his job!
Then who'll support your daughter?
You thought about that?
You're using my daughter
to save his ass,
you're a shit just like him,
get out.
What's there to look at?
Understand, Ma'am?
I'm sorry, this is all I can do.
For the moment,
the city assigns you a hotel room,
it's not much, but...
You can keep your charity.
Put that stuff down.
Put that fucking stuff down!
Careful, I'll report you for verbal
abuse of a police officer.
The judge.
According to article 530.2
of the Code of Criminal Procedure...
Acquitted!
My new address,
you might need it
to come asking for my vote.
I'm sorry, I need time.
You need time? My mother's living
in a 35-square meter cellar
for 700 euros a month,
that's all we can afford.
There's not only your mother,
but lots of people,
it's a complex problem...
A right's a right,
nothing fucking 'complex' about it.
My mother has a right to that house,
but she can't move in
because the State's lost respect for
itself, for the rules, for rights,
because it's governed
by pieces of shit like you.
I see why you're a riot cop:
Because you're an idiot.
Only an idiot can be a riot cop.
Now call the cops, asshole.
- You're sure? - The ones
who knifed Mazinga are there,
- definitely.
- Why doesn't Special Ops go?
What's the problem? They're there
and we'll go get 'em, they're ours!
- Let's call Special Ops.
- Why? - Leave it to them.
We'll go get 'em,
and call our Special Ops afterward.
What do we do?
Let's go.
- We'll go get them.
- Fuck 'em.
If you don't want to come,
you can go home.
Knock it off.
Riot police, sons-of-bitches...
- Knock that off. - Don't like
the music or the lyrics?
Stop!
It was hidden in the bathroom.
It's full of blades.
And there's this too.
They're the ones who beat up
the Albanians at the supermarket.
Take your son home,
tell him to forget everything,
forever.
I'll reset these guys' memories,
if they want to tell,
the bag goes to the judge.
- Call Special Ops
- Not today.
- Do it now.
- I said no, today's a tie.
Today's a tie? We're the police.
Or are these speeches
only for the others?
- That guy's the son of a brother.
- He's a shit.
Him and his friends knife
our brothers,
- or have you forgotten?
- Today it ends right here.
- Is that clear?
- No, it's not.
- It's not right.
- Want to call the cops? Go ahead.
But you have to do it.
I'm not getting a brother
in trouble,
not even when he smashes
some guy's face on a train.
Go home, take a shower,
and forget,
because nothing happened today.
Nothing happened.
What happened?
Nothing.
Will you tell me what happened?
Nothing... nothing happened!
Hide this bag,
it's our life insurance.
- A shit life.
- Whatever you like,
but put this fuckin' bag away.
Go away or I'll call for help.
Last night I was about to smash
in Giancarlo's head, Mazinga's son.
I wanted to slaughter him,
because him and his friends
knifed his father.
His friends knifed his father
and I wanted to kill his son.
What do you want from me?
Let me see Carolina again.
Please,
she's the only nice thing I have.
Please.
- Hello.
- Come in.
Why did you ask to see me?
What is it?
Aggravated assault?
Is this a joke?
What do you want him for?
He's accused of the attempted murder
of three Albanians.
And this is for you.
Five minutes, then leave,
only because you're a colleague.
Thank you.
Listen to me... When the judge
questions you, deny everything.
Clashes at the stadium,
beating up the Albanians,
you know nothing,
you didn't do anything.
Understand?
Are you listening?
Yeah, you want me to say
I wasn't there,
but I was and I want it known
I did the right thing.
- What?
- I did what had to be done!
These guys steal our jobs,
they rape and kill,
someone has to deal with it,
since you and your friends don't.
So you and your friends will?
What is it?
You're scared if I tell the truth,
that you'll be mixed up in it?
I'm already mixed up in it.
I've been mixed up in it
my whole life.
You're sixteen,
don't ruin yourself, Giancarlo,
don't ruin your life.
As long as you're under
investigation,
this is the best thing
It's for your own good.
You're a rat.
You're hiding, huh?
Good for you.
You shouldn't be afraid,
no one wants to dirty their hands
with a guy like you.
Know why? Because you're worth
less than this piss.
- So, what are you worth?
- You have the nerve to talk?
Nero and Mazinga are screwed
because of you, they'll be suspended
and then discharged.
You're a traitor.
So, what are you, cops?
Riot cops,
who piss and spit on their uniforms,
every time you cover your ass
and your friends'.
No, you ain't shit now,
you're fucking nothing.
Next time I see you, I'll kill you.
I wanted an honest job,
and being a cop's an honest job.
That's why I'm in the police.
It was no accident,
the cop shot to kill, understand?
Everyone in Rome knew Gabriele,
he was a good kid,
a brother, and the cops killed him.
Explain why, when Raciti died,
they suspended all the games
and instead, today the games are on.
Where's the justice?
There is none.
A 28 year-old guy
isn't worth a cop.
It's 4 p.m., welcome back
on the air. A Sunday to forget.
A young man of 26, Gabriele Sandri,
was killed this morning
at a rest stop
along the A1 highway, near Alvarez.
The victim is a Lazio Team fan,
hit by the gunfire
of a police officer.
His name is Gabriele Sandri,
it was a tragic error,
as announced this afternoon
by the Alvarez Chief of Police.
We'll go to the rest stop
with our correspondent...
Get ready, we're dancing tonight.
Carletto, what is it?
They're organizing.
Roma fans, Lazio fans, skinheads,
all out to get you.
They're meeting at the stadium,
they want to kill a cop,
an eye for an eye.
We're right here.
Fuck you, they want a corpse!
Bye.
- Everyone outside, we're leaving.
- The game's been canceled.
But not our assignment.
Come on, guys, move your asses.
Inspector, don't send just the guys
on duty, it's not enough.
Want to send the army?
The shits are organizing,
there's thousands of 'em,
they're pissed off, we're too few.
- These are the orders.
- They're crap.
Get promoted,
then you can give the orders.
Then you don't understand,
the politicians want our blood,
they want another Raciti
to make people forget the screw-up
of one jerk in a uniform.
You'd prefer to be exempted
from duty?
Exempt my ass.
I have to pick up
my personal belongings.
Now I feel safe, with a cripple
and a nut job covering my ass.
What was the name
of that school in Genoa?
I bet we pay for it tonight.
Here they come!