Give me something to eat.
Give me some food.
Why are you asleep? Wake up.
You will become wealthy.
Your children
will become healthy.
And they will study a lot.
You have got stuck at
this word. Continue.
You cannot even pronounce
the chants correctly.
Oh Priest, hurry up with
whatever you have to do.
We don't have time
for such minute details.
Your parents had a lot of
time to give birth to you.
To raise you! And you don't
have any time for them?
Look, when my father
expired, he was 50 years old.
If I keep chanting like you,
l' ll turn 50 years right here.
- Yes, l' ll turn 50
years old too. - Yes.
A person should do every
task with full dedication.
Or else, you won't
get the desired result.
Nowadays, even a priest
should complete his work fast.
Or else, you won't
get the desired fees.
Yes, you won't!
I cannot go to hell, just
for a little fees money.
- You go away from here!
- Why should we go?!
- Alright. Then l' ll go. - Go.
Even you are very stubborn.
If you would have agreed
with them,...
-...what would have happened?
- l' m a priest, not a politician!
The way they shorten
their speech...
... to stop the public
from going,...
...I cannot shorten
the incantations.
To live in this world, one has
to learn the ways of this world.
Your hosts are
also like customers.
One who wants to earn money,
has to agree with his customers.
-They may be customers,but l...
- Then you won't get any fees!
Such fees is a punishment for me!
I cannot go to
hell for their money.
Heaven and hell
are a different case.
But we have to eat!
And your religion
cannot fill our stomachs!
Because of your principles,...
... if you keep losing
hosts like this,...
...then how will you
manage this house?
Your village is small.
But your family is very big.
I cannot do both.
Neither can I make
the family small...
... nor can I increase
the village size.
- Understand? - But
l' ll ask you one thing.
Your daughter Shalini
has passed her metric...
... & is sitting idle at home.
Why can't she go out and work?
She will surely earn some money.
You mean that now l' ll have to
live on my daughter's earnings?
So what is the harm? In a job,
a salary is attained every month.
A priest's earnings
are unpredictable.
- You never know when to expect
it. - No, that will never happen.
Ram Shastri's daughter
will go out and work?
No. And she is
still very young too.
She is a child.
Listen! It is already
8 o' clock in the morning.
I've already returned
from the fields,...
...and you are still sleeping!
- Will you get up or not?
- Who is it?
What is this?
- You are laughing?
- On your face...
Uncle! Uncle, don't tell him.
Don't tell him what happened.
But what is the matter?
Why are you laughing?
So uncle? Isn't he
looking like a king?
So, this was your mischief?
I thought that only small
children sleep till so late.
So I made you look older.
When l' ll teach you a lesson,
you' ll always remember it.
Okay, first go and
remove the moustache.
- You are looking like a demon.
- Really?
- Uncle, this moustache
will never come off. - Why?
Because it is made of coal tar.
It won't come off, even if
you' ll scrub it with a stone.
- Never? - Never!
But whatever you say. This
moustache is praiseworthy.
Atleast, this moustache
made father laugh.
Wait! Why are you entering
so quietly, like a thief?
Where are you coming from?
Where had you gone till now?
Forget about doing
housework,....
... she doesn't have time
to come and eat too.
Just look.
You have become so old.
And you play like children.
In your age, I was the
mother of two children.
And you behave like
a small child yourself.
I say, stop it!
The daughter
has grown so old...
... and the father is
getting others married.
But not his own daughter.
Look! There is already a
shortage of food in the house.
And this crow is giving
the message...
... of the arrival of a guest!
Go away from here!
Someone make him go away!
He's not even moving.
Sending the crow
away is of no use.
We should stop the train in
which the guests are coming.
Tell me! Will you come
with me? You won't? I' ll go.
Hey! You are secretly
smoking a cigarette?
- Hey, it's you?
- If l' ll tell uncle,...
-...do you know what will
happen? - How will you go?
- l' ll tie you up.
- With what will you tie me?
Will you tie a rope
around my neck?
Yes, l' ll surely do
that. But not a rope.
- A `Mangalsutra'. - Come on!
You cannot tie a
`Mangalsutra' around my neck.
I' m a Brahmin, and you' re not.
The entire village will
malign our family name.
Let them.
What difference does
that make to me?
Will you drink up
the entire pond,...
... or will you leave
a little for others?
Why do you say anything?
You want water to get rid
of tobacco smell.
And I want water
to fill my stomach.
- Father. - What is it?
I want to buy a Botany record
for college.
I'd told you earlier...
... that I don't have money
for your college education.
But you ignored me
and said that...
... the education is free
for the first year.
Education is free.
But the government
doesn't give free books.
- What did you say?
- I didn't say anything.
But I say that one who cannot
reach their aims....
... shouldn't think of victory.
That is foolishness.
Just look at his hair style.
He is a Brahmin. A Brahmin
of the new generation.
Take this Rs.2. I
just have this much.
- Have you completed
your prayers? - Yes.
Yes! This is it.
Come on, get down.
This is my brother's home.
Get down.
Really? We have
reached uncle's home.
Wait. I' ll have the money sent.
Brother! Sister-in-law!
- Where are you?
- Come, Janki.
Really? Uncle?
- Mother! - Poorna!
The crow had told us yesterday.
It was useless for
you to chase it away.
Come aunty!
Where is sister-in-law?
First tell me
about yourself, Janki.
- Brother! - Hey! Why
did you start crying?
Is your husband fine?
- Come sister. - Sister-in-law.
- Really? Aunty!
Brother, first let
the horse cart go.
The fool was asking for Rs.2.50.
I have decided at Rs.2.
Let him go.
- Go and give the Rs.2 to the
horse cart owner.-But father,...
-...my Botany record?
- Go and give it to him.
Why are you crying?
Is your husband fine?
Don't ask!
- Shall I tell you? - Tell us!
- What happened, Meenu?
Actually, my father
has run away from home.
Ran away from home?
And you are laughing?
- Aren't you ashamed? - Brother,
you had lovingly named me Janki.
My fate was just like my name.
Lord Rama's wife, Janaki, had
faced just 1 4 years of exile.
God knows how many years
my exile is going to last.
1 4 years, 1 4 months or 1 4 days.
Whatever it may be.
Now l' ll live with you.
Till then, you will have
to do everything for me.
Food, water and everything else.
Oh God! This is empty.
Sister-in-law, I don't
need food right now.
I am feeling very dizzy.
Just give me
one big glass of milk.
And one for my daughter too.
You know that I can
live on just milk too.
What can we do?
Here, I have come.
What is this?
Where are you getting
dressed and going?
Won't you pay homage
to your late father?
All that can be done later.
You have come so late!
There, the collector
has come on rounds.
I have to go and greet him.
Greeting your boss
is more important...
... than paying homage
to your father?
Can't you tell him,...
... you were paying homage
to your father, that's why...
-...you got a little late?
- Yes, I can tell him.
But the collector
can also say that...
...I don't need to
go to work at all.
Listen, next year, we' ll
fulfill these rites twice.
- Won't that be a sin? - Why
are you concerned with that?
You want your fees,
right? Take this.
Sir, I am a priest,
not a beggar!
- Father, my Botany record? -To
hell with your Botany record!
If these men have to keep
greeting the officers...
... Iike this, then your studies
won't last for long!
Now go away from here!
Listen Gautam, l
feel pity for you
Take this Rs.2, and
buy the Botany record.
No, Usha. The price of
a Botany record is Rs.2.
But pity is very expensive.
And I cannot repay you for that.
Take it.
Is there any theater here,
or not?
- There is. - Which movie
is showing right now?
You won't like it, aunty.
- Why? - It is not
of any use to you.
But atleast, tell me the name.
`Pati-Patni'(Husband and wife)!
See? Now your daughter has
also started taunting me.
That is her habit.
Hey! You have returned so soon?
What happened? Why did you
throw the scriptures like this?
What else shall I do?
I can't throw them
on those who deserve it!
But what is the matter?
Why are you getting so angry?
Just understand that
the world has forgotten...
...it's religion and the priests
have forgotten their work!
This world has become new!
There is no value of worship
and customs in this world!
Then how will you take
care of your home and us?
God will take care
of this world.
Shall I tell you where
the entire problem lies?
The world is changing. But
you are not ready to change.
Then what do you want? Even l
should become like those who...
...have divided the world
amongst each other?!
Those who have no character,
principles or customs?!
They are just bothered
about their jobs and money!
But you cannot reform
the entire world alone.
The world that couldn't be
reformed by...
... Gods like Rama and Krishna,
cannot be reformed by me.
I can just leave such a world.
- Yes, father? - I am
feeling very anxious today.
- Sing some poetry to relax me.
- Okay, father.
" When..."
"... you draw blank"
" Everything seems confused"
" Who protects religion..."
"... sincerely"
" He wins over the world"
Brothers and sisters!
Shivaratri is approaching.
We have to stay awake all night.
That's why, to spend the
time, we will rehearse a drama.
All of you keep quiet!
All you children of
the new generation, keep quiet!
Now, one by one, ask
for whatever you want.
You will get whatever
you will ask for.
This is the blessing
of a Goddess.
- l' ll ask for something!
- Keep quiet!
Don't create such havoc!
This is not the ticket counter
of a theater.
This is the assembly
of the Goddess.
All of you ask in turns.
- Hey, get up. - Oh,
Goddess. My name is Gautam.
I study in the first year.
I have just one dream.
I want to get admission
in a medical college, and...
...I want to become a doctor.
What is there to laugh about?
- Oh Goddess?
- You must have heard.
A man becomes half a doctor
after killing a 100 patients.
First kill 100 men,
and become half a doctor.
Worship me on every Shivaratri.
After that l' ll come and
make you a complete doctor.
Goddess, I want
to complete my B.A....
... and become an officer
in the army.
- What is your name?
- Chamchu Shastri.
Why are you laughing, Oh Goddess?
His name is Chamchuram, and he
wants to become an army officer.
First you change your name.
Because your name is horrible.
Not worth an army officer.
- What is your name?
- My name is Devi (Goddess).
What?! How can there
be two Goddesses?
No, Goddess! She
is Devi from Earth.
I want a handsome husband.
Impudent children! Stop it! Or
else, the Goddess will go away!
- And my husband should own
100 acres of land. - 100 acres?
I can give you 100 acres
of land, if I want.
But what shall I do? The Goddess
who's ruling lndia nowadays,...
...has ordered to give
only 18 acres of land.
- Hail the Goddess!
- It's my turn now.
- What is your name? - Poorna.
- Who gave you such a nice name?
- My parents did.
I am the third daughter
out of their four children.
They had decided that after me,
this family will be complete.
- Then, is the family complete?
- That is what didn't happen.
They didn't know that these
four will also arrive after me.
First you change your name
from Poorna to Apoorna.
- Okay.
- Now tell me what you want.
I want to become a
very famous singer.
I want my records also to...
...play on the radio
all the time.
Of course, they will.
Run! Father has come.
Or else, both the devotees
and the Goddess...
... will be taught a lesson.
Run away!
- The children were enacting
a drama. - Yes, I saw that.
- Did you understand anything?
- Yes, I understood.
All of them are worthless.
Useless!
Then you did not understand
anything.
You can only read
the scriptures.
But you cannot understand
your children's feelings.
Can't one who is born
to a poor mother,...
...not even dream of happiness?
Look how the ornaments
are shining now.
Yes, it looks
like real gold now.
Who can make
these fools understand?
A person can never scrub brass
enough to turn it into gold.
And even if it does,
nobody will believe...
...Ram Shastri's daughters
are wearing real gold.
You left at dawn and are
returning in the evening.
Have you eaten anything?
You must be thinking
that I am talking too much.
Isn't it? But how
can I stop myself?
- There is nothing at home
to eat and... - I heard you!
Take this Rs.5.
Rs.5? But where did you
get so much money from?
I can see that you want to
ask me thousands of questions.
I have neither stolen
them nor begged for them!
This is my hard
earned money. Take it!
There are boils on your hands.
What else will happen
when l' ll break stones?
But this has shown me one thing.
In today's world, stones are
more expensive than incantations.
But, did someone see you
while breaking the stones?
I had covered my face!
How must Ram Shastri be
looking while breaking stones?
You are laughing, and
my heart is bleeding!
There are boils on these hands.
And my heart has been wounded.
For you, whatever the
climate and season may be,...
...only laughter is important!
"The earth laughs,
there's joy everywhere"
" Rays laugh in every bud"
" Even I laugh every time"
" Under the sky,
youth laughs again and again"
"The sun melts"
" And the moonlight showers
with love"
" Laughs and sings"
" Laughs and sings,
the season changes"
" My scarf slips off
Like a child..."
" Like a child I laugh"
" No matter what the world says"
" My bangles tinkle"
" Every moment..."
"the jingling of my anklets
torment me"
" Laugh and live"
" Laugher is the symbol of life"
" It seems every where..."
"... even God himself laughs"
" Happiness of the heart..."
"... the more expensive
the more cheap"
What is it?
If I want to give you
something, will you take it?
If you cross your
limits, l' ll slap you.
Look, I have bought
a sari for you.
- Why? - I don't like it when
you roam around in torn clothes.
Why don't you like it?
- I don't know.
- Look, l' ll do one thing.
There are several people in the
village who don't have clothes.
I' ll send all of them to you.
- Why? - You can
distribute clothes to them.
But I have brought
this sari for you.
Look, it is not nice to look
into torn clothes. Give.
You did very well. He gave
you a sari. And you took it.
Why didn't you die of shame?
- So what calamity took place?
- Calamity?
You won't be able to see
that calamity so easily.
But you should understand...
...the big difference in taking
a sari from a man & from a shop.
So what? Give me money and l' ll
go and take it from the shop.
You very well know
that I don't have money.
I feel pity for you.
And I feel like crying on myself.
But what can a mother do?
Maybe my child has
just rags in her fate!
Show it to me.
It is silken, just like you.
Listen, did someone see
you while taking the sari?
A mother has to ask. We poor
people have nothing else.
We just have our honor.
You want to wear it, right?
Wear it.
During mealtime, our house looks
exactly like a grain store.
There is a lot of crowd,
and less of grains!
Enough! Now stop
laughing. Start eating.
Wait!
Nobody will touch the food.
Before eating, I want
to find out something.
If you eat,
l' ll break your hand!
Today, someone has
committed a big sin.
I won't take
the name of the sinner.
But I want that person to come
forward and confess the sin!
Till that won't happen,
nobody will eat.
Give me something to eat!
It is better to beg like this.
But what a family member of Ram
Shastri did today, is not good.
Have pity on the poor.
Mother, you must
have done something.
Confess fast. I' m very hungry.
Give me some food.
This is that sin, right?
Yes, this is it.
Have pity on the poor.
Give this to that beggar woman!
Alright. You can eat now.
What is the meaning of getting
up from the meal like this?
- l' m very hungry. - l' m
going to give this to her too.
Her sari was torn, and I gave
her a new one. Was that a sin?
Couldn't you take
permission from me?
Permission for having
pity on someone?
I don't think
this was just pity.
If you have understood,
it is good.
- What nonsense are you saying?
- I mean that,...
-...I love Shalini.
- This can never happen!
She is so innocent!
If she mingles freely with you,
you are trying to trap her?
I' m not trying to trap her. I
love her and want to marry her.
And just listen. I
will marry only her.
Ashok, are you in your senses?
Do you know
how high her caste is?
All that are old beliefs.
- These are new times.
- New times!
What has these new times
given to this world?
- Forget about her right now!
Or else... - Or else?
Or else, l' ll have to
forget that you are my son.
These are also
often repeated words.
In every era of this world,every
father has aid this to his son.
- What do you mean? - Father,
I don't want to forget Shalini.
- How dare you?! - I know
what you will say now.
`You' re not my son! I don't want
to see you! Get out of my house!'
`You won't get a single
dime from me!' Right?
You won't feel the
need to do all this.
I' ll go away myself. So that you
are not defamed in the society.
So that people cannot accuse you
of throwing your son out of home.
I' m going.
Do you know Shastriji's home,...
... where a girl
called Shalini stays?
Yes! That is the house.
Do one thing, take this letter
tomorrow...
Who gave you this sari?
The one you are giving this
letter for, has given this sari.
She is so generous.
Take us with you too,
to the theater.
- I cannot go.
- Look, sister-in-law,...
When a sister comes
to a brother' s home,...
... she asks for several things.
But I don't want anything.
None of the delicacies.
Just show me a movie sometimes.
Your treasure
will never get empty.
- Really? - There is not
even enough to eat here.
And your mother want
to go to see a movie!
Did you hear that, Meenu?
You are fond of movies!
-And I have to hear such taunts!
-I don't say anything to anybody.
I just say that this is not the
correct way to bring up children.
They should not be given
such expensive habits.
Stop it!
Meena's father works in the
tax office of the theater.
We get free passes
to the movies.
And that too, four passes.
Both of us see the movie with 2,
and mother sells the other two.
Stop it!
Since we have come here,...
...we can only hear
one thing. Hunger!
What is this?
You' re giving money offered
to God for seeing movies?
Never mind. Both the money
and the movie are God's.
Do you know what the
name of the movie is?
- `Bhagvat Mahima'.
- Mother! Did you hear that?
Hurry up, mother.
God is calling you.
- Sister, tell us again what
you had said. - Okay, I will.
And l' ll see who
says it the fastest.
- l' ll say it! - Let me say it.
- This is very easy. - Then
say it. Who's stopping you?
What nonsense are you saying?
Hey doctor, you are very proud
of yourself, right? The say this.
Not like this. Say it fast.
Mother has come. We' ll
continue after the meal.
Come here.
What is it?
Nothing has been cooked today.
There was nothing to cook.
These poor children
are playing there.
How can I make them
understand now?
That today their plates and
their stomachs will remain empty?
I' ll make them
understand in some way.
Now repeat fast
whatever I will say.
Today, the food is not prepared.
Even if it's prepared,
it's not good.
Have you still not understood?
We are not hungry today.
Say it loudly.
Sister, I am hungry.
Give me something to eat!
What are you looking at?
Hey, why are you crying?
I am very hungry.
Food hasn't been
cooked at home today.
Will you eat my leftovers?
Here, eat it.
Tell me. Where did
you get this rice from?
- Tell me. - What will he say?
This is my brother's home, who
is so religious and a priest!
And this is his son!
He begs from beggars!
He eats from their used vessels!
I have seen
that with my own eyes!
I caught him myself!
Isn't it a shameful matter
for the entire family?
Oh God!
What kind of a day is this?
First the movie was bad.
Then this scene was even worse.
You were teaching me the way
to bring up children, right?
Today, I have seen your way too.
If my daughter would have done
this, I would have killed myself!
The children of dogs and pigs
are better than such children!
Sinner! Come with me.
Don't hit him!
He's just a child!
No! Nobody can save you today!
- l' ll kill you! - Mother! - You
don't come in between, Shalini!
Couldn't he stop is
hunger for just one day?
Can you stop your anger?
When one is hungry
he can't remember...
... what is written
in the scriptures!
And he is still a child! How
can he understand all this?
That aunty, who has
become 50 years old,...
...cannot stop going
to the theater!
This child, who hasn't even
turned 10 years old yet,...
...should stop his hunger?!
He' ll commit a sin
if he doesn't!
Shall I tell you what
the biggest sin is?
Hunger! And hitting a hungry
child is an even bigger crime!
- Don't drink this, Shalini!
- Why?
Because this contains poison?
You have found a nice way
to get free of your troubles!
Mother, after what you
have done today,...
...no children will be
able to trust their mother!
You used to ask me when I would
become sensible and responsible.
But today I have seen how
sensible and responsible you are!
But what else could I do,
Shalini?
There is nothing at home
for the children to eat.
So you would take eight
lives because of that?!
- Your children are of
such less value. - Stop it.
The children's hunger
had made blinded me!
I couldn't see them suffering.
That's why I hardened myself
and wanted to poison them.
So that they can
sleep peacefully forever!
Do you know why God has given
a heart and hands to a mother?
The heart is for loving.
And the hands are
for giving blessings.
But your heart
has become of stone!
And your hands have
become the hands of fate!
You are making poison
for your own children!
But if this is what
makes you happy,...
...then l' ll go right
now and awaken everybody!
First I will drink and
then the rest of them!
Because I am elder
to all of them!
Don't say that, Shalini!
Till now, I was your daughter
and you were my mother.
But now,
the relations have changed.
Now you are my daughter,
and I am your mother!
Yes, mother. Henceforth, l
am a mother for all of you!
For my brothers,
sisters, you and father!
Now l' ll prove myself
as a mother!
What did you say? You will work?
Never! Where is your mother?
There's no need to ask mother.
I have made her sit in one place.
I am not a child now.
I can think for myself.
But I am not dead yet!
I can still go and
break stones on the road!
A great priest like you won't
get the work of breaking stones.
Like a graduate cannot work
as a peon even if he wants to.
What has happened to you today?
Something has really happened
to me.
If someone else
would have seen what I saw,...
... he would have gone mad.
Death has entered this
house in the form of hunger.
The entire family
is in danger of it.
But I have also decided.
Till I am alive, l
won't let death win!
But my heart has made
some other decision.
That you should get married.
There are 10 hungry people
in the way of your decision.
They have several
dreams and hopes.
But their dreams are much more
important than my marriage!
I will live and die for them!
Inspite of knowing all this,...
... you want me to get
married, and not work?
In front of you,
l' ll ask all of them.
- Tell me what I should do!
- You should work!
What is the harm if
she earns, brother?
- You will work? - Yes, I will.
You are the chairman
of the Panchayat court.
You know so many people.
Can't you find a job for me?
- Did you ask Shastri?
- Why ask him?
To keep hunger away
from our home,...
... I will have to come out
of the house.
The food has been cooked.
You don't need to do anything.
I' ll come back from
work and do the rest.
You do everything.
- Go carefully to office.
- Okay, mother.
Shall I say something?
Will you mind?
Why will we work,
if we are not poor?
But what happened today,
is not good.
Why don't you buy a
new sari and blouse?
It is not for fashion,
but for decency.
You don't know, Sudha. In my
house, someone needs books.
And someone needs clothes.
There may be something to eat
today, and nothing for tomorrow.
My house is
like a whole village.
I have got my first salary
today. Rs.170. Take this.
Won't you give me
your blessings?
I have gotten people married
for just half a rupee.
I have worked
for quarter of a rupee.
I saw so much money
for the first time today.
Hence, I was speechless.
- Take it, father.
- Keep it with you.
You are the mother of this house.
I never defeat you, uncle.
I am a loser in life.
That's why,
I always win in games.
So you finally missed your son!
Your heart is still
suffering for him.
- Right, uncle?
- You have caught me today.
But should that fool have left
his home and gone into the army?
Whatever it is. He won't lag
behind anybody in the army too.
He always defeated me in games.
Just see! He' ll defeat
the enemy in the war too.
- Telegram! - Uncle, go.
There is a telegram.
I' m coming.
Uncle, who's telegram is it?
I don't know. You read it.
What is written in the telegram?
Tell me, what is written.
Shalini, why don't you tell me
what is written in the telegram?
- Weren't you saying that
nobody can defeat Ashok? - Yes?
- Death has defeated him.
- What?
He was killed in the war.
Sister...
... have you told brother...
... that you will get him
admitted to medical college?
Yes, so?
Won't you appoint a
music teacher for me?
What a question to ask at
this hour! Go to sleep.
We' ll discuss
this in the morning.
Ghasite, why is
Gautam doing sit-ups?
I think it's preparation
for marriage.
No. Shastri will not get
his daughter married first.
If he gets her married,
they will go hungry.
That's also true.
Gautam is coming, let's ask him.
Gautam, why were
you doing sit-ups?
I have to go for an interview
for admission to medical college
That is why you were
begging before God?
But it is not so easy to get
admission to medical college.
So what?
I have passed in first class.
Hear that!
He has stood first in class.
Oh really?
But that alone is not enough.
- Then what else is required?
- Do you have a reference?
Nowadays, even death comes
with a recommendation.
If you don't have a reference,
nothing can be done.
I have just one dream, uncle.
That I become a doctor.
Only good marks are not
enough to get admission.
People say that one
even needs reference.
- Who told you that?
- Everyone says so.
Out of worry, Gautam
cannot sleep all night.
Please do something, uncle.
You' ll have to do
something for me.
What are you thinking? You must
be knowing someone in Poona.
I' m not asking you to go there.
I' ll go there myself.
Can't you see!
Uncle is deep in thought.
Yes.
Do one thing. I have an old
friend in Poona who's an MLA.
I' ll write a
letter in his name.
Go and meet him. But don't
mention this to anybody.
I won't.
Where will you live in Poona?
Do you know anyone there?
No, but l' ll
arrange something.
That will not do. You can
go and live with my niece.
Take this card,
her name and address is on it.
- Uncle, write her a letter.
- On one condition.
When you become a doctor, you' ll
have to treat me free of charge.
Not only you,
l' ll treat for free...
... all those who come to me
with your reference.
Alright.
Now massage my legs.
Wow!
You dance very well.
Feel at home here.
You can stay here
as long as you like.
Once Mala's programme is over,
she' ll be with you always.
Shalini, this programme
is making me nervous.
That's natural. You are
performing on stage...
... for the first time.
You must come
to see my programme.
- Here's your invitation.
- I will surely come.
Look child, the easiest way
is not always the best way.
I don't agree that one gets
admission in medical college...
... only with reference.
The government has
formed committees....
...that interview every student.
Where they check the
capability of the candidate.
They see how many
marks he has scored.
That's true.
But everyone says...
People say anything.
You wasted time and
money coming to Poona.
Don't penalise yourself more.
Give my regards
to Jagannath Rao.
I will.
Thank you very much.
- Goodbye.
Listen! I heard
everything you' ll spoke.
Come with me.
Look, no job can be done
without a reference.
You want admission in medical
college for your brother?
I know a person
who can help you.
He does not make proclamations
about helping the poor.
If you like, I can take
you to him in the evening.
You don't believe me?
- Alright, l' ll be going.
- No, it's not that.
My friend has a
dance show tonight.
- I have to go there.
- Alright, then tomorrow.
`Bharat Rang Bhuvan - Poona.'
- Listen.
- Hello!
Come out for a minute.
....Come!
- You' ll have to come
with me now. - Where?
The man I mentioned to you
is leaving for Delhi tonight.
If you want to meet him,
you can only meet him today.
But my friend's show
is about to begin.
Now it is up to you. Either
watch your friend's show...
... or get your brother
admitted to medical college.
- Alright, l' ll come with you.
- Let's go.
`Next programme - Trap.'
Hello!....The P A
to the minister?
How are you Mr.Mathur?
Yes, l' m Lal speaking.
The minister is busy?
No, I want only him. I have
some urgent work with him.
I' ll hold the line.
It's good you came today.
Or after I'd left for Delhi...
Hello, Minister?
I' m Lal speaking.
No Sir, l' m not Ramlal,
l' m Shyamlal speaking.
How are you, sir?
It's nothing major,
it's just a small matter.
Someone need admission
in medical college.
Today is the last day.
You can even do it
at the last minute.
Yes, he has
given the interview.
You can assume that.
They are related to me.
They are close relatives.
What? Name and number?
Give me your brother's
name and number.
Sorry to have bothered you.
I will give the name
and number to your P A.
You don't want me to give the
name and number to the minister?
Leave me!
What thoughts are you lost in?
Even your tea has gone cold.
I was thinking that it's
many days since I came here.
But I have no news on the
admission to medical college.
It is only four days
since you came here.
I am sure your brother will get
admission in medical college.
Look, so much has been written
about my dance in the papers.
They say that my dance
was excellent.
`Shyamlal arrested.'
What are you
reading in the paper?
Damn! Did his photo have
to be published today!
This is the photo of a cheat...
... who has looted many
people in various ways.
The police has arrested him
on charges of forgery.
Sister!
Don't leave us!
I am everyone's
mother from today.
Mother of my sisters, my
brothers, even you and father.
Mother, feed your children.
Mother, we are very hungry.
Mother! Sister has returned!
Brother, Chhotu,
sister is back!
What a noise you' ll are making!
Shut-up of all you.
Devi, get salt and pepper.
Shut-up all of you!
Go from here!
- Take this, mother.
- You also go.
Why do you behave like
as if you know nothing?
Look at what you have done! I
got admission in medical college!
What you have done for me,...
... no sister in the world
must have done for her brother.
`You have wasted time
and money coming to Poona.'
`Don't penalise yourself more.'
A diamond's real value is
known only in the market.
I never realised
your worth, Shalini.
But you are very worthy.
Shalini, you were very naughty.
Where is that laughter of yours?
I lost it in the city.
"The earth laughs,
there's joy everywhere"
" Beauty laughs"
" Rays laugh in every bud"
" Even I laugh every time"
You chose the perfect
time to go to Poona.
Bravo! Admission for your
brother in medical college...
... and a promotion for you!
- And a Rs.200 increment.
- Rs.200 increment?
But I am wondering
how I will go to Delhi.
Only a lucky few
get such a chance.
That's true, but where
women are concerned...
... they have to lose
something to gain something.
What did you lose?
Why? Won't I lose a good
friend like you for this job?
Father, I have got
a good job in Delhi.
I will earn Rs.200
more than I get here.
There are also chances
of getting a promotion.
I had thought I will
only be able to...
... arrange the basic
necessities for the family.
Now even their
dreams can be fulfilled.
There is no end
to one's dreams.
This world is like a train...
... where the passenger first
tries to get a foothold,...
... then aspires to get a seat,
and then, space to lie down.
When he can get space to lie
down, why should he stand?
Savitri, Tuesday is not
an auspicious day for travel.
Ask her to leave on Wednesday.
Shalini will live alone
in a city like Delhi.
Why don't you go
with her, Janki?
- No, brother.
- Let us go, mother.
There are many movie halls
there. More than 30 movie halls.
We can watch a movie every day.
Shut-up!
Watch a movie everyday indeed!
Delhi is a very big city.
The bigger the city,
the worse the situation there.
What difference will
that make to you?
- Sister....Sister!
- What is it?
You are doing the dishes alone?
I' ll help you.
Tell me honestly,
what do you want from me.
Nothing, honestly.
I know you want something.
I can read your face.
- Tell me.
- So you even read faces.
I want Rs.300 to
pay admission fees.
What!
Rs.300?
Rs.300 is just the admission
fees.I've another 5 years ahead.
Wonder how much money
I will need every year.
- When do you want Rs.300?
- Within a week.
You have joined only today, and
you already want an advance?
Sir, my brother has got
admission in medical college...
... with great difficulty.
If he doesn't pay the fees,
his name will be canceled.
You can deduct the amount
from my salary every month.
The women's hostel where you
stay is close to my house.
Come home on Sunday.
You can meet my wife...
... and also take the money.
- Thank you, sir.
- No mention.
- Where's your wife?
- My wife?...There she is.
- She is no more?
- No, she is not dead.
But she is not alive either.
She does not keep well.
Since years, she is in hospital,
and I am here, alone.
Absolutely alone.
But you had called me here
to introduce me to your wife.
You wanted Rs.300, didn't you?
What games God plays!
Where he gives beauty,
he doesn't give money.
You wanted Rs.300, didn't you?
Take it as a gift,
not an advance.
For your brother
on your behalf.
I understand.
Isn't there a single good
man in your rich world?
Here's Rs.300.
You will not accept?
You don't care whether
your brother...
... gets admission in
medical college or not,...
... whether he
becomes a doctor or not.
`l need Rs.300 to pay
my admission fees.'
`Or you will not see your
brother's face again.'
`How will I complete
five years of education?'
`l have only one dream,
that I become a great singer.'
`Won't you appoint me
a music teacher?'
`Even I have certain dreams,
some aspirations.'
`l don't want to suffer
poverty and hunger once again.'
`Get me married to a
rich, handsome man.'
`l want to be a doctor,
I want to be a singer.'
Sing in tune.
- That would be so nice.
- Yes. - Mother, we are back!
On sister's birthday today,
we prayed to all the Gods.
Here's the offering.
May she live long.