Right there on your right.
That's good. Stay in the car.
This is 2L13. We'll be 10-10 at Water at Pier 16.
License 2, Tom, Edward, Mary, 385.
10-4, 2L13.
That's a 10-10 on 2, Tom, Edward, Mary, 385.
Hold on a sec.
Can I see your license, please?
- What do we got?
- Rodriguez and Baker.
- When?
- About a half-hour ago.
- Who's Baker?
- New guy. You met him.
What, a rookie?
We had two boots in the same car?
Look, the cavalry has arrived.
- 14763.
- All clear.
Demps.
Routine shakedown. Thought they were
doping in the car. Three shooters.
- Our guys screw up?
- Rodriguez was searching for his flashlight.
So you had two rookies in the same car.
That's criminal.
Rhinehart, want to come over here
for a second?
You. Yeah, you guys.
It's a crime scene, not a social gathering.
- I want Demps to take this.
- Matt, I'm up.
I want Demps to take this
and you to help him out.
Help him out?
If it's a gang, Alan should do it.
He's been covering these guys.
You assigning the cases? That's my job.
Listen, Matt, I'm set up with these guys.
I got a man in there.
Excuse me. Where are you going?
The coroner hasn't come yet. Just relax.
Where's his badge?
Anybody touch this body?
- Where's his badge?
- Little fucks. They took it as a trophy.
- Let's dust right here.
- You can't get a print off concrete.
- Bring down the portable laser.
- Come on.
Ricky, call the lab, bring them down,
and rotamine two feet around the body.
Alan.
Let's work together on this.
- Whatever.
- I'd like to bring my brother in on it.
Get him loaned to our division
to help us in the legwork.
It's your party.
- What's going on?
- Same old, same old. Let's go.
- What are you doing?
- I just gotta see.
- It's Dempsey.
- For Christ's sake.
What are you doing?
I'm going to check my machine.
It might be important.
Don't worry.
I'm not going anywhere.
'Cause I'm undercover.
Hey, kid. So, where you been?
- Why?
- I paged you.
- I didn't get it.
- Didn't get it?
No. You know, I was kind of tied up.
I bet you were. I left word on your machine.
I just walked in. So what's up? Want a beer?
6:00 in the morning? I'll pass, thanks.
So tell me, what did I miss?
There's a cop down.
I was trying to bring you in on it.
- Look, just return your phone calls, okay?
- I know.
It's the women. I have no self-control.
Look, I'll take you to breakfast,
and you can bring me up to speed.
No, I gotta go home and get some sleep.
Come on. Let me take you to breakfast.
- I gotta get some sleep.
- Okay.
Listen, can I borrow $20 anyway?
- Hey there, what are you doing up?
- Couldn't sleep.
Yeah? Why not?
I'm in a slump. I haven't reached in four games.
What's the problem?
Not concentrating?
That's up to you. 'Cause you control
where your mind goes, right?
You just got to focus on one thing.
The ball.
If you're thinking about whether you'll get a hit,
you won't get a hit.
The power that you have to direct your mind
is the greatest power you have.
So I put my attention on the ball?
There you go.
Now you're talking.
I'll see you later. I'm gonna get some sleep.
I love you.
- What did he say?
- Who?
Capt. Cocksucker's got such a hard on
for Dempsey, it's embarrassing.
- What are you gonna do?
- I'm drinking.
- Then I'm transferring the fuck out of here.
- He's good, Alan.
Did you hear he got a print off the concrete
last night? Those two rookies?
You got the instincts.
You were born for this shit.
But he's a college guy.
He's up on all that technical stuff.
He's good.
Fuck good. He's a politician.
Mr. Navy, test pilot, brown-nosing,
cocksucking Boy Scout.
And don't get me started on his brother.
- Moron.
- Guys like that...
- End up police commissioner.
- Really.
Yeah.
We should get back by 12:00
to get changed and go to the wake at 1:00.
Or we could go to the wake later.
We planned at 3:00 to go to Bruce
and Nancy's to see the new house.
Maybe you can go to the wake without me.
He was a cop, Gail.
Well, I'm not a cop, Demps.
- Honey, this is all planned.
- Dad, can we do some batting today?
No way. You got to check the plan.
It's not on the schedule. Eat your breakfast.
What's with her?
That's not a her, that's your mom.
Let's watch this thing a minute.
Let's just watch and concentrate.
Look. Boom. Right there. Then again.
You're just going to focus your mind.
One thing at a time.
Your eye never leaves it. Okay, go ahead.
Walk up to it. Eye on it.
Focus in.
Yes!
Dude. Yeah. All right.
Boom. Goodbye, see you.
Go ask her.
Come out back, I made something.
I'm tired. I'll see it tomorrow.
- Please, Mom.
- I will see it tomorrow.
You got to. It'll just take a second.
Listen to me. I'm not in the mood for this.
Will you stop pulling my arm?
- What?
- Surprise!
Happy birthday, darling.
What's wrong?
Good job, Damon. Happy birthday, my love.
It's not my birthday until Tuesday.
If we waited till Tuesday,
you wouldn't be surprised.
What's that, right there?
- You like it?
- She loves it.
It's perfect.
Let me get the door.
Let me take your pictures. Get in there.
Mom.
Okay.
Smile.
It's the truth. She's lying there in the tub,
naked with her toe stuck in the faucet.
- Were you surprised?
- Totally.
He's been planning it for months.
Ripping out the faucet.
They cut away the back of the wall.
It's perfect, isn't it?
Everything Dempsey does is perfect.
And we finally put her and about
200 pounds of masonry on a stretcher...
...took her right out
through a cocktail party in the lobby.
Hello?
What? I can't hear you.
Okay. All right. Good.
Ricky, we got to roll.
- What's up?
- They found our shooters.
Where's Nick?
Nicky.
Please, this isn't safe.
Happy birthday.
Can you find Nicky and tell him
to meet us at that address soon?
- All right.
- Tell Gail we had to leave. Thanks.
They're on the third floor.
What's around them?
This guy over here is the super.
He only speaks Spanish.
Ricky, go see what we got.
Third floor, that's what I'm worried about.
- Get him the sketches of the floor plan.
- Right.
- Who called the beetles in?
- I did.
Get rid of them. Get them out of here.
We got five armed crack heads.
I don't think we've got to be heroes.
We've got a residential hotel full of people.
This is our case. We can handle it.
All right.
Our pals are in 313.
Super says there's five of them.
We've got three occupied rooms
on the third floor, 306, 312 and 315.
312 is just down the hall. She's old.
Where can we get a pizza?
Pizza.
Open the door.
Is that a search warrant? I'll take that.
Let's go.
Police!
I got the broad.
Get down!
- You okay?
- Vest.
Get out of there.
Shut up!
Behind your back.
Go!
- Andale, cabron.
- Freeze!
Dame una razon, you sick motherfucker.
You don't kill cops.
How many we got total?
Move, damn it!
There's one more. The super said five.
- Randy?
- Yeah?
- We're secure here.
- Whatever comes out of that hole, shoot it.
I think I know where he went. Come on.
Go!
- Freeze, police!
- Don't anybody move.
- Nothing.
- We're all clear here.
Nick?
Nobody.
- I guess there was only four.
- I don't get it.
Mrs. Cain, he has what we call
some sacral sparing...
...meaning only partial,
not complete, damage to his spinal cord.
At this point, there's no telling if or when
he'll recover the use of his legs.
I'm sorry.
Then the next thing I know,
I'm flat-assed on the floor.
I think I even said, "I'm shot."
No, actually, what you said was:
"What are you looking at me for?
Go shoot him."
What's this about a beeper going off?
Well, I got a phone call.
- What?
- Yeah, I forgot to turn it off.
Your beeper? I was under the impression...
It was my beeper.
Jesus, Dempsey.
- That's harsh.
- Yeah, I know.
I tell her all the time, "Don't call me at work."
Do we want to hear the spec,
or have we had enough?
I've had enough. Besides, I'm hungry.
Where can you get a good steak around here?
Excuse me, quick question.
How sick would a guy have to be
to have you as the night nurse?
That sick?
How you doing?
Wait till you see what I got for you.
I got tacos, burritos...
...chimichangas, and...
...Petrone.
- Nick?
I was just shot by a Mexican.
I knew it, something was telling me Chinese,
but I'm so stubborn.
Tell me, how are you doing?
I'm paralyzed.
Only from the waist down. How are you?
Demps...
...I read your deposition,
you didn't have to do that.
- You're my brother.
- I know, but...
You're my brother.
End of story. You'd do it for me.
- That's good.
- Yeah.
- Just like that.
- Let go.
Roll right down. Good.
I'm going to put this stirrup on your foot.
- I want you to lift your foot. Pull.
- That's pretty good.
There you go. Good job.
Hi. Call me. I just got back.
I spent the whole morning at the hospital.
Really depressing.
Da's staying over at a friend's house, so...
...l'm here.
We got six months of this. Slow down.
Two more.
Now give me some curls.
Again.
Demps?
It's late.
Mom? Dad? Want to eat something?
In here.
Dad?
Hi.
What?
You wanna?
We could try.
What do you say?
I'll help you.
His actions uphold the highest tradition...
...of the San Sebastian police department...
...and are hereby recognized
by awarding him the medal of valor.
- We miss you, take care.
- Thanks.
Congratulations.
Now you could write books or something.
Detective stories.
Sell them to TV, and make a lot of money.
Look, I'll try to keep an eye out for your brother.
Yeah, thanks.
I'll see you around.
Why is your equipment sitting
at the bottom of our pool?
Have I let you down?
Demps, you have to stop this.
I've just realized how unhappy you are.
You used to be happy.
Hell, I remember when we were stationed
at Pax River. We had that apartment.
And you were dancing.
Why did you quit dancing?
You were really good.
Well, being good in Maryland
isn't good enough.
- Listen...
- Did I neglect you or something?
- Let's not go into this.
- Is that it? Have I neglected you?
You're drunk, you're depressed,
and it's late, and just for the record...
...I am not unhappy.
I think we ought to send Damon away
to camp this summer.
Okay.
Does Damon want to go to camp?
I don't want him to stay around here when I'm...
...like this.
- All right, I'll talk to him.
- I'm sorry.
For what?
For letting you down.
Would you stop that? You haven't let me down.
Jesus, Demps.
- Just say it, Nick.
- I am.
It just doesn't seem right anymore,
since Demps...
...you know.
I mean, I'm talking about for me.
That's great, Nick, that's just great.
Want to know what I come home to at night?
A pool full of exercise equipment
and a depressed hulk in a wheelchair.
Come on, Gail.
He's drunk every night.
- He's going through a hard thing.
- What about me?
I'm looking at pushing a wheelchair
for the rest of my life.
I am 35 years old, for Christ's sake.
Who gets the BLT?
Here.
Enjoy.
- Ready?
- I guess so.
I'm your partner.
I'll always be your partner.
That's what you have to remember.
- I still don't want to go to camp.
- Yeah, I know, pal.
You gotta give me some time.
We're out of here.
I love you, Dad.
Have fun.
- Drive carefully.
- Yeah.
I'll call you tonight.
Oh, my God.
Hi. Do you have any lentils?
'Cause I'm making lentil soup,
and I was halfway through making the...
...stock and I realized I didn't have any.
I was wondering if I might borrow some...
...or any other sort of bean that you might have.
$2,795,000, plus they'll take back paper.
I can't present that. Because it's insulting.
Okay. Well, let me get back to you.
Bye.
- How are you?
- Okay.
Sit down.
- You want to buy a house?
- No, thanks.
This may be none of my business,
but I think there is something you should know.
- Jesus Christ. When?
- When I took Damon.
- Jesus.
- He's fine now.
- Is he alone?
- Lois is with him.
The therapist said that his feelings
could come up.
We gotta get him some help.
What?
I don't know. It's just really hard.
Dempsey's not a wheelchair kind of guy.
What are you saying?
I don't know. It's just...
It's his life.
The guy is a total perfectionist.
If his life isn't perfect, I don't know if he wants it.
The guy's depressed, Gail, clinically depressed.
- I'm talking to the shrink tomorrow.
- No, I will.
I gotta get back to the office.
You mad at me?
What are you doing?
Aren't you supposed to be on duty?
Demps called. He...
...wanted to speak to the two of us.
About?
We've been waiting for you to get home.
Well, here I am.
Does anybody wanna have a drink, besides me?
Some vodka.
- You're on duty.
- Kidding. Just kidding.
The other night I tried to kill myself.
Oh, my God.
All I could think of was Damon.
What's going to happen to him?
What am I leaving him with?
I always thought I was a good role model to him.
In his eyes I see...
...discomfort, pity.
And then something inside me has...
...died.
We'll get you some counseling.
It's all right. I have counseling.
I'm very clear about this.
I want to die.
I can't live my life as half a man.
It's not fair...
...to me or Damon.
Certainly not to you, Gail.
I didn't ask you here to discuss this.
I'm gonna end my life,
and I need your help to do it.
Now, I've...
...taken out a $1-million insurance policy.
It pays double if I die an accidental death.
You two and Damon are the beneficiaries.
Of course there's the department policy,
but none of this covers suicide.
What are we going to do,
push you in the pool and watch you drown?
Come on.
- I need to drink. I don't give a shit.
- I'm asking you to help me.
I am asking you to help me
secure my son's future...
...and yours.
I've worked this all out to the last detail.
There won't be any risk on your part.
We'll stage a burglary.
I'll be killed in the process.
I realize the magnitude
of what I'm asking you to do, so...
...don't answer me now. Just think about it.
I think I understand how you're feeling.
I think I do.
But I don't know if I can do this for you.
You park the rental car in that lot,
right over there.
You'll have to change the plates.
Everything will be in the trunk,
and the theater's two blocks away.
You need to get a time-punched ticket
at the parking lot.
Inside the theatre,
cause a commotion so you're remembered.
Then at 10:45 go out that side exit,
right over there.
Be sure you rig the door so you can get back in.
Break this glass and unlock the door.
Muffle the sound with tape and rags.
The lawn will be wet from the sprinklers,
you'll be leaving prints all over the place.
Then start at opposite sides of the room,
put everything to be stolen into bags.
Get the guns out of the drawer, right there.
Then I'll hear you, and I'll come in...
...and Nick you shoot me once,
in the side of the head at close range.
I don't want to see it. That should do it.
If it doesn't, Gail,
you shoot me twice in the heart.
Don't hesitate, I don't wanna suffer.
Then you tip the wheelchair over on its side...
...you get rid of all the stuff,
the way we talked about.
Come back, you discover my body,
you call the police.
Honey?
You all right?
This is just too bizarre.
Wouldn't you love to play
hide the salami with her?
Nick wants to play hide the salami with Iris.
Think you can set him up?
I was just kidding around.
But seriously, what about the shots?
- Won't the neighbors hear them?
- No, you'll use silencers.
- It'll look like a professional hit.
- Illegals use anything they can get.
The films at the theatre, we'll need to see them.
You can go to a video store and rent them.
Is that a good idea? That's our alibi.
- Won't it leave a trace?
- Why don't we go to the movies?
- Bad idea.
- Stupid idea.
I'll take care of the videos. What else?
- How are you gonna do it?
- I'll come up with something.
What else?
Okay, we're gonna do it in two weeks...
...Friday, July 15.
But if anything doesn't go according to plan,
we abort.
Let's get started.
Detective Porado. It's Gail Cain.
Hey, Ricky, it's Gail.
Listen, this is probably nothing,
but I thought I'd better call.
We were followed home today from the bank.
Yeah. I think there were two of them.
Two Mexicans, I think.
- I'll meet you here in half an hour.
- I'll watch all day for you.
Cuàntos dos chaquetas, por favor?
Hey, buddy.
I'm looking for Senor De La Paz.
- Jorge De La Paz?
- No here, wrong place.
My name is Carpenter.
- You called me.
- No.
Franco.
- Where's your friend?
- That's none of your business.
- I like to know who I am working for.
- You're working for me.
- You have money?
- Right here.
Stand on the line.
Look at the red light.
A couple of minutes.
- You have license information?
- Yep.
I make silencers.
- Nice.
- You try, over there. Shoot.
Okay. Looks good.
- $3,000.
- Dempsey said $2,000.
Who?
My friend said $2,000.
$800 for each gun and $400 for the license.
- $3,000.
- Hold on there, Josè.
$2,000 is the deal, and that's all I got.
- Fuck you. Go down the street.
- Bullshit.
Grease ball.
- Gail, let's go.
- What's wrong?
Nothing. Just get in the car.
No, gracias.
What's that on your shirt?
Shit.
Afternoon.
Hi.
How long have you folks been in Mexico?
- Couple of hours. Doing some shopping.
- Where are you from?
San Sebastian.
Can I see your driver's license, sir?
Yeah, sure.
All right. Have a good day.
Thanks.
- You what?
- It wasn't my fault.
- Nick.
- He hit his head.
I think I killed him.
Christ.
- We gotta abort.
- No, wait.
- He said, "If anything went wrong..."
- You said you were alone.
- Yes.
- Are you sure?
- And you got everything on that list?
- Yes.
- Well then, maybe it's okay.
- No!
Dempsey said, "If anything went wrong..."
Shut up. Okay?
We gotta figure this out.
This is what Dempsey wants.
"Bonds of restriction are broken.
"Decisions are reached concerning
beginnings or endings.
"Realize discretion
actually is better part of valor.
"Travel involved."
What are you doing?
Just gathering up some of Dempsey's stuff.
- You working tonight?
- Yeah.
Great. I'll get you assigned to me.
Tonight, no. I'm off tonight.
You want to get in some OT?
I'm going to the movies, actually.
- So how is your brother?
- Demps?
- Yeah.
- He's great.
Think about this for a second.
This man carries a loaded weapon.
- Hello?
- Hi, Damon.
- Hi, Dad.
- How are you doing? How's camp?
- Pretty good.
- Yeah? Did you get any hits?
- A couple.
- That's good.
That's really good.
Well, look, don't let me keep you. I just...
...called, I just wanted...
...to say hi.
I'm thinking about you, and...
...I love you, Damon.
- I love you, too, Dad.
- Bye.
- See you.
- I'll need your credit card.
- I'm paying cash.
Cash? You'll have to leave a $500 deposit.
All right. I'll need a valid
California driver's license.
- You're making a copy of my license?
- I have to.
- I get that back when I return the car?
- Sure.
It's a beige Ford LTD.
Don't forget, if you're seen
leaving the theatre, you can it.
- Yeah.
- Yes.
Drive slow. Stay under the limit.
- You don't have to be back to the theatre...
- We've been through this a thousand times.
That's good. If you space out
on this one and get caught...
...you'll both get the death penalty,
and our son's going to be an orphan.
All right, let's get started.
Be right back.
Tell me something.
What do you think of me?
You're a great guy.
You were a great cop.
You resent me at all?
Resent you? No.
Resent you?
I don't know. Maybe a little.
- Why?
Look at this house.
Look at your career.
We both inherit
the exact same amount of money.
You invest and...
I invest and lose every dime.
- In a nightclub.
- Some people get very rich in nightclubs.
It's you, everything you touch.
You're on the force
and make Detective 3 in 10 years.
I'm six years now.
I'm still in uniform, in spite of all your efforts.
I'm a fuck-up.
You know that.
Why? Why is that?
You don't try hard enough,
or you just can't do any better?
I don't know.
You scared?
Only if something goes wrong.
You're not afraid of dying?
I'm more afraid of living.
I gotta tell you, bro...
...what you're doing is really brave.
I promise I'll look after Gail...
...and Damon.
Yeah. I know.
I promise.
- Here you go.
- Thanks, pal.
A large buttered popcorn, please.
- What is that stuff?
- Butter.
- That's real butter?
- No, it's a butter-like topping.
No, you don't understand. I don't want
any of this golden-flavored shit.
No, put it back. We're not paying for this.
- lf you don't have butter...
- Is there a problem here?
Yes, sir, there is.
It's time.
Any complications?
No.
Good.
Well, I guess this is it.
I can't. I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, man. I can't.
Oh, my God.
What did you do?
- You were fucking her, weren't you?
- What?
- You were fucking my wife.
- What? Nothing was going on.
What were you doing at my house
at 2:30 in the morning?
- When?
- The night the rookie went down.
I tried to call you.
- What did you do?
- Here it is.
Here it is, the phone bill. The call
you made from here to your machine.
She came on to me, man.
I ended it, I swear to God.
It never really bothered me
that you were such a fuck-up...
...'cause you were my brother, and I loved you.
But after all I've done for you, you betrayed me.
And that I can't forgive.
Man, did you set us up.
Hold on, Officer.
Run a check on all these cars.
Hit the next block, too.
Okay, make sure you run this tape
all the way around the house.
Talk to the neighbors.
- Where is he?
- Inside.
Look, let me try to do my job, will you please?
They tried to kill me.
They tried to kill me, Ricky.
Who handled it?
A guy named Sutter. He did the investigation.
We borrowed him from the 15th.
It's pretty open-and-shut.
Justifiable cause. They left a trail a mile wide.
Nick didn't have a criminal mind.
He certainly didn't have a cop's.
Anyway...
I got some bad news.
They were doing each other.
God.
- Ricky, do me a favor.
- Name it.
They want me to stay in here another day.
Damon's at camp, can you go pick him up?
Sure, I'll go pick him up
first thing tomorrow morning.
3:30. His son's in Brighton, Vista Hills.
- Thanks very much.
- Rosa, take that into Dempsey. He won't eat.
I'll take it in.
We've been trying to reach my brother
in Canada, but can't get a hold of him.
- Hi, Damon.
- What's going on? Where's Mom and Dad?
- Tell Dempsey I had to take off.
- Yeah, sure.
Your dad's in the study, come on.
- What about Nicky's stuff?
- Goodwill?
I could box up some of his personal things
and bring them back.
- Hi, Damon.
- What's going on?
- We gotta get going.
- Yeah.
- We'll see you tomorrow.
- All right. Thanks for coming over.
- No problem.
- Take it easy.
Laura says you've got to eat.
- You hungry, Damon?
- No. What's going on, Dad?
I mean, may he rest in peace.
Fucking Nick, so stupid.
Arrested this whore, cuffs her...
...locks her in the squad car with his keys.
- Get out of here.
- Am I right, Alan?
- It's bullshit.
How many cops have taken a bullet
because these vests open up?
You can't wear a suit of armor.
You gotta maneuver out there.
I have a family.
I don't want to end up in a wheelchair.
Suicidal.
- Demps is suicidal?
- Fucking A. Tried to eat his gun.
It's in the report. Sutter told me.
No, Dempsey ain't no dry diver.
Guys like that always end up on their feet.
Figuratively speaking.
Jerry, got a minute?
- I'll come back.
- No, come on in.
So, what's up?
Alan, are you taking your medication?
That's the most baroque tale I ever heard.
- I know it sounds a little complex.
- A little? Come on, Jerry.
- I know it's...
- What about motive?
- They were doing each other.
- Dempsey didn't know that.
What if he did?
I personally am not calling him in.
Demps. You back?
In a manner of speaking. I'm a murder suspect.
And you're one guilty motherfucker, too.
- Just give me a holler when you're ready.
- Okay. Thanks.
Let's make this quick.
Dempsey, there seems to be some confusion.
- Alan, why don't you...
- Are you confused, Alan?
Yeah, we got a little problem
with the angle of the dangle.
Your brother's entry wounds,
they just don't make sense...
...being fired from a sitting position.
I don't understand how that could happen.
Well, I'll tell you what.
I heard a noise, and I came...
...jogging into the bedroom
and saw my brother and...
We're sorry to bring you in like this.
He was crouched down.
Why?
I threw something at him.
- Why didn't you mention that before?
- I just remembered it.
I know, it sounds like a big clichè.
I just remembered it.
Do you remember what you threw?
- Paperweight.
- What did it look like?
Palm tree with snow. Got it in Hawaii.
Fine.
The plot thickens.
Directory assistance. What city, please?
Information for Oahu,
it's a business in Honolulu.
That's great.
Good. That's good, come on.
Have a nice vacation.
Hi.
I was wondering if you could help me.
I'll be right with you.
Take your time.
This is yours. Get your bun.
This is yours. Nice. Very good.
What?
You got me.
Go!
Slippery Sam wins by a neck.
Ain't right that he got a bug up his ass
about the shooting.
- What kind of bug?
- He's not giving up on it.
On his off hours digging away,
spent a couple days in Mexico.
Son of a bitch. What's with this guy?
- Did Captain give him a nod on this?
- No. He thinks he's being secretive.
Captain's not even willing to talk about it.
- That petty, fucking, vindictive...
- Ricky, forget it.
- The guy's got no life.
- Alan.
Explain to me this Dempsey-fixation
thing you got here.
Independents from the 15th come down
and say we got no problem here.
- Get me another beer.
- You say no...
...going behind everyone's back to the IA,
who says:
"We got no problem." Captain, "No problem."
So my question,
"What's your fucking problem?"
There's a lot of us who are confused,
not just me. Who are you working for?
Why don't you back off, Enrique?
You're invading my space...
...and your taco breath is a little appalling.
I'm gonna rip your motherfucking head.
Fuck you, you rat, you mole, you piece of shit.
All right.
How can I help you? What can I do for you?
You wanna come to my house?
You wanna go through my files?
You wanna put me on the box?
That's a fine idea, Dempsey.
Thanks for the offer.
Give me another beer.
Is your first name Dempsey?
Yes.
Do you live in England?
No.
Do you have two children?
Yes.
Will you just drop it?
This is getting sick.
- I can't.
- Why? He passed. What do you want?
People are talking about you. This is ugly.
- You weren't there.
- Where?
When we brought him in for questioning,
he was dancing...
...doing fucking triple axels.
I know this guy. He's dirty.
How do you know? You got nothing on him.
How do I know?
I'm a highly-trained professional.
That's how I know.
Nick might have been stupid,
but he wasn't a killer.
I'll tell you one thing...
...if my brother was banging my wife,
I'd shoot him, too.
No.
Don't give me this,
"No disrespect intended," bullshit.
You're investigating one of my men,
my best man, behind my back.
- Look, I'm saying the paperweight...
- Fuck the paperweight.
You don't have the shred of a case.
You going to take this paperweight
bullshit to the D. A?
I'll tell you what this looks like.
This is a personal vendetta,
and I will not stand for it.
You hear me? Now drop it.
I don't wanna hear about this again.
- All right.
- Okay?
- I said, "All right."
- All right. I want you to work on this.
Surveillance? You're punishing me with a sit?
You call it what you want.
I think he's been through enough, don't you?
- Da, can you get that?
- I got it.
You're not delivering
Chinese food now, are you?
- No. Hi, Damon.
- Hi.
I just wanted to apologize for the...
Well, if I was...
The bar the other night.
- I brought you this. I just wanted to say...
- Come on in.
Just ask me what you want to know.
You said Nick
was crouching when you shot him.
That's why the entry wounds look like they did.
And you said he was crouching because...
...you threw a paperweight at him.
- That's right.
Then how come...
...the paperweight...
...is sitting on the shelf?
Here's a blowup, if you want a better look.
And there she still sits.
I didn't throw that paperweight, Alan. I threw...
...that one.
- It's the same.
- Yeah.
You have two identical paperweights.
While Gail and I were on our honeymoon,
we brought one back for Nick...
...and he never took his home.
- It's not in the photos.
- Yes, it is.
- Where?
- It's right there, under the couch.
You did take photos under the couch,
didn't you?
Will you stop it? I'm off it, okay.
Maybe I got a little nuts.
You got a lot nuts, pal.
Is that her?
It's not her.
You going to eat that pie?
- Rough night? You boys been naughty.
- Fuck you.
You don't have to babysit me.
What you got?
I want to log back into Cain shooting.
Thing is you're obsessive.
Four pieces. Sign the log, please.
Phyllis always said this about you,
and she was right.
- How is Phyllis?
- I need your badge number.
I heard she's moving to Ohio with some dentist.
Heard she looks great, really happy.
No wonder she left you.
You got this obsessive-compulsive
personality thing.
The good news is, you can get help.
There's people you can talk to.
He's killing me.
I'm spinning out.
Hello, Jimmy? Alan. How's it going?
Great. Listen...
...do you remember that Mexican
counterfeiting operation?
They were doing everything.
50s, passports, green cards.
Yeah. Big fat guy.
Dempsey's case. No.
What year was that?
Night, Alan.
Goodnight.
Fuck it.
Chronicle.
I didn't call the papers, all right?
Fuck you, man.
Who else would know this shit?
It's got your name all fucking over it.
- Somebody talk to me here.
- What if we let it blow over?
For Christ's sake.
There is no way IA can avoid
an investigation at this point.
I'm not dragging a good cop to court...
...just to satisfy the press
and some idiot politician.
There's nothing hard here.
It's all circumstantial.
I'll get you more.
Now, if this guy is dirty,
we've got to file charges.
I know your job description, Bob.
We do the preliminary hearing. We keep it
as quiet as we can. See if it survives.
Okay, Detective, you do your worst.
But if you are wrong, I will have you for lunch.
Are you with me?
See you, Dad.
- Gotta go to practice, be home late.
- Okay. See you later.
This is the time and place
of the preliminary hearing...
...in the matter of the State of California versus...
...Dempsey Cain.
How would you describe the relationship
between Cain and your daughter?
Well, from the outside, it looked perfect.
- But I think...
- In your opinion...
...would a $1-million insurance policy
in her name...
Objection. Calls for speculation.
Sustained.
Could you repeat, to the best of your ability,
exactly what she said?
She said, "I'm 35, and I don't want to
push a wheelchair for the rest of my life."
Thank you. No further questions.
Then he took the gun out of his mouth
and broke down in tears.
- And the window shades were open.
- Yes.
If you were really going to commit suicide...
...would you sit in front of a window?
Objection. The prosecutor's testifying.
Argumentative.
Sustained.
The California distinguished service award...
...and Mayor's commendation for public service.
And prior to becoming
a decorated police officer?
He was a U.S. Navy test pilot,
discharged with honors.
I believe his eyesight fell
just below pilot standards.
A typical murderer's resume.
Come on. Objection, your honor.
Sustained. Ms. Wallace,
you have no jury to play to here.
I can assure you, your sarcasm,
however clever, is being wasted on me.
I'm sorry, Your Honor.
Could you describe him for us?
Yes. He was a big guy, over 6 feet...
...had a beard, wore a cap, like a watch cap.
Longish hair, and he walked with a cane.
He walked with a cane.
- Go on, please.
- He picked up a few videos.
Mr. Morphus, do you see the man
who rented those videos in the courtroom?
No.
Is this the man who rented those videos
from your store on July 11?
Yeah.
Yeah. That's the guy.
Your Honor, I'm holding the photograph
of a man. I'm marking this People's 9.
It is a picture of Detective Cain,
altered by computer...
...adding a cap, glasses,
a beard, and lengthened hair.
- Your witness.
- May I?
This is the man you think
rented those videos from you.
Yeah. That's what he looked like.
And you are sure this is the man?
That's the guy.
You Honor, I'm holding a photograph of a man...
...l'm marking it defense Exhibit "C."
It's a computer-altered photograph
of Charles McKenzie, a man on my staff.
You've just identified two different men
as the man who rented those videos.
Which is it?
And what are the chances
of a patient with this condition...
...becoming ambulatory again?
50-50 maybe. It's extremely variable.
Could you tell, Doctor,
if a man were faking paralysis?
One could test the patient
for motor and sensory responses.
Yes or no, could you tell,
simply from an examination...
...if a patient were faking paralysis?
You're asking a complicated question.
Yes or no, could someone fake paralysis?
- Yes.
- Thank you.
Your witness.
Dr. Cole, when was the last time
you examined Mr. Cain?
Six weeks ago.
In your professional opinion,
is Detective Cain faking paralysis?
- No.
- Thank you.
The People call...
...Mr. Jorge De La Paz to the stand.
Wait a second, Your Honor. We object.
I had no prior notice of this witness...
...and I move that his testimony not be allowed.
Mr. Shultz, I don't appreciate
your surprises in my courtroom.
I will overrule the defense's objection,
but I will permit a recess.
Who the hell is this guy, Demps?
Okay. Listen to me very carefully.
- Where is your shop located?
- Tijuana, Mexico.
Did you, on July 11, produce this
counterfeit California driver's license...
...for the man pictured in the license?
Yes.
Let the record reflect that Mr. De La Paz
has identified Nick Cain.
Were you expecting Nick Cain
when he arrived at your shop on July 11?
- Yes.
- Had Nick Cain called you?
- No.
- Who did call you?
Dempsey Cain.
Thank you.
Your witness.
Mr. De La Paz, you stated that Mr. Cain
spoke with you on the phone.
- Did he identify himself?
- No.
- Then how did you know it was him?
- Nick Cain came to my shop.
He said Dempsey sent him.
Then I remember his voice on the phone
because we go back.
You go back to 1988...
...when Detective Cain arrested you
for counterfeiting...
...for which you were convicted and spent
three years in the Chino prison, true?
Yes, so?
I have no further questions for this witness.
Would you describe your relationship
with Detective Cain as competitive?
I'd say we're all a little competitive
with each other.
It keeps us on our toes.
Do you remember saying:
"The Captain has such a hard on
for Dempsey, it's embarrassing"?
Probably. I might have.
Tell me, Detective, were you initially
assigned to the Cain case to investigate?
No.
Did the Captain authorize you to investigate?
Yet you found yourself in
Tijuana, Mexico, investigating.
Yes. I was down there on other business...
Did you arrange for Mr. De La Paz's
trip here today?
Yes.
Isn't it true that Mr. De La Paz is receiving
$75 a day to testify?
- That is standard procedure.
- Objection! Mr. De La Paz...
...is being reimbursed for
legitimate expenses and lost wages.
Sustained.
Is it not also standard procedure
that the detectives...
...augment these legitimate expenses
under the table?
Your Honor,
we strongly resent these insinuations.
Are you suggesting I bought this witness?
Your Honor, I'm suggesting that he has
a personal vendetta against my client.
Come on!
It's clear that Mr. De La Paz will sell
anything to anybody at the right price.
These are unfounded allegations.
This court will come to order.
Mr. Cain...
...did you contact Mr. De La Paz
by phone or in any other manner...
...between May 1 and July 11 of this year?
No, I absolutely did not.
Mr. Cain, on the night of July 15,
did you shoot your wife and brother?
Yes.
Could you repeat that, please? Louder.
- Yes, I did.
- Why?
Because they were going to kill me.
Do you have any feeling in your legs?
- No.
- Are you able to walk?
No.
Thank you.
The defense rests, Your Honor.
It appearing to me,
from the evidence presented in this case...
...that the court does not find
sufficient evidence...
...to hold the defendant to answer to
the charges of murder in the first degree.
The case is dismissed.
The defendant is discharged.
Son of a bitch murdered
his wife and his brother, and now he...
...walks away.
I'm sorry you had to go through this, pal.
Congratulations.
Again.
But I got to tell you something, Demps...
...l'm a better detective than you are.
'Cause I got the nose.
I know you murdered them.
And I know...
I know you can walk.
- Oh, my God.
- Jesus, Alan. What the hell?
Get him out of here. Get this guy out of here.
You have the right to remain silent.
If you waive it, anything you say
will be held against you in a court of law.
You have the right to an attorney.
If you cannot afford one, one will be
appointed for you before you're questioned.
What the hell is going on?
I'll need you to sign here.
We're okay. All right.
Hey there, sunshine.
- How are you doing?
- Fine.
What happened to your leg?
I was in a little accident. It's okay, though.
- She's not very good.
- No, she's not.
But I like her.
What am I doing wrong?
You've got to learn
how to control your concentration.