ADBHUTHAM
Life is a battle.
You must fight and win.
Show the world what you're made of.
Once you know
what the world demands,
you can show it your success and
the attitude that comes with it
and then say a thousand
motivational quotes like I just did.
My frustration is
at such a peak now...
that it's not going anywhere.
Our sins lead us
to wherever we end up.
You need strong reasons to live.
But, to die,
all you need is a small excuse.
Shame on your life!
Who says such lines
before dying, Vennela?
Die bravely.
Good riddance.
Die!
Sorry, dad.
I hate you, dad.
You did this.
Forgive me, dad.
I'll never forgive you.
Hey! I told you
not to open that room.
‐It's really dusty in there, sir.
‐I don't care.
Wonder what he's got in there.
‐Hello.
‐Where are you, man?
‐Home. Why?
‐Why do you sound so cute?
‐Did you just wake up?
‐Hmm.
The guest is here.
We're waiting for you.
I can manage for 15 minutes.
Be here.
He's coming.
Food, again?
Don't know who sent it.
Who's sending it?
I don't like girls getting
too much education or freedom.
They act rebellious.
That is why I got both
my daughters married at 18.
She's the third.
I had to continue her studies
because she is stubborn.
Now, I think it's high time
that she gets married.
Do we have poison handy?
I think we emptied it.
What did you say?
Come here.
You've got me all dolled up.
I have to take the coffee to them.
Why don't I add some poison to it?
If the police ask,
we can tell it's food poisoning.
They'll want to know where
we bought the coffee powder.
Let's say from Pradeep's shop.
That idiot fondles my fingers
every time I take the bill.
He'll be framed for this.
I can happily go to Germany
and study automobile engineering.
How's my master plan sound?
This guy...
‐Hey! Want a cup of coffee?
‐No, thanks.
Hey, stop!
Sister mixed poison in the coffee.
Ew! Don't make me do this, mom.
Please, please, please.
Didn't find poison.
Didn't mix it.
You can drink it.
Wow! What a beauty!
Please have it.
‐What do you do, son?
‐Software.
Is it the same kind where they fire
thousands of you during a crisis?
With my qualification,
people will be dying to hire me.
So, it's an unstable life.
Mom!
You two can go talk in private.
‐Excuse me.
‐Yes?
‐Please sit over there.
‐I'm comfortable here.
‐You sit there.
‐Hey! Get up!
Go sit there. Overexcited.
This is my bed.
It'll be ours when we're married.
‐I don't want this marriage.
‐Your dad told me you'll say that.
I have 4 boyfriends, you know?
I have 10.
‐Huh?
‐I meant girlfriends.
I'm very straight.
You can't put up with me.
I'm really patient.
I go crazy every full moon
and new moon days.
I'll sleep at my friend's
those two days.
I bite when I'm pissed.
I'll get an injection.
Hey, fool!
Why would you still
want to marry me?
What can I say?
The heart wants what it wants.
Oh, god!
Please! I have dreams.
‐Don't come in my way.
‐Germany, right?
You could go to Jharkhand
after marriage for all I care.
I'll support you, baby.
‐What if I want to settle there?
‐Do that. I'll spend my life here.
Why do you want
to get married then?
If you're here and I'm overseas,
will we have kids on the phone?
Oh! I get it now.
You're assuming that,
if you agree to all my terms,
I'll marry you, bear kids
and be a homemaker.
I'll smother you with a pillow
on the wedding night.
Is that why you have
so many pillows?
Answer me!
Let's go back outside.
Uncle, I really like Vennela.
I don't want a single penny
as dowry.
Thanks, son.
Considering there's an age gap,
I want her to give me some time.
I'll get onto family planning
in a year.
What!
I don't mean a vasectomy.
I'll plan our future.
Once we have a kid or two,
doing household chores
shouldn't be difficult.
‐Hey!
‐I mean for her, dad.
Oh!
‐We'll take our leave then.
‐Sure.
The car broke down, sir.
Do you have a toolkit?
Hand me the spanner.
This girl's a mechanic?
It's nothing.
The crank sensor popped. I fixed it.
Start the car.
So, that's why she has car posters
in her room.
Go inside!
The sweets are delicious.
Where are the chips?
‐Inside, auntie.
‐Go get it.
Who are those 4 boyfriends?
He told you?
Have this.
You go crazy every full moon
and new moon days?
I was just trying to scare him.
Thank god I told them
about you beforehand.
Yelling at her won't help.
She's still a little kid.
This one?
She threatened to smother him
with a pillow on the wedding night.
You call her a little kid?
You said that?
She didn't say that.
That idiot's lying. Bad fellow.
I know you both a little too well.
Stop it.
This marriage will happen.
‐I don't want it.
‐Shut up.
I'm drained
getting your two sisters married.
He wants to marry you without dowry,
and you guys are fooling around?
Stop it!
You can't get her married
to any loser who refuses dowry.
Have you even looked at him?
Owl‐faced idiot.
Damn right.
Dad, I'm not marrying him. Period.
Finally, what's your decision?
I'll give the GET exam
one last time.
Go to Germany and pursue
automobile engineering.
‐But you'll have to clear the exam.
‐I will, dad.
This is what you said
the last couple of times.
‐I don't trust you.
‐Do it one last time.
All right.
I'll get you married if you fail.
If you refuse,
I'll put my head under a train.
Okay.
Okay to what?
Your marriage or my death?
Dad, do whatever you want
if I fail this time.
When are the mock test
results coming?
This evening.
If I clear this,
the main exam is a given.
I know what it's going to be.
Come to me with the results.
‐Hello.
‐ Hi, Surya. This is Sameer.
You never answer my calls.
What's the matter?
I have some shocking news.
This year the competition
is really, really big.
You have a prize money.
Stop bragging.
Didn't I tell you
I'm not into it anymore?
I'm out of it.
Bro, just say yes.
I'll manage the rest.
Wild‐card entries, sponsors...
Hello! Can't you see!
‐What are you doing?
‐Sorry.
What happened to the display?
My display is gone too.
Yeah, same here.
I'm going to smack you
if you don't shut up!
Yes, I drink. It's my wish.
Did your dad pay for it?
‐Didn't my dad give you any money?
‐My foot!
That money couldn't
even pay for my parties.
You're always drunk and wasted.
Don't you care about your family.
I drink whenever I think of you.
You're acting up.
Better come home.
Bugger off! I'll kill you
if you find you in my home.
Say it to my face, you‐‐
That was insane, sir.
Was it your wife?
No. Some wrong number.
I've been receiving a lot of
wrong calls since morning.
Why did you yell at her then?
Why do you care?
Is Surya here yet?
‐He's in makeup, sir.
‐Still?
‐ Where are you?
‐Checking up on Surya. Sorry, boss.
How long, man?
The guest's been waiting for an hour.
Boss is really pissed.
I can't manage him anymore.
‐The guest is waiting, bro.
‐I'm coming. Hold on.
Who's the guest?
‐Music director Tijori.
‐What has he achieved?
He's a great music director.
He's a music Taekwondo.
Says who?
Why would I take someone
for their word?
Am I looking like a foolish man?
That guy told me.
Surya is on the way. Be ready.
Hi. Hello and welcome to my show.
We have with us today music
rock legend, the rock king,
Mr. Mizoram!
It's not Mizoram or Manipur.
‐It's Tijori.
‐Yeah, that.
Idiot!
Why Tijori, sir? Your name
sounds musical. How, sir?
Actually, Tijori translates
to "treasure" in Hindi.
Unlike any newborn,
I didn't cry when I was born.
‐Apparently, I said Do‐Re‐Mi‐Fa.
‐Fantastic, sir.
So, even when you sing,
you sound like you're crying.
Next question, sir.
Sir, your recent song
"Pita Pita"...
For your information,
it's "Kita Kita."
Oh. When I heard it,
I had goosebumps all over my body.
How, sir?
When I was in Los Angeles,
at the Niagara Falls‐‐
Excuse me, sir.
Niagara Falls is not in LA.
It's in New York.
A stream flowed all the way
to LA. Do you mind?
Shut up and listen.
A girl from Costa Rica
kept staring at me.
She was in shock!
She wondered how a huge celebrity
is roaming in the US so freely.
Sir, who's the celebrity here?
Remove my mic, guys.
‐Oh, you're the celebrity.
‐It's me.
There I got an inspiration.
Her eyes were glowing.
That's when this magical sound
"Kita Kita" came to me.
Can you hum
a couple of lines for us?
"A mad girl got on the plane"
"She poked my heart
With a popsicle"
"She blinked her eyes
Like Kita Kita Roma"
How is it?
Sir, it's "Taki Taki" by DJ Snake.
This is my original tune.
Own composition.
Do I look like a copycat to you?
It's called copying
when you rip off the tune.
And it's a chartbuster
by DJ Snake.
Who the hell is this DJ Snake?
He's after all a snake.
I'm an anaconda.
Bloody fool!
This is my creativity.
Oh. You're a re‐creator, sir.
Not the creator.
‐Recreation is also an art.
‐Enough!
Let's stop the interview here.
‐Sir, I'm sorry.
‐Don't talk. Not a word.
‐Sir, please.
‐Where's your CEO? Call him here.
‐Sir, please. He is a kid.
‐Seriously?
People would've bashed me
if this was live.
‐Every idiot feels like a musician.
‐Sorry. sir.
What does he even know about music?
Amazing, dude!
Come here.
Sir.
Is the show over?
You rascal!
‐I'll see your end.
‐ Sorry!
Tijori sir, Tijori sir!
Hold on, you fool!
I didn't mean you, sir.
Sir, please.
I came third.
What are you so upset about?
Check mine.
Lord Rama! Please!
Make sure I pass.
I'll take you to Germany with me.
Oh, Lord Rama! Make sure I pass.
Please, please...
You failed.
Yes, you failed again.
Congrats for your marriage!
Shut up!
Hello, mom. I came third.
‐Don't tell dad yet.
‐Let's go.
If you fail again,
you're definitely getting married.
What are girls going to achieve
by studying?
You're failing each and every time.
What are you if not a failure?
How long will you stare, sir?
Say something!
You speak.
I guess you're expecting
an apology.
I'm sorry. Let it go.
I'm asking this
as your dad's friend.
Don't you feel a tad bit guilty?
He copies other people's music.
Why should I feel guilty
when he's not?
You have the channel's reputation
to think about.
Sir! That interview of his
just went viral.
It's trending on social media.
You should throw a party.
‐Promise me.
‐Shut up!
Useless fellow.
Such a spoilsport!
I'll take my leave.
Don't come back!
Never show me your face again.
Are you good at anything at all?
Everybody makes mistakes.
Doesn't mean
you humiliate them on camera.
Didn't you make mistakes?
Your dad died
because of you, remember?
He'd always say that
you're obsessed with music.
He was worried about your future.
He said you couldn't make a living.
How could you take his life?
Bloody loser!
Something strange has been
taking place in Hyderabad.
Cross connections of phone calls
and mysterious occurrences in the sky.
What's the reason behind
the sky's sudden colour change?
What is the reason behind this?
Nobody knows the answer.
The public is concerned.
These changes in nature have
never been recorded earlier.
Hello? Can you hear me?
‐Hello!
‐Hello.
Shit! I can't even get
customer care.
What? Are you going upstairs?
What's wrong, sir?
Even you failed me this time.
I'd rather die than marry that guy.
My death can become news.
But I don't want it
to become a nuisance.
How do I say it?
Suicide note.
I've made enough people
suffer already.
Whom do I send this to?
I don't want to trouble anyone.
I'll send it to my number
so that I receive the message.
Correct.
"Nobody is responsible
for my death."
What?
Who is it?
Who sent the text?
One
Hey! Who the hell are you?
Are you messing with me?
Cheapskate!
Did he just call me cheap?
You weirdo! I'll cut off your tongue
if you don't shut up.
‐Who are you?
‐My name's Surya.
‐Vennela.
Whatever. Tell me what you want.
Answers.
How are you doing this?
Listen. I'm busy trying to die.
Don't annoy me.
Why?
Do I need your permission?
I don't care.
Tell me how you're texting me
from my number.
What?
Oh, crap!
We have the same phone number!
‐Hello?
‐Where the hell are you?
Nowhere, dad.
What?
I'm at Durgam Cheruvu, dad.
What is it?
Grandma had a heart attack.
Come fast!
What?
‐How is she now?
‐She's in the ICU.
‐Which hospital?
‐Maitri Hospital.
Coming, dad.
Hey!
Are you out of your mind?
‐I have something to ask you.
‐Go ahead.
Can two people have
the same number?
Which number? PAN or Aadhar?
Phone number, you idiot!
What are you doing?
‐Making a call.
‐To whom?
‐My number.
‐You're calling your own number?
‐Yeah. It's busy.
‐Does that mean you have to jump?
Sir, I don't want this money.
Just be happy.
Lord should bless you.
Hey! Give it to me. Amen!
Take this.
Don't tell anybody about this. Go.
‐Something is wrong, dude.
‐Okay, sir.
Vennela has the same number as me.
I don't know how.
The moonlight
also uses a mobile phone?
Yeah! And it's the same number.
Do these clouds, stars, coconut
trees and hills also have numbers?
I don't mean the moonlight.
It's a girl.
Two people can't have
the same number, man.
I can't imagine what would've
happened if I was a bit late.
So, you think you saved me
or something?
Of course.
I was going to jump.
But this text
messed with my brain.
I should find out
who this girl is.
You're here.
What's her condition?
‐They just shifted her from the ICU.
‐Move! Give way!
‐She's doing fine now.
‐Move!
Move! Give way!
‐Wait.
‐Please wait outside.
This place really scares me.
Careful.
Dad went down.
Said he'll be right back.
Madam, out. This way.
‐Put him in observation for 6 hours.
‐Okay, sir.
‐Call me if anything's up.
‐All right.
What happened?
Suicide case. He downed
a bottle of sleeping pills.
Oh, no. What went wrong?
Love failure apparently.
Alas! Kids and
their hasty decisions.
Hello.
How long will you keep me waiting?
I've been asking the same question
since an hour.
How can you give the same number
to two people?
Hi! How are you doing?
Are you fricking blind?
I was just making small talk.
First, answer my question.
All right, ask.
How can you give it to two people?
How?
I get it.
But I broke up with Praveen.
I'm not a fool to believe
whatever you say.
I have your chat history
from last night.
No, Surya.
I'll mess up your image on social
media if you try to convince me.
Sir, when will you give me
my 500 bucks?
‐Sorry.
‐Get lost. I didn't get my salary yet.
What?
‐I have nothing more to say.
‐Huh?
What happened to her?
You were yelling
at the customer care guy,
and she thought it's for her.
Girls are like ice cream.
You should handle them smoothly.
They get easily hurt for anything.
She looks fine.
I'm neither interested
nor desperate.
I still can't figure out how Vennela
and I can have the same number.
Are you still obsessing over that?
I mean, how is it even possible?
There's this friend of mine.
When he has no company,
he plays cards from both sides.
Are you saying I'm sending
these texts to myself?
Without a doubt.
What do you call her?
I didn't give her a name.
She told me it's Vennela.
Nice choice.
"Hi, Vennela.
Will you come for a date?"
Why did you say it's a date?
She'll get offended.
Oh. You'll get offended
if I don't reply.
‐What do I say?
‐Don't mess with my feelings, dude.
‐I'll push you off the building.
‐Yeah, right.
First, you try jumping last night.
Now you want to push me.
Why did you go downstairs
last night?
‐I went to the rooftop.
‐Yes. But why?
‐To jump.
‐I see it now.
You must've gotten drunk
and texted yourself.
You're Surya by day
and Vennela at night.
If Vennela existed,
she'd have replied by now.
You think I'm going crazy?
Should we visit a doctor?
First, let's meet our boss.
He's waiting in the conference hall.
Didn't I tell you?
Nobody's on time.
Not even the boss.
What are you doing
in the dark, boss?
I thought you quit.
I had a dream that
you apologised to me.
‐What?
‐That is why I came back.
You continue.
Which page?
Oh, my god! 261!
Unless we come up with something
other than fun‐filled shows,
our TRPs are not going up.
So, we all have to work hard, okay?
That's when we can beat our rivals.
Did she reply?
Why are you banging your head?
Why don't you give us a concept?
Sir, I have something new.
PDA by youth at coffee shops,
bars, metro lifts,
and cinema halls is quite common.
Some make out in daylight
without any fear.
If we shoot this secretively
and telecast a 2‐hour program,
our TRPs will peak.
We shouldn't give
the public space to think.
What do you want to call it?
Pulihora: The Youth Mixture.
Clap.
You said something
about space earlier.
Space, sir. The space.
Come here.
Is he going to hug?
I didn't brush today.
Yes, sir?
Your writings. Read it.
"Blowing."
‐Blow what?
‐Nothing sir.
I forgot to add "winds," sir.
I forgot to add space
between the words.
Read next.
"Fire is‐‐"
Stop!
Stop right there.
Did you say all the words?
‐Did you add space this time?
‐No, sir.
‐Next.
‐It's okay, sir. Let's stop.
I don't mind. Go on.
"The slut is..."
"The slot is open."
That should be it.
Quit your crappy ideas
and learn to spell first.
Go away!
You want the salary on time, eh?
Why didn't she reply, dude?
Come up with nice concepts.
‐You said that last night.
‐I have surprise gifts for you.
‐I can't believe she didn't reply.
‐So, better get your A‐game on.
Hey! How many times
do I have to tell you?
‐She'll not reply. Forget her.
‐She will!
Would we get TRPs this way?
Why would we?
‐Hit me hard if we do.
‐Hey!
If that happens,
I'll get everybody's heads shaved!
Annoying the shit out of me.
Sorry, sir.
Hi, man.
My boss can't function without me.
‐Mom.
‐Hmm?
‐I have a small doubt.
‐Tell me.
Do you think I'll turn into you
if I get married?
Not a chance!
‐He would die if he marries me.
‐Whatever. Let's go downstairs.
"Hi, Vennela.
Will you come for a date?"
I want each one of you to come up
with at least 2 ideas.
Surya.
I got a message, sir.
‐Messages again.
‐Hey!
Is that idiot calling you out?
You think this is a school?
Get out!
‐Hey, where's Prasad?
‐He left, sir.
His phone's off.
You pig! You're so full of crap.
How dare you ask me out on a date!
You jobless idiot!
Hey, shit‐face!
I didn't send that text.
My friend did.
Oh! If I said yes, then you would've
said that you sent the message?
Who'd go on a date
with a crazy girl like you?
You poop‐face!
Do you know
how many go crazy about me?
Dogs, I suppose. I know.
You ass! I'll tell the cops
if you send these texts again.
Sure. Remember
we have the same number.
Let me see whose house
the cops will end up at.
How are you even texting me
from my number?
That's my question too.
How are you doing it, you devil?
If you text me again,
I'll disfigure your face.
Yeah!
I've been so waiting for that.
Just shut up!
I'll never reply to you, loser.
Hey, please, please, please reply.
I can't hold in the swear words.
Come, let's fight.
Why don't you gulp some acid?
Good riddance!
Hey! Thank you for your advice.
Get lost!
Get this.
I'll never text you again.
Thank god!
I don't want you to text me either.
There have been so many
phone call cross connections.
Do you think
it's a network problem?
No, no, no.
It's is not a network problem.
We faced the same issue
five years back in 2014.
People were as confused
if not more.
What do you call this phenomenon?
It's called a Solar Flare Effect.
When there's a high voltage,
all the lights burn bright, right?
Similarly, the sun also
burns bright sometimes.
That's when these solar flares
are generated.
They disturb the short waves
in our atmosphere.
Radio transmissions
and telecommunication signals
are disturbed, leading to this.
Sir, I have a doubt.
You just spoke about
cross connections.
But, is it possible for two people
to interact using the same number?
How can that happen?
Service providers decide
the number, right?
I spoke to them, sir.
They have no clue.
Maybe they really have no clue.
If two frequencies mismatch
due to a solar flare,
two people could interact from the
same number due to magnetic anomaly.
But that's a very, very,
very rare case.
Sir, is this science or
some supernatural power?
Progress of science
in the world is only
as much as the light emitted
from a candle.
Many secrets are hidden
in the darkness around it.
Let's see how far we can go.
The more we dig, the more
we realise that we know nothing.
Hello. You just got discharged
and you're already tiring yourself?
One goes to Mt. Kailash if they die
chanting Lord Rama's name.
It's like buying a ticket to Vizag
and boarding a Mumbai train.
Why will you go to Mt. Kailash
if you chant Lord Rama's name?
You should chant Lord Shiva's name
if you want to go to Mr. Kailash.
‐Don't you know that?
‐I do.
Are you teaching me the epics
I taught you?
Shiva and Vishnu are one entity.
That's the matter.
If you speak logic,
she'll quote some holy verse
and confuse us.
We don't know any holy verse.
Which chapter
are you teaching in Ramayana?
With the clue Jatayu
gave in Ashokavanam,
Lord Rama found that
Sita was in Lanka.
So, hero Rama found out where
villain Ravan hid heroine Sita.
Wow! What a thriller!
My foot!
This is not a movie.
It's mythology, you fool.
Whatever it is, I just want them
to understand it.
Goddess Sita was gloomy,
thinking about Lord Rama.
What happened?
She wanted to leave her body
as she was worried.
What do you mean?
I wanted to commit suicide.
You?
No. Sita.
Who saved her?
‐The message.
‐Correct.
What message?
The ring Rama sent was the message.
He asked her to be strong
by sending it across.
Maruti delivered the message to Sita,
and she was worried no more.
In fact, she hoped for life.
Grandma...
what if the message never came?
It would come definitely.
Or else, the story
wouldn't move forward.
Your story shouldn't stop here.
You shouldn't make foolish decisions
out of fear or anger.
Nature warns you that
you have a lot to accomplish.
Tell me, dear.
Can Ramayana exist
without Goddess Sita?
You think getting me drunk
will make me believe your stories?
No, uncle. Look, I got the text.
I got the cyber department
to check it.
Uncle, don't listen to him.
You'll end up in deep shit
if you do.
You don't want to lose your job,
do you?
‐But I know‐‐
‐Hello?
Just a second.
Uncle, check the message and go.
Go, go.
You're not helping here anyway.
I swear, dude.
She shut up when I countered her.
Did she shut up?
‐Yeah.
‐Okay. Do one thing.
Give her a peg.
She'll shut up forever.
Idiot!
If you don't shut up,
I'll write a suicide note
blaming you and Vennela,
then mix poison in my drink
and die.
‐I swear, dude.
‐Hold on.
Hey!
‐Leave me! I'll go home.
‐Hey!
There's drunk‐and‐drive check.
Let's walk home.
Idiot.
Hello?
Hi.
Oh, I didn't know
we could call each other also.
‐Thank you.
‐For what?
I was trying to commit suicide
when you first texted me.
But your text stopped that.
Thanks for saving my life, I guess.
Try again.
I won't text you this time.
Looks like you're still angry
with me.
You also texted me when I was
trying to jump off a building.
Oh! So, I also helped you.
Return my thanks.
Nobody would care if I die or live.
So, no thanks.
Oh! I'm just realising this, Surya.
We assume we could die
and kill our pain.
But we only pass it on
to a few others.
Suicide is not the permanent
solution to temporary problems.
And sorry.
What's this for?
I cussed at you really badly.
‐Then I'm really sorry.
‐Why?
I cussed you pretty badly too.
Really? What did you say?
Idiot, fool, shit‐face.
Let's not talk about it.
They'd have to bleep
the real cuss words.
You call these cuss words?
Mine sound better.
So, what do you do?
I smile and talk about
people's sins and scams.
TV reporter?
‐Y TV.
‐Y TV?
I still have the same reaction
to that channel.
What about you?
I try really hard and fail.
Been trying to crack GET
for 3 years.
What? The same exam for 3 years?
Where are you from, dear?
Hello!
I'll definitely crack it someday.
I was being serious.
Which city are you from?
Why?
Just wondering
how far apart we are.
I don't intend to move closer.
We don't have to meet,
but our cities could.
Mine's Hyderabad.
Hyderabad's not mine,
but I'm from here too.
‐Such a funny man!
‐Thanks.
We... got each other's messages
when we both were
about to commit suicide.
That too from the same number.
Why do you think
this is happening to us?
I don't know.
Maybe life gave us a second chance.
Why don't we give life a chance
this time?
What say?
‐Are you there?
‐Hmm.
I'll be there.
"Hello, Mr. Wrong Call"
"Where do you live?"
"You claim to be a smart girl"
"Why don't you figure it out?"
"What's his name and city?"
"What the hell's going on?"
"What's your age and size?"
"Give me the details, girl"
"Sorry. Not size."
"Tell me your age
and college name."
"You rascal! I'll block you
if you talk like this!"
"I'll kill you. Got it?"
"Sorry, sorry, sorry
That reminds me"
"Do you look fair?
Do you use Fair & Lovely?"
"Hey! How can you be so rapist?"
"What? Rapist? Hello!
I'm not that type!"
"Sorry. That was autotyped."
"I wonder how he looks"
"Will he be my friend
Or end up being fake?"
"I wonder how she is"
"Is it really a girl
Or is somebody catfishing me?"
"How did this even happen?"
"Will it work out
Or just remain a dream?"
"How did she come into my life?"
"Will she be honest or cheat me?"
"What's his name and city?"
"What the hell's going on?"
"You know this is torture for us"
"Stop texting her, dude!"
‐Surya, I have an amazing idea.
‐What's that?
There were no phones once upon
a time. People wrote letters.
What do you call them?
‐Pen friends.
‐Right. Pen friends.
Let's be phone friends.
What say?
But a few conditions.
We can't meet or see each other.
Let's just talk and text. Okay?
It's an old concept...
But it's new.
"Both tried to kill themselves"
"One due to pain
And other due to self‐respect"
"God laid back
And rejected your attempt"
"They started interacting
With the same number"
"This is surely magical
Not a dream, I swear"
"They're getting to know each other"
"Having dreams of their own"
"What's going on here?"
"Love is in the air"
"Love is in the air, for sure"
"This goes on all day and night"
"Tell me if you feel the same"
Hey, what's up?
"What's his name and city?"
"What the hell is going on?"
"Are you moving
Forward or backwards?"
"What's his name and city?"
"What the hell is going on?"
‐Don't confess your feelings?
‐Why?
Once you say you love each other,
it's game over.
Your life will get boring
like mine.
They'll chase us
only until we say yes.
Trust me.
Enjoy this feeling for a few days.
Are you listening?
‐We're just friends, okay?
‐Oh!
Hey, Divya, don't cry.
We'll do something about him.
Calm down.
Why is she crying?
Don't care. She's a crybaby.
Let's go.
Hold on.
Let's check on her.
What's wrong?
Did somebody die?
Why are you so down?
He cheated on me.
‐Are you pregnant?
‐Hell no!
All right then.
What happened?
We've been chatting online
for a year now.
Initially, he said
we're just friends.
I agreed.
Look at her. Then?
A few days later,
I gave him Rs. 50,000
for my sister‐in‐law's wedding.
It doesn't make sense.
His sister becomes
my sister‐in‐law, right?
You idiot! I'm going to kill you!
Stop! No! Don't!
What can I say? I fell in love.
Hey, stop!
‐Do you even know how he looks?
‐No.
‐But you sent him the money.
‐Yes.
Idiot!
How can you become friends
and love him without knowing him?
‐Huh.
‐Hmm.
The weather report suggests
heavy winds due to a cyclone.
That's all for the day.
Keep watching Y News.
Let's meet?
This guy...
‐Hello.
‐Hey.
I was going to call you.
I need a small favour.
I know.
That's your next step, right?
Step? What are you saying?
You know staircases, don't you?
Oops, I'm sorry. You're the kind
that takes the elevator.
‐I didn't get you.
‐But I'm pretty clear.
So, you want to meet?
I thought some conditions applied.
Clearly you weren't listening.
Conditions applied are
subjected to market risks.
Meet me at clock tower.
5 p.m. sharp.
Okay.
Surya, I've been meaning
to tell you something.
I love you, man.
How much money do you need?
‐Rs. 3,000.
‐Okay, come with me.
‐To the ATM?
‐No, clock tower.
‐What for?
Vennela called me.
She wants to meet.
Oh, shit!
I made peace with your belief that
you guys are texting and talking.
Now you say you're meeting her.
You've gone mad.
I'm worried about why she called.
Come with me, please.
It's Valentine's Day.
Maybe she wants to confess her love.
You think so?
Are you sure?
Don't overact.
You're not a child actor anymore.
You're all grown up now.
Act mature.
‐Are you coming or not?
‐No.
Unlike you, I'm not crazy.
Mr. Aravind, I love you 3,000.
I'm here. Where are you?
‐Hello.
‐I'm also here.
Where exactly?
On the yellow bench.
Yellow bench?
‐How many yellow benches are here?
‐Only one.
If we're sitting on the same bench,
why aren't you beside me?
You're not beside me either.
Are you really here?
Are you lying?
Hey! Why would I lie? I'm here.
I'm also here.
You're definitely lying.
I know you're not here.
Are you in Hyderabad, India
or Hyderabad, Pakistan?
Vennela, stop kidding
and come fast.
The wind's blowing heavily.
What?
Who the hell are you?
It's 40 degrees here,
and you're saying it's windy?
What! Vennela?
You cheat!
‐Hello!
‐I see it clearly now.
Are you out of your mind?
Where are you?
Just shut up!
You're a cheater.
Actually, I should blame myself
for trusting you blindly.
Just get lost!
I shouldn't have shown up,
damn it!
Rascal! Useless fellow!
How could you trust him?
HELLO!! WHERE ARE YOU???
YOU CRAZY WOMAN! IF YOU DIDN'T WANT
TO COME, WHY DID YOU CALL ME?
Hello.
What? You want money now?
Why are you talking about money?
Have you lost your mind?
You kept me waiting for so long.
Why didn't you come?
I'll kill you.
I was there, you idiot.
You didn't show up.
I didn't show up? Do you know
how long I waited in the storm?
Say storm one more time...
All right. Stay on line.
Listen to this.
‐Hear that?
‐Hey...
keep your phone away from the fan.
It's really the wind.
Oh, really?
Hold on then.
Listen to this.
‐Heard that?
‐I didn't hear anything.
Because it's not windy
in Hyderabad.
You're lying
because you're a cheater.
Turn on the TV. Watch
what's become of the roads.
Oh, yeah?
Hold on.
‐Do you see it?
‐Yeah!
OU students are protesting
in the Telangana agitation.
Does that look windy to you?
Telangana agitation?
Why now?
For a separate state, of course.
Separate state?
What are you talking about?
It's been 5 years since Telangana
became a separate state.
What?
Who made that happen? You?
Don't joke, Vennela.
It became a separate State
on February 18th, 2014.
They've been protesting
since 10 years.
Are you going to make it happen
in the next 4 days?
What? 4 days?
‐What's today's date?
‐February 14th.
Year?
February 14th, 2014.
2014.
‐Seriously?
‐Surya, stop fooling around.
Don't try to cheat me anymore.
Don't ever call me, okay?
Seems like science fiction
to me, sir.
Science invented cinema, didn't it?
People have communicated
from the past before too.
Really? Where?
In Russia.
People in 2015
started hearing voices
from a radio station in 1982.
Look.
Some idiot must be fooling them
from the radio station.
That station's been shut
for 30 years.
What?
And the voices?
They came from the past.
But they didn't know
who was sending them.
Wait, wait.
Are you saying we are hearing voices
from someone in the 1980s?
Exactly!
Maybe it's a ghost's work, sir.
That's what they said when
Graham Bell invented the telephone.
Recently, in Canada,
1.5 billion light years away,
they received light signals
from the future.
They're called FRBs.
Fast Radio Bursts.
We don't know who's sending them.
Past‐to‐future,
future‐to‐past communications
like these keep happening.
How is this possible, sir?
Sometimes, few things
go beyond science, Surya.
It wouldn't be called
a miracle otherwise.
Something is magical
only until we figure it out.
When you crack the logic,
it becomes ordinary.
Like this mobile phone.
The science of today
is the technology of tomorrow.
I need to tell you something.
Tell me.
‐There are too many people here.
‐Hold on!
Hold on.
Hello, uncle.
Your daughter's on a date
with some guy here in Somajiguda.
Come catch her in the act.
What the hell, man!
Hey! Aren't you too old for dating?
Hey, what's this, man?
Society is so spoiled.
Damn! You continue.
I know where Vennela is.
‐Where is she?
‐Really far away.
Hayathnagar or Choutuppal?
2014.
Is it a door number?
Which area?
Vennela is 5 years behind us.
Is he nuts?
You mean, in the past?
Yes, dude. She's in 2014.
I'm in 2019.
Both of us are able to talk via
mobile phones from here to there.
I've watched films like
Aditya 369 and 24.
That scientist
also spoke about this.
Don't tell me
she's in love with you.
I'm not sure.
So, according to your delusion,
there's this girl in 2014.
She's in love with you,
but you can't meet her
because you can't go back.
Do you know
where she is in 2019?
You don't know.
This is the most complicated,
unrealistic, hypothetical
love story of the century.
‐Go to hell!
‐Hey!
Where are you going?
You live in the past.
I'll stay in the present.
I can't ruin my future
because of you.
‐Listen‐‐
‐Get lost!
Bill.
Do you have to meet him?
Dad insisted. I can't help it.
Get him another one.
Who the hell is this?
He just took it, dude.
‐Make one more.
‐What will you serve them?
He's looks scary.
Hi, Venny.
Vennela.
Hey, cool down.
‐So, you wanted to see me?
‐What?
Dad told me you wanted to see me.
‐Oh, that's what he told you?
‐Yeah.
Maybe he wants us to get to know
each other before marriage.
Now that you're here,
just have your coffee and leave.
If you crack lame jokes,
I'll have you beaten up.
She doesn't act like a girl at all.
It's all lies!
Oh, lies.
I told you.
When did you tell me?
Oh...
It was blazing hot,
and he says it's windy.
Impossible! See.
I was a fool to trust him.
I couldn't stop crying
for 4 days.
Hey, Venny...
You could've just called me.
‐Who's talking to you, dude?
‐It's okay.
You know he's a cheater. Move on.
Hello. Excuse me.
But I like that idiot.
Love you too.
Here's another idiot,
bothering me about marriage.
Hail Telangana! Hail Telangana!
What? Did they make
Telangana a separate state?
That's what's showing on TV, man.
‐Is this true?
‐Hail Telangana!
Hey, is this true?
Is the state separated?
Is it confirmed?
Don't kid with me, buddy.
Celebrations in Hyderabad
on the passing
of Telangana's bill
in the Rajya Sabha.
Are you going to make it happen
in the next 4 days?
How did he know beforehand?
I don't know.
‐Hello.
‐Hello, Surya.
‐Yes?
How are you doing this, Surya?
Sister!
Hail Telangana!
Is Telangana formed?
Yes.
How is this happening?
Because 2014 is my past.
I need proof, Surya.
I can't believe this.
I need a proof right now!
Why this place?
Are you at the bench?
I sat down.
Which side?
Right. Why?
I sat on your left.
Everything is happening
just like you said.
Like a miracle.
I didn't believe it either, but‐‐
Can you give me another proof?
There are scientific proofs.
But you'd just get confused.
I remember!
Manam movie released
in 2014. It was a superhit.
But it's releasing in May, Surya.
This is February.
Modi's government wins
the elections in 2014.
Kolkata Knight Riders win
the T20 cup.
That's all in the future for me.
Elections and IPL
haven't happened yet.
Say something else, Surya.
What other proof do you need?
Tell me what happened today.
Other than the Telangana bill
being passed,
tell me what happened today.
Right here.
Are you mad?
How would I know what happened
5 years ago?
I'm telling you
whatever I remember.
I can only tell you
what happened in the past.
Wait, wait, wait.
You can tell
what happened in the past.
‐Am I right?
‐Yes.
Yes. So what?
Wait, wait. Hold on.
‐What are you doing?
‐Hold on. I'll tell you.
What are you up to?
Hold on a second.
What?
Look to your left.
To your left. On the bench.
Do you see it?
MIRACLE
Miracle.
Dear...
Get up. Eat your food.
‐Get up.
‐I don't want anything.
I don't want to eat, grandma.
Don't be upset with me
because he did something.
What did he do?
What's upsetting you then?
He's 5 years ahead.
Whoa! 5 years ahead!
I've read about it in the epics.
I didn't know
it could really happen.
It's true, grandma.
‐I swear to you.
‐Maybe he's foresighted.
Maybe he didn't want to meet you.
‐I'll kill you!
‐Oh, no! Don't.
I won't say a thing.
What do you want to do now?
‐I'll forget him.
‐Do that. Very good.
‐You'll forget him.
‐You think I can't?
‐You can.
I forgot him.
I don't know who Surya is anymore.
My sweetheart.
‐Here eat this.
‐I don't want to.
If you eat, I'll give you an idea
to meet Surya.
‐Tell me.
‐You just said you forgot him.
‐Don't you?
‐Grandma!
‐Well, you say he's in 2019.
‐Yes.
So, he must've had to pass
through 2014.
He wouldn't have appeared
out of the blue in 2019.
You mean?
I mean he should be somewhere
around us here in 2014.
‐I know, right?
‐Yes.
Ask him for his address
and meet him now.
Also, give him your address.
He'll go meet you in 2019.
Grandma, you're just amazing.
‐Crazy girl!
‐I'm going.
‐Be careful.
‐Okay, okay. Bye, bye.
Now?
Turn left.
Then turn right.
And then right again.
And then take left.
I could just go straight.
Correct, correct.
Just go straight
and take the third left.
I'm at that place
you told me about.
There will be a pan shop
to your left.
It's closed. Is that okay?
What does it matter whether
it is closed or opened?
Just go right.
Did you?
Yeah, I did. Now?
Just go a little ahead.
Third house on the left.
‐ Black gate.
‐Third house, black gate.
‐Yes!
‐Almost there.
Is this address correct?
I'm right in front of the temple.
Right beside that.
A green‐coloured gate.
Do you see it? Hello?
Why aren't you saying anything?
Did my dad see you?
Your house isn't here.
It is KLM fashion mall.
A mall? Huh?
How come?
Did you miss our house?
Your dad must've sold the house.
You're right. He would have.
Did you find my house?
I guess.
Black gate. But it's locked.
Where did you go?
I must have gone out of town.
Are you kidding me?
Why didn't you tell me
before this?
Which city do you think I went to?
How do we meet?
I think our meeting is not
as easy as our phone calls.
What do we do?
I'm not at my house.
Your house is not here.
‐Let's do one thing.
‐What?
Let's try tomorrow again.
‐Not tomorrow.
‐Why?
It's my birthday tomorrow.
Oh! Then what about the treat?
‐Will you come?
‐What?
How can I come?
Idea!
Do we go to the same place
in different years? Interesting.
"What's with this distance?"
"Why can't we come closer?"
"Two different paths intersect"
"But it's invisible
To the naked eye"
"Time weaves some magic"
"I feel
Like I've seen you already"
"My feet freeze
At the place you are"
"Planets are finally in our favour"
"My heart trembles
At your thought"
"Time brings us together"
"We don't have to miss
Each other anymore"
"This date goes on individually"
"We can't get together, can we?"
"We share the food
But the bill is separate"
"You're all I need in my life"
"As I gently kiss you
On the cheek"
"My silence has
A million questions"
"You're right here
But I can't see you"
This place looks strange.
I come here
whether I'm happy or sad.
This is my most favourite place.
Surya, do you see the idols
of Rama and Sita in the future?
‐Yes.
‐Thank god!
‐Why?
‐If I had any wishes as a kid,
I'd write them on a note
and put it there.
And, surprisingly, each one
of those would come true.
Do something.
What?
Try homeopathy.
You'll recover faster.
"I don't get what you'd call this"
"Nobody could put it into words"
"Those winds that touch you
Emit a beautiful fragrance"
"Let's turn back the clock"
"Get closer like we wish"
"I will make the distance disappear"
"Come running into my arms"
"This is exciting"
"I've never felt like this before"
"I love to be around you"
"I wonder
When our dream's coming true"
Did not find him.
I'll be back.
What's your problem?
Video call isn't getting
connected to Surya.
I sent him the mails,
friend requests.
I searched the entire social media.
Everything shows only loading.
I can't find him anywhere.
He might have given a fake ID.
Who knows?
Shut up!
As it is, blue cup.
‐Are you also holding a blue cup.
‐Dude, why are you sitting here?
Hey!
‐What's wrong?
‐Vennela is sitting there.
Vennela is here?
She's sitting in that chair
in 2014.
We are having coffee together.
Sounds exciting, huh?
Very exciting.
Sorry, madam.
Hey!
Sorry.
Hey! Are you a Pisces?
I'm a Gemini.
That is 2013. Not your business.
You carry on.
What else?
Hello, Surya.
I should tell you something.
Go ahead.
I don't know if this is right.
I'm not even sure when we'll meet.
I thought I'd tell you
when we meet.
But I can't hold it in anymore.
This is a first to me.
I didn't know how to tell you.
So I wrote it on the bench.
Look to your left.
Hello. Did you look?
Yes.
Why are you quiet?
Are you blushing?
Vennela...
I should tell you something.
Don't tell me you're married.
Hey! Listen to me.
I don't have any feelings for you.
I'm sorry.
I know how it feels to be rejected.
I fell in love with a girl
5 years ago.
I don't know why,
but she didn't like me.
Now you're saying you love me,
and I don't know how to react.
Maybe...
I'm still in love with that girl.
You're there, and I'm here.
I thought all this amusing,
but I didn't expect you
to develop feelings for me.
Why didn't you tell me before?
I hate you, Surya.
I hate you so much!
I really hate you!
I love you.
Who the hell are you?
I'm crying over a guy,
and you're proposing to me.
Go away!
Good evening. Welcome to
the evening news bulletin.
A middle‐class father
couldn't buy popcorn for his kid
and committed suicide.
What the hell!
A boy was stoned to death
for rejecting a girl's love
by other women.
What? How could they pelt him
with stones?
Shit! Run ads. Hurry.
What the hell is this?
I should ask you that. Why are you
reacting during a live?
I mean stones...
We can discuss it later.
First, finish the live.
Men have no safety anymore.
You can get it at a pharmacy.
Come on, don't be a kid.
All right, hurry.
How long should I wait for you?
Can't you see that
I'm working here? Get lost!
Such an ass!
‐You pest!
‐Hello!
People like her should be
pelted with stones.
You need to love the girl
to accept her proposal, right?
You can't just kill the guy.
Hey, the day a guy
rejects a girl's love bravely
is the day a guy achieves freedom
according to Ram Gopal Varma.
Damn it, man!
A man has to go through so much.
You're average‐looking.
It's not so hard.
What about a guy like me?
‐What?
‐I mean...
a survey says that girls like guys
like me to look more beautiful.
If so, Vennela confessed
to me recently.
And I rejected!
‐She confessed?
‐Yeah.
Exactly how did she do that?
Did she send a love letter
through a time machine?
Stop it, man.
She wrote it on the bench
and confessed.
‐Where did she write?
‐On the bench.
Do you know why I listen to you
though you're full of crap?
Because you lend me
money whenever I ask.
But you're talking
about a break‐up.
‐Go to hell!
‐Hey!
It wouldn't be a break‐up
if I don't love her.
What are you saying?
Is she heartbroken?
I guess.
Will she commit suicide?
Maybe.
What? Suicide!
Like that news article
you just read,
she might commit suicide.
Do you really think so?
Hey, please don't add a suicide
and a ghost in your story.
Nonsense!
Idiot.
Oi!
Where did you disappear?
Ta‐da!
Hey! What's that?
I'll tell you. Wait, wait.
‐Has she lost her mind?
‐Correct.
Here, have this.
‐What is this?
‐Cheers.
This is really alcohol!
From where did you get it?
It's your dad's.
‐Hey!
‐What's wrong?
You can't put the glass down
after saying cheers.
It's a grave sin.
Do a bottoms‐up.
Hello.
‐No. It's wrong.
‐You have a cold, right?
This will help.
See?
You're sneezing.
‐This will help with the cold?
‐Yes. Just drink it.
Hold on. Open. Open.
Why is it like that?
That's it.
Of course, you had a heart attack.
I just want to get high.
Who's disturbing you at this hour?
Who else?
It's Surya.
What's his problem?
He rejected you, right?
All men are cheats.
He's calling again, grandma.
Ask him what's up.
He's so dead!
Take it.
Have this and blast him.
Have it and bash him.
Hello, Vennela.
Thank god, you answered.
What happened to you?
What are you doing?
Fixing a drink.
Hey! Don't do anything stupid.
So what if I rejected you?
Go, find an adult
and put them on the line.
Hey, fruit.
It's not what you think.
What? Are you drinking?
You ask me to quit
and then do this?
‐This is cheating.
‐Look who's talking.
You thought I'd die
if you rejected me?
I have a goal.
Bloody fool.
I think you're still pissed
with me.
You're punishing me for something
that happened in your past?
How do I even believe
what you said?
Tell me your story right now.
Let's not talk about that.
Do you have something
urgent to attend to?
My maid's on leave since 4 days.
Thought I'd wash my clothes.
Hey! Is she more important to you?
Answer me!
Though I seem
like a boring guy now.
Do you know how I was back then?
"There by the pond
Is a sacred temple"
"It is a shrine to devotees"
"There's the incarnation
Of Lingaswamy"
"He's the God to devotees"
"Oh! Shiva resided at the shrine
Of the pond's embankment"
"You're the precious god
O Shiva"
"Oh! Shiva resided at the shrine
By the pond"
"You're a precious god
O Shiva"
"To the crores of devotees"
"You're a blessing, O Shiva!"
"Accept the prayers, O Shiva"
"Accept the gratitude, O Shiva!"
"Oh! Shiva resided at the shrine
By the pond"
[singing randomly]
Idiot! I play like a rock star
and you made me‐‐
I know, dude.
That's what I told them too.
They agreed to pay Rs. 1,500
if you sang.
We need the money
for the music competition.
‐That is why I took the gig.
‐Where is it?
‐Have you seen a coconut anywhere?
‐Get lost!
Why are you yelling?
Where is it?
On top of that,
you're teasing girls.
They're teasing me.
Didn't you notice that?
‐Oh, yeah?
‐Yes.
If you take up such gigs again,
I'll break a coconut on your head.
No, dude, listen to me.
[classical song playing]
Hey, we got the money.
Go away, man.
If you could give me her details‐‐
You visit a temple
to wash away your sins.
Not to make new ones.
I can't believe you're asking me
for a girl's details.
You're dangerous!
Why? What's wrong?
People ask God directly
for a job, wife and kids.
Why shouldn't we ask
for her address?
‐Please tell us, priest.
‐Yes!
I see your logic.
But she's sensitive,
and you're outgoing.
Do one thing!
Why don't you work in the temple
for a few weeks?
If I like your behaviour,
I'll give you her address.
‐What say?
‐What do I get started on first?
‐I can't do this.
‐Please stop, dude!
"Moonlight has taken me by surprise"
"My heart has skipped a beat"
"I can't stop chasing after you"
"Why don't you show yourself?"
"I see you everywhere I look"
"Don't you see me
In your dreams?"
"I've been to everywhere
Looking for you"
"Where's your home sweet home?"
"I saw you in this temple
For the first time"
"I asked God to show me a way"
"I washed away all my sins"
"I wished for you to be mine"
‐Sir‐‐
‐It's been a week already?
Yes.
She likes the colour blue.
Enjoy.
Yes!
"I've prayed to every God for you"
"Don't you see
I'm crazy for you?"
"Hope no one has to go through this"
"Let me shower
All my love on you"
Dude, your dad.
‐Organic chemistry‐‐
‐Didn't you go to work yet?
Why? Do you plan on going to
the temple as soon as I leave?
It won't start. Here.
‐Thank you, dad.
‐Only 2‐3 hours a day, okay?
You have exams coming soon.
‐What?
‐We'll study well, uncle.
Let's go. Let's go.
"I wrote poems in the dark"
"I sketched my heart
On the walls"
"You're my new universe"
"I'm the Columbus
To your country"
Hey.
"Your voice
Makes my heart tremble"
"My eyes look for you
Without even falling shut"
"Your beauty
Brings colour to the world"
"Your presence
Makes my life worthwhile"
"I'll keep waiting for you"
"No way I can forget you"
"I'll be reborn for your love
Trust me"
"Even pain feels like pleasure"
"I'm digging this feeling somehow"
"Rain on me like a cloud"
‐Bro, the girl's name or address...
‐You've done it.
She stays in Secunderabad.
‐Go look for her.
‐Secunderabad!
"I've prayed
To every God for you"
"Don't you see
I'm crazy for you?"
"Hope no one
Has to go through this"
"Let me shower
All my love on you"
"I saw you in this temple
For the first time"
"I asked God to show me a way"
"I washed away all my sins"
"I wished for you to be mine"
Get up. Go to sleep.
All right. I will go to bed, but...
Well, are you ready for tomorrow?
Of course. He prepared very well!
He's going to rock
the show tomorrow.
So...
you're not giving
the exam tomorrow?
Hey, you're always ahead
in complicating your life.
You never do what I ask
you to do since your childhood.
Is music a legit career?
Dad, not tonight.
I'm saying it
in your best interest.
I mean, it's your birthday, so...
Don't try to divert the topic.
Uncle, life is boring if you eat,
sleep, work and repeat.
Do you know anything about music?
It's a vast ocean of emotions
in which you feel‐‐
Hey! Shut up!
Dad, come to my music
competition tomorrow.
You'll see how talented I am.
All right.
I'll check tomorrow.
‐Where is he?
‐We're here.
Are we?
Uncle, how are you liking it?
Feels like I'm in a circus
after a long time.
By the way, where's Surya?
Surya...
He's over there.
It's enough if this guy doesn't
get on to the stage. We will win.
‐Surya!
‐Dad!
I'm next.
Watch me.
‐Hey, when are you performing?
‐Hi!
‐It is, after yours.
‐Oh.
Hey! This is my favourite guitar.
Oh.
I bought it 2 months back.
‐How much is it?
‐Rs. 25,000 only.
Nice.
Let's go.
He's next. I'll go check
on him. You stay here.
Uncle, you're Surya's father,
aren't you?
‐Yes.
‐He's an amazing talent.
He'll definitely win
this competition.
Thank you.
Man, you don't get
on the stage, please.
Whatever.
What's up, guys!
All set?
‐Yeah, yeah.
‐All set!
All the best, Surya.
You're next.
Thanks for the opportunity.
We're next?
‐Sir, someone's calling you.
‐Who's calling?
We're next! Guys, get ready!
Yeah!
‐Ready, boys?
‐Let's go.
Sure.
Dude, did you find her yet?
Go away!
‐Didn't you go to the temple today?
‐Hold your tongue!
Surya, he's provoking you.
Calm down.
I thought you'd be dressed in blue.
‐What do you want?
‐Drop from the show.
Music or her?
I know where she is at this moment.
Tell me where she is.
Please.
‐So, you're out?
‐Surya, he's bluffing.
Please tell me, dude.
Clock tower.
If you go now, she might be there.
Sorry, guys.
‐Hold on. I'm coming.
‐What!
Hey!
That was a great performance!
The next band to perform
is Surya and his gang.
Surya and gang.
Surya!
Surya ran away!
Final call for Surya and gang.
Okay, let's move on.
Hey!
What will you tell her?
I don't know.
I hate you, Surya!
I really hate you!
I love you.
I'm crying over a guy,
and you're confessing to me?
I hate this!
Come on.
Surya.
All right. You head home.
I failed at everything
I believed in.
My music.
Love.
Everything.
Since when do you know her?
You'll look back at this in a year
and laugh at it.
That's what life's all about.
How long has it been since
mom passed away, dad?
Did you forget her?
Can you?
This girl's still alive, dad.
Okay. Leave it.
I can understand.
Stop it, dad!
You're not my friend.
Act like my father.
I crossed your age 25 years back.
I can understand your anger.
If I had a bad day at work,
I'd come home and yell at your mom.
This is what happens
in every house.
A family tolerates you.
Anybody else would fight with you.
Dad, this is what I hate.
You're being too sweet
and too cool.
You gave me money for fuel
because I was going to meet a girl.
Now I came home in tears,
and you're comforting me.
So, if I keep making mistakes,
you'll forgive me,
leaving me in guilt!
Hey!
Son, we only have each other.
All right.
There's no music or that girl
in my life anymore.
Tell me what I should do.
That's what you want, right?
I met Chandu uncle and asked
for a job for you on his TV channel.
He agreed.
If you keep yourself busy,
it'll make it easier to forget her.
You want me to lead
a robotic life from 9 to 6?
‐I can't do that, dad.
‐Come on, son.
TV is also a creative field.
Dad, I'm good at music
and I love making music.
I can't do anything else.
I can't do what you like
or live like you do.
I'd lose myself.
I'd rather die early.
Are you saying my life is a waste?
Your routine life is what got me
vexed with life.
I found my excitement in music.
You wouldn't get it.
Hey!
Hey...
Surya! Surya!
Don't say another word, dad.
I'll do as you say.
I'll also become a version of you.
Leave me alone for some time, dad.
I might say something hurtful.
All right.
I'll get some air and come back.
He said he'd come back.
But he didn't.
Where did this happen?
A Gachibowli warehouse.
While he was trying
to save somebody.
I'm very sorry, Surya.
I'm responsible for it.
Hey! Don't say that.
It's not your fault.
It's only destiny, Surya.
When you confessed...
Forget that.
I also rejected a few guys.
But...
none of them loved me
as much as you loved her.
To be honest,
I don't know what to say.
But I know one thing for sure.
You're lucky to have had
such a father.
And she's unlucky
to have let you go.
Nothing more about me.
If that incident hadn't happened...
Don't think more about it, Surya.
There is nothing you could do
with what had happened.
Don't punish yourself,
please. Okay?
Thank you.
Good night, Surya.
Bye.
Priest! Check for an auspicious day
in the coming three months.
Why is he back?
What's going on, dad?
‐That...
‐Hi, Venny.
Adults are discussing
about your wedding.
You go inside.
What's the matter with you, man?
What's the matter with you?
I gave you a chance
to pass that exam.
But you failed.
Now marry him.
Uncle, don't give her the credit.
I made her fail.
Yeah, I did.
I broke 101 coconuts at the temple,
praying for her to fail.
How dare he!
It's all my grace.
How dare you pray for me to fail!
‐Stop...
‐Let me go, grandma.
‐Calm down, dear. No.
‐Stop!
‐Cool down!
‐Look at him!
Stop. You shouldn't sacrifice
a human to the Goddess.
Shut up!
If prayers and chants made you pass,
what's the point in studying?
Stop acting up
and agree to the marriage.
Dad, come with me.
We need to talk.
Come!
What is it?
How can you get me married
to someone who wants me to fail?
Dad.
I know that it's your responsibility
to get me married.
But once I'm married,
my new life begins.
I never said I don't want marriage.
I just don't want
to get married now.
And I can't marry that guy at all.
He's not looking for a wife.
He just needs someone
to clean and cook.
I want someone
who understands my dreams.
Are these your dreams? Huh?
Dad!
‐He's back.
‐Priest, fix the date.
‐Okay, sir.
‐Dad!
Why are you yelling?
I'll crack the GET exam
no matter what this time.
You've failed twice already.
How many chances do you need?
I didn't fail because of me.
It's because of this idiot.
Naughty girl!
I won't just crack it.
I'll top the exam this time.
Topper?
No way!
Dad, if I don't clear it this time,
I'll marry any loser you get me.
If you fail, I'll get you married
to this loser only.
Sorry, son.
It's okay, uncle.
I get that you see me as family.
Okay, Venny.
I'll go break coconuts for you.
Why don't you break one
on your head? Good riddance!
I'll kill you with witchcraft
if you pray for me again. Idiot!
‐Come inside.
‐Let go, mom.
He's so useless.
I want to see his end.
Ask her to meditate, uncle.
You challenged that you'll pass
like some wrestler.
How will you pass, eh?
I don't know, grandma.
But there's no way
I'm marrying him.
You won't pass even
if the question paper is leaked.
What did you just say?
You won't pass even
if the question paper is leaked.
Paper leak.
What is it?
What happened to her?
Wow! You gave
such an amazing idea, granny.
Watch me pass the exam.
Why?
Have you never done it?
Don't talk like a nerd.
I did. But according to
the court of law, it's a crime.
I'll get arrested, you know.
When will you get arrested?
In 2014 or 2019?
Just shut up and do it.
Ask for anything else, Vennela.
Please!
Accept my love then.
Where will I find the papers?
Sorry.
Why are we here, dude?
Look for it.
You can tell me at least.
About psychology
in Swathi's book...
Is he looking at us?
We look like thieves
in this mask and glares.
Go ask him what you want.
You go.
No. You go ask.
Go!
I'm taking these maths
and physics books, bro.
Why're you scared?
It's just a book shop.
‐Wait, man!
‐Here.
Here. Take it.
What's there upstairs?
Hello! You don't get condoms here.
We have plenty of those.
Ask him.
That...
Do you have GET question papers?
Which year?
2014.
Why do you need those?
Why are you so nervous?
I have them from 2014 to 2018.
Here, take it!
Why do you need
the question papers?
Vennela needs help.
That's why.
2014. Vennela.
Now she is going to top the exam
and credit you for her success?
I don't mind going to jail
helping her.
Go to jail even?
Sir, do you have a book called
How To Cure A Crazy Person?
I have You're Responsible
For Your Own Karma.
You could just look at my face
to know that.
‐Yes!
‐Idiot!
‐Note it down.
‐Hold on. I'm writing Om.
You're cheating and
making God a part of it?
Just tell me the answers.
Sir, I am back.
Oh, you're back.
You show up every year
like it's your maternal home.
Sir, what's the process this time?
Do you ask questions
based on my answers?
Or do I answer based
on your questions?
Don't come up with new processes.
Follow what's there.
This time, I have something
you'd never imagine.
I also got something for you.
Did you know that?
What's that?
Question paper! Set 3!
Sir, starting with C. Mirchi.
Mirchi? Excuse me!
‐Sir?
‐Question paper.
Actually, I don't need it.
But, I'll take it for you.
I'll check the questions
and answer.
Silence!
‐Sir
‐What?
I have a small doubt.
It will be cold in Germany.
Will sweaters from Koti market
keep me warm?
You didn't even pass the exam, and
you're dreaming about Germany.
‐Sit down!
‐Future planning, sir.
Stupid questions!
Sir.
I shook the class, eh?
Bye, sir.
Is Vennela home?
Dear!
What?
Somebody's here.
I guess you got the wrong address.
Vennela is your daughter, isn't it?
Don't look at me. Say yes.
Yes! She's our daughter.
What did she do?
Call her.
Go.
Vennela!
What happened, dad?
What did you do?
I didn't do anything.
What's wrong?
Congratulations, sir.
‐What for?
‐Come on, sir.
1.3 lakh students appeared for GET
and only 21% passed.
Your daughter's one of them.
Check this out.
Congrats, Vennela.
You got 87th rank in GET.
Really?
Did you pass for real?
Are you dumb? Shut up!
Thank you. Thank you.
One second.
‐Okay?
‐Super, bro!
Record now.
How do you feel as a father, sir?
Whose choice was automobile
engineering? You or your father?
Who's your inspiration?
My dad.
I passed, Surya!
And you know, my marriage is off.
Wow! Congrats!
I got 87th rank in India.
I thought you'd get 1st.
I wrote a few wrong answers
to avoid suspicion.
I'm leaving for Germany
in 2 weeks, Surya.
You made this possible.
Tell me what you want.
No, thanks.
I'd have to buy it for myself.
Forget it.
One minute!
Bro, Vennela got 87th rank.
Congrats. What's next?
Will she go overseas for graduation?
‐How do you know?
‐Try something new next time.
‐Hey!
‐Idiot!
Surya...
I'm not able to enjoy this success.
‐Why?
‐Because I didn't work hard for it.
Like I've done something wrong.
I feel guilty.
It's okay. Feeling guilty is good.
We need to be honest
with ourselves.
I never felt like this
though I've failed so many times.
Thought I'd give the exam again.
But now that I passed,
I feel like I've cheated everybody.
Tell your dad the truth
if you feel so guilty.
Surya! Remember I said
let's give life a chance.
You'll also get that chance soon.
And I'm sure
your dreams will also be fulfilled.
Vennela! Where are you?
‐What?
‐Come here.
‐Mom's calling. I'll call you back.
‐Okay.
[singing randomly]
Pray to the flame.
[chanting]
‐Hello.
‐Tell me.
Why didn't you pick up my calls?
I was in a ritual.
‐Today's is dad's death anniversary.
‐Oh, I'm sorry.
You wanted to say something?
My admission got confirmed
in a German university, Surya.
Congrats, Vennela.
I told dad what happened.
I apologised as well.
What did he say?
He yelled at me a little.
Asked me to focus from now on.
I feel so relieved after
apologising to dad wholeheartedly.
I couldn't apologise to my dad.
Even if I want to apologise now,
it's not possible.
He's never coming back.
Today's the day, huh?
What time did he die, Surya?
8:30 in the night.
8:30 p.m.
In the next 2 hours.
Vennela, what did you just say?
In 2 hours.
Which means...
Dad passed away today.
You're talking to me
on the same day.
5 years back.
Which means you can see dad.
You can talk to dad.
You can...
Save your dad.
But, Surya, what do we do now?
‐I...
‐No, Vennela, listen to me.
You can save him if you rush
to the Gachibowli warehouse.
Please, Vennela.
I guess this is another chance
God gave me.
Please, Vennela. Will you go?
I'll go.
You lost your life this day.
If I can save your dad,
you'll have your life back.
I'll save your dad, Surya.
‐Hello?
‐Hello, Vennela!
‐Have you reached?
‐I just reached.
‐Is dad there?
‐There is no one here, Surya.
I'm looking around.
Search properly, Vennela.
He will be right there.
There's no one here, Surya.
Surya.
‐What was his shirt's colour?
‐Grey!
Grey‐coloured shirt!
Surya, I found your dad.
Vennela!
Hello. Vennela!
Pull her back.
Hey!
Who's there?
Hello, Vennela! Shit!
Bring her in. Quick.
Hello.
Vennela!
Vennela! Can you hear me?
Hello...
Hello.
Hey!
It means
Surya's dad died saving me.
Let her go! Hey!
Dad?
Dad, it's me, Surya!
Dad... Hello...
Move...
Hello, Vennela...
Uncle!
Dear! You go from here!
‐Oh, my!
‐Uncle...
Dear, are you okay?
You're fine, right?
I'm all right.
Uncle!
‐Speak to me, dad.
‐Help!
Dad, what happened?
Uncle, look at me.
Uncle!
Help!
‐Help, please.
‐Dear!
Dear...
Do me a favour.
Tell me, uncle.
My son, Surya...
I know him, uncle.
I know Surya.
Dear...
Surya.
Phone?
Sorry, Surya!
Sorry...
The Surya who loved me and
the Surya whom I loved are the same?
Make sure his last wish
is fulfilled.
Excuse me! Please.
Hold him. Let's go!
Careful. Slowly.
Hold him.
Open the door.
Careful.
Surya!
Hello, dad.
Hello.
Mom's phone is with me. What is it?
I know. I called for you only.
The police are here
for passport verification.
I'll be home in an hour.
Are you crazy?
Why would the cops wait for you?
Come fast!
Why didn't you come to work, man?
I couldn't save dad.
It's been 5 years
since dad left us.
It was yesterday.
I spoke to Vennela.
She met dad.
Hey! Let's go out. Come on.
Your mood will get better.
You won't understand it.
Why are you here?
There are a few files
on your computer.
I came to copy them.
Where is it?
When did you dump them?
I copied it 6 months ago.
Yes! Found it!
What did you say?
I said I copied it
6 months ago and I found it.
I used to put my wishes
under the idol in my childhood.
And, surprisingly,
each one of them would come true.
Surya...
I'm very sorry, Surya!
I couldn't save uncle!
I don't know whether this letter
will reach you or not.
But I hope this reaches you.
Surya, your dad loves you.
He only had one last wish.
He has something for you.
Sameer, we are participating
in the competition this year.
Excuse me!
My SIM isn't activated yet.
‐Your name?
‐Vennela.
I was here yesterday asking for
same number as I lost my phone.
Oh, yes.
We can activate the new sim
only if we deactivate the old sim.
We couldn't deactivate it
no matter how hard we tried.
We don't know why.
I can get you a new number.
‐Hello, grandma.
‐Where are you, dear?
I'm going to meet Surya.
I don't think
you're doing the right thing.
I should tell Surya
what has happened in 2014.
Please don't try to stop me.
I'll call you back.
Sorry.
Thank you.
Excuse me. Is Surya home?
There he goes.
Surya!
Hey, kids.
Come here.
What is it?
Where did Surya go?
He left to Kashi this morning.
‐Kashi?
‐Yes.
‐Do you know when he'll be back?
‐Maybe in a couple of days.
Let's go.
Why are you crying, dear?
I don't understand
what's happening.
Something always goes wrong
whenever I try to meet Surya.
I can't call him either
because my phone's gone.
He's in Varanasi, and I don't know
when he'll be back.
I have a flight to Germany
in 2 days.
I don't know what to do, grandma.
I'll also go to Varanasi.
I'll meet him there
and talk to him.
Listen.
You can't meet him.
Think about it.
If you had met him,
you would've been with him in 2019.
Are you guys together?
You knew his father
was going to die.
Could you stop it?
It's his past.
It's over.
We can't change it.
If we could,
why would they call it fate?
The Creator himself
couldn't escape his fate.
We're just humans after all.
What could we do?
Think about it.
What happened every time
you went to meet him?
Don't try to meet him.
Because you cannot.
Why did God bring us together then?
To separate us and make us sad?
God brought you together
like a miracle of destiny.
Wonder why he separated you now.
When will we meet again?
Only fate knows
what it has in store for you.
The closer you go,
the more danger he'll be in.
Listen to me.
Go far away from him.
"A small way"
"Can't meet yours"
"I sent you away
When you're before me"
"I searched for you
When you're far away"
"I'm in this darkness
Where there is no way out"
"These are the tears
That will stop with time"
"I am suffering
Being alone for a few years"
"My world has changed
Since you came"
"Come to me, my dear"
"I remained half
Come to me"
"Come to me, dear!"
"Walk towards me
And come to this side"
Vennela's phone is switched off.
We are not able to reach her.
Can you please get me the details?
Okay, Surya.
"I asked the motionless voice"
"Asked the stained eyes"
"They led me towards you"
"You're the moonlight"
"Remove the darkness
From my life and come for me"
"My heartbeat stops
When I think of you"
"Quit playing games with me"
"This distance made me realise
The love I have for you"
"I went mute
When I stopped hearing your voice"
"Come to me, my dear"
"I remained half
Come to my side"
"Come to me, dear"
"Move the foot and come to me"
"I remained half
Come to me, dear"
"Come to me, dear"
"Move the foot
And come to me, my girl"
‐Congrats, bro.
‐Thank you.
Thank you!
‐Thank you!
‐That was an amazing performance.
Thanks, dude.
‐Congratulations.
‐You sang well, man. Congrats.
‐Good job, guys!
‐Surya!
‐Hey! When did you come?
‐You were rocking.
‐Thank you.
‐Amazing!
‐When did you come from Bangalore?
‐Surya!
He'll become the next Sid Sriram
if he works hard.
‐Correct!
‐That's true.
I found out why you and
Vennela have the same number.
Why?
Nobody used her number
after she lost her phone.
You were given the same number.
That's how you both have
the same number.
Did you figure out
anything else about her?
Come outside.
I can't hear anything here.
Here. Your dad's belongings.
Our neighbours collected them
when we were in Kashi.
Careful. Take care.
Tell me. What is it?
Surya...
Vennela...
Ah, Vennela?
Did you find out anything
about her?
Vennela is no more, Surya.
Hey, what are you saying?
Look at this.
She died today 5 years ago
in a road accident.
Is Vennela the girl whom I loved?
Hello, Vennela.
Hello. Whose phone is this?
You... Where is Vennela?
Who's Vennela?
Your sister or girlfriend?
Hey! Who the hell are you?
Hey! First, you tell me.
Who the hell are you?
I found your phone and thought of
returning it. Don't act up.
I'm already pissed.
Watch your tongue.
Did you steal her phone?
I'll kill you when I find you.
Oh, really? I can't wait, dude.
I dare you to come here.
Give me your address. I'm coming.
Note it down.
My name is Surya.
I live in Pragathi Nagar.
House number 303. Come here.
What's wrong, Surya? Who is it?
‐It's me.
‐What's going on?
‐What happened?
‐Surya...
Listen to me.
This is my girlfriend's phone.
I thought
somebody must've stolen it.
I'm sorry.
Okay, tell me.
Where do I bring the phone?
‐What's the time now?
‐4:30 p.m.
Can you do me a favour?
‐Please?
‐What?
You need to give this phone
to Vennela.
That too before 5:30 p.m.
Can you do that?
You have a timing set
for collecting your lost phone?
Please try to understand.
I can't give any more details.
She's in big danger.
Where is she?
Hello, Surya.
Where are you right now?
Yeah, I'm here at the temple.
Hey! Come here.
Do you know where LIC Rama Krishna,
Vennela's house is?
She's leaving in that car.
Leaving?
Please help me. Follow her, Surya!
Hello! I'm going. Almost there.
Go faster!
I'm going.
Hey!
Surya, what happened?
Hello?
He is...
Surya's friend.
Ma'am, where are you going?
Hold on! I will be back.
Nothing happened to you, right?
What was that in newspaper then?
When they found out that
I was alive, they changed the news.
Didn't you watch?
Surya, I'm very sorry.
I couldn't save uncle.
As you said, everything is destiny.
We can't change destiny.
You found out today
that the girl you loved
and the girl you were talking to
are one and the same.
But I knew that 5 years back.
I had to go through
all the pain you did.
Maybe that is why
God didn't let us meet.
I went to Germany,
finished my course and returned.
Where were you all this while?
I was around you.
‐Around me?
‐Yes.
Who did you think sent food
to you every morning?
It was me who sent the umbrella
at the clock tower during the storm.
I tried to call you
many times, Surya.
But the line never connected.
Hello! Hello, Surya!
Every time I wanted to meet,
you ended up in danger.
Hey!
I didn't know what to do.
So, I stayed away from you
even though I was around you.
I waited these 5 years, Surya.
When both phone calls got cut
seemed like the day we'd meet.
That's today.
I'm still scared
if something might happen to you.
I can't take it, Surya. I can't.
You fulfilled your dream
in the competition today.
‐I was there.
‐Really?
How did I play?
You sang for me.
So, it was beautiful.
I should tell grandma
that we have met.
She'll be overwhelmed.
Is your granny still alive?
Alive.
By the way, what's Prasad up to?
He's calling his own number,
trying to get a girl.
Some stories have truths.
Some stories have lies.
The stories far from these
are miraculous.