In the past 10 years,
the pace of communication
and commerce
accelerated astronomically,
didn't it?
That lecture was interminable,
I need an espresso.
Duchess Carrie
likes espresso.
Who's Duchess Carrie?
Duchess Carrie likes
certain things,
but not other things.
Can you figure out what
Duchess Carrie likes?
Caffeinated things?
Caffeinated?
- Tea?
-  Nope.
With the Center's latest
technological innovation,
we are working to empower
the average person
with a pragmatic response
to today's unforgiving jun...
Today's...
Impenetrable job market.
Uh, does she eat?
She eats croissants
and crabapples.
She likes things
that begin with "C"?
No. She enjoys espresso.
No collaborating.
Croissants...
She's French.
You need to play
more games, Jules.
Only one of you
can be the winner.
If you cheat,
then nobody wins.
- And as a result...
- Adenine...
And due
to overpopulation...
Cytosine.
- Today's job market...
-  Guanine.
Guanine.
There's no surprise that
anxiety and depression...
Thiamine.
- ...have become the norm.
-  Uracil.
Duchess Carrie
likes looking at the moon.
Duchess Carrie loves
feeling cool.
Moon, cool.
Double letters...
Duchess Carrie
likes double letters.
Jules already got it.
Not again.
Where's your umbrella?
It's not raining.
It is in Cherbourg.
Eternally?
Dave, you're calling me.
Don't you think we should
give this a little more time?
I need to talk to you
face to face.
I wasn't calling
about us.
Mom!
It's something much
more important.
End call.
- Gwen?
-  This conversation has ended.
That's your mother?
Yup.
She doesn't even look
like a mom.
Holo me when
you hear from Arcadia?
Tell her about
the Eastern Board luncheon.
I'll make sure my mom
holds you a spot.
I like it.
It's old looking.
Who was that
with you guys?
Amanda Malthis.
Oh, you decided
you like her?
She has interesting moments.
She wants me
to go with her to this
bonding camp for Eastern.
So they're saying that
all this wacky hormonal stuff,
that's coming from pressure
to be hyper productive.
We have too many choices
and we're making the same ones
over and over again.
And they're the wrong
choices actually.
So it's like
natural deselection.
Our DNA is opting out.
Did you know that by the time
I'm 20, I may not have
any ova left?
You know, for babies.
You'd think awareness
would help things, but...
Awareness influences things.
It just takes time.
How much time?
Jules.
I was going to tell you when
you were a little bit older.
About the eggs.
I can adopt from
other regions.
There's always going
to be orphans who aren't
as lucky as us,
who need families.
Exactly.
And I've always wanted
a big family.
Oh, crud.
What?
It's an automated message
from Arcadia.
Uh, I can't listen.
This is Melanie Matthews
from Arcadia Prep
Dean's Office.
Although Jules' grades
were top-notch
and her test scores
were excellent,
there were a record number
of applications this year.
And ultimately,
due to capacity issues,
we could not make Jules
part of Arcadia Prep.
And I see
the workers fill
those buildings.
These guys are going
to get our economy
moving again
with their innovation
and productivity.
There is a bright
future ahead.
Rebel group
Terra Mamoria
is claiming responsibility
for two of the four nation's
explosions today.
That's a beautiful one.
Here at the Center for
Advanced Health and Living,
our procedure provides
a solution for any long-term
health concerns.
The experience is akin
to a seamless jump into
a disease-free body
of your choosing.
Through a lossless,
relatively painless process.
Would that this process
were more painless.
Let's review Gwen's old test.
It'll remind us of what
we're looking for.
Do they know it could take
a year to find someone
as uniquely qualified?
Gwen Koh's test, please.
Username, please.
Isa Cryer, damn it! We've been
here all afternoon.
In fact, the decisions
we make in life define us.
So, shouldn't every woman
be defined by the totality
of her choices?
Rather than her race,
height or health?
These are things she often
cannot control.
Here at the Center for
Advanced Health and Living,
we are working to offer you
the safest alternatives
to invasive cosmetic surgery
so you'll have every chance
to be the you
you were meant to be.
Thanks for taking
my call, Dave.
I'm sorry, Mr. Fisher.
I know you're quite busy.
That's all right,
what's up?
I've been thinking about
my contract renewal.
I've been working
below rate for a while.
Yes. You know, we've just
been talking about that.
You were?
Marketing just submitted
a report showing
pretty clearly that
a younger demographic
would benefit from
awareness of our technology.
and we simply can't
afford to alienate
any potential market.
Of course.
The board
just realized,
albeit on the late side,
that we're obligated to
go a different direction
for the face of the Center.
Have... Have you already
found your younger candidate?
They've started to search.
Isa Cryer is aggressively
reviewing candidates.
Gwen, I did fight for you.
There's no question that you
possess the highest level of
poise, talent and beauty.
I'm sorry.
No. I'm sorry.
Jules didn't
get into Arcadia.
And I don't know why.
She's brilliant.
Oh, you know, it's just
as likely you didn't know
the right people.
Did she get in
anywhere else?
Eastern.
Oh, well, with Eastern
on her transcript,
she'll have options.
My daughters went there.
I know, but tuition
has doubled since
your daughters.
Oh, okay.
You're going to land
on your feet.
You have to.
Upstairs woman
or downstairs woman?
Both.
Why aren't you
at school?
Conservation day.
Are you going to Paris?
Mmm-mmm. I have a short day
too, so I could meet
you after piano.
Did you have your first
taste of the day?
Incoming call.
Hello, this is Gwen.
Hello, Gwen.
This is Drake with Dream No
More outplacement network.
Oh, hello, Drake.
Uh, just one second,
please.
Sure.
I have to go.
Are you set for today?
Uh, what should we
tell Amanda's mom?
About?
The Eastern luncheon.
Tell her I'll be there.
Get more details.
So I can go to Eastern?
I got a call yesterday...
About the raise?
Yes, about the raise.
Gwen, I called
to let you know,
that your information
as of 3:30 a.m. this morning,
is in our system and
you're good to go.
I'm actually
on my way in
to see you.
Why?
Well, don't you have
a speech to give me and
then we sit down together
and focus on
the new days ahead?
Sounds good,
but you're already
a noted professional.
Thank you.
I'll be in touch the moment
we get a response.
Great.
There's one space you
could fill right away.
I'm sorry. Yes?
Your recent physical
pre-qualifies you to be
a paid egg donor.
An egg donor?
It could offset living costs
until we find you something
more permanent.
Many women are not able
to have children anymore.
And due to the great demand,
the donor age threshold
has risen.
Miss Koh?
How long does
the process take?
Three months.
You'll be paid
after the harvest.
That's not soon enough.
Can we just focus on the jobs
that I've outlined on my form?
Certainly.
Take what you can get.
Have a lovely day,
Miss Koh.
Are you okay?
Are you?
Username, please.
Gwen Koh.
That entity does
not exist.
Please try again.
Gwen Koh.
That entity does not exist.
Hello Gwen.
Evan, my ID's
not scanning.
What can I do for you?
Is Dave Fisher in?
He's offsite at the lab.
Is that wardrobe?
Yes.
Please hold.
Thank you.
Closer.
I found a solution
to our problem, Fisher.
I'm sorry.
I'm a bit surprised.
I've rarely seen you
over the years.
The dungeon's
being renovated.
Yours too?
How's the job search?
Well, there's been interest
in the past. So...
I'm not worried.
You've been pursued?
By companies at our level?
Well, I'm hardly surprised.
People connect to you.
The question that we have
to answer is in this current
job market,
with shifting desirability
targets, can they get ahead
looking like you?
And at your age?
My position here wasn't only
about being a face.
And the knowledge
I've acquired here,
I can carry
into other positions.
Teaching, for instance.
You've taught before?
In grad school.
In grad school?
Well, even in the real world,
you won't make close to what
you were making here.
The education profession has
gone pure tech.
There is nothing in our
generation's skill pool
that can compete.
Well, there must be something
in a mere human existence
that has value.
You and I, in our lifetimes,
will see progress
1,000 times greater
than the previous century.
But, because we're
mere humans,
we won't be able
to comprehend it.
Humans can only grasp
change at a rate they've
experienced it.
Which is why they
are being left behind.
How is your daughter?
I understand she's quite
a talent.
She keeps me alive.
As do my girls.
There is nothing fiercer
than a mother's love.
Hello, Drake.
Hey, Claire.
Uh, no. This is Gwen Koh.
Hello, Gwen.
I see here
you just called me.
Drake?
Yes, Gwen.
Have you heard something?
Do I have an interview?
There's been some activity
on your account.
You've received
several inquiries.
And one counter endorsement.
Counter endorsement?
A flag has been raised about
a detail on your resume.
It is currently
under investigation.
It's a mistake.
I have verifications
for everything.
Drake, can I ask who's filed
this counter endorsement?
Huh, would you like me to tell
you my astrological sign too?
I'm sorry?
Are you sorry?
Drake, are you
a human being?
That's a funny question.
How do you define
a human being?
Do you have blood running
through your veins?
That is a definition
of a human being?
I didn't know.
That sounds more like
a human being.
Not to know.
Account information.
Gwen Koh.
Balance, please.
Checking or saving...
Combined.
743 units.
Automatic payment
will be made after...
Cancel automatic payment.
Canceled.
How long will you
be staying today?
How much is it again?
Alone?
Did you need company?
No.
Did you hear me?
I was terrible.
No, you weren't,
where's Ginger?
I told her
not to come over.
Holoprof was trying to finish
the 20th and 21st centuries
in one class period.
All I remember is
the 2033 bubble
and the New York
traditionalist movement, which
he said is taking over now.
Which I challenged.
Are women really going
backwards going forward?
You're not.
Let's get you
something to eat.
Uh, she's not open.
I don't know why I'm alive.
That's a bit extreme.
What happened with Ginger?
There's so much to do.
I need to exercise more,
study more,
I need to do more
volunteer work
in art.
I need to be smarter, nicer,
prettier and classier.
But what's the point?
Many reasons.
Like?
Music.
Being loved by your
amazing mother.
None of you know
what you're doing.
You all pretend
to have a plan for us,
but everyone's just
either greedy or desperate.
Why did you have me?
When you knew the world was
so bad and you had
to struggle so much.
You're all alone
with no one to help you.
There was a time when
I was also confused
why I was alive.
And I guess something
in me thought that...
I mean,
I thought having you
might make my life more...
Worthwhile?
You make me very happy.
Archived message.
Hi, this is Lily.
Your one and only cousin?
Happy birthday.
I'm at the restaurant.
I still worry about you.
It must be really hard to be
on your own these days.
Tomorrow's events.
Eastern Board luncheon.
I hope you
have somebody.
Would you like
to send a response?
For our next hour,
we'll be discussing the recent
rise in child prostitution
in our country.
Its causes, symptoms and...
One week of water left.
A report
last week from
the Department of...
I should get paid tomorrow.
...found that 4% of girls
and boys between the ages
of 12 and 18,
will have taken part
in a sex work activity...
Where did you
get this recipe?
My cousin Lily.
Lily from the picture?
Yup. She taught me
when I had to work
at her restaurant.
Gwen Koh.
How wonderful you
could join us.
Oh!
My Amanda has told me so
much about you and Jules.
Gwen is the head of the
Center for Advanced Health
and Living.
One of the most forward
thinking companies
in our midst.
About to reveal the biotech
bubble of the moment.
You're a scientist?
Oh, not exactly.
Olivia's intrigued by any
woman making her way through
the job climate today.
Especially with the backlash
we're experiencing.
I'm sorry.
We would have moved forward
a while ago,
but her father has clout.
We do what is best for
our children.
We do.
We studied Jules' CV,
it's clear your agenda for
your daughter is
as your career, unstoppable.
Gwen, the mission of our
bonding camp is hundreds
of years old
and 100 years
into the future.
We comingle the finest boys
and girls, in advance of their
prep school experience.
Have them introduce their
innate talents and dreams
to one another.
To create a culture that will
cohesify them through their
years together in school.
In our world's history,
even when resources
were limited,
there's always been room
for an elite.
As there's less room now,
we're putting our brains
and our pocketbooks
where it counts.
This all sounds good.
Good?
Ideal.
I'm just wondering...
We've put in 30K each,
we would ask you for 10,
to hold the waitlist spot
for Jules.
I might need
a day or two.
Loosen up
Jules' father.
He's not a part
of our lives.
And isn't going to be?
Not even Jules' life?
That is a wild card.
Hello, dear.
This is the only time
in your daughter's life
when her choices
will make a difference.
Take the help you can get.
Gwen, look at us.
We're talking again
after all these years.
What a blessing.
So let's do this right, okay,
and learn from our mistakes?
I'm truly sorry
for leaving you alone
with Jules
and turning my back on you.
Mom, thank you
for saying that, but...
I have to get something
together, now. Or else...
Or else you'll continue
to suffer, I know.
And so will Jules.
So, how much money
do you need?
$40,000 would get us
through the next month.
$40,000?
Access costs money, Mom.
You know that.
So, who does she
look like now?
She looks like herself.
Well, send me
some pictures, okay?
You know, it doesn't matter
who she looks like.
Your father thinks
about you, you know?
He talked about you
in his sermon today.
Mom, don't.
Okay, uh,
let me call Dad.
No!
If I don't ask your father...
He's not ever going to meet
my daughter, Mom.
I will die
before that happens.
Gwen.
He's changed.
God has forgiven him.
Your father says
I can't help you.
Aren't you still working?
Let's pray
for your forgiveness.
Remember,
you used to love to pray?
I...
Dear Lord,
please listen to us.
At this time, we're ready for
you to take away...
I'm hanging up now.
...this sin that
Gwen has committed.
Goodbye.
Thank you for your infinite
patience, dear Lord.
I love you, Mama.
And your infinite mercy
that you have shown Gwen.
Goodbye. End call.
Please look down
on her now with love
and heal her of this sin.
Help her to start
a brand new life.
A brand new life with you
at the center of her heart.
And please...
Please watch out for Jules
and wrap her
in your loving care,
dear Lord.
Sorry, how've you been?
Am I too old?
To be of use?
What're you talking about,
Gwen?
So many women
are out of work.
Some are in real trouble.
To be frank, there is talk
among recruiters about
letting women
stay unemployed and,
well, return to the home.
The perception is it's safer
than putting millions of
desperate men on the street.
Safer? For whom?
Everyone.
Make me
the younger candidate.
I'm sorry?
The procedure
you're launching...
Use it on me.
Put me into
a younger body.
We haven't had any civilian
test subjects yet.
I want to be the face
of the Center again.
I've done all
the prep work already.
I'd be both
an expert and a user.
Your ideal spokesperson.
I'm the best there is
at this job.
Can I talk
about this later?
I really need
to do this later.
I can't get an interview,
Dave, not one.
I really have to go.
I have to
position Jules now.
If I can get her
into a good school,
she'll have a chance.
I can't let her become
one of these women,
so desperate
that they would do anything.
Dave,
you would do the same
for your own girls,
if you were in my place.
Marketing has a specific
physical type in mind.
They're looking at candidates
that come off
as a touch more universal.
So if I could tell them
that you'd be willing to
give them full control
over the creation
of your host body,
that might show them
how much you care about
the product's success.
Okay.
You'd be willing
to do that?
The point is to push
the product, right?
When isn't it?
I'll talk to them.
Thank you.
Evan?
Yes, Miss Cryer.
Make replications
of Fisher's last call.
CC the Board.
Working on it.
Couldn't say this
on the record,
but most of our test subjects
develop breathing issues.
They have to get a shot
every two hours for a year.
There's recurring pain.
I'll deal with it.
Evan, what's wrong
with our filters?
I can barely
understand them.
There's an error.
Working on it.
The board was expecting
you'd offer yourself up.
You're the
logical next step.
After this, the board'll wanna
protect their show piece,
Jules'll get what she needs.
Are you ready to
explain all this to her?
I've been trying
not to think about it.
Well, think about it.
This might be
a bigger sacrifice
than you imagine.
Gwen, it's not like
you're a consciousness
in a jar
that we're dumping
into another jar.
The technology
is not there yet.
What's the reality then?
It's the location.
I don't think there is a fix.
What're you trying
to hide from me, Fisher?
Please don't do this.
But this is still Jules'
only chance though, isn't it?
You know it is.
You just won't say it.
I'm not going to get
another job.
They'll make sure of it.
I want
Christmas with her first.
What's wrong?
Nothing.
I was thinking about dinner.
If I had to go away,
you'd be able to take care
of things here, right?
You'd do okay without me.
I guess so.
How long?
I don't know.
A while.
A while sounds too long.
I hope you think
you're pretty.
Sometimes.
If someone asked you
to change something
about the way you look,
what would it be?
My nose skinnier,
my shins longer,
my jumps higher.
We did this in class.
And what would you change
about me?
Nothing.
We're going through
a shift at work.
It comes along
with my raise.
What kind of shift?
In my appearance.
They want to appeal
to younger audiences.
I guess that makes sense.
It's good that
they'll pay for it.
They're here.
Goodbye, Miss Koh.
Hi, Mom.
Everyone's calling
their families before
we go tech-free.
But you can still reach me
through the camp office
if you need me.
It's super beautiful out here.
Really quiet.
I think I just heard
myself blink.
I love you.
I hope you're not
working too hard.
You should go out
and celebrate your big raise.
New message.
Hi.
It's Lily, again.
I hope you got
my last message.
I wanted to wish you
a happy birthday.
You know where to find us.
I remembered the code.
All three of our birthdays.
We never changed it.
Just one minute.
Is Lily out there?
You need to call us
first and say exactly
why you wanna see us.
Han!
Okay, we're not putting her
through this. Please.
Hey.
I'm sorry, okay?
I didn't know that.
Okay, I'm coming.
Okay, she's had a long day.
It's not
a good time for this.
I need to...
Please.
Go. Please don't do this.
I am begging you.
You need to stop watching
those crime shows.
What's the matter?
Nothing.
Where are the boys?
They're waiting for you
in the car.
You're taking them
to practice, right?
Yeah.
Thank you, honey.
I'll go pick up menus
for dinner.
I have to see her now.
Lily! Lily!
Well, this is
a nice surprise.
But we're about
to open for dinner.
No.
We have time.
It's fine.
Go get the boys.
You should meet.
Lily, do you remember...
Gwen, we're
really busy today.
You know, don't you?
Yes.
Han told me.
It was a long time ago.
I had a child.
When?
We...
Had a child.
That's not possible.
She was seeing other guys.
I lied about that.
Well, then you're lying
about this.
- No. Her name is Jules.
- No.
- She just turned 13.
- No. No.
You can't do it this way.
And so I stayed away
as long as I could,
because I didn't want to do
any more damage.
The only reason I'm here
is to ask that you consider
helping me,
helping your daughter,
and then we'll be gone.
The boys are
still in the car.
Han!
Am I taking them or not?
You know, you never believed
I was there for you.
Even when we were little.
Why would you
be there for me?
I slept with your husband.
And he slept with you.
You must feel so lonely.
I just need help for a year
or six months,
and I can even
pay you interest.
You won't even
have to see us.
You can move on
and be the same
as you were before.
Why do you do this?
Why do you continually
go into things
that will be a disaster?
I've been trying to get you
to help me heal this family.
And when you finally
show up, you just bring
more pain.
That's what I do.
The parking lot's filling up.
We need to open now.
Okay.
Hey, you.
I can't talk about this
anymore right now.
I wish I had time.
But I don't.
We need time.
This is a lot.
Shh, it's okay.
Aren't we going to practice?
As soon as we open
the restaurant, sweetie.
Please.
We have kids too.
I know you've always
been there for me.
I know.
We did sitting
meditation too.
But it wasn't as fun.
Sometimes
if things got loud or...
I couldn't go to my room
I would do the spinning.
I felt energetic afterwards.
Like I could do anything.
I met a ton
of fun people.
People.
A boy?
Both.
But I miss Ginger.
Jules?
Do you remember
what I said about
having to make a change
at work?
It'll be hard for me
to take in oxygen at first,
which will affect
the blood flow to my brain.
You may have to
remind me of things.
Especially
what's important to you.
This is a big change.
No one will recognize you.
I'll have a special ID.
And as more people
get the procedure done,
it'll feel easier
to explain.
She's pretty.
Don't you think so?
Would you feel okay
around her
first thing
in the morning?
If you were sick?
Imagine if she
got frustrated
or even mad.
You keep saying "she."
It's still you, right?
I'm sorry.
This whole thing is
kind of weird for me too.
What is this?
This is me?
You're amazing.
No, I'm not.
Yes, you are.
Listen to me.
It's good to be humble,
but you need
to know your value.
The ideas, the wisdom,
and the kindness
in you.
That's the secret
beauty everyone wants.
Are you okay?
...live emotionally.
The Center's procedure
provides a
painless alternative
to invasive cosmetic surgery.
We move you
into another body
and the lossless...
The Center's procedure
provides a
painless alternative to
invasive cosmetic surgery.
The experience is
akin to a seamless jump into
a brand new body,
circumventing the extensive
recovery period of invasive
cosmetic surgery.
I can attest to
the seamlessness
of this experience,
not only as the head
of the Center for
Advanced Health and Living,
but also a very
satisfied test subject.
Okay. So who
out there thinks
they have an imagination?
Everyone?
Okay, everyone.
Close your eyes.
Imagine a world where you
were diagnosed with
a terminal illness,
but you live to see your
great-grandkids go to college.
Now let's imagine
living 48 years
with a clubfoot.
But on your 50th birthday,
you're a professional
ballet dancer.
Now open your eyes.
You don't have to dream
up that world anymore.
That world is here,
and it's yours.
New recorded
hologram message.
I was in shock.
I hope you understand.
The day you visited us
reminded me how much
I hated who I used to be.
We wanna help.
I miss you.
Did you forget your shot?
Yeah.
I forgot my shot.
Sorry.
Don't come
to meet me anymore.
Not until you feel better.
You think I'm an idiot.
It doesn't matter
what I think of you.
Did the operation
make you weird?
You seem weird.
The majority of
people who are down
on their luck
are peaceful,
law-abiding citizens.
But you know, there are
these people out there,
that think the way
to solve it is
violence and destruction,
bombing and terror.
Look at the success
of our city.
New skyscrapers going up
all the time,
bigger and better.
These are
majestic, gorgeous
works of art
designed by some
of the top internationally
renowned architects.
We live in a great, great
city and we are fortunate
to be alive in these times.
Don't get distracted.
Can you turn that off?
I thought you liked it.
Not right now.
Can you cheer up?
What for?
How about for your mother?
Because of me, you might
actually get somewhere instead
of dreaming your life away.
I'm not dreaming.
I'm thinking.
Where's my mother?
Get back to work.
You're not her.
Where is she?
What happened?
Get away.
Well, you were right.
About the pain not going away.
I feel this anger...
Like
something is sitting next to
me screaming all the time.
It's what we're calling
mnemonic dissonance.
It's your new body's
instincts clashing
with your old memories.
It might help you to
concentrate your thoughts
on what's good
for your daughter.
For some reason I don't
want to focus on her.
Your animal connection
with her may not feel
like it's there,
but it will come back.
I think
she and I need a break
from each other.
Jules needs your help
with her transition
into prep school.
She hates me.
She'll probably be relieved
to get away from me.
But I don't mind.
Then what was the point
of any of this?
Do you
remember this place?
Yeah. We met here
before Christmas.
Well, we didn't.
Someone's got to straighten
out your priorities
before you squander
everything for Jules.
This might be a bigger
sacrifice than you imagine.
Gwen, it's not like you're a
consciousness in a jar
that we're dumping
into another jar.
The technology is
not there yet.
What do you mean? My marketing
characterizes the procedure.
It's just that,
a consciousness transplant.
That's marketing.
What's the reality then?
In order to reproduce
your memories,
we have to plant
electrodes in your brain.
And in the brain
of the new host.
We use a semi-separable
feedback loop between
the two of you,
to generate a
psycho-physiological twin.
New neurons, cloned matter.
Wait.
Twin?
She'll be a copy of you.
Same skills,
same likes and dislikes,
same personality,
but an entirely
separate awareness.
So there'll be
two of me then?
Once the electrodes
are removed,
the host brain
can repair itself
because it's still young.
But your older brain can't.
Your particular awareness
will cease to exist.
You mean, I'm gonna die?
Your cloned brain will wake up
in the new body
with all your memories,
and since she knows
nothing else, she'll
believe she's you.
But this is still Jules' only
chance, though, isn't it?
Please don't do this.
I want
Christmas with her first.
And, Dave,
Jules can never know.
Gwen needed you to perform
without misgivings.
So I excluded this memory
from the transfer.
She gave away her life
with her daughter.
There's nothing inside of you
that knows what that meant.
There's nothing left.
Sales are
through the roof.
Was I someone else before?
Body donor.
Do you remember my last
conversation with Gwen
in the holding room?
Can you feel that part of her
reaching through you
towards her little girl?
That part is lost.
Just inform me if you need
any additional changes.
Did you kill her?
She did this.
She's gone, Jules.
I'm sorry.
I don't believe you.
She wouldn't do that.
I can't seem to find my...
Medicine.
I'm not gonna be here
for anyone else.
for any other reason.
What's wrong?
I don't really know
why I'm alive.
Doesn't matter.
Whatever you do will be
wonderful and worthwhile.
How do you know?
I know because you're kind.
People say being kind
is being weak.
You're alive because
of energy
and empathy.
Your mother had
so much of it inside of her,
she needed to get it out.
So she made you.
You're starting to
sound like her.
I'm sweating.
I hate sweating.
Are they late?
Relax.
Let's do the meditation thing
you learned at camp.
That was fun.