Tashkent Kino-studio feature films
NASREDDIN IN BUKHARA
Screenplay:
L. Solovyov, V. Vitkovich.
directed by
J. Protazanov
Operator: D. Demutsky
Artist: V. Yeremyan
Music:
M. Ashrafi, B. Arapova
Starring:
Nasreddin - Lev Sverdlin
Emir - K. Mikhailov
Jafar, the loan shark - E. Heller
Niaz, the potter - V. Zaichikov
Guljan - M. Mirzakarimova
Bakhtiar, vizier - S. Kayukov
Yusuf, a blacksmith - A. Talipov
Arslanbek - M. Lyarov
Hussein-Husliya - N. Volkov
keeper of Ali chaikhana - A. Ismatov.
The guards of the Emir: M. Mirakilov,
I. Bobrov, A. Pirmuhamedov
Where are you coming from?
-From Baghdad. -From Baghdad.
So many people are going to Bukhara.
Today is Bazaar!
- No, no, no!
Today, our illustrious Emir will
preside over His merciful court.
(sings in Uzbek)
Hold him! Stop him!
This son of a sin has
not paid any tanga!
Ay, yay, yay. Where are
you coming from? And why?
I'm coming from Damascus.
Oh, illustrious Sir.
My relatives live here in Bukhara.
So, you're going to visit relatives!
Pay a guest fee!
But I'm not coming as a guest.
I have an important business here.
Business, ha? Then you'll pay
a guest fee and a business tax.
C'mon, pay, pay, pay, pay!
Now, contribute something to decorate
the mosque for the glory of Allah,
who has kept you safe
on your journey here.
That's it! Here, here!
God bless you!
Stop! Stop!
Wait, wait! Stop! Stop!
And who will pay the
fee for your donkey?
Yes, who will pay the fee for you?
If you go to visit relatives,
so your donkey is going to
visit relatives, too? Pay up!
That's right! O, wise chief!
Indeed, my donkey has many
relatives in Bukhara! -Yes.
Otherwise, Emir would have been
overthrown a long time ago,
and you would have been
executed for your greed!
Wait, stop! Get him!
I'll get you! I know who you are.
Our lord Emir will preside
over his court today.
Today?
Yes, if you do not come, you
will be escorted under guards.
Stop! Wait!
For the sake of Allah, don't take
the water in a jug! You'd scare it!
Who?
A bird.
Where?
There!
Look yonder! I see the most
beautiful bird in the world!
Yes, where?
- Shh... You'd scare it!!
There! There! There, see?
It's not a bird, it's a frog.
What? A frog?
- Yeah!
If all frogs have such black eyes,
so thin eyebrows and delicate cheeks,
I myself would be a
"croak-croak" frog.
Here I see the most
beautiful girl in the world!
And I see two donkeys!
Only I didn't see
who's ears are longer.
Our ears are shorter than
your eyelashes, beauty.
A frog!
Here! Come here! Give us a hand!
What happened? Who's drowning?
- Some rich man is drowning.
We've been trying to save him.
- Come here! Give us a hand!
Hurry up with that rope!
- Wait a minute! What are you doing?
We're trying to save that men!
-You don't save a rich man like that.
Why not?
- Here! Look, look!
See this?
- Yeah!
Here! Take it! Take it!
Here, take it!
That's how you ought to do it.
And you yell "Here, here."
He's drowned!
- Don't worry! Here, take it!
Look, look! Here, take it...
Here! Take it! Take it! Here, take
it! That's how to save a rich man.
Drowned again! -Here! Take
it! Take it! Here, take it!
Don't worry, you will not
drown! Here, take it...
You are my savior!
Come here. I will reward you.
Here!
But I could swim, without your help.
Stop! Here's half a tanga.
Buy yourself a bowl of pilaf.
Here! Take it! Take it!
Here, take it!
Stop! Stop!
It's here!
Take it!
And you say, "Here, come here!"
What are you waiting for, Muslims?
We are waiting for a
righteous and merciful judgment
from our lord and master Emir!
Righteous Emir!
Clear the road for Emir!
And yet we're in a better position...
If I fall to the ground,
I would not be hurt!
But if he falls from that
stretcher, he'd be full of bruises.
Yes, yes... I understand!
Allow me, Great Emir,
to announce your decision
which I read from your face.
In the name of Allah, the
Merciful, the Compassionate,
Lord of the Faithful
and our ruler Emir
has granted a great
mercy to blacksmith's guild,
allowing them to feed the guards,
and thus giving his
subjects an opportunity
to be thankful to our illustrious
Emir every day and every hour!
Oh, wise Emir!
Oh, the wisest of the wise!
Oh, wise, with the
wisdom of the wisest...
Enough! Git!
Blacksmith Yusuf, dared
to show ingratitude.
Mm...
So, the Emir graciously decides:
blacksmith Yusuf, in order
to show his repentance,
will be awarded with 200 backlashes.
Well, that blacksmith, has
got righteous and merciful
judgment of our wise Emir.
Come here, worthy Jafar,
Emir will hear you.
Don't cry, Guljan, I will ask
Emir to give us a reprieve.
Oh, great lord! You
shine on us like the sun!
This man owes me one hundred tangas,
and three hundred tangas
interest on that debt.
Total - four hundred tangas.
The deadline to pay his debt,
expired this morning,
and he was unable to pay.
- A reprieve!
I just ask for a
reprieve from great Emir.
Allow me, Great Emir,
to announce your decision...
which I read from His face.
By law, if someone does
not pay a debt on time,
then his whole family goes into
slavery to him to whom he owes!
But the mercy and generosity
of our Lord is boundless.
Although the deadline to
pay the debt has expired,
the Emir confers
potter Niyaz - a reprieve.
One whole hour!
Praise the great mercy
of the Emir, potter Niyaz!
Oh, generous Emir!
Oh, kind Emir!
Har, Har, Har, Har, Har, Har.
Oh, most generous Emir!
Emir is angry.
Take your donkey away!
Angry! Ay, yay, yay! What can I do?
I can not forbid my donkey to
praise the wisdom of our Emir!
Quite, quite!
Calm down! Hush! Hush! Oh, you!
Beauty, at noon today
you and your father
will come into my home!
Exactly in one hour,
I will come back for you.
Stay here and do not go away!
Why don't you cry?
Why should your daughter cry, potter?
It's useless to cry, because tears
does not turn into silver coins.
We have to try to get the money!
You are mocking at us, stranger!
I don't know anyone in this
town, but I'll try to get it!
To get it! Four hundred
tangas in a strange city!
I'll get the money!
I'll get it for you!
Sit here and don't go anywhere!
Where are you going, my good man?
- Why?
This is not a place for a donkey?
- This is not an ordinary donkey.
He asked me to show him
the palace of the Emir.
That's not allowed! Take it away!
- Where?
Not allowed?
- Of course not!
Sorry, I'll show you
the palace next time!
Well! Very good!
Oh, Bul-Bul, you're
making a great progress!
Why do you put that book in
front of your donkey? -Shh...
I'm teaching him to read.
How could it be that
a donkey learn to read?
This is not a common donkey.
God gave him a sharp mind
and a remarkable memory.
It's just he can not turn
the pages. I have to help him.
The Emir called me once and asked:
"Can you teach my
favorite donkey to write?"
I'll try. Where is it?
He showed it to me. I checked
his abilities... and I said:
"Oh, illustrious Emir!
This is a wonderful donkey!
He is as clever,
as any of your ministers!
Maybe even as you are.
I will teach him. He will
know as much as you know.
And maybe even more.
But for this, I need twenty years!"
Then the Emir gave me a
purse of gold, and said:
"If after twenty years, my
donkey would not be reading,
I would cut off your head."
- Oh!
Unfortunate!
You will loose your head!
After 20 years, someone is bound to
die. Either I, or donkey, or Emir.
You couldn't be the Nasreddin,
could you?
I urgently need four hundred tangas,
exactly four hundred.
Well, who will give me four
hundred tangas? Who? Well?
I will pay back.
- Nasreddin, I've got no money.
But I can give you this hat,
it's new. -Rahmat! (Thanks!)
Take this from me.
- Rahmat!
Rahmat! Rahmat! Rahmat! Rahmat!
Here, take my belt!
And from me, take it, Nasreddin.
- Rahmat!
Take this, Nasreddin!
Take this from me, Nasruddin.
- Rahmat! Little horseman!
And take this from me!
Nasruddin, catch!
- Rahmat! Rahmat!
Nasreddin!
- Rahmat.
Rahmat!
Kapkole!
(Attention!)
A pair of worn shoes.
Still could be used.
I'll sell it cheap,
only thirty-three tangas.
Five for the shoes,
five for being cheap,
and twenty-three for being
from a poor man's feet.
Kapkole!
A tin bowl,
round like the Emir's head.
Emir never gave a drink to anyone,
but this bowl got drunk 5,000 men!
And here... a belt, brand new.
Well... Never buy a brand new belt!
You couldn't see anything through it!
Buy it when it is
torn and full of holes.
And you could see the
entire world through it!
Ah, so you are selling these goods?
- And you yelled: "Here, here!"
How much do you want for
all of this together? -Cheap!
Selling cheap, hurry up,
I'll tell you... Come here!
Take it all for 400 tangas.
- You're crazy!
I will give you 200 tangas!
-Two hundred? -Yes!
Two hundred and fifty!
Look at my donkey,
even he laughs at you.
Two hundred and seventy-five!
- Kapkole!
I swear by Allah, I'll overpay twice
for these goods. Here's 300 tangas!
400!
325!
330!
400!
Stop!
400! -350! -400!
360! -400!
-370! - 400!
380! -400!
-390! -400!
395! -400!
-396! -400!
I agree.
- Ugh!
Okay, okay.
- Quick, quick.
I always suffer losses on
account of my own goodness.
Hey, wait! This one's fake!
-Fake? -Yeah!
Hurry, hurry, hurry!
- Why are you in such a hurry?
Umbala Kidon, Umbala Kidon,
Umbala Kidon, Umbala Kidon...
What business makes you
to go in such a hurry?
Same as yours!
- But you don't know my business.
If you know, you'd be jealous of me.
I want the most
beautiful girl in Bukhara.
And now she will be mine. You hear?
- I've heard.
Like a jackal who saw a cherry
high up on a tree, and said:
"No matter what, I'll eat this
cherry." And climbed up on a tree.
He was climbing for two hours,
all bruised and exhausted...
When he finally got to the cherry, the
falcon flew by and grabbed the cherry.
And he was coming down the tree for
two hours more, and got more bruised.
And then?
- Then he realized...
that cherries do not
grow for a jackal. -Ah...
Your story about the cherry
does not make any sense.
You're a fool!
Hey, potter, the hour has come.
And now, you and your
daughter will come with me!
This was the girl I
was telling you about.
And do you have the potter's receipt?
- Of course!
Here it is! And the deadline
for the payment has expired!
It hasn't been expired, yet!
Here's your money, loan shark
Jafar! Exactly 400 tangas!
I'm buying the potter's debt.
Receipt!
Your receipt?
- Yes, mine!
Look!
Stranger, tell me your name,
so that I know who to bless!
Yes, tell me your name, so
that I know who to curse!
In Baghdad, Tehran, Istanbul and
Mecca... everywhere they call me...
Nasreddin.
- Ugh!
Thank you, Nasreddin.
- Frog!
Nasreddin?
- It can not be, Nasreddin.
Nasreddin! Nasreddin!
Nasreddin? -Yes!
-In Bukhara? Here?
No... it cannot be!
Turkish Sultan wrote us that he
cut off Nasreddin's head. -He wrote!
Khiva Khan announced that
he skinned him alive! -Yes!
And the Iranian Shah
cut him to pieces...
Oh!
Get him!
Listen... You've been working
for me for two weeks now.
During this time,
I earned 350 tangas!
Half of the money,
rightfully belongs to you.
You're saying very strange things.
What would happen on
this earth, if all masters
would start to share their
income with employees?
Would Allah and Emir tolerate such
an outrageous violation of the order.
That would be like...
What are you looking at?
What did you see?
I saw a frog.
The most beautiful in the world!
Oh! Her eyebrows are
pretty as the Moon.
Teeth like pearls, and breasts like
marble, and shoulders... -Enough!
Where is she? -I can
show you her home. -So?
But should it be some reward for
the worthless servant of Emir? -Um...
Praised be the
generosity of our lord,
but my great lord should hurry up,
because someone else wants the girl.
Who would dare?
- Nasreddin
What!? Nasreddin?
Nasreddin, again!
Hey! Arslanbek! Here!
Tomorrow morning, you
shall bring that girl here!
You know, Guljan, I have
long wanted to tell you,
that I... I... Look at that star.
poor thing, it must
be very cold up there.
You know, Guljan, I have
long wanted to tell you...
I'm very...
Look how many thistles
are in my donkey's tail!
He robbed all burdocks
from here to Damascus.
I think I've heard
the sound of a slap?
And you don't put your
lips where you shouldn't.
I'm... Guljan! Guljan?
Eh...
...where you shouldn't.
Oh...
(Nasreddin sings in Uzbek)
You understand what I mean. Yes?
Who would know...
Where to put your lips, and
where you shouldn't... huh?
Oh! Ah!
Oh, oh, oh, oh! Ah!
Painful, is it?
Very, very...
Very?
- Very, uh...
(Sings in Uzbek)
Stop! Stop shouting!
Hush!
Hush, father will hear!
Who's there?
By order of Emir... open the door!
They're after you. Run!
Save yourself, my love!
There is a beautiful
rose in your garden.
And Emir wishes to decorate
his palace with that rose.
Where is your daughter?
Help!
Father, Father, help me! Father!
Father! Father! Help! Help!
Help!
Wait a minute!
We want to look at her.
Today we will deign to be with her.
Jafar! Jafar! Woe to you!
I know everything,
you wretched jackal!
Cherry did not grow for the jackal,
nor for the falcon!
The cherry belongs to the lion!
- Ah!
Not yet!
And you, Jafar, remember,
I saved you out of the water,
but I swear, I shall drown
you again, in the same pond.
But before that,
you will be executed!
Nasreddin is still in Bukhara.
He hasn't been caught!
Emir is angry.
If you do not catch Nasreddin,
I swear by Allah,
the Emir will hang you all!
And those who catch him,
will get a bounty.
Mhm... three thousand tangas.
- Wow!
What do you want?
Gallant soldier, let me through,
to the wives of Emir. -No!
If you wish to know the
cause of your misfortune,
come here and I'll tell you
what threatens your happiness.
(Sings a song in Uzbek).
If you know where Nasreddin
is hiding, tell me.
I have to consult with
him about your case.
All right, I'll try
to find Nasreddin.
Have you seen Nasreddin?
- No, I haven't seen him.
Oh, woman... Woe to you!
Black hand of an evil
spirit is upon you.
But, I know a way to
prevent it. If you learn...
where Nasreddin is hiding,
come here and tell me.
All right, I will bring Nasreddin
to you! -You will bring him? When?
Right now! He is near.
- Where is he?
He's just waiting to visit you.
- Where is he? I don't see it!
But you are a fortuneteller,
look closer.
He's here!
Well, what evil is threatening me?
And what would you like
to consult with me? Well!?
Guards!
Guards! Guards!
I found him! I found him!
I found him!
He is in the market!
Who?
- He's in the market!
Who? -Nasreddin. He's
dressed as a woman.
Ah, so...
And my reward?
Three thousand tangas?
All right! Hey, guards! Hurry!
The reward is mine!
Three thousand tanga!
Hurry! Get him!
(Women scream.)
Muslims! What are you waiting for?
They disgrace our
wives in broad daylight!
What are you doing?
Those are my...
... pots...
Where are you coming from?
From Baghdad.
Show me the way to the palace.
How do I get into the palace? In the
name of Allah, what's happening here?
Who is the master of Bukhara?
We or him?
That damn Nasreddin!
That troublemaker!
Who is the master of
Bukhara? We ask you!
We emir, or he emir?
When will I see Nasreddin's head
presented to me on this tray?
In the name of Allah, what
is happening in Bukhara?
Bazaar.
- Bazaar? Bazaar...
This is a riot, not Bazaar!
Now, how would I get to the palace?
Why do you go to the palace?
Let it be known to you, that I am a
famous sage, healer and astrologer.
And I'm coming here from Baghdad
at the invitation of the Emir.
My name is Hussein-Husliya.
- Ah!
Hussein-Husliya!
- Hussein-Husliya.
You can not be the Hussein-Husliya?
Yes, I'm the one.
- Ah!
You wretch!
You're gonna loose your head!
Your head is lost!
- Whose head?
Don't you know that all those people
are looking for you? -W-w-what?
I must hide you somewhere?
Let's go!
Hide here.
What are you talking about?
Emir was informed that
you are coming from Baghdad
to get into his harem and
to dishonor his wives!
Me... in harem? But I
never said anything like that.
And then, I'm old. What
would I do in the harem?
I don't know! But Emir knew you came
to Bukhara and hiding in the Bazaar.
He ordered, you to be found,
caught and decapitated! -Oh, my god!
I wish I've never been born!
- It's nothing, don't worry!
Allah has much better harem then
Emir! -To Baghdad! To Baghdad!
You would be caught at the gate,
brought to the palace and decapitated.
And one of the guards will get a
reward for your head, 3.000 tanga.
3,000 tangas? That means I
can not be saved! Oh, help me!
Oh, help me, good Muslim!
What could I do for you?
Oh! Ah... no...
Oh! Ah... no, not that, not that...
Oh! That's it!
I've found it! I know!
That's it! Here is your
salvation! Look, look, now...
Here, put on a woman's dress...
Shame!
You can take cover under this veil,
and pass by the guards, to Baghdad!
Stop!
Where to? -To Baghdad.
-Why?
I'm going back to my wives... I mean,
my husband, to my husband in Baghdad!
Oh! Get down, get down!
- Let go of me, guards let me go...
Ah... This is he!
Oh, you! You don't have heads on
your shoulders, but empty pumpkins.
Announce that we raise
the bounty on his head!
Ten thousand tangas!
And woe to you,
you useless trunks,
if he would not be caught.
Soon, I expect a visit
from Hussein-Husliya,
which I've invited from Baghdad.
A sage, astrologer and physician.
Praised be the sun and the universe!
- Speak!
A man just came to the gates, calling
himself a wise man from Baghdad!
Hussein-Husliya!
Show him in! Call him here!
Great Emir, tell me have you
been with your women today?
Let Emir answer to
your worthless slave.
Today? No! We didn't enter the harem.
Oh! Praise be to Allah
that I came in time.
Wait, Hussein-Husliya,
what are you talking about?
Praised be Allah, I came in time!
You words are incomprehensible.
- Let it be known to great Emir,
that last night I saw that
the position of the stars
were threatening to the Emir.
The star Alkap, meaning
the sting of death,
was opposite the star
Ashhala, meaning the heart.
So, until the stars do
not change their position,
Emir should not touch a woman,
or his death is imminent!
Ay, yay, just today we brought
a new girl to our harem.
Ah-ah-ah-ah-ah!
Forget about her! Forget about her!
Until the stars change position.
Otherwise you would die!
And your people would be helpless.
Thank you!
Thank you, Hussein-Husliya.
We can see that you
are truly a sage... Yes!
And devoted to us! And you...
What are you looking at?
Why are we paying you a
great salary? Have you heard?
Your Emir almost died,
and you didn't even blink about it.
Now, you look at them. Look at
them, Hussein-Husliya... Huh?
What a bunch of stupid faces, huh?
-His Highness Emir is absolutely right!
These faces do not
show a trace of wisdom.
That's right!
Do you hear? Boobies!
Besides, let me tell
you that these faces,
do not show any sign of integrity.
The thieves... Thieves, thieves.
All thieves... all thieves...
Would you believe, Hussein-Husliya,
this morning we have forgotten
our favorite belt in the garden.
And when we returned, it was no
longer there. Some of them had...
I see...
You know, Hussein-Husliya...
Allah...
Is this the great emir's belt?
It is!
Almighty Allah! You
are indeed a great sage!
Take this belt as your reward!
Nasreddin is caught!
I caught him!
Who are you?
Why are you hiding
under women's clothes?
I...
I was going to the great,
all-merciful Emir...
But I met a man who told me that
Emir wanted to cut off my head.
I was frightened, so I tried to
escape, dressed like a woman.
We wanted to cut off your head?
Did we want to cut his head off?
Why?
Because I allegedly intended to get
in the harem of the great Emir.
- In our harem?
Who are you?
- Me?
I am Hussein-Husliya, wiseman,
healer and astrologer from Baghdad!
Ha, ha, what a lier!
This is Hussein-Husliya!
Who is Hussein-Husliya?
Is he Hussein-Husliya?
I am Hussein-Husliya! He's a
liar! He usurped my name!
Forgive me, great lord,
but the old man's
shamelessness has no limits.
He says that I, Hussein-Husliya,
usurped his name! -Yes!
And next he could say
that this is his robe.
Of course! That's my robe!
You see?
Maybe this is your turban?
- Mine!
And these shoes?
The book? -Mine!
-Rosary? -Mine!
Maybe this belt is yours, as well?
- Mine! Mine! Mine! Mine!
Deceiver! Dodger!
Illustrious lord, now you
see who stands before you.
Today, this deceitful and despicable
old man says that I've usurped his name,
and tomorrow he will say that
this is his palace... -Yes!
... and that Bukhara belongs to him.
- Yes. You're right, Hussein-Husliya!
We can see that this is a dangerous
man. He has dark thoughts in his head.
It is necessary to separate
his head from his body!
First, it is necessary to know his real
intentions and why he arrived in Bukhara.
Let me deal with him. I will torture
him and he will tell me his real name.
Well, then, take him and torture
him until he confesses everything!
Tell me, Hussein-Husliya, what to
do with this wicked Nasreddin? Huh?
Ugh, ugh!
Oh, my great lord!
He knows that while I'm in
Bukhara, he has nothing to do here!
And now... tell me...
What about your new prisoner?
Do you know who he is?
Not yet. -Try to change
the torture! -You bet!
Yesterday, I spent the whole day
using iron tongs to loosen his teeth.
Yeah, it's a good torture,
loosening teeth, but...
And today, I will squeeze his
head with a rope loop and a stick.
New torture? Good torture!
Using loops and sticks.
What do you want?
- Oh, the great lord!
The star of your harem,
Guljan, is dying!
Dying? How? Ooh!
If she would die,
we would be very sad.
After all, we've
never been with her!
Hussein-Husliya!
Can you cure Guljan?
I've got to see her.
- What? See her?
You want to see her?
Oh, the great lord,
I have to look at her hand, only.
I'm a skilled healer. I can determine
her illness, by looking at her nails.
I just need a hand.
- Ah, the hand...
Well, it will not hurt us!
Emir himself, and
the doctor with him.
Guljan!
My name is Hussein-Husliya.
I'm new sage, astrologer
and physician of Emir.
You're in danger, and I will save you.
Do you understand me, Guljan?
I understand, Hussein-Husliya!
- Give me your hand!
Here.
The left! The left... left!
I want to define your illness,
by the color of your nails.
Here! -Here?
-Yes, there!
Does your heart aches?
- Yes, my heart!
I am separated from my darling, and
though I feel that he is near me,
I cannot hug or kiss him.
Oh, how I wish that he hugs me?
Almighty Allah! What a passion my master
has inspired in her, in such a short time.
Your lover is near.
- Near, near...
He's thinking of you...
- I think of her, yes...
Day and night, he's
thinking only of you, dear.
Isn't that right, Master?
- Right, right, yes, yes! Of you!
Save me, Hussein-Husliya!
Calm down, Guljan!
I, Hussein-Husliya, will save you!
He will save! He'll save you!
- Absolutely!
Thank you, Hussein-Husliya!
She's recovering.
- Ah...
Thank you, you incomparable
healer of diseases.
Dirty dog!
- Very good!
Listen, Hussein-Husliya,...
Now you have to scream again.
- Ugh...
Don't worry... I've invented
such a nice torture...
squeezing the head with a
rope loop and a stick... Um...
Uh... you son of a sin! Damn you!
May Allah drop a stone on your
head and squash it like this!
Good! But just remember,
you have to scream so loud,
that everyone in the whole palace
hear you, and not like the last time.
With what? -Huh? -With what?
Loop and stick!
Oh... Allah!
No! Not so, not so...
You scream lazy. And they
are experts in such matters.
If they would feel that you pretend,
you would fall in the hands of an
axeman. -Oh, you son of sin!
You should do it like this!
Aaaaa!
You, descendant of the wicked!
I don't have such a voice?
Don't worry.
The loop... stick...
Aaaaa!
Calm down.
That's only our Hussein-Husliya,
with a rope loop and a stick.
What a nice torture!
Wretched ragamuffin! May you
be eaten alive by a grave worms!
May Allah will open...
a pit under your feet, so that you
fall in it and break your legs.
Ay, yay! Why are you mad at me?
Did I disgrace your name?
Or did I defame your knowledge?
Here! Look!
Emir sent this to Hussein-Husliya,
because he cured the girl.
You...!
You cured the girl?
Yes, me!
You, ignorant crook, a deadbeat!
What do you know about diseases?
I know nothing about diseases!
But I know about girls!
So... it would be fair
to divide this money...
... in half.
To one Hussein-Husliya,
who knows about diseases.
And to other Hussein-Husliya,
who knows about girls!
Another one fell.
Where did they fall,
all those stars?
On the ground. Where else? -I've
heard, that they fall in the sea.
How would you know all this?
- I know!
Tell us, tell us, the wise lord...
- Wait a minute!
Tell us, wise Hussein-Husliya,
where do stars fall from the sky?
And why people cannot
find them on the ground?
You really don't know?
- No, no, no.
When a star falls to the ground...
- Yes, yes, yes...
... it crumbles into
small silver coins.
Oh, tell us more. More!
Well, then people collect the
coins. I even knew the people
who were enriched in that way.
Allah...
Oh! If only a single
star would fell here...
... we would...
immediately get rich...
Did you hear?
- Yes, I did.
Got it?
- Got it.
Don't worry, Guljan.
Now I will draw their attention.
All will be well.
And then you walk away alone.
- No!
Don't worry, Guljan.
Wait for me in the tea house,
with the chaikhana keeper Ali.
Ready!
One, two, three.
Stop! Who wants to earn
three thousand tangas? Well?
Well, catch Nasreddin!
If you dare...
Nasreddin! Get him! Catch him!
Catch Nasreddin!
Catch Nasreddin! Get him!
Hey, you! Follow me!
Catch Nasreddin! Catch Nasreddin!
Catch Nasreddin! Get him!
Hussein-Husliya...
- Catch Nasreddin!
Look, if he's here somewhere.
I couldn't find him anywhere.
Hussein-Husliya, come
with us in the bedchamber
and protect our sleep.
- No!
Let the Great Emir look at the stars.
Now they are in favor to him.
Now, he can touch Guljan.
Today we deign to go to her.
- Oh, the great lord!
The pearl of your harem,
Guljan, has been kidnapped.
She has been stolen by
that damn Nasreddin.
If you value your
heads, you cowards...
What are these people guilty for?
-They're all concealers of Nasreddin.
They will be put to a cruel
death, if they do not hand over
that beggar and the rebel.
- Well, well, well, well...
You're in a hurry to the city?
And now I'm in a hurry to the palace.
In the name of Allah, the
Merciful, the Compassionate...
ruler of Bukhara, the moon
and the sun of the universe,
weighed on the scales of justice
the crime for hiding
Nasreddin, that blasphemer
and a troublemaker,
deign to decide:
potter Niyaz and
all other concealers,
will be put to death by decapitation.
If anyone of these convicts would
reveal Nasreddin's whereabouts,
he would be freed...
and all other convicts
would be pardoned!
Potter Niyaz!
Can you specify the
hiding place of Nasreddin?
No! I will not say
where Nasreddin is?
Period!
Order to stop the penalty, oh
lord! And I will catch Nasreddin.
Oh, my lord, it wouldn't be fair
to punish these "small potatoes",
before we catch and
execute the main concealer!
What?
The man who has been hiding
Nasreddin all the time, even today!
You're right.
If there is such a concealer,
he should be the first
to be decapitated.
And if the Great Emir doesn't
want to execute this major concealer,
would it be fair to execute
these small concealers?
You're right Hussein-Husliya.
But show us quickly
who's the main concealer
and we shall immediately
cut off his head.
Lord of Bukhara says
that if he refuses to
execute the main concealer,
I'm about to point out,
that all these convicts
will be released!
Is this right, oh, my Lord?
You're right, Hussein-Husliya.
We are giving our Emir's word!
Did you hear that, oh,
people of noble Bukhara?
The Emir gives his word!
OK, OK, who's the main concealer?
The main concealer
of Nasreddin...
Well, well, well...
... is you, Emir!
Well, Emir, order them to
cut off your head! Huh?
The emir promised to free the
prisoners, we all heard that!
Freedom to all convicts!
- Nasreddin!
Freedom! Freedom to all convicts!
Freedom to all convicts!
We must free them,
the people could rebel.
Emir keeps his word!
They are free!
We have to save Nasreddin!
And so, my opinion
is that we should...
cut off his head!
- Aah!
That wouldn't do! The Turkish
sultan had already cut off my head.
Indeed, the Sultan wrote us that
he had cut of the head of this bum.
And yet, he's still alive. We
must take a more sure remedy.
It's best to burn him
alive on a nice fire!
Yes, yes, that was done to
me by Khan of Khiva, uh...
Verily! Your heads are
like overripe pumpkins!
Tell me...
Aaaa!
Tell me, have you ever been drowned?
- Drowned?
No, no one has ever drowned me.
That's it! The only sure way!
Tomorrow afternoon, he shall be
publicly drowned in Laba-Hauze!
The spies reported that the
people in the city are worried.
The people may try to
rescue this son of sin.
Drown him when night comes...
secretly...
Why, why they set
us free on the court?
It would be better for me to die, than
to know that our Nasreddin is caught.
It is better for all of us to die,
than to let them execute our Nasreddin!
Where, where is our Nasreddin?
What will happen to him?
Wait, I want to tell you...
I want to tell you...
- What?
Shh...
Do you carry me on your backs?
Well, yes!
What a pity that my donkey
isn't here. -Why is that?
He would have burst out laughing!
(Singing in Uzbek)
Phew! I'm tired...
We must rest!
Carry him! It's your turn.
We must hurry up.
Oh, brave warriors! Wait a minute.
I want to pray before dying.
Pray, but not for long!
Oh, God Almighty, do so...
that the person who finds
my ten thousand tangas,
would give one thousand to the
mosque and asked to pray for me
for the year.
Carry me further.
I commend my spirit
into the hands of Allah.
We would give three thousand
tangas to the mosque.
We're not evil people!
Tell us where did
you hide your money?
Where are we now?
This is the road through the
cemetery, at the northern gate.
The northern gate?
This is the will of Allah. At the
south entrance, on the other side
of the cemetery, there are three
old tombstones, placed in a triangle.
Under each of them,
I buried 3,333 tangas.
Three thousand three hundred
and thirty three tangas.
Yes, one-third.
- One-third...
You guard him!
We're gonna dig up the money.
Oh, and my share?
- We'll split at equal shares.
Praise be to Allah, glory be
to Allah, praise be to Allah.
Praise be to Allah,
praise be to Allah!
Praise be to Allah!
- Hey, are you a man?
What's so surprising?
- Surprising?
Why are you sitting in the bag?
- I have to be in it.
Maybe you were put in the bag by
force? -Ha, ha, ha, ha, by force?
Would I have to pay six hundred
tangas to be put in the bag by force!
Six hundred tangas!
Why did you pay so much money?
This bag belongs to an Arab
and has a wonderful ability
to cure diseases and deformities.
I was lame, hunchbacked,
and crooked in one eye.
But I sat in the bag for two
hours, and my hunch was gone,
eye sight and leg straightened!
- Ah!
Why are you still sitting in the sack?
- Because I paid for the time!
I paid to be in it for exactly four
hours. I don't want to waste the time!
Listen, oh, you who
are sitting in the sack!
I'm also a hunchback,
lame and crooked in one eye.
And I gladly will pay
you three hundred tangas
to sit in the bag for
the remaining two hours.
All right! But you have
to pay me in advance!
I agree!
But let's not waste the time
which already belongs to me.
Phew! He lied to us
again, that rascal!
What should I do?
If three genies arrive
here and start to beat you,
to swear, and carry you around,
just say the magic spell:
"He who wears a copper
shield, he has a thick skull!
Kiss my donkey under its tail. "
- How, how?
Kiss my donkey under its tail!
He who wears a copper
shield, he has a thick skull...
What?
-Kiss my donkey under its tail!
He who wears a copper
shield, he has a thick skull.
Kiss my donkey under its tail!
He who wears a copper
shield, he has a thick skull...
kiss my donkey under its tail.
Bring him!
Bring him quickly. You're late.
You lazy dogs! Well! Hurry!
Bring him! Bring him...
Why do they hesitate to sound it?
Nasreddin is no longer alive!
It is finished!
The troublemaker is dead!
We have lost our Nasreddin.
Nasreddin is dead.
Wai, Jae-harem!
How will we live without Nasreddin?
And how will I live
if Nasreddin dies?
Wai, Jae-harem!
Ae...!
- I...
Nasreddin?
- Nasreddin!
Nasreddin? -Nasreddin.
-Nasreddin! -Yep!
Nasreddin! Nasreddin!
Ali! Ali!
Wait, Ali!
Guljan! Guljan!
- Nasreddin!
Guljan!
Don't bid farewell to us.
Oh, people of noble Bukhara!
Me and Guljan, we should leave
quietly. Because the guards may think
that all the people have decided to
leave Bukhara, and close the city gates.
Return to your homes!
And may you sleep in peace!
Let's never see the black
wings of trouble, again!
Nasreddin says goodbye
to you! For how long?
I don't know myself.
(Nasreddin sings in Uzbek)
English subtitles made for Karagarga,
by Quigley (12.2012)
-THE END-