Payments of foreign
loans are cancelled.
No more liras will be
paid to international...
financial monopolies, which impoverished
our country for years and...
which seized our people's bread.
Turkish bureau of IMF, which is the
pawnshop of imperialism,
is closed and...
all agreements with it are
cancelled unilaterally.
The budget of foreign loans, promised
by previous governments to...
imperialist countries,
will be spent for
education and health
needs of our people.
Two: Internal loans are cancelled.
You see, they have already started!
So?
Should they wait?
They have the chance,
they will stop at nothing!
The loans that the state borrowed from
leading capitalists with heavy interest.
I don't understand!
We established factories.
We employed people.
We fed them.
Now they walk all over us.
I really don't understand;
What is happening to this country.
You don't understand what, Necla?
What you don't understand?
So, these raiders
will govern the country?
They lose their ways on straight line.
Now, we are leaving everything
we have to this crowd...
How nice!
I surely always
appreciate your ideas!
If you want you can stay here,
I don't force you to come with me!
Can you shut down this,
this is enough!
I can't! If you want get off,
take another taxi.
Mines, foreign trade institutions
and banks are nationalized.
The economic system
based on exploitation of...
by people will be removed
entirely according to a plan...
; the economic roots of inequality
and injustice will be eradicated.
Seven: A major plan will be prepared
for the solution of housing problem.
Everyone is owner of the house he
lives in until this plan is announced.
People living in houses improper
to health and dignity of human being...
will move to new houses
in the one-year period.
Work for years, strive, save;
Not go and leave everything to these.
Fine!
How nice!
We did everything for this country...
We sacrificed...
Now look at us...
We escape like criminals.
So, what should we do?
Say, what should we do?
Should we stay and wait
for they come and put us in jail?
But, what did we do?
Whay should they put us in jail.
I cannot understand
what we have done.
We gave everything
we have to this country...
and now look what we are faced with!
Better! You gave, got, done, finished!
We are going now.
I still do not understand anything.
How can we leave ourwealth
to these communists...
we pinched and saved
this wealth for years!
I really cannot understand
how all these happened!
Necla it's enough, shut up!
Please, enough!
Eeeh! That is enough!
Get out!
What?
Get out! I cannot deal
with you at this time!
Well, but how can we get out?
The car is moving; you should stop.
The carwill continue,
it would not stop...
but you will get out!
Provisions for deresing the weekly...
working period to
35 hours at first...
then to 30 hours.
Erhan, get one and light up.
No, no brother, I will not smoke now.
- Is there water in the car?
- Yes, here you are.
- Thank you.
- Thanks.
I want to say you
something but I'm afraid!
Why are you afraid?
What will you say?
I'm afraid you'll do something
stupid and make me regret saying this.
Let us hearwhat it is.
What will you say?
- Promise me you won't turn mad.
- Of!
- Say what you want to say.
- Promise me!
OK, I promise!
Promise!
I heard that her aunts will visit
Elif's family this evening.
So what?
They always visit them, no?
No, this time it's different.
I heard that they will make
Elif marry her cousin, Hüseyin.
Elif's mother told this to my wife.
What are you talking about?
Mahmut Aga has been saying that he won't
give any part of his land to a stranger.
- Where are you going?
- I have to find Elif.
Come, come, come, come!
- What?
- Open this window, open it!
What happened?
What's this?
Will they come to ask for your
hand to marriage in the evening?
How should I know?
Elif, what are you saying?
What do you mean to do?
Are you insane?
Do you want to marry your cousin?
I would marry you if you'v
e grown into a man!
I've had enough of this for years!
You said the factory is closed,
the construction went bankrupt...
My father has set his mind,
he will give me to Hüseyin.
Listen, either you
find a way and marry
me or go away and don't
come to me again!
Don't annoy me anymore!
I will live what's my destiny...
Leave me well alone!
Elif!
God!
- Selamun aleyküm, uncle Necmi.
- Aleyküm selam.
- Did you see brother Ömer?
- Which Ömer? The communist?
- Yes, communist Ömer. Did you see him?
- What is your job with him?
It is none of your business!
Tell me if you saw him or not!
He may be in the coffeehouse!
Look here! Why are you so angry?
God! Are you mad?
He resembles his father...
They say this.
He found the old man, attacks steadily!
- Brother Ömer!
- What's up?
- I want to talk to you.
- Why?
Come here, I want to talk to you.
You said you will seize the
land of the bastard aga, no?
You said common farms would
be formed; people would...
work together produce together, no?
What happened?
These things are not so easy, brother.
The entire country is changing.
Also, why are you so
interested in this issue?
You were against this
collectivism before?
It's not your job!
Aren't you listening to me? You have
to finish this job until this evening!
Are you insane my boy?
This can't be solved so immediately.
It must! It must be solved
in one day this time!
If not, I will be destroyed,
I will be spoiled!
- Why will you be destroyed?
- Look at me my Ömer! Brother Ömer!
I think you don't understand me, no?
Listen to me!
I say we should lay our
hands on this issue
together and solve this issue today!
If so, go to the District
Agriculture Committee and say:
I reviled at the leftists until today,
now I am alarmed...
- so I want collectivization.
- You say this?
- I actually say what you heard!
- Shit!
- Is it you who broke this window?
- Yes, I broke it, so? So what?
You said you will come to our village,
my friend; you didn't. Ha?
You said you would collectivize the
lands, you would form farms...
people would work together,
earn together! What happened?
- Are you maniac, my boy?
- What are you talking about?
No one would be left landless;
Everybody would work and...
produce together blah blah,
Get you gone!
- We do that, don't you see?
- What do you do?
Why didn't you come to our village, ha?
The same old same old!
But this job is not so eay that
we can solve so soon!
This need a plan, a legal job...
We will come to your village
to when the time comes.
When will you come, when, when?
You will come when
I absolutely loose Elif, ha?
Who's Elif, my boy?
Her father in the evening, OK?
Will give her to her cousin only...
to protect his lands, OK,
her bastard father...
Come in, we will talk.
- Really?
- Come.
For your information,
I can't behave without thinkin...
I only attend to the meeting about
collectivization, that's it!
Do you understand?
God, OK brother,
OK, it's enough for me.
Look, if this man hears that
we will seize his land...
he would forget his daughter,
the weeding, everything...
and he would head out
after you immediately!
What are you saying,
he is such a bastard!
- OK, let's see!
- Let's see.
Listen to me; should
I go and announce from the mosque...
so everyone will be gathered
in the coffeehouse?
- OK. Do you know what you'll say?
- Certainly, I know.
- Let's see.
Dear people of Sakince village!
There will be a meeting in the
coffeehouse about the land...
collectivization in our village.
Everyone has to leave his job...
and come to the coffeehouse.
Don't say "I didn't
hear, what will I do?"!
Immediately, quit your job and
come to the coffeehouse.
Especially, Mehmet Susuzgil
should come, it's a must!
Friends, as you know,
the revolution...
aims a big transformation
in villages as well as in cities.
We have already seized
lands of land masters.
We form big farms on these lands.
We invite small landholders like...
you to these common farms.
These farms will be
formed by your lands.
I mean, your lands will
be combined; you will
cultivate the land together
and work together.
These farms will be
managed by managers...
you choose among yourself and
by expert agriculture engineers...
on the products that will be
cultivated in this region.
Anything you
need for production, seed...
tractor, diesel,
fertiliser, electricity...
will be supplied by the state.
More importantly...
the products you raise
in the common farms will...
be bought by the statel mean...
your products won't be
bought cheaply by merchants.
So you won't...
be afraid of making loss when
you can't sell your products.
You won't be indebted to produce.
This is what I'll say.
I'll be glad to answer your questions.
Brother, Mehmet Aga didn't come.
Who's Mehmet Aga?
Elif's father.
He didn't come.
We have to go. Quick.
It's good, but I don't understand...
why everyone has equal share?
For example,
Mehmet Aga has 300 decares of land.
Whereas Worm Hasan has 13,
maybe 15 decares of land.
Now, if we take part in these farms...
the two will get the same money, yes?
Is it true?
Brother, come on, brother.
This man is probably
working in the field;
We can catch him only now; come on.
Erhan, people are asking questions,
I have to answer these questions.
My brother, why are you
making things so difficult?
What don't you understand?
Listen, you say Mehmet Aga has
300 decares of land, field, yes?
But, how did he get this land...
how did he buy these farms?
Look, all of you were indebted;
All you were in debt to these banks.
This man bought your land very cheap;
And made...
your children worker
of himself on top of it...
and you still defend Mehmet Aga, ha?
Let's go, let's go! Their
question don't end!
We're too late.
- For God's sake, we are late!
- Erhan!
We'll solve it later. We'll
solve it later. He'll
tell you, my brotherwill
tell you everything.
My friends, I'll come later again...
in order to make further
explanation to you.
Sorry about today.
- It's a matter of life and death!
- See you soon! Goodbye.
Brother, please be quick!
- So, why didn't you talk?
- I was just preparing to talk...
- The man standing here is Susuzgil?
- Yes, he is.
Good, you wait here.
- You say so?
- Yes, it is.
- Is this farm yours?
- Yes.
Well, why those
people work on your...
farm as you bum around here?
Who are you?
- You say this farm is yours, ha?
- I said yes!
- It's not.
- What the hell are you saying?
These farms are not yours anymore.
These are theirs!
They cultivate, but you eat!
This came to an end Mehmet!
From now on, we are all together,
both when we rest and...
when we work on the field!
From now on, we will work
together and eat together!
This farm, this soil, this tree...
this reaper belong to all of us!
This farm belongs to Erhan
as much as it belongs to you!
Don't behave cruelly, it's useless.
Don't upset your daughter
due to this land, this farm!
Long live our socialist government!
- Good morning.
You could not sleep
due to the noise, no?
Yes.
Students organize a protest
to support the government.
What nice! Early on Sunday morning,
as everyone is asleep.
It's noon Aynur!
It's not so early.
- What time is it?
- It's near 1 pm.
- Is the tea ready?
- It's ready, but...
The homeowner will be
at the door in a minute.
Let's see him coming!
Let's see, but did you find the rent?
You said you will
borrow from Fikret, did you?
No, I did not.
Did not, the man comes to what will?
We will give nothing!
- What does it mean?
- That is it!
What we paid until today is enough!
- Are you crazy?
- No, I am not.
- So?
- The government published a decree.
We don't have to pay more than half
of our income to somebody as rent.
What the hell is this? This man doesn't
do anything apart from collecting rents!
What should he do? This is his house;
Should he donate this to us?
All these houses are him, yes, Aynur?
How can a man have 8 houses?
How can a man,
who did not work for time...
have 8 houses?
If you work,
if are awake, you can have.
Don't I work?
People like you pay rents
for their whole life, like this...
I asked you, don't I work?
You work, actually you work hard.
But this doesn't help.
It doesn't help as I pay more than
half of my income to this man as rent!
What is that, I won't pay any rent!
OK than, we will be
homeless after this age...
Why will we become homeless Aynur?
What are you talking about
Levent, for the God's sake?
- We will get on the his house, yes?
- We don't get on anyone's house.
We need a house;
And here is a house.
This man has 7 more houses!
Should we seize on his
house because he has 7 more?
We don't seize anything!
Until today,
rulers were on their side.
Today, some people consider us...
work for us.
- Communists!
- Yes, communists.
Levent, pull you together, please!
We can't find a new house
easily in such winter.
We will just be left
homeless after this age...
You see, you said the same thing!
We have worked for
35 years and we depend...
on two words of the house owner!
Just two syllables! If he says "get
out", we are thrown to the street.
Is this just, Aynur?
Can you bear this?
This is his house; he says get out,
or enter; he says what he wants.
I hope he won't say "get out"
because we delayed to pay the rent.
What hope?
I don't hope anything anymore.
What's this!
Hope this, hope that!
Look to the owner, look to the boss!
I won't hope anything anymore!
So, you don't pay, I don'pay,
the other doesn't pay.
How will this man live?
He will work!
He will work once!
He will produce,
maybe for the first time in his life!
Also, he won't become homeless.
Nobody gets the house he lives in!
He has the guarantee to find a job.
Until today, their government
did nothing for us.
But, look, ours doesn't leave
neither him homeless nor us.
Ooo, communists became ours, no?
So, who are ours?
I see, for the first time in my life,
that a government does something for us.
For the last two months I get on
the metro, the busess freely.
For the first time in 12 years,
I could find a proper gift to you.
- You say the sweater?
- Yes.
We you so annoyed because
you couldn't buy something to me?
Of course I was.
You gave your life to me. You dedicated
your beauty, your compassion.
I couldn't give you anything
because I fed these parasites...
He came Levent.
Please tell that we will pay
in a couple of days. Don't be crazy.
Don't worry.
- Selamun Aleyküm.
- What do you want?
- I said selamün aleyküm.
- Aleyküm selam! What do you want?
You can expect what I want;
I came to get the rent.
What rent are you talking about?
There is no rent.
I talk about rent of this house,
that you live in.
It seems you don't
know what's going on?
I don't pay rent anymore.
How come? What do you
mean "what's going on"?
What are you talking about?
What I am talking about? I will show
you what I'm talking about.
Seven: Everyone is owner
of the house he lives in.
People living in houses improper to
health and dignity of human...
being will move to new houses
in the one-year period.
Electricity, water and natural
gas bills will be free from now on.
Basic needs will be met
freely under state guarantee.
What does it say? Everyone is the
owner of the house he lives in.
So, I'm the owner of this house.
I don't pay any rent.
You trust in these communists,
but you will regret this!
I actually regret paying
rent to you for years submissively!
Go along, go!
OK, OK. You believe in those,
we will see your end?
You will see how I will throw
you out of my house!
Do what you can do!
Do you think I will just leave
this house to you? You will see!
- Come, I will make a coffee for you.
- OK.
Friends! Friends!
This factory is nationalized
by the socialist government.
Your former boss doesn't have any...
right or authority
on this factory anymore.
All rights related to this factory
belong to the socialist government...
which means you.
A contact meeting will
be held this evening and...
everyone is supposed to participate.
More power to all of us.
Rıza Master, would they
decrease our wages, do you think?
We will learn in the evening.
Mind your own business,
don't think about this.
Brother Rıza, what will happen?
They said you have the rights...
How should I know Suat, we are going, we
will learn what rights they talk about?
So, what will happen to bosses,
brother?
God, you did everything for yourself,
you worry about the bosses!
Do you think anyone will be fired?
Nihat and others were anxious today.
They were
members to rightist trade
union before, you know...
Don't worry, they will not suffer.
They are men for all seasons.
They will just shift to the
other trade union...
Brother, if I am fired,
it would be a disaster...
Just before the wedding...
I already have no money.
These were saying that
unemployment is banned;
It is written on the
papers they distributed...
Brother, should they
fire us first and put
us in jail because we are unemployed?
Get along with you!
Come!
Until today, we worked
for 10-15 hours a day.
Yet we could not survive on
our wges until the end of the month.
So, what we worked for?
To produce the cars
that we can never drive...
toys that we can never
buy for our children...
clothes that we can only
see in the shop windows.
Bosses get richer and
richer as we produced.
They bought new machines.
They enlarged their factories.
In each new machine...
each new factory
there is our labour...
our blood,
our children's stolen future.
Today, here, and in thousands
of factories all around the country...
production is not for bosses anymore.
That is what nationalization
of factories means.
Nationalization is transition
of factories to you,
to the producers, to workers...
to their real owners.
All other factories belong to
ourworker brothers from now on.
Machines in the factories we work in,
the goods we produce, all belong to us.
So, we will work as before.
Of course we will continue to produce.
We will continue working
heavily and sweating.
But there is a difference:
Things we produce...
won't be used to enhance
the wealth of others!
For example, our labour
won't be used by
the bosses to train
their children abroad.
We will work in our factories,
not theirs!
We won't work for their interest...
but we will work for millions
of workers like us!
This means, friends...
from now on, any profit
that is generated
from the sale of our products...
will be used for only
and only our interests.
For betterworking periods...
for decreasing unemployment...
for education of our children...
for quality health service...
for improving ourselves.
Well, will there be any dismissal
or reduction in wages?
I hope we won't be down
with our children...
No, from now on...
all shift bells will ring
as a symbol of your future...
your children's future
ourworker brothers' future.
Don't worry to be unemployed.
One of the leading
responsibilities...
of the socialist government is to...
end the unemployment.
Don't think how you should
survive till the end of
month; don't worry for
your children's education.
Henceforth, any bread in this
country belongs to the producers...
belongs to you!
From now on, factories...
schools, roads, and bread and books,
anything you see, belong to you!
Long live our socialist revolution!
Long live our socialist republic!
What is the matter?
- They are nationalizing the factory.
- How come?
The factory is seized.
It will be operated
by the state from now on.
- It's good or bad?
- I don't know
I'm so confused.
At least, you will
get your wages regularly.
It won't be like you are paid for three
months and work free for two...
- We will wait and see.
- Yes, yes.
Actually, I also don't think
that it will be worse.
So, what is the matter?
You look so bemused...
This is the first time
I entered into this
restaurant, which I passed
by everyday for 20 years!
A very urgent
document has arrived, sir.
Let's see, what this
urgent document is.
- Yes, sir.
That's it!
- That's what I was waiting for!
- Sir?
Muster will be in 10 minutes.
You gather the soldiers, I'm coming.
Yes, sir.
At ease!
Shun!
Attention!
The squad is ready for
your commands and views
with 120 soldiers, 4
officers, 6 sergeants, sir!
- Thank you, captain.
- Thanks.
This command will be read to everyone
and reading will be signed.
Signed.
To Afghanistan Turkish
Mission Commandership...
- Stop Levent!
- Yes, sir.
- Sinan! - Sinan Acıoğlu,
Kahramanmaraş, your commands sir.
- You get this command and read it to
your commanders and friends. - Yes, sir.
It is announced to all
our soldiers who do
their military service
away from the country:
1- A revolution succeeded
in our country; a socialist
government of workers,
of people is formed.
2- Membership to NATO
and all other military
partnerships are
cancelled as a result...
of the socialist government in
parallel to popular support and demand.
3- All military units sent to abroad
by open or collusive agreements...
will be returned
to the country urgently.
4- All soldiers will
follow this order of
return urgently, regardless
of rank and post.
5- Our soldiers will not participate
in any NATO operations...
as from the date
this order is published.
Any order or directions
by NATO or US Military
forces are invalid grade
of any soldier...
that follow this orders will be
cancelled by one of his subordinates.
The chain of command will
be taken over by this subordinate.
All units and soldiers will be
charged in the new form and chain
of command of the Military Services
after they return to the country.
Your immediate attention
to this matter is appreciated.
Assembly of People's Representatives,
Military Committee.
Thank you.
- Is it understood, Murat.
- Yes, sir.
- Is it understood Recep?
So, what will we do Abdullah?
We're going to back
to our country sir.
Well.
- Captain!
- Yes, sir.
We should immediately start
the preparations for return.
Yes, sir.
Sevgi!
Get the door, who has come?
Move in, bastard, move!
Go there! Go there!
Turn your face!
Turb your face, bastard!
Don't look!
Welcome.
Thank you, hope to see you again.
In today's meeting of
Revolutionary Education Council...
right of education in
mother-language is debated.
It's said that the efforts to place the
right of education in mother language...
in our popular education system are
intensified and the
principle of right of...
education in mother language, based
on the refusal of the discriminatory...
and denialist policies of the
former system will be in short time...
Yıldırım Karakaş, the assistant
professor of Istanbul University...
Faculty of Political Sciences
and author, is assassinated...
Students and friends
of professor Yıldırım
are continuing to arrive to his house.
They filled the front of the
house with candles and flowers...
Police sketch prepared according
to the witnesses' statements are...
distributed to the
press a few minuted ago...
Aleyküm selam.
Chief, are you?
Yes, thank you.
I'm in the hotel, I'll go out.
Chief, this, this...
this suitcase is still in the hotel,
nobody came to get this.
It can create problem
if I carry this...
Good, OK. OK. Of course.
God bless you, too. Al right.
Would drink something?
Sorry, would you drink something?
I said would you drink something?
What do you say?
I asked you if you
want something to drink.
Give me beer.
I'm here to take you to the chief.
Yes, where is the chief.
Really I don't know this;
Ask him to those guys if you want!
Shit!
Catch him!
Walk!
Move up.
We brought the man, brother.
I'm coming.
Isn't there any hanging lamp?
- No.
- Something like hanger?
- Why did you kill professor Yıldırım?
- I didn't kill anyone.
Why do you look at me?
Should I be scared of you?
Will you beat me, ha? Come, hit me.
Come.
Why do you look in that way?
These are book of professor Yıldırım,
who you killed in his house.
He has written 18 books, certainly.
Maybe they killed your precious
professor because of that...
because of what he has written.
You fired 2 bullets to the professor.
The man who has written
18 books is dead...
the man who fired
2 bullets to him is alive.
I didn't shut anybody, brother.
You are on the wrong way.
Have you read
18 books in your life, ha?
No, I didn't.
Will you put me in jail because
I didn't read books?
Listen, my brother...
I didn't kill anyone;
But God bless him, whoever killed him!
He must be a patriot...
a brave man so killed this guy.
What did professor Yıldırım
do to deserve to be killed?
He must be just like you,
I mean communist.
You think...
that your trashy system...
will last long but...
patriot children of this
country are not dead yet.
They will...
reverse the system you found now.
- From which schools you graduated?
- It's none of your business.
Why didn't you go to school
after the primary schools?
Because we didn't have
money to go to schools;
We found a job and
worked, is this wrong?
- Do you have a brother or sister?
- No, no...
Your sister...
was one of the best students
of professor Yıldırım, who you killed.
Also, she was a member to the party.
Now she is studying
in a second university.
She's studying in a second university,
thanks to socialism.
You graduated from the
primary school hardly...
whereas your sister is studying in a
second university, thanks to socialism.
Meral will be very surprised now!
Should she be upset
for her brother...
or her professor
killed by her brother?
I didn't kill anyone;
But God bless who did this!
Listen, Muammer.
These socialist who you
hate got rid of all...
American bases in this county,
which you claim you love.
Those socialists saved this country
from being slave soldiers of NATO.
These socialist you look
forward to kill saved...
these people from
exploitation of bosses.
They made people happy.
How do you love your country,
Muammer?
You kill the beloved
figured of this society, Muammer.
Is this patriotism?
Yes?
What do you want?
Which system will you reverse?
Do you want to be slave of US again?
Why do you serve to US, Muammer, why?
Do you want people die at the
doors of hospitals again?
Do you want them work for
14-15 hours a day?
Is this patriotism, Muammer?
Is this?
Do you want people
die of hungerwhile...
some pack their stomachs?
Do you?
Do you want our children bring up...
in barracks while
others live in residences?
Answer, Muammer, say what you want!
Listen, Muammer.
Now I will leave this paper...
and pencil to you.
You will give me...
the names of who made you do this...
who made you fire that gun...
who made you carry this suitcase...
who made you
kill your sister's professor.
You will give these names...
so the country will not turn
to a burial ground again!
You are an excellent liar my brother.
Bravo!
My sister has no business
with such organization...
Muammer.
You should at least once think
about protecting your sister...
rather than protecting
those who made you a killer...
Now, if it is right what's
written in this document...
I think, you should protect this...
because the first thing I do when...
I get out of here
will be making this.
Brother, it's 7 pm,
I've got to bring...
Give.
- What's this?
- Your dinner!
Enjoy your meal.
I'll ask something.
When is the breakfast?
At eight...
Good evening dear audience.
We have again a precious guest
this evening in "Political Diary".
Minister of Education Gamze Kosar,
one of the youngest members...
of the new revolutionary government.
- Welcome dear minister.
- Thank you.
I want to draw
attention to a current issue...
without losing time.
One of the most important
actions is seems...
to be making education free.
However, some people object
to these free education policy.
These objections include the claim
that the revolutionary government...
seized the right
of choice of people and...
deprived them
of many opportunities...
that were available before
with this free education action.
So, dear minister, how do you
assess these criticisms?
Yes, it is certainly true
that we deprived some...
people of many
opportunities and chances!
We deprived the owners of private
schools and private institutions...
of the opportunity to rub the
people and students!
We deprived some
people of the privilege...
to be educated just...
because they have money!
And we deprive the poor students of the
"privilege" to be not educated and...
to be unemployed just because
they do not have money!
Don't suppose that people...
people want back these
"opportunities"...
like paying enrollment deposits
and dues to schools...
or paying a big share of income...
to private institutions
and moreover...
being very far away
from getting a modern and...
scientific education service.
What you mention is indeed
only the objections of some...
privileged classes who don't
want to lose these privileges...
that they had due to their wealth.
And this is not a subject
that we will discuss on.
As we mention constantly,
the remaning...
private schools will be publicized
in the near future and...
private education
will totally be terminated.
The socialist government will
survive with your support!
Now you have the power!
You are the government!
You save your government!
We end the rule of money!
We embed private education and...
private health to the history!
We take back everything
they seized...
we take back our schools,
our hospitals...
our roads, our rivers!
The socialst government
ends the rule of pillage.
We embed poverty,
hunger and slavery to the history!
Murat, my son!
Your bills...
Yes, what is the matter?
Do your bills come?
Tövbe estağfurullah tövbe!
At this time of the night!
I want to...
ask something.
Yes, my aunt?
My bills don't come for some days...
They won't.
We don't send bills anymore.
How come?
Why don't you send my bills?
We don't send to anyone, my aunt.
From now on, electricity,
water and natural gas are free.
So, bills won't come anymore?
No, they won't; and you will not get
tired to come here and pay your bills.
What will I do?
Committee are calling you!
Committees are calling to
inclue more people...
to organize more tightly...
to get up against fascist crews...
imperialist and their collaborators.
Listen to the raising...
voice of the revolution...
for the future of children...
for our forests, waters,
lands and our bread!
Struggle against capitalists,
imperialists, fascists is continuing.
Workers are continuing their struggle...
organizing in committees.
The struggle continues!
And it will continue
until this country...
belongs to its real owners,
to workers...
to producers!
Comrade!
Selamün aleyküm!
Comrades, what is going on here?
- They are shutting, brother.
- They are shutting?
So, what...
what will be built here?
I am not sure brother, but they say
a Community Centre will be built.
Community centre?
Ohh, this will be very nice, very nice!
More power to you!
- Where are you going?
- I am going to the dentist.
- I will be back in the afternoon.
- OK.
- More power to you, youngsters!
- Thank you, brother.
Long live workers' and
peasants' government!
Very nice, very nice!
- What are you doing here?
- We are waiting for the service bus.
We are going to police office.
Why do you look so sour?
Grim-looking!
Smile.
Or I'll report you.
No of fence, I should report you.
Smile a little.
Don't forget. Please come regularly.
Get well soon.
Thank you. Have a nice day.
- Hello.
- Welcome.
I want to have my teeth examined.
- OK. May I have your ID?
- ID.
OK. You got to second floor.
I am doing your registry...
my friends will call you.
- What if they don't?
- Don't worry, they will.
OK, but, if they don't?
If they don't, you come to me.
They will call...
- Neşet Gülerce.
- I'm here.
Come in, the doctor
is waiting for you.
Hi.
- Sit down there.
- Here?
Yes.
What is your problem?
- My theet.
- What is wrong with your teeth?
They ache.
- How long?
- For 30 years.
Why didn't you come for such years?
I am here.
You said your teeth
ache for 30 years; I am
asking why didn't you
come for such period?
I came once;
They filled my tooth.
- So?
- They...
removed the filling because
I couldn't pay the money!
Let's see your teeth.
Mr. Doctor,
I love toothpaste ads.
I always watch them, I mean.
I want to have pearly white teeth.
I want to...
laugh pearly white, I mean.
If you used that
toothpaste for once...
Mr. Doctor...
we used to be deprived
of underpants before the revolution!
How could we buy toothbrush,
toothpaste?
Thank god the revolution
happened so I am here.
From now on, I promise, I will come
to you every 6 months for my teeth.
What a chance!
Open your month.
Open it more, open.
How are my teeth?
You forget about the revolution.
It will take wrong...
I'm prescribing a medicine.
Come here 15 days later.
We're going to x-ray your
teeth and see again.
Doctor...
I am 59 years old.
I am worker for 30 years.
How long will I live!
Just look at my teeth,
fix it and I will go.
I read the rights
of patients while waiting.
Iso, you said
"forget the revolution" blah blah...
I will report you.
Don't believe all the words you read.
Doctor;
I want to change my doctor.
- OK! Go to another doctor, go!
- No.
I'm staying here, you're going!
- Brother, are you insane?
- Get out! I'm patient.
Neşet Bey.
Another doctor will
be here in five minutes.
Good!
Now I really believe that
there is a revolution!