1942.
The South Pacific.
The New Year finds USS Enterprise
and her crew of 2000 men
preparing to deliver
greetings to the Japanese
in the form of
torpedo bombers and fighter planes.
With last month's attack
on Pearl Harbor still fresh
in the minds of these American aviators
that revenge is a dish best served...
Piping hot!
Chief, this is Aldrich.
Uh, I'm losing her on the Hayrake.
Come on. Where you going?
Chief, I've lost the beacon, over.
Are we close, Chief?
I'll give him a tap.
Maybe his comm is down.
Chief?
Can you hear us, over?
Loud and clear, boys.
Just waiting for this wind
to tell me which direction
she wants to blow.
Pastula, take another drift
sight. That's not how I'm
reading those wave tops.
Yes, Chief.
15 degrees.
Same read as the outbound, Chief.
If that's correct
she's off to the east.
I had her west.
I'm taking her east.
6- Tare-14 requesting
an inbound bearing, over?
Chief, we've broken radio silence!
Affirmative.
We need a bearing.
Confirm you're on 79.
Seven-niner confirmed.
I reckon we're still too far out.
Well, keep trying.
Blue Base, this is 6-Tare-14.
Do you read?
Come in, Blue Base.
Over.
Chief?
Go.
On the MF.
I heard Jap talk.
I pulled the plug.
Roger that. Let's go
silent on Morse.
Silent on Morse, affirmative.
How are we on fuel, Chief?
Low.
Pastula, we need to make
altitude. Drop the ordnance.
Aye-aye, Chief.
Bombs away.
Aldrich
hit that MF.
But the Japs, Chief.
Do it!
Blue Base
this is 6-Tare-14.
Do you read? 6-Tare-14
to Blue Base. Come in,
Blue Base, over.
Like hell she's east.
Enterprise, this is 6-Tare-14.
Do you read?
Get on it, Aldrich!
I'm on it.
We're out of range.
Boys...
before we run out of fuel.
Snug up your vests
and stand by for a
water landing. Understood?
Damn!
Affirmative, Chief.
Pastula?
Aldrich, gather the
flares, the smoke candles
and the first aid kit.
We're going to need the flashlights.
Pastula, grab the rations and the water
and ready the life raft.
And keep your heads, boys.
Pass this back.
Got it.
Coming through.
Grab a parachute!
A parachute?
Prepare to ditch.
Brace for impact!
Ahhh!
Pastula!
Here, chief.
Aldrich!
Here!
Step lively, boys!
C'mon!
Chief!
Ahh!
Oh, no!
Come here.
Damn thing won't inflate!
Ahh!
The valve is jammed!
Train that beam.
Unship your weapons.
They're dragging us down.
I can't get it!
There goes mine!
Mine too.
That makes a difference.
This...
Damn thing.
There it goes!
It's too heavy to lift!
Maybe if we-
Aldrich!
If you get trapped under there again
just deflate the vest a little bit.
Swim down and out.
Understood?
I can't swim much.
You're kidding.
You?
Not really, Chief.
Oh!
For crying out-
Okay.
This is gonna be hard to
turn over in these swells.
If we take off our vests
string 'em together, tie one on here
and throw the other across
then we go around and pull.
Good idea.
Except neither one of you can swim.
Just have to hold tight to the hand rail.
Real tight.
Okay, let's give it a go.
Here.
Alright.
Okay, go around and I'll toss it over.
Okay. Ready?
Yeah.
Here it comes!
You got it?
Alright we got it.
Alright, get a grip.
Now heave like you mean it!
One, two, three!
Hold her down.
I'll go around the other side and climb in.
Kippers in a can got more space.
Let's try laying athwart.
Aldrich...
when I was on deck. Didn't
get a good look at you.
Harold Dixon.
Gene Aldrich.
You'll get a gander in the morning, Chief.
I'm sure I'll be here.
Pastula.
Is that Italian?
Polish, Chief.
I've made a couple of hops with you before.
Oh, yeah?
I don't remember.
We'll be picked up come morning.
You reckon, Chief?
That's what I'm hoping.
Hoping?
Come early morning, they'll be
on us like an old hound dog.
It's so damn hot inside that plane.
It's freezing out here.
Cock-a-doodle-doo, boys.
Well, we made it.
I worried she wouldn't keep us afloat
but she's still ship-shape.
Thank God.
Gene Aldrich.
Now I know you.
I couldn't put a face to the name.
In all my glory, Chief.
Who's up for a fresh cup of coffee?
Henree!
Time to put on the pot.
Yeah.
Thanks, Henry.
'Henry'. Why Henry?
Oh, it's
that show, you know, off the radio!
Henree!
Henry Aldrich!
Nah. Never heard of it.
You were gonna land in the
drink, I thought 'Boy...
Thought I couldn't land her, huh?
Wasn't that some flying!
I mean he just laid her right down.
Yeah, he sure did.
You know, Aldrich
I've been wondering...
I don't understand how you
couldn't raise that carrier.
We couldn't have been more than 20 miles out
at one point.
Even at 40
you should've caught something, right?
You tell me, Chief.
How far out were we?
We should keep our eyes peeled.
Right?
Everybody take a point.
We need to cover 360.
Good visibility.
Yeah, they'll check every
square mile out here.
It'll take a while, but
they'll do it, won't they?
Even if it takes all day
or into the morrow.
Yep.
Could take most of a day.
They'll do a box out to 50.
Even a 100.
They've got the viz.
Divide that by the number of planes.
Heck
it's likely to be
this morning.
Maybe we'll get a real
breakfast, huh, Chief?
You figure we'll see 'em first
or hear 'em?
Shh.
See that speck?
That's a bird.
It ain't moving its wings.
Wait...
That's something, all right.
Steady on her course, whatever-
It's one of ours!
Hey!
Get down!
Got plenty of time to drown.
I think it's an SPD.
She's on a bearing.
About 140 knots.
Half a mile out.
Pastula, grab the parachute.
Spread it on the water.
Chief?
No parachute.
Aldrich, how about those flares?
I couldn't hold 'em, Chief.
Well, wave something!
Hey!
Look down here!
What are you, blind?
Sun's behind you.
Check your three o'clock!
Down here!
Hey!
Hey! Over here!
Down here!
Hey!
Look here!
Come on.
Where you going?
No-no-no. Where-
Hey!
We're over here.
Come on!
Hey!
We're here.
That was our one and only chance.
What?
That was our search.
What do you mean?
They can't just leave us here!
Could be he saw us,
he's goin' back for help.
Why didn't he break course?
Because he's on a box search
is why. Next
pass he'll be
out of sight.
Maybe there'll be more
planes double-checking.
Or ships.
What the hell are they
telling you in boot camp?
We are at war, Aldrich.
We're in the vicinity of enemy naval forces.
We get one quick look at best.
Like you said, there's a procedure.
Alright.
No parachute
or flares.
I don't suppose the chart
board made it either?
Affirmative.
First aid kit?
Everything's gone, Chief.
Including the rations and water.
Oh, God.
I don't get it.
I gave the orders in plenty of time
so I could get busy with the landing
and we have no food and no water?!
We were pretty busy not drownin'!
How are we gonna survive
out here with no water?
Okay, coming aft.
Listen up, lads.
This raft is a vessel
of the United States
Navy, and I am her Captain.
As such, I will be giving the orders
and you will be taking them.
Are we clear?
Aye-aye, Chief.
Aldrich?
Crystal, Chief.
Alright.
Let's take an inventory.
Pockets. Everything.
Pile it on the shirt.
Got two magazines.
I got my pocket knife.
Keep that in your pocket!
The last thing we need
is a hole in this raft.
Pair of pliers.
A bit of wire.
Some cord. Maybe
about 20 feet.
Here's a whistle.
Aldrich.
Rubber cement fluid.
Any patching material in there?
Yeah.
Huh.
Look at this!
We can use it if we see another plane.
Wish we would've found that earlier.
Huh. And a
water bag!
Aha!
It's empty.
That's all she's got, chief.
No fold-up oars under that thwart, Aldrich?
Negative.
Don't forget about the handrail.
That's about 25 feet of nylon.
Yeah, and we've got these two life vests.
No oars.
No flashlights.
No map.
No food. No water.
Chronometers?
Negative.
No.
But if she stays afloat
at least I can figure
her speed and distance.
She looks practically new.
That's good.
Ah, here.
Manufactured
11-30-37.
That's four years old.
Plus some.
Boys, we should minimize
the wear on the fabric.
Shoes.
There's not much room.
On or off, they're liable to scuff.
I say we deep six 'em.
They say it's five miles deep out here.
That's impossible.
Chief?
I'm thinkin'...
Maybe one of us should keep 'em.
If we make land
somebody's going to need to walk.
Makes sense.
Hey.
I've still got this.
For a boy who can't swim
you were a fool to keep it.
Well
couldn't get rawhide loose.
But
you never know.
It might come in handy.
Youngstown, Ohio.
You?
Sikeston, Missouri.
Sikeston?
Where's that?
Nowhere.
Pastula
Take another drift sight.
That's not how I'm reading those wave tops.
Yes, Chief.
15 degrees.
Same read as the outbound, Chief.
What?
If that's correct then she's
east. I had her west.
Aldrich?
Not a peep on the Hayrake.
I reckon you've flown us to
the middle of nowhere, Chief.
We're lost!
Say again, Aldrich?
Aldrich!
That's the craziest thing I've ever heard.
That you have never had
a Kentucky Hot Brown?
So you're not allowed to eat
food from neighboring states?
No.
Glad I don't live in Ohio.
Ham and cheese.
Now you're talking.
I must of made a 1000 of those
in the Civilian Conservation Corps.
The C's?
Me too. I cooked for
a hundred fellas.
Two cooks and no food.
So, how'd you end up Navy?
Well
a few too many mouths to feed at home.
My mother thought I could
become more disciplined.
Hm!
Imagine her disappointment.
And I was ready for an adventure
so I enlisted.
Well, you sure got an adventure!
Yeah. If my mother
could see me now.
Hm.
I wanna make it a career and
see the worid.
Career navy?
Good for you, son.
In these troubled times
there is no higher calling.
You think it's possible we
get seen at night, Chief?
Wouldn't rule it out.
This yellow raft, moonlight might-
Well
no full moon tonight.
We'll schedule a watch
anyway. Four on, eight off.
Who wants first up?
I'll take it.
I can't sleep anyhow.
Alright.
I'll take second watch, Pastula.
Okay, chief.
Told me to rouse you up.
Reckon it's been about four hours.
See anything?
Just ocean.
Did you have anything to drink yet, Aldrich?
Drink?
What?
Oh, you gotta be kidding me, Chief!
Oh, tha-
That's just wonderful.
Oh.
Watch?
Nothing.
Pretty steady breeze though.
Henree!
Time to put on the pot.
How long's the breeze been up?
Uh, an hour, maybe.
Same direction?
Uh-huh.
Chief?
Pastula.
Where are we?
1900 miles to Hawaii.
Samoa's a 1000.
South America, 6000 at least.
That's a lot of zeroes.
But we are moving.
Flat bottom craft like this will sail
along smartly
and we've been getting some 12 knot winds.
A six-knot wind will give us a drift of one.
I bet we can get a two point five out of 12.
Although she sure does like
to change her mind though.
So Hawaii.
Yup.
How come you didn't point that way?
Dead ahead?
The way the wind's blowin' us now.
The Phoenix Islands.
The Gilberts.
Tarawa.
600 miles or less.
Tarawa?
Aren't there Jap subs out there?
Great.
Jap army's crawling all
over those islands right now.
What happens if we land on a Jap island?
Or a sub finds us?
There could be a sub
underneath us right now.
We would certainly be a prize.
But we have a chance.
All we need is some favorable winds
There are islands between
us and Samoa. 600 miles away.
Two knots or so...
I'd say a couple of weeks,
Could be a lot more
accurate if I had my chart.
We'll starve to death first!
Well...
Plenty of fish in the sea, right?
If only I had a hook and a line.
Alright, Aldrich.
There's your line.
Some braided cord in that pocket.
Huh. And here.
Maybe if I can get one
of these magazines open
we can use one of those springs as a hook.
That could work just fine.
Alright.
You know what I could go for right now?
Come on.
Fish fry.
A nice deep-fried basket of cod.
A side of slaw and some potato salad.
Whole thing smothered in cheese.
Really?
Hey, there ain't nothing
that can't be improved
with a good slab of cheese.
There you go.
Alright.
How's that?
That ain't half bad.
Need a sinker.
Kinda looks like a piece of meat.
Well...
let's cast her off, alright.
Watch your eyes, there she goes!
Huh.
Whoa! That
was quick!
Come on, gimme a hand with this!
- Alright.
- Come here.
That's the way, boys!
Guess something down
there's hungrier than us.
Sweet Mary.
Here.
Put this on your head.
Suit yourself.
Hey!
What is it?
It's nothing.
For a second there I thought
I might be in line for a medal.
The Navy Cross or something.
Then I realized there's not much
heroic about sitting in a raft and
starving to death.
Navy Cross...
We'll be lucky if we
don't get charged the cost
of a new plane.
Aw, heck.
It isn't anybody's fault, right?
Perfectly good torpedo
bomber lying on the bottom
of the ocean.
Sounds like it's got to be somebody's fault.
Damn fish aren't biting.
Whoa, whoa.
Where are you going?
There ain't no fish.
Which means there ain't no food.
I can't take the heat no more.
Yahhh!
Come on in, boys!
Water's fine!
No, no, one at a time.
It's 2,000 to Hawaii, you said?
Don't get too far, Aldrich.
This boat's moving, you know!
Real live bait out there now, huh, Chief?
That's another problem.
Sharks?
I don't know if they'd attack.
I've heard arguments both ways.
Hey, Gene!
Chief's wondering about sharks.
Ah, jeez!
Where are you going?
Just a few more
strokes, Aldrich.
We need to
stay with the raft.
I think if we hang onto
the sides we'll be safe.
The others can stand guard.
It did get the blood pumpin', though.
Pastula? You're next.
No, thanks.
That's why you gotta do it last.
Because if you broil
it for too long, well...
And if you go too short,
it's not gonna melt evenly.
It's beautiful, isn't it?
It'd be better if we could eat it.
I was doing alright, see?
I didn't expect no A.
This the mechanic's course?
No, it was another one.
Oh.
I thought I ought to get a B or
anyways a C and that
would've been all right.
You know, I never really cared
about making the best marks
in school, as long as I learned the stuff.
Uh-hm.
And I had this course down good.
When I saw that report card
and saw that big shiny F
I just said the hell with this bull crap.
Excuse my language.
So what did you do?
I just walked out of school and
And you had that course
down good, you reckon?
You bet I did!
But I'm assuming you aced
that mechanic's course.
Ah, did well enough, Chief.
So you could
dismantle and reassemble a drift sight
much less take a reading on one.
Yeah, guess I could.
Yeah?
Just strange, that's all.
I had us headed west.
Your sighting corrected us east
You asked for confirmation
and he gave it you.
I'm discussing this with
my bombardier, Aldrich.
I know you confirmed it.
I'm just saying, it's strange, that's all.
Okay, Chief.
Strange alright.
Henree!
Put on the pot!
Pastula?
Ain't there a rule
a guy can have a handful and still be okay?
Sucks the water right out
of your brains, they say.
Coming up on 120 hours.
Five days, not a sip.
How come we ain't dead?
We've been soaking ourselves
not moving around too much.
A couple shoes full
of the yellow stuff.
While it lasted.
Not even a rudder.
But you know where you want us to go.
Right, Chief?
I know, but to calculate-
Ahh!
Chief?
A pencil
A pencil?
A gol' darned ever-lovin' pencil!
You see that?
I can make a chart!
Pastula
you said east
two to three knots
on your watch, huh?
Uh-huh.
Aldrich
more like southeast
two to three?
Yeah. Affirmative.
Okay then.
Here we are
by dead reckoning.
But where we headed?
With luck, right here.
There's a chain of 'em to our south-west.
Closest friendly land
in the Pacific.
Now if this favorable wind
will just push us there.
What if it just keeps shifting, Chief?
Chart don't take us nowhere.
Unless...
Unless we can hold our
position in the headwind.
Aldrich!
Untie the handrail.
Pastula
I need you to take some of that wire
and you make a frame
to keep this from folding up in the water.
Can you do it?
You bet chief.
Leave one end tied.
Okay.
Okay, good.
Here, hold him up.
Hold him up.
Perfect!
That, sailors
is a sea anchor.
We may not be able to control the wind
but we can avoid being blown the wrong way.
Huh!
That's nice work, Chief.
Now I'll be yelling
Henree!
Put on the brake!
Whoo! Look at 'er
grab that water!
Hey, Tony, look!
I'll be danged if I don't see
a tear of joy on old Chief!
He said we were too dried up for that.
Why, I do believe you're right.
Really? You
saw a tear?
Okay, let off the brake!
Men, it isn't easy.
But it might be worse.
If we can keep this wind
and just get a little rain.
Well
it never hurt to ask.
Dear Lord
Gene!
The only prayers I know are in Polish.
I hadn't marked you for
a church-going man, Aldrich.
I'm sorry to say I'm not much of one.
That's alright.
Just follow my lead.
Dear Lord
we know we ain't always done right by you.
We're askin' for a little help here
during this trial.
If it so pleases you.
Uh...
And, Lord
watch over
all the men back on our ship.
And all the ships at sea
including this one.
Tony?
Dear God
I'll go along with what the other guys said
but mostly
we need some rain, Lord.
Rain, dear Lord.
Please, rain.
Please.
Amen.
Oh, come on!
Give him a second.
He's got to cook it up.
Or maybe...
That's a good one.
Hey, Chief.
You got one?
Uh...
Big finish!
What's wrong?
Nothing.
Hey...
Hey! Hey!
Battle stations boys!
We've got precipitation!
I've got the bag.
Here it comes.
Get as much as you can!
Looks like your prayers worked, Aldrich!
You're going to have to thank Sunday School
at First Baptist Church, Chief!
C'mon you stupid fish.
Haven't you ever seen a fishing line before?
A week of nothing.
By golly, Aldrich, you are
the most patient fisherman
I've ever seen.
Where I come from
you don't catch, you don't eat.
Just going about this
the wrong way, that's all.
Knife in your pocket like I told you.
If you put a hole in this raft...
If we don't eat soon
we might just as well, Chief.
Aldrich
you stow that knife.
That's an order!
If you don't catch
you don't eat.
Aldrich...
I hit one!
Stop it!
I hit the raft!
God! You idiot!
Don't move.
I'll get the cement!
It ain't the raft, Chief!
Oh, shit!
Pastula!
Ahhhhh!
Don't let him go!
I think I got it.
Nice work, Pastula.
Atta boy, Tony.
It fell out of the sky.
A shark just fell out of the sky.
Oh!
Ah, geez!
Looks like she just had dinner!
We've got bait for another day or two.
Probably some for an extra meal as well.
The salt will keep it.
How far we got to those islands, Chief?
According to the chart
roughly 390.
Wind's out of the northeast
which is just right for us.
And if she switches on us, we just
throw on the brake.
No backsliding.
We're going home.
And boy will my wife be sore.
Damn. I thought he was
only married to the Navy.
Neither of you boys are married?
Nope.
I got a girl back in Youngstown.
Irene.
Not me.
But...
I'd like to someday.
Hey, I got a sister.
You two would get along.
No kidding.
What's she like?
I don't know.
People say she's like me.
It's not much
of an advertisement
Pastula.
She don't look like me.
She's, you know, easy to get along with.
And a lot prettier than me.
Describe her to me.
Really?
Yeah, really.
Five-four.
She's got
long brown hair
green eyes.
This is kind of weird, Gene.
Keep goin'.
She's a wiz in the kitchen.
She likes to read.
She wears
clothes
She wears clothes?
Well, I should certainly hope so.
Clothes are not a requirement in my book.
Hey!
That's my sister you're talking about!
And when we get through this
I'll thank you for setting me up with her.
She sounds lovely.
Uhh!
We got company.
Must be all the blood in the water.
I've heard they can smell it for miles.
What do we do?
Well, for starters
I say we cancel the swimming program.
Ah! Ah! Ah!
What's the matter?!
I got bit!
Cease fire!
CEASE FIRE!
Let me see, let me see.
Oh, geez.
Three teeth marks at least.
One nail's ripped off.
Oh, Gene.
Here, Chief.
Well, I've heard of fishing by hand
but that's ridiculous!
We'll get a better look
at it in the morning.
- Keep pressure on it.
- Okay.
What do they call us, Chief?
What?
"Missing in action" or
what?
Lost at sea.
That's how they carried us.
No trace of aircraft or personnel was found.
Our father
who art in heaven
hallowed by thy name.
Thy kingdom come
thy will be done
on earth...
Tony.
Give me the gun.
Huh?
Give it to me.
Oh, Gene. I wasn't...
Shhhh!
Wanna eat or not?
I got him!
Great shot!
Hey, Chief.
Atta boy, Chief!
Come on, Chief!
You got it.
Good work, Chief.
Oh, shit!
What's that?
Double time, Chief!
Come on, Chief!
Ohh...
The slide's jammed!
What? No!
Come on!
- Fast, Chief!
- Paddle, paddle, paddle!
Come on!
Come on, Chief!
Almost there! Come on!
Look at the size of him!
Ain't bad.
Could use cheese.
Huh?
It could use cheese.
Tastes like chicken.
Raw chicken.
So I thought when you saw a bird
it means you're near land.
Not this bird.
They range
thousands of miles.
I still can't believe you shot an albatross.
Why?
Never mind.
Tony, c'mon.
Eat up.
I don't blame you.
I'd leave if I could, too.
Pastula, take another drift sight.
That's not how I'm reading those wave-tops.
Pastula?
Aldrich!
We've lost Pastula!
...nowhere,
Chief. We're lost.
Aldrich!
Enterprise!
No, check that! 6-Tare-14
requesting an inbound bearing!
...Enterprise..
Enterprise!
Enterprise! Help me!
There's no watch.
All hands on deck.
I gave orders
to maintain a 24-hour watch.
And you're sleeping on duty!
What difference does it make?
If that wind shifts
and we don't deploy our anchor
we lose ground, Aldrich!
I don't feel any wind, Chief.
It's because their ain't any.
It's been dead for two days.
Shut your mouth!
Just shut your mouth!
I ordered a watch, there will be a watch!
Sure, Chief.
Whatever you say.
No you won't, Tony.
You want a damn watch so bad
why don't you sit here staring at nothing
all day?
I do my share.
Are you? Then where
are these islands
you told us about?
Yeah.
They must be close, right?
Don't you touch that!
You boys, you can't even
swim much less read a map!
Let me ask you something.
How'd you come up with
that chart of yours anyway?
I- I-I studied the area map
in the ready room every day.
I have a rough picture of it
in my mind.
Plus or minus 10%
After that it's simple dead reckoning!
A rough picture?
Dead reckoning works when you know
where you're starting from, right?
So this route you've figured
is based on where you think we went down
followed by a bunch of estimates
after that on where we've
gotten each day.
What's your point?
My point?!
The reason we went down is because
you didn't know where we were
That's why we couldn't find the ship.
That's why I couldn't
raise her on the radio.
You had gotten us so far
off, we were out of range!
I- I tried to take that into account.
And that's with instruments
and a real map!
And here we've gone all
these days without so much
And the first couple of
days we hardly kept track.
And you're gonna put us on some teeny
islands in the middle of all this?
I, I...
All a big guess
Now, listen. Yes, yes, yes,
I'm relying on my recall.
I may have made a few estimates, but I-
I was trying to
head us dead center to these islands
so even if we were off somewhat
What do you mean
"was trying?"
When were you expecting to see them?
Three days ago.
Or four.
There should be islands
all around us by now.
We missed 'em.
That's the way islands are, Tony.
Didn't you know? You raise
'em and they're past.
It's a one chance deal. You
miss Hawaii, next stop Tokio.
Now, you listen to me...
It's dead reckoning alright
'cause I reckon we're dead out here!
You want to take over
smart mouth?
Guys, please.
I don't give a goddamn!
And you're mister high and mighty.
Keeping your shoes after
we've thrown ours away.
About the radio like I'd missed somethin'!
"What did
Aldrich do with the radio?"
You're all over Tony about his drift sight
because he got the same read on both legs.
Well, what the hell
besides getting us lost on
the biggest body of water
in the whole
damn
worid?
Chief?
I've lost the beacon, over.
Are we close, Chief?
Maybe his comm is down.
I'll give him a tap.
Chief?
Can you hear us, over?
Loud and clear, boys.
Just waiting for this wind to tell me which
way she wants to blow.
I think I fell asleep.
It was so hot
It couldn't have been more
than a couple minutes but...
So we missed the turn
and by the time that we made it...
It was way too late.
I got us lost.
And I don't know how to
square it with you boys.
Ever.
I can't.
I'm a pilot
who lost his
plane
and his crew...
And myself.
I'm terribly sorry-
I'm terribly sorry, men.
I'm sorry.
This map ain't much.
But it's the only thing
we got to get us home.
Looks like the only wind we're generating
is our own, fellas.
I reckon so.
That Is exactly what we need to do!
Where are my shoes?
Oh, here we go.
No, no.
Give me your knife.
Please give me your knife.
Okay.
Gentlemen.
Let's make our own wind.
Tell you what...
Whoever sees land first, gets a dinner.
Anything he wants, anywhere he wants.
The other two are buying.
Deal!
Stroke!
You won't find that funny in a few minutes!
Henree!
Put on
the pot.
Okay
let's get to it.
Gene?
Either of you
know insurance?
Insurance?
Life insurance.
I have a $5,000 policy to go to my mother.
Was Wondering if she was able to collect.
After a whole month
I'd imagine so.
I wonder
how Irene's getting along.
Sounds like a real nice girl.
She works for a doctor now.
You said that.
I used to write her poetry.
We'd sure like to hear one of those poems.
That's right.
Give us a poem.
Tony?
Look alive, boys.
We might be getting a drink.
It's a strange one.
Earhart.
You know that woman flier?
Amelia Earhart.
She went down in these parts, right?
Here it comes!
That was chilly.
Another shower?
I don't like it.
The clouds are movin'
in opposite directions.
What is it?
Get ready.
We're going to have to bail fast.
Are there hurricanes in the Pacific?
Affirmative.
So when's hurricane season?
Why do I keep asking these questions?
Take this!
You can't swim, remember?
You know what I could go for right now?
Get down!
Chief! Chief!
Where is he?
Chief!
We're coming,
Chief! Come on!
Come on, Chief!
STAY
WITH
THE RAFT!
HANG ON!
Gene! Where's Tony?
I lost him!
Work your way around.
See if you can spot him!
Tony!
Zdrowas Maryjo, laskis pelna
You okay?
Chief! Chief!
Good boy.
Alright
we have to flip her!
On my mark
we'll lift
and let the wind catch her.
But hold onto it.
Yeah!
One!
Two!
Three!
Lift!
You go around the other side!
I'll hold it down!
You get in first!
Lock on!
Rub-a-dub-dub
Three men in a tub.
And who do you think they be?
The butcher, the baker
the candlestick maker.
Turn them out
knaves all three.
How is it I just now thought of that one?
The raft'll sink
won't it?
Yeah.
There'll be nothing left of us.
No.
No one will know we've
survived all this time.
No.
Suppose one of us dies.
What do the others do?
Gene, you're always talking about food.
What do you think?
The liver, anyhow.
The heart if you can get to it.
Well, we lost the pliers
and your pocket knife.
Well, the kidneys
would be easy.
Yeah, one for each man.
I think we need some
other kind of talk.
I'm trying but everything's so far away.
Just remember something.
My wife.
She had a pretty yellow dress.
She burned a hole in it with her cigarette.
So she sewed a little
white dove over the hole.
I can picture the dress
and the dove
but I can't really see her face.
Tony?
I do believe I am in love with your sister.
Huh.
You'll make a great couple.
I want you boys to know
if we had made it
I would've put you in for commendations.
If they would've listened
to me after my court martial.
Court martial?
Pastula
can you think of anything they'd
be court martialing the Chief for?
Not a thing I can think of, Aldrich.
Me neither.
I'm sorry it had to end this way.
A man plots his course
but the Lord decides.
Alright.
Enough of that bullshit!
Seems to me
if God chose our course
it's because he wants us to make it!
Right?
Either way
we've come way too far to give up now.
Ahh.
Tony.
Gene?
Poor Tony.
Uh.
Tony.
I hear music.
What kind of music
Tony?
Can you hear it?
I see a beautiful field of corn.
I- I saw our fleet
twice yesterday.
I don't know.
Somethin' green.
Have a look, Chief.
Gene Aldrich.
You have won yourself a dinner!
Land ho!
Thank you.
Paddle, boys. Paddle!
Paddle!
Stand down.
We should drift right in.
What if there's Japanese?
What choice do we have?
Square away, men.
We might be going over.
It's going over!
Uh!