PYRENEES, 1892
This way, gentlemen.
Gentlemen,
l won't keep you waiting any longer.
As you know, Holbein lndustries
have manufactured
the best weapons for many years now.
But to truly revolutionize
our industry...
Gentlemen, l give you...
Artur Prats.
l'm a man of few words.
So l'll keep this short.
Above all,
l'd like you to see for yourselves
what we've got here
to show you today.
Please, come and look
through the telescopes.
Tell me,
how many balloons can you see?
l see two.
These are the best telescopes
on the market.
We already know these models.
l know.
Are you all right?
Are you hurt?
l'm sorry, Daddy.
Forgive me.
l'm not your dad.
Joana, l'm here now.
Don't worry, sweetheart.
Oh, God.
Are you okay?
Daddy?
Look at me,
look at me, darling!
Joana, look at me.
Extra, extra!
Another anarchist bomb attack!
Seven murdered and fifteen injured
in Almirall street!
Stay still!
No, not his face!
Just calm down.
What happened?
l was fired.
Why?
lt's complicated.
Then start at the beginning.
1 1 DAYS EARLlER
The day begins
at half past five in the morning.
At five on Tuesdays,
and at four o'clock
if you have to go to market.
You'll have to make sure
all the doors and windows
are shut tight before night falls.
From that moment on, no one
is allowed on Madam's floor.
Any problem with that?
None at all.
Close up everything before dark
and ask before going upstairs.
Piece of cake.
Hold on.
Let me do it.
This is where Ma'am sits.
What's that for?
To tell them apart.
lt seems she can distinguish colours.
That's why we all wear rosettes.
You see?
Marga, that's not exactly true.
We get branded here like cattle
because of that freak of nature.
Mariano, cut that out!
Take that back this instant.
Mariano...
lt's Mr. Lardin.
He was meant to be back tomorrow.
He's decided to come back early.
Get to your positions.
Set another place, Margarita.
Carles is hungry!
Thank you.
Who is this Carles?
Carles Lardin, Madam's fiance.
l'm going back to Madrid
before the end of the month.
lf you agree,
we can close the deal.
-Fine.
-lt's the answerto our prayers.
That's great. But let's
leave business until tomorrow.
Your return couldn't be more timely.
How come?
l'd ratherthe Doctortold us.
Meissner has returned?
Not exactly.
What? ls he still here?
l won't be for much longer,
l assure you.
Excuse me, Doctor,
l didn't mean to...
Don't worry, Carles.
What he means is that...
Well, you explain it.
My pleasure.
l'm very pleased
to be here this evening
to announce that, after having
studied Joana's case exhaustively,
l can finally give you a diagnosis.
Really?
Are you completely sure?
Please.
The hypnosis sessions with Joana
couldn't have been more revealing.
Hypnosis?
Allow me to explain.
We knew Joana had problems
recognising sounds,
objects and also people,
but we didn't understand why.
Well, now l am quite sure.
lmagine that this jug contains
all the stimuli reality offers us.
lmages, sounds, smells, etc.
Now when you look at this glass,
think of it as a brain,
young, healthy and pure.
From the day we're born
to the day we die,
this is all we actually perceive
of reality.
Thanks to this filter,
we can separate out
that extra information
which would otherwise
submerge our minds in chaos.
Unfortunately,
this is not the case for Joana.
The encephalitis
she had as a child
destroyed that filter.
Since then, an excess of information
has been reaching Joana's brain.
Her brain can't process it
or remember...
l am sorry.
Don't worry.
What are you driving at
with all of this?
The sound proofing
of her bedroom is almost ready,
but l fear it isn't enough.
We need to seal
the room completely.
No inside or outside light.
What?
You want to put her in a cage?
No. ''Cocoon''
would be a more fitting description.
We'll finish this conversation later.
Joana.
l don't feel very comfortable
in this dress.
But you look beautiful.
lt's one of her mother's dresses.
Look.
Look who's here.
Come on, Joana.
Who is it?
lt's Carles.
Carles...
-Come on, say something to her.
-Daddy.
Doesn't she look pretty?
Radiant.
You'll see what a knock-out
she looks in a wedding dress.
lt's impossible to get near her.
That doctor is always there.
You won't find anything
in that house.
Are you sure?
Fine. ln that case...
Let's go.
Right.
We'll be in touch with you
just as soon as we have
a signed statement.
That wretch will nevertalk.
He doesn't know who's paying him.
Sir?
What do you mean by that?
lt's not the first time somebody's
been snooping about yourfactory,
but this time they tried to force
the lock on your office door.
Let's not kid ourselves, this has
nothing to do with anarchists.
l agree with you there.
lf you had any idea
who was behind this,
you'd let me know, wouldn't you?
Now, if you'll excuse me...
ls there anything l should know?
lndustrial espionage?
l'm only asking
if apart from manufacturing weapons,
you've also started
your own line in lenses?
You know l've always been
a very open-minded business woman.
l thought your determination
would have waned after so many years.
Your military friends are very keen
for you to make them
a telescopic rifle,
but one thing is selling something
you still haven't manufactured
and quite another
is speculating
with ''borrowed'' technology.
l hope you haven't come here
just to insult me.
Just accept it!
l never manufactured
the catadioptric lens.
You can look under
every last stone on earth,
but you won't find a thing.
l burnt it all.
So, as far as Joana Lenses
is concerned,
you can say goodbye
to yourtelescopic rifle.
That's a pity.
We were hoping to invest
in Joana Lenses.
l appreciate your generosity,
but we don't need your money.
Doesn't your pet
have anything to say?
-Goodbye, Lucille.
-l'm not finished.
We've known
each otherfor years,
l was hoping you'd invite me to
your beautiful daughter's big day.
By the way,
how is she?
My God, Lucille.
Don't you have any limits?
All right.
Now l'm going to ask you a question.
And l want you to tell me the truth.
During yourwork at the mansion
as a servant,
did you ever come into direct
contact with Artur Prats' daughter?
Carles?
ls that you?
No, Ma'am.
lt's me,
Vicent.
One of the servants. See?
Oh, hello.
l was on my way to my room
but l strayed off the path
and now l need somebody
to get me back to my route.
l see. Where do you need to...?
lf you can just wait a minute.
Whenever you're ready, Ma'am.
Can l ask you a question?
Go ahead.
Why did you stray from your route?
So l could see the stars.
They've started
covering up my bedroom windows,
and from time to time
l need to look outside this ''castle''.
The night sky is one of the few things
l can see just like everybody else.
Come here, take a look.
l'm sure if l pointed out
all l can see up there,
you'd be more lost than me.
For sure.
Truth be told,
l'm also a bit lost down here.
That sounded sad.
l never know for sure when somebody
is cheerful or angry or sad.
But l do have one trick.
Their breathing.
Breathing?
The way people breathe never lies.
Can you help me get back?
-Where to?
-To the handrail.
Of course.
Mind the step, Ma'am.
Thank you, Vicent.
Good night.
Good night, Ma'am.
And don't be sad.
One... two...
and three.
Still dressed?
Yes, l know,
l was miles away. Sorry.
-l'll walk you there.
-No.
l can make it to the bath on my own.
Watch.
l'm sorry, Ma'am.
The Doctor didn't...
But it's right here by my side.
Really?
Yes. Watch.
See?
Careful.
-Mariano, in the cornerwith it.
-Quickly.
-Vicent!
-Coming.
Can you help me with this?
ls the watertoo cold, Ma'am?
No, it's hot.
Could you bring me
some lukewarm water?
l'd have to go downstairs forthat,
and you know l can't leave you
in the bath on your own.
What's going to happen?
l'm not going anywhere.
Daddy!
Vincent!
Joana!
lt's all right,
it's me, your dad.
Call Doctor Meissner!
Now!
Stand up.
What do you want?
What do you want from me?
Carles.
Good luck.
Good night, gentlemen.
Have you got a moment?
Can we talk?
We do need to talk.
Have a seat.
Be honest.
Do you still think that Dr Meissner
won't be able to cure Joana?
l don't want to appear impertinent,
but l need to talk to you
about our current situation,
the company's situation.
Since l came back,
we haven't even...
We don't need a group of investors.
There's something
l can't get out my head.
You told Lucille Prevert
that you'd destroyed
the formula of the lens.
Was that true?
l mean, if we could still
make that lens,
we'd soon get through bad patch
without having to resort
to investors.
Orto Holbein, naturally.
Anything but Holbein,
you know that.
But we can choose our customers.
Just like we always have done.
Really?
Tell me how.
By tossing a coin
to decide if they're any good?
You don't realise.
What's the matter?
What are you afraid of?
Stop worrying about the business,
concern yourself more
with your own affairs.
What are you trying to say?
Your daughter is all l care about.
l'd do absolutely anything for her,
absolutely anything.
She will get better, Carles.
She will be cured.
And she'll be a marvellous mother
and a marvellous wife.
See?
There's nothing there.
How did you do that?
lt's magic.
Magic, he says. The only
magic things here are my balls.
That's real magic.
He took the flowerfrom the vase.
You're a fool,
you look like a fool.
All right, let's see
if you get this one.
Artur,
you're absolutely right,
the figures just don't add up.
We have to tighten our belts.
Eitherthat... or bankruptcy.
Vicent does him better.
Oh, yes, go on, do it for us.
Artur, if you like l could go
to Madrid at the end of the month
to close the deal.
lt would be the answer
to our prayers.
Carles...
lt's so nice to feel dizzy, Carles.
l look at you
but l don't see you!
Why don't you give me a kiss?
Touch me, l can't see you!
Vicent!
Get out.
Let's go.
Get out of here!
lt should never have happened.
Not like that.
l read your report again last night
for a second time.
A quite extravagant option,
if you don't mind me saying so.
The hypnosis sessions
haven't produced anything.
Whateverthe secret
Prats entrusted to his daughter,
we're not going to find it
in her subconscious.
l'm afraid this is
the only alternative.
You've got three days
to carry out a new mission.
Nobody's going to hurt her, are they?
Half yourfee
is just in front of you.
''Darling daughter,
if you hearthese words,
it's because l'm no longer here.
Now, as l write these words,
it's hard to believe,
but l think that
after all these years together
l've come to the conclusion
that to really love somebody
you have to accept
that one day
we won't be here
to give the best of ourselves.
That is when we must
make way for someone else.
l've organised it
so you'll hear my last words
from the lips of Carles,
who was like a son to me.
He'll look after you and the factory
just as l always have.
l love you very much, my dear.
Very much indeed.
No fatherwants his children
to get sick.
But your illness
has made you special,
just as special
as your motherwas.
l've suffered a lot for you,
you know that,
but l want you to know,
l'd never have swapped
the daughter you've been
forthe daughter
you might have been.
You've caused me
more pain than anything,
but you've also given me
more happiness
than l everthought
l could aspire to in this life.
Your loving father.''
Leave me, please.
You must cure her.
Understand?
Now more than ever.
You have to do it.
l promised Mr. Prats l wouldn't rest
until l found a cure for his daughter.
And l will keep that promise.
The ''Cocoon'', remember?
We have to isolate her
from all stimuli.
Sounds, images,
tactile sensations, temperature,
absolutely everything,
for a period of three days.
That includes me, the servants
and even you.
Any interaction with other people
could ruin everything.
You mean lock her up
forthree days.
l know it's tough but we can
put a stop to these nervous fits.
To block out this confusing
universe she is immersed in,
she has to be totally isolated.
Begin the preparations immediately.
But whatever happens, we're getting
married on the 6th of January.
Without any possible delay.
Without delay.
Aren't you going to eat?
Yes.
Excuse me,
l was a little distracted.
l've tried on the tunic.
The doctor says l can't take it off.
l told him that in three days
l'll at least have to do number ones.
He just started laughing.
And so did l.
-Are you leaving now?
-Yes.
l have to go.
l'd love to stay here with you,
but it's late.
Carles, is it always
going to be like this?
Of course not.
Why do you say that?
lt's all right. You go.
The doctor is convinced
you will recover.
You'll see, when we are married.
You're so naughty!
Got any spare change, sir?
Do you want to take part
orto watch?
Take part orwatch?
Watch.
Don't turn around.
l'm not even going to open it.
Leave it inside
without making a noise.
-Are you feeling okay?
-Yes, sir.
Quick! Call Margarita.
Joana?
Who's that?
Doctor? ls that you?
No, Joana, it's me.
Carles.
What?
Put the light on.
You see?
Carles,
is something wrong?
No, nothing.
Don't fret.
l just had to see you.
Right now? Are you crazy?
Let me explain.
Please...
l had to talk to you
before the wedding
and l thought that here
without anybody about...
l've been doing some thinking...
About us... and the factory.
What are you trying to do?
Ruin the treatment?
l know you don't believe
in Doctor Meissner,
but don't spoil everything, please,
even if it's just for daddy.
Please, leave.
l asked you to leave.
Why did you leave the room?
What went wrong?
l don't know.
l don't know, l thought maybe
she had cottoned on.
What are you talking about?
Do you think she recognised you?
No, it's not that.
lt's as if she could sense
l wasn't telling the truth.
-Are you getting cold feet?
-No.
Then go back inside
and follow our instructions.
ls everything in order, Doctor?
Yes.
The boy is going back in.
Carles, if you don't leave,
l'm going to scream.
-Just for a minute.
-Carles, no.
-You're very sad.
-What do you expect?
Joana...
ln all these years,
l've never had the courage
to tell you...
what l really feel for you.
Are you trying to say
you don't want to marry me?
Marry you?
There's nothing in this world
l'd rather do more.
So you've already got
what you wanted, haven't you?
Yes.
l have your hand,
because yourfather gave it to me.
But l'd like to have
asked you for it myself.
Aren't you going to say anything?
What am l meant to say?
Nothing.
l just wanted you to know.
l won't bother you any more.
Where are you going?
l have to go to the factory.
We've got so much work
still to do.
Besides, l don't want
to interfere with the treatment.
-One more thing.
-Yes?
l need...
l need yourfinger measurements.
lf we wait any longer
to orderthe rings,
they won't be ready in time.
Would you mind
if l came back tomorrow?
No. Of course not.
Tomorrow.
l'll be here.
Go and find the accounts ledgers
saved from the fire
and send them on to me at home.
Very well.
The news got to Madrid
quick enough.
-Should l go in?
-Not yet, no.
One thing
is improvising
to get out of a sticky situation,
quite another
is disobeying instructions.
When you go back in,
take up the protocol again
from the part
about the wedding rings.
The wedding rings, yes.
Carles?
What are you doing?
lt's a surprise.
-A surprise?
-Yes. Close your eyes.
But...
-Close your eyes.
-Okay, okay.
l'm watching you.
Now?
No, just a minute.
Whenever you're ready.
lt's my engagement present.
But if you don't like it,
l can get you a jewel.
lt's the most beautiful present
l've ever been given.
They seem real.
How did you do it?
No, don't tell me.
l'd rather not know.
Joana...
What?
Forgive me.
What for?
For having been so distant
all these years.
Are you all right?
ls something wrong?
My recollection of you
was so different.
Joana, we're not exactly
children any more.
The wedding ring.
l had to take your measurements.
Yes, that's right.
What's the matter?
Nothing. l thought you were
about to ''ask for my hand''.
Well,
in a way,
that's what l am doing.
Don't you see, Carles?
We're doing everything
the wrong way round!
You're right.
And it's all my fault.
Don't say that.
You and your dad always did that.
Exactly, it was something
between him and l.
Forgive me.
l didn't mean to upset you.
l'm sorry.
l miss him so much.
So do l, Joana.
So do l.
Anything else, sir?
No, thank you, you can go.
Teresa?
-Sir.
-Margarita. Excuse me.
Where is Doctor Meissner?
Actually, l don't know.
He should be in his bedroom.
Doctor.
Sir.
Can l help you with anything?
What would happen
if she had a problem in there?
One of her attacks?
lf what's worrying you
is the storm, l can assure you
her isolation is absolute.
Absolutely everything
has been taken care of.
lt's okay. Leave us.
Carry on eating.
l'm not hungry.
lt's obvious
that you don't lack
confidence in yourself.
Listen,
in less than twelve hours,
we have to return that girl
to the world she was living in.
lf you carry on playing
this passionate version
of Carles Lardin,
the original by her side
might suddenly look like
a cheap fake in comparison.
And neither you
nor l want that to happen.
For Joana's sake.
What do you want me to do now?
Enough beating about the bush.
When you go back in,
ask her directly about the formula.
And this time,
keep your enthusiasm under control.
What the hell?
What is it?
-lt's the thunder. She can hear it!
-Hear it?
Listen to me!
l don't care if she can hear it.
What concerns me
is that we can't hear her.
Everything's been taken care of.
We paid you to make
the cocoon soundproof, you idiot!
ln the original cocoon...
not this one.
There's a panic button.
A panic button?
Don't worry.
The button is irrelevant
because Joana won't be needing it.
Believe me,
that bell isn't going to ring.
Carles!
l understand you want to see her,
you miss her.
All of us worry about Joana.
Me as much as anyone.
Please forgive me,
l'm...
Joana!
Joana, Joana.
lt's me. Carles. l'm here.
Everything the wrong way round.
Don't pull that face, Doctor.
Does it really surprise you?
This is our last day.
We've got to do something.
Of course
we're going to do something.
You can't harm her.
We made a deal.
lndeed we did,
and then you came up with
this ridiculous circus performance.
What happened?
How long have l been asleep?
l don't know.
You were so tired,
l didn't want to wake you.
What's that?
Daddy's photograph album.
Look, that's you
at Christmas mass.
And how do you know that's me?
l know this book off by heart,
and you're always the one
who's next to Dad.
Well, almost always.
This will be the first year
without him.
But now that Dad isn't here,
l suppose you'll be
the crown prince, won't you?
No, l'm just a faithful squire,
who will always protect you.
My faithful squire.
l like that.
l don't want you to worry,
but l need to tell you something.
lt's very important.
Joana?
Get the kid out of there.
He's had too many chances already.
What? No! Just a minute.
l said get him out of there now.
Carles?
l can't see you, Carles.
Joana,
Joana, l'm not...
You're scaring me.
What's the matter?
What's wrong?
Listen to me.
There's no time.
l haven't found the courage
to tell you before now.
-l'm not...
-What?
We can't escape this.
-What are you talking about?
-The thing is...
l'm not...
lt's the business.
We're in a critical situation.
Because of the fire?
lt's not just that.
We've been operating at a loss
for months.
lf it continues, we'll have to close
Joana Lenses within the year.
But that can't be right.
Daddy never...
Your dad neverwanted
you to worry.
Listen, Joana,
l've been thinking about it
and l can only see one solution.
Manufacturing the catadioptric lens.
-He didn't want to.
-l wish there were anotherway,
but it's our only salvation.
lf we don't, we'll go bust.
Please, give me the formula.
What formula?
My dad never gave me any formula.
And all this...
was because
you wanted that formula?
How can you say that?
Don't you trust me?
Come here.
Come.
Sit down.
Close your eyes.
One.
Four.
Two.
Eight.
Seven.
Nine.
Fantastic!
When l was a little girl and l went
to the factory with my father,
we used to pretend
l was helping him in the lab.
He always wrote those numbers
on the palm of my hand.
Always the same ones,
always in the same order.
l don't know.
Do you think
those numbers might be...?
l think so.
Joana,
l'm sorry it all had to be this way.
No, Carles. l know you're
only doing this to protect me.
l trust you.
Yes.
l have to get back to work.
l thought you'd gone
to the jeweller already.
Yes, l did.
lt's just l didn't want
to give it back.
l thought you'd want to keep it
until l give you the real one.
See you outside.
ln a short while,
my faithful squire.
The payment for your services
is in your room.
Don't be long.
Doctor?
What will happen to her now?
Don't worry.
She's sleeping peacefully,
and she's going to be fine,
as fine as she can be.
You can't cure her, can you?
All that stuff about the treatment
was lies.
Listen carefully, forthe last time.
Son of a bitch!
Look! Overthere!
What's all this?
Sir, l...
The police were here, sir.
The police?
What did they want?
-An escaped anarchist!
-They thought he was here.
They took us into the kitchen
while they searched the mansion!
That's enough.
Mr. Lardin!
There's a fellow here at the station
with a very strange story.
Yes, l know, an anarchist.
What?
No, he's not an anarchist,
not as far as l know.
l know this might sound strange,
but he's made a statement
saying he was forced to take part
in a plot to kidnap Joana Prats.
What are you talking about?
That's absurd!
Yes, but you understand
it's our duty to check out his story.
Hold on.
You came to my house
looking for an anarchist?
No, no.
What are you talking about?
We haven't been near your house.
But, Sir, it's still not time!
Go and find Dr. Meissner!
Joana?
Thank God.
-Are you alright?
-Of course l am!
l was so looking forward
to seeing you.
So, three days here on you own.
Yes, ''on my own''.
Doctor Meissner isn't here yet.
We'll have to wait a while.
Do you know what we could do?
No.
l see you're feeling better.
Do you notice anything different?
Everything is different.
You know what?
l think l've even got over
my fear of thunder storms.
Wait a moment.
You heard the thunder?
A little. lt was very distant.
Maybe l heard it because
l'm getting better.
Maybe.
Excuse me, sir.
Good morning.
l hate to interrupt...
lt's okay, darling.
Go about your business.
l'll see you later.
Marga, can you bring
some more butter, please?
Yes, Ma'am.
The entrance was here.
And her bed was there.
And they controlled it all
from up there.
They?
That's enough.
Let's get out of here.
Come in.
Sir, l don't mean to disturb you...
-What time is it?
-lt's seven o'clock.
Madam has already had dinner.
Would you like to have some?
No. Maybe later.
Has Doctor Meissner called?
-Shall l call the police?
-No, not forthe time being.
Thank you.
l think Marga almost saw me.
Joana!
What are you doing?
-l couldn't stand it anymore.
-What is it?
l had to see you.
Joana, the servants!
We'll be very quiet.
Be careful.
Careful.
Just take it slowly.
Joana, please, the books.
l was so scared
that it was alljust a dream,
these last three days.
l thought l wouldn't be able
to stand being locked up,
but when l saw you
come in the door,
l was simply dying for you
to walk in.
-You really mean that?
-Yes.
Carles...
Oh, Carles...
What is it, Joana?
Who are you?
Joana, it's me, darling.
lt's me.
Last night,
you seemed like someone else.
Last night?
Well?
l know it isn't pleasant.
lt's a load of rubbish.
However, this man seems to have
a lot of information on you.
From having worked in my house.
Well, that's what he claims.
You don't give this any credibility?
Absolutely none whatsoever.
ln any case, it's easy to check
whether he everworked in my house.
ls Joana all right?
How could you do
something like that?
They didn't give me much choice.
They knew everything about you.
Everything except that damn formula.
That formula doesn't exist.
Joana gave it to me.
They wanted to torture her.
l did it to save her.
Save her? You?
-She doesn't even know you exist.
-Ask her about that.
-What are you saying?
-You don't deserve her.
You don't respect her as a woman.
You can't give her
what she wants.
One day, she'll work out that
you're not the man she was with.
And by then l won't be in here.
There's no proof against me.
lf you want to accuse me
of something,
you'll have to let Joana explain
what happened between us
to the whole world.
lf you go anywhere near her again,
l swearto God l'll kill you!
l'll kill you.
Everything alright?
Out, out.
How could you?
How could
something like this happen?
lt makes my head spin.
Did you know that good-for-nothing
worked in this house?
Vicent!
The servant we dismissed!
l see you remember
the bastard well enough.
Carles, l swearto God
that l thought it was you!
l swear.
Well, l'm afraid
that's not the way it was.
Carles, wait.
l wanted it to be you
with all my heart.
Mister Lardin.
Bitch.
l'm with guests.
lf you have something
you'd like to say to me...
You...
and Meissner and that servant...
have taken everything from me.
l have nothing left.
Mister Lardin,
get married, sell the business,
and stop worrying,
l never leave loose ends.
Happy Christmas, sir.
Mister Lardin, Mister Lardin...
Happy Christmas.
We are very sad about
the loss of Mr. Prats.
Joana.
Joana!
lt's you!
Stop or l'll shoot!
Joana!
No!
Joana, Joana...
Are you okay?
lt's me.
ls it you?
Oh, my God.
Fetch a doctor!
Somebody find a doctor!
What is it?
What do you want?
Leave me.
Joana.
Joana?
l'm here.
-Carles?
-No.
No, Joana, it's me.
My faithful squire.
Subtitles: LASERFlLM