Subtitle Extraction from : iTunes
Edit sync By : D.LUFFY
A Singapore registered cargo vessel
Golden Horizon
has been hijacked by a group of
international terrorists.
A total of 10 Singaporeans, 8 Malaysians
and 7 Chinese Nationals are believed
to be held hostage.
Terrorists are demanding a sum of
100 million US dollars
and immediate release of their members.
Negotiations between the terrorists
and the government is ongoing.
The negotiations have broken down.
The terrorist has given an ultimatum
for the huge sum of cash.
It was reported that they will start
killing hostages from 1830 onwards.
Command, PWO.
Golden Horizon 030 15 miles from own force.
Sir, all units in position,
ready for operation.
Launch UAV for surveillance.
Stand by frogmen and follow-on force.
Activate frogmen, get them to approach
from the stern of the ship.
Priority is to ensure the safety
of the hostages.
Roger, sir.
PWO, Command.
Close up acting station. Launch frogmen.
Roger, sir.
Get down.
Go! Go! Go!
Hotel Qebec, Lucky, over.
Lucky, main deck contacted.
Casualty at stake. I repeat.
Casualty at stake.
Request immediate Sierra.
(Sierra: support.)
Execute Plan Bravo now.
Make ropers time on target 1815.
Roger, sir.
Starling, activate Plan B.
Time on target 1815.
TZ, Starling Wilco, TOT 1815.
Sir, they need you.
I can take care of myself.
-You sure?
-Yes, sir.
Okay, you take cover here.
We will come back for you.
Starling, TZ Mission update.
Terrorists with small arms on deck.
Starling copied.
Check it out. This way.
Protect this place.
Get down.
TZ, Starling 5 mins to target.
TZ, Starling 3 mins to target.
Drop your weapon.
-Put down your weapon.
-Help me.
Drop your weapon.
Put down your weapon.
-Let her go.
-Help me.
Put down...
Drop your weapon.
Put down your weapon.
Ken.
There are no female crew on the list.
Do your homework.
Yes, sir.
Gunner standby for engagement.
Copied, sir.
Break right, Break right.
Gunner engage target.
Execute.
Get out.
Get out now.
Calm down. Relax.
Anything we can discuss.
Put your guns down! Move.
Just calm down, we are backing off.
It's okay guys, come down.
Down.
Move.
We are going down.
2, 6. Hooyah.
Faster.
Everybody get down.
Who is your commanding officer?
You.
Tell your men to put their weapons
on the deck.
Do it now.
Relax.
Hold your fire.
He has a pressure release detonator.
Relax. What is it that you want?
Let me know.
I'm tired of negotiating.
I want money.
I want my chopper
so I can go home.
And I want it right now.
Whatever you want, I still need some time.
Back! Get back.
Get back.
Back.
That's right.
Back. Get back. Do it now.
Aloysius.
Man overboard.
Go check it out.
Hello! Do you still remember me?
Yes, I am Aloysius Jin Seah-lan,
Zeng Xie-lang.
What you saw just now is not a game.
Why are we in this counter
terrorism mission?
Yes, I know you remembered
all of us did our BMT in Tekong.
(BMT: basic military training.)
But do you know that
not all soldiers in the SAF
did their BMT there?
So, what if
all of us got posted to the elite force
Naval Diving Unit as mono-intakers?
What's going to happen?
This is our another story.
Let's start with Lobang King.
Ah Beng.
Pretty lady, I'm not Ah Beng.
Then you're Ah Seng.
I bought this handphone from you yesterday
because you told me
it's the cheapest around.
When I asked around
yours is more expensive by 50.
And you short-change me a battery.
How could you cheat me?
Hey Pretty.
I would cheat on anyone,
but never a pretty girl.
I am sure that those you checked
do not have an international warranty.
What if your phone spoils
while you're overseas?
Are you going to take a flight back
just to repair it?
Besides, it's very dangerous to
take a plane these days.
The plane may just disappear.
It's not funny.
I was so smitten that
I forgot about the battery.
Forget it. Just give it to me.
Oh no, you met Justin.
Who is Justin?
Just destined to be sold out.
Can you stop taking advantage of me?
Don't you worry.
Write down your contact number for me.
Okay?
I will give you a call
once the battery stock is in.
You better not lie to me.
Otherwise you will have your retribution.
We can go for coffee and have a good time.
Lobang.
You calculated wrongly.
The boss just gave me a lashing.
You take this and add this. Hold on.
Take this and add this.
Deduct this and you'll get it.
Which unit is Ken going to?
Naval Diving Unit.
Lucky you.
Naval Driving Unit.
It's free and easy.
Just send people to their destination.
Stripping off, taking off shoes,
putting your legs up and shaking.
The kids are here, no vulgarities.
Shaking the butt.
When they are done, you send them back.
Such a easy life.
You're really son of a...
Lucky boy.
Uncle, listen to me.
I'm a diver.
Not a driver.
Diver and driver are just a letter short
but the responsibilities
are entirely different.
You got yourself in as a diver.
You can start digging a hole for yourself.
You can prepare to collect his bones.
Touch wood.
Brother.
What's for dinner tonight?
This is your school fees.
Do you have enough for yourself?
My business here is doing pretty well,
you don't have to worry about me.
That is because of the long queues
at the court.
It's all thanks to them.
Tomorrow is my enlistment day.
You have to take care for yourself.
Send me a message if there is anything.
I will fly out and save you, understand?
Are you sure?
Hey, I am in special force.
If I can't save you, then who can?
You know my friends told me.
That the Tekong BMT camp is very nice,
like a resort.
And all the facilities are very new.
You look at this place, so old,
so run down, all colonial buildings.
Reminds me of the old Changi hospital,
so haunted.
Long.
Son.
Son, wait up for me.
I told you not to come.
Why do you have to be here
and pull a long face?
Like a funeral procession.
How can you talk to us like this?
You two are being a pain.
I never wanted to be here.
Now I have to serve the army.
I've also lost my friends in Hong Kong.
Your friends in Hong Kong
are all good for nothings.
One day you will end up in prison.
Prison? How is this different
from being in prison?
Let me tell you, if I really want to be bad.
Do you think you can stop me?
Look at them.
They are all my henchmen.
What can you do?
I am telling you to go be a soldier.
And stop associating with them.
I would rather stop associating myself
with you two.
You are the ones who wanted to migrate.
Then you should be the ones
getting enlisted.
Why should I pay for my father's choices?
Son, don't be like that.
Can you stop following me?
You're such a pain.
Let's go.
You better don't mess around with them.
No, son.
You should work with everybody here.
Teamwork and brotherhood
is very important here.
No worries, I've got my IQ and my EQ.
And I won't be having any enemies
because my only enemy in the NDU
is me. Myself.
-Right.
-Good boy.
Demolition trained.
Rough and rugged bunch of warriors.
There's nothing we can't do.
Nothing stands in our way.
Don't be crazy. Don't stand in my way.
This army camp looks different
from other army camps.
Frog. There is a frog with wings.
I think the officers from this camp
like to go Geylang for frog porridge.
You okay?
-Shut up.
-Okay.
After all the formalities,
CO speech,
parents asking dumb questions
and followed by CO replying
politically correct answers.
We are now officially NDU recruits
and my new phase of life begins.
Many people
including you recruits,
like to joke about NDU
as a No Discipline Unit.
But I can assure you
We are in fact, one of the most
discipline oriented military units.
Whatever.
You may choose not to believe it now.
But you will, eventually.
You are not ordinary soldiers.
You are combat divers,
amphibious frogmen, yet to be.
You will face high and demanding
standards from me.
Your path will not be smooth or easy.
But if we work together,
nothing stands in our way.
So gentlemen,
are you prepared to complete
this rite of passage with me?
Yes, sir.
In NDU,
you are required to have the best physical
and mental abilities.
Only the best, of the best, makes it.
BMT is a warm up.
To your combat diver course.
If you want to survive the CDC,
(CDC: combat diver course.)
you should give your all
throughout training.
Remember,
you are not the first
and you will never be the last.
-Clear?
-Yes, sir.
I will now hand you over
to your course warrant.
Third Warrant Alex Ong.
The whole lot of you
remove your shirts.
Which part of remove your shirts
do you not understand?
Shirts off now! Take it off.
You, step out.
Yes, sir.
Not you, but it's okay.
You stay there.
You, step out.
Yes, sir.
I want every single one of you
to take a clear and concise look
at your batch boys here.
Right now, most of you
look like this.
But by the end of the course,
I expect all of you to put in effort
to achieve and strive
to have a body that looks
like this.
Is my expectation too high?
No, sir.
Good.
Go back.
Yes, sir.
I want all of you to also remember.
The diver values.
Honor.
Integrity.
And last but not least...
Team spirit.
Bear that in mind.
Is that clear?
Yes, sir.
Drop.
Drop!
So many units in the SAF.
Suay suay kena sent to Sembawang Camp.
Don't understand why they gotta choose me.
To suffer under the sun in the sand and sea.
Why am I here? NDU.
Why they gotta choose me instead of you?
I wanna know. Why me?
From dawn to...
Regardless of which vocation you're in,
we still need to go through
basic military training.
That's why we wear the green number 4
even though we're from the Navy.
Bruises on our bodies, all black and blue.
No choice but to go on,
you know that's true.
Why am I here? NDU.
Why they gotta choose me instead of you?
I wanna know. Why me?
From dawn to dusk kena hammer PT.
48.
Strip weapon.
Strip weapon. Start.
Weapon stripped.
Aloysius, an excellent job well done.
You broke the record.
A perfect 10 seconds.
Sir, may I share my secret
with my batch mates?
Okay.
Step forward.
My secret is
remembering the steps
like I'm singing a rap.
Here we go.
Microphone check two one two. Let's go.
Remove the magazine and push the nut.
Pull up the butt and carrier
with the bolt still stuck
and whack the firing pin so hard
and it will fall apart.
Weapon stripped, sir.
Now that the whole lot
of you know his secret.
I expect every single one of you
to meet his timing.
A perfect
10 seconds.
You want to go OCS, that's your business.
(OCS: Officer Cadet School.)
Don't drag us in.
-Translate?
-Don't sabotage everyone.
Sorry, I was only doing my part and my best.
And actually, I wanted to share
my knowledge with you guys
so that you all can be as good as me.
Done. I don't know how it looks like
I'm sabotaging you all.
Before I came to the army,
someone once told me
in every unit,
they will have a Mr. Know-It-All.
I didn't believe then,
and now I ended up with one.
Can you stop trying so hard?
Didn't your mother teach you?
When the adults talk,
kids shouldn't interrupt.
You want to stick to the wall?
You better remember to take your medication.
Otherwise, you can't seem to figure out
who is the adult or child.
I didn't know that
your father copyrighted scolding.
Why are you the only one who can rebuke him?
Be smart, don't act smart.
Translate?
Ham Ka Chan!
(Ham Ka Chan: curse your family.)
Ham Ka Chan?
What does it mean?
-Over here.
-Wow.
Lobang, you are really like a mini mart.
Don't look down on my mini mart,
this is my NDUC.
NTUC?
NDUC, Naval Diving Unit Cafe.
Remember to write down whatever you take.
Don't try to take advantage of me.
Guys.
Have you heard of this
psycho instructor called No. 2?
No. 2?
You've also heard of No. 2?
That means No. 2 is very famous in NDU.
Who cares about No. 2?
I thought the scary one
should be number one.
Yes, why is he called No. 2?
He is so called No. 2 because
he is a very famous
but notorious course warrant in NDU.
And?
He is also the second longest
record holder in the SAF
to dive without an oxygen tank.
And due to the water pressure
his facial nerves are dead,
leaving him with only one perpetual look.
Grandma flirty. Parents crazy.
Friends in trouble.
Strike 4D. Strike Toto. Strike Big Sweep.
Ancestors' Day. Christmas Day.
Valentine's Day.
But one lucky thing,
I heard he has been posted out.
Lucky us.
What a waste.
Didn't even take his chance to downgrade.
Stupid fellow.
Lobang.
Why do you have an
unlimited supply of titbits?
You got these from the canteen?
Don't utter rubbish!
We are not allowed to go canteen.
This is my business secret,
not for you to know.
Gentlemen, just a friendly reminder.
All these are junk food.
It's very bad for your health.
But once in a while it's okay.
Goodnight. Sweet dreams.
Go sleep.
Alright guys.
What you are going to learn today
is something called Drown Proofing.
This is the ultimate test of
a diver's water confidence.
Go.
Airway. Check for breathing.
1, 2, 3, 4, 10.
Okay guys.
You all can laugh, you all can joke.
But you all better pay attention.
This is a matter of life and death.
Take it seriously.
Okay guys.
All of you have observed
the demonstration earlier.
Right now we will commence with training.
Are you all ready?
Yes, sir.
The first pair I want, Rocky
and Hanrey.
Come.
Hey, what is this?
This is not Man Hunt. Want to drop?
-Get into position.
-Yes, sir.
1, 2, 3, 4, 30.
The next pair I want
Hei-long
and
Lobang.
Sir.
You can pair me with anyone but not him.
-I don't want to pair with you either.
-What do you want?
What do you think this is? Matchmaking.
You want to be a diver,
you have to learn to work together.
In future when you go for ops,
are you only going work
with the person you like?
No, sir.
Go down.
You go.
Yes, sir.
1, 2, 3, 4, 25.
1, 2, 3, 4, 30.
What the hell you think you are doing?
What are you trying to do?
Sir, he spat into my mouth.
It was an accident.
Accident?
Let me show all of you
what is a real accident.
Since you guys don't know
how to work together as a team.
Today I will make sure
you learn the hard way.
Hello.
My business is damn good,
bring me more goods.
I will wait for you downstairs.
Okay.
(Mom took the money you gave me
for my school fees.)
(I can't pay for my school fees now.)
Another round?
Let's go to bed.
Sleep? Let's have another round.
What is that?
Poker cards.
Why?
Casino night?
No, sir.
These cards are for
fortune telling.
Fortune telling.
Okay Mr. Fortune Teller.
Tell my fortune.
Sir.
Please take a card.
You probably think
I am going to pick the centre.
I will go with this.
The meaning of this card is...
You offended the Lone Star.
Destined with no offsprings.
And will live your life in solitary.
I don't understand.
Can you explain in layman terms?
It means Ham Ka Chan.
Ham Ka Chan?
Yeah.
What does it mean?
Ham Ka Chan.
I don't know.
I know Chan Mali Chan.
Ham Ka Chan.
It sounds like a combination of
humble,
courageous
and
charming.
Ham Ka Chan.
Sounds good.
Actually, I'm like that since young.
It's in my blood.
But now,
I want you to tell me.
What is the fortune of this entire cabin
in one minute?
Come...
The four of you stop groaning and sulking.
Just push it out.
You deserve it.
Down.
For one.
So how Hei-long?
You like your fortune so far?
Ham Ka Chan better right?
Up...
Permission to recover, sir.
On your feet.
48.
I'll give you all the benefit
of the doubt today.
But don't ever let me find
any more poker cards
or gambling materials in my cabins.
If I do, bear in mind.
I will hammer the daylights
out of every single one of you.
Clear?
Yes, sir.
Fortune telling! You are really good.
We almost lost our lives
to your fortune telling.
Fortune telling.
If it wasn't you who was walking
like a hairy crab.
I wouldn't have dropped my cards.
Idiots like you in Hong Kong.
I have beaten several.
Hong Kong mafia?
You are in Singapore now,
don't make me laugh.
The fierce tiger will never be
as good as a local tyrant.
Didn't your mother teach you?
I have only heard of brave dragon crossing.
Come on!
Forget it.
I'll make you stick to the wall.
Don't bother with such hooligans.
Sorry I had a tummy ache.
Is everything okay?
Your friend?
Your cabin mate.
If you didn't hold me back,
I would beat him into a pulp.
Cool down.
Hello.
Watch my back.
Where are you?
Throw between the two trees.
Go.
Eating the bread here is indeed different
from eating it outside.
Yeah, it's really different.
What made you so irritable?
That fellow is getting intemperate.
That's all?
Something happened at home.
Short of a few hundred dollars.
I'm stuck in this camp
and can't do anything about it.
It doesn't help that
he keeps getting on my back.
Few hundred dollars isn't much.
Money is not a problem.
Money is not a problem. But I have no money.
I can lend it to you first.
Really?
But I charge high interest.
Just joking.
Today is our book out day.
Book out. Book out.
Book out, book out day. Hey!
Today is our book out day.
Book out. Book out.
Book out, book out day. Hey!
Where is Ken? I can't see him.
They all look so tanned.
And they are all wearing the same clothes.
Of course, they are wearing uniforms.
Why don't we get down the car
and look for him?
Okay.
Ken.
Boss.
Are the things ready?
I ate durians last night.
Here is a good mix of both solid and liquid.
This is my first brew.
Wicked.
Mom. Have you found Amy?
You think your mom is a police post
or information counter?
Can't you just help me?
She has helped you for two weeks,
isn't that enough?
That's enough. Drive.
Bad Maria.
Don't sabotage me.
Ken. Let's go home.
Cow touncil?
Is this cow touncil?
No, I mean town council.
That No. 126 lamp post in front of
the market is not working.
Please get someone to repair it.
Otherwise it is very dangerous at night.
You know about it.
Don't make me call you again.
The next time I'll call straight
to the Prime Minister's office.
Start the action.
Which one is he?
Okay good.
The one who is making a call
in front of the lamp post.
Yes, sir.
Everything is good.
That one in front of the lamp post?
Yes.
They just booked out.
The one on the phone?
Yes.
Alright, sir.
Oh shit.
Panther.
No.
Yes.
This is my boss in NDU.
Your boss in NDU?
Yes.
Isn't he that Wang?
My surname is Wang.
Alex Ong.
What is this?
Herbal tea from Hong Kong.
Herbal tea from Hong Kong?
Homemade?
Yeah, homemade.
Is it nice?
Yes, very nice.
Have you tried it?
Yes.
And you?
-I have not tried before.
-You can try.
Now.
-I try?
-Yes.
-I try it now?
-You try it now.
-Drink it.
-I try it now?
-Yes.
Hurry.
How?
Delicious?
This is damn delicious.
What are you doing?
I almost got sabotaged by you, idiot.
You want to splash urine on my officer.
How am I going to spend
the rest of my days here?
What the hell were you doing?
Can you try to be smarter next time?
I will try.
(Welcome...)
You wrote the word home wrongly.
I don't have a home.
Hence I don't know that word.
Can't you tidy up the place?
This place is a mess.
-Panther.
-Coming.
What's up boss?
Isn't this what I ate
before I went in the camp?
Why is this still here?
Oh damn.
How can I forget this?
Sorry boss.
I have been very busy lately.
You know, there are things
happening on our turf.
Those kids start to owe us membership fees.
And there is this new guy.
Called Wild Boar.
He is vicious and merciless.
I found out that the rest
have became his followers.
You peabrain, there is no need to be afraid.
You go get rid of him.
If the rest try to be funny,
beat them up.
Oh yes boss.
Your mom brought this soup
here this morning.
My mom?
I don't want.
What else does she know besides making soup?
She thinks I will forgive her by doing this.
They think I am a fool.
Boss, don't be like this.
Drink some.
You are putting me in a difficult position.
I am telling you I am not drinking this.
Drink it if you want.
I drank some just now.
Come on, just have a little.
Why are you so concerned with this?
Did my mother bribe you?
No. No.
No?
If I say no, then I'm really lying.
This is yours.
I don't want.
Then I've gained an extra thousand?
One thousand dollars?
Give it back.
I'm going to spend off all her money.
Eighty cents.
Thank you.
What happened to your hair?
They're all gone.
We all look like that in the army.
The town council is very efficient.
They repaired this right after I called.
Yes, you are very efficient too.
What did you tell them?
I told them my sister can't do her
homework without the streetlight.
Hence they sent someone to repair this.
Bullshit.
Let me touch your head again.
Eat your dinner.
How was your training?
Is it tough?
Did you get drilled?
How do you know about this word?
I learned it from watching Ah Boys To Men.
Their terms in the army
is different from us.
Their tekan to us is hammer.
Their fall in to us is muster.
Their bunk to us is cabin.
Our meal time is called chow.
So chow now.
Chow.
Lobang.
What are you doing here?
-Your girlfriend?
-She is my sister.
Your sister.
Hi, I am Wei-ming.
I am Lowei.
Lowei, I am Wei-ming.
I am Lobang.
What do you think you are doing?
Oh yes.
This is what I promised you.
Dowry.
Dowry for my mother?
No need for so much to marry your mom.
This is for your sister.
Didn't you promise me?
Nonsense! Since when was there a promise?
Fat hope.
Can you give me your number?
Hey, I'm still here!
I am just joking, my mother is calling me.
Hello mother, I am coming.
Thank you.
Bye, Lowei.
You only know how to say bye to Lowei.
What about Lobang?
Hey, I will get your number
from your brother.
Get out of here.
Eat your dinner, don't bother with him.
Is there any food? I am hungry.
Over here mom, sit down and eat.
Brother, I will share mine with you.
It's okay, you eat that.
Do you have any money? Give me some.
Didn't I just give you some money.
Where did it go?
Since when did you give me money?
Didn't I do so the other day?
Since when? See for yourself, where?
No wonder you look intoxicated.
Do you know you will be jailed for this?
Listen to me.
Stop it! Listen to me.
Stop it, I will return you.
You have to be careful.
Without this,
I wouldn't have survived until now.
I caused your father's death.
If I hadn't make that turn,
everything will be fine.
It's me who cause your father's death.
No, that was an accident.
It has nothing to do with you.
You didn't do any wrong.
You didn't do...
Mom.
I am in the army and Lowei is still young.
What do you want me to do?
Mom, listen to me.
All your cousins are so proud of you
for being selected as a naval diver.
They will give you a surprise later.
Batch 48 attention.
48 stand still.
Good evening, sir.
Good evening.
48 IC reporting.
Strength 100, present 100.
Permission to carry on, sir.
Carry on.
48. At ease.
Diver Ken Chow. Hooyah.
Welcome diver Ken Chow.
Impressive. How do you guys know about this?
Google, sir.
Good but not good enough.
Everyone, drop 20.
Yes, sir.
They are only kids.
This is what I do in camp everyday.
Every minute, every second.
Life is harsh.
Does this look like fun to you?
Busybody.
They're not bad.
Uncle.
Brother, we miss you.
Miss you.
Sis, this is the first time
my nephew booked out from camp.
The whole place feels so crowded and festive
like the Ghost Festival.
We are just short of a stage with singer.
Didn't I invite you, the singer?
Okay.
If today is the Ghost Festival,
then you must be that hungry ghost.
How can you call me a hungry ghost?
I didn't come empty handed today.
I am here to bring you good fortune.
Yeah right.
Sis, I really brought the good fortune here.
This is the latest rice dispenser.
It not only contains rice.
It also contains all good blessings
and bring good fortune to your whole family.
Thank you. You better eat more tonight.
Hubby, get him some beer.
Let's have a drink.
Come and have some food.
What happened to your hand?
Did they torture you in the NDU?
This is all part of the training.
Don't you know it is tough in NDU?
Sis, there are more here.
Wait. I need to take photos of these
and send in a complaint.
I can tell the training must be hard
just by looking at these.
And no matter how hard the training can be.
After they passed out, they'll be made to
fish corpses from the river
and clear clogs in the canals.
There are only two words to describe.
-What?
-Shit job.
Thanks uncle.
Did you get your facts right?
Those were long time ago.
Times are different now.
Our NDU now is as good
as the Navy Seals in US.
They are the special force.
Only 0.1 percent of the Singapore
population is selected.
And my son is one of them.
You must be so proud then.
Get smart.
Let's drink.
What beer is this? It tastes good.
This is called Dester beer. That's the beer.
Where have you been?
Why do you only call me now?
I have been trying to reach you
for the past two weeks.
Where the hell have you been?
I have been calling you,
texting you day and night.
Why are you ignoring me?
Don't you know I am in NDU?
The toughest unit in the universe.
How can you do this to me?
The reason why
I am calling you now is because
I have made up my mind.
Let's break up.
Break up with me?
How can you betray me like that?
Do you know that every inch of my being
is in pain because of NDU training?
And now you want to break my heart too?
I need someone who is stronger.
Who is able to protect me,
love me, care about me
and understand my feelings.
I need someone who is more determined
and more mature.
You are too childish for me.
Just break up, let it go.
You have been watching too much movies
because the person doesn't even exist.
Even if you go to factories and
try to tailor make, he doesn't exist.
Get that into your head.
How dare you. Pick up.
Pick up.
Shit.
Just stay calm.
This is like a mutiny. It's common.
What's more important now is...
You have to buck up
and carry on with your training.
Such things will go by in a flash.
You will forget about this
before you even know it.
I hate NS.
(NS: National Service.)
Everything will be fine.
Let me give you a way out of this.
Ask him to sign on
with Air Force and be a pilot.
Why does he need to be a pilot?
It's a way to get out of NDU.
Are you sure?
Of course, many people
have thought of this before.
Sir.
After serious consideration, I have decided.
I want to join the Air Force
to be a fighter pilot.
I want to fly, not swim.
Good future, Ken Chow.
Thank you, sir.
I think so too.
I will inform the OC first thing
tomorrow morning.
But a gentle reminder to you.
While you are still here,
you will still have to follow with
every single training.
No excuses.
Understand me?
Yes, sir.
Get lost.
Thank you, sir.
48. Hurry up. Muster.
Lobang, is it red enough?
Can you stop doing this?
Each time you said you are sick,
no one believes you.
You need talent to act.
Plus the fact that you are so big sized.
Even acting skills can't help you.
Hurry up. Muster.
Muster.
Ken. Don't mind,
I'll share something with you.
Let me share with you
what I learned from tuition.
Tuition?
Yes, Special Force tuition.
Number one, focus on your training.
Number two, teamwork.
Don't sabotage your batch mates
is also considered as teamwork.
Are you referring to yourself?
No, I'm just sharing
what I learned from tuition.
I am just sharing the tips.
Don't worry, be happy.
Not war, make love.
With you?
No, please don't get me wrong.
It's with us.
Aloysius, don't make me laugh.
Yeah, the pot calling the kettle black.
Warrant Ong.
Hooyah Warrant Ong.
Hooyah.
Okay 48, before we go for training,
is anyone not feeling well?
No, sir.
Sir.
I think I may have a bit of sore eyes.
Ken Chow.
Last night pilot.
This morning sore eyes.
Since you are such a sick little duckling,
while the rest of 48 goes for training,
you will stand in this position
for the next 15 minutes.
After the time ends,
if there is still soreness in your eyes,
I will release you to the MO.
(MO: Medical Officer.)
I need one volunteer
to make intimate eye contact
with Mr. Ken Chow here
to verify the soreness of his eyes
and escort him to the MO later.
Any volunteers?
Me, sir.
Aloysius, why is it always you?
The whole batch 48 only has one guy?
Yes. No.
48, no team spirit right?
Except for you.
Whole lot drop.
Sir, I will drop too. Team spirit.
Down.
1, 2...
Today is day one of your
Combat Diver Course.
The paddle presented to you
signifies that you are now
a new breed of men.
Let honor, integrity
and team spirit be your guide.
I wish all of you the best of luck
in your CDC.
I will now hand you over
to your course Warrant
who is more than capable to train,
motivate and guide each and everyone of you.
He is non other than Second Warrant B T Lum.
Call sign
No. 2.
I thought he is gone. What is he doing here?
Damn.
Sir.
They are all yours, Lum.
Thank you, sir.
48.
I heard that you are a bunch of dirtbags
with a lot of clowns in it.
If you think BMT was tough,
you better think again.
Because in CDC
the only easy day was yesterday.
The training in CDC
is much tougher than BMT.
It is more physical and mentally demanding.
And the instructors here are all crazy.
They push us to our
maximum limit all the time.
No. 2 said, the only easy day was yesterday.
Even for a person so well prepared, like me.
I could feel that the toughest day
is the following day.
I really can't imagine for the other
unprepared people.
CDC to me now is...
Confirm die course.
Shag?
I can control one batch single-handedly.
Eight of you can't even control a boat.
What's wrong with you?
Tired?
How about giving you two more people?
-Can you?
-Can.
Of course can.
Damn You. You short-lived bastard.
Incompetent idiot.
Ham Ka Chan.
If I don't stick you on the wall,
I'll change my name.
Don't think about it.
Let's go work out and it will be fine.
I didn't feel good at all
when I was up on the boat.
I felt so guilty.
Shut up. Stop talking.
You are really asking for it.
If it was the past,
you would be invited to a party.
-What party?
-Blanket party.
Hello?
Guys?
Anyone around?
Open up, stop playing.
If the instructor sees me naked,
we will all be punished.
Hurry up, open.
Guys, please open the door. Stop playing.
If the instructor sees me,
we'll be punished for nothing again.
Please open the door. I am sorry.
Yes?
Thank you.
Please open the lock.
I want to open the cupboard
and take my clothes.
Please give me my keys.
Please guys, I sincerely
apologise to all of you.
I know I sabotage you guys just now.
I didn't do it on purpose.
I promise I won't do it again.
Hei-long please.
You know it's not my fault.
Not your fault? So it's mine?
No, it's my fault.
You idiot. Listen carefully.
If you sabotage us one more time,
one more time,
I will throw your keys
onto the parade square
and make you go run and pick that up naked.
-You understand?
-Okay.
Stupid fool.
Hi guys, thank you.
Actually I just want you all to know that
I've learned a very valuable lesson
from each one of you today.
And it has helped me in my growing up.
If you don't mind,
Warrant Ong has warned us before
there is no gambling.
Shut up.
-In cabin.
-Shut up.
Okay, I'll shut up.
Sorry, just to let you guys know.
I am the best batch mate that you can trust.
I know that you guys love your game and
I support.
I will be pretending to read
my book outside.
I will be your lookout
in case instructors come
and spot check on us.
I will make sure you guys
get to play in a safe
and friendly environment.
Hooyah.
Get out.
Cards.
Walao Ong.
Hooyah Warrant Ong.
Good evening, sir.
You called me old man Ong?
Do I look like your father?
No, it's Warrant Ong.
Something fishy must be going on.
On your feet.
So gentlemen, what nonsense
are you up to today?
-Smoking?
-No, sir.
-Pornography?
Outside food?
No, sir.
I'll give you my words as a gentleman.
I swear to God that
they are not doing any of those things.
And they are also not gambling.
Gambling.
So, what were they doing?
We were singing hymns.
Bible reading and making prayers.
And evoking the blessing of God
for each one of us
to pass the upcoming team building week.
So holy.
We even shared some inspiring
and meaningful bible stories
like this one.
Don't be shy.
I am about to share with you...
Moses opened the Red Sea.
Isn't this a bible?
I can still explain.
I suck.
Hurry up.
What the hell are you doing?
Boat One and Two.
It is obvious that you guys are showing me
you are taking my kindness as a weakness.
I don't care who you think you are outside.
Once you are in NDU,
you jolly well learn to play by our rules.
Since you guys want to show me
that you don't know how to change your ways.
Tonight we will do something
to get every single one of you
dirtbags accustomed to changing.
On your feet. On your back.
Change to your No. 4 now.
You guys have 5 mins to change
into your wet suit.
Change to wet suit.
On your back.
1, 2...
Is this the standard
you are going to show me?
No, sir.
-What do you want to be?
-Diver, sir.
Change to your No. 4 now.
Flutter kick position, ready.
1, 2, 3...
Hold it there.
I said hold it there.
Jumping jack position, ready.
1, 2, 3...
Change to wet suit.
Unlike army training.
Our training is basically done
under the five S condition.
Sun.
Sea.
Sand.
Sweat.
And shit.
Wet and sandy. Not taking a swim.
Boy scouts move faster than you.
Not just extra PT.
But they also treat us the infamous
NDU crushed peanut mochi.
Who the heck named such a sick punishment
over one of my favourite food?
Ever since Ken found out that
his girlfriend had dumped him
for a commando.
He became very frustrated with his training.
And I seriously think that his attitude
will eventually get him into deep trouble.
I hate tyre PT.
You don't have to like it.
You just have to do it.
Come on. Let's go.
Up...
-Understand?
-Yes, sir.
Do you understand?
Flip it.
You weak piece of crap.
What are you doing?
Flip it.
What's with that pathetic face of yours?
What are you doing?
Flip it. You weak piece of crap.
With that big body of yours,
what can you do?
Shut up. I have had enough of your shit.
What's the point of this useless training?
You can't win a war by flipping tyres.
-Really?
-This is pointless.
I am already pulling out,
giving my 100 percent.
And you still want to give me shit.
I am better than all you instructors.
You guys are from NATO.
No action, talk only.
Ken Chow, lock it up.
What's all these commotion about?
Ken Chow here says he can out perform
all of us instructors.
I am impressed, Ken Chow.
So, are you issuing me a challenge?
Sir, I am just telling the truth.
The truth?
The truth is going to hurt you really bad.
You know what?
Since all of us are so incapable...
He is younger and fitter than I am.
Tell you what, why don't you challenge me?
To a tyre race.
I will give you a 20 metre head start.
Parade Square. Five minutes.
No, sir.
Sure, sir. Let's go.
3, 2, 1.
Go.
Go, Ken...
Hurry up.
Ken, go.
Watch out.
Move back.
Leave him alone.
Don't touch him.
Move back.
You wanted to challenge me, right?
Let me tell you.
You're the worst challenge
I've ever had in my life.
Stand at attention when I am talking to you.
Stand up.
Yes, sir.
This is the top one percent.
You are not even worth to be here.
From day one when you step
through the gates of NDU,
I have been watching you.
Making calls.
Texting.
You think I didn't see all these.
Every other training.
You were skiving,
finding excuses.
You think I don't know all these.
Ken Chow.
You reported sick twelve times.
DIY sore eyes.
Decompression sickness.
From head to toe.
You had every other bloody problems.
Do you think this is
a summer camp?
I will not take your shit
and your stinking attitude.
NDU is only for the elite.
It's your wish to get out of course.
Join the Air Force and be a pilot.
You know what?
I will personally write your appraisal
and the Air Force will hear about
your shitty attitude.
You want to fly?
You can only fly a kite.
You don't deserve to be here.
You want to get out of course.
No need for you to think
so hard from now on.
Ken Chow.
You
are.
out.
Ken, lucky you.
Finally you are no longer a frogman.
You are a free man, bro.
Congrats.
You are finally out of hell.
It's right that you go.
The only thing you know
is to act sick.
As if the world owes you a living.
Your departure
is really a win-win for everyone.
Good job.
Thanks.
Since you like to act sick so often,
the instructors will definitely
tell the Air Force.
The Air Force may not approve
your transfer at all.
-Are you sure?
-Yes.
Land, Air and Sea.
They all share the same database.
Wait, how do you know?
I read it in my book.
Whatever. It doesn't matter.
When I go to the Air Force,
it will be a brand new start.
New man. New attitude.
New me. Trust me.
Ken, let me analyse it for you.
It may feel good to be out of course.
But have you given it a thought?
If your girlfriend
and her current boyfriend find out
that you are being kicked out,
they will probably laugh at you.
Why so?
Because you prove them right.
You are childish and immature.
That's why you are out.
I am serious.
And this great story of yours
will be told by that baldy
until the day he retires.
Your name in NDU
will definitely be more famous
than that frog in Parade Square.
I am not kidding you.
Yeah, think about it.
If I were your girlfriend,
-I would dump you too.
-Why?
Because you suck
and have no backbone.
That's why she looks for a commando
and made you a cuckold.
Chill it, bro.
What I am saying is the truth.
And the truth hurts.
Yes, the truth hurts.
Life is harsh.
So what do you want me to do?
I have already screwed it up so much.
There is no going back for me.
Completing the CDC is the only way
to save your girlfriend
and save your face.
Yeah, faster apologise to No. 2
and beg him to let you stay in the course
and better make sure you complete it.
This is the first time he talks sense.
You better listen.
No. 2.
There is no way in hell
I am going to apologise to that baldy.
We divers are not like that.
If I were you.
I would definitely complete my CDC.
And during my graduation,
I will magnanimously invite both of them
to attend my ceremony
to see how I shine.
It will be like slapping them
on their faces.
Then you get posted to Air Force
and become a pilot.
That will be another slap.
One on the left, another on the right.
Smack her prim and proper.
Besides, you can prove that baldy wrong.
Make him drop hair in anger.
Shed his eyebrows too.
Well said.
Actually this is exactly what I want to say.
Shameless.
You are just taking others' words.
I am really going to stick you on the wall.
Go sleep.
Lights off.
Excuse me, sir.
Yes?
Sir.
Can you help me?
Why are you wasting your time
on this kind of scumbag?
He is really a dirtbag.
His stinking attitude will only
bring the entire 48 down.
Sir, I am vouching for him because
when he came to see me,
he seems very sincere about changing.
Alex.
If he screws up this time,
I will take full responsibility.
Alex,
this time,
last time,
next time...
A leopard will never change its spots.
And his bloody stinking attitude,
his negative attitude towards training
and everything else
will only bring the entire school down
and it's a disgrace to NDU.
Seriously,
I gave him the opportunity
to get out of my course.
He jolly well get the hell out.
Sir.
What are you doing here?
Please hear me out.
I know I used to make excuses
and had a messed up attitude.
I was childish and immature.
But I have realised my mistakes.
I want to change.
All I need is one chance.
Ken Chow, your one chance came.
It's for you to get out of my course.
With your stinking attitude
and your negativity
you'll only bring the whole
entire 48 batch down.
If I let you stay here,
you will be a disgrace to NDU.
Sir. Yes, I admit.
I used to make excuses.
But I'm actually very fit
and I will prove it to you.
I will run 20 rounds
around the Parade Square.
30.
50.
I'll run 50 rounds right now.
Round 5.
Round 15.
Round 30.
If he completes 50 rounds,
he has a chance to stay.
At least he is fighting for it now.
He is doing the right thing.
Hooyah.
Hey guys. It's raining.
This is only round 33.
I'm sure he can't complete 50 rounds.
Definitely out of course.
Ken.
Sir.
You can stop. It is raining.
Is it category one?
No.
Sir, I shouldn't be afraid of
a little water.
Please let me finish it.
Okay. Let's do it together.
Come on guys, don't be shy.
It's time to show some team spirit.
Hooyah.
Guys, what happened?
We are 48.
We are the same batch. We are the same boat.
If Ken can do it, so can we. Yes, we can.
Eat shit.
Never mind.
We cannot.
Round 48.
Round 49.
Round 50.
Who else but we? Somebody tell me.
Who else but we?
Goin' step up to the plate for my city SG?
Naval divers.
We fight on through the plight.
All day.
To righteously earn the right. Everyday.
To call ourselves
masters of the deep, naval diver pride.
Hooyah!
We dem boys from the Navy.
Better known as frogmen.
We be training all day,
rolling wet in the sand.
There's a reason we're the baddest
from the Sea, Air, Land.
Nothing stands in our way.
Cos to us the only easy day was yesterday.
With my brothers at the grinder,
gettin' hammered all day.
Build a body harder
than a rock for the ladies.
48.
Wake up your idea.
Watch where you are swimming.
Keep to this side.
You want to keep swimming to your right.
Want to go Sembawang park
to book out, is it?
But how can I leave my brothers
to suffer themselves?
We were taught to live by that hit.
Honour. Team spirit. Integrity.
The more we get together,
the stronger we be.
Cos we're the best of the best.
Well done, Ken Chow.
That's the way.
Stick with the programme.
You can do it. Come on.
Alex, it's only day one of his redemption.
It's a long journey.
Don't worry, sir.
I believe he can do it.
He is my man.
We fight on through the plight. All day.
To righteously earn the right. Everyday.
To call ourselves,
masters of the deep, naval diver pride.
Hooyah!
Hey mom.
Everything is okay. Trust me.
I will talk to you tomorrow.
I know.
Love you.
Good night.
Bro.
Can you lend me a screwdriver?
How much?
It's free.
Thanks.
Hey Lobang. Anything to share?
What's all these for?
Drill a few holes in your boots
to let the water out.
Hell week is five long days.
Our feet will be soaked.
It will definitely rot.
So bad. Spouting vulgarity.
Don't think we don't understand.
Gentlemen.
As you all know, I am not a vulgar person.
But for this word,
I can vouch that it is not a vulgarity.
He is talking about foot rot
and it is not a vulgarity.
Just like my name.
Jin Seah-lan, it is not a vulgarity.
So please don't be offended by his foot rot
and please take foot rot seriously.
What the foot rot are you talking about?
You are making it worse.
-Go sit down.
-Back.
Come.
5 dollars each.
Lifetime guarantee.
Remember to pay up.
Lobang, why does everyone have a screw?
Can you give me a screw?
Screwdriver.
You know how to screw?
Don't worry. I am an expert in screwing.
Go screw yourself.
-Thank you.
-Handsome.
Yes.
Lobang, you really understand me.
I didn't have time to buy this.
I know. We can't shower for five days
during Hell week.
At least you can wash your face with this.
3-in-1 mud foam plus serum.
You will be more handsome.
Thank you for your concern.
Thank you for your contribution.
-Remember to pay.
-Okay.
Don't be crazy.
How are you going to
bring this to Hell week?
We will all be punished if you are caught.
Don't underestimate me.
Our instructors always have
lots of creative ideas
for us to play with our boats.
Double boats carry.
Triple boats carry.
Double strenuous and triple hard.
Now training is getting more
and more grueling each day.
We're all trying very hard to adapt to it.
As for Hei-long and me,
we still can't adapt to each other.
Boat 2 chain push-up.
Sorry.
Are you trying to be funny?
What's your problem?
He kicked me in the face.
Do I look like I give a shit?
Get into position.
Sorry.
Boat 2, I just need you guys
to give me one good push-up.
Carry on.
You bloody idiot.
Did I kill your family
in your previous life?
Why are you always stepping on my toes?
Translate?
For Hokkien, I can.
For Cantonese, I am trash.
Come on, it's obviously an accident.
Just give him a break.
Yes, Hei-long, I am sorry.
It's all an accident.
My friend.
It was just a nudge.
Are you a girl?
Look at him. He was just giddy
so he accidentally hit you.
Look at his timid face.
He wouldn't dare to mess with you.
Don't make me laugh.
Can't you see?
Even my little bro is laughing at you.
Stop your bullshit
or I will stick you to the wall.
Come if you dare.
I am sorry. It's all my fault.
Please do not fight.
We are batch mates and even cabin mates.
Not war. Make love.
I can't stand you anymore.
I am going to stick you on the wall tonight.
Stick to the wall.
Don't stop them.
Now he got himself onto the wall.
So this is called sticking to the wall.
I had enough of you.
Bloody hell.
From the first day you came,
you think you are the boss.
Everybody should suck up to you.
Everybody should be bullied by you.
You think just because you have a tattoo
everyone should be afraid of you.
You know what is the medical term
for your condition?
ADABHD.
Asshole don't know anything but only
know how to bully and arrogant disorder.
We kept quiet not because
we are weaker than you
but because we have better EQ than you.
Idiot.
Let me tell you something.
I grew up learning martial arts.
Boxing. Judo. Muay Thai.
and Chinese kung fu.
MMA, Jeet Kune Do.
I am good at everything
but why was I willing to be bullied by you?
Because I pity you.
One pathetic loser
with no love and no real friends.
You've got no love from your mommy.
You've got no love from your daddy.
I think you only got love
from your gang of scums.
You only know how to shout
and throw your temper
just to cover up your feeling
of inferiority.
You are one pathetic bastard.
Aren't you very good at talking back?
If I am wrong, tell me.
Hit me here. Hit me if you want.
Sorry guys.
I am not a violent person.
I'm actually a very kind
and easy going person.
My mother gave birth to me
not to be bullied by you.
Don't blame me for talking too much.
Our training is hard enough.
Don't fight over little things like this.
It's endless.
I saw you quarrelling with your parents
when we were enlisting.
Believe me.
We all have family problems.
Yours is no big deal.
Let it go. We are all brothers.
I will treat you to supper.
Where was it delivered the last time?
Side gate.
Between the two trees.
Be careful. That is my secret passage.
Don't let things go wrong.
You are calling for delivery?
It's very dangerous.
No guts? Then don't eat.
I want to eat.
I want it, too.
Engaged.
Call Panther.
Ask him to buy.
Boss, I am here.
Where are you?
No one's here.
I see him.
Can I help you?
Are you from batch 48?
Yes.
Why?
Your order is here.
Bread Talk?
Toast Box?
Over here.
Don't tell me you are an
instructor?
There are no bald instructors.
Only men are shaved.
You are right.
But you look
kind of old.
To tell you the truth.
I am actually nineteen.
Nineteen?
Okay.
Who asked you to buy these?
These...
You are trying to test me.
How can I tell you?
It's the one who asked you here, of course.
Don't think I am a fool?
I am also NDU.
You are NDU?
Night Delivery Unit.
Okay.
Are you sure you are not an instructor?
Just believe me. Hurry.
Hurry.
You really look damn old.
Thank you.
Be careful.
Be careful, don't let any instructors
spot you.
You too.
Look out for cars when you cross the road.
Bread Talk.
Toast Box.
Damn.
Panther is really dumb.
He handed our supper to No. 2.
He is coming up now. What do we do?
What?
Tell everyone to turn their lights off
and pretend to sleep.
Lights off.
Sleeping so early.
The delivery is here.
Muster now.
We are dead this time.
Coffee, tea or me?
Divers, why are you sleeping so early?
Here's your delivery.
Muster now.
Shit.
Come.
Don't be afraid.
We are divers.
Home of the brave and courageous.
Don't be scared, come.
I am very sorry gentlemen.
I have to wake you up
in the middle of the night.
Deprive you of 8 hours of sleep,
knowing tomorrow will be
a very strenuous day.
I am very sorry that the Navy cannot cook
to your taste buds' liking.
Until you have to engage in
this kind of high risk operation
to ask outside NDU
to deliver to our NDU.
You don't know what is outside NDU?
Night Delivery Unit.
You go through so much trouble
might as well eat, am I right?
Don't waste everybody's effort.
Eat.
Don't understand?
Eat!
Eat.
Still don't understand?
Eat, bro.
Eat. Don't you understand?
Good boys, eat the food.
The bread is very nice.
Let's eat.
Still don't understand?
Cannot be.
Bread Talk. Toast Box. Very nice.
You're happy, I'm happy, tummy happy.
Everybody happy.
Eat.
Take.
Why?
Jaws locked?
Brains hang?
Eat.
Enjoy it. Eat.
Gentlemen, it's okay. Come on, eat.
I give you permission to eat. Eat.
Just because of your stupid stomachs,
you want to break the system of rules
and regulations we have here.
Getting outside food in here to be consumed.
I promise you, 48, every single one of you.
I am going to hammer you
until someone stands up
to admit he is the culprit.
Okay, boys. Awesome.
None of you want to own up right?
8 counts of bodybuilder.
48, good job. Well done.
After an hour
you are still able to endure all these.
Good on you.
I am happy that our training has paid off.
Because of your stupidity,
your hunger and your stomachs,
you are willing to sacrifice
the whole entire batch.
Selfish bloody individual.
Gentlemen, you better wake up your idea.
and whoever this coward is,
you better admit it.
Show me integrity and be a man.
Sir.
It's me.
After one hour of hammering,
finally a hero is born.
Good job.
Sir.
It was me,
not Lobang.
What is this?
Drama series?
Fighting to be heroes?
So touching.
Any other accomplices?
No more heroes?
If not, the whole lot recover.
Yes, sir.
Gentlemen,
for condoning the culprit
you were punished for over an hour.
But I also see your determination
not to betray your teammates.
And for that
I am impressed.
But, here in NDU,
we have rules to follow.
You
do not do things your own way here.
As a Navy diver,
you should know what is right
and what is wrong.
Yet you went ahead to do it.
This is not part of our core values.
No matter what wrong you've done previously.
From now on,
exercise caution in all that you do.
-Is that clear?
-Yes, sir.
We've already passed out from our BMT.
You are still not giving up?
Bro, you won't understand.
I am not going to give up so easily.
I underestimated you.
You go, bro.
You want some?
Lobang, Hei-long.
Sorry, I suck.
I should have stood up
and admit it last night.
You ended up taking the blame for this.
Actually I really don't feel like
going back.
Or else, let me stay back too.
Are you crazy?
We would have taken the blame for nothing.
Go home.
Yeah, stop wasting time.
Just book out and go home.
It's okay, don't feel bad.
We are all brothers.
Next time, my turn.
Hei-long, Lobang.
Thanks for saving us.
Stop saying all these.
I have thought about it.
To repay you.
It is dangerous for your sister
to be alone tonight.
I will sacrifice myself.
Let me go protect her.
Don't try to be a good man with me.
It is even more dangerous
to have you there with her.
Don't worry.
I will go with him. Confirm safe.
Don't be a busybody.
Anyway.
I am not here to ask for permission.
I am just informing you.
Don't ever come back here.
Book out.
Let's go.
Go, book out.
Hello?
Radio check?
Handphone check? Over.
Over and out.
You can't even call out.
There is not even a connection.
What is wrong with you?
I have told you many times.
Before you buy a handphone, ask me.
Don't act smart.
Half of the salesmen out there
are just to con you.
But dear,
the guy was very convincing.
He said that there is
the international warranty.
And you believe what he says.
How now?
How?
Howl. Cry.
But then,
where is your receipt?
No receipt.
No receipt?
How do I help you without a receipt?
How do I launch a complaint?
You are really
more hopeless than my trainees.
That guy was so cunning.
You are just blur, period.
Dear, I am not as blur as you think.
I took a photo of that guy.
Where?
This one.
Stop. Hold it there.
Very good.
Wait.
Wear this.
Lobang.
Is this you?
Sir.
Where did you get this photo from?
Lobang, I don't care
what you do in the past.
Now you are a diver.
I am telling you this.
We have our core values.
I have told you many times before.
As a bloody diver,
we swim in order.
In life too, we have to be honourable.
When we swim, we swim straight.
As a person, we cannot be crooked.
I don't make you shout your core values
so many times a day for no reason.
Lobang, if I shortchange you
for your boat PT everyday,
can you take that?
We are here to protect
the people of this country.
We are here to protect everybody.
We will live and die by our core values.
Do you even remember our core values?
Yes, sir.
We, the frogmen of the Navy.
Demolition trained.
Rough and rugged bunch of warriors.
There's nothing we can't do.
We will overcome our enemies.
Nothing stands in our way.
We, the frogmen of the Navy.
Hooyah.
For us go deep.
What do you want?
Titbits, please.
Help yourself.
-Lobang.
-Hang on.
Damn.
What's wrong?
What happened?
Lobang's sister is in trouble.
No answer.
No one is picking up?
No...
Do you want my mom to
go to your place for a look?
Or do you want her to help you
call the police first?
She is very free.
I know how to call the police too.
I just don't want to blow this matter up.
No. I need to go out.
I am going to look for Warrant Ong.
You have to tell me the reason
before I can let you book out.
Sir, I can't tell you now.
It is not a small matter.
Okay, wait.
Thank you, sir.
Warrant Lum.
Sorry to disturb you at this hour.
Our man Lobang is here and
he seems to have
a very serious family issue.
May I have permission to release him?
Did his mother die?
Your mother die?
-No, sir.
-No.
Did his father die?
Your father die?
Died long time ago, sir.
He said he's been dead for some time.
House on fire?
Your house on fire?
No, sir.
I think it is really
a very serious family issue.
He looks very anxious.
If he is not going to tell us
the real reason,
then I am sorry, I can't let him book out.
Furthermore, we have a very important
diving lesson tomorrow morning.
And they need at least 8 hours of rest.
But, sir...
You should know that this man
is a professional con man.
Plus liar,
an ostensible star.
I think he needs to book out
to do some business outside.
Only when he is willing to
tell us the truth.
If not, I will not let him book out.
Alright, sir.
Sorry to disturb you.
Why don't you tell them the truth?
I cashed in on his girlfriend before.
He won't believe me.
Even if he believes me,
he will ask me to make a police report.
I can't make a police report.
I need to go out to resolve this.
How are you going to resolve this?
Are you going to sneak out?
If not, how?
You should know
how heavily guarded the gates are.
The fences are high and with barbed wires.
There are CCTV everywhere.
How can you get out?
Is there really no way out?
Do you dare?
Are you really going to do this?
This is a serious matter.
I know.
But for my family,
I don't have a choice.
You won't understand.
Family.
Be careful.
Let's go.
Family.
Are you okay?
I am good
especially with no No. 2 bellowing behind.
A night swim is much enjoyable.
Sorry to drag you into this.
Don't say that. Let's go.
No matter who you are.
Your actions are dangerous.
Indicate your position now.
(Sembawang shipyard.)
48, stand by bed, now.
Wei.
Okay...
Mother came back to ask me for money.
I don't have any money, she hit me.
Give me money.
Mom.
Get some ropes.
Sorry aunty.
Mom.
You did this...
You unfilial son.
Lobang.
I am in so much pain.
Give me money.
I really...
Mom.
Give me money...
If you are not going to give me the money,
when you go back to camp
you will regret.
Mother.
What do you want me to do?
You have to call the police.
This is a grave matter.
If I can, I would have told No. 2.
How can I turn my own mother in?
Hooyah.
Don't call the police.
Please don't...
Police.
You unfilial son.
You really called the police
to arrest your mother.
How could you?
You ungrateful brat.
Settled?
Yes, sir.
Let's go.
Lobang, Wei-ming.
Good buddy.
Hero.
Hey guys.
Go change to your Smart 4
and muster downstairs in 15 minutes.
The OC wants to speak to you.
Yes, sir.
Sorry to drag you guys in.
It's okay, let's go.
48 watch your front, 48 attention.
Good evening, sir.
Good evening.
Class 48 IC Diver Tan Zhi-hao
reporting strength.
Total strength 80, present strength 80.
Very good.
Stand your men at ease and join your class.
Permission to carry on, sir.
Carry on.
48 watch your front, 48 at ease.
Gentlemen,
I believe you are already aware
of what happened earlier tonight.
Diver Lobang asked for permission
to book out.
But he did not provide valid reasons.
And as such, his request was turned down.
He saw no alternatives
but to leave the camp without permission.
And he knew
he could not get pass the front
guardroom without detection,
so he did it by sea.
Putting what he learned here to use.
Risking his life
together with Diver Wei-ming
in order to save his sister.
Unauthorised absence is a serious offence.
But I also saw
team spirit between them.
And that is what we teach you here in NDU.
Diver Lobang broke the rules
in order to do the right thing.
And that raises the moral dilemma.
How do we choose
between doing the right things
and doing things right?
Lobang
was wrongfully right.
Yet
rightfully wrong.
And so, we have to take
the necessary actions.
-Lum.
-Yes, sir.
Take over.
Yes, sir.
Diver Lobang, front and centre.
Explain to me.
Why did you jeopardise your life
and the life of your swim buddy
by taking the most dangerous route?
Sir.
I knew it would be impossible for me
to escape through the front gate
because there were too many guards on duty.
But, sir, you know what?
When I was about to give up
I saw the frogman from the sea
pointing his finger at the top
of the HQ building.
Then I realised
that was the message
from the frogman from the sea.
Telling me that as a diver
I shouldn't give up easily
because nothing stands in my way.
But at that point of time,
I still don't know what to do
until I saw it fly.
Really, sir.
I saw it flew across the Parade Square,
over the top of the HQ building
towards the sea.
Then suddenly I realised the hidden message.
I remembered what you said before.
If you swim towards the right,
you will reach Sembawang Park
and we can book out straight from there.
That's where I booked out.
No, sir.
That's where I escaped.
So now you are blaming me for teaching you
to take the most dangerous route
to leave camp. Is that so?
No, sir.
Then?
Sir.
It's not dangerous
until you forget that it is.
We never forget that.
We did it very carefully.
If it is easy, we don't want to do it
and we are trained for it.
Sir, the sea is our comfort zone.
The sea is our domain.
Danger is our business.
I really had no choice, sir.
Lobang, I am very impressed
that you hold all our divers' core values
in your heart and in your head.
Join back your class.
Thank you, sir.
48.
As your course warrant,
it is my responsibility
to train you hard.
But at the same time,
I will not overlook your safety.
I trained you to be divers.
What Lobang and Wei-ming did
is something I refuse to accept.
By putting your lives at danger,
it's really jeopardising this entire course.
It is also my responsibility
to understand your problems.
If I cannot solve your problems,
I can guarantee you
the next in rank
following the chain of command
will be able to.
It takes a man courage to admit his mistake.
And I admit.
I did not understand Lobang's problems.
For every mistake
there will be a punishment.
I have no excuse for my mistake.
For that,
I will punish myself
by doing a hundred push-ups.
48. One for all.
All for one.
What do you want to eat?
I will bring back for you tomorrow.
It's okay, I have meat jerky.
Enjoy your weekend.
Lobang, sitting down?
No, sir.
Seven extras not enough.
You want me to upsize?
No, sir.
Handle your weapon properly, understand?
Yes, sir.
Good afternoon, sir.
What's so good about afternoon?
Can't you see I am on duty?
You F.O.
UFO?
The whole lot of you
F.O.
Yes, sir.
Don't worry, we'll take care
of your sister for you.
-Thank you.
-Hey guys.
Lobang's sister is very pretty.
Too bad, she's mine.
You can ask him if you don't believe me.
Right, my in-law?
In-law my foot.
Don't be shameless.
I'm just joking.
Illegal gathering?
If you don't want to leave,
you can all stay with me for duties.
Ten seconds to get out of my face.
10.
7.
5.
-3.5.
-Enjoy your weekend, sir.
2.22.
1.25.
Good afternoon, sir.
Hello.
What time will you be back?
I can't make it tonight.
I'm on urgent duty.
You got extra duty?
Wake up your idea.
It's him.
Boss. How come you didn't inform us
that you are out?
We could have gone to get you.
Anyway.
He is our boss now.
You understand, right?
It's like in the army.
When there is no sergeant,
there will be an acting sergeant.
When you are not around,
we have an acting boss too.
Come over and have a chicken wing.
What is the meaning of this?
They owe us money. You used to do this too.
Stand up and leave here.
Hey!
These are my men.
How dare you ask them to leave?
What do you take me for?
Their mothers gave birth to them,
not to be bullied by you.
Boss, you shaved off your head
to be a soldier or to be a monk?
Your compassion frightens me.
If you want to bring them away,
then make sure you can win me in a fight.
Boss. Actually we knew from the start,
he wouldn't win you in this fight.
-Right?
-Yes.
We are still the
Six Beasts of Tiong Bahru, right?
I announce
Six Beasts of Tiong Bahru...
Disband.
Boss.
Settled?
Settled.
Yes.
Did you do the right thing?
Yeah. I feel really good now.
Great.
Hooyah.
Fire in the hole.
Stay with...
Move.
This is the moment that
all divers are waiting for.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the Hell week
begins.
We've heard many rumours about Hell week.
But actually, is this really necessary
for us to go through all these shit
just to prove that we are divers?
Okay, I know that this is
just team work training.
No, I think this is to
test my determination.
I know what they are up to.
They are trying to break me mentally.
They want to see me giving up
but they will never succeed.
I am mentally well prepared.
The only enemy that is going to
stand in my way is me.
Myself.
Get your act together.
Capsize drill now.
Yes, sir.
Boat 2.
It's okay.
We've got the whole weekend
for you to learn.
Slowly.
Can't even flip your bloody boat.
Integrity. You better help each other.
Boat 2.
You're a bunch of sorry souls.
Look at you.
Take your time.
2, 6, up.
Boat 2.
You're like a dirty underwear
hanging outside.
2, 6, up.
Once you have finished your capsize drill,
head back to the shore.
Well done Boat 1.
Boat 2, you better hurry up.
Safety...
Boat 2 take your time.
Never mind.
The hammer is going to drop on you.
Let's go, boat 2.
Boat 2, the boat IC better take charge
and command your boat crew members.
Right now you guys are operating
in a very messy fashion.
Well done Boat 2.
You are the last, again.
Hit the surf now.
I am a naval diver
frogman from the sea.
Hooyah! Nothing stands in our way.
Eat up.
Mom.
I see dead people.
The only time we don't see demons
is during chow time.
We see
only angels.
Because during training
all our instructors
are like devils from hell.
Welcome to CDC.
My territory.
Welcome to hell.
But now.
I think the reason for me to see
so many angels around us.
It's because during the meal time
or what we call the chow time
is the only time when all instructors
stop yelling and pointing
their fingers at us.
But treat us like pampered little babies.
They are like angels to us.
Or at least for the time being.
Excuse me.
Emergency! Very important.
Excuse me, I cannot take it anymore.
How can you take it
without washing your faces for so many days?
Who wants to wash their face?
I've got this 3-in-1
Nivea man mud serum foam.
Let me demonstrate.
Hold this.
First you apply the mud on your face.
The mud will help you unclog your pores.
Then you add water.
The water will help you.
The water will help you
remove the facial oil.
The serum not only hydrates
but brightens up your skin.
It's really easy.
It's very simple.
Now everybody can be like me.
Fresh, new, handsome diver.
Come try.
I think if we can make it in NDU,
we can make it in life.
How about you?
I aim to work at KPMG.
As a GPMG gunner?
KPMG.
As an accountant.
The auditing company.
Wise choice.
I see you have a bright future.
But the daily half an hour
so-called toilet break
is still our favourite activity.
Because we could sleep
pee and shit
without any disturbance
from any instructors.
It's like heaven.
But after that
the same old shit carry on.
Because we are amphibious diver fighters,
we are trained to fight in any terrain.
Sea and land are our comfort zones.
Unlike the army
who do their SOC on land.
(SOC: standard obstacle course.)
We have our very own SOC,
the Sea Circuit.
Both on land and sea.
Double strenuous.
Sea Circuit is like a journey of life to us.
We need to strive to survive.
We need to run,
swim,
climb
and jump.
Clearing all the obstacles in front of us.
Hei-long, hooyah.
Hooyah.
Tonight,
they are going to invite us to spa.
Ice cold spa.
This is the infamous cold treatment.
It's like the ice bucket challenge.
From hell.
And we are all being nominated
by our instructors.
Rough and rugged bunch of warriors.
There's nothing we can't do.
We will overcome our enemies.
Nothing stands in our way.
We, the frogmen of the Navy.
Hooyah.
For us go deep.
Lean back.
Open your eyes.
So, Ken Chow.
I have some good news for you.
Your application to the Air Force
has been approved.
If you want,
you can ring the bell now and join them.
Sir.
Thank you
but no thank you.
I have been through so much.
I'm not going to give up now.
I want to be a naval diver.
I want to swim in the deep blue sea.
Nothing stands in my way.
Not even you, sir.
Good.
That's what I want to hear.
Sir.
What is it? Diver Handsome.
Sorry, sir.
Permission to go toilet.
No, are you trying to slack off?
No, sir, I'm not trying anything.
I really want to go.
Sir.
No need already.
Handsome, you farted?
No, sir.
You shitted?
I have diarrhea.
The fifth sunrise is when we are in
our worst physical and mental condition.
We are like a bunch of zombies
moving around by our instinct only.
Although our morals are high
with only half a day of shit left.
We are still too tired
to feel happy about it.
We just hope that Hell week
could end as soon as possible
because we are so freaking tired.
Last day,
last segment,
last burst of fire,
we have all been pushed to our limits.
Like what No. 2
and all my tuition teachers said.
It's all in our minds.
Our strong mental power
is now taking over our physical fitness.
Some say
everybody has their own Hell week in life.
For some,
they were born with it.
They have no choice
but to embrace it.
For some,
They created their own Hell week
and made themselves suffer from it,
wasting time and effort
and gained nothing from it.
This stupidity and retardation
is really what they asked for.
But this is how they grow
and grow in the hard way.
After these five days in hell,
nobody is the best here.
We are better than the best.
Hell week
or just a small hurdle in life
really depends on how you interpret it,
handle it and overcome it.
Never give up
is what we've learned these five days.
Pain is weakness leaving our bodies.
The tougher the instructors push us,
the tougher we are.
To those before me,
to those here with me,
to those that come after me.
God, please make me
worthy of the frogmen brotherhood.
48. Muster here now.
Class 48.
Hooyah.
Are you ready to secure?
Yes, sir.
Are you tired?
No, sir.
That's not good enough.
Go get wet and sandy now.
For the past five days,
all of you
have undergone the toughest training
in the SAF.
You are the elite frogmen of the Navy.
You will always remember
in the darkest and lowest time of your life.
You will always remember this day
as the most defining moment of your life.
And you will be able to overcome
any adversity that confronts you.
I
declare
Hell week secure.
Tough times don't last
but tough men do.
I finally realised the meaning of
nothing stands in our way.
We were all chosen
for a very special reason.
When we could overcome
the high demand in both our
mental and physical abilities,
what hurdle in life that
we could not overcome?
Nothing.
Absolutely nothing
could break us anymore.
Well done. Good job.
Thank you, sir.
Well done.
Son.
Well done, finally.
Hey guys, they are my parents
and they are my good friends.
Hello uncle. Hello aunty.
Not war, make love.
Very cute.
Come, let me put this on for you.
Son, I didn't know
your training is so tough.
Good job, son.
You did it. It must be hard on you.
Not at all.
In fact,
it was tougher on you both.
You have grown up.
Thank you, mom.
Smart boy.
How can they do this to my baby boy?
Your training is so ridiculously difficult.
Do you want mommy to go complain?
Mom.
This is elite training.
Your son is an elite frogman now.
He is an elite frogman. Understand?
What is elite?
Like a whole truckload of durian,
the best one among them all.
That is elite.
Understand?
Grandma. It's the Elite Force.
Elite.
Elite Force.
What is Elite Force?
Grandma.
-So cute.
-Take photo.
Wait. Let me put this on first.
Okay.
-Hi Wei-ming, congratulations.
-Thank you.
Hi Wei-ming, we are here to support you.
We know that training has been tough.
We are very proud of you.
Thank you so much.
I didn't expect you two to come tonight.
Thanks for coming.
You are the commando in the photo.
What photo?
You told me that I couldn't find anyone
with a positive mindset towards NS.
I found one
and he is the one.
Your new boyfriend.
Boyfriend? Me?
No.
We are cousins.
Cousin.
You bird brain. You hear that?
I knew the commando brothers are dependable.
Brilliant.
You go to hell.
Congratulations.
Thanks.
Excellent.
Thank you.
Sir.
Whose record is better than No. 2?
I really want to know who No. 1 is.
He was a British naval diver.
He set the record in 1963.
What was his record compared to No. 2?
More than a minute?
Way longer than that.
Ever since he set the record,
he hasn't been up since.
Who?
Hooyah.
Stay with the programme.
(It should be: why do they catch our Ken?)