What are you doing, Ido?
Spelling "Nazli".
It's the name of my beloved.
Boys!
The teacher is coming.
Put it back in your pants.
I haven't finished spelling it.
What's going on? Come here.
How many times do I have to tell you
not to come here?
This place is dangerous, but here you are.
But we've never fallen.
And they wrote a "U" here.
It's not a "U", it's an "N".
The first letter in his beloved's name.
Go on, we're leaving.
I'll take you to your homes.
How many times do I have to tell you?
This place is dangerous.
Do you know what would happen
if you fell from there?
You'd be gone.
I'll tell your mother about this.
Zeyno!
Yes, Dad?
I've given your hand in marriage
to your cousin Kasim.
Idiot.
Idiot!
They're taking you away tomorrow.
Dad, he is like a brother to me.
For heaven's sake!
Look, I'm your father. You'll do as I say.
Go on. Go back home!
Roll the dice.
-It's not your turn to play.
-It's not?
Good God!
Shit!
Let's see what your mothers think.
What have you done?
Not much. I'm just chilling.
The boys were near the cliffs, again.
Damn it!
Didn't I tell you not to go there?
Why did you do that?
Your clothes are covered in dirt again!
Do I look like a washing machine to you?
Sister Kibar.
Seriously, that place is really dangerous.
Please be careful.
Dangerous?
These kids don't care
about danger, Teacher.
It took three delivery nurses
to deliver this one.
See, he is still in one piece.
What's going on, sister?
These brats of yours
went to the cliffs again.
-Oh?
-Yes, I caught them.
-It's so dangerous.
-Dangerous?
These kids don't care about danger.
Hey! Do I look like
a washing machine to you?
Okay, that's enough.
There will be a meeting
at the school today.
-Okay, I'll bring the second wife with me.
-Sister…
-"Second wife" is politically incorrect.
-So what?
-Say "partner". It's more polite.
-Please.
Have a good day.
-Get in!
-Go on! Get in there!
Come on!
Here we are.
You said it'd be closer to the village.
The village is just beyond that hill.
Is there a bridge?
How am I supposed to get across?
-There is a bridge.
-But it's collapsed.
That's true.
When they built the bridge, they said
it would bring freedom, peace, and unity.
-But that didn't happen.
-What are you on about?
How am I supposed to get across?
Go back to the town,
find someone with a car and come back.
Come back?
-Are you messing with me?
-I'm just kidding.
I'll deliver my cargo
and then I'll take you to Teacher Salih.
Come on!
If you're going to try
to educate us again, I don't want to.
What's the point of teaching us
to read and write?
No, it's not about that.
Take a seat and we'll begin.
-No, they're fine.
-We barely have enough room here.
-I'm talking to the women, Brother Zulfo.
-So?
Don't tire yourself out, Teacher. Really.
We're used to it.
You'll get used to it too.
-When will we get our food supplies?
-What are you doing here, Chief?
You don't have any kids.
Who told you to come?
The classroom belongs to the state.
It's not your property.
What is in the box, Teacher?
We've received some shoes for the kids,
thanks to the city.
-What do the kids need shoes for?
-What about us?
-These won't fit me.
-They're for the kids. Just sit down!
At the beginning of the year,
I called you all for a meeting,
but none of you came.
So I had to lie about the supplies.
I'm sorry about that.
Don't apologize, Teacher.
They're too dumb to get it.
There are some problems with the kids.
Idris, for example.
You always talk about their kids.
Talk a little bit about mine too.
Your kid is smart.
He is just having trouble focusing.
How come?
-How many kids do you have?
-How many kids do I have?
To keep a long story short,
the kids are all lagging behind.
Well, do something about it then.
Mine probably takes after his mom.
Her family isn't very bright.
Well, he is my uncle's son.
Right, and there is that issue.
Marriages within the same families
are problematic. We need to talk about it.
It's really problematic.
You can't beat them, can't curse at them!
They're relatives after all.
Does anyone have a shoehorn?
-There is the bell.
-Get up.
-Let's go.
-Where are you going?
Fits like a glove.
Well, Teacher, I…
Well, let me take these and…
give them to needy people in the village.
Go ahead, Chief.
I'd just take them back anyway.
-Chief?
-Yes?
Where are you taking the shoes?
-They're for the kids!
-Well…
You see, these shoes
are designed for city streets.
It's so rocky here.
It would be a shame to waste these shoes.
You know?
"The man said, 'Some love stories
aren't meant to be finished.'"
"'It wasn't likely to happen,
and it didn't,' replied the woman."
"It was a complete disappointment."
"And then they caught each other's eye,
possibly for the last time."
OATH OF LOVE
-What's wrong?
-So did they break up?
It's just a story, Zeynep.
What if our story ends like that?
Our story?
Don't we have a story?
Yes. Of course we have a story.
We've had a story since the day you came
and took a book from me.
Zeynep?
OATH OF LOVE
-Have you finished it?
-I have not.
Why? You seemed to enjoy it
when I was reading it to you.
I believed it when you were reading it,
but it isn't real.
Don't give me any more books, Teacher.
Why?
Because then I'll believe.
Then I'll believe that love exists
and I'll start to dream.
Love does exist.
Not for me.
There is only pain for me.
My dad has given me to Kasim.
My cousin.
But what about us?
There is no us.
Goodbye, Teacher Salih.
Goodbye.
Goodbye?
What do I do now?
FROM SALIH OZTURK
TO THE MINISTRY OF FAMILY, ANKARA
"To the Republic of Turkey's
Ministry of Family,
I've been working as a teacher
in the village of Elaldi for three years."
"This is the 38th letter
I have sent to the ministry."
"I have reported what happened
in the village after the collapse
of the Freedom and Equality Bridge."
"The people here are so cut off
from the outside world."
"Since the bridge's collapse,
the villagers have resorted to
marrying their cousins."
"And these types of marriages
cause problems,
not just for the families,
but also for the kids."
"I would like the Ministry
to do something about this."
"I kindly request
that you take the necessary action."
"Teacher Salih Ozturk."
Hello, Chief.
Oh, hi. How can I help you?
Is this the food from the supply boxes?
No, it's not.
I swear to God, I gave them to the poor.
-Can you please send this letter ASAP?
-Oh, another letter.
Of course.
Let me see if it smells nice.
Teacher, you know…
you keep writing these letters
to your beloved…
but she never responds, does she?
Just accept it.
She doesn't love you back.
She does not.
ELALDI VILLAGE
MARKET
It's not a girl, it's the state.
And it dislikes us, not just me.
DOSTLAR CAFE
See, there's the teacher.
The one sitting over there,
with a gloomy face.
Go!
-Salih Ozturk?
-Yes, that's me.
I came from Ankara.
I'm from the Ministry. We need to talk.
Welcome.
Please, have a seat.
Brother Hasan, we have a guest
from Ankara. Get us some tea.
There is no tea.
-He said "Ankara".
-Let's go before something bad happens.
You already know what it's about.
You wrote 37 letters.
-Yes, I did.
-Bravo.
The Ministry of Family has been working
on a project for years
to strengthen family values.
To increase the number
of official marriages.
To solve domestic issues
involving wives and children.
To stop consanguineous marriages.
If the project is successful,
we'll apply it on a national level.
That is the project.
Would the villagers accept it?
Villagers! A man from Ankara
has set foot in Elaldi Village,
and he has something important
to tell all of you.
So, everyone, please gather
at the village square.
-Someone from Ankara is here.
-Damn!
From Ankara? Who is he?
How'd he get here?
Did you see him? Who told you?
Just go away.
-Help the kids get dressed.
-Which kids?
Yours or mine?
Well, my kids are so little.
I'll help them get dressed.
Don't look at me like that.
You said it'd be nice
to bring your cousin in.
What can I do?
I thought she would help with the chores,
but she is so dumb. Your mom was right.
She foresaw all this.
-I heard everything.
-So? Help the kids get dressed.
Where is my pink turban?
We have a guest from Ankara.
I should look elegant.
It's not about you.
The men will take care of it.
-I should go and see what it's about.
-I have to see it too.
I'll kill myself to see him if necessary.
Why is an official from Ankara here?
We probably messed up big time.
-What will he say?
-Well, it's obvious.
"Don't do it again,"
or something like that.
Do you see any women here?
Hello, boys.
Good God…
Come on, Zulfo.
-Hello.
-What's going on?
-Hi.
-He came from Ankara?
-What is this about?
They say the man came from Ankara.
Why did he come now,
after all these years?
Here comes your guy.
-He'll make you happy.
-Do you believe that?
No, even I don't.
Teacher! How come the mighty Ankara
could only send one man?
Were you expecting
an army with tanks and planes?
No worries.
The important thing is that he is here.
I've been to Ankara more than once.
Mr. Muzaffer will start talking when
the chief and Brother Cezmi stop talking.
-Teacher! It was Zulfikar's fault.
-What?
Dear people of Elaldi Village,
I'm going to talk to you about
the Ministry of Family's latest project.
The Ministry sent me here
to apply some changes
in accordance with
the Ministry of Family's new project.
I guess they will shit on us
in accordance with the new rules.
This village has been selected
as the project's pilot region.
-What is he saying?
-He says they need pilots.
Planes are so complicated.
I can only drive tractors.
Shut up and just listen.
As you all know, there are still
marriages between cousins
and illegitimate children
are being born every day in this country.
To prevent this from happening,
we will be conducting mass weddings.
Ankara!
These marriages will be for those
who are not related to each other.
Those who are not related? Who?
Who isn't a relative?
-Hey, Ankara?
-I'm listening.
Dear Ankara, are we supposed
to marry non-relatives
and bring strangers into our homes?
My wife is my uncle's daughter.
What am I going to do?
Those who already have kids
will also have weddings,
it doesn't matter
if they are related or not.
The project concerns future marriages.
Sir, whose idea was this?
The Minister of Family.
-The Minister of Family?
-Yes.
Well, I can minister my own family.
Well, I'm already officially married.
I've wasted my time here.
I thought Ankara would have
something important to say.
Bringing strangers into our homes?
Shame.
Bringing a stranger into my house?
I don't get it.
Those who meet the criteria
will receive the title deeds
for the lands on which they farm,
and for the houses in which they live.
What, title deeds?
Hypocrites.
What does Ankara say? Explain it again.
Just like you heard,
if you get married under these criteria,
you'll receive the title deeds.
Those who are not related
and those who want
to have an official wedding,
please give your IDs to Teacher Salih
to begin the application process.
Come on. Where are our IDs?
-At home.
-Let's go and get them.
They'll give us title deeds
and those will help with the weddings.
If you'll excuse me,
I'll take the children to the school.
Come on, kids!
We're going to the school. Come on.
Do I have to get married
to an ugly woman from the village?
Right. Because you're too cool for that.
What if I want to go to Ankara
and get married there?
-Also, title deeds.
-Yes.
If they have their own title deeds,
they won't come and work on our land.
It will be the end of us.
I was going to buy all the land
during the elections.
-Seriously?
-Yes.
-I had the politicians in my pocket.
-Sure.
It doesn't matter.
They are all relatives here. Officially,
they are suitable for each other.
Yes, but…
It's hard for the young men
of the village.
Some of them aren't even related,
but they don't know that.
Let's not reveal the truth.
But there are kids! God!
They will get married,
even if they are related.
-These weddings must be stopped.
-Let's think about it.
We've been through so much,
we'll figure something out.
Come on, girls! Come and help us!
We are here.
Give it to me.
-Careful with your back.
-My back is really killing me.
-Easy.
-Right.
-Come on.
-Give it to me, Mom.
Hold it. Right, put it on there.
-Right.
-We've found it.
Mom…
Mom, I remember the hair.
It's mine. I'll give it to you
as a wedding present.
So that you can remember me when I'm dead.
Of course, my sweet mother.
-Don't say things like that.
-You're upsetting the girls.
-Right!
-Are these the ones?
Right. Here are the IDs
for Kehribar, Seyhan, Dad, and me.
Mom, what the hell?
-What?
-It says your surname is "Yazgulu".
Yes. That'd be me.
Yazgulu?
-What kind of a surname is that?
-A slutty surname.
No, come on. It's really beautiful.
When my dad went
to get my identification card,
the officer told him,
"My girlfriend's name is Yazgulu."
"Do you like it?" And my dad said no.
So he said no.
But my dad was illiterate,
he couldn't read the surname.
So it's a gift from a civil servant.
Give it here.
It really is "Yazgulu".
Well, it's so beautiful.
Ado! Stick with the plan.
She is the one who takes care
of your special needs.
Come on. Let's not keep Ankara waiting.
-Come on!
-Okay, we'll handle this.
-Leave it, Mom.
-Come on.
I can't think of any solutions.
And the guy mentioned a pilot.
As if there are
any planes in the village.
Still with that pilot nonsense?
Sister, what did you mean when you said,
"She takes care of your special needs."
Am I a whore?
No, not a whore. You're a bitch.
Go on.
"Will Osman come to the school?"
This is how you build a question sentence,
using "will" at the beginning.
Or you can start the sentence
with "where", "when", "how"
to ask a question.
All right, let's see. Ask us a question.
-The relatives can't marry each other?
-"Can't the relatives marry each other?"
Question mark.
"Can't they…" Okay?
You there, ask us a question.
Marrying makes them relatives,
or doesn't it?
It does. No, it doesn't.
This isn't working.
You're confusing me, kids.
Hello.
I've brought the IDs.
I'm in the middle of a lesson.
We'll handle it later.
-Okay?
-Oh, right.
Get the fuck out, all of you!
-Dad!
-Shut the fuck up and get out!
Go on!
Early break.
Don't go too far,
I'll invite you back in in a second, okay?
-Go on.
-Come on.
Here they are.
But there are three ID cards here.
There are three of us here.
But this won't work, Brother Adil.
You can't marry two women.
But I already have.
I mean, you can't
officially be married to both of them.
Teacher! Here are the IDs.
Do us a favor.
I have classes to attend to.
The kids will be back shortly.
Don't worry about it.
I told them to go back to their homes.
-Whose IDs are these?
-Mine, hers, and my brother Cevat's.
I'll help him get married too.
But aren't they related?
-Come on, do us a favor.
-I can't.
Mr. Muzaffer has all the details
about your family trees.
-I can't.
-Stop!
Cancel all the weddings!
Jeez…
Damn, Chief.
I just wanted to come and see
who is marrying who.
Let me see.
They can't marry each other.
They are relatives.
Don't worry about it.
I'll find a suitable wife
for your brother.
No. This is getting out of hand.
It'd be best to gather all the villagers
and talk about this.
-Sister!
-What is it?
All the men have gotten together.
-They're choosing wives for themselves.
-What?
Is Cevat there too?
What is the meaning of this?
-I'll explain if you give me some donuts.
-Little brat. Just spit it out.
Spit it out!
They mentioned some family tree.
-All right.
-And they'll choose suitable wives.
I'm not really sure.
How long do we have to wait?
I'm making the final adjustments.
I'll tell you shortly.
Thank God.
Okay…
Here are the names of those
who are not each other's relatives.
Sir, how do you know about our families?
The family trees. Sit down.
Even I have only just realized
that me and my wife are relatives.
Yes, Mahmut?
Brother Salih, what is this?
Mahmut, here are the names
of those who are not related to you,
those who can get married to you.
I understand that, but why is
"Melike" next to my name?
Because Melike is the only girl
you're not related to.
What about me?
Well, all right.
Let me read out the entire list.
Kasim and Gulsum.
God bless you, Teacher.
Israfil and Diyar.
-Cevat and Bedevi.
-Bedevi?
Sit the fuck down!
Wait.
What about me?
Murat and Seyhan.
-Murat?
-Damn!
-Teacher! What about me?
-Huseyin.
There are no
suitable women for you in this village.
-How come?
-The whole village is related to you.
Yes, Huseyin.
Unfortunately, you don't have a match.
-There's nobody.
-God damn it.
Well…
Thank you all.
Thanks to you,
I've become one of the village's boys.
I'm not related to anyone,
so I'll write my name down.
Whoa!
Is that possible?
Teacher, you are not one of the villagers.
Let's get these people married first,
then we can talk about the rest.
-Right, Mr. Muzaffer?
-Sure.
Yes.
What happened, Cezmi?
What does the state say?
-Come on.
-Who is marrying who?
-Shut up.
-Tell me, Cezmi.
Cezmi…
Zeyno…
I can't marry you to your cousin Kasim.
The deal is off.
Who is my match, Dad?
Murat, Asim's son.
-Murat?
-Yeah, Murat.
It's the will of the state, dear. So what?
I'll be at the café.
Mom, tell Dad that I will never
marry that disgusting Murat.
Tell him yourself, if you have the guts.
I didn't want to marry your dad either.
Okay. Then Kehribar can say that to Dad.
Dad won't argue with her.
No, I'm not available.
Why wouldn't he argue with her?
Is her pussy made of gold?
-Shut up! I'll go talk to your dad.
-Go on, Mom.
No, I don't have the guts either.
So I have some information.
They say official marriage is important.
The one you marry will get
the title deeds when you're gone.
Just come here.
-Come over here.
-Stop it.
But I'll come over if you marry me.
My Kehribar, come on.
We can talk about it later.
I have something to do here.
-What are you doing?
-I said I had something to do.
It doesn't matter to me.
It can be even better.
You, come here.
And you, come over to this side.
Whoa, Ado! Hold your horses.
Come on! We need to talk.
I know what you want to talk about.
But Ado and I have already agreed.
He is going to marry me.
What? You know…
-Is that right, Ado?
-Well, I just said…
-I mean, it's just--
-I deserve to get married.
I am older. To hell with this slut.
If you don't marry me,
I won't give you any of my corn fields.
You won't get anything, Ado.
For God's sake, Kibar.
What are you talking about?
Are you listening to yourself, Kibar?
A woman has to give
everything she has to her husband.
Well, then the one you marry
should give you what she owns.
Because I swear to God, I won't!
You won't get anything from me.
I won't either.
Make a choice, Ado.
Her fields?
Or my fields?
ID
What kind of fuckery is this?
These ID cards are not correct.
It says I'm 18 years old and you are 72.
I've been using my dead aunt's ID.
What can I do?
Just go to sleep.
So they are going to marry
the ones on that list?
-Yes.
-Then what?
-Then they will get the title deeds.
-And then?
They'll have the title deeds.
What the…
Fucking peasants.
-Kismet.
-Yes?
If that happens, they won't work
on our fields anymore.
They won't work for us.
Do everything you can
and solve this problem.
How can I do that?
-Talk to the women.
-About what?
-Tell them not to get married.
-Sure. Anything else?
Well, tell them marriage is a bad thing.
Not for me.
That's what you're going to tell them.
Kismet, please.
Make it happen.
Persuade them not to get married.
What if they reject it?
You'll find a way.
You are the smartest woman of them all.
Well, everyone knows that.
-Then go and see Kibar in the morning.
-No, I can't.
-Why?
-Her house stinks.
-Good God!
-Yeah.
Kismet…
if you do this for me,
I'll buy you a golden bracelet.
Not good enough.
-Two bracelets?
-Not enough.
Fuck me, what else do you want,
you greedy woman?
-I want a phone.
-What?
Why would you want a phone?
All of your relatives live nearby.
If you farted, they'd hear you.
But I would be the only one with a phone.
Okay, fine.
I'll buy two phones for you.
You can hold the second one
next to your ass and talk to it.
In that case, I will destroy
all the potential marriages.
What the hell? Azime is my match.
Dayibasi?
-Speak of the devil and she shall appear.
-Huh?
What's up, Azime? What do you want?
My dad said I was your match.
-Yes. And?
-Huh?
So?
He said, "Don't bring that dog
into my home. Go to him and…"
"And talk to him about marriage."
Azime, I don't want to get married.
I want to build a career for myself.
Huh?
Azime, go back home. Go.
Turn around!
Just keep walking in that direction. Go!
Get out!
God damn it!
What kind of a project is this?
I'm not used to sitting on the ground.
My backside doesn't like it.
Did you wash your hands, Azime?
The dough seems clean.
Look, sipping tea,
but there's no side dishes.
Can I get you some sugar candy?
-There is no candy.
-Yes, there's some in the kitchen.
That's for our guests.
Am I not a guest?
You rarely come here.
Why are you here now?
I was just passing by with Cemile
and we decided to pay a visit. Right?
No. You came to me,
grabbed me and brought me here.
Dayibasi kind of rejected me.
Don't worry. All these men are alike.
They are all evil.
My husband, for example,
he forgets our wedding anniversary.
He forgets my birthday.
He doesn't care anymore.
I have had enough!
I'm going to get a divorce.
-Damn!
-Divorce? Has he got a second wife?
-How can you say that, sister?
-Well, it is what it is.
Say "partner", it's more polite.
No. He didn't get himself a second wife,
it's just that he isn't romantic.
-What?
-He isn't romantic.
You know, I paid a visit
to my aunt in Ankara and--
They say that's a lie.
That she was home with the curtains drawn,
pretending she had gone to Ankara.
Who says that?
They are probably just haters
who are jealous of me.
Anyway…
I went to Ankara.
Then I went to a movie theater.
It was huge, just like my home.
A grand, flamboyant interior.
In that movie, the man
asked the woman to marry him.
But the way he asked…
And Dayibasi called me "the devil".
The man was lying on the floor.
Ado was also lying on the floor yesterday.
No, not like that.
The man was on his knee,
his other knee was facing forward,
and he bowed before the woman.
-Like this.
-In that position?
Not really.
But he bought a fancy ring for the woman,
with a huge diamond on it.
-Damn…
-And he says, "Will you marry me?"
Asking her a question.
-Asking who?
-The woman.
Why? He should be asking
the woman's father.
Movies are so fake.
Not really. That is what
the men in Ankara are really like.
They say "dear", "baby",
"honey" to the women there.
They say, "I love you."
It's so different there.
Right…
-Sister.
-What's up?
-Tell you what.
-What?
I don't want to marry Israfil.
-What is wrong with Israfil?
-I love Mahmut.
-That can't happen.
-Why not?
-He's not on the list.
-So the list gets to decide, not me?
That's the will of Ankara.
We can't object to it.
I don't want him. I don't love him.
Why can't you understand?
You don't have to love him.
You'll get used to him.
You'll be his partner. You'll collaborate,
but you will get used to him.
At some point you might even
want to see him dead.
Sometimes you will hate him,
but you will get used to him anyway.
It doesn't matter if you love him or not.
Marriage is like shopping.
Give and take. Give and take.
Take more, give less. You see?
Now, get up. It's time to cook.
We'll go to Cemile's house
to prepare the food.
-Mom, I'm hungry.
-You little brat, just move.
-Hi, guys.
-Hi.
Brother Suleyman,
I could use some cold water here.
Go and get it yourself.
I'm in a tough spot.
Who isn't?
No, I don't get it.
Seyhan's grandmother and my aunt
are somehow related.
But that doesn't make us relatives.
Cousins, nieces, those are relatives.
-You know?
-Well said.
It's a distant relation.
I don't understand how we are related.
We are not relatives, just acquaintances.
Well, at least you have a match.
Damn you, Dad.
Why did you marry one of our relatives?
I wonder if we can officially reject
my mom as a relative.
She's a pain in the ass anyway.
-Is that possible?
-I don't know.
Right.
What are you looking at, bro?
It's not like I burnt your field down.
You burnt my heart down with your match.
Well, people get what they deserve, huh?
What the fuck is that?
You didn't say anything
when you were matched with Melike.
-Were you interested in her?
-You have a point.
-Shut up, Israfil.
-Why?
-What happens if I don't?
-Let the real men speak.
People who don't respect
other's lovers aren't real men.
And you're a real man? Is that it?
That's right.
-Watch your mouth.
-Put that hand down.
I hope one of them gets killed,
so that I can have one of the girls.
What are you doing, Seyhan?
The dough is gone.
Always blaming others, right?
What about you?
-Seyhan, look here.
-So what?
-Just leave it.
-My hand!
People get what they deserve, eventually.
Oh, do you like to see me suffer?
-Yeah, I love it.
-Is that right?
That's right.
Come on. Taste my pain then.
-Leave it!
-You…
-Stop it!
-Don't!
What the hell?
Let her go!
Guys! What the hell are you doing?
Guys!
What is going on here? Stop it!
Fuck it, Teacher.
Let me smash his face in.
I'll make him pay
for taking an interest in my lover.
-Calm down.
-I didn't do that!
I've loved Bedevi since childhood.
I want her.
To hell with those title deeds
and weddings!
Brother Orhan, you're the oldest one here.
Why didn't you do something?
I'm not in the mood.
What's their problem anyway?
It's about the weddings.
Uncle Orhan, do you have
a problem with your hearing?
And he smiles.
This guy…
-Stop it!
-Let her go!
Leave her be! Stop it!
What's your problem? What the hell?
-What is going on?
-Mom!
Let that slut explain it!
Watch your mouth, Melike!
Come to your senses!
-Don't take an interest in others' lovers!
-I don't!
I wasn't matched with my lover either!
Let go! Back off!
To hell with title deeds and weddings!
Let go of me!
Damn you all! I'll end up killing myself!
Nobody wants this,
so stop upsetting each other.
Upset? What do you mean, Zeynep?
-We're all crying rivers here.
-Just shut up.
My mom wants to see you.
Mr. Muzaffer!
What are you doing here?
Come here, Teacher Salih.
I wanted to look around,
but there is not much to see.
Yeah, it's a small place.
"Yeah"? Your language is deteriorating.
It doesn't deteriorate,
Mr. Muzaffer, it just changes.
The key thing is to understand each other.
-If it wasn't, what would a mute do?
-You are right.
-The bridge is gone.
-Yes.
It was not safe,
so the state had to demolish it.
But they didn't build a new one.
Teacher! Teacher Salih!
Boys, what is it?
I told you not to come up here again.
-What's going on?
-My dad wants to see you tomorrow.
Yes, I know.
He said, "That asshole
had better remember."
-Asshole?
-That's what he said.
All right, okay.
Let's go, Mr. Muzaffer.
Go back home.
-Dad didn't say "asshole".
-No, that was me.
Zeynep?
I'll wait for you over there, Salih.
Look at him. That evil bastard.
-Why would you say that?
-This is all because of him.
Everyone is upset.
Nobody is with the one they love.
What about you? Are you upset?
I feel sad for my sister and friends.
Aren't you?
Anyway, I'll go get the kids.
Hey! I told you not to come here.
What the hell are you doing here again?
Let's go.
-Who is her match?
-Whose match?
I don't know who you mean.
We will wait and see, I guess.
Well, shall we?
The earth would shatter
If I told you how I felt
What can I do about it?
My beloved is in the wind
Ankara's project
Took my beloved away
They have a list
And we're promised title deeds
I'll marry you and you.
Okay.
What can I do?
I'll just go out and find another woman.
Did you hear him, sister?
Don't worry.
Nobody wants to fuck an old goat.
Well, okay.
I'll buy you whatever you want.
Damn it.
As far as I've heard,
they sweet-talk women in Ankara
and ask them questions like,
-"Will you marry me?"
-What the…
Stop talking nonsense
in front of the girl.
We can talk about it in the bedroom,
if that's what you want.
No. In Ankara men go down
on their knees and ask them,
"Will you marry me?"
What the hell is your problem?
On my knees? How could I do that?
That's what the man in the movie did.
Enough. Are you going to marry me or not?
I will marry you if you sweet-talk to me.
Like…
what was I wearing when we first met?
A bridal gown.
Right. That was easy.
Then sweet-talk me.
Like…
call me baby.
Call me honey.
Call me sweetheart.
Call me your bunny.
Call me your lover.
Call me honey.
"Honey"?
-"My lover"?
-That's right.
-Do you want to hear those nice words?
-Yes, I do.
I'll fucking… God damn it.
God bless you.
God bless these weddings.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
Let me hear some music!
Come here, baby
Don't you know that I love you?
I want to hug you tight
What would I do without you?
Take my breath away
It's ready for you
Don't you cry, wipe away your tears
I'd die for you
Take my breath away
It's ready for you
Don't you cry, wipe away your tears
I'd die for you
The music should go higher, Mr. Drummer
The girl loves that guy
Why would she care about the world?
The music should go higher, Mr. Drummer
The girl loves that guy
Why would she care about the world?
The music should go higher, Mr. Drummer…
Mr. Muzaffer.
I need to do something.
I'll be back in a moment.
Excuse me.
The music should go higher, Mr. Drummer
The girl loves that guy
Why would she care about the world?
The music should go higher, Mr. Drummer
The girl loves that guy
Why would she care about the world?
The music should go higher, Mr. Drummer
The girl loves that guy
Why would she care about the world?
Giving it to people in need, huh?
Cutting up shoes? What the hell?
Damn it! Again?
Hello, God.
I'm the chief of Elaldi Village,
my name is Dayibasi.
I swear that I won't sell
any haram goods anymore. I promise.
But you should also do something
about those thieves.
Hasan, get me a Turkish coffee, please.
-I said a "Turkish coffee".
-Just drink your tea.
God damn…
Boys! I thought you were brave men.
I would never marry my friend's lover,
even if they promised me all this land,
not just a couple of title deeds.
I would though.
God.
Stop talking nonsense, Brother Cezmi.
Don't make me smash your face in.
Look, fat boy. That's what I say.
Don't smash my face in.
Go and smash your lover's dad's face.
Take your lover away, get in bed with her,
and then she will have to marry you.
-What a great idea.
-Yeah.
Cezo!
I'd love to see him try that.
I didn't mean to hurt anybody.
I'm just saying.
This is all just a scam by the state.
Just think about it.
The state lets us have title deeds
in order to collect taxes,
so that you'd have
to pay taxes on it every year.
Otherwise, Ankara wouldn't
give a fuck about it.
Let's not curse.
You know, Brother Cezmi is right.
Boys, Cezmi is never right.
I can tell you that.
Cezo.
I know what troubles you, son.
I'll have my own property.
That scares you, doesn't it?
No, really. I swear to God.
We're not interested in having property.
We just want the ones we love.
Bravo, boys.
Do everything you can to reunite
yourselves with your loved ones.
I just want a woman.
So who is going to marry Ado?
-Your mom.
-Huh?
Don't get upset. She just wants to know
who will marry Ado.
That's right. Who will marry him?
Your mom!
Ado hasn't said anything about it.
We will see.
I'm officially married
and I regret it every day.
Marriage is the end of love.
-We're kind of married anyway.
-This is different.
There is you and there is your husband.
And then comes the state.
So?
She says, "Love is for two.
Who needs the state?"
-Huh?
-Right.
Well, we have a love for three.
If the state wants to join in,
then it'll be for four.
But if Ado finds another woman,
that would make it for five.
If he finds two other women,
that'd make it for six.
Cemile, you're really smart.
-Me?
-Yes, you.
You are smart, kind, and emotional, right?
Why would you marry someone
who does not touch your soul?
-Right, he doesn't touch me at all.
-Huh?
I'm telling you,
this woman is being exploited.
Her husband took her in,
but she was never asked
if that was what she wanted.
She would say, "Let me think about it."
And then probably reject him.
Right, Cemile?
What can I do?
I'll tell you what you can do.
Tell me, Cezmi. What was your plan?
I persuaded Kismet to discourage
the other women from getting married.
-Nice.
-And I chatted with the boys.
I confused them further.
"Why would you care about a list
that the state provided you with?"
"Just go and take your lovers," I said.
Good job, Cezmi. We're on the right path.
I'm also in trouble
with that ugly chick, Azime.
-Really?
-Yes, she came to my store.
"I want you to have me."
"Take me away," she said.
Why the fuck would I marry her?
There's nothing beautiful
or graceful about her.
She looks like a dinosaur.
Chief.
You're not Azime's relative.
No, I am not.
You know those lands
you'd receive if you married her?
-They are just next to mine.
-So?
If we own all that land
and build a chicken farm there,
we could sell those chickens at our store.
Cezmi.
I won't sell my soul to the devil
for the sake of a few chickens.
-Sorry.
-Damn it.
Love is so precious to me.
Don't even mention that again.
Chicken farm…
Here I am trying to
solve the problem of the title deeds,
and here you are asking me
to marry that dinosaur,
sell my soul to the devil,
and set a bad example for the youth.
Is that right, Cezmi?
Cezmi! You don't understand me at all!
Good God! Yeah, right!
As if I was the village bitch!
Shit. He is crazier than I thought.
That's not how I pictured it.
-Same here.
-I knew this was going to happen.
I'll end up like my mom.
-I hope I won't kill myself.
-Stop talking nonsense, Seyhan.
We'll find a way, okay?
We will figure something out.
Don't upset yourself.
The bridal gown looks like
a burial shroud on you, Bedevi.
Stop saying things like that.
-You are so beautiful.
-And you are smiling.
Well, I'm not going to be a bride,
but I wish you every happiness.
I'm so happy, I can't even describe it.
Sister Seyhan! Brother Cevat
is waiting for you on the hill.
Just go and have a chat.
You should go with her, Bedevi.
-Take off that gown.
-Okay.
-Help her.
-Okay. That's enough.
Right. You're also beautiful.
Take off that dress already.
Everything will be okay.
Idris.
Zeynep?
Teacher Salih,
go to the riverbank at once.
Is she mad? What have I done?
It's not about you, Mr. Muzaffer.
It's about me.
Sister Bedevi.
I'll be waiting over there.
You're going to marry her,
but you still call her "Sister Bedevi"?
What are you talking about?
My Seyhan, you are…
All of the other girls
are my sisters, except you.
I don't care about what the state says.
What have they done to us, Cevat?
-Why have they done this?
-I can't live without you.
Zeynep?
Salih.
That's the first time
you've called me Salih.
Salih…
I want you to know something,
just in case my dad
makes me marry someone else.
-Zeynep--
-Hush.
It's already hard enough to say it.
Salih…
I love you.
I love you too.
I have something to tell you.
You've already told me
the best thing you could tell me, Salih.
-But--
-Hush.
Don't say it, Salih.
Let "I love you too"
be your final words to me.
Say what?
You'll ask my dad
for my hand in marriage.
I'll prepare coffee for you.
You'll say, "God knows, I love her."
And my dad will say,
"Well, they love each other."
Your dad is dead, Cemile.
Good night.
-Hi.
-Hello.
Boys! Do you have room for some guests?
Sure, you're always welcome, Teacher.
But I am not?
-I didn't say that.
-The boys are a little angry.
That's why, Mr. Muzaffer.
Two cups of tea, please.
All right, give me a second.
Why are they angry?
Because of Ankara.
Men should be able
to choose their own wives.
Boys, look, I know this
is unorthodox for you,
but everything will be better.
Your kids will be healthier.
-We won't have any kids.
-Why do you say that, Mahmut?
We can't touch our friends' lovers.
That's not right.
-We won't.
-Really?
She's like a sister to me.
Marriage won't change anything.
My man.
We are different from the people
you are used to, Mr. Muzaffer.
I'm doing the right thing.
You'll see that in time.
So everything else is right, it's just
this situation that's wrong. Is that it?
Nobody is happy.
They'll get used to it, Salih.
Change is hard.
It's tough.
-Cevo.
-Yeah?
-You won't touch Bedevi, right?
-Good God.
-Your beloved is like a sister to me.
-You are right.
-I have an idea.
-What is it, Mahmut?
Call the girls here.
I'll explain it to everyone.
Go on.
Ask Kevser for my hand in marriage.
Ask Kevser?
I won't fucking marry you. I won't.
I'll just marry someone else.
In Ankara, women request dates,
as far as I've heard.
-What?
-In Ankara, women--
You already told me that.
Let's go, Mr. Muzaffer.
No, I want to listen to him. Tell me.
I'm curious. How many girls
have asked you out in Ankara?
None.
Well, judging from your looks,
I guess that's normal.
-Sorry?
-I mean, that's normal.
-If you don't have any other--
-I do, Teacher.
I have a problem.
Mr. Minister, please come closer.
Come and look me in the eyes.
One of my eyes was green.
I lost so much weight.
-The other lost its color.
-What are you talking about?
Do you know anyone in Ankara
who might want to marry me?
-No.
-Huseyin.
Please, get up.
I'd better go now.
There are a lot of crazy people
in this village.
There are, unfortunately.
Why is this happening, Grandmother?
Love is lived a little differently here,
my lovely girl.
But I can't live without my beloved.
Of course you can.
How would you know what it means
to be without your beloved?
I do know.
When a girl gets in bed
with someone she doesn't love…
even the man's mustache bothers the girl.
Everything bothers her.
Around here, we don't really get
to marry the ones we love.
Your mom didn't want
to marry your dad either.
"I'll kill myself," she said.
But she didn't.
Your grandfather approved the marriage
and we couldn't say anything.
Your mom cried rivers,
but she married him.
And then you girls came into the world.
Cevat?
Cevat!
-What's wrong?
-Huh?
-What's going on?
-What?
Wait. We'll be right there.
Seyhan.
I need to get food from the store,
but I'm scared. Come with me.
Just leave me be, Zeynep.
Can't you see I'm in pain?
I'm telling you, I'm scared. Come with me!
-Just take someone else with you.
-Get up, Seyhan!
Go on, Seyhan. Get up.
Stop it. Come on.
Cevat is waiting.
-Where?
-Move it.
Zeynep.
Evening.
Look at me.
If you're planning
to take the girls away--
Take them away? No.
Where would we take them to?
How could we take them away?
Okay, that's fine.
Tell me then. Why are you here?
Fine, okay. I get it.
I'll be waiting right there.
But make it quick, okay?
-Okay.
-Yeah.
So, guys, if they want to separate us
just to collect some title deeds
then we need a plan.
-Right.
-Of course.
I don't get it.
Seyhan and I can't be relatives.
Her grandmother and my auntie--
-Shut up for God's sake, Cevat.
-God.
We'll stay married until we get the deeds.
Then we'll get a divorce.
Who keeps the title deeds
when we get divorced?
The man or the woman?
Divorces aren't common here, Bedevi.
-True.
-It doesn't matter.
From now on, it'll be common.
How does one get a divorce anyway?
Well, you go…
I mean, I don't really know.
We'll be reunited with our lovers.
The rest is Ankara's problem.
Murat is the only one for me.
Don't get ahead of yourself.
What if there are kids?
I don't really know.
Anyway, Israfil?
We'll get married, but you'll still
treat me like a sister, right?
Yes, I swear. You're like a sister to me.
Besides, I'm in love with someone else.
-Whatever.
-Let's go.
-Take it easy.
-See you later.
Have a good night.
Go on!
I just comb my hair, mind my own business
I just want my lover
I'm in flames, day and night
What do I have to be ashamed of?
To hell with Ankara's project
I already have a lover
Ado will find another woman
and marry her because of you.
It's because of you. You're younger.
The older one gets to get married.
I'm the older one here.
I deserve to be married to him.
I always carry Ado's burden.
Mom, run! Deva fell in the oven.
-The oven was on!
-What?
Deva!
Don't worry! I'm here, my girl!
-Deva!
She is not here.
Deva!
-She is fine.
-Where have you been, baby?
You're fine, dear.
She's perfectly fine.
There's nothing wrong with her.
You fucking brat! Did you lie?
-Son of a bastard!
-Bastard!
Shameless brat.
Come here, baby.
Thank God, she is fine.
-Put the cream on.
-Stay still, I'm putting it on.
Good God!
Have you lost your mind?
Why would you put your hand in the oven?
Even this kid is smarter than you.
See, she didn't touch the oven.
What could I do? I was worried about her.
Sister, are you in pain?
No, of course not. I love fire.
Send me to Hell when I die
so I can burn in peace.
Fire is good, right? Blow on it.
God.
-Sister.
-What?
You can marry Ado.
Why?
Sister, your home is my home.
Your fields are my fields.
Your kids are my kids too, dear sister.
We're a family, right?
Huh?
What now?
Have you all got it?
Teacher.
-I'm working here, Chief.
-That's okay.
Kids don't bother me.
They are kids, they're fine.
Now, look at me.
How is the process going?
How did they respond?
Everything is fine. I have their IDs.
Why?
Why are you even here?
Oh, right.
This is the letter you wanted
to send to Ankara.
I thought Mr. Muzaffer can take it
to Ankara, if he's still here.
-Has he gone?
-That won't be necessary.
Sorry for interrupting the lesson,
but it's urgent.
That's fine.
I already interrupted the lesson.
I'm here to collect the IDs.
I have some of them here,
but the rest are at my house.
-Okay, bring them here.
-Sure. Let me take the kids home.
No way. That won't be nice for them.
The kids should stay on course here.
I can teach them a few lessons.
I love children.
Come on, Salih.
All right, okay.
You there! Come here at once.
Take these papers.
Give some of them to your friends.
So the first lesson
is about folding paper.
Now, fold that paper like a cup,
so I can put cookies in them
and sell them.
Got it? Then let's begin.
Get to work. You too.
Give the others some paper.
Come on! Hurry up, lads.
Damn! Ido, Come here.
Take this letter to the teacher. Hurry!
Take this ID and give it to the teacher.
But this is Kehribar's ID.
Yes, it is.
She deserves to marry you.
Poor thing, she's young
and has a lot on her shoulders.
Your mustache bothers me, but not her.
Where are you going, Ido?
To find the teacher.
-Okay. What is that?
-Teacher's letter.
-Where is he?
-He went home.
Okay, give it to me.
I'll take it to him. You go back to class.
-But don't read it.
-That'd be shameful. Go ahead.
FROM SALIH OZTURK
TO THE MINISTRY OF FAMILY
"To the Republic of Turkey's
Ministry of Family,
I've been working as a teacher
in the village of Elaldi for three years."
"This is the 38th letter
I have sent to the Ministry."
"I reported what happened in the village
after the collapse
of the Freedom and Equality Bridge."
"The people here are so cut off
from the outside world."
"Since the bridge's collapse,
the villagers have resorted to
marrying their cousins."
"And these types of marriages
cause problems,
not just for the families,
but also for the kids."
"I would like the Ministry
to do something about this."
"I kindly request
that you take the necessary action."
"Teacher Salih Ozturk."
Teacher Salih!
You did this.
I did it for you.
I did it so we could be together.
But everybody else is sad.
I didn't know that would happen.
How can I be happy with you
while there is so much sadness around?
I can't. We can't be happy.
Not anymore.
What is it, Teacher Salih?
I caused this mess, Mr. Muzaffer.
We can talk about that later.
We need to get the IDs there at once.
-Let's go.
-You go ahead.
I don't want to be
part of this mess anymore.
I don't want to influence
others' lives to get what I want.
What do you mean?
I didn't understand them,
yet I wanted them to understand me.
How can someone understand you
when you don't understand them?
They can't.
Ankara!
Mr. Minister!
Mr. Minister.
Minister? I'm just a civil servant.
Mr. Civil Servant, please.
Let's go to Ankara
to find me a suitable wife.
You must know suitable candidates.
I'll pay for the bride, if necessary.
I can also give away three of my sheep.
But the girl doesn't want him.
She says she'll kill herself if needs be.
You have to do whatever I say.
Girls can't choose their husbands!
The teacher and that Muzaffer guy
can both go to Hell.
OATH OF LOVE
Zeynep. Come and take care of me.
Look, I look wonderful.
You're so beautiful.
What about me, Zeynep?
You look so beautiful too.
You're all so beautiful.
I wish things were different.
But here we are.
Whatever. Don't fret, Zeynep. It's fate.
Don't worry about us, Zeynep.
We've already found a solution.
The men promised they won't touch us.
We will reunite with our lovers
once we get the title deeds and lands.
Hopefully.
It's all because of me.
-What is wrong with Zeynep?
-She's probably worried about us.
And she is next in line to get married.
Maybe she's afraid.
Ladies.
Oh, my beautiful girls.
Praise be!
You look fantastic.
But the men have tricked you.
-They wouldn't trick us.
-Shut up. What do you know?
It's impossible
to marry the ones you love.
None of your mothers
loved none of your fathers.
But all of your fathers had their way
with your mothers, obviously.
I also had to let my lover
be with someone else.
And I had to let someone else's lover
have his way with me.
All men are the same.
Of course they will touch you
and have their way with you.
You will be wasted tonight.
Have you seen the looks on their faces?
Hello there.
Look! Look at those brave young men!
I brought you some liquor, guys.
I don't know,
maybe it will give you some courage.
Listen to me.
If you have any questions
about anything, just ask me.
I'll teach you how to seal the deal.
-I'm about to smash your face in.
-Whoa! Look, fat boy.
You are all grown up.
You're about to get married
and you'll have kids soon.
But you still don't have manners.
Stop fucking with the boys, Cezmi.
In the end, they are marrying
each other's girlfriends.
You are right. Poor boys. Hey! Good God!
-Go away before I crack your skull open.
-Come here.
Oh, the mighty fatty!
-Hit it!
-Come here.
Come here, you dumb-ass!
Come here. Start dancing with us.
Salih!
Where are you going?
-Back where I came from.
-So you're running away, huh?
Leaving the village and the kids behind
and running away?
-I screwed everything up.
-Yes, you did.
You're a coward.
That's why I'm leaving.
Go!
Go away, Teacher Salih! Go!
What are you doing, Salih?
Wait a second!
Stop!
What the fuck's going on?
I'm in love with Zeynep.
I am asking you to give me
her hand in marriage.
-Uncle Ado!
-What?
Come quickly!
-The girls are going to kill themselves!
-What?
-Where are they?
-The girls?
Where? Where are they? Run!
-Run!
Stop!
Don't come any closer!
Don't come any closer or we'll jump!
-Don't come any closer!
-Stop!
-Don't!
Stop!
-What are you doing, Bedevi?
-Don't come near me!
What the hell are you doing, Bedevi?
Don't come any closer!
Come here, for God's sake!
Calm down. What is going on?
Are they protesting?
It's not a protest, Chief!
We are suffering!
For God's sake, come here!
What are you doing? Come here!
We can't do what you want us to do, Dad!
We don't want to end up like our moms.
We want to marry whoever we want!
The state can't choose
our husbands for us!
I'm still available, by the way.
Seyhan!
For heaven's sake, Seyhan! Come here!
Please don't do this, Seyhan. Come here.
I'm begging you. Come here, Seyhan!
Stop this nonsense.
I'll kill you if you jump, Diyar!
I swear to God!
I don't care about title deeds.
She is my daughter, after all.
You're absolutely right.
How can someone let their children die?
Shut up, you faggot!
-What the…
-We've made our decisions, Dad.
-If you don't approve, we'll jump!
-Wait!
What a dreadful bridge that is!
-We're still suffering because of it!
-Stop!
Stop.
It's all because of me.
I wrote the letter to the Ministry.
I am sorry.
God damn you, Teacher.
I don't have a woman because of you.
Guys! Enough with
the title deeds and all that.
Put an end to this situation
and let the lovers be reunited. Huh?
What do you say, Dad?
-What do you say, Dad?
-Right?
-Let the lovers come together!
-Yeah!
Right? Come on, Ado.
-Come on, Ado.
-Come on, Dad.
-Right?
-Right, Dad?
-Just say it's okay.
-Dad?
Yes, that's right.
-Come on, Ado.
-Come on already.
Okay. Come here.
Wait a minute!
Why doesn't anybody in this village
take me seriously?
I'm also protesting!
If you don't find a woman for me,
I swear I'll throw myself off here.
Huso! Hey!
I'm in a tough spot, Cevo.
Okay, all right.
Okay, we'll find someone for you.
And we will rebuild the bridge for you.
Well, I'm sold.
Goodness gracious!
"To the Republic of Turkey's
Ministry of Family,
thank you for answering my calls
and choosing us as your pilot area."
"However, this place isn't ready
to change just yet."
"Instead of making radical changes,
we made decisions
that could be implemented gradually."
"Removing borders and uniting people,
adjusting measures
to ensure people's happiness."
"That's what we did."
"Teacher Salih Ozturk."
Hello, Chief.
-Well, hello!
-Let's get straight to the point.
Can you please send this to Ankara?
-Is it another evil plan?
-No, it's not.
It seems that your bags are empty.
Unfortunately, they are.
Some faggot probably stole them.
-Yes. Some faggot.
-Yeah. That's what I said.
Take it easy.
Goodbye.
Faggot.
Look, everyone is gone.
Fucking peasants.
Subtitle translation by:
Ediz Faruk Gulfirat