Proposal:
Akame Works
AKAME 48 WATERFALLS
"Through me the way into the
suffering city..." - Dante Alghieri
I heard that the people there
have a unique attachment to
this town, Amagasaki,
and call it Ama.
"Through me the way into
the suffering city."
I, as a vagabond,
as one of the many who eke out a living,
came from Kamagasaki to this place.
Do you have a light?
My apologies, man.
Take this and buy some cigarettes.
Is anyone here?
My name is Ikushima.
I heard about you in
Kamagasaki and came here.
Oh, it's you.
I heard in Kamagasaki that you
have a college degree.
It seems like you have
a good education.
Were you expelled?
I dropped out.
Dropped out?
Forget it.
There are lowlife losers like pigs.
I heard you want to be hired no
matter how much I pay you.
I don't know how much is enough
for someone exceptional like you.
How much do you want?
5 yen per skewer of tripe.
Chopping them up and skewering
them finally pays only 5 yen,
so you have to work hard and make
1.000 skewers a day to make ends meet.
How much do you want?
The more I get, the better,
of course.
It would be good if you could
put your heart into the work.
And your name?
What is it again?
Yoichi Ikushima.
How dare you come to a place like this,
even though you have parents who named you?
I'll do as you say, sister Seiko.
All right, then.
Thanks for looking after us.
How are you doing?
Not bad, I guess.
Remember what happened
seven years ago?
Gods and foreigners alike are
vulnerable to earthquakes, it seems.
Anyway, this is a Jizo statue for
dropouts, so it fits right in here.
Don't bother with her nonsense.
The window's broken.
And the light...
Oh, still good.
The faucet is working.
The quilts are in the cabinet.
Worry not.
Everything you need daily
should all be here now.
As for your personal belongings,
you cannot be too careful with them.
Those things will go into the
mouths of my customers, right?
I will not pay for a poorly made
skewer. Understand?
- Are you listening?
- Yes.
You're a cute boy.
I should tell you that.
You're still very young.
As a living human being,
I do not fit in this society.
I may think, but I do not act.
Mr. Shinkai, do I have
what it takes?
I don't even have a family now.
This dictionary's been with me
for more than 10 years.
I named it Mr. Shinkai.
At this moment,
only I speak with Mr. Shinkai.
This is the tendon.
Just like this.
Cut it this way.
- Got it?
- Yes.
We want the food to look nice.
So, be sure to be careful
when flipping it over.
It won't sell if it's stained.
Watch over it.
Stick right into the center.
And don't stop making
another piece.
Good.
Got it?
You'll get used to it.
Take your time.
I see.
The guy who just came in delivers the
meat every morning at ten o'clock,
and picks up the finished skewers
at five o'clock in the evening.
It's always the same,
so don't get nervous.
Want some coffee?
No, I don't drink coffee.
It's a rhetorical question.
No answer needed.
Granny!
Thank you for your help last time.
I heard you made it in time.
You really helped me a lot.
Thank you so much!
I'm just glad to have you.
I'm sure he would be
happy to see you.
But my brother is so cold to me.
He's hateful.
He's just shy, you know.
He's getting out of prison
soon, apparently.
Really?
Do you have more details?
He wants to come back to Ama.
But, your brother...
He came a long way.
Why not let him stay for a while?
As long as he's over there,
there's nothing to worry about.
That's just the way he is.
It can't be helped.
That's what master told me.
I shouldn't be talking about it.
Anyway, I don't wanna be involved.
Not much I can do, I'm leaving now!
Granny, see you next time.
Come pay me a visit!
Thanks.
You.
How old were you when the
Expo was held in Osaka?
I was born in July of 1970.
I see.
Wasn't that a good time?
So, you're two generations
younger than me?
I think so.
I was in my hometown, Iga,
until then,
and left for Osaka when
the Expo was held,
and became a whore there.
For five years,
I sold my youth for money.
I, then, went back to see my dad,
wearing red high-heels.
I didn't like those shoes,
you know,
but I bought them anyway.
You know what my dad said?
"Nice shoes".
That's all he said.
Yesterday, when I met you
on your way to the shop,
I was hoping you'd say that,
as well.
- I wanted you to say it.
- What?
You are very well-educated.
You went to a very good college,
right?
- But, now, you fell to such a place...
- No...
Also,
I never told anyone that I
was a prostitute.
Kept it as a secret.
Although I never told anyone,
people seem to know more or less.
But,
I wanted to tell someone this
before I die.
It's painful to hide certain things
from others.
I got it.
Isn't Aya beautiful,
the girl you just met?
Don't give me that face.
Let me tell you something.
That girl's Korean.
Through the center...
Don't make a sound...
Master, thank you very much.
Do not step on it!
Hey, you!
Wanna come to my place?
What do ya want?
Gotanda, Meguro, Ebisu...
Shibuya, Harajuku, Yoyogi...
Shinjuku, Shin-Okubo...
Takadanobaba, Mejiro, Ikebukuro...
Otsuka, Sugamo, Komagome...
Tabata, Nippori...
Uguisudani...
Ueno, Okachimachi...
Akihabara, Kanda, Tokyo...
Yurakucho, Shimbashi...
Hamamatsucho, Tamachi, Shinagawa...
Osaki...
The train is arriving at Osaki!
Ejaculate: to produce semen
Why does it happen so quickly?
You feel almost dead
after you drink it.
Must be that kind of alcohol.
Why would I drink that?
Only this kind of alcohol
makes you happier than death.
The edge of death. This time,
give it a try!
Are we still going to get
returning customers in the future?
Don't jinx it!
Nobody knows the future.
Worrying about your food is enough.
Just live from day to day!
Day to day!
I'm gonna kill you!
Who do you think I am?
What's that attitude?
This job is an opportunity for you.
Go back to Tokyo if you don't like it.
If it wasn't for your damn elder
sister, you'd be nothing by now!
Guys like you can be found anywhere.
Cut your ears off if you do that again!
Keep that in mind!
Ouch.
Thank you so much!
Honestly...
- Can you give me a ride to my place?
- Yes.
Is anyone here?
I'm Sanada.
Is Aya here?
But I sensed that she was.
You, mind out. I'm her brother.
There were five guys who have
been buried or sunk
because of the kind of attitude
you're having towards me.
Hey, look at me carefully.
How about it?
Don't you think I'm cute?
I'm just like Aya, aren't I?
Forget it.
Today, I'm busy.
When she's back, tell her to call me.
I will.
What's your name?
Ikushima.
Okay. Then, excuse me
for asking you this favor!
Ikushima!
What's up?
Mr. Sanada and I met today at noon.
He came here to see Aya.
Who is it? My dad?
Shut your trap, Shinpei.
Mr. Sanada wants her
to give him a call.
Is that so? Then, excuse me.
Thank you for yesterday's help!
That guy's my brother.
A cold-hearted guy,
just like me, right?
No...
He has always been like this.
It's kinda embarrassing to say.
Hey, kid.
You should be glad.
Men should learn to endure.
Or are you dissatisfied with me?
Ouch!
That hurt!
Why did you do that?
- Then, let's do it again.
- Ouch, ouch!
Takeshi.
Whatever happens,
let us gather here.
This time, I'll come for you
soon, so bear with me.
Those words have been said
too frequently.
We pray for his well-being
later in life.
That's right.
For this, we put our hands together.
No!
Our hands together!
This is certainly Horimayu's work.
I've heard so many things about it.
What's with that?
What are you doing?
Mr. Horimayu said it was fine.
- Nobody told me about that.
- Take this, double pay.
I'm begging you.
Your tattoo is very beautiful.
Such a treasure must
be recorded now.
Beauty goes away so
quickly, you know?
What? Say that again.
You don't have to raise your voice.
Give me the tape.
Give me that immediately!
I haven't recorded anything yet,
and I haven't paid Mr. Horimayu either.
That's not my business.
Don't underestimate me as a woman.
I won't lose a fight against you.
- Wait.
- Get out.
Please bear with me. I'll leave you
the money, so forgive me please.
Say that again!
I don't want this kind of creepy
money. Take it back!
Remember this!
I have to go on a trip soon.
To look at Keman* to match
it to your back.
*Keman is one of the ornaments of
a Buddhist temple or statue.
Oh, no!
What's going on?
Please come and see immediately.
Someone's bleeding!
That man.
Don't stand in my way.
So, you wanna blame
me for this, huh?
Where are his pants?
Just move on when you get up.
Thank you for your assistance.
- I heard last night there was a mess.
- Huh?
Don't worry.
I'll have a word with them.
Today,
I need to ask you something.
What?
About 10 minutes before 1:00, go to
the pay phone in front of the station.
- Inside, you'll find phone books.
- Yes.
There are five 10.000 yen bills tucked
into the phone book at the bottom.
I want you to pick them up at exactly
1 PM without being seen.
You said you don't want others to see,
but the police is right in front of...
I know.
That's why I'm asking you!
Got it.
Damn fool, stay here first!
Wait until it's time.
Oh, thanks.
Weren't you gonna pay me off last month?
What's your excuse this time, you fool?
Hey, hurry up and pay me!
Now, we have a problem.
Can he really do the job?
Poor soul.
I think he can't.
What's your damn problem?
It doesn't smell good in here.
Ogin, she's ninety-nine and wants
to marry into the Kumano region
She lost her back teeth
before her marriage
Her back teeth fell out, but
she still had her front teeth
She blackened her two front teeth
And put a hairpin in her
thinning gray hair
Wearing a red kimono,
gen-kora gen-kora
- Sorry for doing that to you last time.
- No problem.
It's not easy to deal with that guy.
If I left him alone, I would
have to take responsibility.
It's very tough.
Thank you for helping me.
As a timid person,
I do things carefully.
Everyone's the same.
I rely on you because you do, too.
Thanks.
No, it's...
A moment ago,
you've heard a song I know
since I was born.
It's a very pleasant song, isn't it?
You think so?
I may get married at 59 just like
the woman in the song, Ogin.
What are you looking at?
You can't look at it!
Uncle, you saw it.
- What is it?
- A frog.
I wasn't expecting to see
a frog inside.
Ah, I was careless.
Let me have a look as well.
It will die, if uncle you look at it!
- Huh?
- You can't look!
Do you want to eat this?
Thank you very much.
It's nice, isn't it?
Working in a place like
this every day.
It's fine here.
Why don't you pick them up?
Oh, thank you very much.
Granny has said lots of funny things.
Funny things? Like what?
She said you're just like the
mummy of an ancient boy
who was brought back
to life in this world.
So, it’s hard for you to live in Ama.
That's right! Previously, you were
sent to steal something.
Did you know about that?
I was watching.
But you saved Granny.
Risking your own life.
But, not long ago,
you seemed to be following me, right?
Better not do that again,
knowing that everyone's
watching you.
Would you like to eat anything?
Grilled mackerel or fried tofu?
You don't seem to have an appetite,
so fried tofu it is.
Uncle, you saw my frog, right?
I did.
The frog's dead.
All because you've seen it.
Screw you!
What happened to your face?
I fell off the stairs.
Liar!
Hey, did you really stumble?
- Yeah...
- Were you hit by someone?
I have to go now.
What's going on with you?
Since I lack necessary documents,
I don't have health insurance,
which means I can't get sick.
Running out of road,
I can only go to Kyoto.
"Let Mr. Okamoto have a look
at my wounds."
That's what I thought.
I have been here in Amagasaki,
for more than 4 months now.
It's obvious that
I don't belong here.
Sooner or later,
I have to leave this place.
I have a premonition of that.
This scented bag,
when the moment of farewell
is certain,
I want to give it to
sister Seiko as a gift.
I'm buying it in preparation for that.
Send this to sister Seiko
before 12:00 pm today.
Understood?
Today at noon.
See ya.
I'm always having nightmares.
This is a tuberose.
Blossomed secretly in the dark.
I've only seen its blooming once.
Just like this.
Well, Sai asked me to give you this.
- It's so annoying.
- Huh?
This has nothing to do with you.
- You went to see a doctor, right?
- Yes.
Sorry for making you worry.
There are a lot of naughty
ones around here.
But, for some,
they still need to be careful.
Thank you for your visit.
A beautiful lady?
Did you find her in a hot spring?
-  A woman from the hostess bar.
- Hostess bar?
The elders will be back soon.
Hurry.
Hey, give that to me.
I'll greet them honestly.
You not giving it?
Wanna do that again?
Once would be enough!
Just stop this already.
Give him a break, okay?
Divine Punishment!
The expression "Divine Punishment"
is quite popular at school now.
Divine Punishment!
If you remember this expression
for 4 years, you will die.
What?
Running around and calling out
the phrase "Divine Punishment".
Divine Punishment!
Divine Punishment?
Divine Punishment:
punishing others for God.
Divine Punishment...
Divine Punishment!
Mr. Ikushima,  can I have a moment?
Please.
In fact, I need to ask you for a favor.
What's up?
Will you keep this for me,
just for two or three days?
Should I just keep that in the closet?
Then, it's all good. Thank you.
Something's wrong?
All you do is eyeing women.
- You better stop doing that.
- Yes...
It's your only hateful behavior.
I'm glad you understand that.
What is it? Don't look at me
with that weird face.
Thanks for giving me
cherries last time.
How's the food I gave you?
Delicious?
Yes.
It'd be good if I could bring
them to you often.
What?
- Why are you acting so surprised?
- Well...
Do you think something
is wrong with me?
No, I just...
Mr. Ikushima.
This place is not suitable for you.
You're different from us.
I also wounded my hand with a knife.
What happened?
Nothing serious.
Your face seems to have
recovered fully.
Despite the scar.
All right.
Would you mind taking good
care of this here?
The room doesn't have enough light.
This plant might be able to bloom here.
Watering a bit every day.
It should be all right.
It's fine if it withered.
Got it.
Just once more.
How good it would be
to watch it bloom at night.
I'm always having nightmares.
Sister Seiko knows,
that story of the tuberose.
That day will be coming soon,
the day when I have to
leave this place.
Stand up.
I'm prepared, in case of emergency.
But,
I don't want to leave here.
Five days ago, that night,
after that heart-pounding start,
with Aya.
I think I might get killed.
It's fine if that happens.
Because of that,
I like being here.
What's up?
Nothing.
Cheer up! Takeshi.
Greet this unusual brother.
What's up?
The box that you asked me to keep...
Oh, that.
That's a very important one.
Yes. Because it's very important...
I have some reasons and would
like you to keep it a little longer.
No, I can't keep that for you anymore.
I believe I deposited 10.000 yen
with you at Amagasaki Station.
Should have given you
10.000 yen as storage fee.
Last time, I gave you too little
at the train station.
Mr. Horimayu...
Huh? When did you start
calling me that?
I'm sorry.
You know,
that box is as important as my life.
I'm asking you, as a man,
to keep this to yourself.
Wouldn't you like to accept it?
No. It's not like that.
Should I tell this to sister Seiko...?
No, not that fool.
She's just a greedy bitch.
She messed up and burned something
I care about, you know.
It's really a good thing.
What?
Mr. Ikushima.
You're a man without self-confidence.
I used to look down on you.
Only a fool would accept a low
salary like that.
Doing that boring work.
Burying your head in it every day.
It's no wonder you have no vigor.
No, I'm just useless...
You don't watch TV after work.
And you have no hobbies.
No wonder Aya is worried about you.
She said, “he’s just like the
mummy of an ancient boy.”
How about it?
Why don't you screw Aya once?
Her clit is itching.
When I touched it,
it seemed eager for
you to touch it.
That's how people say that, right?
It makes me impotent
through jealousy.
No, how could I do that?
She has good pussy juice.
If you excuse me,
I have to go now.
Come in.
The paper airplanes are ready.
Shinpei, what's going on?
It's Yamane.
Yamane from Tokyo.
- Don't come in.
- Hey!
- You're Ikushima, right?
- Wait, wait a second.
What's wrong?
Sorry for coming here
all of a sudden.
Now, I'm working.
I'm sorry.
Can you go and wait for me at the shop
in front of the train station?
That won't do it.
I need to talk to you.
I went to where you used to live.
Heard that you came here.
Others told me you weren't there.
My mind went blank.
You disappeared from Kamagasaki.
I even thought you were already dead.
I've died to come to this place.
Why did you come to this sort of place?
Because it's near Koshien.
There must be some
particular reason.
Can you leave? I'm sorry.
Why?
I don't get it.
Why are you doing this?
Are you still writing your draft?
Forget it!
I have a job now.
I'm earning money for food,
showering, drinking, and sleeping.
That's all there is to it.
I... can finally get my own
project in the editorial office.
If you've finished your writing,
hand it to me.
Forget it.
I'll help you, in any capacity.
Come with me.
- Please, leave.
- Hey...
Leave me alone!
What happened to that guy?
He's been working hard.
Always have and always will.
You're doing that again,
that kind of work.
I do as much as I can
to read writings from new writers.
- Your writings were...
- Stop it.
The other side is powerful, right?
It's not like that!
Don't be so loud!
I don't want people to listen!
What's up with this ruckus?
- Can I come in?
- Please do.
- This place is so hot.
- Thank you.
- How's it going in the shop?
- It's fine, it's fine.
Eat while it's hot.
It looks very delicious.
My pleasure!
Ikushima.
Now, you sit here.
Sorry. I've got other things to do.
It's better if I wasn't here, right?
No, that's not it.
Please, don't think like that.
I think this is a good opportunity,
to hear why you ended up
squeezing yourself here.
Come, sit down.
I'm definitely glad to be here.
I'm not lying.
I could go elsewhere, certainly.
But I feel it's just good to be here.
That's what the other
me really thinks.
You can't really say that.
It's all nonsense.
How can that even be a reason?
Did you hear what that
woman says like a prayer?
"Gotanda, Meguro, Ebisu..."
She's not chic and whim to chant
the names of Tokyo stations.
She's saying that, sweating
her guts out.
Miss Kishida.
Please, listen to me.
This man has something he has to do.
- Forget it!
- Listen to me.
- This is why I came here, too.
- Hey!
I've made everything clear.
Say it now.
Ikushima, let's go back to Tokyo.
You shouldn't stay here,
doing this kind of work.
Is it funny?
No, it's nothing.
"Be here and do this kind of work."
It feels rude to hear
someone say that.
But it's still true.
Ikushima.
You're a lucky person.
Having a friend like him
who tells you the truth.
Why did I keep looking for you?
Why did you come to a place like this?
- I won't be interrupting you.
- Sorry about this.
I'll be leaving.
Thank you very much!
Miss Kishida, I hope you understand.
You're asking me?
Don't care about my opinion.
It's a wonder you can live
in such a place.
Aren't you feeling hot?
Thank you for your care
during all this time.
Don't worry about my business.
Here, your salary for this month.
Sai will be leaving tomorrow.
What's up with Sai?
- He's going to do the same old business.
- I see.
Have you found a new place to go?
No, not yet.
Is that so?
But I don't want you
to stay here either.
I hope you can leave.
You are different from
the people here.
You're the kind of person
who cannot live here.
There's still a lot left here.
Deal with it before you go.
Tell me to come and check after
you're done with everything
I got it.
By the way,
have you seen Aya today?
I haven't seen her for the past
two or three days.
Really?
If you see her,
let me know immediately.
- I understand.
- It must be done.
Did something happen?
Frankly, it's better
if you don't know.
The box that you are keeping.
Take it out.
Okay.
Ikushima.
- This is my request, right?
- Yeah.
Take that with you to
Daimotsu, please.
Shall I do it?
Correct.
Poor you.
Living in such a hot room.
Go to the train station.
The address's there.
In the 5th floor, a guy named Saito
will be waiting for you.
You send the box there.
Let me be clear.
Give it to him. That's it.
Erm...
The guy named Saito has a birthmark on
his forehead. He's around 50 years old.
This is the reward you
worked so hard for.
Who is it?
Horimayu asked me to come here.
Come in.
- Come on, have a seat.
- Thank you.
There's no mistake.
This is the thing.
- Is that so?
- Thank you.
A man is following me.
Would that be Horimayu's guys?
Did he mention that?
Can that man really be trusted?
Horimayu is endorsed and hardcore.
You did us a huge favor.
I'll be leaving, then.
How was it?
I already delivered it.
And you're sure it's Saito, right?
- The guy with a birthmark here...
- Did he say anything?
No, nothing.
Tomorrow, come to the Tennoji Station
on the Osaka Loop Line.
12 o'clock at noon.
If you can't earlier,
come at 5 PM at the latest.
From Aya.
Open the door!
It's me!
You're not opening?
Open the door! It's me!
Sister, I'm sorry.
Thank you very much.
- Sorry about that.
- No big deal.
I couldn't come at 12.
But you still came.
It's nothing.
What are you talking about?
I thought you were not coming.
I even thought it was wrong
to wait for Mr. Ikushima here.
This is terrific!
Mr. Ikushima.
Run away with me.
To where?
To the world outside.
Take me there.
Do you have any cash?
I do, but only some.
Enough to pay for these.
- I need 30 million yen.
- What?!
Without it,
my elder brother will be put together
with concrete and thrown into the ocean.
Sorry for the wait.
My brother has violated their rules.
Did Horimayu know about this?
The place where I live.
My brother has put many things there.
But I do now know.
Because he is like a rotten egg.
I get it.
That's a really hard life to live.
- Hard life?
- Yeah.
Living like a dead body.
Ikushima,
are you a bit light-hearted today?
A little bit.
You ran away from auntie, right?
No.
I got fired.
Enjoy your food.
Auntie must be disappointed now.
Yes, I understand.
I have always been like this.
I keep wasting time while living.
All that Ikushima has said is
difficult to understand.
"Wasting time".
I don't know what that means.
That's called a Kalavinka.
Kalavinka?
A bird living in the Western Pure Land.
It has a human's face.
But the body of a bird.
I heard it sings with
the voice of a Buddha.
Although I, by contrast, miserably
grew up in a ditch in Amagasaki.
It's pretty crappy.
Ikushima.
Did you know about Kalavinka?
Nope.
It's surprising that there are things
Ikushima doesn't know.
I wonder...
What's up?
- Did I do something wrong?
- No...
Ikushima.
You're really not funny.
No, but I mean well.
- Is this for me?
- Yes.
Just pocket your pride.
How dare you give me such a thing?
How uninteresting.
This is all the money I have with me.
I was scammed for 30 million yen
by my brother.
Plus 10 million in interest.
Brother will get killed if the money's
not there before the 20th.
What can we do with
your pocket money here?
He must be searching for me like crazy.
But if I don't go back there,
who will tell them what my
whereabouts are?
Ikushima.
That's enough, right?
It's okay now, right?
What's the matter?
- I want to leave this place just now.
- What?
Why?
You slept really well.
- You're not eating that?
- Take it, please.
It's so quiet.
Here's so nice.
Ikushima.
Show me the bank account book again.
- Can you give me this?
- Sure.
You sure?
But I cannot pay on credit.
I like the one that can't
pay on credit.
Did you feel good
when we were doing that?
I'm happy to do that
if that makes you feel good.
I'm a Kalavinka,
a bird for entertaining people.
I wear a Kalavinka on my back.
- Am I that scary of a woman?
- No...
It's all right.
I'm not the kind of woman
who only wants Ikushima's money.
I just fancy your cock.
That's all.
- I'm just that kind of woman.
- No, you're not.
How so?
How can I say it...?
I'm already a changed woman.
I'm no longer who I used to be.
Just like the viscera that you
worked with, I'm a dead person.
A ghost just like me,
who only fancies your cock.
What a stupid woman I am.
You are...
a lotus flower.
You're a good person.
Takeshi, this is
the pong-pong stone house.
Takeshi, look.
You can hear the voices
of the dead, right?
You know,
someone being sealed
with concrete...
- I've seen that before.
- What?!
I beg you!
Help me!
Stop it. Please?
I beg you... please!
Please! I beg you!
Help me! Help me!
What...?
What are you doing?
Whoa! He's pissing!
Saying "Help me" over and over.
Crying and screaming like that.
Then, being thrown in the
water in an instant.
Brother might end up like that.
That cylinder might still be
at the bottom of the ocean.
Do you remember who
was inside it?
It was a man who used
to follow me very often.
Aren't you Aya?
What are you doing here?
Just a moment ago, past noon,
my office was having a celebration
party. Why couldn't you come?
Oh, really?
Is big brother still there?
He left already.
I don't know why, but he was
just talking to my fella.
In the meantime,
Mr. Horimayu came to see us.
Weren’t you with him?
You purposely come to such
places in such a hot day.
Oh, you were on a date together?
That's right.
We're thinking of going to the zoo.
To the zoo?
Really now?
I love the hippos there,
watching them poop and walk
at the same time.
While their poop is
eaten by other fish.
Their poop?
Is it edible?
Really now?
It's very delicious,
why don't you give it a try?
See you later.
What do you really want?
Now, I have nowhere to go.
So, you wanna be with me?
Yes... Take me with you.
But where shall we both go?
Ikushima,
let's go for a final trip
there tomorrow.
- It's a place worth remembering.
- Huh?
Living with Ikushima here,
at this moment,
will soon become a memory.
I have to do it nicely.
That's right.
Let's polish yours, too.
We may be different in other
aspects, except this.
Ikushima.
Before we go,
I have to do one thing first.
Huh?!
I have to get rid of this bag,
at Tennoji temple here.
Could you wait there for me?
Now, it's before 9:00.
I'll be there at 11:30, for sure.
Do not come.
Don't come!
I wanna get away from everything!
Sorry for the long wait!
No problem.
Ikushima.
You were waiting for me, right?
No, I...
Thanks.
I'll remember this
for the rest of my life.
I'll put my luggage in here.
You also came.
Forget that stuff.
I don't need it.
We'll soon arrive at Akame station.
You should know that as well, right?
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Please, enjoy.
This is a lovely place, isn't it?
Yes, it is.
When my brother was in primary school,
he went on a field trip
to this place once.
But, due to the lack of money,
my mom pretended to be sick
and lied to my brother.
She said: “I'll give you some candy,
rest and nurse me.”
My brother was stunned by that,
and he ate nothing the whole day.
Sometimes, memories are painful.
I now am visiting a place
where my brother hasn't been to.
How's the tattoo? It's a masterpiece
my master made long ago
The wound seems to have faded.
It must hurt a lot
in the beginning, right?
Not just painful.
I thought I was going to die.
I always tattoo with a thirst for blood.
Master's tattoos are famous for
being the most painful in Japan.
Hey, record that pervert.
That way, right?
Take this and go there.
Okay!
Give me that.
How does it look?
Does it describe who I am?
Kids are not reliable.
Says you!
I'm going to take over
the world with my tattoo!
Do as you wish. I still don't
understand the world of a tattoist.
Master, don't say that.
You should be nicer to the women.
No, women are stronger.
Among all my clients, only two
women did not cry at all.
The first one is this auntie.
And the other one who didn't
even let out a moan was...
They're connected!
Connected!
Ikushima.
- You can let go of me.
- Huh?
I can't get you killed.
I thought I wanted to die
together with Ikushima.
I really thought so.
When I saw Ikushima waiting for me
at the train station,
I was really happy.
Today is the 20th of August
that I told you before.
Now, I need to go back to Osaka.
I thought of doing nasty
things to Ikushima.
Forgive me, will you?
But I felt really happy.
Is that so?
Ikushima.
Hug me once again.
My real name is Yi Mingchong,
I'm a Korean.
Yes, sister Seiko already told me.
Auntie has such a big mouth.
I think she's just a lonely person.
Ikushima,
look at the stars and
remember auntie, right?
Yes.
I have something to give her.
What is it?
It's not something precious.
Aren't you going to tell me?
It's this.
I want to give it to sister Seiko.
A scented bag.
It really has a good smell.
Sister has taken good care
of me all this time.
Ikushima, give this one to me, please.
Huh?!
Buy another one for auntie, will you?
I now have taken everything
that Ikushima owns.
We are arriving at Yagi Station.
After that, there are Yoshino, Tenri,
Nara, and, finally, Kyoto.
I'm getting off here.
From here to Kyoto,
and from there to Hakata.
THE END
Directed by:
Genjiro Arato