Tar, you've been silent since we met.
What's up with you?
Boyfriend?
No… What are you doing these days?
Oh, that. Mostly drawing.
What? Just drawing?
No. My lovely cousin is just being humble.
She is secretly making
an illustration book, guys.
Reva, no!
Look at the first page.
See what's behind it as well.
Oh, my. Honestly, I'm speechless.
-That looks great!
-That's so great!
It's great, don't hide it.
Just look at it.
That's so cute! Is it about a couple?
Is this about you? Wait, there's a guy.
Who's this guy?
Tim!
-I invited Timur too. Is that okay?
-Timur who?
Timur, our classmate, Rev.
How could you forget?
-Hello, everyone.
-Hey, Tim.
You're Rumit, right? Of course!
Rumit who?
He was my high school hero, babe.
Why is that?
Because he used to let me copy his work.
Right, Rumit? Thank you so much.
Rev, why do you call him "Rumit"?
If you spell Timur backwards,
it becomes "Rumit," right?
-Okay, I get it.
-Whatever she says.
Anyway, after we're done here,
don't go straight home.
Let's go for some karaoke.
You like it, right?
-I'm so in!
-As always.
Tar, karaoke, okay?
-What? After this?
-Yes, after this.
-I can't. I have an appointment.
-You're such a busy person.
-Tim, can you join us?
-Sorry, I can't too.
Excuses, excuses… Let's just go
for karaoke and see how it goes.
Let's watch the movie next time, okay?
Reva was talking too much.
It's okay. There will be a next time.
TICKETS
Do you want to watch this one instead?
No.
-We still can watch this.
-No way.
No?
Anyway, it's been a while
since we came here.
-Really?
-Let's just stay here.
Okay.
Isn't this the table
where we had our first conversation?
Isn't it that one?
No, this one.
I remember you were wearing a blue shirt,
and your hair looked so shiny,
too much hair wax maybe,
and it was combed backwards.
And then I approached you.
That's right!
And you realized that
we went to the same high school.
What if that was just me teasing you?
Oh, so you used to stalk me?
No. Reva told me.
I was just wondering,
the smartest kid in his class,
the teacher's pet,
suddenly becomes a volunteer
at the open-air cinema.
So it's true then. If Reva knows…
-the whole planet knows!
-The whole planet knows!
But that's cool.
I'm glad that Reva told you.
If she didn't, how could I have met you?
Even though you moved
to Australia afterwards,
and then started dating…
What's his name again?
-Tim, let's drop this topic!
-Oh!
Was it Nanda? The heir of an oil tycoon.
A perfect son-in-law for your mom.
But you're a million times better, Tim.
What matters now
is that I'm happy with you.
Are you happy with me?
About our parents…
I'll find a way to talk to them later.
But let's not rush it.
-Let's go home now.
-Okay.
-But let me pray first.
-Let's pray together.
-Sorry, I'm not Muslim.
I see.
LEAVE YOUR FOOTWEAR HERE
RESTAURANT PADANG JAYA
OPEN
I'm surprised you're not looking
for me today, Ms. Illustrator.
Ms. Illustrator Girl?
Sorry, Mr. Accountant.
-I'm busy organizing the anniversary…
-Tar…
put down your phone.
Dad…
Can I have a little bit?
Okay, this is the last time.
Hello. What's up, Roy?
Roy, I'm having lunch with my family.
I'll call you later.
Okay, cool. Bye.
Mom, do we really have
to go to Nanda's wedding?
Of course, we have to.
Nanda's family invited us.
It won't look good if we don't.
Don't you want to see the Grand Mosque?
Not everyone can get in, you know?
Even though I'm sure Nanda just wants
to show what you could have had
if you didn't break up with him.
You really have to say that, Mom?
Just kidding.
No need to pout like that,
or your face will age faster.
I'm going to the toilet.
Watch my bag.
I'm busy organizing
my parent's anniversary party
the day after tomorrow.
I'm about to meet the event organizer.
Yes, Roy?
Miss me?
Well… a little bit.
Really? Just a little bit?
You want to meet up tonight?
-What are you looking for, Pete?
-The car keys.
Tim!
-Yes?
-Don't forget the microwave!
-Yes, Mom.
-Where is it?
Type 906.
It's not here.
I told you yesterday,
I put the keys in the marble jar.
When did you say that?
That's why you should listen
when someone is talking to you.
Tim, don't get the wrong microwave.
-This shipment is important. Okay?
-Yes, Mom. I'm about to take it.
Sure. I'll pick you up as usual
at the end of the street.
Okay. I'll tell Mom that
I'm going out with Reva.
Ahem.
Bagus!
I thought we are going to meet an EO
for your anniversary party?
-Good afternoon.
-Bagus, have a seat.
Here.
I'm good.
Tar, do you remember Bagus?
Auntie Sari's son.
You used to play together
when you were a little.
Auntie, I'm so sorry for being late.
I forgot how bad Jakarta's traffic is.
-It's okay. Have you eaten?
-Yes, I have.
Huh?
What is this for?
I borrowed it from the church,
for our Bible study later at home.
Mom, you didn't give another discount
for the microwave, did you?
It was free.
Jeez.
Mom, how can we make money
if you just keep
giving them things for free?
But it's for the church in Kupang, Tim.
So I consider it a donation.
But you could have asked me first, Mom.
I have spent my time
taking care of your business finances.
I swear to God, we'll do better
selling this car to the junkyard!
Think about the business side too, Mom.
We can't survive like this.
Yes, I know.
Finally!
Tim, have you brought
that wedding invitation inside?
The one from the head of the neighborhood.
Yes, it's on the dining table.
Did you know that his child
is two years younger than you?
Don't you want to find a girlfriend
at the church, Tim?
Pete!
Tar, Bagus just got
his master's degree from the US.
What are you up to these days, Bagus?
But I also run my own
fintech start-up company.
Isn't he great, Tar?
You're also single right, Gus?
What do you do?
I'm working on an illustration book.
Gus, Mentari's illustrations are great.
-Let's sit over there.
-Over there, right? Sounds great.
Selma?
-Oh, my god!
-Remember me?
Yes! We haven't seen each other
in such a long time!
How are you?
What's keeping you busy these days?
Well, I'm a member of the mosque council.
How about you, Selma?
I work from home, selling things online
with the help of my kids.
Sometimes, I volunteer at the church too.
Auntie Selma, how are you?
Wait… you went to the same school
as Timur, didn't you?
Remember her, Tim?
What? Yes.
Please enjoy your lunch,
sorry for interrupting.
-See you.
See you.
Tim, what's her name?
All I remember is how annoying she was.
-Auntie Rahayu, Mom.
-Right.
I don't think so, Tim. Not a good idea.
Why? Because my entire family is here.
Bagus?
Don't worry about him. He's just
a random guy my mom introduced me to.
Tim, I'm so sorry,
but I have to practice my speech.
Can we talk about this later?
Okay?
I'm sorry.
Ladies and gentlemen, aunties and uncles,
before we continue our dinner…
Dad and Mom, 25 years is not a short time.
Did you notice? For the past few months,
I‘ve kept you out of my painting studio.
But it is not without any reason.
I know this simple gift
will never be able to return
the love you have given me.
But hopefully, this painting can represent
the extraordinary commitment
between the two of you.
This painting is a symbol of love…
that… well…
both of you have given to our family.
Let's give a round of applause to Mentari
who seems to be a bit nervous tonight!
Okay, ladies and gentlemen,
let's continue our dinner.
Are you crazy?
Tar…
I don't want to be…
just another random guy in your life.
Why didn't you tell me
that we need to change clothes?
-Hello, Uncle and Auntie.
-Hello.
Let me do it, Mom.
-It's quite heavy.
-Yes, it is.
I know I should have
introduced Timur to you earlier.
But what do you think, Mom?
Too tilted.
Can you shift it a little?
Yes. That's it.
I'm not talking about the painting, Mom.
Ah…
He seems nice.
What do you mean, Mom?
I'm not mad, Tar.
But, here's the thing.
You have to understand
that not everything in this world…
will suit you.
Can you fetch me that purple blouse?
From now on, you have to learn to choose…
which one suits you best,
and which one doesn't.
So, you think Timur isn't right for me?
You don't know him.
You haven't even talked to him.
Come, sit.
I know, I haven't talked to him.
But I know…
that you two have too many differences.
But that doesn't mean we're incompatible.
And it isn't always wrong.
You're not there yet,
but there will be a time
when you need someone to look up to.
Do you want to pray alone forever?
He will never be able to be your imam.
Are you sure?
So think about it carefully.
Okay?
In the name of the Father, the Son,
and the Holy Spirit,
-Amen.
-Let's eat now.
-Yes.
It's not much.
-We have some fruit punch. We have…
-…like to eat. You're usually the fastest!
-We have some fruit punch.
-I'm sure it will…
Here are the glasses.
Just open that.
What the hell, Pete!
I thought the Bible study was tomorrow.
I thought so too.
Mom said some couldn't make it tomorrow,
so they decided to do it today.
Call Mentari, just tell her
to come some other time.
No way. She's already on her way.
I can't just tell her to go back now.
You're so dead.
Don't worry, Bro.
I'll make sure to be there…
at your funeral.
Get lost.
Ladies, the water is over here.
Thank you.
-Mom.
-What is it?
I want to introduce you to someone.
Who?
I want to introduce you to my girlfriend.
Why didn't you ever tell me? Who is she?
Mentari.
Auntie Rahayu's daughter.
You met her at the Padang restaurant,
remember?
I've invited her to come, Mom.
Will you meet her?
Tim, I think you're old enough
to think about your future seriously.
I know. That's why I asked her to come.
-Because I'm serious with Mentari.
-You know how her family is.
Their lifestyle.
They're different from us.
But Mom, you can at least
meet Mentari first.
I feel bad, Mom.
I'm sure that you will like her.
She's a nice girl.
Look, Tim.
Let me tell you something.
If you insist on keeping
this relationship,
trust me, you're just wasting your energy.
I don't want you to be disappointed.
Do you understand what I mean?
So many people. Did you invite
your whole family to meet me?
-Peter!
-You're here, Mentari.
-Let me call Mom.
-Hey!
I have something for your mom.
Sorry if it's too simple.
I hope your mom likes it.
It's nice, Tar.
But, Tar, I told you the wrong schedule.
My mom is hosting a Bible study tonight.
I see.
But don't worry, we can find another time.
Is that okay?
But everything's fine, right?
Yes, everything's fine.
Where's your car?
Did you drive here?
Yes.
I have an idea. You'll like it.
Pete, I'm going out.
Stay home with Mom.
Help her clean up when it's over.
-Okay?
-Yes, boss.
Let's go.
Now, tell me everything.
I've told you everything.
Are you sure?
What about your mom?
You know her.
What are you doing?
No one is picking up.
Congratulations,
your book is a bestseller!
You sold 10,000 copies.
That's not bad to cover
our wedding expenses.
What do you mean by that?
We will talk about it sooner or later.
Okay, what kind of wedding would you like?
I've always wanted to have
a simple wedding,
a private dinner…
in a garden
and we only invite our closest friends.
Everything has to be simple and…
What about the dress?
High neck top.
Floral brocade with a satin skirt.
Minimalist, but elegant.
It will be the prettiest wedding dress
I've ever seen.
Don't!
-Aren't you scared?
-Of a butterfly? Of course not.
Besides, my grandpa told me
that it might be the spirit
of an ancestor who's visiting.
Same!
-My mom also said the same thing.
-Really?
I guess our families
aren't so different after all.
Let's do it, Tar.
Let's do it all.
What?
All of it.
Let's talk to my mom.
Okay. When?
Right now.
Finally, you're awake.
How was the crash? Was it hard?
Timur Nayoan, right?
You're the last one today.
And…
your status is still on hold.
So you can wait around here.
Who are you?
Where am I?
I'm Aria. You don't have to worry.
You are where you should be.
Just follow my instructions
and you'll be fine.
Let's talk to my mom.
If there's any status update,
I'll tell you…
I was with my girlfriend.
Where is she?
-Full name?
-Mentari Soenaryo.
She's not here.
Then where is she?
Sorry, I can't tell you that.
I am not authorized to…
Hey, where are you going?
Hey!
What is it?
Did you change your mind again, Wang?
It's not like that…
Well…
Wang, we can't be like this forever.
We've talked about this many times.
Okay, but you have to let me go.
I promise…
we will meet again.
Wang!
Hey!
I'd told you it's beyond my power.
-His name must be here!
-It's not here.
-Tar! Mentari!
-Timur!
-Hey!
Timur!
Tar…
-Tar, are you okay?
-Tim, I think something is wrong.
Hey, who are you? You can't be here.
Mr. Gotot! Catch him!
You catch him! Chase them!
Here, Tar.
How could you lose them?
I'm sorry, Mr. Gotot.
What's his name?
Timur, Mr. Gotot.
Timur! Mentari!
Come out, kids.
Stop playing around, it's tiring!
If you come out now,
we can discuss it nicely.
Come on!
-Okay, sir.
-Good.
Let's have a good discussion.
Okay, good.
I just want to know…
why we're here and what place is this.
Don't worry.
This is just a transitory place
before you go to your final destination.
Then why aren't Mentari and I
waiting at the same gate?
Explain to them.
Afterlife.
You have different afterlives.
Afterlife?
Did you see the gate back there?
Did you?
That gate will take you
to your own respective afterlife.
But after we pass the gate,
can we still be together, sir?
You have different faiths, correct?
Am I right?
Then you can't.
Why?
Everyone has their own place
in the grand design.
You'll disturb the balance of the universe
if you defy that rule.
And if that happens, you'll regret
that you didn't listen to me.
-Come on, let's be done with it.
-No, wait.
But what if we were married?
Surely the wedding vow
can override those rules, right?
But were you married?
Not yet, right?
Listen. After a few centuries
on this job, I can tell easily.
Now your situation is very complicated.
-Technically, between one and another…
-Run, Tar.
Hey! I haven't finished talking.
Timur! Mentari!
Smile. Lower it a bit.
One, two… Okay.
Okay, next pose. Okay, Jo.
Are we back?
On the left cheek.
Reflector ready?
Smile. One, two… Okay.
One more time.
Okay, Natasha. Pose.
One, two, three.
Hold.
Change pose. One, two…
Tar.
One, two…
Tim!
We can't touch anything natural…
or organic, Tim.
So we are ghosts now?
-Don't say that.
-Then what?
-Okay, don't panic.
-I'm not panicking. You are worse than me.
Are we dreaming?
If this is a dream, is it yours or mine?
Tim.
I once came here to draw.
It's not far from my home.
Let's go there and ask someone.
How? Can we do that?
Well, I don't know.
Do you have a better idea?
Sir!
Sir, where are you going?
Madam said that
you should stay at home. Okay?
Don't worry.
I'll tell them it was my idea.
Just take care of the house.
Oh, Dad!
Be patient.
-Yu…
-Hey!
-It's all your son's fault! His fault!
-Yu…
-Calm down.
-Watch what you're saying.
It's your daughter's car!
If he didn't go with your daughter,
nothing would have happened.
It's your responsibility!
-Your daughter should be!
-Your son drove the car!
Stop!
No, Dad. Don't.
This is a hospital.
Everyone needs to behave.
Yu.
This has been a tough day for all of us.
Please calm down.
We can talk about it another…
-Dad! Are you okay?
-Dad!
Nurse!
How's Grandpa?
He's still in the ICU.
I think that's not how it works, Tim.
Then how?
When I was a kid,
Grandpa told me this story.
He told me that his uncle
was once kidnapped by the devil.
When he was kidnapped,
he said he saw a forest…
Grandpa.
Come, Tar.
What are you doing?
You said Grandpa
knows something about the forest.
Grandpa.
Grandpa!
Mentari?
Where are we?
Thank god, you're back.
Grandpa.
You used to tell me a story
about your uncle
who was kidnapped by the devil, right?
Did he really see a forest?
Yes, he said it was a mystical forest.
How did he come back to life, Grandpa?
An angel brought him back.
The angel said it wasn't his time yet.
Because if he stayed, it would disturb
the balance of the universe.
Grandpa…
Actually, we just rescued you
from the forest guard.
You mean, that forest really exists?
So….
Am I dead?
And you're dead too?
Maybe…
We have to go back to the forest.
Why Grandpa? You can stay here with us.
But I've been waiting
for this for a long time.
Aren't you afraid?
Since your grandma passed away,
I am not afraid anymore.
So don't you ever be afraid of death.
Okay?
I can't come with you, Grandpa.
Why?
Because…
You don't need to worry, Mentari.
Please take care of Mentari.
Tar.
Goodbye now, Grandpa.
Tar, why didn't you just go with Grandpa?
Because I didn't want to meet
those two people.
And then we'd be separated forever.
Yes, but you might be able
to go back and live.
Like Grandpa's uncle.
But what if only one of us
is allowed to go back?
Also, seeing your mother
and my mother that way…
I'm not ready, Tim.
Are you thinking the same way?
Yes, of course, Tar.
What does this mean?
I don't know.
Where should we go now?
How about going to your favorite spot?
It's closed.
It's made of wood.
Seeing a painting like this…
reminds me that
I still have a lot to learn.
I think yours is just as great.
Oh, really?
Yes.
Even though you rarely show me your work.
I don't even know the details
of the book you are working on.
What do you want to know?
Everything.
The characters are a couple.
What's interesting about them?
Yes, they're a couple.
But they're different.
Different? How?
Everything.
-What else?
-And then…
they're hiding it from their parents.
I don't know
if people could relate to that.
If it's personal for you,
I'm sure people would relate.
Tim…
I haven't finished my book.
I'm sorry.
It's all right.
There's nothing we can do.
Where should we go tomorrow?
It's already tomorrow.
Then today, and tomorrow,
and the day after tomorrow?
How about leaving the country?
-No?
-No.
We should stay at the Presidential Palace.
No way, there are lots of ghosts there!
-But you are also a ghost!
-Stop it!
Tim!
Who are you?
Wait!
Why are you following me?
How can you see us?
Wow. It's been a while since I saw this…
You're still in a coma.
-Interesting.
-Wait!
Where are you going?
Home. Where are you staying?
We're staying at…
We don't have anywhere to stay.
Can we come with you?
It's no use.
You won't be able to see the place.
Why?
Because you still have one foot
in the human realm.
And this place is not for humans.
I don't understand.
Let me explain.
Now, your eyes are closed like this.
There are two things that you can do.
Go up, back to your life,
or dive deeper into this abyss,
move away from your life,
and maybe you will see
this beautiful place
where there is no envy,
anger, and judgment.
-But how do we do that?
-I can't tell you how.
Everyone is different.
You can figure it out yourselves.
Wait, she's gone!
I've heard stories about people in comas
suddenly disappearing.
But this is the first time
I've seen it myself.
How's the story?
Usually, they like to be
near their bodies.
How do I get her back?
Sorry, I can't be of much help.
Mentari!
Tar!
Tari.
I remember when you were little,
you said you wanted to go
around the world,
you wanted to paint…
and then teach other kids how to draw.
Remember that, dear?
Tari.
Uncle, Auntie…
I'm leaving now.
Mom and Dad said that they'll come
after taking care of Grandpa's funeral.
Tar.
I'm sorry.
This is all my fault.
Tim…
getting into the car with you
was my choice.
If there should be anyone
to blame for all this,
it would be both of us.
Not just you, Tim.
Whatever happens…
we'll get through it together, okay?
Hi!
Welcome to Pancarona House!
Strange. It's not completely gone.
What do you mean?
The stamp. Your life.
Never mind.
-I'm Edith.
-Mentari.
I'm Timur.
Luckily someone just moved,
so this room is available.
Moved?
Yes, moved out.
Forget it. Come with me.
I'll introduce you to
the owners of this house.
This is Timur and Mentari.
I told you about them yesterday.
Hello. Welcome.
Hello.
Are you the owners of this house?
Why? We don't look like we are?
No. It's a beautiful house.
Thanks for having us.
This house is always open for everyone.
Edith, the thing you mentioned yesterday…
You too?
Wang, come here!
Man, they gave me another tablet!
You've got to see this.
Wow!
I haven't seen this in a long time.
Wait.
I think I've seen you before.
-At the forest!
-When I was with my wife… Oops!
Actually, I wonder, why are you here?
What do you mean?
What's wrong with you?
Don't you want to go back to your life?
I've tried going back to my body,
but I couldn't.
Did you try with your whole heart?
Don't think too much about it.
Here, it's for you.
What for, Uncle?
Just take it as a welcome gift.
Welcome to the place without envy, anger…
…and judgment.
Hope you enjoy your death.
Come here. Have a seat.
I have to go.
Where to?
A personal matter.
Don't be surprised.
Edith loves to wander around alone.
Since we opened up our home for everyone,
we've met a lot of
different kinds of people.
You mean ghosts.
When did you open up
this house for everyone?
Well, I waited for Diah's passing
for about 30 years.
I used to live here.
But after I died,
everyone left this house,
including my ex-husband.
So we got married
and have lived here ever since…
as ghosts.
Married?
You must be thinking
that we are mother and son.
We fell in love when we were teenagers.
But unfortunately,
Diah married someone else.
Well…
It was an arranged marriage.
Shortly after Diah got married,
I hung myself.
But after so many years…
Herman finally managed
to drive my ex-husband away,
then brought me here.
Died happily ever after.
I made a promise to Diah
that we would be together forever.
That promise binds us
even though I died before her.
Without that…
we might not have met
each other again after death.
But how did you get married here?
We just did it.
Said our vows.
You two are not married, right?
You can if you want to.
Why?
What's the problem?
Your parents' blessing?
We have different religions.
You are ghosts.
Nobody cares.
The question is not how to do it.
But are you ready to
leave everything behind?
Especially with your condition now.
Uncle.
This is where we used to sit and…
chat, joke, and debate.
Me and my wife,
we spent most of our lives together.
Even in death.
Now, somehow I feel…
empty.
Why didn't you go with her
to the afterlife?
She always says,
being a ghost only traps us in the past.
We debated about that a lot.
I tried to convince her to stay…
but she was determined to leave.
I didn't want to force her to stay here,
so I let her go.
Turns out, it's harder to let someone go…
than leave someone.
Tar.
We've tried everything, honey.
The doctor said it's not instant, Yu.
It takes time.
Until when?
We already brought
all of Mentari's belongings.
Maybe…
Mentari doesn't want to go back.
Don't say that!
Maybe…
Mentari feels…
that we are not good parents.
Yu.
Mentari would never think that way.
Be patient.
Hello?
Yes, sir.
What book, sir?
Ah… Yes.
Thank you, sir.
-Yu.
-Yes?
They found a sketchbook in Mentari's car.
A sketchbook?
They only found it now?
It was kept at the police station.
If only I knew…
how to stop all of this, Tim.
Are you even ready?
What do you mean?
I have something to tell you.
Tar…
I used to regret not knowing much
about you during high school.
I also regretted…
that I didn't express my love
before you moved to Australia.
I don't want to make
the same mistake, Tar.
I want to be with you forever.
Do you want to…
leave everything behind and marry me here?
What's wrong?
Nothing, I'm just…
happy.
Congratulations!
If you need anything to prepare,
don't hesitate to call
our housekeeper, okay?
Herman and Diah, thanks a lot.
Dith!
-Where are you going?
-Personal matter.
Can we come?
You won't like it.
Aren't you curious
as to where Edith is going?
Just let her be. We don't need to know
other people's business.
You are not really good at tailing people.
Come here.
Let me introduce you
to my little sister, Kamila.
What do you think?
She's cute, isn't she?
How old is she?
She's 75 years old.
When I died,
she was younger than you.
When I was alive…
I spent too much time for myself.
I didn't spend enough time for Kamila.
Even though, during my final days,
when I needed someone,
Kamila was the one who stayed by my side.
That's why I'm waiting for her.
Since when?
Forty or fifty years ago.
Time has no meaning anymore.
But Dith,
why do you have to wait here?
It's harder to leave someone
rather than being left behind.
I've felt both.
Edith.
You better leave
if you don't want to be taken away.
You're Kamila, right?
Strange, your death is supposed
to be in two weeks.
But I'm ready, sir.
Can we go now?
Have you been dead for a long time?
I see… you should've gone
to the afterlife a long time ago.
But you're lucky
your sister passed away earlier.
At least it's enough
to cover your debt to…
To keep the balance? I understand.
-Tar.
-Yes?
Are you okay?
I'm fine. I'm just happy that
Edith got to see Kamila again.
Okay. Let's go.
Tar.
Tar?
Mentari never told us
about the contents of this book.
Honey,
does Roy still work
at the publishing house?
He does. Actually, he just got promoted.
He's looking for lots of new material.
What did he say about Mentari's book?
He's interested.
It has potential, he said,
but it still needs to be polished.
That's good, we should follow up with him.
Yes.
But the only person
who can finish the book and do it justice
is Mentari.
Tar, did you hear that?
You still have a lot of dreams
that you haven't achieved.
Wake up, kid.
Finish your book.
Tar.
Yu.
They also found this in Mentari's car.
Since when…
has she liked stuff like this?
Well…
I've just realized that
we haven't fully understood Mentari.
Hi, Pete.
Relax, Mom. The car is safe and sound.
Don't forget to prepare the 906 type.
Two units.
So someone's really going to buy them?
Yes. And there is another customer
who ordered a dozen more.
Okay, got it.
They don't need me anymore, Tar.
Pete.
Mom.
Please let me go.
I am ready to go.
Pete.
Yes, Mom.
Do you think that
your brother will forgive me?
I can't let him go like this.
I don't want him to misunderstand me.
What do you mean, Mom?
Before he left, we had an argument
about Mentari.
I told him that I disapproved
of their relationship.
Your dad and I were of the same religion,
but we still fought a lot.
What more of them,
having different religions?
I just don't want him to be disappointed.
If only I'd let her come in,
none of this would have happened.
It's my fault, Pete.
Tar, Mentari…
Tar, I'm sorry.
I shouldn't have lied.
I just didn't want to make things worse.
It's not only about your lie, Tim.
Don't you feel that
something is wrong with all of this?
Pancarona, Edith, Wang, Herman, Diah…
Us.
Us?
We're not supposed to be here, Tim.
I thought you wanted
to be with me forever.
I want to be with you forever, I do.
But not here. Not in this limbo.
So you prefer to return to a world
where everyone disagrees
with our relationship?
Don't you feel guilty
seeing your mom suffering like that?
Take a look at my mom and dad too.
They're also suffering, Tim.
It's all because of us!
Tar.
-Don't you have any feelings?
-Hey.
Can't you see that my family
doesn't need me anymore?
They're not the only ones
who are suffering.
We are too!
You have to remember, Tar.
I am willing to leave everything…
for you.
Isn't that what you want?
Mentari.
I haven't been fully honest with you, Tim.
What do you mean?
Today,
I went to the hospital
not because of my parents' pleas.
I went to hospital…
because that was what I wanted.
There were times…
when I really wanted to see them, Tim.
I really miss them,
and I want to be with them.
Okay, Tar.
But let me ask you this question.
Do you still want to leave
everything behind…
and marry me here?
Okay. Now I get it.
Tim.
ALWAYS AMAZING
LET'S DO IT AGAIN
EVERY TIME WE MEET UP
DON'T GIVE UP, MENTARI
Tim!
How's my car? Is it cool?
It's great, Uncle.
Where did you get it from?
Oh, I'll explain later.
Where's Mentari?
Had an argument?
Jeez.
Rather than being all gloomy,
just come with me now. Get in!
Where are we going?
Just get in if you want to know
where I got my car from. Come on, get in.
Oh, boy…
Okay. To cheer you up,
anything I get today will be yours. Okay?
Wow, you get an airplane!
Can you fly a plane?
She is my youngest child.
Isn't she pretty?
She takes care of my business now.
He is my oldest one.
Hey, come here!
-Uncle.
-Yes?
I think he is scared.
There's no way that
he's scared of his own dad.
Is it okay
for you to haunt him like this?
Look at his condition, Tim.
He still needs me to be around,
to protect him.
If I may ask, why is he…
He was really sick
when he was little, a high fever.
The stupid thing was I didn't take him
to a doctor, but to a shaman.
After that, he couldn't stand
on his feet anymore.
I had to be on his side
everywhere he went.
Can you imagine
how terrified he was when I died?
He became like this because of me,
and I died instead of helping him.
Why not look on the bright side?
He needs to be independent anyway.
You're just like my wife.
My wife doesn't like it
when I follow him around.
At home, to the mall.
She doesn't understand
that I need to protect him,
even from afar like this.
Besides.
if not me, who else will?
Sorry, Uncle.
So that was the reason your wife left?
I'm not asking you to understand, Tim.
But look, whose photo is it
that he keeps holding?
He can't let me go just yet.
How can I leave him
and move on to the afterlife?
He still needs me around here.
I won't leave him twice.
Maybe everyone has their own way
to bring happiness to their loved ones.
Maybe this is my way.
I'm sure you have your own way
to make Mentari happy.
Stop holding on to it.
Uncle, can I borrow your car?
Mom, the doctor said
his condition has improved today.
I hope he can recover soon.
-Honey.
-Mentari.
-Mentari! I'm calling the nurse.
-Hurry!
Mentari.
The nurse is here, Yu.
-Excuse me, ma'am.
-Nurse.
-Call the doctor now! Code blue.
-Okay.
Come on. What are you waiting for?
Tar!
Mentari!
Timur…
Hey, where are you going?
Please, let me talk to him one last time.
It's time for me to go, Tim.
I don't want to make my parents
suffer any longer.
Let me go.
Okay?
Yes, Tar.
I'll let you go…
back to the world of the living.
The balance, Tar.
My body is still in a stable condition,
and I want to give that to you.
What are you talking about, Tim?
My life is over, Tar.
My mom.
Peter.
They don't need me around anymore.
And you know…
I have always tried to make you happy.
Even though I always fail in the end.
But now…
I'm sure that
I can finally make you happy, Tar.
But not like this, Tim. Not like this.
Tar…
Promise me…
that you will follow your dreams…
and let me go, Tar.
Okay?
Wherever I will end up…
I will always love you.
Hello, Auntie.
Go ahead, Mentari.
Auntie.
I'm sorry for everything that happened.
I can only give you this book.
I'm sure Timur wants you to read this.
I'm the one who needs to apologize.
All these times, I was wrong about you.
Please don't apologize to me.
I'm the one who should be grateful to you.
Timur…
is the most beautiful memory of my life.
I heard you wanted to go abroad?
Yes, Auntie.
There are some places
I need to visit for my second book.
But not for long.
Actually, I still have
many things to do here.
I'm going to open
an art school for children,
just as Timur asked.
I miss him so much.
I'm sure he is still around.
Subtitle translation by:
Ika Wulandari & Robert Stitson