(dramatic orchestral music)
(lively music)
(people chattering)
(mellow music)
# It doesn't seem so long ago
# We laughed and joked with dear old Joe
# Then Joe departed from this Earth
# But he's around to share our mirth
# Some vandal committed desecration
# And now we ask in desperate desperation
# Oh, we'd
# Like to find the guy who took his ashes
# In the urn that stood
in front his bungalow
# For the urn in which the
scoundrel flicked his ashes
# Held the ashes of our dear, departed Joe
# Oh, we'd like to trace
the fiend who cigaretted
# Nonchalantly flicking ashes for a joke
# Well, if that's a joke,
believe us, we don't get it
# And we know it wasn't
Joe, he didn't smoke
# It was I who accidentally
spilled the ashes on that day
# And the wind blew none too gently
# Scattering most of them away
# And believe me I've been busy
makin' up for what I spilled
# I've been smokin' till
I'm dizzy, but it's filled
# It's filled
# Oh, it's not so much
because you pulled a boner
# That is making us
displeased, we'll have you know
# It is just we'll never know an El Corona
# From the ashes of our dear, departed Joe
# Our dear
# Old
# Joe
(audience applauding)
Well, what are you looking at?
I'm not trying to learn
the combination, sir.
Oh, no?
What were you looking at then?
Nothing, sir.
I was just dreaming of my
home in merry old England.
Well, do your merry old dreaming
on your own time, will you?
I think I've proven that
you can trust me, sir.
I don't trust anyone.
I wanna understand, sir.
You're a pretty smart fellow, Stumpy.
Thank you, sir.
But don't get too smart.
Oh, no, sir.
(crowd chattering)
(lively music)
[Man] Hey there, Ike.
Lend me 50, will ya, Steve?
Hey, you're a freaking freighter.
That's why you got it and I ain't.
Now you'll get rich a
lot sooner haulin' it
than I will diggin' it.
All right.
(lively orchestral music)
(audience applauding)
[Man] A dollar for a drink of whiskey,
it's robbery, that's what it is.
[Man] You steal it from the
ground, we steal it from you.
What's the difference?
[Man] He is right, I took out
close to 5,000 post gold Wednesday.
And they found Charlie in the goats
with a bullet in his head.
United States Marshal's all right.
But he ain't bulletproof.
Hello, Bill.
Gary, Gary Corbett.
- Say, don't you ever change?
- Oh-ho-ho, Gary.
Boys, I want you to
meet Pop Corbett's son.
This is Steve Jones.
- Howdy, Corbett.
- Howdy.
- And this is...
- Bailey, Joe Bailey.
Glad to meet you, Bailey.
What are you doing in Moose River?
I thought you were in the States,
learning all there is to know about mines.
I was, but now I know all about it
and I'm here to help Pop with his.
I hear it's a whopper.
Well, if it is, Pop and
you won't have it long.
- What do you mean?
- You'll sell out.
Oh, no, we won't.
Oh, yes, you will, or
lose it all together.
Looks like we find
mines to stake 'em out
for the syndicate, not for ourselves.
No, we sell 'em cheap
or they kick us off.
Well, what happened to the law?
The law's on a vacation up here.
Ask your friend Pete.
Well, I aim to but, I
missed him at the post office.
Oh, well, he'll show up later.
Have a little drink?
Thanks, I don't mind if I do.
(laughing)
- Oh, good evening, gentlemen.
- Good evening.
Well, how's the Chamber
of Commerce tonight?
(chuckling) Fine, thanks.
Hey, as a rule, you should
change the name of this place
from the Palace to the (mumbles).
(laughing)
Yeah, how would you
like to make a trade?
Your place here for half
interest in my bank.
Well, I don't know what for.
After all, they withdraw
their money from you
and deposit it with me.
(laughing)
(audience applauding)
(big band music)
I'd gladly give you my entire store
for an interest in Roxie there.
That's a deal, your store
and all the gold in Alaska
and all the tea in China.
- Uh, huh.
(laughing)
- Well, have a good time.
- Thanks.
# This is the story of a fool and his gold
- Come on, let's get a table.
# This is the story
# That has never been told
# I'll tell you how it started
# And how they really parted
# Just listen to my fable unfold
# There was a lady who
was painted and bold
# Skin just like marble
and a heart twice as cold
# The gold was her religion
# And he was such a pigeon
# More pity on that fool and his gold
# His poor old heart was brittle
# Of love he'd been bereft
# He asked for oh so little
# And that's exactly all that she left
(laughing loudly) Come on
let's have a lot of drinks.
You know I ain't no minor, I'm a sailor.
I can drink plenty, I'm tellin' ya.
All right, sailor, but quiet down,
give the lady a chance to sing.
What?
# This is a story of a fool and his gold
# Proving the difference...
Oh, I can sing better than that
with one had tied behind my back (laughs).
(yodeling)
Hey, pipe down, sailor.
Hey, don't tell me to pipe down.
Hey, let's have some more drink, come on!
Oh, I'll teach you fellas how to drink.
You don't know how.
Hey, don't leave me, don't leave me.
Hey, don't leave, where we goin'?
# That painted gold collector
# Is the only one who really got stuck
# This is the payoff and
it's time that it's told
# True that she took him
for his bundle of gold
# Here's the part that's funny
# It was stolen money
# All her work was wasted
# 'Cause the sheriff traced it
# Found it on her person
# And which there's nothing worsen
# Whosie goes to prison
# Who taketh what ain't hisen
# So don't be smart and try to part a fool
# And his gold
(audience applauding)
(crowd chattering)
Hey Nick, who busted up my number?
Some big guy down there.
Hello, stranger.
Hello.
How'd you like my act?
Well, it gets you a drink.
Well, I didn't like
yours, and it gets you this.
(laughing) Just a case
of mistaken identity.
And she (mumbles) wants me in a cup.
Well, why didn't you stop her?
Well, (mumbles) didn't stop her.
The person last March didn't stop her,
who am I to...
Besides, she slaps too fast.
Who is she?
Roxie Reagan, she's billed
as the Queen of Yukon.
- Queen got a king?
- Yeah, a king of spades.
They ought to bury him
with his own shovel.
Listen to me, brother, that
Roxie plays with a full deck.
No room even for a joker?
Not unless you wanna
finish the game face down,
in the discard.
I'll take a chance.
Oh, Roxie.
Yes?
How about having supper with me tonight,
after your last number?
Just to celebrate.
Whose birthday is it this time,
yours or George Washington's?
(laughing) Both, we
were twins, you know.
Not tonight, I've really got to go home.
Not even for a little while?
No, I've been neglecting John too much.
Maybe that's why he's...
But surely, you can't be
in love with that drunkard?
Look, Tom, you've been swell.
I like working for you.
But let's leave it at that, hmm?
All right, if you say so.
(crowd chattering)
Ah, Gary, Gary Corbett (laughs).
Petey, hi, boy am I glad to see you.
Is that so?
Well, why didn't you come straight
to the old postmaster when you got here?
Well, it was after store hours,
so I figured I'd wait for you here.
How bout something to eat?
Come on, I could eat the hip of a horse.
You probably will.
Yeah, say Joe, bring us a couple of them
porterhouse steaks, rare, flock of onions,
golden brown stack of
french fries, you know.
Yes, sir, Postmaster.
Come on Gary, let's
go eat somethin', huh?
Say, Pete, the letter I
got was in your handwriting.
Why didn't Pop write me himself?
He couldn't spell fabulous.
You mean the mine's that good?
No, but if somebody
doesn't take it away from ya,
you and your old man don't
have to worry from now on.
Imagine Pops striking it
rich after all these years.
Well, nobody deserves
it more than he does.
Now don't go leaving
yourself out, you old galute.
Where would he be if you hadn't been
staking him year after year?
Well, I got faith in him,
same as I got faith in Alaska.
I hope you're gonna stay
home for awhile now.
Home is where the gold is.
Not only gold, it's the land.
Son, you better settle
here and raise yourself
a crop of good Americans.
(crowd chattering)
Say, do I see a peculiar glint
in your elderly but active eyes?
Yes, and if you'll listen carefully,
you can hear me lickin' my chops.
I'm the oldest fool on
Roxie's list (chuckles).
- Hello, Pete.
- Hello, darling.
Roxy, I want you to meet Gary Corbett.
Gary, shake hands with Roxie Reagan.
You mind if I get acquainted
with your left hand?
I've already met your right.
Ah, I'm terribly sorry,
the bartender told me.
I mistook Mr. Corbett for a
drunk and slapped his face.
- Oh.
(laughing)
You will forgive me, won't you?
Oh, why yes, of course not.
What I mean to say is,
the pleasure was all mine.
What's this all about?
Won't you sit down?
I, I, I really can't.
Will you have supper with me?
Oh, yes, I'd love to.
Eh, what'll you have, Roxie?
Just some scrambled
eggs and coffee, waiter.
Bring me the same, please.
Well, I've read about this in books,
but I never saw it in real life before.
(laughing) Goodness.
(light, happy orchestral music)
Ah, what have we here?
Forsooth, a canine.
(crowd laughing)
Art lonesome for thy master?
Well, so am I for mine.
Only mine wears a skirt.
(crowd laughing)
No?
I wish that I had your wisdom,
to scorn the cup that destroys.
Romans, countrymen, and lovers.
Hear me for my cause, and be silent!
(crowd laughing)
If there be any among you,
any dear friend of Caesar's,
to him I say,
not that I love Roxie less,
but that I love this more!
(crowd laughing)
Why, I was in San
Francisco at the same time.
No.
Hey, Roxie, do you know the
cigar store on Market Street,
the one with the wooden
Indian in front of it?
With the dress store right next to it.
Yeah, that's the one.
To think that we might have met then.
You going in for a cigar
and me going in for a dress.
(laughing)
(crowd chattering)
(light orchestral music)
Sorry to interrupt, but...
Same as usual?
A little worse, I'm afraid.
Where in the world does he get it?
I've asked everybody in town
to help me straighten him out.
Not here, none of my bartenders
would give him anything.
We're talking about my husband.
Very charming gentleman,
but a hopeless drinker, I'm afraid.
I'll take him home.
No, your number is on shortly.
Nick and I will take him home.
Thanks, Tom, you're very sweet.
- Gary...
- Yes, Mrs. Reagan?
It's one of those difficult situations.
I couldn't explain it in the first hour.
I'm glad it explained
itself in the first hour.
You shouldn't leave your wedding
ring at home, Mrs. Reagan.
Without it, some darn fool
might get some darn fool ideas.
(clinking)
Bye.
Gary.
Well, so long, Pete.
You're not gonna start for
the mine tonight, are you?
Yes, I always do things the hard way.
Bye.
(whistling)
Stop whistling, you drunkard.
My peace is addled enough
without that wail of a banshee.
Maybe you better stop drinking.
I have that in mind, my good innkeeper,
when and if I choose (laughs).
Now you think you could stop.
Instantly, but not too suddenly.
You did bring me some, didn't you?
All right, let him have it.
Ah (chuckles).
I'd ask you, gentlemen, to join me,
but unfortunately, my wife is supposed to.
If you tell her that I gave it to you,
I'll wring your Shakespearean neck.
You have my permission, sir.
Well, you won't get another drop.
That will be a far,
far greater calamity.
Good wine is a good familiar
creature if well used.
Exclaim no more against it.
If I was crazy about a gal,
I'd bend so she'd get a divorce.
The trouble with Dr. Reagan
is his marriage is for keeps.
Yeah, but she don't love him.
No, but she thinks he needs her.
Listen, Leroux, suppose he kicks off?
She would leave right away
and she wouldn't come back.
No, my best bet is to
leave things as they are
for the time being anyway.
Roxie, Roxie, you're on.
(audience applauding)
(slow orchestral music)
(Roxie singing, lyrics indistinct)
(bold orchestral music)
(gun firing)
(melancholic orchestral music)
Pop, Pop!
(fast beat orchestral music)
(guns firing)
(firing)
[Man On Mountain] Let's get outta here.
(upbeat suspenseful orchestral music)
(melancholic orchestral music)
They won't get away with it, partner.
(dog barking)
Drop that gun, Corbett.
Now come forward.
Hello, Corbett.
I'm John Masters, United States Marshal.
I'm arresting you for murder.
They're the murderers.
They killed my father.
Let's let the court worry about that.
I'm taking you to Juno.
Two names scratched, huh?
We'll have to hang you twice.
Good joke.
I'll get the rest.
That's the wrong attitude, Corbett.
Now get your stuff.
(slow, mysterious orchestral music)
(people chattering)
Gary Corbett, handcuffed.
Pete, Pete!
[Pete] Huh?
- Come here, hurry.
- What's the matter?
Come on, come on.
[Pete] What's the matter, son?
What do you got him for, Marshal?
[Marshal] Murder.
[Pete] What about it, Gary?
[Gary] Yeah, a bunch of
claim jumpers murdered Pop,
and I got a couple of them.
[Pete] Well, a man has
got a right to protect
his own property, hasn't he?
[Man] You can't hold
a man for that, Marshal.
[Man] No, and he ain't goin' to.
[Man] Come on now, Marshal,
take off those irons.
I'll take 'em off and put one on you
if you don't get outta here.
[Man] I'm telling you,
you better take 'em off.
Hold on, wait a minute,
wait a minute here.
What happens to him is up to a jury.
(men talking excitedly)
I'm taking him to Juno.
Now I don't want any trouble,
but if you fellows want it, you'll get it.
(men talking excitedly)
Wait a minute men, wait a minute.
The marshal's right.
Nobody wants to see that
boy free more than I do.
When they killed his dad,
they killed one of the
best friends I ever had.
Now we gotta get Gary out of this.
But we're gonna do it the American way,
with law and order.
Now you're talkin' sense, Pete.
Now go on, scatter
fellows, scatter, go ahead.
(men grumbling)
Don't say nothin' to nobody now, Gary
and we'll try and think what to do.
Let's get somethin' to
eat here in The Palace.
I'll be over there and
see you in a little while.
Corbett, if you'd behave yourself
I'll take these things off,
at least until we've had something to eat.
I'm going to square things my way.
I'm wanna take the first
chance I get to do it.
Glad you warned me.
Do we have to go in here?
What's the matter with it?
(mumbles)
(crowd chattering)
(audience applauding)
# Forget if you can
# The moment we knew
# Let memories fade
# Of plans that we made
that never came true
# Forget if you can
# My arms about you
# Our favorite tune
# Our favorite moon, or two
# Forget if you will
# The moment that will reveal every dream
# Don't reminisce, don't think of the kiss
# That sealed every dream
# We couldn't pretend,
so it came to an end
# Before it began
# So shouldn't we both
# Forget if you can
(audience applauding)
(light, happy orchestral music)
- Hello, Roxie.
- Oh, please don't get up.
- Hello, Gary.
- Hello.
- Won't you sit with us?
- Just for a minute.
I see you still don't like my act.
I like it very much.
You didn't applaud.
What did you do?
The marshal calls it murder.
That's what the warrant calls it.
Does he have to wear these things?
He doesn't have to, Roxie.
I offered to take 'em off
if he'd give me his word,
- but he refused to...
- All right, Marshal,
you have it.
Well, tell me about it.
There isn't much to tell.
Bunch of claim jumpers killed
my father and stole his mine.
So far I've been able to get two of 'em.
Who were they?
- Madison and Holden.
- Madison?
Yes, did you know them?
Well, only through Leroux.
They were friends of his, you know?
Hello, how are you?
You know Mr. Corbett?
Glad to see you again.
Well, see you later.
Roxie, why don't you stay
and have supper with us?
No, thanks, I'm having supper with Tom.
(light, bouncy orchestral music)
Shall we eat in my dressing room?
Great, I'll be up in a minute.
Give me time to change.
You know you're a funny girl.
I am?
Yes, first night in a year
I haven't asked you to supper,
and you ask me.
Gal's entitled to a change of mind.
And heart.
I don't know, mine never
seem to work together.
I'm glad you took them
things off him, Marshal.
You know, I've been thinkin' about
this epidemic of claim jumpin'.
There's brains behind it,
tight, smooth-workin' organization.
We just found out that the two I shot
were friends of Leroux's.
- What?
- Say Pete,
what do you know about this Judge Bennett
who signed the eviction notice?
Well, you fellas are wastin' your time
because those eviction notices are legal.
Pete, you miners spend so
much time lookin' for gold
you forget the little matter
of paying your assessment.
Well, Pop paid his.
Fine, that's good, where's your receipt?
You show that to me and I'll,
I'll chase those claim jumpers off so fast
it'll make your head swim.
Well, you didn't give me
much time to look for it.
Wouldn't done you any
good, son, it isn't there.
First thing them bandits go for.
They not only rob and kill decent men,
but they're makin' a joke out
of the territory of Alaska.
Look, Masters, if you'll
give me few days free time,
I bet I can find out who this
Judge Bennett's working for.
Then we'll know who really
should be tried for murder.
That's a good idea, only
I can't give you free time.
Why not?
You can't get outta here
for a couple of days yet.
The Yukon's a roarin' flood,
you can't get across till it settles down.
Well, tell you what I'll do, Pete.
How'd you like to be a
deputy United States Marshal?
I'm postmaster now.
Well, we'll say just
for a few days, and then,
well, if Corbett here
doesn't behave (laughing)
the government can take
it out of your hide.
All right, Marshal, you
got yourself a deputy.
Postmaster, U.S. deputy.
Maybe I'll run for governor
next, huh? (laughing)
(knocking at door)
Come in.
Where's Mr. Leroux?
He's still in his office, Mademoiselle.
Thank you.
(flowing orchestral music)
[Tom] I'll tell you, this
man Corbett's a dangerous man
to have running around loose.
But he's not loose, sir, he's
in Marshal Masters' custody.
Well, Corbett has enough friends
to take him away from 10 marshals
once they get out of town
and hit the Juno trail.
[Man] Is there a
reason why he should ever
get to the Juno trail?
Yes, I hear since the
blizzard, the wolves and bears
walk right into town these dark nights.
- [Man In Black Vest]
And it's a public duty
to shoot 'em down.
Anybody can make a mistake.
[Tom] Shooting Corbett is one thing,
you've gotta be jolly well careful
if the marshal is with him.
Oh, Roxie, Leroux said to tell you
he'll be up in about 10 minutes.
Thanks, Nick, where's the marshal?
Over there.
[Roxie] Oh, Marshal.
Hello, Roxie, have a drink.
Where's Gary?
Oh, he just left, I hope
he's not too far away.
You let him go alone?
He is all right.
Not without you.
You've got to go after him right away.
Don't leave his side for a minute.
Why?
Because, because his life's in danger.
What makes you think so?
I, I can't tell you now,
but he mustn't be left alone.
Well, he's with Pete, they'll
take care of themselves.
They don't care how many
of his friends they kill.
He'd only be safe if you were with him,
someone they didn't dare hurt.
Well, I'll try to find him.
(upbeat orchestral music)
(tense music)
No, no, don't stop,
I'll walk along with you.
You look like you had
a drink with the devil.
- What's the matter?
- Oh, nothing.
I wish women would stop
saying, "Oh, nothing."
Me too, when they say, "Oh, nothing,"
I'm off like a rocky mountain goat.
I'll see you later.
Oh, please don't go, I,
I only want to say goodbye.
To this fellow without a chaperone.
Hey, Pete, Pete.
Come on.
What on earth's the matter with you?
Nevermind, just keep walking.
You shouldn't have come
out on a cold night like this
- in that thin dress.
- I know it.
Maybe you better turn back.
I'm going home.
Then you better put my coat on.
No, don't stop.
I don't wanna take a
chance on hitting her.
No, Tom would kill us.
What's she doin' with him anyway?
Had they rained all
kinds of sores and shames
on my bare head,
steeped me in poverty to the very lips.
Must be pretty tough goin'.
At times.
Someday people will realize
that an alcoholic isn't a bad man.
Make me the fixed figure
of the time for scorn
to point his slow and moving finger at.
Yet could I bear that, too.
I'm glad you like my performance, sir.
Roxie, my dear, I present canine Rex,
the king among dogs.
Unheralded and unsung,
he came to see my performance of Othello.
Who's our other guest?
This is Mr. Corbett,
he owns the dog and...
Congratulations, sir.
My husband, Mr. Reagan.
I seem to have a rival
for the dog's affection.
You should, after all, the dog's his.
I will avoid the obvious parallel.
John, I'd like Mr. Corbett
to stay here all night.
Well, I'm, I'm staying with Pete.
No, the dangerous part is getting back,
you don't understand.
[Gary] I think I do, those
men who were following us.
Why take chances, what
can you lose by staying?
Yes, what can you lose?
You might even gain, who knows what?
John.
(pensive music)
(clinking)
Sir, how would you like to trade?
Trade what?
My wife for your dog.
You're drunk.
Of course, I'm drunk, that's
why I'm speaking the truth.
Have you never heard the
old saying, in vino veritas?
He understands, he's a
remarkable quadruped.
He even appreciates Shakespeare.
My friend and critic.
But that I am forbid to tell
the secrets of my prison house.
I could a tale unfold whose lightest word
would harrow up thy soul.
Freeze thy young blood,
make thy two eyes like stars
start from their spheres.
Thy knotted and combined locks to part.
And each particular hair to stand on end,
Like quills upon the fearful porpentine.
But this eternal blazon must not be
to ears of flesh and blood.
List, list, oh, list.
If ever thy dear father thou didst love,
revenge his foul and
most unnatural murder.
Murder most foul, as in the best it is.
But this most foul, strange and unnatural.
Seems even Shakespeare knew
what was going on in Moose River.
Thanks Roxie, goodnight.
Gary, please don't.
Stop worrying, we'll
be all right, all of us.
Come on, Dike.
This is pretty tough going, John.
I'm sorry.
I made a mistake.
I guess we all do.
The worse mistake you
ever made was to marry me.
And then to run away with me
when the law came yapping at my heals.
Even now it's only through a
misguided sense of loyalty.
I don't think that
loyalty is ever misguided.
[John] You love him, don't you?
I'm trying very hard not to.
(people chattering)
You will see, Judge Bennett,
that these are simple statements of fact.
Proving that we did pay our assessments.
Affidavits aren't proof.
You're not trying this case, Judge.
All we want you to do is
certify our signatures
and put that little red seal on it.
Aren't you men being
somewhat hasty about all this?
You didn't hesitate to certify papers
that threw us off of our property.
Those evictions were perfectly legal.
We'll let the high court
in Juno decide that, Judge.
Now young man, you know
that won't do you any good.
As a defendant in a murder
charge, you have no standing
in the civil court until the...
Nevermind the speech, Bennett,
all we want is your John Hancock.
And you ain't got no right
to refuse us, have ya?
Oh no, it's perfectly legal,
but it's a waste of time.
There you are, men, that'll be $2 a piece.
- $2?
- What for?
Well, you're a public
officer, ain't you?
It's the regular recorder's fee.
It's...
[Men] Perfectly legal.
(people chattering)
[Marshal] Hi, boys.
See, now you've offended me, Marshall.
You've got my word, haven't you?
Have you changed your mind?
No, not at all, I
just wanted you to know
that the trail is open, Corbett,
and we're leaving first
thing in the morning.
I thought you'd like to
know as soon as possible.
(upbeat orchestral music)
Who's that?
Jones and Bailey.
They must've kicked something in the dark.
Better go down and keep 'em quiet.
Well, I hope you find something
that'll do us some good.
That does it.
(suspenseful music)
(lively orchestral music)
(applauding)
# You can't forget the
menu at the Poker and Waltz
# For they're the nicest
dancers that I know
# But don't forget the
menu at the Poker and Waltz
# Our dances are that cannot do alone
# But if you can, can, can
# You're not a (muffled)
# Just imitate the kangaroo
# You get your pose about
# Just all your woes about
# Like the fellow that followed you
# Show your knees and dimples please
# A bit of this you'll never miss
# For if you can, can, can
# Then you can plant your man
# And maybe he can, can, can too
(audience applauding)
(lively orchestral music)
Certainly has a nice
(mumbles) of girls up there.
Yeah, you sure have got an
eye for the girls, Tyler, huh?
How'd you get here so quick, Judge?
What do you mean, I've
been here for two hours.
Now wait a minute, I just seen you
movin' around your office.
You what?
At least, I thought it was you.
The blind was down, but there was a light.
Is somebody tryin' to get
something on you, Judge?
That's not funny, come on.
Wait a minute, we
better see Tom first, huh?
Yeah, the boss'll wanna know about this.
[Man] Yeah.
Yes, it's Corbett all right,
there's no doubt about it.
Pick up your boys and get
over there as fast as you can.
But no shooting.
- Why not?
- What for?
Pin a burglary charge on 'em.
Let's see what happens when
Corbett takes his case to Juno.
Yes, that's the way to do
it, I never thought of that.
Uh, should Carter and I go along?
By all means.
Two outstanding citizens for witness,
- it will make it per...
- Yes, perfectly legal.
Wasn't that what you were about to say?
(laughing)
Well come on boys, let's get started.
[Man] See you later, Leroux.
Well, we might've known
Bennett wouldn't leave
anything important here in the office.
- Oh, but he has.
- Did you find something?
Come on, let's go.
Wait a minute.
We don't wanna be caught in here.
(suspenseful music)
They're on the way over.
We'll hide in the shadows.
When they come close, we'll jump 'em.
You two hide around there.
[Man] The light's not on.
I wonder if they're still inside.
[Man] Let's find out.
[Man] What, hey, hey.
[Man] Help, help!
Help!
[Man] Hey, now where do we get them?
[Man] Help!
[Man] Hey, somebody's fighting here.
I wonder what it's all about.
How many pounds of coffee do you want?
[John] You better
make it a couple, Pete.
Two.
Look, Marshal, there was
a, there was somethin'
I wanted to ask you, I...
Yes, I know what you want
Pete, but I can't do it.
I've overdue in Juno now as it is.
- Oh.
- Got any beans up there?
Yeah.
And some salmon too, Pete.
There's your beans.
Say, Marshal, Gary's got a little hunch
he wants to follow up, but he
needs a little time on it...
How'd last night's hunch work out?
Huh?
Come on now, Pete, you know
you're legally my deputy.
Legally, right now I'm sellin' salmon.
Where'd you get that cut?
You mean this little scratch on my face?
Yeah, and don't tell
me you got it shaving.
(laughs) Well, no (laughs).
I had a little bit too
much to drink last night
and I come in here to light the lamp
and I fell against the counter (laughs).
Sure you didn't get it outside
Judge Bennett's office last night?
What happened there?
Well, it seems like a bunch of fellas
broke into his office last night
and turned it upside down
lookin' for somethin'.
My goodness, where were you?
I was away.
So the prima absent evidence, eh?
(laughing) Here's your
salmon, anything else?
No, this oughta do it.
You about ready, Corbett?
[Gary] I'll be packed in a minute.
Now, how much do I owe you?
Let's see, get your
hands outta the raisins.
Two hard pack.
Listen, Marshal, give that
boy a couple of days more.
- Can't do it.
- Just one day then.
Not for his sake, not for my sake,
but for the sake of the justice
you're suppose to represent
in this great territory of Alaska.
(laughing) Ah, Tratchall
I'd beat you a run
for congressional delegate.
Can you do it?
One day, and it's as
much as my badge is worth.
(laughing) I could kiss you for that.
Here have so more raisins,
go on, take 'em all.
(both laughing)
(bouncy orchestral music)
[Roxie] Hello, Pete.
(knocking at door)
Come in.
Hello.
You shouldn't have come here.
I heard you were
leaving this morning and
I couldn't let you go without
at least saying goodbye.
I'll be here for another day.
Let me fix that breakfast.
Are you a good cook?
You'll know in a minute.
(slow, gentle orchestral music)
Where are the eggs?
Over there.
Bacon?
I'll get it.
Gary.
- Yes?
- I...
How do you like your bacon?
With egg.
I wish you didn't have to go, alone.
Oh, I won't be alone.
The United States is providing
me with a paid companion.
Let me go with you.
Why, Mrs. Reagan?
Don't you think it's time I
did something about my life?
Well, sure.
Don't let your heart run away
with your tongue, Mr. Corbett.
You say such exciting
things as, "Oh, sure."
You'll turn a poor girl's head,
make her think you're as
interested in what happens to her
as you are in, in breakfast.
(slow, gentle music)
What are you trying to
do, burn up the place?
(clanking)
I'll tell you boss, the
whole town is talkin' about it.
Get Bennett, take him (mumbles).
Right, boss.
- Mr. Leroux.
- What is it?
I've received a letter from England.
Yeah, tell me about it later.
But it's quite important.
I said, never mind.
At last, give it to me.
You know where Roxie is?
Rehearsing, I suppose.
That's right, rehearsing a love scene
with a new leading man, Gary Corbett.
It's a lie, you're lying your teeth,
you wretched barkeep.
Let's go.
Oh, please don't, you've
got to let me have a drink.
Barkeep can't leave if
I give him a way to stop.
Oh, I didn't mean that, I apologize.
Apologies won't pay your bill.
I'll pay you, I'll get
it from Roxie, some way.
Suppose Roxie's not here?
Suppose Roxie goes away with Corbett?
Oh, she wouldn't.
You can make sure that she doesn't.
I've committed many sins
in my life, but not murder.
Wouldn't be murder to defend your home.
No jury would convict you.
And every man in Alaska would honor you.
Yes, even applaud you.
Why do you want this man dead?
Well, I got my reasons,
but not as strong as yours.
Well, what about it?
I could think better if I had a drink.
Reagan, here's a chance
for you to play a better part
in real life, than you
ever did on the stage.
Give me a drink.
You'd solve all the problems.
You could swim in a river of whiskey
for the rest of your life.
Well what do you say, yes or no?
I can't think.
What kind of a man are you
not to defend the honor of your wife?
Mr. Leroux, you are mistaken.
I may not be like Caesar, but my wife
is like Caesar's wife, above suspicion.
Good day, sir.
(pensive orchestral music)
You had a good chance of
getting Corbett last night.
Instead of that, what did you do?
Start fighting each other.
- Well, it was dark and...
- Couldn't see a thing.
(knocking at door)
Yes?
- Oh, hello, Marshal.
- Hello, Tom.
Big time last night, huh?
- Yes, we had, uh...
- We sure,
now listen here, Marshal,
we, respected citizens
of Moose River resent a murderer
runnin' around loose on our street.
And after all, Marshal,
a prisoner in Judge Bennett's jurisdiction
should be in his custody.
That's right.
Is the Corbett mine
located in Moose River?
Just outside.
Well then, as long as your
city limits don't extend
to the scene of the crime, he's
still my prisoner, isn't he?
What about the crime
he committed last night,
breaking into my office?
That's Moose River, isn't it?
Sure, but can you prove he did it?
Yes, Tobin and I can identify...
(laughing) What, with those blinkers?
Boys, you'll have to think up
somethin' smarter than that.
So long.
(door slams)
Well, what do we do now?
I think somethin' oughta
be done about Reagan.
What about Reagan?
I heard him yellin' about
what we'd done to old Corbett.
Something about, if you ever
had any use for your old man,
kill the boys who done him in.
"Murder, darn foul," he called it.
What?
Now, now, old boy, he was
merely quoting Shakespeare,
don't you know?
Well, if this guy Shakespeare's in it,
then let's get him, too.
Yes, we, huh?
- Corbett's here.
- Alone?
No, the whole shootin'
match is with him.
Oh, get out.
And see it doesn't become
a real shooting match,
not in my place.
See you later.
Well, Bennett,
looks like we got saddled
with a bunch of fools.
Seriously, Tom, what are we gonna do?
Take it easy, I'll think of something.
(melancholic music)
Stumpy.
[Stumpy] Yes, sir.
You know, it's too
bad that you haven't got
the body to match your brains.
I'm so sorry sir, but
I feel I must withdraw
even the little I've had to contribute.
What do you mean?
I've been trying to
tell you all day, sir.
I received a letter from England.
The family has squared
things with the authorities,
I can go home.
How soon do you expect to leave?
In the morning, sir.
I shall accompany Marshal
Masters and his prisoner to Juno,
and go home from there.
There, I've been putting
my papers in order
to make it easier for my successor.
Will you just sign those
sir, and (mumbles).
How much of a family have you got?
Oh, I've got an old mother,
an older brother and three sisters.
The youngest is about 18,
and they're all lovely,
every one of them.
And they're fond of me too, in spite of,
in spite of everything.
Excuse me running on like this sir but,
you can imagine how anxious
I am to see 'em all.
I understand you.
Stumpy, have you got any money?
Just enough for my
passage, but I don't care.
But you should care.
Man coming from the
gold country, you know,
people expect gold
pouring out of his ears.
Well, we, we can't
all strike it rich, sir.
Oh, but you could.
What did you say, sir?
You heard me right.
You may take home as much as $10,000.
10,000...
Uh, no sir, I'm a very poor shot, sir.
(laughing) No, I don't
expect you to kill anybody.
Sit down here, I'll tell you what to do.
(lively music)
[Pete] Come on Nick, let's
have a little service here.
Hey, you're havin' quite a
party, ain't you Postmaster?
Yep, farewell party.
Young Corbett man's leavin' for Juno,
first thing in the morning.
I'll be back before you know
it, you old snow bear, you.
You're sure they won't
convict you of that murder, huh?
[Man] They won't convict him of nothin'
when they hear what he knows.
[Nick] What'll it be, boys?
Little rum and gum, please.
- Whiskey for me.
- Bourbon.
I wish I could be in Juno
when the judge gets a load
of what Gary's got to tell.
(laughing)
So you've got the evidence
you were lookin' for, Corbett?
Enough, I think.
Good, now you just hand it over to me
and it'll make it official.
Well, thanks Marshal but I,
I haven't written it down yet.
I'm carrying it around in
my head for safe keeping.
Would you have a little touch, Marshal?
Sure, bourbon.
Well, a safe return to you, son.
Hurry back.
Why don't you watch what you're doing?
Sorry.
(clattering)
Why don't you leave me alone?
Now take it easy fella, I
think you've had a few too many.
That's an insult, take it back.
Hey, what's the matter with you, Stumpy?
[Gary] Man, you're loco.
Take your hands off me.
Are you gonna apologize or not?
Well, I don't know what
there is to apologize for,
but if you want it, you've got it.
Well, you'll laugh at me, would ya?
You think I can't fight, huh?
Well, (grunting).
[Gary] Now, now, now, now, hold on.
You better go someplace
and sleep this off.
Who hit him?
He did.
He had it comin' to him.
That's no excuse for
hitting a man like that.
Take the little fellow into my office.
(crowd chattering)
Fine thing to hit a man like Stumpy.
(men talking, indistinct)
Put him down here in the chair.
He'll be all right.
Yeah, it's only a bump.
(suspenseful music)
Well, what are you staring at?
Nothing, boss.
Corbett hit the poor
little Stumpy so hard
that it killed him, understand?
Now get out and spread the news.
And don't let him get away.
- Stumpy is dead, boys.
- What?
That's right, he just
died in the office.
[Man] What kind of a lug is it
that would slug a man like Stumpy?
(crowd talking excitedly)
Boys!
Boys, please, boys.
Boys, you all knew poor Stumpy.
You know why this inoffensive little man
was standing at the bar?
He was celebratin', celebratin'
his last stay in Alaska,
for tomorrow, he was goin'
home to his poor old mother.
And now, he lies dead in there.
(men yelling)
Stumpy's been killed, and
they say Gary Corbett did it.
I don't believe it.
What are they doing to him?
Nothing yet.
(crowd clamoring angrily)
- Take it easy, take it easy.
- Give the man a chance.
What chance did he
give poor little Stumpy?
[Crowd] Yeah!
[Man] I told you Stumpy started it.
You all saw it.
[Man] Yes, he was drunk.
[Man] That any excuse for murder?
[Man] Why, Corbett's no murderer.
[Man] No, why is the
marshal taking him to Juno,
for a tea party?
[Crowd] Yeah!
(crowd clamoring)
You've gotta stop this, Tom.
How can I?
Well, you can't let them kill him.
Does it really mean that much to you?
Yes, it does.
You made a deal.
(crowd talking excitedly)
Men, will you listen to me.
Stumpy was my employee,
but he was also my friend.
And I assure you that I am
as interested as you are
to see the murderer
punished for his crime.
[Man In Crowd] Let's lynch him, boys!
(crowd clamoring)
Be quite.
But there is no reason
why we shouldn't do this
in a civilized manner.
There's nothing
uncivilized about a hangin'.
(crowd yelling)
Quiet, listen.
We have law and order in this town,
and we are going to do
it in a legal manner,
and after a proper trial.
As judge of Moose River,
I order you to disperse.
(crowd grumbling)
Quiet.
Judge Bennett will take
charge of the prisoner,
and he will be perfectly safe in our jail
till we can give him a fair trial.
[Judge] Everything's
gonna be done (mumbles).
(crowd clamoring)
Only gonna let them put
him in jail here, aye?
No, might be a good idea for you.
You'd be safer there than
you would in my custody.
At least tonight, you will.
This time, Marshal, he's my prisoner.
[Man] I just wanna warn you, Judge,
that jail better be
lynch-proof to catch on.
I know you didn't do it, Gary.
Thanks, Roxie.
Come on.
Tom.
I wanna thank you what you've done.
I thought there's more than
a mere polite thank you
involved, wasn't there?
I didn't understand you to mean...
We made a deal.
Your friend is safe in jail, isn't he?
Yes.
You think there's nothing to stop us?
We can leave tonight.
And don't pack.
We can buy everything
and anything you want in San Francisco.
I see you expect me to keep
my end of your deal.
Well, look, come on.
Fun idea.
Just got some news for you.
Yes?
Corbett's friends are planning
to break him out of jail sometime tonight.
You want us to (mumbles)?
No, you are much too fidgety
with your shooting arrows.
Besides, they will never get him out.
But suppose they do get him out?
Don't worry, they won't.
And this time it's gonna be an accident.
This time, it'd be done in jail.
(mellow orchestral music)
(clattering)
(soft, lively orchestral music)
(fire crackling)
(bell tolls)
- There's fire there.
- See it.
[Man] Hey, where's the fire?
(man talking, indistinct)
(crowd clamoring)
Hey, somebody let us out!
Let us out.
The jail's on fire.
(ominous music)
(clamoring)
Hey, open up.
(banging bars)
Let us out.
Hey, somebody open up.
Let us out!
[Roxie] Hey.
Please, you gotta let him out of there.
[Pete] I would, take it easy, darlin'.
We're doing the best we can over there.
But you can't go in there.
[Roxie] Why?
Go help him!
Who has the key to the cell?
Here it is but...
Let me have it.
John.
John!
(suspenseful orchestral music)
Help!
Let us out.
Hurry!
Move it!
(fire crackling)
(suspenseful orchestral music)
(thuds)
(crowd clamoring)
(fire crackling)
Gary, Gary, thank heaven, you're safe.
(coughing)
[Man] Men, don't stand there
trying to save the jail (mumbles).
Save the rest of the town.
[Man] Get out, everybody get out.
Fire spreading to this place.
Come on, get out.
(screaming)
(fire crackling)
(crowd clamoring)
(coughing)
No, don't waste it.
I hope the devil's generous with his.
I should like to be met with a drink.
Don't talk, dear.
Dear?
It's been a long time.
All my fault, I know.
Now maybe I can answer
that old problem (coughs).
To be or not to be,
that is the question:
whether 'tis nobler in the mind
to suffer the slings and
arrows of outrageous fortune,
or to take arms against a sea of troubles,
and by opposing, end them.
To die,
to sleep,
no more.
To sleep,
perchance to dream.
To dream.
(somber orchestral music)
(suspenseful music)
Gary, we just found out
that Leroux's the man
behind this whole thing.
The court clerk (mumbles) back of the jail
made him talk.
Leroux?
Let him go, he can find his own debts.
(fire crackling)
(crowd clamoring)
(suspenseful orchestral music)
I'm certainly glad that you got out.
I was smoked out by your friends.
My friends?
I don't understand what you mean.
Leroux, I want you to tell me
who was with you in this scheme
of robbery and murder.
Not really.
I suppose the next thing,
you're going to ask me to sit down
and write you a letter
about it, (mumbles).
What's strong and Leroux, who are they?
(gun fires)
(clattering)
(punching)
(thuds)
(clattering)
(punching)
(thuds)
(clattering)
(punching)
(thuds)
No, don't.
Why, are you going to talk?
All right, I'll talk.
Well, go ahead.
I'm not the head man.
I'm only telling you.
- I told...
- For whom?
You may yet find out.
(firing)
Thanks, Marshal.
I wasn't in trouble.
You are now.
He meant you?
Well, you didn't think
that he had brains enough to organize
a plan, did you?
A very good plan, if I do say so myself.
But he only fronted for me until,
like you, he fell in
love and lost his head.
Speaking of losing heads,
I'm sorry I have to blow your resolve.
I won't let you suffer, I'll aim through.
I like you, Corbett.
Oh, before I die,
there are a few things I'd like to know.
Say it, mate.
Make it quick.
Tom, if you're behind all this,
why did you bother to arrest me?
Why didn't you just snuff me out?
That's a fair question.
I'll answer it, really.
Meanwhile, pack the gold dust
in that leather pouch, for me.
(people clamoring)
(fire crackling)
I let you live for the same reason
I took those handcuffs off.
I wanted to find out just what evidence
you could collect.
I was gonna get it all
from you on the trail
after a little accident I planned for you.
But when you told me that the evidence
was not in your pocket, but in the head,
that put me on the spot, Corbett.
I had to find some other way
to get the truth out of you.
This fool upset everything
by being too impatient.
He wanted his share now,
so he had to die.
Sorry, Corbett.
(firing)
(thuds, clattering)
Get up quick, Marshal.
It's gonna get a little warm in here.
Finish our little chat
if you were gonna join with us.
(fire crackling)
(tranquil orchestral music)
How would you kids like
to go (mumbles) of Frisco
when we get there and
have dinner with me, huh?
You know, I guess you wouldn't.
Imagine, he has a gold mine in Alaska
and they gotta go all
the way to San Francisco
to dig up a little gold band for a finger.
Beautiful any day.
Kinda hate to leave it
for a crowded little town
like Washington, D.C.
but they sent me to congress.
Well, leave.
And I've got something to tell
those congressmen in the whole country.
I'm going to make them see that gold
is not the only important thing in Alaska.
Gold is just a decoy.
Come on.
Old dame nature's way of getting
the right kind of people here;
rugged, solid people like Gary here,
men who'll change the whole fate of Alaska
and fill it into pig sty for the plague.
They can't stop a stake.
We're America.
(mellow orchestral music)