A Boaz Davidson film
" Alex in Love"
With Yossi Shiloah
Hannah Roth
Shmuel Rodensky
Hinna Rosovsky
Sharon HaCohen
Avraham Mor
Director:
Boaz davidson
Alex, Alex...
Alex...
Pass it on to Gingy.
Give it to me.
l want to see it first.
Fishenson!
-Yes Sir.
What's that in you hand?
What? -Don't say what to me.
Tell me what's in your hand.
ln my hand? -Yes, in your
hand Give it to me now.
But it's not mine.
-But doesn't interest me.
l want to see it here,
ln my hand.
Fishenson!
Answer your teacher.
Who gave you this rubbish?
Alex.
l might have known
it was Alexander.
Come up here to the board.
Who me?
-No, your grandfather.
My grandfather can't come.
He's dead.
l' ll show you what dead
means.
ln another minute,
you' ll be dead.
Go to the board at once.
Come on. Now.
Punishment.
Say 50 times:
" Naked girls that's
an abomination."
Now say it the first time.
Naked girls
that's an abomination.
No disturbing!
Second time!
Naked girls,
that's an abomination.
Again -Naked girls
Naked girls that's an
abomination. -Enough!
Naked girls
that's an abomination.
l said enough. lgnoramus!
Go back to your own place.
Now.
Today we have a new student.
The name.
-Mimi.
The name is Mima.
-My name is Mimi. -What?
Mimi. -What sort of a name is
that. Meemeemee...
l say it's Mima.
She greets the class
and says Hallo.
So? And says Hallo.
-Hallo.
So what the class says
to Mima?
Naked girls,
that's an abomination.
What's that?
That teacher is a real
nut-case. ls he the only one?
That one is reckoned normal.
Wait till you see the others.
l hope you don't have a lot
of homework.
As it happens, we do have
lots of homework
but l can always help you
if you like.
No, that's alright. -Do you
need a lift home?
l can take you on my bike.
No thanks, they've come to
take me home. Bye.
Bye.
So, did you fix anything?
-With her? What on earth for?
So what were you talking
about all the time?
She just wanted help with
her lessons.
You' re just wet. She's
a real good looker.
Hi Alex, did you bring back
my pictures?
Yes, but they were
confiscated. -Who took them?
Leonid, the teacher took
all the pictures.
l told you to be careful. They
were the best ones l had.
l' m sorry, he took them off
Fishenson.
lt's all because of that
son-of-a-bitch.
l hope he didn't say
who they belonged to.
lf my father hears about this
he' ll beat me black and blue
with his belt.
-Here's that idiot.
C' mon gang. Let's get him.
He's coming.
Fishenson! You again.
Fishenson!
l caught you.
-But l didn't...
Alexander!
Alexander, is that you?
-Yes.
Why are you so late?
lt's almost night time.
l was at Ginger's.
We were studying together.
Well alright. Go and shower.
After. -No, not after. Your
father' ll be here any minute
and the food is all ready.
-What are we eating?
What you like. Take a clean
towel and go shower.
Alexander, don't wipe your
feet on that towel.
Take the blue towel
for your feet.
l can't get washed, there's
someone in there.
lt's no-one. lt must be Farouk.
Mr. Farouk?
Farouk, do you hear me?
l' m sorry but l've put on my
hair treatment.
Your hair treatment doesn't
interest me Mr. Farouk.
The child has to shower.
-But Mrs. Koprovsky,
l only put on the tomato paste
two minutes ago with the
frog powder. That only leaves
the parsley and scorpion oil.
and l've finished. -Farouk,
it's all rubbish.
You' ll grow hair on your head,
the day l grow wings.
That's where you' re wrong,
Mrs. Koprovsky.
Soon l' ll have a head of hair
like James Dean.
l' m fed up with all your
tenants.
Quiet, we have money problems.
and we' re lucky he's here.
Farouk? Are you
coming out?
What's up Mrs. Koprovsky?
You inviting me to the opera?
We need a murderer like him at
home? -Don't give him ideas.
You' ll see. That Farouk will
kill us all again.
Come my angel, l've got
something for you.
l hope it's not chocolate
before supper.
Who said anything about
chocolate.
From chocolate you get the
belly ache.
Farouk, get out of there.
lf you upset me, l don't come
out till New Year
Like l would give him chocolate!
Take it my angel. Take it
and eat it quickly
before your mother
goes crazy.
All this? -Why not? No one
ever died of eating chocolate.
Angel-face.
Mrs. Koprovsky, maybe you
wont grow wings
but my hair has grown two and
a half centimeters..
Moron. Get out. Alexander
you can go in.
The Farouk is out!
Well hi there Alex.
Hi there. Have you seen
Ginger?
l think he's over there.
Give' us a bite.-l don't
take the food out of my mouth.
Honestly, don't be so mean.
Well don't take a big bite.
Are you and Ginger going to
see " Gone With the Wind" ?
Maybe.-lt's not worth while.
lt's a crappy movie.
What are you talking about.
l've seen it three times.
lf it's such a crappy film, why
see it three times?
l didn't pay , l snuck in round
the back, so what do l care?
Leave the hot dog for me. Hey
You didn't even leave me half.
You owe me one hot dog.
-Alright, alright.
What's going on? Are you
coming to see the movie?
lt's not worth it. l've fixed it up
with two good looking chicks.
We know your dogs already
When are they coming?
Any minute now.
-How old are they?
Big. ln high school. You can
do what you want with them.
They've got boobs like this,
like watermelons.
Hi guys. You going to the
movie?
Ginger, tell your brother to
leave us alone.
Yanosh, how am l in the way?
Shuky, say l' m not in the way.
Go on get out of here already.
Motke go!
Don't want to. Mom gave
me permission.
lf the chicks see him, they' ll
go for certain.
Are there girls? -Motke, l told
you a million times,
stop following me everywhere.
Get out of here.
l don't care. Mom says l can
stay out till 9:00.
Yanosh, will there really be
chicks?
Shut up! Here they come.
These are Malcah and Zippy.
Pleased to meet you.
Hi, Yanosh has told us a lot
about you.
Yanosh, when will the chicks
you told us about come?
Girls, do you want to go to
the beach?
Guys, have a good time. l' m
going to see the movie.
Alex, wait up a minute. l' m
coming with you.
They' re just dogs.
Let's go. What a good job
we got rid of them.
Now we' ll be able to have a
really wild time.
Take your hands off me, idiot.
You' re just pretending that you
don't like me. You do really.
Hi girls! -Hi there.
Someone sitting here? -Yes.
-Who? -You.
What are you doing here.
-Same as you.
l came to see the movie.
Why are you sitting near me?
-l need an explanation.
So go and sit close and read
the subtitles.
l can't read the small writing.
l don't care. Go away!
l wont go. l wont go. -What do
you know about the movie?
Nothing, but l go to all
Clark Gable's movies.
So do l. -Alex, introduce us.
Sit quietly. -Who is this?
-My name is Motke.
l' m Alex's best friend,
aren't l Alex.
Who says? He's nothing to do
with me.
He's Ginger's brother.
-What's your name?
Mimi. -Meemee? Meemee?
l've never heard such a funny
name, Meemee!
l hope we' re going to see
Mickey Mouse. l like him.
Just shut up! Alright.
What's the matter with you?
Alex, get on with it.
Start getting fresh with her.
-Shut up!
Sorry.
'Cos if my brother Shuky was
here, he' d be all over her.
Shut up already. -Shuky says
that the girls love being felt
up in the movies.
Can't you shut him up.
-Keep your mouth shut.
Boy, enough speaking like
gramophone. -OK. -Not OK.
You understand l want l see
movie in quiet?
Lady stop shouting, you' re
making a disturbance.
Nobody's talking to you
imbecile. -Quiet!.
Get out idiot. You' re
making a disturbance.
What are you putting in now?
l don't need anything else.
You have to keep clean. -l
don't need 20 bars of soap.
l' m going for 2 days. -Even
for two days you need soap
You want to get typhus?
Look, l've also got something
for you.
More chocolate? Haven't you
got anything else for him?
Why not? l've got mints and
toffees.
Why does he need candy?
lt's good for him. -No, lt's not.
Yes it is! -No, it's not.
Let me go already.
lt is good for him.
Don't show off OK?
And don't drink boiled water.
Kova, tell him. - Don't
drink unboiled water. Alright?
Don't run around in the sun.
Did you hear? -l heard.
Dad, what are you doing?
You know what's the most
dangerous thing on trips?
What? -Snakes. -Oy vey!
-Don't worry Mrs. Koprovsky,
Alex sweetie, no worry. lf by
chance you go to sleep
under the pillow is a snake,
please hold Mr. Koprovsky,
You take spoon, take cream,
lift pillow, give snake to eat.
He just put out tongue, sleep.
-Farouk, enough already.
Look what you've done, Mrs.
Koprovsky, l made it for now.
lt's fresh.
Farouk. -Farouk...
Farouk, oy vey.
l think l've become a
glasses snake.
What happened? -Oy vey.
Farouk... -Oh Kova!
We have to call the doctor.
-Go and call the doctor.
What happened? -Farouk
fainted. -Serves him right.
lt's his own fault. This piece of
crap wanted to murder us all.
Very good.
Yanosh Miflosh. -Yes Sir.
Sarah Piper. -Yes Sir.
Shuky Potash. -Yes Sir.
Gady Fishenson.
Fishenson, come here.
-Yes sir.
You've come late again
Fishenson? Yes!
l' m sorry sir, my clock
didn't ring.
l don't care if it didn't ring
or didn't sing. Stand straight.
Yes teacher.
Fishenson. -Yes Sir.
Fishenson, take your rag off
my face! -Yes Sir.
Stand in line at once.
Now lets get on the bus.
One at a time.
" Brother driver, brother driver,
off you go, you drive slow.
" Don't you speed, you know.
You go slow, you drive slow."
l want to read you
a love song.
l've waited a long time
for this trip. -Me too.
What's this?
What's going on?
Who threw that egg?
Hooligans! Animals!
Hooligans!
Devora! -Not here.
The students are watching.
OK. We' ll go into the bushes.
-Now? -Now, now.
Do you want a bite?
-No thanks.
Do you know what
this flower is called?
l think it's the " Lame Monk"
-The lame what?
The " Lame Monk" ,
can't you see?
lt's because of
the stalk.
What rubbish.
There's no such flower.
Mimi? -What? -l' m sorry that
l upset you in the cinema.
l can see you hang around
with those characters.
lt's not true. l just couldn't
shake him off.
Whatever...
l owe you a movie.
You don't owe me anything.
-But l' d like to take you.
May l? -l don't know,
we' ll see. lf l have time.
Thanks for the apple.
What are you doing here?
What are you teachers
doing here?
ldiot...
Fishenson, what are
you doing?
Girls, girls over there, quickly.
We' ll meet at night. At 2:00.
-But how will l wake up?
Don't worry. l' ll wake you up.
l've got a clock.
Fishenson!
lgnoramus!
Alex, Alex, Alex.
What's up? Let me sleep.
Let's go and paint the girls.
Alex, come on.
-Just a minute.
Don't disturb me.
Devorah! Devorichka!
Devorichka!
lf we don't get a move on,
there' ll be nothing left.
l don't understand why
we have to go so far
for a little food. -Alexander,
stop talking.
l' m doind all this for you.
-For me? -You think it's for me?
l can make do with marge and
water but you need butter and
that you get on the black
market. -But l don't like butter.
You like butter. -l like butter?
l see you eating it. -l only eat
it because of my ulcer.
Otherwise, l wouldn't touch it.
Now that's enough. Be quiet.
Who's there? Koprovsky.
-Who? -Clara Koprovsky.
Good day Madam.
-What have you got?
l was told that today
you have...
Ssh, no speaking
on the stairs.
May l come in? -What's that?
-What? -The little one?
That's my son. -Not good
to bring here children.
lt's alright.
He wont breathe a word.
So come in. Come in.
Quickly.
They bring children here.
That's all l need.
Go on. Go inside.
So what is it that you want?
A packet of butter please.
-Only half a packet.
Can't l have
a whole packet?
That's what there is Madam.
ls it Dutch butter?
-We haven't had Dutch butter
for ages. This is Swiss
and it's top quality.
So, it' ll be Swiss butter.
Lady, you wait a bit. -Yes.
-And the child not touch, yes?
This crystal, Madam. -l know
lt's crystal, Madam
We also have crystal.
-But this is Rosenthal.
Stand up straight Alexander.
Don't pick your nose,
we' re not at home now.
l know. We' re in the black
market. -Who said that?
l' m sorry. -l heard a boy say
black market.
No! -l not want child talking
about in street,
that here in house,
black market. -No Madam,
he didn't say anything,
did you Alexander?
l didn't say anything about
the black market.
You don't say another word.
-Don't say a word Alexander.
Don't say another thing.
Here's half. -But you have
a whole packet.
Lady, you' re not the
only client here.
There are others
who want to eat.
What are you sniffing? -ls this
fresh? -By me, it's fresh.
Two Lira. -Two Lira?
Lady, this butter
you don't get anywhere.
Tomorrow you pay 4 Lira.
Madam, this is expensive.
l don't need to sell anything.
l don't need no favors.
Yaacov, be quiet Yaacov.
Lady, you hear what
my husband will say.
That's the price. You want,
you buy, not want, not buy.
Alexander, hold that.
Have you got change for 10?
-You have small change? -No
Wait a minute.
Are you looking at my money?
No! Stop looking.
So be it. -Mrs. Yaacov,
Perhaps l could get,
l saw some nuts inside.
Lady, those are my
husband's nuts.
Then maybe l could get
a little meat for my boy.
There is meat here for soup.
-ls there any chicken?
Yes. Today they bring from
farm. -Mr Yaacov, how much?
For why you shouting? All
the neighbors can hear.
How much?
-l' ll give you a good price.
Yaacov, get some chicken.
-Here.
But it's alive.
-l told you it was fresh.
Look how lovely it is.
lf you not want to eat it,
it can bring every day
fresh eggs. -What eggs?
lt's a cockerel, not a hen.
You boy, don't speak here.
-You be quiet.
Before you were born,
l knew what a hen was.
But Mom, it's not a hen,
it's a cockerel.
Alexander, be quiet.
Alexander be quiet, l say.
l told you, we don't need
no pigeons here.
What's this chicken...
-Children are crap.
Gently, softly.
Not nice. Mrs. Koprovsky
can hear sweetie.
Don't go wild, don't go wild.
Your lips are like a crocodile.
What's this? Am l dreaming?
Heaven preserve me.
This isn't a dream. lt's a ghost
A ghost has come to take me.
Help!
Help me, Mrs. Koprovsky,
Mr. Kova.
Help me! l' m on fire.
Help! Why won't
anyone help me.
l' m dying. l' m not asking a lot.
l' m just going to get some
tablets from the kitchen.
l' ll be back in a minute,
don't worry.
Help, a ghost has come
to get me.
Help me Mr. Kova.
-Why have you gone crazy?
Mr. Kova, l' m dying and ghosts
came to take me away.
Why are you talking rubbish?
-Save me Mr. Kova.
He's going to kill me.
-So he' ll kill you, madman.
Show me some pity.
-Get out of here.
l...l' m a protected tenant.
Go away. -So who will
save me? -Madman!
Help! Can anyone hear me?
Neighbors! ghosts have come
to take me away. Help!
l' m going to die. lt's such
a pity. Only 40 years old.
So young. Who should l
leave my gold teeth to?
Mr. Ghost, forgive me.
l' ll do the cleaning for you.
l' ll wash your dirty socks.
My last request, Mr. Ghost,
please don't kill me.
What's all this? get out
of here murderer.
Aren't you ashamed?
With a woman at my age.
Where am l? ln paradise?
lt doesn't hurt at all to die.
Sweetie, you' re also here.
Kerosene, Kerosene!
Alexander, get a move on.
Just look at that line.
Keep the place,
l' ll be right back.
Where are you going?
-To get some without the line.
Mom don't make a show
of yourself. -Trust me.
Excuse me? -What you
want Lady?
Excuse me. -A moment
you see there's a line here.
Perhaps you can help me.
l have a sick child at home.
-Lady, l' m not a doctor,
l sell kerosene. Take him
to the clinic!
Just a small tin, please.
-l' m sorry lady.
A small tin is nothing, really!
-She wants special favors.
l' m sorry Lady, there's a line.
-Some people are heartless.
You should be ashamed of
yourself not standing in line.
Lady, what are you doing?
-And you' re behind me
But l was standing here.
-That's what you think.
Alexander stand straight,
you' ll get a hunchback.
Mr. Misha, do you have
any mail for me?
Let's see. -Move forward.
Move up.
From abroad. -Thank you.
Give me the stamps,
l want the stamps.
Afterwards, first of all
let's see who it's from.
lt's from Lola, your Aunt Lola.
She's coming here.
Who's Lola? -Lola's mother
was your father's cousin.
Your father will be so pleased.
She' ll be here on time
for your Bar Mitzva.
How much Lady?
-Two tins please.
ls that your sick kid?
-No, his brother. The other
one's at home. -Since when
do l have a brother?
He's also sick. His memory
is not so good.
Just wait till we get home.
Your father will get you.
What are you looking at?
-l' m not looking at anything.
You' re not? Your nose
is right in my letter.
That's just what you think.
-Not just what l think.
Go on read it then.
-Mom, that's enough.
Alexander, stand straight.
" Arise, awaken,
the light cometh.
"The glory of the Lord
shines upon you.
" For behold...for..."
lf that's the way you' re going
to sing at your Bar Mitzva
all the guests will run out
of the synagogue.
Listen carefully and follow
me. You understand?
Good, begin.
" Arise, awaken,
the light cometh,
The glory of the Lord
shines upon you.
Your name should be
blotted out, you terrorist.
Are you making fun of me?
You said to say what you say.
-Only what you need to say.
But l didn't say to say
what's not needed.
Carry on, non-believer.
Read the book.
" For darkness shall cover
the land.
" And people lost in the mist
" And God will shine on you."
Rabbi, you have visitors.
The guests have come.
-Peace be with you.
Oy vey!
What's wrong? Why are you
in such a state?
Oy vey.
Lord of the universe.
-Are my fringes not kosher?
Help!
The train is arriving
on platform 2.
Lola, this is my wife.
Hallo Lola. -Hallo.
Please meet Lola.
This is my family.
You look good. -Thank you.
Please. -Thank you.
This is my mother.
-What a beautiful woman!
And how does the lady feel?
l want l speak only Hebrew.
-Well done.
My boy, Alexander.
-Hallo Alex.
Alex, say hallo nicely.
-Hallo.
Go on, give her a kiss.
-You a big girl
-l' m nearly...
You' re a big boy.
-you a big boy.
l' m nearly 13.
-You are big girl.
You are a big boy.
-Kova, stop correcting her.
Let's take the suitcases
and go home.
Alexander, take her bag.
Lolitchka, have another
chicken leg.
Thank you, but l've
really had enough.
But a leg like mine, you
won't find in any restaurant.
lsn't that right Kova? -lt's
true. Clara's legs are good.
But really l can't,
not anymore.
Sorry. -You know l hate you
putting food on my plate.
Alexander, you eat it.
Why are you giving it to me?
l hate chicken.
Alexander, behave yourself
in front of guests.
Kova, l' m really embarrassed.
l don't want it.
Lolitchka, perhaps you' ll
have a little chicken neck.
lt's really very good.
-Stop nagging her.
Perhaps you' ll have some
stuffing. -What? -Stuffing
Thank you, l' m full. -Mom,
why don't you leave her alone.
How can l? She hasn't eaten
a thing, Kova.
Maybe you' d like some
stomachs. They' re good.
Clara makes wonderful
stomachs. Eat, it's good.
Hallo. l' m here.
-That's all l needed.
l' m sorry l' m late. l hope
you started without me.
l' d like to introduce Farouk.
He's our tenant.
That's not a tenant.
lt's a murderer.
Lola, pleased to meet you.
Miss Lola, l very, very happy
to be meeting you.
Farouk, close the shutter,
we' re at the table.
Farouk, eat with your
mouth closed.
Miss Lola, you come special
for Alex Bar Mitzva?
Or you hear l am a bachelor?
-l came for private reasons.
l came to find my fiancee.
What? -To find my friend.
-l see.
He's called Tadeck.
-What? Tadeck Kamelly.
We were going to be married.
That was before the war.
Then the Nazis took him, and
since then l hear nothing.
They said he was dead.
Then my girl friend's brother
said someone like him was
seen here in lsrael.
Do you have his address?
You have to go to the
Missing Persons Bureau.
What's that? -They look
for lost relatives.
lt's worth a try, and really
Lola, l hope that you find him.
But if not, remember
that l' m free.
That's good. Take a look
at the murderer.
" And the glory of the Lord
shall shine,"
Shine, yes. " For behold
the darkness..."
Hi there Fishenson. Did you
bring the stamps? -Yes, 30.
Tell me, do you think
l' m a sucker?
You think you can see my
sister naked for 30 stamps?
Ginger will give you another
She's here. lf he doesn't
show soon, it' ll be too late.
Why did you have to bring
your idiot brother?
Alright, he won't bother you.
Here are your stamps.
But he has to go home.
Be quiet. -That doesn't
interest me.
What do you care Fishenson?
l' ll bring you 50 stamps.
Don't want them. He' ll go
and tell the whole street
that he saw my sister
Fritzia, naked.
He won't say a word Motke.
-l won't say, l won't say.
No way.
l' ll give you 100 stamps.
Tell him Shuky. Tell him l' ll
give him, my album.
l want to see Fritzi naked.
Make sure you've got 100
stamps. -l have, at home.
l knew you wanted to trick me.
-No, l' ll give them to you.
l' ll give you my watch.
Take my watch.
lt's his Bar Mitzva watch.
ldiot. Dad will kill you.
l don't care, l want to see
Fritzi naked.
But she must be completely
naked. -lt's guaranteed idiot.
Heaven help you if you' re
not quiet.
Here, she's coming.
Come on.
Wow, what a cutie! -You bet.
Best looking ass in lsrael.
Where can we peek?
-The shower's best
But will she be completely
naked? Of course, idiot.
What do you think, that she
showers with her coat on?
Come on, follow me.
Now, climb up.
But if she closes the window?
She can't. -Why?
l took the whole window out
together with the curtain.
But will she be naked?
-Shut up, climb up quietly.
Why are you kissing me idiot?
She's going to be naked.
Ssh! She's coming.
So? How are her boobs?
Like apples aren't they?
Guys, the son of a bitch
has tricked us.
lt's not Fritzi, it's her father.
What are you doing here?
-Dear God almighty.
Where are you going?
lt's not Fritzi, it's her father.
l want Fritzi naked.
Get out of here.
l' m going to kill you.
Fishenson, it's you again!
-lt's not me Sir.
Breathe in! -Alex, breathe in.
-Hold it! -Hold lt.
Madam? -What? -Breathe in.
l hope you' re not playing up
to get out of going to school.
Who's playing up?
l don't feel well.
Hold your breath. -Not
feeling well isn't a reason
for not going to school.
-Don't breathe.
Open you mouth please.
-Your mouth, wide.
Yes,yes. -Doctor, l hope
it's not serious
He's got a children's disease.
-What? -He's got chicken pox.
He must lie down
and not go to school.
That's exactly what l said,
Doctor. You hear Alex?
You don't go to school. You
have a dangerous illness.
Don't worry. lt's good he's got
it when he's young.
l hope it's over by his
Bar Mitzva and
Won't spoil the celebration.
-When is your Bar Mitzva?
Tell the doctor.
lt's in another 3 months.
He' ll be better in two weeks.
-Thank God.
Should he be on diet?
-No, he can eat everything.
You hear that Alex? -Yes.
Miss Lola, l request you
that you iron me my pants.
Farouk, leave her alone, you
see that Alex is sick.
Sorry, dear Alex, please,
not be worried.
l think he have collywobbles.
-Not so. He has chicken pox.
Chicken pox? ls it catching?
Sure it is. -lt's catching?
Oh dear. The Lord protect me.
My hands touch him.
Mrs. Koprovsky, l see red.
l feel dizzy. -Take the
watermelon off your head.
Then you won't feel dizzy.
-l request doctor, quick.
Here's a glass of tea. -Please,
get me an ambulance.
l' ll get the Burial Society
for you, you animal.
l beg you, Alex, shouldn't
come near.
Now all my hair will fall out.
l' m telling you, that Farouk
will be the death of us all.
He won't kill us. -He will.
-No, he won't. -He will.
Alexander, go to bed at once.
-Don't want to.
Go to bed at once. -But l
don't want him to come here.
You can't talk like that.
He is your cousin after all.
So what. l don't need
him here.
Hallo. Now what has
happened? -Ask him.
He's shouting at me
about Arehla.
What's with Arehla?
-She's invited him here.
So what? On the vacation
you went there.
But now it's not vacation,
l' m sick and don't feel good.
Why do you need Arehla
here? -Don't you mix in now.
Arehla hasn't
had chicken pox.
Bluma wanted him to get it.
Dr. Fried said it was good to
to get it when you' re young
and avoid complications.
-Dad, l don't want him here.
Tell him to go straight to bed.
-So, go to bed.
So, go to bed.
ls there anything to eat?
-So, sit down.
Kova, there's someone
at the door. -l heard.
Bluma! Arehla! Hallo.
How come it's so late?
l was worried about you.
-Arehla was hungry.
We had to stop and
get some food.
All day Alex was saying:
Where's Arehla, where is he?
Arehla!
The boy looks good.
May he be protected.
l brought some things
from the farm.
Bluma, you really shouldn't.
A thousand times l tell you,
we don't need anything.
ls that all the eggs you
brought? Never mind.
Alex, Arehla is here.
Come in Arehla.
l don't understand.
l' m waiting...
l was so worried,
l didn't understand.
Open wide. -You've already
given me Cod-liver oil
Only 2 more spoons. You
must get stronger.
You can't lose weight
before you' re sick.
One and ...two.
How can you swallow
that disgusting stuff?
Don't be so clever.
lf you took Cod-liver oil
then you wouldn't have
chicken pox. -Exactly.
So why give to me if you want
me to get chicken pox.
Don't you mix in.
Go to bed.
But why do we have
to sleep in the same bed?
Alexander, are you
starting again?
Doctor Fried said you have
to sleep in the same bed.
At least 3 days. -4 days.
Heaven help us!
What happened?
Arehla, move over, you
pushed me out of the bed.
Say, when do you eat breakfast?
-ln the morning!
But l' m hungry now. -So go
to the kitchen and eat.
Shall l make you a sandwich?
Just let me sleep in peace.
-You sure. -Yes, go.
l see that you also
cannot sleep.
Tell me, can you give me
one sandwich.
Help yourself.
-l like with tomato.
lt's tasty! -Say, what's that
green stuff on your head?
lt's hair cream. lt's the best
on the market today.
lt's made of Hammer fish
and Sword fish.
You mix all up. You take
the juice of wild beast
that cries at night
of full moon,
the gall bladder juice.
Disgusting! -Why you say
that? ln 2 days time
l have long hair like
Samson and Delilah.
Hey, can l have another
sandwich like that one.
Sure, but the spread
is finished.
Really? -Look,
the jar is empty.
God save us. ls that what
you gave me in the sandwich?
Yes. -That's my hair cream.
My God. My stomach
not feel good.
l've eaten a hammer and
a sword. No good.
Now l' ll grow fins and scales.
l must drink much soap
and wash all the cream out.
What will become of me?
Who will help me?
l think l will have tail.
Hairs in my stomach and a tail
What shall l do
Mrs Koprovsky?
Up, up parasites.
l' m all out of breath.
Come quickly, the
teacher is going to kill us.
Wait for me!
-Mimi wait a minute.
There's a new movie with
Sandra day, " Summer Oasis"
l saw that in the " Coming
Shortly" , with the blond guy.
Troy Donaghu. -That's him.
Do you want to come?
l can't, l' m going out
with my girlfriend.
What are you doing Saturday?
Do you want to go to the sea?
l' m going to my uncle's
with my parents.
lt's a shame l' m not your
uncle. -What did you say?
l said, it's a pity l' m not
your uncle. -lt's a shame.
Thank you, Mr. Aryeh.
Lola, you really don't need
to hang up washing.
l' ll do it later.
-Please, l want to do it.
Hi. -Alex, will you help Lola
with the washing.
Go up to the roof with her.
lt's really not necessary.
-l don't mind.
Thank you.
Dad said you hadn't heard
anything from Tadeck.
No, they looked through
all sorts of documents,
and they didn't find anything.
-You mustn't give up.
Yesterday they put a noticei
in the paper, that l' m here.
They also announced it on
the radio. Maybe he' ll hear it.
l' m sure they' ll find him.
-l don't know any more.
Maybe he was killed in the
war. -You mustn't think that.
You must find him.
-Thank you.
You' re a good boy Aletchko.
Hi there! -What's up?
-Everything's OK.
What are you going to do in
the vacation? -Don't know.
Hey, do you like calypso?
-Sure.
The Palm Tree Group is
coming to lsrael. -Really?
They have a show at the
Amphi. l' m dying to see them.
l bet there's no seats left.
-Can we finally take the shot?
Alex, Mima not to disturb.
-Leonid!
So Dobrov, please.
-l shall count to 3 and take it.
One, two, three.
Alexander, what are you
looking for? -Cold water.
Who drinks cold water in
summer? Have some tea.
Not tea. l' m hot and sweaty.
-Exactly, that's why.
You drink cold water,
you get a sore throat.
Never mind.
-Where are you going?
Cold Sabras. Cold Sabras.
Two tickets for the group.
-60 grush.
Anything cheaper? -That's
the cheapest. -OK.
Hallo! -Hallo! ls Mimi at
home? -No, she's out.
You sure? -Yes, did she
know you were coming?
Not exctly. -l' m sorry.
Shall l give her a message?
-No, it's not important.
Well' goodbye. -Goodbye.
Alex, did you see my brother
Shuky? Alex!
Have you heard anything
about him?
Lola, don't cry.
Please, don't cry.
You' re a good boy Aletchko.
-You' ll see, it will all be OK.
Aletchko...
My Aletchko...
Hallo, -Hallo.
-Do you live here? -Yes.
Perhaps you know the
Koprovsky family?
Yes, that's my family.
Perhaps you can help me. l' m
looking for a girl called Lola.
Lola? l don't know her. -Did
you have a family visitor?
You' re mistaken.
-Are you sure?
Maybe l' ll ask your parents.
lt's not worth trying.
They've gone away,
they' re on holiday.
Whatever the way, if you hear
from a girl called Lola
would you give her this letter.
Yes, thank you.
Alexander, who were
you talking to? -No one.
So go empty the pail and
wash it out in the yard.
Good morning.
-Good morning.
What's this?
l made you breakfast.
For me? Thank you.
-lt's nothing.
Enough Aletchko!
Lola...
l... -Aletchko...
Mom must be worried about us.
Lola... -Lets go.
Come on, lets go.
Popsicle, lemon popsicles.
l thought you were drowned.
-Lola, take a sandwich.
So, how was the sea? -Good.
-Maybe some fried fish Alex?
l hate fried fish! -So wear a
hat or you' ll get sun-stroke.
Mom, enough. -Kova.
-Do as you' re told.
Don't want to. Alexander!
Hallo every one. -lt's
impossible to get rid of him.
What made you come to the
sea? -Something important.
What happened now?
Miss Lola, this for you.
-For me? -Yes.
What's this, a birthday?
-Much more important.
Miss Lola, l've thought a lot.
l' m not married, nor are you.
Farouk, stop talking rubbish.
She's not for you.
Why not? l think she's for me
and l am for her.
Miss Lola, l guarantee, there
is not another man like me.
What do you say?
You' re a real Don Juan.
Tell me miss Lola,
l make you big party.
l make you the biggest
wedding in the country.
Farouk stop jabbering.
Before we make a wedding
We have a Bar Mitzva.
-Mrs. Koprovsky,
l already had a Bar Mitzva.
" Arise awake, the light is come
The glory of God shall shine
" Darkness will cover the land,
People are lost in the mist.
"The Lord will shine on thee,
His glory on you, be seen.
"The nations will come to thee
And kings to your light.
" Lift up thine eyes and see
"Your sons come from afar,
Then will you see
" the rivers flow abundantly"
You' re not getting peanuts,
-l don't like peanuts.
" From Sheba they will come
Bearing gold and myrrh.
" Flocks of Kedar will tell of
The love of the Lord ."
What page are we on?
" What is the..."
" For the ships of Tarshish will
" Bring your sons from afar
"Their gold and silver too."
-Mazal tov, good luck.
" Lord of the universe,
who reigned
" Before all creatures
were created
" And he was and will be"
Mom...
Lola, have you seen Mom?
-She went with grandma.
She' ll be back soon.
Why are you packing?
-l' m going. -Where?
l' m going back home,
tomorrow morning.
l still have to go to
the travel agent.
But why Lola? Don't you
like being with us?
You' re my family and
l love you all,
especially you, Aletchko.
-l love you too Lola.
Don't worry. l' ll be back.
-What about Tadeck?
Perhaps he's in lsrael?
-No Alex, he's not here.
lf you found him
would you stay?
lf l found him l' d
give him my whole life.
Lola, this is Sonia, my wife.
Sonia, Lola, a childhood
friend from before the war.
Pleased to meet you.
Tadeck told me about you.
And this is our daughter.
Come in. Sit down.
l' ll make some tea.-Please.
No thank you, l only came
to say hallo.
l' m in a real hurry.
We' re just suckers for not
bringing girls with us.
We know your dogs
Yanosh. -Yes.
Malcah and Zippy.
lt's a pity Fishenson didn't
bring his sister, Fritzy.
Don't talk about my sister.
What about your aunt?
She's better. -You know
at the Bar Mitzva
l kissed her 7 times.
So what, l kissed her 11
times with my tongue.
She's crazy about me
the nymphomaniac.
Shut your mouth idiot.
But your mother
told my mother that
she has to leave tomorrow,
your aunt, lsn't that right?
She was supposed to go
but she's staying now.
lt's a pity his aunt isn't
staying with me.
Smart guy! What would you
do with her?
More than you would do,
lmbecile.
ls that so? -Yes it is!
-Like what?
l' d put her in the shower,
and then l' d....
Take a peek!
Dope!
All together now,
one , two, three.
Where were you all night?
-We had a bonfire.
Mom went crazy. Lola
Really wanted to say goodbye
Why, has she gone? They
left with her half an hour ago.
Where are you running to?
Eat something.
All passengers to Haifa are
requested to board the train.
The Haifa train is leaving
from platform 1
Lola! -Alexander!
Aletchko. -Lola
-Aletchko.
Why are you going?
-l' ll come back, l promise.
Will you write to me?
Do you promise?
' Bye Aletchko.
-' Bye Lola.
Guess who this is. -Don't
know. -Try. -Don't know
What are you doing here
so early?
Just felt like it.
Did something happen? -l
think l got sand in my eye.
Are you alright? -Yes. -Do
you fancy a drink? -Sure.
So come on, let's go.
" Alex in Love"