-Good morning.
-How's it going?
-Good morning, Santi.
-Hi.
How did your night go?
Nothing special. You?
Same.
...the bird flu,
it concerns a worker...
-What'll it be?
-The usual.
Did you go to the doctor?
And?
It's my nerves.
And my cholesterol is sky-high,
so no tripe or shit like that.
But we have to die of something
and better to do so happily, right?
And fast. The sooner the better.
Sorry.
-Here you go.
-Thanks.
I'm picking up my last fare.
I'll call you later.
-That's 30 euros.
-I'll pay with my phone, okay?
Okay.
-Okay. Do you want a copy?
-No, thanks.
-Have a good trip.
-Thanks!
-Hi.
How's your night going?
Fine. Like always.
Are you coming home now?
Yes. I'm close by, actually.
I'm at the airport.
Okay.
Want me to make something?
No, it's okay. I already had breakfast.
Okay.
I was thinking, if you want,
we could go somewhere for lunch today...
Just to get out.
Sure, if you want to.
Do you want to or not?
Sure, it's all the same to me.
Whatever you want.
Okay, we'll see later.
All right.
Christ.
Oh, my God.
Come over here.
Please.
Hold on to me.
My taxi’s right here.
I'll take you in my taxi, don't worry.
Careful.
Don't worry, don't worry, kid.
I'll take you to the hospital.
Here. Have some water.
-Raúl! Wake up! Get dressed.
-What's going on?
There was an attack. I'm calling Dad
-but he won't pick up.
-What?
Mom!
There were two powerful explosions...
Mom, what are you doing? What happened?
I don't know.
There was an explosion at the airport.
-Your dad was there.
-He was?
Yeah, I just talked to him,
I just talked to him.
Before the explosion?
Two explosions
in the terminal between...
Ramón's on his way over.
Let’s go find him.
Don't worry. Don't worry,
we're going to the hospital.
Get me out of here. Now.
Get me out of here.
Get me out of the city.
Don't look at me!
I said don't look at me.
Don't look at me and drive. Let's go.
It's my wife. No, no, no,
please, let me answer...
Give me the other phone.
The other phone. Now.
Go. Get me out of here.
-Relax.
-Get me out and don't look at me.
Not a word, not one.
I said to get me out of here.
I can't move, I can't move,
I can't move.
Go, go, go.
Go.
Go straight, go straight, go straight.
One has failed.
And the remote detonator doesn't work.
The phone must have gotten
damaged in the other explosions.
Dammit.
Selma,
when you hear this message,
I will no longer be in this life.
I am going to Paradise.
The Adolfo Suárez Airport
has four terminals.
The international terminal...
It can't be...
What's wrong, Selma?
Honey, what's wrong?
Hamza's dead.
What about Hamza?
There, we will be happy forever.
God willing.
Allah is the greatest.
Mama...
We have to go to the police.
-Mama...
-I said no!
You really think they won't discover
he is one of them?
If we don't cooperate,
we'll be in trouble.
We have done nothing wrong.
And your brother...
Hamza is no killer.
He was tricked...
He is not a killer.
-My son is not a killer!
-It's okay, Mama.
-The car skipped the checkpoint.
-Stop!
You can't be here.
Turn around immediately.
We're looking for someone.
Evacuate the area immediately.
-Go. Don't enter.
-Please.
-Evacuate the area immediately.
-Please, my husband is here.
Ma’am, please. It's very dangerous.
You can't be here.
Everyone was evacuated,
go to the hospitals.
-Wait, my dad's a taxi driver...
-Leave now!
-I heard you...
-If you heard me, then evacuate.
-Yeah, we're leaving, sorry.
-Come on. Let's go, leave.
Let's go...
His car's not here.
He's not here. Come on, get in.
Where are we going?
Where's the GPS?
-What?
-Are you deaf? Where's the GPS?
In... In the glove box.
How are you doing?
We finally have a signal.
Santi, it's Ramón.
Do you copy?
-Santi...
-Shut that off.
There's been an attack.
We're looking for you. Do you copy?
-Where is it?
-Over here, Commander. I'll show you.
Good morning.
Sorry I'm late, getting here was hell.
-Is Gerardo here yet?
-No, but he should be shortly.
-What about the tapes?
-On their way.
-Heck of a start you've had.
-Yes. A real triumph.
This has been a monumental fuck-up.
Sorry for the delay,
downtown is in chaos.
No problem.
Pilar just got here too.
We'd better identify these assholes
as soon as possible.
-A few heads are going to roll today.
-As they should.
This isn't the army.
Things are quite different here.
I'm here to do my job.
I'll be aiming at you the whole time.
Okay...
Try pulling anything and I'll shoot you
and anyone else I need to.
Don't worry.
I won't do anything stupid.
Get out of the taxi.
Grab the pliers and the screwdriver.
-Good morning.
18.70, please.
Sit there.
Hands on your head.
Stay still.
Get out.
We've got them.
Three. There are three.
Yes, 20 years old or so.
All right.
But there were two explosions,
not three.
The third explosion could have failed.
Or he backed out and he's still alive.
Yeah, let's hope not.
It must be this way.
Excuse me, where’s the person in charge?
-I don't know.
-Thank you.
Excuse me,
the person in charge of this floor?
Over there.
We're looking
for a victim of the attack,
-could you help us, please?
-Full name?
-Sa...
-Santiago Gómez Lasarte.
-Okay...
-Lasarte.
Santiago Gómez Lasarte...
He's not here.
Check Isabel Zendal Hospital
or the forensics department.
Don't worry, we're going to find him.
Okay?
All right, let's go, Raúl.
These images
captured by the security cameras
show the three terrorists
moments before the attack.
Driss Manzur, age 20,
Malik Jalaf, age 18,
and Hamza Chait, age 19.
All of them are Spanish residents
originally from Morocco.
So far, it is not known
if they have a history
linked to jihadist terrorism.
-Minister, do you have them?
-I have them in front of me.
What do we know about them?
We know that none of them have a record.
We also have
their social media profiles,
which are clearly fake.
They made them two years ago,
when Kadar Abadi was still free,
so there's a lot of evidence
pointing in his direction.
I asked that he be brought here
for interrogation.
Understood. How is the search
in the hospitals going?
Minister, we're working on it.
But at the moment, none of them appear
to have been wounded or unconscious.
Okay, thank you, everyone.
Please keep me updated.
Thank you.
Give me the keys.
Stay still.
Hands on the wheel.
Do you recognize them?
No.
Kadar, give me a name.
Just one name and your life in prison
will be much easier.
You know as well as I do
that we all use fake names.
No one knows who anyone really is.
So when you catch us,
all you have is one thing...
Nothing.
What about you, Kadar? What do you have?
A fucking isolation cell
where you'll spend your whole life
trying to convince yourself
that it was worth it.
But deep down,
you know that no one cares about you.
Your bosses are free,
living their best fucking lives,
tricking someone just like you
to do their dirty work.
Hell on Earth.
That's what you have.
Think about it.
Just one name.
Stop! Military Police!
Military Police!
-Stop!
-Go, go!
Military Police!
Stop!
Stop there! Don't move!
Military Police! Hands up!
Hands up!
Turn around, turn around!
Turn around!
Where is he?
Why the hell
isn't he answering his phone?
Hey, Laura, do you have access
to Santi's GPS application?
-Yeah.
-The GPS?
-Yeah, yeah, I do.
-Open it.
Here.
-Nothing.
-What?
It lost signal over an hour ago. Look.
-Let me see.
-There.
That's Somosierra.
-Somosierra?
-Yes.
Hey...
I have to pee, please.
Please.
Get in the car.
Now what?
I don't know.
Whatever I do, I'm fucked.
It doesn't have to be like that.
The police will protect you.
You're important for them.
Until they get what they need.
Why didn't you press the detonator?
Because I'm a coward.
They said, before we die,
you see the face of Allah.
But I could only see my mother's face.
Maybe it's best
if you turned yourself in.
They aren't moving.
What do we do?
We found him.
Let's get him.
-Let me see the GPS.
-Here it is.
Here it is. Here's the gas station.
See if the car's in the parking lot.
I'll ask inside.
It's not here.
Have you seen a taxi driver here
in the past couple hours?
I don't know. I just started my shift.
Is there anyone from the other shift
that can give me a hand?
I'm sorry, my coworker's already left.
Look.
What is that?
Holy shit.
This is Santi's, no doubt about it.
We have to call the police.
-They aren't going to do anything.
-Why not?
-He's an adult, Ramón.
-So?
Without evidence
that something's happened,
they won't look for him.
Not with everything going on.
But we have to report this.
He clearly doesn't want to be found.
Raúl, no.
Your dad would never disappear
and leave you like this.
Okay?
All right...
He's right, honey. He's right.
The taxi driver
is Santiago Gómez Lasarte.
These are
the gas station's security cameras,
where the family reported
his disappearance.
The GPS loses signal
at that same service station.
Without a signal,
this is going to be complicated.
Yes, that's Hamza Chait.
It seems
he took the taxi driver hostage.
Locate Hamza Chait's family.
We haven't heard from Hamza
in almost a year.
We know he was in Syria
from October to December last year.
Most likely receiving military training.
That's when he disappeared.
Did you notice
anything strange before he left?
Yes, but...
we'd never imagined something like this.
What did you notice?
When did he start acting different?
It was...
after coming back
from his last vacation in Morocco.
He started going to the mosque every day
when he'd never gone before.
He made me start wearing a hijab
when I never used to wear one.
My son wanted to be a good Muslim.
But they tricked him.
Good Muslims don't do what he did.
What's going on?
We think Hamza is still alive.
And he might possibly
get in touch with you.
If he does,
it's important that you tell us
so we can help him.
Thank God.
Thank God. Thank God.
God's wrath will fall upon you.
Come on, let's go.
Get out.
Let's go.
-Come on.
-Let's go.
Move.
Khaled Saidi. For the past two months,
he shared an apartment
with the two suicide terrorists,
Manzur and Jalaf.
They met in an internet café,
and though it's too early
to rule anything out,
it appears he didn't know
his roommates' intentions.
We're also interrogating
their families in Morocco,
but we don't have anything so far.
We have to go public
so that bastard
doesn't have anywhere to hide.
If we make it public,
we put the taxi driver's life in danger.
His life is already in danger.
If Chait hasn't killed him yet,
he plans to use him as a shield.
In any event, we shouldn't forget
what our priority is.
We need to find Hamza Chait alive.
Let's wait until dawn.
Why, Pilar?
Chait doesn't know
we're looking for him.
He's probably feeling confident
and he'll make a mistake.
It's only been five hours
since the attack,
the coming hours are crucial.
I agree.
Agreed.
Until dawn,
but not a single hour longer.
We have to notify the driver's family.
If you don't mind,
I'd like to speak with them myself.
Of course.
Papa wanted these to be yours.
Do you know what all the beads are?
There are 99.
One for every name of God.
-The first name is Allah.
-Allah. (God)
The second is Ar-Rajman.
Ar-Rajman. (The Merciful)
Ad-Dar... (The Causer of Harm)
Al-Qawiyy... (The Strong One)
-Al-Hamid...
-Al-Hamid. (The Praiseworthy)
Al-Mumit... (The Bringer of Death)
-Al-Muntaquim...
-Al-Muntaquim... (The Avenger)
-Al-Muhyee...
-Al Muhyee. (The Giver of Life)
-Al-Kabeer.
-Al-Kabeer. (The Greatest)
-As-Salam.
-As-Salam. (The Giver of Peace)
Hey.
Hey, kid. Hey.
Come on, kid.
Come on, kid. Come on, kid.
Hey, hey.
Can you sit up?
Do you think you can walk?
-Don't leave me alone.
-No.
Shit...
Shit.
Hang on.
Several witnesses say
the terrorists detonated their vests
at the check-in desks
for the airlines,
a very busy area
at the time of the attack...
Happy birthday
to you.
There you go!
Okay, a few words. It's a family video.
There. That's it.
Such coordination, such coordination.
I'm going to fall out. Hey, hey, hey!
Hey, sis.
How's my sister today?
I'm making you
a lovely collection of videos.
No, leave me alone.
No, I can't.
I want to make a collection of videos
of you becoming a titan.
A titan... What for?
Because you'll get better.
Well...
Hello?
Yes, this is she.
These images were captured
an hour after the attack.
The man with him is the third terrorist
that didn't detonate
his bomb at the airport.
We think
he has taken your husband hostage.
But we won't stop until we find him.
What can we do?
Stay here until we find him.
It'll be quiet in here.
We'll let you know if we hear anything.
Thank you.
Hey.
It's okay, Mom.
It's okay, it's okay, it's okay.
It's okay.
YOU AND YOUR FAMILY
ARE FUCKING GARBAGE
IS YOUR BROTHER REALLY ONE
OF THE GUYS FROM THE ATTACK?
Will you talk to my mother?
Relax.
Okay?
I won't have to. You'll make it.
I don't think so.
Give this to her for me.
Don't be silly.
-Please.
-Don't be silly.
-Please...
-Give it to her yourself.
Please.
My oldest child's name was Mónica.
She died a year and a half ago.
Of cancer.
No one deserves to lose a child.
No one.
Relax.
Okay?
There, we will be happy forever.
God willing.
Allah is the greatest.
Hamza.
Hey! Hey!
Here, over here! Please.
Hey.
Over here, help.
We had an accident, please.
How life twists and turns, eh, Santiago?
Now you will finish
what that coward Hamza
could not.
What?
Listen carefully.
When this call is over,
the bomb
you are wearing will be activated.
It works
with very sensitive motion sensors.
That means that
in order for it not to explode,
you must walk.
If you stop, you will die.
-But what...?
-And don't try any tricks.
You have to walk.
Why are you doing this to me?
Why are you doing this?
I haven't done anything!
A picture is worth a thousand words.
And yours will be seen around the world.
Hey!
Please... Please, I need help.
Please, help me. I need help.
Please, listen... Listen to me.
Listen to me! Help, please.
Please, call the police.
Security!
Yes, here.
Please, you have to call my boss.
-Freeze!
Freeze!
-I can't, I can't stop moving!
If I stop, it explodes.
I can't stop, it'll explode.
Please, listen to me.
Listen to me!
You have to call the police.
Call the police.
Evacuate the building!
Go, go, go.
Come on, come on.
Please, don't stop.
Come on, come on, come on.
Go, go.
-Good morning, Captain.
-How's it going?
Almost ready.
Let's go! Let's go, let's go!
Come on...
-Hello.
-Commander.
This is everything we have.
Stop!
Don't shoot. Don't shoot.
Please, I can't stop, I can't stop.
They said if I stop,
the bomb will explode.
I'm going to throw you
a radio so we can talk, okay?
Okay?
Okay, I'm going to see
what kind of explosive it is, okay?
-While I walk?
-Yes. Don't worry.
My name is Jesús. What's your name?
Santiago Gómez Lasarte.
Very good. Keep walking.
-Yes?
-I'm Pilar Montero,
Military police commander.
We're very sorry about your situation.
We are doing our best to find a solution
-as soon as possible.
-Raise your arm.
-Tell me what happened.
Hey... Hey, I need
to talk to my family, please.
You have to contact them.
Don't worry, they're with us.
Now I need you to tell me what happened.
Well... I don't exactly know.
I picked up
one of the terrorists at the airport
thinking he was a victim
and he kidnapped me.
Then we got in an accident
and some men appeared
and they shot Hamza.
-Keep walking.
-And they knocked me out.
And...
That's all I remember. I woke up
in the bathroom
with this explosive vest on.
And they...
They called me on a phone and said...
-Hamza Chait is dead?
-Yes...
Yes, he's dead.
Tell me
exactly what they told you
during that phone call.
They said... that the vest
has motion sensors
and if I stop walking, it will explode.
Santiago, don't worry,
we're here to help.
We won't let that happen.
Now please give the phone
that the terrorists gave you
to Jesús. Thank you.
Keep going. Keep walking.
Keep walking, don't stop.
Keep walking.
Go.
Thanks.
Sorry, the number
you dialed does not exist.
Of course.
The Islamic State, also known as Daesh,
previously attacked Spain
in the attacks in Barcelona and Cambrils
on the afternoon of August 17th, 2017.
On that occasion, there were 16...
The three terrorists had been residing
in Spain for several years
and officials weren't concerned
about their ties to the Islamic State.
They do not seem to have been looking
for licensed lawyers either.
This suggests that, once again, it'd be
a terrorist cell coming from Paris...
The explosive
seems to be TATP, 22 units.
And there are three locks on the opening
on the back.
It has a built-in timer
with a phone underneath,
so it's very likely
they can trigger the vest remotely
and the motion sensors
seem to be connected
to a red flashing light.
It's impossible
to deactivate here now, right?
If the hostage was immobile,
it'd be risky but viable.
But in these conditions,
I'd say it's impossible.
So what options do we have?
To reduce the consequences
of an explosion as much as possible,
we should move him to a clear area
and, once there, remove the vest
on a surface we can control.
Like a treadmill, for example.
-Does the vest have GPS?
-Probably not.
Where is the nearest safe area?
This industrial zone is ideal.
It's secure enough
to direct the convoy there.
Commander,
I'd take him there without a doubt.
-How far is it from here?
-About 10 kilometers.
There's no time for that.
They can set off the vest at any time
and if we don't want any more deaths
or severe injuries,
we have to trigger
a controlled explosion.
Yes, it has to be right here.
The area is clear
and the media doesn't know anything yet.
We can't sentence that man to death
without weighing all our options.
Fine, what options
do we have? What options?
Make no mistake, Pilar,
we aren't the ones
that sentenced him to death.
INCOMING CALL
PRIVATE NUMBER
Am I speaking to Pilar? Pilar Montero?
Yes, this is she.
What are you playing at, Pilar?
I thought you were a woman of action.
It's 700 steps to Gran Vía.
If Santiago isn't there in five minutes
for the whole world to see live,
we'll activate the vest.
Fuck.
We can't let them get their way.
It's my decision.
And a controlled explosion
isn't an option.
We'll see about that.
We cannot allow the image
of a civilian
walking through the center of Madrid
with a bomb that can go off
at any moment, Pilar.
Don't forget we're setting
a very dangerous precedent
giving in to what the terrorists want.
It is equally dangerous for us
to sacrifice a civilian
behind closed doors.
We know full well they have images
of Santiago in the vest in the bathroom,
so even if we wanted to hide this,
they'd release those
and accuse us of his death.
I'm aware of all that this entails.
But if we can't keep
that man from dying,
we must at least make it clear
that we did all we could to save him.
Go ahead, Commander.
-Captain, go ahead.
-We'll continue the operation.
Santiago, this is Pilar again.
-Hello.
-We'll be in constant contact
through this device.
I appreciate that,
but do you think I have a chance
of surviving this?
Do you think we'd set all this up
if you didn't?
May I please ask a favor?
Anything.
And no need to be polite...
I think the occasion warrants it.
I need to talk to my wife.
-What?
-We've found Santiago.
-Great...
-Is he okay?
-Is... Is he okay?
-Where?
-He's with us...
And he wants to talk to you.
Santi?
-Santi, can you hear me?
-Laura?
-Hello, my love. Hello, my love.
-Laura, can you hear me? Are you okay?
We're fine, how are you?
-Where is he?
-How are you?
Fine, fine, fine.
Okay, listen to me, Laura.
-You have to stay calm, okay?
-Where...?
Listen, where are you?
We'll come get you, okay?
Laura, you have to... You can't come.
You have to stay calm, okay?
Sa... Santi, what is it?
Why can't we go?
-Can I have the phone?
-What is it?
Please give the phone back. Please.
-What is it, Santi?
-Laura...
-It's under control, all right?
-Laura!
You have to stay calm.
It's all under control.
All right?
Calm down.
-Let's see...
-What is it?
Let's see.
"As you can see,
there's significant police presence
and the reason is this:
the Military police is escorting a man
with an explosive vest
attached to his chest.
The Military police tells us
he is not a terrorist,
and all we know about the man
is he's Spanish.
That's all the information we have.
Neither I nor my media colleagues
have received
any additional information.
But we'll do all we can
to try to find out
what's going on and inform our audience
as they deserve."
We're going over
all the operations with explosives
-in Iraq and Afghanistan.
-All right.
Pilar, this is a mistake.
Director?
Interior command is furious, Pilar,
they want to know the plan. Now.
We're working on it.
I'll be right back.
We'll trick them and take Santiago
without them realizing it.
-Trick them how?
-By rigging the footage.
Making them think it's live
when it's really not.
It's the tactic used by the terrorists
that attacked us in Afghanistan,
remember?
They hacked the security cameras
on the base, right?
That's right.
We don't know if we have time
for an operation like that.
The vest could explode at any moment.
I think we have some leeway.
They like to extend suffering
as long as possible.
In their words,
they said they want everyone
to see Santiago live.
-And?
-The sun hasn't come up yet in the US.
It's not long,
but the time difference will help us.
And what about people looking outside?
They're already posting videos,
it'd be easy to discover the farce.
We'll have to shut down the internet
in Madrid for a few hours.
Gerardo?
At this point, we have nothing to lose.
I can't take this.
I can't take it.
-Raúl, where are you going?
-The bathroom.
No, no, no.
Please, please, don't touch him.
-Please, please.
-Okay, okay.
Listen.
I need to talk to my dad, please.
We have orders for you and your mother
to stay here until further notice.
I need to talk to him,
don't you get that?
No, we have an operation to save him,
-you have to trust us.
-I don't care!
-I have to talk to him now.
-Okay...
Dad.
Dad?
Go ahead, son.
I saw you on my phone.
You're everywhere, man.
You're blowing up online.
Raúl, you... You shouldn't be looking
at anything online.
Yeah. But what am I supposed to do?
Hey...
Listen to me.
Do me a favor, okay?
Don't give up.
Okay?
Please.
-Do you hear me?
-Yes.
Yes...
I know you've felt like shit
since Mónica died...
Me too, Dad.
I'm exhausted.
I feel like...
I feel like nothing...
Nothing is the same,
it's all cold and strange.
But Dad...
If you die now...
Well...
Mom and I will die too, okay?
Got it?
Raúl.
Raúl, listen to me.
Listen, everything will be okay.
Do you hear me?
These guys know what they're doing,
it'll be okay, promise.
I promise.
Son.
Son, I love you.
I love you too.
Look at the image. See it?
It's the same image over and over.
As security watched this,
three soldiers were dying right there.
We need something similar.
Yes, but it wouldn't work in this case
because Santiago is constantly moving,
so is the convoy.
We have to film
an empty section of Gran Vía.
A section they've never been to.
And then, using artificial intelligence,
splice in a previous recording
of Santi and the convoy.
That way they'll still be moving.
And we can replace
one image with another
at a specific moment
for them to leave the street.
Pilar.
We'll be in touch.
Ready.
Santiago.
You should eat something
and stay hydrated.
No, thanks. I'm not hungry.
How about a drink?
Anything but alcohol is on the house.
I'll bet the house has never faced
someone like me before.
Actually, no.
You've really raised the bar for us.
But I'm grateful for the chance
to impress my bosses.
Don't be scared,
but it's only my third day.
You've made a hell of an entrance.
You can say that again.
Hold on a minute.
PERFECT!
What does it say?
What's that mean? You have enough?
How long until sunrise
on the west coast of the US?
-Not long. We don't have time.
-Shit.
Do you have the images you need?
We're going as fast as we can,
we're almost there.
Okay, thank you.
You're certainly in good shape.
Do you smoke?
No. Do you?
Like a chimney, but I want to quit.
Yes?
Accelerate the mission.
Number one or two?
Number one.
We have something.
We've intercepted a call
that could be related to the terrorists.
Here. In Madrid, in Lavapiés.
-Good work, prepare the operation.
-Yes, sir.
Pilar.
-Yes?
-Pilar, a...
A phone rang and a timer started,
it's counting down from 21 minutes.
The lights changed.
A timer was triggered.
Relax, Santiago, we're here.
Now.
Yes?
-Pilar, we're ready.
-Thank you.
-Prepare the detour.
-Everyone ready.
What's going on?
It seems the man is going...
-Does your Twitter work?
-Not WhatsApp, not Twitter, nothing.
Go ahead.
Cue effect.
Effect ready.
Roll effect in three...
Two... One...
Go.
Santiago, turn right when you can.
-Here, right, Pilar?
-Yes.
Santi...
Commander. Commander, get behind me.
Santiago.
Santiago. Can you hear me?
-Yes.
-We have time and we won't fail.
Pilar...
Leave me alone, okay?
Leave me alone, please.
We aren't leaving you alone.
Santiago.
We'll be in contact at all times.
I'm behind you, I'm not leaving.
Let's go.
"It's truly awful.
How can an ordinary citizen,
like any one of us at this table,
find himself in a situation
as grim as this one?
I don't know
if we are doing better or worse
in the fight against terrorism,
but something like this
leaves a lot of unanswered questions.
The fact that we still know nothing
about the reason for this situation
is incomprehensible.
I'd even go as far
as to call it unacceptable.
Why are they letting us
record something like this?
His face says it all.
And it's not just us Spaniards
wondering.
People demand to know
what is happening and why."
Stop!
-Freeze!
-Don't move!
-Stop, get on the ground, dammit!
Freeze!
-Don't move, stop!
-Stop!
-Freeze!
-Get on the ground!
-You're under arrest, dammit!
-Stop!
Stop!
Move aside!
Are you okay?
What happened?
A phone, there's a phone.
Hide it, hide it.
-It looks broken.
-Maybe it's only the screen...
Come on, quick.
I'll cut the first lock, okay?
Almost done.
Santiago, how is it going?
Good.
Good, it's going good.
The first lock is off.
Now for the second.
Stay calm, stay calm, please.
Just keep walking.
They've reached the area.
-You have to take us.
-Sorry, that's not possible.
Stop saying it's not possible.
-Why not?
-Be quiet for a second, please!
Put yourself in my shoes.
I need to see him.
If the bomb explodes,
Santiago doesn't want you there.
Santi?
Santi, can you hear me?
Laura.
Santi, can you hear me? Are you there?
-Santi...
-Yes, my love.
Laura.
Laura, listen to me.
I want to apologize.
I want to apologize to you and Raúl.
Don't say that, my love, please.
I've been very unfair.
But I love you so much, my love.
I love you both so much.
I never stopped.
You're my whole world.
I know, my love, I know.
That's why I'm apologizing.
I'm so sorry.
But listen,
now I need you to focus on you.
And saving yourself.
Do you hear me, Santi?
I know you will. I know it.
You know I hate it
that you always get your way,
that you're always right.
But listen, this time,
I want you to fight
with everything you have, you hear me?
With everything you have, okay, honey?
Stubborn as a mule.
That's it, that's it, my love,
don't think about anything else.
Just that mule.
Okay, my love?
Promise me, please.
Mule’s honor.
I love you, honey. I love you so much.
You too, my dear.
I don't think it works.
We should check the contacts
and call somebody.
It's not ours, Jamal.
-We'll call tomorrow.
-No.
-Look, there are only two numbers.
-Then call the first one.
There's no answer.
-Jesús.
-Stay calm.
-Santi, calm down, okay?
-Jesús, Jesús.
Something happened, the numbers changed.
Hold on.
Okay, stay calm. Stay calm, okay?
Hello?
Who is this?
Who are you?
Jamal.
Okay.
I'm moving to the last lock, okay?
The last lock.
Okay, come on.
-How is it going?
-Good, good.
Whatever you do, don't turn around.
Okay, there. Stay calm, Santi, okay?
Where did this come from?
Whose phone is this, Jamal?
-I found it on the street.
-And you just thought you'd keep it?
-When it's not yours?
-Can you let us watch the game in peace?
Okay, there. Stay calm.
It's done, hang on.
I'm almost done, come on.
Fucking hell!
Come on, come on, come on.
God fuck dammit.
Jesús...
Take it off, take it off! Take it off!
Come on, take it off.
Take it off, take it off.
Come on.
Take it off. God dammit...
Wait, wait, wait.
Okay, okay...
Take it off, take it off. Run, run!
Run, run!
Come on, come on.
Santiago, how are you?
Huh? How are you?
Jesús...
Jesús, Jesús.
Are you conscious? Are you conscious?
Are you conscious?
-Hello...
-What's your name?
What's your name?
-Jesús.
-Jesús, I'm a doctor.
-Look at me.
-Your name?
-Are you okay?
-Santi...
Santi. Easy, Santi,
I'm putting a brace on you.
Are you okay?
Jesús... It's okay, come on.
A plane is coming for you.
Good. Anything hurt?
Breathe normally.
So? How are you?
Fine.
Your family is on their way.
Do you need anything?
No, thank you.
You did it.
We did it.
Commander.
Pilar.
-You did well, very well.
-Thank you.
"None of us will forget this day
that is now inscribed
in our nation's history.
And it's all thanks
to a masterful operation
by security forces
in close collaboration with the media
that's never been seen before
and they've managed to outwit
the abominable orders
of the terrorists..."
The ground is looking at us
The sky is supporting us
We took what we were given
We each used it how we wanted
Look at me from afar
You feel so close
I don't want you near me anymore
I split in half
I learned to come back
Move aside if you don't know how to look
Don't let anyone tell you not to cry
Not to cry
The storm is about to hit
People love when things go wrong for you
They give you Judas' kiss to drink
They'll kill you a thousand times
But you're reborn again
You're reborn again
My love
Maybe no one could show you
That the world has many sides
And by looking at them head on
You can better dodge the bullets
You're greeted as you pass
You can be sure of that
But only a firm gesture
Distant
Poison
Far from this door
Far from this house
Far from this air
The storm is about to hit
People love when things go wrong for you
They give you Judas' kiss to drink
They'll kill you a thousand times
But you're reborn again
You're reborn again
My love