Hey, Krzys!
Let have a drink.
Have a drink and then
fucking dance with our friends.
Wonderful Idea.
No looking around yet.
You don't have to look around.
Hey, wait, don't
look around here, okay?
We're gonna focus on each other.
Tell you what...
You look like that
guy, you gotta...
You need to have
them look at you.
Don't look at them, everyone's
looking at them already.
But they like it.
Before, I just think
we need like a little...
a little preface on...
Just like, um...
I have a lot of friends,
and I was like,
just gotten into, Out of
relationships you really don't
know what to do.
Let's say you don't know what
to do, you mean, you know
exactly what to do.
But it's a bit of like, uh...
Put it this way...
My number one rule...
with women,
is imagine every woman,
when you walk in the room,
every girl has
a boyfriend already.
There's nothing more
that a woman likes than
somebody with
fucking confidence, man.
Forget it.
Just practice now,
we're just practicing.
Just close your eyes,
it's even better that way.
There you go.
You need more of this.
Move it like this.
Just bring it up.
Time is running out.
Stop thinking so much.
I have to! I have to!
-How are you?
-No.
Who are you?
Here?
Your make up, and your dress.
Yeah?
You are someone...
I mean,
some character from the movie,
or just like...
your imagination?
Uh-huh. I check, a little bit.
I don't know exactly...
Always.
-Thank you.
-You're welcome.
Okay?
No need. No need. No problem.
No, I have to go.
I'd like to say bye to my
friend, okay?
Okay.
See you tomorrow.
-Bye.
Oh, wow.
No.
It's like a boxing match,
take a break.
Have some water,
and go back in.
-Next time, next time.
-Okay!