There is an unholy
spell upon this village.
Our foolish greed
has dimmed our past
and darkened our future.
Yet there is nothing
to be done about it.
No one marries now in Piano.
No one falls in love,
or even dares to.
Last night, as he lay dying,
the old man confessed
what he knew
and what he tried to do
to rid us of this curse,
that gypsy spell he wove.
I can bury a man,
but not his sins.
Whoa!
Tyler Hutton's office.
Yes, of course. I'll
tell him immediately.
Tyler?
Hey, Tyler, your dad wants you.
Are you okay?
Well, they finally came in.
The divorce papers, they're
so official looking.
Look.
I'm really sorry, Tyler.
Okay, no, I'm not.
I'm glad, actually.
And you should be, too.
Megan treated you like...
So did you win?
She got the business,
what's left of it.
And she got the car.
The nice one, too.
And she got the cat.
To be honest, I hated that cat.
He's waiting.
Move it.
What do you think
of this hemline?
Go for it.
And this?
Good.
Okay.
Okay, everybody, thank you.
Out.
Out!
Bye.
Sorry, guys.
Sorry.
What happened to you?
Pinched nerve.
Have a seat, Tyler.
I can't fly,
so I've decided to send you.
To Milan.
It's just a quick check
on the new spring lines.
By the way, you look like hell.
Thank you so much.
Handbags and boots.
You won't have to place any orders.
I'll do that.
You leave tomorrow.
Marta has your
travel arrangements.
Questions?
Yeah. You know, you might
want to send somebody
that's a little more up
to speed on handbags.
Look at me, Tyler.
How did a bed and breakfast
look good to you on paper?
Do we have to go
through this again?
I told you I made a mistake.
Why do you have to keep rubbing
it in my face all the time?
Because I don't want you to
forget the smell of failure.
Look, Tyler, I know
I'm partly to blame
for the way things are, but if
your mother hadn't poisoned...
She didn't poison anything.
We might've gotten to
know each other better.
But that ship has sailed.
What matters now is that you're
exactly where you need to be,
learning how to
run this company.
You just have some
catching up to do.
When did I ever say
that I wanted to
run this company?
You had your dreams, Tyler.
And what did they get you?
A messy, expensive divorce,
chapter 11,
and that... that stinking cat.
I didn't even get the cat.
Don't piss this
chance away, son.
You are gonna be
very, very successful.
And when you are,
you're gonna thank me
for kicking your butt
when you needed it.
Just get on that plane
and hit the ground running.
Got it?
Got it.
Bravo.
Gonna do it your way.
What have I got to lose?
You've got everything to lose.
Just a couple of details, Tyler.
First, window or aisle?
You look tired.
Are you sure you
don't wish to rest?
No, let's eat.
Let's talk business.
I like to hit the
ground running.
Driver,
Trattoria Del Vecchio.
And for you, sir?
Uh, what's good here?
May I suggest the
risotto Milanese
or perhaps the veal Milanese?
We'll do both.
Yeah.
Gentlemen, I'm so sorry.
Traffic was an
absolute nightmare.
Scusami, Paolo. Mr. Hudson,
I'm Hugo Galante.
Nice to meet you. Uh, Tyler.
Tyler is fine.
Have a seat.
So, what are we having to drink?
Do you want some...
wine? Red wine? It's killer.
Red wine is perfect, thanks.
-Yeah.
-Absolutely fine, thanks.
You see this thing?
What is that?
You know? It's,
like, where are we?
It keeps making me want
to go to the toilet.
That's weird.
Sorry.
Mm,
I'm sorry, but I'm gonna have
to disagree with you guys.
I think that social media is
great and all that... but...
you really have to think about
the full-page magazine ads.
I mean, glossy things. That...
that's what sets fashion apart.
Yet your father's approach
was quite the opp...
My father.
was quite the opposite.
He was always...
very quick to embrace
new technologies,
and he's done fairly well in
this billion-Euro industry.
Well, my father
isn't here, is he?
He's not around.
Look, I'll look at
your stuff tomorrow.
And if I like what
I see, I'm in.
Does anybody want another round?
-No, no, no.
-Come on.
No, it's my pleasure.
Don't worry about it.
It's not like I'm paying for it.
To the old man. Pops!
Mm, you know what I
really want to see?
I want to see boots
with a purpose.
Yeah. I'm talking
about actual boots.
Riding boots, cowboy boots.
Man, I'm talking
about authentic boots.
That's what I want to see.
It's gotta have life, purpose.
It's gotta mean something.
Am I right?
-Aw, come on, hey?
-Mm-mm.
Whoo.
That tastes like purpose.
Can you believe this guy?
Good night!
Crying out loud.
Hey, man.
Come on.
-Door's deceptively transparent.
-No, you did that.
That wasn't there
when I walked in.
-It was there.
-It wasn't there.
It was...
-Steady, steady.
-Okay, hey.
How much further is it?
It's really easy.
It's just right...
it's right around the
corner, I told you.
So we'll talk some
business tomorrow.
Come pick you up, yeah? Hmm?
Maybe we should just
get him a taxi, eh?
No, no. There's...
we don't need a taxi.
I told you. We don't have to do that.
I'm right here.
I told you it's right...
it's... no, no, no.
No, no, no. You guys are idiots.
It's over there.
-You sure?
-Yeah, no, I'm... I'm...
It's... I'm fine. I'm good.
I'll take it from here.
-Boots! Authentic boots.
-Boots.
He got his dad's looks.
He didn't get the brains.
There, that's him.
Mr. Tyler?
Come with us, please.
No, I'm okay.
I don't need a taxi.
Hey, hey, hey!
-Come on!
-Ow!
Wait! What's going on? Help!
-Hey! Hey! Help!
-Shut up!
You think maybe we should
have gotten him a taxi?
He'll be all right.
Faster!
Shut up or you go in the boot!
-Shut!
-What is it with boots?
Bambo, take A-4.
Do you have any idea who I am?
Ow!
We only know what
we need to know.
That really hurt.
That hurt my face.
And it hurt my neck.
The police!
Bambo, take A-4!
And do not stop for
anything except fuel.
Any possibility of food?
No!
-Bambo?
-Yeah?
Where the hell are we?
You tell me. You got the GPS.
Stupid thing doesn't
work in the rain,
and never in mountains.
Cetto,
what does the map say?
We have a map?
We are lost.
Lost? What do you mean lost?
You... you don't have a plan?
Of course we do.
We got a safe house
to stick you in
until we find out just how
much your old man loves you.
Aldo, do you think we
should be telling him that?
Shut up.
Look, there's someone.
Some old hag.
Pull over.
You stay down. Get down!
Go on, ask about rooms.
Mi scusi, signorina.
We are tired and hungry.
Mostly hungry.
Can you share with
us a place to sleep?
Share what?
A place to sleep.
I share my bed with no man,
and never three.
You fool! Signorina,
a room is all we ask!
A place to lay
our heads, please!
Bambo, let's go.
Let's go!
Get out of here.
Sit up, you.
Look, a village.
Where could we stay?
There.
That place.
It looks empty.
Do you think we could stay here?
We have no choice.
We have no mini bar.
Get our stuff from the
boot and take it up.
And take that idiot, too. Move!
Excuse me?
Um...
Oh, Madonna.
Oh!
Madonna.
Why?
Why you don't work?
Wait. Wait, wait.
Wait! Wait! Wait for me!
You're so beautiful!
Wait for me!
You're so beautiful.
You are the woman of my dreams!
Wait! Hey!
You are so beautiful!
Amore mio. Wait! Wait!
Mama Mia.
Mama Mia!
Hello!
Moo?
Ow!
Who are you? Who are you?
Why do you torment me? Idiota!
Ow! No, please help me!
I'm a prisoner.
I'm an escaped hostage!
Please help me!
Help you? Look
what you have done.
I say, look!
Leave me be.
-What? What?
-Leave me be.
No. Where are you going? Please.
Are you just gonna... just
gonna leave me like this?
Yes.
You can't just
leave me like this!
I'm sorry about your wagon!
Please, come back!
Who are you?
I'm Tyler.
I love you!
Good morning, my
magnificent staff.
Mr. Hutton, may I have a word?
-Morning, Mr. Hutton.
-Yes, you may.
Milan called. Apparently,
Tyler missed his
morning meeting,
and he never checked
in to the hotel
even though his bags are there.
Ah, damn kid. He must have gone
off backpacking or something.
Let's just, um,
give it a day.
Ow! Ow! Ow!
No, please! Please!
Ladies, please!
Where are you going?
Wait.
Wait! Wait!
Please, don't go!
Please! Please!
Sorry.
You are robbing the mayor!
Stop thief!
I will pay for this cow.
Not for all the
treasure in the Vatican!
Get out! Get off my land!
Ow.
Hey!
Oh, it is you! My friend.
What are you talking about?
You guys kidnapped me!
Well, we didn't mean to. Sorry.
You... you hit me.
Yeah, you. One of you did it.
It really hurt.
Uh, I remember.
I feel so ashamed,
now you mention it.
Oh.
Well, good.
I guess we're cool, right?
What are we doing
just standing here?
Actually, I'm trying to
find the woman I love.
I, too! Sort of.
That makes three of us.
Where's the other guy?
Don't ask.
Why we are just standing around?
We need to talk about this,
but not here.
Let's go.
Hey.
You guys wouldn't happen to have
a spare toothbrush, would you?
Some underwear or...
Hey, hey, hey, hey!
I swear upon my family's name,
I never felt like this before.
What could it be?
All I know is,
Don Rossi will want to
see his ransom soon,
or see us dead,
but I cannot leave now.
But if Don Rossi
cannot find us...
I like it.
All in favour?
We stay!
Ahem.
Here we are.
Well,
you again.
Very well.
Sit where you can.
So,
what do you mean, you
are in a travel club?
What is a travel club?
We are like tourists, see?
But we make no plans.
We just, um, pop up.
Yeah.
And do you like our little town?
-Piano?
-We love it.
It's great, and the
wine is awesome.
-What do you call this?
-Fatto in casa.
Only the very best.
Uh, would you
happen to have milk?
Milk?
Cow milk?
-Milk for him.
-Hmm!
Can somebody, anybody,
please tell me,
who is that woman?
Her name is Rosalia Drago.
And, like her name,
she breathes fire.
I heard that, Nonna.
And I hear that you men
are planning to stay.
Why?
We're trying to find some work.
Mm-hmm.
So, what kind of
work you boys do?
I... I like fieldwork,
anything to do with asses.
You know, donkeys, mules.
My name is Pio.
You can work my place, yeah.
But do not say nothing
about my ugly niece.
No, no, no.
Me,
I like hard lobar.
The harder, the better.
My name is Robustelli,
and my son Rocco
can use some help.
Cows.
I mean, cow. Ju... just one.
I will let you clean, sweep,
maybe paint the barn.
But you stay away from my Nuta.
Do you hear?
I'm not really good at anything.
I can wash dishes
for you, if you want.
Wait, as a travel club,
you must obtain permits
to work in this village...
from me, the mayor.
And it will take one month.
One month?
-Maybe two.
-Oh.
Oh, God.
No, no, no.
What do you want?
Impossible.
Work permits are like gold,
and I am just a
simple village mayor.
It could take months,
as I told you.
Of course, of course.
But there are ways
to grease a pan, no?
Show me this grease.
Mama Mia.
Be careful!
You should be more careful.
Forgive me, Fedelia.
-Oh, I see you.
-Ooh.
Ooh, little puss.
I love furry things.
Do you, Aldo?
I, Aldo Lupo,
love everything you love.
Baby.
And when you finish with this,
mop the floor.
Cetto,
take care of Nuta.
See that she gets water.
Hey,
she trusts you.
That's good, Cetto.
Tomorrow, you'll milk her.
Me?
Mr. Hutton, you're
in awfully early.
I never left.
I got a call last
night as I was leaving.
Tyler's been kidnapped.
Kidnapped? Are you serious?
I need to send money.
They say they're gonna kill him.
I can't believe this.
The sheer stupidity.
Look out!
Look out below!
Whoo!
Well, good night, then.
Ciao.
Ciao, Tyler.
Wait, Tyler?
I wanted to say something.
Um,
I want to say thank you.
Thank you?
-Can I say something?
-Of course.
I have been in love with you
since the instant
that I saw you.
I know that we're working
together, and, uh,
I know nobody knows what
the future really holds,
-but I do know...
-Give me your hand.
Yeah.
Time for you to go home.
Okay. Okay, okay.
Can I ask you guys something?
What?
How much am I worth?
What do you mean?
Ransom-wise.
Like, how much does this...
Don guy want? A million?
Half a million Euros.
Don Rossi, you know, is
a very reasonable man.
Shut up, cow-boy!
You know nothing.
Besides, we all want
to stay here, right?
So why are we even
talking of ransom?
You're right.
It doesn't matter.
Nonna,
what do you make of that...
odd American?
The one called Tyler?
Oh.
The poor stupid boy.
He's under a spell.
I'm sure of it. I can
feel it when he passes.
So?
I mean, some say that
love can be like that, no?
Stupid?
Rose,
a spell is nothing to fool with.
How would you ever know
if his love is true?
More than anything,
you must protect your heart.
Okay, so, um, we got
off on the wrong foot.
Where is he going?
The cantina, I guess.
He's upset about Rosalia.
We had better watch him.
He might try to do
something stupid.
It could ruin everything.
Hello?
Oh! Oh, my gosh.
Sorry.
It's a little dark in here.
I didn't see you.
I'm saving my light bulbs.
Oh, yeah. That's a good idea.
You're looking for my Rosalia?
She has no time for you.
Did she say that?
She's gone for firewood.
Each day she must find wood.
I tell her to leave
this sad place, but no.
She does everything for me.
We have little money, yet
she stays here in Piano for me.
Look, she's my Rosali.
Hmm.
I wish there was something
I could do to help you.
And I for you.
Excuse me.
The mayor.
Signora Corvo!
Your list.
Yes.
Hmm. Medicine?
-That is all?
-It is all we can afford.
Signora, I do not have all day.
Ah, these hands.
You see why I need my medicine?
Very well. I'm off.
Hey, wait. Wait!
Where are you going?
To the city, the big city.
What can I get for you?
Uh, actually, could...
could I come, too?
I'd like to pick up some, uh,
supplies and things.
How... how big is this...
um, this city?
Big! The selections
are unlimited.
Let's go!
Well, this is it.
My big date.
Sorry!
Rocco,
do you believe in spells?
My friends and I, you know,
we think perhaps
we are under one.
Could it be?
And if it could,
could it be that,
well...
without this spell,
without sarbolai,
you and me
would not be partners?
Oh.
Well,
that's for you to decide, Bambo.
Each man must know...
his own heart.
Oh.
Aldo!
Ah, there you are.
Yes.
You sound funny.
You catch a cold?
Si.
But, uh, no problems, right?
-Pronto.
-Perfetto.
I'll let you know when he's
ready to make the drop.
Si.
Okay, sit tight then. Ciao.
Ciao.
-Ciao.
-Funny.
Usually, I cannot
get that moron Aldo
to shut his mouth.
Something's wrong here.
Get the coordinates
of that phone call.
I want my money.
Hi there. Sorry I'm late.
I went into the city and,
well, that's why I wasn't here.
I got some presents.
I got this excellent
scrubbing pad.
I use it at home...
when I'm at home.
Um, I got, well, this
is a little something
that I got for your nonna.
Kinda lame, but...
who doesn't need light bulbs?
I thought they were...
Are you mad at me?
Well, that kinda sums it all up.
I'm just gonna
take my things and, um,
I'm gonna go then.
So, good night.
Ciao.
I'll, um...
What rhymes with 'romantic'?
You are writing another poem?
Yeah, for Rocco.
'Gigantic'?
Yeah.
Yeah, I can make that work.
Bambo, olive oil.
Perfetto.
Where were you?
Just some, uh,
travel club shopping.
Here,
catch.
Huh.
Cologne!
And some hand cream for Cetto.
What's with him?
Cetto, hand cream.
Just gonna leave it right there.
Hey,
you know what?
Maybe I, Aldo Lupo,
was wrong about you.
I suspected you might leave.
Rosalia's not going anywhere.
Why would I?
That's good.
Shh.
My love, Fedelia!
# Banyo #
'Banya.'
Banyo, that's what I said.
No, banyo, it's, uh, toilet.
Yeah, I know.
I thought we were
singing about a toilet.
# Banyo #
No.
I just heard the big news!
Your package has come!
I am going now to see it!
Tell Tyler!
Wait, Mr. Mayor, wait!
Wait for me!
Wait for me! Hold on!
What package is this?
Huh?
Oh.
That guy.
I can never really understand
what he's talking about.
What have you done with my boys?
Okay, okay.
Talk to me then.
Who do you work for?
Rosalia.
A woman?
Si.
Well, you can tell her
that I will mount
an army against her.
-Si.
-We have your coordinates,
and it's only a matter of
time before I find you.
And when I do,
I will hurt you both!
You and Rosalia! Capisci?
I do not play games!
So, even though
cultivation of lavender
would be new here in the valley,
it's being done elsewhere,
and there is money to be had.
Everybody likes flowers, Papa.
Hmm.
Ah.
A partnership?
So this is why you two
are so inseparable.
My brother and I once,
we were like this.
Living together,
farming together,
until...
until he tried to
steal my lady friend.
That betrayer. That devil!
God help me, because
I still dream
of choking the life
out of that snake
with these bare hands!
Papa!
It's okay,
it's okay.
And there will be
no lady friends
to come between us.
That I promise.
Hello?
Mr. Hutton,
sorry to disturb you
at such an early hour,
but I believe you have
been waiting for this call.
Yes, I have. It's about time.
Where's my son?
With my men, and perfectly safe.
Let us talk about this money.
What's there to talk about?
I sent it just like
I was supposed to.
What do you mean, you sent it?
My son's email had very
detailed instructions,
and I followed
them to the letter.
What email? Where
did you send it?
-I don't know.
-Because I do not have it.
Some place in Italy.
It's on my computer.
Either you're lying
or we have both been duped.
Hey, there.
We are closed now. It's Monday.
I'm not really
here to do dishes.
Why are you here then?
Did you get my package?
Money.
You brought me money?
Your father, he sounds
so very successful.
Yeah, whatever, he is.
He's got a lot of money.
You... you...
I don't know,
you deserve the life of a queen.
Something is wrong with my life?
Well, no. No, no.
No. No,
It's not that. It's just...
Yes. Yeah, something is
wrong with your life.
It's too difficult here.
Your nonna, she can
barely afford medicine.
I mean, look, this
place is beautiful.
It's magical, but, come on.
Is that gonna be enough?
You've really, really, really
got to think about your future.
Think about all the cool
places you could go,
all the things you
could see and do with...
with me.
How much?
How much what?
Money. If you're
asking to buy me,
I want to know what I'm worth.
No, you're taking
this the wrong way.
I don't mean it like that.
No, Tyler,
it is very clear.
You're attracted to me, yes,
and probably under a spell,
but that doesn't mean you
can chain me to your money.
That's not true!
I'll tell you the truth.
You, Tyler,
cannot afford me.
I have never yet
met a man who could.
The church has your money.
So,
you were abducted?
Kidnapped.
And they brought you here?
By mistake.
I understand.
But if you're not being held,
why not leave?
I would.
I should, but...
I can't.
No.
It is because you are condemned.
-What? I'm...
-Condemned to love, Tyler.
You're under a spell.
A spell?
Believe as you like,
it makes no difference.
Um...
The spell has you.
-Come on, Father. I...
-The spell has you.
Okay. Um,
wow.
Okay, well, why don't
we say that you're right
and that I'm under a spell.
Um, can you, um...
can you do one of your...
exorcisms or something?
My son, an exorcism
can only cast out evil.
As for your money,
Rosalia does not want it.
She does not need it.
She asked me to
give it to the poor.
They are the poor.
Everybody here is poor.
Take it.
Do what you must.
But do not fool your heart.
Love cannot be bought.
Money cannot break a spell.
Rosalia!
Rosalia, come on!
I'm sorry, all right?
I'm sorry about the money.
I'm not trying got buy you!
I'm just...
it's a symbol.
Look, look, look. The
money doesn't even matter.
I just want to show you
how much I care about
you, that's all!
This is all just a stupid
misunderstanding. That's it!
If you come downstairs, we...
we can talk about it.
Nuta.
For God's sakes.
It's just a cow.
Nuta.
Oh, Nuta.
No.
No, it's more than that.
What's going on?
Behold your Mayor!
Behold this cow!
Behold the beginnings
of a new day
in the greatest
village on Earth!
Piano!
You are drunk, you old fool.
-What's the purpose?
-The purpose, my friends,
will soon be abundantly clear!
Cetto, come here!
Ah, Cetto!
As you know, citizens,
Piano has suffered its
share of disappointment.
-Get to the point.
-Eh, the point.
The point is...
I am rich!
And when I am rich,
Piano is rich!
And when Piano is rich,
she celebrates!
Let us celebrate
the greatest festival
the world shall ever know!
The festival of Sarbolai!
Sarbolai!
And now for you, sir.
Adieu, Nuta.
My Fedelia,
I would like to
tell you something,
something that has
been bothering me.
-I am not in a travel club.
-No?
No,
I am in another club.
It's name is famiglia Rossi.
You are Mafioso.
I was,
until I met you.
So, you do bad things.
Like I say, not now.
Not since I met you.
You changed me.
Aldo, dear,
you know I cannot love a man
who does bad things.
Oh, please.
I'm sorry.
Do not mention
this to Uncle Pio.
I will pray about it.
Thank you! Thank
you, my friends!
That's my boy!
Have you seen Rosalia?
We saw her leave.
Where did she go?
All we know is what she said.
Which was?
'We know nothing
about festivals.'
She took her big wagon.
She did not say where to or why.
Thank you.
Whoa! Ho!
Can I talk to you?
Can I please talk to you?
Rosalia, can I talk to you?
Hey. Hello.
As you can see, I am busy.
My horses are thirsty.
Um, can I pretty
please talk to you?
Talk!
Why talk?
I know what you did.
I understand everything.
You tried to buy me...
like a cow.
A cow!
Yes, yes.
But that was only for a minute,
and I realize that
was wrong, and I...
You know nothing
about women, do you?
Or about love,
do you?
Obviously not.
You did a nice thing for Cetto
and the people of Piano,
and I would forgive
you if I could,
but I cannot.
Besides, you're crazy,
and you're under a spell.
Go away, Tyler.
I'm not crazy!
And I'm not under a spell!
Those mountains up there,
once, they were covered
with cedar trees.
In my time, we
called them sarbolai.
We loved them,
but not enough.
We cut them down.
The very last tree
was used to repair your cottage,
and it was then that
our misfortunes began.
In this life, we
make many mistakes.
That's for sure.
Definitely made a few of those.
But I don't think me
being here was a mistake.
You know, part of me wants
to stay here forever,
and the other half just wants
to leave, never come back.
There is but one answer.
You must break the spell
and find a way to win the love
of she who drives you mad.
Wait for a sign, foolish boy.
A single kiss will tell
you all you need to know.
How much farther is this?
How long you figure, Salvatore?
Uh, we are very close.
Aldo!
Come here.
Me?
-Aldo!
-You, you, you!
Aldo!
Come on!
Fedelia, come on!
Jump in!
Yeah!
And now,
Bambo! Ha, ha!
Hey, Bambo!
Bambo!
-He's my son!
-Thank you.
Rosalia, Rosalia, Rosalia!
Rosalia!
Let's go, boys!
See ya... later!
See ya!
All my dreams come true.
Come on, Rosalia! Pick someone!
Me, me, me.
Send me a love that is true.
An ass?
This is what the gods send
me when I make a wish?
They are so cruel with love.
Make way.
-Make way for the ass.
-Come on!
-Hello.
-You again!
Oh, were you expecting
someone else?
I thought I told you to go away!
Then why are you here?
You hit like a girl.
What's the matter?
Can't you keep up?
It's like I'm under a spell.
How about a kiss?
In your dreams.
-Come on!
-You are insane!
Whoa!
Whoo!
You're not bad for a goat.
Oh! Arrivederci!
-Whoa!
-Ha!
Whoo!
-Woo hoo!
-Hey!
He is an ass!
Really?
Well?
You.
You broke the spell.
What... what in the name of...
All right, all right, all right.
Someone explain to
me this madness.
Father,
it's me, Tyler. Remember?
The condemned one?
I brought a few friends,
and we came here to be married.
Are you drunk?
Yes!
-Rosalia?
-Yes, Padre?
Did you break the spell?
Yes, Padre.
-Very well.
-So do we, Padre,
want to get married.
Padre,
my partner and I,
we deserve nothing less.
Wait. What about us?
Are you all mad?
Padre. It comes from above.
A wedding here tonight?
You mean for who?
My boy here?
Yes!
Why not? He's my son!
-Bravo!
-And that's my son.
And I am here...
for one reason.
Actually, two.
Money and revenge.
And I came for my son.
So whatever it is you're doing,
you can stop it now.
Tyler, what are you doing?
I'm, uh, getting married.
Uh, Dad, this is Rosalia.
I have not time for this.
Where is my money?
Okay, I hate to break
it to you, Mafia man,
but your money's gone.
Seriously?
Tyler,
have you lost your mind?
Mm-hmm.
Yup.
Completely lost my mind.
It totally ran away.
But now it's back,
and it helped me find
something else that I'd lost.
I found my heart.
So I send you on a simple
buying trip, Tyler,
and this is what
you come up with?
Dad, I'm sorry if
I let you down,
but to tell you
the truth, really?
Purses, and totes, and
shoes, and all that stuff,
it doesn't matter
to me, all right?
And boots! Ugh! I hate boots.
All that stuff, it
doesn't matter to me.
It never has. That's
your world, Pop.
I don't care about any of it.
What do you care about then?
You know, you asked
me that before
and I didn't have an answer,
but now I do.
Her.
I care about her.
And you, too, Dad.
Despite everything,
I care about you.
Son,
please,
just come home.
We have business to run.
Yeah. Yeah, I know.
I know, I'd have everything
a guy could ever ask for.
But then I'd just be under
another crazy spell, and...
I'm done with those.
I pick her.
You will give it all up for me?
In a heartbeat.
Then I will marry you,
Tyler Hutton.
Wait a second.
You're both insane.
Nobody move.
I'm taking my men and leaving.
Aldo, Bambo, Cetto.
Andiamo.
-No!
-No.
We are getting married!
We are nice people now.
-What?
-Si.
And we are all in love.
Father?
It comes from above!
Who will give these brides away?
You must stop this.
So,
let the weddings begin!
Bacio, bacio, bacio,
bacio, bacio...
Ah, bacio, bacio!
Bacio, bacio, bacio, bacio...
How you doing? The happy couple!
-Hey.
-I wish you all the best.
-Oh, hey!
-Oh, oh, oh.
-Hey, hey.
-Hey, watch me!
Triple step!
Okay, well...
Aah!
-Hey!
-Okay, okay, okay.
We've had enough, okay?
Father,
Rosalia, Tyler, everybody,
thanks for everything.
It's been quite a night.
-So, good night.
-Bye-bye.
Good night.
I'm not giving up on you two.
We're family now.
Stay in touch.
More vino!
Wait, I lost my hat.
Where are you taking me?
To the car.
Where is my hat?
Nuta!
Where are you?
Why are you here all alone?
I see.
I understand.
Hey.
What is your name?
Yeah.
Want to be my friend, huh?
Hey, we can be
drinking buddies, huh?
Do you like milk?
Hey!
Where...
Where did you say you are going?
Uh, we didn't. We don't know.
We're in the travel
club, remember?
We just pop up.
Will you be all right, Nonna?
I will be fine.
Thank you, boys.
Do not scratch my beloved car.
Oh.
Shoot.
Rossi?
What?
We overslept.
Get up.
Get dressed. I'll
meet you downstairs.
Hello.
Oh, yeah.
Hello, you.
Shall we?
Si?
Hello?
Come in!
Enter.
I said come in!
Ciao, ciao.
Oh, Madonna.
Quiet.
And action!
Hyah! Hup! Hyah!
Viva Italia!