A home we didn't have any porn
and I never noticed any
but of course between the age of 6 and 7,
I started to browse my father's library
where I found a wonderful picture book
about Africa
which was about pictures of people,
many of them in the nude.
It was totally fascinating to me
and I thought it was great.
I memorized the pictures
because the book had to stay in the book shelve.
But I memorized the pictures
and then I went to my room. Sure!
I remembered them
and I got intoxicated with their beauty.
A bit later, when I was 11 or 12,
I saw real porn magazines
and I didn't dare bring them home.
But of course I looked at them with my friends
and we'd jerk each other off.
I asked him how he ended up
in the porn business
and he answered that Disney wouldn't
be happy to hear that
but after doing Disney On Ice for 6 years,
it was time for him to do something new.
So he thought 'Why not porn?'
and he got in touch with John Rutherford,
the president of Colt Studios,
who offered him a contract very quickly.
Even though I'm a political activist,
I don't have a problem with gay porn.
My question always is:
Under what circumstance were these films made?
Did the models decide to do it voluntarily?
Do they do it out of their own free will
and because they have fun doing them?
Then it's porn I can enjoy.
Are you models or are you distributors?
You're ... a fast train.
Sorry!
Do you take part in the movies?
Yeah, ... but ... no longer.
On DVD.
- You sell them? You sell DVDs?
Yeah.
They asked us
if we take part in the movies
and they wanted to take pictures of us.
Of course they were welcome to take pictures.
After all, we're representating our movies.
'An erotic fair -
a house full of cocks!'
That's funny!
I found this job offer on the internet,
so I applied.
I wanted a regular job
and I ended up in Prague.
I definitely don't want to be
a model anymore.
No way.
Great, and now get it up once more!
Wait.
Your next movies is going to be called
Bareback Bowling Bonanza.
It's going to come across like a party
Where are we gonna shoot?
- At a bowling alley.
You're gonna be bowling and partying.
That's gonna be fun.
And of course we'll also shoot at Dan's.
How many scene am I gonna have?
Just one but it's big one.
- At the bowling alley.
And what am I gonna do?
How about if I'd ...
I'd better not say it out loud.
Anyways, I'm not gay.
I don't wanna have my hair cut.
But you look really great
in this magazine.
And on that poster.
I like this one especially well.
Cause I'm the only one on it.
It's more professional than porn.
Yeah, it looks great.
I don't get it.
How many magazines does Dan owe?
Just one.
Every month there's a picture
of a Czech boy.
Or one from Russia, Latvia or Estonia.
Okay, great.
Sorry, Friday.
I'm at the office.
Bye!
Are they any good?
- Yeah, they're fine.
My name is Ruda Prochazka.
I was born on April 22nd, 1985.
I'm 22 years old
and I grew up in a children's home.
I don't wanna talk about my family.
I have a brother and a sister.
Did you ever meet with them again?
- No, they're living at the children's home.
What would you do
if you had a lot of money?
Save it and start an normal life,
without Dan.
You'll lean on the box.
Action!
I'm a big star in the US.
If they gave me more money,
I wouldn't have to work as hard.
I know that I'm a star over there.
Here at least I act like one.
I mean, like a star,
not like someone who's gay!
I wear these fancy clothes
and I show them off on the streets.
And everybody's like 'Wow'!
Dan has the best clothes.
He's got really good taste
the bastard.
I always wore great clothes.
Even the Americans stare at me.
Are you recording this?
I don't wanna work in construction.
I used to be a bricklayer.
But I hate that job.
Take my card. When you see a young guy
at a shoot,
you'll get a commission.
You get 1,000 for a regular-looking boy,
and more,
if he's really good-looking.
If we contract him,
you'll get 5,000 crowns.
75 kilos ...  when I look at you,
I'd say it's more like over 80.
Please stand up and undress yourself.
How long is it when it's hard?
- 7 inches.
Could you give me your phone number?
731...
Tell me when you get a new number.
How about the socks?
- You can keep them on.
I think yours is bigger than 7 inches.
Can you get it hard?
Are you nervous?
Right now?
Please turn around.
I'd like to see your ass.
Do you shave it?
Great.
I'd like to see an erection now.
I'm gonna get you a couple of magazines.
Would you like the film crew to leave
while you get ready?
Just an erection?
Yeah, just an erection.
Don't ejaculate.
I wanna see the ejaculation live.
- Okay, I'll give it a try.
You can sit down.
A magazine with pics?
That would be better.
Please stand up again,
right where you're now!
For smaller projects we pay
5,000 crowns per scene.
The boys get to decide
if they want to do smaller projects.
Would you be interested in that
or are you more into the bigger projects?
Hey, how did it go yesterday?
Pretty badly.
I was so damn tired.
I'm an old hand here
because I've been in the business for 6 years now.
People wanna see new meat,
new contacts.
You get around 90,000 crowns,
expenses included.
90,000 for expenses?
No, it's 90,000 plus the gym,
tanning and hormones.
I've gotta be available all the time.
When they call you,
you've gotta be there in 2 days time.
Australia, Greece or Italy,
if you're not there within 2 days,
you've gotta pay 100,000
for breach of contract.
Just try coming up with 100,000!
You have to sign the contract
before you start shooting,
not afterwards.
When you sign,
you agree to the fines.
But he said I needn't worry about that.
Hi!
- How are you?
Fine. Hello!
I don't know anything about computers.
Young people can find a job
at an office.
But not me.
You need connections.
- I probably wouldn't even like it.
You wouldn't?
- Nope.
I'd like a job at an office.
A friend of mine said he'd help me with that.
Even when I was a child,
we were poor.
Later I understood
that we couldn't afford certain things
that others could.
Other kids could go on trips,
go hiking or skiing.
We couldn't afford to do that.
'Bareback' is very popular right now
so I've gotta do it too.
It's my job,
that's how I earn a living.
So I follow the trend.
I always have their health
at the back of my mind.
After all, I have a family too.
I insist on good hygiene.
Your signature and the money
if you're interested.
If you aren't, no worries.
In the future,
more and more movies will be made,
resulting in falling prices.
But there'll always be some people
who'll do it for less.
These old Greeks don't even know
how to do it right.
If you deep-throat Jyrka,
you'll get an extra 1,000.
There are these injections
which will give you a hard-on.
I never had any problems
getting it up.
I take a Viagra and that's it.
Then I'm in ecstasy
because I'll be hard for hours .
The whole time.
I was dating Dan.
By now I've forgotten it all.
He wasn't a bad person
but he always acted so gay.
I asked him
if he couldn't act more normal.
But his position made him king.
He could tell everybody to fuck off.
I tolerated that
while we were living together.
I like Dan
but he messed around a lot.
I hated that.
So I did what I wanted to do.
I was never unfaithful.
But he cheated on me.
I don't know ...
For how long were you together?
- 3 years.
Not bad, right?
There wasn't anyone I could talk to
about my problems with Dan.
So I kept them to myself.
That's my mom with me and her dog.
My mom ...
She likes living on the countryside.
She doesn't like living in a city.
Have you ever talked to Josef about his job?
No, I haven't.
What work?
- In the adult film business.
I have to admit,
we never did.
And I think he'd lie.
He would be afraid to tell me about it.
I don't even know
if he still does it.
And I don't know either
how I'd react.
Probably nothing would happen.
He's my son
but I still don't like what he does.
Let's be honest,
I don't like what he does.
But we always forgive our children,
no matter what.
He said he was buying groceries.
That shouldn't be a problem.
You've gotta find a job and an apartment
and you have to buy
all the stuff you need.
It's getting colder.
- Yes, it's cold.
I don't like getting up in the morning.
I don't want to work either.
It's hard.
You never have enough time.
But that's life.
But you can't change that.
When I was your age, I already had had you.
You were born
and life changed.
It changed a lot.
Sure, it was easier for us
than it is for you now.
My name is Petr Sokub.
I'm from Jablonec nad Niosou.
I'm 27 years old
and I've been in Prague for 10 years now.
I sell my body
in order to be able to survive.
I appeared in 14 porn movies.
It felt good.
I'm an exhibitionist
so I liked it.
I have several jobs.
I drive a cab,
I'm an employee at a company
and I'm a porn model.
I started driving a cab
because I wanted to buy a car.
The monthly installments are pretty high.
I'm an employee because I like the job
and because I did that before.
But nowadays I don't work there that often.
Okay, now pull the t-shirt up.
Show us just one nipple.
Okay.
Now you rub your hand over it
and spread the stuff.
Now go for it!
One more.
And Filip.
That's my fishing jacket.
I had been drinking a lot.
And there was this big dog.
Right into my face.
Oh, fuck!
One tooth here and one tooth there.
Fuck!
- Fortunately it's not that bad.
Big as a pony.
Idiot.
Dan stayed in Prague.
It's pretty.
I don't know where he got it from.
He prefers pines.
- Firs are prettier.
I don't know where he got it from.
I don't wanna constrain my son
or force him into anything,
like his father does.
He should decide himself
what makes him happy.
And when he's found it,
hopefully he'll come to me
and we can talk about it
without me having to ask a lot of questions.
I once managed to do that
but I don't know how it went.
We were at some spa town.
They know I used to work
in the adult industry.
But not a lot of people know that.
We don't really care.
How do you feel about it, Lenka?
About what he did?
I couldn't do it.
And I think,
if he were to start with that again,
I definitely couldn't accept it.
I don't know.
Surely not.
I think, I'd have a problem with it.
You wouldn't,
if we went on a trip to Egypt afterwards.
No, I'd rather earn my own money
instead of ...
Instead of what?
It's just a job. A regular job.
Lots of people don't get that.
They don't get the business.
For the people in the business
it's just a job.
A normal job.
I think, I'd have a problem with it.
Maybe if you took me along
so that I could watch.
Why not?
I wouldn't mind watching.
I'd like to be a super-star,
like Jim Carrey.
We'd better hide the girls.
All of them.
So, what is it all about?
First of all, it's about satisfying your sexual needs
and if you've been alone for a long time
then that's what you have. Well ...
It's also because it's fun.
If you don't have a steady partner
and if you've been in
a monogamous relationship for a long time
then you try out something new
and actually, it's a lot of fun.
I was with my first boy-friend for 17 years.
After he died,
cause you hear a lot about it in pubs and bars,
I thought to myself,
they're all fine with it, why don't you?
So I gave it a try.
Well ... at first I thought it was great.
Getting to see new people, something new.
Getting to know them was great at first.
But still, I'd always rather have my old love back.
Simple as that.
Money, my friend.
If you have money,
you don't need to dream.
You're calm, you don't worry.
You buy whatever you need.
But do you know the feeling
of not having any?
Your fridge is empty,
you're hungry.
And you ask God:
Why am I so unlucky?
I don't have anything to do anymore
with the porn industry.
And I don't want to.
I haven't been in the business
for a year and a half now.
I work as a technican
for a cable TV broadcaster.
I'm a supplier.
That's okay.
That's the result.
- Thanks! Really great!