This story is fiction
based on a true story.
Directed by Yôichi Sai
WHERE IS THE MOON?
Company Precept:
"Think and come up with ideas."
"If you can't think,
work till you sweat."
“If you can't think or work,
piss off. “
- By Yoichi Kaneda.
- No. Seichi.
Listen.
Take your work seriously.
Yes, sir.
- Throw away your pride.
- Yes.
Let your mind go blank.
- Understand?
- Yes.
Hey! Are you new?
I am honoured to join you.
My name is Mitsuru Anbo.
Pleased to meet you.
When does the Defence Force
start its New Year?
- Pardon?
- Like yakuza, you know.
They celebrate it
on 13 December.
I'm afraid I know little
about gangsters.
Hopeless.
No good.
When I won a gold medal
in the bantam class
The guy who I KO'd
died four days later
in the hospital.
That's when I gave up
on becoming a pro.
He tells me in my dreams
I should go for the world.
Then go for the world.
Can you lend me
some money, Chun?
Good morning.
Hachi!
Me not Hachi.
Me Hassan.
- Have you taken my money?
- No.
I counted and counted.
I'm short.
It's unfair of you
to suspect Hassan.
Siding with him, eh?
We shouldn't discriminate
against someone
of a different race.
Japan's becoming
a multiracial country...
Did you read that
in your porn magazine?
Let's go, Kanda.
Idiot.
Shut up!
Give me a cigarette.
Watch your manners.
We're just old classmates today.
The bride and groom!
Give them a warm welcome.
We're young. North-South
isn't our problem, is it?
- Meaning?
- Was your school near Fuji TV?
- The Korean School?
- I often go there for work.
Are you in the industry?
Well... yes.
I suppose I am.
- I go to Asia University.
- I'm impressed!
Banks won't give the nod
in this climate.
Anyway, any profit
goes to the Japanese.
Our People's Finance Group
can't even stand on its own.
They'd sell their school...
and pocket the money.
Our country can't be united
without mutual understanding.
The scent of your hair
turns me on.
You're not asking for sex
by any chance, are you?
You're blunt, aren't you?
Did you think you had a chance?
I don't think
I'm far off target.
Go buy a whore somewhere.
I'll pay.
These gentlemen
played baseball together
in their days at the Tokyo
Korean High School.
Your attention, please.
In this group behind me
there are two bachelors.
That ex-junkman tried
to get into the golf business.
But he's got a good business
selling discount skis.
You don't understand, Sell.
He wanted status, you see.
"The Happiest People Alive"...
More applause, please.
The sky is blue,
our hearts are gay.
Play your accordions.
We are proud of our country
where people live in harmony.
Our great leader Kim II-Sung...
Why only North Korean songs?
It's an order from above.
Why not ask our group leader
to sing a song?
There's no time.
- You won't let him sing?
- It's not that.
We won't accept this.
You're discriminating
against South Korea.
His money dried up
after 18 holes.
He can barely pay the interest.
30 our boss stepped in.
How can Koreans work
with the right-wingers?
It's give-and-take.
Money can bend principles.
When we're in trouble,
Japan's behind us.
I can only borrow
600-700 million on my land.
It's a bargain.
A golf course for 2. 5 billion...
This is your chance
to seize destiny.
Destiny...
The boss will take care
of that guy
and we'll combine your brains
and our power.
What about the money?
Why do you think I'm in finance?
We can't talk on the phone.
Let's sit down.
My conviction is that
the couple makes the family,
the family makes the nation
and the nation creates the age.
Let me sing.
Come on, let him sing.
But, sir...
Do they teach sex
at the North School?
Don't the students demand it?
I want to be a student.
Go back to primary school.
The leader of the Nakaya
South Korean community,
Mr Son Chul-Yu,
will sing for the couple.
A famous South Korean song
'Willow Trees along the River...
Let's enjoy it.
Hello, Tadao.
How's business?
When I ask "How's business?"
you say "It's so-so."
It's so-so.
Good morning.
Good morning, Mama.
Look at this big boy getting
pocket money from his mum.
It's called appreciation,
a Japanese custom.
You Filipinos
wouldn't understand.
Who's that?
Connie. Her Japanese is good
so I hired her to assist me.
But she's such a tart!
Bye.
Sorry, I won again.
I've won more than I want.
Your luck's run out.
Look, I've got the whole lot!
- You plucked my last feather.
- Grow it back.
Can you grow it back?
Hello. Kaneda Taxis.
Oh, it's you.
Where am I, sir?
Mr Anbo, where is the moon?
It's in the east...
or in the west...
or the south...
or maybe the north.
Mr Anbo, just drive
towards the moon.
Good evening.
- Why aren't you up?
- I have a headache.
- Don't use my futon.
- Mine's dirty.
You bastard.
- Doesn't that hurt your eye?
- My head's pounding.
When I dream,
I feel so sad
that I can't move my body.
I don't know why.
Do you, Chun?
Stop complaining
and go to hospital.
You know I've no money.
And it makes no difference
where I am.
- I'm tired of hearing that.
- Chun...
Give me a cigarette.
I like you, Chun.
But I hate Koreans.
I'm tired of that too.
Koreans are cunning,
dirty and uncultured.
You're just like
a Korean yourself.
No way!
I'm pure Japanese.
- Chun...
- What?
Can you lend me some money?
I'm the madam's son.
- How's business?
- It's so-so.
Be quiet!
Sir...
Just between you and me,
this place is a rip-off.
You know, Connie...
my heart is full of sadness.
I want someone...
to heal my heart.
Do you want a drink?
Sol drown my loneliness
in drink again.
By the end of the month?
Well, I'm not sure.
Do they need cash?
I check the tachograph
every day.
It can't be wrong.
Anyone can make a mistake.
I don't make
three mistakes in a row.
Never mind.
I know it's a chance
for a bargain.
Listen, Mr Ono.
Why do tachographs record
time, distance and speed?
For the safety of the drivers.
If they're not
overworked or driving too fast...
If they're not being lazy
or embezzling the takings...
In other words, tachographs
are there to tie us down.
Hey, lend me some money?
Don't, Anbo. You'd be
throwing it down the drain.
I'll repay it straight away.
- Aren't you ashamed?
- Of what?
- Of sponging off a junior.
- Don't talk, you crook.
I work harder than you.
You always cause trouble.
Don't talk, you drain.
I'm not a drain.
Are you picking a fight?
Will you two quarrel outside?
Excuse me, sirs.
Your hair's a mess.
Work hard, all right?
The Korean School spirit, eh?
You know I trust you.
Bye.
Will you at least
work your quota?
200 km a day is nothing
compared to other companies.
Moving 100 million yen
with one phone call
isn't like making 400,000 yen
driving a taxi.
Chun...
A taxi driver
earns from mileage.
Stop whining and do your job.
Run, Hoso,
or you'll be in trouble.
How's this, sir'?
Happy now?
Irene...
When you finish with clients,
you must come back at once.
Translate, Connie.
Irene, pull your socks up.
Use your brains.
You're in Japan,
so adapt to Japanese ways.
Translate.
Follow their system.
Why? I'm a Filipina.
Not a bow-legged Jap.
Lolita...
Don't waste your time chatting.
Make sure you offer drinks.
Japanese men will always
order drinks if you ask.
Japan is a country of gentlemen.
We make our money on drinks.
The more we make,
the more your salary goes up.
Money is everything.
Understand?
Translate, Connie.
I'm not an interpreter, Mama.
Money buys a house back home
and makes your family happy.
Well, Connie?
So don't make a fuss
if a client touches you.
I get paid for singing songs
and pouring drinks
but I don't get paid
for anything else.
Who do you think
made you a manageress?
I don't have to sell my body
like others do.
I came to Japan when I was 15.
I came to Japan when I was 10!
You can't fool me.
Don't you think
you should open the hen?
While you're lecturing us
you're losing customers.
I've gone through everything
you've gone through.
You should look up to me
as a role model.
If you do as I say,
you'll never go wrong.
Translate, Connie.
She made lots of mistakes.
That's how she learned.
I think in Japan people like you
aren't treated fairly.
You're discriminated against.
I think I can understand you
very well.
- Are you coming on to me?
- No, Connie.
I'm a very serious man...
so serious as to be idiotic.
Idiotic?
- Pure.
- Pure?
Pure, eh?
A long time ago,
there was a big war.
People of my country
were enslaved like cattle.
My mother, like you now,
came to Japan to earn
a living for the family.
She crossed the wild seas...
Did she swim?
In a boat.
I don't know how she was
before, but now she's rich.
She's gone through a lot.
My father was killed
by the Japanese Army
and all my brothers died.
How?
From malnutrition.
Only I survived.
My mother worked like a dog.
As for me...
I had to spend my nights
alone at home.
It's embarrassing for a man
of over 30 to say this...
but I'm starving for love.
Good night.
Connie...
What?
Platonic love is lonely,
isn't it?
I only screw men I love.
Be honest with yourself.
Does being honest mean
I have to screw you?
I love you, Connie.
I love you.
I felt your tongue.
Oh, well... why not?
What?
A kiss.
Come off it.
One night, that was all.
- Shit! I forgot something.
- We're already late.
Give me the key.
Welcome home.
I've run you a bath.
What's this?
My stuff.
I'm unpacking it.
Get out!
Go and have a bath,
then we'll talk.
- Talk about what?
- Don't get mad.
- I'll call the police.
- What will you say?
"Do you know him?"
"He's my boss's son."
"Have you lost anything?"
"I have more stuff now."
Stop this nonsense.
Connie...
Why are you doing this?
I need you.
Connie...
I don't need you.
Have a bath while it's hot.
It's my bath!
The pitcher's first ball...
The batter hits it. It's big...
Big...
Connie!
Look, Connie.
It's big...
- Hello.
- Good morning!
God be with me.
Hello.
Yes, that's right.
- Chun's there, isn't he?
- Chun?
Tadao Kanda.
You know, Chun for short.
- Hello.
- It's me.
- Hello, Hoso.
- I always wanted to ask...
Why are you Korean?
Why is your Japanese
better than mine?
Hoso, this isn't
a kids' counselling service.
Pervert.
- Hello.
- Is Chun there?
What?
I don't like Koreans,
but I like you.
- So?
- Lend me some money.
Connie, darling...
Get me Chun.
For you.
- What do you want?
- Don't leave me!
- Are you stupid?
- I told you I like you.
How many times
do I have to tell you?
Hoso...
Don't call me again.
Connie...
The fire's out.
Stop this shit, Hoso!
Tadao?
What are you doing there, Tadao?
- Is Sell in?
- Mr Arai...
- Kang Su...
- Hello.
Chun Nam.
Hey... won't you work for me?
I'll pay you a good salary.
I don't like money-lenders.
We Koreans in Japan...
have to make money
for as long as we're here.
We must all get stronger
and pull together.
Don't lecture me.
Koreans just don't have
a spirit of self-sacrifice.
What I want is to use
the money I make from lending
for the unification of Korea.
The money I make belongs
not to me but to society.
Koreans only think about
themselves and their relatives.
That's the bad side
of capitalism.
To end our people's tragedy
and build a unified nation
I'm prepared to lose
all my money. Believe me!
So says the guy
who got VD from a whore.
"“Oh, my dick hurts..."
You betrayer of the nation.
After the golf course,
I'd like a hotel.
To accommodate 2000 people.
It's good to plan ahead.
That old fool couldn't see
beyond a pinball parlour.
We're a new generation of
Korean businessmen in Japan.
We're the children of capitalism.
Damn unification!
- Mr Arai...
- I'm sorry.
That was a private matter.
When you deal with Mr Konno,
talk to me first, okay?
I know.
I ask for your generous
assistance.
Let's have a meal
with our president again.
We learn so much
from him, you know.
Hey! Wake up.
To Ikebukuro.
Come on, wake up.
Open the door, you bastard.
- I want to fuck her.
- It's not for hire. No.
No...
Go on, get him. Kick him!
I don't like scolding.
It's not my style.
But how can a taxi driver
raise his hand to customers?
Some customers they were.
They're demanding compensation.
They stink, you know.
The authorities will come down
on us if we refuse customers.
You can't drive a taxi
and be scared of the authorities.
Don't you know that drivers
can't argue back?
They provoked me.
Osamu...
If you hit them, you lose.
Endure all the blows,
and you'll win.
They were savages.
Don't be racist.
Say "white native
South Americans".
Savages are savages.
Hello. Kaneda Taxis.
It's Anbo here, sir.
Where am I?
What do you see
around you, Mr Anbo?
I see a golden object
that looks like a turd.
Turn right at the turd
and drive straight.
You can all bloody well...
Good morning.
What's happened?
My wife's run away.
Mr Senba,
I'm taking a few days off.
What are you saying?
- Who is it?
- It's me.
I know Chun's there.
He's mad.
Let me in, Chun.
I'm not here.
- He's not here.
- Liar! I saw him go in.
- The neighbours will be angry.
- He'll give up.
Let me in, Chun!
- Who are you?
- Shut up!
What have you got to do
with my man?
I look after Chun.
- Chun!
- What do you want?
- Are you jealous?
- You're a lunatic.
I came to see Chun.
You get out of my way.
Hello.
Go home, will you?
Are you angry with me, Chun?
I don't like Koreans...
but I like you.
Hoso...
Tell him to go home.
He's not a bad guy.
- Shall I kick you both out?
- Go home!
I slept in Chun's bed.
What are you saying, you idiot?
We're tied together
by a strong friendship.
Don't worry, Connie.
Get out!
What's your name?
You're dark, aren't you?
Mum...
Stop sulking.
You're like a child.
I borrowed this video for you.
I always think of you
more than anyone else.
Whenever you're being sweet,
there's always something...
- Shall we pack the video too?
- Don't be stupid.
I'd gladly send you to the North.
How are my brothers?
Some brother you are!
I think I want to live
in a warm climate.
Could you face your brothers
without shame?
Yes.
You can have fun with Connie.
But if you tell me
you want to marry her
I'll disown you.
No Japanese girls...
no Filipinas...
no Cheju Islanders...
no Southern girls...
Who can I marry, then?
Heaven help me!
Done.
Pack them.
People's Democratic Republic
of Korea
in the light of factors
of an economic nature
or a political nature
or the benefits provided
By the Japanese economy.
But at the moment
many of these conditions
can hardly be improved upon.
And yet we can see
so much hardship.
And in these circumstances
it's very hard to maintain
our faith in religion.
I wonder how people see us.
Two young lovers.
- You'd be the pimp.
- Are you picking a fight?
I have an eye for men.
- I do love you.
- You're so shameless!
I love you.
- How do you know that?
- I'm learning.
What else?
Let's fuck.
You'll be punished one day.
Let's go to hell together.
Get out.
Come on, get out.
Show me your ID and licence.
He broke my tooth!
Quick, the handcuffs!
See how he returned my kindness?
There are plenty
of other Iranians.
I agree, sir.
Out with all rogue foreigners!
- I agree, sir.
- They should go home.
I agree...
Excuse me, sir.
I'm sorry to interrupt,
but the bank rang.
Mr Arai has passed a dud cheque
and gone on the run.
The bloody idiot!
Where's our pay?
I'm going to quit.
For my little angel's sake,
I'll quit driving.
Our president is trying hard
to raise some money.
I won't work until you pay me.
I won't work for nothing.
I'll quit... definitely.
We will pay you.
By the way...
What happened
to our recreation trip?
Haven't we saved for it?
We're hard up now.
We're supposed to have
lots of fun with geisha girls.
That's right. I remember.
Can't we still go,
and make it Tada's farewell?
Sure. Let's go.
Here are the keys
to your cars, sir.
Fine.
305,000 yen received, sir.
Please wait.
How was the spa?
Was it good?
The geisha girls were so old
we got a shock.
The bill shows you had fun.
I wouldn't mind staying
another night.
Now that you've had your fun,
we must help each other
to get through this crisis.
Can we stop for some milk
on the way?
Hey!
Aren't you aware of the state
our company is in?
It's been a good trip,
hasn't it?
We'll be back!
Thanks a lot.
We Koreans
should help each other.
What for?
I'm only your employee.
You're all fired!
Now is the time
for us to work together
across national
and racial borders.
We must look to the future
and work as hard as we can.
Effort in business!
Only effort in business
will save the world.
We're like a family.
Think of me as your real
mother and work harder.
But we're only
humble guest workers.
That's what's wrong
with South-East Asian women.
Filipino, Thai, Malaysian,
Taiwanese, Chinese...
Chinese are the least
trustworthy.
Isn't Korea in South-East Asia?
It's in East Asia!
Oh well, too bad...
Why don't the two of us
pool our efforts tonight?
Mama too can devote herself
to saving the world.
Whether you're on a short date
or an overnight stay
I'll keep shop for you.
Don't you know
how hard I work for you?
Stop it, Mother.
You're an embarrassment
So what?
The reason I have
this place and all
is because I've done
embarrassing things.
I can see that, Mama.
Shut up! You've brought
nothing but trouble.
- Don't blame me.
- It's not her fault, Mother.
Don't you ever sympathise
with your poor mother?
You should be on my side.
Come on, cut it out.
Why shouldn't I rely
on my own son?
You know, I'm going to quit
that rotten company.
I want to become
an independent cab driver.
You got a ticket for speeding
the other day.
You have to have
a clean record for 10 years.
- Have I ever had an accident?
- I'm talking about offences.
I can become independent
any time I like.
And...
I'll bring my mother out
from Niigata. My son, too.
I'll start a new life
with my ex-wife.
- You should quit driving taxis.
- I'll build a house.
I'll get my family together.
My ex-wife's working
at a club in Ginza.
She rang me the other day
and said she wanted
to come back to me.
- Where did she ring you?
- In my apartment.
Will you lend me money, Chun?
Let's go and see her.
- Where's the club?
- Somewhere around here.
Perhaps I got it wrong.
It may be in Tachikawa,
not Ginza.
How can you mix up Gina
They're similar, aren't they?
Hoso...
Slow down.
Don't worry. I can easily
handle 100 or 200 kph.
I know your left eye
is rather weak.
And so is my right ear.
My head is aching badly.
It feels like
it's burning inside.
I'll do it, damn it.
I'll stake my life.
Why should I be knocked down?
I'll knock him down.
Damn it...
Let's go home. We both have
to work tomorrow.
You think I'm telling you
a lie, don't you?
- That's not true.
- Yes. You think I'm lying.
You look down on me.
I don't like that.
Let's cool ourselves down.
I don't like Koreans
looking down on me.
- Let's go home.
- Shut up!
I'm going to see my ex-wife.
She rang me.
You don't have a phone.
She wanted to see me.
She was crying.
She wants our family together.
I understand.
Get out.
I hate Koreans.
Yes.
Thank you very much, sir.
- Any radio message yet?
- They're trying to call him.
Wouldn't it be quicker
to call the police?
Body temperature...
Someone's life is at risk,
you know.
Same here.
He may have been killed.
He's stupid.
He should at least contact us.
He couldn't call us
from the bottom of a dam.
Are you enjoying this?
I'm worried.
- He may be asleep.
- Then someone would see him!
Please don't shout.
What if my angel has a fit?
Weren't you going to quit
for your angel's sake?
I'm here until I find
another job.
You were with him last,
weren't you?
I'll report it to the police.
I can't take responsibility.
Who cares about responsibility
now in this company?
Hello. Kaneda Taxis.
This is Anbo, sir.
Where am I...
Look, Connie.
It's a little far from here...
Make it strong.
But it's a very nice club.
How far is it?
- Shiojiri in Nagano.
- Nagano?
My friend owns it.
I told him about you
and he's very keen.
Eat some, Tadao,
before it dries up.
The manager's young
and energetic.
I left the tuna belly for you.
You can see snow there.
Cut it out.
I don't want to see snow.
Filipinos hate snow.
Are you so keen to separate us?
You don't have to take the job.
Enough is enough. Let's go
to the Philippines, Tadao.
What's this about?
We're going to live together
in the Philippines.
He wouldn't go
and leave me behind.
He said he was sick of you.
There's a Japanese saying,
"Blood is thicker than water."
Isn't it
"Money's thicker than water"?
Don't, Connie.
Tadao, you have to choose.
Me or this old bitch.
You little tart!
Go back to the Philippines.
- Does it hurt?
- I'm not a nut case.
I've got a headache, that's all.
The cops are threatening
to send me to the hospital.
They say I might not come out.
I just wanted to see Mother.
I didn't know she was dead.
It was my fault
that I didn't know
but I wanted to see her,
that's all.
I'm not a lunatic, am I, Chun?
No.
You won't put me
in the hospital, will you?
I couldn't put you
in the hospital.
So don't worry.
I like you,
though I don't like Koreans.
I know.
You'll come to see me again?
Yes. I'll come again.
I'm a poor man. It makes
no difference where I live.
Chun...
Can you lend me some money?
You have some forms to fill in.
Where are you going?
Cigarettes.
In the drawer.
So we still have some...
Here they are.
- I want some beer.
- Shall I go and buy some?
It's in the fridge.
What's that for?
You're really disgusting.
What have I done?
Lies, lies!
Always telling lies.
Have I lied to you?
Your father was killed
by the Japanese
and your brothers died
of malnutrition?
What a story!
There were people like that.
Stop it!
Stop it, Connie.
Don't waste food.
You'll never find a woman
as lovable as me.
You're so modest.
- I wish you'd drop dead!
- Life's hard enough.
Bastard!
Stop it.
Idiot!
- You sex maniac.
- Suck her sagging tits!
After all I've done for you!
- When did you do what?
- I worried so much over you.
- Come to the Philippines.
- No, I won't.
- Don't come, then.
- I said I won't.
Come!
I've had enough of you.
Come to the Philippines!
Hey, I know that character.
It's in the word "ginger".
Is your name pronounced "Ga"?
It's Kang, sir.
- Are you from China?
- I'm Korean.
So, you're a South Korean
immigrant in Japan, right?
I have lots of Korean friends
like you.
They live in a ghetto...
A place where there are
many Korean immigrants.
I can't remember
my friend's name.
- Isn't he Mr Kim?
- Like the one on TV?
I visited him once.
Their apple tasted
like their pickles.
Everything they had
smelt of pickles.
Do you still hate our pickles?
I absolutely love them.
I buy jars of them. I'm fussy
about Korean barbecue.
Their grandmother kept
talking to us in Korean
but my poor friend
couldn't speak the language.
She should speak in Japanese
if she's in Japan.
- Do you think so, too?
- Of course.
You know...
the Korean comfort women issue
is a bit odd, isn't it?
"What's the
“comfort women" issue?
Weren't they prostitutes?
And it was during the war.
It was before we were born.
We don't care, do we?
I was born after the war, too.
But we say
"after the liberation".
I've been following
Korean issues.
That riot in I. was incredible.
They just shoot, don't they?
It's scary, isn't it?
You know what they call
“Korean power“...
I wish I had
some of their power.
Me too.
Maybe I should go to Seoul.
I'd like to come with you.
You could show me around.
Oh... I'm short of money.
Would you mind waiting?
It's just there.
I won't be long.
I'll be back.
Police!
You bastard!
I'll call the police!
I'm sorry. Forgive me.
Don't hit me, Mr Ga!
- Kang is my name.
- I won't do it again, Mr Ga!
I said my name was Kang.
I'm sorry, Mr Kang.
- Pay your fare.
- Yes!
- It was a joke.
- The money!
I really didn't mean it.
Your change of 1390 yen, sir.
Thank you very much, sir.
At the present moment
many of us cannot escape
from our own beliefs.
There are times
when we see the ills
in God's world
and want to change direction...
Connie...
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry I hit you.
Not now.
I want to say this to you
before God.
Can't you be quiet?
I love you, Connie.
Go to hell.
The sunset over Manila Bay
viewed from Rizal Park...
must be very beautiful.
Will you run
a karaoke bar for me?
Then...
we'll build a house...
and live with my family.
Will you live in the Philippines
until you die?
Your lies...
have affected me a bit
this time.
I'm not lying.
I can't take it any more.
I love you, Connie.
I'm sick and tired
of hearing that.
There's nothing we can do.
We can't escape.
They won't kill us
but we'll be their slaves.
But times will change for us.
After all, capitalism
is all about money.
Until then,
imagine you're in the North
and work hard.
What happened
to our Japanese support?
We've been betrayed.
I didn't realise
they were so racist.
I did try hard, though.
You played a dirty trick on me!
Just pretend you're dead.
Why should I clean up your mess?
Let's talk quietly, Mr Kaneda.
Loan Agreement
We must do this...
or we'll both be in deep shit.
1. 5 billion yen
He'll never come out of this.
They're yakuza, aren't they?
Real ones, too.
Guess who's here.
It's Mr Arai, the financial king
of the Korean immigrants.
What are you doing here?
You're needed
to unify our homeland.
You'd better hurry off
in your Mercedes.
Watch your tongue, you loser.
Why don't you wind up
the business?
It's only a tiny taxi company,
no big deal.
Would you mind leaving us alone?
We're talking as ex-classmates.
Please ignore us.
I suggest you act at once.
You're not bound
by Japanese law-.
Shut up, you idiot!
This is none of your business!
Shall we come back another day?
You guys seem to get
easily excited.
Keep well, Tadao.
You too.
Why don't you say
a gentle word or two?
Idiot!
Can't you even tell a lie?
I could shed some tears then.
Damn you.
How's business?
It's so-so.
It's so-so...
Work's been very intense.
Our boss is working
a lot harder.
The trouble is the loan
from the yakuza.
Working flat out,
we can just pay the interest.
Nothing can surprise me now.
What's that for? Why do you
hit an old man like me?
My wheel came off
on the expressway!
You changed it this morning.
No violence, please!
Stop it, Anbo. Who'll pay for
his funeral if you kill him?
- The company can't.
- I'll see to my own affairs.
How will you do that?
That's enough!
He says he'll kill himself.
Hello.
You know...
I wanted to own a golf course.
I had to have it.
You should have been satisfied
with a pinball parlour.
You'd have owned a building
if it had been successful.
I'm sorry.
It was an accident.
For both yakuza and Koreans...
there'll be a lot of work to do.
It's not a big deal.
May I? Thank you.
Another one, please.
A different pose.
Now, now.
There's a good baby...
Fire! Fire!
Bring water!
The hose, quick!
Sell!
Put it out, quick, you bastards!
You fucking...
The fire!
I want a Filipina called Connie.
Found her at last!
I caught a bad disease
from that rotten woman.
I'm coming for her now.
Tell her to wait for me
right there.
You bastard!
I hope you rot in hell.
What a coincidence!
Where are you going?
Want a ride?
So it was you, eh?
- I've missed you, Connie.
- You make me sick.
Connie...
I'm the only one
who can understand you.
Listen, Connie.
Once there was a big war.
I've had enough
of your bloody stories.
- Where to, Miss?
- Manila, the Philippines.
Thank you for riding with us.
I'm your driver. My name...
is Ga.
Gorô Kishitani as Chun
Ruby Moreno as Connie
Moeko Ezawa as the Mother
Original story: Yan So Gil
Music: Masahide Sakuma
Director. Yôichi Sal
Subtitles: Chiaki Ajioka, Richie
Buenaventura, Kenneth Kang, Andrew McCormick
Subtitles © SBS Australia 1995