This is the story
of the girl who saved me.
♪ There's this thin crack
in my coffee cup
♪ that's never seen by light
♪ It fans in all directions
Like a scar from lightning's bite
♪ I can't shake off
the shadows
♪ But I cling hard
to the light
♪ I was looking for a reason
Why my heart itches to fight
♪ But it set on my mantle
♪ Carves away my mind
♪ My bravery is compromised
♪ Fear has made me blind
♪ Sit easy, tiger
♪ You'll get it
next time around
♪ Your silver bones
♪ You'll give 'em
back to the ground
♪ Those easy winters
never get written down
♪ I was born in fever
Little fisted little rage
♪ I've walked through a
thunderhead To reach a fragile age
♪ Coughed up all my memories
till they crumpled up like shade
♪ They beg to be a part of me
And beg to have a name
♪ They ate at all my marrow
♪ Carved away my mind
♪ My bravery is compromised
♪ Fear has made me blind
♪ Sit easy, tiger
♪ You'll get it
next time around
♪ Your silver bones
♪ You'll give 'em
back to the ground
♪ Those easy winters
never get written down
♪ It's decimation
It breaks us inside and out
♪ Breaks us inside and out
Hey, Tits,
wanna come over,
help me with some homework?
♪ Paper bags for lungs
♪ A broken kick drum
for a heart
♪ I seem full of life
♪ But mother nature
takes her toll
♪ She'll take what she wants
♪ And in a way
she'll lead you home
♪ She hid it on my mantle
Loser.
♪ She carved away my mind
♪ And all my fears
were compromised
♪ I left them all behind
♪ Sit easy,
tiger You'll get it next time around
♪ It's decimation It breaks us inside
and out Breaks us inside and out
Were you
hiding from us?
Heard you
called me a bitch.
- I didn't.
- What a weirdo.
- Ugly fat freak!
- Rip her shirt.
Who do you think you are?
You're such a loser.
Who the fuck are you, bitch?
I'm the girl with the knife.
Who the fuck are you?
Change it.
Don't let them
do that to you, okay?
They're assholes.
Say it.
Okay.
Okay what?
Okay, they are.
They're what?
Assholes.
Good.
Now get the fuck away from me
before some rent-a-cop
busts me or some bullshit.
So where do you go to school?
Do you live around here?
Did you get that
from Hot Topic?
My dad won't let me go there.
He says it's too intense.
Fine.
Come buy me a taco.
Okay, you got your tour.
Get out of here.
Leave.
Your parents home?
Yeah.
Not till 6:30.
Cool.
You want to hang out, right?
So let's hang out.
Jesus.
It's like Whole Foods
threw up in here.
Cool. I gotta go.
My stepmom has some money.
You want to see my room?
Wow.
You really like to
cut shit out
and tape it together, huh?
Let's go.
Hey, you got a flashlight?
- My stepbrother has one.
- Go get it.
Go on.
- I don't want...
- Fucking get it!
Hey, I'm sorry
I yelled at you.
Elly?
"Brendan's Dojo."
Who's Brendan?
Stepbrother.
It's like the fucking
Death Star in here.
Hentai porn.
Brendan's a freak.
Wait.
Oy. Two dollars.
You're not supposed to
touch his stuff.
Don't!
Don't?
"Karate master eighteen."
Jesus Christ,
so much karate bullshit.
Are these pictures of you?
He made me.
Get in here.
Get the fuck in here!
Come on.
Do it.
Hit it! Fuck him!
Say, "Fuck him!"
Harder, come on.
Fuck him!
Come on, harder!
You think I'm gonna waste
my hard-earned money on rent?
Fuck that.
My house is free so long
as you follow the rules.
Rules?
Can't live without rules.
Who makes the rules?
I do.
Camp only with
people you know.
All kinds of shit can happen
when you're sleeping.
Like what?
We live in
a transactional reality.
Everyone is either buying,
selling or stealing.
Information
is fucking currency.
So you don't give
anyone anything
that they can use to hurt you.
Also, stay the fuck away
from anyone
who says they love you
after like a day.
Nobody loves anyone.
Next, don't fuck with people
and they won't fuck with you.
And if you do fuck with people,
you're gonna run into them
again, so...
Actually, the rule should be
don't fuck with people.
Unless you're sure that you
can beat the shit out of them.
Is that it?
No.
Stay out of my shit.
Come on.
Yo, Daphne.
Yeah, I wasn't
expecting company.
You don't even know
who you talking to.
Magic trick.
Dude, that's a five.
Hey, you can't be here.
Dude, you can fuck off,
it's fine.
Dude, I'm serious.
No panhandling in front of my restaurant.
- I'm...
- Get going.
Come on, get going.
- We're leaving.
- Thank you.
Grab the cup.
- Sharing is caring, thank you.
Fucker.
You're in my spot.
- Sorry love, early bird...
- Gets their drug-dealing ass out of my fucking spot.
Hold up, I know you.
It's that chick I told you about
that pulled a knife on me.
You invaded my alley while I was
sleeping you crusty, fucking wannabe.
I was looking for my shit you
stole outside the Coffee Bean.
- Duct-taped in the garbage can.
- It was my inventory.
Which you took while
I was getting busted.
- That's a bitch-ass...
- If it wasn't me it would have been someone else.
The way I see it, sounds like
he paid his rent.
You can have your spot
back tomorrow.
Hey, fuck you, man.
- Deal?
- Fuck it.
Hey, 5-O, 5-O.
I apologize, you mean,
mean ladies.
Fuck you.
Zip up your sweater.
- What? Why?
- Just do it.
Okay.
Got any applications?
No.
I'm not getting picked up
for kidnapping.
You're 16.
- I'm 13.
- Out here you're 16.
- And we're getting rid of Elly.
- But my mom's middle name was...
Close your eyes.
Smelly Elly does not even pass
the playground test.
What the hell
were your parents thinking?
It's better than Tits.
Yeah, well.
Anything is better than Tits.
No appointments till 3:00,
bitch.
This was the second-worst
day of my life.
I was just ranging in Echo Park
and I'm cleaning up.
Thanks.
I've got a week's worth of cash in my cup.
And like, there's this girl,
who cries for me on a bench.
She had this '80s sweatpants.
And those, like,
green plastic glasses.
I'm like, is she a hipster
or is she mentally retarded?
And this cholo comes up to me,
jacks my bank, breaks my nose.
I spent the rest of my night
bleeding my face off
under a giant mural
of Johnny Depp.
- Wake up.
- Hey.
What is that thing, anyway?
Give it back.
What the fuck are you saying?
It's...
I'm homeless, I have time.
It's gonna be for something.
Stop.
What was the worst?
- What?
- You said Echo Park was the second-worst day.
What was the worst?
That's a risk I'm willing to take
'cause I love my customers.
Here you go,
best dollar Pop-Tart
this side of Mar Vista.
Drive your shit bucket
back to the valley, Rob.
Fuck you talking about, Tracy?
She's a classic.
You owe me a dollar for that.
You want one?
I got blueberry frosted,
confetti cupcake.
- Limited edition cinnamon roll.
- Fuck off.
I told you we don't split up.
You didn't tell me that.
You don't need to be so harsh.
- Just helping the kid out.
- I promise he wasn't doing anything.
Shut up, sit down over there
and take the chips.
She looked hungry,
gave her a Pop-Tart.
What a fucking monster.
Jesus.
Hey.
I even got a flavor
you might like.
- How much?
- 40 each.
Twenty or I tell them you tried
to solicit my sister.
Twenty-five
and we're friends again.
- Deal?
- I'm not your friend.
Stay away from him.
- That's a rule.
- Okay, jeez.
There's these things
called tiny houses.
They're really cheap.
And we have the money
from my stepmom already.
We can save it up, right?
We could have a place
and like, be a family.
Except better.
See, there's our garden.
There's like a forest around it
so nobody would bother us.
It's Vancouver.
Where my mom is from.
It's only 50 dollars
to get there on the bus.
Angie, I got you.
Can't we just get food
like normal people?
Normal people pay 20 bucks for a bag
of popcorn and some gummy bears.
Eat.
- I'm gonna be sick.
- Come on.
It's like a treasure hunt.
It's not funny, it's disgusting.
Fine.
If my life's so gross then...
Just go back home, then.
- Wait...
- No, go back home to your fucking brother.
Stepbrother.
Shit.
Go get a corn dog or something.
No, that's for our bus tickets.
It's for us.
Yo, Crystal.
Got a present for you.
- How you doing?
- Sup, Jenga?
I don't know them.
They're cool.
I'll be back.
I like your stuff.
It's art.
Look, I just want you to know
I love my wife.
Okay.
Um, do we...
- You taking good care of my baby brother?
- What the hell?
Aren't you gonna introduce
yourself to the nice man?
Go on.
He doesn't bite.
I'm Rusty.
- Uh... Kevin.
- Isn't he just the cutest thing, Kevin?
So... What do we...
It's 30 bucks, you just
show him what to do.
Fuck. Right...
I'll wait for you
across the street.
- Should I...
- Bless you.
Do you want me to watch?
No.
Wow, okay. I...
So, this one time Rusty did
this thing and it was really hot.
- Do you wanna hear?
- Uh...
I'll take that as a yes, okay.
So, it's winter and
we're living in Minnesota.
And Rusty decides he wants to
do an outdoor
performance.
And he climbs up on top
of the garage.
And our neighbor, this dirty little
old man is totally peeping on Rusty
like, totally violating his
personal playtime space, you know.
Yeah.
Anyhow, so Rusty strips down
to his underwear
and then jumps off the garage
and disappears.
Like, he fell off
the face of the Earth.
I mean, this is bear country.
Little naked Rusty could've
eaten by a big bear.
Like Cujo, or whatever they are.
Getting close, Kev?
- Ah.
- No rush.
So, our neighbor sees Rusty
just waist-deep in a snowbank.
He puts his little hands above
his head and he goes, "Ta-da!"
Well, the sight of Rusty
there just made him laugh.
He actually couldn't stop.
I mean, he really, he really couldn't stop.
So he had a stroke and he died but...
He died laughing, Kevin.
Laughing
in the snow.
Ah!
Thank you.
You're hilarious.
Well, you obviously had no idea
what the fuck you were doing.
- I'm Tracy.
- Rusty.
There's a sprinkler
by the boardwalk.
Yeah.
It's not like
we're like, dating.
You know,
it's more than that.
Yeah, it always is.
I mean he's got to
stay behind in Oxnard
until school gets out,
but I don't even feel like we're apart.
- I think I like Ashley.
- We knew, like the first time.
- He was in the choir room.
- Kinky.
- Yeah, I know. I don't even like the choir.
- Sofia.
But then my fucking mom, she picked
up the phone while we were talking.
- and she started asking all these questions.
- Ariel.
- Do you like Ariel, Tracy?
- We both got really scared.
Both of use kind of freaked the fuck out.
So, he gave me some money,
he told me to come out here and
that he'd come and meet me.
- How long have you been waiting?
- Only like, a month.
So Rusty, has Tracy given
you a street name yet?
- I'm getting one.
- A street name?
Yeah, maybe we'll
let you help us.
Okay. Uh...
Name of your first pet and
the street you grew up on?
- That's porn star name.
- Pickles Washington?
That's... that's awful.
- I like it.
- Um, what's your favorite cartoon?
Winnie the Pooh.
Please, not Pooh.
I think...
Eeyore.
Nice. Eeyore.
I like it. Eeyore.
Let's grab our shit.
Let's go home.
Can we bring him?
Do you wanna come?
Yeah.
♪ If disappointment
was like a drug
♪ I've overdosed again
♪ I can't take the razor-sharp
edge Off your crooked grin
♪ I lost the war, I lost it all
And I can't get it back again
♪ I can't set you right
when you go into a spin
♪ All I can do is survey
the wreckage from here
I've got a thing.
Bring me lunch in an hour.
Asshole manager starts his shift at 2:00.
So, don't be late.
You're babysitting.
Nobody eats if you fuck it up.
So, don't fuck it up.
- You wanna go?
- I guess so.
Hey, kid. You must
pay before you microwave.
- What?
- Pay first.
It's $4.17.
I'm counting. Jesus.
Dammit, I see that.
- What, I'm...
- You little thiefs.
- I see you. Get out of my store.
- I'll put them back.
- They take it out of my paycheck. Get out.
- I'm sorry.
- You and your friend don't come back.
Shit.
Why'd you do that?
Sorry.
What are we supposed
to do now?
Hey, don't worry about it.
That guy is a dick
to everyone.
Thanks.
This is Germ. Hey, no begging.
You're friends
with the mean lady, right?
I'm Squid.
I'm Eeyore,
that's my street name.
- Yeah.
- I'm Rusty.
He's Rusty.
- My real name.
- Where you from?
- Oxnard.
- I hear Oxnard sucks.
Yeah.
Here's your change.
Thank you.
Get the hell out of here.
This isn't a hotel. Get out.
This is a place of business.
I'm calling the cops.
- A little faster, please.
- Yeah, I'm fucking... I'm going.
Eeyore! You guys fucked up.
You were supposed to come
get me.
Rusty got in trouble with
the counter guy.
You stole like a half a pound
of gummy.
You guys just lost us our camp.
I'm sorry.
I don't care.
- You guys can sleep in our spot.
- Okay.
Fuck that.
- But we know them.
- Not really.
- It's a pretty dope spot.
- It's only for one night.
Well, come on.
I am the machete!
I am the protector
of the innocent.
I am the stains of the wicked.
Evening, lady.
Little sister's making coffee.
Chill.
Don't spill it.
Where you going?
So, there would be flowers
all around here.
And, I know what kinds
of flowers grow here,
so that would be my job.
I mean, if you'll want then
you all could come with us.
What would my job be?
You'd make the art on the walls.
You could paint skulls
and stuff.
That say like, "beware" and
"keep out".
- Ah. Cool.
- What's Tracy's job?
She'll keep the house clean.
Hey, guys.
- How's it going?
- Hey, Rick.
Oh, um... Anyway.
- Hungry?
- Nah, we're good.
We don't need your Jesus
cheese man.
I volunteer at an organization
called Safe Streets.
We don't give a fuck,
just go off, man.
- We're open 24 hours a day.
- Hey, get away.
- Get away...
- Grab a watermelon martini, man.
Yeah, get the hell away from us.
If you need any jobs,
we can help with...
Get the fuck outta here, Rick.
It's just temporary.
Don't fuck with me and
I won't fuck with you.
And the Earth shall drown
as it brings forth this bounty.
It's a long way...
All right. I know a place.
Unless you wanna curl up
with the machete.
Aye! Everything hurts.
I am Machete.
Jesus! We know!
You stole my dog!
And my radio...
Swing and a miss.
Hey!
Let's go, Germ.
Come on.
Okay, now just how I did it.
Grab it, get a running start
and jump.
There we go.
Oh! Congratulations,
you just learned how to hop a train.
- A train?
- A train.
People still do that.
People still do a lot of things.
We can catch one
and go wherever.
I'm waiting for someone.
Besides, isn't that dangerous?
Waiting for someone
who's never going to show up?
Yeah, it's fuckin' treacherous.
What about this one?
Drew that in Flagstaff.
Dad had a missionary complex.
Drew lots of demons
just to piss him off.
Uh, and this one?
For-profit foster home.
Parents kept the checks
from the state.
I don't even think
they knew my name.
What are y'all doing?
None of your business.
Took you long enough.
Get to work.
♪ What I got, they ain't got
♪ I got something
I got a lot
♪ What I lost on
a broken sphere
♪ I'll find in a tender mirror
♪ A lot of love from the heart
♪ I'm not in love
♪ With a stranger anymore
♪ I slipped out of the spell
you can go to hell
♪ If that's what
you're headed for
♪ Unintelligible cries
♪ Of an animal in the night
♪ Mean more to my ear
than the noise I hear
♪ You trying to get it right
♪ That's fine, you know.
♪ I'm so happy that you're gone
♪ All the bells ring out
we can sing and shout
♪ And drink and carry on
♪ In the love from the heart
You think I should
call my dad?
Think he'll believe you?
It doesn't matter.
I believe you.
They won't do it for us.
- Portland, really?
- I really wanna go there, dude.
Yeah, it'd be cool.
She's a little kid.
What are you doing
having her out here?
You taking money from her?
I started when I was like...
Six.
I could have a place
to stay tonight
but I don't get down
like that.
So, I didn't know what to do.
I saw you guys talking.
- Did he say anything about me?
- Critter?
Yeah, he said you're 13.
You're just mad because he likes
me more than he likes you.
Do you ever think
you could kill him?
I mean, Brendan.
For what he did.
Will you do some fucking work here?
I'm doing it all myself.
I work! I make a lot of
money for us.
Everything ok, ladies?
- I'm 16.
- You look about my daughter's age.
I'm guessing seventh grade?
We're homeschooled.
This your sister?
Jesus! Angie,
stop being so spacey.
- Our mom says we need to broaden our horizons.
- We go to school at home.
We're supposed to write this essay
on how poor people use laundromats
- more than rich people.
- Right?
- Mom would've come, but she's sick.
- She has AIDS.
- And the flu.
- Uh-huh.
This happens all the time.
If you want to see it,
our certificate's in my bag right there.
Sure.
Hey, hold on.
You can't do that.
- I have rights.
- This is yours? Calm down!
I am calm. You ever
hear of the Constitution?
This bag... You need a warrant to
even touch my... Yeah, okay, great.
It's stuck.
Get down.
- Who's Angie?
- Get back.
You called me Angie.
Who is that?
She was my sister.
Be quiet.
- Is she at home?
- Shh.
- Is she dead?
- Do you want him to take you home?
- Don't you miss her?
- No.
I don't.
Shit.
I got to pee.
Think it's okay?
Go back there.
All done.
Cool.
Let's go.
How long is this gonna take?
I'm fucking jonesing.
- Can I just...
- I said no.
But I'm the lookout.
He's paying me $6.
- Critter.
- It's fine.
You don't want her to be the lookout,
you be the lookout.
- Wait. So, I'm not the lookout?
- Not anymore.
- I got to be something.
- Fine, you're assistant.
- How much does the assistant get?
- $6.
Yes. I'm the assistant.
You're lookout.
- Come on, man. That's twice what I paid last...
- I understand that.
And I like you.
Don't use, you're
a good customer.
But it's so dry right now It's
like Georgia O'Keeffe at 85.
You know what I'm saying?
Oh man, this guy doesn't know
who Georgia O'Keeffe is.
Hey, you need to go down to
the Getty sometime, papi.
Read a book.
Juan Carlo,
you're really not gonna take this cash?
- I need another $150.
- I don't have another $150.
- Then I can't help you.
- Boss.
Critter. Just get halves,
let's go.
Hey, who the fuck
is this? Tell your lady,
- outside. Not cool, papi.
- Yeah, I'm not his lady.
Hey, back the fuck off!
Okay, Okay, Okay. I thought
I recognized that voice.
She's a friend.
We go way back.
Hi, Rob.
- Hi, Eeyore.
- Hey, put it down.
- But he's so cute.
- They are cute, aren't they, sweetheart?
All right, Critter.
Do whatever the fuck you want
with your gangster friends here
but me and Eeyore are leaving.
Come on.
Rob is paying me
to babysit the kittens.
Hired her for the hour.
Look, Juan Carlo,
I've been A-one since day one.
Let me buy this shit
on credit, man.
You know I'm good
for it.
You know what?
You're right.
Your girlfriend's
a crazy bitch.
But you're a good customer.
Dan, give him the shit.
- Juan Carlo.
- Yeah.
- Can I play devil's advocate here for a second?
- Anytime.
I don't know this kid.
But, this one,
I've known her a while.
Look, none of these people have anything to do...
- Excuse me!
Excuse me!
She's gonna take what you
entrusted to her friend here.
She's gonna put it
up her arm and float away
where you can't find her.
But I'm not
an unreasonable person.
So, I propose
a compromise.
We retain our babysitter until this
one makes good on his promise.
Just for a few days.
He's good for it.
Motherfucker! You're such
a piece of shit.
Get the fuck away from her.
- Fuck you!
- There she goes, what did I say?
Get the fuck out of here,
take that crazy bitch with you.
I see your fucking face again,
kill you in shower like Psycho.
- Hey, like Scarface.
- Ah, even better.
Look at him,
he has no idea what I'm talking about.
Fucking millennials. Go!
Hey, give me your phone.
I got to call my friend.
Hey, not out here.
Meet me in the garage.
See you in a second.
Hey, I've only got forty, so
- can you spot me the...
- Shut the fuck up.
Let's go.
I don't want your fucking money.
That's it.
Oh, fuck!
Yeah, you like that.
Fuck!
Come on, you fucking slut!
Get the fuck out.
Guys.
Squid, Critter, I lost it.
- Fuckin' sleep.
- Lost what?
My picture, the money,
my phone,
- it's all gone.
- Listen, I think Tracy might...
I think it must
have fell over at the laundromat.
I looked.
I went through everything.
I already messed up
with the kit...
- I'm so mad. I can't tell her.
- Listen, calm down.
We're gonna find the money.
How? It's lost. I can't.
I can fix it.
I'm gonna fix it.
Watch her.
So, uh, how far is your house?
Uh, you want to tell me
why you left?
My stepmother's a bitch.
What? It's true.
I'm sorry,
the word doesn't fit your face.
Well, she is.
Not much of a reason to leave.
Her kid, Brendan, he's 17.
He uh...
Did stuff to me.
Well, I hope he's home,
so I can kick his ass.
♪ I thought
I'd heard it all before
What's your name?
♪ My heart is so heavy
and sore
- Hey, Sadie, leave that lady alone. Come over here.
- Bye.
Come on.
♪ Song birds are storming out
on me, I'm denied
♪ Nobody round
but us pigeons and crows
♪ Pigeons and crows
♪ Sleep through the empty sky
♪ Nobody knows
I leave no trace
♪ On the empty sky ♪
Shit, Brendan.
Oh, my God, Elly.
We have been so worried.
Where have you been?
Who is this?
I said, who are you?
He's my friend.
He's not your friend, Elly, do you hear me?
He's not your friend.
- Did you take her?
- He didn't take me.
Do you know
how old Elly is? Hmm?
She's 13 years old.
You have taken a child,
- and put her in danger...
- He didn't.
- I swear to God, if you hurt her...
Look, I don't know
who you are,
or what you think you're doing,
but you're not doing it
with my daughter.
I'm not your daughter.
Okay, Elly,
that's enough.
You are staying here,
and this boy is leaving. Now!
I'm calling the police.
She wants to leave.
She's not gonna stay here with
you and your fucking kid, so...
- Don't...
- Yes. Hello.
- I'd like to report a...
- You want to know why she ran away?
It's cause your fucking kid,
Brian, or Brandon or whatever
the fuck his name is,
was raping her.
You knew, didn't you?
Um, no, I'm sorry.
You're lying.
Look, I know that you have
brainwashed her into thinking
- that what you are, and whatever you do...
- He didn't.
- ...is more exciting than living here...
- I'm not lying.
...and going to school,
but it is my job to protect her.
Okay. Then call her dad.
Tell him what happened.
Tell him she's okay.
You're protecting
yourself.
Let's go.
Elly, I...
So we're in Reno, huh,
my dad's trailer, right.
My dad is so fucking drunk,
he can't even get a bead and
then all of a sudden...
Blasts a hole through the side
of the trailer.
Fucking tears apart the
cardboard Christmas fireplace,
and I pick up a beer and I smash
him right in the side of the head,
and we're out!
And he's screaming,
"Get back here, you cocksucker!
I'm gonna fucking kill you!"
And Scabius shits his pants.
The end!
No, no, no, man.
So I'm sitting here,
drinking with ass scratch,
right, and he says to me,
"You can't take that shit
sitting down," right.
So we get this thing
of gasoline,
throw it all over the fucking car,
over the roof, the hood and everything,
and his guy hands
me a Molotov,
lights that shit, and just
like the movies,
I chuck that son-of-a-bitch up,
"Aah! Boom!"
flames of destruction, everywhere.
That was an anarchist piece
of fucking art, man!
It was beautiful. I've been in LA
looking for your ass a month now.
You and me,
we're gonna have some fun, huh?
Maybe go back out to Reno,
fuck shit up a little bit.
- You're gonna fucking leave...
- Aah! I'd never leave you, bro.
What's up? I'm Scabius.
I know you.
You know, you should
draw more shit like this.
Like more demons and skulls
and fucking hard shit.
I mean, you should try
to appeal to more,
like an adult audience,
you know.
Like, you should draw, like,
only, like, real shit.
None of this cartoon shit,
you know.
You should stay on your side
of the street.
Okay.
Whatever, fuckhead.
- Get your sketchbook?
- Yes.
Come on, Germ,
I'll walk you.
We don't have to go to Portland,
you know. We can go wherever.
There's trains up to Vancouver.
Then you can find the house.
Can't you guys just wait
till she comes back?
Why is that so hard?
- Listen, Eeyore, Tracy's not...
- Just come with us.
Germ needs a babysitter.
I'm not leaving Tracy.
You're stronger than you think.
Hey, take care of her.
That's what I do.
♪ You're standing there
cause the springtime has come
♪ We'll throw down our shovels
♪ And we'll go on the run
♪ Hallelujah, I'm a bum
♪ Hallelujah, bum again
♪ Hallelujah,
give us a hand out To revive us again
Look at 'em, man!
Starbucks in the cubicle,
and fucking back again.
These fuckers, any one of them
could just hop up on that empty curb
and be home in five fucking minutes,
safe and dry, not like us revolutionaries,
though, right, Eeyore?
We don't care if we get wet!
It's futile, man!
Fucking futile!
Destroy your fear and embrace
the chaos!
The rules won't save you!
What the fuck are you doing,
Eeyore?
- I was just...
- That's not cool.
- I was just trying...
- Eeyore.
You're a fucking little kid.
Fuck you, I am not.
Eeyore.
It's okay. I've done it before.
♪ Nobody's got the time
to hear your troubles through
♪ You best go back to
where you came
♪ You best go back
to where you came
♪ You better want to catch
your train
♪ You better go and catch
your train ♪
Shit got all over
my hands, man.
That'd be fucking crazy.
It burns right through
the latex...
I am never settling!
Right!
- Get out of here.
- Fuck you!
Fuck you! Fuck you! Fuck you!
All in God's name!
This is my spot!
Get your fucking spot,
old man!
Whoa!
Yeah!
Critter.
Critter, do something!
Scabius!
You're fucking going
to kill him!
I'm sorry,
I'm sorry.
Get the fuck
out of here!
I said, go fuck!
Fucking stay out!
I'm sorry, man.
I'm sorry.
Whoa, give me another one.
Come on, come on,
one more!
Yo, creature,
got an inspiration, man.
How about we hitch back to Reno,
take Eeyore with us,
see what kind of throwing arm
she's got,
light one for the revolution.
Whoo. Bullseye.
Reno, man, we're gonna fucking kill it!
Reno!
- Man, fuck Reno.
- What?
Is that the only shit
you've ever done?
Blow up a car in fucking Reno?
You're always talking
about that shit.
Yeah, man,
cause it was anarchy, man!
Man, fuck anarchy!
Fine.
Yo, come on,
us fighters got to stick together, man.
For the paradise,
for the proletariat...
Goddamn, grow the fuck up, man,
all of that is bullshit.
And get your fucking hand
off of Eeyore, man.
Yo, where are you going, man?
Yo, Critter!
Come on, man, what the fuck?
Hey.
- Does it hurt?
- Fuck off.
- I can make you feel better...
- Get off of me!
If you weren't hanging on
everybody all the time,
I wouldn't have so many fucking problems,
you fucking poser!
- I'm not a poser.
- All you gotta do is go home.
And Mommy's gonna give you
a fat, sloppy hug
- and say, "Oh, we were so fucking scared..."
- My mom died.
Yeah, big fucking deal!
My dad tried to kill me.
And street girl saved you, huh?
Saw an opportunity, decided to turn
you into a little fucking Orphan Annie
- moneymaker, huh?
- She did not.
Took all your cash while
you were sleeping
- and put it in her arm.
- Fuck you, you don't even know know.
Yeah, but Critter does.
He told me.
You're a liar.
You know I'm not.
Nobody wants you here,
all right?
- Just go home and watch your fucking TV.
- I can't.
- I...
- Get the fuck out of here.
Go!
You want me to fuck you up?
Beat it, you fucking twerp!
Jesus fucking Christ!
Eeyore!
Elly!
Eeyore! Hey!
- What do you want?
- Hey.
- Get back.
- Stop, stop.
- Okay, stop, stop.
- Fuck you!
- Okay, stop yelling.
- What, so you can lie to me again?
- No.
I took the money.
I'm not gonna...
I'm not gonna lie.
Here. Here. Okay?
Look at what I have.
You take this. Take it, okay?
We're gonna go there together.
Just like you wanted.
- You said you were my friend.
- I am.
You're not anybody's friend.
You don't know how.
- You left.
- I came back.
So you could leave me again,
like you leave everybody.
- Like you left Angie.
- Shut up. Shut up!
You left her.
You left your sister.
Shut the fuck up!
You left her!
After whatever happened
to you,
you said you wouldn't
leave her, right?
Just like you told me.
You're a liar.
You're right.
I am a liar.
I'm not a good friend.
I was using you.
This is a fucking picture
from a magazine, Elly!
It's not real.
- I don't fucking like you!
- Sorry. I'm sorry.
I'm not coming back.
I'm not lying this time.
Wait.
Please don't go. Don't leave me.
Tracy!
Tracy, I'm sorry.
You know, you need dope,
I could get it for you.
I don't have to like all
of my customers, you know.
I'll even spot you some.
Yeah?
Yeah.
Come on.
Take me with you.
Juan Carlo doesn't
exactly love you.
You're gonna make me
wait longer?
Come on.
They're gonna be up there.
For real.
You want me to end up
with nothing again?
Yeah, fine.
I'll be an hour.
He's cool, right?
Yeah. He's cool.
Scabius, huh?
Like the parasite?
♪ Well, my belly's just aching
♪ For a couple strips of bacon
♪ Hunk of pork
And a little pot of brew
♪ What can I do? ♪
Hey, Tracy. Tracy?
Hey, I got some Oxy.
Tide you over a little bit.
You want me to crush it up?
I'll use your knife.
I'll do it.
What if you decide
not to share with me?
I don't know you.
I don't know you either.
And I'm the one
sharing my hard-earned drugs.
Come on. I'll give it back.
I promise.
God.
What?
I'll just go all the
way upstairs,
get my fucking grinder
and do it myself.
Hey.
See?
Ladies first.
Ha ha. You like that shit, huh?-
Whoo.
Uh.
I'm sorry about the...
The parasite joke.
Ah. We all feed off
of each other.
You know, me...
Off all of this...
And you off of Critter.
I get it.
You know, if you ask me,
you're getting the good end
of the deal.
Maybe.
Yeah.
It really rubs me the wrong way
when people use my friends.
All right.
Fuck this.
Yeah. Fuck this, right?
Where the fuck
do you think you're going, huh?
You're the fucking
parasite. You know that?
You keep scaring everyone away, you bitch!
Yeah. Never fucking come back.
Please don't. Don't!
Just like him.
I'm just like him.
- I'm fucking better than him.
- Stop!
Every day that I work,
I get a gram and Taco Bell.
I get my own room.
And you don't talk to me
when I'm not working.
What is this shit for now, like,
some webcam shit?
Don't give me a stupid name.
Got yourself a deal, butterfly.
Your office.
You want a Pop-Tart?
Wait till you see what I found.
We are gonna make thousands.
Get that thing off me.
- Hit me up.
- Shut up.
Hit yourself.
So, quick rehearsal.
You found her diary.
You know her secrets.
Fuck this!
Fine. We go handheld.
I can't.
Oh, come on. Really?
You wanna be here, right?
She wants to be here.
Old enough to know
what you want? Hmm?
- Yeah.
- She's old enough.
So, I don't see
what the problem is.
I've got snacks,
there's a nice hot shower, TV.
You can even use the pool.
Not with her.
- We have a verbal agreement.
- I know. I'm sorry.
We have a deal!
I didn't force you
to come here, Tracy.
Down there in Santa Monica,
when I found you,
I've never seen you like that.
So, I offered to help,
to keep you safe, protect you.
Who do this
to your face, hmm?
It could have been anyone.
It's brutal out there.
Is that what you want?
You walk out that door,
this is what you're gonna get.
Stay here with me,
I'll keep you taken care of.
- This is bullshit.
- This is a gift.
I'm giving you a fucking gift!
If it's not you,
it'll be someone else.
I understand you're nervous.
It's easy.
Now it's a rehearsal, then just do
the same thing over and over again.
You can do that.
Right?
It's okay, Tracy.
Uh-uh. After.
Fine.
See? We can always make a deal.
- Run!
- I'm not leaving without you!
Fucking run!
Tracy, what the fuck
are you doing?
- I'm waking him up.
- Hold on.
God, you're such a fucking
wussy. Come on. Get up.
- Get up.
- Tracy, he's my friend.
Your friend kicked Eeyore
out on the street.
I didn't fucking kick her out.
- Where'd she go then?
- I don't fucking know.
She was about to start turning tricks
out there, you fuck, because of you...
- You brought her here.
- Come on.
So what?
You really think
you're taking care of her?
You're a fucking junkie.
Right.
You're all just fucking better
human beings than me, huh?
But just so you fucking know,
your friend there
threw me up against that wall
and raped me
while you were off
on your last score.
- That's bullshit.
- What you did to me,
that's bullshit? Huh?
That's bullshit?
Yeah.
You wanna look at me
and tell me that?
Come on. Look at me. Look at me.
Come on. Fuck you! Look at me.
Look at me, you little bitch!
Didn't you tell me how you
take care of everyone?"
'Cause I don't see you
saying shit.
Would you go into his bag,
get me my knife?
No?
Well, you fucking deserved it.
Tracy.
Tracy!
- Stop it.
- I hate you!
Stop!
Before Brendan...
Before my mom died...
And before everything...
She would bring me up here
and teach me the names
of the flowers.
I can't take care of you.
I know.
You have to tell your dad.
He won't believe me.
He will.
I can't.
Okay. Trust me.
Your dad loves you.
You said nobody loves anyone.
Dad?
This is the story of the girl
who saved me.