I'm in a supermarket, you know,
and I look at the checkout girl,
or maybe I'm on the bus
and it's the bus driver...
or my family...
my daughter even,
but I'm looking at them and I...
I just know what they
all look like dead.
No, it's more than that. I...
I know what they'll
look like dying...
having their throats cut.
I can't sleep.
Um, I just have...
when I start thinking about
everything that happened,
uh, I start to sweat profusely.
I just feel like shit,
I mean, whenever anything
or any situation's overwhelming...
just everything, I mean.
What's your experience of...
fighting alongside women
in the battlefield?
They don't belong there.
A 7,000-foot mountain...
we gotta get to the top of it.
I gotta hump my ass up there
with a 100lb pack on my back.
You think they can do that shit?
Do you think they can go
92 days without a shower?
Are you familiar with
a fucking period?
- Hey.
- Hi.
Captain White for
Dr. Andrews, please.
Thank you.
Andrews.
Well, he's not returning my calls.
No.
You've seen her file.
What she went through is extreme.
Hey, Mom.
Yeah... no, I'm coming for sure.
Is she coming straight
home after school?
Okay, well, I'm not gonna
be able to get away
for another half-hour, maybe
more, so that should be perfect.
I'm excited too.
Love you too.
We're in session.
You're needed in Intake right away.
Well, it looks like we're
gonna have to cut this short.
I'm gonna go home
today and see Lauren.
Wow, I...
how long has it been?
Mm,
182 days.
I thought we were gonna
wait another month.
I think I'm ready.
How does your family feel about
what you're experiencing?
Are you in contact with them?
What the fuck?
Jesus Christ.
- You okay?
- Yes, ma'am.
What about you? Are you okay?
I asked you a question, Sergeant.
I'm good...
ma'am.
- You want to keep trying the call box?
- Yes, ma'am.
Do you guys have the main
number for this building?
- You got a phone, soldier?
- Yes, ma'am.
Try it. Call any number.
See if it works.
It says I got three bars,
but it won't connect.
I don't fucking believe this.
You guys hear that?
- What the fuck?
- Maybe it's a fire.
Come on.
How are you doing there, Captain?
Anything you need me to do, ma'am?
Let's get these doors open.
We can see how far up we are.
Maybe we're on a floor.
Can't see any doors, ma'am.
Oldsman, you could fucking help.
You'd better not let go of that.
No, sir. No way.
He's right, there's nothing doing.
There's no doors in sight.
It's an express.
There she goes.
It's a long way down too.
Come on.
Hello.
Can you take your hand
off the alarm, please?
- Thank you.
- This is Catherine White.
Diego, Private First-Class.
And Sergeant Bradley Oldsman.
We've been stuck in here
five minutes and no answer.
We've got a lot going on, ma'am.
- What? What happened?
- We don't exactly know yet.
What do you mean you don't know?
How long is this gonna
take, for Christ's sake?
Calm down, please, ma'am.
We're gonna get you out,
but we've got systems down
and we don't know what's
going on outside.
We'll get back to you as
soon as we know more.
Who am I speaking to?
Lieutenant Blau,
ma'am, AMC Liaison.
Hey hey, come back here!
Hey, I want to speak to
your commanding officer.
Now!
Hello?
What, you want to be
stuck in here all day?
What do you think's
happening, ma'am?
She said systems were
down. It's not the power.
Maybe there was an earthquake.
Here?
Jesus Christ.
What?
Listen.
I don't hear anything. What is it?
That was the Power
of Rap, 102.2 F.M.
Radio stations are down.
I can't believe it.
What?
It finally happens and I'm
stuck in a fucking elevator...
with you.
You.
Captain.
- What's the update?
- There's gonna be a short delay
before we can get you out, ma'am.
Why? What's going on? Why are
the phones down, the radios?
I don't have that
information right now.
As soon as I do, I will
pass it on, ma'am.
You need to remain calm.
We're doing everything we can.
This is unacceptable.
Who is in charge?
We'll contact you shortly.
Blau...
shit.
All I could think about was Lauren.
Her dad died before she was
even born and I'm all she has.
I think the only reason I
survived being tortured
was to get back to her.
And then I got back to her and
then I endangered her life.
There was just a night where
I ended up waking up,
standing in the middle...
of the street
with cars passing, and
holding her and screaming.
And I woke up while I was
holding her and screaming
and I didn't know how I got there.
You hear that?
You mean the game?
Turn that off.
Hey, I said turn it off.
I said, fucking turn it off.
Listen.
Hello.
What's going on out there?
We're still trying to locate
the maintenance team, Captain.
No, what is going on outside?
We hear people panicked,
people shouting.
Available personnel must assemble
at the calling point
in parking lot C.
We are soldiers, for Christ's
sake. We can handle it.
Please, ma'am, you
need to be patient.
No, you need to tell
us what's going on.
What gives you the right
to keep it from us?
Yes, ma'am, you'll be out of there
soon. We haven't forgotten you.
We're doing our best.
What?
She knows more than she's
telling us. Did you hear all that?
They'll figure it out.
They'll get us out of here.
Do you know something
that we don't, Sergeant?
This had to happen.
It's always "when," not "if."
it seems that "when" is now.
What are you talking about?
This.
Them out there.
Who?
Well...
Thanks for the insight.
I think texts are working.
Come on. Come on.
Come on.
Everything okay, ma'am?
Stop breathing like that.
Ma'am.
Stop it!
- Stop fucking breathing!
- Sir.
Don't you fucking touch me.
I respectfully request
that you calm down.
You need to see this.
The breaking news here
is that a series of explosions
have hit Washington, DC.
I'm here on the ground and this is
still a dangerous situation here.
No one knows if any more
bombs are going to go off.
I'm speaking to you on a sat phone
because some kind of
electromagnetic pulse explosion
has taken out our camera feed
along with other electronic
systems in a five-mile radius.
I can see in the distance right
now several plumes of smoke.
Those are located, as you
can see in this footage,
right near the Capitol Building.
Homeland Security is saying
the real threat here
is not those bombs but another one
that went off a few miles from here
in Brooklines, Maryland.
They're saying that bomb contained
radioactive material...
a so-called dirty bomb...
and the radiation cloud is
heading right this way.
So we're going to have to
move out at any moment.
Civilians are evacuating
and heavy traffic is already building
on routes out of the city...
Let's talk a bit about
everything that happened.
Are there some specific incidents
that trouble you more than others?
Uh, a few of the sergeants...
staff sergeant
was in the front... the front...
the first Humvee.
And we were in the second...
me and my best buddy Pete.
It gets hit with an RPG, just bam!
And it... it tips over.
And evidently there might have been,
like, an IED in the road as well.
And the shrapnel shot up and...
and what I think
happened is that it...
it hit the staff sergeant
and just took him out.
I was the next one in
line, so I got out.
A bunch of us got out... Pete.
And we decided to try
to get the survivors,
if there were any survivors, out.
And as we got up there,
they started shooting.
And pretty much they were all...
they were shooting from afar.
Answer, God damn it.
Yes, ma'am, we hear you.
Captain, can you please calm...?
Do not tell me to calm down.
We know what's going on out
there. You are gonna tell us
how you're getting us out of here
and when. You understand me?
Captain, we've been informed
that a series of bombs
have hit the city.
And we have reason to believe
that one of them is a dirty bomb.
Now we're waiting for an
update on wind direction
and projected path of
the radiation cloud.
But the city is being evacuated.
Ma'am, we really need
to get out of here.
I know, but we've not
been able to locate
the maintenance team responsible
for the elevators yet.
But we are still trying.
Where the hell are they?
We don't know, but I will
continue to try to locate them,
and then we can get
you out, Captain.
Okay, come back to us
as soon as you can.
You need to get out
of here too, right?
My room mate Pete...
he won't understand
what's going on.
He had a piece of
shrapnel from an IED.
You know, about like yea big.
You taking care of him?
He ain't got no family,
so I've been...
I've been looking after him,
you know, since we got back.
It'll be okay. We'll get them safe.
Whoa, Distinguished Service Cross.
You should be proud, soldier.
It's nothing.
- Hey, you need to get a message out?
- That's okay.
Come on, maybe someone
can go get him.
Calm down, Sergeant.
Hey, anyone there?
Yes, ma'am.
Captain, the building
is being evacuated.
- What do you mean?
- The wind, ma'am. It's...
it's blowing the
radiation this way.
What... what about the maintenance
engineers? Where are they?
They left the building
some time ago.
They're civilians.
Captain, I... I'm afraid we've
been told to move out as well.
You're leaving us here?
We have no choice, ma'am.
Wait, there's gotta be
something you can do.
And I have orders for
you from AMC, ma'am.
Stay where you are.
A rescue squad from J-corps
will come and get you
as soon as they can.
How long?
We don't know for sure, Captain.
But if the wind keeps blowing,
it could be safe in 48 hours.
- We'll be dead by then.
- No, ma'am.
No.
Listen, um...
do you have children?
- Captain?
- I said, do you have children?
Oh, Jesus Christ.
You wouldn't understand.
You don't have any.
Yes, ma'am.
My daughter... she's missing.
She's six years old.
I need to get out of
here and get her safe.
I'm sorry, ma'am, but there's
really nothing I can do.
If you give me her
name, maybe I can...
Lauren White, 674 Westbrook
Drive, Annapolis.
And there's a wounded vet that needs
help to be evacuated. Come on.
Pete Laker, 9920 Millchurch
Avenue, apartment C.
I'm sorry.
Listen, if you can't get to them,
you fucking get us out of here
so we can do something
about it, okay? Anything.
Ma'am, there's got to
be some other way.
Hold on.
Come on. Come on.
Okay, I found a
maintenance handbook.
Okay, all right.
Just give me a minute, ma'am.
She was right about one thing.
We won't be dead
when they get here.
Really? Why not?
It takes weeks to die of radiation.
Fuck you.
- What are you doing?
- Conserving power
so we can contact the rescue team.
Don't you want to get out of here?
I'm a soldier.
I follow orders.
All right, come on.
Captain, I have something here.
Okay, what?
I've been through the manual.
There's one way maybe
you could get out.
What? What do we do?
How do we do it?
Ma'am, if you can get onto the roof
of the elevator, there's
a master control panel.
It says here there's a button
marked "safe-mode descent."
If you hit that, it should lower
the car down to ground level.
Safe-mode descent. Thank you.
- Good luck, ma'am.
- Wait.
How long before the radiation hits?
Uh...
best estimate... 10 minutes.
- Come on, let's get this open.
- No!
Our orders are to stay
put in this elevator
until J-corps comes and gets us.
They will come.
You'll see.
No one gets left behind,
not even you.
No one gets left behind.
You might believe everything
you're told, but I do not.
Listen. You hear that?
That is the ventilation system.
In 10 minutes that ventilation
system will be pumping
radiation into this building
and then into this elevator.
If you want to stick around
for that, that's up to you.
I need to get to my
daughter and get her safe.
And if that means risking the radiation,
I will take my fucking chances.
You with me, Private?
- Let's get out of here, ma'am.
- Let's go.
Get on your feet, Private!
Diego, stop!
I am your superior officer.
I order you to sit down
and stay out of our way.
You are no superior officer.
You are showing disrespect
to that fucking uniform
just by wearing it...
ma'am.
All right, Private,
I got your back.
No one gets left behind.
What the hell?
You hear that?
"We're fighting our enemy in
Iraq and Afghanistan today
so we will not have
to meet him again
on our streets,
in our cities."
George W., 2003.
I guess that didn't work.
I was ordered to drop a bomb
and I dropped the bomb.
I'm sure that's not
what's in your report.
Well, where did the bomb land?
I don't miss.
What did you hit?
It...
it hit women and children.
It says here you were
told to abort the attack.
Someone's covering their ass and
the shit's rolling downhill.
And look's who's holding
the fucking bag.
- What the fuck?
- What is this?
Let's go, let's go.
Let's do it, come on.
Excuse me, sir.
Oldsman.
Oldsman, please.
It's a word you like a
lot, isn't it, Captain...
"please"?
I don't know what you're talking
about. Get the fuck out of the way.
- Want some help?
- Yeah.
- You got it?
Motherfucker!
- Captain.
- All right, let's go.
We were ordered to
stay in the elevator.
You got it?
Nine screws, but they're loose.
I can do it, ma'am.
You cover that wound and if you
don't have a fucking screwdriver,
shut the fuck up.
I know who the fuck you are.
Please please please,
I'll do anything.
Death to America!
You listen to me,
Private. She is nothing.
She is no officer.
You open that hatch...
you're gonna let radiation
in, so stop it now.
And that is a fucking order.
- Are you ignoring me, Private?
- Yes, I am, sir.
That took about a minute.
You get the rest out that fast,
it's gonna take about eight.
The radiation hits in five.
- You do the fucking math!
- Good point.
Diego, help me.
All right.
If you think that hatch
is gonna save you,
you can close it as
soon as we're out.
Jesus Christ.
What do you plan on doing
with that knife, Sergeant?
Radiation from a dirty bomb
is carried by the dust cloud
created by the explosion.
Avoid inhalation at all costs.
If you keep it out of the lungs, you
keep it out of the blood stream.
Get off of me!
Diego, stand down! I got this.
Get back up there.
You know how I know
who you are, huh?
I saw the video.
I know why you're here.
You're crazy.
And I bet you're crazy too. You
gotta be, doing what she says.
- What about you, sir? Are you crazy?
- Yeah, I thought so.
But now I think I'm the
only sane one here.
- We're so close.
- I mean, look at you.
- Don't touch me.
- Two fucking crazies...
- Don't fucking touch me!
- ...opening up the hatch
- just to let the radiation in.
- Give those back.
- And the prize... crazy pills.
- Give them back!
- Give them back.
- Who wants one?
Are you gonna beg like you
did in the video, huh?
Jesus Christ, what's
fucking wrong with you?
We don't got time for this shit!
- You got it? Okay.
- Yeah, almost.
- All right.
- Orders are fucking orders!
All right.
- You okay?
- Yeah.
- Ma'am, do you see anything?
- I might have something.
- It won't open.
- You got one fucking minute.
Take as long as you need, Captain.
- I found it.
- Yes!
Whoo!
You guys ready to go down?
Yes. Yes, ma'am.
Ma'am, what's going on?
Why has it stopped?
- I don't know.
- What's happening?
Are we down?
- Fuck!
- Ma'am, are you all right?
Avoid inhalation at all costs.
Ma'am.
Then Pete, you know, he...
he didn't want to get out
of the car, but I said,
"Pete, come on, we gotta get out
of the car. We gotta go right now.
We gotta go right now.
The shit's hitting the fan."
And... I made Pete
get out of the car.
I made Pete get out
of the Humvee and...
But you got a medal
for what you did.
We just follow orders. We just...
we just follow orders.
Ma'am, what's happening?
What's going on?
Shit.
Coming down.
- Radiation.
- Oh, shit.
- Diego, get the hatch.
- Hold your breath!
- Cover your mouth.
- You got it?
- Cover your mouth. Cover your mouth.
Oh fuck.
Oh my God, do you think the
dust cloud has passed?
- Yes, ma'am.
- Get those doors open.
It's clear, ma'am.
What kind of reception have you
had in the army since returning,
given the extraordinary
circumstances of your capture?
I kind of try not
to think about it.
We were ordered to stay put.
You disobeyed that order.
And you got us all killed.
Might as well die happy, right?
How long till event 12?
A little over three minutes.
We're okay.
Let me...
let me see if I can get
this thing going again.
You know what's funny?
You killed me.
Killed by a traitor.
A dirty traitor bitch.
You would understand
if you had a child.
You should have kept
one for yourself.
You should have kept a bullet
for yourself.
I did.
I couldn't leave her.
So fuck you.
What would you know about war?
You've never even been in battle.
I read your file.
You sat on your ass in Texas
and you pushed a button
like it was a videogame.
You aimed that Predator
missile right in that crowd,
16 innocent women and children,
when you were ordered to abort.
Well, you really want
to know the truth?
I don't regret it.
'Cause there ain't no such
thing as innocence over there.
You're a fucking piece of shit.
Look at me.
All right, we have to stop this.
Let's get him out of there.
- Bring it back up.
- Okay.
- I can't do it.
- What do you mean you can't do it?
It's not going through.
It's on automatic.
I told the systems guys
there had to be overrides.
I guess they weren't listening.
Get off, get off!
- Oh my God, event 12.
- How long does it last?
About, uh, 30 seconds.
Oh, wait wait. I know
a way around this.
Um, abort codes in Section 10...
- pull them up.
- I'm already on it.
Let's start shutting this down.
I'm on it.
She's going into shock.
The sight of blood...
it's... it's her trigger.
It's... it's what sets her off.
My God, is she helping him?
She broke through it.
I'm sorry. I...
What?
Pete?
9920 Millchurch
Avenue, apartment C.
I got it, I got it. I'll get him.
I'll find him. I'll find him.
Oh, God.
You know what?
Take some breaths.
Just try to get some air.
I can't do anything. I can't.
If I pull it out,
it'll kill you. I...
I'm sorry. Oh, God.
Jesus Christ, what are you doing?
We need to call General Black.
Oh, God.
Motherfucker! You bitch!
You'd better watch your step, Cap.
Stupid bitch.
Okay, found them... the
first set of abort codes.
Delta, foxtrot, numeral
three, alpha, uniform, delta.
Okay, now yours.
Alpha, kilo, numeral six,
sierra, tango, delta.
Sierra, tango, delta.
Are you hearing me?
I just... I need to
think this through.
Hey!
Is anybody in there?
Help us!
- Please help us.
- Dr. Andrews.
- What are you doing?
- Help me.
She's on the roof. She's safe.
Are you serious? Protocol says
we abort if any participant
is in mortal danger.
A man just bled out. Isn't that
the definition of mortal danger?
Well, there's nothing we
can do for Diego now.
We can use this.
It's the ultimate test.
Lieutenant, would you pull
up some background files?
I need to see if there's
something we've missed.
Will do.
Hey, Captain.
Help yourself.
You must need one by now.
White has performed
incredibly well.
You wanted battlefield testing,
General. You just got it.
Sir, a man is dead.
This incident is a tragedy.
Private Diego was a hero.
We're going to need some time to
work out the best way forward.
Until then, you should
continue the trial.
General,
if we don't stop this right now,
I am walking
and will file a formal
complaint with AMC HQ.
This is crazy. We'll all
end up court-martialed.
This is about more than
three soldiers, lieutenant.
We're at war.
On two fronts.
More of our soldiers
are committing suicide
than are killed in combat.
Post-traumatic stress is
now our greatest enemy.
But a line has been crossed.
Enough.
Lieutenant Blau, permission
to leave granted.
I want your full
report on this matter?
While it's fresh in your mind.
Report to Major Whitcomb
at Jackson immediately.
Yes, sir.
I don't see how removing
Blau helps us, general.
This shitstorm you've created
needs to be dealt with.
And Blau doesn't have
the stomach for it.
This drug has to be on the
front line in three weeks.
You say you're a patriot?
Well, today you're
going to prove it.
Help!
Can you hear us?
Somebody fucking help us.
Want your pills pretty
bad, don't you?
Fuck you, motherfucker.
Dr. Andrews.
Where are you?
In my car, at the gate
on my way to debrief.
Where... where's your
escort Major Cortez?
He never showed up.
I found the emails about
the side effects.
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
Those are rare and
they're not proven.
You say here one in 100 patients
experience severe side effects.
It appears to intensify their
post-traumatic stress,
makes them psychotic,
just like Oldsman.
Possibly, but we need more data.
That's why we're doing this.
Even if it is true,
it can be managed.
Fuck.
Whoa.
All right.
Hey.
Need some help?
Maybe you want some of mine?
No?
Maybe you want one of his.
Diego's.
Maybe we don't need any at all,
because our insides are disintegrating
with fucking radiation!
Where are you going?
J-corps is coming.
Come down.
I won't hurt you.
You're never gonna make
it, not even close.
If you fall from up there,
it's going to hurt even worse.
This is why you fucking
follow orders!
You follow orders!
All right.
Motherfucker.
You fucking set me up?
I found one of those cameras
in my fucking house.
You filming me to get me put away?
Fuck you!
General, we have to stop this.
You're a doctor.
You want to save lives.
That's why you're
doing this, right?
Here's something they don't
teach you in med school,
something I learned on the
battlefield written in blood:
Saving lives costs lives.
Have you seen the news?
We've got a serious problem here...
suicide rates off the scale,
tens of thousands
off active service,
all thanks to post-traumatic
fucking stress.
In a couple of years there will
be no one left to fight...
just a parade of
traumatized crybabies.
They need this.
The army needs this.
America needs this.
Once those survivors get out,
the whole thing's blown.
How many events in your trial?
14.
As of now, we're at 15.
Event 15 will be
an accident...
a tragic fatal
elevator accident.
I wish there was another way.
What... what about Lieutenant Blau?
Stick to what you know, Doctor.
I've cleared the building,
now get the fuck on with it.
You are all traitors.
You're all fucking traitors!
Oh, fuck.
You remember the code, Captain?
I am an American fighting in
the Force to guard my country
and our way of life. I am prepared
to give my life in their defense.
I will never surrender
of my own free will.
And if in command, I will never
surrender the members of my command
while there is still
means to resist.
If captured, I will continue to
resist by all means available.
I will make every effort to escape.
I will aid others to escape.
I will never accept parole or special
favors from the fucking enemy,
you stupid fucking bitch!
I will never betray my country...
even if my country betrays me.
Is anybody there?
Hello?
It wasn't supposed to be like this.
Dr. Andrews?
Is that you?
I'm... I'm so sorry.
Why aren't you helping us?
You're a doctor.
You took an oath to help people.
Not to kill them.
How do you feel about being part
of a trial for this medication?
I'm not here by choice.
I was told this is
what I had to do.
I was ordered to do this.
I follow orders.
I mean, if you asked
me to be a part
in an experimental
trial drug or whatever
a few months ago, I probably
would have said no.
But, like, now I would
just do anything.
I just want it to be...
I want to be normal again.
I just want to be able
to be a mom to my kid.
And I want to feel like
I can do my job again.
Andrews.
Sir, I hold you
personally responsible
for the deaths that
occurred here today.
I have right here a complete
record of what happened.
I will make sure that by the end
of today you will be in custody.
Put me through to Lambro security.
I understand you're unhappy about
what has happened here, Captain,
but everything we are doing
is for the safety and
security of this country.
If you do this, you're a traitor.
I'm sure by now you've
called security.
But that's okay, because by the
time they get here, I will be gone.
What you're watching is a
recording made over an hour ago.
Right now I'm at the news
desk of a major newspaper
or at the DA's office
or the police station
or a freedom of information
group, I haven't decided yet.
You crossed the line.
Diego and Oldsman were soldiers.
They willingly offered their
lives for this country.
And in return you
experimented on them
and killed them like lab rats.
I'm doing this to make sure that
they haven't died for nothing.
When this goes public...
maybe then the military
will treat its veterans
with the respect
they deserve. Good-bye.