Oh God, let my scent be
perfume to him.
Let my taste be honey
and my embrace more dear to him
than all the world,
with the exception of you,
who wields power.
Oh God, let me aid him
in his obedience to you.
Let him aid me in mine.
God, let me be the apple of his eye
and endow him with virtue.
Let us not unleash our violence
on each other.
Come on, Grandma.
Use the one upstairs.
My stuff's in here.
Why is Grandma still staying with us ?
Again, Halima ?
Not now, Mother.
Spare me the headache.
Get inside before your father
sees you.
Make up the guest bed.
Your sister will be staying
for a while.
Hurry up and make the tea.
-Welcome.
-Thank you. Thank you.
Welcome. Welcome.
Amra, you're drowning in work.
Slaving over a hot stove with no help.
A woman is a queen
as long as she's at home.
Your little queen got beaten
up today.
The educated engineer swore
an oath to divorce me.
Come on, Jiji. Sit down.
Meat again, Mom ?
I'm vegan now.
The teacher taught us to respect
animal rights.
Eat what's there, you spoiled brat,
instead of whining.
- What's wrong with it ? It's halal.
- No, Mom, it's torture to animals.
Salad ?
Hurry up, Grandma,
I need the bathroom !
Give me your hand.
Do your eyes still hurt ?
When are we going
to Tuha's concert ?
Tuha who, Mother ?
Just sit here.
Who's Tuha ?
Grandma's losing it.
She's stuck in the 70s.
- The tea, woman !
- I'm coming.
God, safeguard my husband's heart,
ears, eyes, tongue and loins.
I ask you who preserves
those under Your protection.
God, God, please don't deny us
Your blessings.
AMRA AND THE SECOND MARRIAGE
Subtitles from
YavkA.net
Amra, your prices are sky high.
Take whatever you like.
Can I take some ma'moul for fifty ?
Sure.
Can I take two dozen
and only pay for one ?
As you like.
Amra, if you keep selling at a loss
you'll never make any money.
I'm happy. I enjoy working
with my hands.
What would they say if I refused ?
A penny saved...
Hilal retires in three months and
with his check we'll be set for life.
Hey, Amra. Seen this stunner ?
That's privatization.
Her father's one of the contractors
doing the restructuring.
They moved in opposite me and suitors
are lining up outside the house.
I bet you she'll be engaged
before the week is out.
God take those dirty field workers,
with their oil-stained hands.
How does she get her hair so silky ?
That's privatization, sister !
Not public sector, like us.
She lives at the beauty salon.
Where's your mother, Jamila ?
Come closer.
Do you need me to refill
your gas tanks ?
We filled them last week.
Drop Jamila off at school.
The bus was late today.
And hurry back here.
Amra, you need to economize.
The monthly allowance ?
Be patient, just for this month.
- But...
- A temporary hardship.
Yes, sir.
Ask the girls to economize too.
As you command.
You're their father.
I see. Wonderful.
The operation will be in a month.
I'll give you...
a recommendation.
Of course, we need
your guardian's approval.
I'm sorry, Um Jamila.
Gasoline prices have soared.
Here, Uncle Marzouq.
May God protect us.
Get ready. We're leaving
in ten minutes.
Alright, I'm coming.
And try to economize.
The bills are piling up.
Mommy,
is it okay if I stay at home ?
You want to stay here all alone ?
So what ? Halima's staying.
And I could practice the piano.
The lessons are only once a week.
You especially need them,
to improve your Arabic.
But Mommy, the microphone
and the sheikh's voice hurt my ears.
Sheikh Odeh is a man of God.
We go so God will bless us.
Don't talk to me
about God anymore !
May God bless you.
Sheikh Odeh's monthly donations...
Women are the firewood
that makes Hell burn.
They take their mates for granted.
Showing ingratitude to one's husband
is a mortal sin.
Fear God and obey your husbands
and your families.
Don't show ingratitude
to your husband.
Fear God, because women are
Hell's firewood.
- How was your piano lesson ?
- Don't be late again.
I waited half an hour in the sun.
We've paid the electricity bill.
Didn't we agree to economize, Amra ?
We appreciate you, Mama Sa'adia.
The house lacks a man's presence
for weeks on end
and you run in and out as you please.
Someone had to pick up Jamila
from school.
Why ? Where's the bus ?
A temporary hardship
for a few months.
- Then we'll get the retirement check.
- Costs go up.
- Economize, Amra.
- God help us.
What's this ?
How long has Nafisa been here ?
- Just since my father passed away.
- Is she planning on staying forever ?
- Where else can she go ?
- Nafisa is old. She needs care.
Hilal and your family require
your full attention.
You'd both be better off
if you put her in a care home.
While I'm still alive ?
I'll care for her.
She doesn't need much.
What this house needs is a man,
not more old women.
Hilal deserves a son.
You've been a good mother
to his daughters,
but what Hilal needs now is
a new bride.
What's a man worth in our society
without a son ?
How much are these ?
No, Mama Sa'adia. No way.
That's very kind of you, Amra.
I hope Amra didn't see.
She's been suspicious lately.
- Shall I knife her ?
- What ? She's a harmless lady.
I could almost believe
she bakes these for smokers.
It's good to be outside,
to see the horizon.
- Stick your hair out of the window.
- What ?
I want to see your hair flowing
while I drive.
Is that how it is, brother ?
"Obey, girl" and "Yes, master !"
At least persuade me.
God, you're in a strange mood.
Indulge me.
No.
God. Women.
Abu Lama, may I burden you
with a favor ?
Could you drop Jamila off at school ?
Just for a few days.
It would be my duty as a neighbor.
MA'MOUL = 150
KLEICHA = 175
KLEICHA = 200
Finally we can congratulate Hilal.
- God bless you. We're delighted.
- You turned out a wise woman.
Sa'adia bet on the winning horse.
You know, we were worried
about how to tell you.
Tell me ?
What are you talking about ?
Hilal's retirement.
We've slaughtered a sheep.
So you don't know !
Hilal's getting married.
Sa'adia has already spoken
to the new neighbors.
She's arranging for Hilal
to marry Ishtar.
Ishtar ?
Look, Amra, don't wail and pout
like these young girls.
These are our old ways.
You're a woman who values tradition.
Yes, of course. No wailing.
The cell number you are calling
is currently unavailable.
Amra ? Are you OK ?
- My kleicha ! My ma'moul !
- Your what ? What's going on ?
Hilal's getting married. Sa'adia's
arranging the Syrian girl for him.
I'm sorry, Amra. We were afraid
to break it to you.
- With my kleicha ?
- Consent. What can you do ? Object ?
- Life isn't like the movies.
- Hilal won't accept this.
This makes you more well-liked
in the camp.
Everyone in the camp is relieved.
They feared for their men.
What about me ?
We gave them sons. They have
no reason to take a second wife.
Oh God, who harnesses hard hearts,
wayward servants and solid mountains,
harness my husband to my service,
blind him and block his ears,
so he may perceive no woman's charms,
save mine. Amen.
ISTIKHARA PRAYER
I've decided to look for
a second wife for him.
Hilal has the right to a son.
God says in the Quran,
"Wealth and sons are...
"Adornments."
"...adornments of this life."
May God bless your offspring.
Sheikh, a woman seeking reassurance
in her decision
isn't ungrateful to her husband.
She's afraid Satan is deceiving her.
How can she be sure
God is pleased with her ?
- Did you hear me ?
- Perform the Istikhara prayer.
Purify your intentions and turn to God
with a pure heart.
He will guide you towards
the bountiful path.
But Istikhara, Sheikh...
Please don't be angry but...
its effects may take a while.
Are there other tangible signs ?
Come closer, my child.
There are those who see signs
in the shapes of the clouds
that praise their Lord.
Signs come to others in flashes
that soon fade.
Istikhara ? That's it ? Nothing else ?
And reciting the Quran to protect
your home and children from evil.
Really, Sheikh ? When will you come
to recite upon our home ?
Play the tape at your home
and drink holy water.
Know that victory comes with patience,
relief with affliction,
hardship with ease.
Pay on your way out.
Find holy water for drinking.
Also olive oil.
Wait. One moment.
Take this for the girls' tuition.
HOLY WATER
Darling...
Your tuition fee is on the desk.
Take it in tomorrow.
Don't play music.
Not while the Quran is playing.
God, I seek aid in Your knowledge
that encompasses everything.
Oh God, guide your lost servant
and grant me a sign.
You'll love her.
You'll absolutely adore her.
Congratulations to us !
We finally found a bride for Hilal.
A well-presented lady.
And they happen to be our neighbors.
Ishtar is radiant.
You'll go together well in this house.
Light upon light !
Where's Nafisa's hospital form ?
I've already told all the ladies
in the camp.
Amra is my daughter.
She has always behaved with honor.
She never refuses me a request.
Nor do I her.
Ishtar will bring the family a son,
who will provide for your daughters
when Hilal grows old.
Hilal has never said to me
that he wants a son.
Don't shame Hilal's manhood !
Stop your selfish woman's wailing.
Wailing ? Me ? Wailing ?
We're both women. You come with me
to arrange Hilal's marriage.
A lady of honor and tradition
appreciates another like her.
Ishtar will bring happiness
to your home.
Endear yourselves to each other
like sisters, not rivals.
She's nothing special.
A sack of bones.
Inflated lips and a designer dress.
She's adorable.
Like a Datsun to a Ferrari.
We don't compare.
What if she fails to deliver a son ?
She who is fortunate
remains fortunate.
She has the face of a rival.
We won't get along.
Tell me. Are you going
to arrange the marriage ?
I don't know.
I have to pray more.
No signal. There's interference.
That's a devil eye, Amra.
That's bad.
It is an eye.
I need to protect my home,
so it might subside.
Greetings, neighbor.
I just wanted to tell you that...
it's no problem at all driving Jamila
every morning.
It's a blessed opportunity.
Say, do you need some help here ?
No, no. May God reward you
for your kindnesses.
We've paid the amount due
for the bus.
Great. Well... Can I ask you
for your cell number ?
Just in case the bus continues...
to be unavailable.
You can call me whenever.
Or you could just knock on the door.
I live right here.
My cell number, yes. I'll have Jamila
give it to your daughter.
OK, well...
I'm going to finish my jog.
OK, sure, go please. Thank you.
Know that hardship comes with ease.
WE ARE PROPOSING TOMORROW.
BRING SOMETHING. HONOR US
So...
What do you think ?
The customization is killing us.
Are you paying anything ?
Eat shit and keep working.
- Hello.
- I'm dry.
What ?
Can you hear me ?
Nothing is for free, except...
I got us enough cash
for a couple of months.
Alright. I can get what you want.
Where are you going at this hour ?
- I won't be long.
- Entrusting sheep to a wolf.
Don't tell your little sisters.
It's God's will in the end.
And Hilal wants a son.
- God ! Do you believe that ?
- What use is it to object ?
It's a small community.
I do my duty.
For God's sake. The problem is
our own subservience.
Also, God hasn't given me a sign.
Does no signal mean he's pleased ?
A flash.
A sign. Hilal belongs to his daughters.
That's the sign !
I have a confession.
You're getting older.
And I've been too strict.
We need more dialogue
in this house.
Not centralized power.
Not tyranny.
We should vote on everything.
Like who comes and goes.
Especially who comes in.
Your grandmother Sa'adia
is up to something.
- She...
- Cut it out.
- Dad's marrying the new girl.
- It's his Mom !
Hilal's only doing it
because of her meddling.
When he gets home, set him straight.
Tell him, "How dare you ?"
Stop stressing me. Leave me out
of your arguments.
When Dad gets back, I'll ask for money
so I can go to school in the morning.
- What ? I gave you the full amount.
- You didn't. You never do.
Great. Let's fight
and forget the food.
Cheese as well ?
I told you, I'm vegan,
which means I don't eat cheese.
These international schools
don't teach you manners.
Your baking's wonderful, Amra.
Whatever happens, I'm your mother.
A stepmother has a heart of stone.
- Yes, of course.
- If Hilal finds out, he'll ground you.
- Where do you think I go ?
- How should I know ?
But a stepmother won't cover
for you with Hilal.
Hilal ? Where is he ? He only shows up
at the end of the month.
And I'm only using this app,
like everyone else.
Stop wailing like the old ladies
in the camp.
Listen, Amra.
Nobody wants you here.
You didn't congratulate Ishtar
and give her your blessing.
You spoiled the spirit of the camp.
- I just...
- Spare me !
Take your things and leave.
No one will eat from the hand
of a spiteful traitor.
This is a collective decision.
- But I...
- Enough wailing.
Be on your way.
Victory comes with patience,
hardship with ease.
Me ? Wailing ?
I'm not here. I'm not here.
Sa'adia will not allow herself
to be dishonored in front of the camp.
Ishtar is moving in.
She'll occupy the ground floor.
But Nafisa can't use the stairs.
Nafisa ? Take her somewhere else.
She's none of our concern.
She's expelled from Hilal's home.
Ishtar, Hilal's wife,
enters her husband's house
with her head high.
From now on, the ground floor
of the house is Ishtar's wing.
You deserve that.
Hilal will never accept this.
Don't be naive.
Isn't this the happiness
you promised for us ?
Husband, house and home.
Stability. The big prize.
Listen.
Your idealism is your failing.
Don't revel in my misfortune.
Tell me what you would do.
Me ? Nothing extraordinary.
He'll get back with me eventually.
I have his boy.
Enough of this shit.
Sands, in the kingdom of sands,
are your biggest enemy.
Where is your will to lift up
your head from the sand ?
What do you want ?
How are you ?
Good. Thank God for your return.
Prepare and iron my shemagh
and thobe by this evening.
As you command.
And don't forget my formal cloak.
I'm going to lie down.
What's wrong ?
You look pale and weak.
Ishtar moves into my house ?
The Istikhara didn't do any good.
It's not like putting chlorine
in a pool.
You need faith.
Nothing is difficult to God.
Istikhara opens your heart.
I can't get a signal.
It's not God.
The problem is in you.
You think it's a punishment ?
What did I do ?
Nothing. Someone cast a spell on you.
This is the kind of magic that drives
a wedge between a man and his wife.
- Istikhara can't undo it.
- Don't talk nonsense, Sarah.
Nonsense ?
A sieve can't hide the sun.
These are all signs of magic.
When your husband stops
looking you in the eye,
and abandons your bed,
when you dream of someone else...
Who would do it ? Sa'adia ?
Don't ask me. Ask yourself.
Search the depths of your soul.
Revelations will come in dreams.
I can't handle Sa'adia's evil.
Should I resist or just submit to her ?
Too late for that, sister.
They want to force you out.
You need to stand your ground.
Cast a counter spell.
Now she wants to take my mother
from me.
Tomorrow she'll get rid of me.
The Syrian is controlling Sa'adia.
It's like she found the Prophet's coin.
She took all that golden check
and spent it on her shopping.
Sa'adia believes in God above
and in Ishtar below.
Even her honeymoon.
Sa'adia arranged a trip to Malaysia
and Ishtar insisted on Europe.
A cruise to Europe.
Is this magic or is it not ?
In a divorce I'd end up on the street.
- I know what to resort to.
- To magic.
No.
KHUL'
THE PROCESS FOR A WOMAN
TO DIVORCE HER HUSBAND
Welcome, sister.
And that's why I want a khul'.
Do you know why women
were created ?
- Why ?
- I'm asking you.
To worship God ?
Correct.
And obedience to your husband is part
of obeying God.
A wife's role in an ideal Islamic
society is to establish a family.
Establishing a family.
Of all lawful acts,
the most detestable to Allah
is divorce.
- Isn't the law to protect people ?
- Sharia contains common good.
When there is polygamy between
a worthy male
and wise women,
to share the burden of responsibility,
it can impact the family, the community
and the nation in many good ways.
- When can I see the counselor ?
- Which counselor ?
The judge.
Am I not worthy of the role ?
I am the judge.
Look, sister. A khul' requires
proof of conjugal abandonment,
And you must return the dower
and the expenses of 20 years
of marriage, in your case.
And litigations are long.
May I ask you a question ?
How many wives do you have ?
I have Um Abdul Hakim,
Um Oais,
and Um Ghaliya.
How old are you, Sheikh ?
And sharia allows me a fourth.
Yes, hello. Is that the care home ?
May I ask about the conditions
for your elderly residents ?
A good Muslim doesn't smoke
cigarettes.
Enough. You're doing my head in
with your noise.
Where can I rehearse in this house ?
Bring it in here, Jiji.
Leave her alone.
Things are missing.
Where's my hairdryer ?
Take it easy. No fuss.
Fuss ? The whole camp is talking
about us and our house.
All because you
defy Grandma Sa'adia.
Thanks to you,
we're constantly broke now.
We've grown accustomed to burying
our heads in the sand,
in the kingdom of the sands.
Whole generations have closed
their minds,
burying their heads in the sand.
Lift up your head from the sand.
Luck is fickle, here one day,
gone the next.
When it comes,
be ready to seize it.
Lift up your head, Amra.
Hello, Um Jamila.
Lama's birthday is this weekend.
We want a big cake, cold cuts,
some cupcakes.
Cookies... Lotus cookies.
They will be my gifts.
No, no gifts.
We should do this properly.
This is some cash for your cooking
and your time.
But Lama is like my child.
And you're taking Jamila to school.
No way. Driving her is my duty
as a neighbor.
For making the food and cakes,
this is your fair due.
Right ! Have a nice day.
If we doubled the prices,
we'd make the money we need
in two months.
We need to innovate though.
Amra, start a new line
like those women on Instagram.
Sell toffee ma'moul
or pomegranate kleicha.
Don't you think you've overdone
the baking ?
- Where does the neighbor work ?
- His wife's grave's still warm.
I didn't ask about her.
Rashid works at the consultancy
that's doing the privatization.
They're laying off the old guard
and hiring non-nationals.
May God forgive him for cutting jobs.
And other things.
What other things ?
For one thing, his daughter is
at the international school.
- Jiji goes there too.
- No, with him it's different.
He's secular.
- Secular ?
- I get it.
Your star's shining.
No, I'm just asking.
Why are you clinging to this house ?
Hilal says no good,
but he says no evil.
And ingratitude to your husband
is a sin.
Ingratitude ? Again ?
When will you stop this ?
I'm only here for the kids.
They'll be lost if I leave.
- I'll go tell Mom.
- You scared me.
Go play this noise for her
at her soup kitchen.
Take your mother and get out
of this prison cell.
Start a cooking business.
Dump the children on her.
Let the new bride take care of them.
That would be the best punishment.
Start a new life
after all these years ?
I'm a housewife, not a businesswoman.
And where do I go to start with ?
Secularists are still Muslims.
You can marry one of them.
Please, God, forgive me.
LIFT UP YOUR HEAD
To all disappointed ladies: rise up !
Subscribe to my online coaching.
Scroll down for info on that.
Why hesitate ?
I'm talking to you, the marginalized,
the broken waste of society.
Subscribe to my online coaching.
I'm talking to you, Amra !
Peace be upon you.
I am Amra.
My head is here in front of you.
Lift it up from the sands.
I salute you.
You're one step away
from lifting your head up,
getting out of the quagmire.
All you have to do is
make your payment.
Oh Lord, Holy one, bless with this soul
the union of Hilal and Ishtar.
Jamila, come here.
She's torturing her.
She'll cut her head off.
Is Nafisa alright ?
Good timing, Amra.
I've found someone who'll take
Nafisa's old furniture.
How generous of you.
- When will you come for the meat ?
- Why would I ?
Don't you want to give it out
to ward off the envious eye ?
No, darling.
The whole camp has given its blessing
for the new wedding.
The meat is for you,
to save us from your eyes.
Be happy for us. It is God's will.
Kiss Jamila for me.
She was squeamish about the blood.
Yes, I will.
What do I have
from 25 years of marriage ?
A useless husband
and an evil mother-in-law.
If a new door opens for me,
should I take it ?
We live in the post-truth era,
a time of flux,
the Trump era.
Populism is the answer.
Take the new door.
Make Amra great again.
I can't believe it.
Lama turned 13 today.
It makes me feel old.
Blink... and she'll be a bride.
Don't use the word bride.
Amra. You have to make tough
decisions sometimes.
Better to take the bitter medicine
in the short term,
than to be ill for the long term.
You have the right to resent
sharing your husband.
Don't sell yourself short,
afraid of what people will say.
Amra.
It's a big world.
Don't let tradition stop you making
a fresh start.
You still have options.
I'm sorry.
I have to leave now.
Congrats again to Lama.
May she enjoy her father's grace.
Control your mother.
Don't play dumb.
We can all see.
Your mother wants to move out
and come take my father.
My mother won't move out.
She will.
If your grandmother leaves,
your mother will file for divorce
and move out.
If she comes close to my father,
I'll make your life at school hell.
My heart stopped.
Give me a puff.
Let me drive in front of the guys.
You don't deserve to.
No one drives her but me.
She's my Darling.
That was awesome !
Nice one, King.
- King !
- Glad you liked it.
Alright !
That's what I'm talking about !
Today I answered him.
But when I did, the call dropped.
I'm scared.
Amra.
Seen my phone ?
Has she turned your head too ?
Um Saleh has a new recipe for kleicha
with orange peel.
You sent the money ?
They're privileged girls.
Born with a silver spoon.
She's selling you illusions
from New York.
They're different than us.
You raised us to believe that
lifting up your head breaks your neck.
New York ? Her accent's like ours.
You're so out of touch.
Where's the old furniture for sale ?
- Sarah, you startled me.
- Come here.
Tie together a lock of hair
from Hilal and Ishtar,
and throw the spell into the deep
of the ocean.
The ink on it doesn't fade.
How much did you pay for this heresy ?
Ten months of your future kleicha sales
for God's help.
- I'll pay in this world and the next.
- Goodbye.
This is Hala calling,
from the Women's Association
in the capital.
We've scheduled a visit to you
tomorrow.
- OKkay.
- What time suits you ?
The morning.
WE ARE THE FUTURE
Look, Amra,
we arrange everything.
Transport, accommodation
for your mother and your girl.
We arrange a lawyer
and the press conference.
We force the officials
to listen to us.
- Who are you ?
- We're the future.
The future ?
Women's education, driving,
shura council,
practicing law, civil affairs,
they were all our demands
before they were legalized.
We'll soon see an end
to male guardianship.
I can see the future flashing
on the horizon.
No flashes, please.
Listen, at the Women's Association,
we don't only help and serve
victims of domestic abuse
and divorced women denied
their rights.
We also need to encourage women
to share their stories of suffering,
so our current becomes
the mainstream.
So I'll be on TV ?
Like The Dawood Show ?
Yes and no. There are different forms
of pressure.
Shock is not the same as influence.
Look, we only want your true story.
Tell it honestly.
As for us, we provide protection,
financial and psychological security.
And if you're afraid of retaliation
or stigma after being in the media,
we can move you to New Zealand
or Canada.
Well, that would be a last resort.
Amra is a lady of community.
We'll integrate her into the capital.
I just want Nafisa cared
for in a home.
Nafisa's case is settled.
We want to lift the injustice
you've suffered.
How could you live with
another wife ?
Polygamy is backward, chauvinistic,
and it makes me sick.
It's degrading for all women.
Where could I go ?
It isn't easy for a woman of my age
to start her life over.
What life ? They're freezing you out.
Soon they'll kick you out
of your home.
- What was that ?
- Don't worry.
It's only for internal use.
What if I don't want your help ?
What business is it of yours ?
There's a simple answer to that.
When slavery was abolished,
many slaves refused to leave
their masters.
There can be no voting
on basic rights.
Jiji, come and say hi.
- I'm sorry.
- Don't be.
Everyone must be upset.
It's difficult.
Look, Amra, we need a decision.
Either we give you Nafisa's ticket,
or two extra ones for you and Jamila.
Honestly, any intelligent woman
would choose the future.
Disobedient wives are fated to be
tortured in their graves
and are the fuel of hell.
How's our beautiful bride ?
Are you ready for the cruise ?
Grandma, I found the hairdryer.
Let me show you where.
Jamila, where are you ?
Here I am, Grandma. Hurry.
Today in Kuwait, a sentence
of capital punishment was carried out
against Nussrat El-Inizzy,
the woman who burned down
the wedding tent
of her husband and his second wife.
The woman involved in the incident
in 2009, Nussrat El-Inizzy,
burned the tent down with a gas tank
as revenge for her husband's marriage,
claiming 56 lives,
including women and children.
Good evening.
-Is this the home of...
-Al Hilal.
Is this the Al Hilal residence ?
We have a subpoena.
We have an arrest warrant for...
- Hamida Bint Hilal.
- What ?
- What did she do ?
- We're investigating a cyber crime.
- Flaunting sinfulness.
- Crime ?
- A video on Whatsapp. What was it ?
- Land Cruiser Girl.
Jamila.
Where are you ?
- Where are you, girl ?
- One more step, Grandma.
- She's not here.
- Then come with us.
Me ? Ask her father, her guardian.
- He's at Field 14.
- A guardian isn't necessary.
Mama Nafisa ?
Right. Patient's name ?
Nafisa Mohammed.
We need her guardian to sign.
She needs urgent surgery.
- Take my ID and help the old lady.
- Great. This way, please.
How could you have let the poor
old woman fall in the pool ?
Because of your selfishness.
You're deserting us.
You chose yourself and your mother
over us. I hate you !
We can't take a road that's blocked.
Amra, this isn't the time.
My help here has no strings attached.
My life isn't a company
for you to restructure.
Amra. Calm down.
Let's talk tomorrow.
This is all your fault.
You and your consultants forced
the old employees to retire.
That promise of a check is
what made Hilal greedy.
Please leave us alone.
Leave you alone ?
Okay.
That's what you want ?
As you wish.
Uncle Marzouq.
I need the gas tanks refilled, please.
Uncle Marzouq, one of these tanks...
Could it burn a whole...
tent ?
Hearing others' misfortune
causes idle thoughts.
How much do I owe you ?
One tank can set a large group
of tents on fire in under 40 seconds.
Why ? Do you want to get even
with someone ?
The fire of vengeance
yields nothing but ash.
But if you're resolved to do it,
I have a dozen blowtorches
awaiting your signal.
I'll put it on account.
You're in distress.
Peace.
This is not acceptable.
What's she doing here again ?
She can't get upstairs, she's injured.
I don't care !
- Where can I put her ?
- The street !
- Give me a week.
- You have one night.
Tomorrow morning, she's gone.
The furniture's arriving from the city.
Either get rid of your mother,
or you'll get your divorce papers.
I will. I will.
Either put your mother in a home, or
I'll see you both in a women's refuge.
Amra, darling.
- Don't stand outside. Come in.
- I'm in a hurry.
The ladies are collecting
for Ishtar's wedding banquet.
- They need your contribution.
- Where would I get any money ?
- I have to pay for that heresy.
- That's what I told them.
So instead, we thought
maybe you could cook the meals.
It'll pay you good money.
- I'd rather stay broke.
- Why the attitude ?
God is giving you this opportunity
to restore your status
and rejoin the camp club.
We'll give you back your spot.
No need for wailing and whining.
What wailing and whining ?
We're not asking for a camel !
Just some lamb and a little rice.
Turn your sourness into sweetness.
Be happy for someone else.
It's God's will.
I'll send the girls to get
some of your kleicha and ma'moul
for tonight's bridal party.
I leave you in God's favor.
Wailing ? I'll show you wailing.
This hall is primed with gas.
It will explode in a second.
I get to eat dirt,
while you walk on silk ?
You're hurting me.
You go on a European cruise,
while I haven't set foot past
the local beach ?
No, we're going to the Bahamas.
Where's your Darling ?
I'm hiding her until my cousins
deal with the police report.
Since this isn't the Darling,
let me drive it and do skids.
Skids, huh ? You're so funny.
That's what I'm talking about !
What did you do to the room,
you psycho ?
Get that out of my face and talk to me.
I said get rid of it.
Help me !
See what's happening here !
Amra's breaking her vow to Hilal.
She has no place in Hilal's house.
The court will have you dragged out
by the hair like a bitch.
God Almighty,
provide us with strength.
Bravo. You forced him to move her
to his mother's house.
I didn't force anything.
Didn't we agree to cut the crap ?
Sa'adia's death changed everything.
That woman was evil. Now she's
more comfortable and so are we.
Sa'adia was only an excuse.
The coward hid behind her.
He's still marrying a girl
his daughter's age. For a son.
- Always the same with men.
- Time will heal your heart.
My heart is still burnt.
Let's not say "burn".
The ladies are anxious.
Everyone's worried that you'll set
the wedding tent on fire.
You wouldn't do that, would you ?
Go tell the crones that sent you:
mission accomplished.
I'd be a fool to object.
Raise your head from the sand,
they'll fill your mouth with it.
Amra, you're reasonable.
At least you got your home back.
Your pots will be ready soon.
My dear Amra, we eagerly await you
here in the nation's capital.
You'll find three airplane tickets
included.
Everything's arranged
for your arrival.
Have a safe trip.
Jiji, get ready. We need to start.
Please welcome
our talented student, Jamila Hilal.
The board of trustees wants to offer
a full scholarship to Jamila.
Jamila's a talented girl.
A symbol of integration.
Our role is to remove any obstacles
that might distract her from focusing
on her academic and musical careers.
Come on, Mommy.
Let's go home.