Jakubisko Film
in cooperation with
Czech Television presents
a film by
Juraj Jakubisko
Starring
AN AMBIGUOUS REPORT
ABOUT THE END OF THE WORLD
Also starring
Producer
Production Manager
Dialogues
Art Director
Winter will soon be over.
Sound
Music
Good rose-hip wine.
To the newlyweds!
Editor
A thousand years of happiness,
a thousand children!
Director of Photography
To your health, neighbours!
Verona, have some wine!
I'm cold.
Come and dance, my bride
you'll soon warm up!
Written and Directed by
Wolves! The message is clear.
A beautiful cake,
too pretty to eat.
I'll cut some,
may your life be as sweet!
The wolves are here!
Holy mother of God!
Get the guns!
They're all drunk!
Goran, here's your cake.
Only two, thank God.
The winter was long
and they're hungry!
They've lost all fear.
Hurry! It'll be dark soon.
Hurry up, innkeeper!
Let's go get them!
They're drunk!
Let's kill them off!
Teach'em a lesson!
They won't come around here!
Let's show 'em!
Save your ammunition, Mayor!
Faster, innkeeper!
We mustn't let them get away!
Stop drinking, pope, and pray!
Jesus Christ, wolves!
More wolves!
Women, protect the children!
Mummy, where are you?
Wolves!
Janek!
I had a premonition...
Goran, the shutters!
Our Father,
who art in Heaven ...
Hurry, they're here!
The beasts!
Those idiots took my gun!
Where's the axe?
My baby!
I'll hack you to pieces
Verona!
Granny, get out!
The innkeeper's wife
is in there...
Janek, save that child!
The trapdoor!
Verona and the child
are down there!
You're bleeding.
Don't cry, I'll bandage it.
They're eating the cakes!
At least they'll let us be.
Higher, quick!
Hurry, Verona!
Hold her fast, Goran!
They'll tear you up, Gran!
Don't go anywhere.
Stay with Goran.
Janek, take my hand!
Save Verona, Goran!
Don't look! No! You musn't!
Verona, you mustn't look!
Lord, why did You allow this?
Is there anyone alive here?
Uncles!
It's Semek!
-Here, in the well!
-I'm drowning!
Search the houses,
maybe someone survived.
We lost all the women.
I did shoot,
sure as my name is Semek.
I barely reached the well.
Thank God she's a girl.
Want to see something?
Goran!
Let's go home, Daddy.
Go and see to the little girl.
Lord, why do you punish us?
Mother of God, pray for us.
This is Veronika.
When she grows up
she will be your bride, Goran,
because you saved us
from the wolves.
TEN YEARS LATER
Veronika, this is
your great day.
Your tenth birthday
and your engagement to Goran.
-Are you glad?
-Yes, Mum, because you're glad.
-May I go?
-Yes, go.
-Help yourself, Semek.
-Thank you, aunt Verona.
How nice!
Keep pouring, make the inn
a happy place again!
Goran, Veronika.
According to the fiancé's father
makes the first toast.
So few of us are left.
The gods have made you
our future,
our hope and promise.
To your health!
A thousand years of happiness!
To you, dearest!
To an early wedding!
You have a lot of waiting
ahead, Goran!
Silence!
Listen!
Wolves! The wolves are back!
Let's get them!
We'll kill them off.
Now we'll show them.
The message is clear.
Do you always greet people
with guns?
Is there a war on?
-Who are you?
-Ordinary people.
Hungry as wolves
and mild as sheep.
So many women!
Circus artists!
I'm the Showman, their boss.
We're en route abroad.
Give us some food, we'll pay
you well, and then we'll leave.
Come closer so we can see you.
You have some fine girls.
-Irena's the loveliest.
-I'm the Mayor.
Irena also holds
the purse-strings.
Madina. That's my name.
Have you lost your way?
I bet you want to cross
the border at night!
I love smart people, Mayor.
There are borderguards,
but the snow's the worst.
I never want anything for free.
Thank you, lrena.
You don't understand.
Not even diamonds would
help you in winter.
You'd need wings.
Any other ideas, Mayor?
We have some empty houses,
also a mill.
Wait a few weeks
untill the snow's gone.
A few weeks?
That's an eternity.
And time is money.
-Don't go yet, Simon.
-No, I've had enough.
Good night.
God bless.
Veronika, see Goran out.
And we're home.
I'll help you, Juzek.
See, my friend?
There are ever more wolves
among the humans too.
What the beasts don't destroy,
the humans will.
She could knock out a bear.
You promised a house,
but you gave us ruins.
Joseph worked at the border.
He can deal with the guards.
We should bribe the chief.
It'll be expensive.
Just settle the price.
Stop staring, pope!
Our Jirinka is the tallest
woman in the world.
She grew up in a convent.
It's my lrena who keeps
the circus together.
No money problems to shackle us
to the ground.
The duo from La Scala,
Margot and Fagot!
And Chocolate, the innocent
flower of Africa!
You have everything. Women!
We have nothing.
A Gipsy?
That's not very kosher, Boss!
See those orphans,
with my son Michael?
Their parents were stars!
Circus folk have short lives.
You provide the eats,
we'll supply the art.
Let's roll out a cask
of rose-hip wine!
-Three casks!
-I'll bring some moonshine.
Moonshine? Never heard of it.
A few drops work wonders.
Isn't it poisonous?
It's a cure, priest.
The only medicine
for a sick soul.
-It's liquor!
-Right!
Those circus gals
are classier broads
than ours were!
I wish Madina'd leave one here.
If we get the Showman drunk,
I can win Marlyn at cards.
We'll make her village property.
I'll wager the mill, meadow
and woods against Marlyn!
The message is clear!
-Isn't she worth more to you?
-I'll throw in my house and pig
-Semek, shuffle the cards.
-The message is clear.
Thirty, twenty, done.
You can't stay when
they're playing cards.
There's nothing to fear.
Our girl sleeps here alone.
Dad says there are wolves
here that eat children.
-Your father is exaggerating.
-No, he isn't.
He'll win it all by morning.
When he's wearing rainbow vest
he never loses.
Maybe it brings him luck.
No, it's magic.
Ten...
And ten.
We're screwed.
What about you?
Throwing in some more?
The ladies are still in the pot
We still have a church left.
Good night.
-What's your name?
-Veronika! And yours?
Michael.
Can I sleep in your bed?
If you like.
Are you frightened? Scared of
walking the tightrope, too?
I don't, my father forbids it.
-Scared of him, too?
-Everyone is.
Of my mother, too.
Gotchar!
Twenty-one!
We have twenty-one!
Jirinka is mine!
Sorry, ladies,
I can't get rid of you.
Two aces.
You're the devil!
Jirinka, I lost you!
That's enough. To bed!
You too, clown.
Wait, Verona!
Now I'm playing for you!
I'll wager all the money
I've got here and in my trunk!
Plus the circus!
The message is clear!
-And all the women!
-For this shitty peasant?
So many women - paradise!
Verona, take it.
Right. We need women.
Let's play together, Matous.
Aren't you hot, Madina?
Take off your vest.
You're sweating.
I don't mind a bit of sweat.
But I do.
Or wouldn't you win
without your vest?
A wise guy?
If you like my vest,
we can play for it.
I'll add it to the pot.
Drunk old fart!
Enough.
Fourteen. That's not much.
Hell!
The women are ours!
We won! The girls are ours!
Verona, do you need
seven slaves?
Take back your house, Mayor.
Give me the blonde.
We'll divide up
the money tomorrow,
fight it out for the women now.
The message is clear!
First you marry me!
Where's your church?
I'll show you in the morning.
She's mine!
The message is clear!
His pockets were full of aces!
I'm floating like an angel.
Marlyn, I'll be your motorcycle.
-You pig!
-You can ride me!
-I have my human rights!
-I have my human needs!
Jirinka, you're an arch
in my temple of Christ!
My victory arch.
It's our turn
Let's go to the mill.
There's the pussy
who smokes cigars.
The titsy cashier's for me.
How about me?
Take the old one.
Even you can manage her.
The message is clear!
Be gentle, we're artists!
You saw through him, Verona.
It's happy days
like harvest-time!
Pity it's only for one night.
Irena and Max are gone!
So is the money!
You have no circus!
This is what they left.
The orphans and me, that's all.
What's this hick doing here?
You should've seen
the goings on last night!
Swine! ls this gratitude?
Irena, you ungrateful whore!
I risked jail to show
your brother the ropes.
And you threw me overboard?
Degenerate clowns!
You can't even raise a tent
without me.
I've lost my circus,
my money, my vest!
In this damn hole!
I hope you fall on concrete
and don't die,
and have no money for a doctor.
I always come up on top.
I'll be stinking rich yet.
I can start again, even here!
O Lord, bless our seeds
and let them grow...
Pull! It's not a motorcycle.
Sowing poppy and hemp
means ploughing deep.
Shit on this!
Oh no you don't.
We'll be rich soon.
Poppy and hemp! Drives me nuts.
Keep pulling, poppy-head!
It might even grow.
Madina's said so,
he know what's what.
See Goran, Michael?
He has a horse.
When I grow up,
I'll be his wife.
So what? Look, I caught it.
-Look at its feathers.
-It's a hemp tit.
It's only a baby,
let it go, Michael.
D'you know what it's worth
in the city?
-What's this?
-It's called electricity.
-That's beautiful!
-Don't burn yourself.
On windy days we have light
like in the city.
I'd love to live in a city.
Look!
We don't need stupid horses
like your husband does.
When I grow up,
I'll live in town.
You can come with me, Veronika.
-Really, Michael?
-Close your eyes.
Michael!
City people do this
when they're in love.
-You'll really take me?
-I swear.
So I'll close them again.
Electricity must be beautiful
if city people
keep closing their eyes.
A FEW YEARS LATER
I'd get them!
Up to your old games again,
Michael?
Get off my back, old fart.
Shut up!
The guards are gone.
Let's go, then.
Quiet! We'll be home in no time.
Hold the horses!
Something's coming down!
Rocks are falling!
It's an earthquake, kid.
Shit! ls this the place?
Smugglers! There they are!
Halt! Come back!
Next time stay home,
Michael, damn you!
Get back! That's an order!
We're going, men.
Kiss our arses, guards!
Move, hunchback,
they'll shoot your cock off!
What happened, Michael?
An earthquake. Otherwise, okay.
We sold the goods,
bought horses and sheep.
Why did they shoot?
Did you give him less money?
Me? Same as always.
So why the shooting?
Some of the guards
are honest, the swine.
Better talk to your son. He's
been up to old his tricks again.
That was the last time, Matous.
I nearly died of fear.
Innkeeper,
did you swallow a ruler?
Matous?
He's dead.
Pour out the drink! Forty sheep!
Blessed Mary, what
are you punishing me for?
You took my bride-groom,
and now Matous!
That earthquake was a warning!
-Go to bed.
-The cards told me.
If we don't leave,
more will die, Madina..
The cards never lie.
-Don't scare us.
-She's right.
Today, the innkeeper.
Who will it be tomorrow?
When bribed men fire at us
it's time to stop.
The border won't be closed
forever.
That's why we need to rake in
a lot of money fast.
I don't mean to stay
here forever.
We need a new plan.
Give me the gun.
We need a different set-up.
I'm sick of your cowboy games.
Don't hang around.
Take the money from Vayda
and come home.
You shouldn't have
let him go, Mother.
He wouldn't listen.
He wanted to give you
a grand wedding.
I'm too young to marry, Mother.
When I got married,
I also thought I was too young.
In fact, it was too late.
I don't want to leave you,
Mother.
I'll help you.
Goran saved us from the wolves
so I promised he could have you.
Promises mustn't be broken.
That's the order of things.
Don't cry, Mother.
We'll help you, too.
God's rocking us!
Brother! Joseph!
The world is lopsided!
What's bitten you?
I have two messages!
One is clear,
the other unclear!
But the clear message
isn't very clear either.
I'm tipsy!
We're tilted over!
-An earthquake!
-It's from the poppies!
-The message is clear!
-A fucking earthquake!
Why only our house?
The others are upright!
Help me push it back!
Veronika, leave Katka
and Jenik at Goran's.
That's what we get
for not going to church!
It's for owing Matous a twenty!
Matous, I'll buy some brandy
and pour it on your grave!
The best slivowitz!
Sacramental wine!
Just straighten our house,
damn you!
He's talking to
your father, Veronika.
Semek tilted his house!
He's crazy.
He was bitten by wolves!
Hold my horse, give him water.
-Hello, chief.
-God bless, Michael.
I've come for an advance
on the horses, Vayda.
We want money. No bartering.
Money isn't everything.
What kind of smuggler are you?
Anyone with balls has a gun!
My old man has a gun...
but this!
-I'll get you a smaller one.
-I like it.
You don't call me your beauty
any more, Mike.
Don't you want to marry me?
I don't have time now.
Make your choice,
if you can't ride two of us.
Am I less important to you
than your Veronika?
Don't spy on me!
I'm your destiny.
Your happiness.
Enough!
-Go to hell, varmint!
-As you wish.
Go to her, white swine,
and you've had it!
You're finished...
Hi, Uncle Goran!
Katka! Jenik! My helpers!
I'm first on the swing!
Where did you leave Veronika?
Herding sheep to the chalet.
And your Mother?
She keeps crying.
You'll get used to it.
Just like me and Misha.
It's better than the circus.
Martin's a fine mother.
-Hello, jazzmen!
-Hello, Michael!
I have to go home.
Hello, ladies.
Hello, Lucy.
Michael, can we brush the horse?
You can ride it, too.
Bring it back to the mill
after the funeral.
The world isn't going to end.
So you'll marry him, so what.
I'll never stop loving you.
You'd do better to help me.
Stop it!
How can I help you?
You don't want to marry Goran,
nor make love with me!
If you were to carry my child,
there would be no wedding.
You promised to take me to town
How about a snort instead?
Let's run away together.
It's made from poppies,
that's our living.
I'd rather die than marry Goran.
Dad says a man shot
by the guards is a hero.
May you be remembered, Matous...
In the name of the Father,
the Son and the Holy Ghost.
Who'll be first at the inn?
Semek! Come and dance!
Vayda didn't pay much,
but there's a lot here anyway.
This was the innkeeper's.
We'll split it, too.
No, give it to Verona!
But after today we'll
split the extra money.
She didn't shed a tear
at the funeral.
She's beside herself,
'cause she won't get laid now.
I'll be a smuggler. Gimme!
You swiped it! Give it back!
-Just like the Mayor's.
-You'll shoot your eye out.
The message is clear.
You just cock it...
Take it away from him!
Then you pull...
Stop, you idiot!
What a hero you are!
You show off in front of
the girls, and duck the crazies!
Get off my back!
It's not my fault you could
only get the nigger chick!
What did you say, shithead?
You junkie!
If I blow your head off,
I'll get a medal!
Stop it, Joseph!
-What's the hurry, Juzek?
-Business is business.
You're nothing but trouble,
you and your Dad!
It's your fault they've
forgotten how to sow oats!
We just smuggle
hemp and poppies.
And stuff your pockets!
If you can't hold your liquor,
take Chocolate and go home!
I want a victory arch!
At least ten times!
You'll wake the children.
-First show me your bird.
-Two poppy tits.
-Three arches.
-Five, at least!
Four, but quickly.
Your bird gets smaller
and smaller.
Time enough, Jirinka.
The priest's playing cards.
And he's forgotten his promises.
I have to take care of him,
the church and the fields.
I have to deal in birds
to get an organ.
"You know this song?
""He promised her kingdom come"" "
Shut up and start marching!
He promised her kingdom come
then gave her his bare thumb.
The first arch!
Second!
Keep out of this, Michael!
I could keep the pub in funds
like Matous did
and you'd save money.
For you, such a fine a widow.
I'm the one that fired, Semek!
The message is clear!
I'll be a smuggler!
I'll smuggle sheep, goats,
poppies and hemp!
Idiot! He'll kill us all!
The heathen!
We've said it all.
So go home, Michael.
I'll never marry Goran.
He's an old man!
Michael would ruin your life!
-I won't allow it.
-I don't care!
Good night, all!
Don't worry, Goran.
I'll straighten her out.
I like crystal-clear messages.
I'll have to settle this myself.
A circus clown screwed my bride.
Veronika is a virgin.
And stop boozing.
Gimme that!
You'll ruin your life, Goran!
That remains to be seen.
Mother'll never forgive me.
Forget about her.
No! I don't want it!
You want me, not Goran!
Do it, quick! Even if I die!
I can't live without you!
-It's Michael.
-He overdid it last night.
I'll wake him.
Michael, your horse!
He's dead!
It's my fault, son.
I let you get away
with anything!
We should've left and let
the devil take the money.
I'll find your murderer.
I promise, my son.
I'll avenge you, Michael.
Who knows who did it?
Whoever it was,
hand in all your guns tomorrow.
I know who shot you, Michael.
The message is clear.
My Michael...
Give it to me, Jenik!
Be good, children.
Cheers to the newlyweds!
A thousand years of happiness!
Look, my tree is in pain too.
-They shouldn't have married.
-Why not?
Veronika's not like you.
She doesn't have your strength.
She should live in town.
And they didn't marry for love.
Did any one us marry for love?
You promised us off
in our cradles.
My son should have married you.
He was only ten when I married.
Sow the seed in March or May.
Wheat ripens at the same time.
Veronika, Goran!
It's your happy day!
And they opened the border!
No longer shall we be living
at the end of the world.
We'll become a crossroads!
Not even the wedding
held them back.
-They hope for better pastures.
-I'm off and away!
Joseph, Semek, wait!
Let's have a drink for the road.
We may be back in a week.
I'll send you seeds
for American tobacco!
What's in your suitcase, Semek?
Right now nothing!
When I come back,
it'll be full of gold!
Are you really leaving?
Who knows how long
the border'll stay open.
Goodbye, Semek!
Good luck!
The message is clear!
Hope to see you again
in this world, not the next!
She's forgotten you already,
Michael.
-What is it, Misha?
-A tummy-ache.
Have some water, it'll pass.
Goran, you're the only
real man here...
Verona!
A handsome Gipsy boy
gave me a ring to keep.
I took his ring and weep
I don't want a lover yet!
Michael had you, didn't he?
You were his.
They shouldn't have married.
An earthquake!
Misha!
The end of the world!
Calm down, folks.
It's just a storm.
Lighting struck the tree.
It's not a storm.
It's a sign from God.
-I can't find Misha!
-He was sleeping in the barn.
Go and find him.
Misha!
Here's his hat.
What's wrong, lovey?
Blessed Mary!
It was an earthquake!
All the houses sank
into the ground.
The earth will swallow us.
Semek's house
is straight again.
Don't go in there, children!
Do we sleep in the loft, Mum?
Lord, why do You try us so?
As usual.
Nothing happened to Verona.
The inn's sitting there
snug as an arse on a nightpot.
It sank a bit,
but we can still live in it.
Live in it, then. We're moving.
Let's take Semek's house,
children.
'Bye, Daddy!
Don't be silly,
we had a good life here!
They left and God straightened
their house.
And we're in the shits again.
All these rose-hips,
we'll have a lot of wine.
I'll be an innkeeper
like my father.
-Blow on it, Mummy.
-Show me.
It's going to rain.
Let's run to the brook.
No.
What if we get drenched?
All right,
but whoever spills
any hips, loses.
And... go!
I'm going to win!
She's cheating!
She jumps like a goat!
I won!
Don't drink icy water, Jenik.
Do you hear?
I'm thirsty and
I have a tummy-ache.
Blessed Mary! You're burning up!
Quick, he's dying!
We'll save him.
Lord, be merciful...
The prayers aren't helping.
The Lord has forsaken us.
Drink, you'll feel better.
The sacred herbs will help.
You Christians mouth prayers
all day.
You'd do better
to see justice done!
Even your blessed Mary's
sick of you!
Not me, I'm half Jewish.
What about my son's murder?
I confiscated all the guns!
-Goran's too?
-He didn't have one!
If you suspect him,
bring me proof!
I suspect you all.
The city police are here!
Oh shit!
-Where's the patient?
-She just woke up.
You're our last hope,
for the whole village.
You should have sent for us
sooner.
My boy died, Doctor.
She's all I have.
I'll pay anything.
Money's not all.
Just save her for me.
Sergeant, test this right away.
Don't cry, Jirinka.
Your children are in heaven.
Let's have some fun.
Make you forget.
It's healthy, too.
Get out, you heathen!
God has forsaken me
because of your filthy mind,
you lousy hunchback!
One more arch! You could
have had your organ!
We've taken measures to
stop the epidemic.
The infection is from animals,
probably smuggled sheep.
Yes. Shoot them.
Water...
Drink, Katka.
-Wake up, smuggler.
-Are the sheep yours?
You're under arrest.
Why?
All the children
are on your conscience.
He's drying hemp here.
Burn the filthy stuff.
He only minds the sheep!
-Martin, say something!
-Be quiet, Lucie!
Doctor!
What is it?
She can't breathe.
I'm sorry, but...
How can they live here?
My children...
Katka!
Right, I'll accept that
the sheep are only his.
But you're all growing
poppies and hemp!
Nothing else grows here.
If you can't live off the land
we'll move you away.
This is a free country
and you're under surveillance.
Sure, Captain.
If you break the law again,
I'll have all your crops
destroyed.
Yes, General.
No, Martin!
Lucie...
He's forbidden everything,
even arse-kissing.
It's Goran's fault
for bringing them!
They didn't help us, anyway.
They lock away an innocent,
and let a murderer go free.
Martin!
Lucie!
I'll wait for you,
the baby and me!
If they don't release him,
Lucie won't last the winter.
He took all the blame.