THE EVENT
based on the story with the same
title by A. P. Chekhov
Calm down, Jaka.
There, go there.
Leg.
Easy.
There, take it.
Marjan.
Marjan, come on.
What time is it?
- Hurry up.
Come on, Mira.
Are you ready?
- Yes.
Did you hear the wolves?
You're wearing that?
- It'll be cold on the road.
Hold the horse.
Easy, Mira.
As if they're coming down. - They won't,
there's no ice in the mountains.
I'm not afraid of wolves.
- Fools aren't afraid. Prepare the dog.
Lets go, Mira.
If way over river isn't working
we'll have to come back.
It was working yesterday.
I was reading in newspapers that wolves
are intelligent. - You don't have to be
afraid now, they stayed in mountains.
You think it's possible?
It's possible, everything's possible.
The Bedekovic forest is near.
- Then the sawmill is close too.
Here's the forest.
Look.
We shouldn't lose our way.
You're right. It's better to wait.
Easy, Mira.
We won't long like this, are we?
Is it a wolf?
No, a bird...Easy, Mira!
Wolves won't come here.
Are you going to the faire?
Stand here and don't move.
Sawmill is somewhere here.
Don't think I feel sorry for Mira.
What?
Don't think I feel sorry for the hourse.
She isn't for work anymore,
we have to sell her.
I'm not sorry for horse,
but I thought how father left
and never came back.
Now mother left and didn't return.
She sent you a blouse.
Yes.
If you leave I'll be left alone.
What did you eat?
Where'd I go?
It just came to me.
Why are you laughing?
When I was child, there was a fairy
at my grandpa's.
She was like a picture. With long hair
and beautiful voice when she sang.
But she always hid her legs.
Once she slipped
and under the skirt there was a
horse hoof.
My grandpa laughed and said to me
'Look at the horse hoof of our Marica'.
She just looked at him,
tapped with legs and...
...off to the skies.
As a rocket.
- Indeed. No one saw her after.
It's a beautiful story.
Perhaps it is a story.
Shall we go?
Did you see? - What?
- That dog.
That's a wolf.
- So close?
Keep close to me. He's not alone.
Keep close. Hold the horse. Tight.
Shall we go back? - It's safer to move,
we'll make a torch.
Don't be afraid, Marjan.
Don't be afraid.
Lets go.
Maybe it's a dog, there sawmills here.
- Don't talk, find another branch.
Come on, Mira, come on.
Marjan, come to me.
We're ruined, grandpa.
Light over here, give battery here.
Here, Matijevic.
Matijevic, do you hear me?
He killed him.
Don't Marjan, don't son.
Come on, calm youself,
everything's finished.
Where did the wolves come from,
damned beasts.
It's not real?
- Yes, it's real.
He killed him near sawmill.
He must have rabies.
Why does he carry it around?
- I wouldn't play with it.
He'll get reward.
He'll get it alright.
That over there is a man
the wolf attacked.
A child is with him?
That's his grandson.
The only one.
What is it godmother, you wouldn't
want a wolf, would you?
Did you go crazy maybe?
Don't worry I wouldn't you.
What do you want?
Leave me alone.
Move people!
What got into you?
Come on wolf, bite.
Taking it to a sell?
If chance appears.
I wouldn't give it under 300.
We'll see about that.
Matijevic, do you want a drink?
Of course he is.
Yes, he's floating downstream.
He's not floating but he's in your house.
When he dies he doesn't bite.
You're selling the horse, Juro?
- Yes, I do.
I want to tell you something.
- Say it.
When people get out...
I'll be fast, Marjan.
On Jesus' day one has to watch out, Juro.
- What's going on?
At the last faire that Moholjic
change leader from Luzane was coming
back by himself
he had money for payments...
- And?
It happens. One should be careful.
All sorts of things pass by.
The one in leather coat over there
came back from prison.
I see by the way one holds knife in hand.
That Logar is pure bum.
There are all sorts of people.
- There better be none like that.
They wait up for a man, traveler,
on deserted place
rob him and put knife over his throat.
If you make sound, they will kill you.
People keep quiet.
If they're quiet how do you know?
Don't joke Jura, something's in the air.
I hear it.
It makes waves.
Okay, Blaz.
I'll look around myself better.
Look Juro, look. I can smell blood.
Water flows clear and suddenly it gets red.
Why did you talk for so long?
- Nothing, he just kept me longer.
It must be for something.
He's alone for long time without a faire
and he can't wait to talk to somebody.
He lives on water so his thoughts
flow easily.
All who want to have fun
all who want to spend pleasant evening
tonight at Lipovac
at Stari grad
there is a traditional carnival show
that since a couple of years
is organized by touristical society.
Award for the best mask...
Hi, Juro.
- Hi, Miko.
Selling the horse?
Yes, I do.
- How much does it cost?
3 thousand.
You'll sell it, Italians are buying.
Good bye.
Why don't you take a walk?
I want to be at your side.
As you wish. You'll get bored.
What is it, boy? You'd like a drink?
How much does it cost?
- Three thousand.
2.500 without bargain.
I said 3, I won't give it for less.
You could lower it a bit.
Don't butt in.
How come there are no Italians?
Come on boy, take it.
I'll go for a bit.
You may, just not too long.
- Watch my umbrella.
Take it with you.
- No, I don't need it.
Alright, give it to me.
You wanted batteries for transistor.
A whole package? - Yes, okay.
Just a moment to take a look at magacine.
What's it with you? What are you babbling?
What is it?
What do you want from me?
You don't speak...?
What's that language?
That's my language, I made it up.
You don't know how to make up anything.
You've got a couple of boards in
head missing.
How in head? Boards are in house.
I made up 'boards in head'.
Here are your batteries.
How long will it be like this for God's sake?
Here it goes.
Watch his fingers, he's a real doctor.
Who has no luck shouldn't play.
Hold on you lying son of a bitch.
You found me to...
Oh people...
Let police make a record.
I deserved it when I plant pumpkins with
the Devil.
Why do you watch me?
Are you hungry?
Do you want one?
I want.
Take from mine.
What did you do?
There was hair in it.
What hair?
- Hair. I'll get poisoned.
Why do you hang to me?
Done.
You sold it good.
Three thousand isn't small money
you should celebrate.
Another... - You did well, old guy.
- Another time...
We should leave by day. Are we going,
Marjan?
Last Wendsday my son in law was selling
the same horse and got only 200.
He got his axe in honey, when I tell you.
Are we going Marjan? Lets go.
He's a good merchant, he sold it good.
I sold it in the last minute.
You're not okay with it?
- I wasn't hoping to never seeing it again.
Is that Mira over there?
Perhaps it is. They payed me good.
What are they going to do with it?
They sell meat. There are people who
ear horse meat.
And they make sausages.
You mustn't be sorry.
You're not child anymore.
I'm not sorry.
Wind blows from south.
- Yes.
As long as there's no frost after.
It's good now.
You mean because of the wolves?
Yes.
We'll get home during the day.
When we made it this morning
I'm not afraid anymore.
I believe that wolf was either old or
sick, it wouldn't wander to sawmill.
It better not to meet it.
I love you like this and not like before.
I was thinking about it all.
And what did you come up with?
I remembered a story.
Which one?
It's not a story, it's truth.
In North Pole mothers hunt fish
for young seals
and they just eat and grow.
One day when mother leaves he just
stands and waits.
Until he spends all reserves.
Then when he sees mother's
not coming back
he jumps alone in the water
and hunts fish by himself.
You made it up well.
I know.
The boat is on our side.
You two are returning first from faire.
We have to go home by day, Blaz.
You sold the horse, Jura?
As you can see.
Who are those people?
Nothing good, my Jura.
Wait, we want too, wait.
Did you see who came?
Don't mention them.
Hey Lugar,
did you sell the wolf?
How does it go?
River moves it.
I see but I don't undestand how.
It's connected to the rope
water carries it while rope holds it.
Understand?
I don't.
I don't understand either.
Wood squeaks.
Ducks are coming back.
Good bye, Blaz.
Do you want to spend the night at
my place?
Don't even think about it.
Everyone have their own houses
for sleeping.
I thought you'd stay and catch up.
Another time.
Boatman!
Are you coming this way?
Easy.
You'll all get your turn.
We'll go here, it's shorter.
What are you looking at?
- I looked accidentally.
Spring could come soon.
There will be more winter.
I forgot it has new batteries.
Play that, it was good.
It easier to walk.
Others are returning from faire too.
Don't look back.
Look in front of you.
Aren't those Lugar and the skinny one?
Turn off the music.
Why do we walk so fast?
- We're going home.
Should we go back to the boat?
Give me your hand.
They are after us?
- I don't know, we'll see.
Play the music.
Perhaps we just imagined.
Why would they chase us?
Wait.
Throw the umbrella!
Throw it, don't you hear!
There's sawmill in swamp.
We have to get there.
Hold on to me, grandpa.
Leave it.
Lets go.
Run away with this into the forest.
- I won't! - You have to.
I won't without you.
- They won't hurt me.
I won't, I won't.
You have to Marjan.
- I'm not going without you.
Listen to grandfather.
- I won't leave you.
Marjan stop.
You have to run.
Take the money and run.
Run!
Run, Marjan!
Run Marjan!
Stop you son of a bitch.
Throw it to me.
Do you want one, old man?
I've got mine.
Matijevic, do you have something to drink?
Of course he is.
Yes, he's floating downstream.
He's not floating but he's in your house.
When he dies he doesn't bite.
Good bye brothers.
You killed me.
What?
Let me in.
- What?
My grandpa and me were chased.
I'll give you something warm.
To catch your breath.
I'm here.
I won't go anywhere.
Don't be afraid.
Sit.
I'm afraid.
They want money.
Grandpa told me to run.
Here this.
We'll put it in safe place.
No one will touch you now.
Did you lock the doors?
I locked them, don't worry.
You should go to bed right away.
You'll remember me, you bump.
I'm afraid.
Eat, it's warm.
When my husband returns,
he'll go to the sawmill.
It's not far, only a kilometer.
There's a phone in sawmill.
They'll phone the police.
What is your name?
Marjan.
You must be hungry and cold.
Eat while it's warm.
I can't eat.
Eat.
Eat, it's warm.
When it's warm in the belly
then it goes all around the body.
Fear melts away.
Come on
cry.
Cry out.
Come on, Marjan.
I made the bed.
Wake up.
What?
For a moment and you'll sleep again.
You'll be warm here.
There's a chimney near.
You don't have to cover yourself.
Fire burnes the whole night.
Sleep.
Everything will be alright tomorrow.
Call if you need anything.
Are you alone?
Why are you laughing?
- Everything turns out how I want it.
How do you think?
- Everything.
Do you want me to bring sunny beats?
It's sugar beats.
Mine is sunny.
Is it nice now?
We'll stay forever on the wall.
The one downstairs is my mother.
That woman?
Not woman, she's mother.
Okay.
I ran away to the faire
and neighbours returned me
when sausages got spilled.
What sausages?
You don't remember sausages spilling?
You mean what happened today?
- It wasn't today but now.
How now?
- Now that I remembered.
When I returned mother beat me and
sent me to bed without dinner.
Why did you run away?
Because I didn't want to eat eggs.
Why didn't you want to eat them?
Because they were from my favorite hen.
Those eggs are her children.
Hen lays eggs and chickens come out
and I didn't want to eat her children.
I'm good for nothing.
Why do you say that? - My mother says so,
I'm always weak and ill.
Cause you don't eat eggs. - Lets see what
witch's doing. - What witch? - Downstairs.
She's your mother.
- No, she's witch.
She's feeding us and will kill us
and cook us in the pot.
I read that when I was little too.
Quiet.
Isn't she really beautiful?
She'll discover you're not in your room.
- No, she'll wait for her husband.
What husband?
- My father.
Then he's father not husband.
- Husband, he beats her.
Lets let her wait.
Just don't beat me please.
You're crazy, why would I?
- Please don't.
I will if you're like that.
See how nicely we play.
Do you speak English?
- I don't.
I know.
- Come on, say something.
That's English?
You don't believe it's English?
I believe, everything could happen.
We talked nicely.
Now we have to pack up and go home.
How when our home is far?
There's plenty of snow we'll take sledges.
Come on, help.
Prepare the horse.
It's 3, not one.
It's three you don't know.
- Wait to dance the last dance.
Hurry up, wolves will attack us.
Cover yourself, there will be wind.
Brace yourself not to fall.
Mira's in the middle.
Mira's the fastest horse.
Do you hear wolves?
I hear them.
- They're running after us.
Do you see?
- I see.
Don't let yourself go.
Are they going to catch us?
- No.
They won't, there's our house.
We're going to bed now.
- We won't have dinner?
There's no table in our house as you can
see, that's why we go straight to bed.
Cover me with your cape, it's cold.
What is your name?
Marjan.
Kiss me, Marjan.
Why?
- Cause we're husband and wife.
You know Marjan
I see all sorts of things.
What are you doing?
I look if you have a hoof.
I see nicely.
Workers got ants on railroad
they put railroad on little tables.
Did you go to the forest Fecuan?
Forest Fecuan never existed.
You see grandpa I'm left alone.
Son of a bitch.
- Quiet, you'll awake the child.
Leave that.
Why are you angry with me?
What did I do to you?
Shut up.
I'll brake your head.
It's to go crazy.
I was saying it'll bring unfortune
to the house. - Shut it!
I'll pull your tongue out.
Don't cry.
Take off my boots.
You beat me as it's my fault.
Don't talk too much.
What would you do without me?
I didn't move from house but money
came by itself. - Where from?
Did he have a red blouse?
Is it fair?
As brother to brother.
You're fine brothers.
By blood.
Aren't you a witch, woman.
I was sure we killed the man
for nothing.
Marry Matijevic, I tell you
see what's woman like.
Who would want such a bum?
- Don't start!
Bring brandy.
O Matijevic, do we want a drink?
Just don't shout.
What did you give us?
Give us proper glasses to drink like
men.
Leave it, you'll destroy everything
of mine.
You poisoned my heart...
That's how you sing to those whores
of yours at the faire?
I sing to nobody as I sing to you
my doll.
My people
how harder is to bury a man
than to kill him.
Did you hide him well?
Don't let something happen.
What'd I do without you?
- Leave me.
You poisoned my heart...
Well, cheers.
No.
I scared you?
- You'll wake up children.
Come on, I was joking.
Here,
drink.
We'll together.
You Satan,
from whose face did you take that smile?
Don't touch me, woman.
Be calm.
I didn't touch you yet.
Don't challenge him.
Quiet, you'll wake up the little one.
Quiet, your child will wake up.
My mother, why did you give brith to me?
Don't cry...
Why do you cry?
What is it?
It's nothing.
Let me cry.
Don't cry, don't cry,
don't cry, don't cry...
Lets go.
Ivan?
What is it?
- Get up.
Get up fool!
What is it? What do you want?
We have to kill the kid.
It was enough of killing.
I don't feel like it.
- We have to, he saw everything.
I told you this one would ruin you.
That's Devil in human form.
Leave my husband alone!
Enough.
Enough!
That's our business.
Alright, kill him.
- Oh no, cousin,
you'll kill him.
- Me? How come?
You.
I want you to be my cousin.
Blood ties are the safest.
If something happen, you can't get out
as an accomplice.
Why me? Lets throw a dice.
Alright.
Don't Ivan. He'll trick you,
he cheats.
Shut up.
Do you want first?
- Just pull a card.
King.
Ace.
All boards in my head thumbled over.
Is it over?
Leave me alone.
I've to come to my senses.
What is it?
Leave me alone,
I've to come to my senses.
I want to see her, I want to see  her!
It's your fault, you led him to it!
Satan!
Grandpa!
My grandpa!
Grandpa, where are you?
Grandpa!
My grandpa!
Grandpa, where are you?
Grandpa!
My grandpa!