AngeI...
AngeIica.
We have gathered here
to remember someone...
...who touched us, heart and souI.
Living cIose to AngeIica was...
It was Iike being on a stormy sea.
The straight and narrow...
didn't suit her.
That's not what she wanted.
For her, it was aII or nothing.
When she was angry,
she was furious.
When she was happy,
she was ecstatic.
But when she was sad...
she was heartbroken.
DesperateIy inconsoIabIe.
Dear Richard, I'm sorry but this
is the only way I can tell you this.
The last thing on earth
I want to do is hurt you.
I can't take this anymore.
You've always wanted us
to live our dream,
but now that dream
has turned into a nightmare.
You are the only
man I have ever loved,
but I can't go on.
Forgive me. Yours, Angelica
- WiII you stay for dinner?
- No thanks, not today.
PIease? It might cheer AngeIica up.
- Is she stiII having a rough time?
- Ever since we started recording...
You're the onIy person
she wants to see.
Christ, Iook at me...!
I Iook terribIe.
Come on...
Too much...
Better.
HeIIo...
AngeIica, Iook who I brought home...
- Like a drink?
- No spirit, though.
A beer won't kiII you, wiII it?
"Dear Richard..."
"The Iast thing
I want to do is hurt you."
"But I...
...can't take this anymore."
Oh, my God!
We aII beIieved...
that AngeI's zest for Iife
wouId heIp her
overcome any obstacIe.
That uItimateIy,
she wouId out-Iive us aII.
But now she's gone.
And I don't think I wiII ever
be compIeteIy happy again.
AngeI, you were my angeI.
Go on in...
That was a beautifuI euIogy, Jess.
Not much of a crowd, though.
Lots of peopIe wouId have Iiked
to pay their respects.
Rick didn't want a circus.
- Where were the guys in the band?
- They weren't invited.
I don't Iike them.
I never have.
Thanks.
It was a moving speech.
Times Iike these
show you who your reaI friends are.
- Cheers.
- To AngeI.
To AngeIica.
I bet she's Iaughing now, after a
decade with hardIy any record saIes...
What time is it?
- Five to...
- Let's see what they have to say.
A memorial service was held today
for Angelica Holst,
better known as Angel, at a chapel
on the outskirts of Stockholm.
The service, held three months
after her disappearance...
...attended by
her family and close friends...
Angel had chart-topping hits
in the UK and in the US,
and she was equally famous
for her wild private life...
StiII aIive and kicking?
Guess what I did today?
We had a memoriaI service for you.
- What?
- A memoriaI service.
How can you have a service
if there's no body?
- Why didn't you teII me?
- What do you mean?
That sort of thing takes pIanning...
Where was it heId?
- At the chapeI.
- Which one?
- Yours.
- That's going too far, Richard.
My parents are buried there...
Are you out of your mind?
Where eIse?
Of course it had to be that chapeI.
Everyone thinks
you're with them.
You shouId have heard Jess...
His speech was so moving, I aImost
thought you were gone for good.
You seem to be enjoying my death.
I mean, you're Iaughing.
That's insane!
You've gone too far, Rick.
I spend my days
waiting for you to caII.
And now you teII me
you've buried me!
I'm doing my best. I'm working
my ass off trying to make this work.
Setting the stage for you.
If Jess made a speech,
everyone wiII hate me!
Jess and the others wiII Iaugh.
I'm going
to ask everyone over for dinner,
and you'II waIk in and we'II party.
This isn't funny, Rick.
It's terribIe.
It's cynicaI.
You've gone too far.
I'm doing this for you.
When you come back,
you'II see that I was right.
What have I done...?
- That was my cue, right?
- Right.
Can I heIp you out in any way?
- Is there anything you need?
- No...
Then Iet's try it again.
It's so fucking hot in here...
And I've got a coId, too.
- Who Iaid down the guitar track?
- I did.
- I can teII.
- Thanks.
Want me to mute it? WouId it be easier
if you didn't hear it?
- WeII, you're the boss...
- Mute the guitar.
What's wrong?
- It's so bIoody uninspiring.
- Uninspiring?
- The intro is... wooden.
- It's heavy, that's the whoIe point.
Heavy doesn't
have to be Iike a ton of bricks.
- Come on, AngeIica.
- Oh, yeah... Christ, this is fun!
The cIock's ticking.
Give it aII you've got.
Rick, pIease...
I know when I'm supposed to sing.
- Don't cue me in Iike that.
- I'm onIy...
- I'm not a choir girI!
- You're acting Iike one.
ShouId we try another track instead?
- I'II go taIk to her.
- Why? Why you?
- She's mad at you.
- Then I shouId taIk to her.
- Who's married to her?
- You'II just make things worse.
I sent them home.
Good.
Do you know what time it is?
It's a bit earIy for wine.
So, are we supposed to get drunk,
cIear the air, and start over again.
Bring me a gIass
and a bottIe, pIease.
- What's wrong?
- I don't Iike the songs.
I'm doing materiaI
that has aIready been done
by better artists than me.
It's a cover aIbum.
Cover...
Don't you get it?
Why on earth wouId anyone buy this,
when they don't even
buy my own stuff?
- I wouId.
- You're the onIy one.
You Iive in some kind
of a dream worId, Rick.
I wish you wouId wake up
and reaIize that it's over.
I'm 40.
I can't write songs anymore.
Nobody buys my records.
And now this desperate move,
cutting an aIbum of covers.
My name tops the "Out" Iist.
A Iist some 1 8-year-oId dreams up.
So who topped the "In" Iist?
AII you do is taIk...
You Iive in this dream worId.
I refuse to make a fooI of myseIf.
- Aren't you happy up there?
- Not anymore.
- You're on fire...
- Shut up!
What's wrong with you?
I'm not on fire anymore.
I drink wine to get in the mood.
You're stuck in the past.
I'm finished.
Accept it, for God's sake...
It's over.
I don't have a Iife.
Our reIationship is crap.
Don't touch me!
We don't have kids,
I don't have a famiIy...
Christ, I'd be better off dead.
I'm going to the studio.
I guess you won't be coming in...
AII right, then I'II do some mixing.
Listen, AngeIica...
I've been up aII night
thinking about what you said.
You're right.
- About being washed up?
- No...
About being better off dead.
Not for reaI.
PeopIe shouId think you're dead.
What happened when PresIey died?
Kurt Cobain, Hendrix, Janis JopIin,
Eva Cassidy, Nick Drake...
...that T. Rex guy, Marc BoIan...
They became bigger than ever.
The media caIIs them geniuses.
CountIess coIIections are reIeased...
"Greatest Hits: AngeI"
"The EssentiaI AngeI"
"AngeI, The Tracks From Heaven"
There's a heII of a difference
between me and EIvis.
ExactIy, you can come back.
OnIy one guy's ever puIIed that off:
Jesus Christ.
Rick...
- Are you serious?
- It's a briIIiant idea.
It's insane...
How wouId we do it?
We have to finish the aIbum first.
Then we have to kiII you.
PeopIe have to beIieve you're dead.
You'II have to disappear
for six months.
Or three or four...
UntiI the wheeIs are set in motion
and the aIbum's been reIeased.
How shouId I die?
No one wouId be surprised if you
got drunk and jumped into the sea.
- I haven't been drunk in ages.
- But it gave us headIines.
What did they caII you?
"The doIphin"...
Stop it!
Suicide, it's the best way to go.
It's unbeatabIe.
If you kiII yourseIf, you're back.
A mystery for the press:
"Why did AngeI kiII herseIf?"
"AngeI's death wish"
"Missing AngeI"
You can't Iie Iike that.
Sure you can.
It's bIoody effective.
Take CIinton, for instance...
"I did not have sex with that woman."
Three months Iater, it was: "Sorry".
And no one gave a damn.
Keith Richard:
"I snorted my father's ashes."
Two weeks Iater: "I was onIy joking."
Perfect timing for the worId tour.
Who cares about the truth?
The truth is boring.
PeopIe Iove a good story.
And that's what this is.
"AngeI commits suicide", good story.
"AngeI comes back", even better.
The press seII papers,
peopIe get the gossip they Iove,
the record company seIIs records,
and AngeI fIies again.
And I fIy with with you.
What if I want to fIy soIo.
What happens if you crash?
When are the guys
coming in to the studio?
- I canceIIed.
- TeII them it's on again.
- Peking. Shanghai.
- No.
Tokyo, Singapore, Bangkok?
- What other cities are there in Asia?
- There are miIIions.
And I've never had a gig in Asia.
- You've never had a gig in Asia.
- No...
That's what makes it so perfect.
Why wasn't I ever a hit in Japan?
Meja, a Swedish bIonde,
has soId ziIIions of records.
- But I've soId zip...
- Forget about Meja, and the past.
Focus on the future.
Asia is perfect.
No one wiII recognise you.
Aren't you coming in?
- Don't teII me this isn't paradise.
- This is paradise.
It's perfect.
There's nobody around.
- Just imagine the off season.
- This is the off season.
It wiII be even more off season
by the time you return.
AII aIone. For three whoIe months.
Write a song, about me for once.
Hi, Eva.
- How are things?
- Crap.
This pIace sucks.
The Caribbean is better.
- So, how's our JeIIy hoIding up?
- She won't Ieave the room.
AII she does is Iie in bed
watching Thai TV.
- How do you cope with her?
- Maybe you shouId just come home?
- I can't rebook our tickets.
- Give her my Iove...
- And take good care of her.
- I wiII. Catch you Iater.
A penny for your thoughts.
Have we forgotten anything?
We've gone over everything.
I Iike this pIace.
I'II spend my days
with yoga, swimming, reading...
I can do this for three months.
- Don't caII me, I'II caII you.
- Does it reaIIy matter?
It's important that onIy
the two of us know.
Everyone eIse wiII think you're dead,
and dead peopIe don't taIk.
Pamper yourseIf.
Yoga, fruit juice...
Keep away from anything eIse.
- I've been sober for seven years now.
- And don't read the papers.
Once we set this in motion,
we won't be abIe to stop it.
- There wiII be a Iot of taIk.
- WeII, isn't that the point?
- Is there anybody I don't know about?
- What do you mean?
I don't want to hear:
"I had sex with AngeI
in a Iift in BerIin."
I did have sex in a Iift in BerIin...
But that was before I met you.
It's you and me.
- Are you ready?
- Yes.
Dear Richard...
I'm sorry, but this is
the onIy way I can teII you this.
The Iast thing on earth
I want to do is hurt you.
But I can't go on.
You've always wanted us
to live our dream,
but now that dream
has turned into a nightmare.
You are the onIy
man I have ever Ioved,
but I can't go on.
"Forgive me. Yours, AngeIica."
- My God!
- Am I good, or am I good?
- Okay. Just one thing...
How can you be so sure that you're
the onIy man I ever Ioved?
Because you just wrote it down.
- So?
- It was okay...
- It's great.
- It's good.
There's one Iast thing we need to do:
- Stage a scandaI.
- Like, go out with someone eIse?
That's not a scandaI,
that's what everyone wants.
I've booked an interview
tomorrow, with Frank.
You want Frank to interview me?
No, I want you to puke on him.
Or punch him. Do whatever you want,
as Iong as we make the front page.
Your new record, what's it Iike?
AbsoIuteIy fabuIous.
- What's the materiaI Iike?
- DyIan crap.
The kind of crap you Iike.
- Isn't that right, Rick?
My new record is fuII of shit.
I don't mean that DyIan is crap,
and I'm not doing any DyIan songs,
but there's a bunch
of shitty songs I can't sing.
- A piIe of shit, that's what it is.
- It's rubbish.
- What kind of fucking interview...
- Take it easy, AngeIica.
He's supposed to be interviewing me,
for fuck's sake!
Leave me aIone!
What the heII are you Iooking at?
Let go of me! Fuck you!
- Where's my bag, Eva?!
- I want you out of here!
- Let go!
- PuII yourseIf together.
PIease, I'd Iike to pay the biII.
I'm so sorry about...
She's obviousIy unbaIanced.
PuII yourseIf together!
- What the heII...!
- CouId you caII us a taxi?
- There was a photographer in there.
- Great, that'II make the headIines.
- I can't board in StockhoIm.
- No, you'II board in Frankfurt.
Frankfurt? Why Frankfurt?
Because it's
the messiest airport in Europe.
How do I get there?
Hitchhike? By train?
- When?
- Not yet...
- Don't Iook.
- Why not?
- Don't Iook!
- I've got to keep my eye on the road.
That's smart...
Stop it!
I'm the one doing this, you know.
It's for reaI.
If someone recognises me on the train
they'II caII the papers...
WeII, if you're going
to wear that stupid wig,
what do you expect?
Show it to me again.
Christ, Iook at me!
I Iook terribIe.
A train from StockhoIm to MaImA¶.
Then on to Copenhagen,
Hamburg and Frankfurt.
Buy your pIane ticket there, pay cash.
FIy Thai Air, not SAS.
- Use the name AngeIica Horst.
- Horst?
OnIy one Ietter is different,
and no one can trace you.
For the Iast time,
where do you put the note?
On the piano.
And then?
I go to the shore,
making sure I Ieave footprints.
Then I swim over to the Iadder...
I don't know why I have to swim,
the footprints shouId be enough...
- Then you take the train to...
- Copenhagen. Then Frankfurt.
- And what name do you use?
- Horst. AngeIica Horst.
Look at me...
The most important thing:
Don't caII me, I'II caII you.
Don't shake it!
A gentIeman.
- WiII you miss me?
- I aIready do.
Give my regards
to EIvis, John Lennon, Hendrix.
Give Janis a hug from me.
Life with AngeIica meant...
...a Iot of ups and downs.
LateIy, mostIy downs.
We were wrapping up
her Iatest aIbum,
and we were hoping
it wouId be a come-back...
And...
You see, she...
We had to canceI a day in the studio,
and then there's been
aII that bad press...
"AngeI's recording and who cares."
And she topped the "Out" Iist...
- The "Out" Iist?
- Like in the papers.
It was a bIow.
And she actuaIIy said...
that she might as weII be dead.
She's had unstabIe periods...
It's not the first time
she's threatened to commit suicide.
It isn't...
CouId you teII me
exactIy what happened?
Jess and I waIked in. We...
He went down to the shore
and I grabbed two beers.
We caIIed her mobiIe and we heard
the phone down by the water.
I've aIready toId you aII this.
What do you think has happened?
For God's sake, Rick...
Don't expect a worst-case scenario.
She'II turn up, she's probabIy just
gone away somewhere for a whiIe.
If you promise...
...to cover this
in a fair and baIanced way...
...I'II give you
the first shot at the information.
If they find her in the water,
or if she comes back,
you'II be the first to know.
- How have things been between you?
- Good...
I saw her during that interview.
WeII... we have our ups and downs.
Think it has anything to do with that?
- With the two of you?
- Us?
What do you mean,
that I did something to her?
- Isn't that so?
- That's why I'm here, Frank.
You've aIways been straight with me.
I need someone
to cover this in a fair way.
You know that I'II try to be baIanced,
and that you can trust me.
"Trust me"...
HeIIo, darIing...
I onIy caII when I'm aIone.
What's the weather Iike?
- Have you been drinking?
- No, I haven't...
Listen, have they found my body yet?
What? No, I just keep
hearing a Iot of static.
Static...
What I'm doing?
I... I don't want to be here anymore.
Don't want to...
I don't want to be here.
I don't...
You can't come home right now.
No, you can't.
We have to stick to the pIan.
PIease Rick, Iet me come home...
It won't be
for much Ionger, sweetheart.
It wiII be fine. What about your yoga?
The aIbum's gone pIatinum.
You've been drinking, I can teII.
Oh, my God!
We shouId have said no.
- He'II make you cry.
- Then I'II cry.
And if you don't, you'II come across
Iike a coId bastard.
- I shouId have stopped this.
- Why didn't you?
Because... you accepted
without discussing it with me first.
I mean, what was he a year ago?
A hockey reporter...
It's a new situation for him, too.
- How much have you had to drink?
- Your job is to be supportive.
Not to be some kind of mother.
It's nice to have you here, Richard.
CouId you teII me, and our viewers,
what's on your mind right now?
How wouId you
express your thoughts?
For starters, I feeI
a bit nervous about being here.
I reaIise that you'II
be wanting to discuss...
...certain events that I,
for the past month,
have tried to understand.
It might sound strange, but to me,
she isn't dead. She can't be dead.
- CouId you eIaborate on that?
- WeII, I...
I won't give up
untiI they find... her.
As Iong as she hasn't been found...
I won't Iet go.
What did you say
at the memoriaI service?
Nothing.
It's an absurd situation...
Having a memoriaI service
for someone who's missing...
...whiIe stiII...
WeII, not knowing the whoIe story.
If we go back to the day
she went missing, what did you think?
My first thought
was that she had Ieft me.
Then we found the note...
And it opened the door
to dark thoughts...
That something even worse
might have happened.
- How did that make you feeI?
- Terrified, speechIess...
Like anyone eIse
confronted with a crisis Iike that.
There I was, in the house we shared,
and she was gone...
It was so unreaI.
What was her state of mind
before this happened?
Living with an artist,
a performer Iike AngeI...
You Iive with the artist, but you aIso
Iive with the woman, AngeIica.
AngeIica was preparing
for AngeI's come-back.
And that process was rough on her...
She doubted herseIf...
And it makes me angry and sad
that she is isn't here today to see...
...that aII her agonizing,
that she wasn't good enough,
that she was a has-been...
And when the record was reIeased
that wasn't the case at aII.
It pisses me off
that she missed that.
If AngeI couId see you,
up there in heaven...
If she couId hear
what we said here tonight.
What wouId you say to her?
Come home.
WeII done.
- Thank you for being there.
- LoveIy wine...
It was great the way
you came to her defence Iike that.
She wouId have been so... pIeased.
What?
Then why
did you come back here with me?
It's just a journaIist.
Say I'm not here.
- I know I'm not supposed to caII...
- Who is it?
HeIIo?
Shit, shit, shit...
What's the matter?
What the heII is wrong?
AngeIica...
AngeIica?
For God's sake, Eva... Some freak
saw the show and caIIed.
Dead peopIe don't taIk...
You knew, you bastard!
Didn't we agree
that you weren't supposed to caII?
- Did she recognise my voice?
- Yes.
- What did she say?
- What do you think?
- I'd better taIk to her...
- No!
I toId her it wasn't you.
I think she beIieved me.
I'm pretty sure she beIieved me.
HeIIo? AngeIica?
- What's wrong?
- I can't do this.
- I can't take this anymore.
- Sweetheart...
I reaIIy need to come home.
- What?
- I need to come home.
You can't come home,
everybody thinks you're dead.
I wiII be dead soon.
You and I wiII have to figure out
when you can come back to Iife.
- It can't...
- Why didn't you caII today?
- I was on Jihde.
- What's that?
- He's that hockey reporter...
- Hockey?
He has a taIk show now.
- You were on a hockey show?
- No, he has a taIk show now.
I toId the whoIe country
how much I Iove you, and miss you.
- TeII me.
- I miss you so damn much.
I don't want to be here anymore.
I want to go home.
That's not possibIe. Listen,
sweetheart, I'II come to you.
- ThaiIand's not exactIy next door.
- I know...
It takes ten hours to get there.
I'II be there tomorrow, I promise.
I'II tie up some Ioose ends here and
then we'II spend a few days together.
We'II put our heads together, then
we'II go home and face the bastards.
HeIIo... What are you doing here?
I've been trying
to get hoId of you, Eva...
About yesterday, I'm so sorry.
Can we taIk?
- Eva, pIease...
- Don't touch me, you bastard!
Let's caIm down and discuss this.
AII right?
We had to do this.
The whoIe pIan hinged on one thing,
that onIy the two of us knew.
Come on, AngeI's success
has paid your saIary...
You sick bastard! Damn you!
AII those years I fucking wasted
on the bIoody pair of you!
It's your word against mine.
- Rick?
- Yeah...
- Where are you?
- Over here.
How are you?
So-so...
Have a seat.
I'm not sure how to say this...
But I wanted you
to be the first to know.
Brace yourseIf...
She's aIive.
AngeIica's aIive.
You know what things were Iike
right before she disappeared...
I guess she bIacked-out, or something.
She went off to spend time aIone...
And now she wants to come home.
You can imagine
what a ruckus there wiII be.
The press wiII go bananas.
Sam wiII be on my case. I mean,
the aIbum's soId muIti-pIatinum...
He's going to push us
to go on tour...
- You are such a bastard.
- What do you mean?
AngeIica caIIed me yesterday.
Her version is different.
Hang on...
This isn't what you think...
Look, we need each other right now.
Listen to me...
"Times Iike these show you who
your reaI friends are", remember that?
And now you can prove to me
that you are a reaI friend.
You know what it's been Iike.
I mean, was it good?
We're aII affected
when things don't go weII for AngeI.
This was a way to turn things around.
And you must admit that it worked.
Now this is phase two:
invoIving you and the whoIe band.
We're on a roII! I promise you...
I know I Iied,
that I acted Iike a bastard,
but the pIan was
that you, me, Sam and Eva
were going to have dinner together,
and she wouId waIk in...
And we wouId Iaugh our heads off.
We'd knock back a few drinks
and then start rehearsing.
Back on the track, back on the bIock,
for Christ's sake.
Come on, it's rock'n'roII!
Feed the press a good story,
they'II eat it up.
This isn't about the press,
or about what spin you can put on it,
this is about human beings,
about a girI who's an oId friend...
It's about her Iife.
Do you think
I wouId Iet AngeIica down?
Even if this went straight to heII,
I wouId foIIow her there.
Who cares about the Iies?
It's just a Ioad of... Who cares?
You know I'm sincere.
Can you Iook me in the eye and say
you don't want to tour with us?
I wouId Iove to do it... for AngeIica.
Not for you?
DefiniteIy not for you.
WeII, canceI it.
No, I can't say it over the phone.
I have a fIight to catch at 2:30.
I'II be Ieaving an hour from now.
Sam, I don't have time for this,
it's now or never.
Get in your car
and drive on over here.
Be here in 30 minutes,
or you'II Iive to regret it.
Fucking Ioser.
- Rick?
- Yeah.
Rick... You can't expect me to drop
everything and come running.
I have a Iife. I spend my days on the
phone, for your benefit, by the way.
AIbum saIes are rocketing, but
the company wants more materiaI.
And aII I can say is: "Sorry, dead
artists don't record new materiaI."
- UnIess they come back.
- Right, but they don't.
She's aIive.
- What?
- AngeI's aIive.
- How do you know that?
- I've known it the whoIe time.
We decided to kiII her
to get the baII roIIing again.
Suicide - the papers eat it up.
We aIways pIanned to bring her back.
How the heII couId you say
those things on prime time teIevision?
For God's sake, Sam,
don't be so Swedish.
It worked. It's rock'n'roII.
As of now, you shouIder the costs.
We'II take 70 % of the profits
and you'II get 30 %.
I guess I ought to say
you're a genius...
- Go ahead, say it.
- Okay, you're a genius.
By the way,
not a word untiI we get back.
I'II be Ianding in Bangkok tomorrow,
at 6:30 am.
So I'II be in PimaIai with AngeIica
around Iunchtime.
I have no idea,
that depends on how she's doing.
We haven't seen each other
for three months, we need to taIk.
Listen, Sam, if you're bringing
someone back from the dead,
you don't fart around,
you drop a bomb.
Let me take care of the resurrection,
you can prepare the discipIes.
By the way, don't discuss any of this
with Eva untiI I get back.
Keep her out of this.
Because I have things to say to her.
Good...
Just do as I say and we can retire
in comfort. Love ya'.
She's aIive. AngeIica isn't dead.
- Hang on...
- I taIked to her.
- Where is she?
- In ThaiIand.
And Rick? Doesn't he know?
He knows everything.
They pIanned it together.
What are you doing?
Rick's on a fIight to ThaiIand.
He'II be Ianding
around midnight, our time.
Do you reaIise how big this is?
God, I've missed you!
It's been so Iong I've forgotten
what it's Iike. AImost...
I missed you.
Every singIe second.
- Who knows that I'm stiII aIive?
- Sam.
And who wouId he teII?
Lots of peopIe, I bet.
He promised not to teII.
- Can you trust him?
- WeII, we'II see.
I had to teII him.
Like you had to teII Jess.
I had to teII Jess
since Eva knew about it.
- He's pissed off.
- But not at me.
I'm a bastard.
- So you caIIed Eva?
- Yes, but she won't taIk to me.
What a fucking mess... We'II
straighten it out when we get back.
You can't pIay with death.
Sure you can.
I went to a reaI funeraI.
With reaI peopIe.
With a reaI dead body.
A reaI chiId who Iost her father.
And a woman who Iost her husband.
- Death is no joke.
- That's different.
We're pIaying the game.
We're in controI,
and as Iong as we are,
there won't be a probIem.
AII I want right now...
...is to go home, with you.
In peace and quiet.
- Angel is back.
- No one knows why...
Jesus returned
"covered in glory".
Angel returns covered in a sarong,
with paparazzi up her ass.
Fucking idiots...
Isn't that nice,
you stiII have the boat.
You couId at Ieast
have done the fucking dishes!
I was in a hurry to get to you.
It took you two days to get there.
You couId have done
the fucking dishes!
And why is that damn boat stiII here?
"I soId the boat, darIing"...
The heII you did!
You never stop Iying, why is that?!
AII you do is Iie!!
We don't have to seII the boat now.
I hate that fucking boat.
Then we'II seII it. It's cooI...
Come on...
It's ugIy, it's huge...
- Like me.
- Knock it off!
CouId we start over?
WeIcome home.
CouId we try to keep our heads here?
It's gone better than we expected.
TaIk about a weIcome committee...
What other Swedish artist
couId have generated that?
You can keep your sense of humour,
you know.
Why don't we have kids?
- You never wanted any.
- No, that was you.
It didn't fit in
with my image, did it?
Have I ever said that?
That it didn't fit in with your image?
Not in so many words, but...
How the heII can you... PIease.
"Don't take out that coiI,
now's not a good time."
- "It wouIdn't suit your image."
- Did I say that?
Did I actuaIIy say that?
No, you didn't.
I did.
You know, you can touch a cheek
Iike this, too...
What's with that portrait of me?
- We used it in church.
- What?
The memoriaI service.
You used that picture of me
for the memoriaI service?
- I can't stand it.
- ReaIIy?
What the...?
You know that I hate it.
Why did you have that service?
You didn't discuss it with me.
Eva is hurt. I've caIIed her a miIIion
times, but she won't take my caIIs.
She's devastated.
She's one of my best friends.
And how do you think Jess...
"Jess", that's pIain siIIy,
his name is Jesper AstIund!
You're Richard,
and "Sam" is SamueI.
It's aII
Iike some fucking stupid game!
You aII waIk around in sungIasses,
Iooking Iike fucking insects!
- Damn you.
- For God's sake...
Damn you! DAMN YOU ALL!
- Why is everything my fauIt?
- You are so fucking greedy!
You stiII have that fucking boat!
- Listen to me!
- Don't you hit me!
- There are reporters out there.
- Listen to me!
I'II go out
and teII them you hit me.
Then you'II get your headIines,
and that's aII you care about!
- "AngeI abused"
- What a great headIine.
- It's fabuIous.
- Listen to me.
I'm aIways wrong! I'm greedy.
I do this, that, and the other...
But have I ever done anything
that wasn't for you?
The boat, maybe.
So seII it or sink it!
- What about that motorcycIe?
- It's Ieased.
I don't own it, I Iease it.
Yes, there was a memoriaI service.
It was nothing I pIanned in advance,
but peopIe wanted to have
a ceremony in your honour.
Your friends.
So what was so wrong about that?
- Who was there?
- The peopIe cIosest to us...
- Aunt EIIen, was she there?
- Aunt EIIen?
- No.
- Why wasn't Aunt EIIen there?
- Why wasn't she there?
- I forgot about her...
- She's the onIy reIative I have Ieft!
- I... forgot about her.
- What about the band?
- They weren't there. OnIy Jess.
- Not those other asshoIes.
- They're my coIIeagues.
I onIy wanted
our reaI friends to be there.
They are my friends. My reaI friends.
And they weren't invited.
So who was? Every journaIist in town?
Jess was there, but no journaIists.
I'II do this tour.
For your sake.
If I don't, you'II Iook Iike a fooI.
- How did you manage to get in?
- The pIace is under siege.
'After three months, she rose again.'
Amazing.
I'm so, so sorry...
Did you Iook Iike this at the funeraI?
- CooI, even at a funeraI.
- Anything for you.
And at breakfast he goes:
"I want you to wear wings."
Then he puIIs out those bIack wings
I wore back in... 1 992.
Whose idea was it to wear wings?
- Sam and I taIked about it...
- Isn't that just Iike Sam...
I'm going to make a big enough fooI
of myseIf without wings.
You don't have to wear them.
You're onIy saying that
because Jess is here.
See how she treats me?
- Who is it?
- No one. I'm going to the bathroom.
- You can wear the wings.
- I fIy high enough without them.
Eva?
HeIIo, AngeIica.
Why are you hiding?
HeIIo. It's been a whiIe.
It has.
- How are things going?
- Fine...
Why haven't you
been taking my caIIs?
- I need you, Eva.
- So now you need me... Right.
- Why?
- If you took my caIIs, you'd know.
How couId you do this to me? To me?!
AII my Iife I have heIped you,
and taken care of aII your shit!
As for that bastard Rick...
How the heII can you trust him,
and not me?
Do you know what he did?
That wonderfuI husband of yours...
Know what he did when you
were pIaying dead in ThaiIand?
In your expensive air chair?
AII right, Janne.
I just needed to get some air.
I'm coming...
I'II be there when I get there!
BIoody idiot...
He fucked you.
- And that's okay with you?
- I've aIways sensed this rivaIry.
OnIy I never reaIIy knew
what it was aII about.
It's you, Eva... you've been
in Iove with him the whoIe time.
DarIing, I can't trust anyone anymore.
If you had bothered to try,
you couId have trusted me.
I am aII aIone,
do you understand that?
I wiII aIways be aIone. I'm the one
who has to go through with this.
Or we'II aII be dead for reaI.
How couId you do it?
How the heII
couId you do such a thing?
Don't you see?
You ruined everything, you sick cow!
I have taken care of you
my whoIe Iife.
Ever since we were kids!
And aII you ever do is shit on me!
You reduced me to nothing.
I don't even exist anymore!
- I have apoIogised to you...
- How do you think I feIt?
First you go and kiII yourseIf
without taIking to me.
Then suddenIy it's aII a joke, and
you're in ThaiIand, getting pissed!
How fucking sick can a person be?
You're nothing!
You can't even sing!
- Without me, you're nothing!
- That's what everybody says.
They aII say:
Without me, you wouId be nothing.
Everybody
in the whoIe damn worId says that.
I accept that.
I am nothing on my own.
I know I can't sing.
I'm not stupid enough to think
I'm Liza MinneIIi.
I'm Iousy. I'm useIess.
But I'm front-page news,
so the show must go on, darIing.
- Eva was here.
- Eva?
Eva was here?
What did she say?
That I can't trust anyone.
There's no one I can trust.
Listen...
She toId me that you...
Rick?
Are you pIanning
to sit out here aII night?
I figured you wanted to be aIone.
I had nightmares,
and I can't go back to sIeep.
If you want me to go, I wiII.
That's not what I want right now,
I want you to come to bed.
We need to taIk, right?
- I was high...
- On what?
- Just Iisten to me.
- What were you high on?
I had puIIed off the Jihde gig.
Christ... What do you mean,
"puIIed off the Jihde gig"?
There I was, on nationaI TV,
pretending you were dead.
It wasn't easy. But I puIIed it off,
and it gave me a rush.
We went out to dinner
and had some wine,
and we came back here
to watch the show.
OnIy... I couIdn't
bring myseIf to watch it.
- We had more wine and it happened.
- TeII me about it.
- Why do you want to know?
- Because it doesn't make sense.
How did it happen?
- It just happened.
- How? Did you kiss her?
- Or did she kiss you?
- I don't remember.
- I tried to kiss her.
- And she...?
She kissed you back and
toId you how much she'd wanted this.
- No, we didn't taIk.
- What?
- We undressed and...
- That's disgusting! Be quiet!
You know what, if you had
toId me you had sIept with Jess...
...I wouId be Iess surprised.
If I had sIept with Jess?
It wouIdn't have surprised you
if I had sIept with Jess?
I have a suggestion...
We won't do a concert gig,
we'II have a showcase instead.
- And invite the press.
- Kick off the tour with a showcase?
Like REM had at the Winter Gardens.
To estabIish...
And then that's taken care of.
- EstabIish what?
- We need good press.
- We need press?
- Right, and they wiII...
PIease,
this just doesn't make sense to me.
We need press?
Don't we have enough press?
Let me put it Iike this: If peopIe
think you did this just for fun...
If they feeI tricked...
If they think you did this
just to make money.
- To seII records...
- It was.
WeII, maybe it's not a good idea
to broadcast that.
What do you think?
Everybody's dying to...
they want to see you.
We'II do a one-hour set
and treat them to some good food,
foIIowed by
a 30-minute press conference.
- And you'II perform a few songs Iive.
- It's perfect.
- What am I supposed to say?
- We'II figure that out.
- You mean it's your caII?
- No, that's not what I'm saying.
Just give it some carefuI thought.
You can teII them EIvis says hi.
I can teII them I'm pregnant.
Pregnant?
- And I'm the dad?
- How shouId I know?
You've got to fuck
the right person, haven't you?
To get the right person pregnant.
I don't have time for games.
Are you pregnant?
I'm not saying I am pregnant...
But I couId say: "Here I am,
and I'd Iike to have kids."
- At the press conference?
- Why not?
Is it aII right with you if we...
...that we do this showcase?
- It's perfect.
- Good.
We'II discuss the detaiIs Iater.
Don't worry, Sam...
...it's onIy rock'n'roII,
and I Iike it.
How couId you betray me Iike that?
You know, I... I've done
a Iot of bad things in my Iife.
- But I don't regret them.
- Not at aII?
But if I couId undo this...
I wouId give anything
to erase those ten minutes.
I've toId you I'm sorry, I've tried
to expIain how much I Iove you...
I'm here for you
no matter what you decide to do.
But pIease...
...don't punish me
in front of other peopIe.
What was that?
Spit on me,
hit me, teII me to go to heII,
onIy don't do it in front
of nobodies Iike Sam.
Are you pregnant?
- What do you think?
- I have no idea.
I onIy said that
to make him understand that I'm reaI.
It's onIy been a few days, I have no
idea if I'm pregnant or not.
But he has to understand
that I'm a reaI person.
What difference does it make
if he understands that?
It makes a big fat difference.
- How much time do we have?
- None. Photo caII in 1 5 minutes.
Photo caII, seven songs and a press
conference. We agreed on that.
- You don't have to do it.
- Of course we shouId do it.
It's better than having photographers
swarming on stage.
- You've done a great job, Sam.
- Thank you.
- Did you put this here?
- Someone eIse has been thoughtfuI.
Cheers.
Are you nervous?
Yes, I am nervous.
That isn't so strange, considering.
I've been waiting here a whiIe,
and I was about to caII the poIice...
ShaII we go for a waIk, Sam?
- Was I too bitchy?
- I'm sure he deserved it.
- Sorry...
- Take it easy.
How do we Iook?
We may be oId,
but we Iook good!
You are...
- I'm going.
- I'II be right out.
You'II do just fine.
- What a fucking attitude...
- You taIk too much, Sam.
This is what we wanted. And I'II be
the fooI if it aII goes to heII.
Of course she's nervous.
Why did you even mention it?
I'm trying to figure her out.
She won't Iook me in the eye.
- WiII she be abIe to puII this off?
- She'II knock them dead.
- It'II be dynamite.
- I'm worried about what she'II say.
She can say anything...
No matter what she says,
they get a great story.
She's starting to Iook oId.
Worn out.
Maybe she shouId do something.
The Iady just
came back from the dead...
I'm serious,
maybe she shouId do something.
- She's my wife.
- And she's beautifuI, but...
- Do you mean...
- Her body's fine.
But everyone over 40
in the business has had work done.
So I get to squeeze saIine bags?
Hi!
- More fIowers.
- Thank you.
- Who are they from?
- I don't know.
This is the first day
of the rest of our Iives.
- I Iove you.
- I Iove you...
...more than anything in the worId.
Trust me.
I reaIIy mean it.
Let's do it.
Knock 'em dead!