Hello... agent 166 here.
Hello it's the police station.
Hello... hello.
This is the police station... hello.
Let's go.
He's dead.
Should have arrived?
Looks like it.
Let's go.
Okay.
Come on.
The new agent from London is here.
Looks like the detective has
high hopes for him.
What hopes? More like another agent
for us to kill.
Let's go.
Lady do you need a taxi?
Got a light?
"Flying Horse Night Club"
Where am I staying?
The Crown Hotel.
Thanks.
Although you have my life
but you don't have my soul.
Because in my heart
there's only one person.
My life has gone numb
but my soul is still alive.
No matter what you do
you don't have the key to my heart.
I don't ask for much
just some time together.
It might only be a dream
but I'll treasure every second of it.
Why linger on a sad life... one may ask!
Makes sense if I can at least
keep my soul pure.
For my love for him
the one I can never forget.
Check that babe out.
Where?
Judging from her jewellery
she must be rich
...and she's quite a looker.
Have you seen her before?
No.
I'll go up to her.
Go on.
Hey when did you get here?
You look preoccupied
what are you looking at?
Hello!
Who are you?
Such a lovely occasion and yet you ask?
What are you doing?
Are you alone? Let me keep you company.
Do I know you?
I'm 403 now you know me.
Let me keep you company.
You must be drunk.
What's the mission?
Drunk? I'm only intoxicated by
your beauty.
That man there with songstress Dolly...
He is Cheng Tiehu. You take a look
He's our lead.
Come on
...we're friends now.
Please leave right away.
The next point of contact.
Got it! Don't be such a party pooper.
The bowling alley at 9 p.m. tomorrow.
Come on dance with me come on.
You hit me?
How dare you!
You should be flattered.
You must dance with me come on.
Come on...
What are you doing?
Please stop bothering the lady.
Who the hell are you? Beat him up.
It's alright...
It's over...
Put all the damages...
on my bill.
Okay
Where are you staying?
I'll give you a lift.
Oh where's my necklace?
Let's go.
Get back on stage.
A pretty lady like you
...shouldn't be drinking out alone.
That's just too dangerous.
You have a point.
You should get some rest.
See you.
Bye.
Sorry I forgot to return this.
God it's broken!
Let me take a look.
Should I fix it?
You know how?
I'll try.
Quite precious I must say
Must have cost you around $100000
Very good. How do you know?
You paid too much for it.
I'd only charge you $85000.
You?
"Cheng Tiehu Manager Echo Jewellery"
So you're in the business.
Mr. Cheng my name is Luo Na.
Are you here on a vacation?
No actually I'm here to see someone
Might as well...
buy some good quality diamonds.
Excellent
Should you need to buy any jewellery
...my store welcomes you always.
It's fixed.
Thanks.
I don't know anyone here
I'll certainly pay a visit to your store.
Please give me a good price
for the jewellery.
Of course it'd be to your satisfaction.
I should go now.
Alright.
Bye.
You still remember me?
Good timing right?
Where did you go with the woman?
Don't be jealous.
Let me tell you she's something.
Of course young and pretty
...and she looks rich.
Not that
I saw a picture of her in the locket
It's her with the "Bald guy"
The "Bald guy"
I think I should check her background.
Haven't you heard that after
he got arrested
a woman has got hold of all his wealth?
Could that be her?
Get me a towel.
What is it Dolly?
Chief
Tiehu has just met a woman who's new here.
She's very rich could have links
with the Bald Guy.
Tell Tiehu to check on her background.
Keep on guard.
Yes chief.
Dolly.
Here.
Good job at the phone booth.
You'll be rewarded.
Thank you chief.
Lucky you!
Zhicheng.
"Unloading coffin by River Xia
on April 17th"
Please come inside.
Is the manager here?
Yes he is.
Mr. Cheng.
Hi!
What a surprise welcome!
Please come upstairs.
Have a seat.
Smoke?
I'd like to buy some diamonds.
Sure.
Inlay diamonds or loose ones?
Whatever!
I'll show you.
OK.
I know that you won't be interested
in these.
2 days later we got a new shipment
coming in.
The 17th?
The best grade from South America;
You won't be disappointed.
Then I have to wait two more days.
I'll be bored.
I could show you around.
You won't be bored.
You will?
Sincerely.
Thanks.
"Bring Tiehu to meet the Bald"
Come with me.
I think she could be the Bald guy's
mistress.
It'd be a big deal if she really is.
Where is she now?
We said goodbye after the prison visit
she said she wanted to go shopping.
Now that we've confirmed her identity...
What's the next step?
What's the rush?
I'm not hurrying.
Rather we'd get it over with
this being a big issue
I must ask for the chief's instructions.
I'm Luo Na.
I've been looking for you everywhere!
What for?
The Bald guy gave you a large sum;
You should give it up
what are you waiting for?
The money's for me
...you've got nothing to do with it.
What? You want everything to yourself?
We deserve the money.
At least we should get half.
Half of it?
What a joke! He treated you guys...
really well when you worked for him.
Be smart Luo Na.
Bald guy's men wanted to split
the money with her.
From the way she speaks
I could imagine that she isn't
easy to handle.
You aren't getting a dime.
Fine don't regret.
We'll see.
Show me what you've got.
I'm not scared of you.
Follow them.
Traffic unit... traffic unit.
We await your order.
Send back up... send back up now.
Got it.
Let's go.
Attention all units.
Urgent...
Pull over the car
with a license plate AA2058
Grey roadster.
Two young male suspects in the car.
They're armed.
Please pay attention... over.
What is it?
Go.
Chief.
B1 and C7 have arrived.
I'll see them right away.
Yes.
The chief will see you right away.
Chief I've told Tiehu and others
...to spy on Luo Na.
Nothing suspicious so far.
She's indeed Bald Guy's mistress.
These are the pictures I took.
Pass it to C7.
Yes.
Keep spying on her.
There's a hidden infrared camera
in this jewellery box
...which can film in the dark.
C7 give this to her as a present
Yes.
Tell her to meet me
at Fair Lady Beauty Salon.
I want to take a look at her.
Yes.
Why did you give this to me?
I walked pass an antique shop
...and sort of took a fancy to it.
I thought you might like it.
Thanks.
Luo Na about the shipment I told you
I've already made an appointment
with the seller.
Where?
Fair Beauty Salon 3pm tomorrow.
I'll go with you.
Sure.
Why isn't she here yet?
It's only 2:50.
And why does she want to meet me
...in a beauty salon?
I don't know
I guess because beauty salon is a
favorite for women.
I'll set your hair Mr. Cheng?
Sure.
Please come inside.
Miss Luo would you like to read
the headlines?
What do you want?
Just a chat with you.
What about?
The Bald Guy.
Move over...
The police is here.
Let's go before we get into trouble.
Let's go.
Go!
Pick him up.
Mr. Chen.
Mission accomplished sir.
Have a drink.
Thanks.
Who were they?
What do they want from you?
Sorry I shouldn't pry.
There's no point in keeping things
from you.
Remember the man
I visited in the prison the other day?
His nickname is "Bald Guy".
Have you heard of him?
A very well known smuggler.
I was an orphan since I was very young.
He has been taking care of me.
Before he got arrested
he left me a large sum of money
to safe keep.
And his men have been stalking me
...tracking me down and hassling
for the money.
I've been on the run.
Who'd have thought that
they could find me!
If it wasn't for you...
I'd have been kidnapped by them.
Don't say that Luo Na.
We are friends.
I can't let them bully you around.
They are ruthless.
I'm totally on my own.
They could kill me sooner or later.
What should I do?
Don't worry.
I'll do whatever I can to protect you.
You?
Why are you so nice to me?
You should know.
You're lying!
No I'm very sincere.
Don't lie to me don't let go!
I love you trust me.
Stop it.
I know you have a lover.
Who?
The singer.
Dolly? She's just a fling.
Since I've met you
I fell in love.
Come in.
What do you want?
You should know that it's my room.
So what? Where's Tiehu?
Haven't you got any manners?
Don't pretend that you're from
the upper crust.
I know that...
you're the mistress of the Bald Guy
the smuggler.
So you've done your homework.
Of course.
It's not a big deal that you have money.
I'm warning you Tiehu is my man.
Get your hands off him!
Don't even think of stealing him
away from me.
I don't want to have a conversation
with you.
I'll call the police if you won't leave.
Don't try to mess with me.
Little obnoxious tramp
if you don't speak clearly
...l'm gonna kill you.
Very impressive!
We need a talent like her!
She's loaded with money...
why'd she join us?
If I want her then it's not up to her.
She has no choice when I want to pick her.
Tell Tiehu to arrange with her.
Bring money to my yacht to see
the merchandise.
Yes.
Please sit down.
This is Mrs. Jin and this is Miss Luo Na.
Have you brought your money?
Yes.
All there.
These are the best grade.
Miss Luo Mr. Cheng Tiehu sent us.
The bank's safety deposit box is ready.
He told us to escort you to the bank.
This is Mr. Cheng's card.
Please come in.
Thanks.
This is it.
Alright...
Let's go.
Leave her here.
Hurry.
A woman let's take a look.
Luo Na.
Are you looking for Miss Luo?
Has she gone out?
Not since she returned this afternoon.
She looked pale when she came back.
If you could please open the door
Sure.
Thanks.
Luo Na...
"Luo Na like we said before
we'll eventually claim back the money...
which was left to us by the Bald Guy.
If you dare to call the police
we'll kill you for sure"
Who are you?
I'm her friend.
Didn't you spot the...
no visitors sign outside?
Sorry.
She's still in critical condition.
No guests.
Please leave right away.
Sure.
Doctor you must save her.
You see she has no friend...
or relative here other than me.
Don't worry we'll try our best.
Thanks.
Detective.
Well done Ai Si.
What's my next step?
What they're trying to do is obvious.
First they sold you the diamonds
at a low price. Then
they stole it all back pretending to
be Bald Guy's men.
So you're forced into a dead end.
I guess their goal...
is wanting you to join their group.
If that's the case
I'm looking forward to it.
But they didn't know that...
we've already caught all of
Bald Guy's crew.
But why are they forcing me
...to join them?
I reckon they take you to be
Bald Guy's mistress
...and they need a talent like you.
So they want your money and you.
They are so wicked.
Go with the flow infiltrate them.
According to our sources
they have a large network
...robbery smuggling
drug trafficking... you name it.
Find out where their HQ is
...and try to blow it up.
We'll work with you
...to put them in jail.
I'll try my best.
I have some gadgets for you.
A bottle of perfume...
on this end;
And it works as a tranquilizer
on the other.
This is a camera
you can take pictures in the dark.
As for this purse
press here and bullets will fire
from both ends.
Could kill within 20 yards.
As for this watch...
there are two time bombs inside.
It can attach to any metallic surface.
When in danger just turn...
the gem on the headband
through these fine wires;
We'll receive your signal
...and it will show us your location.
We'll rush to save you.
Got it?
This is a dangerous and tough mission.
You've got to be very careful.
Since it's my job
and to get revenge for Zhicheng
I'm not afraid.
Good luck!
You could be hassled by the Bald guy's men
That's why I checked you out
from the hotel.
Where am I staying then?
Stay at my place for a while.
I'll take care of everything.
Let's go.
Who is it?
Me.
How about a truce?
I know everything about you.
You've come to an dead end.
What are your plans?
I don't know what you mean.
Fine I'll be frank.
You know we're sort of in the same boat.
You don't want to be hassled
by Bald Guy's men
...and you want to be alive.
You also wish to maintain your
luxurious lifestyle.
There's only one way out.
What?
Join us.
Dolly.
I've asked for the chief's permission.
What kind of an organization are you?
The Dark Angels
Tiehu say if eventually I do agree
to join;
Will they guarantee my safety...
and a good lifestyle?
The chief is mighty impressed with you.
You'll be in danger should you refuse.
Is that true?
Fine I'll join you.
Come with me.
Chief
B1 and C7 are here with Luo Na.
Line up everyone.
Yes.
Send them in.
Yes chief.
We're here to recommend Luo Na to join us.
Hello chief.
Luo Na are you sincere in joining
the Dark Angels?
Wholeheartedly.
Once a member you'll never get out.
Are you willing to give everything
including...
your life and absolute devotion
to the society?
I do.
And that should you betray us
you'll be shot to death.
I understand.
No regrets?
No.
Good.
What is it?
Bangkok branch wants to report to you.
Chief.
Connect the Bangkok branch.
Yes.
The call's ready chief.
This is the HQ.
The goods have been shipped
and it'd be...
unloaded at 2am in a deserted island
in Pattaya.
Yes.
We already have the diamonds of
Pinjun Jewellery Co.
Police is keeping watch
we can't use the original plan
Change of plan. Use toys instead...
and shift to Flight 709.
Yes chief.
Let's welcome our new member.
Welcome.
Thank you everyone.
Serve the organization well.
Yes.
I'll show you around.
This is the most dangerous;
Tunnel of Fatal Light.
Anything through here will get burnt.
Look.
You must wear one of these
protective gear.
Attention all departments...
The chief is inspecting...
Follow me.
Our experts have a new creation.
It's still in testing progress.
Not only that it provides a boost of
energy
...it will also regenerate your youth.
When we succeed
...this will be the only
drug people purchase.
I believe we'll be successful.
A4.
Here.
Show her to her room.
Yes madam.
This is your new home.
I'll give you an important mission
tomorrow.
You must take all orders from A4.
Yes chief.
What a nice room!
Our chief is always concerned that
every member will be settling
in comfortably.
Can you tell me...
what's my mission tomorrow?
You'll know.
Get some rest.
Now you could tell me?
You have to kill someone.
Kill someone?
A special agent of the police.
Where?
Should be here any minute.
This is a special packet of cigarettes.
One blow and poisonous needle
will be shot out
...victim will be dead in three minutes.
I'll do it here?
Action.
Excuse me can I borrow a light?
I'm 009 there's a poisonous needle
inside.
Light up and act normal.
Fake your death three minutes later
thank you.
Congratulations on your first job
well done!
Piece of cake.
You were really calm.
No wonder the chief thinks highly of you.
How do you know that...
he's working for the police?
Since he stepped off the plane we knew...
he's here to investigate us.
You guys are really fierce!
Have some wine.
In the past we've had our oversight
There was a fellow called Xu Zhicheng
who...
infiltrated our society and revealed
our name list.
Luckily I found out in time
and I shot him to death.
Well he should have known better.
Exactly. If or not someone's a spy...
one can't escape my deft eye.
I can tell by just one look.
In that case am I a spy?
If you are a spy then you...
Then you'll shoot me to death.
Right?
Of course not I trust you completely.
Even if you were a spy
but being such a beauty
I wouldn't want to kill you.
Thanks.
Luo Na are you willing to devote
yourself...
to the Dark Angels?
Of course.
Are you suspecting me?
No but I have another challenge for you.
A challenge?
You should know that I find you
very attractive.
Don't do that.
You can't force me.
Fine then. Truce?
What are you doing?
None of your business.
You...
Stop it.
He...
Send Luo Na to her room.
Yes.
Chief.
I beg you to forgive me.
Please spare me just once.
Get rid of him.
Yes.
Are you sure that's my box?
So wicked.
I never thought that...
they'd trick you into this.
I wouldn't let you join if I knew.
What should I do?
I've already joined.
The rule is one can't leave
without orders.
But if you really want to go
...I can think of a way.
But where can I hide?
Even if I can get out
the men who worked for that Baldie
are still after me.
Even if they can't find me
...what will I live on?
Dolly's right.
Gotten myself in a dead end; no way out!
Luo Na.
I'm surrounded by enemies.
Only you are on my side.
Tiehu I know that you love me.
You're my only friend
I want you to protect me.
Don't worry.
I won't let you get hurt.
The chief told you to take this.
It'd counter the anesthetic's effect.
Thanks.
You must be tired get some rest.
Where were you?
I...
I asked you a question.
I was in Tiehu's room.
Really?
Don't be scared.
I wouldn't interfere in your
relationships.
Come here Luo Na.
I like you a lot.
I won't treat you as a regular member
I'll trust you in an important position.
I knew you would.
Oh really?
Because I'm pretty and I'm able.
What else?
Because I am in a dead end.
It's my only chance to shine working
for you.
That's right you will be rewarded.
When all the representatives
from different...
countries are here for the meeting
...l'll tell the others about you.
Thanks chief.
Your second job...
is to attend a swimsuit show.
A swimsuit show?
Only those I think high will be
assigned to this job.
The rule here is
you can't tell anyone else about
our conversation.
Sure.
What were you doing? Napping?
No.
C7.
Here.
Was Luo Na in your room earlier?
Earlier?
She said that she was with you.
She...
Tell me is that true?
Yes what's the matter?
Nothing.
Where were you?
I...
Why did you tell the chief that
you were with me?
What's going on with you?
I couldn't sleep...
and I sneaked into the chief's office.
What for?
I wanted to find my jewellery box.
Did anyone see you?
No.
I didn't get any work done.
I warn you this place is full of traps.
You can get killed easily.
Don't run around like that anymore.
But my jewels...
We'll think of another plan.
The chief was asking me about you earlier.
She was waiting for me here.
What does she want?
She gave me a second job.
She told me not to tell anyone
but you know I won't keep any secrets
from you.
I am to participate in a swimsuit show.
A swimsuit show?
Why her?
She's more able than you.
She's prettier than you.
Don't shoot it's me.
Bald Guy?
You got out?
Where's Tiehu?
Tiehu?
Hurry and tell him that...
the Luo Na with him is a fake.
A fake?
The real one's been dead for two years.
Oh no!
What?
She infiltrated our group!
She's an agent for the police
where is she?
At the HQ.
Hurry we must catch her.
Sure.
Presently I have some good news.
According to our experts
...our drug will be successful.
We will have mass production of it
the daily production to supply
a population of 100000
We'll be controlling half of
the world's market share.
Chief under your leadership
...our society's growth is limitless.
Three cheers for the chief!
Hurray!
Please take a look around.
This is an electronic oven.
Let me introduce you our new member.
Luo Na.
Here.
You'll be A2 from now on.
Yes.
She'll be based in the HQ.
If I'm not around
...you can report to her.
Yes.
I've called this regional
representatives' meeting
...to review what we've done;
And to seek ways for bigger expansion.
Look.
In just a few years we have...
already established branches
in so many places.
Owing to the hard work of you all...
our members will enjoy
...the best lifestyle on earth.
But I've found out that
one of you hasn't been loyal.
A16.
You've made the biggest mistake...
you know?
I...
From the portion of March collections...
you've kept 100000 dollars to yourself.
You've broken our rule.
You must be punished.
If any of you think of making
the same mistake again
...remember what happened to A16 today.
Being a time of unrests in many places
I think it's our chance to expand
our business.
You must all work harder in
your own district.
What is it Dolly?
The Bald Guy wants to see you.
I'm in a meeting ask him to wait.
It's urgent.
Please see us immediately.
Alright game over. Stand up.
What's going on?
She's not Luo Na.
She's works as a police...
C7.
Here.
Come here right away.
Yes.
Chief.
Tiehu it's all because of you.
You must get rid of her for me.
Yes.
Never could guess you'd lie to me too!
Why are you all so nervous?
I wouldn't be here if I was scared.
Who are you?
I'm 009.
Who else is working with you here?
No one;
But there'll be plenty who'll die with me.
How come?
I've set up a time bomb.
You'll all die with me.
Don't panic.
Where is it?
Don't even dream that I'll tell you.
Fine.
You want to blow up my HQ
...you'll know what I'm made of.
Tie her up.
Golden Bay.
Get ready.
Yes.
We're going now.
You won't die a quick death.
Only you'll know when the bomb will blow.
Sit here and enjoy!
Let's go chief.
Be calm when we're heading out.
Don't create a commotion.
Yes.
What about the other members?
No big deal!
Who cares!
Fifteen more minutes to go.
What should we do?
That way... hurry.
No more protective suits.
Forget it. Let's climb through on top.
Which way?
That way.
I've got the chief's permission.
No.
Careful of the machines.
Sure.
The police is here...
Don't shoot...
Upstairs! Hurry!
Come on.
Have you seen Tiehu and Luo Na?
No.
No? Hurry we must catch them.
Hurry go!
What are you doing down here?
She's new I'm just showing her around.
What's to see in such a dirty place?
Be careful.
Have you seen them? Come on.
Go that way.
Go.
You go that way.
Come.
That way.
A snake!
Let's go.
Look chief.
Look!
Shoot them.
Tiehu.
Don't move...
Ai Si are you alright?
I'm fine but they're really violent!
No but you did a good job.
Inform the marine police to
intercept the yacht.
Yes sir.
There's no need to.
Just a few more seconds.
A few more seconds?
Look.