(SWITCH CLICKS)
ED: It was a big mistake
acknowledging this doll.
And through that,
the inhuman spirit tricked you.
You gave it permission
to infest your lives.
NURSE 1: What's an inhuman spirit?
ED: It's something that's
never walked the earth in human form.
It's something demonic.
NURSE 2: So, the doll
was never possessed?
LORRAINE: No, it was used as a conduit.
It was moved around
to give the impression of possession.
Demonic spirits don't possess things.
They possess people.
It wanted to get inside of you.
And given this unusual feature,
the doll will need to be
properly cared for.
- Cared for?
- ED: Mmm-hmm.
It should be destroyed.
(ED SIGHS)
That would only make things worse.
We think it best the doll come with us.
We'll keep it somewhere safe.
That sounds like a great idea.
She's all yours.
(SOUL MUSIC PLAYING ON CAR STEREO)
(ED SINGING ALONG IN FALSETTO)
The dreams I hold
(ED HUMS ALONG)
Memories
Love could be
How much longer, do you think?
Eh, about an hour.
Why don't you put your head back?
Get some rest.
No, you get lost coming home
from the supermarket.
(CHUCKLING) If I do that,
we might end up in California.
Well, so you wake up
to the sound of the Pacific.
- Nothing wrong with that.
- (BOTH CHUCKLE)
I'll pick up Judy on the way.
Ah, that actually sounds so nice, Ed.
We should plan on it.
ED: Uh-oh.
What's this?
(TURNS OFF MUSIC)
You folks need to turn around.
Pretty bad accident up ahead.
Uh, anything we can do?
You a doctor or something?
Or something.
He just meant if you need
an extra set of hands.
Yeah.
We got it covered. Thanks.
Nice doll.
That's what you think.
All right, you're gonna head
three miles back to the last exit.
You'll hop on 26,
that'll loop you around.
- Twenty-six. Got it.
- Thank you, Officer.
(CAR ENGINE STARTS)
OFFICER: A guy and his doll.
(INHALES SHARPLY)
(POP ROCK PLAYING ON CAR STEREO)
I think we missed our turn.
We didn't miss it.
Bridgewater's just up ahead.
Bridgewater? Old Ridge Road.
Where did you get Bridgewater from?
You know what?
I think we missed our turn.
- I'll keep my eye out for the Pacific.
- (CHUCKLING)
(CAR GRATING)
Ed?
- Ed?
- Hang on, hang on.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
- (CAR HALTS)
- Come on.
What just happened?
(SIGHS) I'll pop the hood and find out.
Well, be careful.
There we go.
(MUTTERS INDISTINCTLY)
(TWIG SNAPS)
(WHISPERING) I like your doll.
(LORRAINE GASPS SOFTLY)
I feel cold.
(LORRAINE BREATHING SHAKILY)
LORRAINE: You were just in an accident.
YOUNG WOMAN: I was?
- (CAR HORN HONKS)
- (GASPS)
Sorry. Wires crossed.
That should do it.
Honey, you okay?
(ED GRUNTS)
(GASPS)
(GRUNTING)
(TRUCK HORN BLARING)
Ed!
(BRAKES SQUEAL)
ED: I'm okay.
TRUCK DRIVER: I'm so sorry!
All of a sudden it was like
somebody took over my truck.
I had no control. Are you okay?
- I'm fine.
- (BOTH PANTING)
LORRAINE: It's the doll, Ed.
It's a beacon for other spirits.
(VEHICLE APPROACHING)
(KEYS JANGLING)
(DOOR UNLOCKS)
(DOOR CLOSES)
(DOOR UNLOCKING)
ED: Over here.
(CLEARS THROAT)
(CLOCK WHIRRING AND TICKING)
Father, sooner the better. Yeah?
Yeah.
(FATHER GORDON CLEARS THROAT)
Be not wise in thine own eyes.
Fear the Lord and depart from evil.
(HISSING SOFTLY)
The curse of the Lord is in the house
of the wicked.
But he blesseth
the habitation of the just.
(HOLY WATER SPRINKLING)
Surely, he scorneth the scorners,
but he giveth grace unto the lowly.
The wise shall inherit the glory,
but shame shall be
the promotion of fools.
(HOLY WATER SPRINKLING)
ED: (SOFTLY) Amen.
(CREAKING)
(CLOCK CONTINUES WHIRRING AND TICKING)
We need another barrier of protection.
A holy one.
I agree.
The blessing will only do so much.
That chapel glass we got from
Trinity Church before it was torn down,
where is that?
(SOFTLY) Let us forgive those
who trespass against us
and lead us not into temptation,
but deliver us from evil.
Amen.
(CLOCK STOPS TICKING)
- (FATHER GORDON EXHALES)
- Did it work?
Hmm. The evil is contained.
(CHORUS ON TV SINGING)
Colorful, magical, wonderful, wow!
The Captain is coming
Just look at him now
Super sensational, special and new
The Captain is coming
With something for you
Here comes Captain Kangaroo
LORRAINE: Okay, Judy.
I just saw Mary Ellen pull up.
Go and get your things.
But first put your cereal in the...
All right. Never mind. I'll do it.
(SINGING CONTINUES ON TV)
Captain Kangaroo is who
Will make this day so great with you
Colorful, magical, wonderful, wow!
The Captain is coming
Just look at him now
Super sensational, special and new
The Captain is coming
And you're gonna love him
What's that?
Captain Kangaroo
ED: Oh.
Well?
You're my hero.
LORRAINE: The pizza money
is on the counter
and numbers are by the phone.
MARY ELLEN: Perfect.
ED: And we'll be back early
tomorrow morning.
Well, and take your time, we'll be fine.
Right, Judy?
Yeah.
- So, you'll...
- JUDY: Behave? Yes.
- And you'll remember to go to...
- Remember to go to bed on time.
- Absolutely.
- (ALL CHUCKLE)
- All right, don't forget to...
- To have fun.
- I know.
- ED: That, too.
Did you guys rehearse that, or what?
(ALL CHUCKLE)
(SCHOOL BELL RINGS)
(STUDENTS CHATTERING)
Earth to Judy!
What's wrong?
Nothing.
I'm fine.
Well, it's just a couple more hours
until the weekend.
I'm gonna run to the market for supplies
during my free period.
I'll pick you up after, okay?
JUDY: Sounds super.
MARY ELLEN: Bye, Judy!
Have a good day!
(SIGHS)
(STUDENTS CHATTERING)
(CASH REGISTER DINGS)
MR PALMERI: Mrs. Faley,
it's right over here. Let me show you.
How could you not tell me
what the Warrens did for a living?
Shouldn't you be in math class?
DANIELA: Mary Ellen!
I babysat the Smiths for over two years
and never told you what they did.
Oh, what do they do?
They're podiatrists.
- So not the same.
- (CHUCKLES)
Well, obviously, I'm coming over later.
We do have that social studies project
- that we need to work on.
- Uh...
We don't have any project.
Okay, but how would they know?
She's psychic.
Then, they're heroes.
I think they're concerned parents
who wouldn't want negative influences
around their child.
What negative influence?
'Cause I sometimes stay out past curfew?
Among other things.
So, what's it like inside the house?
Is it all creepy music and cobwebs?
No. No, it's boring suburbia.
The inside of your locker is scarier.
Wait. Whose party,
and why wasn't I invited?
Judy's birthday is coming up,
so we're gonna celebrate early.
You really are the best babysitter,
you know that?
Compliments will get you nowhere.
What about threats?
Did you happen to notice
who's working checkout?
- BOB: Have a good one.
- WOMAN: Will do.
- Thank you so much.
- BOB: See you soon.
You wouldn't.
You know what they call him, right?
What?
(DANIELA SIGHS)
Bob's-Got-Balls.
How you doing?
Hi, Daniela.
(INHALES)
(EXHALES)
(CHUCKLES) Uh...
Hi, Mary Ellen.
(STAMMERS) Is this everything?
- I think so.
- Oh, cool.
You live near the Warrens,
don't you, Bob?
- BOB: Uh...
- Yeah, Mary Ellen's babysitting
for them tonight.
Yeah.
Yeah, I live right across the street.
Do you ever see
anything scary over there?
Like a ghost, maybe?
Bob...
Mrs. Faley went ahead and dropped
a can of tomato sauce in aisle five
and it looks like a crime scene,
so get the mop.
- Ladies. Did you find everything okay?
- Yes, sir.
Bob here is not giving you
any trouble, is he?
- (CHUCKLES) No.
- No.
- Yeah, I got it. Thanks, Dad.
- All right.
I'll do it right after.
So, what'd you see?
At the Warrens'?
- Uh, nothing. Nothing.
- (CASH REGISTER DINGS)
Your total is $3.50, so...
Oh.
But you knew what the Warrens did?
There were rumors, I guess, but...
Rumors. Interesting.
Did you know there's a rumor
going around about you, Bob?
Wait, really?
(STAMMERS) What is it about?
Uh, it's about a girl who has a...
(WHISPERS) Fine. You can come. Stop.
- BOB: Oh. Sorry.
- MARY ELLEN: Sorry.
- That's totally my fault.
- It's okay.
- (CASH REGISTER DINGS)
- Um... So, what...
Bye, Bob. Thanks.
Bye.
Uh, she forgot her eggs, so...
Here.
She likes you.
(CHUCKLES)
There's been an accident.
(SCHOOL BELL RINGS)
(STUDENTS CHATTERING)
Don't touch her.
You'll get obsessed.
- It's "possessed."
- ANTHONY: That's what I said.
Anyways, if you know so much,
why don't you tell us
if you can catch cooties from a ghost?
You can't.
Well, then how'd you get 'em?
- (KIDS LAUGH)
- MARY ELLEN: Anthony Rios!
Don't make me get your sister.
Please don't.
Then go. All of you. Come on.
BOY: Come on. Let's go!
I'm sorry I can't come
to your birthday party, Judy.
You can't either?
My parents said I'm not really prepared
to process death yet.
It's a birthday party.
GIRL: I'm sorry.
MARY ELLEN: Hey, how long
has that been happening?
JUDY: Since everyone heard
about the article this week.
Please don't tell my parents.
I won't. I won't as long as you do.
- I don't want them to worry.
- They're parents.
They're worried about everything
whether they need to be or not.
Are you sure the bullying is
the only thing that's bothering you?
That isn't bothering me.
MARY ELLEN: You know what I mean.
And remember our deal. No secrets.
JUDY: I know.
I don't have any.
What did you get at the store?
A surprise.
- You said no secrets.
- A surprise isn't a secret.
- What is it then?
- It's a surprise. (CHUCKLES)
(JUDY GIGGLES)
(POP ROCK MUSIC PLAYING
ON RECORD PLAYER)
- (INDISTINCT CHATTER, LAUGHTER)
- (KNOCKING ON DOOR)
(BLENDER WHIRRING)
MARY ELLEN: You're gonna make a mess.
Hey! Save some for the cake.
No.
(KNOCKING CONTINUES)
I think there, s someone at the door.
(BELL JINGLES)
I was knocking on the door
for, like, 10 minutes.
(SIGHS) How did you even get in?
Back door. Is this a spirit bell?
- (BELL JINGLES)
- What's a spirit bell?
It tells you if you're in the presence
of any spirits.
- So, it is one.
- JUDY: No.
It's just a bell. My mom collects them.
- (TURNS OFF MUSIC)
- Oh.
Who are you?
She's Daniela,
and she leaves after cake.
Oh, good!
I love cake.
So, Judy.
Don't your parents keep
any creepy stuff around?
JUDY: No.
They keep it all locked away in a room.
Well, can we at least go in and look?
MARY ELLEN: No!
It's not really good for anyone
to go in there.
How come?
Just isn't.
Wait.
Here.
Birthday present.
What is it?
DANIELA: Look inside.
Mmm? (CHUCKLES)
(POP ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
MARY ELLEN: How did you
even afford those?
DANIELA: They're my old ones.
But I only ever used them once
'cause I broke my arm
the first time I put them on.
- (THUDDING)
- You're kidding.
- (RATTLING)
- She looks way more coordinated.
(SIGHS) They're gonna ruin the floors.
Can we go around the block, then?
- I don't think...
- DANIELA: Good idea.
You guys go. I'll watch the cake
and make sure it doesn't burn.
Fine. But don't snoop. Don't touch.
Don't do anything. Please?
Stay in the kitchen. Promise me.
I promise.
(POP ROCK MUSIC CONTINUES)
(DOOR RATTLES)
(SIGHS)
(SCOFFS)
Fuck it.
I am calling out to the spirits
on the other side.
Please unlock this door and let me in.
(DOOR RATTLES)
(SIGHS)
Shit.
(CREAKING)
(DOOR CREAKING)
(SIGHS)
Please don't judge me.
(SCOFFS)
Amen.
(DOOR CREAKING)
Whoa.
(GASPING SOFTLY)
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
What'd you do to get in there?
(TAPPING)
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
(CLICKING)
(GASPS SOFTLY)
(PLAYS NOTES TO
"TWINKLE, TWINKLE, LITTLE STAR")
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
If there is a presence here
in this room...
please give me a sign.
Any sign at all.
Dad?
(SCOFFS)
This is stupid.
(SNIFFS)
(THUD)
(SCOFFS SOFTLY)
(BREATHES SHAKILY)
(ALARM BEEPING)
Shit.
(MUFFLED BEEPING)
(THUDS)
- (BEEPING CONTINUES)
- (DANIELA COUGHS)
(DOOR CLOSES)
You burnt the cake? Daniela.
(SIGHS) Only the top.
Just put frosting on it.
She'll never know.
How'd it go with the skates?
She loved them
until she fell on the way back
and skinned her knee.
Better than breaking her arm.
Where is she anyway?
She's out feeding the chickens.
They have chickens?
(CHICKENS CLUCKING)
DANIELA: Hey. How's your knee?
Oh. (GROANS)
Looks like your jeans
will at least need some stitches.
It's okay.
Accidents happen.
So, are you scared yet?
Scared? What? No.
Who says they're scared?
Kids in my class.
Anthony Rios started it.
I hate him.
Wait. Tony Rios started it?
Do you know him?
Yeah, he's my brother.
Anthony Rios is your brother?
Yeah, I know. Don't hold it against me.
I don't like him either.
You know, he still wets the bed.
You didn't hear it from me.
Or maybe you did, I don't care.
Still, just...
go a little easy on him.
It's been a tough year.
You lost somebody, didn't you?
My dad. Uh...
Did Mary Ellen tell you?
No.
I just knew.
- Um, for delivery.
- (MUSIC PLAYING ON RECORD PLAYER)
Could I do one large, please?
Um, it's gonna be 3506 Wayman Street.
Oh, perfect. Thank you.
(DOORBELL RINGS)
Coming.
(DOORBELL RINGING REPEATEDLY)
(QUIETLY) Hold your horses.
(POUNDING ON DOOR)
Who is it?
(DOORBELL RINGS)
Hello?
Daniela?
GIRL: Is Annabelle there?
Who?
GIRL: Can Annabelle come out to play?
I think you have the wrong house.
There's no Annabelle here.
Yes, she is.
She's right behind you.
- (GIRL GIGGLING)
- (FOOTSTEPS RUN OFF)
People are just...
They're really weird about death.
That's probably why the kids
pick on you at school.
It scares them.
They treat it like it's some disease
they don't wanna get
even though everyone already has it.
But here's the thing.
I used to think it was fatal and whammo.
It's, like, out.
Like turning off a TV.
Then I learned about your parents
and their whole exploration
into the afterlife and stuff...
and they gave me hope.
That maybe life goes on somehow.
Maybe...
my darling dad
is still out there somewhere.
"Darling dad"?
It was a thing.
He was darling dad,
and I was darling Daniela...
Stupid. (CHUCKLES)
He's still out there, you know.
You think so?
My parents would say he is, too.
MARY ELLEN: Where are you going?
Be right back.
(VOICE BREAKING) Dad?
Daniela?
Daniela!
- Where did she go?
- (FOOTSTEPS THUDDING)
MARY ELLEN: What are you doing?
Daniela, you're not supposed
to go down there!
- What are you doing?
- I thought I saw something.
What did you see?
Forget it. It doesn't matter.
(WOOD CREAKING)
- (CREAKING CONTINUES)
- (BREATH TREMBLING)
(DOOR CREAKING)
(JUDY BREATHING SHAKILY)
(RUSTLING)
(BREATH TREMBLING)
(DOOR RATTLING AND BANGING)
- (WIND HOWLING)
- (INDISTINCT WHISPERING)
(RUMBLING)
(MIRROR RATTLING)
(BONES CRACK)
(FOOTSTEPS RUNNING)
(JUDY SCREAMING)
Judy?
(DOOR CREAKING)
JUDY: In thee, O Lord,
do I put my trust.
Let me never be put to confusion.
Deliver me into thy righteousness
and cause me to escape.
Incline thine ear...
MARY ELLEN: Hey! Hey, Judy! Judy.
- (GASPING)
- What's going on? What's wrong?
What's going on?
What happened?
Nothing.
Judy...
I just got scared.
Scared of what?
Sometimes...
I see things.
Like how my mom sees things.
You mean like ghosts?
Where do you see them?
Everywhere I go.
Judy...
Ghosts used to be people.
And not every person you meet is bad...
so maybe not all ghosts are bad, either.
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
Daniela.
- You have to see this.
- MARY ELLEN: What?
It's this case the Warrens investigated
about this girl
who was terrorized by something
called the Ferryman.
Here's a picture of the girl he killed.
Look familiar?
I mean, you two could be sisters.
Here's the rest of the file,
if you want to take a look.
Look at all this stuff.
(GASPS)
How cool.
Okay, this is the file
on the Black Shuck.
MARY ELLEN: The Black Shuck?
DANIELA: It was a case
the Warrens investigated
about a hellhound
that possessed a man in England.
He terrorized the shit out of this town.
What's with the coins over their eyes?
What?
DANIELA: Oh, I don't know.
I didn't get that far.
They used to put them
over the eyes of the dead
to pay the Ferryman, so he could take
their souls to the underworld.
It was his toll.
Okay, we should go.
It's okay.
I sometimes like to snoop, too.
DANIELA: Do you know
what this does, Judy?
I think it's called
a Mourner's Bracelet.
It helps you contact
your lost loved ones.
- What's that?
- Um...
It's a case
my parents investigated recently.
The wedding dress.
It haunts people.
And it makes them violent.
Where is the dress now?
Down the hall in the artifact room.
I mean, that's where all this stuff is.
Right, Judy?
- That's what you said earlier.
- Oh, um...
Yeah.
My dad says that everything in there
is either haunted, cursed...
or used in some ritualistic practice.
What about the doll that's in there?
Because I read this interview
with your dad...
No.
Don't talk about her.
Why not?
She's in a case for a reason.
Okay, we should go.
- I wonder what's on this.
- MARY ELLEN: No, Daniela! Wait!
(WHIRRING)
I command you, unclean spirit,
along with all your minions,
I command you
to obey me to the letter!
Okay, show's over.
Let's go do something else.
Do something
that's actually appropriate.
DANIELA: Come on, don't you
at least wanna hear about the samurai?
What about this one?
I don't remember that one.
DANIELA: How do you play?
Let's find out.
(CHUCKLES)
Okay. Okay, so you draw a card,
and whatever picture it has on it
is the object you try to find
by feeling around inside the box.
If the object you pull out matches
the picture, then you get a point.
You go first.
Okay.
(OBJECTS RATTLING)
(DOORBELL RINGING)
You gonna get that?
Yeah.
Sorry, you guys keep playing.
Oh, got a point.
Nice.
(HEAVY KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Hello?
(SIGHS)
Hi, Mary Ellen.
Hi.
Remember how, at the store, Daniela said
that you were babysitting here?
Yeah. Yeah.
BOB: Me, too.
Anyways, that's why I'm here.
Oh.
Bob, they don't really want me
having boys over.
No, that's not what I meant.
I don't wanna come in.
I just, uh...
I mean, I would, but...
(CHUCKLES) well...
I just knew you were gonna be here...
and I just wanted to come by
and talk to you
without my stupid dad
or somebody interrupting.
Bob's-Got-Balls!
(CHUCKLES) Nice.
You two sharing some pizza?
- MARY ELLEN: I should get the money.
- Yeah.
Are you two, like...
I... I wish. (CHUCKLES)
You know you need to, like,
woo her, right?
- Woo her?
- PIZZA GUY: Yeah.
Guys like Mary Ellen,
they need to be wooed.
You mean girls like Mary Ellen.
What did I say?
Guys.
(GUFFAWING)
So, how do I woo her?
PIZZA GUY:
There's only one way to woo.
It's obvious.
Rock and roll.
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACH)
Here. Keep it.
Sweet.
Thanks, and that means
you can keep this.
(CHUCKLES) Minus one slice.
I enjoyed that in the car.
(SNAPS FINGERS) See you later, Balls.
I would invite you in,
but like I said...
No, yeah, it's cool.
I thought I'd just stop by
and say hi, I guess, so...
I'm glad you did.
Me, too.
Hey, Bob, um...
how come they call you that?
Um...
Well, you know how I'm the equipments
manager for the basketball team?
- Yeah.
- That's why.
There's not really, like,
a story or anything behind it.
Just like, "Hey, I need balls."
I'm, like, "I got it. Balls. Got 'em."
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
I'll see woo later.
You. You. I'll see you later.
I'm gonna go.
Bye, Bob.
BOB: Bye.
(DOOR LOCK CLICKS)
JIM LANGE (ON TV): All right, Carolyn,
even a fortune teller
couldn't have predicted
the place we picked
for your date with Don.
Because who could ever have
dreamed up a place
as unbelievably fabulous as...
Las Vegas, Nevada?
(AUDIENCE CHEERING)
Yes, "amazing" is the word for it.
You'll be flying off for a fling
at the fabulous town of Las Vegas
to be guests
of the fantastic Flamingo Hotel,
a favorite spot along the Vegas Strip.
And, Dawn,
as a little special gift for you...
Can you get your arms around there?
(SWITCH CLICKS)
(FLOORBOARD CREAKING)
Mary Ellen?
Daniela?
(BOTH SINGING)
Happy birthday to you
Happy birthday, dear Judy
(ALL CHUCKLE)
(DANIELA SIGHS) Okay, Judy.
Ready for bed?
This is for you.
What's this?
JUDY: It's an invitation
to my birthday party.
I don't think
many people are gonna come...
but will you?
You see what I got?
I got mine weeks ago.
So, you'll come?
I wouldn't miss it.
(GUITAR PLAYING)
(MAN SINGING)
You sheltered me from harm
You kept me warm
What's that?
Oh, my God.
It isn't.
It is.
(SINGING CONTINUES)
You sheltered me from harm
You kept me warm
You kept me...
(STAMMERS)
Warm
DANIELA: Bob!
You gave my life...
Uh... Um... (CLEARS THROAT)
(STRUMS GUITAR)
(SINGING) Nobody else will ever know
(STAMMERS)
The part of me that can't let go
I would give anything I own
BOB: Uh...
Bob's got balls.
(CONTINUES SINGING)
Just to have you back again
How do I look? Where's my inhaler?
Shit, no, it's in my car.
What am I supposed to do?
You will be fine. It's only Bob.
Just to touch you once again
(STOPS PLAYING GUITAR)
- (STRUMMING)
- (RUSTLING)
(GASPS)
(GROWLING)
- (SNARLING)
- Shit!
Shit!
No!
MARY ELLEN: Bob?
He left.
Hmm, hopefully he went home to practice.
Okay. Back up to bed.
- Daniela.
- DANIELA: Yeah, yeah.
(CHUCKLES)
I'd feel better if you let me stay.
I can wake up early.
- We don't even have to tell Judy.
- No. No, it's fine.
Go home.
But...
But what?
Thank you for coming.
I actually think it helped Judy a lot.
Sorry you didn't get to see any cobwebs
or hear any creepy music.
Well, the Bob thing
was kind of creepy, at least.
(CHUCKLES)
But if Bob comes knocking on this door
late at night,
forget you're you for a minute
and let him in.
(BOTH LAUGH)
Call me tomorrow
and tell me the details.
There will be no details to tell.
(DOOR CLOSES)
(HOWLING IN DISTANCE)
- (HOWLING CONTINUES)
- (DOG BARKING IN DISTANCE)
Shit.
(LOW GROWLING)
(DOOR LOCKS CLICKING)
(DOOR CREAKS)
How'd her dad die?
I don't know if that's
the best bedtime story.
Look who my parents are.
I'm used to it.
Well...
the short of it is that he died
in a car accident.
And the long of it is that...
Daniela was driving.
Was it her fault?
MARY ELLEN: No.
There's only one person
who actually thinks it was her fault.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
- (THUDS)
- (GASPS)
(BREATHES DEEPLY)
Okay.
Let's try this again.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
If there is a presence here...
(CHAIR CREAKING)
(GASPS SOFTLY)
- (DOOR SLAMS, LOCKS CLICK)
- (GASPS)
(PANTING)
(PIANO PLAYS NOTES TO
"TWINKLE, TWINKLE, LITTLE STAR")
Dad?
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(PLAYING
"TWINKLE, TWINKLE, LITTLE STAR")
- (DANIELA GASPS)
- (STOPS PLAYING)
(WHISPERS) Dad?
(BREATHING SHAKILY)
You did this to me!
- (SCREAMS)
- It's all your fault!
Get back here!
- (SCREAMING)
- You did this to me!
(MUFFLED POUNDING)
(CRICKETS CHIRPING)
- (FAINT RATTLING)
- (BREATH TREMBLING)
(FLOOR CREAKS)
(FOOTSTEPS)
- (BOB GASPS)
- (GROWLING)
(RUSTLING)
- (DOOR OPENS)
- (BREATH TREMBLING)
(CREAKING)
(THUDDING)
(LOW GROWLING)
(CHICKEN CLUCKS)
(CLUCKING)
(WHISPERING) No, no, no. Please.
Please, no, no. Don't go.
Don't go.
(CLUCKING CONTINUES)
No, no, no. No, come here.
Come here, come here. No. No.
I'm sorry.
- (SNARLING)
- (CHICKEN SQUAWKS)
(GLASS SHATTERS)
(SIGHS)
(POP ROCK PLAYING ON RECORD PLAYER)
(TURNS OFF MUSIC)
(CREAKING)
(CREAKING CONTINUES)
Judy?
(SIGHS IN RELIEF)
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
BOY 1 (ON TV): Is that why
he picked her up from the closet?
BOY 2: Yes. That must have been it.
BOY 1: He's not gonna pick her up
in a closet, is he?
BOY 2: You stay here
and don't make any noise.
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC
PLAYING ON TV)
- (FAINT RATTLING)
- (GASPS)
(RATTLING AND HISSING)
(WHIMPERING SOFTLY)
(SWITCH CLICKS)
(BREATHING SHAKILY)
- (HISSING AND RATTLING)
- (GASPS)
- (SCREECHING)
(CONTINUES SCREECHING)
(INAUDIBLE) What is happening?
(SOBBING) What is happening?
(LAUGHTER ON TV)
(MAN ON TV) Where's my coffee?
(WOMAN ON TV) Good morning.
ED (ON SPEAKERS): You've been
experiencing supernatural...
(ON TV) Good morning. Where's my coffee?
- (LAUGHTER ON TV)
- WOMAN: Just a second.
- (REMOTE CLICKING)
- (LAUGHTER ON TV)
(GIRL ON SPEAKERS)
He had silver coins for his eyes.
She said his light shows you
the way to the land of the dead.
I just wanna find my sister.
ED (ON SPEAKERS):
And when did she first see him?
GIRL: Not long before he took her.
She said she'd wake up,
and he'd be in her room...
watching her sleep.
The night she went missing,
we both woke up to a noise.
It sounded like a coin
falling on the floor.
She told me to wait in her room.
So I did.
She never came back.
I went to look for her
and ended up in a long hallway.
Filled with coffins.
(TEARFULLY) Last night...
I woke up to a noise.
Another coin being dropped.
(SOBBING SOFTLY) It was like he was...
Like he was calling me.
ED: Have you ever seen the Ferryman?
(GIRL CONTINUES SOBBING)
If you don't pay his toll,
he'll take your soul.
(TAPE REWINDING)
If you don't pay his toll,
he'll take your soul.
(TAPE REWINDING)
(DISTORTED)
If you don't pay his toll,
he'll take your soul.
(TAPE REWINDING)
If you don't pay his toll,
he'll take your soul.
(TAPE REWINDING)
If you don't pay his toll,
he'll take your soul.
(TURNS OFF)
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLES)
(COIN RATTLES)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(COIN CLATTERING)
(FAINT METALLIC RUSTLING)
- (COIN CLATTERING)
- (GASPING)
(COIN CLATTERING)
(METALLIC SCRAPING)
(BREATH TREMBLING)
(COINS CLATTERING)
(BREATHING SHAKILY)
(FLASHLIGHT BUZZES)
Shit! Shit! Shit! No.
(BREATHES HEAVILY)
(SCREAMING)
(WHIMPERING)
(SCREAMS)
- (DOOR RATTLES)
- Judy! Judy!
Judy!
(POUNDING ON DOOR)
Judy! Open the door, Judy!
(FAINT CREAKING)
(SHOUTING FADES)
(CREAKING CONTINUES)
(GASPS)
(BREATHING SHAKILY)
(CREAKING CONTINUES)
(BED CREAKING)
- (SCREAMS)
- (JUDY SCREAMING)
(BREATH TREMBLING)
(GIRL GIGGLING)
(GIRL WHISPERING)
I like your dolls.
(FAINT CRACKING)
- (ROARS)
- (SCREAMS)
- (THUD)
- (GASPING)
MARY ELLEN: Judy! Judy!
(JUDY SOBBING)
- (CREATURE ROARING)
- (BOTH SCREAM)
(CREATURE SNARLING)
- (DOORBELL RINGS)
- (DOOR RATTLING)
- (SCREAMS)
- MARY ELLEN: Go out the back!
(LOW GROWLING)
We're trapped.
(PHONE LINE RINGING)
- LORRAINE (ON PHONE): Hello?
-Oh, thank God. Mrs. Warren?
Mom?
LORRAINE: Mary Ellen? Judy?
Is everything okay? What's going on?
Judy's fine. Um...
Something is happening
inside your house...
and I don't think it's safe
to go outside.
We're not really sure what to do.
LORRAINE: Can I speak to Annabelle?
I'm sorry?
LORRAINE: You need
to give her a soul, dear.
- What?
- LORRAINE: A soul. She wants her soul.
(BOTH GASP)
Give me her soul.
(BELLS JINGLING)
(DANIELA SOBBING)
(GASPING RAPIDLY)
(RINGING)
(RINGING CONTINUES)
JUDY: Wait! Don't!
- (RINGING CONTINUES)
- I'm so sorry.
MARY ELLEN:
What are you doing here?
(RAPID BUZZING)
(TYPEWRITER DINGS)
(TYPEWRITER KEYS CLACKING)
Annabelle.
The doll. She's the one
who's doing all of this.
A doll?
(TREMBLING) She wants a soul.
I... I just wanted to see him again.
What did you do?
(TEARFULLY) I wanted to tell him
I'm sorry.
I know it was my fault.
Daniela...
what did you do?
I let her out.
What else did you touch?
(BREATH TREMBLING)
Everything.
- (STATIC CRACKLING)
- (CLOCK TICKING)
- (CREAKING)
- (MECHANICAL CLANGING)
MARY ELLEN: Run! Run! Go!
(STIFLED GASPING)
Mary Ellen!
It's her asthma. She's having an attack.
- JUDY: The inhaler's in her car.
- (WHEEZING)
I'll go get it.
No! Let me!
(PANTING)
(STIFLED GROANING)
(GASPING)
- (SCREECHES)
- (DANIELA SCREAMS)
(PANTING)
(GASPS)
(QUIET GROWL)
(RUSTLING)
(WHIMPERING)
(SCREAMS)
(CREATURE GROWLS)
(THUDDING)
(JUDY SCREAMING)
- (GROWLING)
- (CONTINUES SCREAMING)
Judy! Run!
(GROWLING)
(BREATHING SHAKILY)
- (MUFFLED THUDDING AND SNARLING)
- (SCREAMS)
(MARY ELLEN COUGHING)
JUDY: Mary Ellen!
Here.
(INHALES DEEPLY)
Are you okay?
(COUGHING)
Where... Where's Daniela?
She came after you.
(DANIELA SHAKILY) Mary Ellen?
Judy? I'm up here.
No. That's not Daniela.
Something has a hold of her.
I can feel it.
What do we do?
We have to find Annabelle.
We have to put her back in the case.
Do you know where she is?
No.
(JUDY BREATHING SHAKILY)
Wait, wait, Judy, don't.
Not all ghosts are bad.
Right?
(SIGHS)
(MARY ELLEN WHISPERING)
Not all ghosts are bad.
(VOICES CHATTERING INDISTINCTLY)
(WOMEN WHIMPERING)
(INDISTINCT, WORRIED CHATTER)
(WOMAN SHOUTING IN JAPANESE)
(WOMAN WAILING)
(MAN 1 SHOUTS)
- (WOMAN SHOUTING, WHIMPERING)
- (MAN 1 YELLING)
- (MAN 2 SPEAKING JAPANESE)
- (WOMEN WHIMPERING)
(SWORD SWISHES)
(WOMEN SOBBING)
- (MAN 2 SHOUTING IN JAPANESE)
- (WOMEN SCREAMING)
(SWORD SLICING)
- (METALLIC CLASHING)
- (WOMEN SCREAMING)
(JUDY SPEAKS INDISTINCTLY)
(VOICES STOP)
What did you say?
Come on, let's go.
(BREATHING SHAKILY)
(INDISTINCT WHISPERING)
Come on.
(DOOR CREAKING)
I'll get her.
No, no, no. No! Just stop! (GRUNTS)
Where do your parents keep the key?
I don't know. It's never locked.
(DOOR RATTLES)
I know where the key is.
- I'll get it.
- No! No, don't.
I'll do it.
(EXHALES)
Judy!
I got it.
Our Father, who art in heaven,
hallowed be thy name.
(CONTINUES PRAYING INDISTINCTLY)
(DOOR CREAKING)
(WOOD CREAKING)
(BREATHING SHAKILY)
(COINS CLATTERING)
(GASPING)
(GASPS)
(VOICE SHAKING) Oh, my God.
(LAMP THUDS)
(BREATH TREMBLING)
(GRUNTING)
(METALLIC SCRAPING)
(SCREAMS)
JUDY: Give us this day our daily bread,
and forgive us for our trespasses
as we forgive those
who trespassed against us.
(DOOR CREAKING)
Mary Ellen?
MARY ELLEN: Go!
(FOOTSTEPS RUNNING)
Daniela.
- Daniela, please!
- (MARY ELLEN YELLS)
(GRUNTING)
(GASPING RAPIDLY)
Daniela, stop!
(DANIELA YELLS)
(SNARLING)
Stop! (SCREAMING)
(GASPS)
(CONTINUES SCREAMING)
(PROJECTOR WHIRRING)
ED: I command you,
unclean spirit,
along with all your minions,
now attacking this servant of God.
- I command you to obey me to the letter.
- Judy, run!
In his name,
they will take up serpents.
(SCREAMING)
...with his hands and condemn all evil.
I command you, unclean spirit,
along with all your minions,
- to obey me to the letter.
- (POSSESSED MAN) No, no.
- I, who am a servant of God,
-(DANIELA SCREAMING)
I command you, unclean spirit,
along with all your minions,
now attacking this servant of God...
(SNARLING)
(SCREAMING)
(ROARING)
- (CREATURE ROARING)
- (JUDY SCREAMING)
- Judy!
- (SNARLS)
(SCREAMS)
(WOMAN SPEAKS JAPANESE, SCREAMS)
(SNARLS)
(SCREECHING)
Judy! Judy. Judy.
Get the doll!
(CREATURE SNARLING)
(MECHANICAL CHIMING)
- (METAL CREAKING)
- (CLOCK TICKING)
- JUDY: Close it!
- I'm trying!
JUDY: Hurry!
(GASPING)
(MARY ELLEN STRAINING)
Our Father who art in heaven,
hallowed be thy name.
Thy kingdom come, thy will be done,
on earth as it is in heaven.
Put her in!
Give us this day our daily bread,
and forgive us for our trespasses
as we forgive those
who trespassed against us,
lead us not into temptation,
but deliver us from evil...
- (NOISES STOP)
- (ALL PANTING)
Amen.
(STAMMERS) Is it over?
The evil has been contained.
- (THUDDING)
- (ALL SCREAM)
Bob?
- Are you guys okay?
- Yeah. We're okay.
(ALL PANTING)
- Are you okay?
- BOB: No!
There was a werewolf outside!
You saw the werewolf?
Yeah.
He saved me from it.
You did?
Yeah. Yeah.
Kind of.
Maybe we should talk about this
somewhere else.
(MAN ON TV) Good morning from the staff
of WPKW-PV6 in Hartford, Connecticut.
- (VEHICLE APPROACHING)
- This is Hartford, Connecticut,
the land of steady habits...
My parents.
Shit!
You're not supposed to have boys over.
I think that's the least
of our concerns right now, Bob.
Yeah, yeah.
I should probably still get going.
Hey, listen, um,
so, Homecoming is coming up
- and I would really like...
- Yes. I'll go.
With me?
Yes, if the Warrens don't kill me first.
(BREATHES DEEPLY)
We tell them everything.
(DOOR CLOSES)
JUDY: Mom!
LORRAINE: Judy!
What are you doing up so early?
JUDY: Don't get mad...
ED: What happened to your car?
Here we go.
We'll have our own party, huh?
- What?
- Can you please take that off?
It won't always be like this, I promise.
You know, and sooner or later,
you'll find people who understand.
And as for young Anthony,
he better hope I don't run into him
anytime soon.
Ed.
(DOORBELL RINGING)
Happy birthday, Judy.
JUDY: Thank you.
Happy birthday.
I, uh, had a little talk
with my brother.
Thanks.
Come in.
MARY ELLEN:
Is it okay if my boyfriend joins?
Sure.
Um...
- Hi, uh, thanks for having us.
- ED: Hey.
Bob's-Got-Balls.
No kidding.
- GIRL 1: Hi, Judy!
- Happy birthday, Judy!
- Happy birthday!
- GIRL 2: Hello, Judy, happy birthday.
- ED: Hey, guys, welcome.
- Keep comin'.
- (BOTH CHUCKLE)
ANTHONY: Happy birthday, Judy.
- Anthony?
- ANTHONY: I'm really sorry.
Am I still invited?
Sure.
LORRAINE: Daniela?
I have something for you.
DANIELA: For me?
(SIGHS)
You found out the hard way
that there is a lot of evil
in this room.
But you know what
I actually like about it?
All the evil in here...
reminds me of all the good
that's out there.
Darling Daniela.
Did Judy tell you that?
No. Your dad did.
He also tells me that he misses you.
And to stop being so hard on yourself...
'cause it was not your fault.
(SOBBING QUIETLY)
(SNIFFLES)
(BREATHES DEEPLY)
Thank you.
Um... (SNIFFLES)
I'm sorry.
LORRAINE: Oh.
It's okay.
You're young.
You know, when I was about your age,
I once ran off with a boyfriend
for three days
without telling my parents.
(CHUCKLES)
I unleashed a demon.
So not the same thing.
Well, okay. True.
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
Does Mr. Warren know
about this boyfriend?
He was the boyfriend.
ED: Anybody wanna hear a song? Whoa.
- BOY: Yeah!
- (ALL CHEERING)
ED: All right, okay.
(POP ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)