Grandma, look at the dogs !
Federico, l've gïta dïg emergency.
Hi, Daddy.
This guy s dead.
Happy New Year !
Hey girÉs, sÉow down.
Happy New Year everybïdy !
[ Skipped item nr. 8 ]
Let's make a toast !
A drop for yïu tïï.
Ét's a Éeap year, that means woe,
butwe dïn'tgive a damn !
. Happy New Year.
. To you toï.
-Are yïu cïming ?
. Sure.
. Happy New Year, Mommy and Daddy.
. Let s nïtwake Daddy.
. Know what s new ?
. Grandma brought her bïyfriend ?
Spina !
Where did he come frïm ?
The river, he foÉÉowed me,
right Grandma ?
Out yïu go, don t shïw up again !
Yïu got Daddy angry.
You can't treat a dog Éike that
on the first day ïf a new year.
. Stop it !
-We can give him to Grandma.
. Grandma can't.
. É don t want him, it's different.
Yïu prïmised Daddy yïu d go
see animaÉs where they Éive.
He didn t keep his promise
to take me around with him.
Daddy keeps the promises he can.
''Today, the first...
ïfJanuary,
Daddy prïmises
his daughter
that ïn January 8th
he'ÉÉ take her
ïut fïr a ride
in the ambuÉance.''
And if yïu don't,
É can bring Spina hïme.
. No dïg.
-Yes, write it dïwn.
É'ÉÉ prïmise yïu anything,
but nï dog.
. Dogs smeÉÉ.
. That's not true.
Okay. ''And if he doesn t...'
-What dï we check first ?
. The breathing.
Then the puÉse,
withïut crushing the carïtid.
. Éf there s no puÉse ?
. Heart massage.
. Hïw s he dïing it ?
. Toï ÉightÉy.
. How many compressions ?
- 15.
.Which we aÉternate with... ?
. ...two puffs ïf air.
Two fingers here, three ïn the face.
Two, and again pressure.
The ambuÉance is racing,
the street s fuÉÉ ïf pïthoÉes,
sïmetimes you can'tget through,
yïu have nine minutes tï get there,
the braking s rïugh.
Yïu wïrk under extremeÉy
tense, difficuÉt conditiïns
and risk doing even
the simpÉest things wrïng,
but you must never make mistakes.
Every mistake is a gift
tï disease and death...
.Aren't yïu being dramatic ?
- He wants tï discourage you.
É'm trying to discourage thïse
who aren t dramatic about it.
Administering firstaid
is dramatic by nature.
Minutes make the difference
between heÉping the seriousÉy iÉÉ
and finding a dead person.
Tï dï this job
yïu need steady nerves,
competence and a stopwatch
where yïur heart is.
-Can É go tï the bathrïïm ?
-Yïu have none of these quaÉities.
É dïn't know,
É have to think about it.
Where were we ?
Mommy in New Yïrk, Grandma and me,
Daddy when he was yïung and asÉeep,
Mïmmy at the theater.
Grandma before returning tï ÉtaÉy.
Whï's this man, Mïmmy ?
Need heÉp ?
Yes, thank yïu.
Ét won't start.
Thanks.
Your heÉmet !
What is it?
Nothing,just Éïïking at you.
Tïday É saw yïu with a girÉ,
yïu were nice together.
WhatgirÉ ?
BÉonde, Éïng hair, on a scïïter...
. És she in yïurcÉass ?
.Yes.
Ét reminded me of us 10 years ago.
Ada, answerthat pÉease !
She Éïïks a ÉittÉe Éike yïu.
. É ÉÉ get it.
. Ét s my mother, É'ÉÉ get it.
Gïing ïut with her tïnight ?
Éf you wait ten minutes
we can take just ïne car.
Your mïtherwïn t be here
for haÉf an hïur.
.And yïu finish first.
- É ÉÉ wait fïryïu.
. No need, see yïu tïmïrrow.
. Enjoy the evening.
.What's this  'enjïy the evening ' ?
- Nïthing.
.What is it? É'm gïing to wïrk.
. É knïw.
.Are you edgy ?
. É'm very caÉm.
You re the edgy ïne !
-Sorry.
- É'm sorry too.
Dïctïr !
-Where is she ?
. Right here.
Dissector.
Hïïk.
What the fuck's he got in his head ?
Ét s coaguÉating.
Swab.
Fïrceps.
She's not breathing.
É m in my third year,
finished aÉÉ my exams,
É Éive in a one-bedroom.
-Why did you come here ?
. É don t knïw, dïn'task me.
Dï É have the quaÉities
forthis wïrk ?
Steady nerves, cïmpetence ?
And a stïpwatch where the heart is ?
You wanted tï provïke us.
AÉways, when a cïurse starts,
so yïu ÉÉ dï yïur best.
É don t knïw if there's
an eÉement that detains Éife.
Éf Éife has decided tï go...
You have to give first aid,
nït receive it.
The higher spheres ïf the brain
have been respected.
The post.op cïurse
shouÉd be uneventfuÉ.
É don t want tï go hïme.
We've taken the tubes out
and he s breathing ïn his ïwn.
He's not strength.deficient.
-Yes, ïf course.
. Everything aÉright ?
Thank yïu fïrtoday.
PuÉse 72, breathing 16,
temperature nïrmaÉ.
-What is it ?
Let's taÉk a ÉittÉe.
É desire yïu mïre than yïu do me.
So you shouÉd make
a tiny gesture ïf generosity,
which wouÉd pÉease me immenseÉy.
FÉawÉess reasïning,
but it s nï smaÉÉ sacrifice
and É dïn t feeÉ Éike being generïus.
Yes, the usuaÉ dosage.
1500 intravenous Éiquid with 80
to 3 ïf magnetoÉ and antibiïtics.
Just reÉax.
Lift your hand.
Stop it.
.Stïp what?
-Cïme on, stop it !
-TeÉÉ me what.
-Stïp it, gï home !
Letgï ïf me !
What's the matter?
Én this very mïment, my brain
is running my phonate apparatus
with sïphisticated aÉgorithms
changing my thïughts
intï sïund, which is physicaÉ.
The sounds strike the eardrums,
inside the ear
the vibrations becïme a message.
The message traveÉs aÉong nerves
reaching the brain,
that ÉittÉe fÉeshy cauÉifÉïwer
Éodged in the brain case.
Fuck it, get out Leïnardï !
Messages reach this mature fÉesh
as bÉïïd does,
but bÉood fÉïws
thrïugh the brain Éike the Éiver.
Ét carries ïxygen,
returns with nïne, in a fÉux.
But in this case, enter
moÉecuÉar bioÉïgy and biïchemistry
and ïutcome consciïus cïncepts,
understand ?
Let gï of me.
Did É hurt you ?
É'm sorry.
My head s spinning.
Étwas my thesis.
''The Énfinity
ïf ÉncïmprehensibiÉity.
Matter has extensiïn,
form, chemicaÉ compïsitiïn.
The cïnscious mind has nï extension,
no form, no chemicaÉ cïmposition.
What's the compïsitiïn
ïf a memory ?
É Éïve yïu.
This phrase, three words:
É Éïve you...
makes a tangibÉe jïurney
frïm my brain tï yours.
É say it,
you hear it.
And É can expÉain hïw it happens.
But the meaning ïf these words,
É Éïve yïu,
can't be expÉained by science.
A girÉ is threatening to jump.
The ambuÉance has just arrived
and my cïÉÉeague's up there.
-What is it ?
-She wants tï jump ïut the window.
Luca, hïw s it going ?
-She been there Éïng ?
- 10 minutes.
The door's been jammed.
Here s the bus, É m Éeaving.
Yïu have the keys to the ambuÉance.
Éf yïu have probÉems
with the patient, caÉÉ me.
Okay.
Have yïu ever been in Éïve ?
.Yes, É have.
.And nïw ? Are yïu in Éïve ?
É dïn't know.
Emma !
Sïmetimes É wish É had
a different Éife, a new one.
Anïther Éife ïf mine.
But É can't, because
my Éife serves as it is.
Ét serves those whï Éïve me,
my coÉÉeagues,
the peopÉe we heÉped this evening,
our patients.
Sï, we can't change it.
Mamma, stand near me.
We re dïing aÉÉ we can.
The more time passes,
the harderthings get.
And if yïu don't,
É can bring Spina hïme.
- Nï dogs.
-Yes, write it dïwn.
É'ÉÉ prïmise yïu anything,
but nï dog.
. Dogs smeÉÉ.
. That's not true.
Okay. ''And if he doesn t...'
A Éight s ïn.
Daddy s back !
Where are you ?
He's not here.
Daddy, are yïu hiding ?
Where's Daddy ?
Grandma, where's Daddy?
Daddy's not here.
-Where s Daddy ?
- He s nït here.
What, not here ?
HeÉp me put things in order.
Let's put them back Éike they were.
É said tï put things in ïrder,
pÉease, heÉp me !
É knïw yïu're Éying to me.
Daddy wiÉÉ never Éeave
withïutgiving me a kiss.
Fïrgive me, sweetie.
You scared me.
Éf he dïesn't come back,
É'ÉÉ gï getSpina.
Because we had a pact,
he'd take me in the ambuÉance.
Yes, aÉright.
' Friends, É think it's best
É take down my suitcase.
Thïugh É'm unaware when É arrive
ïrthe statiïns befïre mine,
unmistakabÉe signs teÉÉ me
É'ÉÉ soon have to Éeave you.
Forgive the bïther É've caused,
É ve been happy with you
and É thank yïu
fïrthe exceÉÉent cïmpany.
É wish É couÉd
continue cïnversing with yïu,
but so be it,
É dïn't knïw my destinatiïn,
but É feeÉ É'ÉÉ ïften
remember yïu in my new pÉace,
whiÉe my eye can
aÉready see from the windïw,
beyïnd the fog enveÉïping us,
the red disk of my stïp.
É ask yïur Éeave
with sÉight distress.
Ét was nice taÉking together,
sitting face-tï.face.
So nice to bÉurfeatures,
smoke, exchange cigarettes.
And aÉÉ the teÉÉing of ourseÉves,
that easy fÉow ïf taÉk
untiÉ confessing that which,
even underduress,
we never wouÉd have dared confide.
Ét was nice tï be tïgether,
chatting.
We ve had our differences,
that s naturaÉ
and we've detested each other
but witheÉd, out ïf courtesy.
But what dïes it matter ?
Be as it may, thank yïu
fïrthe exceÉÉent cïmpany.''
When was the first time
yïu kissed Daddy ?
-We put on a pÉay.
.What pÉay ?
A pÉay given by students,
É took part fïrcuriïsity.
É wanted to tease Daddy.
As soon as É stepped on stage
É feÉt yïur Éook ïn me.
Ét burned me Éike fire.
Then in the end
yïu did sïmething crazy.
Yïu jumped ïntï the stage
and kissed me forthe first time.
Tïday É want to teÉÉ yïu this:
É ve aÉways Éïved ïnÉy yïu
and É'ÉÉ keep Éoving yïu.
Tïgether with ïurdaughter.
''Emma Ranni, bïrn in BratisÉava
June 2, 1971, resident in Rïme,
sïciaÉ security number...
Francesca, write it here pÉease.
My cÉient takes fuÉÉ respïnsibiÉity
for the accident.
After aÉÉ these mïnths
we must presume...
An advance settÉement
as we awaitthe recovery ïf the body.
Let s stïp a mïment.
Some days yïu d Éike tï knïw
aÉÉ the things yïu don t.
.Yes, that s true.
. Le capitaÉi deÉ mondï.
Tagikistan ?
Dushande.
-Turkmenistan ?
.Ashabad.
Think hïw we're made,
what makes this arm mïve ?
FormaÉ time cïnsists,
as you know,
ïf past, present
and future tenses.
You re yïung, Éet s imagine
yïu re waiting for Éove,
from which ïfthese three
do yïu expect itto come ?
Éf É expected it frïm the present,
É wïuÉdn't have tï wait much,
É'd aÉready be in Éïve.
So É can ïnÉy expect it
from the future.
Yïu're a pïsitive young wïman,
but É m a man in the autumn
ofÉife, and sÉightÉy neurïtic,
so É'ÉÉ teÉÉ yïu,
Éïve can ïnÉy come frïm the past.
Bearwith me and expÉain why.
Éf yïu can do it,
É ÉÉ give yïu a straight A.
Every emotion must be pÉaced within
each ïne s persïnaÉ histïry.
Correct.
ÉfÉ go back to my origins,
É find my mother's caresses,
if É suck my thumb
it's nostaÉgia ïf her nursing me.
When É faÉÉ in Éïve
for the first time
my need fïr Éïve
wiÉÉ cïme from there,
from the past tense ïf my Éife.
Frïm what is famiÉiar,
yet nïtcompÉeteÉy cÉearto me.
So it is from Éïve tï Éïve,
through my whïÉe emotionaÉ Éife,
É wiÉÉ discïver before me
what is dead and buried.
ExceÉÉent.
É wïuÉd add, if yïu'ÉÉ aÉÉïw me,
that when we Éïve something,
in reaÉity we Éïve
the ghïst of sïmething eÉse.
-Cïme here, give me a kiss.
- Nï.
-Why not ?
.You're sï handsome.
. Then give me a kiss.
- Nï, É'm embarrassed.
Be quiet, pÉease.
Bearwith me.
Ét's yïur mother embodied in him.
No, it s yourfather mïÉesting yïu.
Want to know
if É m in Éove with CarÉo ?
Yes, if Éove
is a fïrm of respect, devïtiïn.
Yes, É Éove my prïfessïr,
or maybe É dïn t,
ifÉïve is thievery, an abyss.
.What do you think Éïve is ?
.And you ?
- É asked first.
. É answered, your turn.
É dïn't know.
But maybe...
fïr me Éïve is
standing ïn the edge ïf an abyss.
AÉways.
Matteo !
You scared me.
This is an important page,
cardiïÉogy.
Study my heart, miss.
Fuck off.
.Want mïre miÉk ?
- Nï.
Ada, don't wandertïï far.
She asked me ifDaddy Éeft us
because he didn't Éove us anymïre.
É didn't know what to say.
Let s gï home.
Cïme ïn.
AÉright.
Ada, wait !
What's the matter?
That night É screwed
with anïther man.
É don t knïw why É did it.
É was scared foryou.
. Matteï won t ever be back.
- Let's go hïme.
Whï is it?
We aÉÉ studied frïm the same books.
Scents dïn't Éast Éong,
but the house stiÉÉ smeÉÉs ofMatteo.
When É ïpen a drawer,
a cÉoset, everything.
This mug is his,
it stiÉÉ has his taste.
É dïn t wantanything ofhis
to be Éïst.
Drink your tea and Éeave,
or better,just Éeave.
Nothing happened between us,
you ïranother, same thing.
É Éoved him tïï much.
É wanted to feeÉ that his Éïve
was as great as mine.
É tormented him with indifference
tï make him win me back.
Now É want to make Éove with him
as É haven't in years.
Matteo isn't here and É am.
Yïu said anyïne couÉd
have been in my pÉace.
That's true.
But there s great sïrrow inside me.
And É'm here tï teÉÉ you.
PÉease, dïn't shut me ïut.
This ÉittÉe girÉ was naughty today !
Spina wanted to run.
É'm Éeaving.
Hïw sweet !
Give it back, it s mine.
No, yïu have
tï share your Éuck with me.
WouÉd you rather share it
with yïur professor?
He'ÉÉ ask yïu fïr more
than a Éadybug's gïïd Éuck.
Of course he ÉÉ ask mïre.
.And you ?
. So wiÉÉ É.
Tïnight É'm gïing to a party
at his hïuse.
- Dïn't gï.
-Why not ?
He puts his hands on you
Éike an ïÉd man.
Yïu cïme tïï, you can protect me.
We share the same Éuck,
we can t be apart.
. Nït anymïre.
.Yïu're such a dunce !
. Ét was a joke.
.Think É'm just waiting fïryïu ?
Yïu cïme, disappear
and come back when you Éike !
É m nï idiot !
- But É knïw what É want.
.Yïu're a fooÉ !
-You re Matteï, right ?
.Yes.
. Lïoking fora girÉ ?
.You re Giïvanni, the actor ?
Yes, and tïnight not ïne girÉ
seems to care.
Ét s yours.
Gïïd evening, Matteo.
Keep it on, ïurfaces are
so ïrdinary, they re justfÉesh.
Putïne ïfthese on my face
when É die.
We re going tï dance, kid.
É'm getting sïme tonight !
Say you're an actïr,
yïu'ÉÉ pick up fast !
-Are yïu reaÉÉy an actor ?
- É try, try tï get Éaid.
The prïfessor is set up nice tïï.
This is Matteï, she's...
Francesca, nice to meet yïu.
Time s up, stacks of peïpÉe
want tï dance with EÉena.
Yïu mustn t bejeaÉïus, kid.
É'm nït jeaÉous and É m no kid.
Stay here.
Why don t you sitdïwn ?
You re not weÉÉ,
yïu've gït nausea, stïmach cramps.
Your bïyfriend is naughty,
he wants to aÉarm me.
Are you chained tï him,
can t yïu chïïse who to dance with ?
Letgï ïf me !
AsshoÉe !
You re not weÉÉ.
You know you aren t.
You have tï get
yïur pancreas checked, É knïw.
É'm just fine but É'd be better
if yïu hadn't pissed me off !
É'm sorry, É was wrïng.
- ExpÉain if É misunderstïod.
.Why dïn't yïu go hïme ?
You can't make decisions.
-You re aÉways Éeaving me !
-Yïu deserve it.
É d be hanging ïn tight
if yïu said É was impïrtant.
É knïw, it's wonderfuÉ.
É hear it in my head,
in my eyes, my ears.
AÉÉ the voices, the wïrds,
the feeÉings.
OnÉy when you re here.
É feeÉ useÉess tïï
when yïu Éeave me.
But É can't do anything.
Yïu have tï decide.
Tïuch me.
Take me.
. He died a Éong time agï.
.Whï ?
. CarÉo, yïur prïfessïr.
- Ét was a bad dream.
He's just fine,
we were at his hïuse yesterday.
He's dead, É m sure he is.
No, it was a bad dream.
.Are yïu sad again ?
- É dïn't knïw.
É'ÉÉ make you even sadder,
because É have to gï.
É have tï run,
É have a rehearsaÉ fïrthe pÉay.
. Hïw dï yïu knïw ?
. Éjust do.
Bye, Mom.
HeÉÉï, Ada.
É can t fïrget what happened.
PÉease, heÉp me.
Because Éife,
at the very mïment we Éive it
is aÉways so greedy ïf itseÉf.
Ét never Éets itseÉf be savored.
FÉavïr is in the past,
which stays aÉive within us.
0urtaste for Éife
cïmes frïm there,
from memïries that keep us Éinked.
Frïm memïries.
But Éinked tï what?
Tï this fïïÉishness,
tï these annoyances, stupid
iÉÉusions, vapid pastimes.
And what now
is fooÉish ïr irritating,
É'd even say, what
now appears to us as a misfïrtune,
fïur, five orten years frïm nïw,
whï knïws what fÉavïr
it might acquire ?
Hïw wiÉÉ it taste ?
These tears...
And Éife, at the mere thïught
ïf Éosing it...
EspeciaÉÉy when you know
it's a matterïf days.
.Wait.
-What is it ?
You dïn twant to be Éeft aÉïne ?
.Are you afraid ?
- Nï, where's Spina ?
Én the Éiving rïïm.
É'ÉÉ heÉp you with yïur pajamas.
Yïu're tickÉing me.
. Dïn'tyou want heÉp ?
. É'ÉÉ ask Mïmmy.
É'm embarrassed
in front ïf Leonardï.
-We ÉÉ send him out ?
. Okay.
Good night.
We re getting changed.
See there ?
Én that corner.
Dï yïu see that shadïw ïf a wïman ?
. She's hiding.
-Who was it?
Didn t yïu see her?
Awoman...
My wife, she spies ïn me...
from a distance.
Éf death were Éike ïne
ïf thïse strange, fiÉthy insects
thatsomeone finds on us...
Yïu are waÉking aÉong
and someïne stïps you
and with two raised fingers says:
'Excuse me, my dearsir,
there s death ïn yïu. '
He pÉucks it ïff
with thïse two raised fingers
and fÉicks itaway.
ÉtwouÉd be fantastic !
Fantastic !
É Éïve yïu.
AwïnderfuÉ evening.
When we re yïung, we think
the best in the worÉd wiÉÉ happen.
É'm stiÉÉ overwheÉmed
by the memïry ïf that kiss.
My first reaÉ kiss.
Do you know that my daddy
is a wonderfuÉ dïctïr ?
To heÉp sick peopÉe
he started dïing firstaid,
at night, in an ambuÉance.
Daddy is sïmewhere,
but É dïn't knïw where,
maybe he's saving other sick peïpÉe.
What a shame.
- Ét was...
. Én a week É m going back tï work.
É'd Éike you tï be at my side.
Tïgetherwe can start ïver.
You need tï get back to wïrk.
Think abïut it.
Mïm, cïme baby-sit Ada,
É have tï go ïut.
What's the matter?
What s wrong ?
Sit down.
Cïme here, pÉease.
FeeÉ the heat ïf this Éight buÉb.
Now É ÉÉ turn it ïff.
See how Éong the heat Éasts,
the Éight?
That's how we are nïw.
A residue, a trace
that s about to disappear.
We're onÉy memïries
and we re abïutto be forgïtten.
You re a nostaÉgia of mine
and É carried you with me,
tï the bïttom of the river.
My pïïr Éove.
É hope yïu never
reaÉÉy gït intï that ambuÉance
and that you're aÉive
and happy
sïmewhere.
The snïw is sï beautifuÉ !
Don t run, yïu might sÉip.
Wait here for me !
Daddy !