Provided by explosiveskull
https://twitter.com/kaboomskull
What the fuck?
Hello?
Hi, Patrick.
Come on, it's not that late.
It is when
your kids are gonna
be waking you up in a few hours.
Just do what Mom did,
tell 'em to get their asses
back in bed or else Santa
will give their presents
to poor black kids.
God,
she was a bitch.
Was?
Oh, right, now she's a cunt.
Um, hey, remember at
lunch the other day
that book I was reading,
"Undiscovered Girl"?
The one about the
teenage blogger?
Are you smoking?
What?
No, I quit.
Stop.
Look, anyway, I just
finished reading the book
and at the end Katie,
that's the blogger's name,
Katie Kampenfelt,
she goes missing.
What, you mean...
She narrates the whole
book and then at the end
her mom takes over
and says that a ton
of what Katie told
us about herself,
even her name, it isn't true.
And then after her last blog
entry she got into her car
and she was never seen again.
She's never used any
of her credit cards
and never used a cell phone.
The mom wants us to
try to help find her.
So, what are you...
I just, I need to know what
happened to her, you know?
Like...
Was she kidnapped?
Did she run away?
They discovered a dead
body at the end of the book
but we don't know if
it's Katie or not.
You're talking
about her like she's real.
She could be.
Maybe it could be
based on a true story.
It's possible, right?
Where'd
you buy the book?
Amazon.
Fiction
or nonfiction?
Wait, didn't you
say a guy wrote it?
I'm sorry, I'm-
- Lonely, I know.
Get some sleep.
Come over whenever
you want tomorrow.
The earlier the better.
Oh, hey, tell Mom
to pick up a gallon
of apple cider on the way.
Okay.
- Love you.
- Love you, too.
Dear Katie,
I just finished your book
and now I can't sleep.
I keep imagining your body
lying in the woods somewhere.
Empty eyes, wet, filthy hair.
Bugs crawling inside
your nose and ears.
It's been awhile since
my mind turned this dark.
What can I say?
I'm by myself too much.
I overthink everything.
Anyway, I'm not an idiot.
I know you're not really Katie.
You're just an author.
Some dude trying to sell books.
But if you really were
Katie, we'd be best friends.
I know it.
Do you think he's
gonna write back?
Who?
The writer.
Oh.
He's probably too busy
jerking off in the mirror.
What do you mean?
Well, yeah, he
wants to sell books,
but he also wants
fangirls to write him
and tell him what
a genius he is.
It's pathetic.
Let it go.
Yeah.
Dear
Katie, I loved your book.
I'm 16 and I live
in a wheelchair.
What happened to you?
Are you dead?
I won't tell anyone, I promise.
Dear
Katie, my father was a lawyer
and a drug addict
who beat the shit out
of me and my two brothers.
When I was in the third
grade he overdosed and died.
It left a hole in my heart
so huge nothing can fill it.
If you were real, I
know you'd understand.
Dear Katie, one night
last summer my boyfriend
and I made love for
three hours straight.
Tonight memories of
him tear me apart.
If you're really
flesh and blood,
thank you so much
for listening to me.
Is this some sort of joke?
Your mom said that
you disappeared.
My mom
didn't write that, I did,
and I never disappeared.
I just wanted to
end my blog forever,
cancel my reality show, so
I pretended to be my mom.
But
if you're a real person
why is your book
sold as fiction?
And why is there a
man's name on the cover?
Same reason I made up
the name Katie Kampenfelt;
to be anonymous.
I think private lives
should stay private.
I'm a big fan of boundaries.
Do you
write back to every reader
who contacts you?
Actually, you're the first.
It's obvious you're smart,
cool, and need a friend.
So do I.
And according to your Facebook
we live only 87 miles apart,
which is wonderful.
But
if you never write back
why even bother having
a contact button?
Because I love being loved.
What's better than fan mail?
You wouldn't believe
how much I get.
Elle, my publisher
forwarded me your letter.
I'm sorry to have
to tell you this,
but I have nothing to do
with KatieKampenfelt.com.
I have no idea who
created this site
or who's emailing you,
but it's not Katie,
because she doesn't exist.
She's just a
character I invented.
She is not and never was real.
Be well.
So, what should I
do about fake Katie?
Nothing.
I'll do it.
Hey, creep.
The author says you're a liar.
Katie's make believe.
Write to me again, I'm
calling my uncle at the FBI.
You're welcome.
Okay,
butt head, here's the story.
I met the author
at a book signing,
he clearly wanted to bone me,
so I sent him the link
to my blog archive.
He loved it, he thought
the way I ended it
using my mom's voice to say
I disappeared was genius.
He offered to help me
re-write it and get
it published as a novel.
I told him no way, but
if he wanted to do it
we could split the money.
Only he'd have to promise never
to tell anyone I was real.
And that's why he lied to you.
You see?
What?
You actually don't believe me?
You really think
I made it all up?
Dude, why would I even do that?
Men do all kinds of
sick shit for no reason.
Either you're a
Christian or you're not.
Clearly she's not,
otherwise she wouldn't
have married a Jew.
At least not that one.
Do you know he didn't
even give little Olivia
a choice about the bar mitzvah?
Can you imagine?
Bat, not bar.
I don't care
if he did adopt her,
it doesn't give him the
right to impose his faith
on a defenseless child.
It's...
Where do you think you're going?
Plate, sink.
My
best friend Natasha thinks
you're dangerous,
but I'm not sure what
I'm supposed to be afraid of.
You can't get any
money out of me,
because I don't have any.
You can't hurt me worse
than I hurt myself.
The first time you wrote you
said that you were listening.
It's what I need more
than anything right now.
Can I tell you my story?
Please.
Are you judgmental?
Yeah, right.
My story is about the
infinite stupidity of love.
You can relate, of course.
You swear you won't tell anyone?
On my vaginal health.
I'll write it
out in big chunks.
Where do I begin?
My mom made me audition
for the cheerleading squad
even though cheering
represents pretty much
everything I hate about America.
L-E-T-S-G-O,
let's go, let's go.
L-E-T-S-G-O, let's go, let's go.
Go, Bulls!
Thank you for your time.
Dude, I would cum
on her face with the force
of a thousand suns.
That little brown one
was pretty hot, too.
Yeah.
But what if you knocked her up?
Consider the genetic
consequences.
Ooh, you make an
excellent point, sir.
Wait, who was the one
from the Special Olympics?
- Elle something.
- Right.
Cute face, but, curses
on them tiny titties.
I
knew they were idiots.
Didn't matter.
Did you swallow these?
Thank God it's coming up.
You have been given
every advantage.
Why should I pay for college?
What you need is
missionary work.
A few weeks at our camp in Ghana
would wake you up pretty fast.
They live on a dollar a day!
Come on.
Mommy.
That's enough for today.
Sweet
dreams, beautiful girl.
Don't call me that.
Why not?
You seriously think I'm a dude?
Fap, fap, fap, fap.
I'm sorry.
Don't be mad, it's
just so ridiculous.
Want me to send you a pic?
You look just like
I thought you would.
Dear
Katie, as soon as I started
to love you toward the end
I knew you'd be destroyed.
Pretty much everyone I've
ever loved has died on me.
Why is God so cruel?
I hated college.
After freshman year
I begged my mom
to let me transfer
to art school.
Instead, she pulled
strings to get me into
a Christian sorority, also
known as hell on earth.
Excuse me.
I seem to have lost my
virginity, can I have yours?
Offensive lineman?
Why do you say that?
Because that was
an offense line, man.
- Yo, my name's-
- Hold on, hold on,
let me guess.
Kyle.
Not even close.
Biff?
Nope, it's-
- Okay, hold on.
Chip.
Chad.
Oh, I'm getting warmer.
Um, oh, I know.
You're a Tad.
How did you do that?
It's magic and
you're a tad annoying.
- Not so fast.
- Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Hey, too rough.
They
say you know everything
about a person the
minute you meet them.
I sure did.
Look, you don't
know how to kiss.
There is one right way
and a million wrong ways.
But don't worry,
'cause I can teach you.
And for years bitches
be like damn, boy,
where you learn
to kiss like that?
I have a better idea.
Shut the fuck up.
It
went on for months.
I saw the way
you looked at him.
He
always cried afterwards.
Apologized, said it
would never happen again.
Pretty nasty.
Yeah, he is.
Your boyfriend did this?
Indirectly.
And this?
This?
Directly.
Isn't it time to move on?
I guess
it just depends.
On what?
On whether or not
I deserve better.
What will it
take to convince you?
Um, I don't know, maybe death?
I'm sorry.
Will he let you go?
Not without a fight.
Let's avoid that, okay?
How?
We live together.
Do you have someone
who can help you move out?
Maybe someone from
your sorority.
No.
Parent?
Mom, I...
Yeah.
Look, see I...
I'm thinking about
hurting myself again.
I dream...
Can I please just come home?
Um, Patrick?
If I did quit school, could I...
Could I maybe stay
with you and Marcy?
You know, just like until
I get like an apartment
or, you know, like a job.
I mean, I could babysit for you.
I was thinking that maybe
I could move out there
and like stay with
you for a bit.
I won't be in your
way at all, I...
And once I get a job I can...
I hardly
knew my oldest brother Connor.
He left for college right
after my father died.
Then he went to law school and
only came home for Christmas.
By the time I was in high school
he never came home at all.
I never knew why.
Oh, Ellie belly.
You need so much love.
I do.
Hey, meet the
in-house expert, huh?
This is my fiance, Joseph.
Delighted.
You really had no clue?
Hello?
Are you there?
Paging Elle Overton.
Please don't disappear again.
I'm begging you.
♪ Struggling to feel something ♪
♪ Other than this pain ♪
♪ Don't know why I
can't clear my mind ♪
Sweetheart,
you're roasting.
You want a hat?
You need a hat.
Multiple choice:
you're ghosting me because, A,
telling your life
story is painful.
B, Natasha found out we're
pen pals and kicked your ass.
Or C, you killed yourself.
C is closest.
Writing to me doesn't
make you feel better?
Does a little.
Temporarily.
Here's the next chapter.
Enjoy!
Come, come on!
When
my mom found out Connor
took me in, she
called him Judas.
If she'd known he was gay,
she would've hired a hitman.
I don't get Joan Crawford.
Her shoulder pads were
like condor wings.
Hi.
Molly Andrews, such a
pleasure to meet you, Elle.
Thank you, same here.
Did Sage offer you
something to drink?
Diet soda, coffee,
coconut water?
I'm fine, thanks.
Come in.
Welcome to En Garde Creative.
Thanks, I'm so
grateful to be here.
- Even just-
- Your brother thinks
the world of you
and my boss thinks
the world of your brother, so-
- Here we are.
- Yeah.
How much do you know about us?
Well, just what's
on the website,
but I wanna know everything.
Well, we're
small, but growing.
Our work is exclusively digital,
marketing directly
via email, text,
social media, and
search engines.
Right now all of our
clients are domestic,
located west of the Mississippi,
but we are starting to
attract some interest
in the Pacific rim as
well, so who knows.
Wow, really exciting.
It is.
Now tell me about you.
Well, um, I was blown
away when Connor told
me about the job because
in college I majored
in marketing with a special
focus on interactive media.
I actually left because
I just felt like...
I felt trapped in the
classroom setting, you know,
it just felt theoretical.
Like it was sort of just
like I really wanted
some real world experien...
Oh, I got bit by a dog.
What kind?
A beagle.
I had one as a kid.
It got run over
right in front of me,
I still haven't recovered.
Oh.
Dave Hastings.
Welcome aboard, Connor's sister.
Wait, you mean, I-
- That's right.
We're over here.
Go ahead, hop on.
Okay.
You might want to check
underneath first, though.
Your predecessor stuck
her chewed gum down there.
That's why I fired her.
Wait, really?
No, I dreamed her paltry.
Oh.
So, let's talk business.
What did Connor say about me?
That you are charismatic,
brilliant and funny.
He didn't mention humble?
- No.
- That's weird.
So, tell me more
about the gum chewer.
Because you don't wanna
make the same mistakes?
Yeah, I wanna make new ones.
She was just too passive.
If there's a way for the
office to run more efficiently,
I wanna know about it.
If there's something
in my blind spot
I need you to
scream, "Watch out".
Maybe you have a concept
for one of our campaigns,
it doesn't matter if it's
above your pay grade,
I wanna hear it.
It'll be so much
fun finding them.
Hey, look who's here.
My new assistant, Elle Overton.
My wife Carmen.
Hi, I've
heard so much about you.
Same here.
So, Elle just had
a great idea about
the Eye Candy account.
You know those eye test charts?
She thought it would be fun
to post a chart each week,
but hidden inside the jumble
of letters is a promo code.
Baby, will you
tell me in the car?
We're gonna be late.
Shit, I lost track.
Can you close up?
Yeah.
Oh.
Hey, you wanna make extra money?
Uh, who doesn't?
We need a babysitter.
Oh.
You have kids, wow.
Yeah, I would love to.
I have a lot of experience.
Perfect.
I know
what you're thinking,
it was just like when you
were hired to be a nanny.
But there was a huge difference.
You were way hotter
than the mom.
I was a boy compared to Carmen.
Perfect timing.
Three minutes after
brewing the antioxidants
start to evaporate.
Is that Facebook
or actual science?
It's actual Twitter.
Rough night?
Yeah, the roughest.
What happened?
Went to a cocktail party
sponsored by a tequila company.
I behaved, Carmen didn't.
She, uh...
Oh, she'd kill me.
Well, I won't tell anyone.
I promise.
When I met Carmen she
was just a few years
out of college, I mean, still
pretty much a party girl.
She said she was sick of it,
she wanted a husband, four kids,
and start her own business.
I mean, that
sounded great to me.
So we got married,
Esme was born,
and out of nowhere she announces
she doesn't want anymore kids.
Well, that was a surprise.
When I started En Garde I
assumed she'd get involved,
help us out, but she
doesn't give a shit.
I mean, she wants it
to succeed, of course,
for financial reasons,
but that's it.
So if she doesn't
want anymore kids
and she doesn't care
about the business,
then what makes her happy?
Shopping.
Oh.
A few nights a week she
still goes out partying
with her old college friends.
So she's not over it.
Looks that way.
Anyway, last night she, uh...
Man, this
is so inappropriate.
Oh, my favorite.
She puked up on me.
Wait, literally?
No, trust me, it
was no metaphor.
How does that even happen?
I don't know, I
was fast asleep.
I assumed she'd just staggered
in from the loo and blah.
Oh, my God.
I woke up drenched in puke,
she was passed out on the floor.
I had to take her to
the guest bedroom.
By the time I
finished cleaning up
Esme was awake demanding
breakfast, so...
Yeah.
Oh, you poor thing.
You know, it's nice
to have someone pity me.
Other than myself, of course.
Your emails
are like my favorite novel.
Oh no, you're depressed again.
Are you bleeding, too?
I am.
I wonder if our
cycles are in sync.
You know, like roomies.
I
loved your book until
I found out it was written
by a middle-aged man.
For to your appropriate
the heart, soul,
and body of a young girl
is absolutely disgusting.
What do
you eat when you're bleeding?
I just ate an entire
bag of kettle corn.
Telling your story
will save your life.
I promise.
It definitely saved mine.
I know how to wake you up.
I'll tell you something
about myself you don't know.
Let me see.
Okay, how's this?
I'm married.
Seriously?
We have a baby.
I thought you got an abortion.
I did, my
daughter was conceived later.
The right way.
With someone who loves
me unconditionally.
I want that so badly.
You'll have it,
and you'll love your baby
as much as I love Sarah.
Sarah.
That's my middle name.
Cool.
Now, please get
back to your story.
Why do you even care?
We're friends.
Strangers.
We're both.
It shouldn't even be possible.
Good job.
This one or this one?
Um, it's so hard to choose.
Which one goes better
with vampire red?
The black one.
You're right.
Miss Elle, you
have pretty lips.
Thank you.
You, too.
So Dave says you wanna
start your own business.
Definitely.
Well we could use some
help over at the office.
How come you don't
drop by more often?
You'll understand
when you have kids.
This little bug kicks my butt
all day, don't you, bonita?
Except when I'm at Rainbow.
What's that?
Her preschool.
After Rainbow Rosalinda
comes over, she's my nanny.
But there are some things
only a mommy can do, right baby?
Rosalinda plays hide
and seek and monsters
and we build pillow forts.
Mommy takes you to movies
and yummy restaurants
and buys you pretty dresses.
Mommy, can Miss Elle
take a bath with me?
No, I know.
I'm not sure, as quick
as I can darling, okay?
Bye.
This is my favorite.
What do you think of him?
Brilliant.
If you're ever looking
for a present for Carmen.
The bikini or the girl?
The bikini.
It's right up her alley.
It is exactly
why'd she wear it.
I would too if I had her body.
Her closet is like
backstage at Fashion Week,
I mean, it's insane.
How do you afford it?
I don't.
I can't.
She blows through my
trust like play money.
Each month we barely make
it to the finish line.
I am gonna email
the photographer
and see if he is available.
Can I ask you a
personal question?
Why'd I marry her?
Honestly, we had fun at first.
Went to the gym
together, we went hiking.
We traveled loads.
Nonstop shagging, our
chemistry was incredible.
Once Esme was born
all the fun stopped.
No more sex?
On the once-a-month plan now.
Such a cliche.
Even a blind man
could've seen it coming.
Marry for conversation, it's
the only thing that lasts.
So, Mom called.
Welcome back.
What'd she say?
I'm still disowned,
still Judas, but not you.
She said that even
though she'd preferred
if you went back and
finished at State,
she is fine with you going
to any school you want.
Even art school.
She'll pay for it, too,
no questions asked.
Wait, really?
Yeah, yeah.
I'm pretty sure
it's the first time
she's surrendered to
anyone since she spread
her legs for our
lord and savior.
What's the matter? You won.
You're supposed to be happier.
Oh, shit, you don't wanna leave.
What's his name?
You don't know him.
Besides, it doesn't matter,
he's got a girlfriend.
Is he into you?
No.
I don't know, maybe.
Maybe.
Listen,
any guy that you like
who's unavailable, isn't a guy.
He's a drug.
And not like a
drug, an actual one.
And way back in the 80s, what
did the scary skeletor lady
in the White House tell us to
do when we get offered drugs?
I don't know.
Just say no.
Did anyone listen to her?
Of course not.
I should've
phoned home the next day.
It was the perfect
time to leave.
But you thought Dave
was your destiny, didn't you?
Molly.
Hey, you made it back.
I wouldn't miss this.
Happy birthday.
Thank you.
Hey.
Where's Carmen?
Already passed out.
You slip her a roofie?
Yeah, but I didn't
take advantage.
I heard there was cake.
Yeah, she saved you some.
Yeah? Where?
In the kitchen.
What?
I'm just happy
to see you, is all.
You drunk?
Yeah.
Are you?
Stoned?
Come on.
Dave and I continued on
like everything was normal.
But then a week later we
were at the office late
and he kissed me again.
This time he was sober
and I didn't run away.
If I had been a cartoon,
my tongue would've
popped out of his ear.
Then, finally, he
pushed me away.
He said, "I'm so sorry,
but I can't do this."
He was a married man.
I laughed.
Like, what, like I
didn't know that?
But I thought he was joking.
And he said it like I was
the one who kissed him.
It was nuts.
But I didn't freak out.
Just shrugged it off and said,
"You're right, whatever".
Well, I must've been
a pretty good actress
because he actually looked
hurt that I wasn't that upset.
But then he started
kissing me again,
but this time it
was more intense.
He started grabbing my ass,
my boobs outside of my shirt.
And then he got on his
knees, lifted my skirt up,
pulled my underwear down
and started licking me.
It was so fucking dirty.
It's the most exciting thing
that's ever happened to me.
My eyes were open the whole time
and I just kept imagining
somebody walking in on us.
I came so hard.
Then about 10 seconds
later he said,
"Shit, I'm late to meet Carmen".
He got up, door slammed,
and he's gone.
And I...
What
he did to you was rape.
Not literally, because
you enjoyed it,
but emotional and
psychological violence.
How did
you get to be so strong?
I'm
not a teenager anymore.
I understand the
evil of human beings,
especially those
cursed with nut sacks.
On
Sunday nights, if I watch
a corny Christian
movie with my mom
she lets me borrow her car.
My
husband's name is Kevin.
He's tall, dark and handsome.
He used to be a Marine, now
he sells medical equipment.
I stay home all day
with Sarah, she's three,
beyond precious, the
best thing I ever did.
How come you say
you wanna meet me
but you never suggest that
we like talk on the phone?
You never even ask
if we can text.
That's just weird.
Kevin's a jealous freak.
If we called or
texted each other,
sooner or later he'd snoop
in my phone and bust me.
That's why I only get
fan mail on my laptop
and I delete everything
the second after I read it.
Bust you for what?
Having a friend?
Is that an actual crime?
No, but we have a deal.
No secrets.
If I told him about you I'd
have to tell him how we met.
He knows nothing about my blog,
my book, what a slut I was.
If he knew he would go insane.
Fine, I get it.
We'll keep things
the way they are.
Where was I?
Right, you won't believe this.
But after he went down on
me, he put me right back
in the friend zone
like it never happened.
Being insane, I decided it
was because it grossed him out.
Like there was
something wrong with me.
Katie,
I just finished reading.
You've probably been chopped
into itty bitty pieces by now,
but it's just as possible
a miracle occurred.
I'm an aquarius, we're
all about miracles.
So I choose to believe
you're out there
having an awesome life.
Hello?
It's just me.
I thought you weren't
gonna be back until tomorrow.
I managed to escape early.
What are you still doing here?
Don't you have your own desk?
I'm just seeing beyond
my job description.
Working on some ideas.
You have pluck.
Well, you noticed.
What a waste of
time, the whole trip.
Who ever the
Japanese were polite?
Someone who's never
heard of Pearl Harbor.
Well, at least that
was over pretty quick.
This was more like
the Bataan Death March
with an order of cold uni.
You want a drink?
If it'll wash the taste
of uni out of my mind, yeah.
Fun fact, uni isn't
the actual urchin.
It's the urchin's gonads.
Make that a double.
Thank you.
So, how've you been?
Honestly?
Come here.
Tell me everything.
What did you...
It's manicure scissors.
Is that my fault?
No.
No, no, no, no, no.
I um...
Been doing it for
years on and off.
It's just whenever I get
overwhelmed by a situation
or I feel like-
- You wouldn't feel
overwhelmed if I had
the courage to admit that
I was in love with you.
Okay,
three crucial questions
after a night of boneage.
How big was his dick?
Did you go down on him?
Did you cum?
Waiting for my answers.
I'm watching "True Crime" on TV.
Did you know the leading
cause of homicide
in women is having a smile
that lights up the room?
In men it's giving friends
the shirt off your back.
It's true!
Last week a girl disappeared
a few miles from here.
Stella something-Polish.
Did you read about it?
They found her body this
morning floating in a reservoir.
Yuck.
Hello?
Where are you?
Are you dead?
Sorry about last night,
I had a sugar crash.
How do you stay up
so late and raise
a kid at the same time?
I have a
nanny five mornings a week.
I'm as lazy as Carmen.
Hey, maybe I am Carmen.
Ew, creepy.
Not funny if true.
Dude, it was a joke.
I have real boobs
and hate spicy food.
Now stop being such
a paranoid loser
and tell me what happened.
You smell so good.
You feel so good.
Taste so good.
You're perfect, you know that?
I wanna crawl inside
you and never come out.
Okay.
Here's something I don't get.
If you and Carmen
fight all the time
then how does you staying
married help Esme?
Wouldn't it be better
to get divorced now
before you mess her up for life?
It's an excellent question.
Yes, I'm aware of that.
I wish I had an
excellent answer.
You know, I'm not asking
for myself, I promise.
I just want you to be
happy, and Esme, too.
What about Carmen?
She can suffer.
Okay.
The real reason I don't divorce
her is quite humiliating.
For who?
Whom?
For me.
If we get divorced she'll
take half of everything,
which means En Garde goes under.
So you care more
about your business
than your own happiness?
Honestly?
I...
I doubt I'll ever be happy.
Not in this lifetime, anyway.
I want to be secure, own
a business I'm proud of.
The
letter U instead Y-O-U.
No question mark.
But the weirdest
thing was that Dave
would never say fucking,
always making love.
Oh no,
the bitch stole his phone.
100%, I knew it.
It was a trap.
Definitely.
But maybe also a gift.
An opportunity.
An open door in my jail cell.
I might never get a
chance like this again
and no one could
blame me for escaping.
How was I supposed to know
the text wasn't from him?
I'm only happy when
you're inside me.
God, how I love you, David.
Come over again tonight.
Oh, shit.
You're my hero.
Hello?
Did you just text me?
Well, I mean, I
responded back to you.
Shit, what
did my text say?
You don't remember?
Quick, tell me.
You said that you loved
fucking me last night
and that you wanted
to do it again.
I said tonight.
No, no,
Carmen wrote it.
She stole my phone.
I'm trying to talk my way out
of it, I'll call you later.
Don't, Dave.
What?
Listen to me, take
care of your family.
Forget about me, I mean it.
I quit.
What? No.
Listen, you're not gonna...
I was
so excited to move on
that it never occurred
to me that Connor
would find out.
I'm sorry that I let you down.
I kinda assumed that you'd
be a bit more pissed off.
Listen.
Dave gets most of the blame.
He's older, he's married.
He was your employer.
You know, if you wanna
sue him my friend
would be happy to take the case.
No, no.
He's a good guy.
He's just really unhappy.
And...
It's on both of us.
I could've prevented it.
Anyway, um, I know
somebody who will hire you.
The pay is really
shitty, but the uniform
is really unflattering so
nobody will hit on you.
Thank you.
Oh, Katie.
So much pain seeing
myself in your words.
What I wouldn't give
to reclaim just one
tick tock of my youth.
It's
the first time you didn't
write back after
one of my emails.
Did something happen?
Finally had enough of me?
Ready for a little uplift?
And as views
of his miraculous power
spread across the land
the people delivered
unto our lord the
cripple, the blind,
those wracked by pain,
tormented by seizures,
even those possessed by demons.
Sorry I disappeared.
Kevin walked up behind me
while I was on my computer,
he asked who I was writing
to and I had no choice.
I told him the truth.
About you, about my book.
He freaked out.
He thinks the fact that
you won't meet me in person
means you're a dude
who wants to rape me.
But even if he's wrong
he said he still hates
your guts because I
kept you a secret.
Anyway, he made me promise
never to write you again.
I lied and said okay.
Like I'd ever let a man
control my existence.
He should know better.
Go on with your story.
Please tell me Dave was history.
The chosen
will banish the demons,
speak in new tongues,
bring the word of God
to every corner of the earth.
I hoped so.
I went to work every
day and every day
I missed him less and less.
Elle!
We should talk, right?
Actually, we were all
pretty jazzed Carmen
finally busted him.
I thought that
you all love Dave.
We do, we just hate that he
sleeps with his assistants.
Hopefully that's over now.
We can all finally
look Carmen in the eye.
Oh.
You thought you were
like the first one?
No.
How...
How many others?
All of them, really.
Except for the one
that was born male.
Dave didn't know that
when he hired her.
What about the last one?
The gum chewer?
Yeah.
She got super attached.
She went psycho and
moved back to Florida.
Hey, hey.
Don't freak out.
You won.
You are young and
gorgeous and you have
your whole life ahead of you.
He has to go straight home
to Carmen every night.
He's not allowed to
travel without her,
she even picked out
his new assistant.
Why doesn't she
just divorce him?
Well, she probably
would if she knew
the truth about you guys.
But he told Carmen you guys
only slept together once.
He said he did it because
he felt sorry for you.
How do you know so much?
I'm smarter than Dave, so
he isn't attracted to me.
But that also means he
tells me everything.
I'm sorry.
Are you? Really?
Why doesn't he just divorce her?
I mean, is he really
so scared about losing
half of his money?
What do you mean?
He loses all of it.
He signed a prenup.
If they get a divorce
he doesn't get a cent.
No, what about his trust?
Is that what he told you?
No, she comes from one of the
richest families in El Paso.
Her dad bankrolls the company.
He even helped him
get his green card.
When she met him he was
literally selling used cars.
Hey.
What did Molly tell you?
Are you stalking me now?
You know, I should be
angry at you for hiring me
just so you could fuck me,
but I'm so insane I'm
weirdly flattered.
But what I can't forgive
is what a liar you are.
Carmen isn't a gold
digging whore, you are.
You make me sick.
Stop, wait, please.
Just let me say something.
Look, no matter what
happened before,
it was different with us.
We had something special, Elle.
I go to sleep and I miss you,
I wake up and my
life, it's empty.
I need you, Elle.
I love you.
Carmen's with her parents
on Saturday night.
Have dinner with me, please.
I can't.
I have a hot date.
I
had no idea that cruelty
could feel so good.
Do you have any tall,
gorgeous male friends?
Sure.
Black?
Yeah, of course.
Straight?
Ah, can't help you there.
No.
So you're not
racist, you're just-
- Heterophobic, yeah.
Yeah, breeders?
What about a tall
gorgeous black male friend
that can pass as straight?
Oh, my God.
I love it.
Why is
it no matter how liberal
a white guy is, when
it comes to a black guy
boning his girl he
goes full Albright?
I
think it's 'cause of
the true myth about black dicks.
Maybe deep
down they wanna suck one.
Don't we all.
Oh, hey, gorgeous.
Back at ya, blue eyes.
It's just on the hill,
do you mind if we walk?
I prefer it.
Don't look
now, but he's across
the street stalking us.
Don't worry, he's not dangerous.
I'm not worried about a thing.
You're smooth.
I minored in theater at
Arizona State University.
Is he live tweeting this?
No, he's texting me.
It's working.
Mute!
By the way, adore
the Miu Miu Slingbacks.
Well, thank you,
Connor picked them out.
Figured.
Why, because the rest
of my outfit is shit?
Oh, great.
Did locusts attack these?
This is unacceptable.
It's time for you to
woman the hell up.
You're not a teenager anymore.
What do you suggest?
"La French" as
the French call it,
even though we invented it.
Pale pink base, white tip.
Womanly, sophisticated,
timeless.
Well, that's me.
And leave these
poor cuticles alone.
If you're angry, chew
out other people.
Wow.
You should be a life coach.
Connor didn't tell you?
It's what I am.
You know, if you
were into vagina
this night would
definitely not be over.
At least, I'd hope not.
Oh, we'd just be
getting started.
Thank you.
- Goodnight.
- Yeah.
While
he was sending them
Carmen was probably
on her way home
ready to crawl
into bed with him.
Carmen, who believed he had sex
with me only once out of pity.
I didn't forward her
the dirtiest ones,
just the ones where it was
really obvious we were in love.
Did you write anything?
I kept it simple.
Dave just sent me
these, I'm moving on.
Why can't he?
Come in.
Stay.
What's wrong?
I just spoke to Dave.
He's in jail.
What? What happened?
When you sent the photos
to Carmen she kicked him out.
Told him that he'd
hear from her lawyer.
And then she threatened
to move away with Esme.
He can't explained
what happened next.
"Something snapped", he said.
What did he do?
He beat the shit out of her.
She's in intensive
care at St. Luke's.
Fractured skull, broken jaw,
one of her implants
has ruptured.
Esme saw the whole
thing from the landing.
Oh, my God.
Lucky for you,
he's pleading guilty.
He won't contest the divorce,
he won't contest
the sole custody.
That means no trial.
You won't get dragged into it.
Thank god.
But I'm finished with you.
No.
No, please.
Please, I'm sorry.
You had every right
to lash out on him.
But not to his family.
Carmen did nothing
to you, nothing.
Esme did nothing to you.
You're dangerous, Elle.
You're ruled by your obsessions,
you have no self control.
Go home, get help,
figure your shit out.
I had no idea that Dave
was capable of violence.
Like my dad.
Like my mom's godson
Leon after he pinned
me down when I was seven.
Like Dad who couldn't
go more than a few weeks
without hitting me.
You're breaking my heart.
I'm sorry.
Kevin's taking Sarah
to his parent's in
Michigan this weekend.
Let's meet up finally.
Please.
It's time to trust again.
Let me take care of you.
Why are you always
looking backwards?
You need to dwell on the future.
Pick a dream, make it come true.
I don't know, it just
feels like sometimes
like no mater what
I do I always end up
with a guy who hates women.
Like I can't help it, like
it's my destiny or something.
You know that's bullshit.
There's good men everywhere.
Well, okay, not everywhere.
But they're around and
you just don't see them.
And you won't until you
get your mind right.
What, like medication?
Or yoga or therapy or church.
Or maybe you hug
kids with cancer.
You just need to stop
expecting a man to save you.
It's just you, Elle.
Nobody else.
Hard work, the journey inward.
You know, I'm gonna
miss our run on Saturday.
I'm going out Friday
night and I'm expecting
to have a massive hangover.
Is it a date?
Yeah.
I'm on my way.
I didn't tell anyone.
What about you?
Remember, exit 26B,
on the left as soon
as you get off.
It's a bar that
used to be a diner.
Amazing martinis.
You can't miss the neon.
Oh, I booked us rooms
at the motel next door
in case we get too
drunk to drive.
I know, how responsible
and mature of me.
Katie?
Um, I'm sorry.
In back.
What can I get you?
One of your world
famous martinis, please.
How old are you?
21.
I believe you.
The
place is almost empty
except for a bored
couple, fat bartender,
a tired waitress and a
creepy dude who keeps on
trying to get the
courage to talk to me.
Hurry up before he succeeds.
- Where are you, dude?
- Thank you.
Thanks.
I'm starting to worry
that you punked out.
Or maybe before Kevin
left he handcuffed
you to the stove.
Shit.
Raining, fuck.
Get here.
I'm way
too drunk to drive.
Why don't I have
your phone number?
Right, it's your stupid
jealous husband's fault.
You know, if they really
think that we're such whores
then why are they even with us?
It makes me sick that Kevin
made you keep me a secret.
He's a jerk.
Yeah, I know, I'm a bitch.
What the hell happened to you?
Did you get into a car accident?
Can I help you?
Yes.
Do you have a reservation
for an Elle Overton?
Um, nope.
Really? Okay.
- Wow.
- Oh, oh, wait, wait.
Yeah, sorry.
E. Overton, yep.
Paid in full.
And is it just for myself?
Um, single, smoking.
I'd have to see some ID.
Right.
Oh, sorry.
There you go.
Here we go.
Checkout's at 11, room is
right down there on the left.
And did she get
a room for herself?
Right next door.
Is there a door between them?
Nope.
Is she in there right now?
Thank you, thanks.
Enjoy.
I'm in the room.
It's not bad.
I can't let you
pay for it, though,
especially since I'm leaving
as soon as I'm okay to drive.
I'm here, bitch.
Okay.
Dear Katie,
I've only left New Mexico
one time and it was
for boarding school.
I've never even see the ocean.
I want an exciting
life like yours.
Hi, Katie.
My name is Annie Dormer.
I feel faintly idiotic
even typing your name
because you're a
fictional character,
but I just wanted to say
I wish you were real.
Katie,
is this really the best
our society can do?
To treat females this way?
We're the world's mothers,
sisters and daughters.
Annie
Dormer again, I just had
the weirdest dream about you.
We were at a party, you
said that you were gonna
have sex with this
hot guy you just met
and did I wanna watch?
I got scared because
for some reason I did.
Katie,
my dad died at work.
He was basically cut in two.
I don't think I even loved him,
but just like you, his
death scarred me for life.
The whole world
is drowning in lies.
Our hearts are in constant pain
of a sort we can neither
identify nor feel.
We're not human,
just virtually human.
Your honest, brave,
lively spirit is just
what the world needs right now.
What I need.
Provided by explosiveskull
https://twitter.com/kaboomskull