There is only one option.
Abortion.
Are you mad Sia?
What.. what.. what nonsense is this?
Do you have any other solution?
But why do you always
look for a solution?
Because l need a solution!
l know, let us get married.
Okay.
Look, Rags l don't
want to pressurise you..
..but your results are
going to come in 15-20 days.
No, you are right Sia.
We should get married.
And your parents?
- Don't worry about them..
l will go home tomorrow.
Chandrasheel.
Yes sir, Please sit.
Take a left from ahead.
Say something sir.
Now you are really
driving me bananas..
..l told you clearly l don't want
to get my son married this year.
Come here.
lf you could take a look
at the girls photo once.
What's this, eh? Want to cut my ears?
Go way, keep the water heated
What is the point in
seeing the photograph?
We will show you the girl,
if you want.
Mister, can't you
understand Hindi, l told you once..
..l don't want to get my son
married this year. No means No!
That's all.
Greetings father.
- Bless you.
How did you come so suddenly?
l had some work in Patna..
..so l thought of
coming home for a day.
Go, go, go wash up l am coming.
- Yes.
He has come only for a day..
..otherwise l would have
asked him to see the girl.
Why are you pestering me?
Do l have any compulsion?
Everyday someone or the
other keeps coming for you.
lt's fine mother.
l am tired of making
tea and snacks for them.
Look son, now even
l want you to get married.
Mother please, please,
Just wait.
Laxmi, bring the photo.
- Yes ma'am
Which photo?
First see and then tell me.
Look.
Though your father does not like any.
lf you like anyone, then tell me.
What mother!
Have a look.
Ma'am, the cooking is done.
l will just come.
What will you have for breakfast?
Did you like anyone?
Who is she?
Sia.
Whose daughter is she?
Sampuran Singh's.
She was with me in college.
ls she from Delhi?
Punjabi !
Look Sir, it is very difficult
to find good girls these days.
Listen, once my son
becomes an l.A.S officer..
..then there will be many.
l am ready for 2-3 millions even now.
You are getting annoyed sir.
No, what's there to get annoyed.
What did you think, l will start
dancing hearing of 2-3 million?
lf you say, l will
increase some more..
What is this?
Why this cheap haggling?
Now please let me go, this is enough.
My son has come only for a day,
so please. Goodbye.
Please leave.
Since how long has
this been going on?
Since 4 years.
And all this while you
never got the time to tell me.
What are you thinking now?
What will you tell him?
Please why don't you talk to father.
l don't know how to..
And if your father doesn't agree?
Then l will have to listen to him.
Seriously.
Sia, Sia, look at me.
l love you, okay.
And l can fight not just my
father but the entire world, for you.
When are your results
for the civil services out?
ln 10-15 days.
You will make it, won't you?
l have a friend Mr. Jagdish.
He is a very big man,
a rich man of our area.
He has a lot of business.
He has 4 cold storages,
2 houses in Patna.
He has a daughter, she
is educated and cultured..
And the best part,
she is the only child.
Do you understand what l am saying?
She will be best for
you in every respect.
She won't roam around in
pants like Delhi girl.
Not all girls in
Delhi are same, father.
Don't try and tell me,
about Delhi girls !
l have not greyed my
hair in the sun, son!
l understand everything,
what all happens.
Anyway forget whatever happened.
You will marry Mr.
Jagdish's daughter..
..l have promised him.
Even l've promised someone.
You have promised someone?
..what standing do you
have to make a promise!
What do you think of yourself?
All the fun n' frolic that
you are having in Delhi..
..the motorcycle, the
roaming around here and there..
..you are doing it on
your father's money!
Don't forget that!
The food is served.
Promise my foot !
Come on, let's have food.
What is this?
Don't you have to just
wait for the results?
lf you could stay
for a few more days.
What ever happens l'm
the one who suffers!
Raghu, l am talking to you my son.
Will there be a calamity if
you stay back for 2 more days?
Yes.
Bye..
- Bless you.
Grab him! Grab him!
Who are you? Leave me! Leave me!
Put him inside!
Lallan, inject him,
inject him quickly - Leave me!
Where are you, Veer's mother?
Where's my tea?
Where is your son,
is he still bathing?
He left.
Left ? .. have you gone mad?
Where did he go?
Why didn't you wake me up?
He didn't even tell me.
When l woke up in the
morning he was gone..
Now don't lie to me.
Why will l lie?
Because you only have pampered him!
lt is the mother and son's
conspiracy, don't l understand!
Jagdish sir, is coming today.
How will l face him now?
He was coming
especially to meet Veer!
You are a stupid woman!
Hell with you!
Stop, stop, Stop.
Yes, that's it.
Mehfooz, get him down.
Careful.. he shouldn't get hurt.
Come on fast.. come on.
Hello handsome, how are you?
Tea!
Have it, it's good for hangover.
l am Laltu.
Don't you want to go to the toilet?
Come on.
Come on fast.
Come quickly.
hey Lakhan, we will be back soon.
Come quickly, man.
- Come on.
What place is this?.
First go and shit.. hold this..
..we will talk later.
l am sitting here.
Breakfast.
Brother, please tell
me what place is this?
Jhumri Telaiya. Got it!
Please let me go please.
- What?
Do one thing.. take some money.
You keep a lot of money.
So handsome don't you want to go?
Bastard.
Thinks l'm an idiot?
What is this! You have
still not had your tea.
Have it.. no use starving..
..you have to get beaten up too.
Eat it, you will feel strong. Eat it.
ls the sugar fine?
You bastard!..
Catch him! Catch him!
Lallan! Lallan, catch him!
Lallan, catch him!
Leave me!
Let me go!
Don't stare .
Told you, lower your eyes.
Always keep it low in
front of the master.
So handsome are you hungry?
Didn't l tell you to eat?
l knew it.
So ! you finally ate !
Hello.
- This is Sia speaking.
Can l talk to Raghuveer?
Stop acting?
- What?
l know the ways of girls like you!
But l..
- Keep quiet, listen to me!
lf you desire men so much,
open a brothel..
..all your desires will be fulfilled!
And don't you dare
call at my home again..
Come on .. move..
How are you my son?
Why have you kidnapped me?
Kidnap? Who told you
that l got you kidnapped?
l have only invited you.
Like this, in this way.
What else could l have done,
l was helpless..
..your father wouldn't
have allowed otherwise..
He acts like a lord,
now he will know.
Look, if you have any
enmity with my father..
..then settle it with him,
why are you dragging me in-between?
My l.A.S. results
are going to come out!
No son, l don't have any
enmity with your father..
..Mr. Madhukar.
But he should realise that
other people have self respect too.
Now he will know.
Anyway.. now you take rest.
But let me go, why are
you holding me captive.
Why? Didn't you tell him till now?
Where is it?
This Lalatua will
always be a dumb-ass!
Look boy, on the
13th is your marriage.
What nonsense is this?
Oh.. English !
Look sir, you don't understand.
l am already engaged.
lf you were engaged..
..then your father wouldn't
be licking Mr. Jagdish's ass!
Son, the girl is beautiful, cultured,
she cooks well, respects her elders..
..what more do you want, tell me?
This is crazy!
Where are you going,
my girlfriend is pregnant..
No matter what you do,
l will not agree to this marriage.
You cannot force me like this.
Please let me go.
guard, remember two things.
Don't hit the boy on his face.
The marriage photo won't look good.
Leave me.
Hey Laltu, don't let the boy sleep,
not even a minute, understood?
Leave me.
What did you do! You kidnapped him!
No need to shriek.
What was the need for you to
do all this, it is illegal.
Now you will teach me the law!
l don't understand..
- lf you don't understand..
..then don't blabber.
Do as l say.
Look, just once..
Listen to me carefully.
There is no need to
tell Janki anything.
l will talk to her
myself in the evening.
Ask her not to go
to college any more.
Where is Janki?
Queen of my dreams, sweet Anju.
Lots of love.
Am writing with my blood,
don't think it is ink.
Am dying for your love,
don't think l am alive.
Your husband turned out to
be a poet. - Future husband.
lt is the same thing.
Read further.
l miss you all the
time specially at nights
Don't ask about the nights.
Now even l am waiting for the D day.
Janki.
- Coming.
Give me my letter.
- Here.
Janki.
- Yes.
Sit down.
- What is the matter, mother.
Mother, l am getting late.
Janki, your father does not
want you to go to college..
Why?
- l don't know.
Ask him.
But there must be something..
- l said ask him.
l told you what he
asked me.. that's all.
Mother, won't you tell me.
Will l get my tea today or not!?
What happened ! You
didn't go to college today?
Father's orders!
Today's chemistry practical was so..
Sister-in-law, you know
what's the matter? Don't you
Sister-in-law, tell me.
- lt is nothing.
Look sister-in-law, cross your
heart and say it's nothing .
Tell me. Please.
Has your father ever listened to me ?
What do you think l
like what he is doing ?
Mother, tell me one thing.
ln today's time how can you
force some one to get married..
Sister-in-law, why don't you
talk to my brother. Explain him.
Janki, may be the boy is really good.
And he may start liking
you after the marriage.
And what if he doesn't ?
Don't say that.
l don't care, l will never
marry this way, that's final.
So Mr. Groom, yes or no?
8.. 9.. 10..
What you say now.
Come dear.
Come.. sit here.
You must be thinking, what
has happened to father..
..why has he stopped my college?
lsn't it?
Dear, whatever the parents do..
..it is for the
betterment of the children.
lsn't it? Yes or no?
Yes.
l have found a very nice boy for you.
Educated, cultured. That's why we
have to do everything in a haste?
lts fine, isn't it?
You do know, whatever l will do..
..it will be for your better future.
She is afraid that,
by forced marriage..
Forced, who said forced?
But that boy.. - lf you
don't know the entire thing..
..then don't speak in between.
She is talking nonsense,
no one is being forced.
The boy is ready for the marriage.
What happened?
Janki.
What is the matter,
you have come adorned.
Shall l say something?
Why, want to buy something or what?
The way you are getting
Janki married, is that right?
l mean, will she be happy?
So you think , only you care for her?
No, l was saying because..
Your uncle's daughter's marriage..
..took place in the
same manner. Right?
And then Mr. Tiwari's
daughter's marriage.
Both of them are happy, isn't it?
l don't know about
Tiwari's daughter..
..but sister Guddi is
not happy. l know that.
Look, l don't want
that our dear Janki..
The marriage has
been fixed on the 13th.
Shakti.
- Yes.
Distribute the sweets.
Hurry up.
The boy is studying in Delhi.
This year he has
appeared for l.A.S. exams
an educated son-in-law ..
..will be beneficial
for the entire village.
All of you are
invited for the marriage.
Come along with your family.
Okay.
And Mr. Sharma
special invitation to you .
l will come.
You got your daughter
married without any merriment.
Now come and see what
a real marriage is like.
Janki, Janki.
The date has been fixed for the 13th.
Good morning mister.
l told you no sleeping
Do you want to get thrashed again?
Why are you awake ? Go to sleep.
lt has been 7 days
since he has gone..
..he has still not called.
l know.. he is doing it purposely..
..so that we are tensed about him.
You are getting worried here..
..and he is roaming around
with that girl in Delhi.
Go to sleep Now.
He was saying that
the girl is very nice.
of course why will he not say that..
Raghu really likes her.
So what if he likes her?
Even l liked a lot of
things when l was young
but what did l eventually get ?
Duck-egg!
l know everything, what he likes.
Sleep quietly, don't make me mad now
There is something
that you don't know about
She is pregnant.. from Raghu!
Hail king Ram, Sita-Ram.
So, your marriage has been
fixed and you didn't even tell us.
Will you stop
studying after marriage?
What happened? ls everything fine?
My brother was saying, that
your groom has been locked up..
..they are even beating him up.
Janki, Janki.
He is very stubborn.
He won't understand like this.
He is thick skinned.
l will answer it.
Sunil, how are you?
He got through, l knew it.
Listen, Veer got through the exams.
Congratulations to you too son.
When is the interview?
Veer, he is in Delhi.
What happened?
- Just a minute.
When did he leave?
He left the very
next day of his arrival.
Tell me, what happened.
Just a minute.
He didn't reach Delhi!
lf he didn't reach Delhi,
then where is he gone?
The boy looks like a hero.
Did he run away to Bombay or what?
On which date did your son leave?
- On the 26th.
And you are lodging
a complaint today.
As l told you.. we
thought that he is in Delhi.
When did you know
that he is not in Delhi?
Today, will you lodge
the complaint or not?
l am writing it. Hey Nawal.
Bring the FlR book.
Don't you understand?
Why can't you understand?
Do you enjoy being thrashed up?
Come master.
The Prince has come from heaven
Has come to take you away with him.
The forest green veil.
The golden yellow gown.
And where will l get
the nose ring from?
They are so costly.
l will marry him,
live on morsels too.
What are you doing?
You scoundrel, what are you doing?
Through happiness
and sorrow, my love.
Quiet!
Everything will be fine.
You are looking very pretty.
Come, let's see you smile.
Now you are looking
like a real groom.
So handsome.
Very nice.
Come on..
Drink it..
My youth is of no use
without you, my darling.
This is my story, my darling.
Why are you making me jealous?
Come close to me.
Why are you making me cry?
My youth is of no use
without you, my darling.
This is my story, my darling.
My beloved is so naive.
And so shy of me.
l told him, come slowly,
come close to me.
My youth is of no use
without you, my darling.
This is my story, my darling.
Why are you making me jealous?
Come close to me.
Why are you making me cry?
My youth is of no use
without you, my darling.
This is my story, my darling.
The nights are very restless l
lay awake counting the stars.
With tears in my eyes l say,
darling please come to me now.
My youth is of no use
without you, my darling.
This is my story, my darling.
Why are you making me jealous?
come close to me
Why are you making me cry?
My youth is of no use
without you, my darling.
This is my story, my darling.
Laltu!
Laltu!.. Laltu!
You bastards!
Dear..
So, how did my
sister-in-law like her groom?
ln one day only you have
even learnt how to blush!
Tell me, how did you like him?
He is nice,
thank god, l am relieved
to see you smile like this!
Will l get my tea today?
Coming.
You know.
- What?
l think we should get married.
Brilliant idea,
but there is a small problem.
Who will marry us?
What happened?
Excuse me Mr. Raghuveer Sahi.
- You are excused.
You should be worrying
about that and not me.
Whenever l want, there
will be a long queue for me.
Oh! Where are they?
- Sia... Sia...
What should l do...
You do whatever you want,
l have to leave.
Sia... Sia... Come here...
Before leaving... tell me something.
One second.
Sia, will you marry me?
What is it?
Listen.
- Leave my hand, leave my hand.
Why are you behaving like this?
Ask your father.
Singh sir, we enjoyed a lot.
great food, great drinks,
and what a dance.
My youth is of no use
without you, my darling.
l have never seen such a dance.
We had paid 11,000 rupees.
That's fine, but how
much did you splurge on her.
Lawyer sir splurged 50,000 on her.
Come, come Mr. Sharma.
We all were remembering you...
...so l thought that
l should call you.
Sit down please.
Jagarnath! Get the fish.
Just a minute.
l didn't understand
one thing Singh sir...
When you have so much money?
why did you kidnap the boy?
But Singh sir saved all of his money.
What is money and wealth?
lt is transient.
lt comes, it goes.
For me, the biggest thing is honour.
Sometimes, for your honour...
...you have to put your life on risk.
Great Mahender sir, great.
For your honour.
You risked your daughter's life.
No one's life is at risk,
both are living together...
everything will be fine
...let us have
another peg on that note.
Hello... can l talk to D. G sir?
This is Madhukar Sahi speaking.
Yes.
Greetings sir, Madhukar speaking sir.
Yes sir.
l had talked to the Mr.
Pande, about my case.
Yes sir.
Nothing has happened sir.
There is a lot of
tension in the house sir.
Wife has stopped eating.
Yes sir. Yes sir.
Okay sir. Thank you sir.
My heart has been broken.
Some looter plundered it
Tell me, how are
your nights these days?
ls that only you can think of.
Then what?
You are married now,
what else should l ask you?
Ask her, when can we
meet brother-in-law?
Okay, l'll ask that only.
When are you
introducing us to brother-in-law?
l want to meet him too.
Can we meet him today?
No dear.
Please sit down.
lt will take sometime to meet him.
Dear, the thing is that...
...the priest has
restricted anyone to meet son-in-law
...for the next 15 days.
Because the auspicious
occasion has not come.
You know that son-in-law is
still living in the outhouse.
He has not even been
brought in the house.
That means we cannot meet him.
meet him the next time
when you come.
l'm in town only,
will meet him when
the priest allows to.
But will surely meet him.
Yes.
Tea.
What happened?
What should l do sister-in-law?
What do you mean?
He doesn't even talk to me.
Why don't you do something.
- What?
Anything.
- Anything? But what?
Plead to him, fall at his feet.
Sister-in-law!
What sister-in-law?
Look dear, l would have done
anything to save my marriage.
Anything.
lf you want to sleep on the floor...
...sleep comfortably atleast.
You stay away from me!
What is the matter!
You got up so early in the morning?
Have you talked to Janki?
Yes... but why?
ls brother-in-law fine?
Yes, he is fine.
But he doesn't talk to anyone.
l had already told you that...
...you are not doing the right thing.
But in this house, who
listens to the women...
Will l get my tea today?
Stop... stop.
Tea.
l told you stay away from me.
What are you doing?
Why don't you talk to me?
Please leave me. What are you doing?
l didn't want to get married myself.
Now if you don't accept me, then...
Look, l am sorry. Please, sit.
Don't say please to me.
Look, l have a girlfriend in Delhi.
You do understand girlfriend,
don't you?
l mean, for the past 4 years
we have been staying together.
And... she is pregnant.
And l don't even know
what condition she is in...
And even she doesn't know
what l have gotten into.
Why should l ruin
your life purposely.
Look, you are a nice girl,
intelligent...
...that's why l am telling you.
Oh God!
How is it?
- Good, sir.
Buy 5 kilos of it.
Come, come inspector sir.
Who have you come to
ruin in the market?
l wanted to talk something
important. - Please sit down.
Went to your home first.
Say.
Your son-in-law's father has
become fully active in Patna.
He has approached the DG Police.
But nothing to worry about...
l have suppressed the matter.
ls everything settled in the house?
Sir... everything should
have been settled by now.
The matter has become serious now.
...that's why l was looking for you.
l met the inspector.
The police are
looking for son-in-law.
So now?
- So what?
He was asking if
everything is settled with them.
How long will it take?
How would l know?
l cannot ask Janki about this?
Ask her.
Why can't you ask her,
you are her mother?
So what if l am her mother,
how can l ask her that?
Don't give me a lecture.
Explain to her, that
she is married now...
...they are husband and wife.
Then why is it taking so long.
Look, the marriage has to be
consummated... as soon as possible.
Understood.
Tell me what is it?
Won't you tell me?
Dear.
lt is not something to
think about so much.
...will you say something?
Have you gone mad?
What is wrong with this?
Let them go out? So
that he can run away!
Will your men do nothing?
Send them along.
Look... don't you want...
...your sister's life to get settled?
Everything becomes fine between them.
Tell me.
Okay.
What is the name of your girlfriend?
Sia.
- Really.
Do you know Janki
and Sia mean the same?
ln this case, there is a lot
of difference between the two
Ramkishen... tie the
calf in the shade.
Laltu!
Did you come from the temple?
What's wrong?
Dear.
Just a minute, listen.
Listen to me.
Dear, what happened?
Sister-in-law, no
matter what we do...
...but he will never accept me!
Look here, look at me.
Don't say that,
Look, everything
will be fine gradually.
just take it from me
nothing will be fine!
Don't say no to her, or else
we will have to force you.
You are very delicate.
He is feeling shy.
Don't you like girls?
What kind of a man are you?
You have been living with a girl
in the room for so many days...
...don't you feel
like doing anything.
l don't think he is capable!
Sir, all this useless talk.
Ask him for what we have called him.
He is intelligent himself,
he lives in Delhi.
You are not doing your duty,
the duty of a husband.
Tell us if you have any problem.
lt can be treated then...
Did you understand?
Tonight if you don't do
anything then you had it...
Listen...
Are you fine?
How many times have
l told you, don't touch me!
You think l am impotent!
ls anyone there?
Shout... let me see who comes.
This is what your
father wanted, isn't it?
Leave me! Leave me!
No!
Dear.
What are you doing?
l am sorry...
But... you are my husband!
My incomplete story,
my incomplete saga.
My dreams have been shattered.
My hopes have been broken.
On the unknown path,
amidst the strange season.
ls my lonely,
lonely, lonely heart.
Just the shadows of memories.
And drowning in the
joys and in the sorrows.
ls my lonely,
lonely, lonely heart.
There is sadness everywhere.
Every eye asks a question.
Every single moment
is void of happiness.
l have come a far from my
destination, all l am left with is.
ls my lonely,
lonely, lonely heart.
l agree it is the
ambience of night.
There is darkness everywhere.
l agree it is the
ambience of night.
There is darkness everywhere.
There is the dawn just ahead.
Thinking that, is feeling happy.
ls my lonely,
lonely, lonely heart.
Just the shadows of memories.
And drowning in the
joys and in the sorrows.
ls my lonely,
lonely, lonely heart.
Tea.
Father.
The accounts.
Guess everything is fine now.
l was thinking of going
to Darjeeling for 10 days.
Not now.
- Okay.
Look...
it has been so many days.
l was thinking, let us call
son-in-law home for dinner.
Will he come?
There is no harm in asking him.
We'll tell Janki to ask him.
l like this place very much.
Whenever l get bored, l come here.
lt's a nice place, isn't it?
Will you come home to
have dinner tonight.
...with everyone?
Mother wishes so, and me too.
Okay.
lf you don't mind,
please wear these clothes.
Okay.
You get ready, l'll
be back in 5 minutes.
Daughter-in-law.
- Yes.
l am feeling very nervous.
- Why?
We have been waiting
for this day for so long.
Why are you nervous now?
Who knows what
son-in-law will like to eat?
Mother, we have
prepared so many things...
...he will surely like something.
You go and change, l
will get all done here.
Okay.
You fool! He ran away!
Who is it?
Mr. Mahender, so late in the night?
Son-in-law ran away.
- How?
Think of something and catch him...
...if not, then file a case
against him, but bring him back!
Mr. Mahender, it is not so
easy as you think it is...
...his father knows
the police general.
So you can't do anything.
Look l have always supported you...
...l supported you in this also.
But Mr. Mahender,
don't feel offensive but...
lt has been so many days...
...your daughter
should have done something.
Look, l will try.
Who knows how far he
must have gone in the night.
Ramlakhan, take the jeep out.
And you actually expect me to
believe this bizarre story of yours.
Sia, you still doubt me!
You can't imagine... - Can you
imagine what has happened...
...with me here?
Mom is a heart patient, you know!
Anyways, what
difference does it make to you!
You are already married
And l am about to get married.
Why are you looking at me like that?
Why are you doing this to me Sia?
Rags please, please
don't say anything more.
my parents have gone through hell...
...l don't think l will be able to
forgive myself for doing this to them.
But the least l can do is...
not hurt them anymore.
And l don't think my dad
will be happy to see you here.
Tell me one thing, has the
marriage been consummated?
Then there is no problem.
We have already lodged a case
of 498A and dowry prohibition.
Now we will file a case for
restitution of conjugal rights.
Then we will see how
your son-in-law escapes.
Greetings Mr. Mahender.
l heard that your
son-in-law ran away.
lt was very sad to hear that.
And what were those bouncers doing?
What will you do now, have
you thought of anything?
lf you need my help...
Just get these two
medicines that's all.
Greetings Mr. Mahender.
Congratulations! You are going to be
a grandfather. Distribute sweets now.
Okay, l will leave.
- Fine.
There is so much
tension in this house...
...and you are drinking.
There is no tension.
l have thought of everything.
Janki will go to her
in-law's house tomorrow.
Do you know what you
are talking about?
Speak softly.
Look, you know that...
The doctor has said, Janki
needs at least 3 months...
Just do what l tell you to do...
Go, and send Janki here.
Go!
Where are all of them?
Where are my specs... Bechen?
Who knows where he kept it?
Hello...
- Hello.
- Hello
Who is it, Veer!
Where are you son?
How are you?
We were searching for you...
l had a feeling it will be
that scoundrel's work only.
Where is mother?
She has gone to Deoghar
yesterday to pray for you...
...and look, you called today.
Veer listen to me carefully son.
Leave the hostel today,
and shift with Sandeep.
You had been selected in
the mains, do you know.
That's it, stay with
Sandeep and prepare harder...
...next year you
have to become an l.A.S!
And tomorrow when
your mother comes...
l'll call you up.
Take care, bless you.
Are you feeling okay?
What do you think, all
this happening is fine?
What difference will it make
if Janki goes after a few days?
ln this condition? who knows
what kind of people they are...
...how the place will be.
Why don't you say something?
What's up? What's taking so long?
Mr. Jagdish is in a hurry,
quickly send the tea.
Let it be, Mr. Sahi, l have
to go to the cold storage...
...some other time.
No, no, no sir sit, it
will come right now.
Send some tea.
Did you find out anything?
- No. - Don't worry.
One minute! One minute!
Congratulations Mr.
Sahi, sweeten your mouth.
What's the occasion?
You are about to become a
grandfather, and me too.
Did you hear Mr. Jagdish?
Have you all come here drunk?
My son is not even married,
then how can l become a grandpa?
Ram, Ram, Ram, such
inauspicious words.
The entire village knows...
...that my daughter is
married to your son.
Dear, touch his feet.
Hey, stop it, stop it! There's no
need for this drama. l don't know her.
l have not opened a
charity-home for you.
Move on, move on.
What you are doing is wrong,
brother-in-law.
l am doing the wrong thing?
...and what you have done
being the uncle... was right?
Don't push me brother-in-law,
what had to happen...
...has happened. Take a
look at the wedding photo.
l have seen many such fake photos.
Look Mr. Sahi, l have been
talking to you with respect...
And you are?
- l am crossing the limit? Eh?
My son has been kidnapped.
l have lodged an FlR with the police.
Mr. Jagdish is the witness.
The police are on their way.
All of you get out of here, or
else you will be behind bars!
Mr. Sahi, it is against
the pride of our village!
l don't do such buffoonery like you.
You people are into this racket.
Hey shut your mouth! Shut up!
Brother-in-law, what had
to happen has happened.
This is your blood.
How would l know whose blood it is?
How would l know where
all she has been to?
Who all she has slept with?
Mr. Sahi!!
Don't shout!
l will file a case against you.
- Go and file it!
l will not let the
judgement pass. ls this a joke!
Don't brag about yourself.
l will brag about myself.
You know the entire
village is the witness.
l will see you! Bloody uncouth,
barbarian, rascal!
Now...
Seems like, maybe l
made some mistake.
Maybe?
l was telling you
from the beginning...
...that all this is wrong.
Quiet! just be quiet!
l will get Janki married again,
with someone else.
Far away.
Have you gone mad?
She is pregnant.
How long does it
take to abort the child?
Great, you have said a
very wonderful thing today.
lf you have the courage, go
and tell your daughter too.
Because l can't even think
of such a disgusting thing.
Dear, dear.
Sit, sit.
Sometimes a man
thinks of something...
...and something else happens.
No one can go against
the will of the Lord.
We will go to Patna in a day or two.
We will meet a good doctor.
Everything will be fine.
This boy was not right.
doesn't matter.
l will look for another boy.
This time nothing will go wrong.
Come, we will have
breakfast together. Come on.
Janki. Janki!
Where are you going?
l don't know, l have
not thought about it.
What is the problem here?
- YOU!
What are you doing?
Quiet! Tell her
that she has gone mad!
What are you doing?
You keep quiet! Tell her!
Whatever l am doing,
it is for her good...
...she doesn't understand!
l know father, you have always
done everything for my good!
But you have done enough
good for me!
Now no more.
- Janki, you...
The life that's budding in me...
...l will not tolerate
anyone who thinks ill of him!
Dear, you... in this condition...
alone.
Nothing will happen to me mother.
You won't go anywhere?
- l will go father.
Without my permission, you
cannot step out of this house!
but l can kill myself can't l?
- Janki!
Till now l have been living my
life according to your wishes...
...but not anymore.
Now l will live my
life the way l want to...
...and don't even dare to stop me.