Enobarbus!
My friend Eros?
Where is Mark Antony?
Is walking in the garden.
There are hard news come with this.
Will desire your presence.
I'll bring him to hom
If it be love indeed, tell me how much.
There's beggary in the love that
can be reckon'd.
I'll set a bourn how far to be beloved.
Then must thou needs find out new
heaven, new earth.
Nay, but this dotage of our general's
O'erflows the measure:
his captain's heart,which in the
scuffles of great fights hath burst
The buckles on his breast, reneges
all temper,
And is become the bellows and the fan
To cool a gipsy's lust.
You shall see in him.
The triple pillar of the world transform'd
Into a strumpet's fool
News, my good lord, from Rome.
What news from Rome?
Let Rome in Tiber melt!
and the wide arch of the ranged empire fall!
Here is my space..
Kingdoms are clay: our dungy earth alike
Feeds beast as man:
the nobleness of life
Is to do thus
speak not to us.
Is Caesar with Antonius prized
so slight?
Sir, sometimes, when he is not Antony,
He comes too short of that great quality
Which still should go with Antony
Alexas, sweet Alexas,
where's the soothsayer
that you praised so to the queen?
Soothsayer!
Is this the man?
Is't you, sir, that know things?
In nature's infinite book of secrecy
A little I can read
Show him your hand.
Good sir, give me good fortune
I make not, but foresee.
Pray, then, foresee me one
You shall be yet far fairer
than you are.
He means in flesh
Nay, hear him Good now, some excellent fortune!
Let me be married to three kings
in a forenoon, and widow them all:
let me have a child at fifty,
find me to marry me with Octavius Caesar,
and companion me with my mistress
You shall outlive the lady
whom you serve
O excellent! I love long life
better than figs.
You have seen and proved a fairer former fortune
Than that which is to approach
Out, fool! I forgive thee for
a witch.
Fulvia thy wife first came
into the field....
Against my brother Lucius?
and then, joinined their force 'gainst Caesar;
Who from Italy, drave them.
Well, what worst?
The nature of bad news infects
the teller..
When it concerns the fool or coward.
On:Things that are past are done with me.
'Tis thus:
Who tells me true, though in his tale lie death,
I hear him as he flatter'd.
Labienus This is stiff news--hath,
with his Parthian force,Extended Asia
from Euphrates;His conquering banner
shook from Syria to Lydia and to Ionia; Whilst--
Antony, thou wouldst say,
O, my lord!
Speak to me home, mince not the general tongue:
Name Cleopatra as she is call'd in Rome;
Rail thou in Fulvia's phrase
From Sicyon, ho, the news!
Fulvia thy wife is dead
Where died she?
In Sicyon
Forbear me.
There's a great spirit gone!
Thus did I desire it:
What our contempt doth often hurl from us,
We wish it ours again;
she's good, being gone;
I must from this enchanting queen break off:
My idleness doth hatch
Enobarbus!
What's your pleasure, sir?
I must with haste from hence.
Why, then, we kill all our women:
we see how mortal an unkindness
is to them;
if they suffer our departure,
death's the word.
I must be gone.
Under a compelling occasion,
let women die;
it were
pity to cast them away for nothing;
though, between them and a great cause,
they should be esteemed nothing.
Cleopatra, catching but the least noise of
this, dies instantly;
I have seen her die twenty
times upon far poorer moment:
I do think  death, which commits
some loving act upon her,
she hath such a celerity in dying.
She is cunning past man's thought.
Alack, sir, no; her passions are made of nothing but
the finest part of pure love:
we cannot call her
winds and waters sighs and tears;
they are greater storms and tempests
than almanacs can report:
Would I had never seen her.
O, sir, you had then left unseen
a wonderful piece of work
Fulvia is dead.
Sir?
My wife is dead.
Fulvia?
Dead.
Why, sir, give the gods a thankful sacrifice.
If there were no more women but Fulvia,
then had you indeed a cut,
and the case to be lamented:
this grief is crowned with consolation;
The business she hath broached in the state
Cannot endure my absence.
And the business you have broached
here cannot be without you;
especially that of Cleopatra's, which
wholly depends on your presence.
No more light answers.
For not alone The death of Fulvia,
but the letters from  Rome petitioned us at home:
Sextus Pompeius Hath given the dare to Caesar,
and commands The empire of the sea:
The sides o' the world may danger:
Command the officers Our quick remove from hence.
You may see, Lepidus
from Alexandria this is the news:
he fishes, drinks, and wastes
The lamps of night in revel
hardly gave audience, or
safed to think he had partners
you shall find there a man who
is the sum of all men' faults
Noble Octavius!
His faults in him seem as the
stars of heaven,
More fiery by night's blackness;
hereditary, Rather than purchased;
what he cannot change,than what he chooses
You are too indulgent
Let us grant, it is not
Amiss to tumble on the bed of Ptolemy;
To give a kingdom for a mirth;
to sit and keep the turn of
tippling with a slave;
To reel the streets at noon, and stand
With knaves that smell of sweat:
say this becomes him,
As his composure must be rare indeed
Whom these things cannot blemish,-
yet
must Antony no way excuse his faults, when we do bear
So great weight in his lightness.
Here's more news.
Thy biddings have been done;
Most noble Caesar
Pompey is strong at sea;
And it appears he is beloved of those
That only have fear'd Caesar:
I should have known no less.
No vessel can peep forth, but 'tis as soon
Taken as seen;
For Pompey's name strikes more
Than could his war resisted.
Antony,
Leave your lascivious wassails
When thou once
Wast beaten from Modena,
at thy heel
Did famine follow;
thou didst drink The stale of horses, and the
gilded puddle that beasts would cough at
Was borne so like a soldier, with patience more
than savages could suffer
'Tis pity of him
Let his shames quickly
Drive him to Rome:
'tis time we twain
Did show ourselves i' the field;
Pompey
Thrives in our idleness.
To-morrow, Caesar,
I shall be furnish'd to inform you rightly
Both what by sea and land I ...
Till which encounter,
It is my business too. Farewell.
Farewell, my lord!
If the great gods be just, they shall assist
The deeds of justest men
Thet Know, worthy Pompey.
They will not deny you
I shall do well:
The people love me, and the sea
is mine;
My powers are crescent.
Mark Antony In Egypt sits at dinner,
and will make no wars out doors:
Caesar gets money where
He loses hearts: Lepidus flatters both,
but  neither  cares for him.
Caesar and Lepidus are in the field:
a mighty strength they carry.
Where have you this? 'tis false
From Silvius, sir.
He dreams:
I know they are in Rome together,
Looking for Antony.
But all the charms of love,Tie up the libertine
in a field of feasts, Keep his brain fuming;
that Cleopatra
sauce his appetite
Pompey!
How now, Varrius!
This is most certain that I shall deliver:
Mark Antony is every hour in Rome expected:
Menas, I did not think this amorous surfeiter
would have donn'd his helm For such a petty war:
his soldiership
Is twice the other twain:
that our stirring can from the lap
of Egypt's widow pluck
The ne'er-lust-wearied Antony.
I cannot hope
Caesar and Antony shall well greet together:
His wife that's dead did trespasses to Caesar;
His brother warr'd upon him;
I know not, Menas,Were't not that
we stand up against them all,
'Twere pregnant they should square between
themselves;
Good Enobarbus,entreat your captain
To soft and gentle speech
I shall entreat him
To answer like himself:
if Caesar move him,Let Antony look over
Caesar's head And speak as loud as Mars.
Your speech is passion:
But, pray you, stir no embers up.
Welcome to Rome.
Thank you
Sit.
Sit, sir.
Nay, then
I learn, you take things ill which are not so,
Or being, concern you not.
I must be laugh'd at,If, or for nothing or a little,
I Should say myself offended,
and with youChiefly i' the world;
when to sound your name It not concern'd me.
My being in Egypt, Caesar,
What was't to you?
No more than my residing here at Rome
Might be to you in Egypt:
Your wife and brother
Made wars upon me;
and  you were the word of war
You do mistake your business;
my brother  makes his war against us both
Of this my letters
Before did satisfy you.
If you'll patch a quarrel,
It must not be with this.
You patch'd up your excuses.
Not so, not so;
I 'm your partner in the cause !
You have broken
The article of your oath
Soft, Caesar.
which you shall never
Have tongue to charge me with.
Caesar...
No,Lepidus, let him speak:
The honour is sacred which he talks on now,
Supposing that I lack'd it.
But, on, Caesar;
The article of my oath.
To lend me arms and aid when I required them;
The which you both denied.
Neglected, rather;
Truth is, that Fulvia,
To have me out of Egypt, made wars here;
For which,I do here ask pardon
on my honour
Noble spoken.
If it might please you, enforce no further
The griefs between you
Forget them quite
For't cannot be We shall remain
in friendship, .
Yet if I knew What hoop should hold us stanch,
from edge to edge
O' the world I would pursue it.
Give me leave, Caesar,--.
Speak, Agrippa!
You have a sister by the mother's side,
Admired Octavia:
great Mark Antony
Is now a widower!
Say not so, Agrippa:
If Cleopatra heard you, your reproof
Were well deserved of rashness.
I am not married, Caesar: let me hear
Agrippa further speak
To hold you in perpetual amity,
To make you brothers,
and to knit your hearts
With an unslipping knot
take Antony
Octavia to his wife;
beauty claims
No worse a husband than the best of men;
her  virtue and whose general graces speak
That which none else can utter.
By this marriage,all little jealousies,
which now seem great,Would then be nothing.
Will Caesar speak?
Not till he hears how Antony is touch'd
With what is spoke already
What power is in Agrippa,If I would say,
'Agrippa, be it so,'To make this good?
The power of Caesar.
and from this hour The heart of brothers govern
in our loves And sway our great designs!
Let me have your hand.
There is my hand.
A sister I bequeath you, whom no brother
Did ever love so dearly:
let her live To join our kingdoms and our hearts;
and never Fly off our loves again!
Happily, amen!
I did not think to draw my sword
'gainst Pompey
For he hath laid strange courtesies and great
Of late upon me
Time calls upon's:
Of us must Pompey presently be sought,
Or else he seeks out us.
Where lies he?
About the mount Misenum.
What is his strength by land?
Great and increasing: but by sea
He is an absolute master
Would we had spoke together!
Haste we for it:
Yet, ere we put ourselves in arms, let's finish
The business we have spoken of.
With most gladness:And do invite you to
my sister's view, Whither straight I'll lead you
Good Enobarbus!
Welcome from Egypt, sir.
If beauty, wisdom, modesty, can settle
The heart of Antony,
Octavia is
A blessed lottery to him
Charmian!
Regina?
Give me to drink mandragora
Why, madam?
That I might sleep out this great gap of time
My Antony is away
You think of him too much
O, 'tis treason!
Madam, I trust, not so
What's your highness' pleasure?
Not now to hear thee sing; I take no pleasure
In aught an eunuch has:
Hast thou affections??
Yes, gracious madam
Indeed!
Not in deed, madam; for I can do nothing
But have I fierce affections, and think
What Venus did with Mars
O Charmian,
Where think'st thou he is now?
Stands he, or sits he?
Or does he walk? or is he on his horse?
O happy horse, to bear the weight
of Antony!
Do bravely, horse! for you know
for whom you move
The demi-Atlas of this earth,
And we shall talk before we fight.
Most meet
That first we come to words;
let us know
If 'twill tie up thy discontented sword,
And carry back to Sicily much tall youth
That else must perish here.
To you all three,The senators alone
of this great world,
Chief factors for the gods,
And that is it
Hath made me rig my navy;
I  mean To scourge the ingratitude
that despiteful Rome cast on my noble father.
Be pleased to tell us--For this is from the present--
how you take The offers we have sent you.
There's the point
You have made me offer
Of Sicily, Sardinia;
and I must
Rid all the sea of pirates;
then, to send
Measures of wheat to Rome;
this 'greed upon
To part with unhack'd swords
That's our offer.
Know, then,I came before you here
a man prepared to take this offer:
but Mark Antony
Put me to some impatience:
though I lose The praise of it by telling,
When Caesar and your brother were at war,
Your mother came to Sicily and did find
Her welcome friendly.
I have heard it, Pompey;And am well studied for
a liberal thanks Which I do owe you.
Let me have your hand:
I did not think, sir, to have met you here
The beds i' the east are soft; and thanks to you,
That call'd me timelier than my purpose hither;
For I have gain'd by 't.
Well met you!
I hope so, Lepidus
Thus we are agreed:
We'll feast each other ere we part; and let's
Draw lots who shall begin
Or last, your fine Egyptian cookery
Shall have the fame
I have heard that Julius Caesar
Grew fat with feasting there.
You have heard much
I have fair meanings, sir
And I have heard, Apollodorus carried
What, I pray you?
A certain queen to Caesar in a
mattress
I know thee now: how farest thou, soldier?
I never hated thee: I have seen thee fight,
When I have envied thy behavior
I never loved you much; but I ha' praised ye,
Aboard my galley I invite you all:
Will you lead, lords?
We came hither to fight with you
For my part, I am sorry it is turned to a drinking.
Pompey doth this day laugh away
his fortune.
If he do, sure, he cannot weep't
back again.
You've said, sir.
We looked not for Mark Antony
here:
pray you, is he married to Cleopatra?
Caesar's sister is called Octavia
True, sir; she was the wife of
Caius Marcellus
But she is now the wife of Marcus
Antonius
Pray ye, sir?
'Tis true
Then is Caesar and he for ever
knit together
I would not prophesy so.
Octavia is of aholy, cold, and still conversation.
Who would not have his wife so?
Not  Mark Antony.
He will to his Egyptian dish again
And thus it may be.
Come, sir, will you aboard?
Thus do they, sir: they take the flow o' the Nile
By certain scales i' the pyramid;
What manner o' thing is your crocodile?
A toast to Lepidus!!
Pompey, a word.
Say in mine ear,what is't?
Forsake thy seat, I do beseech
thee, captain, hear me speak a word.
Forbear me till anon.
To Caesar!
I could well forbear't.
Go hang, sir, hang! Tell me of
that? away!
If for the sake of merit you
will hear me, you arise from thy stool.
I think thou'rt mad.
Wilt thou be lord of all the world?
What say'st thou?
Wilt thou be lord of the whole world?
That's twice.
How should that be?
These three world-sharers,
these competitors,
Are in thy vessel:
let me cut the cable;
And, when we are put off, fall to their throats:
All there is yours.
Ah, this thou shouldst have done,
And not have spoke on't!
In me 'tis villany;
In thee't had been good service.
being done unknown,
I should have found it afterwards well done;
But must condemn it now.
Drink!
I'll pledge it for him, Pompey.
Bear him away!
Ha, my brave emperor!
Shall we dance now the Egyptian Bacchanals?
Let's ha't, good soldier.
What would you more?
Good brother,let's ashore
I'll try you on the shore.
And shall, sir; give's your hand
O Antony,we are friends.
Come, down into the boat.
Take heed you fall not.
These drums! these trumpets, flutes! what!
sound and be hang'd, sound out
Captain, come
Give me some music
The music!
music, moody food
Of us that trade in love.
Let it alone; let's to billiards:
come, Charmian.
My arm is sore; best play with Mardian
As well a woman with an eunuch play'd
As with a woman.
Come, you'll play with me, sir?
As well as I can, madam
I don't know..
we'll to the river: there,my music playing far off,
I will betray Tawny-finn'd fishes
and, as I draw them up,
I'll think them every one an Antony,And say
'Ah, ha! you're caught
'Twas merry when
You wager'd on your angling;
when your diver Did hang a salt-fish
on his hook, which he With fervency drew up.
That time...O times!
O, from Italy
Madam, madam
Antonius dead
If thou say so, villain,
Thou kill'st thy mistress
but well and free,
there is gold
First, madam, he is well
Why, there's more gold.
But, sirrah, mark, we use
To say the dead are well
bring it to that,
The gold I give thee
will I melt and pour
Down thy ill-uttering throat!
Good madam, hear me
Well, go to, I will;
But there's no goodness in thy face
Will't please you hear me?
I have a mind to strike thee
ere thou speak'st:
Yet if thou say Antony lives, is well,
Or friends with Caesar, or not captive to him,.
Madam, he's well
Well said
And friends with Caesar
Thou'rt an honest man
Caesar and he are greater friends than ever
Make thee a fortune from me
But yet, madam
I do not like 'But yet,
Prithee, friend,Pour out the
pack of matter to mine ear,
The good and bad together:
he's friends with Caesar:
In state of health thou say'st;
and thou say'st free
Free, madam! no; I made no such report:
He's bound unto Octavia
For what good turn?
For the best turn i' the bed
Madam, he's married to Octavia
The most infectious pestilence upon thee!
Good madam, patience
I'll spurn thine eyes
I'll unhair thy head:stew'd in brine
Gracious madam,
I that do bring the news made not the match
Say 'tis not so, a province I will give thee,
And make thy fortunes proud:
He's married, madam
Rogue, thou hast lived too long!
Good madam, keep yourself within yourself:
The man is innocent
Some innocents 'scape not the thunderbolt.
Melt Egypt into Nile!
and kindly creatures Turn all to serpents!
Call the slave again:
Though I am mad, I will not bite him: call!
He is afeard to come.
I will not hurt him
These hands do lack nobility, that they strike
A meaner than myself;
Come hither, sir.
Though it be honest, it is never good
To bring bad news:
Is he married?
I cannot hate thee worser than I do,
If thou again say 'Yes
He's married, madam.
The gods confound thee! dost thou hold there still?
Madam should I lie, ?
I would thou didst,So half my Egypt were submerged
and made A cistern for scaled snakes!
get thee hence!
I crave your highness' pardon
He is married?
he's married to Octavia
The merchandise which thou hast brought from Rome
Are all too dear for me:
Iras,Charmian!
'tis no matter
Go to the fellow, good Alexas;
bid him Report the feature of Octavia, her years,
The colour of her hair: bring me word quickly
Let him for ever go:---
-let him not
Mardian,bring me word how tall she is.
In praising Antony, I have dispraised Caesar
Many times, madam.
I am paid for't now.
You take from me a great part of myself;
Use me well in 't.
Sister, prove such a wife
As my thoughts make you,
..
Anthony!
.. cherish'd.
Make me not offended
In your distrust
I have said.
So.
,,,
...
...;
the gods keep you,
And make the hearts of Romans serve your ends
Farewell, my dearest sister, fare thee well:
The elements be kind to thee
My noble brother!
The April 's in her eyes: it is love's spring,
And these the showers to bring it on.
No, sweet Octavia,
You shall hear from me still;
Be cheerful
Come, sir, come;
I'll wrestle with you in my strength of love:
Look, here I have you; thus I let you go,
and give you to the gods
Adieu; be happy!
Let all the number of the stars give light
To thy fair way!
Farewell!
Where is the fellow?
Half afeard to come
Go to, go to
Come hither, sir.
Most gracious majesty,--
Did you behold Octavia?
Ay, dread queen.
Where?
Madam, in Rome;
I look'd her in the face, and saw her led
Between her brother and Mark Antony
Is she as tall as me??
She is not, madam.
Didst hear her speak?
is she shrill-tongued or low??
Madam, I heard her speak;
she is low-voiced
That's not so good:
he cannot like her long.
Like her! O Isis! 'tis impossible
I think so, Charmian: dull of
tongue, and dwarfish!
What majesty is in her gait?
Remember,
If e'er thou look'dst on majesty
She creeps:
Is this certain?
Or I have no observance
Three in Egypt
Cannot make better note
He's very knowing;
I do perceive't: there's nothing in her yet:
The fellow has good judgment
Excelent.
Guess at her years, I prithee.
Madam,
She was a widow
Widow! Charmian, hark?
And I do think she's thirty
Bear'st thou her face in mind? is't long or round
Round even to faultiness
For the most part, too,
they are foolish that are so.
Her hair, what colour?
Brown, madam: and her forehead
As low as she would wish it
There's gold for thee.
Thou must not take my former sharpness ill:
I will employ thee back again; I find thee
Most fit for business:
go make thee ready;
Our letters are prepared.
A proper man
Indeed, he is so:
Why, methinks, by him,
This creature's no such thing
Nothing, madam.
The man hath seen some majesty, and should know.
Hath he seen majesty? Isis else defend,
And serving you so long!
All may be well enough
The world and my great office will sometimes
Divide me from your bosom.
All which time before the gods my knee shall bow
my prayers to them for you
Good night, my Octavia,
Read not my blemishes in the world's report:
I have not kept my square; but that to come
Shall all be done by the rule.
Good night.
Good night
..
eternity was in my lips and eyes....
Now, sirrah; you do wish yourself in Egypt??
Would I had never come from thence, nor you !!
Hie you to Egypt again
Say to me,whose fortunes shall rise higher,
Caesar's or mine?
Caesar's.
Antony, stay not by his side.
thy spirit  is high unmatchable,
Where Caesar's is not;
but, near him, thy angel Becomes a fear,
as being o'erpower'd
therefore make space enough between you
Speak this no more.
To none but thee; no more, but when to thee.
If thou dost play with him at any game,
Thou art sure to lose;
and, of that natural luck,
He beats thee 'gainst the odds:
I say, thy spirit
Is all afraid to govern thee near him
But, he away, 'tis noble
Get thee gone:
Say to Ventidius I would speak with him:
He hath spoken true: the very dice obey him
And in our sports my better cunning
faints under his chance
Ventidius!
If I lose my honor I lose myself.
Sir.
You must to Parthia:
your commission's ready;
Două zile rămase.
Sir...
Though I made this marriage for my peace..
In the east my pleasure lies
You stayed well by 't in Egypt?
Ay, sir; we did .
Eight wild-boars roasted whole at a breakfast, and
but twelve persons there?
we had much more
She's a most triumphant lady,
if report be square to her
When she first met Mark Antony, she pursed up
his heart
upon the river of Cydnus?
yes,There she appeared indeed; I will tell you
The barge she sat in, like a burnish'd throne,
Burn'd on the water:
the poop was beaten gold;
Purple the sails, and so perfumed that
The winds were love-sick
the oars were silver
Which to the tune of flutes kept stroke, and made
The water which they beat to follow faster,
As amorous of their strokes
. For her own person,
It beggar'd all description:
she did lie
In her pavilion--cloth-of-gold of tissue
O'er-picturing that Venus where we see
The fancy outwork nature:
on each side her
Stood pretty dimpled boys, like smiling Cupids,
With divers-colour'd fans, whose wind did seem
To glow the delicate cheeks which they did cool,
And what they undid did
O, rare for Antony!!
Her gentlewomen, like the Nereides,
So many mermaids, tended her i' the eyes,
And made their bends adornings:
at the helm
A seeming mermaid steers:
the silken tackle
Swell with the touches of those flower-soft hands,
That yarely frame the office.
From the barge
A strange invisible perfume
hits the sense
Of the adjacent wharfs.
The city cast
Her people out upon her;
and Antony,enthroned i' the market-place,
did sit alone,whistling to the air;
which, but for vacancy,
Had gone to gaze on Cleopatra too,
And made a gap in nature.
Rare Egyptian!
She made great Caesar lay his sword to bed
Now Antony must leave her utterly
Never; he will not
Age cannot wither her,
nor custom stale
Her infinite variety:
other women cloy
The appetites they feed:
but she makes hungry
Where most she satisfies;
for vilest things become themselves in her:
that the holy priests bless her when she is riggish
Lord of lords!
....
...
Octavia!
That ever I should call thee castaway!
You have not call'd me so, nor have you cause.
Caesar's sister: the wife of Antony has become
A market-maid to Rome.
Good my lord!
My dear sister, the adulterous
Antony has turned you off
Do not say so, my lord
I have eyes upon him,
And his affairs come to me on the wind
Where is he now?
In Athens?
No, my most wronged sister
Cleopatra
Hath nodded him to her
In contempt of Rome he has done
all this and more
In Alexandria, in a market place
Cleopatra and himself
in chairs of gold were  publicly enthroned...
unto her he gave the establisment of Egypt,
made her absolute queen
This in the public eye?
I' the common show-place, where they exercise
Let Rome be thus Inform'd.The people know it;
and have now received
His accusations
Who does he accuse?
Cezar: for having Pompei spoiled of Sicily
we have not give him his share
then he say, he lent me
Some shipping unrestored
lastly, he frets
That Lepidus shoul be deposed
and, being, that we detain
All his revenue.
Sir, this should be answer'd..
'Tis done already, and the messenger gone
I have told him I grant him part
but then, in his conquer'd kingdoms,
I demand the like.
He'll never yield to that
Nor must not then be yielded to in this
Hi is giving up the empire to a whore
our world...You have a pair of wolves
...no more
and throw between the food you have..
The one wil tear the other
I will be even with thee, doubt it not.
Dar pentru ce?
But why?
why?
You're against my being in these wars,
And say'st it is not fit
Well, is it,
Is it?
If not denounced against us, why should not we
Be there in person?
Your presence needs must puzzle Antony
Take from his heart, take from his brain,
from's time,What should not then be spared
'tis said in Rome that your eunuch
and your maids manage this war.
Sink Rome, and their tongues
rot that speak against us!
A charge we bear i' the war
And, as the ruler of my kingdom, will
Appear there for a man.
Speak not against it:
I will not stay behind
Nay, I have done
Here comes the emperor
Is it not strange, Canidius,
That from Tarentum and Brundusium
He could so quickly cut the Ionian sea,
And take in Turin?
You have heard on't, sweet??
Celerity is never more admired
Than by the negligent
A good rebuke,
Which might have well becomed the best of men,
To taunt at slackness.
Canidius, we
Will fight with him by sea
By sea! what else?
Why will my lord do so?
For that he dares us to't.
So hath my lord dared him to single fight.
Ay, and to wage this battle at Pharsalia Where Caesar fought with Pompey:
but these offers which serve not for his vantage,
be shakes off;And so should you.
Your ships are not well mann'd;
Your mariners are  swifters
in Caesar's fleet
Are those that often have 'gainst Pompey fought:
Their ships are yare; yours, heavy:
no disgrace Shall fall you for refusing him at sea,
Being prepared for land.
By sea, by sea
Most worthy sir, you therein throw away
The absolute soldiership you have by land;
Distract your army,  war-mark'd footmen;
Quite forgot your own renowned knowledge;
and give up yourself  to chance
I'll fight at sea
I have sixty sails, Caesar none better
if we should fail,
We then can do't at land.
Canidius,Our nineteen legions thou shalt hold by land,
And our twelve thousand horse
to our ship
How now, worthy soldier?
O noble emperor, do not fight by sea;Trust not to rotten planks
do you misdoubt
This sword and these my wounds?
Let the Egyptians
And the Phoenicians go a-ducking;
Have used to conquer, standing on the earth,
And fighting foot to foot.
Well, well: away
By Hercules, I think I am in the right.
Soldier, thou art:
but  our leader's led,
We are women's men.
Agrippa?
My lord?
Strike not by land; keep whole:
provoke not battle,
Till we have done at sea.
Do not exceed The prescript of this scroll:
our fortune lies Upon this jump.
Retire!
The egyptian queen flies!
Sail!
Retire!
Naught, naught all, naught!
Do not fight by sea!!
Our fortune on the sea is out of breath!
Gods and goddesses!
The greater cantle of the world is lost
; we have kiss'd away
Kingdoms and provinces.
How appears the fight??
On our side like the token'd pestilence,
Where death is sure.
ribaudred nag of Egypt,--
Whom leprosy o'ertake!-
-i' the midst o' the fight,
The breese upon her, like a cow in June,
Hoists sails and flies
That I beheld:
Mine eyes did sicken at the sight,
The noble ruin of her magic, AntonyClaps on his sea-wing
and, like a doting mallard,
Leaving the fight in height, flies after her:
I never saw an action of such shame;
Our fortune on the sea is out of breath,
And sinks most lamentably
Had our general
Been what he knew himself, it had gone well:
O, he has given example for our flight,
Most grossly, by his own!
Ay, are you thereabouts?
Why, then, good night indeed
To Caesar will I render My legions and my horse:
six kings already Show me the way of yielding
I'll yet follow
The wounded chance of Antony,
though my reason
Sits in the wind against me.
! the land bids me tread no more upon't;
It is ashamed to bear me!
I Have lost my way for ever:
Leave me, fly,
Make your peace with Caesar.
Fly?Not I.
Be gone!
No, no, no.
See you here, sir?.
Out!
Madam!
O good empress!
Sir!The queen!
I have offended reputation,.
O my lord,
O, whither hast thou led me, Egypt?
O my lord, my lord,
Forgive my fearful sails!
I little thought
You would have follow'd
Egypt, thou knew'st too well My heart was
to thy rudder tied by the strings,
And thou shouldst tow me after:
Thy beck might from the bidding
of the gods command me
O, my pardon!
Now I must
To the young man send humble treaties, dodge
And palter in the shifts of lowness;
With half the bulk o' the world play'd as I pleased,
Making and marring fortunes
You did know how much you
were my conqueror and that
my sword, made weak by my affection,
would obey it on all cause.
Pardon, pardon!
Fall not a tear, I say; one of them rates
All that is won and lost:
give me a kiss;
Even this repays me
Love, I am full of lead.
Some wine here!
Fortune knows
We scorn her most when most she offers blows.
Let him appear that's come from Antony.
Know you him?
Caesar, 'tis his schoolmaster
An argument that he is pluck'd, when hither
He sends so poor a pinion off his wing
Which had superfluous kings for messengers
Not many moons gone by?
Approach, and speak.
Such as I am, I come from Antony:
I was of late as petty to his ends As is the morn-dew
on the myrtle-leaf To his grand sea.
Lord of his fortunes he salutes thee, and
Requires to live in Egypt
which not granted,He lessens his requests;
and to thee sues
To let him breathe between the heavens and earth,
A private man in Athens:
For Antony,
I have no ears to his request
The queen
Of audience nor desire shall fail
so she From Egypt drive her all-disgraced friend,
Or take his life there:
So to them both.
Thyreus!
From Antony win Cleopatra
promise, And in our name, what she requires;
add more From thine invention, offers:
women are not
In their best fortunes strong;
but want will perjure
The ne'er touch'd vestal:
try thy cunning, Thyreus.
What shall we do, Enobarbus?
Think, and die
Is Antony or we in fault for this?
Antony only, that would make his will
Lord of his reason
. What though you fled
From that great face of war,why should he follow?
The itch of his affection should not then
Have nick'd his captainship;
at such a point,When half to half the world opposed,
he being The sole question:
'twas a shame no less Than was his loss
, to course your flying flags,
And leave his navy gazing.
Is that his answer?
Ay, my lord
The queen shall then have courtesy, so she
Will yield us up
He says so
Let her know't
To the boy Caesar send this grizzled head,
And he will fill thy wishes to the brim With principalities
That head, my lord?
To him again: tell him he wears the rose
Of youth upon him;
from which the world should note
Something particular: his coin, ships, legions
May be a coward's; whose
ministers would prevail
Under the service of a child as soon
As i' the command of Caesar:
I dare him therefore
To lay his gay comparisons apart,
And answer me declined, sword against sword,
Ourselves alone.
I'll write it: follow me
Yes, like enough, high-battled Caesar will
Unstate his happiness,
and be staged to the show Against a sworder!
Caesar, thou hast subdued
His judgment too.
Madam,A messenger from Caesar.
What, no more ceremony?
See, my women!
Against the blown rose may they stop their nose
That kneel'd unto the buds.
Admit him, then.
Mine honesty and I begin to square.
The loyalty well held to fools does make
Our faith mere folly:
yet he that can endure
To follow with allegiance a fall'n lord
Does conquer him that did his master conquer
Caesar's will?
Hear it apart.
None but friends: say boldly.
So, haply, are they friends to Antony..
He needs as many, sir, as Caesar has;
Or needs not us.
So...
Thus then, thou most renown'd:
Caesar entreats,
Not to consider in what case thou stand'st,
Further than he is Caesar.
Go on: right royal
He knows that you embrace not Antony
As you did love, but as you fear'd him
Oh!
The scars upon your honour, therefore, he Does pity,
as constrained blemishes,Not as deserved
He is a god, and knowsWhat is most right:
mine honour was not yielded,But conquer'd merely
To be sure of that,
I will ask Antony.
Shall I say to Caesar
What you require of him?
It much would please him,That of his fortunes
you should make a staff To lean upon:
but it would warm his spirits,
To hear from me you had left Antony,
And put yourself under his shrowd,
The universal landlord.
What's your name?
My name is Thyreus
Most kind messenger
Say to great Caesar this:
in deputation I kiss his conquering hand
tell him, I am prompt
To lay my crown at 's feet, and there to kneel:
Tell him from his all-obeying breath I hear
The doom of Egypt.
'Tis your noblest course
Give me grace to lay
My duty on your hand.
Your Caesar's father oft,
When he hath mused of taking kingdoms in,
Bestow'd his lips on that unworthy place,
What art thou, fellow?
One that but performs
The bidding of the fullest man, and worthiest
To have command obey'd
You will be whipp'd!
Ah, you kite! Now, gods and devils!
Authority melts from me!
of late, when I cried 'Ho!'
Like boys unto a muss,
kings would start forth,
And cry 'Your will?'
Have you no ears?
I am Antony yet.
Take hence this Jack, and whip him!
Moon and stars!
Whip him.
Were't twenty of the greatest tributaries
That do acknowledge Caesar,
should I find them
So saucy with the hand of she here,
what's her name,
Since she was Cleopatra?
Whip him, fellows,
Till, like a boy, you see him cringe his face,
And whine aloud for mercy:
Anthony!
Take him away!
being whipp'd, Bring him again:
this Jack of Caesar's shall
Bear us an errand to him
You were half blasted ere I knew you?
Have I my pillow left unpress'd in Rome,
to be abused by one that looks on feeders
Good my lord
You have been a boggler ever
I found you as a morsel cold upon
Dead Caesar's trencher
Nay, you were a fragment
Of Cneius Pompey's; besides what hotter hours,
Unregister'd in vulgar fame, you have
Luxuriously pick'd out:
Wherefore is this?
To let a fellow that will take rewards
And say 'God quit you!' be familiar
with My playfellow, your hand;
Is he whipp'd?
Soundly, my lord
Cried he? and begg'd a' pardon?
He did ask favour.
If that thy father live, let him repent
Thou wast not made his daughter;
and be thou sorry To follow Caesar in his triumph,
since you have been been whipp'd for it:
henceforth the white hand of a lady fever you,
Shake thou to look on 't.
Get thee back to Caesar.
Tell him thy entertainment:
look, thou say
He makes me angry with him
for he seems proud and disdainful,
harping on what I am, Not what he knew I was:
he makes me angry!
And at this time most easy 'tis to do't,
When my good stars, that were my former guides,
Have empty left their orbs, and shot
their fires Into the abysm of hell.
begone!
Have you done yet?
To flatter Caesar, would you mingle eyes
With  that ?
Cold-hearted toward me?
Ah, dear, if I be so,
From my cold heart let heaven engender hail,
let the first stone Dissolve my life!
Together with my brave Egyptians all, Lie graveless,
till the flies and gnats of Nile Have buried them for prey
I am satisfied
Caesar  comes near in Alexandria; where
I will oppose his fate.
Our force by land is nobly held;
our shattered navy too knit again, and sails,
threatening most sea-like
Where hast thou been, my heart?
Dost thou hear, my heart??
If from the field I shall return once more
To kiss these lips,
I will appear in blood;I and my sword will earn
our chronicle:We'll beat them
There's hope in't yet
That's my brave lord!
Let's have one other gaudy night:
call to me all my sad captains;
fill our bowls once more;
Let's mock the midnight bell.
We will yet do well.
Come on, my queen;
There's sap in't yet.
The next time I do fight,
I'll make death love me
Now he'll outstare the lightning
To be furious,Is to be frighted out of fear;
and in that mood The dove will peck the estridge;
and I see still, a diminution in our
captain's brain Restores his heart
when valour preys on reason,
It eats the sword it fights with.
I will seek
Some way to leave him.
He calls me boy; and chides, as he had power
To beat me out of Egypt;
dares me to personal combat,
Caesar to Antony:
let the old ruffian know
I have many other ways to die;
When one so great begins to rage, he's hunted
Even to falling.
Give him no breath
Let our best heads know, that tomorrow
the last of many battles We mean to fight
within our files there are, of those that served Mark Antony
but late,enough to fetch him in.
See it done And feast the army; we have store to do't,
And they have earn'd the waste.
Poor Antony!
Enobarbus!
Sir?
He will not fight with me,?
Why should he not?
He is twenty men to one.
To-morrow, soldier,
we'll fight by land
or I will live,Or bathe my dying honour in
the blood Shall make it live again
Woo't thou fight well??
I'll strike, and cry 'Take all
Well said; come give me thy hand.
Thou hast been rightly honest;--you have served me well,
And kings have been your fellows
What mean you, sir?
To make your followers weep?
Good friend, good night.Tomorrow is the day.
. You that will fight,
Follow me close; I'll bring you to't
Call  Enobarbus
He shall not hear me
What say'st thou?
He is with Caesar
Sir, his chests and treasure
He has not with him
Is he gone?
Most so
Go, Eros, send his treasure after; do it;
Detain no jot, I charge thee
write to him--
I will subscribe--gentle adieus and greetings
Say that I wish he never find more cause
To change a master
Dispatch!
my fortunes have
Corrupted honest men
Enobarb.
A plecat ca un erou.
Oh, dacă el a decis să Cezar marele război
luptă singur, apoi folosit Anthony...
si acum...
Go forth, Agrippa, and begin the fight
Our will is Antony be took alive;
Make it so known
Caesar, I shall
The time of universal peace is near:
Prove this a prosperous day,
the three-nook'd world
Shall bear the olive freely
Mark AntonyI served.
He was my master.
I will serve you honestly  as I served him
so I'll be yours
Enobarbus, Antony
Hath after thee sent all thy treasure,
the messenger came on my guard;
and at thy tent is now Unloading of his mules.
I give it you!
Mock not, Enobarbus.
I tell you true
I am alone the villain of the earth,
Tomorrow we'll fight by land
Oh, Anthony, eu lupt împotriva ta?
You have been honest..
You served me well
I will go seek
Some ditch wherein to die;
Forgive me in thine own particular;
But let the world rank me in register
A master-leaver and a fugitive
Anthony!
this is fought indeed!
They are beaten, sir!
fire in the air, we fight there too.....
Look, emperor they fought up us there!
Prepare, Scar.
See Anthony be took alive!
This foul Egyptian hath betrayed me!
Mark Antony!
Triple-turn'd whore!tis thou
Hast sold me to this novice!
Cleopatra, you will have my revenge!
The hearts that spaniel'd me at heels,
to whom I gave their wishes,
melt their sweets on blossoming Caesar;
Why is my lord enraged against his love?
Vanish, or I shall give thee thy deserving,
Follow Cezar' chariot and hoist thee up
Help me, my women!
O, he is more mad
To the  Roman boy she hath sold me,
and I fall under this plot;
she dies for't
Is mad.
To the monument!
There lock yourself, and send him word you are dead.
Mardian, go tell him I have slain myself;
Say, that the last I spoke was 'Antony,'".
O this false soul of Egypt
this grave charm Whose eye beck'd
forth my wars, and call'd them home
Whose bosom was my crownet, my chief end,
Like a right gipsy,at fast and loose, beguiled me
to the very heart of loss
Hei, Eros! Eros!
Sometimes we see a cloud that's dragonish;
A vapour sometime like a bear or lion
A tower'd citadel, a pendent rock
A forked mountain, or blue promontory
With trees upon't, that nod unto the world,
And mock our eyes with air:
thou hast seen these signs;
Ay, my lord,
They are black vesper's pageants
My lord?
That which is now a horse, even with a thought
The rack dislimns, and makes it indistinct,
As water is in water.
It does, my lord.
My good knave Eros, now thy captain is
Even such a body
here I am Antony:
Yet cannot hold this visible shape,
I made these wars for Egypt: and the queen,--
Whose heart I thought I had, for she had mine
O! thy vile lady!
She has robb'd me of my sword
No, Antony;
She hath betray'd me and shall die
Death of one person can be paid but once,
what thou wouldst do
Is done
the last she spake
Was 'Antony! Thy name so buried in her.
Dead, then?
Dead.
Unarm, Eros;
the long day's task is done,
And we must sleep
That thou depart'st hence safe,
Does pay thy labour richly; go
Off, pluck off
The seven-fold shield of Ajax cannot keep
The battery from my heart
Apace, Eros, apace.
No more a soldier:
Stay a while
I will o'ertake thee, Cleopatra.and
Weep for my pardon
So it must be, for now All length is torture
since the torch is out
Lie down, and stray no farther ,all is done
Eros!
I come, my queen
Stay for me
Where souls do couch on flowers, we'll hand in hand,
And with our sprightly port make the ghosts gaze:
Dido and her AEneas shall want troops,
And all the haunt be ours.
Come,Eros!
Eros.
What would my lord?
Since Cleopatra died,
I have lived in such dishonour,
that the gods
Detest my baseness.
I, that with my sword
Quarter'd the world, and o'er green Neptune's back
With ships made cities, condemn myself to lack
The courage of a woman
art sworn, Eros,That, when the exigent should come,
which now Is come indeed,
on my command,
Thou then wouldst kill me:
do't; the time is come:
Thou strikest not me, 'tis Caesar thou defeat'st.
Put colour in thy cheek.
The gods withhold me!
Eros,wouldst thou be window'd in great Rome
and see Thy master thus with pleach'd arms
bending down His  neck, before the  seat
Of fortunate Caesar, ?
I would not see't
Come, then; for with a wound I must be cured.
Draw that  sword.
O, sir, pardon me!
When I did make thee free, sworest thou not then
To do this when I bade thee?
Do it at once;
Or thy precedent services are all
But accidents unpurposed.
Draw, and come
Turn from me, then, that noble countenance,
Eros!
My captain, and my emperor, let me say
Before I strike ," farewell"
'Tis said, man; and farewell
Adio la un mare lider!
Shall I strike now?
Now, Eros
Why, there then: thus I do escape the sorrow
Of Antony's death
Thou teachest me, O valiant Eros
, what
I should, and thou couldst not.
but I will be a bridegroom in my death,
and run into't as to a lover's bed.
Come, then; and, Eros,
Thy master dies thy scholar:
to do thus
I learn'd of thee.
How! not dead? not dead?
Thy death and fortunes bid thy followers fly
Who's there??
Take my aword and give me death
My mistress Cleopatra sent me to thee
When did she send thee?
Now, my lord
Where is she?
Lock'd in her monument
She had a prophesying fear
Of what hath come to pass
fearing since how it might work, hath sent
me to proclaim the truth;
and I am come,too late
Too late
Your star is falling, sir.
You may not live.
Hei, good friend..
Do not please the faith with your sorrow.
We welcome to which will punish us and buried
lately you will have my thanks for all???
O Charmian, I will never go from hence
Be comforted, dear madam.
No, I will not
Anthony.
Anthony!
I am dying, Egypt, dying;
only
I here importune death awhile,
until of many thousand kisses the poor last
I lay up thy lips,
Dear my lord, pardon,--I dare not,
come down:Lest I be taken
I am safe
Help me, my women
And welcome, welcome.! die where thou hast lived
Quicken with kissing
had my lips that poweri!
Thus would I wear them out
I am dying, Egypt, dying:
Give me some wine, and let me speak a little
Of Caesar seek your honour, with your safety
They do not go together
Gentle, hear me:
None about Caesar trust but Proculeius
My resolution and my hands I'll trust;
None about Caesar
The miserable change now at my end
Lament nor sorrow at;
but please your thoughts
In feeding them with those my former fortunes
Wherein I lived, the greatest
prince o' the world,
The noblest; and do now not basely die
Not cowardly put off my helmet to
My countryman,-
Noone but Anthony could conquer
Anthony
Noblest of men, woo't die?
Hast thou no care of me?
shall I abideIn this dull world,
which in thy absence is No better than a sty?
O, see, my women!The crown o' the earth doth melt.
My lord!
O, wither'd is the garland of the war,
The soldier's pole is fall'n: young boys and girls
Are level now with men;
the odds is gone, And there is nothing left remarkable
Beneath the visiting moon.
Lady!
Madam!
Peace, peace, Iras!
No more, but e'en a woman,
and commanded By such poor passion
as the maid that milks
and does the meanest chares
It were for me
To throw my sceptre at the injurious gods;
To tell them that this world did equal theirs
Till they had stol'n our jewel
Ah, women, women, look,
Our lamp is spent, it's out!
Wherefore is that?
what are you?
What you say?
I say, O Caesar, Antony is dead
The breaking of so great a thing should make
A greater crack:
the round world should have shook lions
into civil streets, and citizens to their dens
He is dead, Caesar
but that self hand,
Which writ his honour in the acts it did,
This is his sword;behold his blood
Look you sad, friends?
The gods rebuke me, but it is tidings
To wash the eyes of kings
Caesar is touched
When such a spacious mirror's set before him,
He needs must see himself
O Antony!
I have follow'd thee to this
we could not stall together
In the whole world:
Whence are you?
A poor Egyptian yet
The queen my mistress,
Confined in all she has, her monument
Of thy intents desires instruction,
She soon shall know
Proculus.
My desolation does begin to make
A better life
'Tis paltry to be Caesar;
Not being Fortune, he's but fortune's knave.
Cleopatra, Caesar sends
greeting to the Queen of Egypt!
And bids thee study on what fair demands
Thou mean'st to have him grant thee
If your master Would have a queen his beggar,
you must tell him I beg a kingdom.
This I'll report, dear lady.
Have comfort, for I know your plight is pitied
Of him that caused it.
Hold, worthy lady, hold:
Do not yourself such wrong, who are in this
Relieved, but not betray'd
Where art thou, death?
O, temperance, lady
Sir, I will eat no meat, I'll not drink, sir;
If idle talk will once be necessary,
this mortal house I'll ruin,
Do Caesar what he can.
To Caesar I will speak what you shall please.
Say, I would die
Most noble empress, you have heard of me
I cannot tell..
Assuredly you know me
What's your name?
My name is Proculeus.
Antony did tell me about you.
I may trust you.
I have no use for trusting
Madam...
Don't matter so..
I dream'd there was an Emperor Antony
O, such another sleep, that I might see
But such another man
If it might please you...
His face was as the heavens; and therein stuck
A sun and moon, which kept their course,
and lighted
The little o, the earth
Most sovereign creature
...His legs bestrid the ocean: his rear'd arm
Crested the world:
his voice was propertied As all the
tuned spheres, and that to friends.
But when he meant to quail and shake the orb,
He was as rattling thunder
For his bounty,there was no winter in't;
an autumn 'twas that grew the
more by reaping
in his livery walked crowns and crownets;
realms and islands were
As plates dropp'd from his pocket
Cleopatra!
Think you there was, or might be, such a man
As this I dream'd of
Gentle madam, no
You lie, up to the hearing of the gods
Hear me, good madam.
Your loss is as yourself, great
I thank you, sir
Know you what Caesar means to do with me?
I am loath to tell you what I would you knew
Nay, pray you, sir,--
Though he be honourable
He'll lead me, then, in triumph?
Madam, he will; I know't.
It is the emperor, madam
Which is the Queen of Egypt?
Arise, you shall not kneel:
I pray you, rise; rise, Egypt
Sir, the gods Will have it thus;
my master and my lord I must obey
Take to you no hard thoughts:
What injuries you did us,we shall remember
As things but done by chance.
Sole sir o' the world,
Cleopatra, know,
If you apply yourself to our intents,
Which towards you are most gentle, you shall find
A benefit in this change
but if you take Antony's course,
you shall bereave yourself Of my good purposes
I'll take my leave
And may, through all the world: 'tis yours;
and we, your signs of conquest, shall
Hang in what place you please
No, dear queen,Our care and pity
is so much upon you,
That we remain your friend;
and so, adieu
My master, and my lord
Not so. Adieu
He words me, girls, he words me,
that I should not
Be noble to myself: what think you?
Thou, an Egyptian puppet, shalt be shown
In Rome, as well as I
mechanic slaves with greasy aprons, , shall
Uplift us to the view;
O the good gods!Nay, that's certain
the quick comedians extemporally
will stage us Our Alexandrian revels
Antony
Shall be brought drunken forth,
and I shall see Some squeaking Cleopatra boy
my greatness In the posture of a whore.
I'll never see 't; for, I am sure, my nails
Are stronger than mine eyes
Why, that's the way
It's finished, good lady.The bright day is done.
And we have it all done
Now, Charmian!
Show me, my women, like a queen: go fetch
My best attires
I am again for Cydnus,
To meet Mark Antony
Good Iras, go.
And, when thou hast done this chare,
I'll give thee leave to play till doomsday.
Bring our crown and all.
You bring me liberty
My resolution's placed.
Now the fleeting moon no planet is of mine.
Hast thou the pretty worm of Nilus there,
That kills and pains not
Truly, I have him.
His biting is immortal
Rememberest thou any that have died on't
Very many, men and women too
Indeed, there is no goodness in the worm.
Take thou no care; it shall be heeded
get thee gone
Yes, forsooth.
farewell
I wish you joy o' the worm
Give me my robe, put on my crown; I have
Immortal longings in me:
now no more the juice of Egypt's
grape shall moist this lip:
Methinks I hear
Antony call;
I see him rouse himself
To praise my noble act;
I hear him mock the luck of Caesar,
which the gods give men
To excuse their after wrath
Husband, I come!
I am fire and air; my other elements
I give to baser life
So; have you done?
Farewell, kind Charmian
Iras, long farewell
Dost thou lie still?
thou tell'st the world
It is not worth leave-taking.
Come, thoumortal wretch,with thy
sharp teeth this knot intrinsicate
Of life at once untie
O, couldst thou speak,that I might hear thee
call great Caesar ass unpolicied
O eastern star!
Peace, peace!
Dost thou not see my baby at
my breast...
O, break! O, break!
that sucks the nurse asleep??
As sweet as balm, as soft as air,
as gentle,
O Antony!
What should I stay?
In this vile world?
Now boast thee, death, in thy possession lies
A lass unparallel'd.
Your crown's awry;
I'll mend it, and then play
Where is the queen?
Speak softly, wake her not
Caesar hath sent...
Too slow a messenger
dispatch
What work is here!
Charmian, is this well done
It is well done, and fitting
for a princess
Ah, soldier
O sir, you are too sure an augurer;
That you did fear is done
Bravest at the last,
She levell'd at our purposes,
and, being royal,took her own way.
She looks like sleeping
As she would catch another Antony
In her strong toil of grace.
Take up her bed;
She shall be buried by her Antony:
No grave upon the earth shall clip in it
A pair so famous.