Hail to thee, Lord Harihar.
Please answer my prayers.
O Lord Jagannath,
O sanctifier of sinners,
O saviour of the poor…
You're my protector
Lord Jagannath.
Madan, how can you
joke with God?
I wasn't joking, mom.
I was only praying to God
that he should protect you.
Get away.
Why haven't you
left for college?
I'll leave in a bit.
Sheela, did you serve
breakfast to your brother?
She already did.
I've had enough to eat.
I only need some money.
How can I provide
you with money?
Men should earn money and
women should cook for them.
Right, but a man can start earning,
when he has completed his studies.
Before I can do that, I
must appear for exams.
To appear for exams, I must pay
admission fees, 200 rupees.
200 rupees!
After a whole month of working
hard for the committee,
...your father gets
paid 150 rupees.
I know, mother.
But I'm helpless.
Only three days left
to pay the fees.
If I don't pay up, all my
efforts will be wasted.
It's the last exam that
I must appear for.
Talk to your father about it.
He won't spare me a
lecture if I do that.
At least start talking about it.
Are you coming? -Yes, I am.
Are you sure? -Yes, sure.
Mom, you aren't following me.
Anyone there?
Where is everyone?
I was having breakfast.
-Where's your mother?
She's praying. -Oh, come on.
Someone's praying,
someone's eating.
No one's bothered about me.
I'm still quite strong.
If I weren't, all of you
would've gotten rid of me.
What happened? -Look
at the collar.
It needs some darning.
Ram Lakhan will be
here with the laundry.
Forget about him.
Mend this first.
I'm getting late for work.
Father. -What is it?
Well… it's just…
I have to pay exam fees.
-You need money.
I have no money.
Everyone only wants
money all the time.
Do you think it's
easy to earn money?
Why are you always scolding him?
How will he appear for the exams,
if he doesn't pay the fees?
Let him not take the exams.
You always support your son.
When is the exam? -It's
in the month of April,
…but I must pay the
fees within three days.
It's 200 rupees.
Only three days to
pay 200 rupees.
Why didn't you tell me earlier?
We've mortgaged our home for
the sake of your studies.
No one's willing to
lend me any money.
And he wants to pay exam
fees within three days.
Everyone is in a hurry.
Please try to manage this.
It's the last exam.
Once he has passed the exam,
he'll get a job somewhere.
He'll soon relieve you
of all your worries.
That's my only hope.
But what can I do right now?
I can't help you unless
I get my salary.
Mother.
Don't worry. He's angry right now.
But he'll manage to get the money.
You must go now.
Brother… -Yes.
I have some money
that I can lend.
Of course! How much do you have?
Ten rupees. -That's it?
Yes, that's it.
I've saved all the money you've
been giving me for years.
You mean the one rupee,
I give you every year?
Keep it safe for that one.
-Which one?
The one, tapping his feet. -Or
the one, swaying her hips.
How dare you! -Dad! -Madan!
On my way to college.
Munni, you haven't
gone to school.
No. -The English lady!
Why didn't you go?
How can I go?
All my clothes are too small.
You're making excuses
for avoiding school.
Do I miss college, because I
have to wear father's pants?
You better stop making excuses.
If I complain to
father, you had it.
He'll punish you.
He won't. -Such a brat!
Hello, aunt. -God
bless you, dear.
Hello, sir!
I have a permit.
A permit!
Jamunia, where's Ram Lakhan?
-He's inside.
Hey, Ram Lakhan. -Yes, sir.
Please come here.
-What's going on?
You have shaken up my family.
Don't touch my iron.
How do you say, I
shook up your family?
Of course!
You don't get the clothes on time
and my father can't leave for work.
We need your adept fingers to
work magic on our white collars.
Hurry up. -Don't you
see, I'm about to leave?
Why are you arguing with me?
Don't walk your way there. -Why?
I swear by your moustache.
Ride your donkey. You
look like a king.
What?
Fifteen.
That's fifteen, ma'am.
Please come a little earlier.
Your master got late, because
he didn't have ironed clothes.
I'll get it earlier, ma'am.
Today I was late,
because it was raining.
Uncle Ram Lakhan, will
you wash my dress too?
How about a double
rate for that?
Double rate?
Where did she learn that?
Who would give a washerman
double rate in this town?
We charge single only.
-Okay, single it is then.
But get it early in the morning.
I have to attend school.
Go away. She talks nonsense.
We're experiencing tough times.
It's difficult to buy
a new dress for her.
Right, ma'am.
Your lives are indeed difficult.
If a goat goes weak, it can
live on the grass around it.
But if a tiger goes weak,
he can't live for too long.
You're right. You know
about our family.
Of course! I remember the day,
...when you came here
after getting married.
I got a turban
with brocade work.
My wife got silk clothes.
She still remembers
that day very fondly.
Your father-in-law was here.
The family was so prosperous.
Gone are the days, Ram Lakhan.
Now there are only memories.
Wait until master Madan
completes his studies.
He's our only hope.
Good bye, ma'am.
Mind your pawns. -You
mind your queen.
Won't you say hello, Mr. Soni?
There goes! -Okay.
Another pawn is out. -Okay.
Here goes another one.
What is that?
Strange people.
They come whenever they want.
It's not that strange, Mr. Soni.
Madan, how long have you been here?
-Long ago.
Please take care of that. My
horse's life is in danger.
Just take a look.
Sure!
Three gallons.
What are you doing?
Oh no!
I'm sorry, ma'am.
It was a mistake.
You spoiled my clothes.
I haven't spoiled them.
They're dry washed.
They're dry washed with petrol.
I wanted the petrol for
the car, not my clothes.
I'll pay the price for
three gallons only.
But it shows six gallons.
Please charge her for
three gallons only.
I'll pay the rest.
She may not have enough to pay.
-Shut up.
Aren't you ashamed?
Please take your change.
-Give it to your boss.
Why did you do that?
You enraged a good customer.
If we lose customers like this,
…we'll have to shut
the petrol pump down.
Do you think it'll shut down,
or will you start a new one?
You got the money for six gallons
of petrol instead of three.
Why are you cribbing?
Let's get back to chess.
Why are you swatting flies?
Don't you have enough customers?
-No, Madan.
Neither customers nor
death is to be seen.
Are you coming in? -There!
She's calling out to me.
Lunch must be served.
-Right now?
Oh, I see. It's in your faith.
You have dinner before sundown.
We must. What if nocturnal
insects fell in the food?
You eat any kind of meat.
I'll take your leave.
Madan, will you stay for some time?
-Why?
If there are customers… -Of course.
Have your dinner.
No one's going to visit.
You may go.
I'll sit down here.
For coating, voting,
shooting or shirting.
You'll find a variety
of fabrics here.
You!
Yes, it's me.
Weren't you at the petrol pump?
-Me, at the petrol pump?
Oh, no. He is the younger one.
I'm the elder one.
I'm a human being, not
God, who is omnipresent.
It seems you had been
to a petrol pump.
Please show me a
'Lal Imli' fabric.
'Lal Imli'?
You must be joking.
Is that even a name?
Strange! Don't you know
it's a type of fabric?
Oh, 'Lal Imli'!
I'm sorry, we don't have it.
We have 'Hari Imli'.
What? - 'Hari Imli'.
We have written to 'Lal Imli'
to grant us the dealership.
Do you have Dhariwal? -Why
don't you check for yourself?
Here you are.
This one? -No.
Then, is it this one? -No.
This one's beautiful.
No?
What about this one?
These are the best.
Show me some 'dupattas'.
We have dozens of them.
Here you are.
It's chiffon.
Here you are. It's nylon.
And this one.
It's a red one in 'mulmul'.
But I want a white 'dupatta'.
What? -A white dupatta.
White.
There's the white one.
What are you doing?
That's my 'dupatta'.
Of course, it's yours.
The entire shop is yours.
Here you are.
Mannerless fool!
I don't want the 'dupatta'.
What do you want? -Nothing.
Are you a shopkeeper, or a fool?
I'm sorry, ma'am.
Ma'am, please give me the money.
What happened?
Take care of the shop. The
customer left without paying.
Take this.
Excuse me, is there
a florist around?
It's at that corner.
Jumman, give me the cap
and the cigarette. -Why?
Give me that.
Now go away for a minute.
What's the matter? -A lady
is coming to buy flowers.
She speaks English.
You don't understand.
Okay, you take care of her.
Excuse me. -Yes.
Please make me a bouquet.
Sure, I'll make one for you.
Place it in vases
or flower pots.
They're fresh, fragrant flowers.
The bouquet must be beautiful.
Price isn't a concern.
Wonderful!
If we have customers like you,
we can give away our hearts.
Daffodils, marigold,
lilies and bluebells.
But I want roses. -Why not?
Here you are. A bunch
of fresh roses.
It's you again.
Yes.
I get it.
Anyone, who comes that way,
mistakes me for my brother.
They were Maganlal and Sadanlal.
I'm Chhaganlal, their
eldest brother.
I sound different.
But both of them look exactly…
The three of us are triplets.
Triple fools.
That's why we look…
I'm sorry, but your
brothers are rude.
They're quite young and foolish.
Okay. Do you have
creepers for gardens?
Look at this one.
The night-blooming jasmine.
This one blooms during the day.
And that one…
…is the lover's bud. -Excuse me?
Don't you get it?
Lover, the one in love.
And the bud, that’s the flower.
Is that clear now?
Scoundrel, cheat, shameless!
Where are you going? -To hell.
Wait!
You'll see one of my brothers.
Gaganlal. Say hello to him.
What happened?
She threw a bunch of flowers.
Mind you, Madan.
All wounds heal, but those
from a flower rarely do.
What a pity!
She left without accepting
flowers from me.
What is going on here?
Nothing, father.
Come on, let's go home.
Shameless. Brazen.
You're always whiling away time at a
blacksmith, cobbler or florist's.
If you want to be friends
with these people,
...why mortgage our home for
the sake of your education?
I've told you a thousand times…
...you should spend
time with equals.
But you don't seem to get it.
Shameless!
I've told you a thousand times… you
should spend time with equals.
But you don't seem to get it.
You're back, Indu.
Yes. Can't you see? -What?
Of course, I can see you.
If you did, you wouldn't
praise this town so much.
My dear, there's no city like
this one in the whole country.
It seems you've never been
beyond the limits of this city.
Your next destination
will be Heaven.
It won't be as good
as this either.
Lovely city and the
people are lovelier.
Don't say that. I haven't
seen one decent person.
They're rude and mannerless.
They interfere with everything.
They're friendly people.
They love helping others.
I was trying to buy
something… -Buying?
You went shopping
all by yourself?
If you start doing things all
by yourself, what would we do?
If I were with you, you'd buy
anything worth a rupee for two.
What? -I mean, help you get
things at a cheaper rate.
Mr. Accountant,
what's the matter?
Anything worth a rupee for two?
Is it cheap or expensive?
If you buy, it's
quite expensive.
If you don't, it's cheap.
My dear, why are you so sad?
Father, it was a huge mistake…
...that we left a huge city
like Delhi to settle down here.
Now that I'm a pensioner, why
not settle down in my hometown?
This place is special for me.
I feel connected to
everything around.
I spent my childhood here.
Your mother and I started
our life together here.
But I don't like it here, dad.
You don't have to spend
all your life here.
I'll get you married soon.
You'll move to a bigger city.
You'll have a wonderful
life partner.
But sir, there are
boys in this town.
They're all fine men. -Not a word, Mr.
Accountant.
My dear, please try to
finish your graduation here.
What if the college
isn't good enough?
You'll be glad to
see the college.
It's a two-storey building.
Girls and boys study together.
You leave.
What did you say? -Leave.
Okay.
There's no reason to worry.
You'll like it there.
Madan, come here.
The professor is here.
Please come in.
Sit down, please.
Students, you'll
be glad to know…
…we have a new student, who
has migrated from Delhi.
Her name is Indumati.
I'm sure, she'll
like our college.
Take a seat.
Not there.
Prakash, please shift here.
Sit.
Silence, please.
I have the results
for your exams.
I'm sorry for those
who've failed.
But I'm also glad that…
one of the students,
...who have passed...
has worked really hard.
He has also opened up new avenues
in the field of criticism.
This student is not only
excellent at studies,
but also excels at sports.
The name of the student
is Madanlal Malhotra.
Silence, please.
I want each of you to read
Madan's answer sheet carefully.
You'll notice that his answers are
clear, brief and to the point.
You may take it from me
after the lecture is over.
Now, open your books.
Page 63, second paragraph.
Excuse me, may I have
your answer paper?
Sure!
If you don't mind,
may I drop you home?
Thank you.
I'm sorry.
I was really mistaken yesterday.
You can't tell until you
come closer to someone.
But how did you manage to be
present at all the places?
All I can say is that the
marketplace is like home.
Is it?
I'm glad we've met.
I thought, there are no
decent people in the city.
Nothing to see, no
markets to shop at.
You haven't seen the city yet.
There are some posh neighbourhoods,
huge bungalows and rich owners.
Which way do we go?
There.
Don't you live near the
place we met yesterday?
How can you say that?
Do all Parliament members
live in the Parliament house?
It's the place, where
business takes place.
Where's your bungalow?
My bungalow?
It's right there.
Is it close by?
Well…
…it must be close by.
There!
Where? -Right behind
the cement pipes.
That one, over there.
Does this bungalow belong to you?
-No, to my father.
Do you have a problem?
Not at all. The bungalow
belongs to your father.
Why would I have a problem?
May I drive in through the gate?
-Oh, no!
I'll get off outside.
It wouldn't be a problem.
I would've driven in.
Thanks a lot.
My father may not like it.
He may misunderstand, if
he saw us together. Bye.
Diwan, Kulwant Rai.
Diwan, Kulwant Rai?
Where? -There.
Oh, Diwan Kulwant Rai.
He's my father.
I see.
Good bye.
Hello, dear. -Hello.
What took you so
long at college?
Are you Mr. Diwan? -No,
he's in his room upstairs.
He's working on a case file.
Who are you? -I'm
the accountant.
You mea, the money man.
It's nice to meet you.
I wanted to see you. -What for?
I'll tell you. Let's go in.
I wanted to talk to you.
Well, actually… -What is it?
What can I do for you? -I'll
do something for you.
Please sit down.
Sit down. -Please sit down.
Sit down. -Sit down.
So, what's the matter?
Well…
Actually…
Well, actually…
Your house is lovely.
It is. But what's the matter?
Well, actually…
Insurance.
#NAME?
Savings are very essential.
You can save by
investing in insurance.
So, you're an insurance agent.
-Yes. You may say so.
But I have no children.
-You'll have them soon.
There's no hope.
Did you consult a doctor?
What did he say?
Get married.
Get married?
But we've met only
a couple of times.
To me. -You?
The doctor said that.
That means, you are… -Unmarried.
Actually, men in our family
often end up single.
What do you mean?
Your father must've
been married.
Father?
What are you saying?
If he wasn't married,
how would you be born?
Me? -No, me.
That's fine.
Investing in insurance is
essential if you're not married.
They say, blood
relations don't help.
You children leave you.
Your savings are
your only support.
That's right, but I can't get
an insurance. I'm diabetic.
Diabetes?
Then I think, you'll be…
Dead! -Dead?
How did you come in?
I thought, I should take
a look at your home.
By all means.
If this is your home, where am I?
-In my bungalow.
Actually, I got her along.
Hello. But… -He's right.
I came in with him.
You're with him, he's with you.
Who am I with?
What's commotion all about?
Who's that? -My father.
If that's your father,
what about hers?
Indu. -That's my father.
Where's my father?
Mr. Accountant.
-That's my father.
Strange! Everyone's
father's here.
It's time to run.
Hey, listen.
Mr. Accountant. -Father!
What is this, father?
-Insurance papers.
I'll have to apply for a loan
to pay for your exam fees.
Is it? -As per my calculations,
we gain absolutely nothing.
I haven't repaid the interest
on the previous loan.
What about my exam fees?
What can I say?
We won't have money, until
I receive the salary.
Ask the principal for a
week's time if you can.
How is that possible?
It's a University exam.
What can I do about it?
Steal, rob or consume poison?
Why are you staring at me?
At least try asking.
How much is that? -Hundred.
Here's another hundred.
Sir, please be careful with it.
-Don't worry.
Mr. Melaram. -Just a moment.
Madan.
Finally, you have paid
the admission fees.
You must've been
worried, but so was I.
I was worried.
It's so obvious, those who
have money, have no brains.
No brain.
Those who have brains,
have no money.
No money.
No one knows God's plans.
If you couldn't have enrolled,
it would've been a
loss for the nation.
It would've been
a national loss.
Are you walking home, Mr. Madan.
-Do you have a problem?
Of course. If a talented man
like you has to walk home...
…he won't have time for studies.
If he has not time for studies,
he won't pass the exams.
If he doesn't pass, it
would be a national loss.
I promise, the nation won't
lose anything even if I'm dead.
You may go.
Excuse me.
You took me to your
home yesterday.
Now, tell me where my home is.
You're poking fun at me.
I'm very sorry for
what I did yesterday.
You're such a sensible man.
Why did you do that?
You probably won't understand.
Someone said, 'you
smile so often'.
'How much pain is
hidden behind it?'
When poor people smile, they
hide their pain and tears.
You may never know.
Each time I
experience happiness,
I want it to last as
long as possible.
I don't care even
if I have to lie.
You had to lie.
Does that mean, you liked
being around with me?
I still do.
Thanks for the compliment.
Before getting into
the new business,
have you consulted
Sadanlal and Chhaganlal?
Sadanlal and Chhaganlal quickly
agree with whatever Madanlal says.
Is it? -Yes.
Stop at that corner.
That's where I'll get off.
I'll drop you home.
Oh, no.
I don't want to get used to it.
Thank you.
Bye. -Bye.
Tell me where the idol is?
-I don't know.
I'll break your bones! -What
are you doing, mother?
Why are you beating her up?
-Because she deserves that!
She has grown older,
...but can't tell the difference
between an idol and a doll.
Go away. -Look at that.
I wonder where she
took the idol.
I'm responsible for that.
You!
Yes.
I didn't know how to arrange
money for the fees.
So, I took the idol… -Sold it?
I didn't sell it. I gaged it.
Good Lord!
You gaged the idol!
The idol of Lord Jagannath.
He's the Lord we worship.
That's terrible, Madan.
Why do you think so, mother?
You told me, each time His
devotees are in trouble...
He protects them.
Today, he had to be given away
so that we get what we want.
I haven't gaged the God
that resides in your heart.
It was only a piece of silver.
I don't understand your logic.
We have faced a lot of
difficulties so far...
...but no one ever thought
of gaging the idol.
I wonder what we'll
have to face.
Don't worry, mom.
When I start earning,
getting your idol back
will be my first priority.
Madan.
Did the principal allow you
to pay the fees later?
I have paid the fees already.
You did!
Where did you get
the money from?
Well, actually… -Well.
I gave him the money.
How did you manage that?
I had saved some
from… the money,
you give me for daily expenses.
You had savings!
Really?
If it wasn't for you,
I would've been
in great trouble.
Forgive me, son.
I was disappointed with myself,
...so, I kept scolding
and avoiding you.
But it was killing
me from within.
It was excruciating.
We have our hopes pinned on you.
Start preparing for your exams.
-Sure, father.
Indu, come here.
Congratulations, you've passed.
Congratulations to you too!
I must go, I've to
tell my father.
I'll drop you in the car.
I don't need the car.
I think I'll just fly back home.
Sheela.
Munni! Where is everyone?
Mother!
I passed the exams!
Sheela.
Brother!
Sheela, I passed the exams.
Really?
You owe me a hundred!
Brother!
Munni, I passed the exams.
I passed!
Munni. -Mother, brother
passed the exams.
Get some sweets from
the sweet shop.
Yes, get it. -Tell him
we'll pay the rest later.
Tell him, we won't pay the rest.
Brother, has everyone
else passed?
Many other boys
have also passed.
None of the girls?
-What did you say?
What are you doing?
Will you get me a new dress?
Why not? I'll get
a dozen of them.
We'll get Sheela married
with great pomp.
Mom. – Mom.
I'll take mom for a pilgrimage.
-Really?
Of course! -What's the matter?
Where are you taking your mother?
-Father! I passed the exams.
No!
That's right. I just came
back from the college.
Really? -Yes, father.
Congratulations, son!
The God has answered my prayers.
Son, you've got to take
care of everything now.
I am too tired now.
Father, it's a happy occasion.
Do you think I…
These are tears of happiness.
They're washing away all
the sadness and worries.
It seems as if…
someone just relieved
me… of a huge burden,
I'd been carrying all my life.
It's not you.
I have passed.
Now you must look for a job.
My friend Premnath… is an
officer at the Secretariat.
You must meet him.
He'll offer you a good job
based on your qualification.
Of course, he will.
Let's celebrate
with some sweets.
Here you are, son.
Listen…
I can't do much.
Even if it was my son, I
wouldn't be able to help.
These days, it's quite difficult
to find Government jobs.
Even if there's a
single vacancy,
...there are thousands of graduates
on the waiting list already.
Could you tell me what I can do?
What can I say?
Why do you want a
Government job only?
Why don't you try
at other places?
Okay.
Bye.
Hello. -Hello.
Please sit down.
Mr. Madanlal, I read
your application.
We're looking for people, who
have a degree in teaching.
You're only a graduate.
I'm very sorry.
If I get a teaching degree,
can I become a teacher?
That's hard to say.
We had only two vacancies. But
we received five applications.
Thank you.
So, you can take up office work.
-Yes.
There's no vacancy
in the office.
We need people in the
technical department.
Do you have any experience?
I have no experience in
the technical field.
I'm very sorry.
Next.
Madanlal Malhotra. B.A.,
Punjab University.
Your registration number is 555.
Next.
May I ask you a question?
-Of course, you can.
When can I expect my turn?
It's difficult to say.
There are thousands of
candidates on the waiting list.
They are not only B.A. students.
There are B.A., L.L.B., M.A. and
others with even higher degrees.
Actually, Mr. Madan…
...ninety per cent
of young men today,
...want to work in offices.
There aren't as many offices.
What are you doing?
Where did you get the
sewing machine from?
It belongs to one of
brother's friends.
Once I've learnt using it,
I'll earn some money. -Money?
Do we have to stitch
clothes to earn money?
Has that ever happened
in our family?
I'm sure it's his idea.
Where is he?
Madan!
Madan. -Yes, father.
Take this machine
back right now.
What about your job?
I haven't got one.
-Didn't get one.
Drown yourself and die!
With such great difficulty, I
let you study until graduation.
You should help your old father.
Instead, you're doing nothing.
It's not my fault, father.
I've been visiting so many
places, asking for work.
But there are no jobs at all.
How is that possible?
Undergraduates have
high-paying jobs.
Matriculates have
Government and police jobs.
How can you not find one?
What are you talking
about, father?
Times have changed.
How have the times changed?
Have the tigers turned vegetarian,
or started working with farmers?
I'm sure you aren't
trying enough.
You want to enjoy
without having to work.
I have a feeling…
until I breathe my last…
I will have to feed the family.
Get out of my sight.
Enter the house, only after
you've earned some money.
There's no God like Ram and
no brother like Lakshman.
There's no woman like Sita and
no river as pure as the Ganga.
Hey, Master Madan.
What brings your highness here?
I'm in no mood for jokes.
It's a really tough time.
What happened, son?
-What can I say?
My house was mortgaged, so
that I could study up to B.A.
All the effort seems
to be useless.
I can't find a job. -A job?
Why would anyone give you a job?
What do you mean?
You've studied so hard.
All I can do, is write my name.
But I have a full-time job
that pays me sufficiently.
But you won't take
up a job like that.
What do you mean?
-Just go for it.
Whatever you're
offered, say 'yes'.
Why would educated people
like you take up such a job?
You want white-collar jobs.
Crisp, ironed collars, pants
with a straight crease.
You can't take up anything
that involves labour.
Labour? Why not?
If you do, what about the
reputation of your family?
What about the honour
of your forefathers?
What would the
world have to say?
If an educated man like you
takes up a laborious task…
…you'll make a difference.
All you must ask of God is
to keep your hands intact.
The drops of sweat that fall off
your body, when you toil hard...
…turn into precious pearls.
You have an idol
of Lord Jagannath.
Have you ever thought
why it has no hands?
The Lord cut His hands off
and gave them to man.
He gave them to you and to me.
He gave them to
everyone in the world.
Everyone uses their
hands while working.
A potter uses his hands
to make his ware.
Men working in industries
use their hands.
If you're blessed with
two strong hands,
but you can't feed yourself,
then you're being ungrateful.
What are you blabbering?
Don't you have work to do?
Of course, I do. -Take this.
Sorry, master.
I dared to advise an
educated man like you.
Ram Lakhan!
Yes, master.
What happened?
You've enlightened me!
You taught me something new!
Enlightened? -Yes.
I won't bother about
reputation anymore.
I'll learn your trade. -No!
Have you lost it?
I had lost it, but
now I'm a wise man.
Give me your blessings.
-God bless.
I didn't want you to do this.
I'm in a fix. What
about your father?
I'm sorry. That was by mistake.
Mistake! You spoiled my suit.
It was by mistake.
Give me your suit.
I'll clean it for you.
Should I stand naked until then?
Am I your father's slave?
None of my father's slaves are naked.
-Shut up!
How dare a washerman
argue with me?
Do you expect washermen
to not say a word?
Shut up, you brute!
How dare you talk
to me like that!
Why should I listen
to your rude remarks?
I say, stop that nonsense!
Do you know, who you're talking to?
-Yes.
To a man, who thinks
no end of himself.
What did you say? -A snob!
You could've also been
careful while walking.
There aren't as many stains as
the amount of rubbish you said.
Do you want me hanged to death?
-Yes, I will.
Do you see this washerman?
This rascal is arguing with me.
A washerman, who cleans
dirt is a rascal.
And the one, who makes
things dirty is a gentleman.
Shut up! -Will you?
Even washermen dare
to argue these days.
Such a snob!
I'm sorry that I'm late.
Before coming here, I had
an argument with a snob.
We have such fools
settled in our town.
What are you thinking, Indumati?
-Nothing.
I'm thinking of the person,
I'm going to marry.
Good! Think about it.
There's nothing to think about.
Father must've made
the right decision.
He is a Labour Welfare Officer.
That's right.
He's from a well-to-do family.
He gets paid a thousand
rupees per month.
That's great.
His salary makes me
want to marry him.
Go away! Shameless!
Why do you think, I'm shameless?
Try comparing us.
A Labour Welfare Officer
and a labour, who labours.
There's no officer. -I don't
want to marry an officer.
You're always joking.
I've spoken with my
father about you.
You must see him
tomorrow morning.
You spoke with him?
What did he say?
Why don't you meet him first?
I can't come in the morning.
I've to go to the washermen's.
Why? -I've started
washing clothes.
You don't get it?
Washing clothes.
You're joking again.
That's incredible.
It's the first time that I spoke the
truth but you think I'm joking.
I've actually joined
the washermen.
What do you mean? -I mean,
after learning the art,
I'll go to a new city to learn
washing, dyeing, printing and…
Enough. Stop explaining.
I'm sure you'll do well, no
matter what you choose to do.
Why not?
It's indeed progress.
My grandfather was
an accountant.
My father is a treasurer.
And I have progressed
to become a washerman.
I am okay with whatever
you choose to do.
But don't tell everything
about yourself to my father.
Otherwise, all my
efforts will be wasted.
Do you think I'm a baby?
I'll leave no stone unturned
to impress your father.
He'll be mighty impressed
with this educated washerman.
What nonsense!
-Wait, listen to me.
I was joking.
If you talk nonsense,
I'll just leave.
Hello, Madan.
Hello, Ms. Indu.
Ms. Indu? -Yes.
Why are you being
so gentlemanlike?
It's a deliberate effort.
Where is your father? -He
is out, but he'll be back.
Then, I'll forget about
being a gentleman.
When he's around, I'm
going to floor him.
Stop joking, Madan.
This meeting will decide the
fate of our relationship.
Don't worry.
We're going to be lucky.
Convincing your
father is as easy…
He is… -My father.
Is he your father?
No! How is that possible?
-What are you saying?
I mean, you're so
short-tempered.
But he is…
He seems so calm…
…and so friendly.
Nice!
His eyes shine with wisdom.
But I can't take it.
-Stop blabbering.
I mean, I must prepare
well to meet him.
I'll take your leave now.
Give me your blessings, father.
May God bless you, son.
Father!
Give me your blessings, father.
-May God bless you.
Get up.
Father, this is Madan.
I see.
How are you, son?
-I'm doing great.
Sit down. Let's have some tea.
Indu, you may go upstairs.
Indu has been
praising you a lot.
Son, why don't you sit down.
What happened? Are you okay?
I've caught cold. -Do
you want medicine?
I don't need medicines.
I have a feeling,
we've met before.
I think the same.
But I don't remember.
Anyway…
So, you've completed your studies.
-Yes.
What do you plan to do next?
I want to open a laundry,
...where I'll offer dyeing,
printing and washing services.
You'll need a lot of money.
-That's right.
What does your father do?
-He deals in money.
Is he a money-lender?
-No, a treasurer.
A treasurer? -Yes.
Have some tea.
Then, you may have
inherited a decent amount.
What did you grandfather do?
He was in the estate business.
He was a landlord.
-He was a landlord,
...but he donated all his
land before he passed away.
If that's the case, how will you
arrange money for the business?
Sir, I believe in hard
work and my own belief.
Having belief isn't enough.
What are you doing right now?
Right now? I'm talking to you.
I mean, what do you
do for a living?
I'm not working. I'm learning.
There's no institute, where
you can learn the trade.
Actually… -Sir, please
paper the sign.
What are you saying?
-Sign the papers.
How are you, my friend?
-Very well.
Do you know him?
Yes, I know him.
Are you friends now?
Friends? When did we fight?
You didn't fight, but yesterday
at the washermen's corner…
I knew we had met before.
So, you were the one.
Are you a washerman?
Well, we could say that.
You can call me a washerman.
-Of course, I will.
But I won't let my daughter
marry a washerman.
Aren't washerman human beings?
One who mends is a cobbler,
...another who makes
them is a brand.
One who weaves is a weaver,
...another who produces
in bulk is a businessman.
Stop that comparison.
-Bye. -Shut up.
Please listen to me.
I don't want to
listen to anything.
I'd rather kill my daughter
than let her marry you.
Get out of here.
Dad! Madan!
You can't talk to
guests like that.
Let go of him!
Get out of here.
Madan! -Shameless girl!
Did I give you freedom so that
you romance a lowly washerman?
Go upstairs and stay there!
Mr. Accountant, write a letter to Mr.
Sardarilal right away.
I'll get her married to Narendra.
-Okay.
Madan!
Hello, there. How are you?
Very well.
Come in and sit down.
Welcome.
You've come over
after a long time.
I came over to drop my laundry.
Drop your laundry? -Yes.
Madan is working as a
washerman these days.
I thought, I'd rather let him do
my laundry than to anyone else.
Here. Count them.
Laundry?
Madan is doing that?
What are you saying?
I'm saying that because I saw
him with the other washermen.
You're behaving as
if you have no clue.
Are you out of your mind?
Has any of our ancestors ever
washed clothes for a living?
Take that away.
Did you all see that?
You just can't
wish someone well.
I thought, it would bring
you some earnings.
But this man is being so rude.
Here comes your son. Ask him.
Have you started
washing clothes?
Yes, father.
There!
You were so confident!
Where's the harm, father?
Harm?
Do you even bother about
our family's reputation?
Do you want your sister's
engagement to be called off?
Do you want her to stay
single all her life?
Do you want our neighbours
to look down upon us?
But I don't pick pockets or gamble.
-Enough of that nonsense!
Did you study so
hard to do this?
Is that why we
mortgaged the house?
Did we go hungry, so that
you can be a washerman?
It's because of my education
that I can think broadly.
We Indians care for our reputation
more than anything else. -Shut up!
Indians care for reputation!
You've always spent time
with these lowly people.
You must've been a devil
in your previous birth.
It's our bad luck that
you were born to us.
But father… -Don't
call me father!
From now on, I
consider you dead.
Why are you saying that?
Get out of my house!
Now!
If you want to continue
doing this, leave the town…
so that no can your damned face!
Son, please don't do that again.
Mother, please try to understand.
-Are you leaving or not.
Get out of here. -Father! -Out!
Brother! -Madan!
Madan!
My son! Stop him!
Someone, stop my son!
Stop! Let him go!
Consider your son dead!
-Let go of me!
You won't know how
a mother feels!
Age and tough times
have driven you crazy.
My son! I'll die without him!
Then go to hell!
If you don't forget about
him, you'll regret it!
Mother!
Madan, what is it?
Did anyone see you come in? -No.
I'm sorry for my
father's behaviour.
Whatever happened
was fair enough.
Unless a person
proves his worth,
...the closest of
people turn away.
My father asked me
to leave the house.
He asked you to leave!
Yes.
I'm going away to far-off place.
I don't know where I'm headed.
I won't let you go.
If you must, I'll come along.
Don't be foolish, Indu.
You belong to a rich family
and lead a luxurious life.
You won't be able to tolerate
a moment of the tough life.
You don't know what
I'm capable of.
If you're with me, I can
face anything in life.
Without you, my life
would be meaningless.
But please try to understand…
-I don't want to do that.
If you leave without
me, I'll kill myself.
Indu!
I didn't know you
loved me so much.
I was…
If you're with me, my life
would be so beautiful!
Madan! -Indu!
Let's meet at 11.00 p.m.
in the garden.
I know, that scoundrel was here.
But I didn't expect you
to be so thoughtless.
You should've thought about
your family's reputation,
…before doing something like that!
-Father!
If you step out of the
house, before your marriage,
you'll see the worst of me!
Get back in!
Father!
'So, Indu decided not to come.'
'It was the right decision.'
'The luxuries of
her father's home'
'are far better than
the uncertain future.'
'She would marry an officer.'
'Why would she choose a beggar?'
'Love and affection are myths.'
'It's nice to talk about them
while seated on luxurious sofas.'
'When it gets dark,
your own shadow abandons you.'
'I'm all alone in
this world now.'
'I must walk alone.'
I have a long way to go.'
'It's an unexplored path...'
'and an unknown destination.'
I told Mr. Motiram,
it would be too soon for Mr. Dhaniram
to make arrangements for the wedding.
What did he say about it?
What could he say about it?
His wife insisted on it.
She said, her son had a job at the
deputy commissioner's office.
I want him to get married
first and then start his job.
Sister will get married soon!
-Quiet!
Sheela, go upstairs.
You go with her.
My greetings to the astrologer.
-Greetings to you too, ma' am.
How are you?
I'm doing fine.
Did you ask, if he wants tea?
-I had it, ma' am.
They want the marriage to
be held within 15 days.
I don't know how
we'll manage that.
It's a real wedding,
not a doll's wedding.
You're right, ma'am.
But you rarely find
such good boys.
You know, the groom's family
usually has an upper hand.
If they call the engagement
off, they have nothing to lose.
Your reputation is at stake.
Think about it.
How would it help to think?
A girl's family is like a
tiny bird in the fist.
Neither dead, nor alive.
Tell Mr. Motiram, we're ready.
-Very good!
That's very good!
I'll convey your message to him.
Good bye.
Good bye, ma'am. -Good bye.
That's too much!
Why did you agree?
There's jewellery to be bought,
arrange for gifts and dowry,
...the marriage ceremony
and food for everyone...
What could I have said?
We must do something.
We have nothing that we can spend.
-We'll manage.
Well, I wanted to say…
...that I need five thousand rupees.
-Is that it?
Why do you hesitate?
When do you want it?
The wedding is on the 12th
and the preparations are on.
If you could give it
to me in a day's time…
A day's time.
That's a little difficult.
You probably don't know that
merchants don't have so much money.
Dhaniram, do as I say.
For now, borrow the money
from someone else.
You may return the money, after
I give it to you 15 days later.
It's okay if you take 10
years to return my money.
Thanks a lot. You've relieved
me of a great burden.
Why are you saying that?
Am I doing you a favour?
Sheela is like a daughter to me.
-Of course.
I was only saying
...that your help at this hour…
...is something I will never forget.
-It's okay.
Well, I'll do as you say.
I'll try to arrange
for the money.
If God wills, that will be done.
I don't think, we'll
charge an interest.
But the problem is that
my boss in in Japan.
As you know, he looks after
the money-lending business.
I can't do anything much.
Okay. Bye.
You may go.
The time is over. Please
come back tomorrow.
It's the last day for paying
taxes, or I'll be fined.
Okay, give it to me.
Congratulations, sir. -What for?
Your daughter is
getting married.
Let me help you with
the decorations.
I usually get contracts
for leaders' meetings.
Okay.
I'll do that when it's time.
'Dhaniram, do as I say.'
'For now, borrow the money
from someone else.'
'You may return the money, after
I give it to you 15 days later.'
It's okay if you take 10
years to return my money.
Indravar. -Who is it?
Dhaniram.
What happened?
There's nothing to say.
The fact that I'm alive…
…is a miracle.
You know…
…how much it has
rained this year.
But there was a
storm after that…
...and timber worth
millions was washed away.
I've gone bankrupt, Dhaniram!
Dhaniram.
Will you ever forgive me?
What are you saying?
You asked me for help
for the first time,
...but destiny had
something else in mind.
I surely can't lend you
five thousand rupees.
Be strong, Indravar.
It's not your fault.
You must get well soon.
Everything will be fine.
Don't worry about me.
Sir.
The boss wants to see you.
Okay.
What is this Dhaniram?
There's five thousand
rupees in the cash box.
Why haven't you deposited
it in the bank?
It slipped out of my mind.
You're a senior officer.
How could you do that?
Don't you know, it's
people's money?
Both of us could be
in jail for that.
The bank must be closed now.
Deposit the money in the bank
tomorrow and show me the entry.
Sure.
'Don't you know, it's
people's money?'
'Both of us could be
in jail for that.'
'The bank must be closed now.'
'Deposit the money in the bank
tomorrow and show me the entry.'
'Where are you going, Dhaniram?'
'You can't face anyone
at home as the culprit.'
'You'll be arrested.'
'Your house will be auctioned.'
'People will look
down upon you.'
'Wouldn't it be
worse than death?'
No one knows what God
has planned for us.
What has happened,
was meant to be.
Please come with me.
Uncle, why is mother crying?
I can't bear to see
you like that.
Please come with me.
There's nothing left.
You don't have your
house anymore.
The money-lender is wondering
when he can take over.
If not for my sake, you must come
for the sake of this little one.
Come on! It's lunch break.
My teacher!
Master Madan!
My teacher, I've
proved my worth.
My business flourished
in the city.
I have 20 people working for me.
Look, what I've got for you.
I've got gifts for everyone!
A dress for Munni,
a sari for Sheela,
a shawl for mother and for
father… Wait a minute.
Look!
When I left, he had said,
I was good-for-nothing.
When I show him the
money, he'll be happy.
I'll place the money at
his feet and tell him…
I'm here to relieve him
of his responsibilities.
He may relax now.
What's the matter, Ram Lakhan?
Why are you crying?
Your father isn't
around to see this.
What do you mean?
Oh, no!
No, Ram Lakhan.
His clothes were found
at the riverbank.
Father!
Be strong, master.
He did all he could for my sake.
When it was my turn…
I'm so unfortunate!
It's destiny, master.
Be strong.
If you lose hope, who would look
after your mother and sister?
You're their only support.
Get up.
Let's go home.
Have courage.
My Lord!
Munni. Munni…
Madan!
You're back! -Yes, mother.
You're back!
Yes, mom. – Dear.
Lord, you're great!
I knew, when I have
the idol back,
I'll have all my good luck back.
We have been through
a lot, my son.
Your father…
I know, mother.
Ram Lakhan told me about it.
If it wasn't for his support…
I would've drowned
myself and Munni.
Good Lord!
What are you saying, ma'am?
Thank you, Ram Lakhan.
We owe you a lot.
Mother, whatever I have
learnt and earned in life…
…is because of him.
Don't worry, mother.
Your son is back…
...and he earns very well.
All your troubles are over.
'Bhai Dooj' is on the
day after tomorrow.
I'll see Sheela on that day.
Mom.
Brother has got me
a pretty dress!
Uncle, isn't it pretty?
It is indeed pretty.
Master, please freshen up.
You must be tired.
Yes. -Come on, son.
Hey!
Is that you, brother?
Brother!
Sheela, how did you
guess it was me?
Why wouldn't I?
Who else has hands
as hard as stone.
I see! Does my brother-in-law
have soft hands? -Oh, come on!
How is my brother-in-law?
Is he nice?
He is in office.
I'm not in a hurry, either.
I'll see him in the evening.
My left eye had been
twitching since morning.
I knew it was a good omen.
What's the good news?
I met you on 'Bhai Dooj'.
Isn't that good news enough?
I'll get the vermilion.
-Yes, get it.
I remember…
dad's scolding would hurt me.
But today, I really
want to hear it again.
You would know what happened.
Sheela…
do they treat you well?
They're all so nice.
But I blame myself.
If it wasn't for me,
why would father do that?
Sheela, it's my fault.
I couldn't perform
my duties as a son…
…nor as a brother. -Brother!
Don't say that.
I'm sure you'll be
successful someday.
I pray to God,
...that he should bless
my brother a long life.
He should be successful
and do so well in life…
...that he should be a star!
Sheela, what are you doing?
Who let him in?
You know, what your
family is known for.
I have told you a thousand
times… if you want to live here,
...you must consider
your family dead.
Mother! At least today,
you shouldn't say that.
My brother has come
back after a long time.
Don't insult him.
Those who are bothered
about their reputation...
…don't become washermen.
They don't steal money. -Mother!
Brother! -Why are
you shouting at me?
We've let your sister live here.
Isn't that enough?
Are you here to remind us that
we're related to someone like you?
Mother, my family's reputation…
-To hell with the reputation.
If you're bothered about
that, just get out of here.
Brother!
I can't take it anymore.
If you feel sorry for your
brother, you may go away with him.
If you must stay here, you must
forget about them forever.
Brother!
Sheela, mother is right.
You're my sister,
...but you're their
daughter-in-law.
Go back in.
Go.
Mother, please forgive Sheela.
She is innocent.
It's my fault that I came over.
Son, did you meet your sister?
-Yes, mother.
How is my girl doing?
She is very happy.
-Really? -Yes.
Her parents-in-law
are very nice.
They treated me very well.
Thank you, God.
At least my daughter is happy.
We're blessed to
have such in-laws.
You're right, mother.
You have to be fortunate
to find people like these.
Madan, I still find it
hard to believe that…
...a loyal employee
like Dhaniram,
...who never made even a small
mistake in keeping accounts…
...could take five
thousand rupees.
Probably, something happened
on the way to the bank.
We don't know what happened.
Only God knows about it.
All I know is that…
it's people's money.
That's why I'm returning it.
My late father's reputation
shouldn't be tainted.
I wish he was still alive.
A father, who has
a son like you…
…can't be dead. He will live on.
I'll take your leave. -Okay.
So, Mr. Vilayatiram.
What brings you here?
Do you know, Diwan Kulwant Rai?
It's his daughter's wedding.
I'm here to attend it.
Okay. Carry on. -Bye.
Brother! -Sit down.
Mother, please get ready.
We'll take the bus
in the evening.
Today? -Yes, mother.
Ram Lakhan, you should
also get ready.
Where's the hurry, master?
We must hurry up.
I can't live here any longer.
All the lanes and markets,
that I loved walking about…
…seem so hostile now.
And then…
I've to get back to work.
You're right, son.
I'll get ready soon.
Then, I'll return the clothes
without washing them.
Jamunia. -What is it?
Pack up all our stuff.
We're leaving in the evening.
I'll come back and help.
Come on, Munni.
Uncle, did you inform
the music band?
Yes, they've arrived. -Okay.
Ram Lakhan, how are you doing?
I came to congratulate you.
I'm going to Bombay
in the evening.
Bombay? -Yes, sir.
I found a job there.
You could've left
a few days later.
This was a good opportunity
to make some quick money.
I'm helpless sir.
I would've never returned your
clothes on such an occasion.
Okay. Here you are.
May God bless you. -Sir!
The procession just
heard that I'm coming.
What did you say?
You're coming?
I've been here for so long. The
procession is almost here.
Okay. Now take the clothes in.
Come on.
Where's your daughter?
I'll give her my blessings.
She is in her room upstairs.
What are you doing there?
Get those things quickly.
Be right there.
How are you dear?
-Welcome, Ram Lakhan.
I'm going to Bombay, so, I
came over to bless you.
Bombay? -Yes.
Mr. Dhaniram's son,
Madan… -Madan?
He is living with me right now.
He has started his own
business in Mumbai.
We're all leaving
in the evening.
This evening?
Yes. We're taking the bus
that leaves at 6.30 p.m.
May you have a long life, dear.
Have a happy married life.
I'll always pray for you.
The procession is here.
Let's take a look.
Let me take a look.
Why are you so eager? Is it
your marriage procession?
You're always poking fun at me!
'He'll always think,
I betrayed him.'
'Time is passing by.'
'If I don't gather courage,
I'll regret it all my life.'
Doctor…
There are two fractures
in the same bone.
That will be set right.
But the main concern is…
...she isn't responding to
the hammering on her knees.
What do you mean?
It seems, the shock has rendered
both her legs without sensation.
We'll try our best.
She may recover soon.
Son…
Yes, uncle.
Narendra is waiting outside.
Narendra is here?
I can't face him, uncle.
This girl has put us to shame.
You may let him come in.
But I'll step out first.
I'm very sorry…
that you're in such a condition.
But…
...you can't be blamed for that.
Instead…
I have caused you trouble.
This wasn't intentional.
If I had an idea,
I'd never let that happy.
I wish, we could've met…
and I could've
told you about it.
Nothing in life is
as great as love.
I'd consider myself lucky,
...if I could help
bring lovers together.
Narendra…
...there was a time when I…
...could be a part of his
happy and sad moments.
I could've been a
part of his life.
But now,
I can hardly carry
myself around.
How can I face him
...in the condition that I am?
I'll be a burden to him.
Don't lose hope.
I truly believe,
you'll soon recover.
God won't let someone like you
be in trouble for too long.
If I could be of any help,
I'd be more than glad.
Narendra…
We couldn't be life partners.
But we can be friends.
Madan, how are you doing?
Welcome, Mr Popatlal.
How are you? -Very well.
Will you have lunch?
-I've had it.
Okay, then. Let's go.
What about my order?
We have 6000 yards
of fabric ready.
What about the remaining 9000?
I wanted to talk
to you about it.
Imported dyes are not available
because of Government's policies.
Whatever was available, is
not yet out in the market.
Traders are waiting to
sell them in black. -Then?
If you don't mind, we'll
use the local… -Oh, no!
I won't accept local dyes.
My order is an old one.
I want exactly that.
If we insist on imported stuff,
...how would our local
manufacturers prosper?
I'm not here to listen to
speeches on patriotism.
I've heard enough of them
before the independence.
If the dyes are available in black,
you must buy them. -No, sir.
Buying in black is
against my principles.
Then I shall cancel my order.
Sir! -You and your principles!
Listen to me, sir. -It's
either principles or business.
Return all the fabric.
-Please have mercy, sir.
We've refused small orders because
we had a huge one from you.
It's a small workshop.
Our earnings matter a lot.
If you cancel, we'll
suffer a huge loss.
Isn't it a loss for me?
Return my fabric by evening.
I can't wait any longer.
Sir! -Let him go, Madan.
We're with you.
Of course!
God takes care of
us, not this man.
Sheela! -Brother!
How are you?
Calm down.
Are you excited?
She is married and a mother now.
Do you still think
she's a child?
Even when she's a grandma,
she'll be little sister.
Oh, my dear Madan!
Mother!
Greetings, mother. -May
you have a long life.
May God bless you
with happiness.
My scolding worked wonders.
Had I not scolded you,
...would you have
been so successful?
Scold me once more.
I'll be a millionaire.
You should swear at me from
the bottom of your heart.
If it was someone else,
he'd take it to heart.
You may ask her.
I praised you after
you had left.
That was too quick.
People usually do that
after someone's dead.
Don't say that, son.
All of us have our
hopes pinned on you.
May you live to be a hundred.
May you have a few
years of my life too.
Don't say that. If that happens,
...whom will I take care of?
Your son is such a darling!
Look at my son, your son-in-law.
He's stone-hearted.
-Don't say that mother.
Why not?
He's completely useless.
Oh, no! Why are you saying that?
There's a reason I say that.
Son, please help
him settle down.
Find a job for him.
Oh, no! I'm a washerman.
He will do anything you ask him.
Farming, small business, or clerical job.
-Will you shut up?
Let's have dinner. It's ready.
-Okay.
I'll have dinner
and be right back.
What's for dinner? -It's
a sumptuous fare.
Take a look yourself.
Okay. -Let's go.
Come on.
She talks too much.
Brother.
Did you see the baby?
So, baby!
What took you so long to
come and see your uncle?
Brother, sis told me…
...she bought a baby, when she went
shopping for vegetables. -Shut up.
Why should I?
Brother, why don't you
go to the market?
Quiet!
Brother, what are you doing?
I'm making a picture of you.
Why did you move?
I was wondering what
you were up to.
Let me see.
Who is this? -It's the Lord.
Is it so? -Yes.
If that's God, this
one's a ghost.
It's not a ghost, it's you.
Don't you recognise yourself?
Is that me? -Yes.
I see.
Who is this? -Your wife.
What? -Your wife.
It's your wife.
Naughty girl.
What are you thinking about?
Nothing at all.
Since I've come here, I've noticed…
you get lost, while you're talking.
We have everything
now, except for one.
Brother, you must
find a life partner.
A life partner?
Yes. Who else would be with you?
Who will marry me?
Why? What about Indu? -Sheela!
Don't mention her again.
Why not? I quite like her…
...and mom too.
She came to see us
after you had left.
I could tell she
loved you dearly.
Loved me?
Love.
When someone's at a
crossroad in life...
...where one road leads to love,
...and the other, to wealth…
...the path of wealth
is the only way to go.
She got married a year ago.
She must be revelling
in luxuries.
What happened?
Did you break something again?
I've told you to ask for
help, if you need something.
Why don't you accept
that you're handicapped?
You're a burden for
yourself and everyone else.
That's what girls
like you deserve.
Uncle, what about the men,
to be hired on daily wages?
There, Gattu will handle them.
Don't worry.
Okay.
What's your name? -Dinanath.
I'm well-versed with
dyeing and printing.
Sure? -Yes, sir.
Thank you, sir.
What's your name?
Gopal.
Will you be able to
do physical labour?
Yes. I'll do whatever you say.
You may go in.
Be careful.
Enough. -Please take some more.
We've had a hearty meal.
We'll pray for the peace
of your ancestors' souls.
Sher Singh. -Yes, ma'am.
Distribute these sweets
among the workers.
Sure, ma'am.
Munni, what are you doing?
Don't wake the baby up.
Go with Sher Singh.
Distribute sweets among workers.
Take this.
Cute kitty, how many rats
have you had since morning?
One less than you have.
-Very good!
Take this.
Munni when are you
getting married?
Very soon.
Why are you worried?
Take some sweets, sir.
Munni.
Take it.
Munni. -Let go of me!
Munni!
That girl… -The younger
sister of our master.
Master? -Yes.
His name is Madan. -Madan?
He's the owner!
He is a big man!
My son!
Madan.
Do you want to see Madan sir?
-Yes.
He isn't here. -Where is he?
At home.
It's his father's
death anniversary.
Death anniversary?
Right.
His father is dead.
His father died long ago.
'How can I face them?'
'Your sins mustn't
overshadow their happiness.'
'I'm in an abyss of anonymity.'
'That's where I deserve to be.'
Brother, I'll make him laugh.
-You can't do this. Come to me.
He'll laugh and his father too.
Brother. – Yes.
Is everything okay,
uncle Ram Lakhan?
I heard, you fought
with your wife again.
She picks up fights.
She watches movies every day.
Let her. Where's the problem?
You know, how things
are in the city.
Who is absent? -Gopal.
He is old and sick.
We have to deliver by evening.
How do we manage this?
Don't worry. I'll do his job.
No! -Let me do it.
I've lost touch and I have time.
Wash off all the
stains on your mind!
Tell the accountants, not
to deduct Gopal's salary.
He is unwell. -Okay, master.
Wash off all the
stains on your mind!
Mr. Madan. -Yes.
The new welfare officer is here.
-Let him wait in the office.
Okay.
Wash off all the
stains on your mind!
I'm sorry.
No problem.
That happens when
you're working.
So, do you get your
salary on time?
What?
Yes, I get it on time.
How many members in your family?
Two people besides me.
My mother and sister.
Have you saved up for
your sister's wedding?
She's quite young.
Young. -What about you?
Any problems?
Not at all. No problem.
The owner must be around.
I've been trying to tell you…
Mr. Madan, he's the
new welfare officer.
That's our managing director.
You? -Yes.
Don't I look like one?
Actually, I'm one of them.
It's so nice to see you.
Please come along.
Come in.
It's surprising to see you
working with the labourers.
There's an order
that goes out today.
I had nothing else to do.
The labourer got his daily
wages and our work got done.
Sit down.
This isn't something ordinary.
Such things make
the labourer proud
and they work very hard.
They progress in life,
so, does their master...
and in turn, the country.
I also saw the arrangements you
have for their entertainment.
Congratulations for that.
-Thank you.
I'll be really grateful, if you can
inaugurate the facility for us.
Sure. I'll do that gladly.
Some tea.
My friends,
it's a great honour for us…
that our Labour Welfare Officer,
Mr. Narendra Kumar
is present with us.
All of you have worked hard...
...to build this
entertainment centre.
And he will be inaugurating it.
Whatever I have observed during
my brief meeting with Mr. Kumar,
I can say that
...he is not only compassionate
towards labourers and workers,
but also, patriotic
and a humanitarian.
I'd request him to
say a few words.
Friends, it's not these kind
words from Mr. Madanlal…
...that make me obliged
to praise him.
The unique relationship he
shares with his labourers…
that Mr. Madanlal has
formed and is living up to…
...is an example for business
owners all over the country.
This beautiful relationship
that he has formed…
...will help us progress… will
help our country to progress.
As I inaugurate the hall, I'd
like to present the decision…
...that the labour committee
has just presented to me.
All the labourers wanted to
name the hall after the person…
…whom they're always proud of.
That is why,
everyone has decided
to name the hall…
Dhaniram Hall.
I congratulate everyone for
this wonderful decision.
By immortalising the memory of
the late father of Mr. Madanlal,
...all of you have proven, the roots
are more important than the fruit.
I appreciate the father, who
acknowledged his son's calling…
...and gave him the freedom
to make his own choices.
Mr. Dhaniram could've had his son
working as an officer or clerk.
But he let his son
choose the path…
...which was uneven, thorny and
demanded blood, sweat and tears.
It was Mr. Dhaniram, who wiped
off the feeling of inferiority,
...related to jobs that
require physical labour.
That's because he was sure,
...that in today's day and age, a
farmer, who toils in his field…
...or a worker, who
works in a mill...
...put in as much effort as a clerk
or an officer, with a desk job.
Finally, I'd like to pray that
each young man in our country…
…should be blessed with
a father like Dhaniram…
...so that the country
progresses at a rapid pace.
Friends,
I don't know what to say.
Today,
when I came in…
I didn't know…
...that you'd name the
entertainment hall…
...after my honourable,
late father.
I didn't know,
...this was his portrait.
I had no idea,
...you love for me
was so tremendous…
…and I have no words to express…
What can…
a son say about his father.
He's the father.
And there's nothing
more that I can say.
My father worked
hard all his life.
He worked so hard…
that it affected his health.
Whatever I have learnt today,
is thanks to the teachings...
…given by him.
He sacrificed his entire life
to make sure we led good lives.
I wish…
my tired, old father...
could've witnessed this.
You have honoured my father.
I feel honoured.
I'd like to thank our
honourable chairperson…
...and all of you.
Lakhoba…
What Mr. Narendra said was
exactly opposite of the truth.
What is it? -We can't say that
...each son should
have such a father.
But we can say that each
father should have such a son.
Come on.
'Get out of my house!'
'If you want to continue
doing this, leave the town…'
'so that no can
your damned face!'
'I appreciate the father, who
acknowledged his son's calling…'
'and gave him the freedom
to make his own choices.'
'Lakhoba…'
'What Mr. Narendra said was
exactly opposite of the truth.'
'What is it? -We can't say that
...each son should
have such a father.'
'But we can say that each
father should have such a son.'
Hey!
Gopal.
Why are you here at this hour?
I'm…
You know, you aren't allowed
to come here at night.
Go home and get some sleep.
Okay.
Your father is at the doctor's
to get your examination report.
He'll come back later.
From what the doctor said, it
seems that you'll recover soon.
Thank you.
We're indebted to you.
How can we ever repay that?
If you say that again, I'll leave.
-Mr. Narendra!
I'm actually leaving for work.
If you need something, please
tell the servant. -Sure.
I'll take your leave.
Mother, I've been
invited for tea.
You're always busy.
When can I have a word with you?
My dear mother, I'm
never too busy for you.
What is it? -Go away.
By God's grace we have everything,
but I feel so lonely.
The house seems empty.
The house seems empty. -Yes.
What do we do about it?
I'll take you for a pilgrimage.
I'll feel blessed only when
I see my daughter-in-law.
Mother, I've told you not to
mention about my marriage.
But Madan, listen to me. -I
said, I don't want to marry.
Is Mr. Narendra home?
-No, he's not.
He'll be back in a bit.
He has asked you to wait. -Okay.
It's you!
Madan!
Why are you here?
I see.
So, the welfare officer was Mr.
Narendra.
I'm sorry, I couldn't
congratulate you on the wedding.
How could I?
I never had the chance.
Anyway, it's not too late yet.
Congratulations.
I wanted to apologise as well.
I couldn't make it that night.
Then? -I'm sorry about it.
You must've left home with
a lot of dreams and hopes.
You're a woman and you
were out at midnight.
It was also raining.
You must've waited for me all
wet and shivering in the rain.
The clock must've struck one.
Then two.
Then three.
Four.
Finally, you must've
left while cursing me.
How can I explain?
-Where's the need?
You were right.
What did I have to offer?
Only love.
You can't eat it or wear it.
You're used to good
food and clothing.
It's all about being used to.
For example, I can't sleep
on soft and cosy beds.
Please don't say that. -Shut up!
I know you're someone
else's wife.
I have no right to talk to you.
But, can I not express?
I've suppressed my
pain for years.
Can I not tell you about it?
The wounds have left scars.
Can I not try healing them?
I thought, the story was over.
But I didn't know,
you'd drag it here.
Madan! -I can't bear
crocodile's tears.
I don't want you
to fool me again.
I don't want you to
have fun at my expense.
I have progressed
tremendously in life,
...but I couldn't tread
the path of love.
I lost my feet.
Mr. Madan, I heard it all.
Before you accuse this poor
girl for betraying you,
...did you ever think,
...her father could've stopped
her, when she was coming to you?
Did you ever think, she
would've tried to look for you?
It's a lie.
If that was true,
she'd wait for me.
She would've never
married anyone.
Whose marriage are
you talking about?
Narendra! -Madan…
Indu was always yours
and will always be.
Did you ever think,
...why Indu never get up even
after seeing you in front of her?
You said, you lost your
feet on the path of love.
Did you see, it wasn't you?
It was actually her.
She tried to catch up with you,
while in her wedding dress.
Indu, why didn't you tell me?
Because, she loves you
more than herself.
It was her love that forbade her
from being a burden to you.
It's a coincidence that she
came over for her treatment…
…and destiny brought the
two of you face to face.
Probably, she would've gone away
...and you'd never meet her.
Indu…
...why did you think
I'd be so heartless?
Do flowers make a burden?
Madan! -Indu!
I never thought you'd accept me…
...and give me a
place in your heart.
I won't ever let you go away.
Indu…
I had everything in life,
...but without you,
...it all seemed incomplete…
...so useless.
Madan! -Indu!
Silence! Quiet!
What's the matter?
What is going on?
Mr. Madan, Gopal tore your
father's portrait. -What?
Tore the portrait?
Why? -No idea.
He was wandering
there last night.
He was staring at the portrait.
Gopal,
...has my father
ever wronged you?
A workshop is the labourers'
place of worship.
Having that portrait is like
humiliating the labourers.
Why do you say that?
Because, I know Dhaniram.
What do you know about him?
He worked as a clerk
all his life.
He was vain.
He always thought, white
collar jobs were the best.
When his son tried
to labour hard...
...and earn a living
by honest means,
...he got rid of him.
-What nonsense is that?
For the sake of his pride…
…he laundered five thousand rupees
to marry his daughter off. -Gopal!
He was unfaithful, a thief!
-Stop that nonsense!
That's my prize.
I don't deserve what
you gave me yesterday.
What?
Father! -Master!
Father!
Let go of me!
Your father's dead. -No, father.
Where had you been, father?
Why did you leave us?
Why did you put
yourself through that?
Why did you put us through that?
Don't call me your father.
I've made some
terrible mistakes.
Ram Lakhan, take father home.
I'll get mother.
Let's go.
Mother, it's a miracle!
What happened? -It's
incredibly miraculous!
What has happened?
-Father is alive!
Yes, mother. He's is alive!
Yes!
What are you saying? -That's right.
Father's alive.
We're so lucky.
He was a labourer
in the workshop.
Where is he? -Come with me.
I can't walk.
There he comes.
You're…
I've given you a lot of pain.
Forgive me. -Oh, no!
Don't say that.
You're back.
I feel so blessed.
So blessed!
Mr. Dhaniram, we must say…
...both hard work and love
have won the race of life.
May God bless you, dear.
You were meant to be
my daughter-in-law.
Congratulations to you all.
The doctor has said, in a week, Indu
will start walking and running.
What? -That's right.
But I won't let her run away.
Right?