[1994 July 2, Midnight]
This is the Parish Hall
The prayer for the dead...
Please do it
Andres Escobar?
The Colombian player?
For hitting a self goal
To be frank, I can't sleep
after hearing that, Father
Look at his face, Father
and those who are sad, depend on You
The Father, the Son, and
the Holy Spirit, the Lord of all, forever
Amen!
As you arrive with grace
on the day ofjudgement
[Continues the prayer]
That was my father
Chandramohan
The story of the football
fans of Kaattoorkadavu
Hey! Buy sweets for everyone
- Khaderkutty?
- Seems like you're busy?
Didn't you bring sweets?
Keep this next to the well
He was the defender of
the Columbian team
Because of that, many people
ganged up and shot him dead
- My dear father!
-Yes!
If they continue to play like that,
we will win the cup for sure!
What happened?
Say Hi, when you see him
A stretch of green that Lord Parasurama
brought out from the sea with his axe
the biggest celebration of a huge group of
people in Kerala happens once in 4 years
Though different teams
have fans in our State,
'2010 World Cup Season'
Najeeb!
No, it will scratch you!
Suni, before you wrote that, we took
measurements and printed the flex!
Instead of writing 'Booked' on trees &
pillars, go write that on the World Cup!
"A naughty breeze,
or a striking lightning?"
"Are you a smart jasmine flower?"
"0 smiling girl!"
This fight happened now,
just because of her
What all are you reading?
Can't you call before coming?
The meeting at the library
will start now
I need to take bath
Don't wearthat cream shirt
Even though you are handsome,
you don't have any sense of beauty!
Baby Chandana, Smitha Thomas and
all are talking about you now
That's all here
Yo u com e
"A glance, as precious as a treasure"
"A glance with a smile on the lips"
"If we sit together merrily, my beauty"
"As the heart flies high
like a small feather"
There's a knack for all this
Do what I tell you
"If we sit together merrily,
my beauty"
- But isn't she slightly olderthan me?
- Crap!
That's true
I need to start reading, right?
She would have
mistaken us orwhat?
- By the by, Krishna...
- Not interested
That's not the tension
I'm not as good looking as you, right?
Come, boy! Let's go!
What say?
Herdad Khaderkutty
should be saluted!
Hey Palliveedan!
Hello! Just a second
Chechi...
I mean...
Which all are the important tourist
attractions in ancient Roman empire?
Crap! This is why Emperor Nero
burned all this down!
Open the door
lwant to come inside
I'll write the romantic poem
Dude, that won't be right
Please write it
Come on, say it!
For her, you need to be
literally proficient
"A glance, as precious as a treasure"
"A glance with a smile on the lips"
This was the turning
point in my life
When it has to come, love catches
a bus and comes into our lives correctly!
A) l4<ZowzCL£m~A£
"0 sweet moonlight, did you touch
within my heart with yourfingertip?"
"0 sweet breeze, did your soft verses
just give me a kiss on my ears?"
"Did someone come rushing to my memory,
as a thousand stars?"
A) l4<ZowzCL£m~A£
"Is a mysterious fragrance
caressing my soul?"
"ls someone approaching
my door-step without telling me?"
"I can hearthe rhythm of footsteps
approaching my lonely path"
"I am drifting like a flower,
in this feeling that can't be named"
"0 sweet moonlight, did you touch
within my heart with yourfingertip?"
"0 sweet breeze, did your soft verses
just give me a kiss on my ears?"
"Did someone come rushing to
my memory, as a thousand stars?"
A) l4<ZowzCL£m~A£
We're not saying this because we're
in 12th and you're in 11th
- Understood whatl said?
-Juniors, all of you leave!
Don't you know about PTA's decision that
politics isn't allowed in school, Ajayan?
We went to their houses & gave it to
them, without breaking any rules
-Ajay, run!
- Hey!
Sir, due to the presence of
gravity in this school ground,
- Mehru, go to your class!
- Sir...
You were floundering about
so much to say this?
whenl see her, my heart beats like
the fireworks during our festival
l'm clueless and l have
no idea what to do, man!
Don't you guys cultivate
tobacco in your Kaattoor?
This 'Beedi' of yours
is too light
Vipinan!
-What?
-A Colombian story of valour
Still, isn't it better to confess
everything from your side?
Escobar, don't come into
my fantasy and speak nonsense
continues in a draw without any goals,
even as it enters the 85th minute
You losers! Someone hit a goal, man!
-
only asked for some water
- Go and hit a goal!
Come on!
We'll be the ones raising
this football cup!
f
lose this game,
'
shave off half my hair
Palliveedan, you're the captain
of Green house...place the bet!
the star player of Red house, Vipinan,
is moving forward strongly...
The possibility of a goal is
disappearing forthe Red house now
We can see an injured Vipinan
limping out ofthe ground
- Hey!
'
sort you later
-You get lost!
I'll give my boots
Ask if someone else is ready to play!
Sir!
Him?
As a substitute for Vipinan,
Ajayghosh enters the ground now
Does he know to play football?
Let's celebrate and go to the barber shop
here, and shave off your hair, okay?
Their goalkeeper is
the district team player Vincent
What are you? A hedgehog?
Running here and there?
Suni, hit it!
It's okay, Seban! It's the 90th minute
Just kick it smoothly
Suni!
With the single goal that Ajayghosh
scored in the last minute of extra time,
Mehru wouldn't have been
serious about it, right?
Oh no! What a shame!
Palliveedan has lost his hair!
What happened, Chetta?
Moreover, he's a voracious
reader too, right?
After that, he never played football
Go, man!
He stopped playing that day!
Right, Vipinan?
I'm asking you out of that affection
- Oh my God!
- Get lost!
- Rascal!
- Three
Dude, you ask Mehru directly
If you like her, say it openly
If you're done peeing, come here
Why are you so lethargic?
Dude, do you remember our
Physics teacher from 8th grade?
Well, l was thinking whetherl should
fill some air in this cycle tyre
Mehru...
That won't happen, boy!
l have to go home and come there
right away to apply Henna
The boys in town are saying that Mehru and
that rascal Ajayghosh are dating now
I could have lived with it, ifshe
didn't like me because I was a Hindu
After all, he's from a lower
caste, rig ht Esco bar?
Hey Vipinan...
No! Leave it
You aren't old enough to knowthat
But if Riquelme was also there,
it would have been even more awesome
What doubt?
But I heard you saying
about going to some bar?
and to start making money
by riding an auto rickshaw
This time, flexes are
trending apparently
- Is it?
- Try to arrange the money forthe flex
- Hey Sunny! Give me a packet of Beedis
-Yes, coming
I'm thinking how
we will make that
There aren't many days left
There's only one way now
Get it from Thomas Master somehow
- Mom!
- What is it?
Try and get admission in
the Polytechnic first
Let's see after that
I want to know now
if you were serious,
I want a cowfull-time!
Your son hasn't just
failed in 12th alone
I want to buy a calf, feed
grass and water to it,
Give me the money
- Come
- Here's the full amount
Come, dear
My dear Messi, aren't
you seeing this?
- Like that!
- Here! Eat it!
Look who's here!
Vipin?
That's true
I also feel so often
It's an enemy country
I shouldn't be giving this
No! We're going to try
out something new
"The roar ofthe sea,
the preparation forthe battle"
'Sri Ganesha'
"The messiah of football is arriving
to the scorching heat ofthe Sahara"
We need to go to
the flex printing place right away
- Let's go
-You're stinking, man!
- Look!
- This is it
Give this lion's head to Messi
Chetta, no need all that
Shut up and get lost!
They have reached our
spot, to tie the flex
because she leaked the news
about the flex to Ajayghosh
Using a Panchayat member's power,
I will cut both these trees down
and since there are Argentina fans and
Brazil fans in our village since ages,
The club who wins
the toss can tie it first
- Stop!
- It's okay for us
- Move! Move!
- Hey!
- Not for us?
-Who are you?
Do you have a flex?
Hey! Give me a coin
Viva Brazil!
"Speeding like a lightning"
A) l4<Zowzﬁle~A£
What all do you want to knoiAf?
Write it fast
A) l4<Zowzﬁle~A£
-Anji
i wood is also fine, right?
-Yes
When they are roaming around for a space,
we should do that fans show in Kaattoor
Mehru, ask him smoothly
There's no fun in watching
the game at home
Anyway, who watches the World Cup at home?
Anyway, we need a colour TV
He's an Argentina fan, right?
And thus, flattering her dad,
Mehru got the TV from the mill
They started their fan club
in the Karayogam room,
Everyone started fan
clubs in a frenzy
With four goals
scored against us
I had warned Dad
not to vote for this rascal
They didn't even give
me a chance to correct,
You also stay strong, man!
It's not like that
everywhere in the world
- What about Mehru?
-I don't know
Study well
You shouldn't procrastinate
- Seena Mathew
- Hi
The college looks good, right?
"My heart is in pain, unable
to reach close to you"
to speak to you next,
Comrade Mehrunnisa Khaderkutty
from Kaattoorkadavu
Namaste
"You're a flowerthat blooms
on a branch far away"
What is this, man?
He has sense
He reads a lot
I told you earlier, right?
Mom, elder sister
& younger sister
"As the rhythm of the red army,
As the flame of the red em ber"
"You're like a shining star"
"My heart is in pain, unable
to reach close to you"
"You're like a shining star"
"le heart is in pain, unableto reach you"
confined myself to my college
with my studies & welding
Base calling for diver
Returning back, following the umbilical
Over
So this is your last
job before going home?
Yeah
Did you knoiAf? I've been asked
to dive from tomorrow
Don't you know
that I can't do this?
Hey!
f
wasn't scared of water,
I would havejumped into this water & died
You know, once upon a time,
l was a classic tennis player
- Shall I go, dear?
- Excuse me
lrinjalakkuda
Kaattoorkadavu
a young man who can lead the dairy
dreams of Kaattoorkadavu from the front,
No point, man!
You guys will lose!
Mr SunimonArattukuzhy
Respected voters,
my dear dairy
farmers of Kaattoor,
has ruined this society of ours
this Khaderkutty is
a wolf in a goat skin
Wolf in a goat skin
Say it
So cast all your valuable
votes to this Ajayghosh...
Muneerkka, this guy deserves our respect
It's been 4 years since he went there
He would want to take so many things, right?
He doesn't have to take this
He can buy this from his town
By working hard under
waterfor these 4 years,
It's been 5 years since
I started constructing my house
Come directly to our house tomorrow
Even though I'm late to come, things
are happening smoothly there, right?
Muneer Koduvally
Temple-dweller?
There's a limit for welding, man!
lfthis doesn't get repaired, I'll have
to carry that bunch of grass on my head
I like you as a fool
When I saw you working, I thought you'll
be starting the car after engine repair!
I think she wants you to
weld her scooter for free!
I want to join Argentina fans club
It's like Kuchela's thigh
which got hit by a mace
Maryam Rashida
Yeah, right! To change
the team fearing defeat,
I said that I'll think
about it and let her know
If we don't take her in,
she will join the Argentina fans at Tana
Suni, get your vehicle
We have ajob to do
What?
When I'm talking, you're
listening to music?
Heard me? Then why aren't you shocked?
- We...
-You?
Dude, tell me the truth
Let me take it to my grave with me
You Scoundrel!
You will never come up in life!
You had to fightjust now!
You'll take it to your grave, it seems!
and who will write slogans
& poems to print on them?
None ofthis was necessary
You're as big as a bull!
Why are you scolding me, that
too in front of our kids?
To get me scolded
Get lost!
But still, to hate Brazil itself,
Do we need such a person?
Isn't there an ethical issue in that?
On second thoughts,
my opinion is that we should let herjoin
And with them, there are four girls,
including Devi who goes to Kalamandalam
- Is that even a fair reason?
- Isn't it?
If she passes that,
we'll let herjoin
When she chased him away,
Ajayghosh became the refugee, right?
Vipinan, our Master would decide whether
to let her pass or fail in the interview!
Mehru, right?
A democratic interview
is going to happen here
The President of Brazil fans, Ajayghosh?
He's a bourgeois rascal!
The policies against
imperialism by Argentine...
So our President Kirchner is a tigress!
-What do we tell Vipinan nouf?
-I don't know
Don't turn Argentina Fans Club into
a place to take out your personal grudges
Didn't you just ask that?
When she said some tongue
twisting foreign name,
With that, our Master's tongue
got stuck in his throat
We should have brought someone
from outside for the interview!
Are the Brazil fans rascals
barking too much this time?
She's so shy!
Vam os!
Get lost!
Don't talk such vulgar stuff!
I mean, this is my first
bride-seeing ceremony, that's why...
You must be waiting for someone
with good height like me, right?
lfthe horoscopes match, Karthika's
wedding should be at Koodal Manikyam
She got 4-5 marriage
proposals before this
To protect our tradition,
faith and rituals,
Dad, Brazil fans have a woofer
That's bigger than this
AC?
What?
Not now, Dad
I'll take all that from you later
Hey! Where is your extension cable?
What's this new programme?
Let's think about it once more
That is, 'Forthe mouth speaks
what the heart is full of'
Basically, you will speak
only what's in your mind
Mom!
Oh my Neymar!
Vamos Argentina!
Alex Palliveedan
He stayed at his mother's
house & studied engineering,
No one in Kaattoor has understood why
Ajayghosh & Mehru split up, till date
Anyway, one knot tightens
only when another gets loose
Even though he was mocking me,
I like to believe that
Only mint?
No smoke?
My grandpa brought it from America
Hey Alex! We, Brazil fans have been
maintaining a standard for ages
That's correct
Aren't you watching all the games then?
Only some games?
- Messi?
-Yes
This Palliveedan has a special
enmity towards traitors like her
Look! There's your old friend
Alex!
Shouldn't we place a bet again?
Nice
the Football World Cup
kicks off in Brazil
A) l4<Zowzﬁle~A£
"The football brings
excitement to us"
A) l4<Zowzﬁle~A£
What? You've been sitting there all alone
and idle for many years now, right?
- Let's keep the flex there
- Come on
Viva Brazil!
Then we'll do one thing
We'll name it afteryou
A) l4<Zowzﬁle~A£
"A community that would even sacrifice
their lives, for their teams to win"
A) l4<Zowzﬁle~A£
Yaay!
Boss, aren't you seeing this?
"The football brings
excitement to us"
A) l4<Zowzﬁle~A£
CR!
I'll show you now
No?
That's gone
Anthrukka, when we win against
Germany in the semi...
- Load it
- Hold this
Is it RDX instead of fire-crackers?
Since I'm from a rich set-up...
Let the boys drink!
Then you guys talk
Let me make a move
Anthrukka, Neymar is
a strength for our team
So when they lose, they can say that
they lost because Neymarwasn't there
It's okay! We'll get it
We will win, man!
- Isn't that a foul?
- That's a foul, no doubt
Yaay! They have been beaten!
Don't worry! The World Cup will come again
Stay strong
We can!
Looking at Mehru's face
is your problem, huh?
Stop scratching your
head and go fast
-Is he going to beat us up?
-Why?
What do they want?
It's not foolish, man!
It's 7 Up!
What if the whole village had Alzheimer's
and forgot everything by sunrise?
That day, notjust Najeeb...
But we beat Holland during
the shootout and entered the final
It's looking great
But have you seen Rosario
street earlier, Raghavetta?
We're going to give Kaattoor
a blue dawn tomorrow!
Then let's book St Antony's, Master
You got lazy and slept off during every
PT period at the staff room,
Here
Go and tie this
My grandma is paralyzed
this Vinod Aikkarakkundu...
Or leave it
Oh no!
I'm trapped
-You rascal!
- That's not me! (in Hindi)
Hey Mehru...
That's not going to
happen, Vipinan
Isn't she feeling even
a bit of love towards me?
Your younger sister is about
to be of marriageable age
Those caste people you talked about
it long ago, would know that
apart from a diploma certificate,
that too if you pass Polytechnic,
Not just that...
'Dear, you bit the hand that fed you milk!'
Even if she loves you, she's
not going to confess that
We will rock tomorrow's game!
Instead of catching a cold sitting in
this temple ground, come home, Escobar
(Football Commentary)
You fool!
Thumbs up is given for good luck
Dude, you coloured your hair?
Nice
- Great!
- Suni, awesome!
Off-side!
Don't cry
It's okay
Okay! Let's burst some
small crackers decently
That too, during extra time
Didn't you see this?
I gave the barber 2000 Rupees!
Thanks, dude
All ofyou got such
sportsman spirit now, huh?
Hey! Anyway you lost only
in the final, right?
she stayed awake for the whole night
drinking black tea & mocked me non-stop
We didn't have to think too much
about why no one was mocking us
another organized fan club
was born for the first time
Those guys were in our
team till yesterday
This is a gameformen!
Hey! Are you interested in
reducing my loneliness?
- Messi who came after, also peed
- Bloody scoundrel!
Messi who came after, also peed
You haven't grown enough to defeat
the whites of Europe, you rascals!
Neymar peed, Messi also peed!
Hey Vipinan, she isn't shy
anymore after changing the team!
He's not Palliveedan
He's a cheat
neither did we become Brazil
fans because ofthem!
- That's nice
-Yes, true
What should I tell them?
If you keep watching the World Cup and
go for work only once in a while,
I'm asking you because
I don't know...
if you want to blurt out your cliche
philosophy, don't open your mouth!
When I was in my home-town,
used to go
to Church every morning, with my mother
And
...
Still...
Poor Christ
Christ would have had atoughtime,
not being able to face my mother
So, it was too bad that
you hurt your mother
You had gone for an interview in
an agency in Kochi, right? -Yes
I heard the postman saying this
at Sunnychettan's shop - Really?
I won't stay in this
Kaattoor without you
Hey!
'
ridethe bike
if you want me to
She's a big shot in the party now
DYFK district vice president
That's when Columbia is
going to win the World Cup
To be frank, I really miss our Kaattoor
Our village would have
changed a lot, right?
-Are you going there like this?
-What's wrong with this?
Shave that beard and go in
a presentable look, it's a wedding, right?
And yeah, you should buy a packet of
Havana cigars from the duty free shop
Technically, I'm not
from Kaattoor now, right?
howl started rearing cows,
even my parents alsojoined herto
go and say that in every house
Even if you stand alone,
you're a colossal disaster...
Why did you stand with
Ajayghosh, to lose again?
and even the music troupe for
the wedding eve is ready
Hey! You could have held
this next year, right?
But the upcoming World
Cup won't wait
Take that suitcase inside
-Vipinan...
-What is this?
What about the bouquet &
garland for tomorrouf?
Mom, I haven't gotjasmine
flowers for my caryet
- Namaste!
-Vipinan, you reached?
I thought you'll skip this like
your elder sister's wedding
She came quite early
Didn't you see her?
"There's beauty all around"
"Little flowers are turning red"
"Yourwedding day is almost here"
"The sweet feeling that flows
through the rhythms of life"
"As a burning flame...
As a stunning bride..."
"The eyes are locked with each other...
Someone is singing within your heart"
"The full moon night is almost here"
"The sweet feeling that flows
through the rhythms of life"
A) l4<Zowzﬁle~A£
"Your handsome groom arrives, like
a dawn during the darkness of night"
"when the sun arrives with
gold foryourwedding chain"
"The moment we awaited,
when the eyes are adorned with silk"
"The sweet feeling that flows
through the rhythms of life"
l was busy with work, and then there's my
loan and this wedding, you know, right?
we have to find a sweet,
innocent girl for you
Ali came and proposed to me...
l have to get married sometime or
the other, right? Sol said okay
Okay then
See you tomorrow
Shall we go?
See you
it's her wedding the next day
The groom is a PhD
fellowfrom Hyderabad
Boss, will I die of a shock
before Portugal wins the cup?
Get lost, Sunikkuttan!
And not because you got fed up
of washing your wife's clothes?
Tie it up, man!
Member, look
We, German fans, who are
the World champions,
Don't you know that this place is
for us this time, Palliveedan?
Swearing at my dad?
Rascal...
- Get going
- I'll see you later!
Then why did you
swear at his father?
Hey! The boys also got beaten up
Order tea for them too
You guys are making me mad!
I didn't know that a fight happened
Vipinan, that member would
give them that place,
You are smart, man!
Even though I have to take some effort,
I have peace of mind
Leave it, man
Do you give all this
milk to the society?
Mom told me that the groom's family
is coming tomorrow to meet Mehru
Sincel didn't know how to ask,
I left it
Leave all that
Shouldn't we tie the flex tomorrouf?
We should do something and
get the boys on our side
My life would get over
in this cow-shed, man!
Only some of our
neighbours are here
Mehru grew up in their house
Sometime back, when a fight happened
in Christ college during SFK's march,
She was engaged in party
activities full time
Take some selfies and put them up
on our page, let everyone see it!
- Scoundrels! They got scared
-Ask them to get lost
They are trying to mess with Nazis!
Not Dollars, dude
There would be at least
10,000 Dirhams in this now
- Really?
-Yes
What?
What the hell are you saying?
Shouldn't we also erect
a cut out of CR 7 like this?
get passports, go to the Middle East,
work hard and make money like him,
Hey! Don't cry
-Anthrukka!
- Hey!
"Lord Ganesha Son of Lord Shiva
Bless us, let ourwish get succeeded"
'If you can, will you try to stop
this cup from his hard kick'
I'm also thinking about going to
my uncle's house in Thrissur
What?
Here
Hold this
Ajayan, look at Vipinan
sitting there
After all, it's the land where revolution
was born, as Mehru always says
- Go and switch on that TV
- Go!
Since Argentina had to squeeze in somehow,
our excitement levels were low
Absolute genius
Even ifArgentina gets a
draw against Nigeria today,
Or will they rise from the ashes?
That question booms around!
This is like Emperor
Shahjahan playing the Veena,
Can't you stop yourself from
correcting me at least once?
If we lose tomorrow's game,
I thought that she would tell me that she
loves me, at least during the last moment
Or, maybe because she doesn't
want to hurt my mother
l have lost, man!
finally, inthe reality show called life,
Do you know what makes me
sadderthan her wedding?
I made it up on my own
What did I say?
After the game?
Should I look for brides?
Do as you please, mom
Whatever it is, lam fine
Hannah, no need of all this
Embracing the tradition is also a pure
leftist way, Comrade
Leave that
He was really sad when he
left from our house today
If you both had such a wish, did you
think that anyone would object to it?
Did you think that I would say that
you bit the hands that fed you milk?
But the happiness of my children
is more important for me!
Chetta, over here
A) l4<Zowzﬁle~A£
"The lamps are burning...
and the wedding will happen at sunrise"
"O flowers...b
ossom quickly"
"The palm leaves are
swaying and laughing"
A) l4<Zowzﬁle~A£
"What do we hear beyond the skies?"
"The groom will arrive forthe wedding,
with his people"
"The palm leaves are
swaying and laughing"
A) l4<Zowzﬁle~A£
"The sparrowthat sings atop the
mountains also has secrets to say"
"...the bride is ready for the wedding"
"The palm leaves are
swaying and laughing"
"The wedding will happen at sunrise"
No one will burst crackers
here to celebrate our loss
If you fulfill all your wishes
in life, what thrill would remain?
I never wished for too
much in life, Escobar
Another wish...
have you ever heard this Vipinan saying
anything else as a wish or even a greed?
lam all alone
We will
Don't worry
Vam os!
Vipinan! Vipinan!
Come on! We have work to do!
Argentina!
- ls Mehru with you?
- She is here, I'll put her on
- Dad...
-What have you done, dear?
my heart will be as heavy as a rock,
till the end of my life
Khaderkka, don't think that I'm
finding faults at this time
howthe hell will I find new cooks to cook
a veg feast for them, at this midnight?
"The lamps are burning...
and the wedding will happen at sunrise"
"O flowers...b
ossom quickly"
"The lamps are burning...
and the wedding will happen at sunrise"
I don't want it
"What do we hear beyond the skies?"
"The groom will arrive forthe wedding,
with his people"
A) l4<Zowzﬁle~A£
"The sparrowthat sings atop the
mountains also has secrets to say"
"...the bride is ready for the wedding"
When you have kids, will you give
them Hindu names or Muslim names?
If it's a boy, the name is already fixed
Andres Leo...
ljust hope things end
happily for my team as well
then, now and until our last breath...
"The whole world is following
the football in all vigour"
"The football brings
excitement to us"
"A community that would even sacrifice
their lives, for their teams to win"
"Speeding like a lightning"