How deep is he now?
- 400 feet.
Craig, Doug here.
How are you doing, boy?
I'm switching over to O-2-3,
I'll turn up from there
and then we'll have
a sonar check, out.
'Okay, steady to go, boy.'
Hello, beautiful.
What about that chopper,
they are still waiting
for my permission
to come aboard.
I'll talk to them.
Doug here. Brinkman, if we
slow down and take you aboard
we'll lose contact below.
Then please terminate
your mission and ask Dr. Mosby
to surface at once.
I'm taking you both back
to Federal Science Council
in Washington, urgent.
Oh, right in the middle
of a test. Yeah alright, okay.
Hey, look.
Craig?
- Yeah, go ahead, Doug.
I want you to surface,
but there's a pod of whales
above you, so maintain present
depth now until I tell you.
Roger, Doug.
I'll maintain this depth.
Watch out
for those whales now.
Yeah, Doug, I'm watching.
Must be headed for their
breeding lagoons.
Let's drop closer.
What's he doing?
That'll make 'em dive.
Get me the chopper.
It's too late,
he's spooked 'em.
Alright, come up now, Craig.
The whales have passed.
How do you do, Craig?
- Stand by, Doug.
Craig!
Doug, I'm taking water in.
You build up air pressure?
- Roger, that's a maximum.
Then abandon.
- I'm coming up fast. Hang on.
I said abandon.
Get out of there, you hear?
I can't, the hatch's stuck.
Left a dent from the collision.
Break out the floatation gear.
Underwater team, on the double.
Man your station.
How deep is he?
- 150 feet.
Don't go away, pal,
I'll be right down.
That's it. Give me a wrench.
I'll start off.
You follow me down.
Give me my air down below.
Rat!
Be quiet, they're not rats.
They're guinea pigs.
Hold these.
Got you, come here.
Craig, come on.
I've caught them all.
- Well, that's nice.
We've got work
to do, boy.
I'm sorry, I have to go.
- The guinea pigs.
Oh, yes.
You Americans,
always in such a hurry.
'Of death and destruction
on a worldwide rampage'
'these films show the tragic
effects of a tidal wave'
'on a population centre.'
How do we relate this?
- Had to start because of him.
Who's that?
- The vice president.
Vice President.
'Giant waves strike in costal
cities first and always catching
the population unaware
and unprotected.'
'Although three fourths of all
earthquakes originate beneath'
'the oceans, cities far in-land
cannot escape devastation.'
'This Turkish city,
hundreds of miles from the coast
'was struck by a quake
lasting only 27 seconds'
'taking a toll of
15,000 lives.'
'As the casualty lists grow, the
pattern of earthquake activity'
'becomes clearer and
the need for scientific study'
'and action becomes imperative.'
All of these earthquakes,
Mr. Vice President
have happened during the first
few months of this year.
Six times the average number,
three times the average strength
and we feel there are more
coming of greater intensity.
Is there any way
to foretell, where or when?
Professor Hamaru has developed
a theory of forecasting.
Sir, we cannot prevent
earth or sea quakes.
But we can erect
a warning system.
We have a new vehicle,
The Hydronaut
which is capable of
establishing that system.
Did she prove that
on her shake down?
I don't know, it just returned,
little scarred from a typhoon.
But with a perfect score.
She was tested at 26,000 feet.
She's fully automatic
and can circle the globe
on one cartridge
of nuclear fuel.
The Hydronaut was built along
lines of Dr. Doug Standish
and engineered
by Dr. Craig Mosby.
Mr. Vice President.
- How are you, sir?
I'm glad you got here,
I heard it wasn't easy.
Well, I had help.
This warning system, once
established around the world
would give us time
to evacuate the cities
if an earthquake with an
intensity of the one in Alaska
were to hit Japan without
warning, millions would die.
This is the warning device.
It's so sensitive
that before an
earthquake happens
before it's seen or heard,
this device senses it.
Obviously, we call
it a sensor.
The sensing devices are all
on this section here.
'Let me show it to you.'
These...veins here
will transmit the information
to a seismographic centre.
And down below...in here
is an explosive charge
that anchors this device
in place on
the ocean floor.
Now, Mr. Vice President,
if we plant these sensors
around the world under the sea,
then pressure points along here
and through here and anchor
them in the crust of the earth
we'll have the early
warning system we need.
Well, this means a great deal
of risk, doesn't it?
We know less about the oceans
than we do the moon.
You're willing
to take on this risk?
Well, that's why
we're here.
Gentlemen, I'd like you
to proceed on the assumption
that I can get
the necessary appropriation
for the voyage
of The Hydronaut.
Great.
Yeah, we've got pretty good
visibility on this sub.
We've got a TV camera topside
and we've got one out there
in the bow
and one under the hull.
Watch, let's see
if we can pick up Doug.
Ah, there he is.
'Look, see him?'
'He's X-raying the hull from
any damage after the typhoon.
Should be in,
in a minute or two.
What about that crazy
color on the hull?
It's pretty wild, isn't it?
But it's international
rescue color.
Now, you know, the sub
will change color
as we go deeper, it moves from
yellow red through to green.
What about your crew,
have you decided who you want?
Yeah. Now we've got
to have Phil Volker.
He's designed half the
electronic gear on board.
And we decided to go for
Orin Hillyard as the geologist.
But here's where the hang up
comes, we want to combine
our doctor and our marine
biologist in one.
Doug and I don't agree on this,
I wanna go for Bob Johnson.
Yup, I'm for a new comer
on the field.
Hello there, Gus.
- Hi, doctor.
Nice to see you.
He's done some
very impressive research
in Marine Biology.
M.E. Hanford, from England.
I'm sure you've read
some of his published material
the last couple of years.
Her material.
What?
- What?
The M.E. stands for
Margaret Elizabeth.
Very attractive too. She just
finished a research for me.
Now, shall we make it, Johnson?
Why, because
Hanford's a woman?
Half the doctors in Russia
are women, not a bad example
for the rest to follow.
He's got a point.
You want a woman on a submarine
for four months?
She's a scientist
and so are we.
Brinkman says you met her
in the science building..
...under a desk.
Her?
- That was M.E. Hanford?
What do you say now?
- No! No.
Alright, don't worry,
first we've got to get
Phil Volker and Hank Stahl,
without them we can't start.
Stahl, he lives at the bottom
of the Caribbean Bay
studying underwater survival,
you'll never get him.
We've got to. At the depth's
we're gonna dive
we can't plant our sensors
without his breathing gases.
I'll get him, no matter
how deep he is. I'll get him.
Well, Dr. Hamaru is all wrong.
I want no part of it.
Well, then we can't do it.
I mean it.
Without you, it'd be impossible.
No one has your knowledge
of breathing gases
at deep pressures.
We've got to be able
to get in and out of the sub.
What do you want with
a garage mechanic like me.
I bet you've got guys with fancy
degrees who'll work for you.
Yeah, sure. You're just
a big dumb hot head.
Dr. Hamaru, warned me
about that line of yours.
Well, I am.
I didn't go to college
You know how I started
under water?
Cropping keel for buck fifty
an hour, learn or drown.
You can give us all lessons.
- Soft soap.
Is it...rabbits underwater?
How did you accomplish this?
Oh, that's
an artificial gill..
...that allows them
to breathe underwater.
There's no garage mechanic, eh?
Now this, what's this?
- Uh.
Oh, these are embryo's,
shark embryo's.
'They're called swell shark'
Here, look. Right there.
See him turning around?
See, he's trying to free himself
from the nourishing egg yolk.
'There, see. He's trying
to break the umbilical cord.'
'They always do that
just before they hatch.'
See him fighting
to get out of there?
'Look at that strength,
he wants to be born.'
How's that for
their will to live?
What about people,
The millions who'll die
if we don't put down
our warning system.
People! Sharks, animals, they
kill each other for reason
because they're hungry.
People kill each other
for nothing.
Wait a minute. There might be
some people like that.
It doesn't apply
to the whole human race.
Boren was right.
He did say you're hard to reach.
You let me in.
I haven't reached you yet.
Go ahead and reach me.
Alright. What about yourself?
You are people.
You know that you built your
house over an earthquake fault
that you're about 50 miles
from the Martinique Volcano?
If we complete our system, we
can give you an advance warning.
I couldn't care less, doctor.
Let 'em all go.
You don't mean that.
Well, maybe there are
a few human beings up there.
Dr. Hamaru, Gus Boren..
...Dmitri, my crazy Russian
chess-playing friend.
Hey, Dmitri. I just moved
my bishop from D2 to F4.
Let's see you get
out of that one.
Shortwave.
It's his move.
It's your move, Mr. Stahl.
I couldn't care less.
I got it made done here. I got
my research, my books, my music.
Why'd I leave for idiots
who'll blow themselves up?
You really think you can keep
on escaping like this?
That it's not going
to bother your conscience.
Conscience, doctor?
What conscience?
You've got one.
Here.
This'll help you
get back home safely.
To civilization.
No, thanks. I wouldn't want
to salve your conscience.
You'll never make it
without my breathing gas.
And you know it.
- That's right.
Don't gamble on me coming out
after you, 'cause I wont.
I can't believe that a man with
your intelligence will let
a few million people die when
he could keep it from happening.
I'm talking about you. You don't
have enough air in your tanks.
What difference
does it make?
I'm not on your preferred list
of people worth saving, am I?
Here's a man who is. I don't
think you even read this.
"Japan has borne seven
cataclysms from the sea
"in 29 years. If the one
which I fear is coming
"strikes my country,
my dear Hank
it'll be worse than Hiroshima."
What the hell's
the matter with you?
Trying to kill yourself?
No, I knew
you'd come through.
Well, just in case,
you didn't.
Of all the lousy tricks!
You had that thing
on top of you all the time?
I'm sorry. But you
left me no alternative.
Now that you've come
this far
how about going all
the way with this?
'That's a real
floatin' laboratory.'
We've also got the crew.
Well, right now my partner's
working on Orin Hillyard.
At Harper Island.
You'll be alright.
Decompress for 20 minutes
and he'll be back to normal.
Watch me from here.
Close the hatch.
Hi, I'm Dr. Craig Mosby.
- Jack Smith.
Hi, Jack, how are you?
I've an appointment
with Orin Hillyard.
Is he still down below?
- Yeah.
Can I go down
and see him?
Sure. Yellow flag's still up.
- Thank you very much.
Oh, Jack, you got a lot of
divers in wet suits down there?
Yeah.
- How'll I know who's Orin?
You'll know.
- Okay.
'Anything the matter?'
- What?
No, no, uh...could've sworn
I've seen those legs before.
Jack.
- Yes.
Was that Dr. Mosby?
- Yeah.
'Lift him easy.'
What the hell is
going around here?
'Swing him over.'
'Set him right on
to the deck.'
'Easy now.'
Who's the idiot inside
this diving suit?
Dr. Mosby, I presume.
Orin. Orin, what the devil
are you doing?
Oh, we're testing out
some new mining gear.
I wanted you out
of that water fast.
Why?
Ha-ha. Thank you.
'Thank you very much.'
Oh, Maggie, you know
Craig Mosby?
'Maggie Hanford.'
- Yes, I think we've met.
It's nice seeing you again.
- Hello, Dr. Mosby.
Orin, are you alright?
- Oh, yeah, I'm fine. I'm..
Excuse me, please.
What's the matter
with her?
We got a phone message
for you from Dr. Boren.
You're first choice
for medic is unavailable
and there's no time
to shop around.
We're getting
new tremors.
Oh, yeah, big ones.
- Ah, boy.
Ah, Boren says you've got
to take Maggie
even if you don't
want her.
And, uh, unfortunately
that was the part of
the conversation she overheard.
Well, I better go talk to her.
- Yeah. I think I would.
Dr. Hanford.
- Yes.
I'm sorry about that message.
I hope you'll understand.
'Let me be the first to welcome
you aboard the Hydronaut.'
Orin and I shall be there. We
already know the starting date.
Well?
I hope Doug is having an easier
time recruiting Dr. Volker.
Phil, I'll keep you on
the sonoscope.
'How long do you think
you're gonna be?'
We'll be back in half an hour.
- 'I'll keep watching you.'
Phil, will you tell me
why the guided tour
in this half-pint sub of yours?
I've seen all these coral reefs.
Patience.
You know why I'm down here.
Come on, give me an answer.
You came to me with the premise
of a recruiting sergeant.
The least you can do
is to humor me for a few minutes
while I show you
my latest gadgetry.
Apparently, I've
succeeded in establishing
electronic communication
with another specie.
You watch.
I talk.
He learns.
You watch,
I'll make him turn.
To the left.
You need me?
That's right.
Well, I'll come.
At a price.
And just how high
is your price?
Look, there's a manta ray.
It's attracted
to the color of the submarine.
Ha-ha, and the dolphin's
attracted to the manta.
And now..
...the grand finale.
What are you going
to do with the mine?
Now, I'll make him
drop it.
Don't worry. It won't
explode on contact.
Now, he'll pick
it up again.
What are you
up to now?
You see the bottom
of that boat up there.
Well?
- Watch.
That is magnetic.
Poor thing.
It takes quite
an intelligence to understand
the devious mind
of a human being.
Yeah, I know
what you mean.
Excuse me.
I arm the mine from here.
We head for the surface.
Fifteen seconds.
Turn your boat.
You're gonna blow her up?
She looks new.
It $20 worth of paint.
I like to dress up
my demonstrations.
Impress you?
Mm-hm. I suppose that's
just what you had in mind.
Why?
I want the Hydronaut
to make one dive for me.
For me, personally.
'You personally?
A dive for what?'
To salvage four million dollars
worth of transistor crystals.
You mean a treasure hunt?
Phil, I came to talk
to you about people.
Thousands, millions of life.
- That's for you.
I'm talking about millions
of dollars...for me.
I don't buy.
I don't go.
Our mission is to
plant warning sensors.
I know that. We take care
of my mission after yours.
I can't commit
the crew.
Don't worry.
How'd you say? Cut them in.
What makes you think
they'll go along with you?
Haven't you heard?
It's better to be a rich
scientist than a poor one?
If I didn't need you,
I'll tell you
to go to the bottom
of the ocean.
The earth's crust
is crumbling, Douglas.
You've no choice.
We'll leave a week
from today.
Alright, fellas, come on now.
That's not chopped liver.
Get up. Put it on
the floor there.
'Get it loaded.'
'Easy, come on.'
That's a set of whiskers
I haven't seen before.
It's hydro electronic.
From below to the surface,
surface to Syncom
Syncom to Washington.
It's quite simple, really.
We're all loaded.
Where's the dame?
The dame is exercising
her rights as a lady.
She's late.
Check. Good.
- Okay.
Do you know what's
holding Maggie up?
I understand she's exercising
a dame's right to be late.
We can't sail without
a cook, you know.
Margaret Hanford is as handy
with a skillet as a scalpel.
You, um, you know
Maggie Han?
'Hello, there.
A lady coming aboard.'
Hi, how do you do?
We were worried.
Thank you, Orin.
Hello, Dr. Mosby.
- Doctor.
Philip.
- Hello, Maggie.
And you must be Mr. Stahl.
It's a privilege.
Just call me Hank.
- Just call me Maggie, Hank.
Excuse me.
I have to get my hatbox.
Hatbox?
- Hatbox?
Hatbox.
You'll love it.
It's absolutely adorable.
Iddie and Biddie.
- Iddie and...Biddie?
For oxygen analysis.
Well, I see
we're all here now.
It's a real pleasure.
- Thank you.
Get into the ward room,
everyone.
What the devil is that?
- Oh, uh, this.
That's Iddie
and Biddie, buddy.
That's very clever.
Dr. Mosby. Dr. Mosby?
Yeah, right in here.
Thanks. Look at this.
- Here you are, doctor.
You sign for the sub should be
all civilian, we'll cast off.
Aha.
- All civilian?
You mean the ladies out?
- Yes, sir. Yes, ma'am.
Thanks, Doug.
- We're the whole crew?
Well, the Gemini capsule
only had two.
Thank you, sir. I wish you
and your crew all the best.
Thank you.
Please try not
to scratch her up.
We'll do our best.
As you already know, of course,
the program calls for us
to put down 50 sensors.
Now...here is where
the first one goes.
The east end of a Puerto Rico
trench. Got that?
Looks like the first one's
gonna be the toughest.
'I, uh, assume that
after signing on'
'no on has had
any second thoughts.'
Okay, good.
Well, I don't see any reason
why we shouldn't get underway.
Man your stations.
I thought we were
a civilian boat.
Man your stations,
please.
Ten degrees.
Doug, I'm adding negative ions
to our atmosphere.
Make us feel a little better
first time down.
Hmm. Take a whiff of this.
I feel better already.
We're coming over
the trench.
We made that in 500 feet.
1500 more to go.
Keep it moving.
Look out.
Here. Make the drop.
Sensor number one.
Orin, come up
and take over the scope.
Easy.
We're coming in over target.
Stand by.
That's it.
You all set?
- It's fine.
Let's get outta here.
Bring the pressure up inside
to...eight tons per square inch.
We left an empty tank
in there.
Sensor in position.
Roger.
This is it.
Sensor down.
Anchor it.
Here goes.
Number one.
Here.
Signal works great.
- Is it reaching Washington?
I know my theory
and calculations are right
as far as
the ocean agrees.
Craig, alert Washington.
- Roger.
Hello, Seismo Washington.
This is Hydronaut.
This is Hydronaut. Over.
'Hello, Seismo? Hello, seismo.'
'Overseas call coming in
from the Hydronaut.'
Hydronaut calling.
It's the Hydronaut calling, sir.
Hello, Hydronaut.
This is Seismo Washington. Over.
Standby for Dr. Standish,
over.
Seismo, this is Hydronaut
from 30,000 feet
in the Puerto Rico trench.
No, I said 30,000. The chart
at this point is 5,000 feet off.
Our first sensor is planted.
Are you receiving it's signal?
The first sensor is down,
Dr. Boren.
Doug, this is Gus Boren,
you alright?
Hi, Gus. Ah, yeah, fine.
Everything routine. All well.
Brink's gone to check
the reception now.
Okay.
- What's happening?
They're checking.
Pressure, strain, gravity, clear
as bell from the next room.
It's alive down there. They must
be right over the pole.
The reception
is as clear as a bell.
Our signal is coming
through fine.
The message says you better
get out of there now.
Okay. We'll get back on course.
Hydronaut signing off.
Well, our first one
is down, uh.
Let's get back
upstairs.
Stations, everybody.
- Six miles straight up.
Alright. Standby
to blow ballast.
Oh, the air.
Isn't it wonderful?
Now don't tell me
you don't like submarines.
Six miles down.
Yes, and that's only
the first one too.
How many more
are there?
Forty nine.
It's a bit confining
down there.
'Maggie, don't worry.'
'We're in good hands.'
Orin, I'm glad you're here.
It makes things a lot easier.
According to maritime law,
Doug could perform a marriage.
Oh, Orin, can you imagine
spending a honeymoon
on a submarine
with four other men?
Yes, well, I have to admit
it's far from ideal.
Thanks anyway.
What is this,
Big Brother is watching?
Well, it's better than
what you get on the television.
Clear the deck. Standby to dive,
on the double.
Well, how do you do,
Captain Bligh?
Dr. Hanford.
I asked you not to wear perfume
aboard this submarine.
I'm not wearing any.
Maggie.
Yes.
- 'Bring me a cup of coffee.'
It's never the same.
But always beautiful.
Sometimes when I'm here alone
looking out there..
...I feel I'm in
a some kind of a dream.
You always
were a dreamer.
A dreamer
and a scientist.
They don't quite go together.
do they?
I still don't know
which part of me
was attracted to you
in the beginning.
The dreamer.
No, I think you're wrong.
I think it was
the scientist.
I remember the first time
I saw you, you looked so..
...efficient.
Do you think maybe we could pick
it up again where we left off?
You're dreaming again.
You know as well as I do.
It's quite, quite finished.
Really?
Are you so certain?
A mountain,
and you didn't see it?
That sonar must have been
going like a fire alarm.
Only the two of you up here
while everybody's asleep.
Just what're trying for?
- Are you her father?
That's just...
- 'What're you, two boy scouts?'
You're supposed
to be scientists.
When'll you start
acting like that?
Stay outta this.
- Knock it off, knock it off.
Maggie, take a look at Hank.
He got tossed out of his bunker.
Orin, give her a hand.
You didn't start reversing until
you actually saw the cliff?
What about the sonar?
I was on visual.
Why didn't you see
that rock sooner?
Because I wasn't looking.
- What were you looking at?
It's none of you business.
Oh, it isn't, eh?
Now, look. I'm aware
that I made a mistake.
I'm aware that I've made a
complete, utter fool of myself.
I'm sorry.
Now, if you don't mind
we'll leave it at that.
What do you think of having her
aboard now, huh?
I think you better start
simmering down, Craig boy.
We want to get
this job finished.
And our job is
to put down sensors, right?
Yeah, that's-that's our job.
Put down sensors.
Have got you the answer
to Hydronaut's question?
I'm just sending
it out now.
A-N-F-S-Q-7, answer my request.
Top priority reply.
Computer analysis as follows.
Rook takes queen.
Check.
Rook takes queen?
Rook takes
Black's queen.
Oh, pretty cocky,
aren't we?
Playing a little over your head,
aren't you, buddy?
Maybe,
don't you think
a little incentive
might make us play better.
Well, what sort of stakes
did you have in mind?
Something friendly.
If I lose,
I do something for you
and if I win...then
you do me a favor.
Favor? What for example?
- Oh, I don't know.
Let's wait and see
how the game goes.
Say, Doug, I've been
wondering for a long time..
...how you got Phil to come in
this voyage with us.
I know how you got me, that was
a fair shuffle, but Phil..
I gotta be telling you
about this, something
that he needs
your okay for.
Something he needs
my okay..
Yes, yes, now I seem to remember
on that first dive, him saying
"If I don't make your dive,
you won't make mine".
What dive?
- He'll talk to you about it.
Yeah, so that's how
you hooked him, huh?
You promised him one dive,
for what?
I'd rather he told...
- I'm asking you.
I'm on this ride
for Dr. Hamaru, not for him.
At least listen to him.
Anything that he's in on,
I'm on the outside of.
Now look, you hooked me once,
you're not gonna hook me twice.
What's the deal?
- I needed him and I needed you.
That's the only way I could
get you both to come along.
'You didn't have your mind?'
- 'No, I didn't.'
'You don't have to do
what he's asking you to do.'
'You're dynamite right,
I don't.'
Position?
Doug, we're approaching Ceylon.
We're 50 miles off the target.
And we're getting
some shock waves.
Okay, Craig. We're
approaching the Fumaroles.
Better get ready, Hank.
Standby for sensor drop.
- Oh, roger.
I want you to know, that if
Doug hadn't already promised
I wouldn't go
on this dive of yours.
I know that. If I needed
to ask you for your consent
I wouldn't have come.
Everybody, into
the control room.
Fumaroles.
Alright, standby
for exterior heat readings.
120 degrees.
130.
140 degrees.
165 degrees.
Orin, what's the temperature
in the center of the fumaroles?
Anywhere from 290 degrees to 320
degrees, boiling under pressure.
We go in there, we're gonna
be in one big pressure cooker.
Okay, boss,
how do you figure it?
It's gonna be hot,
alright.
'We'll have to get those sensor
in as close as possible.'
'Have to do it by hand.
We'll have to swim it in.'
What do you say, Orin?
- Yeah, there's no other way.
I know it's my job
to pick the spot.
I'll come with you.
Okay, let's break out
the hot suits.
Take over, Craig.
- Yeah.
How about
the breathing gas?
You told me to
get it ready, didn't you?
Maggie.
Alright, I'm settling
down in the bottom.
This will help boost your
resistance to the heat.
'When it gets hot there,
this gas is gonna taste sweet.'
'But just keep
breathing normally.'
Mag will be reading you.
Keep talking. I'll know how
your are by your voices.
Alright, let's put them
under pressure.
You okay, boy?
- Alright.
Come on.
Maggie, get up to control room.
Monitor them on the viewer.
Stay with me.
Are they out?
- Yes.
Put them on the TV.
Put them on
the loudspeaker.
Phil, Orin?
Can you hear me?
Acknowledge.
'Orin here, receiving you.'
Phil?
- Receive you, loud and clear.
I want to hear Peter Piper.
Orin, you first.
'Peter Piper picked a peck
of pickled peppers.'
Phil.
'A peck of pickled peppers
did Peter Piper picked.'
'If Peter Piper picked
a peck of pickled peppers.'
'Where's the peck of pickled
peppers Peter Piper picked?'
Alright, Maggie?
Phil, give me
a heat reading.
A 175 degrees.
Inside, it's a comfortable 80.
Come on, keep repeating
Peter Piper.
'Peter Piper picked a peck
of pickled peppers.'
'A peck of pickled peppers
Peter Piper picked.'
'...peppers Peter,
'Peter Piper..'
Orin!
Orin, can you hear me?
He's in trouble.
Phil, Orin's in trouble.
Get to him quick.
Phil, do you read me? Over.
Phil! Answer me.
Answer me, Phil.
Keep trying to contact.
- Phil, come in, Phil.
Phil! Phil, do you read me?
Phil's going for him.
Don't risk it. It's too hot
out there for this suit.
Orin's already picked
the spot for the sensor.
I'll just get in there
and get out fast.
Now, come on. Get out of here.
Put me under pressure.
Standby to pick up
Phil and Orin.
Come on, Maggie.
- Craig, look. Doug's gone out.
Doug! Doug!
- Gimme that. Doug! Doug!
Wait a minute. He doesn't
have a radio on.
Get him up!
- Hold it! Hold it!
Come on, get him out.
Watch the arm.
Maggie, come and take
a look at Orin.
Phil, what happened down there?
Didn't you hear me calling you?
Hell, no.
I didn't hear anything.
I just turn around
and saw him.
Must have been a die out failure
or something with the heat.
Yeah, the heat.
I hope there's no failure
when I anchor the sensor.
How's Orin?
- He's alright, I think.
Alright, standby
to take Doug aboard.
Oh, I've never been
so hot in my life.
Ah, pretty hot.
Alright. How's Orin?
- He's okay.
What happened to you
down there, Phil?
He says he didn't
hear us.
I didn't hear you.
Is Doug aboard yet?
- Yes.
Alright, I'm anchoring
the sensor.
You can reduce
the danger of the bends.
Oh, boy, you're just a dumb,
old hard-hat, alright.
Just like Doug says you are.
Now, If I could find me
a mermaid built just like that.
For once that guy and I agree
on what would make
a really tasty dish.
'Hello.'
- Hello.
A swim in the middle
of the Bay of Bengal.
Not every girl can
make that claim.
What happens if a big,
hungry shark comes along?
Shark?
Or wolf?
Maggie.
What'd you say to making a
salvage dive in the Hydronaut?
Has Doug okayed it?
- Yes, but..
I need everyone's consent.
Yours and Hank's, and Orin's.
Philip, Orin's very
grateful to you
for going into the fumaroles
to help him.
And so am I.
Well, in that case, there's
something you can do for me.
Well, then I'd say Orin
owes a speedy recovery
to this particular mixture, huh?
Well, looks like something
topless is going on topside.
Hey, hey, hey.
Take it easy.
You'll blow a gasket.
Share and share alike,
all of us.
Then why should Hank object?
Oh, he seems to hate everything
connected with civilization.
But don't worry, I'm working
on a special approach to Hank.
Could you, uh, possibly,
sort of persuade Orin for me?
I'll tell you what?
If you get Hank to agree,
I'll get Orin.
Dr. Hanford,
can I see you, please?
Close the hatch.
Yes?
Doctor, I don't know quite
how to tell you this.
Except, turn it off.
- What are you talking about?
Are you trying to tell me,
you don't know the affect
you're having on
the men on this sub?
I'm not trying to have an affect
on anybody, especially you.
'Why?'
Because I haven't tried to drag
you behind the conning tower?
Maybe it's because I haven't
asked you to co-pilot me
on a midnight watch.
Is that it?
You wouldn't notice
whatever I did.
I've noticed you
the first time I saw you.
I noticed the way
your hair was fixed.
I noticed your eyes..
...and that perfume.
I can still smell that.
But that was Washington
and we are on a submarine
and as long as we are
on this submarine
I've turned you off.
To me, you are M.E. Hanford.
Doctor of medicine,
and that's all.
Which is all I've been
since I came aboard.
Now, look..
We've got, maybe one more
month in this submarine.
And after that..
...after we get our work done..
...we have a whole lifetime.
A lifetime to find out..
...what our feelings are
for each other.
You men are
in beautiful shape.
Well, I might say
the same about you.
Thank you, doctor.
You, uh, you're pretty
rough on a man's blood pressure.
If I weren't a happily
married man with few kids..
I might be causing
a little trouble, too.
Are you thinking about
what happen with Phil?
Do you think it was my fault?
- Well, let's put it this way.
If you weren't there,
it wouldn't have happened.
Where shall I hide myself?
In your work, I guess.
- I do.
I know. You've been
doing a great job, but...
I'm a problem.
You men gave
us our freedom
but sometimes it's difficult
to cope with.
We'd better learn how to cope,
because you'll be there
working right along beside us.
Whether it's in outer space
or deep under the ocean.
You'll be there.
Check!
Look at them,
thousands of them.
Must be in some kind of a
special layer in the ocean.
Where did they go?
- Don't look at me.
I didn't do it.
Hank got to be through
collecting his samples by now.
Uh, sensor number 41.
Nine more to go.
You two, plant this one, huh?
Okay, Phil?
Where's Maggie?
- In the lab.
Let me tell you.
Just not an ocean out there.
It's a veritable
minestrone.
What?
- You've never seen such food.
Enough to feed a billion fish.
Look at that!
Yeah. But what is it?
- It's food. It's food.
Hey, Maggie.
Maggie, I got something...
- Wait! Wait! Wait!
I know, I know. You gotta
close the hatch.
Come on, hurry it up,
will you?
Come on. Come on!
Okay?
- Okay, yeah, go.
Hey, Maggie!
Look out, fellas.
What's with him?
Ah, he found
some minestrone.
Mine..
Put us under pressure,
will you?
Oh, yeah.
Phil, hold this, will you?
Maggie. Maggie, look.
Look at this.
Look at that food.
There's life in there so big,
you don't need a microscope.
But check it out
anyway, will you?
I gotta feed Doug.
Hey, Doug, Doug.
'Hey, Doug.'
Hey, Doug, Doug. I gotta
get out there again.
Wanna get full set of samples.
- Hold it, Hank. Hold it.
But the stuff out there
isn't even in the books.
Okay, while they're
planting the sensor.
That'll give you ten minutes.
- Ten minutes.
Hank wait.
- Not now.
Doug, have a look at this.
What?
There.
Craig.
- Yeah, Doug.
Tell Hank to wait.
Well, I can't. He's gone.
Well, call him back.
- Well, I can't, Doug.
He hasn't got a radio.
Ah, never mind,
forget it.
You're worried
about him, aren't you?
Huh? Oh, uh, it was just
a silly thought I had, but..
Hank said there's a lot of fish
there like a feeding ground.
You gave me this article.
I read about, uh, little fish
being eaten by the big fish
and the big fish being eaten
by the bigger fish.
Position is good.
Move it over.
Doug, I'm planting the sensor.
- Okay, Craig.
Alright.
Sensor down.
- Okay, boy, I'll anchor it.
Sensor's coming through fine.
Where's Hank?
Did you see him?
No, he's got five
or six minutes, though.
Oh, boy, I wish
we had him inside.
Philip, you got Hank
in your scope?
Yes, but I'm getting
something else.
About 300 yards behind him,
moving along the bottom.
Looks like another sub.
Or a whale?
Whale?
Whales might dive this deep but
never travel along the bottom.
I see something.
It's moving fast.
I've lost him.
He must be between
the ballast tank.
Craig, Doug, look.
Where's Hank?
- I can't see him anywhere.
He must be under the sub.
- 'Well, I hope so.'
Get in the airlock.
See if you can help.
Hank come in yet?
- 'He hasn't.'
Doug, you must do something.
- I don't know what. Phil.
What can you do
electronically?
Oh, nothing, His capacity
is higher than ours.
There he is.
I get the..
- Hey!
Come on..
- Easy, easy.
'Hank.'
Hank, you alright?
- Yeah.
It's caught in the tow.
Bring out a sensor.
A sensor?
- Bring out a sensor.
Done?
- Yeah.
Alright, send it down easy.
Lower, lower.
Doug.
- Yes, Craig.
Hank's aboard.
Anchor the sensor.
What?
- Anchor the sensor.
What are you talking about?
- Blow it! Just blow it.
Okay, got you.
Hydronaut calling
Seismo, Washington.
Seismo.
Roger, Hydronaut.
Understand, signing off.
They're approaching the location
for the last sensor.
Send for the American.
Reports an earthquake
of 6.5 on the Richter scale.
You'll get a warning
system in time.
Even after they
put the last one down.
Will the system interlock?
- Well, we'll know soon enough.
Standby on your regional map.
The last one.
Let's give her our
blessing and let it go.
Hank, standby to inform Seismo
as soon as it's anchored.
And if the whole
system works then..
...my dive.
Alright, here she goes.
Anchor it.
Dr. Boren, Dr. Hamaru.
The last sensor's down
and the signal's perfect.
Get me the Hydronaut.
Are all the sub
system's working?
Signal okay. Roger.
Coming through.
- Fine here.
Okay, check.
Alright, standby
for an interlock.
Well, doctor, this was
your conception.
Or misconception.
It's interlocked.
It's okay.
Call the Hydronaut.
'Hello, Hydronaut.'
'I think if it's closed,
and it works perfectly.'
'The system works.
It really, really works.'
We did it!
Great, great.
Hey, gang, guaranteed not
to be over 10 minutes old.
It'll have you gone in 90
seconds without a hangover.
Hey, who is minding the store?
Get back it.
Sure, but gimme time
to try one on.
You know, we never did really
settle on just what
we're playing for.
Anything you say.
Anything?
You don't want to take
a look at that last move?
No, no, no.
You go ahead and name it.
Well, according to an agreement
I have with Douglas here
I need your consent
for a salvage dive.
And I also need
your breathing gas.
If I win, you help me.
And if you lose, no dive.
You're checkmate in two moves.
No that's impossible.
Why, because you couldn't
outfox me with that
rat-thing
computer of yours?
Didn't you think
it was wrong to use it?
Wasn't it wrong to piggyback
your treasure dive on this sub?
No.
Then maybe you ought
to ask your computer
whether it's right or wrong?
Maybe it'll know
the difference.
Or maybe it'll get
a nervous breakdown
in trying to figure it out.
The computer I used
was conceived by me
designed by me
and engineered by me.
It's merely an electronic
extension of my own mind
I've a perfect right to use.
That makes no difference.
You lost.
No dive.
Using the computer
to figure his moves.
About three weeks ago,
on my night watch..
...I found a teletype
from Washington.
He's getting his information
from some big stupid called
MX2NR2.
Does it make any
difference to you
that the big stupid
belongs to him?
That he designed it?
You don't really believe he
designed that thing, do you?
I have seen it.
You think he designed it?
From top to bottom.
He-he really did?
- Yup.
Takes a real brain
to build one of those.
Real big brain.
But he still felt
he had to cheat to beat me.
Any guy with that much talent,
who wants something that bad
that he feels he has
to cheat to get it.
Let the pirate
have his treasure.
Nothing.
Look at this.
'Oh, I'm sure you'll find it.'
That, uh..
Go back. Back, back, back.
Reverse, reverse.
Phil, you were right.
- There. You're right.
'The propeller.'
- 'That's nice.'
Well, what are you waiting for?
I'll give you a hand, Phil.
Good luck, boy
When I come back, we're all
going to be very rich.
If the stuff is still there.
- Yeah.
Phil's going out.
Dr. Boren.
Dr. Boren, Dr. Hamaru.
What's happening?
- Must be a malfunction.
'Dr. Boren, there's an
outside call for you.'
Put him on the loudspeaker.
'This is Canal Zone,
Seismic station.'
'We want to relay transmission
from Lufthansa aircraft'
'approximately 250 miles,
south west of Canal Zone.'
This is Washington.
Go ahead, Lufthansa.
Seems to be an island
in eruption
or an island which
is coming out of the sea.
Heavy formation
of steam clouds.
Black material
thrown up continuously.
Get the Hydronaut.
'There's time for one pass.'
'My position is 130 degrees,
12 minutes 18 seconds west.'
'11.15, 22 north.'
Contact the air force.
Nearest base.
Request reconnaissance.
Televideo if available.
Hydronaut here.
Hydronaut, this is Dr. Boren.
- Oh, hello, Gus. What's up?
Hi, Doug. There's an underwater
volcanic disturbance
a 100 miles due, south of you.
We need an additional
sensor dropped in there.
How close to the disturbance
you want us to drop it?
As close as possible.
We need it to fill
a gap in the grid.
The volcano is
103 west, 11 north.
103 west, 11 north, right?
- 'Right.'
Okay, Gus.
We'll do our best.
They're out there.
I was right. I saw them.
They're out there
by the cage.
Millions of them.
I know the market value
of those crystals.
Hank, Pill come in yet?
- He just came in.
Well, lock off the sea hatch.
We're leaving.
What do you mean
we're leaving?
What about the salvage?
Well, there it is, Doug.
No islands, deep water,
easy access all the way.
That's what I figured.
- Why?
Orders.
It's there. We just have
to pick up with our hands.
I'm sorry, Phil.
Washington said now.
We had a deal, when you planted
the last sensor we...
It's not the last one,
they want us to put one more.
We'll lose them.
So many of them.
We won't. No, I took
a fix on them.
It'll only take
a couple of hours.
Later, we'll get
to your crystals later.
Stations everybody.
Can't they wait?
No, it's an underwater volcano.
Dr. Boren, transmission
from the air force.
Reconnaissance
plane's coming through.
'This is air force,
Roger Niner-Two-Niner-Two.'
'I have your island on camera.'
'Are you receiving
our transmission? Over.'
Roger, Air Force Recon.
We have it. Over.
'My position, a quarter mile
due south of disturbance.'
'Altitude 1500 feet.'
'New eruption starting on edge
of older one.'
'Heavy fall out
of hot ashes.'
'Estimated height of vapor
clouds, 3500 feet.'
'Deep underwater,
faint red glow visible.'
'Estimated depth, 800 feet.'
Get the Hydronaut.
We must have a sensor
in that area.
It's the only way we'll
make a reliable prediction
on what coastlines
are threatened.
Tell him to approach the area
with utmost caution.
And the time to get
that sensor in is now.
You were right.
Origin of the shock waves,
500 meters to port.
On the bottom of 800 feet.
It's like a hell itself.
Orin, what do you think?
If we got to the sensor
there in about
three-four hundred yards,
that'll be alright.
Three or four hundred yards?
See that shelf over there?
I'll take another look at it.
- Yeah.
I'll get the sensor
ready for the drop.
Here. Look through these.
They're filtered.
Doug, the sensor is ready.
- Okay, drop it.
Alright, here we go.
Craig, Craig.
Phil, Hank, come up forward.
We're buried.
Question is..
How deep?
Craig, the airlock,
what shape is it in?
No good at all.
It's all stowed in.
The breathing gases and the
scuba gear is down there too.
Orin.
- Yeah.
The eruption,
is it growing or dying?
It's growing.
Phil, if we do
reach the surface
we'll have to give them
a fix, can you do it?
I'll rig up something
to send out a signal.
How much air we got
left in here?
Six adults, one hour.
No, no, no.
We'll need two hours.
If I can lower metabolic rate,
that might give us two hours.
Can you?
- I can try.
Alright.
Now, this is what we better do.
There's no other way.
I'll blow us out of this
rock pile up to the surface.
Doug, you're gonna
blow this up in half?
Can you think any other way?
- No. It's the only way.
Then get all the plastic
dynamite we've got
and put it into AFCOM.
Detonators, primer cords,
the works.
Others, gather all the
mattresses, pillows, blankets
anything soft you can find
and bring it here.
Hurry now, we gotta move fast.
We're buried from here down.
Let's not knock 'em.
Grab that axe.
Alright.
Go ahead.
Get rid of that
paddle first, huh?
Alright, give Craig a hand.
Get all that dynamite in here
as fast as you can.
Get four of these
dynamite boxes.
Okay.
Alright, move ahead.
Let me see what
I can salvage here.
Airlock's underwater.
I salvaged this tank.
Good boy. This is
not a dynamite, is it?
No, there's more coming.
- Alright, hurry up.
'Alright.'
Work fast.
Shape it into corners.
It's gotta blow out.
Or else..
Maggie.
Which leads do I use?
Take a lead from
the main distributer panel.
We can ground
it anywhere in here.
Got it?
- Yeah.
Gimme the black one.
Okay.
It's no.
Got it?
The guinea pigs.
What about the guinea pig?
Guinea pigs?
Women and men first.
'Leave every cubic incubator
we've got.'
Alright, there's a spare
mattress down in the lab.
Leave it alone. It's gotta do.
Come on, get out here.
We got no time.
Phil, We are all set.
How about you?
You connected up?
- They are all connected.
Everybody here,
where's Hank?
Hank.
Hank!
Hank, get outta there.
- Yeah, I'm coming.
Get back here, come on.
Come forward.
I'm coming.
- Come on up here.
Get up there.
Get in.
Hurry. Hurry.
Mind the wires.
Avoid the explosion.
- I'll watch 'em, get up there.
Hurry up.
We haven't time.
Wrap this stuff around you, now.
Alright.
Brace yourselves.
Here goes.
Anchor up.
We're not freed.
No, no, we are not moving.
Hung up on something.
If we had gone for those
crystals, we'd be rich
and alive.
I'm gonna go out there
and cut us lose.
Craig, cut us down.
- 'Give him a hand.'
Yeah.
Here.
- What are we doing this for?
We are gonna have
to equalize the pressure..
...gradually.
Hank.
You're first.
Did you hear me?
Yeah.
Stand by, I'm gonna open it.
'They're not easy.'
- 'Let it out easy.'
Orin.
- Yeah, Dough.
Give me some flares.
- Okay.
'How many do you want?'
- Two.
Here you go.
Alright, the pressure
is equalized.
That's as high
as it will go.
Should we open it up?
- Open it up.
Sorry, but I have to take
a little more than my share.
Alright.
You said we'd have
a whole lifetime.
There's not much of
a lifetime left.
We'll make it.
There's a float.
Yeah, good.
Come on, hand me a mask.
I got Doug, gimme a hand.
- Yeah.
'I cut the cables.
We must be rising.'
Well, the time has come
to show and share the light.
So there's a crystal for you.
One for you.
- Thank you.
No, you don't get one. You blew
the bloody submarine in half.
Well, I'd rather be a poor alive
scientist than a rich dead one.
Hold on, we are turning over.