Office party.
A pretty blonde, rather plump.
She only had short affairs,
for she was mean and passive.
Then she was stroking my hair.
I saw a tenderness in her eyes
which I knew to be love.
NOW THEY'VE REACHED THE TOP.
BUT THEY DON'T KNOW WHAT TO DO NEXT.
HARD WORK IS USELESS IN ITSELF.
ARTISTS IN THE BIG TOP: PERPLEXED
1. MOURNING WORK:
DAY OF GERMAN ART 1939
He gave joy to many,
young and old.
Millions of them.
Who will weep for him now?
2. MOURNING WORK: MANFRED PEICKERT
Manfred Peickert is a circus artist.
He has plans.
I say, "Couldn't we hoist up the
elephants right over the ring?"
And the director says, "Of course,
but would the roof hold up?"
I say,
"It would be something quite new."
He says, "New?
I think it's strange and irrational."
I say, "Something has to burst.
What if they went up
with a balloon?"
The director says,
"I think it's too irrational."
But I say,
"The effect would be great."
"Genius is the capacity
for endless effort."
Success was the main goal
for the Peickerts.
Four generations of chemists.
But in their enslaved souls
something said,
"If we've been made slaves,
it would be unwise
to give us weapons."
In 1945, Manfred Peickert
went to Australia to sell oil.
But that wasn't a new world either.
He joined a circus.
I think it would be wonderful
to have the elephants
hanging up in the big top
to help build up the show.
I can't put it better than that.
"HE WHO RISKS NOTHING
SHALL NEVER WIN."
Countess Fanny Ghika
of the Imperial Circus
had herself trampled
by horses every day,
to rise again
and be cheered by the crowd.
HE WANTS TO BE A CLOWN.
TO GO AROUND MAKING THE SKY TREMBLE
WITH HIS TRUMPET,
AND BE WITH WOMEN
LIKE A REAL MAN SHOULD.
Leo Uffland worked on his
astronaut trick for 14 years.
He was to appear in a spaceship.
He died in an accident.
The remains of his contraption
are useless.
Sojkowsky survived dozens of
snake bites and died in the ring.
He worked with 20 poisonous snakes
and a non-poisonous boa.
Sojkowsky will do his hanging trick
for the first time ever.
He'd kicked away the chair.
After 2 minutes he was lifted down.
The iron noose had strangled him.
"Like the sword of Damocles, the hour
of my death looms, and I am hurrying."
I sailed off and went to...
I went to...
any old city... to Sydney.
I went looking for something,
I don't know what...
I never found it, but then
maybe it wasn't anything definite.
I turn a somersault to the high bar,
and then back again to the platform.
That's all.
It's a funny act, really.
One day
he goes up on the high bars again.
He puts magnesium powder on his hands.
His adrenalin starts to flow.
He is overcome by melancholy.
He misses his partner's hand,
and breaks his neck.
Death is the negation of time.
Lust desires eternity.
They had reached the top.
But then they didn't know
what to do next.
Hard work is useless in itself.
Leni Peickert, Manfred's heiress.
Where is it?
For the following 'double passage',
we would like to ask
for your kind attention.
The trapeze artist,
whose 5th husband shot the 4th,
threw herself onto the body and cried,
"I will avenge this,
or not be able to bear it.
But I'll have forgotten it in a week.
Fire in the Chicago elephant-house.
"Alarm! Fire!"
The director: "It isn't a real fire."
The pachyderms are getting desperate.
"Freedom", said one of the elephants,
"is risking one's life.
Not because it's freedom from slavery,
but because human freedom is defined
by its negative relation to others."
The elephants swear,
"We forget nothing."
"A wounded mind heals without scars,
but a wounded body poisons the mind."
The elephants swear,
"We forget nothing."
An adult elephant is one
that knows its enemy.
The one who doesn't protect him
in order to exploit him.
The elephants swear,
"We forget nothing."
We won't forget the firemen
and the director
who said, "It is just a fake!"
It wasn't fake, but a real fire.
Truly, the day is near,
The end of the Hitler-state.
Happy is the one, who'll still
Be alive by then.
The fascists who burn
should be thrown into the sea.
Even those who don't burn
or extinguish should be packed
and thrown into the sea.
We should also throw
our memories of the fire and
our suffering into the sea.
Or revenge.
He affected by revenge will be shot.
Rather shoot than forget.
Better to throw them into the sea.
We should throw
our memories of the fire
and our suffering, into the sea.
It's better to throw them
into the sea.
Leni Peickert wants her own circus.
She imagines herself
opening her own circus.
A circus worthy of a dead man.
She watches the performance
of a leading circus.
She wants nothing but the best.
Leni Peickert says, "I'll change
the circus, because I love it."
Answer: "She loves it,
so she won't change it. Why?
Because love is conservative."
Leni Peickert: "That isn't true!"
She says to a famous tamer,
"I plan to open my own circus."
The tamer:
"I'd be happy if you did."
Leni Peickert:
"I want the animals to act authentic".
The tamer: "They're only authentic
in the jungle."
Leni Peickert says: "I read about
so-called Evil. Change your mind!"
Let it rise... to the level of
great ideas.
Not just doing what the market wants,
but really... doing what you want.
I want to start my own business.
Do you already have an idea?
Ms. Anna Fedorjewna Saizeva,
of the Russian ministry of culture,
is on a tour of Western Europe.
Leni Peickert hopes to get some help.
We already met in Salerno,
2 years ago.
I was fascinated by your lecture,
you spoke about
the lion on horseback.
What side are you on? Are you
for the military kind of dressage?
It's funny, certain circus words are
the same in different languages:
"Big top", "artiste"...I could...
Could you lend me some artists?
Just temporarily?
I plan to start my own business,
and I would be very grateful
if you could lend me a few artists.
For a time.
They were a charming couple,
aged about 30, highly intelligent.
I'd never believed ballet-dancers
could be intelligent.
And then the organizer said to me,
"I don't know why,
everything was all right.
Good service, waiters in tailcoats,
and the stripper
was a party member since 1917."
Leni Peickert needs money
to realize her plans.
She's prepared to compromise,
and signs a television contract.
Dad, how are you? - I'm okay.
It's a bit wretched, but I'll manage.
Come on. Lola! Sascha!
Girls!
You keep on walking.
Of course, while you're walking.
He passes you and the camera follows.
Mr Müller?
- Phone is on.
71-70-1st.
It's the first time
Carlo drank too much.
The last time was when
Tim was born.
I brought you a drink.
- Thank you
How long will this take?
We rushed here today...
They don't need any circus artists.
They're all actors playing the roles.
WE SEEK ARTISTS FOR TOURS OF EUROPE
AND OVERSEAS. PLEASE CONTACT US.
A shirt, open here
and this side, or that one?
And here... pearls.
Open here, and here...
pearls... and two stars. All right?
Two stars here.
Good day.
- Good day.
I saw your advertisement.
We can use anyone who's willing.
- That's me.
You must have an open mind, of course.
- I know. What is it, exactly?
Troop entertainment.
Morocco, Libya, Thailand and Saigon.
What's new about it?
- We have an extra attraction.
The artists drop pamphlets
from high up in the big top.
Saying what? - Peace.
- Peace in general? - Yes.
What we need is something funny.
That's hard on the trapeze. - Our
boys' peace-making efforts increase
their need for entertainment.
- This is what I can offer.
I don't know it, but here it is again.
A sawmill owner orders 5 beers.
Have you seen my toothbrush?
Someone please open the tram door!
A mouse running on a hot stove.
Imagine it high up in the big top
with red spotlights.
Haven't you got anything funny?
Something special?
Haven't you got a shirt...
open here,
with some pearls and two stars...
Should I bring my own money, too?
- We can't pay much, really,
but this is about ethical values.
"Then I'll go to Maxim's"
The violin sweetly sings good-night
Your heart has turned off the light
A last kiss on your lips
And the song is over...
Mr von Lüptow talks about "The
situation of the circus artist today."
...afterwards they rode horses again.
World War Il: 2 of the Blumenfeldts
near Orel, 1942. They thought
they could fight inhumanity
if all the artists in the world
raised their standards simultaneously.
THE FRENCHMAN DIES SMILING,
THE AVIATEUR CRASHES SMILING.
JUST THINK OF A KISSING MOUTH:
OF YOURS, TRAVIATA.
I only study pieces...
I shouldn't do exercises, just play
the difficult parts of those pieces.
Facing this inhuman situation,
the artist's only recourse is to
raise his standards still higher.
Leni Peickert visits
her friend Dr Busch.
Tell me something.
Come on.
Some people kept an alligator
in an aquarium.
The alligator grew bigger,
but they didn't put him
into a bigger aquarium.
He became bigger and bigger,
and eventually grew square.
I can't imagine that.
It's a cruel story.
We grow in our cage too.
But we didn't grow square, see.
I'm used to Dr Busch.
I've known him since I was 14.
He lured me to his room
and gave me an apple.
Then he said he was sleepy,
and insisted I lie on the bed too.
He stroked my hair
and asked if I liked it.
I said yes, to be polite.
I said, "What if I cry out?"
He opened his fly
and told me to look.
I said I wasn't interested,
I'd seen the like before.
Our education was all illusion,
illusion and hope.
And how disappointed we were!
And where are we now?
Just employees in the economy!
We just have small tasks
without any responsibility.
You don't know how hard it is to work
without being able
to determine what you want.
For what? Nobody knows.
Why indeed?
Yes... in the past, we thought
we could change things,
make things better...
Make life more human.
Stop it all.
We created a bouquet:
The attention-values for women.
Flowers are top of the list.
Then soap...
- No, babies first,
they all love babies,
and then flowers second.
And what comes last?
That's why we use babies and flowers
in our ads for females.
And all mothers love babies?
It's crazy.
About 80% attention-value.
For instance,
Santa Claus as a child
giving a box of cigars,
gets 70% attention-value.
Without the child
it would be 30 or 40%.
They go crazy for flowers, too.
So it's flowers and babies.
We'll make some flower...
- Tell me more. - Flower fertilizer.
A brand of artificial fertilizer:
"Dr Happiness".
We bought the name "Dr Happiness".
"Dr Happiness!"
It calls on the mother-instinct,
gives it an outlet.
I discovered it.
The opera ball, 1968.
Leni Peickert wants to meet the friends
and promoters of her enterprises.
Mr Donndorf, assistant secretary,
ministry of education and the arts.
As Mosca, he is...
it's really the wrong role for him.
He can't help it.
- Totally wrong. He can't help it.
It's hard to find
a young actor to do
a convincing Ferdinand...
it's actually a stupid part.
Hardly playable. - Hardly playable.
And yet he is convincing.
Yes, it's due to
some sort of electric impulse...
Ammonia and methane
could produce living matter
like protein cells and so on
with a strong electric discharge
such as lightning.
The earth was once like Jupiter.
So one could reasonably assume,
although conditions are not the same,
that in millions of years
Jupiter will have
an atmosphere like ours.
"Dr Happiness in danger"
St. Petersburg, around 1900.
100 horses going in a circle.
But happiness is gone,
disappeared.
Accountant Lotte Losemeyer
often criticized
the bad management by her boss,
a building contractor.
Fortunately, she won't give in.
She takes 156,000 DM from the safe
and decides to destroy it.
It's a shame about that nice money.
Even this is more hard work
than satisfaction.
One must take it out again
and throw it back.
Forgive the woman, for you would
do the same if you'd her troubles.
Leni Peickert wants
to make even more effort.
Leni Peickert says,
"I just need
love for my work to go on.
That's what makes
poor Nolde do his deeds."
Interesting sexual problems
with space travel.
Disinclination grows
out of proportion,
but love can't be accumulated.
An astronaut who was
in hospital for a post-flight check,
filled a bottle with semen
when he saw a nurse go by.
A vessel containing about 1 cc,
like a small vase.
It's a rather unlikely
that he'd fill such a vessel...
It's a hospital urine-flask,
with a long neck...
The story's exaggerated
just to emphasize the point.
She treated the lion-tamer Mackensen
to dinner in a restaurant.
Leni Peickert admired
the tamer excessively.
...they can even whistle.
I'd like to build a great aquarium.
"Could we let a child
play with dolphins?"
"It'd be too dangerous", he says.
Leni Peickert:
"Then I can't hire you.
One has to take risks."
"Dear lady...
Dear lady, please be sensible."
My dolphins...
"Don't... don't be like that."
They can jump
up to 6 metres, maybe more.
Well, I'm sure you'll find
something to fit in later on.
I had a moment of clarity.
The police...
I can't remember a thing,
except that I was lying in bed
the next day...
lying in bed, and...
I felt a pain...
It hurt... I had a swollen hand...
terribly swollen...
then I found the note in my pocket.
A 500 km drive,
just for a Sunday with Dr Busch.
If you sit, then sit.
If you walk, then walk.
If you talk, then talk.
Leni Peickert realizes she can't
unite art and free enterprise.
Only as a capitalist
can one change things.
She buys an elephant.
She rented an animal enclosure
to wait for the season.
The business swallows money.
She asks Mr von Lüptow for a loan.
She hired Mr von Lüptow
as her deputy.
Be watchful, be watchful!
Come sit around me, and listen.
Gitti Bornemann meets
her friend, Leni Peickert.
Von Lüptow hears too late
that she's a millionairess.
Leni Peickert forbids him
to ask her for a loan.
Mr Böhme, I'll put it clearly.
I can't pay back
the 8,000 DM right now.
I don't have it.
I don't understand.
I don't understand what you said.
And if you can't give a guarantee,
I'll have to back out.
What do you mean?
- I can't just take your word.
The world's full of people
who make promises they can't keep.
8,000 DM is no small matter.
Give me six months grace.
Six months is a lifetime,
one can die in six months.
It's a very long eternity.
I understand, but...
She borrows from the large banks
to pay off the small banks.
The bank wants a total guarantee
for the money it spends.
Your animals are no guarantee.
You can't ask the bank to open a zoo
and keep them until you can pay.
As a banking counsellor he can't
act like a simple cashier.
No ordinary cashier
can do that anyway.
There must be a way, Mr Wiese!
There might be many ways,
but I can't name any right now.
"If a capitalist does what he loves
instead of what he needs,
he won't be supported
by that which is."
Look, if I get involved
in your problem...
Tell me how to analyze...
what to do...
First, you have to
establish your target group:
A) regular spectators
b) occasional spectators
c) people who never go to a circus.
Then...
People who never go?
- Their views are interesting.
What about television?
- Later on, it's irrelevant now.
But why?
- It's a competing medium. It is...
I could add
theatre and film to the circus.
Yes, but the circus on television...
We know that the circus
is interesting in itself.
But visiting a circus is inconvenient.
You have to dress up, it costs 16 DM,
you have to sit on a bench...
It costs money, the wooden bench.
You have to plan it...
so circus on television is easier.
That's why people rather watch a
circus on television than a real one.
But now back to the target group.
Maybe I could do
an African act with my elephants.
That's implausible.
Because a circus elephant
is viewed differently...
I already told you:
What counts for ideas, products
objects, people, animals
is their social background.
First modern circus: Astley in Paris.
Time: The French Revolution.
The artists: Astonishing.
There isn't a thing
the New Revolutionary Man can't do.
Then our sensational finale:
The Submarine Circus!
Delightful fountains.
Illuminated cascades.
Revolving stars above.
Soft music and the splashing of water.
Lights on, the ring is filled
with water with ducks swimming,
a boat and toy fish.
And then our comedy.
The great Danish clown Olchansky.
He was successful,
went to China, buried his child,
and came back to St. Petersburg.
The creditors take the animals.
The elephants, kept a mile away,
are taken away.
Leni Peickert
files for bankruptcy.
A break, since there is no money.
Perez sent his report to the
Condor Oil Company in San Francisco.
"Does that dirty Indian know
whom he is dealing with?
Does that dirty Indian know
whom he is dealing with?"
Thus spoke the president, Mr Collins.
"There is no land in the universe
I want that I can't get.
Not in this universe. For sure.
If I wanted land on Jupiter,
I'd get it. For sure."
Love? Your love for the circus
won't earn you any money.
Your love is a misconception,
it's not 'intersubjective'.
Others won't love it just because
you do. That's why I propose
a combined motivation-image survey
to find out what others love.
Gitti's father led a socialist
scientific institute in Frankfurt.
He transferred its capital
to the USA in 1932:
Many opportunities for entrepreneurs,
none for socialists.
Gitti Bornemann is under medical care.
No chance of recovery.
Von Fritsch said to Ebert, "Swine!"
Gitti Bornemann dies.
Leni Peickert is her sole heir.
LENI PEICKERT INC.
Ms Peickert,
I'd like to return to this...
So I dive into the net from
a height of 60 feet.
I could also show you some ballet,
and some acrobatics
and gymnastics on the floor.
I think you'll like these things
because I had
thorough training in Switzerland.
Have you ever studied
the physics of the trapeze?
No, it's purely intuitive.
What do you want to change? The front
four? - Yes, that gap is too big.
I like it, though.
Give me a smile.
I'd prefer to leave it too, but...
You don't notice it.
Oh yes, you do!
Leni Peickert
informs the press about her plans.
I think I understand
what you want now.
You want the public to participate,
not to submit passively to sensations.
Indeed...
you want them to feel
really confronted with the animals.
Quite original,
to conceive the circus as a novel.
Isn't there a risk of confusing
two quite heterogeneous genres?
I know the practical side,
the theory's the problem.
I leave that to my assistants.
As a circus it is... - Circus too!
It's inherent in the circus.
I think you should
leave the circus as it is
and just give people what they want.
- I won't...
I don't want to.
A large transparent pool...
Mr Arbogast, public relations.
Joe Willkins, dramatist.
...a few dolphins driving
smaller fish towards the clowns.
Acting...
I know, you need drama
but let's not fight over details now.
I'd like to come back
to the distrust you mentioned.
I mean,
I don't understand that.
We must get rid of that distrust
and work together.
I think it's bad
that you should think
we distrust each other.
What put that into your head?
...which you can't separate
if you think about it.
I think it could be successful
provided there is a good publicity.
It could be done...
...he keeps running away, and
they smash against the wall.
It shouldn't be boring, there
should be a progression in brutality,
different ways of dropping them,
building to a climax...
Let it fall into the sand first,
then some hard object
is pushed there with the foot...
...suddenly add a level,
chase after them,
and try to catch the small animals
and paint a Star of David on them.
That's too direct.
- If we leave the tigers with the mice
primitive people will indeed laugh.
Yes, there is that David and Goliath
idea which has a very strong appeal.
But David must win, and this one won't.
- Yes,
but we could make a huge
papier mâché Mickey Mouse figure
and the tamer would come out
very small, against the tigers...
How the piously the heath sings,
How the sound enters my soul!
An old winter circus is for rent.
LENI PEICKERT INC., WINTER CIRCUS
With just 4 weeks to the opening,
we don't know
if the circus will have 1 or 3 rings.
The shooting of
Mexico's emperor, Maximilian.
The emperor was a poor privateer,
but his counsellors were tough.
The soldiers cock their rifles
but don't shoot. They say,
"Let's use kindness for bullets.
The echo will be more quiet.
This emperor is a loser anyway."
He was reinstalled right away.
The violin
sweetly sings good-night
Your heart has...
Happy is the man
who can forget what he was.
A last kiss on your lips
And the song is over.
A sweet greeting
waves you all the way home.
Tonight our comrades will be shot.
Thus the comrades shot Emperor Max.
Von Lüptow rehearses with the clowns.
One foot down, the other one,
the other one up.
I'm waiting until I can fly.
Then I fly...
One finally flies.
You hit something,
but it doesn't hurt.
No, it's fun to crash like that.
Just to crash like that...
to roll around on the ground,
to fly into there...
right there into the mud.
Program plan:
1st part: The clowns.
1) The staff enter.
2) Record concert.
3) The shooting of Emperor Maximilian.
4) Encounter with alien intelligence,
represented by dolphins.
Guns being set up.
- That was the fifth act.
2nd part: The animals.
1) Rats at work.
An elephant smashes 3 barriers
and charges at the audience.
He looks violent.
In the big top hangs a model
of a Japanese dive-bomber.
Will this stop the raving pachyderm?
3rd number.
4) Pack of elephants.
Seek Greece with your soul.
Mandolin concerto by the elephants.
1) The ring is dark.
Storm, thunder, lightning.
Polar bears up high,
a plane landing.
Seven tigers trying to stop
sixty red mice.
They fail.
The tigers form a pyramid
and give paw.
3) The polar bears in the big top
light a fire to warm themselves.
4) Some artists,
disguised as firemen, declare that...
They're all destroyed,
but none will admit it.
Clowns mourn their lost honour.
7) All performers leave the stage.
The end.
After my release as a POW,
it was established that my right eye
had been somewhat damaged.
It happened in the East,
in a partisan battle,
when I was hit in the eye
with a rifle-butt.
Yes, so it was damaged, and now...
I have to wear this eyeglass,
a monocle, to aid my sight.
I have to use the muscles,
it doesn't work with this one...
But I have one
with an elasticated ring.
But this one's very hard to hold in.
It should hold somehow...
And...
You see?
That's why a system
working with springs...
What do you do?
In what sense do you mean?
I'm a trapeze artist.
I work on the high trapeze.
Perry Woodcock, a horse owner,
asks for advice.
It started out quite well.
She attracted me,
and we were sitting at the bar,
and then she said,
and then I said...
I was rather direct, so I said,
"Why don't you take off your bra..."
So she did it, and gave it to me.
It was great fun.
We left together after closing time,
she asked me to,
and I didn't mind.
I wasn't that interested in her,
anyway. Only a bit.
She said I looked like
Roy Black, or something.
And then she lay on the bed
and masturbated.
I prefer a woman like that,
she knows what she wants.
Seen from the psychological side,
I could condemn her
or behave improperly,
but I think I gave her
much more like that...
I don't mind being Roy Black for her.
At this time there was a congress
of circus directors in Nuremberg.
WELCOME TO THE GUNPOWDER FACTORY
Leni Peickert and von Lüptow
assess the congress papers.
"I'd like to see the man
who, after Auschwitz,
tries to stop us saying something
that has to be said."
I'd like to see the man
who, after Auschwitz,
tries to stop us saying or doing
what we believe to be correct."
Moscow State Circus, Mr Reisch:
"After two wars, I don't want
to show off animals any more."
Perizoff laughs. Petoletti:
"We know what we don't want."
Mr Reisch, Moscow State Circus:
"The modern circus should be
scientific." - Where?
Burkhardt-Footit, USA,
"...and yet respect ethical limits."
Blumenfeldt for all present:
"I'd like to see the man
who, after Auschwitz,
tries to stop us saying or doing
what we believe to be correct."
Unanimous: "We'll keep the rats."
Drinks are being served.
- Applause. A pause.
Mr Michael Saluti: "Disgusting!"
The end.
"Cannot be shown."
Korti: "Cannot be shown."
Ferry Corvey shows a film
about a prime minister
who for a moment
believes in the impossible.
"That has to be said."
Blumenfeldt, for all present:
"No one can stop us
showing what we want to...
I'd like to see the one
who, after Auschwitz..."
Mr Arbogast speaks
on entertainment again.
Leni Peickert decides,
"Mr Arbogast is right.
Freedom means that
the spectator thinks
entertainment is that
what we offer him.
But it needn't
actually be entertainment."
The staff are desperate.
They think this is nonsense.
To put it more concretely:
You're like a child
blowing soap bubbles,
blowing, or producing,
more and more bubbles,
never stopping, because you hope
you'll blow one bubble
more colourful than the last.
You thereby forget
that you're blowing bubbles.
So that one bubble will remain?
That's the problem.
That's why it begins at all,
the blowing, the senseless part of it.
Because one wants a bubble
that really exists?
A bubble that 'should' exist, I'd say,
because they don't
actually exist at all.
It should be one
that could retain its form
for more than a few seconds.
To put it in a more abstract way:
You don't want utopia
just flying round in your mind,
you want to see utopia
realized in a concrete way.
Utopia grows ever better
the longer we wait.
Leni Peickert looked at it thus:
"One should be true to oneself."
She asks von Lüptow,
"How much will we have
if we sell out right now?"
He answers, "About 200,000 DM."
Enough for a new start.
They bring the elephants
across the border.
They are arrested, the elephants
are seized. They launch a lawsuit.
Tax investigations.
Leni Peickert:
"Great reformers are great obstacles."
She read it in "Die Welt".
A lawyer reforming Thuringian jails
in the 1920s took a leading position
in the Hesse judiciary after 1945.
He used it to impede
any attempt at reform except his own.
WHERE YOU CANNOT LOVE, PASS BY.
ELEONORA DUSE
She reads that countless mines
and oil wells are lying unused
in the wilds of Nigeria, in Biafra.
One could do business
with just a few weapons and a plane.
On her return, Leni Peickert
takes up her studies again.
So the receiver can change
the signals
into luminous dots on a tube,
reconstituting the picture...
The technical process can
be defined like this:
We see...
THEORY OF MASS MEDIA
...the act of perception
as it is produced.
Place a man in front of a camera,
film him,
he's scanned electronically,
dissolved into dots.
The dots are transmitted
and reach a receiver,
reach my eyes,
but what do they evoke?
That's the question!
"Giving a sense of life happening.
The acoustic perception in recording
is like sound-film technology
and transmission in radio."
Leni Peickert intends
to take a job in television.
I studied Italian and English,
but little German, I'm afraid.
...can't be granted.
Lost 4 seconds again.
The enchanting woman smiles, like now.
The enchanted man wants
to meet the enchanting woman.
If you could pass on the enchantment
it would save time.
Bi-phase. Regulator channel open.
...two reports
with similar contents: A1 = A2.
All her former staff
now work for television.
At night, they work on serials.
Dot, paragraph, new line.
Saturn underlined.
120,800 km in diameter,
1.4 times the earth's gravity,
0.7 g/cc mean density, 37 km/s...
Professor Gerloff wants to use
television to spread his ideas
of education, in particular
the global promotion of Latin.
Let me explain...
Have you ever been
to the Sistine Chapel? - No.
No? You've never been there?
I mean, it is something
one really must see.
This will grow together, sometime...
Love for work, novels and television.
Korti allows his soul to wander
among beautiful things.
He sometimes
has little visual adventures.
He is an official
in the D.A.'s office, vice department.
Scientific and artistic writings
which deal with sexual issues
ennoble them, raising them
beyond their sexual appeal,
so that one's sense of propriety
is not offended...
Korti is eating pig's ear
on a bed of vegetables.
Looks rather good.
The vegetables came from Malta by air.
The pig's ear lies on the plate
like a broad, firm cloth.
In her attempts to change the world,
Leni Peickert will meet Korti.
He will smother her desire for change
unless he himself is redeemed.
Then the revolution will have in him
the upholder of its rights.
After 18 months, Leni Peickert
rose to salary bracket IVa.
Great steps make one ridiculous,
but with small steps
I could make it to State Secretary.
Where do I talk into?
Where? Right here?
So, the Troubadour.
A rather complicated story.
It starts with a prologue.
It takes us to the inner courtyard
of a castle.
The prologue tells of a...
if I only knew, I'd be happy...
about Manrico and Count Luna,
2 brothers, unaware of each other,
who love the same girl, Leonore.
And Azucena, a Gypsy,
is their mother.
No one knows about the two boys.
We only find out at the end that
they're related, when everybody dies.
It is terribly complicated,
but I think
it's one of Verdi's best works.
Subtitles
Alexander Zuckrow
Film und Video Untertitelung
Gerhard Lehmann AG