As I remember, Adam.
It was upon this fashion.
My father bequeathed me by will
but poor a thousand crowns.
And charged my brother on his
blessing to breed me well.
And there begins my sadness.
He stays me at home unkept.
For call you that 'keeping'
for a gentleman of my birth.
That differs not from
the stalling of an ox?
He lets me feed with his hinds.
Bars me the place of a brother
and as much as in him lies.
Mines my gentility with my education.
This is it, Adam, that grieves me.
And the spirit of my father
which I think is within me.
Begins to mutiny against this servitude.
I will no longer endure it.
Psst. Master Orlando.
Yonder he comes.
Stay apart, and thou shalt hear
how he will shake me up.
Now, sir. What make you here?
Nothing. I am not taught
to make anything.
Marry, sir. Be better employed.
Shall I keep your hogs
and eat husks with them?
Know you where you are, sir?
I know you are my eldest brother.
And in the gentle condition of
blood you should so know me.
I have as much of my
father in me as you.
What, boy.
Come, come, elder brother.
You are too young in this.
Wilt thou lay hands on me, villain?
- I am no villain.
I am the youngest son
of Sir Rowland de Boys.
And he is thrice a villain that
says such a father begot villains.
Wert thou not my brother, I would
not take this hand from thy throat ..
Till this other had pulled out
thy tongue for saying so.
Sweet masters, be patient.
For your father's
remembrance, be at accord.
Let me go I say.
I will not till I please.
You shall hear me.
My father charged you by his
will to give me good education.
You have trained me like a peasant.
And the spirit of my father grows strong
within me. I will no longer endure it.
Therefore, give me the poor allottery
my father left me by testament.
With that I will go buy my fortunes.
Well, sir. Get you in.
I will not long be troubled with you.
You shall have some part of your will.
I pray you leave me.
I will no further offend you
than becomes me for my good.
Get you with him, you old dog.
Is 'old dog' my reward?
Most true, I have lost my
teeth in your service.
I will physic your rankness.
And yet give no thousand crowns neither.
Holla. Dennis.
Calls your Worship?
Was not Charles, the Duke's wrestler,
here to speak with me?
So please you, he is here at the door.
Call him in.
Good morrow, your Worship.
- Good Monsieur Charles.
What is the new news of the new court?
There is no news at the court,
sir, but the old news.
That is, the old duke is banished
by his younger brother the new duke.
Where will the old duke live?
They say he is already
in the Forest of Arden.
And many merry men with him.
And there they live like the
old Robin Hood of England.
You wrestle tomorrow
before the new duke?
Marry, do I, sir.
And I came to acquaint
you with a matter.
I am given, sir, secretly to understand
that your younger brother Orlando ..
Comes against me to try a fall.
Tomorrow, sir, I wrestle for my credit.
And he that escapes me
without some broken limb.
Shall acquit him well.
Therefore, out of my loved to you.
I came hither to acquaint you.
That you might stay him.
Charles.
I thank thee for thy love to me.
Which I will most kindly requite.
I'll tell thee, Charles.
My brother.
Is the stubbornest
young fellow of France.
A secret and villainous
contriver against me.
His natural brother.
Therefore, use thy discretion.
I had as lief thou didst
break his neck as his finger.
I am heartily glad I came hither to you.
If he come tomorrow.
I'll give him his payment.
If ever he go alone again.
I'll never wrestle for prize more.
And so keep good, your Worship.
- Farewell, good Charles.
I hope I shall see an end of him.
For my soul.
Yet I know not why.
Hates nothing more than he.
I pray thee, Rosalind, sweet my coz.
Be merry.
Dear Celia, I show more
mirth than I am mistress of.
Unless you could teach to
forget a banished father.
You must not learn me how to
remember any extraordinary pleasure.
Herein I see thou lov'st me not with
the full weight that I love thee.
If my uncle, thy banished father.
Had banished my uncle,
the Duke thy father.
So thou hadst been still with me.
I could have taught my love
to take thy father for mine.
So wouldst thou.
If the truth of thy love to me were so
righteously tempered as mine is to thee.
Well.
I will forget.
You know my father hath no child but I?
And truly, when he dies,
thou shalt be his heir.
For what he hath taken away
from thy father perforce.
I will render thee again in affection.
By mine honor I will.
And when I break that oath,
let me turn monster.
Therefore, my sweet Rose.
My dear Rose.
Be Merry.
From henceforth I will, coz.
And devise sports.
Let me see.
What think you .. of falling in love?
Marry, I prithee do.
To make sport withal.
Love no man in good earnest.
Nor no further in sport neither
than with safety of a pure blush.
Thou mayst in honor come off again.
- What shall be our sport then?
Here comes Monsieur Le Beau.
With his mouth full of news.
Bonjour, Monsieur Le Beau.
What's the news?
Fair princess.
You're going to lose much good sport.
Sport? Of what color?
What color, madam?
How shall I answer you?
As wit and fortune will.
Et bien, j'allais justement vous dire.
Good wrestling, ladies.
And they are ready to perform it.
Let us see it, coz.
Come on.
Since this youth will not be entreated,
his own peril on his forwardness.
Is yonder, the man?
Even he madam.
Alas, he is too young.
How now, daughter and cousin?
Are you crept hither
to see the wrestling?
Ay, my liege.
So please you give us leave.
You will take little delight in it I can
tell you. There is such odds in the man.
In pity of the challenger's
youth I would fain dissuade him.
But he will not be entreated.
Speak to him, ladies.
See if you can move him.
I'll not be by.
Call him hither, good Monsieur Le Beau.
Monsieur the challenger.
The Princess calls for you.
I attend them with all respect and duty.
Young man.
Have you challenged
Charles the wrestler?
No, fair princess.
He is the general challenger.
I come but in as others do, to try
with him the strength of my youth.
Young gentleman, your spirits
are too bold for your years.
We pray you for your own
sake to give over this attempt.
Do, young sir.
I beseech you, punish me
not with your hard thoughts.
Wherein I confess me much guilty to deny
so fair and excellent ladies anything.
But let your fair eyes and gentle
wishes go with me to my trial.
Wherein, if I be foiled.
There is but one shamed
who was never gracious.
If killed, but one dead
that is willing to be so.
I shall do my friends no wrong.
For I have none to lament me.
The world no injury.
For in it I have nothing.
Only In the world.
I fill up a place which may be better
supplied when I have made it empty.
The little strength that I have,
I would it were with you.
And mine, to eke out hers.
Come.
Where is this young gallant ..
That is so desirous to lie
with his mother Earth?
You mean to mock me after?
You should not have mocked me before.
But come your ways.
Now Hercules be thy speed, young man.
I would I were invisible.
To catch the strong fellow by the leg.
No more. No more.
How dost thou, Charles?
He cannot speak, my lord.
Bear him away.
What is thy name, young man?
Orlando, my liege.
The youngest son of Sir Rowland de Boys.
I would thou hadst been
son to some man else.
The world esteemed thy father honorable.
But I did find him still mine enemy.
But fare thee well.
Thou art a gallant youth.
I would thou hadst told
me of another father.
Were I my father, coz.
Would I do this?
My father loved Sir Rowland as his soul.
Gentle cousin.
Let us go thank him and encourage him.
Sir.
You have well deserved.
If you do keep your
promises in love, but justly.
As you have exceeded promise.
Your mistress shall be happy.
Gentleman.
Wear this for me.
One out of suits with Fortune.
That could give more.
But that her hand lacks means.
Shall we go, coz?
Fare you well, fair gentleman.
Can I not say 'thank you'?
He calls us back.
My pride fell with my fortunes.
I'll ask him what he would.
Did you call, sir?
Sir, you have wrestled well.
And overthrown more than your enemies.
Will you go, Rosalind?
Have with you.
Fare thee well.
What passion hangs these
weights upon my tongue?
I cannot speak to her.
Yet she urged conference.
O poor Orlando. Thou art overthrown.
Or Charles or something
weaker masters thee.
Good sir, I do in friendship
counsel you to leave this place.
Albeit you have deserved
high commendation.
Yet.
Such is now the duke's condition that
he misconstrues all that you have done.
I thank you, sir.
And pray you tell me this.
Which of the two was daughter of the
duke that here was at the wrestling?
Indeed, the taller is his daughter.
The other is Rosalind,
daughter to the banished duke.
I can tell you. Of late this duke takes
displeasure against his gentle niece.
Grounded upon no other argument.
That people praise her for her virtues
and pity her for her good father's sake.
And on my life, his malice against
this lady will suddenly break forth.
Sir. Fare you well.
I rest much bounden to you.
Fare you well.
Thus must I from the
smoke into the smother.
From tyrant duke unto a tyrant brother.
But heavenly Rosalind.
Rosalind.
Why cousin.
Why Rosalind.
Cupid have mercy.
Not a word?
Not one to throw at a dog.
But is all this for your father?
No.
Some of it is for my father's child.
Come, come.
Wrestle with your affections.
O, they take the part of a
better wrestler than myself.
Is it possible on such a sudden ..
You should fall into so strong a liking
with old Sir Rowland's youngest son?
The Duke my father.
Loved his father dearly.
Doth it therefore ensue that you
should love his son dearly?
No.
By this kind of chase I should hate him.
For my father hated his father dearly.
Yet I hate not Orlando.
No, faith. Hate him not for my sake.
Look.
Here comes the Duke.
Mistress, dispatch you
with your safest haste.
And get you from our court.
Me, uncle?
You, cousin.
Within these ten days if
that thou beest found ..
So near our public
court as twenty miles.
Thou diest for it.
I do beseech, your Grace.
Let me the knowledge of
my fault bear with me.
Never so much as in a thought
unborn did I offend your Highness.
Thus do all traitors.
Thou art thy father's daughter.
There's enough.
So was I.
When your Highness took his dukedom.
So was I when your
Highness banished him.
Treason is not inherited, my lord.
Or if we did derive it from our
friends, what's that to me?
My father was no traitor.
Then, good my liege,
mistake me not so much.
To think my poverty is treacherous.
Dear sovereign, hear me speak.
- Ay, Celia.
We stayed her for your sake, else had
she with her father ranged along.
If she be a traitor, why so am I.
We still have slept together.
Rose at an instant.
Learned, played, eat together.
Still we went coupled and inseparable.
Thou art a fool.
She robs thee of thy name.
And thou wilt show more bright and
seem more virtuous when she is gone.
No, my liege.
- Open not thy lips.
Firm and irrevocable is my doom.
She is banished.
Pronounce that sentence
then on me, my liege.
I cannot live out of her company.
You are a fool.
You, niece. Provide yourself.
If you outstay the time.
Upon mine honor.
And in the greatness of my word.
You die.
O, my poor Rosalind.
Whither wilt thou go?
Wilt thou change fathers?
I will give thee mine.
I charge thee.
Be not thou more grieved than I am.
I have more cause.
Thou hast not, cousin.
Prithee, be cheerful.
Know'st thou not the
Duke hath banished me ..
His daughter?
That he hath not.
No.
Hath not?
Rosalind lacks then the love
which teacheth thee that thou ..
And I am one.
Shall we be sundered?
Shall we part?
Sweet girl.
No.
Let my father seek another heir.
For, by this heaven,
now at our sorrows pale.
Say what thou cans't.
I'll go along with thee.
Why.
Whither shall we go?
To seek my uncle in the Forest of Arden.
What shall he have that killed the deer?
His leather skin and horns to wear.
Take thou no scorn to wear the horn.
It was a crest ere thou was born.
Thy father's father wore it.
And thy father bore it.
The horn, the horn, the lusty horn.
Is not a thing to laugh to scorn.
Now my co-mates and brothers in exile.
Hath not old custom made
this life more sweet ..
Than that of painted pomp?
Are not these woods more free
from peril than the envious court?
Here feel we not the penalty of Adam.
The seasons' difference.
As the icy fang and churlish
chiding of the winter's wind.
Which, when it bites
and blows upon my body.
Even till I shrink with cold.
I smile and say:
'This is no flattery'.
These are counselors.
'That feelingly persuade me'.
'What I am'.
Sweet are the uses of adversity.
Which like the toad, ugly and venomous.
Wears yet a precious jewel in his head.
And this our life,
exempt from public haunt.
Finds tongues in trees.
Books in the running brooks.
Sermons in stones.
And good.
In everything.
I would not change it.
Happy is your Grace.
That can translate the stubbornness
of fortune Into so quiet ..
And so sweet a style.
Blow, blow, thou winter wind.
Thou art not so unkind.
As man's ingratitude.
Thy tooth is not so keen.
Because thou art not seen.
Although thy breath be rude.
Alas.
What danger will it be to us.
Maids as we are.
To travel forth so far?
I'll put myself in poor and mean attire.
And with a kind of umber smirch my face.
The like do you.
So shall we pass along and
never stir assailants?
Were it not better.
That I did suit me.
All points like a man?
And in my heart.
Lie there what hidden
woman's fear there will.
We'll have a swashing
and a martial outside.
As many other mannish cowards have.
That do outface it with
their semblances.
What shall I call thee
when thou art a man?
I'll have no worse a name
than Jove's own page.
And therefore look you call me Ganymede.
But what will you be called?
Something that hath
reference to my state:
No longer Celia.
But Aliena.
But cousin.
What if we assayed to steal the clownish
fool out of your father's court?
Would he not be a comfort to our travel?
He'll go along o'er the
wide world with me.
Leave me alone to woo him. Let's away.
Now go we in content.
To liberty, and not to banishment.
Can it be possible that no man saw them?
It cannot be.
Some villains of my court are of
consent and sufferance in this.
I cannot hear of any that did see her.
My lord.
The roinish clown at whom so oft Your
Grace was wont to laugh is also missing.
Hisperia, the Princess' gentlewoman.
Confesses that she secretly o'erheard ..
Your daughter and her cousin did commend
the parts and graces of the wrestler ..
That did but lately foil
the sinewy Charles.
And she believes.
Wherever they are gone,
that youth is surely in their company.
Send to that wrestler.
Fetch that gallant hither.
If he be absent,
bring his brother to me.
I'll make him find him.
Do this suddenly.
And let not search or inquisition quail.
To bring again these foolish runaways.
O my gentle master.
O my sweet master.
O you memory of old Sir Rowland.
Why, what's the matter?
O unhappy youth.
Within this roof.
The enemy of all your graces lives.
Your brother.
This night he means to burn the
lodging where you use to lie.
And you within it.
This house is but a butchery.
Abhor it. Fear it.
Do not stay in it.
Why whither, Adam,
wouldst thou have me go?
No matter whither, so you stay not here.
What, wouldst thou have
me go and beg my food?
I have five hundred crowns.
The thrifty hire I saved
under your father.
Here is the gold.
All this I give you.
Let me be your servant.
In all your business and necessities.
O good old man.
How well in thee appears the constant
service of the antique world.
When service sweat
for duty, not for meed.
Thou art not for the
fashion of these times.
Where none will serve but for promotion.
But come thy ways.
We'll go along together.
And ere we have thy
youthful wages spent.
We'll light upon some
settled low content.
O Jupiter, how weary are my spirits.
I care not for my spirits.
If my legs were not so weary.
I could find in my heart to
disgrace my man's apparel.
And to cry like a woman.
I pray you bear with me.
I can go no further.
For my part, I had rather
bear with you than bear you.
Well, this is the Forest of Arden.
Ay, now am I in Arden.
The more fool I.
When I was at home
I was in a better place.
But travelers must be content.
- Ay.
Be so, good Touchstone.
O Corin.
That thou knew'st how I do love her.
I partly guess, for I
have loved ere now.
How many actions most ridiculous hast
thou been drawn to by thy fantasy?
Into a thousand that I have forgotten.
O, thou didst then
never love so heartily.
If thou remember not the slightest folly
that ever love did make thee run into.
Thou hast not loved.
Or if thou hast not spoke as I do now.
Wearing thy hearer
with thy mistress' praise.
Thou hast not loved.
Or if thou hast not broke from company.
Abruptly, as my passion now make me.
Thou hast not loved.
O Phoebe.
Phoebe.
O Jove, Jove.
This shepherd's passion
is much upon my fashion.
And mine.
But it grows somewhat stale with me.
I pray you.
One of you question yond man if
he for gold will give us any food.
I faint almost to death.
Holla, you clown.
Peace, fool. He is not thy kinsman.
Who calls?
Good morrow, to you friend.
And to you, gentle sir.
And to you all.
I prithee, shepherd.
If that love or gold can in this
desert place buy entertainment.
Here's a young maid.
With travel much oppressed.
And faints for succor.
Fair sir, I pity her.
But I am shepherd to another man and
do not shear the fleeces that I graze.
His cote, his flocks, and bounds
of feed are now on sale.
But what is, come and see.
And in my voice, most
welcome shall you be.
I pray thee.
If it stand with honesty, buy thou
the cottage, pasture, and the flock.
And thou shalt have to pay for it of us.
I like this place and willingly
would waste my time in it.
Assuredly the thing is to be sold.
Go with me.
And if you like, upon report the soil,
the profit and this kind of life.
I will your very faithful feeder be.
Why, how now, monsieur?
What a life is this that your poor
friends must woo your company?
You look merrily. A fool, a fool.
I met a fool i' th' forest.
A motley fool.
A miserable world.
As I do live by food, I met a fool.
Who laid him down and
basked him in the sun.
And railed on Lady
Fortune in good terms.
In good set terms.
And yet a motley fool.
'Good morrow, fool', quoth I.
'No, sir', quoth he.
'Call me not 'fool' till
heaven hath sent me fortune'.
And then he drew a dial from his poke.
And looking on it with lack-luster eye.
Says very wisely:
'It is ten o'clock'.
'Thus we may see', quoth he.
'How the world wags'.
'Tis but an hour ago since it was nine.
And after one hour
more 'twill be eleven.
And so from hour to
hour we ripe and ripe.
And then from hour to
hour we rot and rot.
And thereby hangs a tale.
A noble fool. A worthy fool.
Motley's the only wear.
What fool is this?
- O worthy fool.
Would that I were a fool.
I am ambitious for a motley coat.
Forbear and eat no more.
Why, I have eat none yet.
- Nor shalt, till necessity be served.
Of what kind should this cock come of?
- Forbear I say.
He dies who touches any of this fruit
till I and my affairs are answerèd.
An you will not be answered with reason.
I must die.
What would you have?
Your gentleness shall force ..
More than your force
move us to gentleness.
I almost die for food.
Let me have it.
Sit down and feed.
And welcome to our table.
Speak you so gently?
Pardon me, I pray you.
I thought that all things
had been savage here.
And therefore put I on the
countenance of stern commandment.
But whate'er you are.
If ever you have looked on better days.
If ever been where bells
have knolled to church.
If ever sat at any good man's feast.
If ever from your eyelids wiped a tear
to know what 'tis to pity and be pitied.
Let gentleness my strong enforcement be.
In the which hope I blush.
And hide my sword.
True is it that we
have seen better days.
And have with holy bell
been knolled to church.
And sat at good men's feasts.
And wiped our eyes of drops.
That sacred pity hath engendered.
Therefore.
Sit you down in gentleness.
Yet but forbear your
food a little while.
There is a poor old man.
Who, after me hath many a
weary step limped in pure love.
Till he be first sufficed, oppressed
with two weak evils, age and hunger.
I will not touch a bit.
Go seek him out.
And we will nothing
waste until your return.
I thank you.
And be blessed for your good comfort.
Thou seest we are not all alone unhappy.
This wide and universal
theater presents ..
More woeful pageants than the scene ..
Wherein we play in.
All of the world's a stage.
And all the men and women.
Merely players.
They have their exits
and their entrances.
And one man in his
time plays many parts.
His acts being ..
Seven ages.
At first .. the infant.
Mewling and puking in the nurse's arms.
Then the whining schoolboy with his
satchel and shining morning face.
Creeping like snail
unwillingly to school.
And then the lover.
Sighing like furnace.
With a woeful ballad made
to his mistress' eyebrow.
Then a soldier.
Full of strange oaths and
bearded like the pard.
Jealous in honor.
Sudden and quick in quarrel.
Seeking the bubble reputation.
Even in the cannon's mouth.
And then.
In fair round belly.
With good capon lined.
With eyes severe and
beard of formal cut.
Full of wise saws and modern instances.
And so he plays his part.
The sixth age.
Shifts into the lean and
slippered pantaloon.
With spectacles on nose
and pouch on side.
His youthful hose, well saved.
A world too wide for his shrunk shank.
And his big manly voice.
Turning again toward childish treble.
Pipes and whistles in his sound.
Last scene of all.
That ends this strange eventful history.
Is second childishness.
And mere.
Oblivion.
Sans teeth.
Sans eyes.
Sans taste.
Sans.
Everything.
If that you were the
good Sir Rowland's son.
As you have whispered
faithfully you were.
Be truly welcome hither.
Good old man.
Thou art right welcome as thy master is.
I am the duke.
That loved your father.
Not see him since?
Sir, sir, that cannot be.
But look to it:
Find out thy brother wheresoe'er he is.
Seek him with candle. Bring him dead
or living within this twelvemonth.
Or turn thou no more to seek
a living in our territory.
Thy lands.
And all things that thou dost call thine
worth seizure, do we seize in our hands.
Till thou can quit thee by thy brother's
mouth of what we think against thee.
O, that your Highness
knew my heart in this:
I never loved my brother in my life.
More villain thou.
Well, push him out of doors.
And let my officers of such a nature
make an extent upon his house and lands.
Do this expediently and turn him going.
Hang there my verse,
in witness of my love.
And thou, thrice-crownèd
queen of night ..
Survey with thy chaste eye,
from thy pale sphere above.
Thy huntress' name that
my full life doth sway.
O Rosalind.
These trees shall be my books.
And in their barks my
thoughts I'll character.
That every eye which in the forest looks
can see thy virtue witnessed everywhere.
Run.
Run, Orlando.
Carve on every tree
the fair, the chaste.
The unexpressive she.
'From the east to western Ind'.
'No jewel is like Rosalind'.
'Her worth being mounted on the wind'.
'Through all the world bears Rosalind'.
'All the pictures fairest lined'.
'Are but black to Rosalind'.
'Let no face be kept in mind'.
'But the fair of Rosalind'.
I'll rhyme you so eight years together.
Dinners and suppers and
sleeping hours excepted.
Out fool.
- For a taste.
If a hart do lack a hind.
Let him seek out Rosalind.
Stop.
If the cat will after kind,
so be sure will Rosalind.
Stop fool.
Wintered garments must be lined..
So must slender Rosalind.
Sweetest nut hath sourest rind.
Such a nut is Rosalind.
He that sweetest rose will find,
must find love's prick and Rosalind.
Peace, you dull fool.
This is the very false gallop of verses.
Why do you infect yourself with them?
I found them on a tree.
Truly, the tree yields bad fruit.
- Peace.
'Helen's cheek, but not her heart'.
'Cleopatra's majesty'.
'Atalanta's better part'.
'Sad Lucretia's modesty'.
'Thus Rosalind of many parts'.
'By heavenly synod was devised'.
'Of many faces, eyes, and hearts'.
'To have the touches dearest prized'.
'Heaven would that she
these gifts should have'.
'And I to live and die her slave'.
O most gentle Jupiter.
- How now? Back, friends.
Shepherd, go off a little.
Go with him, sirrah.
Didst thou hear without wondering ..
How thy name should be hanged
and carved upon these trees?
I was seven of the nine days out
of the wonder before you came.
For look here what I
found on a palm tree.
I was never so berhymed
since Pythagoras' time.
When I was an Irish rat.
Which I can hardly remember.
Trow you who hath done this?
Is it a man?
And a chain you once
wore about his neck.
Change you color?
I prithee, who?
Is it possible?
Nay, I prithee now.
With most petitionary vehemence.
Tell me who it is.
O wonderful, wonderful.
And most wonderful, wonderful.
And yet again wonderful.
And after that out of all whooping.
Good my complexion.
Dost thou think though I am
caparisoned like a man ..
I have a doublet and
hose in my disposition?
One inch of delay more is
a South Sea of discovery.
I prithee, speak apace.
I would thou couldst stammer.
That thou might'st pour this
concealed man out of thy mouth.
As wine comes out of a
narrow-mouthed bottle.
Either too much at once or none at all.
I prithee take the
cork out of thy mouth.
That I may drink thy tidings.
So you may put a man in your belly.
- What manner of man?
Is his head worth a hat?
Or his chin worth a beard?
Nay.
He hath but a little beard.
Why, God will send more
if the man will be thankful.
Let me stay the growth of his beard, if
thou delay me not knowledge of his chin.
It is.
Young ..
- Young who?
Orlando.
Orlando?
Alas the day.
What shall I do with
my doublet and hose?
What did he when thou saw'st him?
How looked he? Wherein went he?
He asked for me?
When shalt thou see him again?
Answer me in one word.
You must borrow me
Gargantua's mouth first.
But take a taste.
I found him under a tree.
Like a dropped acorn.
It may well be called Jove's tree.
When it drops forth such fruit.
There lay he, stretched
along like a wounded knight.
Though it be pity to see such a sight.
It well becomes the ground.
Cry 'holla' to thy tongue, I prithee.
Thou bring'st me out of tune.
Do you not know I am a woman?
When I think, I must speak.
Sweet, say on.
- You bring me out.
I thank you for your company.
But good faith, I had as lief
have been myself alone.
And so had I.
But yet for fashion sake I
thank you too for your society.
God be wi' you.
Let's meet as little as we can.
I do desire we may be better strangers.
I pray you ..
Mar no more trees with writing
love songs in their barks.
I pray you mar no more of my verses
with reading them ill-favoredly.
Rosalind is your love's name?
- Yes, just.
I do not like her name.
There was no thought of pleasing
you when she was christened.
What stature is she of?
- Just as high as my heart.
You are full of pretty answers.
I am weary of you.
I'll tarry no longer with you.
Farewell, good Signior Love.
I am glad of your departure.
Adieu, good Monsieur Melancholy.
Forester. Do you hear?
Very well. What would you?
I pray you, what is 't o'clock?
You should ask what time o' day.
There is no clock in the forest.
Then there is no true
lover in the forest.
Else sighing every minute.
And groaning every hour.
Would detect the lazy foot
of time as well as a clock.
Where dwell you, pretty youth?
With this shepherdess, my sister.
Here in the skirts of the forest.
Like fringe upon a petticoat.
Your accent is something finer than you
could purchase in so removed a dwelling.
I have been told so of many.
But indeed, an old religious uncle
of mine taught me to speak.
Who was in his youth an inland man.
One that knew courtship too well,
for there he fell in love.
I have heard him read
many lectures against it.
And I thank God I am not a woman to be
touched with so many giddy offenses.
Can you remember any of the principal
evils he laid to the charge of women?
I prithee recount some of them.
- No.
I will not cast away my physic.
But on those that are sick.
There is a man.
Haunts the forest.
That abuses our young plants.
With carving 'Rosalind' on their barks.
Hangs odes upon hawthorns.
And elegies on brambles.
And all forsooth.
Deifying the name of Rosalind.
If I could meet that fancy-monger
I would give him some good counsel.
For he seems to have the
quotidian of love upon him.
I am he that is so love-shaked.
I pray you tell me your remedy.
There is none of my
uncle's marks upon you.
He taught me how to know a man in love.
What were his marks?
A lean cheek, which you have not.
A blue eye.
And sunken. Which you have not.
A beard neglected. Which you have not.
Then your hose should be ungartered.
Your bonnet unbanded.
Your sleeve unbuttoned.
Your shoe untied.
And everything about you
demonstrating a careless desolation.
But you are no such man.
You are rather point-device
in your accouterments.
As loving yourself than seeming
the lover of any other.
I swear to thee, youth, by
the white hand of Rosalind.
I am that he.
That unfortunate he.
But are you so much in love
as your rhymes speak?
Neither rhyme nor reason
can express how much.
Love.
Is merely a madness.
Yet I profess curing it by counsel.
Did you ever cure any so?
- Yes.
One.
And in this manner.
He was to imagine me his love.
His mistress.
And I set him every day to woo me.
At which time, I.
Being but a moonish youth.
Would now like him, now loathe him.
Then entertain him, then forswear him.
Now weep for him. Now spit at him.
That I drave my suitor from
his mad humor of love.
Into a living humor of madness.
And thus I cured him.
And this way will I take upon me.
To wash your liver as clean
as a sound sheep's heart.
That there shall not be
one spot of love in 't.
I would not be cured, youth.
I would cure you.
If you would but call me Rosalind.
And come every day to my cote.
To woo me.
Now, by the faith of my love, I will.
Tell me where it is.
Go with me and I will show it you.
And by the way, you can tell me
where in the forest you live.
Will you go?
With all my heart, good youth.
Nay.
You must call me 'Rosalind'.
Rosalind.
Come, sister. Will you go?
And therefore take the present time.
With a hey, and a ho,
and a hey-nonny-no.
For love is crownèd with the prime.
In springtime, in springtime.
The only pretty ring time.
When birds do sing,
hey ding a ding, ding.
Hey ding a ding, ding.
Sweet lovers love the spring.
And how, Audrey? Am I the man yet?
Doth my simple feature content you?
Lord warrant us. What features?
Truly, I would the gods
had made thee poetical.
I do not know what 'poetical' is.
Is it honest in word and deed?
Nay, truly. For the truest
poetry is the most feigning.
Do you wish then, that
the gods had made me ..
Poetical?
I do, truly.
For thou swear'st to me thou art honest.
Now, if thou wert a poet ..
I might have some hope thou didst feign.
Would you not have me honest?
Nay, Truly.
Unless thou wert hard-favored.
Never talk to me. I will weep.
Do, I prithee.
But yet have the grace to consider
that tears do not become a man.
But have I not cause to weep?
As good a cause as one would desire.
Therefore weep.
His very hair.
Is of the dissembling color.
Even browner than Judas's.
Marry, his kisses are
Judas's own children.
His hair is of a good color.
An excellent color.
Your chestnut was ever the only color.
And his kissing is
as full of sanctity ..
As the touch of holy bread.
The very ice of chastity is in them.
But why, why did he swear he would
come this morning, and comes not?
Nay. Certainly, there's no truth in him.
Not true in love?
Yes, when he is in.
But I think he is not in.
You have heard him
swear downright he was.
'Was' is not 'is'.
Besides, the oath of a lover is no
stronger than the word of a tapster.
He attends here in the forest
on the Duke your father.
What shall he have that killed the deer?
His leather skin and horns to wear.
Take thou no scorn to wear the horn.
It was a crest ere thou wast born.
Thy father's father wore it.
And thy father bore it.
The horn, the horn, the lusty horn.
I met the Duke yesterday.
He asked me of what parentage I was.
I told him, of as good as he.
He laughed and let me go.
But what talk we of fathers ..
When there is such a man as Orlando?
Mistress and master.
If you will see a pageant truly played.
Between the pale
complexion of true love.
And the red glow of
scorn and proud disdain.
Go hence a little.
And I shall conduct you.
- O come.
Let us remove.
The sight of lovers
feedeth those in love.
Sweet Phoebe, do not scorn me.
Do not, Phoebe.
Say that you love me not,
but say not so In bitterness.
I fly thee, for I would not injure thee.
Thou tell'st me there
is murder in mine eye.
'Tis pretty, sure, and very probable.
And if mine eyes can wound,
now let them kill thee.
Now counterfeit to swoon.
Why, now fall down.
Or if thou canst not.
O, for shame, for shame.
Lie not, to say mine eyes are murderers.
O dear Phoebe. If ever ..
As that ever may be near.
You meet in some fresh
cheek the power of fancy.
Then shall you know the wounds
invisible that love's keen arrows make.
But till that time,
come not thou near me.
And when that time comes,
afflict me with thy mocks.
Pity me not.
Until that time I shall not pity thee.
And why, I pray you?
Who might be your mother.
That you insult, exult.
And all at once over the wretched?
What, though you have no beauty.
Must you therefore be
proud and pitiless?
Why.
What means this?
Why do you look on me?
'Od's my little life.
I think she means to
tangle my eyes, too.
No faith, proud mistress.
Hope not after it.
'Tis not your inky brows,
your black silk hair.
Your bugle eyeballs,
nor your cheek of cream.
That can entame my spirits.
To your worship.
You foolish shepherd.
Wherefore do you follow her, like foggy
south puffing with wind and rain?
You are a thousand times a
properer man than she a woman.
'Tis not her glass but
you that flatters her.
But mistress, know yourself.
Down on your knees.
Thank heaven, fasting.
For a good man's love.
For I must tell you
friendly in your ear.
Sell when you can.
You are not for all markets.
So take her to thee, shepherd.
Fare you well.
Sweet youth, I pray you
chide a year together.
I had rather hear you
chide than this man woo.
I pray you do not fall in love with me.
For I am falser than vows made in wine.
Besides.
I like you not.
Come, sister. Let us go.
Good day and happiness, dear Rosalind.
Why, how now, Orlando.
Where have you been all this while?
You a lover?
An you serve me such another trick,
never come in my sight anymore.
My fair Rosalind, I come
within an hour of my promise.
Break an hour's promise in love?
He that will divide a minute
into a thousand parts.
And break but a part of a thousandth
part of a minute in the affairs of love.
It may be said of him that Cupid
hath clapped him o' th' shoulder.
But I'll warrant him heart-whole.
Pardon me, dear Rosalind.
Nay.
An you be so tardy,
come no more in my sight.
I had as lief be wooed of a snail.
Of a snail?
Ay, of a snail.
For though he comes slowly,
he carries his house on his head.
A better jointure, I think,
than you make a woman.
Besides, he brings his destiny with him.
What's that?
Horns.
Virtue is no hornmaker.
And my Rosalind is virtuous.
And I am your Rosalind.
Come, woo me.
Woo me.
For now I am in a holiday humor
and like enough to consent.
What would you say to me now?
An I were your very, very Rosalind?
I would kiss before I spoke.
Nay.
You were better speak first.
Very good orators, when
they are out, they will spit.
And for lovers lacking matter.
The cleanliest shift is to kiss.
Who could be out, being
before his beloved mistress?
Marry, that should you
if I were your mistress.
Am not I your Rosalind?
I take some joy to say you are
because I would be talking of her.
Well .. and in her person.
I say.
I will not have you.
Then, in mine own person I die.
No, faith.
Die by attorney.
The poor world.
It is almost six thousand years old.
And in all this time there was not
any man died in his own person.
In a love cause.
Men have died from time to time.
And worms have eaten
them from time to time.
But not for love.
I would not have my right
Rosalind of this mind.
For I protest her frown might kill me.
By this hand.
It will not kill a fly.
But come.
Now I will be your Rosalind in
a more coming-on disposition.
And ask me what you will.
I will grant it.
- Then love me, Rosalind.
Yes, faith.
Will I.
Fridays, Saturdays, and all days.
And wilt thou have me?
- Ay.
And twenty such.
- What sayest thou?
Are you not good?
I hope so.
Why then, can one desire
too much of a good thing?
Sister. Sister.
You shall be the priest and marry us.
Give me your hand, Orlando.
What do you say, sister?
- Pray thee marry us.
I cannot say the words.
You must begin.
'Will you, Orlando ..'
'Have to wife this Rosalind'?
Go to.
Will you, Orlando, have
to wife this Rosalind?
I will.
- Ay, but when?
Why now, as fast as she can marry us.
Then you must say:
'I take thee, Rosalind, for wife'.
I take thee Rosalind, for wife.
I do take thee, Orlando.
For my husband.
Now tell me, Orlando.
How long would you have her
after you have possessed her?
Forever and a day.
Say 'a day' without the 'ever'.
O no, Orlando.
Men are April when they woo.
And December when they wed.
Maids are May when they are maids.
But the sky changes when they are wives.
But will my Rosalind do so?
By my life, she will do as I do.
O, but she is wise.
She is wise.
But the wiser, the waywarder.
For these two hours, Rosalind,
I will leave thee.
Alas, dear love.
I cannot lack thee two hours.
I must attend the Duke at dinner.
By two o'clock I'll be with thee again.
Ay.
Go your ways. Go your ways.
I knew what you would prove.
My friends told me as much.
And I thought no less.
That flattering tongue of yours won me.
'Tis but one more cast away.
And so come, death.
Two o'clock is your hour?
By my troth, and in good earnest.
And so God mend me, and by all
pretty oaths that are not dangerous.
If you break but one jot of your promise
or come one minute behind your hour.
I will think you the most pathetical
break-promise and the most hollow lover.
And the most unworthy of
her you call Rosalind.
Therefore, beware and keep your promise.
With no less religion than if
thou wert indeed my Rosalind.
So, adieu.
- Adieu.
Adieu.
At two.
Two o'clock.
At two o'clock.
At two. At two.
Two o'clock.
At two o'clock. At two o'clock.
You have simply misused
our sex in your love-prate.
O coz, coz, coz.
My pretty little coz.
That thou didst know.
How many fathoms deep I am in love.
O but it cannot be sounded.
My affection hath an unknown bottom.
Like the Bay of Portugal.
I'll tell thee, Aliena.
I cannot be out of the sight of Orlando.
So I'll go.
Find a shadow.
And sigh till he come.
And I'll sleep.
Tell me where is fancy bred.
Or in the heart or in the head.
How begot, how nourishèd?
Reply, reply.
It is engender'd in the eyes
with gazing fed and Fancy dies.
In the cradle where it lies.
Let us all ring Fancy's knell:
I'll begin it, ding-dong bell.
Ding-dong, ding-dong bell.
What say you now?
Is it not past two o'clock?
And here much Orlando.
I warrant you.
With pure love and troubled brain
he hath ta'en his bow and arrows.
And has gone forth to sleep.
Good morrow, fair ones.
Are you not the owners of this house?
It is no boast, being
asked to say we are.
Orlando doth commend him to you both.
And to that youth he calls his Rosalind.
He sends this blood-stained napkin.
Are you he?
I am.
What must we understand by this?
Some of my shame.
If you will know of me what man I am.
And how and why and where
this handkercher was stained.
I pray you tell it.
When last the young
Orlando parted from you.
He left a promise to return
again within the hour.
And pacing through the forest.
Lo, what befell.
Under an oak.
A wretched, ragged man
lay sleeping on his back.
About his neck a green and gilded
snake had wreathed itself.
Suddenly, seeing Orlando, it unlinked
itself and slipped away into a bush.
Under which bush's shade,
a lioness lay couching.
Head on ground, with catlike watch.
When that the sleeping man should stir.
This seen.
Orlando did approach the man.
And found it was his brother.
His elder brother.
O, I have heard him speak
of that same brother.
And he did render him the most
unnatural that lived amongst men.
And well he might so do.
For well I know, he was unnatural.
But for Orlando?
Did he leave him there?
Twice did he turn his
back and purposed so.
But kindness, nobler ever than revenge.
Made him give battle to the lioness.
Which quickly fell before him.
In which hurtling, from
miserable slumber I awaked.
Are you his brother?
- Was 't you he rescued?
Was 't you that did so
oft contrive to kill him?
'Twas I.
But 'tis not I.
I do not shame to tell you what I was.
Since my conversion so sweetly
tastes being the thing I am.
But for this bloody napkin?
Bye and bye.
When from the first to
last betwixt us two.
Tears our recountments
had most kindly bathed.
As how I came into that desert place.
In brief, he led me to the gentle duke.
Who gave me fresh array
and entertainment.
Committing me unto my brother's love.
Who led me instantly unto his cave.
There stripped himself.
And here upon his arm.
The lioness had torn some flesh away.
Which all this while had bled.
And now he fainted.
And cried in fainting upon Rosalind.
Why, how now, Ganymede.
Sweet Ganymede.
Many will swoon when
they do look on blood.
There is more in it. Cousin.
Ganymede.
Look, he recovers.
I would I were at home.
We'll lead you thither.
I pray you, will you
take him by the arm?
Be of good cheer, youth.
You a man?
You lack a man's heart.
I do so.
I confess it.
I pray you, sir.
Tell your brother how
well I counterfeited.
This is not counterfeit.
There is too great testimony in your
complexion. It was a passion of earnest.
Counterfeit, I assure you.
Well then, take a good heart.
And counterfeit to be a man.
So I will. I do.
But, i' faith, I should have
been a woman by right.
Come you. You look paler and paler.
Pray you draw homewards.
Good sir, go with us.
That will I.
Counterfeit.
I assure you.
Audrey.
There is a youth in the forest
here lays claim to you.
Ay, I know who 'tis.
He hath no interest in me in the world.
Here comes the man you mean.
Aha.
It is meat and drink to
me to meet a clown.
We shall be flouting.
We cannot hold.
Good ev'n, Audrey.
God gi' good ev'n, William.
And good ev'n to you, sir.
- Good ev'n, gentle friend.
Cover thy head, cover thy head.
Nay, prithee. Be covered.
How old are you, friend?
Five-and-twenty, sir.
A ripe age.
Is thy name William?
William, sir.
A fair name.
Wast born i' th' forest here?
Ay, sir, I thank God.
'Thank God'. A good answer.
Art thou wise?
Ay, sir, I have a pretty wit.
Why, thou sayst well.
I do now remember a saying:
'The fool doth think he is wise'.
'But the wise man knows
himself to be a fool'.
You do love this maid?
I do, sir.
Give me your hand.
Art thou learned?
No, sir.
- Then learn this of me.
To have is to have.
For it is a figure in rhetoric.
That drink, being poured
out of a cup into a glass.
By filling the one,
doth empty the other.
And all your writers do
consent that ipse is 'he'.
Now, you are not he for I am he.
Which he, sir?
He, sir, that must marry this woman.
Therefore, you clown.
Abandon the society of this female.
Or, clown, thou perishest.
Or, to thy better understanding.
Diest.
Or, to wit, I kill thee.
Make thee away.
Translate thy life into death.
I will kill thee a
hundred and fifty ways.
Therefore, tremble and depart.
Do, good William.
God rest you merry, sir.
Is 't possible that on so
little acquaintance ..
That, but seeing Aliena,
you should love her?
And loving, woo?
And wooing, she should grant?
Neither call in question my sudden
wooing, nor her sudden consenting.
But say with me: 'I love fair Aliena'.
Tell me where is fancy bred.
Or in the heart or in the head.
How begot, how nourishèd?
Let your wedding be tomorrow.
Thither will I invite the Duke
and all his contented followers.
Go you and prepare Aliena.
God save you, brother.
- And you, fair sister.
O my dear Orlando, how it grieves me.
To see thee wear thy heart in a scarf.
It is my arm.
I thought thy heart had been
wounded by the claws of a lion.
Wounded it is.
But with the eyes of a lady.
Did your brother tell you how
I counterfeited to swoon ..
When he showed me your handkercher?
Ay, and greater wonders than that.
- O, I know where you are.
Nay, 'tis true.
There was never anything so sudden.
For your brother and my sister.
They are in the very wrath of love,
and they will together.
Clubs cannot part them.
They shall be married tomorrow.
And I will bid the Duke to the nuptial.
O, how bitter a thing it is to look into
happiness through another man's eyes.
By so much the more shall I tomorrow
be at the height of heart-heaviness.
By how much I shall think my brother
happy in having what he wishes for.
Why, then.
Tomorrow I cannot serve
your turn for Rosalind?
I can live no longer by thinking.
I will weary you then no longer.
With idle talking.
Know of me then.
That I can do strange things.
I have.
Since I was three years old.
Conversed .. with a magician.
And if you do love Rosalind so near
the heart as your gesture cries it out.
You shall marry her.
When your brother marries Aliena.
It is not impossible for me.
To set her before your eyes tomorrow.
Human as she is.
And without any danger.
Speak'st thou in sober meanings?
I do.
By my life.
Which I tender dearly.
Though I say I am a magician.
Therefore, put you on your best array.
Bid your best friends.
For if you will be married
tomorrow, you shall.
And to Rosalind.
If you will.
Youth, you have done
me much ungentleness.
I care not if I have.
It is my study to seem despiteful
and ungentle to you.
You are there followed
by a faithful shepherd.
Look upon him.
Love him. He worships you.
Good shepherd, tell this
youth what 'tis to love.
It is to be all made of sighs and tears.
And so am I for Phoebe.
And I for Ganymede.
And I for Rosalind.
And I for no woman.
It is to be all made
of faith and service.
And so am I for Phoebe.
And I for Ganymede.
And I for Rosalind.
And I for no woman.
It is to be all made of fantasy.
All made of passion and
all made of wishes.
All adoration, duty, and observance.
All humbleness, all patience.
And impatience.
All purity, all trial and all obedience.
And so am I for Phoebe.
And so am I for Ganymede.
And so am I for Rosalind.
And so am I.
For no woman.
Pray you, no more of this.
'Tis like the howling of Irish
wolves against the moon.
I will help you if I can.
I would love you if I could.
Tomorrow. Meet me all together.
I will marry you.
If ever I marry woman.
And I'll be married tomorrow.
I will satisfy you.
If ever I satisfy man.
And you shall be married tomorrow.
I will content you.
If what pleases you contents you.
And you shall be married tomorrow.
As you love Rosalind, meet.
As you love Phoebe, meet.
And as I love no woman.
I'll meet.
So fare you well.
I have left you commands.
I'll not fail, if I live.
Nor I.
Good duke, receive thy daughter.
Hymen from heaven brought her.
I brought her hither.
That thou mightst join.
Her hand and his.
Whose heart within his bosom is.
If there be truth in sight,
you are my daughter.
If there be truth in sight.
You are my Rosalind.
If sight and shape be true.
Why then, my love adieu.
I'll have no father.
If you be not he.
I'll have no husband.
Nor ne'er wed woman, if you be not she.
O my dear niece.
Welcome thou art to me.
Even daughter,
welcome in no less degree.
I will not eat my word.
Now thou art mine.
Thy faith, my fancy to
thee doth combine.
Let me have audience for a word or two.
Duke Frederick, hearing how every day
men of worth resorted to this forest.
Addressed a mighty power, which
were on foot In his own conduct.
Purposely to take his brother
here and put him to the sword.
And to the skirts of
this wild wood he came.
Where, meeting with an old religious
man, after some question with him.
Was converted both from his
enterprise and from the world.
His crown bequeathing
to his banished brother.
And all their lands restored to them
again that were with him exiled.
Welcome, young man.
Thou offer'st fairly to
my daughters' wedding.
Meantime, forget this
new-fall'n dignity.
And fall into our rustic revelry.
Proceed.
We will begin these rites.
As we do trust they'll end.
In true delights.
If it be true.
That good wine needs no bush.
'Tis true that a good play
needs no epilogue.
Yet to good wine they
do use good bushes.
And good plays prove the better.
By the help of good epilogues.
What a case am I in then.
That am neither a good epilogue.
Nor cannot insinuate with you.
In the behalf of a good play.
I am not furnished like a beggar.
Therefore to beg.
Will not become me.
My way is to conjure you.
And I'll begin.
With the women.
I charge you.
O women.
For the love you bear to men.
To like as much of this play.
As please you.
And I charge you.
O men.
For the love you bear to women.
That between you and the women.
The play may please.
..w-g..