I love Japanese.
They're all kind.
I love Japanese girls. Guys, too.
I love long-hair girls.
And I love petite ones, too.
I hate work, but I love money,
pleasure and disco.
I hate Japanese men,
because they're lewd.
The most interesting
places in Japan...
are Disneyland and Bay Bridge.
I love Japan, but Japanese
have cold heart.
Japanese are actually kind.
I bought a prostitute
in Japan one time.
I was supposed to pay 20.000 yen.
But she came to hotel, and looked at
me. Then, I must pay 25.000 yen.
Because I'm Asian, or maybe
because my skin is more dark.
I very angry after that time.
But important thing is...
I paid the moneys
she demanded me.
Some customers say we
Filipinos are mean and stupid.
Is sad. I think such customers
are base beings.
Because I'm not American, a girl
broke off a relationship with me.
We were pen-pals.
I requested a meeting and we met.
Won't see me again
because I'm Bangladeshi.
Even so, I love Japan.
Because it's so convenient
and great to live in.
But the people are...
Tokio... Tokio...
I am... here.
I want that.
Yes, ma'am.
You're a wise shopper.
- 1.000 yen.
- All right.
Here you have.
Tokio!
Did you quit the pachinko
parlor?
I did. Too noisy.
- Buy some.
- I don't want them.
Taiwanese bananas
are good.
- Give me one.
- Just one?
One bunch!
They're delicious!
Okay, you win.
Give me two.
Yes, sir.
700 yen.
Thank you!
How are you doing?
I'll give you one.
Don't go stealing.
Boss!
Wow...
Boss, what is this?
Shit.
How can we eat all this?
Tokio, I told them to send women.
Why do I get bananas?
Maybe they didn't
understand your English.
That bastard Tony!
Those primitive Filipinos are hopeless
Come on, eat some!
I bought these.
We aren't getting anywhere.
I can't eat anymore.
This is terrific.
Can't stand the banana smell!
Open the window.
What window?
Toa Detective Agency and
Far East Model Club.
Oh, that?
Yes, yes!
Can't you make the
conditions better?
There're illegal workers everywhere.
On the record, they're trainees.
That'll be fine. We'll deliver
5 Bangladeshi next week.
About their meals, no pork, okay?
Yes, it's a religious thing.
Huh? Well, tell them it's beef.
They won't know the difference.
Yes, yes, see you then.
5 Bangladeshi for a cast
factory in Kawaguchi.
Yes, sir.
We're only contributing to
Japan's internationalization...
But they try to bind
us with stupid laws.
We're doing a favor,
but they say it's illegal.
I hate this damn
oppressive country.
It's suffocating. Don't take me wrong.
I hate Asia, too.
They're all cheapskates.
Hey, what're you doing?
Bananas have the same
substance as LSD.
Working?
Not yet?
Yeah... it is.
A bit.
Is it working for you?
What're all these bananas?
Honey!
I'm so glad to see you.
You told me to come.
What're all these bananas?
Did you keep my promise?
Yes, I dyed the hair down there.
It's sore.
Honey, I'll be right with you.
What're all these bananas?
Let's go, let's go!
Come with me.
Tokio, you poor thing.
I hear you can't get it up recently.
What?
Cecile at Bacchus told me.
That bitch!
What a pity.
You're still young.
I've got some pills that really work.
You'll have a hard-on all the time.
No thanks!
Unlike you, I function no matter
what color the chick's hair is.
Is that so?
Well, see you.
Trash the bananas.
What? All of them?
It's the wrong day for the garbage.
Can't you read?
You're trouble.
Loud-mouth bitch.
Fuck you.
What did you say?
I'll call the police.
Why the police?!
You're uptight.
What else do you have here?
Just bananas!
I wonder. I'll have the
police take a look.
Go ahead!
May I have some bananas?
Can I have some?
Sure, take all you like.
Thank you very much!
They're not good to eat.
- I make wine.
- Wine?
Yes, banana wine.
- Shall I carry some?
- Don't worry. My friends come later.
I take all.
I'm Tokio.
What's your name?
Banana.
This is the report for last week.
Tokyo East: 5 Pakistanis, 3 Filipinos
and 5 Red Chinese.
Tokyo South: 5 Filipinos, 2 Malays
and 3 Thais.
Tokyo North: 4 Bangladeshi,
2 Taiwanese and 6 Koreans.
Total: 32. We have asked them
to return to their homelands.
I am impressed by everyone's
remarkable efforts.
I repeat. It is best for the Asians
to live in their own countries.
We must have them leave
as soon as possible...
before they are reduced
to misery in Japan.
Well, our activities have just begun,
and we're a very small group.
The road we are paving...
will protect our beautiful homeland,
Japan, so that we may live...
in harmony with Asia,
where their homelands are.
I believe and look forward
to your endeavors...
to bring forth further results
to pave the correct road.
Now, all together.
The yonder mountains
where I hunted rabbits
The yonder river where I fished
Such images appear...
in my dreams
Images of my unforgettable home
Are you Tokio?
My name is Wang.
Yang's my friend.
You know Yang, the Chinaman?
He live same apartment you live.
Oh, that Yang.
I have no job.
Help me.
I speak little Japanese.
I need job.
Anything?
Yes, anything.
I start now.
Let's see...
Okay, okay!
I take it.
It's easy work.
Left-overs in here
and wash the dishes.
He's all yours.
Put on the white overalls.
Tell him to wear clean ones everyday.
They are over there.
Foreigners aren't
sanitary conscious.
They must have different
standards.
See you, then.
I no can do this job.
You said anything was okay.
I'm a pianist.
This is bad for my hands!
You said you'd do anything.
I'm a pianist!
Don't be so fussy.
You're impossible. All the jobs in
Japan are bad for your hands.
But I'm a pianist.
Get me a better job.
Damn you.
Say hi to Yang for me!
- Hey, Tokio.
- Huh?
Yang lost in mahjong game.
He said he'll run away.
What? He owes me money!
Tokio, I need a job.
Anything okay!
Where's Yang?
He owes me 4 months rent.
That bastard!
You haven't paid this
month, either.
He owes me, too.
A bunch of gangsters came...
and took everything of value.
He imported a lot of fake
Chinese medicine.
Maybe we can sell that.
Nothing but trash left.
Didn't clean, didn't pay rent.
Chinese are the worst kind.
Hey, wait!
I'll take these as rent.
- He owes me, too!
- Wait, thief!
You Japanese...
pick on us Koreans!
What's this?
Don't you have any decency?
Hey, keep it down.
"In my bed, I caress..."
"the flower in bud."
"The warm of my hand..."
"will melt the snowy white skin."
Kabuki player Kikugoro said...
women should have cold hands.
I agree. I hate women
with clammy hands.
Really? I don't get turned on to
women with low body temperature.
You're sensitive to cold.
Ever made love to a dead woman?
No thanks. I have no trouble
getting live women.
Was certainly cold that time.
Her uterus was cold, too.
You've got some perverted tastes.
Women should be nice and warm.
You're right.
Dead women are so stiff.
"Mature women hate
to let us out."
It's getting lewd here...
attaboy!
Ever heard of banana wine?
I was down south during the war,
but I've never heard of it.
It's Filipino.
You know more about the Philippines.
He was in Sumatra.
We lived on bananas, but...
How's this?
- And this?
- All right!
Or this?
Now, what about this, then?
That's it!
Sorry, Tokio.
It's not bad.
Only 5.000 yen.
It's your unlucky day, Tokio.
I've had no luck recently.
At least, you still have an erection.
True! He's still young.
He can get lucky again.
It's the talk of town that
a rightist group...
is hunting down foreigners.
Those kids have no war experience.
What's got into them?
I was sent to China
when I was young.
That changed my life.
He became a pervert
because of the war.
I was a military policeman.
We'll end up in hell.
There's no way out.
Tokio, make sure you don't make
the same mistakes we did.
I'm not so sure.
That's it.
Sorry, Tokio.
Isn't she gorgeous?
Just like Madonna.
Miss Candy.
She'll make money.
A genuine blond singer.
And her singing's great.
Smashing.
You're right.
A real good-looking broad.
- Isn't that right?
- She's my type of broad.
- I knew you'd say that.
- It's decided, then. Get her next week.
- Is that so?
- Yeah.
Here's the down payment.
Oh, thanks!
You have pretty good taste.
Do you think so?
Broads like this are welcome.
You're right.
Hope to do business with you again.
Thank you! Thank you!
Tokio, I did it!
Blonds turn them on!
Boss, there seems to be...
a rightist group after the Asians.
Really? Asia is not in vogue now.
Blonds will rule the world.
I'll go buy some cigarettes.
What happened?
Tokio, tell your boss that
I'll never do that again.
It's swollen down there from dying
the hair. I can't work like this.
What are you doing?!
You pervert!
Oh, hi, Banana.
Tokio, you lousy pachinko player.
Shut up!
Hold your tongue, woman.
- You don't know.
- I'll teach you.
You play like this.
That's dangerous!
You've got guts.
Where did you get the keys?
I found them.
Tokio, banana wine is ready.
Come drink it.
Can you really make
wine from bananas?
It's good.
My God!
Wait.
Oh, Banana, are you from Luzon?
Mindanao.
Mindanao, huh? I don't recall
banana wine in Mindanao.
My invention. It's delicious.
It looks terrible.
Noisy here. I know good place.
Let's drink there.
Terrific. Wow.
Banana Special.
This will give you power.
You'll get a hard-on.
What do you do for a living?
- Pachinko?
- Of course not!
I worked in a karaoke joint.
In Tokyo?
No, in Toyama.
I ran away because promotor was bad.
He won't pay. Beat me.
It was cold.
Customers were lewd.
What're you doing now?
All kinds.
Pachinko, slot machine, mahjong...
horse races, poker...
A woman gambler, huh?
Do you always cheat?
Japanese are poor gamblers.
I'm good gambler.
I always win.
Cheating is thrilling.
I love the thrill!
Be serious.
You'd better watch out.
Some goons are hunting
down Asians recently.
Goons?
I don't understand.
Why? Japanese are rich.
Why pick on us?
Filipinas are tough.
Nonsense.
Do you know what Japan did and
is now doing in my homeland?
I know about it.
I really do.
Where did you learn Tagalog?
In the Philippines long ago. I was
in Mindanao, and Davao, too.
Davao is not Mindanao.
I was born in Cagayan de Oro.
In the north, huh?
It's all right.
What's going on?
Teresa's old trick.
Thank you!
Be brave, okay?
I will.
Thanks...
Banana!
Teresa, banana wine.
Booze.
You never give up, Teresa.
Badger Japanese men.
Barn lots of money.
Teresa send money for
her baby in Bankok.
How much?
500.000 yen a month.
Wow!
No kidding?
My family very poor.
Big family, many relatives.
- And many lovers.
- Banana!
Hey, I'm Tokio.
I'm poor. This is true.
No family, no relatives.
No girlfriend either.
Poor Tokio.
Broke up with girlfriend?
My girlfriend...
Tokio, cheer up.
You'll meet her.
If Teresa gives me a free
ride, I'll cheer up.
- Dirty old man!
- Ouch, that hurts!
What do you want?
We are the Asian Homeland Society.
So what?
I'm a busy man. Fuck off.
They're all on tourist visa.
You shouldn't be doing this.
Aren't you Japanese?!
You pollute Japanese blood...
with your two-bit business.
What's it to you?
Asshole!
What you are doing is blasphemy.
Pure blasphemy!
Sucking blood from Asia...
and cause Japan to rot.
I really despise you.
- Disgusting...
- Hey.
- You...
- Hey!
Do you know why
Japan is beautiful?
Why it was able to be
developed this much?
Why Japan is called the leader of Asia?
It's all because we're a
homogeneous nation.
If the dirty Asian blood mixes...
Japan's beauty and her
superiority will deteriorate.
Listen, we Japanese are
the chosen people.
Haven't you bastards
studied history?
Homogeneous? You believe this shit?
That's a big fat lie!
Faggot.
Why should I allow a traitor
scum like you disgrace me?
Your ideas are dangerous.
We should talk someday.
Big talk now, but you'll
soon beg for mercy.
What shall we do?
Punish him and then dump him.
It's cold. Fuck you!
Those guys are bad news.
I'm sure that's Ohtsuki.
You know him?
He was with the Cleanse Japan
Youth Legion Homogeneous Congress.
He's like a mad dog.
That famous?
I had trouble with him long ago.
Trouble?
Before I began this business...
I took part in an ecology movement.
You're really a joke.
Shut up.
What's wrong with
Love and Peace?
Anyway, when we held a meeting...
he wrecked the meeting
all by himself.
That was the end of
our movement.
He's insane.
Keep away from him.
He must be after your
Asian friends, too.
Hello!
Excuse me.
Excuse me!
It's amazing how so many
were able to live there.
I live here, but I had no idea.
I knew dark faces
were increasing...
but I never thought
they were here.
You're a strange boy.
Playing with us old folks.
Here he goes again.
I don't have friends. I specialize
in foreigners and old folks.
This parlor is closing
down next week.
Is that true?
Land re-development.
Tokyo has completely changed.
There's no place for us anymore.
I see.
So, it's closing down...
Old soldiers only fade away.
Tokio, your future will be rough.
Pretty soon, Japan will
be completely different.
More foreigners.
Whether they're foreigners or not,
skinship will solve it.
And if you get close,
quarrels begin.
Quarrel, make up and quarrel again.
And someday, we'll all grow up.
That's it!
Sorry, Tokio.
Are you sure it's today?
She wasn't there...
This is her.
Your blond broad... Candy?
Can she sing?
I had her sing...
And?
I'm going to Manila to kill
that son-of-a-bitch Tony.
A Madonna look-alike, huh?
Her singing makes me puke.
I don't believe this.
What should I do?
I remembered!
I've got to some urgent business.
- Don't leave me here.
- My half-brother's dying.
Damn it, Tokio.
You're dead, too.
You made a big mistake, Sumio.
I'm disappointed in you.
You let the woman get away.
I'm deeply sorry!
We have a guest.
Mr. Gonzalez, this is Morita.
What we're looking for
was not in that hide-out.
The woman took it.
Mr. Gonzalez, take Morita with you.
He's at your service.
Chairman, I don't understand.
He's a savage!
Sumio, no racial discrimination.
It's for Japan.
Your enemy's enemy
is your friend.
This is how politics work.
What did the woman run off with?
If you find out...
Big deal.
Hey, why don't we split?
I'm told we work together.
What?
I'm a rightist, damn it!
It's my job to kick out Asians.
Why do I have to work
with a Filipino scum?
Searching for a Filipino woman?
So typical.
You betray your own people.
If someone does a good job,
you tell the police it's a murder.
Thwarting each other.
Have no mind to be
happy together.
Why do I have to stick my
nose in your trouble?
You're wrong.
This is not for Philippines.
It's for Japan.
I can't trust you.
Because you're not Japanese!
- Make your boss angry?
- I'll get the woman, anyway.
I live for my country.
Not for pride!
I'll go this way, you go that way.
Don't you dare follow me.
The Homeland Society, huh?
You deported my woman
back to Korea.
Next time, we'll kill you for sure.
You all right?
- Banana!
- Sorry...
You all right?
Yes?
What? I paid the rent.
It's not about that, Mr. Atori.
What did you do with the junk
you took from Yang's room?
Oh, it's there.
- Take it all.
- Oh, no, it's not here!
Wasn't there anything
like an arm?
That was eerie.
I put it in the garbage.
The rats are eating it by now.
- What's wrong?
- All my hopes are gone...
I'll be killed.
What's going on?
I'm a little diabetic.
And I can't get it up.
My wife beats me every night.
My mistress kicks me.
She's a martial arts champion.
The way things are,
my life is at peril!
Hold on, what's that arm
got to do with it?
Yang's friends are
looking for that.
Yang won that at some
gambling scam.
He didn't know what it was.
I do, did homework.
That is the ultimate Chinese medicine,
made with 3.000 years of wisdom!
That is the world's
greatest aphrodisiac.
They say even a dying elephant
will have an erection with that.
That... was the legendary medicine.
I threw it out...
Goodbye.
No erection, better dead.
Are you okay?
Wait here.
Found it!
You'd better stay out
of Tokyo for a while.
Those bastards are insane.
Really persistent.
I stay in Tokyo.
Still want to make money?
Guess Filipino economy survives
on money you guys make abroad.
This your girlfriend?
We were separated when
my dad was murdered.
- Murdered?
- By terrorists.
The guerrillas in Mindanao.
- Why?
- Probably because he was Japanese.
Tokio, you hate Filipinos?
Banana, you hate the Japanese,
but you earn money here.
It's a big lie that Asia is one.
Even the same race hate
and kill each other.
When interests conflict,
anyone can be your enemy.
I'm not strong enough
to hate all Filipinos.
Not that serious.
But the N.P.A. guerrillas killed my father.
I'll kill them someday with my own hands.
I'm Japanese...
But I am myself.
I'm not interested in what
people do or their nationality.
I'll hate and love people
with my own rules.
That's not realistic.
Then, something's wrong!
Tokio, you impotent?
Hey...
Don't be ridiculous!
- Poor thing.
- Shut up!
Get out when you're well!
Hey, Jap, don't under-estimate
a Filipina.
"The Constitution of Japan,
Article 13."
"Respect for Individuals
and Public Welfare."
"All citizens shall be respected
as individuals and..."
I got my finger bitten by a dog...
when I was a kid.
I'm stronger than that dog now.
I get intimidated by dogs.
"The Constitution of Japon,
Article 22"
"Emigration and Freedom to
Renounce One's Nationality."
Even small, they're dogs.
Still my weak point.
Hey, what the hell is this?
That's not what we agreed on.
- You deceived me!
- It was a mistake.
Foreign bitch, out of the way!
What the hell?!
- Damn it...
- Candy, don't!
Excuse me...
This is your down payment.
Please.
Let's call it a day.
So, Madonna's a wrestler, huh?
What are you saying,
you white hippo?!
Mafia boss?
Boss...
You're having a fine time.
Where the hell were you?
Toa Detective Agency,
and Far East Model Club.
Tokio?
You're speaking to him.
Hi, long time, no see.
What do you want?
Let's meet.
No thanks.
You're bad news.
That's a compliment.
It's about Banana, the girl
you're keeping in your apartment.
She's in danger.
We'll talk about her.
Are you interested?
7:00 at the Golden Plaza.
Nice to see you.
You look well.
You became a fine young man.
Who's after Banana?
And why?
Don't rush.
Do you want a drink?
Brandy?
Cut out the crap.
Get to the point.
I'm busy.
All right.
Banana is an...
N.P.A. activist. She's a member of
New People's Army Sparrow Unit...
...which killed your father.
My God, you didn't know?
All right... go on.
Since last year...
Japanese companies in South-East Asia
have been attacked by terrorists.
She has an illustrious record.
She brought in some data, concerning
activities of Japanese companies.
They could be very
dangerous for Japan...
and trouble for me,
if made public.
You know the Asia Homeland
Society, don't you?
They're looking for the data by
orders of some powerful people.
You want me to hand
Banana over?
Yes, you can be rich.
I'm only interested in the data.
No thanks!
What's the rush?
I see.
Then, think about it.
My number's registered here.
Call me.
You still have bad taste.
None of your business.
Lay off!
Tokio!
You're really a pianist.
Tokio, what happened?
Nothing.
I play plano. I also have many
other work. Everything okay.
Girls, guns, drugs, passports...
Everything.
- Give you discount.
- Not today.
Wait.
Tokio, you be careful.
I good fortune-teller.
I see in your face, something
bad will happen.
Don't worry.
I know good magic spell.
Give you discount.
Some other time.
Tokio, you watch out.
Korean Barbecue
Hey!
Yes... yes, dear.
Welcome.
What's happening?
Change business.
I'm opening an English
conversation school with Candy.
Want to join us, Tokio?
No thanks.
You were great.
This month's salary.
Thank you.
Tokio, keep up your spirits.
Yeah.
You, too, boss.
Love and Peace forever, baby.
Right, some girl called you up.
Banana or papaya, or something.
- What did she say?
- "Come to the cemetery."
Have you seen my right arm?
Sorry, I'm in a hurry.
- Tokio!
- Banana!
Tokio, I have no time.
Keep this.
- I run away.
- Wait a moment, Banana.
- Are you really a guerrilla member?
- That's right.
The same group that killed
your father.
- I...
- No need.
I bellieve in you.
I'll keep the data.
No one will touch it.
I may not return them
to you, though
Okay.
But I didn't come as a terrorist.
Then, what for?
We have no money.
Terrorism is expensive.
I came to Japan to earn money.
Blow up Japanese companies
with money earned here?
- Bit embarrassing.
- So, that's what you did...
If this goes public,
no need for terrorism!
No one will print it.
- Why?!
- That's the real world.
I'm sorry for getting you involved.
Should be.
Sorry.
Watch out.
Don't worry.
I take care of myself.
You are the first
Japanese I slept with.
Romantic sequences are over.
Hand over the data.
You faggot!
- Banana, run!
- Hand them over.
Glad to see you again.
Traitor. You take money from Japanese
companies to betray your comrades.
Tell me all you know.
Mr. Gonzalez, take her back to
the Philippines and torture her!
Make her talk!
Banana!
Tokio, you know nothing...
Goodbye!
Banana!
Shit! She's dead...
Better to die than to be handed
over to the security police.
Let's see!
You're supposed to have
committed double suicide...
to resolve your dead-end
romance.
It's the most beautiful
way to die.
Be grateful! You two can
reincarnate as crickets.
Then, you can mate all you want,
all sing all night long.
Morita, you...
Banana... Banana!
I was a fisherman
in Nagasaki.
Poor Banana...
I've decided to raise
a family with her.
Tokio, Banana is...
No time for tears.
What made you decide on that?
A Japanese man cannot throw
away his ideals for a woman.
So, I've decided to become a Thai.
Sumio, you're renouncing
your homeland for a cunt?!
I'll go to Thailand to make
money on the Japanese.
I don't believe this. She has a baby.
Must earn a lot.
Hey, hurry up and go.
Quick, go!
Right? Hurry up and leave!
I'll get even.
In Johoku Cemetery in Tokyo...
a young woman, seemingly a
Filipina, was found murdered.
Her neck and abdomen were
stabbed by a knife.
She was found some 30
minutes after she died.
The police think this is
a crime of passion.
They are looking for Tokio Atori,
age 26, currently unemployed...
He is reported to be
the woman's lover.
Now for some bright news...
Let's walk with your head up...
so the tears won't...
roll down your cheeks.
Walking all alone in the night...
with tears in my eyes.
Tokio, you know nothing.
You're Tokio. Hand over the
data and I'll help you.
I'll give them to the press.
Go ahead.
But if you don't give
me the data...
you'll be killed no matter
where you go.
I won't play by your rules!
Hey, what are you doing?
That hurts!
Ouch, let me go!
I've received the data.
Thank you.
I'm sorry about Banana.
Damn you.
It's not fair to blame me.
What were you going
to do with the data?
Blow up Japanese companies
in her place.
She was a terrorist and you're not.
That's life.
You're a Japanese, after all.
Be a good Japanese.
Here's your reward.
I'll also guarantee your freedom.
Remember, Tokio Atori is
supposed to be dead.
He committed double suicide
with an Asian prostitute.
Banana's murder is
a crime of passion.
Killed Teresa!
Who?
From today, you're a
different person.
This is you.
It'll take 3 months for the bodies
to be found. Leave Tokyo.
The rest is up to you.
Why not work for me?
You bitch!
I am myself!
I live by my rules.
I'm sick of you and this country!
I'll keep in touch.
Tokio is dead.
Lay off!
Why, sir.
Tokio is dead!
This is an order of the state.
Forget Tokio!
Why?
Remember, Tokio is dead.
Why, sir?
What happened to Tokio?
He's dead sir.
Can you touch him?
No, sir...
Good, you seem to understand.
Sasaki, how did it go
with the horse races?
Big hit on Race 8, sir.
Thank you for your tip, sir!
What're you doing?
Get my luggage.
I go back tomorrow.
Gonzalez, why don't you
and I burn that kid?
Woman is dead.
The secret is safe.
My business finished.
That's why you people are
nothing but savages.
We Japanese will not forget shame.
Shame must be paid with life.
I'm going home.
This is your country.
You're free to kill
yourselves off.
Hey, it's me.
Tokio, what's matter?
You need something?
Must leave Japan.
Who?
Me. I have a reason.
I'm renouncing Japan.
Your head very funny.
Japan is paradise.
Money, merchandise, women...
you can get anything!
I need a counterfeit passport
and a way out.
- You serious?
- I have money.
Okay!
Go to Mack and...
you tell what nationality you want.
Tell him Wang send you.
It'll be okay.
This is introduction fee.
Hey, Mack, right?
Pakistani. You same apartment,
next room.
Tokio, why you want to leave?
It's a wonderful country.
It's crazy.
This is your homeland.
I found it!
Help!
Where's Tokio, huh?!
Maria...
Is that you, Maria?
Understand?
Money.
Filipino...
Taiwanese...
Malaysian...
Boat at Pier 7.
3 A.M.
Be punctual.
Thanks.
With these, I can settle
down somewhere.
Punk, you're mine.
You, I cannot pardon.
You're persistent!
Shut up!
Can't get you off my conscience.
I'll make you suffer good.
Then, I'll kill you.
What's this?
"Made-in-China" are so unrealiable!
Serves you right, faggot!
You two-bit punk!
Fruit cake, I'm leaving Japan.
No time to play with you.
So what?
Nothing else matters.
Except that I detest you.
Wherever you are, you're mine.
I detest you.
That's why I'll kill you.
I see.
I understand!
The feeling's... mutual.
Horny bastard!
Piss ass!
Cocktail weenie!
Banana scum!
Shit head!
Asian cunt!
Lunatic!
Imbecile!
Oh, shit!
Oh, my passports!
The passports...
Since you're on my boat...
you have the duty to take my orders.
If you complain, l'll throw
you in the ocean.
All is fate.
You are here, this is fate.
Passports...
Blind belief is no good.
But ignoring is worse.
Make friends with fate and live.
What're you saying?
Hey, this is too much.
Pop...
Pop, your telephone!
I said the phone's ringing!
Hello?
Tokio, I have a favor to ask you.
What are you anyway?
Don't be angry.
Since you're leaving Japan,
work for me.
I'm busy because there is
trouble all over Asia.
Listen.
I only play by my own rules!
Do you understand the
sad feeling of this song?
Okay.
This man's putting out to sea.
Sing for him.
Please sing a song for him.
On the clear waters of the river,
a boatman sings
Years long past, he sailed
away on a boat
Where has that boat gone?
Life is sad, but is also merry.
I miss you, dear
You, my dearest
When will we meet again?
TO BE CONTINUED...
Masatoshi NAGASE as Tokio
Haruko WANIBUCHI as Kusanagi
Mika OHINE as Maria
Ruby MORENO as Banana
Yukio YAMATO as Ohtsuki
Xiu JIAN as Wang
Shiro SANO as Sasaki
Botan NAKATA as the Gangster
Juro KARA as The Captain
Yukio HASHI as the Rightist Bigwig
General Producer:
Ko TESHIGAWARA
Executive Producers:
Kosuke KURI & Kaizo HAYASHI
Original Concept by:
Kaizo HAYASHI & Masashi YAMAMOTO
Cinematography by:
Hatsuhiko OKATA
Lighting by:
Yuki NAKAMURA
Sound Recording by:
Kazuharu URATA
Edited by:
Osamu TANAKA
Music by:
Meyna Co., Hidehiko URAYAMA
& Yoko KUMAGAI
Written and Directed by:
Daisuke TENGAN
English Subtitles by:
Jeanette Amano
Transcription and timing:
kagetsuhisoka