FILMEXPORT HOME VIDEO
Presents
A Film Based on the Original
Screenplay by Ludvik Askenazy
HOUSE AT THE TERMINUS
Made by the Barrandov Film Studios
Feix - Daniel Creative Group
HOUSE AT THE TERMINUS
In Lead Roles
Director of Photography
Music by
Film Symphony Orchestra Conducted by
Dance Music by Karel Krautgartner
and His Nonet
Architect
Film Editor
Sound
Make Up Artist
Produced by
Assistant Director/Director's Assistant
Associate Producer
Film Crew:
Camera Assistants
Architect's Assistant
Set Designer
Costumes by
Costume Designer
Make Up Assistant
Production Assistant
Chief Lighting Technician
Editor's Assistant
Sound Editor
Sound Effects
Directed by
ONE SPRING DAY...
We're at the terminal, gentlemen.
It is time to get off.
Hey, we're at the terminal, sir.
Where are we?
- At the end, old chap.
The terminal. You know what
a loop is, don't you?
Yeah... a loop.
Do you know why I came here?
- I certainly don't.
Get out of my way, you soak!
- Shut up, you fool!
Make sure you get to work on time,
slogger!
Good morning. I can wait.
- Good morning, I'll be right back.
Here it is. Goodbye.
- Thank you.
A glass of hot grog for me, boss!
Lay off!
- Come on, don't be so fussy.
Milk is healthy
but for kids, you see?
I've got a little girl, too.
You didn't know
I came here for a visit, did you?
Knock it off!
- Did you, sucker? You...
You know nothing at all
but I do!
You sure do.
- I know it all.
Morning.
- Good morning.
Why are you staring at me?!
Good morning, Mother.
- Good morning.
You're drunk again.
What do you want?
I came to see you.
And I came to see my little Hana.
- Is that so?
What do you want?
My life is miserable. You know?
I can't be alone.
- You can't be alone, eh?
You were never home
when your wife was still alive.
Let Hanka live with me, Mother.
I'm her father, aren't I?
- You've never deserved it.
A child needs care and order
and no man can provide that.
No man.
And you the least!
You think I'm bad, don't you?
Go now and get some sleep!
You've never liked me!
You... you..
Don't close the door!
You old hag!
Damned old hag!
Let me in!
My kid is in there!
Put the kettle on, Zuzana!
Wait. Don't go there.
Do you hear that?
He's always raising the roof.
Your son-in-law, huh?
I'd teach him a lesson,
if it wasn't for my heart...
I can see you! Do you hear me?!
His drinking drove my poor daughter
to the grave.
Not once did he visit her in hospital.
He said couldn't stand hospitals.
And now that scoundrel
wants my granddaughter.
Just look at her.
She's just like her mother.
I will never give her to him.
Never.
I'm going downstairs, Mrs. Mala.
Go away!
Go! Shoo!
Don't run. Come here.
Come on!
Be human a little, doggy.
Come here!
Stop barking!
Don't bark at me!
You're making quite a scene
again, Mr. Pesta.
Why?
- Isn't the bakery working today?
The bakery? It is...
It is working today.
- Then what are you doing here?
Well, you know...
the baker's baking buns,
nibbling some,
the bakeress is helping him...
Baloney! She isn't helping him!
Nobody's helping me either!
And as I have baked so I must eat.
How about getting some sleep instead?
With you, miss?
I'd...
If you allow me...
You're quite hot tempered, huh?
Hurry up, Mr. Pesta,
or you'll miss the tram.
You're right. Men are bastards.
Not me, though!
Not me! Understand?
Good morning.
Two sour and two poppy.
You've got courage, Miss Olga.
Mr. Brzobohaty here wanted
to run to your rescue.
You're exaggerating, Mrs. Volfova.
When I had noticed him on the tram,
I knew he'd cause trouble again.
It's all because of morals.
And, I beg your pardon, accumulation.
One more, Mrs. Volfova.
- Another one?
Yes, one more, please.
After a night shift,
Mr. Brzobohaty?
I'm always after a night shift.
You know how it goes...
Newspapers have to come out
every morning.
May I offer you today's paper?
You're most kind
but I wouldn't have time to read it.
Two bottles, please. For the last time.
- I beg your pardon.
So it is for the last time after all?
Have you heard, Mr. Brzobohaty,
that Miss Olga's sister got married?
To India, am I right?
- To Indonesia.
I've heard he's a big shot.
- Oh no, he's just a purchasing clerk.
But it makes no difference, does it?
I've never travelled further
than to Moravia.
And what about you, Miss Olga?
With men, you have to know the tricks,
don't you? It's pure science.
Like national defence education, eh?
They ought to teach it at school.
Goodbye.
- Goodbye, Miss Olga.
You won't finish your milk?
- It's too much for my stomach.
Thank you. -Goodbye.
- Goodbye. -Goodbye, Mr. Brzobohaty.
An old tree and young sap.
We'll sweep the pavement.
- And then?
Then we'll clean the stairs.
We'll hang the laundry in the attic.
- And then?
Then we will go shopping.
And then?
- We'll make lunch.
Then...
- What then?
Live well, Mrs. Mala, here's the key.
I won't forget it any more.
When are you coming back?
- Hana will be a big girl by then.
Hurry up.
- I'm coming!
Keep an eye on Olga for me, will you?
She knows nothing about life at all.
She's a sensible girl.
- That worries me even more.
Goodbye! Oh, my luggage!
- Good luck.
Goodbye!
- Hanicka!
Thanks.
- Good luck and don't forget to write!
And you take care of yourself. Bye!
Bye! And don't open the door to anyone!
Are you sad, Olga?
I don't know.
You're lucky you're still single.
- Olga!
I'll clean the stairs.
- Good girl.
You should've left it there for another
day. You wouldn't feel so lonely.
I don't like pretending.
What's gone is gone.
I have two names on my door for 4 years
and it isn't true either.
That's something different.
Isn't it strange?
We hardly know each other.
I wouldn't worry about that.
It must be because we are neighbours.
Goodbye.
- Goodbye.
Good morning. - Off to work?
- As usual.
The postman had a registered letter
for you the other day. - I know.
Any news?
- Not much.
And what about your husband?
Have you seen him?
There'll be a court hearing soon.
They didn't know much back then.
Your husband will come back.
I'm certain.
Write him to stop by.
That I have slivovitz from Moravia.
Let's hope they'll fix the lift by then.
Good day.
- Good morning.
Nothing doing. He won't stop by.
Go away! Hurry up!
- Let's go.
What did you want, Hanicka?
I'm on my way out.
He's ringing the door bell. - Who?
- Some man. - Where? - There.
Do you know if anyone's in?
I beg your pardon. I'm Karel Martinec,
master of pharmacy.
And... I'm supposed to live here
from today.
They're not answering the door,
are they? - I'm afraid so.
You'll have to wait. They must have gone
shopping and will come home soon.
But I only have an hour or so.
I need to go to work, you see?
You're a pretty girl.
Come here.
What's your name?
Is it your only child?
Oh no, I've got four more at home.
You're a worthy mother indeed!
- I beg your pardon?!
Oh no, I'm very fond of children.
I really am.
I should be going.
Do you know where I could...
Are these two trunks all you have?
- A lamp.
Give it to me. -Are you angry at me?
- Not at all. - Careful.
We'll put it in my flat. Hurry, though,
I'm late for school.
Wait for us!
Hurry up! Come on!
Infrequency increases word emotionality
as may be demonstrated quite easily.
In Czech, the voiceless
labiodental consonant "f"
may only be found in borrowings...
We're not doing it for the money,
my husband earns enough.
Our evenings are somewhat sad, though.
We've told each other everything
in the twenty years of our marriage.
Here's the bathroom.
You can wash as you please.
We live here.
And this is your room.
I didn't expect you so early.
The floor's still wet.
Your husband didn't mention any child.
- I beg your pardon?
What about the baby cot?
- Oh no. I use it to store the blankets.
We don't have any children, you see?
We bought it long ago.
I was with child but I lost it
and we kept the baby cot.
We can put it in the hall, if you want.
Are there no hangers?
- I'll put them there.
And what about breakfast?
- I can make it for you.
Will they deliver your things?
- No, all my things are here.
Oh, our new neighbour. You've come
for your luggage, haven't you?
I'll fetch them for you. - Let me do it.
I can't let you carry my luggage.
Well, well!
Forgive me for being a little curious.
The lamp got unwrapped so I...
- It's all right.
It looks nice here,
as if made for your flat.
You know, I believe you can't put
a lamp just anywhere.
You have to find the right place
and plant it like a tree.
Only people keep moving all the time.
And their lamps with them?
- And their lamps with them.
I'll wrap it for you.
- No, please don't.
At least I don't feel as such
a stranger here.
Why don't you sit down for a cup
of coffee? The kettle is on. - Thanks.
This is my tenth rented room. A jubilee.
Poor lamp.
How many cubes?
- Two, please.
Quite frankly, I don't like moving
from place to place at all.
It's just that sometimes I get a strange
feeling that everything is too ordinary.
My landlady, the grandpa in the picture,
the carpets and wallpapers.
I suddenly feel so desperate...
...and I tell myself: "Maybe something
will happen if you go elsewhere."
And what should happen?
- Something.
I don't know.
You're too pragmatic, miss.
Why? I'd only like to know what you
expect from your new lodging.
Nothing.
I have a feeling
as though I've been here before.
Although...
...I've never lived at a tram terminal.
Doesn't this place seem like
the end of the world to you?
Why the end?
The world begins here for me.
Do you know you can see
Prague Castle from here?
Which way is it?
- This way.
And that way, you can see the woods
with binoculars in daylight.
Really?
- Yes, real woods.
I hope you're not doing this too often.
Young ladies shouldn't do such things.
Why?
I like watching people.
When they are getting off the tram.
I pick a person and talk to him.
I ask him: "Where are you going?"
And he walks on without answering.
I ask him: "Where are you carrying
the pictures? Are you a painter?"
And he goes on without a word.
Until he vanishes out of sight
and someone else appears.
You know...
I sometimes play like that
when I'm alone.
And you've cut yourself
while shaving today.
Where were you in such a hurry?
- For my luggage.
You can learn a moral lesson
from that, miss.
Don't look at people with a magnifying
glass or you'll see their freckles.
I can also look at you
the other way around.
You're this tiny now.
You don't believe me?
See for yourself.
I want to see you up close.
I can almost touch you now.
Wait, don't shy away.
Wait.
Well, it was a pleasant evening.
But I should be going.
You've been most kind.
Oh my, what have I done.
- I'll go and switch on the light.
Your lamp!
It was my fault.
Watch out for those splinters.
I'll turn the light on.
ONE SUMMER DAY...
Good evening. -Good evening.
Your paper's upstairs. - Oh yes, thanks.
Hana, dinner is ready!
It's so hot today.
- Good evening. - Hello.
Towel!
- Hop!
How are you, sweetheart?
Men aren't human...
I'm hungry, woman!
- It's almost ready!
Shoo!
What does his lordship wish?
- Something for starters.
Only if you like me, though.
- I do.
All so sudden?
- Yes, all so sudden.
Stop it.
They've deducted 10 crowns
from my salary today.
It's the second time they've done it
without a reason.
Why trouble yourself
with such things if I love you?
It's easy for you to say.
It's not your salary, is it?
It's no use sweating away, Olga
I used to be just like you.
And today... the pharmacy, the canteen,
beef roll, and meetings.
Comrade Martinec hasn't paid
his membership fees.
Why did you study pharmacy then?
- I'd like to know myself.
My father had a chemist's shop
and I was to raise it to a pharmacy.
They published my poem when I was
a 6th year grammar school student.
My Czech teacher used to tell me:
"Continue, son, don't give up."
And now I eat their soup
and live in a God-forsaken place.
Three months ago,
it seemed like a nice place to you.
Never mind.
If only...
If only one always had
such expectations.
Olga, come here.
- What is it?
What did her husband do?
- I don't know.
Something in the factory.
A new investigation will start soon.
How many years did he get?
- Many.
But those who know him
stand up for him.
It's no use for him, is it?
Nobody will miss him in a year.
Would you be faithful to me?
- Hardly. Come.
She's not like that.
- I see.
Blonds are luckier as they say.
And brunettes are more passionate.
- Let go.
Heavens! I didn't say that much.
Nothing ever surprises me
and I never judge anyone.
Maruna!
I must be off. Thank you.
No! Don't.
Go home now.
What a pity!
It's my evening off tonight.
You ought to take a long walk.
I can't. It's not right.
Seeing you once in a while
is enough for me. - But not for me.
Good night.
Are you all right?
- It's stuffy.
Have a nice Sunday.
- Good night. -Good night.
Yes?
May I come up? Just for a moment.
Do you hear me?
Answer me, Maruna!
Good morning.
Miserable life.
They should ban Sunday shifts.
I've had a dream
and I can't remember it now.
Listen, stranger.
I've got news for you.
We're going to have a baby.
Well I never!
Is it certain?
It isn't just wishful thinking, is it?
If only I didn't have to get up
so early.
What are you doing here?
- I'm the door-keeper. -Are you?
And what's your grandma doing?
- She's asleep.
She's asleep?
- She's sitting there without moving.
She isn't moving?
- No, she isn't.
Mrs. Mala. Are you all right?!
Mrs. Mala!
Maybe she could stay with us.
She can't be alone.
She has a father, doesn't she?
We could take her to him.
Did anybody let Pesta know at all?
- I don't know.
Olga! Olga!
No matter what you may think,
it's like reaching the tram terminal.
Pesta? Waiting for him would be
a waste of time. -Goodbye.
You really don't know
when he's coming home?
Only God knows.
Come, sweetie.
Quiet! Can't you give us peace
on Sunday at least?!
Who is supposed to listen
to that roaring all week long?!
Thank you. - You're welcome.
- I'll be right with you, Olga.
Just a moment. Export or ordinary?
- Export.
Good day.
30 crowns, please.
Go and sit down, Hanicka.
Thank you.
Goodbye.
- Goodbye.
He wasn't home at all.
- Who wasn't home?
He'll have to come home sooner or later.
Here, have this chocolate.
It's full of vitamins.
I've heard he's seeing some widow.
I've got something for you, too.
Something good for you.
What is it? Vitamins?
Take it. It will help you.
Agomensin...
- It's hard to get. You see?
What's it for?
- Don't be naive.
Do you need directions for use?
- I surely don't.
Let's not...
Not in front of her.
I'd really like to go out tonight.
Somewhere with good food and music.
Where you can let
all your troubles go away.
Come to think of it,
we didn't even have a proper date.
Good day.
- Good day.
Go now.
May I help you?
- Yes, please.
Bye.
Do you dance like this with other women?
- No. Differently.
Doctor Ruzicka is asked to the phone!
Box No. 2.
This place seems like
a small railway station.
The train will be here any minute
and cover everything with steam.
Where are you going? You're waiting
for the Blue Express, aren't you?
No, second class in a passenger train
is good enough for me, sir.
I'd only like a place by the window.
- With a view of the terminal?
With a view of you.
We have to come here more often
after we get married.
Are you proposing to me?
Are you surprised?
- No. Not at all.
Waiter! -Yes, sir?
- What finer red wines do you have?
Pomar, Bikaver or Chateauneuf du Pape.
- Bring us two glasses of Bikaver.
I'm afraid...
- Then a small bottle, please! -Yes.
Let's get tipsy, shall we?
May I?
Is to make me a punctual... wife?
Yes, to make you punctual.
- And will we go on dates?
Of course we will.
What's the matter? - Nothing.
I thought I saw a familiar face.
Do you like it?
Have some wine.
Did you take it?
No, not yet.
What do you want to do?
- I don't know.
Look, Olga.
I'm a man that makes mistakes.
You may think I'm different but...
Are these chairs free?
- No, occupied. - Pardon me.
I wanted you to know that I have
a strong sense of responsibility.
I got used to looking twice before
I do anything. - Thrice.
It's not funny, Olga.
I feel it's pointless to bring new life
into a world full of bombs.
You agree with me, don't you?
But I want to have your child.
- Be sensible, Olga.
You're still a child yourself.
Perhaps... perhaps one day
when the situation is different.
Are we in such situation now?
Tell me.
You have only your scholarship
and my salary is a pittance.
Instead of love we'd feed on dumplings
and barely scrape enough money for rent.
Say no more, please.
At least not now.
You know I will obey you.
I feel like crying now.
I look terrible.
Excuse me.
Are you leaving already?
I've never seen you here before.
I've never been here before.
Do you come here often?
- No. I don't go anywhere much often.
It doesn't matter.
- I know.
One feels a little sorry, though.
Mind your own business
and I will mind mine.
While people live next to each other,
they are far apart as the stars.
We will find someone sooner or later.
Agomensin?
- Give it to me.
Did he give it to you?
- No, I got it myself.
It's nobody's business.
- I thought you were smarter.
As you wish,
we can compliment each other.
You wouldn't do this and
I wouldn't do something else.
Let's dance, shall we?
Are you angry at me?- Why?
That we went home early.
It was too crowded, you see?
A small railway station, eh?
It's still ticking. Do you hear?
You really can't hear it, can you?
It's my first watch.
Wait a moment.
Would you like some coffee?
- No, Olga.
Sleep tight.
I'll sleep in my room tonight.
At the Kovanda's flat.
- But...
To feel free a little
since we are engaged now.
I also thought it would be better
to give you some space.
One sometimes needs to look inside,
think and be alone, don't you think?
Yes. Tonight's the right moment.
Good night, Olga.
I enjoyed myself.
Really. Bye.
Miserable life.
ONE AUTUMN DAY...
I wish we finish that damned track soon.
Here, catch.
Those boys are going to kill me one day.
Good morning, Mr. Brzobohaty.
- Good morning.
A pint of milk and two rolls?
- Yes.
It's a fine day, isn't it?
- Let's hope it is.
Miss Olga has already stopped by.
- I didn't ask.
What though!
Good morning, Olga.
Did you sleep well?
Well, unfortunately.
- Why?
Do you know a Mr. Martinec by chance?
Mr. Martinec? I believe I do know him
more than well.
Would you be so kind and tell him
that it's his birthday today?
Is it? Time really flies.
I have some presents for him.
I see.
- Three.
And I'd like to give them to him
tonight. Do you think he'll come?
Crickey, I can't come tonight,
I've got a meeting.
You're so nice.
- How about over lunch?
I wouldn't have enough time.
But how about now?
It won't be a party but at least
you won't have to clean up afterwards.
How about that? - Why not.
- Great.
What have you been doing lately?
Yesterday and the day before?
- I'm terribly busy.
We were taking over a closed down
pharmacy. Every day's the same.
My first present is coffee or breakfast.
- And what's this?
That's my second present.
Sit down carefully. It's brand new.
Fifty translated pages
for 18 crowns per page.
And the armchair comes
with slippers - my third present.
And next year,
you'll buy me a bath robe, huh?
Not for me, dear!
You won't get me that easily.
You'll have to wait
for your third present.
I don't mind. As long as it's worth it.
Is it a big secret?
I've been wanting
to tell you for a long time...
... that the baby that I was expecting
will be born.
There's no other way.
Why aren't you saying anything, Karel?
I'm taking it down, you see?
It seems much too well prepared
to be true.
What are you saying?!
To be quite frank,
I think you've tricked me.
I feel it's all happening despite of me.
Something I never expected from you.
My birthday.
A small secret, eh?!
I'm no dumb youngster, Olga.
I'm no dumb youngster!
You shouldn't have done this to me!
- What was I supposed to do?
What we agreed on!
Without dirty tricks!
Say one thing and do the other.
For heaven's sake! It's your baby.
It has nothing to do with it!
This is about honesty and fair play!
Now we have to get married.
- It's not true. We don't!
Think whatever you want about me,
but my father taught me one thing!
To pay debts of honour!
It's my bill and I will settle it.
What are you doing all day?
Here's the butter.
We're cleaning and cooking.
- You're quite busy, aren't you?
I'll put the eggs in the bag.
Do you cook for Mr. Martinec, too?
No, but we make his bed.
His bed? Well, well.
And where are you today?
To the merry-go-round.
You're so lucky.
- I also have a cat.
A cat?
- I do.
Here's your money back.
Your mummy!
I have to go now.
Come again. - I will.
- I'll be happy to see you again.
Goodbye.
- Goodbye.
Good day.
- Good day.
Let me see.
I see you've bought all we needed.
Now we'll tidy up.
- And then?
Then we'll cook dumplings.
Good morning, Mrs. Kovandova.
- Good morning.
Then we'll bring lunch to uncle.
- And then?
What will we do then?
- Then we'll go to the merry-go-round.
Yes, we will. Let's go.
It's nice, isn't it?
Why don't you wash your eyes, eh?
Your youngest?
- Our only child.
Catch me if you can!
- Wait, Hanicka!
Don't run!
Wait for me. You'll run yourself out.
You know I can't catch you.
Hanicka.
Do you see what you've done!
Didn't I tell you?!
Good Lord, it's Pesta!
- Good day.
I came for my daughter.
Would you like some cherry brandy?
- There's no need.
Do sit down, Mr. Pesta.
It's all so sudden.
It's a pity my husband isn't here.
Why aren't you drinking, Mr. Pesta?
- Will you drink with me?
No, I don't drink.
You can be together all day
and bring her back in the morning.
It's no use. We're not coming back.
Mr. Pesta, we've got quite
used to having her.
She is all we have in this world.
All you have?
And what do I have?
Frantisek?
It's you, Mr. Martinec?
Mr. Pesta's here
and wants to take our Hana away.
Citizenship... What?
- What should I do now?
Will you come with me?
You won't? Don't be scared,
I'll buy you something very nice.
A doll with winking eyes.
How about that?
I never interfere in such affairs.
I have no right or time to do that.
I have enough troubles of my own.
There you have it.
So will you give me her things or not?
Of course. Just a moment.
Do you want to marry me or not?
I always thought I did, Karel.
But I'm not sure now.
Fill in the forms and the wedding agency
will take care of the rest.
We don't want many guests, do we?
- I don't know.
Besides, it doesn't matter.
Tell me. Do you love me at all?
You have the right to ask a hundred
times. It's a privilege women enjoy.
I've never asked you. Not once.
The thing is that people abuse the word
much too often nowadays.
And maybe I do love you in a certain
way. Would I be here, if I didn't?
Fill in the forms. Here's the address.
Dr. Arnost Brazda, M.D.
What am I supposed to do with it?
- I called him this morning.
He's the best doctor you'd find.
And he's a good friend of mine.
He said it still might not be late.
But he has to see you. Today.
He's expecting you
at half past eight tonight.
You've made an appointment for me?
And what if something happens to me?
Look, Olga, we have to act responsibly
since we got ourselves in such a mess.
There's always a risk.
As a father I also have the right to
decide whether I want the baby or not.
One of us has to be sensible.
What makes you think it's you?
What am I to do now?
- What's the matter?
What will I tell my husband?
- What happened?
Look outside. Our Hana is down there.
Pesta simply came for his daughter
and that's all.
Mr. Pesta!
Don't cry, Mrs. Kovandova.
Calm her down, Olga. I'm already late.
I'll be waiting for you tonight.
Why didn't you tell him anything,
Mr. Martinec?
Wait, Karel.
Wait! You were there?
- I was.
And what did you do?
- What could I do? It was obvious.
He's the father. Don't forget
about tonight. The Variety Arcade.
What an extraordinarily warm
attitude towards fathers you have!
You see, little one, I'm back.
I have something yummy for you.
There. Have a drink.
I'll cut it for you.
Take it in your hand.
It's very good.
Eat it.
Why aren't you eating?
Don't you like it?
And would you like a cream roll?
- No, I want a winking doll.
Wait here. I'll be right back.
Your dad will give you a hiding
if you're naughty.
Here's a cream roll for you?
It's sweet. Try it.
You always liked cream rolls.
I remember you say:
"Daddy, buy me a cream roll!"
I don't want it.
- Don't you like me?
No.
- No?
And why? Will you tell me?
- I won't.
Right you are!
- Mind your own business!
You...
Come. Let's pray for your mummy.
And your daddy.
Hail Mary...
Repeat after me.
Hail Mary.
- Hail Mary.
Full of grace.
- Full of grace.
Our Lord is with thee.
- Our Lord is with thee.
Blessed art thou among women.
- Blessed art thou among women.
Blessed art...
Hanicka!
Hana, where are you?
Hanicka?
Hanicka!
Hanicka! Hanicka!
- Shh!
Hanicka!
Hanicka.
Wait, come here.
Have you seen a little girl?
Alittle girl.
About this big. You haven't.
Please. Have you seen...
Good evening.
- Good evening. What is it?
Am I disturbing you? - Not at all.
- I need to talk to you.
I feel terrible, you see?
And I have nobody else to talk to.
I'm sorry but I can't right now.
Tomorrow perhaps.
Now's not the right time.
Excuse me.
Tomorrow then?
- Yes. Tomorrow perhaps.
Who was that?
- My neighbour.
They always come when you least
need them. Was it salt she wanted?
I don't know what she wanted.
Won't you take your coat off?
- If I may.
That's my husband.
So this is him?
What was he like?
- Why was? He still is.
Forgive me.
Did you love him very much, Maruna?
Why are you using the past tense?
I love him.
You love him and not me.
- I love you, too.
Don't be angry at me
but I don't seem to understand.
I don't like to talk about things
that people don't talk about.
Although years are passing.
You're alone and you're not happy.
You have someone
and that someone is me.
However, there's someone else
who is not here.
It's a pity to waste a single hour,
a single day, a single night.
What do you know?
I never share anything with anybody.
I want either everything or nothing!
Why am I here?
To help you live your dream?
Or did you want to show me his picture?
- Maybe.
It seems it's not enough for you, is it?
We've never talked like that.
- Leave me alone, please.
You don't mean it, do you?
Should I go?
Go. Quick.
Until there's time.
All right.
Let go of me!
We only went to pray!
Why did you take her away
if you can't look after her?!
Do you realize what could happen
to her?! You bastard!!!
Don't yell at me.
I have a terrible headache.
You have a headache?!
- Let go of him, Frantisek!
Go home!
Get inside, rascals!
Did you go to the police?
- Don't worry, she'll turn up somewhere.
Besides, you can keep her.
Who would be her chaperon one day?
I'm...
Calm down. Waiting isn't that bad.
It sometimes takes hours
before they find a missing child.
Ferdi over there
has been waiting here all evening.
Are you bored, Ferdi?
- I am.
So am I.
The chief wants one of them...
- Tell them yourself.
We've found some things
so if you could have a look at them.
Wait. I'll go.
You say there wasn't anyone nearby
in the church. Did you look well?
Nobody was there. Except for Our Lord,
though it seems he wasn't there either.
Good evening.
- Good evening and sit down, miss.
Look at the things found today
and see if you don't recognize anything.
Let us admit that she may have
run away. Why?
Did you treat her badly?
Was she afraid of you?
So you don't want to give me
any answers, do you?
It seems we will have to recommend
that your child be taken away from you.
You certainly qualify.
Not to worry, my record is clean.
I only booze a bit more than I should.
Speak to the point, please.
- To the point.
What is the point for you?
Everything's plain and simple
for you all!
In apple-pie order. Here's good,
there's evil, with a line in the middle.
But I walk the line every day!
Understand?
You don't, do you?
You won't find it in any handbook.
Stop blethering.
Can't you see that something
may have happened to the child?
Someone may have taken her away.
She may have been killed.
You're a father, aren't you?
I know I'm a father.
But what do you expect me to do?!
Who do you call a father?
- It doesn't concern you, miss.
Did you recognize anything?
- No.
In that case, thank you.
- Goodbye. -Goodbye.
I do love her.
I even wanted to buy her a doll.
What's your name, little one?
- I don't know.
And where's your mother?
- Home.
And where is that?
- At the tram terminal.
At what tram terminal?
- Our tram terminal. - I see.
We've ruined your plans
for tonight, Miss Olga, haven't we?
No, don't worry.
I had no plans for tonight.
Where is he? Is he all right?
You are Mrs...
- Here you are!
You little rascal!
How could you leave the house?!
Mummy, don't smack me!
- Not a word!
You've scared your mummy to death.
I thought he got run over by a car.
I was bored, Mummy.
- Bored! I'll teach you a lesson!
You won't be bored
after you see your daddy.
Come, Ferdi. Say goodbye.
- Goodbye, Ferdi. -See you.
I hope I won't.
Will you sign this, please?- Yes.
One can't help all that paperwork.
After you.
That's how it goes.
Some have a child without wanting it,
while others wish for it and have none.
- You can't take it like that.
Say it. Say what's troubling you
in front of Miss Olga here.
Let it out. - But, dear.
- And don't pity me.
Say that I didn't give you your own
child and that I let him steal this one!
I was never angry at you for that.
- Don't be so kind!
Do you think I don't hear you at night?
Do you think I can sleep?
Olga!
The phone!
The phone's ringing!
Are you stupid, you silly goose!
Olga!
What took you so long? I've been
waiting for you for half an hour.
Do you know what we said about
punctuality when I gave you the watch.
I understand. Come on.
What's the matter?
- I'm not going anywhere.
We can't let him wait, Olga!
Don't be scared.
Many women walked up these stairs.
Let's go.
Olga! Where are you going?
Don't make a scene, Olga!
We can't leave it like this.
Really? I will have the baby
despite that it's yours.
We can sort it out,
I'm not forcing you to do anything.
You know I love you.
Did you fill in the forms?
You'll take all your things tomorrow.
I want to be alone.
I didn't deserve this
after what happened between us.
I don't care about you any more.
It's as though you had never existed.
Olga! Olga!
Get up, young man,
or I'll have to sweep under you.
AND ONE WINTER DAY...
Alittle bit to the right! And up!
Good day, Mr. Brzobohaty.
Happy New Year.
- A Happy New Year to you too.
Good day.
- Good day.
Good day, Mr. Brzobohaty.
I've got something for you today.
For me?
- Where is it? Ah, here it is.
It must be an invitation to a meeting.
- Happy New Year. - Happy New Year.
Goodbye.
- Goodbye.
Hanicka, where are you?
What did you get for Christmas?
- I'm letting snakes out.
Happy New Year, Mr. Brzobohaty.
Who are the flowers for?
Good day.
Happy New Year.
If you allow me...
...a quartrefoil for good luck.
How nice of you.
Won't you come in?
- I have to go to work.
Well...
I'll water it.
Another year has passed...
...and look at all that happened
in our rather ordinary house.
I beg your pardon?
I said all that happened
in our house this year.
All sorts of things happen.
- Be careful.
Nothing happens to bastards, though.
Only good people have to pay.
Always the good people.
Well, I should be going now.
Goodbye.
- Happy New Year.
Miss Olga, would you marry me?
Me?
Marry you?
- Yes.
I've been thinking about it a lot.
Quite a lot but...
You would marry me just to help out
a friend or a neighbour or...
No, I just want the baby
to have a name. So...
But it will have a name.
My name. - Of course.
Don't you think that two people have
to love each other to live together?
That's what they say.
Yet one has to be humble.
Sometimes.
I'm not humble at all. - It's all right.
- Don't be angry at me.
Not at all. -Take it for good luck.
- No, I can't.
Forgive me, I thought you were alone.
- It's all right. I'm leaving.
I only wanted to ask you
whether you would like
to celebrate New Year's Eve with me.
Would you?- I'd love to.
I'm not much of a drinker, though.
Settled then? - Yes.
Goodbye. -Goodbye.
Last station.
Everyone please get off!
Hey, this is the end.
Get off.
You forgot something!
Should I throw this away?
- Give it to me.
It's for my little girl.
I came to visit her, you see?
Oh boy! What is this place?
- This is the end, old chum.
And is this place called the Loop?
- Oh no. We've passed it.
The terminal is further now
and in a year, we'll be even further.
You talk like a pamphlet.
Nothing's changed!
There's a pub here like everywhere else!
I wouldn't put on airs, you optimist.
All trams will soon be gone.
Do you know what I fear the most?
Loneliness.
And I've got plenty of it.
Wouldn't you like to cry just a little?
I'm not sure whether the circumstances
are right. We may try, though.
I'm really not good at crying today.
Do you think I could drink a little?
Won't it harm the baby?
I'm sure it will be a boy.
So let's drink to him being a true man.
Because life is much easier for men.
Let's hope it is a true human being.
- That would suffer a little bit.
That wouldn't be lazy, stupid
or conceited.
That would know how to love someone.
That would really love someone
and wouldn't be alone.
And he mustn't be a pharmacist.
What of it! You can be a pharmacist
if you want.
Don't kick me. I'm your mummy.
Hurry up, fellas!
We're playing at two more pubs!
Hurry up!
Goodbye!
Come here, don't be scared.
Is your name Hanicka?
- No, my name is Madla.
Madla?
Do you like the doll?
I do.
- You do? Here, take it.
Take it before I change my mind.
And hurry, your father's thirsty.
Anyone getting off at the Loop?
At the Loop?
Just a moment. Wait.
THE END
CAST