MAN [ON RADIO]:
Hi, I'm a loafer.
I don't like to work at all.
I'd much rather loaf than work.
Wouldn't you?
I like to fool away
the time, goof off, put
my feet up, and take it easy.
It's my time, isn't it?
And I waste it if I want.
Now, the reason I lie in bed
till noon is I'm a rich man.
You may wonder how a loafer
like me got to be rich.
Well, I didn't inherit money.
My father was a
small town preacher.
He never made much and
gave away what he did make.
I don't gamble,
and I don't steal,
and I didn't marry
any rich girl.
But I found a way to work
just a few hours a day
and make a fortune.
You could too, buy
sending me $5.98
for my book, "The Poor
Man's Guide to Easy
Living and Instant Wealth."
By following the
principles of my book,
you could be sitting
right now by the pool
of some fancy hotel.
You could put
steak on your table
instead of pork and beans.
You could have the things you
want, do the things you want
to do, travel, live it up,
drive a Cadillac convertible,
or if you're like me, maybe you
just want to sit back, relax,
and watch the grass grow.
You can do it.
Send me $5.98 today care
of this radio station.
It'll be the best investment you
ever make, better than stocks
and bonds, better than
watching that old devil
inflation eat away at the
money in your project.
And if you're not satisfied,
if you don't learn how to live
easy and make money fast, I'll
be glad to send you your money
back.
But keep the book anyway.
I can afford it.
It only cost me
$0.20 to print up.
But it's worth thousands,
maybe millions.
You and your family
will thank me for it.
[inaudible]
[non-english speech]
[alarm clock]
[coughing]
Hi, Elaine, uh,
get me 758-2610.
Oh, come on, Elaine.
Just-- just get me
the number, will you?
That ain't your job
collecting the bills.
All right, I got the message.
Now can I-- can I
just have 758-2610?
Hello, how are you?
This is 322.
What do you need my name for?
I just give you my number.
They'll call me back.
[radio]
Now, wait a minute.
If your new, then they
should tell you how it works.
I phone in.
I give my number, and
they call me back.
No, I'm not going to
give you my name, man.
That's not how this
game is played.
Yeah, now, wait a minute, man.
Now, look.
You're, uh-- you're
talking a little too much.
You're beginning to make
me nervous, you know?
[knocking]
Roland?
I'm getting off
this phone right now.
[knocking]
Roland, are you there?
Wake up.
Roland?
Hey, nursie, want to
take my temperature?
LUCY: I'm sorry.
I'm trying to wake
up my boyfriend.
Roland?
MAN: Will you come down here
and take my temperature?
Yes, I'm sure.
Roland, will you open this door?
OK, OK, OK, I'm coming.
[knocking]
I'm coming
Roland, there's a man out here.
Oh, thank goodness.
Hey, what's the matter?
That old wino bothering you?
Roland.
Why didn't you answer the door?
I was knocking for hours.
I was asleep.
Come on in.
What a creepy guy.
Nah, he's a good guy.
[inaudible]
[seagulls]
I got the check, Mr. Banks.
I'm sorry I couldn't
do more for you,
but it's a difficult time
of year to sell a boat.
I can tell you.
35 grand?
I have almost twice
that in it, Bill.
I know, easy.
I think figured you'd
get at least 42.
Yeah.
Well, I better get
this to the bank.
Send you a commission when I
get back the office, OK, Bill?
No problem.
Oh, Mr. Banks?
Do you see this little runabout
we got in-- real little beauty.
You trying to talk this
check out of me, Bill?
Thanks.
Isn't that the one with the
house up on the heights?
Didn't I pick you up there once?
LUCY: Yes.
She has this fabulous kitchen.
Do you like meatloaf?
Uh, yeah, yeah, it's OK.
I make this incredible
meatloaf, Roland.
Oh.
I do.
Everybody loved it at home.
ROLAND: Hey, come here.
Oh, Roland, you're
messing my uniform.
The head nurse is
going to kill me.
Ha.
MAN [ON RADIO]: You
young people see
the world different from most
of us old timers, don't you?
You see everyone out
working and struggling,
but you can't see
any meaning in it.
I know how you feel.
I was young once too.
Yes, I was.
My father-- he was just
a small town preacher.
And he couldn't understand me.
All I wanted to do was sit
back and watch the grass grow.
He'd say, Bob,
you can't do that.
Well, I did.
And I even wrote
a book about it.
[phone ringing]
-Oh great.
-Wait a minute.
Don't say anything.
MAN [ON RADIO]: It's called
"The Young Man's Guide to Easy
Living."
Hello?
Larry, son of a bitch,
what the hell's going on?
Yeah, hey, you're calling
me to change the number.
Man, I already
called the number.
No, no, no, no, I
didn't say anything.
Man, I didn't say a word to him.
Yeah, yeah, I'm
going over there now.
Should be no problem at all.
You just tell me what to do
once I get in there, huh?
It's so cold in here.
I wish somebody
would warm me up.
Yeah, right.
About that money
I owe you, look,
I should be able to clear it
in a couple of weeks, huh?
So call off your army, huh, man?
OK.
That's it.
Give them out.
They can all go back to work.
Hey, sorry, Phil.
Times are rough.
The cupboard's bare.
See you all later.
Wait a minute, Rich.
What about the bank?
One thing at a time, Phil.
God dammit, one thing at a time.
All right, you might
as well give those out.
I'll see if I can
hold off the bank.
Here.
Goodbye.
Thanks.
Hey, look, can you loan me the
money for the rent tonight?
They're really
starting to bug me.
I guess so.
Look, I'll try.
Don't forget.
7:30 you are meeting me.
You know where it is?
-Yeah, yeah, thanks.
I picked you up there once.
Remember?
OK, bye.
Yeah, I'll see you later.
Bye-bye.
MAN [ON INTERCOM]: The Golden
Sands Bathing Boutique is open.
The Gold Sands Bathing
Boutique is open.
You can purchase lotion, bathing
caps, kiddie toys, [inaudible]
Mm.
[inaudible]
Well, you taste it and
tell me what it's like.
[inaudible]
RICH: Hey, Jennifer!
Daddy!
Daddy, Daddy, [inaudible] here.
I never thought I'd see this.
Hey, I wouldn't let
you down, Freddie.
Hey, I heard things are
really busy around here.
I'm kind of looking
around, you know?
Oh, you gotta see Steve.
Hey-- hey, Steve.
Come here a minute.
-Who's that?
Who's Steve?
Do I know him?
No, no, no, he's from Miami.
What's up, Freddie?
Uh, this is Roland.
He's a friend of mine.
He's a real operator.
But I like him.
Roland, this is Steve.
Roland.
Uh, how are you doing?
Yeah.
Uh, Roland, here,
is looking for a job.
He's been around a long time.
Talk to him, Roland.
Ah, shit, I ran my
first pool when I was 15.
No kidding?
That's too bad.
See, I don't need
anybody to run this pool.
I run the pool.
MAN [ON INTERCOM]:
The Golden Sands
wishes to welcome the Kiwanis
club of Camden, New Jersey.
What about the money
I've got in there?
What about my money?
I had to sell my damned
boat, for Christ's sake.
Your boat, your boat--
who cares about your boat?
I've got over a half
million dollars in there,
and you're telling
me about a boat?
Hey, take it easy.
I said maybe foreclosed.
The bank's just making noises.
I can shut them up.
Did you talk to my
lawyer about this?
Howard?
He said talk to you.
Listen, Ellen,
with, I don't know,
maybe a few hundred thousand
I can stall them off until we
start renting.
Now, I know you
have that much left.
And what do I do
if you lose that?
I don't want to talk about it.
Hey, listen to me.
We're in trouble here, dammit.
You have to talk about it.
You want to throw away the money
you put in the building so far?
I don't think so.
I don't know how
to be poor, Richard.
I haven't had any practice.
Ellen, you were born
too rich to ever be poor.
All right, I'm not
going to beg you.
Shit, I can't find Jeremy.
I can see her, but
I can't see him.
I told you to watch them.
[crying]
Hey, he's OK.
He just got knocked
down by a wave.
He's OK.
Hey.
Jeremy, you're all right.
Roland.
Roland, I need a porter.
[LAUGHING] A porter?
You mean someone to sweep
up the cigarette butts?
Yeah.
Hey, I'm no porter, man.
Well, that's all I got.
MAN [ON INTERCOM]: The
Golden Sands would like
to congratulate the winners--
Let's go back [inaudible].
MAN [ON INTERCOM]: --of
the cha-cha contest.
Mr. and Mrs.--
Well, if that's all there
is currently, I can dig that.
MAN [ON INTERCOM]: --of
Brooklyn, New York.
There's some white
pants in the shed.
See, normally I wouldn't
take a porter's job,
but just take a look around you.
You got a gold mine here, bud.
What do you mean?
Well, I mean all I
got to do is walk along
here with a racing form,
and you and me could
clear a grand a week, easy.
I mean, you could be
dealing dope here.
Haven't you ever
thought of that?
I mean, you could be running
girls in and out of here, man.
You just give me a
chance, and you and I
are going to clean up.
We're going to be rolling in it.
OK, take a walk, friend.
I don't want your dirty money.
I don't mean real dope, man.
I mean grass and
coke, like that.
Come on.
Let me throw a few numbers.
It's easy.
Look, I've got to
rub some oil on Mrs.
Schwarzberg's back over there.
When I come back, I don't
want to see you here, OK?
You're making a
big mistake, Steve.
You'll make a big mistake
if I catch you here anymore.
Screw you, too, asshole.
Hey, Steve, somebody
through some dirty money
all over your nice, clean pool.
Ha.
MAN [ON INTERCOM]:
In five minutes,
we will have a diving exhibition
by Steve-- a diving exhibition
off the high board by Steve.
Hello, Marie.
It's Ellen Banks.
Fine, thank you.
How are you?
Good.
Marie, Richard asked me to call.
There's going to
be a slight delay.
We had a little accident,
and he went to his department
to change clothes.
But he'll be in soon.
Oh, no, no, it's
nothing serious.
Um, Marie would you leave a
message for Richard, please?
Yeah.
Just tell him I'm sorry, but no.
That's right.
I'm sorry, but no.
Oh, they're fine.
The kids are just fine.
Oh, hi, honey.
Uh, yeah, I have to talk
to Mommy for a few minutes.
Sure, I'll talk to you after.
Yeah, right now I have
to talk to Mommy, just
for a few minutes.
Would you get her?
Uh, honey, would you
tell her that it's
really, really important.
I must talk to her right now.
OK?
Go ahead.
Honey, tell Mom-- uh,
just tell her to call
me as soon as she can, OK?
Sure.
What do you want to talk about?
No, I don't think it
was funny when Jeremy
got lost in the water, honey.
It's never funny when
someone could get hurt.
You know that.
That's right.
Let's protect little
children and keep
them from getting hurt.
I agree.
Right.
Bye-bye.
I love you too, sweetie.
Marie!
MARIE: Goodbye.
[hanging up phone]
Where the hell is Phil?
I don't know!
I mean, where-- maybe
he's over at the building.
Well, would you give
him a call and tell
him I'll pick him up, huh?
And get rid of these
damned magazines.
It looks like a goddamned
dentist's office in here.
MAN [ON INTERCOM]:
Ladies and gentlemen,
--you will see this [inaudible]
before your eyes very slowly
growing to a length of
six to eight inches--
the long, straggling
hair of a gorilla or ape.
It will continue to
grow down the neck,
over her breasts, both breasts,
and down the body itself,
changing this beautiful
girl before your eyes
into a horrible,
ugly, male, gorilla.
Anything can happen.
But you're safe in there,
because Dr. Edison have
her under complete control.
But if you've got a weak
heart, then don't go here.
Young ladies in the family
way, you're not invited.
This show is not for the timid.
I mean, we're going to scare
the hell right out of you.
This is the same
[inaudible] Princess
Uraina, the gorilla girl.
Was Darwin right?
Did man come from ape?
You're going to see
a beautiful girl
locked in a solid steel cage.
You're going to see her
change before your eyes.
Very slowly she'll change
into an ugly, male gorilla--
a gorilla so strong that
it can bend a steel bar.
From the top of her head
to the tips of her toes,
you'll see the hair grow.
The ape girl, the
ape girl, the ape
girl-- she's alive,
so much alive
that only the brave are invited.
Princess Uraina, the gorilla
girl-- anything can happen.
But you're safe in there,
because Dr. Edison will have
her under complete control.
But if you've got a weak
heart, then don't go here.
Young ladies in the family
way, you're not invited.
This show is not for the timid.
Was Darwin right?
Did man come from ape?
OK, where are we off to?
Someplace profitable, I assume.
We're going to see the friend
of a local businessmen, Phil.
The man who comes through
when all else fails.
So they tell me.
Afternoon, Lou.
I'm glad I caught you.
I want you to take a
look at these, Lou.
These are the projections
on what we're going to make
as soon as the building's up.
What building?
Come on up.
Just a quarter to play.
Just a quarter.
Win yourself a very nice
doll-- very nice doll.
How are you doing?
Uh, do you want to play?
It's just a quarter.
You can win yourself
a nice doll.
Like the chances.
Love the chances.
You can set a quarter
on any name you want.
Yeah, give me some change.
Okey-doo.
Here we go-- 2, 3, 4,
5, and that 5 is 10.
You get a quarter on
any name you want.
Bud, Dan-- that's my name.
Yeah?
Yeah.
Dot, All right,
press the button.
And we have Bud.
[inaudible] You caught a winner.
You get a doll.
What kind of doll do you want?
I want to play for
some real money.
That's illegal.
Yeah, I know.
Give me 50 to 1.
OK, you got 10 to 1 on
the inside, dollar minimum.
Hey, I bet you get more dollars
now than you get quarters, huh?
Huh?
Right?
Bud?
[inaudible] be twice in a row.
Loser.
Irv!
That your name?
Uh, yeah.
-It is?
-Yeah.
Well, good luck, Irv.
It's off.
Sorry.
Nope, sorry.
Hey!
Hey, hey, Irv!
Now, you don't
have to say a word.
The old bastard won't
give you a dime, right?
You know, for a minute
there, I though you had him.
I did.
I did have him.
He wants to give us $1 million.
He wants the whole deal
for a fast million.
He wants to buy us out?
Believe that?
The nerve of that guy.
You know, it might not
be a bad deal, Richard.
We might even turn a profit.
I say let's take his offer.
At the very least,
we'll break even.
Come on, Phil.
I want a lot more out of this
deal than just breaking even.
I can be a very rich
man when this is over.
And you're not going to
do so badly out of it
yourself, my friend.
You don't expect me to
back out now, do you?
Hey, Phil, let's get
out of here before I
lose my confidence in you.
Hey, come on, Phil.
I'm busting my ass to
make this thing work,
and it's going to work.
Ahoy matey.
[cheering]
Come on, [inaudible]
Jesus, I thought that three
was a sure winner, you know?
[inaudible]
Thatta boy, [inaudible] hey!
I'm going to do it, man.
I am.
You're going to
do what, my friend?
Nothing.
[inaudible]
ANNOUNCER: --at the
break returns $52.20.
[cheering]
Fuck you, Sonny!
Fuck you!
You know how to
work the TV, right?
Oh, sure.
And let's see.
I left a number where I'll
be at the tennis club.
It's on that pad in the kitchen.
Oh, OK, Mrs. Banks.
Oh, and the stereo.
You know how to work that?
That's that knob.
I'm sure he knows.
Let's see.
What else?
LUCY: Oh, we'll be
fine, Mrs. Banks.
MRS. BANKS: Oh, you know
where the kids rooms are?
LUCY: Uh-huh.
MRS. BANKS: And if Jeremy wakes
up, give him some orange juice.
If she wakes up,
just talk to her.
She loves to talk.
LUCY: I know.
Next stop, the kitchen.
You know how to work
the oven and everything?
You just switch
this dial, and it'll
ring when everything's ready.
LUCY: You have a fabulous
kitchen, Mrs. Banks.
Well, I guess I'm ready to go.
Think I'll just check the kids.
Oh, let me come with you.
I never get to see the children.
Come on, Roland.
You have to see these
gorgeous children.
ROLAND: Right.
Come on.
Be very quiet, OK?
Careful of that wire.
[WHISPERING] Isn't he cute?
Oh, what a pretty
little-- oh, look, Roland.
[inaudible]
ROLAND: Yeah.
Bye, Lucy.
Bye, uh--
Roland.
Look, I got to talk to
you about something.
Huh?
Oh, later.
Come here Roland.
Sit down.
I have everything ready.
Sit.
OK, first, you add
the ketchup, see?
Hm, and then, um--
oh, wait a minute.
Wait a minute.
Oh, oh, then you add the meat.
You see, Roland?
Roland, I've already added the
BAKEN-ETS, the green pepper,
the cracker crumbs, and
my special ingredient,
the oatmeal-- to
stretch it, you know?
I got an idea.
You
Careful of your ashes, Roland.
It's not in the recipe.
Ha ha.
Uh, now I'm going to add some
soup-- cream of mushroom.
Look, I gotta talk to you.
Mm.
Now, a little cream.
Oh, isn't that beautiful?
Isn't it beautiful, Roland?
Yeah, beautiful-- I may puke.
Oh, come on.
Don't make fun.
This is the best part
that's coming up.
I'm going to decorate it.
OK, watch this.
See?
It's a little heart.
All right.
Oh, come on, Roland.
The trouble with you is
you're just not romantic.
Now, all these
delicious ingredients
are going to bubble and
simmer in this terrific oven
for about an hour and a half.
Well, now what shall we do?
[chatter]
MAN: You just won a game--
a game of [inaudible]
You won the first--
Ah!
Wow.
LUCY: Roland!
Hey, Richard.
Hey.
[inaudible]
Hey, terrific.
Hi, hi.
[inaudible]
Hey, hey.
Come on.
[crying]
[inaudible]
MAN: Go ahead.
Serve.
I like to watch you serve.
[crying]
We going?
We're going on a trip.
One heart.
Play a spade.
Three hearts, partner.
He can hear you.
I pass.
Four, no trump.
Uh-uh.
I'll pass.
Let's see, uh, five hearts.
Oh, two aces-- it
means he's got two aces.
He can count, Harry.
Pass.
Look, Richard, if you're
going to go for a slam,
do you know how we score that?
That means you get 2,500
a piece from each of us
if you make it.
If you don't, you lost 5,000.
7,000 grand slam.
Plus we get to score
too-- a buck a point.
Mhm.
OK.
Seven hearts.
I'll give it a try.
It's only money.
If it's only money,
I'll double you.
That's double with
the side bets too.
Pass.
Good luck, Richard.
OK, Harry, it's your lead.
Make it a good one.
What the hell.
I have to call
my babysitter, OK?
Look, forget your
kids for one night.
Let's go for a drink.
Well, OK, but just one.
Trump is king.
I pull the last trump.
I take my diamond, and I go back
to the board for my two clubs.
Ace, king are good.
-Woo.
-That's right.
Shit.
I should have led hearts.
Then you couldn't pull
trump and trump my ace.
I know.
I took a big gamble.
I'm sweating, Christ.
Grand slam bid and made.
That's double.
Good going, partner.
Keep it up.
You guys are off to
a pretty good start.
What do you think of high-stakes
bridge so far, Richard?
I like it.
Come on, somebody deal.
I got a long way to go.
Here cut.
Oh, I forgot my [inaudible].
Oh my god, low bridge.
You OK?
Yeah, I'm fine.
Listen, you got to
have one of my omelets.
Did I ever tell you how really
terrific my omelets are?
You told me.
Well, it's true.
Richard doesn't like them.
He hated them.
That doesn't count.
Uh-oh, the door's locked.
Where's my key?
Why don't you
just ring the bell?
No, no, if you ring the bell,
you'll wake everybody up,
and then you never
get your omelet.
[inaudible]
Lucy, I'm here.
Lucy?
Maybe they went out.
Oh no, Lucy wouldn't go out.
She's probably in the library.
Lucy?
It's me.
I'm home.
[WHISPERING] The
library door is shut.
What should we do?
Why don't you knock?
Oh, that's a good idea, Howard.
I'll knock.
[knocking]
[moaning]
[WHISPERING] Howard,
Howard, I can here her.
They're doing it.
What?
I hear her making
these moaning sounds.
They're making love.
Huh.
Let's just [inaudible]
[moaning]
[inaudible]
[WHISPERING] What should we do?
Let's get out of here.
[moaning]
Let's go into the
kitchen instead.
Until they finish.
[moaning]
[inaudible]
That boy Frankie's
a hell of a man.
Something's cooking.
Ew, what is that?
[moaning]
[phone ringing]
Thanks for telling them.
I'll be back in a second.
Harry, can you play first?
I got to think.
[inaudible] Hello.
Well, what happened?
Jesus, come on.
Take it easy, Richard.
I got the whole night
riding on this one hand,
and the phone rings?
Hang in there, Dick.
Hey, Richard.
Your secretary called, said
your ex-wife called her at home.
It's an emergency.
Is she on now?
She said for you to
get in touch with her.
Didn't say what
it was all about.
Said your ex was
pretty shook up.
You better call,
Oh Christ.
Let's finish Austin's
hand of cards first.
Well, aren't you going to call?
I'll call Ellen, all right.
Probably the washing
machine that broke down.
Let's play.
Come on.
Here's your food.
-I don't like to eat in the car.
-That's for you.
I'll throw up.
That's for you.
Can I get out?
There.
There are some fries--
some fries for you.
Hold on to them.
There are some fries for you.
OK, put this thing down.
I-- I-- um, um, um, tomato.
Tomato [inaudible]
OK, we got to get going now.
And ketchup.
Huh?
And mustard.
Round two.
Changed my goddamned
mind at the last minute.
OK, call Ellen.
All right, I'll call Ellen.
You know, she cost me a
hell of a lot of money.
I'm thinking about
her, and I'm trying
to play cards at the same time.
Hell, I can play the jack.
Who put the Jack there?
I need a drink.
Oh, and get me a beer while
you're up, too, will ya?
And get the cigars.
They're on the bar.
Fries.
Ellen, Ellen, will
you please calm
down, because I
can't understand what
the hell you're saying to me.
Come on.
We got to go. [inaudible].
We got to go.
Hold on to your brother.
[inaudible]
[crying]
Don't start crying.
You two talked me
into coming here.
I was doing you a favor.
You can't drive.
I'll get sick.
You won't get sick.
Yes, I will.
You will not.
Yes.
Wait a minute.
I think we're even a
few thousand ahead.
Anything wrong?
No, I gotta go.
I'm sorry.
I'm really sorry.
Hey, wait, anything wrong?
Anything we can do for you?
Uh, no, not a thing.
One of my kids is
sick-- my daughter.
She keeps calling for
me, so I better go.
Yeah, those kids really
love their old man.
Yeah, they do.
Uh, figure out what I owe you
and give me a call tomorrow.
Sure, yeah.
I'm really sorry to
break up the game.
Hey, it's no problem.
We can play some gin.
Oh, and I'm sorry
about that hand.
I should have played that king.
That's OK.
It's only money.
You go take care of that kid.
All right.
Roland would never
hurt the children.
He's just a little crazy
sometimes, I guess.
That's enough.
I'm going to call the police.
No, no, no, don't do that.
He'll bring them back.
Please wait.
Richard's going to come.
Why should we wait?
For God's sake, this
maniac has your children.
He is not a maniac.
Wait, Howard.
Please just wait.
Richard will know what to do.
He's the children's father too.
Right, Mrs. Banks.
Roland knows how to take
care of the children.
He's watched me take
care of children before.
He knows what to do.
What does he want,
Lucy, to ransom them?
I'll give him money.
Oh, I'll-- I'll
give him anything.
Just call him, please, and
tell him I want them back,
please, Lucy. [sobbing]
[phone ringing]
You answer.
He knows you.
Hello?
Um, oh, um, Mrs. Banks
can't come to the phone.
Oh yes, yes.
Yes, Mr. Banks called
a few minutes ago.
No, Mrs. Banks wants me to
thank you for contacting him.
Um, um, yes, yes,
it's all right.
Nothing's wrong.
It's just a family matter.
Fine, OK, thank you.
Goodbye.
Why are we keeping
this such a big secret?
Because Richard said to, and
he knows about these things.
LUCY: My mother always said
that people's own troubles
embarrass them most.
There's no use letting
everybody know.
That's not it, Lucy.
Richard probably just
doesn't want to upset Roland.
We don't want that.
We don't want Roland to
do something too hastily,
you know?
I'm sorry.
Richard.
He took the children!
He took the children.
ANNOUNCER [ON TELEVISION]:
Bases loaded, one out.
The Yankees 2 and the Orioles
2 in the top of the seventh.
Outfield deep,
and straight away.
The infield back in
double play depth.
[inaudible]
Why would he kidnap for ransom?
We all know who he is.
It doesn't make sense.
So what if we know who he is?
We don't know where
he is, Howard.
What does he care if
we know who he is?
[inaudible]
That's fine.
Thank you.
Ellen.
Tell me something.
Was your boyfriend interested
in drugs or anything?
We're both followers of
the cosmogenetic faith.
We don't believe in polluting
our minds or our bodies.
You're the followers of what?
The cosmogenetic faith.
Oh, that's terrific.
OK, Howard.
How long have you
known this guy?
Roland?
Roland.
About six months.
He came to the hospital where
I worked with a lacerated toe.
He cut it on a shell.
I was dressing it, and we got
to talking, and, well, you know.
That's very romantic.
Uh, Richard, listen.
I'm a lawyer.
I'm an officer of the court.
I have no right to hold this
from the police anymore.
Ellen?
I don't know.
Listen to me, Howard.
You make one move
to call the police,
and I'll kick your
goddamn teeth in.
Now, I mean it, Howard.
Who knows what this--
this Roland is going to do
if the cops start chasing him.
And you're so qualified
to deal with it?
They are my kids,
Howard, and I'll
decide what to do with them.
So you just keep your
goddamned nose out of this.
Why don't you get
out of my house?
Your house?
If it was your house, it would
have been lost a long time ago.
Please.
Get him out of here
before I kill him.
Will you stop it!
[phone ringing]
That's Roland.
I know it is.
Hello, is this Banks?
Hey, hello, Mr. Banks.
How are you doing?
This is the guy
who's got your kids.
Hey, yeah, yeah, sure
they're all right.
They're sitting
here watching TV.
But look, what I called about
is if you want your kids back,
it's going to cost you, right?
Uh, 200 grand--
100 grand apiece.
How's that?
Oh, come on, Mr. Banks.
You're loaded.
Yeah, sure, sure.
Hey, you want to
say hello to Daddy?
Yes.
Hi, Daddy.
I'm watching a silly show on TV.
We're in Paris.
Are you going to
come and get us?
I want to talk.
[inaudible]
Please give me the phone.
Bye, Daddy.
I was finished talking.
Jesus, why'd she
hang up like that?
Taught her to.
She used to leave phones off
the hook all over the house.
What'd she say again, parish?
No.
I think Paris.
Well, where's
your Yellow Pages?
Maybe there's a Paris or
a Parish Hotel somewhere.
I mean, it's worth a try.
Shut up, Howard.
Just shut up, will you?
He'll call back.
When he calls back,
Richard, just tell him we'll
give him whatever he wants.
ROLAND: Yeah, the
shopping mall, man.
[inaudible]
ROLAND: Hey, don't
worry what I look like.
I'll find you.
Here's 11,000,
6,100, 2,600, 17,000.
Here are some bonds.
500, 750, 25-- $25-- 750.
What's this?
Why is my passport here?
Here's another bond-- $5,000.
My father sent this to the
kids when Jeremy was born.
There's 20,000 in this account,
a bond for 50 from your mother,
bond for 750.
This is written to both
of us-- a wedding present.
500-- that's for something
I don't remember.
I don't care.
25 from your mother--
it's another one.
More bonds-- why do
I have so many bonds?
I I never knew I
had so many bonds.
Here's some contract
or something.
No, it's a will.
It's our wills.
Take this.
Just take everything.
Just get the kids back, Richard.
RICHARD: Don't worry.
There's stock
certificates in the vault.
We should get them out.
[inaudible]
Roger, give me the winning
number for yesterday.
I may get the right one.
6, 6, [inaudible] I
dreamt of sixes two nights
running a week ago,
and I didn't play.
MAN [ON INTERCOM]: Come
along, with Captain Skull
and sail the seven seas.
[inaudible]
[laughing]
NEWSCASTER [ON TELEVISION]That
final score again.
[inaudible] 3, Orioles, 2.
Temperatures reached a
high yesterday of 92.
And they're expected to
go back to that today.
The National Weather Service
predicts a possibility
of the mercury hitting
100 this afternoon,
with clear blue skies
and no chance of rain.
The ocean temperature is 74.
The air quality is--
[bells chiming]
WOMAN: Good morning, Mr. Banks.
Jim.
Richard, how are you?
Sit down.
[QUIETLY] Somebody's here.
Tell him I'll get back to him.
Well, how'd you make out with
that fellow you told me about?
Not too well.
I saw him yesterday, and
he wasn't interested.
But I did get some money
from another source.
Good.
Enough to cover the month?
Well, just about.
I have 200,000.
Well, that's
certainly something.
If we apply the 200,000 to
this note that's due now,
they should cancel
the foreclosure
and not bother you again until
you've got everything ready.
If you had a check with you, we
could put it through right now.
That will certainly
make them happier
with you upstairs, Richard.
Well, I certainly hope so.
What I have here
are some savings
accounts and some bonds.
They're all in my wife's name.
All the withdrawal
slips are signed
and the bonds are all endorsed.
Oh, you got it from your wife?
Well, she has a big
interest in the project.
And I sort of convinced her
she ought to protect it.
JIM: Good for you.
Well, it all looks
all right to me.
Here, just fill this out
to renew the other notes,
and you should be fine.
Could I get about $25,000 of
this in cash, do you think,
Jim?
In other words, you only
want to put down 175,000.
I'd rather have it all, Dick.
Well, I need about 15,000 to
finish things up at the site,
and I could use the
other 10 personally.
I could sign another
note for the 25,000.
JIM: I don't think they'll
take another note, Dick.
Why don't you try to limp
by on what you've got
and let me give them
the whole 200,000?
You're a pretty resourceful
fellow, Richard.
You can come up with
25,000 somewhere, I'm sure.
No, I can't.
I'm pretty far out
over the edge as it is.
I can tell you it was
not an easy matter
coming up with this money.
It was really just
luck, actually.
JIM: Can you do with 10,000?
That way I could
give them 190,000.
It sounds almost like 200.
If that's the best
you can do, OK.
JIM: Here, let's take one
of these books to a teller.
This one in trust for your
daughter has about 10,000.
Thanks, Jim.
My pleasure.
I'm glad everything
turned out all right.
Me too.
Could you make out
a check for this?
Make it cash, please--
fifties and twenties.
That's a lot of bills.
Put it in a bag
for him, will you?
Well, I'll put everything
into work right away.
I'll call you this
afternoon, just
to verify that everything's OK.
But don't worry.
There won't be any problem.
I'm sure.
Thanks a lot, Jim.
JIM: Hey, how are the kids?
You have two, don't you?
That's right--
a boy and a girl.
They're just fine.
Glad to hear it.
Well, here's your money.
Jim, thanks again.
Whee!
[laughing]
Now, look, you
kids just sit still,
because Daddy is going to be
with you in about five minutes.
Daddy!
[inaudible]
MAN [ON INTERCOM]:
--a black button.
And you can save money
if you get one right now.
It's a bargain at our
[inaudible] prices.
But it's a real steal at our
sale price of just $19.99.
Imagine [inaudible].
Excuse me, sir. [inaudible]
Oh, uh, uh, yeah, I've never
been here before [inaudible]
It's quite all right.
Just put the dime
right in there, sir.
MAN [ON INTERCOM]: In honor
of still another member
of the famous
[inaudible] family,
Mr. [inaudible] we
present the graffiti mug.
Wouldn't it be great
to have a miniature oil
lamp hanging in your room?
They look absolutely far out,
and they really work too.
You can fill them--
May I help you, sir?
I'm passing through.
MAN [ON INTERCOM]: The
regular price is $5,
but the sale price
right now is just $2.99.
[inaudible]
See something you like.
MAN [ON INTERCOM]: It
comes in white or red.
[honking]
Morning.
You the maid?
Yeah, I am.
Who are you?
My name's Lucy.
I babysit here.
Miss Bank's upstairs asleep.
Oh.
We were up all night.
Where are the children?
Um, Mr. Banks has them.
I mean, uh, he's
picking them up now.
Why, you want to make
them lunch or something?
No, was just wondering.
Oh, Mr. Banks should
be back any minute.
Do you know what time it is?
11 o'clock.
Guess I better get to work.
Where's Mr. Bank
picking up the children,
their grandmother's house?
I don't know.
I guess so.
He should be back any minute.
I'm going to wake up Mrs. Banks.
Why?
Why you want to wake her up?
She has to pay you?
I'll give you the money.
She can pay me back.
No need to disturb her.
Well, I think she'll want to be
up when the children are here.
Why?
What for?
Because my boyfriend
kidnapped them.
That's why.
He tied me up, and he
took the children away.
They call the police?
No, they were afraid
to call the police.
I mean, they didn't want
to get the police involved.
So Mr. Banks went with the
money early this morning.
He should be back by now.
Well,he isn't.
Now, where did your boyfriend
take these children?
Come on.
I don't know.
You don't know?
He didn't tell you
anything about it?
Where are the children, girl?
I don't know.
He tied me up.
Where did Mr.
Banks get the money?
I think Mrs. Banks
gave it to him.
Look, don't ask me anymore.
I gotta go to work.
You won't tell
anybody, will you?
No, girl.
Don't forget.
You stay here.
I'm going to go and
wake up Mrs. Banks.
ROLAND: Park over there.
You got to be kidding me, man.
Take the money, Roland.
Fuck you.
Oh, you think you're
a big operator, right?
Trying to buy me
off with 10 grand?
Fuck your 10 grand.
I'll explain it again, Roland.
You just take this
money, and you disappear.
Get away from me, buddy.
I don't want that money.
No one will come after you.
And that is a promise.
Yeah, a promise, right.
Look.
Just tell me where the
children are, Roland,
and then you can get off.
You'll be free.
Look, I'm tired of
telling you, man.
I want it all.
Eat something, Mrs. Banks.
No, no, I will later.
[dog barking]
Where are they?
They'll be here soon.
Shit.
Goddamned fucking machine.
Listen, mister, I
need that 200 grand.
I had this thing all
figured out, man.
And I need all of that money.
God damn it, now
I need that money.
I wouldn't hurt your kids, man.
I just need the money.
Why?
Because I'm tired
of scrounging, man.
I'm tired of scrounging
my whole life.
I know what you mean, Roland.
[LAUGHING] That's
no lie, Roland.
That damned money.
When you have it,
somebody's always trying
to take it away from you.
You know, you have to
keep protecting it.
Funny thing is, deep
down, you really should
feel guilty about having it.
So when someone really wants
your money, he can get it.
See, you want to give it
away, because deep down you
feel uncomfortable having it.
I don't know.
I guess you want to be
even with everybody else.
Why don't you take
the Cadillac too?
Take the money.
Leave me here.
By the time I walk back up to
the road, you're long gone.
Take the money.
You got to sign over
the registration too.
Take off your watch.
What?
The gold watch.
I've been noticing it.
I want it.
My watch.
What about my kids?
I told you not to worry, man.
What about my kids, Roland?
I want to get the
car started first.
I want to make sure there
are no double crosses.
They're at the shopping mall.
They're in the parking
lot at the shopping mall.
You rode right past
them, you dumb bastard.
They're in a blue VW, man.
They're locked up.
You got my kids
in a locked car?
You son of a bitch.
Hey, hey, hey they're fine.
They're fine.
A blue VW-- you
can drive it home.
Is that a car?
It's OK.
They're OK.
Where are the
children, Richard?
They're--
Where are the children?
They're safe, honey.
They're all right.
Where are they?
I took them to the hospital.
He had them in a locked car.
I don't believe you.
They're OK.
I'm telling you.
We'll go see them right now.
Go get the keys to your car.
Honey, he took my car.
We'll got to the
hospital right now.
I'm going to call the hospital,
and if they're not there,
I am calling the police.
Ellen.
Howard was right.
We should have
called the police.
This is all your fault.
God damn it, go do
whatever the hell you want.
It's not my fault.
Mr. Banks?
What the hell do you want?
Where's Roland?
And how should I know?
He didn't hurt the children.
He left them in a locked
car in this god damn heat!
He just wanted the money.
That's all.
It's all right.
They're OK.
Here's the keys to your car.
Go move it so we can get out.
Oh.
I'm sorry, Mrs. Banks.
I'm sorry for everything.
It's all right.
It's all right, Lucy.
It wasn't your fault.
Well, what about Roland.
Are you going to
call the police?
What's the point?
What about the money?
I don't care.
Guess I better move my car.
[car starting]
See, they're fine?
Hi, Mommy.
What's that bandage?
Oh, it's nothing serious.
As far as I can figure
out, she was playing
with the cigarette
lighter in the car,
and she's got a little
burn on her lip.
It's not bad.
Mommy.
Hi, honey, you feel all right?
We were locked in a car, mom.
Everything's going
to be all right.
Don't you worry about anything.
[children playing]
Yes, sir?
Hey, how you doing?
Good.
I'd like a room-- a
big one, by the week.
All right, just sign.
Hey, look, I got
this Caddy outside.
You got a bellhop?
Of course.
804.
95 [inaudible]
WOMAN [ON RADIO]: Why
not come over right now.
You should see what's
happening in the game room.
Here you go.
Keep the change.
Thank you, sir.
Holy shit, [inaudible]
You'd never
get a job where I come from.
Look, I got this Caddy outside.
I want you to take it
to some indoor garage.
you tell the guys there
to wash it up real good.
And you tell them to
stow it someplace so they
don't have to move it around.
See, I won't be
needing it for awhile.
Yes, sir.
And bring the
ticket get back to me
and you give them this $10 bill.
Yes, sir.
Keys?
Thank you.
Hey, make sure you
give them the whole 10.
MAN [ON RADIO]: Hi,
you know that fellow
that wrote the song "the
best things in life are free"
was a liar?
Yes, he was.
And folks that say money can't
buy happiness, they're wrong.
I'm living proof of that.
I've got money, and I'm
happier than two skunks
in a crowded movie theater.
Friends, with money you can do
the things you want to do now.
Sit down at the most expensive
restaurant and order anything
you want.
And the waiter won't
snub you, neither.
No, sir, people
will look up to you,
call you, mister
instead of hey you.
-Listen, Lou.
-What?
I want you to give me a
few minutes of your time.
Have you got a few minutes?
I hope so.
[laughing]
That's good.
You've got time, Lou.
Now, what can I do for you?
Let me show you something.
MAN [ON RADIO]: Now, you may say
to me, "Bob, I can't do that.
I've been trying to all
my life to be a rich man,
and I can't make it.
I don't have the brains, Bob.
I don't have the luck.
I don't have the know-how."
Well, I'm going to
give you the know-how.
And you don't need brains,
and you don't need luck.
All you need is $7.98.
That's right, just $7,98.
Tell you what, send
me $8.00, I'll send
you my book and $0.02 change.
Put those two pennies in
a jar and read my book.
By following my
principles, that $0.02
will grow to $2, then 200, then
2,000, and maybe 2 million.
You can do it.
Get "The Poor Man's Guide to
Easy Living and Instant Wealth"
now, before you forget.
If I'm wrong, if you don't get
rich and learn to live easy,
I'll refund your money by
return mail, no questions asked.
Heck, I'm just a country boy,
and I could be wrong, I guess.
But listen, friends,
what if I'm right?
MAN [ON INTERCOM]:
--a gorilla so strong,
that it can bend a steel
bar from the top her head
to the tips of her toes.
You'll see the hair grow.
The ape girl, the
ape girl, the ape
girl-- she's alive,
so much alive
that only the brave are invited.
Princess Uraina,
the gorilla girl.