What about it, Komorov?
We're in deep shit.
Yes.
Blessed I'll be to receive God's gift.
His gift of free will
which makes us the master
of our own destiny.
But be careful, my children.
Don't let ambition and
the thirst for knowledge
turn into arrogance.
We can not strive to
win over the holy power.
Those who are longing
for it will pay the price
and their soul will only be the beginning.
Such power is reserved
for God himself only.
And there will be no
absolution for those
who claim such power for themselves.
Hell itself will rise
and through the Four
Riders of the Apocalypse
become the whip of mankind.
I looked and behold a pale horse
and its name that
sat on him was Death,
and Hell followed with him.
Amen.
How did you find me?
Well, you're not
exactly invisible, are ya?
You shouldn't have come.
I wouldn't have come if I
didn't need your help, Heinrich.
This name belongs to
a life I left behind.
You should know that.
Yeah, but this is important.
I need your help.
Nothing you can
say will make me leave.
Komorov.
Victor's killer?
Hm, impossible.
It's possible.
My leads are reliable.
I just need you there
to help identify him.
This here is my mission
now, my last mission.
Bullshit.
You're tryin' to
save one soul at a time
to wash the blood off your hands.
You wanna save souls?
Come with me and save all the souls
on this goddamn godforsaken planet.
That makes us even.
You won't ever see me again.
Maybe.
I heard that.
Blessed are those
who long for justice.
They shall be pleased.
I'll be back.
Never underestimate your opponent
and never lose your concentration,
even when you think
the battle has won.
Your opponent may take
advantage of your mercy.
This is where knowing your
enemy becomes very important.
Appear weak when you are strong
and strong when you're weak.
All warfare is based on deception.
Sun Tzu, "The Art of War."
Stoker.
Class dismissed.
Hup!
Darwin.
For you.
All right, honey.
Run along now.
Okay, Daddy.
Well now who the hell's that?
Ain't nobody got this number.
Ain't got no idea.
It's me.
Well, horseshit.
What you want, Stoker?
Long time no see.
Not since the Espiritu Santo.
What's up, Zimmerman?
Look like you
gained a little weight.
Look who's talkin', old man.
I'm surprised you aren't
wearing any glasses.
Well, I usually hit what I aim at.
I don't need to see it.
How 'bout you?
Hey, I never doubted
you for a minute.
Hey, John.
Are you finally finished here?
Gimme 10 minutes.
Well let's say 15.
Yeah, yeah, right.
What do you think?
Yeah, yeah, you still
got it, baby girl.
That's the newest
explosives from our company.
No shit?
That big explosion came
from a little girl like you?
I figure with the
right gear we could carry
more explosives than
on our last mission.
We?
Who said anything about we?
I just came here to say goodbye.
We went over this last time.
You can't keep protecting me.
No, no, this mission
is much too dangerous.
How can you tell me
you're going to capture
my father's killer and then
expect me to just sit at home?
You know something?
You're just like your
father, ornery and stubborn.
You coming or not?
So, you wanna play, little man?
I gotta admit, I'm kinda impressed.
You can take a lot more
than most other people.
Maybe you're into pain.
Whatever.
We got all the time in the world.
And then at the end,
I will break you.
You are gonna tell
me whatever I want.
Please, can I have my gag back?
Your wish is my command.
You want more pain?
You shall have it.
What you doing
laying around here for?
We've got work to do.
Yeah, tell me about it.
Uh-huh.
Oh, you don't have to be
able to travel into Belgium.
Way too known over here.
No, we got all the people we need.
Howdy, y'all.
Darwin.
In the flesh.
Look around ya.
Everything of what
you see is nowhere,
and y'all in the middle of it.
Here.
Synchronize now.
Radiation's got it so that we
can't be here longer than 36 hours.
Of course, unless you
wanna glow in the dark.
What kind of place is this?
This used to be a
Soviet mining facility.
Guess they were excavating
shit until that one
fine April day when they
decided to quit outta the blue.
The catastrophe?
Well, whatever happened
happened a couple of days
before the disaster.
Whatever it is they found in there,
they didn't want
nobody lookin' for it.
Of course that ain't gonna
stop us now, ain't it?
Watch this.
Nice.
Thanks, cowboy.
God dang it, I'm gonna
shoot the next person
that calls me cowboy.
I done told you, no
nicknames, butter knife.
Where are the others?
John's up at the lookout.
Stoker and the
priest are out and about
meetin' up with a contact
and gettin' somethin',
I don't know what.
But come on, I'll show ya the rest.
What's that?
This is all you, Reiko.
Stoker wants to see what's inside.
What do you think?
This is Soviet made, not
the usual American trash.
Which means it might take
me a while to open it.
I can blow it up.
Well, I like the
cut of your jib, little lady,
but this here ain't
no Barbie doll house.
Whatever's inside Stoker
wants in one piece.
Hey.
Aren't you on guard duty?
Look around.
Who is going to find us here, hm?
This here is dynamite
left over from the Soviets.
Check it out.
Well, that leaves you and me
with the equipment on the bus.
Come on.
By the way, who's the little one?
Laurie?
Mm.
I'll warn you,
mate, she's explosive.
Trust me, I have
no idea what I'm doing.
Now you listen up.
I don't care who
you are, or who you know,
or what you think
you know about me.
I'm not a little girl.
Who do I have to fuck to get
some respect around here?
I need some help.
Give me 15 minutes.
Oh man, fuck off.
Too bad you ran, man,
at Spiritu Santu.
Come on.
Ah, we were getting worried.
Meeting in five.
Hey, you look like you
could use a drink, amigo.
Too weak for me.
That's something for pussies.
Hey, may I?
I really could use some.
Thanks.
What is this?
Where the hell does
this shit come from?
Brewed in
Texas, just like me.
Say hello to your new
best friends, Komorov.
This man is our phantom.
I've been looking
for him for a long time
with no success till now.
Underneath us is
a vast tunnel system
built by the Nazis
during World War II.
What was its purpose?
A command center underground
in case of another war,
invisible to the skies.
All right, and what's that
go to do with this asshole?
This man knows these tunnels.
He's going to be our tour guide.
This man killed my father.
Where did you find this guy?
My friend, Sergei, he bumped
into him in the Ukraine.
I want to see his face.
Okay.
Wait.
He is Komorov.
You have no fuckin' idea
who this man is, do you?
We're in deep trouble.
Where you going?
Get my rifle.
Hey, Stoker, what the fuck?
What about it, Komorov?
We're in deep shit.
Yes.
Why is that?
Take cover!
Oh shit.
Holy shit.
What the hell's goin' on out there?
Everybody all right?
I'm fine.
I'm okay.
Still here.
What do you see?
More than two dozen.
Armed, masked.
They don't look military.
All right, everybody take
whatever you can carry.
Let's get the hell outta here.
You're with me, little lady.
Don't you want a weapon?
I got everything I need.
The name of the Father, the Son,
and the Holy Ghost.
Amen.
You really think this is
the right time for that?
Hell, didn't know
there was a wrong time.
My God.
Drop the gun.
There are more coming
in on the west end.
Cowboy, Laurie need support.
Copy that.
Hold your position.
Goodbye.
Shit, there are too many of them.
Stoker, nice of you to join us.
I just finished talkin'
to John on the radio.
Well, it sounds like
these guys are outta ammo.
There's only one way to find out.
Right behind ya.
Hey.
Don't mess with Texas.
And stay down.
Cute.
Ashes to ashes, dust to dust.
We lose anyone?
John and Brenner.
Damn.
Good people.
We killed at least
30 of them, maybe more.
However, I count about 50
more on this side alone.
Holy shit.
Who are these guys?
All right, time to tell the truth.
I want to know why the fuck
people are dying out here.
What's this mission about, Stoker?
All right.
The Nazis were working
in one of these tunnels,
creating a secret weapon.
It was designed to help
Hitler win the war,
but fortunately he didn't
get a chance to use it.
This project was
called Atomic Eden.
The ultimate weapon
of mass destruction.
The power of God.
Doomsday device.
I mean, that's what we're
talkin' about, ain't it?
A motherfuckin' doomsday device?
Stay calm, soldier.
We believe the
Soviets found this weapon
and they created
a explosion on purpose.
It created a radioactive fallout.
The tunnels were blocked and
the area became uninhabitable.
Then why the fuck are we lookin' for it?
Things changed.
Since the disaster, radiation leakage
has minimized significantly.
Now, we can walk
through certain areas
for small amounts of time.
Komorov knew where the weapon was.
He was selling it to the highest bidder.
That's why we have to find this weapon.
Weapon can not fall
into the wrong hands.
Who's ever out there, they are after it.
What equipment do we have left?
Some weapons, but we are low on ammo.
There's the generator,
cable, and a few floodlights.
The rest is still in the car.
Still got that Soviet
dynamite in that old box.
Too dangerous.
The stuff is way too old.
Who knows if it's still reliable.
But I saw several chemicals
in the lab upstairs.
I could create something
similar to napalm.
Without enough ammunition
we won't stand a chance.
We can gather some
ammunition from the bodies.
Whoever they are, they
know our strengths now.
Maybe we should use that against them.
We secure the main
entrances by lighting them.
We have everything we need for that.
Nobody likes to sneak up when
an area is bright as day.
And if they take out the floodlights,
we'll know where they're coming from.
What about the main entryways?
I mean, hell, they could
get in through the windows.
We could secure the main entrances
with my explosive traps.
That should stop them for a while.
All right, people,
let's get on this now
before the sun sets.
Yeah, they could hit us
anytime from dusk till dawn.
Keep radio silence.
Let's move it.
David, would you gimme a hand?
It's a woman.
Who are they?
What are we looking for?
I don't know, I don't know.
Anything that we can
find that help us find
the exact position of this weapon.
I mean, I have one half of the map.
Komorov shows up, it's possible
he has found the other half.
A key.
I have a date with the vault.
Hey, Laurie.
I got one for ya.
Okay, what has 40 teeth
and holds back a monster?
My zipper.
All right, what the hell
do you know about funny?
Hey, will it work?
Bam.
The key fits.
Wait, wait, hold on, hold on.
How do we know this damn
thing is not gonna go kaboom?
It's a women's intuition.
If you are afraid, step back.
All we need now is the third part.
Well, maybe this is important.
Let's go join the group.
Son of a...
Okay.
You gonna help me with these
goddamn bodies or what?
Yeah.
We're getting close,
Heinrich, I can feel it.
Be careful what you wish for.
I have.
What the hell,
you wanna live forever?
If it is God's will.
I pray for you.
I need that.
Find any ammo?
Just a few clips.
Most of their weapons were out.
They unloaded on us so they
could better detect us.
Goddamn death wish.
Who the fuck
are these guys anyway?
Maybe they
find peace in death
that they never found in life.
Amen.
Aw, hell, Jesus wouldn't
have said it like that.
All right, cowboy.
Why don't you show me
what Jesus would say.
He'd say, rest in peace.
It was a damn good fight.
And stop callin' me cowboy.
Touching.
Waiting sucks, huh?
Hang tight there, little lady.
Nothing's moved.
Why doesn't Stoker advance?
May I, cowboy?
Wow, that's definitely the best
moonshine I've ever tasted.
Not too strong, not too weak.
Just perfect.
Well, hell.
Might finally get
a use outta these.
Can I ask you somethin'?
If it's about my father, then no.
Sorry you didn't get
to kill Komorov yourself.
Thanks.
To us.
To life.
How bad is it?
Deadly.
Forgive me, Father, my...
Goodbye, my friend.
God go with you.
We can't keep
this up much longer.
We won't make it
through another attack.
She's right.
We are running
out of ammunition.
We're running out of luck.
And we're running out of time.
Our Alamo.
It's time to go.
There's no shame in a
strategic retreat, sir.
To give them this
device is not an option.
It will cost too many lives.
Seems like an awful high price
for somethin' nobody wants.
You got something to say to me?
No, sir.
You know I follow orders and
lay down my life for you,
but this mission's been
desperate from the get go.
I'm all for tryin' to keep
this thing out of wrong hands.
All's I'm sayin' is, how do we know
who has the right hands?
Aw, shit.
Look, there's no
point in dying here.
Not now, not like this.
We'll get reinforcement,
new equipment.
We can come back.
If we leave, we come
back, it won't be here.
Then we will find them and
we will take it from them.
But now we have to get out of here.
Ethan, remember what
you promised my dad?
He wouldn't want us to die here.
It's not my plan to die here.
It wasn't my plan to
bring you here either.
You know you wouldn't
have been able to stop me.
Yeah, yeah, you're probably right.
All right, we can
escape through a tunnel
underneath the city.
Tunnel?
Why the hell didn't they use that?
I don't think they knew about it.
I saw it on Komorov's map.
If that's true, they have
nothing to do with Komorov,
which means they are here for us.
Son of a bitch.
They could follow us
through the tunnels.
Not if Laurie does her thing, right?
There's nothing in the
world I can't blow up,
but it's gonna take a while.
This stuff is really unstable.
All right, I say we move out.
They're probably planning
another attack on us right now.
All right, move out.
Careful, this stuff
doesn't like friction.
Well, I like friction, don't you?
Sure, makes me explode, too.
Gonna have to remember that.
Little lady.
So how does this thing work?
With adjusted time triggers.
They won't be too precise,
but they'll do their job.
We have 15 minutes.
And the tunnel?
I used my last bit
of napalm containers
and some wires for the entrances.
It's old school but it'll work.
Just be careful with
the wires, though.
When does the countdown start?
About two minutes ago.
Then let's get out of here.
Sniper.
I'm sorry I let you down.
Sir.
They will pay for this.
They'll pay.
Sir!
We have to get out of here.
Let's go.
Darwin, let's move it.
Good luck, partner.
Where's Darwin?
Didn't make it.
Let's go.
Attack!
Give me five minutes.
Fuckin' hero.
David, don't keep me waiting.
Haven't I killed you before?
Where was that again?
Espiritu Santo.
Yeah, you're right.
Shit.
Wait, we should wait for David.
I wouldn't worry about David.
He can take care of himself.
Take care of your mother, honey.
To me.
What is it?
I don't know, I don't
know, something's wrong.
I remember from the map,
the tunnel stops here.
But that's not true.
It continues.
We have to go.
It's here.
It has to be.
How is there power down here?
When the Germans build something,
they build it to last forever.
Mein Kampf?
I don't think so.
It's here.
I know it's here.
He can still make it.
Time's up, let's go.
Maybe the dynamite was too old.
No, no, trust me.
It's Laurie's way
of saying goodbye.
What?
Head down.
You da bomb, Laurie.
You're the real bomb.
David.
So, that's why all
those people had to die?
For a Nazi secret
in an old suitcase?
They sacrificed their lives
for the future of mankind.
Then why do I have the feeling
this should have remained where
it was, lost and forgotten?
Sooner or later Komorov
would have found it,
or somebody like him.
That's why we had to secure it.
And what are
you gonna do with it now?
You guys waiting for me or what?
And here you are.
One second, just hold on.
Is this what I think it is?
That's what we came here for.
You sure you won the fight?
You should see the other guy.
Yeah, right.
I hear traffic.
Home is that way.
Let's see.
The last time I saw you, you
were twice as big and black,
which means that
either the last mission
that you were on
completely changed you,
or you're not Stoker.
He couldn't make it.
Couldn't make it.
Well.
Ya see, I was really
hoping that you were
a white midget Stoker,
'cause we have a problem.
A big fucking problem.
You see, I had a date with Stoker
and you're telling me
that you're not Stoker,
and I really wanna
believe that you are.
So who the fuck are you?
Insurance.
Well, at least ya
did the right thing.
I hope so.
A lot of good people died for it.
Do you have any idea what this is?
This is the beginning and
the end of everything.
This is what every man craves.
This is what every man fears.
This is the power of God, man.
This is Atomic Eden.
Stoker trusted you.
He found out who Komorov
was, didn't he, goddamn it?
Goddamn the fuckin' Russians!
You'd think after years
of espionage they'd know
how to fuckin' keep a secret.
So that's why Sergei is off the map.
Now it's all starting
to come together.
Stoker thinks he's got the
upper hand, doesn't he?
Maybe not, but it's the right hand.
Where the fuck do you
think you're goin', punk?
Huh, you think this is a game?
Do you know how many
people are gonna die
to try to get that?
Do you have any idea
what you're dealing with?
Atomic Eden is ours.
You're gonna tell me
where I can find it
and gonna tell me now.
You can't kill me, not
if you want to find Stoker.
You tell Stoker if
it's war that he wants,
it's war he's gonna get.
Greatest victory is that
which requires no battle.
Sun Tzu.
Yeah, I know, "The Art of War."
Fuck you!
Yeah, it didn't go so well.
I was stood up.
Don't worry, we'll find him.
I got the best chefs in the kitchen.
Yes, sir.
I understand.
You're fuckin' mine, Stoker.
He won't stop until
he gets what he wants.
He's coming after you.
All right then, be prepared for war.