"I was like grass and I was not torn out."
Fernando Pessoa
What are you...?
- Stop it!
Stop it!
You stop it!
What are you doing?
Stop it!
See?
AUTUMN BALL
I forgive you everything.
Do you still love Jaan?
It always annoys me
when I go into an interior
which is not done by a professional
and I see that it is so good...
How can it be? I feel that
I should be the one to do...
And well I'm doing but...
You've got a problem.
Someone, who has not studied it
can suddenly do something...
Well, if one has a sense of style.
It's interesting the way
they've done it outside...
I wonder if it is finished
or still in progress.
They sure seem
to have something in progress.
Good party.
Listen Maurer you still live
in your... housing estate?
I do. - Why?
Practicing humility.
Yes, but really?
You're back early.
I'm so tired.
Of what?
With them everything has to be
so cozy,
pleasurable and soft.
With whom?
I cannot stand my friends,
colleagues any more.
That cynic attacked
me again today.
He asked me
why do we live here.
Does he really think
I'm insincere?
What a worm.
Yes, but really...
Why do we live here?
What?
I'm sure you could still be a fabulous
example to the mankind if you would live
a little bit closer
to the center of town.
What are you talking about?
Nobody lives here!
Here, there, over there!
Nobody lives here?
I'll get something to eat.
LITERARY CONFERENCE -
BALTIC CONCIOUSNESS 2006
Latvians and their hysterics again...
I don't think I have met you before.
I just came to eat.
What else is there to do here.
The presentations are as dull as always.
It is so contrived, the way
Eastern Europeans are continuously
trying to construct their identity.
Don't you think? - I do.
The West is financing
all sorts of nonsense,
trying to deal with its over fed guilt.
But all this financing is simply
a continuation of colonialism.
There is no such thing
as Baltic consciousness!
There is no such thing as Baltic!
Naming things is pure violence!
You are looking at me
as if I was an idiot.
You know it all yourself.
What's your sign? - Aries.
You don't live at all like an writer.
Have you read Pessoa?
"I made of myself something
beyond my knowledge,
And what I could make of myself
I failed to do..."
No, I haven't read it.
Who's Pessoa?
Who's Pessoa!
You're different.
You are... real.
Like a real person.
I'd like to read something
you've written. Will you let me?
I have nothing to give you.
You are modest, as well.
May be even a genius?
A quiet hermit noticed by no one...
But after your death your small,
shabby bachelor flat
will reveal the best text in
the world. - I'm a doorman.
I don't understand.
What is there to understand?
Maurer?
I saw a one-armed man today.
I'm saying that I saw a man
with one rotting hand,
drinking cologne
and smelling of piss.
Do we have to discuss this now?
Oh Jesus!
I'm afraid of them.
I'm afraid that I might get
some horrible disease from them.
Something really contagious
even through the air.
Is it awful of me to speak that way?
Is it, Maurer?
Can I speak that way?
Can I even think that way?
Can't we discuss
this in the morning?
Two rooms... That's normal.
Three is already a luxury.
Two rooms with a kitchen
and a bathroom.
Not bad.
Not bad at all.
I'm a very lucky person.
I'm done for today.
I'm not doing your clients.
What clients?
I've got no more
appointments for today.
What about the queue?
What queue?
Kaski!
The fact that you're Finnish
does not change anything.
This here is
a business establishment.
Success does not come overnight.
What we need is enthusiasm.
Don't call me! You're drunk!
Don't call here any more!
Well...
Yes, it seems to be working now.
I wouldn't say no
to a drink, if offered.
Such a ladies' drink.
Sweet.
Nice flat you've got here.
Lots of space. - Yes.
You live here alone...
I mean with your daughter?
- Yes.
It is not easy, everything
being so expensive these days.
And you, all alone...
And adults have their
needs as well, don't they.
What are you...
Oh no, don't! I'm just saying...
I'm just saying I know!
Sometimes these needs
overwhelm you so that...
And it's not getting
any easier with age!
Stop talking!
Listen young lady, don't be so...
I could... with you...
I'm a complete stranger to you.
We can be honest with each other.
There is no point...
You have my number.
If there is anything...
Laura!
Wait!
Listen!
I want to see my daughter!
You're drunk.
This is unfair!
I'll have her
taken away from you!
I know about all these men
who go to your place!
Don't think that I don't know...
You are a slut!
I'll kill you!
Lotta! Come in! You'll catch cold!
What is this film about?
That woman is the main character.
Her love is forbidden love.
- What is forbidden love?
It's love that is not permitted.
Have you read Pessoa?
"I made of myself
something beyond my knowledge,
And what I could make of myself
I failed to do."
I know one too.
A pig and a duck had a good fuck.
No! No!
A pig and two ducks had a good fuck!
It's from Marjamaa region.
I'm sorry. You're a cool guy.
No offence.
My bad mouth...
You're cool.
It's nothing personal.
You're very cool.
What a bad mouth!
I'm really sorry!
If we have some time later on,
we'll feel sorry for you.
I'm so sorry.
MERIKE - Aquarius
Listen, I was thinking...
If you've got time
and have nothing better to do,
could you keep the front
of the restaurant clean?
How?
With a broom or something.
But I'm the doorman.
Well, we all have our responsibilities.
You have yours and I have mine.
I'm the manager here and
your job is to keep things tidy.
Differentiated task management.
I understood that it is not my job
to clean around here.
So, we seem to have
a difference of opinions.
But I'm the manager here.
Cleaning is not my job.
Not your cup of tea?
And where is the jacket?
The Jacket!
Employees work!
Writers read books!
Hello? - Well, congratulations,
God damn it! - About what?
You really don't know?
Everybody knows.
No, I don't.
- You've been given
The Cross of Terra Mariana
and a hundred thousand kroons.
The Cross, to me?
- Yes, to you.
It was in the paper as well.
Did you believe me?
No, I didn't.
I've already made this joke to five
people today. Everyone believed me!
Piss off with your stupid pranks!
Listen, have you heard people saying
that I have gone mad? - No, I haven't!
It's not boredom that ends love,
but impatience.
The impatience of bodies yearning
to live, yet dying each day.
Impatience of bodies dying
day by day, but yearning to live...
and not letting go a single chance.
Who wish...
Impatience of bodies yearning
to live but dying each day,
Bodies that cannot
miss of single chance...
Who wish to make the most of their
limited, diminishing, mediocre lives.
Who can't...
Who wish to make the most of their
limited lives and cannot love anyone
because all others seem to them limited,
diminishing and mediocre.
Limited, diminishing and mediocre.
Who cannot love anyone...
It is not boredom...
So poorly printed.
Such a lousy print.
Is it really that much?
Natasha! - Yes?
How much is "Maaja"?
- Forget it.
What's that?
- The porn magazine!
Doesrt it have a price on it?
It does but the print is so bad,
I can't read it.
Hold on, I'll find out.
- Forget it.
How much is "Maaja",
that porn mag?
Yes, porn. It does, but the print
is so bad, impossible to read.
Well, there is,
but it is impossible to read.
Thirty nine kroons.
- Thirty nine?
Thirty nine, it's clearly visible.
Well yeah. I also looked that
thirty nine, but that seemed too much.
Thirty nine, it's quite clear.
What is going on here?
What are you doing here? Dear God!
I... I just...
- I know your sort!
You're not going anywhere! Pervert!
Look! There is a pervert!
Where are you going now?
Jump in, I'll give you a lift.
Closed all the time.
Bad road.
You must be wondering
about my behavior.
I have been watching you
from a distance for quite a while
and I like you.
You are sad and...
...Ionely.
You have... class.
Be mine. - Why?
There is no fairy in my house.
Or do you despise people like me?
- Like what?
Perhaps you want to kiss me?
Lotta!
Do you remember
what I told you about strangers?
You mustrt accept anything
from strange men.
What does 'pervert' mean?
It is very important
where and how I live!
I'm an architect, not an estate agent!
- I see. You're a maniac.
Don't look.
Some psychopaths don't like it
when you look them in the eye.
Why did that doorman
look at you like that?
I'm afraid the kitchen is closed.
Give me a bottle of brandy.
Waiter! Bring me champagne!
You are divine.
Like Aphrodite rising from the sea.
You know?
No, I don't. Behave!
People are looking.
- What people?
They're automats.
You know, my wife left me...
because of my friend...
Lets drink!
Hello!
Drinky drinky.
Don't be so conservative.
So reserved.
It's not a beauty contest!
Let's drink!
Why do you always
wear that same dress?
What? - Shut up!
I'm bored with it.
Your breasts are
too small for this dress.
Hey, young lady! Respect!
Thank you for the lovely evening.
What's wrong?
I cried your shirt wet.
I'm sorry.
Where did that woman go!
- What woman?
Get my jacket.
I'm sorry.
I don't know what came over me.
Give me the keys!
Let's drive around for a bit.
I'll drive.
Let's drive, we'll go to my place.
- Please. Please stop.
Where are you going?
Please don't!
Dont go.
Bastard!
- I'll drive the car into the tree!
You hear?
How did you sleep?
Are you drinking this?
Very good!
Shit,
my shirt is so ugly.
These...
These are large eggs.
Large eggs.
Anton!
Why are you dressed like that?
I got a job. It's impossible
to survive as a sculptor.
Your car is not properly parked.
Three rooms is something
completely different.
Twenty one thousand kroons per
square metre. Pretty sweet isn't it?
I think it's safe to say
I'm a very lucky man.
But you, now that you're alone,
you should sell your apartment.
I don't know...
- Or find a new woman.
Where? How? I don't know how.
Then you should sell the apartment.
I just don't know
how to approach women.
It's very easy to approach women.
You should find out
when a woman is ovulating.
Women are extremely
receptive during ovulation.
But of course mainly to the men
who have angular jaws
and lots of body hair.
Do you have to stick
these things everywhere?
Egoist!
You see? See!
Ovulation? What ovulation?
I saw it on Discovery Channel.
- Discovery?
Fuck off!
I don't think I've ever eaten here.
Exquisite cuisine.
I have enough money now
to buy two skip containers.
What?
Skip containers.
Skip containers rental.
For construction waste and garbage.
First I'll take two,
four and a half cubic meters.
Later when the money
starts to pour in I'll take ten,
fifteen, hell, thirty cubics!
For tractors, dump cars,
the whole deal.
Think how much construction
takes place in this town.
Think how much
construction waste it leaves.
I'm not going to be
a doorman all my life.
That is all just fine...
But I have to be going now.
Please wait!
Wait!
What just happened?
Nothing happened.
I just have to go.
But I thought...
we had something.
Don't say you didn't feel it.
Yes, I felt it.
So what happened?
Theo, I just really have to go now.
Give me your phone number.
I'll call you.
Where have you been?
You know how much construction
waste the city generates?
I asked you a question.
- I'll ask you something as well.
Will you? - Yes, I will.
Well, ask then.
Lets talk honestly at least for once.
Honestly?
Yes, honestly. Not being afraid
to appear in a bad light.
Honestly?
- Yes, honestly.
Honestly.
I'm bored with you.
Your dry skin. Your cold eyes.
Your petit bourgeois egotism,
which is so vibrant and natural,
but to my mind
it is just plain stupidity.
I'm bored with
your childish craving for attention.
I'm bored with your...
...femininity.
And you think I'm the problem?
I don't care about the reasons.
Do you know what you are?
You're like some Bergman character,
not even human any more.
Tiny little man suffering
because of your God's silence,
squirming within his personal
black and white world.
Maybe... Yeah.
What are you?
What sort a man are you?
All clean surface and self-admiration.
That's what I think about
your clean surface.
This is complete
lack of responsibility!
You come here as you wish!
If you disappear one
more time, you're gone!
Is it clear?
Where are you going?
Get out! - Shit!
Don't treat him like that.
He's a great actor and director.
- How great?
Rather well known.
What do you direct?
Relationship comedies...
Relationship comedies?
Relationship comedies.
I came.
Yes.
You must hate me so much now.
These buildings cannot
hold the past very long.
I guess that's because they were
built thinking of the future.
I just wanted to be happy.
I want to be happy?
In every fucking
little box out there,
there is a human being
trying to be happy.
Whole generations of mothers
and sons, fathers and daughters,
spouses, their lovers,
car owners...
Everybody wants to be happy.
And their lives blow past like wind
against the grey limestone walls.
And what is going to last of it all?
Maybe you don't believe me,
but I still love you.
I don't believe.
The movie is inspired by the book
"Autumn Ball" by Mati Unt
and dedicated to all the men
with gentle heart and weak liver
who stand alone
in the night in underwear.