MEMORIAL EYES
This movie is dedicated
to the crews of civil aviation.
His characters are fictionalized.
Nevertheless, the feat
performed on February 17, 1947.
over the Atlantic by one
by one of Air France's crews,
was inspired by the final
episode of the picture.
Calling Dakar Control!
This is the USS Mariner
Rescue, come in!
Calling Dakar Control!
Airborne Marine Rescue,
repeat: F-BARJ.
It's located 15 kilometers south
of Cape Cisneros.
Looks like the plane
has crashed.
There are two men lying motionless
two men lying motionless.
Send help right away!
Well! It's crazy!
In a coma?!
I've never seen anything like it in my life!
They're drunk as pigs!
What a shame...
No, look at that drunken face
at that drunken face!
This is what we came here for?!
They're lying dead!
Come on, get up!
Get up!
Get the stretcher over here!
Get up, you hear me?!
Not even a fracture...
A couple aspirin tablets will suffice.
I'm going to give it to them!
What were they carrying, these knuckleheads?
Liquor, Mr. Major!
Well, what's the matter with you
happened to you?
Oil pressure
has dropped to zero.
I had to sit down.
The airplane is junk!
It's a piece of junk!
We didn't know what to do...
in the desert. how to have fun.
So. while we were waiting.
Pulled the plugs.
What are you laughing at, old man?
Same as you!
Do you think the landlord
the landlord throw us out?
What are you doing? He wouldn't dare!
No, man, no!
Quit drinking!
So here are your tickets.
And your money.
It wasn't easy...
We leave in an hour:
don't drink any more!
Oh, Pierre! - Before the flight.
don't joke around, don't piss off the company.
Don't be stupid and take care
and take care of yourselves!
Come on, buddy, come on!
We were lucky, after all,
to have met him.
He was luckier! We
We met a friend, and he met two.
He's certainly got the upper hand.
I guess I'm a little short.
Hey, do it again for two!
Here you go!
- Thank you!
Is that for me? - Yes, Captain.
Diplomatic pouch.
All right, we'll take care of her
we'll take care of her!
Mademoiselle Mani!
Diplomatic mail is
of the utmost importance!
Do not use for cigars!
- We'll see to that!
Do you have a minute?
- Uh, yeah.
There will be two additional
passengers.
These are my friends--
nice guys.
They've been through
a serious blow,
and I'm asking you
to take care of them,
because they're a little
a little tipsy because they had a little too much to drink.
I'm gonna put them
in the last row.
Those bastards!
What? They just keep drinking.
On board, just juice
and vittel water.
Aubrey!
- Yeah, I'm coming!
If they demand beer
or whiskey, call me!
Attention! Attention!
Air France passengers,
traveling to Casablanca and Paris,
please come forward for boarding!
Bonjour, mademoiselle!
So you're coming with us?
- As you can see!
How did you like it this time in Dakar,
did you enjoy it? - The usual.
Then the usual!
You shouldn't have. You really shouldn't have.
Your belt, monsieur!
Mademoiselle, may I have a word
a word? - Yes, sir.
It's about the stroke, actually.
- Very well, monsieur, I'll take it under advisement.
Oh, no, no, no, no!
No "all right, monsieur"!
Just in case...
find it in this
pocket. see.
brand new razor...
You're going to oblige me by making
a small incision on my earlobe.
Do you understand? - You must rely
on me, sir. - Thank you!
Your belt, monsieur!
All right, master!
Where have I seen her.
Who?
- The stewardess.
I don't know her.
- I don't know her at all.
So what?!
I have a lot of memories,
but I've forgotten them all.
Would you like to come
sit next to me for a while?
I'd love to!
You know, I really love
this town, it's, uh.
I have my habits.
I don't know why, but.
you make me feel
safe.
Life is a strange thing!
Once upon a time.
I lived in Montmorency,
I used to ride every morning
on the 8:12 train.
and every morning I'd see the same people
in the same compartment every morning.
And in this airplane.
something similar.
It's awful what these commuter trains
these commuter trains have gotten!
Do you at least occasionally
change your route.
and fly one day
Somewhere in the--
See you later!
- At the little bistro?
The usual.
Don't say that
that horrible word!
What's the word?
- "Usually."
See you at the little
bistro. Not the usual!
We're going to be eating
brand-new dishes.
and exchanging completely
unprecedented kisses.
You know, I'd like to, uh.
at any given moment to think that we've only
we've only known each other a couple hours.
You think I'm stupid?
But I don't have time for calculations.
I feel like
you've fallen in love for the first time.
Do you understand?
Our love should always
to be like an adventure.
You--
- What?
I adore you!
Are you going to sleep here? - If you know everything
in advance, what kind of adventure is it?
See you tonight!
So what?
Nothing. See you tonight!
I'm sorry, I forgot something.
He won't come now!
He could have called you.
Maybe he tried.
Men are all made of the same
are all made of the same dough.
Mrs. Bastide!
Pepper, please!
May I? In the whole house.
there's not a pepper shaker left in the whole house.
Mr. Jacques picked up
picked up the last one.
If he deigns to return it,
it would do me a great favor.
Now, you'll notice that I realize that
every client has their own quirks.
One has corkscrews,
the other has ashtrays.
One colonel even stole a coffee grinder
even stole a coffee grinder right in front of me!
And he's got the Legion of Honor
of the Legion of Honor!
Thank you.
I gotta go. Uh, just hold this table for me
this table for me tonight, okay?
If he happens to call,
tell him I'm on Segur 23-15.
All right. Uh-huh.
Stop it, stop it!
Fernanda, please laugh alone!
Hey, you, there, stop it!
Be quiet. Now...
Laugh!
No, that's not it. It's too serious!
Laughter is light and fun!
You have to laugh freely,
with the laughter of happy people!
Ah, there you are!
Take your time, okay.
No, no, no, don't rush!
I'm sorry we're
got here on time.
We can keep going, can't we?
We're not bothering you,
are we? Then fine!
So, let's get on with it!
Where was I?
What was I saying?
You tell me what it's about!
Nico! Where was I?
Oh, yes. yes, yes! You were saying
how healthy people laugh.
That's great!
Someone who has a good laugh,
isn't always a good actor,
but the ability to laugh
is often necessary.
Let's move on to another topic!
Let's take-- Claire!
If you would do us the honor
and take a few minutes,
to show off your talents,
you're going to make me very happy.
Come on, come here!
So, uh. look at me!
She's not bad at all!
She's late,
but she's worth something.
Look over there!
Over there!
From that look, you're able
to determine her virtues.
and her weaknesses?
Just like that,
by eye?
Sweet!
- Mysterious!
Smart!
Restrained!
Sensual!
Sensual, sensual...
Who can say it better?
Melancholy!
Innocent!
- Her role?
A stealthy ingénue!
A secretive ingénue? Not at all!
She's in love!
Romantic in love!
Who are you, monsieur?
It's not like you're on the roster
in this class! - No.
So what are you doing here?
You were walking by.
and decided to come in.
not a bad idea at all!
an opportune occasion.
soft grass...
Please make yourselves
make yourselves at home!
It's very kind of you
that you stopped by!
I have a few words
a word with Mademoiselle Mani.
What?! You're my date
making dates with me now?
You could have just
bring you back to your bedroom.
All right, say your piece!
Go! And if you get the chance.
come back to us!
So, where was I?
At "very kind,
that you stopped by!"
I came from Jacques.
Did something happen to him?
- No, nothing serious.
Nothing serious?
Is he hurt?
No, he wasn't hurt at all.
Why would he be hurt?
He must have told you
to you about me? About Paul?
No. Why?
Except for the jokes?
- No kidding.
That's great!
He told me about you
he told me about you!
We should have had lunch
together, but we didn't!
This is ridiculous!
So what are you here for?
I came from Jacques.
- I get it. What's next?
First of all, he apologizes
for not showing up for lunch.
Well, there's no way he could have
told you about me!
What a strange guy: as soon as he says goodbye to you.
as soon as he says goodbye to you, he forgets!
I love him, that's clear, otherwise
I wouldn't be here right now.
Well, uh. I've been thinking all along the way
about how to tell you.
And when I came here, it was over!
I can't say a word.
Mind you, I could have
not care about that,
because I won't see you
You'll never see me again.
So be it!
He's not coming over
to have dinner with you tonight.
And on other nights too!
He doesn't care about that!
And don't look at me
like it's my fault!
I'm an honest man, and I'm fed up
and I'm fed up with other people's misdeeds,
that I don't do myself!
Calm down. And give me
me your hand!
It doesn't matter at all!
Wow!
You're unusual.
Is he leaving?
Where's he going? - Dakar.
I'm tired of pretending
of pretending to be an air cab.
Found a company in Senegal
a company called CAFA.
"African Air Transportation Company
air transportation company.
Flying among the Moors
it will change our minds.
I'm a mechanic, and he
could have told you that.
И... how long had he been
this negotiation?
Yes! Two months. And four
four days ago, I got an answer.
Well, that's great!
When do you leave?
- Two hours from Orly.
Anyway, you came in
at the last minute.
Yeah, but not because, uh.
- Because there's nothing you can do?
You've got it all planned out,
my admiration!
What's that with you?
What's that look on your face?
Shake it up!
No, it's fine!
I thought, "She'll do what everyone else does,
"maybe slap me around a little bit,
and be done with it!"
You've stumped me!
At least you're smart.
I'm sure if he knew
if he knew how sensible you are.
Well, what's done is done,
and we won't go back to that.
If you want, I can give him
I can give him a message.
Have a safe trip!
I will. I will!
And thanks again!
You're welcome!
Cab!
What will be mademoiselle?
Cognac.
A bottle of Perrier, Leon!
Hey, you?!
Well, that's it...
Lie down for a night -
and you're good to go!
Shouldn't we be warning someone
to warn someone?
No?
You don't need anything?
Would you prefer
to stay here?
Great! If there's anything
if you need anything, don't hesitate!
Chief Stewardess Marigny.
And that's why you
you wanted to die?!
Sounds like a femme fatale...
Handsome, isn't he?
Drink up!
And don't worry!
I'll keep your secret.
You don't have to worry
because of some fool!
Drink up...
Tasteless?
Here, take
a lump of sugar!
Anyway,
the play is over.
You'll make me happy
if you live. And you will live!
A little later, when you've come to your senses
we'll discuss it.
The future awaits you!
...If you know English,
is never bored.
And I speak
in English.
There's a great way
a great way
to have an English mistress.
I have a girlfriend--
a lovely girl.
Excellent girl!
While I was with her,
and I learned English.
I'm a fast learner, though.
I just crushed
that English.
How funny!
We arrive in an hour, sorry!
- Yes, yes, go about your business, please!
Claire!
I'm sorry, please!
I'm sorry I didn't recognize you at first,
but it's so weird.
to meet here.
Just think about it!
You're the last one...
The last woman
I knew before I left.
And the first one I met.
coming back after three years!
Isn't that great?
Jacques!
You don't remember me?
Jacques.
Well, answer me
something!
You're right: it is
incredibly funny!
You could have said hello to me
to say hello,
if you saw that
I didn't recognize you.
Especially since I'm with Paul!
With Paul?
- Well, yes! Yes! With Paul!
Paul admired you so much!
You know, I've often thought
about you. You have!
And to meet you here,
today. is a sign for me!
I don't believe in accidents.
If we're meeting
now, it means, uh.
But, uh. really. what made you
did you choose this profession?
Didn't you have, uh.
a different calling, didn't you?
Yes. Theater!
Are you still
living on Charles-Mont?
Oh, Rue Charles-Monet!
Claire, I want to kiss you!
You should go back to your seat.
It was good to see you!
Oh, don't talk to me like that!
Do I mean anything to you
I mean something to you!
And then, uh. after everything.
you remember me like the others.
You said "like the others."
I'm sorry!
Claire!
The stewardess is Claire!
Yes, yes, yes, yes! I assure you.
it's Claire!
Is that what you think?
What will it be, Mademoiselle Mani?
Cognac.
Oh, yes. Cognac!
What are you doing here alone?
You're drinking cognac?!
Isn't that amazing?
- Yes!
Why?
It's weird seeing you
alone in a bar.
when I just saw
something incredible!
What's unbelievable?
I can't say.
Pay up and let's go!
Well, are you coming?
The car's waiting.
Does that remind you of anything?
How do you know?
- It's not hard to guess!
Uh, do you drink cognac?
- She drank to her memories.
Aha! I couldn't get away
from those two guys! - You didn't?
They've been asking me
a bunch of questions about you.
These two are friends of mine from the war.
from the war, the good guys!
So you met!
What did he say to you?
Who? - Don't make me
a fool! Forestier.
Well, there you go.
- Thank you.
Why don't we have dinner together?
- Oh, no, I'm exhausted.
I need a shower
and my bed.
Going to your place?
Oh, mademoiselle, first.
I'll take my things first,
and then, if I'm not too
tired, I'll go for a drink.
with two of your fans.
I don't know what you
told them on the flight,
but you made quite an impression
a big impression.
Especially on Forestier.
Huge!
Will you see them?
They want me to help them
them back into the company.
If only they'd pour
more water in their wine!
Good night!
- Can I carry your suitcase?
No, monsieur, thank you.
See you tomorrow!
Why are you looking
looking at me like that?
You look unusual.
You seem upset about something.
Only by my fatigue!
Then get a good night's rest!
Hey, time to get up!
So, uh. What's the matter?
Who sleeps till noon
at your age?!
The maid has to clean
the bedrooms! Hey, get up!
Oh, you look great!
No, I mean, what's the big deal
dragging people around.
without warning
from your own bed?!
You're gonna have a heart attack!
- Hold this!
Good morning, Philippines!
Why do you call him that?
- He's got a chubby ass.
Hey, uh, this is the same room
where I lived three years ago.
I recognized it after all! - Huh, and it's still
the ring on the curtain is missing!
Here, drink this!
It'll help you.
What is it?
- Aspirin.
Yeah, there's someone downstairs
looking for you. I'll go get them.
Lorette's mom hasn't changed.....
That's just the way it is!
To think of it. Claire!
- So?
Nice girl.
- О!
That's better, guys!
Oh, it's Kiki!
Hey, me first!
- No!
He's been nicer to me
nicer to me than you!
So much for getting even with me!
It's so good to see you!
You still live here?
- Yes. And still in the same room.
Oh, you're here!
You found them.
She will not relinquish her place
on a cannonball!
What the hell is that?
- Your suitcase.
You left it in my custody
three years ago. It's an honest home!
Nothing important...
But thanks anyway!
Oh, boy!
You're such a slob!
Wow, that's funny!
Did you collect pepperoni?
- Monsieur's secret passion...
Cretin!
Oh, I remember...
When we went to the dance,
I gave one of these to Claire.
Will you give it to me?
Well, it's a souvenir.
- So give it to me as a souvenir!
Here you go!
- Thanks, Paul!
Anyway, I don't owe you
I don't owe you anything, and that's fine!
Tell me something.
- What?
Let's go out to dinner tonight.
all three of us.
Oh, Mr. Jacques!
What a surprise!
That's so sweet! Especially since
we've had everything taken away!
I'd like to introduce my friends:
Mademoiselle Ketty, Monsieur Paul!
It's a pleasure!
- Nice to meet you, too.
Well, what good things
to offer us?
I'm starving!
What, we're out of rooster in wine?
But it's the rooster in the wine that I want!
He always wants
for something he doesn't have!
There's still
some rooster in the wine!
I'm telling you I don't!
Good afternoon, Mrs. Bastide!
- Oh, Mr. Jacques!
How wonderful!
Wait, I'll wipe my hands.
Who have you become
in that time?
A lover of rooster in wine....
What are you looking for?
Oh, this is just what I was looking for!
Terrible!
After all, it's not every day
every day you come back after three years!
You know she's here?
Have you seen her? - I knew it!
It's me again!
I know: I heard you.
Do you mind if I, uh.
if I sit at your table?
Besides, I'm done with dinner.
You didn't forget about my
dessert? - Uh, no.
What have you been reading?
Oh, very nice...
Come on, tell me!
But first. first.
look at me!
You haven't aged a bit.
What about me? How do you find me?
What have I done to you?!
Are you gonna act like you did yesterday?
You can't be mad at me
just because I didn't recognize you!
If I'd only been told
that I'd meet you as a stewardess!
Bring me, too.
strawberries and sugar and the bill!
We're not gonna stay
here all night, are we?
Are you still
not drinking coffee? See?!
I remember that!
It's like you never
never left my side.
Coffee, as usual.
- Two coffees!
How funny! And here I thought
you hated coffee.
You can have dinner without me!
We weren't expecting you!
Come over here!
He's overreacting...
I am a woman after all.
- Yes, you are!
You're not interested
how I lived after you?
In fact, how long have we
were together? A month?
8 days.
No?! How much we've accomplished
we've accomplished in eight days!
We went to a dance,
taking pictures at the fairgrounds
near the Invalides.
See? I didn't forget anything!
And the night at the Merano Circus.
Remember that too?
Of course I remember!
- Liar!
Our feet were never there!
And I feel like
like we've been there too.
Since yesterday. I've been thinking
of you. incessantly!
No, no, that's right!
I can even think of
a lot of tiny details.
Like how you told me
that I was, uh. like I was falling in love for the first time.
You're the one who told me!
I remember, as you can see!
I hope you didn't believe me!
But isn't the fact that I left,
without daring to say goodbye,
doesn't prove that it, uh.
upset me?
But now it's over!
I'm very happy to see you.
It's even better that I made you
forget about the guy who went to Dakar!
I even deserve
respect because, uh.
he was three
three years younger than me!
All right, let's go!
See you tomorrow! I'm sorry, Kiki,
you're not mad at me?
What hard feelings?
Paul, you stay for me!
- All right, old boy!
I hate you!
I'll never be able
forget Berenice!
Do you remember how you were
practicing while I was shaving?
Never, ever, ever, ever....
I could not have loved
more tenderly. Never.
...then you're like, "Love me.
me, take care of me!"
And, helpless, I yield to the ingrate,
who leaves me without regret.
Uh, no, no, no, you're cheating!
You just jumped through a whole tirade!
And your poem has
at least three mistakes!
First of all, I'm not ungrateful.
Second, you didn't give in to me.
Third, I didn't leave you.
Claire...
Jacques!
Claire!
- Jacques.
No, don't make fun of me!
We'll be right back
at your house,
as if they'd left him
just this morning.
It was a short day!
I think you're missing something!
What do we do
if we're happy to meet?
Kissing each other?
Good night!
It's me again!
Are you obsessive compulsive?
- I'm here for a kiss,
that you forgot to give me
to give me. - Those cute little amusements.
to Rome. I know!
[Cell phone rings] Hello?
Police? Officer on duty?
What's with the weird reaction?
I don't have a choice, unless
you don't realize that, uh.
your presence
makes me uncomfortable.
You're a bad liar!
Too bad for a woman.
- Listen, Jacques.
You're a nice guy, but a little too
frivolous for my taste.
It's over
it's over, you know?
I've had enough!
And there's no use insisting!
You're always being cranky.
You want what you don't have.
But I'm no longer
on the map! I'm crossed off!
Stop being angry!
I'm not angry-- that's how much
I don't care about you!
If I loved you.
or if you loved me.
I would never forgive you!
Okay, okay. You
you want to seem unapproachable.
It's part of your coquetry.
And I, uh. pretend
that I believe you.
Claire hates me.
Claire curses me...
Claire is an unapproachable
personality.
Well? Are you satisfied?
And now that your honor
is saved. kiss me!
Get out of here! - How aggressive you are
aggressive tonight!
I was dreaming.
- You don't love me at all!
You mistake love for love
your stubbornness!
And yet. now.
I love you!
It's undeniable.
And it feels like
it's forever.
Maybe!
See, I'm being honest with you.
This would have been
dreamed of three years ago.
But three years ago, I was
I was already in love with you!
Just didn't realize it...
There are some things
we realize later.
You didn't seriously think that
I was gonna wait three years for you?!
That I have no one in my life?
- But I'm back!
And away with your paws! You're back,
but the seat's already taken.
Who?
Do I know him?
It's possible.
This guy is neither frivolous,
nor empty, nor reckless.
So he's an old man?
You're his age.
You'll never reach his age.
This is the age of reason.
It's not true!
What's his name?
Please leave
things where they belong!
In my day, it was standing
there. - In your time!
Well, let's talk about it!
"Hi! Bye!" -
that's our story.
You left just as
I was about to leave.
We owe nothing
to each other.
When your friend Paul
came to me with news,
there was already a letter in my purse
a letter about our breakup.
The thought came to us
came to us at the same time.
Because I was
so flighty back then.
frivolous.
that I looked like you!
And now, and this is something
you've got to deal with it.
I have a different
outlook on life.
So go away:
you're not for me!
How can anyone take
take you seriously?!
Look at you: Who are you?!
You come in through the window for a joke,
like the hero of an operetta!
But I don't want to have
to have any more fun with you--
go ruin other people's lives!
I don't have time!
Go away! The night is long and
full of accidents!
You're not saying
what you think you're saying.
Uh, hello?
Hello?
Mr. Aubrey?
Yeah, put me through to him!
Hello, Pierre!
I went straight to
to the phone.
Yeah, I'm alone. Why?
No, there was no one.
What's wrong with my voice?
No, I wasn't asleep.
Yeah, I had dinner at a little restaurant.
I got held up
because of some nerd.
Yeah. childhood friend.
We see each other once every ten years.
He likes to poke me.
and remind you of unpleasant things.
Uh, hello?
Oh, I don't know what's
on the line today.
No, no, no, I'm fine
I'm fine.
Just a little tired, that's all.
This is what's in your feet, and you can
you can move the cards.
Cover the lady...
...then the jack!
- I'd rather cover the brunet.
Shut up! - I don't know what happened to you
this morning! I'm sorry!
But you could have been
a little more polite!
Ketty, would you mind
leave us alone for a minute?
Not at all!
Okay, I get it.
Go get dressed! - Ha, you can
to say more than that!
Come in!
Still in bed? - In order to get him up
I'd have to get up early to get him up before noon.
Well?
So, uh. you've decided
to rejoin the company after all?
Pfft...
- Why not?
You don't seem very enthusiastic.
- What do you want us to say?
I gotta be honest, the thought of going back
to the company makes me kind of sad.
Life is too measured...
It's like I'm becoming
an aviation desk rat.
Anyway, you've got to live.
At 5:00, I've set up
for you to meet me at the office,
but if you'd like, I can
call and cancel it.
Oh, never mind
the whims of monsieur!
Monsieur has a heartache, Monsieur.
a slap on the nose, monsieur.
Shut up! - But, uh, let me--
- No!
I told you to shut up!
You got it?!
- Well, what did I say?
It's over, isn't it?
It's over!
Will the internship be serious?
- Very serious! Why?
Well, uh. I'm not sure
I can learn.
You know the basics,
they'll teach you the rest.
There is no limit
there's no limit to perfection.
It's gonna be fun!
I've been through it.
Didn't die, as you can see.
Don't worry! Our instructors
are friendly and understanding.
You'll see for yourself!
Good afternoon, gentlemen!
I have been entrusted with your training.
You have been accepted
for this internship.
thanks to your experience
from your experience in the military,
in naval aviation and
overseas.
But regardless
of your past.
Or from your experience...
you're on equal footing
on an equal footing.
Initially, I believe
that you don't know anything.
I'll start my training from scratch.
- Discipline, discipline...
Mr. Forestier, let's see,
how talkative you'll be,
when it comes to
when it comes to a pilot's knowledge.
In the meantime, I don't require
your comments!
Five more degrees!
Cap!
Can't you feel the wings?
How much longer do you have to be here?
- No. Five minutes.
Get back on the beam!
The car's waiting for us. - Do you have a seat
Do you have seats? - Yeah, for two orchestras.
Well, what else?!
What do you mean "what"?!
We're not done!
Close the hatch!
You pass the cone of silence.
What's your reaction?
You go to 2,000 feet,
not 1,200. Get back!
Get back on the beam!
What's wrong? - He's in a corkscrew
into a corkscrew, and that's dangerous.
Now you're dead!
Crashed!
You're going into a corkscrew
at 1,000 feet, that's smart!
So, am I still
piloting like a boot?!
And I don't know how to do anything?! Come on,
spit it out, I'll listen!
You have absolutely no self-control
to control yourself.
Yeah, well, now you can
get rid of me!
And I know why!
Come on, let's go! I've lost my
my flying qualifications, right?
I agree! But I told you
I warned you that I did everything I could to make this happen!
Like the fact that you can be a good pilot
pilot and the last donkey.
Haven't you realized that yet?
You didn't realize that I was supposed
to pick on you,
to get you
you to pull yourself together?
I wished you success.
There are people in the company...
are demanding and don't like
anyone who tarnishes her reputation.
I would never repeat
such an experience with a friend of mine.
This is beyond me!
I'm even crazier
than you think.
I don't think that's possible.
- And yet!
You should know what I was thinking!
I thought you were jealous.
- Jealous?
Uh, yeah. Because of Claire.
The other day when you
reprimanded me in front of her,
I thought it was on purpose.
I said to myself, "Aubrey, who
who was protecting me, wants to drown me."
Aubrey knew we'd met...
How would I know that?
Claire isn't being honest with me.
There's nothing between us.
Just a little bit of friendship...
As for the rest...
What's the rest of it?
- We switched roles!
You're the one who was jealous of me!
You're a terrific guy!
- Yeah, yeah.
You're the one who could have told me
that you knew me.
What did I look like?!
With your permission, I'll report
to the patron on the results of the training session.
You're not mad at me?
On the contrary, I'm grateful
for what you've done for me.
What did I ever do for you?!
Well, let's just say. you've pleased
me as, uh. as an apprentice!
Simone!
Oh, sorry, didn't see you there!
Are you in or out?
- I leave for Cairo in an hour.
Will you stop by my friends' house?
- All right, Sunday!
Bon voyage!
- Did you get my stockings?
Three pairs, gorgeous!
- No, leave them in the locker room for now.
I'll pick it up when I get back from Saigon,
and we'll settle up then.
Don't forget my friends!
- Okay!
Well, it's like the Merville market!
By the way, how's your fountain pen, steward?
- Thanks for the reminder!
Pierre!
What happened to you, Pierre?
You were supposed to call me three weeks ago
you should have called me.
I didn't mean to bore you.
What's that strange thought?
- It's nothing special...
I called your house--
no answer.
I'm sorry! But I don't think you missed me
missed me. - Not at all!
Are you from New York?
- Uh, yeah.
Good flight?
- It was great.
When are we flying
to New York together?
I'll be right there.
- All right!
What are you doing tonight?
Why don't we have dinner together?
Impossible.
I'm busy tonight.
Of course, I'm not at liberty to give you
advice, but you'd better go to bed.
New York-Paris is exhausting!
- We'd have a quick dinner.....
I'd love to....
Good luck!
And don't think too badly of me
too badly!
Ah, there you are!
Here's your goodies!
Your nylons...
Your cigarettes. Here!
My head is spinning!
- Why?
Look at me,
how exhausted I am!
I just met Aubrey, who
who said I look terrible.
No surprise there! Do you know
how much I have this month?
160 hours of flight time!
Can you believe it?
The day after tomorrow you're flying
Paris-Saigon!
Is this a joke? No?
No, they're not getting this!
Well, why can't I
fly to Dakar anymore?
What's the good
about this Dakar?
Sun and mosquitoes!
And you're complaining?!
Aubrey told me he didn't understand
why we don't fly together anymore!
Oh, really?
- Really what?
Nothing... Uh, are you sure
that Aubrey told you that?
Does that surprise you?
- More than surprised!
Look at the flight schedule!
See, when he flew to Fort-de-France
he flew to Fort-de-France,
I put you on the flight.
He asked me
for another stewardess.
On what pretext?
- No reason.
You could have told me!
For what?
So he asked you to, uh.
So when you say
that he's sorry.
let me smile!
I don't see what Aubrey
that Aubrey could blame me for!
And you don't hear what Forestier
Forestier could have told him?!
You're blind and deaf!
Absolutely!
I will demand that Jacques
to explain himself to Aubrey in front of me!
You won't demand anything
from Jacques. It's too late!
Because, uh. Aubrey's leaving.
What do you mean. "leaving"?
Yes. Dakar-Rio is flying
for the last time!
For the last time?
- Yeah. He's leaving for good.
Asked for an assignment
to Indochina.
Who's flying to Dakar tomorrow?
No, it's impossible!
- Why not?
Because Jacques!
Ah, Forestier...
Well, uh. if you would be so kind.
Sign me up!
You're crazy!
- Sign me up.
I thought you were tired...
Good afternoon! - Flight
Bordeaux-Madrid-Casablanca,
10,000 feet, alternate
Marrakech.
Is the paperwork okay?
- It's in order.
Good afternoon, commander!
О... that feels so good!
That feels so damn good!
Bring me the data
on the fuel! - All right. Uh-huh.
Here's the passenger list.
Did you know I was coming?
- Yes, commander.
I'm so glad to be flying with you!
- I'm glad too, Commander.
Stop calling me
Commander! - Yes, commander!
I love you!
If you call me
as my commanding officer,
I'll give you one!
- All right, commander!
Hey, old man!
Are you leaving?
Decided to meet us?
- Yeah, yeah.
Are you okay?
- I'm fine, thanks!
But it's true what they say,
that you're leaving us?
Yeah, I got the transfer.
A net loss for the company!
You could have at least warned your friends!
Well, it was good to see you.
See you later, buddy!
Pierre!
Back on the road again?
I'm here because of you.
Why didn't you tell me
you were leaving Orly altogether?
Well, uh. I have my own
my own little secrets.
Are you interested in them?
You wanted to say goodbye to me?
Look, I've got
I have other things to do on board,
but why don't we meet you
at the bar in half an hour?
Well, uh. why not?!
Got a razor, old man?
- Take it yourself!
Thank you!
Hey, you know what?
- What?
Claire's room.
- So?
Just because she's here,
next to yours.
So?!
- Come on, come on.
We'll die again
from the heat like the last time...
Hello, Gilberte!
- Are you here to stay now?
It's my pleasure to leave
my seat to you! What a hole.
I couldn't sleep, it was so hot!
Been outside half the night.
Okay, am I forgetting something?
Ah, the most important thing!
Goodbye!
- See you soon!
I guess I'll see you the day after tomorrow
in Rio? - Anything can happen!
Hey! Gilberte!
Your picture.
Oh, I'm sorry!
It's my fiancé! You know.
Do you have a soapbox?
- I used to. I lent it to Mulino.
Hey, Mulino!
Give me back my Forestier soap!
All right!
- I'll give it right back.
It's not on fire!
Soap! Catch!
- Thank you!
The sea! You can see it dancing.....
Along the clear bays
in the silver reflection...
Shit!
Hey, can somebody
lend me some soap?
Mine ran under the door.
A bar of soap, please!
Thanks, buddy!
Oh, it's you!
In the pool of whiteness
of bathing flesh.
I want to hold your hand
and give you back your soap...
Would you like to stop
and let go of my hand?
Say "you" to me!
I am naked, you are naked.....
When naked people come together in a place like this.
they say, "you."
You!
- You what?
I'm sick of you!
Let go of my hand!
Please!
Take your proud hand!
Claire... How beautiful is your
unadorned beauty.
a few meters away.
Claire!
Claire, I represent you, uh.
Your soap!
Here you go!
Claire?
The great battle
of the masters begins!
The killer will fall into our hands.
The poisonous creatures
scatter in terror,
but they'll be our prisoners.
And mosquitoes above all else!
Please do not disturb anyone's sleep,
especially between 10:00 p.m. and 7:00 a.m.
Ah, there you are!
A surprise visit like this
it's very kind.
Are you sulking?
I'm not pouting at all.
On the contrary!
I'm in a great
I'm in a great mood.
Life is beautiful!
Life is extraordinarily good!
What a miracle!
My dear Jacques. I have
wonderful news for you.
You asked me
to say "you" to you--
and I'm saying "you" to you.
for the last time!
It's time for me to share with you
my joy.
Jacques.
- Wait!
When people say "you" to me,
it's for life!
No!
Just for a week!
Jacques... My baby Jacques!
I'm getting married!
Married to Aubrey.
Pierre is for friends.
So, uh. I wanted to say
"you" to you good-bye!
So, uh. congratulate me!
There are ready-made formulas...
Liar!
To think that Aubrey decided
to step aside just because
that I imagined that you were still playing
some role in my life,
that you so subtly
hinted at!
Looks like you bragged to him
before you tried your luck with me.
I didn't say those words!
It's not that you left me
me, that you have a claim on me.
I took that flight
to look for Aubrey.
If you have a sense of humor,
laugh at this situation!
Can you believe it: you're the ones
you're the one who got me to Aubrey,
it was you who served
as my coachman!
Get out! - Tomorrow we're
we're meeting him in Rio.
Who's taking me there?
You, Jacques Forestier!
What? This is not what you
you were expecting from Dakar?!
This flight was worth it, huh?!
- Get away from me!
I'm sorry about that outburst!
I acted like a scumbag.
I couldn't help myself.
Claire. Can we be friends?
Leave me alone!
Friends?
- Okay, okay, uh. friends.
And a little smile
to smooth things over?
Just one smile...
It's settled!
That's not true, is it?
Aubrey?
That's not true!
You're kidding.
You don't like Aubrey?
Can you tell me
to my face that you love Aubrey?
I love Aubrey.
No-o-o-o.
- All right!
Aubrey's a nice guy, but there's nothing unusual about him.
there's nothing unusual about him.
Life with him is like a game
of dominoes, always by the rules!
No, no, I have a lot of respect for Aubrey....
He's well-mannered, courageous. precise.
judicious and honest.
Capable...
hard-working.
Discreet... educated.
well-mannered.
But he looks like an umbrella!
You're as ill-equipped
to live with an umbrella as I am...
That must be a strange girl
who fits what you've made up!
Virtuous!
Like a button on Aubrey's shoe!
Button!
- I want to live in peace!
Living on a schedule?
Typewritten?
Without a single typo?
Living without hope...
This life is simple!
You talk about hope--
I need security.
Ah, here it is. there it is,
the cowardly word!
For you to get married
it means getting insurance
against robbery, fire.
...and from love!
I have no ambition.
Attachment
is enough for happiness.
You don't believe my
Aubrey story?
You don't believe it's true?
How are all the stories without the tall tales?
It's true, I swear to you!
You know, for three years now.
we've been living our own lives.
You're going to laugh...
but when you left.
I experienced this
deceptive feeling,
this meaningless feeling
you call love.
Yeah, I wanted to kill myself
because of a guy.
the guy that I
took seriously.
but I haven't had much
experience in life or death....
and it didn't work out!
I was in the hospital
for three days, and, uh.
and I realized
how ridiculous I am.
There she is, Miss Gardenial!
It's me!
If you knew who this ridiculous drama
all this ridiculous drama was for.
No, let's be fair:
love is more than
a trivial event!
Good night!
Anyway. if I hadn't
hadn't left you, you would've--
Who knows?!
You wouldn't have met
with this guy!
Who was that?
Well...a man of your kind!
Why did you want
to kill yourself?
What did he do to you?
It's nothing! He just left me
all of a sudden.
But I left you, too!
And you survived it just fine!
Of course. you didn't love me
you didn't love me!
Three meetings...what do they mean!
A simple whim!
Please. don't
make a scene over something
that I didn't kill myself
because of you!
Did you, of course.
you went out with him afterward, of course?
Oh, you bet, Jacques!
You met him - and then?
Then nothing.
He wanted to start over
as if nothing had happened.
And I'm paying for it now!
- Quiet.
Yes... Yes, you're marrying Aubrey,
to get rid of him!
Panic!
You still love him,
it's obvious!
Just understand, this marriage is
is a second suicide!
Suicide,
stretched out over time!
Delayed suicide!
I'll be happy with Aubrey!
Claire!
Now I know who
you really are.
We met too soon,
we didn't know how to live seriously.
If we thought about us,
I'm sure we would love...
each other for real
until now!
It was all it took--
just a moment's attention.
I love you.
- No, no, you don't love me!
It's just a regret...
It's like when we
think of the dead.
"If I had known, I would have been
I would have been more attentive to her."
And it's not:
you wouldn't be any different!
Don't think about me anymore!
Don't think, because
it's not worth it!
You're mistaking
you're mistaking yourself for someone else.
I loved someone else,
not you, you fool!
Claire.
- No, Jacques, no!
Will you two stop yapping in there?!
I forgot to close the window.
- Never, Jacques, never again!
Hey, you're keeping people awake!
Stop yelling! Shut up!
- All right, all right. All right.
Are you happy now?!
Control tower?
Air France - BBDK.
We're at 3,000 feet,
five minutes north
of the landing site.
Come in!
Let the passengers know
that we're approaching Rio!
See you tomorrow!
- Bye, bye!
So you sure you're not coming
to the La Playa Hotel with us?
No, Jacques, I told you,
I'm expected at the Rio Branco.
I didn't lie to you.
- But, uh, I thought maybe, uh.
What is it? - No, nothing.
You made your choice.
Bye, see you tomorrow!
- Bye! Bye!
Wait a minute!
I'm booked!
Mademoiselle Mani?
- Yes. I have one!
Z08, mademoiselle!
- All right.
They're waiting for you at the bar.
Did you win?
How long have you been here?
Just arrived. And imagined
something like this!
Take it away!
Greetings!
I can't believe my eyes.
You're here!
Does that surprise you?
Go away, you liars!
I just wish you guys
to never regret it!
You know, uh.
I've already told you that
there's nothing unusual about me.
nothing dazzling...
But you can count on me,
I always keep my word.
I'll make you happy.
I believe you!
Did you explain yourself to Forestier?
He was forced to admit
that he had no rights to me.
He even apologized
to me.
It just touched me!
He can't hold a grudge against you.
I envy myself...
Imagine, I hardly know
I know almost nothing about you!
But I'll learn you by heart!
You'll find that with each passing day.
I'll know you better and better...
Well, I'm going to teach you right away
something very entertaining.
I'm very hungry!
How convenient: I know a great restaurant
a great restaurant!
Just a moment,
I'll take off my uniform!
Hurry up!
Do it again!
I love Rio! It's the most beautiful
city in the world! In the last 5 minutes!
I really love the left bank.....
Bonaparte Street ... Street of the Holy
the fathers. Tournon Street...
Neya's restaurant in the winter...
And starting in May.
we'll be living in Virofl.
I have a beautiful property.
For radishes alone.
I get up to 300 francs.
My mother manages
the household.
You'll get along fine with her.
I'm sure you do.
Shall we dance?
Please! Sit down!
- Ooh-la-la, yes, yes.
Did you hear that? Bottle
"ooh-la-la-la, da-da!"
Yes, that one!
I'm calm in my cubicle,
I'm my own boss.
I don't depend on anyone.
My crew is myself.
And what roads brought you
to Orly?
Oh, it's the other way around for me!
I need a panorama.
I love change...
new faces.
People in the air are different
are not the same as on the ground.
What about you? What will you drink?
- What are you drinking?
Uh...
- Yes!
"Yes, yes..."
You don't understand anything!
Other women, too.
women, too.
They're all foreigners.
I love you!
Ooh-la-la-la!
"Yes" and "la" are all words,
you know in French?
You're a cutie!
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
I'm a cutie!
Well, that's it:
it's all been said!
You'll let me, won't you?
All women carry
the same thing in their purses.
In my heart, though, too.
A pack of cigarettes, a notebook
notebook, handkerchief.
Mascara!
Lighter!
О! Do you have a revolver?
Souvenir? Love? No?
How much?
- 2,000!
Ha, the word "how many"
you get it right away!
You're a real woman!
Revolver. How much?
2,000! That's great!
All right, all right!
I drink and to life.
and death and everything,
that follows!
To the soul - and to oblivion!
Let's dance!
Let's dance. It's
it's also a way to talk!
Would you like to go back
to the table? - Yes, I'd love to.
We can leave.
- If you want.
Maitre d', the check!
О... what a meeting!
What, you think you're Robinson
you're Robinson?
Hey, Aubrey!
Good evening, Claire!
First of all, no
no misunderstandings or ambiguities!
Aubrey. as I promised
Mademoiselle.
I do solemnly swear
on this spot.
that there's nothing between me and Claire
there's nothing. Not even a little bit!
Just memories!
Friends?
No, no, let me!
It's for me!
Bring us
a pair for her!
I'm sorry, but Claire is tired.
You'd better go to bed.
I'll go, don't worry!
That's why Madame is here.
What is it?
You don't look
very cheerful, my children!
Oh, there's the girlfriend!
Thank you, buddy, thank you!
Some crave security...
Isn't that right, dear Claire?
Others crave madness.
Cabbies like me.
Isn't that right, dear Claire?
Shall we have a toast?
Ah, yes! I present
my fiancée.
This is the perfect woman!
Doesn't know anything
except the word "how much."
And you don't need more than that!
She's beautiful, isn't she?
Is she beautiful, my fiancée?
Good wives don't stay
more than one night.
Hey, hey? What's the matter with you two
with both of you?
You look like
both widowed!
You really are
pathetic.
Are you too well-mannered
to punch me in the face in public?
And for nothing! I'm so bored
here without entertainment!
No, Pierre!
He's not worth it.
Ah, I'm not worth it.
I'm not worth it!
Then I'm worthless,
and she thinks her love
for Aubrey is worth anything?!
She's driven by her love for Aubrey!
Goodbye, Claire!
You disgust me!
Yeah. It's pretty
disgusting.
This is my way
to say good-bye to you.
I don't want you
to have any regrets.
Because I have a feeling
I'm never gonna see you again.
My life is over...
along with the bachelorhood
life, my little Claire.
Tomorrow morning, you'll understand
what I wanted to say today.
No explanatory notes!
И... be happy!
Between you and me,
happiness is an illusion,
that we give ourselves.
Bye. Claire Aubrey!
Goodbye, Claire...
Goodbye!
363-й.
- Thank you.
Please wake me up
at half past five!
I don't have long to sleep...
So, Thursday at Dakar?
Yes, Thursday in Dakar.
- Remember me!
I don't forget.
Good night!
Your key!
- Oh, thank you!
Thursday at Dakar!
- Sure...
Hello? Hotel
"La Playa, please!
Hello, Hotel La Playa?
Is Mr. Forestier in?
Foo-rah-ho-ho-ho-ho!
Thank you.
So he's back?
Can you put him through
to his number?
Yes?
No answer?
Can you call me back?
Do it again!
Call again!
Uh, hello?
I'm sorry. But, uh.
Yeah, he's probably asleep by now.
Thank you.
Please...
Tell Mr. Forestier that Mademoiselle Manny
Mademoiselle Mani is asking for him.
That it's very important!
Hello? Hello?
Strange... The phone's been answered,
but no answer.
Hello? Hello?
Nothing...
- Call again!
I'm sorry, call back again!
No, he picked up the phone,
but he won't talk.
Thank you.
This is Forestier's room,
señorita.
Please open the door!
Mr. Forestier doesn't answer.
I'm sure he's not well.
Sick!
Mr. Forestier!
You came to make sure?
Not yet!
It's too soon!
Leave us alone!
You can have him!
I don't have to kill myself
to kill myself if you're here!
You're here...
Because you love me.
- I just didn't want to be guilty.
Otherwise. what do I have to worry about?
When a man wants to kill himself
he doesn't brag about it.
Oh. I forgot.
You're the expert!
What about Aubrey?
Good Aubrey! Sweet Aubrey!
How could he let you--
all alone, in the middle of the night.
to go to some monsieur's house?
He must be very
worried, poor Aubrey?
We have to calm him down!
We'll tell him that
it's okay.
and he can revisit
an interrupted nap.
Hello?
Hello...
Watch out! If you call
Pierre, I won't hesitate.
Well, well, well, Mani.
what are you waiting for?
Hello?
- Jacques!
Hello? Would you mind
bring me two whiskeys?
No!
Just a little while longer!
How could I have believed that
it was over between us?
That's ridiculous!
- Of course it is!
How could I have lived
for three years without Jacques Forestier?!
It's unimaginable!
And when he left me,
why didn't I tear my hair out
and screaming in public?
Why didn't I scream in pain?!
Why didn't you go crazy?
Why didn't you throw yourself into the Seine?
I could have made a big fuss,
instead of writing you farewell letters...
so that I don't overshadow
your life!
Silent suicide...
on tiptoe!
Claire...
Yeah, you're the reason
I wanted to die.
A common thought...
A little girl's thought...
We've been at odds
we didn't understand each other.
You were my first love,
and I was your casual girlfriend.
Oh, no!
- Yeah, yeah, remember.
I thought it was
for life.
Did you know that
just for a week!
I was making plans while you were
packing your bags.
Just a misunderstanding...
I don't blame you: after all,
you didn't promise me anything.
Another woman...
Does that count?
Maybe I meant a little
more. in retrospect.
We both had to suffer.
But now we're even!
If I said it now,
then there's nothing else I can do.
Nothing at all!
We're both totally smashed!
Claire!
It takes a miracle.
And there are no miracles!
I'm gonna make Aubrey happy.
regardless of us!
There's got to be
somebody's lucky!
It's gonna work out, buddy.
It'll all work out!
Here's, uh. the last memory
of our love.
and the final proof
of my trust!
No! No, it's over!
The decorations are ready!
Yeah. But they're kind of dirty.
It's a little early to be thinking
about a black coat.
Hey, put that one away!
I bet you can't do that kind of piggery
at home!
Then don't sit there in your socks!
My feet swell at altitude.
Crossing the equator soon?
Yes, but don't start the baptism until we've crossed
we cross those dark clouds!
There may be some chatter.
Will you be participating
in the baptism, commander?
If there's time, of course.
Please come forward for those of you who have
who have never crossed the equator!
For these people, we will prepare
baptismal certificates.
We'll be presenting them during
the traditional ceremony,
as soon as we cross
the storm front.
Whoever signs up first,
is the first to get it.
I don't get it!
We're issuing certificates
of baptism! - Ah, thank you.
Now, who has no certificate?
- Me, mademoiselle!
Я! Me, mademoiselle.
Me, mademoiselle!
For me, mademoiselle!
Turn on the ultraviolet!
Sometimes you can't see anything!
Looks like we made it.
- Yeah.
Yeah, we can see that:
4-meter waves...
I wouldn't want to go
to go to sea right now!
Don't drift, we've got
3,000 feet high!
I'm gonna come over and grab
something. I'll be quick!
Baptized in the name of a citizen
of the equatorial territories.
We are Neptune,
god of the sea and sky,
we welcome you
into our kingdom.
and by our divine
by our baptism we pronounce you.
a citizen
of the equatorial territories!
We are Neptune,
god of the sea and sky,
we welcome you
into our kingdom.
What's the matter?
- What's that sound?!
Is it serious, commander?
- No, it's nothing!
Nothing!
I'm counting on you:
nothing serious!
Which engine?
- Engine one! Overload!
I've lowered the revs!
I've disabled the automatics.
- All right! Flux!
It's not coming!
Fluctuate, damn it!
damn it! - It's not working!
Try again!
Slow down!
Am I sending an SOS?
- No, wait!
Just a warning!
Not an SOS!
The plane is on fire!
Fire extinguisher on 1!
- Fire extinguisher on one.
Flaps-15!
- Got flaps-15!
Reduce speed!
No. 1 is not jammed.
We're only at 145 knots!
The 1st is still sparking!
Any smoke?
- No, no smoke!
Give me our coordinates!
- Here!
Is it serious?
- Yes! Yes, it is!
If the screw doesn't stop,
it's gonna cut us into slices.
The 1st is on fire again!
Turning on the fire extinguisher?
- No! Wait!
The revs are down!
Keep it that way for now!
Watch the plane!
What's the contour?
About 8! - Should I turn on
fire extinguisher? - No!
Don't worry, everything's fine!
It's just a minor malfunction.
No, you're just trying
to make us feel better!
No, no, no! So, uh,
whose turn is it to be baptized?
We can still save the plane!
- Should I turn on the fire extinguisher?
Give me a second grade!
Send an SOS!
- Got it!
Paul, turn that sound off:
it's hurting my ears! - Okay!
Mulino, find me
some iron!
Turns to 30
and take off the flaps!
Turns 30!
Flaps retracted.
There's a freighter
15 degrees to the left!
Call them, have them give us
their coordinates! - Yes, sir!
Delois! Look at the 1st
screw and what's wrong with the plane!
The screw is breaking off!
Wouldn't cut us in half!
This shake is no better!
Put your seat belts on!
Fasten your
seat belts!
Monsieur, please be
be sensible, set an example!
Madam! - You're the ones
you're used to it, not us!
I'd like to see you
if you were us!
We are all mortal, madam!
Well, we don't have to die now!
Oh, Monsieur le curé! Monsieur le curé!
- Please, madame.
God is with us,
we risk nothing.
Stay in your seats
and fasten your seat belts!
Did they get the SOS and
our coordinates? - Yes, they did.
And the passengers? What can I tell them?
I can't hold them any longer!
Clear the last three rows:
our tail is too heavy.
The screw's about to come off!
That's right!
It's gone!
Ladies and gentlemen, I just
just got off the phone with the commander.
If you do exactly
as you're told, you'll be fine.
You'll undoubtedly
will feel a jolt.
A little jolt,
don't worry!
Mademoiselle!
Mademoiselle.
It's not a big deal!
Fire's spreading to 2nd!
- Stop 2nd!
Fluxing!
- Flugging 2nd!
Hurry, hurry, Borda!
SOS and coordinates!
Fire on 2nd!
- Fire extinguisher on 2nd!
More traction on the right!
I can't hold it anymore!
How high?
- 50 meters.
What's the matter with this
fire extinguisher?!
I've cleared three back rows!
- Prepare for water boarding!
Life jackets!
Loosen your ties!
Switching to generator four!
The passengers are sitting in the dark.....
Well, here we go! Now, with the light.
we'll be much more comfortable.
Stay calm, we'll take the steps
and we'll take the measures required by regulation.
Loosen your shoes,
loosen your ties,
get out and put on
your life jackets.
I repeat: Remain
stay calm!
I'm sure that
everything's gonna be okay.
It's 20 meters high!
Go back and put on
life jackets!
Quick, we're going down!
He's stopping!
It's 15 meters high!
He's stopped!
We're not sitting down, damn it!
Don't sit down!
25 meters!
- Help me with the pedal!
4th from the right!
He's stopped!
You're hurt, buddy!
Delois, get the stewardess!
Leave me alone, I don't care!
I can't take it any higher.
- drain 2,000 liters!
Look, we're going up!
- I told you it would be all right!
Breathe! Breathe deep!
But why take off your shoes?
- To avoid damaging the dingy!
What?!
- An inflatable boat.
It's 50 meters high!
A little lower!
We can't hold on!
Going for 50!
The shore is coming up!
But you're hurt.
- After!
Get the stewardess!
- I'll be right back! - No!
Shall we go back, commander? - Uh, no,
no, man! We're overheating!
Can we go lower still?
No, we have to get up!
We won't get far that way!
Are you hurt? - Uh, yeah, I think
hit by a piece of shrapnel.
150 meters!
Don't go down!
Overheating, damn it,
overheating.
All right, but just
straight back!
Want some rum?
- All right, baby, all right!
The vessel we contacted
is already within visual range.
Shall we sit down?
- No!
It's not like we're gonna make it to the end:
the engines are overheating!
No, I'll get to the end!
Mulino!
Take control!
I'll take a look at the engines.
Illuminate them!
Do you believe we're going
we'll make it to shore?
Congratulations:
you've trained them!
So what is it, commander?
- What?! We're going to Dakar!
Do you think we'll make it?
Why not? If we're going
If we're out, we're in!
So I can put on
my shoes?
Where do you want to go?
A barefoot man is happy!
There's my radio operator -
always barefoot!
Look at him!
Flying alone?
How big?
And she's not afraid! Or are you?
- I've seen worse!
What a good boy!
I've seen it all!
And your stewardess
has seen it too!
Yeah, we've both been through a lot, haven't we?
Then there's reason
to hope! Right?
Miracles still happen!
I never doubted it
I never doubted it!
If we don't get the rpms down,
the engines will fail!
Clean up on 50!
Vessel!
Shall I make a request?
The captain has the lifeboats
lifeboats at the ready.
Shall we sit down?
- Uh, no.
I won't!
I never drink water
before eating!
Come on, but, horsey!
We'll save on cab fare!
I'm opening the flaps:
the engines are overheating!
No, close it!
Otherwise we'll lose altitude!
Air France F-BBDK, calling
Jaffe Tower! Can you hear me?
Come in!
Air France F-BBDK, this is Joff Tower!
Can you hear me? Answer me!
Delois! Give me
the exact coordinates!
Has everyone figured out how a life jacket
a life jacket?
Just pull the laces,
and compressed air tanks
will inflate your vest.
How much fuel did you drain?
- 2,000 liters.
It won't last more than
than ten minutes.
Make sure that the tubes
the blow tubes are free!
No, no more alcohol!
Check all the belts!
Not now, monsieur!
Quickly, another vest!
- Why, mademoiselle?
If you land on the water, you're gonna
you'll stick to the ceiling like that!
To the ceiling?!
I've made up my mind! If
we're headed for Dakar,
it's a five or six minute flight.
Air France F-BBDK, calling
Jaffe Tower! Can you hear me? Over!
Yoff Tower, this is
BBDK!
Approaching from R-0-3-4
at an altitude of 500 meters.
How much fuel do we have?
- It's nothing!
Prepare the rescue team!
Over!
Bingo!
The lighthouse, it's him!
Where? Where is he?!
Notice anything?
- Yes! Dakar!
I see him!
Sorry, old man!
- Dakar! Here we go!
Oh, my God!
- Madam, sit down!
Please calm down!
It's hard to hold the plane!
Shortcut!
- Done!
Sit down, madam!
Sit up!
Sit up straight!
Under no circumstances
do not unbuckle!
Release the landing gear!
Release flaps!
The chassis are out of production!
Let it out by hand!
The pulley must be jammed!
- Abort! Well, uh.
We're not going to land on our bellies!
Up! Lift!
- Lift!
Pick it up! - Goddamn it!
No engine, no landing gear!
It's out!
Attention! Are you okay?
- Oh, it won't be long now!
Pull over! Pull over!
There's not enough lane!
Fool!
What a fool.
We almost died together.
You'd like that, wouldn't you?
Then I would have stayed with you
with you.
Don't be silly!
The Commandant requests
you to the pilots!
Tell Mademoiselle
Mani that, uh.
No, you shouldn't.
Don't say anything!
Subtitles: Linda