"THERE'S ROOM UP AHEAD..."
Excuse me!
- Excuse me!
Hey, easy!
- Watch out, there are kids!
Make way, I gotta go!
- Watch what you're doing!
There's room up ahead.
You make me waste time with that!
I don't have any change.
I said there's room up ahead!
I gotta get through! Excuse me!
Excuse me! I gotta get off! Excuse me!
Young man, one gets off at the front!
- How can I get through?
You're telling me that?
- Who else? My grandpa?
Hey, watch out!
- You watch out! I gotta get off!
For how long?
- For a month more.
I got a pass!
- Show me.
I said I got a pass.
- I said show me.
If I said I got it, I do!
Whom do you think you're speaking to?
I'll know by the pass.
- There!
Where are you going?
- To the Chinese.
Poker again? - No, bridge!
We had a game last night. - Really?
Ladies, tickets.
- Just imagine, 3 kings!
Three aces and a straight.
Mussi was also there.
Still blonde?
- As if! Black as ebony!
Didn't she want it red?
- Yes, but her husband made her.
He didn't want to see red!
- Like the bulls!
Dammit!
I never have change.
- How much you need? - Wait, I've a lira.
Did you win this month?
- Oh, please! It was bad. I was hexed.
Excuse me, did you say
hexed or vexed? - Hexed.
That guy must be an announcer!
Funny!
- Yes.
Have you found it? - What?
- The lira. I'll put the rest in.
Thank you.
- Here you go.
Make some room here, we can't breathe!
- Fine, go ahead! I'm coming!
When do I get off?
- You're still here?
Why didn't you tell me?
Why didn't you tell me to tell you?
You're supposed to tell us when!
- Yeah! Stop!
Well, we passed it.
We've arrived at the end of the line.
You call this manners?
Excuse me, excuse me.
Go on, please!
There's room up ahead!
Move on, move on! The more people
who come, the more beasts you see.
Isn't that cute!
How did it go?
Move on, move on! The more people
who come, the more beasts you see.
Aren't you ashamed of such idiocy?
- What's the matter?
My purse!
One moment!
Don't touch anything, I'll count it.
Excuse me! One moment!
I must pass through!
Excuse me!
Let me pass! What happened?
- They stole my 500 lire!
Are you sure?
- I had it when I got on!
Did you look around?
- I did and it's not here!
Close off the bus and get the thief!
- Right, Ma'am. A roll call. Doors shut?
Did you stop?
Yeah, we're stopped.
One moment! Who among you...?
- What?
That is who played this joke?
- How dare you?
I don't dare anything but...
a purse has disappeared!
Disappeared!
What are you implying?
That's why that guy wanted
to get off right away! - What?
Careful what you say! - Careful or not,
I don't care! If that purse doesn't show...
Where's the police station? - How
would I know? Thank God... - Nearby!
The police station? Right of here.
Come on, don't worry, be calm.
We'll find it!
People!
I ask you for a moment's patience!
What's this? - My doctor's waiting!
- I've an appointment which can't wait!
What do we have to do with it?
- Hey, young man, I'm not going!
I was always next to you.
You saw, yes or no?
Yes, but that means nothing
'cause the girl was down here.
Down here? What are you alluding to?
- I'm alluding nothing.
You were alluding!
- No, I was not alluding!
You alluded!
- May I go blind if I alluded!
He didn't allude.
- But what the heck does this guy know?
Look, it's useless, the 500 lire are gone!
- What?
Don't listen to him.
Don't worry, we'll find it.
Wanna bet?
- 10 lire? - Done.
Where exactly did you lay it?
- In front there.
Don't worry,
you'll see I'll find it in a minute.
Yeah, right!
You always hafta be in front of me?
Excuse me, lemme check. Move a bit.
Keep your hands to yourself!
- Ma'am, please, I was pushed!
I'll give you a push!
What can I do?
- Wax wroth.
What?
Wax wroth my foot! You're lucky
a lady's here. Let's go to the station.
Let's go, I'm in a hurry! - People,
remain calm! It'll be just a few minutes!
A half hour?
It's already night!
We've been here for 15 minutes.
I've got to go!
I'd sure like to know
where he needs to go.
Don't cry. Those who steal
purses are never moved by it.
Three more! - Ah, finally!
- Here we go, eh? - Here!
I'm here!
- Three at a time.
But I need to go!
- How funny!
What are they making them do in there?
- Get naked. - Really? - Yes.
It happened to me at
the border with my lady boss.
Smuggling.
- No, for heaven's sake. Mrs. Belardi.
Belardi? - Margherita!
- Exactly, Margherita.
A friend of ours. And you?
- I was her chauffeur.
How Margherita gets around!
What is your name? - Bruno.
Margherita always has dark drivers!
And now? - Trolley.
I drive the tram. The war, you see...
Three more!
- It's our turn? - Yes, go on!
Stop! Here I am!
- Ladies first!
Don't give me "ladies"!
Here I am!
- One moment! - Here I am!
They were nice, eh?
I like the blonde
but I bet she's expensive!
You think only of money.
You too, Miss. So much fuss for 500 lire.
Should she laugh? - No, but not cry!
It's not the end of the world. Allow me.
It wasn't mine.
It was the rent for my mistress.
Are you a maid?
- Yes.
And what was Th...?
- Wax wroth.
Three more.
- Courage, Miss, it'll all be fine.
But the 500 lire... bye-bye!
Let's go! Let's not waste time!
I've wasted plenty and I hafta go!
Where would he need to go?
That's enough, eh?
Cut the chit chat! Open the bag.
I'm a professional. I've my cards.
And I refuse! - C'mon, let's go!
In 20 years of my career,
this has never happened!
See! You happy now?
- That's why you were crying, dear.
Silence!
Come forward.
You may go. Excuse me.
- Excuse me! Excuses!
Now I'll won't find my clients and who
knows what the consequences will be!
If you act like that, your liver'll
be bad. - What do you mean?
It needs some onions!
You were robbed?
- Yes.
I'm sorry but the thief must've
got off before you realized it.
Anyway, we've your address
and will contact you if needed.
Sign there.
You two as well.
Are you the driver? - No,
the usher Cesare Montani from Rome.
Here. Sign.
Gimme 10 lire.
Why?
- Didn't you hear the commissioner?
Good grief!
Why you don't say "wax wroth"?
I bet 100 lire that you'll
never say "wax wroth" ever again!
Who knows? Maybe by mistake!
Good day, Miss.
730.
- Mondani!
Hurry!
The tram must leave right away.
Mondani! There was
a robbery in your car, eh?
Remember, a tram is not only a machine,
but our life's partner.
But yeah with the life you lead you
could end up alone. Always in the clouds!
Always.
When I was a tram usher...
- The tram was led by horses.
When I was  a tram usher,
I fried the fish and eyed the cat!
Now they fry the cat and eye the fish.
Go home and explain how
it was and she'll understand.
More than that, I cannot do.
Bye.
Gimme the usual.
Didja hear about Lazio?
I'm never wrong. Whadya like?
A drop of coffee.
Again!
What's wrong now?
- I can't go home. I'm ruined! Ruined!
Well, what can I do?
Eh?
What's the matter?
- I'm ruined!
Some people deserve jail!
- Yes!
What are you saying? You crazy?
All  I need is to people to think that...
Well? - I get it, eh!
- Get what?
I brought you to the station, got chewed
out for you, what more do you want?
I'm sorry.
Where are you going? Hey!
What is this nonsense?
It ain't the end of the world, right?
You  don't know. I can't go back alone.
- Fine. Don't go.
Why not?
My mistress is so mean.
She always says that I'm dreaming
and that I only think of love.
Is she right?
- No, Sir. I work all day to the night.
OK, I'll go with you. Let's go.
And the coffee? - Keep it warm,
I'll get it later. - OK, I get it!
Here it is.
Don't worry. - Whatever happens,
I must say you're so nice. I thank you.
There she is finally! The Miss has come!
You dare come at this hour?
Excuse me, Ma'am...
- And who are you? Shame!
Wicked hussy, you bring them
home now? Why not invite them in?
Why don't you come in? Have a seat?
Make yourself at home! Please! Please!
Thanks.
- Thanks! Get out!
Ma'am, if you keep that up, you'll lose
your voice. It'd be a shame: so sweet!
He's even witty! Rude lout!
You should be ashamed at your age!
Lil' Miss Innocent, can't deny
it this time, eh? - Ma'am...
You get inside! March!
You've been gone since 5! 2 whole hours!
Ma'am, the 500 lire are gone.
- 2 hours!
What? - Vanished!
- What? - The 500 lire!
Can we come in now?
Tullio!
Tullio! Come and listen to this!
What happened?
- Listen to me! The 500 lire! The rent!
The rent? The 500 lire?
Go on! Speak!
- Be calm, Ma'am.
How is it possible? Did she lose them?
- No, it's very simple. It was an accident.
On the bus, there was a big crowd
and she was robbed. - Great!
Robbed? What do you mean robbed?
Who did it? Where is he?
It's being investigated.
I told you not to take the bus! Jinx!
Criminal! You're the ruin of our house!
And you don't speak? Not one word?
Ah... what time did it happen?
- It happened when it happened!
Impossible! Who were you talking to?
What'd he look like?
Ma'am, it could happen to anybody.
- Hear how he defends her!
What? I just met her.
Sometimes there's nothing you can do.
Would you like to talk to the landlord
then? - Me? Why should I give a damn?
You hear how he answers! You hear that!
They're in cahoots!
What cahoots? I've never seen
her before! It could've happened to you!
Not me! I've a head on my shoulders!
I don't dream of love! - Thank God.
Ma'am, what do you mean by that?
- What I mean? You gab with everybody!
She stops to gab with everybody.
I pay you to serve,
not to flirt on trams!
I know what your type always do!
- You've no right to say that!
No right to say it? You dare to talk back?
Take that!
Enough! Shame on you!
- Please mind your own business!
Wait a minute! - What minute!
Must I be scolded by a tram driver?
Ma'am... - Oh, yes! You're just a driver!
- A driver!
And you're just passengers! - But...
- Quiet, you ride the tram! I've seen you!
Aren't you ashamed to treat that girl like
that? And for why? For a few peanuts!
Get out! Out of my house!
You too! I don't want to see you again!
Yes.
We're both leaving.
Yes, go away!
- Come on, let's go.
Tullio, you're not letting her leave?
- Ah, no!
She must first pay off what she owes,
then she can go.
The girl will no longer stay here.
- And who will pay us? - Me.
Yeah? Go on then!
Here.
What's this mean? - Means
you'll get the money on the 27th.
27th! I want it right now!
- You'll get it in installments.
50 lire at a time. 10 payments of 50 lire.
Or 500 payments of 1 lira!
Make that face again and
I'll make both of you sorry!
Don't forget that I'm an official of
the tram company of the streets of Rome!
What was that? - I won't repeat it,
saying it took a miracle!
Forget anything? Good.
Don't be afraid, I fixed
everything with these people.
Wait a second.
You again!
- Close the door quietly. Got it?
That's more like it.
Have any relatives?
- Yes, an aunt.
She wrote me once.
But I don't know where she is.
Any friends?
- No.
Oh, God! Why did you come here
if you had no relatives or friends?
But it was you...
- Now it's my fault!
Before you wouldn't stop complaining.
You cried and begged.
I come with you and now it's my fault!
But I... - What are you saying?
They were hitting you. Can I watch that?
Did you tell me you had no one?
But you lemme leave without a word.
Now where can we go?
To sleep in the gardens?
Is there any mark?
- No, it's a little red.
Did it hurt?
- A bit.
It felt like I was slapped!
It's quiet here. Are you afraid?
It's only one night.
Tomorrow God will provide.
May I help you?
- Do you have a room?
Bridal suite?
- No, just for the young lady.
Luggage? - What?
- Luggage?
This.
- ID?
That was stolen too!
Calm down, it's alright.
She has no ID?
- No, her money and ID were stolen.
Yeah? I understand.
I'm sorry but... there's nothing I can do.
Just for tonight. Then tomorrow...
- Of course. Tomorrow.
Why are you laughing?
- Not me. I'm not laughing.
Yes, you are!
Maybe you don't believe us.
I believe it all.
But no ID, no room.
Let's go.
Laugh!
- I believe there's nothing left to say.
Let's go.
May I use the phone?
- Yeah! But be snappy.
Like this?
Where are you going?
It's here.
Are you tired?
- A bit.
Not me.
Just 5 flights of stairs to go!
There's 130, but they're tall.
I made a joke and you didn't even get it!
They're tall! Let's go. Come.
I live here. Under the skylight.
I just love climbing stairs!
3 more and we're there.
One, two, three.
Quiet or you'll wake up Mrs. Camilla.
And she's so curious.
- The landlady?
Mr. Cesare!
Good night.
Very nice, Mr. Cesare!
It went well. She didn't see you.
Just imagine her being there!
I'm afraid.
- Of what?
Tomorrow morning
we need to get up early.
Here you go.
You sleep here.
And you?
- Yeah. I'll make do.
I couldn't let you do that.
Quiet!
If I hafta, I'll sleep in the street.
You're tired.
And a bit pale.
Let's see what Mrs. Camilla
prepared for us. Come.
Good! Cod! And it's fried!
Sit. - Thank you, Mr. Cesare.
- Let's drop the compliments, eh?
You like cod?
Cod? I was wrong. It's chicken.
But without any bones.
No, it can't be.
What the heck is this?
Potatoes!
Baked and then fried.
This ain't potatoes.
You see, we eat without knowing what
the heck we eat. But one must eat.
Thank God, it all went well.
What did I tell you?
Who is it?
- Mr. Cesare, I must talk to you.
Can't we do it tomorrow?
- No, right now.
What is it, Ma'am?
- A woman. In your room.
A woman?
- Mr. Cesare, you mustn't do this.
But...
- You know all. - Me?
For the blessed soul of my Alfonso
who over there watches over me.
He who cared so much
for the dignity of the house.
But if Mr. Alfonso knew the facts...
Please, Mr. Cesare, make her leave
right away and don't let it happen again!
He'll make her go. Don't worry.
- You think he gives a damn if...
Mr. Cesare, please, don't blaspheme!
- For heaven's sake! Don't cry, she'll go!
Right away!
- Right away!
You must leave.
Don't do that or I'll hit my
head on the wall again, OK?
It's all my fault.
- Your fault? Your fault...
C'mon, let's go.
- Where?
Who knows? Somewhere.
Go get your stuff.
What a knock!
Let's bring some stuff.
The apples, these are really apples,
bread...
She can eat this junk.
Let's go.
Are you happy now?
We're going to sleep on the streets.
Let him pay the rent!
Express from Naples at track 5.
We'll be fine here.
First class!
Papers!
Now what do we do?
- Ballet!
What should we do but sleep?
Let's go over there.
We'll eat the apple.
Tomorrow your mouth'll be so fresh.
Apples freshen you up.
What a strange thing life is.
This morning we didn't even know one
another and now 'cause of some thief...
Who knows where that 500 lire went to!
Here.
A dance troop. Merry, eh?
- It must be nice to travel like that.
Don't be fooled. So many things
seem nice when you imagine it,
but when you have to live it...
They laugh 'cause they have to.
It's written in their contract: laugh.
But on the train,
they curl up and laugh no more.
Who has no pain?
Just look at us.
So stupid, eh?
Sorry, I don't know what else to say.
Go home, Sir.
Don't put yourself out anymore.
Don't worry, have no doubts.
You sleep and tomorrow I'll come back.
But if you don't fall asleep,
how can I go?
If one doesn't begin,
no one sleeps. Lean back.
Go night-night.
Express from Venice at track 7.
You're back already.
- Sure.
You stayed here.
I fell asleep I too.
We must go.
- Where?
To have a latte.
Warm up the tummy.
Papers!
I'll see if there's something for you.
- You think the papers will mention it?
What?
- The theft.
Please! I'm looking for a job for you.
- Oh, yes, I hope so.
Here we go.
"Campo Marzio 37,
seeks a girl Friday, good looks".
We got the good looks down.
If you show up like this
they won't take you.
Let's go to Campo Marzio 37.
I'll change and go with you.
Giovannino! Giovannino, go answer it!
I'll get it!
- Mama told me!
Don't play so loud! What the heck!
Will you move?
Get down now! Get...
Hello, we read your ad seeking a lady.
Grandpa! The maid is here!
The maid is here!
Quiet!
I must talk. This way, please.
Sweet! So sweet!
I'll kill you, drug addicts!
- Quiet! Knock if off now!
She studies. Studies the piano.
She's having her exam soon.
Everything in order, no?
Yes, I like this girl. Right, Dad?
Will you have a seat?
We can talk better sitting down. Yes?
- Yes.
I'll kill you! - I'll kill you!
- Have a seat!
Therefore you are...?
- The brother.
Yes, I knew it.
You have the same face.
Good! Very good!
Let's sit down.
Get out, traitor!
We need to talk, go!
- I'll kill you! I'll kill you!
Ah, boys!
- Ah, kicks!
What?
- Nothing. Are they all yours?
No, no. Two are friends
from the apartment upstairs.
You'll find it just like home.
Unfortunately, my husband isn't here.
It's a bit noisy but so very nice!
You'll love it. The other girl
when she left was in tears!
Right, Dad?
- Ah, yes.
There's not much to do.
Stop!
You know I'll slap you!
As I was saying,
in the morning you go shopping.
But not to those below, good God,
they're thieves! To the market.
Next you clean the floors, help me cook.
You're a good cook, right? Very nice!
Then do some small things:
wash, iron, sew!
And then take the kids into the garden.
This way she can have fun too, no?
Die!
- Stop it!
Eh, make him happy
so he'll go away. Die!
Die!
- Doesn't count! His eyes are open!
Close them! Just like that.
Go away now! Go away!
- I want him to die! - Another time!
You'll die later, right?
- I'll kill myself now!
Over there! Go over there!
Ah, kids! Kids!
Do you have many? - What?
- Ah, right! You're father and daughter!
The girl'll lunch with us.
We eat in the kitchen, right?
And we're here everyday.
So sweet and cozy!
You've no idea how much
stuff costs now. 2000 lire!
This is his crib.
It doesn't look it but it cost 300 lire!
A little thing from Japan.
For my part, for heaven's sake!
Everything will be great. Right, Dad?
Ah, yes.
Very well.
But stop coughing!
Grandpa is playing!
By the way, a simple formality:
Do you have a health certificate?
'Cause of the kids, disease, we need
this trifle. We'll be living together.
You can see she's a healthy girl
but it's better to have it, isn't it?
Sure. Tell me, are all
of you healthy? - Yes, indeed.
Do you have a certificate?
- No.
Better to have it.
Grandpa has quite a cough...
I am...
very... well!
The gentleman is quite right!
I've always said you smoke too much.
So where does that leave us?
- Just fine. OK, you understand?
Child's play!
You get up at 5 or 5:30.
The morning air's so healthy.
It has oxygen!
Some market shopping
but not with the thieves below.
When you get back
you cook, wash, iron,
sew some clothes for the kids,
'cause their things never last long.
Then sing some songs at the piano.
Miss plays so nicely and never shuts up.
Then scrub the floors! She may look
delicate but what muscles she has!
In fact, if you move, she can
help with the furniture. Are we agreed?
But we haven't mentioned pocket money!
- What money? It'll be like a family visit!
Right, Dad? You should really watch
him or you might lose him. Good day.
Am I working here?
- Are you nuts?
No, we'll find something else.
I just love climbing stairs!
Mr. Cesare.
- What's up?
Let's hope this time...
- You'll see it'll be good.
I've a presentiment...
- Hurry! Come up! Hurry, come up!
One moment!
I'm afraid that here too...
- Let's get away.
Now we're here, let's check it out.
He's here! - He's come?
- Yes, he's coming up the stairs!
Where is he? - He's here.
- Oh, Virgin Mary!
May I enter? - Finally,
we were so anxious! Gimme that!
I'll take your hat.
- Hurry, in here! You're late.
We were expecting you since this
morning. - We were at 4 other houses.
You should've came here right away!
- If we only knew!
Some big trouble has
shown up with the feet.
Let me in! - Be calm, Mr. Fandulli!
Be calm, it's nothing!
Ginevra! Ginevra!
Oh, the doctor! Oh, good day, doctor!
I'm the midwife. Come.
The father is besides himself.
Take heart! It's nothing.
You're not the doctor?
- He's the new tenant.
Please, doctor!
Great, doctor!
Ice and alcohol! Hurry!
- Yes.
Ice and alcohol! Hurry up? - Where?
- In the kitchen! The dining room!
Hurry! Hurry up!
I can't take anymore!
You come!
- Where? - Come!
You come too! To help!
Fan the flames!
- I don't want to be a maid! - Hurry!
I have to make it boil. Got it!
Just like that.
Careful it doesn't boil over!
- It's boiling.
Here's the water.
Please, work it harder.
I can't take anymore!
I can't!
You understand?
He's coming out feet first!
Feel this! Feel how it beats!
Eh? - Uh! Always like that, daddy?
No, but it's the first time my wife
is giving birth, poor thing, understand?
Will it take much longer? - Yeah...
- 'Cause I can't take anymore!
Me too!
Feel this here! Feel this!
- I did. - What? - I felt it!
Really? I can't stay still!
- Then help fan!
No, I can't, impossible!
Here! You fan it 'cause...
Well? - It's going well.
- Oh, blessed Madonna!
Mr. Cesare...
Hurry up in that kitchen!
You don't have worry anymore about me.
I've already given you so much trouble.
So much time it takes to be born
and so little time to drop dead!
We're there! We're there!
Harder! Harder!
Ah! He's born! He's born!
- He made it!
He's born!
A boy! A boy! A boy! A boy!
Cheers! Long live our little Cesare!
- Thanks.
What? - Thank you.
- Why, it's nothing!
We'd like to thank you,
you were great!
Long live our Cesare!
- Thank you.
Who told you my name?
- Nobody. Why?
My name is Cesare.
- Just like the Caesars?
Who else? - What a coincidence!
Same name as the boy!
A double toast: long live
little Cesare and big Cesare!
Hooray!
What a great idea! I want you absolutely
to be my son's godfather. For sure.
The godfather of my son!
- Very good! And she the godmother!
The godmother and godfather!
- You see...
Don't refuse, it'd be a sacrilege. You're
name is Cesare and you live here too!
I don't live here. - Upstairs?
- No, I live in Via Del Pellegrino.
You're not the new tenant?
- I'm an usher. - Usher? - For the tram.
We came for the ad.
- Why? How come?
"Water heater for sale"?
- No, no, no! The one under it.
Ah, we don't need a maid.
Ah, the Rossis were looking for a woman.
But they found one this morning.
We've been all around since last night.
I thought that here... Too bad!
I should've been at work by now.
Now where shall I leave you?
What must I do?
Poor girl, she has nobody. No one. Zilch.
Mr. Angelo? - Yeah?
- Why don't we keep her with us?
Well, you know that... - No! Just for
tomorrow 'til everything is settled.
There's so much to do today.
And besides she can be the godmother!
- Ah, right! Very good!
It's settled: The girl stays
with us 'til tomorrow morning.
I thank you!
But I can't be the godfather.
- Blasphemy!
I've never done it before and could
mess it up! - Impossible! Say yes!
Excellent! Great!
- I must fly! - Where to?
I hafta be at work or I'll get fined!
They're so strict!
Wait a moment! A moment!
We need to plan the baptism of Cesarino!
Saturday? Saturday the 15th at 9, eh?
I'll even come tomorrow
now that I started...
Our home is always open.
We're godfathers, right? Got you!
Cesarino! It's him! Excuse me!
- He woke up! - Poor little thing!
Forgive me.
You see I can't do anything more:
yesterday the school, today the fine...
And now I hafta to be a godfather!
Does it really bother you?
- No, but there'll be relatives...
They're so nice.
- Yeah, they are but so?
I'd like it here.
So would I!
Maybe they'll ask you to stay.
- I wish!
I gotta run, eh?
See ya tomorrow. Goodbye.
Are you leaving?
- Yes. Pardon me for a moment.
Listen, that girl in there
I just met yesterday on the tram.
Her 500 lire was stolen and her mistress
kicked her out. - Oh, poor thing!
Since this morning, I've been trying
to find her a job but with no luck.
We came here but
it was for the third floor.
Couldn't you find a place for her...
I don't know...
Yes, what a coincidence!
Yesterday, my boss fired my coworker.
What do you do?
- Sell movie tickets.
That'd be great 'cause she's nice, smart.
Listen.
What are you doing?
- No, no! For heaven's sake!
Have her hair done, a manicure,
so she can make a good impression.
Fine, I'll see to it.
- You'd be doing me... a great pleasure.
I need to run but I'll be back soon.
- See ya.
If you've any good news, send it
to terminal 6. - OK. - Thanks! - Bye!
Mondani!
Always oversleeping and careless!
Listen here, Mondani!
Please, it's Montani. - Fine! Mondani
or Montani, you don't mount!
What mounts is the tram
which ain't like your drums!
There you just need to beat them
and something will come out.
The tram is tied to the clock.
And the clock says your 15 minutes late.
Don't interrupt me!
Be late again and I fine you!
One hand washes the other. And both
of them can throw you out of the band!
And who'll play the drum then?
Everybody is useful
but nobody is necessary.
Got chewed out, eh?
I'll knock your head off!
How's your adventure going?
- Knock it off. I'm late 'cause of her.
Lost your head? - My head!
I've ran around everywhere for her.
But she's cute.
- Yeah, cute. An ugly shrimp.
Mondani!
Please, Bellini, be very watchful...
Very.
Let's go.
- You're going with me?
And Rossi?
- They called him to duty.
They'll never call you, eh?
Bellini, please keep an eye out!
- Don't worry, boss. I got this.
"The higher you climb,
the faster you fall."
Watch it, you'll break it!
That's what mechanics are for, right?
- Don't make me laugh.
Maybe... I'm better than you now.
Want to bet I make you mess up?
- Knock of this betting, Bruno!
30 to 10!
What will ya make me do?
- I won't tell ya 'til it happens. - Fine.
Hey! Hey! Whatcha doing?
- I can't go on.
I got no sleep.
And running around all morning.
And the stairs!
They never ended.
How my feet hurt!
How I'd like to sleep!
But I gotta meet her at the terminal at 6.
Her again?
You'll say, "Forget about her.
Why should you care?"
I need to take care of her.
- Or have you already taken care of her?
You're always like that.
You don't understand certain things.
Do you realize what it means to be
alone in the world without any relatives?
Without a soul.
I envy you then. I envy you.
I'd like to fall in love but I can't.
Wait, I'm not in love.
- Yeah! Whatever!
No, for heaven's sake. I'm nice.
- Yeah, yeah, I know...
But no! I'd like you to know,
excuse me, but between us...
Never mind.
Change of plan: I'm going now.
And call me at 5 or 5:30 tops.
I can't go on.
If we continue, I'll run over someone.
Anything else?
- Let's whistle down the street at 5:30.
By the way, if the boss asks,
just tell him I drove well.
And then?
Then one day if you need me,
I'll pay you back big time.
What are you doing? Brake!
You braked in park, stupid.
Give me 10 lire and wax wroth.
- Doesn't count.
Why?
- Don't count! I was sleeping.
And even if it did count,
I wouldn't give it.
Who can put his hands in his pockets?
Wax wroth...
Morning, Miss. How are you?
- Fine. Thank you.
I barely recognized you.
Remember me?
Of course, the driver. But Mr. Cesare?
- Just so. Sent me with his apologies.
Wasn't he free?
- No, he's in training.
I'm sorry. 'Cause I've good news.
Finally, I got a job. I start tomorrow.
Nice. I'm glad.
What is it?
An employee.
Ticket seller at the Rex Cinema!
I'll have to do a week's trial
and after...
Congratulations!
- I was really lucky.
Well then...
Seeing we're going the same way, if you
don't mind, I'll go with you. - Please do.
You like it here?
- It's very nice. But I gotta go home.
Fine, I'll go with you.
What a shame!
What? - That I didn't meet
you before the war. Oh, yes.
I woulda got you to Rome in 2 hours,
to the top of the world with my sports car.
Eh, Miss,
I wasn't always a tram driver.
A private chauffeur for the best
families in Rome. - Really?
During that time, we were always at
the Riviera, Bordighera, San Remo...
And abroad too: Cannes, Juan-Les-Pins...
- Lovely places?
What hotels! What women!
- Beautiful? - Fantastic.
But none like you.
- Yeah, make fun of me! - No.
At a certain point a man like myself
gets tired of chic women.
And he needs somebody,
beautiful, simple like you.
Thank you, it's done.
Tomorrow, you can get a copy.
- It was a snapshot!
Shall I rip it up? - No! It's the first
time somebody took my photo!
Rosella.
Better you leave me here. Thank you.
Where do you live?
- Over there at 71. I'll be late.
Because of me?
- Oh, no.
For me the day was wonderful.
I left that house.
I found a job and then...
You met me.
- Of course. That too.
Meet again tonight?
- No, I can't.
Why would you want to see me?
- C'mon, Rosella, what a question!
I still got many things to tell you.
Tonight at 9. OK? Agreed? Thanks.
By the way, if you see Cesare...
don't say we met. - But he sent you!
Yeah, I know, but... don't tell
him we spent so much time together.
Oh, Mr. Cesare!
- A strange guy.
Not that there was anything wrong
but better not to tell him.
Then at 9? OK? Goodbye.
Mr. Cesare!
- Oh, God! What is it?
What time is it?
- It's 9.
In the day?
- Yes. 9 o' clock! - Oh, God!
I'm ruined! What time do I begin?
- You're asking me?
Why didn't you wake me?
- You've a short memory, Mr. Cesare.
I didn't want to enter this room again
but I was afraid you were sick.
How long did I sleep? - You were so tired.
Not even the energy to undress yourself.
I'm ruined!
Ruined!
Cesare, harken! - For God's sake, Ma'am,
don't preach or speak of Mr. Alfonso!
I gotta go to the depot. No time to lose.
- Cesare! Why do you speak to me so?
And how should I speak?
Don't you understand?
Cesare... I...
Oh, God!
How can I? I gotta go.
I'm ruined!
I won't be just fined but fired!
Alfonso, have no worries about me.
What? No?
Mondani!
Where are you going so fast?
Taking my shift.
It's 9:30. Your turn is at 11.
An hour and a half early!
Never on time.
"The apple does not
fall far from the tree."
Hey! Gimme a light.
I got here an hour and a half early.
Will you stop playing these stupid jokes?
A fine friend you are! - Why?
- Yesterday, you shoulda whistled for me.
I did come.
I was whistling for an hour! Damn!
How sleepy I was!
I slept til this morning and that girl...
Mr. Cesare!
Hey, whatever he says, play along, OK?
- Don't worry.
My dear Cesare! I've been running around
all of Rome but I finally found you, eh?
How lovely! - Have you heard? - What?
- Teresa got Rosella a job at the Rex.
The two girls hit it off and
Teresa has her stay at her place.
Thank goodness! - Yes, but you
can show up once in a while, no?
For good reasons. He was asleep
for 2 days. - Some sleep! Why?
For two days, yes, I haven't slept!
Coworkers? - Bellini. - A pleasure.
Bellini? Bellini? I've heard that name.
Sorry, I confused him with Rossini!
See, Cesare, the 15th is the great day!
We're still on for Saturday, eh?
But on Saturday...
- No, no! We're agreed. No compliments!
But it ain't...damn my eyes if... go figure!
I've being trained on Saturday.
He's the teacher. - Teacher? C'mon!
For an hour and a half. If I don't go,
I'll be fired. - Fired? Just a little fine!
The fine is expensive.
- Oh, yes: 3 lire.
Just 3 lire! Let's go!
But... I got it! I got it!
Now I remember...
Oh, good heavens, I can't go.
I can't.
I have a concert after work.
- What do you have to do with a concert?
He's a musician. - Him?
What do you play, my dear?
The bass drum.
The timpani. - Bravo, Godfather!
I love timpani when they keep that beat!
You'll gimme some tickets, right?
- Oh, heavens, the public isn't admitted.
Only families allowed, right?
- No! Just ask the boss. He'll be happy to.
Once he brought 14 people.
Was it 14 or 16? - 2000!
Then we'll be 1, 2, 3, 4 and
Rosella 5. A good number 5!
Look, Mr. Pandolin...
- Pandolin! Godfather!
Godfather, you can't. - C'mon, Cesare,
you're rude. What'll godfather think?
I'm shocked! - But...
- We're agreed then?
Whatcha doing on the 15th?
- Me? - Nothing. - He's free!
You'll be with us. Long live the tram!
You'll be with us.
A modest little party but
after all it's my first born!
After so many years married,
we were losing hope.
But God sent me Cesare. I mean
2 Cesares: Lil' Cesare and Big Cesare!
Rosella's waiting tonight at the Rex.
Bye, goddad!
Mr. Rossini, goodbye!
Whatcha doin?
Waxing wroth...
- Mondani! Here!
We were playing.
- None of that!
Hey, what time do you get off tonight?
- I get off at 9.
You get off at 8. - Thanks.
- Yes, but we'll be rehearsing.
Again? - Yes, again.
It's your fault I'm doing it.
The 15th is the concert, right?
- But we always play the same thing.
"He who want to be happy, be so.
Tomorrow brings no certainty."
Which means don't put off tomorrow
what you can do today.
And as for you today is always tomorrow,
tonight we rehearse.
"The more one knows, the less one knows."
What a bore! Tonight, I was going to
that poor girl. Bet he did it on purpose!
Want me to go?
- You won't go.
C'mon, this time I'm not joking.
I can bring her to the rehearsal.
Wow, that'd be doing me favor.
- Count on me.
Halt!
Eh, Mondani! Mondani! Will you keep up?
- I was anticipating...
By how many beats?
- How should I know?
Fine! I made a mistake! - That's just
what I wanted to hear "I made a mistake"!
Anyone can make a mistake.
"To err is human".
The wrong is not realizing it!
How can you correct it if you don't?
What's right isn't right 'til I like it!
And I like you to realize your errors!
Now then... you're behind by 6 1/2 beats!
Got it? 6 1/2 beats! No big whoops!
Music is not a tram
that can makeup for being late.
And even Mondani should know that.
Being late is his specialty.
Where were we then?
You must keep ahead of the sol.
Then enters the clarinet.
Mi, sol, fa, la, sol, do!
Mi, Si, fa, la, mi, la!
Mi, Si, fa, la, fa, la! Like that!
Play on the mi, Si, fa, la, fa, la!
But you're doing it on
the mi, Si, fa, la, mi, la! Got it?
Watch out, Mondani, 'cause if not,
"Better alone than in bad company".
Now let's begin again.
Rather three beats before the 3 F.
Rather, a beat before the M!
It's our fault.
- Better leave or we'll mess him up.
Yes, Bruno.
- I'll stay here.
Where are we going?
- I'll show you the gym.
Come.
We'll turn on the light.
Where's the switch?
- One moment.
Rosella!
Can you see me?
Yes! I see you!
Watch this, eh? I'll do two swings.
I won the championship.
Bruno!
Are you hurt?
- It's nothing.
I was so scared.
We should call somebody.
- No, stay. It's passing.
Let's sit here.
- Ah, of course.
There. Next to me.
Is that better?
- Yes, fine.
My pain is here.
I said the pain is here.
Rosella.
Don't go. - The rehearsal must
be over. It's better to go.
Hear that?
When I said I never met anyone like you...
- I thought you were joking but...
But?
- It made me so happy.
So after the rehearsal,
you'll return home with Teresa.
But we'll see each other later. Alone.
At 10:30 or later, you'll come down.
How can I? - Can't you do what you like?
- Yes, but... - Well then?
I'll wait at the gate
then we'll go to my place.
My room has an entrance on the stairs.
It's better furnished than Cesare's.
Bruno! - What is it?
Why do you look at me like that?
Let me go.
I should've known it!
I beg your pardon, maybe I shouldn't
have asked you. - Let me go!
Fine, I said sorry. But you had...
had gone in Cesare's room!
Mr. Cesare!
- What is it? What?
I'm glad to see you.
- You scared me!
How cute you look tonight!
Bravo, Mr. Cesare! What lovely music!
- Thanks. I didn't write it though, eh!
Bravo to you for what
you've done for Rosella.
See? I kept my promise.
- What promise?
That I'd bring you here to our Cesare.
He wouldn't believe me.
He must not trust you very much.
- No, joking aside, Bruno is a true pal.
Shall we go?
- Yes.
"Volo". You respond, "Volo".
- Volo.
He sleeps blessed by God.
Now he's a Christian too.
Congratulations.
- Thank you, father. - Thank you.
What a treasure!
Father!
Allow me.
For the poor of the parish.
- Thank you and may heaven help you.
I'll see you soon.
- Another baptism?
No.
A marriage.
The cake!
- The boy didn't know who sent it.
Nice! Very nice! Cream and chocolate?
- What? It's candied apple!
Good!
- I just love that!
We need a small glass! Get me a cup!
- Let's go to Cesarino's. Dont move.
Get her a cup.
And the cake after the concert!
Oh, what a pity!
Rosella, you haven't
even looked at me once.
You really don't want to look at me, eh?
Wait a moment. Do I annoy you?
- Please, Bruno, let me go.
Listen. If I went away, far away,
would you mind?
Answer me!
I've met many girls and not one
acted like you. Who d'ya think you are?
You're hurting me.
How delicate you are.
I can't take it! He showed me his album,
all his family photos,
him at three months, his first communion...
What's the matter?
- Nothing.  I don't feel so well.
She has a bit of a headache.
She was just saying so earlier.
Headache? Would you like a sedative?
- It's no big deal.
It'll do you good. There's a pharmacy
below. - Don't worry, Mr. Cesare.
I'll just be a sec. You'll see
it'll go quick. Back in a jiffy!
Why are you so mean to me?
Who is it?
- Cesare.
Come in.
Wasn't I quick? Here it is.
How do you feel?
- Better.
Were you crying?
- No, I've a chill.
Of course with these thin dresses,
it takes nothing to get sick.
You're not hot.
I always get a chill too. Don't be scared.
Take this.
Oh, yeah, the water!
Where?
Ah, there.
You'll see. It'll all be gone
in 5 minutes. All of it.
Go on.
How good you are, Mr. Cesare. - Well?
Why would you say something like that?
You've done so much for me.
You are the kindest man in the world.
Yeah, I'll win a prize!
Just for going downstairs.
I like going up and down stairs!
Even when you were grouchy,
I knew you were so kind.
You must forgive me if sometimes
I wasn't nice to you.
Oh! You're not capable of it!
You're so young!
- Who knows if you weren't there...
I feel so calm near you.
- Listen, Rosella. I...
You see, it's the first time that I...
I don't know how to say it.
It's that... you... me...
Rosella, not ready yet? It's late.
Will there be many people? - Where?
Where? Aren't you bringing her to
the concert? - Ah, right. How dumb! - Yes.
We must hurry.
- Right. - Right.
Excuse me, I'll leave you alone.
Excuse me.
Excuse me. How stupid!
Yeah.
Rosella, aren't you dressing?
Did you go to the pharmacy already?
- It's just below.
Did she take the sedative?
What?
- Want to bet? - What?
That within six months...
I'll be married.
Really?
I'll make another bet.
That within a year,
two little things will sprout from here.
If you knew who she was, you wouldn't
speak so. - Who is she? A fairy?
An angel.
It's Rosella.
Anymore bets?
Poor Cesare.
I won't bet anymore 'cause I pity you.
Why?
She found the right guy for her.
That would be me?
- Yeah.
I'd be happy if you don't joke about this.
- I'm not joking, I'm serious.
You can't be serious.
You're a clown. - Oh, yeah?
I'll double the bet and
get paid in advance! - Take it!
Cesare!
Cesare! Goddad! Come here!
Look at these ties.
Which do you prefer?
This one? Good, goddad, come with me.
I wanta make him look good today.
I'm not sure if I'll put on you a double
breasted jacket or not. Come! Come!
Mr. Bruno, aren't you coming with us?
- No, no. I'm working.
What a pity.
- Yeah.
Where's Miss Rosella?
- In her room. She must be almost ready.
Rosella, Mr. Bruno wants to say goodbye.
Don't be afraid, I'm leaving.
I wanted to tell you something:
I've always had fun with women,
but it never became serious.
And now I realize I did right.
Not 'cause you're prettier than the rest,
you see, but this time I thought...
rather I was sure:
I loved you.
For real.
Well, that's done. But it had been better
if you told me that you and Cesare...
No!
It doesn't matter anymore.
We won't see each other for a long time.
Bruno!
Goodbye, Mr. Bruno.
- Yes, goodbye.
Rosella! What? Aren't you ready?
- Yes, I'm coming.
Mr. Bruno is a strange guy.
First he looked happy then such a face...
Oh, finally!
See you after the concert. Watch
the little one. - Don't worry, have fun!
Thanks, Cecilia. I'll have fun!
I had words with Bruno.
I must speak with you but not here.
I'll wait for you tomorrow
at 10:30 near the San Pietro line.
"I'll double the bet!"
Bravo! Bravo, Godfather! He deserves it:
Always off the beat! Syncopation is hard!
Go on! You can go in!
You already know the way.
Come in.
It's me. Yesterday I received the card:
I'm driving a tank.
I'm leaving today for Naples.
And the... embarkation day is unknown,
but I think it'll be about a month.
I got lucky.
I like the heat and over there...
This morning, I was in the barracks.
Everybody had somebody to say bye to.
But me... oh, well.
It's my fault. I don't know
how to make anybody love me.
Did you write your mama?
Why wait when you can do it?
Come here. Sit down.
Take this. Here's paper.
Here's the pen. Write.
"Dear Mama..."
You got a mama
and you say nobody loves you!
Did you write it?
"I'm leaving for Naples."
"I'm a tank driver."
"But don't worry, I'll be back soon."
"Right now as I write,"
"I'm with all my friends who love me,"
Comma.
"I depart cheerfully."
"If you need anything,"
"write to Cesare Montani,
Via Del Pellegrino 58, Rome."
"He's like a brother to me!"
Exclamation point.
What am I? The schoolteacher?
Well? Is it done?
You really wrote all my words?
Well, put your salutations.
- You write them.
Did you really believe
what you told me yesterday?
Why did you say that?
Because I never met an honest girl
and couldn't tell the difference.
So no more bets?
- No! I sure don't want to lose!
Well, now for the address. Go on.
You're one of those who write letters
and forgets to post them.
I'm sorry to leave like this.
Gimme a light.
Wax wro.. oth!
Sorry, I'm a bit late.
See this morning Bruno came
to my place... noooo... to say goodbye.
He's a naughty boy
but he's not bad at heart.
I'm sure when he gets back...
Where is he going?
Naples.
Then to Africa.
He'll be a tank driver.
Excuse me.
Wanta see him?
Piero, we needta go!
- So soon? There's a good 5 minutes left.
You're off!
We needta go. Let's go!
Hey, move it!
Well! I'm going if not that guy...
Piero! We needta be at the station by 11.
- Are you crazy?
I'm not. Hurry. - It's 10 minutes before
departure. The arrival is for 11:10.
Hurry! There's a guy who owes me
a 1000 lire that I don't wanna lose.
Who? - I know him. - And then?
- 500 for you if we hurry!
Go, Piero!
- We need to stop!
OK, but just for a second!
Let's go! No time to lose!
Dicky! Dicky, hurry up!
Hurry!
- Dicky!
Hands off! What manners are these?
Gemma! Gemma!
- My husband was left alone!
Maybe he'll be happy now.
- What?
We can't stop so get off! Go on, get off!
- Get off? Get off, my foot!
You do what you like!
Louts! Boors!
Insane! They close the doors without
looking! But I'll complain, understand!
Ah, sure.
- Then I get threatened!
What kind of braking is that?
Excuse me. Excuse me!
One moment. One moment!
Hey, I say, usher, is this a joke?
If you keep talking, you'll never get off!
Won't you give me my change?
- Here. She's driving me crazy.
I only gave you 2 lire. - Here.
- Thanks. - Moving forward?
Oh, I swear this isn't the end!
I will complain.
Just wait! Riffraff!
What? - Ticket.
- Ah, move ahead, please.
I gave you 5 lire.
- So? - Gimme my change!
Faster!
Say, what time is it?
- Give me my 25 lire!
Have  any change? - No!
- Pay tomorrow. Go away.
The time?
- 3 to 11.
It's 3 to 11! Got it?
- Got it.
Why are you stopping?
- It's red.
One for the 70!
Still red. It's still red.
Whadya want?
- The traffic light put a spell on him!
There.
It's green.
I thought you had a pass.
- No, a ticket. - Hey, don't push!
Watch out!
- Are we in a rush?
I wish! We'll never get there.
You can't rush with this bus!
Some service! I'll never take it again!
What time is it - It's past 11.
Hey, Piero, I'll be right back.
He must be here.
There he is!
Bruno!
Now say nobody loves you. Here.
Well, I must go.
I'll say goodbye even if I get fined!
Bye, eh!
Rosella.
- Bruno.
Usher, a ticket! For the 70.
Well?
Who is smoking?
- Smoking? What an exaggeration!
One can't even hold
an unlit cigar in his mouth!
I'll take it out, OK? But you do your
best to exhaust the public's patience!
Then wax wroth!
- What? What? Think you're funny?
Ah, you must be patient.
Even they can make a mistake.
Up ahead!
There's room up ahead.
English subtitles by sineintegral@KG