Move... Hurry
Commander-in-chief
What?
We arrested another
ten illegal salt venders
God damn it! Take care of it as usual
Put them in the torture chamber
Interrogate them and kill them after
Yes, sir
They dare to sell salt on my turf!
Isn't life dear to you!
I'm scared when you even talk of killing
What are you afraid of?
Didn't you used to sell illegal salt
Shit! Shave my head!
Yes, I did
The salt is from the ocean
And the hard work of the people
There is no difference
if its legal or illegal
From the period of Cuen Chew
The sale belongs to the government
This monopoly system continues until now
The legal one is called Government salt
Without permission it's illegal
But in the Chin Dynasty
there was corruption
Some of the officers kept the profits
It was a great deal
They stole government salt
There is no cost or tax
That kind of salt is illegal
It's against the law to sell it
It's the death penalty if you get caught
Still there are people taking the risk
Because of the good profit
Over here! Chou Ju
Din Wei, it's time to eat
It smells so good
Hurry up! You have to work harder
It's best to work for the Government
I'd rather be my own boss
I'd rather sell illegal salt
What?
That's great!
One is a thief and another is the police
Three of us are like brothers
We're working together side by side
We can barely afford three meals a day
That's all we dare to ask for
We need to help each other
Let's swear to be good brothers
Joining in the Royal secret societies
Kneel down!
The candles are above your head
There are heroes among us
Flying like birds
Fighting like dragons
Two pairs of candles on the table
Shining above all of us
It will always take care of us
And last forever
The candles and flowers
Put them in between
Since our ancestors
We're from the same family
All for one and one for all
We'll be able to handle anything
No one can beat us
After we took the vow to a secret group
Brother Pei and I became dealers
Ly Chen Piao joined the force
He was in charge of illegal dealing
Three of us divided to two sides
He worked for the Government
At the beginning he gave us a break
He wouldn't give us too much trouble
But after Brother Pei got sick and died
He didn't consider
the relationship any more
Between the coast where the salt is made
and the Northern wilderness;
There are many check points...
which you can't avoid or detour
One's got to pay them off
Say, if they wouldn't take the bribe...
You have to fight your way through
It's very dangerous
Stop...
Are you selling illegal salt?
Are you?
Speak up!
No, it's Government salt
Are you sure? Tell me the truth
I'm asking you
Is it illegal salt?
It's white!
I don't care whether it's white or black
I only want to know if it's legal or not?
Of course it's legal
Do you have a permission slip?
Yes
Let me see
Hurry up!
Ma'am
You can give bills instead of slips
You're Brother Pei's widow
Why didn't you say earlier?
Shit!
She is one hell of a lady
Brother Pei was our leader
Since he died his wife took over
She has been very nice to me
She won't remarry and I'm single
We love each other
We are a couple
Just no ceremony
She didn't want to get married again
It's for all of us
There are seven or eight hundred people
With their families
it must be around 7 thousand
We can't live without her leadership
She is the chief of our team
And I'm one of her aides
There are four officers who work for me
Four Jin Piao -dart experts
They are Dong, Chu, Ko and Ce
The best of the best
Is the boss in?
Yes...
Is he?
Yes
Are you ready?
Yes, everything is ready
Hurry up!
It's all here
Damn!
We work our butt off
and have to share with them
Hurry... watch this
Shoot
Yes
Come on
Get the boat closer
Who is your leader?
Me, Dong Jin Piao
He is the leader
It's Dong Jin Piao
I've heard about you before
Yes...
This time Brother Pei's widow didn't come
She retired long time ago
This is a small case
We don't need to bother her
Where is the shipping list?
Here you are...
Sir...
The list
The General is here
How are you? Sir
Mr. Commander
Did you check it? How many are there?
Yes. There are 560 sacks
All of them have been stamped with a chop
In the book it just mentions 160
The rest of it will be confiscated
But...
What's wrong?
Confiscate it
Yes
Who was shooting?
It's a false alarm
False alarm?
Yes... there were whole bunch of them
on the boat
Someone shot accidentally
I thought that they were resisting arrest
...so I told my men to shoot
What do you get from them?
Nothing!
Really?
Listen, tell the tiger Xu
and the window Pei
The confiscated salt
is paying the penalty
Otherwise I will close down all of you
Yes...
I'm just doing my job
Remember it
Good bye! Commander
That's it
We have to get rid of him
Dong contacted his uncle
He is the secretary of
Transportation Department
I hear, the Chief didn't like
Ly Cen Piao either
My sister-in-law
My uncle suggests
we should bribe the Chief
to accuse Ly Chen Piao of something
What should we accuse him of?
He is stealing money
That's not enough. Add something else
He colluded with the salt dealers
Please sit down
No formalities.
Let's sit down and discuss it
When did you arrive?
At noon. I'm here to report right away
I got information about you recently
Someone tried to set you up
But you have to consider my situation
Don't blame me; I can't really help
You're too kind
I understand completely
It's that Pei widow after my back
She persuaded the Governor to accuse me
You're a fair person.
I trust your judgment
That's great
Did you just mention the widow of Pei?
What kind of person is she?
She is a salt dealer.
Her name is Pei Chou Ju
A salt dealer, huh?
Everyone on Nanjing waterfront
knows about it
The toughest dealer is Xu Pao Shan
No one dares to utter
his nick-name; the "Tiger"
So they called him Pao Shan
The widow Pei
is the real leader of the group
Tiger Xu is just her...
Her...
He is her helper
Yes, one of the aides
The widow is very nice to Tiger Xu
She is helping him
and lets him handle the work
They are all the same
All this is unavoidable
They hate the anti-smuggling officers
If I still assigned you to the job...
to be the chief of Young Chou City;
What are you going to do about widow Pei?
I'll warn them before I arrest them
Give them a chance to surrender
Nothing personal;
just discharging official duty
Last year we lost the war
with the Japanese
Ly Chong Tan signed the Ma Kwan agreement
The compensation is hundreds of millions
Plus 30 million to get back
Liao Dong Peninsula
The first payment of 50 million...
is due in September
Where will the money come from?
We've got to mete out
largest part of compensation
The only way for us is by collecting tax
And try our best to settle
So you must continue dealing with
the smugglers
Be more firm and strict than before!
Don't worry! You have my backing
Mrs. Pei is here
Mrs. Pei?
I don't want to see her. Why is she here?
I heard that he got a promotion
I'm here to congratulate him
This is a wonderful pen
It's not the best
but the carving is beautiful
And this is for you
Imported cloth from Shanghai
These are for the kids to play with
It's too bad that he is not at home
I would really like to congratulate him
It's not easy to be a government officer
There are many friends here
I heard Chen Piao
wanted to go into business
You should take this pen back
You'll need it in the future
No one is satisfied with their job
It's not easy to keep up with business
Please tell our third brother
There is no problem. Please don't worry
I won't put him in a difficult situation
I'll leave now. Sorry to bother you
Why don't you stay for dinner?
Our brother is coming home.
I shouldn't be here
We'll teach him a lesson
if he doesn't agree with us
Yes, teach him a lesson
Yes, give him something to remember
Stupid, all of them are idiots
Ly Chen Piao has been recruiting people
He'll train them to be the best soldiers
They'll arrest us when they are ready
Then we won't have a chance
Hurry up...
Get ready
Release it
We can't wait here and let them...
either die or go to jail
Hold on
Attention
Let's go...
New officers always work harder
Looks like he is trying to
prove something
It won't be pretty.
We need to calm things down
How do we do that?
Let's ask the Fifth Lord a favor.
He'll solve it
There are three respectful people
in Young Chou
In the seniority of vagrants
he is the oldest one
With his position...
he should be able to take care of it
He'll think through this matter
What if he doesn't go our way;
Then what should we do?
All of this is for our brothers
We have to work to pay for our living
If we don't have an income,
how do we live?
Can we leave them alone?
Everyone goes their own way
And we don't get involved
Do you think either you or I can do it?
I don't think it's so serious
Do you remember fifth lord's
only daughter
Jin Mei and what happened with
Lo Xio Mou!
The little potato Lo Xio Mou?
Yes, he wanted to marry Jin Mei
The fifth Lord got so mad and scolded him
But he couldn't believe
She was pregnant
Are you? Tell me! Is it true?
I've told you already
I don't know. I really don't know
You...
Fifth Brother
Fifth Brother, take it easy!
It's all my fault
because I'm not strict with you
You really embarrassed me
Just go to hell!
Stop there
Where are you going?
Didn't you tell me to go to hell?
All right, go ahead
I'll kill you
Fifth Brother... please calm down
Fifth Brother... don't hit her anymore
Please...
You should die
Yes, I don't have mother.
No one cares about me
Anyone can hurt me
Mom...
Fifth Brother, you are too much
She is two months pregnant
We should find a solution
Yes
Jin Mei, you have to consider your dad
His social position is very respectful
As his family you should think for him
Then why don't you give me an idea?
What idea can I come up with now?
I'm not afraid to die
It'll make it worse
How can your dad face others?
You're right!
My sister-in-law,
please give me a good advice
Alright, ask Jin Mei to accompany you
to Shanghai
You can stay at your place first
As it is, you just said you needed a break
Look for a good doctor
Have an abortion
This matter can't be delayed
Sister-in-law, two women on a trip
Would you please help us?
Send someone with us
Don't let too many people know about it
I'll send Xio Chou to accompany you
Xio Chou?
My cousin. He won't leak the secret
Chong Hua is here
Cousin
Chong Hua, this is auntie Suen
Auntie Suen
Oh, please!
Chong Hua, this is Jin Mei
Jin Mei
When Jin Mei reached Shanghai
She found a doctor to have an abortion
She felt so grateful to Xio Chou...
she wanted to marry him
The fifth Lord knew this
But he tried not to pay attention
We need to go to the
Anti-corruption office
I already arranged to see someone for info
I'll go to see him.
We both are from same town
I helped him to borrow 100 dollars
He needed the money to go to Nanjing
This time it's different though
He is very busy
Because of his relationship
with Ly Chen Piao
I heard Commander Ly is getting promoted
We should throw him a party
Commander Ly refused all the gifts
He said this time it was business
He will upset many people
There is nothing to celebrate
The word is, many would die at his hands
Really?
It could merely be a rumor
I'm afraid that it's probably true
The Governor has ordered him to
He has no choice but to follow the order
That's true
His superiors
take severe disciplinary measures
The Commander has to do the same
The superiors want arrests
The Commander has to find them
There is no other way!
Yes...
Excuse me
I need to go inside
We'll come to see you some other time
This is a little token
Thank you...
Those servants are really...
You said there was only one alternative
There's a saying you swallow
whatever you put in
Are you saying...
You're responsible for what you did
Yes
What did you say?
Um, I...
Those people who follow Din Wei
They address Pao Shan as "boss"
But I'm still the person in charge
This is no good for Pao Shan
They will say that
Xu Pao Shan is chicken shit
And that, he is not good enough
Everyone knows that
Pao Shan is not a coward
The last couple of years
I tried to let Pao Shan take over
I wanted him to take over the burden
Then I could take it easy
and enjoy my life
I haven't been out for a while
And if Pao Shan is not there
I have to take all the responsibility
And if I cannot do it right...
Those subordinates will have to leave
They'll have to work
in those slimy places
Fifth Lord,
I don't think that you'll like it
They will come to bother you all the time
I think
If Pao Shan is in charge
Sheng Xio Lo wouldn't stand a chance
If I take control...
I can keep 7 or 8 hundred people
We can maintain ourselves
It's not the best situation
but it's alright
Fifth Lord, please allow me to do this
Please get up...
I promise you
Be quick... get up
I thought there was no one here
Dad is here and Sister-in-law Pei
You're always ever so pretty
Last time you were here
I was riding on my horse
but I couldn't concentrate
I thought there was something
going on at home
I rushed home and found you here
Isn't that strange?
It's not strange
because we like each other
Sister-in-law Pei
Sister-in-law Pei, about this matter...
It stays between you and me
I'll reply to you in a couple of days
Relax!
Don't let Pao Shan know
I mean, his temper...
Yes...
What did it say in the documents?
They didn't have any specifications
It's only the name of criminals
Chen Piao, the General has told you
You should know how many there are
What's wrong?
You wouldn't even tell us
How many?
Six of them
You have to arrest all of them
It has been addressed in the document
If anyone resists you can kill them
How can you take this job? Chen Piao
It's a tough one
Uncle, I had no choice
Please forgive me
Is there any other way? Chen Piao
Can you not kill them?
We can't let the robbers run free
Selling illegal salt
Can you give them a chance?
Yes, I've been trying to tell the General
But he asked me a question
I didn't dare be persistent
What did he ask? Please tell me
He said to me
Would you be able to ask them to promise;
From now on, in this area...
there will be no more illegal salt
What a joke! Who dares to guarantee?
My luck is no good
He wants them dead and I have to do it
Say, how about
if you don't kill all of them!
We just find one to be a scapegoat
Who would it be?
Xu Pao Shan
Without Xu Pao Shan
What will the rest of us do?
No more illegal salt
Should we rob households instead?
Then you will have more to deal with
Can we just give you the widow Pei?
Did she volunteer?
Could we force her if she disagreed?
We have over 200 years between us
Would we bullshit you here?
We're making a great play
The criminal agreed to confess
It's your call now
Yes. Please don't get mad, Uncle
I was too rude
No need to bullshit. Chen Piao
There is only one question
Will this arrangement solve it?
Well...
Will it work?
Then I'll tell Mr. Liu
They all escaped except one
No more trouble?
They'd better behave
Otherwise I don't think I can cover them
Chen Piao is trying his best. Brother
You'll have to tell Pao Shan later
The widow Pei will be the hero among us
Pao Shan becomes the coward
It's all up to you to be hero or a coward
You need to face it
even if it's difficult
What's wrong with you?
I'm going to ask you right now
What happened?
Second Lord told me about it
Why didn't you discuss it with me first?
You gave yourself in
and embarrassed me!
It's not your business
Their first target was me
I'm guilty! It's not your problem
Why did it embarrass you?
All right, maybe you're the first one
The next will be me
You're guilty
I'm also guilty
Don't be a fool! Pao Shan
I'm not doing this for you
It's for my own good
Just for the sake of our past
Please listen to me
You are not doing this only for yourself
I understand it's also for me
But I don't appreciate
your way of doing things
You made me the bad guy
I'll go talk to Ly Chen Piao
Pao Shan
What are you going to say?
The same deal but I'll go instead of you
Pao Shan
It doesn't matter who goes to surrender
This is our own decision
It doesn't mean that
the court will accept
We haven't got an answer
They will reply to us later
That's all right
Let's wait for Jin Mei
and Xio Chou's wedding
We'll decide after they set a date
Fine then! I'll take your word
But I have one request
Go ahead! I'll promise you anything
Did you sew it?
It's not very nice,
please don't laugh at me
It's admirable; I dare not mock you
Can I show you more?
This is called Blossoms of wealth
Very good
The flowers blossom and Spring is coming
You'll be a great couple
When is your birthday?
I was born on the Double Ninth Festival
As per lunar calendar it's September 9th
What time?
What for?
It's a lucky day
Yes, I checked the calendar
It's a good day to get married
Also it's Jin Mei's birthday
We can choose that day
If everything is set
We can have the wedding
before the year ends
I'll try to arrange it for Chong Hua
Would it be too hurried?
I'm afraid that I won't be free to wait
After all it's a happy occasion;
sooner is better
That's all right!
Don't worry! Sister-in-law
I'll try my best to handle it
When is it coming?
It depends on you
I want to take care of
my cousin's wedding
Tell me the date when you're ready
Pao Shan is here
You hide first
You got a promotion, my dear brother
I haven't had a chance
to congratulate you
Oh, come on now, Brother Pao Shan
Okay then, let me be honest
How can you and Chou Ju...
make decisions behind my back
Well, I didn't know she hadn't told you
You made me look like a fool
I can't let her take my place
And help me hide
I'd be too embarrassed
How can I go on living?
But...
No more talking
The same deal but I'll go instead of her
All right, honor is more important
I promised you
You set a date
I'll come. The sooner the better
How about tomorrow?
I heard that Xio Chou is engaged
We can wait until the wedding
That's a long time
I have work to attend to
It's a deal. I'll wait for you
All right
Be it to share sorrow or joy
We can't let our big brother
take everything
Yes, it's not right
What if the government
breaks its promise,
Or pushed for more
One is not enough!
They will arrest more
They will want to get all of us later
What should we do?
Tell them to get ready
We'll fight back if there is any action
Yes
Why should we surrender to them?
Am I right?
Yes, he is right
No
Sister-in-law
According my experience
Mr. Ly will follow through his orders
Even if we fight back...
we won't be able to run away
We should make a plan
If Pao Shan gives himself up
What will we do if he's in Nanjing?
And what should we do if he is here?
In Nanjing, it doesn't matter
who the officer is...
or how much we will spend;
We'll rescue him
Money is not the problem
The money is easy it's the officer
that is the worry
I know the officer of Transportation
Maybe I can pull some strings
No, please don't even try it
He doesn't like Ly Chen Piao
or Liu Wen Nan
They are enemies
Don't screw things up!
They couldn't help us even if
they wanted to
If he is going we will all go
It doesn't matter what will happen
Yes... we have to
share the responsibilities
That's not the best way
More people doesn't mean better
Also we need to take care of our place
That's why I've been saying
I should go
and you take care of the family
Here we go again!
I mean it
I'll surrender to the law
All of you plead with the Government
With your talent you'll be
better than Ly Chen Piao
If I really wanted to work
in the Government
I didn't need to wait until now
We'll find a solution
Let's wait until
after the Double Ninth Festival
Gentlemen, we must stay together
Pao Shan is in trouble
All of us have to help him out
Yes...
You're responsible for what you did
Pao Shan is our hero
Let's raise a toast for him
I should raise a toast to all of you
Fifth Uncle
Chen Piao
Third uncle, Second uncle, Pao Shan
Brother
Please sit down
Mr. Sheng has said it
This time, because of Pao Shan...
He considered my situation
Helped me out a lot
I can't express my gratitude in words
I can only propose this drink
to thank you
Pao Shan, please drink with me
I have to say something. My brother
I'll take the full responsibility
And I won't cause trouble for you
Mrs. Pei has been retired for a long time
If she did anything wrong before...
Please let her go. As a favor for my sake
Pao Shan didn't need to ask
But as long as he said it
I need to make myself clear
Well...
Yes, you should. Chen Piao
Gentlemen, Mrs. Pei is a heroine
We all admire her
I'm not the best
but I still know the difference
What kind of person do you think I am?
Come on, cheers
Yes...
More, a little more. That's it
You're here
Sister-in-law
Come on in
Take it slow, you play by yourself
Third brother wanted to ask you
I'm ready to carry out the plan
Cousin
Third sister-in-law
Granddad Ju is here
Xiao Chou, please take the fish tank
This little one likes it
No...
It's nothing
It can be a souvenir
When I'm not here
Take care, Third Granddad
Chou Ju is an extraordinary lady
She took care of everything
Congratulations...
Thank you, please sit down
Thank you, take a seat
Congratulations...
Fifth Lord
The presents are too much
You're too kind
It's nothing
Compared with the bride Jin Mei
We know that
you are different than others
You only have one daughter- Jin Mei
Chong Hua will be your son-in-law
Let's drink to it... cheers
Bottoms up
Come on... look
Will sister-in-law preserve her life?
Hard to say! Unless the dowager orders it
Dowager Ci Xi
Is there anyone who can persuade her?
Who? You or me?
Those three old men? Mr. Liu?
Quit dreaming
Mrs. Pei surrendered to the authorities
If Mr. Liu doesn't keep his promise...
how can you face others!
Father, one is dead
Please... go ahead
Let's make a toast
Where is your cousin?
She just went back to her room
Tell her to join the party
Cousin, Cousin...
She is not in her room
Take some more, help yourself
- Chou Ju...
- Cousin...
She is gone
Gone? Where did she go?
She must have turned herself in
Where? Where did she go?
The city
No
The Anti-smuggling Department's office?
Then where did she go?
She must have gone to Ly Chen Piao's home
Maybe he'll take her
to Nanjing over night
She is gone
Who?
Our fifth sister-in-law
I think she has gone to the authorities
She could be stopped
at the 12th pier if we hurry
Let's go, come on
You find the guard and ask him
Hurry up...
Bring the criminal
What happened?
We'd need to interrogate
Who?
The widow Pei
Come on out
Hurry up...
Come over...
Bring Pei Chou Ju
Yes
Pei Chou Ju is here
They are calling you
Third brother
The statement has been delivered
to Nanjing
We've tried all we could
The interrogator is an acquaintance
If you co-operate...
It should be easy
Pei Chou Ju
Are you the criminal Pei Chou Ju?
Yes
What is your husband's name?
Pei Din Wei
Was he a salt smuggler before he died?
He had no other choice
How many people worked for him?
From 20, 30 to 200 - 300
You've been committing organized crimes
We were forced to break the law
Had he ever violated the law?
Did he resist arrest?
It was normal to run
when you see soldiers
Certainly you'll resist if you can
Whose nick name is Tiger Xu?
His name is Xu Pao Shan
He works for me
The word around is that
he was the real boss
You can tell from his nick name...
the kind of personality he carries
His temper isn't that bad
And he is not mean at all
It's just his look that's so intimidating
Why do people link you
and him so closely then?
Well... there are other reasons
Would you be able to elaborate?
I'm afraid it's not relevant here
I'm the one who has broken the law
On March 8th last year
Xu Pao Shan shot an officer
What happened?
I was also there
I told him to fire the gun
Why did you order him to shoot?
Because I couldn't do it
No one can shoot like Xu Pao Shan
He shot at the officer's leg
There is another case
Sir, if there is any case
It's totally my idea and all my fault
Take her down! We'll continue it later
It's unfair! Everything is on her
She can't be responsible for everything
It's not right to sentence her to death
Then we should let her off easy
It's indeed a very tough decision
Any better suggestion?
Can we drop the case?
Then what should I write in the report?
I'll try to figure out a solution...
To keep both sides happy
It doesn't matter what will happen
We'd better keep Pei Chou Ju alive
The government wants salt dealers to stop
I think the best way
is to offer Xu a deal
He and his subordinates
can start a new life
Nonsense!
Are you all day-dreaming'?
We've been in this business
for over 20 years
There're 7 - 8 hundred people
working for us
We should just surrender
when they tell us
They built the fort with canons
Put Mrs. Pei in jail in Nanjing
It's their trick!
If they let her go
We can divide our fortune
After that we can go on our own way
You can surrender or run
Otherwise we can fight them to death
Damn it! I won't fall for his trick
Please consider Mrs. Pei
If we make trouble...
Maybe they'll do away with her
All right, if that's the case
I'm going to be honest with you
There is no future here
Sure, I won't keep you
But please don't do anything against us
We wish you good luck;
Where will you go?
My friend works
in the Transportation Dept.
I intend requesting him for a job
The chief Song Cuen?
All right, just remember Mrs. Pei's words
The Chief doesn't like Liu Wen Nan
And Ly Chen Piao either
They are two separate matters
We shouldn't mix them up
I'm going to pack
Don't forget where you are from!
Mrs. Pei is in trouble
But you're switching your side
Bastard, I'll pay them back
Shit! Those two?
What's wrong?
Don't you know the widow Pan?
She is with Xio Ko
She lost her husband two years ago
What a bitch!
She is trying to get attention
Xio Ko had the affair because of her
Are you serious?
Why did you keep mentioning her?
Shit! You think that Pei was a nice one
They are all the same kind
There is no difference between them
It happened one night
Take it easy
Don't forget that you are a widow,
Mrs. Pan
Don't you feel ashamed?
Listen to how honorable she sounded
Especially with her and Tiger Xu...
He's here
Who?
The Chief, my new boss
What are they going to do with the case?
What are we going to do?
That's convenient
What a joke!
You're right
Are there any laws?
No, I don't think so
Someone filed a complaint about me
It said that I took the order
I was in charge of arresting the dealers
Pei Chou Ju and Xu Pao Shan
But I took a bribe from them
That I discreetly ordered their release
And also to go easy on Pei Chou Ju
I tried to help the salt dealers
There is someone here to investigate
When did it happen?
Where did the complaint come from?
Did the chief check it up first?
Yes
The order is from Song Cuen
He hated me from the beginning
How can he know all the secrets?
It must be someone from inside
They wanted to screw us over
What do you think about this case?
The sooner it's over, the better
How about Mrs. Pei?
We don't need to worry about her
When the verdict is out we'll move
We have no choice
But...
It's for the good of Pei Chou Ju
and Xu Pao Shan
I have to ask
If Pei Chou Ju can't stand it
Because they keep on interrogating her
Maybe even torture her
Say, if she can't make it...
And confesses everything to them;
Xu Pao Shan won't be able to get away
When is she going to court again?
She's scheduled
to be interrogated tomorrow
Interrogated?
Bring the criminal
Yes
Come back, be nice and stop swaggering
The criminal Pei Chou Ju is here
Come in
Your honor
What are you doing? Get out
Hurry up
Lift up your head
You don't look like a killer
I've never killed anyone
How many subordinates do you have?
I didn't count
I've never thought of them
as my subordinates
We're just working for a living
Helping each other when need be
Do you know it's illegal dealing salt?
Please forgive me, your honor
I know it's illegal
I have a big family to support
There was no choice for me
Please listen to her
We are the officers of the Government
We should take care of their livelihood
You're absolutely right
Who is Xu Pao Shan?
He works for me
He does what I tell him to
If he has done anything
it is because of me
I told him to; so it's my fault
What kind of a person is he?
He is very kind and capable
Not a mean person at all
Just for jobs sake, he listens to me
He is innocent
Do you think that he can change?
I mean, if I allow him a chance
If your honor is so understanding
Not only will Xu Pao Shan appreciate it
I would also be grateful to you
Pei Chou Ju, the Government is generous
I would like to release you too
But you've been charged with
serious crimes
I HAVE TO sentence you to death
Is there anything that
you would like to say?
Yes, your honor
I'm responsible for all the crimes
I don't want to hurt the innocent
And please grant me a last favor
I'd rather avoid being embarrassed
She wants to have death by hanging
Don't chop her head off in the public
I won't let you be embarrassed
Take her back
Yes
Thank you, your honor
It's a set up, he set us up
Son of a bitch! Ly Chen Piao
Let me go... leave me alone
Pao Shan, Pao Shan
Fifth Uncle, please do something
All right, please get up
I have to get even with Ly Chen Piao
You don't have to tell us, Pao Shan
We understand your feelings
But I have to be fair
Chong Hua and myself saw it in Nanjing
Chen Piao was trying his best to help
But she still got the death penalty
I can't let them do it
I'm going...
What are you going to do?
We are going to Nanjing
To do what?
To have Pei Chou Ju freed
Nonsense
I'm telling you, don't be stupid
Don't do anything stupid
Should I just let her die?
How can I forgive myself?
Pao Shan, be serious
If you fail, you will also die
Even if you're successful
where will you go?
Just for fifth madam
You will kill many of our brothers
I don't think Mrs. Pei
would agree with it
Brother, my cousin gave you a message
She said the same thing hundred times
She wants you to stop breaking the law
Lead a normal life
She is not only doing it for you
But also for everybody
If you go against her wishes...
You'll ruin the whole plan
Who broke the original agreement?
We've arranged it already
Someone complained about us
Who did this shit?
I heard it was
the chief of transportation
It's so strange; he knew everything!
Someone must have leaked the news
Who do you think?
The Chief of Transportation
It's him
For sure
Brother...
It's him. Brother
Son of a bitch! It's really him. Let's go
What happened? Pao Shan
I'm going to get the person who betrayed
Who?
You'll know very soon
Jin Mei
Fifth Sister
What are you doing here?
How could I not come to see you!
We really miss you
No, come on
Please sit down
Before it's time for me to leave,
let me take a good look at you all
Have you chosen the date?
Not yet
Why not?
You're young; you can take it slow
But how about your father
He wants to have grandsons
The earliest will be over the New Year
Why not before the New Year?
There are too many things happening
We're so looking forward to your return
I sewed a pair of pillow cases for you
I don't think I can attend your wedding
Please accept my gift
When you see it, it'll be like seeing me
Jin Mei, cousin
You are here!
There is nothing I should say
I hope you will have a wonderful future
Help and be considerate to each other
I'm your match-maker
I'd be so happy...
If you have a great life
Cousin, I'll remember your words
Always
Chong Hua, the message I gave you
Did you tell Xu Pao Shan?
Yes, I did
What is he doing now?
He went out to take care of some business
What kind of business?
He has gone to find out who framed you up
Who did it?
Who?
Bring Dong Jin Piao in
Dong Jin Piao
You broke your vow
Do you know the rules?
Are you guilty?
I don't know. What do you mean?
You're lying
Why did you leak the news?
You gave Chief information
I didn't. Who told you so?
I did
You... you don't have any proof
We've got the proof, you can't lie to us
Please bring out Ce Jin Piao
So you were undercover
All right, I made a wrong friend
Not you, it was Mr. Pei
He shouldn't have kept you as a friend
Yes, Pei Din Wei went blind...
to have you as his friend
Marrying an old hag Pei Chou Ju
Dong Jin Piao
Would you again
violate predecessors crime;
Disrespect those before us?
All right, I confess
I'll accept the punishment
Do you submit willingly?
Yes, I do
As long as you agree
I have to use our domestic regulations
Bring it
Yes
There are rules that we need to follow
You'll get the punishment
If you broke a rule
Everyone is treated equally
Dong Jin Piao is no longer one of us
Brand his arm
Yes
There are gun shots
Gun shots?
Nothing! It's all right...
Stop! Don't run
What are you doing?
Stop running! I'll shoot
Don't run
Don't fight anymore...
I'm telling you
It's our own family matter.
Stay out of it
Stop running
Wait a moment
Shit! So many on one
What kind of people are you?!
You shot without warning
What rules are you talking about
What? I can't handle you
There are regulations everywhere
You shouldn't hit after the punishment
Do you dare to go
against the domestic rules?
Brother, we don't need to talk to him
Come on
Wait
None of you is allowed to take him
Commander Ly gave this to you
It's your time. You should try it
You'll be fine after you eat it
Thank you
Thank you, Auntie Wong
Thank you, Commander Ly
Thank you, Secretary Chen
I'm satisfied with my life
I'm ready to die
Everyone is so nice to me
I can't repay it even with my life
Sister-in-law Pei, you are the hero
I've never seen it before
All the stuff, see if anyone can use it
Please give them away
We've been friends for a long time
I ought to give you something for memory
I don't want it. You should keep it
I'll split these among the others
Chou Ju
She's dead
Who is dead?
Pei Chou Ju
How could she have died!
It's really scary
Follow me... let's go...
Carry her out
Cover it up, cover it up
Nails
There is always a way to bribe an officer
After pulling some strings...
We used a switch
Mrs. Pei was rescued by us
Dong Jin Piao deserved it
We simply couldn't have allowed her
to sacrifice
We sold lots of illegal salt
With our wealth
we can make the difference
But we are carrying a dead person
It's pretty spooky!
Stop...
Don't move
We're from Anti-smuggling.
What're you up to?
This is Mrs. Pei's coffin
I don't care whose coffin it is
Open it. C'mon, be quick
They need to check it
Try offering them some money
Okay
Mrs. Pei was a private person
Please help her for the last time
All right! Let's leave
What a pity!
I was a civilian and became an officer
Because I'm an officer I have to be fair
We once swore we wouldn't let anyone go
Even the commander in chief
Now he is the president
But he aspires to be the Emperor
If he becomes the Emperor
Damn it! One day I'll...
Sir
The President sent me to bring you
He wants the commander
to go to the capital
You tell the President
When my millions of soldiers are ready...
I'll go to see him
Yes...
The President knows that
you admire antiques
He told me to bring a vase as a gift
Please accept it
What are you looking at? Get lost
Yes sir...