A post funeral ceremony
(religious verses in Punjabi)
Losing both your parents in an
accident seemed like a conspiracy.
It was just that I
had no one to blame for it.
Chhoti.
No need to make any more tea.
Are they to mourn or...?
It's only close family now.
Grandpa, aunt and ...
Chhoti is crying in the
bathroom go give her some water.
I'll take the tea.
Till the time he
completes his college..
..Mukesh will stay with you.
Father-in-law,
I have a touring job.
Your daughter runs the house.
I will abide by
whatever you two decide.
Papaji, we never dared to
have a second child of our own.
We have neither the
space nor the means...
Nothing is hidden from you.
He is like my own son.
But, how can I take
his responsibility?
I understand...
It was my son's age
to take responsibility.
But instead he has
left me with his share too.
Don't worry, I will take
care of any extra expenses bourne
by you from my pension fund.
But, his is a responsibility
we all must share.
I am not going to Delhi.
I am going to stay here.
And take care of Sonu and Chhoti.
Bring me some butter.
Coming!
No breakfast, Mukesh?
College must have already started.
Eats enough... free loader!
'I was offered the most
pedestrian course in college.'
'B.A Pass.'
Why are you standing on my head!
Want to inhale the smoke?
What do you want?
You are always
in need of something.
Aunt...I need some money.
To get fliers printed.
I am thinking of giving
private tuition to school kids.
Will return the money
as soon as I get the job.
No harm dreaming.
But what if you don't
get the tuitions?
Your grandfather does
not send us a fortune!
No point wasting
money on silly schemes.
Don't you know a chess board attracts
evil spirits with scores to settle.
Wait! Let me search your bag!
Why? Am I a thief?
Kid, this is Delhi!
Here everyone is a thief!
On a good day you get robbed.
On bad days you get killed
first and then robbed.
Kasparov.
Wipe that innocent
look off your face!
I catch coffin thieves
like you everyday.
Hey! Stop!
What have you stolen?
Must have stolen something?
What?
A corpse's gold tooth?
A diamond ring maybe?
Come...follow me.
Pious! Need an extra
day to make one box?
He is the one Johnny bhai!
Always loitering around
with a chess board!
Come on, Kasparov...
Sit down.
Kasparov played like a bull!
Karpov was the wily one!
Come on.
Take out your chess board!
What kept you so long?
The ladies have already
started arriving.
Clean up,
at least look a little presentable.
We're having a kitty party.
All the ladies are here.
Yes! Yes! Sarika is here too!
Sarika, my husband says hello.
Hello.
So, Mukesh!
Working very hard.
Come over to help me sometimes too.
So... when can I expect you?
Mr. Khanna is of hardly
any use in the house!
She just likes to embarrass you!
Don't go pink in the face.
Sarika wants to send
over a case of apples!
Go and pick it up soon.
I'll go next Sunday.
Make us all a pot of
good steaming tea, son.
Sarika called again
about the case if apples.
Tomorrow is a holiday
go pick it up.
Listen, her husband
is your uncle's superior.
When such a people call you
even to pick up their rubbish
you thank them for the chance.
And here she wants to
send over a case of apples!
Don't delay it... go tomorrow.
Let me know if you
need anymore bread.
Amit! Get up, son.
It's noon already.
You still here?
Just leaving...
Is Sarika ma'am at home?
Who has called you?
There is no Sarika here.
What do you want?
I am Mrs. Verma's nephew.
I have come for the case of apples.
Listen to me carefully.
She is a witch! A proper witch!
A snake in a woman's body!
There are no apples here.
I have thrown them all away!
Now run away!
There is no one home... run away!
Beware of her!
Now you show me respect
but later you will also abuse me!
Beware! She will tie you up!
Go! Run away!
Biji!
I have told you not to
open the door to strangers!
One day someone will slash
our throats and rob everything.
Shut the door behind you.
Dolls?
They are mine, my father
was in the foreign services.
I have travelled to many countries
with him when I was a child.
Sit.
Did Pammi not tell you my name?
Sarika.
Why are you always
doing od jobs in the house?
Don't you have friends?
What's the matter?
Do I make you nervous?
You are not a little boy anymore.
Someone might think
that I am misbehaving.
Who?
Biji.
She is sleeping...she
can sleep through a bomb blast!
I have come for the case of apples.
You took your time coming
there was a last one left.
My husband gave
it away this morning.
More will come soon from
my brother's orchard in Shimla.
Your hair is thick like a girl's!
Comb it properly or get it cut!
Lie down.
Hmm... you're not as afraid
as you were pretending to be!
Are you in a hurry? Do you
have an appointment elsewhere?
Hello.. - Pammi... Sarika here.
I am sending Mukesh to the
market to run an errand for me.
Hope you don't mind?
No...no...not at all!
He hardly does anything
after returning from college.
I've taught him everything so that
he does not sit around in the house.
Idling his time away.
But do make sure he
gives you proper accounting!
Thank you, Pammi. I'll talk later.
Your aunt has taught you shopping
and I'll teach you the rest!
Take a bath.
I already did... in the morning!
Then take a bath again.
Bite me.
I want you to leave marks!
You are too much in a hurry kid!
There goes your queen!
You are making progress.
But there is still
a long way to go.
Check!
Choke me!
Get a haircut and
buy some decent clothes.
You bloody virgin!
You have become quite a whore!
Delhi air is something!
Did you look at his hair style?
Your grandfather is yet
to send money this month.
From where have you got
the new shoes and clothes?
I managed to get
a couple of tuitions.
He is lying.
There has been no inquiry
for an under graduate tutor!
I got it through
the college librarian.
Stays nearby, few blocks from here.
Where are you off to on a holiday?
I have tuition to give.
Ashok is at home.
Keep your ears & eyes
open and your mouth shut.
She puts chains on my feet!
But I am not a fool! You hear?
Biji! Apply the brakes
or it is off to bed for you!
He is always hanging around
the house in your absence!
He got late going
to the club today...
I'll have to buy
you a cell phone now.
Don't forget to get the bill.
who is he?
Mrs. Verma's nephew,
very helpful boy.
'That evening I could not
make it back to Sarika's house.'
'I was on my way to my home town,
Tohana.'
Sonu and Chhoti
are our responsibility
but we are barely making ends meet.
Mukesh, finish your college quickly.
Everyone's counting on you.
We should sent Chhoti
and Sonu to a girl's home.
Pammi is over burdened as it is.
Sonu...Chhoti...hurry up.
Come on its getting late.
Don't worry,
your brother will visit you often.
'Sarika knew what
was going on in my life.'
'But at first she
chose to remain quiet.'
'Then one day out of the blue..'
Now you will be needing money!
Help this lady out.
She will pay for small
but important errands.
If you are reliable
there would be more jobs.
I am Mukesh.
Stop here.
Hello! I'm Mukesh.
I spoke to you over
the phone yesterday.
Yes...yes... come in.
I can't do this.
Why not?
You seem to be doing
pretty alright here!
I wasn't doing it for the money!
What happened?
First she gave me money,
it seemed excessive.
Then...
When I refused she
said she would scream!
She never said anything of that
sort to me seemed pretty happy.
She threatened me that
she would call in the neighbors..
..and say that I had
broken into the house!
I can't do this...
I am not that kind of a boy!
Really!
What kind of a boy are you?
To sleep with women for money!
You take the money!
I don't want any of it!
I've taken my share,
the rest is yours.
I won't do it.
What else do you think you are qualified
for in the first year of college?
Fine! Leave then Don't
come around here anymore!
Get lost!
I give you a chance and
you come back crying like a kid.
Don't show me your face again!
Mukesh.
Do you really want to go on living
like a servant in your aunt's house?
Come.
Think of all that you
can do with the money.
You can call your
sisters to live with you!
Don't think how the
money comes be happy to know
that there will be more coming.
If nothing else think
of it as social service!
Just do it...
As it is one has to do
a lot for other's happiness.
Think about yourself for once.
Don't you like me?
I like everything! You as well!
I also like the benefits
of a marriage in Delhi's society.
I have taught you well!
Now the world will
enjoy your talents.
'The phone numbers were real,
the names were not.'
'I had to ask for the fake name.'
Hello, Neha ma'am.
'If there was any hesitation
on the other end..'
'..I pretended to have
gotten the wrong number.'
You understand what client
servicing means, don't you?
Keep them happy and
they will call you again.
Do whatever they ask of you.
Complaints will not be tolerated.
(Soap opera on TV)
Didn't this fellow Rakesh
die in last week's episode?
Don't you have a TV in your house?
I hardly get the time,
catch up on it.
When I am with you.
Ok, I will tell you
the story after that.
A speeding Rakesh
loses control of his car.
Which then falls into a river...
Dheeraj, you scum! You low life!
But he is saved by
the second heroine Ganga!
You were dying to have an affair,
were you not?
Get lost!
So Ganga saves Rakesh's life.
But dies herself. A distraught
Rakesh returns to the city!
to the first heroine Priya.
Who is Dheeraj? If I may ask.
The asshole in my lord
and master... my husband.
Rakesh is dead again !
Yes, this time he's really dead.
Forget about that episode.
Let's finish this episode first.
Hello! Chhoti,
did you get the money I sent you?
Yes, but the warden was
asking too many questions.
Give the phone to Sonu.
Always wants to speak with you.
What was the warden saying?
Same old stuff, who sent the money?
How do I know that
he is really your brother?
If he is so loaded then why
has he dumped both of you here?
Don't worry, I will come
there and have a word with her.
Chhoti, you go from here.
There is something
not right with this place.
The girls here...
Are they troubling you?
They go out at night in fancy cars,
all dolled up.
Return in the morning,
drunk and loaded with money.
The warden gets a cut too!
Yesterday they were forcing
me to go out with them...
Don't worry, I will come
soon and speak to the warden.
Take care of yourself..
bye.
Don't schedule anything
for the weekend.
Why?
I am going to meet my sisters. I
will go every weekend from now on.
What do you think this is,
a government job
that you will get the weekend off?
Go this time...
But don't make it a habit!
Which way to the warden office?
Why don't you take then with you?
I will soon.
Till then, I want them
to be looked after well.
They are still very young
and I have heard that...
What have you heard?
Don't think there is
nobody looking out for them.
I have brought a phone for them.
No need for a personal phone.
There is a public phone here.
You talk to them often, don't you?
Buy some gifts for your children.
Keep this and call me everyday.
I will make sure
there is enough credit.
We don't want to stay here!
Just a few more days
then I will come and get you.
Promise.
O Mauritius.
You are not going to become any fairer
by spending hours under the tap!
Fat fuck!
Has bath once a year and finishes
the whole colony's water supply.
Why would I have a bath everyday,
pretty boy?
I don't run a side
business like you.
Then maybe you should
start running one!
Or else you will keep dreaming
about going to Mauritius
and never actually get there!
Stop whining!
There is water left for
you to wash your ass clean!
Johnny bhai.
Hey, tuition master!
Come meet the headmaster.
He is studying to be
a doctor of philosophy.
Ph.D?
Yeah, in chemistry during the day
and in biology during the night!
Better than you, you slob. Making a
living out of scavenging the dead!
That's where you are going to end
up yourself sooner than you think!
It doesn't take much
for the times to change, son.
Fuck off!
Your entire existence is ill timed.
Johnny bhai.
I have a small gift for you.
Forever indebted to you, my friend!
In the beginning I waited
for my husband to get better...
Knew that it might never happen,
but I had hope...
Then eventually,
I started waiting for him to die...
Years went by...I
just kept on waiting...
Sometimes hoping that
my husband would get better.
Sometimes wishing that he would die
so that his suffering would end.
You have no one close?
No immediate family?
I have a son,
a little elder to you...
Lives in Singapore...
sends money too.
But can't come himself
He's got a job, it's difficult.
You go now, the relatives
will be arriving any time now.
Not much action seems
have happened here last night!
Her husband passed away...
I was trying to call,
Why didn't you answer?
I was in the hospital,
Has switched the ringer off.
Come on, then! We have
paid the rent, why waste it!
What's the matter?
I have just left
his body at her house!
Come I'll drop you home.
Don't come home for a few days.
Ashok seems to be in a strange
mood he has no fixed routine.
Comes and goes as he pleases.
Are you angry with me?
You are not my husband that I need to
throw a tantrum to get your attention?
Just do as I tell you.
I'll let you know when
is a good time to come.
Just drop me off here,
I have some work.
That's my friend Johnny.
I'll leave now.
Why did you make me meet him?
He is a friend! Lives nearby. I play
chess with him in the cemetery.
Have you blabbered anything
to him about our work?
No! I just told him that
you help me get tuitions.
Good! Your minds has also
sharpened up along with your body.
So partner,
why did you want to see me?
I need a house.
Are you looking to buy one?
No, want to rent one.
So what is the problem?- Nobody
wants to give it to a bachelor.
And I can't call my sister
here until I have a house.
Don't worry! Call your sisters!
How can I call them
till I have a house!
Don't worry about that!
I have a lady friend too!
What family were you talking about?
He is a bachelor!
Why? I am there!
These days even two
men can start a family!
Stay within your limits, Johnny!
Just kidding!
He has got two lovely sisters.
They will come and stay with him.
You can lord over them!
They will help you
in your housework too!
How much is the rent?
3,000 rupees, no security because
Johnny has brought you here.
But I will take
three months advance.
My tenants will vacate
the room in 15 days.
But you need to
pay the advance now.
His sisters will
be here in 15 days.
He will give you the advance then and
you hand us the keys at the same time.
Fair and square, is it not?
Look Johnny, my room shouldn't
go vacant even for a day.
Your house is like my own!
I wouldn't be able to bear it.
If you were to incur
any loss on my account!
May I take one?
Get lost!
Are you a moron?
Rushing to pay the advance when
the house isn't even vacant yet!
You haven't understood
this city at all.
Johnny bhai, thank you.
Oye! What do you
think you are doing?
Hey! I am talking to you!
That is my drawer.
It was my drawer till
you stuffed your things in.
Your mother has given me the key.
If my mother gave you
the house keys someday..
..would the house be yours too?
I pay my share of
the rent every month.
You eat worth much
more in a single day!
I will leave your house...
and your drawer as well!
Quit talking about it.
Why don't you actually
do it for a change.
I told you not to come here!
What was so important?
You should not trust me so much!
Where else can I keep it?
All the banks are asking
for an income proof.
I will come and take
it in a couple of weeks.
This bank will charge interest.
Biji has woken up.
If you can't knock like a civilized
person have the courtesy to look away.
Slut!
Where the fuck do
you think you are going!
Sit here!
I thought my old
mother had gone senile!
Then one day I asked myself
how long since Sarika nagged you?
She seems content!
What has changed?
I has my eye on you
but you sensed it some how!
Clever slut that you are... But
you couldn't resist for long eh!
Today I am going to knock
you back to your senses!
Oye!
Sit! Mother fucker.
Watch and learn!
Usually you are of no use
does seeing me with him
turn you on? You pervert!
If you think you are going
to fuck around behind my back..
..and make me look like a fool...
then think again.
'I was scared to go
back to my aunt's house.'
'I needn't have been for Sarika's
husband had already dug my grave.'
Mukesh had come home in the
afternoon to ask Sarika for a loan.
Said that he was not
being treated well by you.
That you do not give him
proper food nor any pocket money.
Inspite of our constraints
we try to do our best for him...
He had been working well up till
now so Sarika felt sorry for him.
At his age boys tend
to mistake sympathy from women
for an interest of another kind.
Yes, boys at this age
can indeed be very foolish.
He tried to grab her
in front of my old mother.
He was smelling of cheap liquor.
So, Sarika pushed him away.
After that he just went mad.
Tried to kiss her..
Caught her arm so hard
that he has left marks!
Sir, let him return home
my husband will take him to a task.
Do not let him return
is what I came to say.
Your husband is due for a promotion
it will be very unfortunate..
..if instead of a promotion he has
to sit in front of some
anti-corruption inquiry committee.
Mukesh...
pack your things right
away and leave the house!
Where will I go, Buaji?
I don't care.
Go to a friend! Or rent a room!
Very independent you have become.
You make enough money giving
tuitions to get drunk on.
Mr. Khanna is lying! I had
just gone over to meet Sarika.
Everybody is aware
of Sarika's reputation.
Why her husband is targeting you,
I don't know.
But if you stay here, you
will land all of us in trouble...
So for God's sake please spare us.
Oye!
Tuition master!
What happened?
And what's with all this luggage?
Come with me...
Come in.
Settle down.
Mauritius.
My aunt's son lives there...
Keeps calling me, says..
..a little investment
can take me far there
But I say, I am too old
to settle in a new place.
Johnny bhai.
My money is stuck somewhere.
I will rent the room
as soon as I get it back.
Play chess with me every night.
Stay for free as long as you like!
When are you coming to get us?
I'll be there soon!
Why? Has something happened?
No, but just come and get us fast.
I'll be there don't worry!
Hello, Kavita ma'am...
Mukesh here.
Who Mukesh?
There is no Kavita here...
Don't call back again.
Hello, Reena ma'am.
This is Mukesh here.
You haven't called last few days so
I thought I should call and inquire.
Wrong number.
Mrs. Kajal?
This is Mukesh calling.
Usha ma'am.
Mrs. Vandana?
- Wrong number.
Sorry, I won't call back again.
Hello, Sarika ma'am...
I have told you not to call here...
Don't call back again.
This is Mukesh calling.
Sorry.
Who is there ma?
Somebody's got the wrong address.
What are you doing here?
Leave! My husband can come anytime!
Did he hit you?
What else do you expect? A trophy?
My sisters are coming,
I need my money.
Are you done?
They rescheduled my
appointment for tomorrow.
Breakfast!
Johnny bhai, I need a favour?
What?
You will have to go to that lady's
house the one that you met with me.
Why don't you go yourself?
My aunt lives in the same
colony if she sees me there...
What work do you have with her?
Sleeping through the
day begets bad luck my friend!
She says that your due
has already been paid to you.
Your lady friend didn't
even let me enter the house!
She started shouting
and threatening me saying
that she will call her husband!
They have given your number to the
cops even filed a report against you...
What the hell are you upto? You
will get me into trouble as well
Screwed up my work.
Got me thrown out of the house.
And now she says
she will not pay me!
Bitch! Does she think I
am scared of her and her husband!
What does she think of herself?
Calm down!
Shut up and listen to me!
What the fuck do
you think you are doing!
Come to your senses!
Have you lost it!
I don't know what kind
of tuitions you have been giving.
But learn this from me.
Take out your sim card!
Stay away from them
they are rich and connected!
They will get you busted
so bad you won't know what hit you!
Give me the sim card
I will throw it away.
If you throw my sim card
then how will my sisters call me?
Give them my number!
And what if someone calls you?
- Have you ever heard my phone ring?
Use my card and
give them this number.
I am not going to let
her get away with this!
I will cut her to pieces!
Don't talk shit.
We are out of booze as well!
Come...
Come on...
This godforsaken town
is a real shit hole!
You place your trust in people
thinking they are your friends.
But the moment you turn around
they ram it right up your ass.
I'll go give this
number to my sisters.
Ok, but now don't go
stressing them out as well.
Hello, Sonu!
Are you alright?
Who's number is this?
It's a friend's number,
save it on your phone.
What's this noise are you outside?
What are you doing out so late?
- We have run away from there...
We are on our way to Delhi.
Run away!
What do you mean you have run away!
Have you gone mad!
What the hell is going on there?
I'll explain everything
once I reach.
I told you to stay
on for a few days!
Can't you understand that much?
Are you little children!
Brother, please don't
get angry...the warden.
What did she do?
Sonu, tell me what happened?
She got drunk and came in Chhoti's
room...
Was trying to slip into her bed.
I'll explain everything tomorrow.
You both take care of yourselves...
Do you have money?
Yes.
Call me as soon as your reach,
I will come and get you.
Here, gulp it down.
Johnny bhai.
Could you lend me some money?
I will return it soon.
Money?
If I had any money saved do you think
I would have been stuck in this city.
I would have gone away
to Mauritius long back!
I live off the dead!
I bury one corpse to get one meal!
I am surviving because
people die in this city everyday.
I would have run
away long time back.
To Mauritius...
to white sands... to blue skies...
You are young you
will get many chances.
Brother.
Stop for a minute...
You are with me because
this is your first night.
From tomorrow you are on your own.
Be tough! Don't be scared!
Do we wait here?
I'll go first.
How much money should I ask for?
2,000 rupees don't settle for less.
Drink up!
Go on, have another swig.
It eases the pain!
Move aside.
Time to get to work!
Looking for fun?
- Yes!
How much will you pay?
- Let's bargain on the way.
There is one!
Standing all by himself!
Back up.
I am tired of whores around here
let's try the pretty boys for size!
Three of you?
Why, you gonna cook for us tonight?
All three of you will have to pay!
Sure, but let us
see the goods first.
Go on, he is calling you!
Why so wound up?
Are you a first timer?
2,000 rupees for each of you!
That's the rate,
take it or leave it!
The little fucker wants
to play posh! Drag him in boys!
Get in you faggot spreading
filth on the streets!
Give the money first.
The motherfucker thinks
he is prime piece of ass!
Let go of me!
Don't worry about the three
of us you won't get past even one!
Open the door! Let me out!
Stop the car! Let me go!
What happened?
Come here... Mukesh!
Show!
Look, I don't know
what's going on with you
but whatever it is, get out of it.
Forget the past... start afresh.
Johnny, I won't give
up what is rightfully mine.
Have you lost your mind!
What do you want?
I am not here for you...
My work has been stopped.
Your work?
I told your friend about it...
go ask him.
Who stopped it?
- What do you think?
Your husband?
Why?
He did not know about the work
or the boys.
Boys?
There were others.
For the last time,
where is the money?
There is 2,000 in the almirah,
take it and leave!
Next time you come my husband
will be waiting for you!
I haven't come for a handout!
I want money that
is rightfully mine!
So go and ask the
one who has taken it.
Ask whom? Your husband?
He earns more in a day than you
have managed in all these months!
Go and ask your friend!
The scoundrel even
looked like a thief.
Don't lie.
Why do you lie?
Did you learn anything
from me in all these months?
Apart from sex!
Our work can start again,
leave now... Think of your sisters.
I am never sinking
back into your filth again!
I want my money and I want it now!
Sarika, open the door.
Did you foresee this while
you were planning your break in?
Sarika! Open the door!
I know there is someone inside!
Open up!
Open up or I will
cal in the neighbors!
Today the whole world
will see your true colors...
I will rub your face in dirt.
Mukesh.
Come here.
I don't care what people
will think of me...
But you will never be
able to face anyone again!
Put the knife in me!
What?
You don't have to kill me!
Insert it in a little bit!
Sarika! I'll break open the door!
He will kill both of us!
Good! We will die together
like star-crossed lovers!
I am warning you for
the last time Sarika!
That felt good.
First class first!
It was never Johnny who betrayed
me...It has always been you.
And today,
you want to get away again.
Not this time!
This is Mukesh.
Is Johnny there?
Who, Karpov?
Yes.
He took off.
To Mauritius.
The lucky fucker
ran into a bag of cash!
Johnny!
Brother, we have reached.
Where are you?
We have been waiting
outside the train station.
Are you coming?
Wait there, I am on my way.
He is the one, sir.
Hey!
Stop!
Where are you?
How much longer do
we have to wait here?
Do you want us to
wait here all night?
We will have fun skinning
you alive tonight! You runt!
Why are you not answering?
Nowhere to run now motherfucker.