Good afternoon.
The victim is upstairs,
Commander. Please. This way.
Flashlight.
- Yes, sir.
Watch out, sir.
Blood.
Can I see him?
- Yes, sir.
Yes.
How can he be like this?
- The victim's bones are shattered.
What's wrong, miss?
What's going on?
Baby sacrifice.
Dead baby.
Dead husband.
Calm down.
I'll take you to a safe place.
Come on.
Oh God!
Didn't you.....
- No!
No, you did.
I remember. You did.
No, it was one class.
- No.
I don't have the talent.
- No. You're better.
You did more. Not just one class.
- No.
I've never seen. I should.
- No! We're not doing it.
You're embarrassing me
in front of all the people here.
Excuse me.
- Please.
Thank you.
Is this you?
- You know.
Shall I pour this?
- Please. Thank you.
Thank you.
Enjoy your drink.
- Thank you.
That's enough.
- Enjoy your drink.
Yeah.
- Thank you.
I have a surprise for you.
Wait. I got something for you.
- What?
Oh, my gosh!
I love it. Thank you.
Let me put it on you.
- Okay.
Can you open it?
- Yes. There we go.
Thank you.
Happy anniversary.
Cheers.
- Happy anniversary.
Why aren't you drinking it?
No.
- Wait a minute.
It's the one you like, right?
- Yes, the usual.
Hold on. Maybe there's another.
- No.
No, you're not wrong.
- I'll get you the other one.
Then why aren't you drinking?
- Yeah, it's okay.
You don't feel well?
- No.
Why? What's wrong?
I'm pregnant.
We're going to have a baby.
You're pregnant?
Yes.
- A baby.
I'm going to be a dad.
- Yes.
I'm going to be a dad!
High five!
- Sorry.
Sorry.
I'm so happy
I could die right now.
Okay.
Firstly, I want
to thank everybody...
...who joined
this construction bidding.
As we agreed,...
...the announcement of the winner
of construction project bidding...
...is done openly.
Okay. I'll read the announcement.
The winner of this
construction project bidding...
...is Rafa Green Construction,
led by Mr. Rafa.
Hold on, wait.
Is that right?
Congrats, Mr. Rafa.
Thank you for your trust.
We won't disappoint you.
Thank you again.
Yes.
Mr. Ronald, don't be disappointed.
Thank you. Good morning.
- Thank you.
I was sure that we would win.
- We have to celebrate this.
We win this fair and square,
unlike the one behind me.
What do you mean?
Ronald, we won this fairly.
So we don't have problem with you.
See you on the next project, okay?
So, you were intentionally
looking for trouble with me, right?
Ronald.
Okay. Rafa, I pray you'll still
be alive to finish this project.
Ronald, are you threatening me?
Threatening?
- You just threatened me.
Listen, I was
just praying for you...
...to have a long life and be
healthy to finish this project.
Let it be.
- What?
He can't be like that.
Just because he lost this tender.
It's a habit already.
Sir, congratulations.
- Yes. Good job. Come on.
Sir.
- Hello.
You're late again,
Mr. Rubber Watch.
You're right.
Buy a proper watch.
- Buy for me.
As if you can't buy one yourself.
- I can. Sir.
Excuse me.
- Please.
Okay. Like the usual.
It's still thin, so just trim it.
Okay.
- Raf, to buy a watch,...
...we have to know ourselves,
our personality.
It has to suit our characteristic.
That's what important.
- You have too many excuses.
It's just a watch,
you're not buying a girlfriend.
See, he's talking about girls
just because I'm single. Fine.
One more thing, you're in
charge of the office tomorrow.
I'm moving tomorrow.
- That's right. New house!
That's right. Nice!
Don't forget
the house cleansing ritual.
Later. I'm very busy right now.
This project has just started,
and there are also other projects.
One more thing.
Farah is pregnant, man!
Pregnant?
- Yes.
Wow, you must be happy. Congrats.
- Thanks.
Still, you must do
a cleansing ritual for the house.
To protect you from danger
and bless your house.
Do you want me to help you?
Yeah. If you want to help,
just help me find a maid.
You know someone who owns
a helper institution, right?
Yeah. I'll help you find one.
I'll ask my friend
who owns the institution.
Okay. Thanks, bro.
Okay. Wait.
- It's okay. I can do it myself.
Let me help you.
- I can do it.
My goodness.
- Hold on.
You're so pretty.
- How about the luggages?
I'll get that later.
Let's go in first.
My dear?
Come on.
- Okay.
Okay.
How about this? I asked them to put
the piano here. It's okay, right?
Yes.
- It's okay, right? The sofa?
Not there.
- Maybe here, but it's up to you.
Where do you want it?
- Move it over there.
I'll move it there, okay?
- Yes.
That would be here,
but I want to have one thing,...
...I want my work desk
to be placed here, okay?
So I can do my work
while looking at the scenery.
Thank you. I'm so happy.
Yes.
Done?
- It's working.
Let's start.
My dear?
- Yes.
Our two- year wait
has finally been answered.
Thanks.
I vow to be by your side
for eternity.
I will protect you forever.
From anything?
- From anything.
Really?
- Yeah.
Yesterday, Ronald threatened me
just because he lost the tender.
Just ignore it,
he can't hurt me.
What if he decides
to do something?
I can do Krav Maga.
I can fight him.
What if he uses a pistol?
- I catch the bullet.
Then I'll throw it back to him.
What if he uses black magic?
Witchcraft?
Do you believe in those things?
- It could happen.
Come on.
Think wisely.
If witchcraft exists,...
...why didn't we use it
on our invaders during the war?
We wouldn't have to face the war
for 350 years, right?
Come on, don't think
about such things.
Edi. Hello, Edi.
Edi, how about tomorrow?
I'm at the new house.
Okay? Bye. Thank you.
Babe?
- Yes?
I want to tell you something.
- What is it?
It's about my past.
Your past?
If you want to do that,
you can't expect me to do it too.
You'd be confused
if I were to tell you everything.
What I mean is.....
Come on.
Everyone has a past,...
...but that's not important to me.
I don't want to know your past.
I just want a future with you.
All the important things in my
life are in this room right now.
So, let's forget about the past
and focus on the future. Okay?
All right? Okay.
Listen here.
I don't want to fail again.
What happened yesterday
was because we didn't use...
...the usual method.
Rafa,...
...he has to pay
for what happened yesterday.
What's wrong, babe?
I had a nightmare
that all my teeth fell out.
It felt so vivid and real.
It is said that is an omen...
...that someone close
to you will die.
Just forget it.
It was just a dream.
I'm so sleepy.
Don't wake me up again.
You're still not feeling well?
- Yes.
In the late stages of pregnancy,
sometimes it's hard to sleep.
It's okay. There you go.
- Okay.
My tummy feels so heavy.
Well, there's a baby inside it.
If it's light, then we
have to be suspicious. Right?
Coffee.
- Thank you, darling.
Here.
- Thanks, darling.
You're eating steak in the morning?
- I'm craving for it.
Why is the steak so raw?
I like it rare.
This is delicious.
It's not rare. This is raw.
- It's the baby who wants it.
Dear?
No.
Pregnant women aren't allowed
to eat raw meat like this.
This is not healthy for you,
nor the baby. It's dangerous.
It's fine if you want steak,
but you have to make it well done.
You can't eat it like this.
Here you go.
Make yourself a new one.
Okay, I got to go to the office.
I'll pick something up on the way.
Okay? I'll see you.
All right?
Wake up.
- What's wrong, darling?
There.....
- Why, darling?
There was an old lady over there.
She held my stomach.
You were just dreaming.
Come on, let's go back to sleep.
Dear.
- Yes?
It was so weird,
I saw some kind of hand in there.
You're just tired.
I told you,
you should just rest today.
Don't force yourself
to go for a doctor's visit.
I've told you,
I can't accompany you today.
I have to go to work,
I have a project.
Yes, but it's scheduled for today.
I can go by myself.
Okay, I'll call Edi and tell him
that I can't work this morning...
...and I'll accompany you, okay?
- Why would you do that? Just go.
I can go by myself.
- I know you can, darling,...
...but I don't want you to.
I want to be there for you.
I'm not asking you to do that.
What's the big deal?
Then how will you come back here?
You don't know the way here.
I have GPS.
Okay. Okay, fine.
Tell me the result, okay?
I'm going now.
Okay, thank you.
Raf. Come on. Are we going now?
- Edi. Yes, but wait. I.....
What?
- I want to ask you something.
I don't know why,
but lately my wife's a bit.....
A bit exaggerating.
What do you mean?
I don't know, but.....
This is one example.
Yesterday, she wanted to eat steak
in the morning. That's fine.
She wanted to eat it very rare.
At night, she wakes up screaming
as if she had a nightmare.
I don't know what's going on.
It's a bit strange, but.....
Maybe it's a hormonal issue.
That's common.
Maybe it's been a while
since you two, you know?
What are you talking about?
She's in her late pregnancy stage.
You're so weird.
- I don't know these things.
No wonder you're still single.
You're crazy!
By the way,
did you get a maid yet?
Not yet.
It's so hard to find one.
Most of them just stay for a
while and then they would leave.
Didn't you say
that you wanted to help me?
Yes.
- You know someone, right?
Yeah, but I don't know what kind
of maid you two were looking for.
Do you want a young one,
a pretty one, or a sexy one?
Of course not!
- So you want an old one?
You're a changed man, is that it?
Is it because your wife is pretty?
It's not a case of old or young.
I want someone who is diligent
and competent at her job.
Usually the old ones
are like that.
The young ones don't come back.
- Relax.
Help me find one.
- I'll ask my friend. Let's go.
You go first. I'll catch up.
I have some business with Evelyn.
Okay.
- All right?
Evelyn, is it done? Let me see.
All right?
Bye.
- Okay.
Check it.
Yes. It suits him. Good job.
Mrs. Farah, do you have
any concerns lately?
I have a meat craving, doctor.
Also, my tummy feels heavy.
That's normal, right?
Meat craving?
- Yes. Steak.
Steak?
Okay, as long as
it's not too much.
There are many types of cravings.
If it's big and heavy,
that means the fetus is healthy.
Excuse me, doctor.
- Right.
Hold on.
Mrs. Farah, do you want to know
if it's a boy or a girl?
Yes.
Good afternoon.
- Afternoon, sir.
Good afternoon. It's a boy!
Now you want a male maid,
you said you wanted a female one.
Not that. My wife called.
She was at the doctor.
My baby is a boy.
It's a boy?
- Yes.
Congrats, man. Happy for you.
I'm so jealous of you.
Your wife is pretty and thoughtful
and now you're having a boy.
I think, if you're not around,...
...I'm the most suitable man
to accompany Farah.
Come on!
Why are you here?
Go be with Farah!
I want to but.....
It's a long story, bro.
Anyway, we have a lot of work.
- Forget this.
Let me finish this today.
Go be with Farah. Seriously.
Let me tell you.
It's just the living room.
I was right to bring you this.
- Look, this is just.....
What's this?
- It's for you, bro.
Rolex?
Seriously? For me?
Oh, man! Seriously?
It's crazy! Thank you, man.
Just consider this
as a token of our friendship.
You have helped me
get this project.
You help me on site,
and at the office, everyday.
Hey, come on.
- I can't trust anyone else.
Thank you so much.
- I really appreciate it.
Me too. Thank you so much.
Thank you.
So, how is it?
- Hold on. I'll surely wear it.
Don't be late again.
My dear!
Darling!
No signal!
Hey, darling.
Darling.
Help!
Help me, sir!
Oh, God. What's going on?
- Let's help.
Help.
- What happened?
Your stomach is so tense now.
We'll help you deliver it now.
No. Take me home. Help me.
- Come on. Put her in the car.
How about our motorcycle?
- Just lock it first.
Come on, ma'am. Slowly.
Slowly.
Where's the baby?
Our baby is being cleaned
by Miss Siti.
Sir, ma'am, I've cleaned the baby.
Bring him here.
Excuse me.
- Thank you.
Rangga.
Rangga, sweetie.
Let me play a song
for you to fall asleep.
Dear.
- Hey, darling.
I have something for you.
Darling?
Open it.
There are three of us now.
You have to be tough.
Yeah.
Ouch!
Rangga, what's wrong with you?
Rangga?
Dear!
- What's wrong?
The baby. His eyes.....
What?
- His eyes are like fire.
Hold on. His eyes are like fire?
- Yes, his eyes are like fire.
Okay. Relax.
Take a deep breath.
Relax. Take a deep breath.
Just look at him.
- Wait. Think about it.
It's a baby.
It doesn't make sense.
Yeah, but.....
Maybe it was the reflection
from a car's headlight outside.
Maybe light reflected in his eyes.
- No.
It doesn't make sense.
- Just look at him. Come on.
Let's look at the CCTV.
Okay? Come here.
Come on.
Just now, right? Okay.
Okay, play.
Look. It's you.
You were shocked, right?
Now, let's pause.
Look at the baby.
Look at him.
Nothing, right?
Let's watch it again.
There.
Wait.
What's wrong with it?
- What's wrong with this thing?
It was just installed.
Maybe the connection. Hold on.
Look at it again.
- It's okay now. Look. You ran out.
This is now. This is live.
Look at the baby.
Rangga's fine.
There's no problem.
This is my friend's house.
- Edi.
Hey, Raf.
Why are you so disheveled?
I'll tell you later.
- Anyway, as I promised.
This is Mbok Wati,
from my friend's institution.
This is just the right time.
Mbok Wati, please come in.
There's a room on the left.
- Thank you, sir.
Please, that way.
- Has it started for a while?
It's just started. Come on.
Ladies and gentlemen,
thank you for coming.
Okay. Let's start.
- Yes.
Please.
Sorry, sir. There's a difficulty.
What do you mean?
It's not working.
Hey, Edi. What are you doing?
- Hey, Raf.
I have to take
some time off next week.
We are very busy now.
- Listen to me.
Who knows, right?
This girl might be my soulmate.
Soulmate? Seriously?
- I have this girl.....
Just pray for me.
- When these two are together,...
...be it at home or at the office,
they can't be separated.
He's gossiping.
- Come in. It's started.
Okay.
- Come in. What did you cook?
"Baby Blues" is a mood disorder
to mothers after giving birth.
Sir, this house is occupied.
Yes. Me, my wife,
and my son. What's the matter?
This house is haunted, sir.
You believe in shaman?
Please, come in.
This is a new house, right?
Has it been cleansed?
It has, just several days ago.
It's weird.
It should have been safe by now.
Wait, where did
the cleansing take place?
As usual, in the living room
and in the middle room.
Where did you get disturbed?
When it happened yesterday,...
...I was cleaning the bathroom.
Then, when I was
cleaning the toilet,...
...a hand came out,...
...and then it was gone.
Has the bathroom been cleansed?
It has, using carbolic acid.
Where's the bathroom?
Let me clean it.
It's up there, sir. Follow me.
Ma'am. Sir, this is
the owner of the house.
I'm Farah.
Thank you for helping us.
I need to check this room.
Please, but my son is sleeping.
Is that okay?
It's okay. Excuse me.
- Yes, thank you.
Did he check downstairs?
- Yes. He's checked everywhere.
There is
something unnatural with.....
With what?
You should all
get out of this place.
What do you mean?
- Your fee, sir.
Mbok?
From tomorrow onwards,...
...nobody can
get in my way anymore.
Rafa!
Help!
What's wrong?
- There's a demon.
His face was all black just now.
His nails.
He changed just now.
I saw his nails in the mirror.
- Calm down. This is Rangga.
There's nothing wrong with him.
- No! His nails were long.
You're just tired.
- I saw it myself.
Why don't you believe me?
I saw it. His face was all black.
- Calm down.
Darling, calm down. Listen to me.
- His nails were long.
It's not that I don't believe you.
I believe you.
I believe you're
having baby blues.
No! This isn't baby blues.
I saw it! His face was all black.
- Listen.
I read that baby blues happens...
...to mothers who feels
unfamiliar with her baby.
Calm down. Tonight, we'll let
Mbok Wati take care of Rangga.
You calm yourself down. Okay?
Are you sure you
have to go tonight?
My workmates are working overtime.
The deadline is approaching.
If I don't go there, everything
will be messy. I have to go.
That baby.
- That baby?
That baby is our baby!
His name is Rangga!
What's wrong with you?
What is your problem?
All of this is only in your head!
It's all in your mind!
Mbok Wati left because of you!
Maybe this is the best for you.
Now, you take care
of this place by yourself.
Take care of Rangga
until you can face your fear...
...and you realize that all of this
is only happening in your head!
Rangga?
Rangga.
Wait!
- Let me go!
Darling.
- That's the demon baby.
That's Rangga.
- It's not him. He has to die!
That's Rangga, Farah.
- No!
That's Rangga. Look at me.
That's Rangga.
What's wrong?
You saw it?
Yes.
I saw it.
I saw it, too.
We have to leave this place.
Excuse me. You just moved in?
Yes, sir. My husband
is unloading the luggages now.
Who are you?
- I'm your next door neighbour.
Your baby's crying non- stop.
Is he sick?
That's just what babies do.
Why are you chatting? Let's go in.
- Please continue with your chores.
If you need help.....
- We don't need anything, sir.
Why am I so rude?
Calm down, Rangga.
Stop crying, please.
Rangga.
He's crying again?
- Yes, all day.
May I help to carry him?
Why did he stop crying?
- I don't know.
I didn't do anything.
Maybe I'm experienced.
Here.
Thank you.
Can I tell you something?
- Yes. About what?
This is important. It's about
the safety of your family.
What do you mean?
Hold on. I'm going home first.
I'll be back.
Maybe this story
does not make sense,...
...but your situation...
...reminded me of a case
from several years ago.
What case?
A brutal homicide
and suicide case.
Oh, God!
This is the news report.
Because of my carelessness,...
...I caused an
innocent woman her life.
Then the guilt...
...made me quit the police force.
However, it didn't stop me
from solving this case.
Who was the killer,...
...and how could human force...
...destroy the victim's bones
without any beating mark?
How come a baby...
...turned blue all over...
...from running out of blood?
I asked the elders with
spiritual ability in the village.
They said...
...it was because of
a dark ritual.
Sacrificing a baby
to harm other people.
The victim's neighbours said...
...the baby was always
crying very loudly...
...during the call of prayers.
What was weirder is that...
...the temperament
of the parents looked different.
They became rude, impatient.
Their characteristics
were exactly like...
...what you showed me earlier.
Rafa!
Rafa, come here, quick!
What's wrong?
Rangga won't stop coughing?
It's okay, sweetie.
He won't stop coughing.
Rangga? What's wrong with him?
What's wrong with his mouth?
Why is there hair in his mouth?
- I don't know.
What's wrong?
- No, I'm just.....
Rafa?
It's clearly...
...the doing
of someone vengeful...
...to you.
This means that this
person used dark magic...
...or witchcraft to harm you.
These things...
...are usually used
in those practices.
Your baby is
being used by someone...
...to harm you...
...with dark magic or evil spirit.
So, all of this.....
All of this happened
because of our baby?
Why don't they just hurt me?
Those kind of people are cowards.
They don't have the courage
to face you directly,...
...let alone hurt you.
They want to hurt you slowly...
...and also harm
your loved ones,...
...like your wife and child.
Please, help us.
Whatever the way,
just please help us.
If God permits,
I'll try my best to help.
All this comes back to you two.
You two should make peace,
or have you forgotten your God?
Who would want to harm us?
Who?
Who clearly threatened me?
And who.....
Who lost the bidding...
...because of me?
Rafa, I pray that you'll still
be alive to finish this project.
Are you threatening me?
I have to end this tonight.
Ronald!
Stop. Stop all this!
Scumbag, what are you doing here?
- Stop all of it now!
Stop what? What?
- Stop your black magic!
Don't disturb my family again!
- Black magic?
Black magic?
You have to know.
I want to get my revenge on you.
I want to teach you a lesson,
but I want to do it in court.
Do you remember how you
embarrassed me at the bidding?
Do you remember?
You embarrassed me.
Now you break into my house,
embarrass me in front of my wife.
Honey, who is he?
I'm so sorry.
I'm sorry. I apologize.
Ronald, please forgive me.
I misunderstood.
I'm sorry. Sorry.
Man, I'm really sorry.
I was wrong about you,...
...but my family
is being disturbed...
...and I don't know
what else to do.
I'm so sorry. Forgive me.
Hey!
You know the phrase
"keep your enemies close to you"?
Or "enemy lies
under the blanket"?
Dark magic is usually...
...done by people closest to you.
Dark magic or witchcraft
can be done in many ways.
For example, using your hair...
...to channel his evil doing.
He uses baby's placenta
to be ritualised.
With this ritual...
...I curse...
...the baby of Farah Nirmala.
Have a seat, Di.
- Rafa called me.
He asked me to check
on you and Rangga.
Rafa told you?
He told me everything.
You're okay, right?
I'm okay.
- What about your baby?
He's okay.
May I see your baby?
I just want to make sure
that both of you are really fine.
Okay. Wait a minute.
Uncle Edi is here.
He just woke up.
What?
Rafa told me everything.
I think you should take a rest.
Let me hold him.
Are you sure? Okay. Wait.
Hold on.
Okay, here.
- Okay.
Okay.
He likes you.
Watch his head.
I should be with you.
Imagine me as your husband.
I wouldn't leave
you and our baby...
...in critical times like this.
Di, what happened
between us is over.
I'm happy with Rafa now.
I thought you're also happy
with someone else.
After all the good times
that we had?
That time...
...we almost had a baby, Farah!
Our baby died, Edi.
I thought we have moved on
with our lives.
You're even friends with Rafa now.
I don't understand.
What happened between us
was in the past.
It's in the past?
- Yes.
For you, it is!
What if I tell you
that it's actually the present?
You are destined to be with me!
You and that person, Rafa,...
...should have
only been temporary.
Because of this baby,...
...all of my plans are messed up!
Di.
Pass him to me now.
- Shut up!
Please.
- Don't come close to me!
Do you remember?
I told them that we'd get married!
- Please, Di.
Run!
Rafa!
Rafa.
Give me Rangga!
Give him to me now!
I could've killed you before,
but I didn't want to.
I want to see you suffer like this.
Give me Rangga!
That's my child!
I'm going to break
every bone in your body.
You don't deserve
to be Farah's husband.
There are three of us now.
You have to be tough.
Yes.
That's my child!
Even if the love between
the two of you is strong enough...
...to fail my witchcraft,
I don't care.
I don't care!
I'll kill all of you myself.
Edi, wait.
- What?
You're weak now.
I'll kill you in a second.
Then I'll kill Farah.
After that, I'll kill your baby!
Everything's going to be okay.