Resync by zannetmovies
Watch & Download Full Movies www.zannetmovies.net
Kong.
Yes, mom.
Get home and don't rush out today, ok?
What's going on?
It's your dad's anniversary with me.
Why?
He'll work and forget just like every year.
'Kay, mom... see you soon.
Sometimes we are still confused.
We don't know where to go.
Never know who we really are.
Yeah, this is called aero-dynamic.
My throat hurts now.
- Here...
- What are you doing?
I've read about it.
It generates more speed.
Didn't you see how the racers lean on their bike?
- Show us.
- Do it.
Shit, that's aero-autistic.
Make it look more energetic, yeah.
Hey!
That was awesome.
Here's your phone.
Hold it tight. Here.
Did anyone do anything to him?
It's you!
He's had a concussion,
blood goes to his hair instead.
- All is good.
- Let's continue.
Truck crashed into a Bangkok - Chiang Mai bus.
"16 July 1995"
Tum, I love you forever. - Som
Call me back 9482092
On facebook feeds,
A lot of people share updates about the storm.
Please be cautious and take care.
Let's hear this, a new single from Polycat
Paclink
Pager
You said you won't forget.
What time is it now, you just got back? Huh?
Mam...
All these years...
I had to work.
When will we celebrate anniversary together?
I'm sorry.
We have been married for 20 years.
But you never...
never forget Som, do you?
Hey, I think we made that clear already.
Why do you have to get Som involved?
Tum, I love you forever. - Som
Why?
I can't even talk about her?
Mam, Mam.
Will there be just one time
that you make us all happy?
Kong, this is adult's matter. Not yours.
And this...
is also adult's matter as well, huh?
Kong.
Can you come here now?
What?
I had argument with my dad.
Again?
Yeah, come to see me.
OK.
I'll see you. At your house, ok?
Hey, it's raining.
Shit.
Hey, hello?
Hey, can you hear me?
Hello?
- AUM
- Broken.
Shit.
Call me back 9482092.
Altermajibe
1144 Paclink. Can I help you?
Yes.
May I have the number, please?
Tum, what are you doing?
I've just get to look at your roof.
Good night.
From Som.
Thank you for choosing our service.
Yes.
You pervert!
Wait! Hey!
Even though I don't want to.
Hey, bro.
Is this the market behind Rachasart University?
Yes.
Where is 7-11?
7 what? There's no such thing.
Huh?
Why are you freaking out?
"3 July 1995"
Bro!
Why are you selling old newspaper?
They are not old, this is the latest.
1995?
Yes, pal.
You're funny.
Hey, do you think we are friends?
Aren't you on high?
What's that, Tum?
Pager.
Why did Som have to text you?
Why did she say sweet dreams?
Better than bad dreams, Mam.
Why did she has to see your roof?
Doesn't she have the roof at her house?
It's not just one message,
she texts you every night.
She is like my little sister.
What's wrong with you?
Are we fighting again?
Sister?
Stop seeing her then.
What did she do wrong?
Then what did I do wrong?
Why are you knocking?
It's closed now.
Dad!
Dad my ass.
I'm closing, come again tomorrow.
Mam, where are you going?
- Wake up! Wake up!
- Get away, I'm leaving.
- Mam, we haven't finished talking.
- Mam?
No more talking.
I want to break up.
Mom!
Are you crazy?
Mam!
Mom!
- Mam.
- Mom.
What mom?
What mom, huh?
D... Dad...
Oh, man!
Kong.
Kong, what's wrong?
Kong!
Hey, how is it going?
Dad.
Dad my ass, stop calling for your dad.
Where is he, your dad?
You wake up now, boy?
Ghost!
What ghost is this?
Ghost... Ghost... Ghost...
- I'm not a ghost.
- You're the ghost.
He was calling for his dad in front of the house.
I looked back to talk to Mam,
he already passed out when I turned back.
Yeah?
This is not a dream.
What is your name?
Where is your home?
Name... my name is Kong.
My home?
Yeah.
It's here.
I think he is stoned.
You should call the police.
Good.
Wait, wait. Please wait.
I come from the future.
Enough, don't call the police.
Now call the psycho ward to come get him.
That's good, uncle.
Stop, calm down. Let me explain.
Wanted - Sales assistance
I come to find a job.
So you're looking for a job
or you come from the future?
If I can get a job here, then I have my future.
I have an argument with my dad.
And I ran away from home.
I really have nowhere to go.
I beg you, please.
If I can find another place, I will leave.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
I'm not a cruel person, I can be moral.
Are you crazy?
- Get out.
- Go.
Modern Dog No.1 Hits
Oh?
What's wrong with it?
Bro! You make a call or not?
What takes you so long?
Sorry, I forgot the number.
Why don't you use phone book?
Through the lonely nights
and pointless days.
It's the thoughtless day
and the endless night.
There is a painful story
that everyone has been through.
On the day we make mistakes
You'll fully understand when it happens.
Talk about love.
Talk about sadness.
Talk about loneliness.
Talk about stories in my heart.
Through those happy days.
This just keeps eating the tape.
Oh crap!
What are you doing?
Rewinding the cassette tape.
Or you think I'm cleaning it up?
Do you not go to school today?
No, I'm lazy.
Huh?
And... don't you help uncle at the shop?
No, I'm lazy.
Huh?
You're lazy?
Why? Do I look like a hard working person?
Well...
I don't know.
I think you take everything seriously.
No humour.
- Don't care about people around you.
- Huh?
- Always make people uncomfortable.
- Hey.
Are you talking shit about me?
Want me kick your ass?
Just kidding.
Forget it.
I'll be out.
If you're hungry, just take care of it yourself.
I have a rehearsal.
Huh? Wait, you're in a band?
You live around here, don't you know my band?
Nope.
Buy this, and you'll know.
CONCERT ALTERNATIVE -
PROUD meet Warm Up Band - TTNK
Are you tricking me to buy the ticket?
When I have the album released,
the ticket will be even more expensive.
Give me the money.
It's ok.
Don't worry, you can keep it.
Give me the money when you can. I'm in no rush.
Where do you go for rehearsal?
At the university.
Great, can I come along?
I need to use internet.
Internet?
Yes.
You're lazy, I can see it.
You can actually take care of the shop yourself.
There is no need for another person.
I feel sorry for him.
Is he from an ice age?
He doesn't know any songs or singers.
He also told me that that singer is gay.
He is gay.
Here, brother. There are 4 guys in this band.
One of them is gay.
You don't believe me?
Here, there are 6 in this band.
One of them is gay.
I don't believe you.
Are you crazy?
Gay?
I told you to be a salesman,
not to tell them who is gay.
If the sales drops, don't you wish...
that you'll get time off for holiday with Mam.
That won't happen anyway.
We broke up last night.
Broke up?
Listen to this then. Here, here, here.
Assanee, Nuvo, Micro.
The heartbroken gangsters songs.
The songs are spot on.
I'm sorry, uncle.
I'm "Alter"
Alternative, that is.
Here, bro. The fastest internet in campus.
64 K.
What do you want from the internet?
Just ask me, I know everything.
I'd like to go on google.
- Google?
- Yes.
You're getting a guru confused.
What is it?
It is...
It's a website for searching information.
Searching information?
Yes, google.
There is no google.
But there is a guru that can help you.
I'm the guru you're looking for.
Librarian
What are you looking for?
Sorry.
Som, I'm leaving now. I'm bored.
See you.
You pervert!
You!
Theory of Relativity and Time Traveling
Hey!
Do you know now that I'm ok?
We should do it again.
Ready? 1-2-3-4
Tum!
- Tum! Help me!
- Som.
Tum!
- Som, what happened?
- Help.
Tum, I saw a pervert.
A pervert! Where?
At the library.
He is chasing me.
Don't worry, we'll take care of it.
Let's go.
Come on.
We better go hard for someone like him.
Beat the shit out of him.
I yield.
Wait, wait.
That's Kong.
Wait, that's the boy at my shop.
Wait, for heaven's sake!
Listen up.
He is dying already.
Are you ok, Kong?
Kong, this is Som...
My friend.
Som, this is Kong. He works at the shop.
You're Som?
Experts said that time traveling can happen
He ran after me. He followed me a long time.
You called him a pervert, he just wants to explain.
When same situations happen over and over in the relative timing.
He is a pervert! I'm not.
Then the portal of dimension will be opened.
If so, I won't let him stay with me.
- He really is a pervert.
- Who?
There he is.
I told you many times that I'm not.
Do you still not believe?
How could you not be? You were under my skirt?
What are you looking at?
What do you want from me?
Hey, listen.
I passed out in the phone booth.
When I woke up, I was already under your skirt.
Do you think I wanted to see your panties?
What colour?
I didn't see.
You didn't wear panties?
Tum!
Come on, you two.
I don't know.
Why did you run after me then?
I was going to ask, I have lost the...
What do you call that thing...
the thing with the message?
- Is it pager?
- Yeah, pager.
I lost pager in the phone booth.
I was going to ask if you saw it.
You lost your stuff, what does it has to do with me?
Pervert.
Pervert?
You pervert!
- Som, calm down.
- Calm down.
You still have bruises.
Calm down.
Stop it, you both.
Trust me, Som. Kong is not a pervert.
I guarantee, even though he looks...
a bit off. But he is not a pervert.
Tum.
Trust me.
Ok, if you say so.
Good.
I said the same, you don't listen.
Hey now.
If there is nothing else, we'll continue rehearsing.
Go home safely.
I came here to tell you,
I'll go to see you at the shop on the weekend.
What?
Do you forget the appointment again?
About guitar lesson.
Yeah, I forgot.
Is that it?
You can text him via Line.
What?
I'm leaving!
It's getting dark outside, so scary.
Yeah.
It's scary for girls to go home alone late at night.
The bus is here, this is ok.
Aren't you scared?
Wait, wait
How about pager?
Hey!
Come, let me teach you.
Here... Proud.
Take a look.
Barbie.
Y Not Seven.
Modern Dog.
The Must.
You remember now?
Let me ask you.
Who is this?
Pr... Proud?
- Is it right?
- Proud.
Correct, which band?
No answer.
Which band?
- Y... -
- Too slow.
Bro.
Give me some time.
Which band?
Modern Dog.
Modern Dog, correct.
What is this?
Bro, I beg you. Gentle, please.
Memorize these.
We sell cassettes downstairs, alright?
Then you'll know who are out there.
1144 Paclink. Can I help you?
May I have the number?
993-399
Mam.
Are you still mad at me?
Can we meet?
That'd be all.
Not this one, this part I'm talking to you.
From...
Tum.
Thank you for choosing our service.
Are you done?
Hello, this is 1144 Paclink.
May I have the number, please?
Mam, I have to go for audition
with the record company.
Will you come to support me?
No, let me change the message.
I love you, Mam.
I love you so much.
Can I change it again, please?
I still want to be with you.
I miss you so much.
I don't want this part.
Excuse me.
You might want to revise it,
that won't waste your time.
No it doesn't. I have a lot of free time.
Yes, so which part do you want?
Forget it.
Thank you for choosing our service.
Moron!
So, I can use the phone now?
Uncle, one more time.
Ok, I give you two.
Uncle!
Give me!
Can I call first?
I want to call a gas company, it runs out.
I have been waiting for hours.
Get away, let me make a call.
If the sky is out there, you can still see me.
If the sky knows, will you recognise?
You're my ultimate dream.
When the sky is clear, I'm still waiting.
Damn, that's brilliant!
Is it that complicated each time
you send a message?
Yeah.
How is it? Is that good?
Look at the rhyme.
What rhyme?
So tacky.
Why so?
Is this from grandpa's generation?
Are you sure?
Why, is it not touching?
You want it touching? Let me.
May I have the number, please?
993399, please.
My dollface.
My dullface.
No, "doll"  face.
Doll?
Doll... doll...
Doll, can you spell it?
D - o - l - l.
D - o - l - l... yes.
I miss you heaps.
Sheeps, right?
Heaps, please. Heaps.
Heaps, can you spell it, please?
H - e - a - p - s.
Do you miss me?
I miss you loads.
I miss you...
Loads, that is.
Toads?
It's L.
l - o - a - d - s.
What are you reading?
Loads, yes?
Very good.
From Tum.
Yes, "From Tum". Thank you.
Still waiting for Mam's message?
The tide on Chaopraya River is high.
Your love life is going rocket high.
Damn, this is bullshit.
I'll cancel all the service.
Who are you calling?
I'm calling Mam.
Let me get it.
Hello, Kittimanan House, how can I help you?
Shit.
What's wrong?
It's her dad. He is intense.
Grandpa is so kind.
Let me talk.
Huh? Whose grandpa?
Will you dial?
Hello. Kittimanan House, how can I help you?
I told you. He is so intense.
I have an idea.
Kittimanan House, how can I help you?
Err... hello.
This is May. Can I speak to Mam?
Oh May, one moment.
Mam, it's May.
Yes.
Hello, May?
Hello Mam, this is Tum.
Mam, what are you doing?
What's wrong?
It's disconnected.
She hung up on me.
Tum.
Let me ask you something.
Is Som your ex-girlfriend?
Som and I are never together.
Friend with benefit?
What friend with benefit?
More than friend but...
not a girlfriend.
We call it "lover"
But Som is not my lover.
Som and I know each other since we were kids.
We are very close, like brother and sister.
I don't understand why Mam is so jealous.
Maybe Mam is jealous...
because she knows of something
that Som...
is not thinking of you as a brother.
There is no way Som will think of me differently.
Believe me, Som will...
cause you problems in the future.
You're overthinking.
I'll go to bed now.
Colonel Buncha Kittimanan
Bro, bro.
Hello
Is Mam here?
Yes, wait here.
Yes.
Hello Mam.
I'm Kong, Tum's friend.
Yeah, I know.
How do you know my house?
Tum told you?
No, Tum didn't tell me anything.
It's just that I know.
Why are you here? What do you want?
I'm here to talk about Tum.
Well...
Wiat up.
Let me explain.
- You can go now.
- Mam!
I haven't finished.
Does it hurt much? Err...
You have bruises.
I'm sorry, I didn't mean it. Is it hurt?
What are you smiling at?
Nothing.
It just...
You reminds me of my mom.
You're saying I'm old?
No, I'm saying you have same personality.
Yeah, whatever.
Mam, the thing is...
Tum still loves you very much.
Please get back to him.
The day we broke up...
I told him to stop seeing Som.
He said he couldn't.
So if he couldn't,
I should break up with him.
The one who breaks up should be neither of you.
It should be Som.
But it's ok.
I'll make her out of Tum's life.
But Tum's band will go for audition.
You know, it's his dream.
Will you please go to support him?
Please?
Kong, help me here.
Help uncle at the shop ok?
Don't argue with the clients, ok?
Kong!
Are you listening?
Tum.
It's a good day today.
I know you need supports.
And the most important support for you...
is from no one but...
Tum!
Did you bring Som here?
No, I...
Tum.
Please do your best.
Don't forget me when you become famous.
See you later.
Do you best.
Sure, bye.
Tum, are you ready?
Let's go.
Do you best.
You're the best.
What are you looking at?
If you only want to say this, you can just call.
You're...
Raeya.
Raeya what?
What's wrong with him?
Raeya?
These 2, please.
Yes.
- Thank you.
To Tum... Som
Oh shit.
Tum, from now on...
I don't have to fight for the phone anymore.
Uncle, I don't understand.
Why is Som so into Tum?
She knows he has Mam.
Yet she is after him until they broke up.
Som is unfortunate.
She doesn't have much friends.
She was always with her brother every where.
Tum is her brother's best friend.
One day
Som's brother died.
She doesn't have anyone to rely on.
Tum offered to take care of her since.
Kong, seriously...
If you were in his shoes, would you leave her?
Yes.
I love Mam.
I'm her team.
Hey, seriously?
Is Mam your mom?
Why do you love her so much?
I tried to convince you so hard,
doesn't help at all.
I don't want to talk to you anymore.
- Hey?
Hi Uncle.
Hi.
You're all up here, who takes care of the shop?
It's closed.
Closed?
My sales will go rocket down now.
Tum.
How was it, did it go well?
Yeah.
What does it mean?
Just yeah.
I know now.
Will you help uncle the whole day tomorrow?
Why? Where are you going?
I have to teach guitar to Som.
Tum.
Uncle told me all about Som.
Do you know, the more you're good to her,
things will get worse.
And what did she do wrong?
There is nothing wrong
as long as she only think of you as a brother.
If you care for her,
you should let her go.
What do you want me to do?
Som.
Tum.
I have to prepare myself for audition.
I don't have enough time to teach you.
Oh?
But don't worry, I have a replacement.
Who?
Tum! You know how serious I am with this.
I will go to the school contest.
And you let this pervert to teach me.
Does he even play guitar?
How's that?
He is a lefty.
Just like Kurt Cobain.
Better than you for sure.
Alright, it's going well. I'm leaving.
Tum!
Hey...
I won't charge you this time.
I promise I'll help you write
a song as you wanted.
But there is one simple rule.
Until you finish writing the song...
don't contact Tum... at all.
Why do I have to do what you want?
Tum told you, didn't he?
That he needs to focus.
If you really care about him,
I think you should understand.
Fine.
Hey, about that day...
that you called me Raeya, what is it?
Raeya is a woman.
Very pretty.
Really?
But bitchy.
Kong, sit here.
What's up?
How was the teaching?
It went well.
And...
are you sure that she could step away from me?
Don't worry about this.
I think you better worry
about getting back to Mam.
What a woman! It's been a while...
and she is still mad at you.
Don't worry about that.
I have a great plan.
Is it for real?
- That cool.
- Brilliant.
Is it for me?
Flirting Card?
Are you trying to chat my friend up?
No Meddling Card
What card is that?
Chill out, don't hurt him.
That's cute.
Flirting Card
I don't talk much and I'm interested in you.
I'd like to know you more and become friend.
If you don't mind, just nod...
or smile a little.
Let me flirt with you.
Still remember - Tum
I still remember the day
you told me how you feel.
Said you will only have me.
The first time we have each other,
it's beyond any memory.
It's so hard to forget.
It's more than words
to explain to you.
Hello. Kittimanam House.
How can I help you?
It's May. May I speak to Mam?
May.
Are you sick? Your voice sounds husky.
Alright, wait.
Mam.
What's up, May?
Hello Mam, it's Tum.
Mam, please listen to me. Don't hung up.
I'm sorry about what happened.
Whether you believe me or not...
I just want to tell you...
that I really don't have a feeling for Som.
She is just a sister.
The one I love
is only you.
And tomorrow
I'll perform the opening act for Proud.
I'd like you to come.
Is that all?
And...
did you listen the tape I gave?
What tape? Why do I have to listen?
Is that all you want to say? Bye.
Is she good? How was it?
Stop.
Shut up. Close the shop.
Yes.
Malay, Malay, Malay
Malay what is it?
Well, it's...
Malay Malay.
Malay Malay...
Still confused?
Let me tell you...
Around my neighbourhood, this is the most popular.
Where is your home?
Let me ask you this, haven't you felt...
having someone falling for you or being in love...
or in a serious relationship?
Plenty.
But nothing serious.
There. That's why you suck at writing songs.
You have to feel like...
feeling good about someone and...
secretly falling in love.
If so...
I think I have some.
There, that feeling.
Write it, write it now.
I forgot to feed my baby.
What?
You have a baby?
In the cold night, it's still raining.
My tears are falling like the rain.
I want to love. I want good memory.
I need someone to think of me.
- Hey!
- Wait, wait.
Hey.
Why do you come so late?
I can't call you.
Don't you want to have a pager at all?
I don't have money.
Working with uncle, he pays so little.
I'm lucky enough to be able to pay for meals.
I figured.
Here is my old one.
I've just got a new one.
You can borrow it for now.
Get it registered yourself.
This is my pager.
Ungrateful.
I gave it a second ago, now you say it's yours.
Give it back to me now, you don't need it.
Of course I do, thank you.
Don't you find those messages.
I deleted them all.
Deleted them all?
Yep.
How can I get home then?
Why do you hurry back? You've just got here.
Where is my song?
Is it Alternative?
Not Altermajibe, huh?
Seriously?
Why does it have to be alternative?
Don't you know it?
I'll take you to a geek tonight.
I actually don't want you to go.
This is so cruel.
I have myself prepared,
but it doesn't get better.
I want to get down on my knees
to beg you. I just have to do.
Hurry up.
Hurry.
Please don't go, I beg you.
Do you know now that I'm ok?
We are TTNK.
Now welcome Proud.
This is awesome.
Som.
You did great.
Let's take a photo.
Come on.
Hurry up.
- Hurry.
- Come on.
One, two, three!
Hurry up. Hurry.
Sorry.
Kong, have you seen Mam?
Not at all.
Not at all?
What are you doing? Hurry.
Because I only have you all along.
Never want to find someone to take your place.
Always have you by my side.
The world is beautiful when we are together.
Because we are strong
never fool ourselves in our relationship.
We will always be honest.
Never get distracted because we are strong.
We will always look for happiness.
If any of us walks to the wrong path.
There are the sayings
that love always hurts.
Try to remember.
You're the dream in my mind.
Just a dream.
This is alternative, the new choice of music.
But I think, in not so many years...
It will be gone.
If it's gone, what will you say?
Nothing really.
At least, this is my good memory.
Won't you regret?
No, I rather spend my time to regret
to remember the good memory here.
If only you understand,
I am confident that one day.
I will try to find the answer.
My dream will come true.
I will have the love for you,
Like others can't.
Only if I have you.
Hey Kong.
What are you doing so loud?
My phone will be broken.
I'm sorry.
I want to send a text.
But I don't know what to say.
It's in your heart.
Send whatever you are thinking.
I shouldn't have to teach you this.
Don't you know,
it's 3 baht every time you hang up.
3 times, 9 baht.
This month's bill must be 603 Baht.
1144 Paclink. Can I help you?
Hello.
May I have the number, please?
4... 5... 4
13... 135.
May I have the message?
Som...
Som.
Today, you were great.
Thank you.
That'd be all.
That'd be all. From?
From Kong.
Thank you for choosing our service.
That was frigging sick. Nite-nite. Som
Frigging sick
Sick What's that?
Nothing.
Then why are you smiling?
Smiling what?
I'm not.
Why are you smiling?
Adult's matter, bugger off.
I better go to bed.
Won't you go to sleep?
You can go upstairs.
It's ok, I can sleep here.
Suit yourself.
Typhoon warning, The capital will be hit
How could you understand
that we get along,
understand and trust each other.
How is it going with song writing?
From the beautiful Som.
Let me read it.
Read what?
Come on.
That's Som, right?
Today Showing - Romantic Blue
What are you watching?
Nothing.
Whose picture?
The feeling I have for you,
I don't know how good it is.
But the answer you gave me
is that we can't be together.
I has been hurting me all along.
From the beautiful Som.
Hey!
Let me kill someone first.
Fire in the kitchen.
Oh fire, I have to go.
You are a dead man, Fire, huh?
It's crowded in there.
Whose birthday is it, uncle?
Yes, birthday.
But it hasn't been born yet, 7 more months.
You are pregnant?
How many months? Is it due date soon?
Pregnant my ass.
I'm not pregnant.
Who then?
Mam is pregnant?
Why are you shouting? Damn it.
It's getting intense here.
You come sit here. Over here.
Stay still and do nothing.
Let the adults discuss the issue.
Date of Birth: 16 Feb 1996
Shit!
Dad.
Who is your dad?
Colonel then.
I won't let my girl's future ruin because of him.
But colonel...
For the moment...
Mam is already pregnant.
Then get the abortion!
Wait, wait, wait.
I don't think it's a good idea.
The baby must fee sorry if it gets to know.
Shut up, stay right there.
Sorry about what?
It's only 2 months, it doesn't even have ears.
It's human, not an eel.
Dad, please. I beg you.
I know what Mam and I did is wrong.
But I really love Mam.
I am ready to fix the problem.
I will be graduated soon.
And I will find a job.
I will take care of Mam and the baby.
I don't believe that
someone like you can take care of them.
But I believe in Tum.
Huh?
And by the way,
this is my baby, not yours.
Thank you, Mam.
Take care of yourself.
I hope you become famous.
Good luck.
Do you really quit the band?
I already quit.
You said this is your dream.
When I know I have a baby,
I think my dream has been changed.
In that dream, there is not only myself.
But there are 3 of us.
I don't want Mam and my baby to struggle.
I will take care of them.
Why are you crying?
Your baby is very lucky.
You are quite sensitive, huh?
Don't forget to meet me at the cinema. Som.
Som, huh?
What's with you guys?
Nothing between us.
Maybe about the song.
About the song?
Love song, maybe?
You just tell her you love her, alright?
So you want to see me?
I just want to tell you...
thank you for teaching me guitar
and writing the song.
Umm.
Is that all?
Yep.
You can just send me the message.
Let me ask you something,
Why don't you use telephone or send messages?
You make an appointment just to say one sentence?
Are you not tired?
No, I think the message can't explain everything.
I prefer to talk face to face.
What's the difference?
Well, the texts can fool us.
But the eyes...
cannot lie.
Let me see how you feel.
Boo!
Nutter!
Since you are out today,
Let's take photo sticker, as a souvenir.
Go.
Yeah, photo sticker. Come on.
Photo sticker machine still exists?
This is brand new!
You country boy, never know it huh?
Excuse me.
- You have 12 acts.
- Yes.
One, two, three!
Hey!
Look at this shot.
Whoa.
You are too slow.
Here.
These are mines, those are yours.
What should I do with them?
Put them in sticker book.
You don't have?
Well then...
put them on your pager. Hold this.
You've never done this, huh?
Here.
Give them back to me.
Kong.
What's up?
Can I ask you one thing?
I'll be attending musical contest tomorrow.
Will you bring Tum there to support?
Why do you need Tum there?
I keep my promise.
I finish writing the song, I can see him now.
Tum will keep his promise.
Huh? Promise?
Well, Tum promised me...
if I can be good like you and I win,
can I ask you something?
What will you ask for?
You will have to be my boyfriend.
Is it ok?
How about...
go to the contests and win something.
I'll think about it.
He will be my boyfriend.
I will get to be his girlfriend, Kong.
Som.
Well...
I have something to tell you.
Wait.
One moment.
My friends need me at the rehearsal.
I'll see you later.
Wait, wait.
I'd like to talk to you first.
Sure, hold this then.
Here.
Give me your hand.
This is my number, call me.
Take that back. See ya.
Call me back 9482092
9482092
Don't forget to bring Tum along tomorrow. Som.
Alright.
We have come to the last band tonight.
Please welcome "Purr".
Hello. We are "Purr".
Before we get started,
I'd like to thank a friend of mine...
who helped me write this song.
And I'd like to thank my brother,
I don't know if he is here tonight.
But I believe that he will come.
I'd like to tell him that...
You are the one that changes me.
I'm here because of you.
Looking for an answer of what love is
from every words and letters.
Look into the songs
and listen in every melody and lyrics
but still don't understand.
Tens of thousands of messages, theories,
or meanings can never be touching.
Through the time until I met you,
until I have found the way
to explain better than words.
You make me realise,
love can be told through the eyes.
There is no need for more explanation.
Only a glimpse from you, I can feel the answer
what love really is.
Through the time until I met you,
until I have found the way
to explain better than words.
You make me realise,
love can be told through the eyes.
There is no need for more explanation.
Only a glimpse from you, I can feel the answer
what love really is.
When you know that love
can be told through the eyes.
There is no need for more explanation.
When you look into my eyes,
you'll know I have something...
that my eyes are telling you.
Yes! We won!
You girls are so good.
Kong!
Wait, wait. Don't you stay to celebrate with us?
I can't stay. Let go.
Kong, I made it.
I did it. I just did it.
And Tum? Where is he?
I didn't see him.
He got caught up with something...
He couldn't make it.
It's ok, I'll tell him myself.
Tum.
Som.
You didn't go.
But it's ok.
I brought you the award.
And...
Where is my award?
Award?
Som.
Don't you remember?
You promised me that
If I can be good like you one day,
you will start dating me.
I made it, Tum.
I made it because...
I love you.
I have loved you a long time.
I'm so happy.
Som.
Well...
Listen to me.
Here is the thing...
I'm about to get married with Mam.
I'm sorry, Som.
I can't love you more than a sister.
I know how you are feeling.
I can kind of see it.
But I want to tell you that I don't love you
and I will never change my mind.
That might make you disappointed and sad.
But it's better than letting you wait.
I don't want you to get the hope up
because I have been there.
I don't want you to go into deep.
It could be too late,
and you won't be able to forget.
Cry... cry only today.
Forget... and let everything be gone.
Keep your feeling for someone who loves you
Don't dedicate yourself for nothing.
You only need to cry now
and time will help you forget.
When I was with Tum,
I always have faith
that one day I can be with him.
When Tum started dating Mam,
I was always certain
that they'll break up one day.
And the one that gets to stand next to him...
is me.
I never gave up.
But I have to give up. Now I lost.
Do you remember that day,
you brought me to the concert?
And you told me,
even though there is no more alternative,
it's not important.
Because...
there is still good memory for us.
Of course you can say it.
You have never been in love.
Look into my eyes.
And you'll know how I feel.
I don't want you to get the hope up
because I have been there.
I don't want you to go into deep.
It could be too late,
and you won't be able to forget.
1144 Paclink.
May I have the number, please?
539... 926
Call me back 9482092
Som.
- What's wrong?
- Bro.
- Is he dead?
- He is so still.
Call someone, the rescue unit or whatever.
Try tapping him?
Kong!
- Kong, are you ok?
- Are you alright, son?
Kong!
Are you alright, son?
Kong.
Kong, are you ok?
Dad.
Kong.
You worked late again last night?
You are sick, why don't you go to bed?
Dad...
Thank you.
Thank you for what?
For everything you have done for me.
And for mom.
And I want to apologise
that I get you wrong...
about Som.
Kong.
You don't have to worry about her.
She won't mess with our family.
Because...
She is dead.
What?
She died on my wedding day.
She was going to live with her mom in Chiang Mai.
She mightn't take it that we are getting married.
Who would have thought...
that it was the last day I saw her.
If I asked her to stay
she wouldn't have been dead.
Truck crashed into a Bangkok - Chiang Mai bus
Kong?
Som!
Kong!
I'll show you push ups.
Punch here. Punch.
Bro.
Where is the phone booth?
The authority took it away.
Which way did they go?
They go to many places.
Where?
They go to Thaewet, Bang Po, Bukkalo,
Bang Ping, Merry King, Saphan Kwai,
Kiak Kai, Odien,
Bang Khun Thien, Wong Wien Yai,
Saphan Mai...
Don Muang... he's gone.
Thief!
- Go after him.
- Go, go.
Alright, guys! Whoosh up!
Hey!
You dipshit.
Dumbass.
Moron, douchebag.
- Curse him.
- You caught me off guard.
You little piece of shit.
I thought they came to seize my motorbike.
I didn't steal it.
I just borrow it.
Borrow? Or did he just borrow?
Let's go then. He'll bring it back.
He'll take it back...
You think it's that easy?
You obviously stole it.
We have to chase after you.
This is our enemy's area, we'll get in troubles.
I beg you.
If you want a fight, can we do it later?
I don't know later, I only know hater.
Why, why later?
Is there a reason? Speak now.
If it makes sense, I'll let you go.
Otherwise I'll beat you into rice porridge.
Add 2 eggs in it for me.
No ginger.
Damn it!
You guys only think of food, shut up.
I know you won't believe me.
But I really need that phone booth
to travel back in time.
It's like a portal of dimension...
to bring me back in the past.
He is mental.
I have to go back to save this girl's life.
If I can't find her, she'll die.
Oh crap.
Who would believe this lame reason.
I do!
Are you serious? Because I am.
To travel back in the past,
and forward to the future
is true, believe me.
Didn't you see it in the movie?
Back To The Future
- Yeah.
- Oh.
It's at Rangsit.
Yes, it goes back in time to Future Park.
Not that, you piece of shit.
Trust him, it's true.
So we should get going.
Let's go.
- Do we have to help him?
- Yeah.
Whoa!
Oh crap.
Damn it.
Shit.
Will we find it?
Just standing here, we won't find it, split up.
Go.
What's the colour?
Damn it.
Is it the coin or card system?
Do, did you look at that one?
Did you look thoroughly?
Sure, in every corners.
I only see you talk.
Found it!
You found it?
Found it.
Go then. Go go.
I knew it must be this one.
Tum!
- Yeah, yeah, I'm coming.
- Tum!
Coming.
Here I come.
Where have you been these days?
- Where is Som?
- Wait, wait.
Listen to me.
Som came here, she brought me this.
Where is she now?
- She told me...
- Where?
She was going to live with her mom in Chiang Mai.
What's wrong with you?
Will I get to talk to you properly? Damn it.
Kong?
Will you calm down?
Easy, easy.
Where are you going?
Kong!
What's wrong with him?
Tum.
Thank you so much...
for being such a good brother to me.
I'm sorry that I have been messing with you.
For my brother. - Som
I did everything I could.
I really walk away from you now.
I wrote this song for you.
I hope you like it.
...Som."
Looking for an answer of what love is
from every words and letters.
Look into the songs
and listen in every melody and lyrics
but still don't understand.
Tens of thousands of messages, theories,
or meanings can never be touching.
Through the time until I met you,
How are you? Come to pick me up tomorrow.
There is someone waiting to use the phone.
I miss you.
How about you?
Ok, that should be all. Hey...
Tell mum to make curry.
Ok... yes, yes.
What love really is.
You make me realise,
love can be told through the eyes.
There is no need for more explanation.
When you look into my eyes,
- Mister.
- Yes.
Which one is going to Chiang Mai?
Chiang Mai?
Too late now.
There, the last one has just left.
Hey!
Stop!
Aero-dynamic...
It generates more speed.
The racers like to lean down.
Aero-dynamic!
Huh?
You think you are so good, huh?
Stop, please!
Open it! Open!
Damn it!
We could be all dead!
What is it?
One moment.
Damn... sorry. I'm sorry.
Som, don't get into the bus, wait for me. Kong
Excuse me... sorry.
Did I get back already?
Get back my ass.
You haven't been anywhere.
You walked into the phone booth.
There is a thunder bolt and you were bounced here.
How's that? Back to the future?
I told you, he is on high.
Flirting Card
Mam.
What do we have for dinner?
Who wanted to have omelet since yesterday?
Me.
You look beautiful today.
You compliment me everyday.
I only have you, and only love you.
So I should compliment you everyday.
Aren't you shy in front of the kid?
No, and I'll do it everyday.
I want to go to the beach, let's go next week.
Ok, let's bring Kong along.
Or just the two of us?
Two of us is fine too.
We might come back with one more.
Kong?
Where have you been?
Come here, now.
- Come, honey.
- Let's eat.
Let's eat what?
He came home in the morning,
shouldn't we ask where he has been?
Aren't you the bad example for him now?
I'm like this every day.
- But I finish work late...
- Wait.
Wait, it's not that.
Isn't that I was sleeping,
then you went out and came back?
And I didn't know, huh?
- No, I didn't.
- Don't you?
I don't know where Kong gets this from.
- Watch yourself.
- Let's eat.
Let's eat.
Here, it's from grandpa.
You must be excited.
You got a new phone, aren't you excited?
It's kind of new.
I'm just happier that 3 of us get to sit
and have a meal together.
I am very happy.
Tum.
Mam.
What did you do to him? Why...?
- Are you ill?
- Why...?
It's not hot,
but I'm not sure if there's
something wrong inside.
How about we eat first, I'm hungry.
I've been waiting.
Ok, dad first.
Thank you.
Looks like I went back to fix the problem
for Tum and Mam.
But for Som and myself
even though it's not possible.
But at least it's my best memory.
But...
I'm still curious about one thing.
Please check the number and try again.
Hello?
Hello? How can I help you?
Hello... may I speak to Som, please?
This is Som speaking.
Hello?
Is that a pervert?
Translated by Thanatcha Saksiamkul
I'd like to thank the world for creating you.
And it gives me the joyful moment.
Even though you are so far away.
I will still send you my love... to you.
A Film by Yanyong Kuruangkura