- This is a
Manhattan bound local train.
- Albert...
Albert...
- Hey!
Hey buddy, how you doing?
Hello!
- Can we have two hot dogs please?
- Thank you.
Uh...
Buddy, I'm guessing that hot
dog is not for me, right?
- No, that one's not for you.
- Okay, alright, who's it for then?
- Pays for tomorrow's customers.
- And how do we know that
the hot dog you're giving me
wasn't on the ground?
- Here's your hot dog, okay,
it's nice and clean and fresh.
- Buddy, that is disgusting, okay?
I'm totally gonna call the
health department on you.
- Look, do you want your hot dog or not?
- Why would I want that shit?
What the hell's the matter with you, dude'?
- Excuse me, good people?
I think the rule of thumb
is if you want a hot dog,
you gotta buy it, right?
Okay?
No sense in sweating these
little things, right?
They'll drive you crazy.
- Listen, buddy.
Did you see this pig?
He dropped it on the ground,
and then he placed it
back up on the grill.
What do you think about that?
- I think you should just
pay the man, walk away,
find yourself a little fancy restaurant...
- I think you should just
mind your own business,
find your own hot dogs...
- Actually, I'd like a hot dog.
- I bet you would.
I bet you would like a hot dog.
- Let's go babe, okay?
- I'll take that hot dog right over there.
- Listen you fat fuck-
yeah, that's right, I went there.
I'm sorry, that's where I went.
- You didn't go far enough,
cause if you did, you'd be home.
- Yeah, that's great, thanks,
yeah, I'm gonna go home now.
- Take yourselves right
back up to that graveyard
you call the Upper East Side.
- Just ignore him.
- This looks terrific.
- Yeah, I bet
you like that hot dog.
- I sure do,
this is what a real hot
dog looks like, darling.
- Are you fucking serious?
Really?
- Stop doing this, please stop-
- are you serious?
- I am absolutely serious.
- That's how you talk to a lady?
- Actually, I thought that
was a culinary opinion.
- I bet you know about
culinary opinions, bud.
- Yeah, I know more than a couple.
- You have a good night.
- Good night.
- Snob shit.
This town is filled with em.
It's a darn good hot dog.
What do I owe you?
- Two dollars.
Keep the change.
- Thank you.
- What's your name, anyway?
- Albert.
You know, the heat from the grille
actually helps keep the hot
dogs clean and germ free.
- Really?
You're a smart one.
I'll see you around, kid.
- Responding officers
felt they had no choice
but to shoot the suspect multiple times
to end his vicious attack.
The 68 year old victim
was fighting for his life
in the front of a hospital.
- You're a lazy man.
- I know.
- Why you make mess?
- What?
- Why you make mess, dirty man?
- Look...
Why are you late?
- Savoy does not work.
- Oh, I hate it when that happens.
- I'll take over, see you later.
Okay.
What are you doing?
- Taking your picture.
- Why?
- It's my job.
I'm a photographer.
- You should ask for permission first.
- Really?
Well, okay.
Tell you what.
Here's your permission.
Okay.
- So you like money, huh?
You want to make some more'?
- I don't know.
- I'm not suggesting anything untoward.
I was thinking about a job.
- What kind of job?
- Art.
Real art.
- I don't know anything about art.
- I could teach you.
- I already have a job, I don't have time.
- Oh yeah?
I'll give you my business card.
And here's a little out of incentive.
Make time.
- Hey!
Albert!
- How's it going?
- Long time no see.
- I've been trying to find
a job lately, actually.
But I haven't eaten in a while,
can I have a hot dog'?
- Yeah, sure, but I gotta
go to the bathroom first,
could you just watch the
hot dog stand for me'?
- Sure, Albert.
- Thank you.
- The
onion crunch, I like it.
- Yeah, you should actually
try the onion crunch dog,
because it's really good.
Especially, like, with
the onion, super crunchy.
Is that your camera?
- Yeah, yeah.
Night street photography is my thing.
- Oh, wow, cause I have some contacts
that actually help you get
your stuff in galleries.
- I'm not quite at that level yet.
I think I need some more
practice, what do you think?
- Let me see.
- I like this one.
- You took all of these?
- Yeah.
- Can I help you with something?
- Yeah, can I get a hot
dog and a soda please?
You know, for some reason, i
thought you were the vendor.
- Oh, no, I was just watching
it for my friend Albert.
- Good friend.
I figured you were too
hot for this anyway.
- Um...
Albert, can I have a hot dog too?
- That'll be five dollars.
- Can you charge me for hers too?
- Oh, actually, I get them
for free from Albert, so...
But you could buy me a beer instead,
and we could look at
some more of your photos.
- Sounds like a plan.
- Albert, is my hot dog ready?
Thank you!
- Well, look what the cat dragged in.
Our model has finally arrived.
Welcome to my studio, Albert.
- Honey!
Hi honey!
Hello?
Hi, I'm Nancy, I'm with wardrobe.
Okay?
I have some paperwork
i need you to fill out,
so come with me,
we're gonna put it over here,
and then we'll get you changed,
so fill this out for me, okay?
Here, let's put this
down, we'll put it here.
I'm just gonna have you sign right there.
- What is this?
- It's just legal, standard
legal, don't worry about it.
- I would like to read it first.
- Read it later, Albert.
It's a basic model's release form.
Just protecting you and me,
legally and otherwise.
- We're just gonna take your shirt off.
- Why?
- Just...
- Albert, it's part
of the job, just do it.
- Come on.
We have a robe, it's alright.
Do you need help?
You know, you do have a nice body.
- Ivan, she's ready.
- Thank you, Jackie.
Nancy?
- Just about!
- Ls Albert ready?
- You're good?
- We're in a very
animated mood, aren't we?
Albert, lose the robe.
Oh, I love it.
Terrific, go stand next to her.
- Hi.
- Okay, now, Albert,
I want you to get
acquainted with Sarah, okay,
because we're gonna make
a little scene here.
- He's so shy.
- Oh, he is shy, but he's
not gonna be shy in a minute.
- I think I'm his first girlfriend.
- Oh, yeah, that's it.
She's your girlfriend,
she's your girlfriend.
Do you remember your first girlfriend?
Remember, you want to get to second base?
Now get closer to her.
- Have you been to second base before?
- Think of the Madonna, you know?
And you're like the baby Jesus.
Take him there, Sarah.
She's kind of like mama.
Don't you want to go home to mama?
Think about going home to mama
after a hard day at school.
The first thing you do is
you hug mama, don't you?
- He's getting excited now.
- Uh oh, he's a
growing boy, isn't he?
He's already...
- You're a big boy.
- My goodness, why don't
you give mommy a big hug'?
Yeah, show mommy some love.
Oh, but you know what you want.
That safety of returning.
Give mama a hug, that's right.
Don't you want to unhook her
bra and feel her titties'?
Don't you want to know what
they feel like in your hand?
- Doesn't that turn you on?
- Oh my goodness, Sarah,
why don't you feed him a strawberry.
I think he's hungry, he
wants you to feed him.
- Are you hungry?
I think he's hungry.
Is that what you want'?
- Yes he does.
He needs his fruits and
vegetables, he's a growing boy.
- Some milk, it's a little creamy.
- Mmm, look at that cream, wow.
Look at that cream!
- Take it all!
- Oh yeah, take it into your mouth.
Yum yum yum.
Bring her closer to you,
bring her closer to you.
That's right, that's right.
Okay, Nancy, can you hand me the bag'?
Give it to Albert.
Okay, Albert, put the bag over her head.
- What's this?
- It's a bag, we're gonna
put it over her head.
She wants it.
- Just put it over my
head, it turns me on.
- That's right.
- Why?
- Because she likes it.
- Because it's sexy.
You're sexy, be sexy!
- Put it over her head, Albert.
- Come on, put it over
my head, don't be scared.
- Oh yeah, she wants it.
Look how horny she is, my god!
Oh my god, look at those sugar walls
part for you like the red sea!
She wants it, she's really
horny, can't you see her?
Look at her, she's dripping,
she's giving you a platinum
shower with the cup juice.
Look at that, your hands are hugging her.
Harder, harder!
Harder, strangle the shit out of her!
Choke her hard!
She loves it!
That's it, that's it, we've got it.
Thank you.
Thank you, that's a wrap.
Excellent, people.
Sir, I'd like you to stay.
Okay man, good job.
- Look at you!
Little something for later.
- So when am I gonna start working?
- You already did.
Wasn't that easy'?
- But I thought I was going
to be taking pictures.
- Albert, in order to take good photos,
you need a lot of knowledge
and a lot of skill, okay?
- That's why I'm here, i
want to learn about art.
- Look, buddy, what more do you want?
I don't think you've had a
better deal in your life.
- I want to learn.
Or...
- Or what?
- Or I won't come back here again.
- Alright, from now on,
you're my assistant.
It's just that right now, this
is how you're assisting me.
You need to be a lot more
patient, Albert, okay?
What do we always say,
Patience is a virtue?
Yeah, I need you to be
more virtuous, okay?
Alright, we'll talk about this later.
- Let's go.
- Bye, Albert.
- I need to go to the restroom.
- Okay, but, you know, hurry it up.
- Just right around the corner.
You're up to something.
- I'm telling you, he is gold, okay?
- How is he gold?
- He's gonna be the
centerpiece of my next show.
- But where did you find him?
- He's a hot dog vendor.
- Oh, you're making this up.
- Why would I make that up?
- Wait a second, what were
you doing eating hot dogs?
- Yeah, what happened to your diet?
- I walked by a cart, I see this clown,
and I think-
Eureka!
- Albert!
- Oh, speak of the devil,
here he is, Albert.
Man of the hour, right?
- Thank you, time to go, thank you.
- It was nice working with you.
- Good job there, Albert.
- Take care.
- I'll be in touch.
- You're gonna come back
here, enjoy doing it?
- I don't think so.
- Really?
- I wanted to learn about art.
- But you had a hot girl, that's art.
- You like the pretty girl, though.
- Come on, he likes the girl right?
- Admit it!
- Pretty girls are nice.
- I did like the pretty girl.
- He liked the pretty girl.
- He'll be back, he'll be back.
- You know where to go, Albert?
- No, wait, I forgot my bag upstairs.
- You can get it tomorrow,
you can get it another time.
Come on, let's go.
- No, I need it now.
How do I get back up again?
- Go on up.
- Go on.
It's alright, just push the button.
You'll find your way.
Go on, Albert.
- Oh yeah, you like that?
Better get me more work!
You'll pay me double next week?
- We'll see about that.
It depends on what you give me, okay?
- You better pay me double!
- I'm gonna put
that bag over your head.
- Yeah, you want to be so dirty,
why don't you give me more work?
- How dirty do you want it?
- I can be as dirty as you want.
Ready to put another bag over my head?
- You like it
when he strangles you,
you little bitch?
- Yeah, I love it!
Pay me double.
- Yeah, you'll get double.
I like strangling you.
- Have some passion, baby!
Put that bag over my head!
- She loves it!
Harder!
- Fire!
- Hello, miyoki.
- See how clean this is?
You make clean.
- I might be getting a new job soon.
- A new job?
- Yeah, I'm gonna be making a lot of money
as a photographer.
- My cousin can have your job!
- Yeah, it's going to be great.
I just had my first day yesterday.
- Please keep clean, okay?
- Okay, see you.
- Hi.
Can we have two hot dogs please?
And could you please take a picture of us?
- Yeah, sure, I'm a
photographer, you know.
Okay, I need you to stand closer together.
Okay, now pretend that
you're eating the hot dogs,
and you're really hungry.
Open your mouths.
Wider.
Yeah, that's perfect.
- No, this is great.
This picture's great.
- Thank you.
- I gotta tell you something.
I've got something really really
good I've got to show you.
- Oh yeah, really?
Is it another hot girl, Ivan?
- No, no, this is...
I've found quite a specimen.
He looks like a fucking bagboy in a deli.
From a deli in hell.
I mean, he's gonna put
me in the history books.
- That gives me a hard on.
- It's better than whitkin, arbis...
He's so fucking...
- Wow, that's exciting, Ivan.
Sounds like yummy butter to me.
- On baby.
Where are you?
- Milan.
- Oh, really?
- Yeah.
I'm working for this magazine,
and we might have a big job for you,
cause their photographer's super poopy.
- Oh yeah?
- Yeah, they're not 100% sure,
but if they do need you, it's 25k.
- Oh man.
Don't get me too excited here.
When will you know?
- Probably by tomorrow,
so I need you to be ready to travel
at a moment's notice, okay?
- Yeah, okay.
That's fine.
Alright, well, you know, keep me posted.
- I will, and don't even bother
bringing any equipment here.
We've got everything ready.
Just get ready to impress these people.
- Yeah, will do.
Okay, cheers.
- Bye.
- Little bastard.
- Hello?
- What's up, good looking.
- Oh, hello, Ivan.
- Are you ready for the next one?
- Next what?
Next job?
- Of course the next job.
- Okay, but I don't
want to model this time.
I want to learn.
- Again with this shit?
I thought we were clear.
You model, and I teach you photography.
- Yeah, but last time
you only had me modeling.
I want to learn photography.
- Okay.
Come to the studio,
I'll take some pictures
and then I'll teach you.
- How about this, you teach me,
and next time I'll model for you.
- Look, Albert.
I'm being too good already.
Now if you try to take advantage of me,
I'd rather work with someone else.
- Okay, find somebody else.
Hello?
Who's there?
. Daddy.
As in sugar daddy.
Hello, Albert.
- What do you want?
I told you I'm done modeling,
I don't want anything to do with you.
I don't want you here.
Go away.
- Fair enough,
but let's not be completely ungracious.
In fact, I brought you something.
Wow, is this your place?
It's fantastic.
Wow, what is that?
What an amazing use of cardboard.
- No, don't take any pictures!
I told you, no fucking pictures, okay!
- Okay, okay, well,
open what I brought you.
Yeah.
Isn't she something?
That was my first camera.
I got a lot of early
attention from that camera.
Got my first show with that camera.
Yeah, I was nobody.
I wasn't as lucky as you are
to have somebody take him under his wing.
No, but you see,
I just see so much
potential in you, Albert.
Do you know what I mean?
I got this weird sixth sense
when it comes to real artistry.
It's spotting a real artist.
My only question is, are you ready?
- Ready for what?
Ready to snort coke off
the tits of some model
on the beaches of Saint tropez!
To go skiing with the jet set in gestadt.
To go on safari with silicon valley CEOs.
To live the life.
To get the best tables
at the best restaurants,
to hemorrhage money.
To get yourself a real place.
To not live like a nobody.
Are you ready for the life'?
- I don't know, maybe.
" Maybe?
Maybe as badgirl stares
at you from the wall,
you're just gonna jerk off to
her for the rest of your life?
- No.
- Or...
Who's the other lady here?
Miss August.
Stare back at you while you jerk off'?
Is that all you want out of life?
To be a nobody for the rest of it?
- No.
- No?
So my question is, can I count on you?
- Yeah.
- Yeah?
- Yeah!
- Well then, you know what?
You and I are gonna take a photo,
because this moment must be documented.
Smile.
- The fuck are you doing?
- I'm making art.
Real art.
- Dumb mother fucker.
Get out of here.
- I think it's another work of art,
just the way you like it.
- Maybe just a little more on the face.
Okay.
- How are you doing there, sport?
- Yeah, I'm alright, I guess.
- You're alright you guess?
You better know, cause i
got a really expensive model
waiting on the set for you, okay?
And when you see her,
you're gonna get crazy.
- Where do you find these models?
- Where do I find them?
I book them.
" How?
Because I'm-
I'm too modest to say,
maybe you could explain
to him how I book models.
I'm one of the city's best
photographers, that's how.
- He pays them.
- A lot.
- How would I find models?
- Probably the way I did
when I was starting out.
On the street, you know?
You walk up to somebody,
you charm them a little bit.
You know how to be charming, don't you?
- Yeah.
- Yeah, you sure do.
Okay, we're ready to go.
Let's go.
- Yep, think you're done.
- Well, well, well.
She's looking great there, Nancy.
Albert, get on set.
Okay, Albert, say hello
to the pretty piggy.
Say hello to that lovely,
lovely, pink, little piggy.
Say hi.
- Hi.
- Hi, I'm Albert, and
i love pretty piggies!
Yeah, touch the pretty piggy!
Yeah, you love that, right?
You love, love, love that.
You love that so much
that you want to kill her!
Kill the pig!
That's right, piggy.
You're about to die because
butcher Albert's come to town!
The demon butcher of meat street!
Kill that pig!
Yeah, yeah, look at her
writhing in pain, oh my god.
This is your destiny, sweetie,
cause this is where you meet the butcher.
You were born to be butchered,
sad destiny of a little piggy.
She never knew it could be this bad.
Oh, it's unbearable, it's unbearable.
That's a sad way for a little piggy
to meet her end, isn't it?
But Albert's a butcher.
You like taking pretty pink flesh,
pretty piggy flesh.
Yeah, that's you, Albert, that's you.
Grab those tongs over there.
Grab the pitchfork, grab the pitchfork.
That's it.
That's a big dildo you've got
in your hand there, Albert,
because you're not man
enough to use your own cock!
Now take that pitchfork
and shove it in her gut!
Who knew you were born to die so young,
so pretty, and so piggy?
And you can spit on him.
Spit on the butcher.
That's it, spit on that
filthy fucking butcher!
He's a piece of shit!
This is what he's done to you.
Look at him.
He's a piece of shit.
Now drag her over to the grill.
Do it like a man!
That's it, baby, that's
it, let her sizzle.
Look at you, you want to
turn her into a hot dog,
and then you want to sell it back
to the streets of New York!
Isn't that what you do,
you little demon butcher of meat street?
Look at you, look, she's
gonna turn into hot dogs.
Look at that piggy ass.
Let her sizzle.
Then you're gonna eat it,
you're gonna eat it all, aren't you,
cause you're a cannibal.
You're just a filthy
cannibal is what you are-
- this is unmotivated, Ivan.
I'm a vegetarian, for goodness sakes!
I pose nude for art,
not for this sick perverted idea you have.
- Excuse me, you pose because you're paid.
And this is art.
Now get back on the grill.
- No.
- Would you believe this shit?
- She's a feisty one.
- "Ivan, I need motivation,
I have very high ideals,
and in order for me to bear
my breasts to the public,
I have to feel I'm making art,
because otherwise I'll just
feel like a cheap whore!"
- You need motivation more
than a fee we're paying you?
- Shut the fuck up.
Let me explain what's going on here.
See, this is a metaphor, right?
That maggot right there?
Yeah, him?
Big head and a skinny little body.
He's a maggot.
He's a parasite.
He feeds on people like you,
and that's all he does, he's
just gonna chew chew chew chew.
But you see, you're ruining
what I'm trying to do here.
Now I'm not asking you
to fuck this monster.
I'm just asking you to present
your pretty pretty pink
flesh as fresh meat for him.
That way we get some nice,
lovely photos out of it.
Do you understand me?
Is that motivation enough for you?
I'll tell you, some days
it doesn't pay, right'?
Fuck.
What's up, Angela?
I'm in the middle of a shoot.
I'm okay, what's going on?
When?
An hour and a half from now?
At jfk?
I need a hair person...
Okay, okay, I'll see you in Milano.
Thank you.
I'm off to Italy.
That's a wrap.
Where the fuck did you get
that model we used today?
- Oh, come on, you didn't
mind it when she was upstairs
with her boobs in your face-
- just hold the magazine and tell them
that that cunt is not
welcome in that studio.
- Okay, okay, I'll take care of it.
- Take the spare keys,
and I want the studio cleaned, alright,
it's like some misbegotten matadero.
- Oh yeah, you gonna pay me more for it?
- Jackie, take a hike.
- Oh...
- I love you, see you.
- See when you get back, bye.
- You look like a real killer here, kiddo.
You did a good job, should be proud.
I gotta get a fucking cab
to jfk, I'm going to Italy.
Italy, you know, like Europe.
You work hard, you'll get there, too.
You'll see.
You can travel and fuck
all over the planet.
What the fuck's the problem dude'?
You're gonna get us arrested.
Oh my god, here.
Put this jacket on.
I'm getting a whole new
wardrobe when I get to Milano.
You don't need the pocket square,
you don't have that much style.
Oh, here.
This is the money for the shoot.
Get in the cab and follow the one I take,
if it ever fucking gets here.
Always the days I gotta rush to jfk
that there's not a taxi
in front of the building.
Look at this...
- In the street, you know?
Walk up to somebody,
charm them a little bit.
You do know how to be charming, don't you?
- Nice apartment.
- It's not an apartment,
it's a photo studio.
- Is it yours?
- Of course.
I want you to pose for me,
okay, stand over there.
And lift your arms up.
I want to see your armpits, okay,
and bend forward.
Try to be sexy.
Sexier.
But act natural.
- If this is your place,
then you probably have a lot of money.
- Of course.
- So you will fuck?
- I want to take pictures, okay?
And I want you to be
quiet and pose for me.
Stick your ass out.
- Are you gonna give me more money?
- More money?
We haven't even talked about
how much I'm gonna give you
and you're already asking me for more'?
Take off your shirt first.
- Well, if you're getting something extra
than the regular John,
memories for you to beat off to,
then you've got to pay a special rate.
- Rate?
Rate'?
Who the fuck are you?
R...
I'm speechless.
You're talking about rate'?
You're a fucking homeless
hobo I found off the street.
If it wasn't for me-
- I'm a muse.
- You're not, okay, you're a bum.
You'd be lying face down in your own-
- I wouldn't be here in
front of this thing right now
if I weren't a muse.
Do you want me to suck your cock or not?
I'm really good at it.
- You know what, this...
This is not working, okay,
let's go over to the fire escape,
pose some more over there.
- Then I'm putting my top back on.
I'm not going over there topless.
- Okay, I want you to caress yourself.
Yeah, this is turning me on.
Exactly like that.
Sexy.
Alright, now stand over in profile.
And spank yourself.
Yeah, harder.
Perfect, perfect.
Alright, now I would like you to just
stick your tongue out.
Right, stick your tongue out and just...
Just keep your tongue out for me.
Yeah, like that.
Perfect, perfect.
Um, yeah, let's just...
Let's just go inside now.
Come on.
Wait here, I have to go to the bathroom.
Alright, come over here,
and stop playing around.
Come on.
Alright, stand over there.
Over there, over there!
Now, I want to try something
new with you, okay?
I want you to put this bag over your head.
- What?
- Just put the bag over your head.
- You're crazy, aren't you?
You're some kind of sick pervert.
- Look, I'm paying you, aren't I?
So put the fucking bag
over your head, okay?
I'm not paying you for nothing.
- You're a fucking freak, you know what,
I think it's just a good idea
if you can give me my money
and I get the hell out of here.
You're like a complete idiot.
I didn't even want to-
who the hell do you think you are?
You think that I'm gonna
stick a plastic bag
on my fucking head?
- You're a fucking waste of time.
Don't spend it all at once.
Yeah.
Yeah, look at that.
You're so much more beautiful
now that you're quiet.
Yeah, not so tough now, are you bitch?
Can't fuck up my shoot now, can you?
What have you got to say now?
What, what?
Fuck.
Fuck, fuck, fuck!
Shit, fuck!
Fuck!
- What can I do for you?
- There's something wrong with my camera.
I was using it yesterday,
and it takes the pictures,
but they all come out blurry.
See, you can't even tell
what I was taking a picture of.
I don't know, there's
something wrong with it.
It's not working.
- It's a polaroid.
A five year old can use this.
- So why wasn't it working?
- Try to take a picture of me.
- Qkay.
- Buddy...
You're moving the camera.
Now try to take another one.
Aim, take the picture,
and count to five, okay?
Look!
It's fine.
Yeah, you're perfect.
So much more beautiful
than that whore yesterday.
We're gonna take some great
pictures together, you and I.
- Come oh, come on, come oh!
- Are you ready to model now?
Yeah, you're so beautiful right now.
Yeah, okay, let's try something.
Let's try to be creative, let's try to...
Yeah, like that, yeah.
You're holding...
Yeah, it's like, what are you thinking?
It's like, huh,
thoughtful, but still sexy.
Let's try something else.
Scratching your head.
Like that, that's sexy.
That is very sexy.
Let's try something else.
You're feeling an itch,
but further down, yeah.
Like that, like that, that's perfect.
Let's see what else we can do.
I have an idea now.
This is why you shouldn't be drinking,
because it limits your
creativity, you know?
Like, I don't drink,
and that's why I come up with this stuff,
this really good stuff.
So let's try...
Yeah.
That's hot.
That is really hot.
I wish you could see yourself right now,
you're so beautiful.
Let's try something else.
Twice as hot.
Perfect, perfect.
Perfect.
See, this is the problem.
I'm so creative, but,
sometimes there are
limits to what you can do.
- Who is there?
- I live
downstairs, you fucking retard.
My apartment is shaking!
If you don't quit jumping around,
I'm going to call the police.
- I'm really hungry.
You know, let me try one of these burgers.
They good?
- Yeah, yeah, they're great.
- Let me get one.
- Alright.
You see, it's the new
thing we're trying here.
We've tried to get it
as fresh as possible.
It's straight from the cow.
- Well let me ask you something,
is it imported or American meat?
- It's 100% American.
- That's what I want to hear.
I love America.
- Albert, you're such a stallion.
- Thank you.
It's all for you.
The workout, the art...
Walking around taking photos in the park.
You inspire me to create art.
- I like it when you do things for me.
- You're my muse, you know.
I know you like my hot dogs,
but you haven't seen anything yet.
- Oh yeah?
What are you gonna show me?
- I want to kiss you.
- Albert!
I need a place to stay.
- Why?
- Cause I got evicted,
and I don't have a job,
and I ran out of money.
- I think you should
get a real job like me.
- I don't want to sell hot dogs,
I want to be with something better.
- I'm quitting my job.
I'm moving onto selling my photos.
- I don't believe you.
- I don't care if you believe me.
I could even help you get
some work if you wanted to.
- What kind of work?
- Do you want to model?
- Albert, I need to find
some place to stay first.
- You can stay in the studio where I work.
- Seriously?
Albert, if you find me a place to stay,
I will do anything you want.
- Okay, let's go.
- Don't you want to leave your cart?
Aren't you afraid someone's
gonna steal all the hot dogs?
- I don't even care
about my stand anymore.
I'm making way too much money.
- Albert!
What the hell are you doing here?
- What the fuck are you doing here?
- What do you mean what
the fuck am I doing here?
I belong here, I came hereto clean up,
but it looks like somebody seems to have
already taken care of it.
How did you get in here?
- I have keys.
- Oh, yeah, right, from where?
- Ivan gave them to me.
- Bullshit!
Ivan did not give you keys.
- Albert, maybe we should just go-
- you outta here!
Okay.
- Wait for me downstairs.
- You are not supposed to
be here, and you know it.
This is not a place for
you to bring girls to fuck!
- I wanted to take photos.
- Oh god, that again.
You have no idea what a big
mistake you have just made.
Ivan is never gonna let you in here again.
- Don't tell him.
- Why not?
- Hey baby, I'm almost home.
How are you?
- I'm at lvan's.
You are not gonna believe this.
- Why are you at lvan's?
- I came hereto
clean, and guess who's here?
- Jackie?
Jackie?
- Where's your friend?
- She's not my friend.
I told her to leave us alone.
- I didn't see her leave the building.
- She must have left some other way.
- Does she still know you're here?
- Yeah, yeah, it's fine.
I told her to let us work.
- Come on, Jackie.
Pick up.
- Do you think you should answer that?
- No, no no no, no.
That's nothing, there's
always strange people
coming through here ringing
the doorbells at all times.
- Maybe it's her?
- No, no, no, it's fine.
Don't worry about it.
I'm gonna take some pictures now.
- Can I put this on?
- Jackie!
Jackie!
- Guess who?
- You look beautiful.
- Cause I was talking to my girlfriend.
- Mmm-hmm, and what happened?
- She said she was here,
but she's not picking up the phone now.
- And where is she?
- That's why I called.
I don't know where she is.
I called because I need you guys
to find out what happened to her.
- This is going to be real art.
- Well, I'm ready for you, Albert.
But only if we get
married in the pictures.
- No.
- Oh come on, don't be shy.
It'll be fun.
You can wear...
This.
- Hello?
- This is NYPD, we have an emergency.
We have to enter the building.
- Okay, one
moment, I'll be right down.
- Do you think your friend will let me
keep some of her clothes?
Oh, Albert, you look so cute.
- Thank you.
Now let's take some pictures.
- Okay, what do you want me to do?
- Over there, please.
Okay.
This good?
- Yeah.
Alright, now I want you to imagine
that you're a lioness in the Savanna.
Okay?
You are hunting for your prey.
- I'm hunting, okay.
- You're the queen of Africa,
okay, you're a predator.
You're just moving around
silently in the bushes,
waiting to strike, waiting to jump
onto your unsuspected
victim, this antelope.
Okay.
- Okay, beautiful, just like that.
I want you to model with your eyes.
The predatory eyes.
Yeah, beautiful.
Just like that.
- What's your name?
- Tony-
okay.
Yo, Ivan?
Ivan, it's Tony.
Hey man, it's Tony, I live downstairs.
Everything okay in there, Ivan?
- I'm busy working!
Go away!
Okay, this time, you're in a sun chair.
Okay.
- Okay, it's warming your skin,
making it bronzed and beautiful.
Can you feel the sun on your skin?
It's like paradise for you.
Imagine that.
Perfect, like that.
Oh, but what's happening now?
The rain.
But it's gentle drizzle,
but it makes your skin
feel sensationally soft.
Enjoy it, you're enjoying this.
It's cooling you down.
Yeah, beautiful, just like that.
And then you get up.
Get up.
And taste the rain, taste it.
Taste it.
Yes, yes, exactly like that.
You want to really experience it
in a way you've never
experienced it before.
You start to dance around in the rain.
You're making this, cause this is like,
it's a tribute to the rain.
Okay, yeah.
This is the rain dance.
This is...
Yes, yes, just like that.
Just like that, perfect.
Alright, now...
I would like you...
To put this bag over your head.
Okay.
- Alright, perfect.
Okay, I would like you to imagine
that you're being asphyxiated.
Somebody's trying to kill you.
You can't breathe.
You're struggling.
You're struggling against
this unknown killer.
You're fighting for every breath of air.
Just like that.
You like it'?
It's like an aphrodisiac.
Yeah, just like that, exactly.
- This is actually kind of cool.
Kiss me, Albert.
Albert.
(Gunshob
- Albert.
Albert, Albert, Albert.
Your life cut short.
Gone too soon.
We were such good friends.
I had so many plans for us.
- Why?
- Why indeed.
Man's eternal question.
Are you part of his family?
- Uh, no.
I was with him when he got shot.
- In my studio?
- I had nowhere to go.
Albert said I could stay there.
- He was so generous, wasn't he?
Such a kind, generous soul.
That's a terrible picture of him, though.
I didn't take it.
He was a lot better looking
in real life, wasn't he?
So...
Where are you going after this?
- I don't have anywhere to go.
- Well, I'd be honored to give you a lift.
My chauffer is waiting outside.
But I need some time with Albert.
A moment, just to say goodbye.
- Of course.
Bye, Albert.
- You son of a bitch.
Do you know the trouble you've caused me'?
The havoc you've wreaked?
I can't get insured.
And you fucking killed Jackie!
Jackie!
She was so dear to me!
Oh my god.
Do you know what it's gonna be
to try to find a makeup
artist of her caliber again?
You couldn't have knocked off Nancy?
You little ungrateful worm.
After all I did for you.
You're gonna pay for this.
You'll live on through my art.