Brazil, a few years ago...
What did you bring?
Is it something good?
It's a pocket watch.
Made of pure gold.
Who did it belong to?
What difference does it make?
It was no use leaving home.
It's the same everywhere.
We work hard and achieve nothing.
So? there's always prison
from time to time.
Matias knows this very well!
He's stupid enough to
compete at the port.
I'm tired!
If I don't find work soon,
I'll leave this hole!
I'll go away and
leave it for you guys.
Some people will mock me
for leaving.
Where do you want to go?
At least here
we manage to get by.
We? If not for Matias...
This is nothing!
Matias is a failure.
If we go to the port,
we won't do it like him.
Who would we
steal from, anyway?
Everyone here is poor.
There is no work
and everyone knows it.
All we can do is
go on living like this.
It's no use going away.
Everyone who goes down South
comes back soon.
Many people come back every day.
To move to another city
you need a protector.
Do you have one?
Do I have what?
A colonel?
It wouldn't do me good.
Not a colonel, boy.
It could be any big shot from Rio.
The gringo is here!
Don't tell him anything.
He doesn't work for us anymore.
I know it's not much, but next time
we'll have silk and cigarettes.
It's guaranteed.
It's getting worse.
I don't know why we're still together.
It would work better if we split up.
Each one living as he pleases.
Tonight, all the buyers
will be at the coffee bar.
They must come.
Did you hear that?
Everyone at
the coffee bar tonight!
You're all going South,
but not now.
Mother Sabina?
That's me. Why?
Where are your documents?
I don't have any.
You don't need to know how to read
to be aware of the president's decrees.
Even illiterates
know them by heart.
African matrix rituals are forbidden!
If you don't obey for your own sake,
you will obey by force!
You should be ashamed of yourselves!
Place the dolls
on the sheet. Now lift it.
Now, off to the well!
What happened, grandma?
They think we should live as they want.
They want to end it all.
But they can't reach
in here, deep inside.
Is my mother inside?
Don't mind us.
Did they hurt you?
No.
Don't mind us.
Go away.
Your father didn't
belong here either.
The situation there was very bad.
The captain almost
arrested the old woman.
Everyone is afraid of her.
If Tonio still lived there he would
have been caught.
It's bad to be registered
by the police.
Let's not talk about it
anymore. It's over.
The old woman's
patron saint is strong.
The boy is drunk.
Pour me a cachaça.
Have the men arrived yet?
It's about time.
They'd better not
see you like that.
Go dance with her.
Today of all days...
Enough, Tonio.
Please, stop.
That's why they
don't take us seriously.
To hell, all of them!
They're just customers,
everyone is!
Everyone!
My mother.
My father.
Who knows where
that bastard is.
One day I'll take revenge on him.
On second thought,
it's not worth it.
Do you want to
get us in trouble?
You are Sabina's grandson. If someone
hears you, you'll be in trouble.
Whose grandson?
Everyone is afraid of her.
My mother too, but I'm not!
I've got nothing to do with them.
Sometimes I go
there because of...
I don't even know
why I go there.
Really, why?
Stop it, Tonio.
Calm down, I don't exceed my limits.
But mark my words.
One day I will take revenge.
I will start with my father.
Father?
Yes, I do have a father!
He does exist and he is white.
Look who's back.
Came from São Paulo
for a change of scenery.
Whoever goes South gets rich.
He set up a gambling
and prostitution racket.
He's got prostitutes
living like princesses.
Treated well and always full of money.
Very different from us here.
The gold pocket watch belonged to him.
They're here!
We are going to dance.
Let them take care of business.
What I had to do
today I already did.
Hey! Forget about the business.
We need to get Tonio out of here!
Come with us.
I'll explain everything.
The cops are here!
Let me go!
Leave me!
Let's go now!
Let me go.
I want to talk to the police!
Don't forget tomorrow morning
we'll deliver some merchandise!
Everyone needs to go there to help.
Leave me alone!
I'll take you down South.
Trying to live there
will be the same as here.
Neco doesn't like work...
You don't understand.
Let's go somewhere that has work for us,
so you can leave that life.
Do you have the competence for that?
Documents.
I'm a fisherman.
I'm also a fisherman, I work with him.
What about yours?
You've been drinking again.
Do you know how long you haven't been here?
Good morning, mother.
How are things at the port?
Tomorrow there will be
a general workers' strike.
We expect everyone to go,
but you know how people are.
Otherwise there will be no salary increase.
We can't go on like this.
Just look at Luis.
All of his children are ill
and the money he has
is not enough to buy food.
We made a list to help them.
At his house everyone is seriously ill.
But will this strike be successful?
There's a freighter yet to arrive.
If we don't work,
all the fruits will spoil.
They won't like that.
Why hasn't Tonio come over yet?
He must be hung over.
Why didn't you take care of him?
There was no way, mother.
Drinking helps sometimes.
Just look at the Candomblé house.
The police took everyone out of there.
Tonio doesn't live there with them,
but I think it hurt the same.
It doesn't matter.
Any time soon we'll be leaving here.
This freighter must be bringing
good smuggled products.
It's coming from America.
It would be a good deal for them
If it weren't for the strike.
When are we going to the Union?
Tomorrow afternoon.
But there is no Union yet.
We're struggling to make one.
You introduce me to the staff
when the ship docks.
As soon as the meeting is over,
we meet at the cafe.
The men that will be there
are the same from last year.
If we're lucky,
it'll be a piece of cake.
But even with the meeting,
will you able to handle it?
Yes, but I can't be seen with you.
I'm the one who
puts food on the table.
Do you think Tonio
will get into that?
Tonio is not from the party.
Mother, what are you talking about?
Who's in the party?
Here we only speak of food.
I'm going to Alice, she has a friend
who is offering me a job.
Did they order another naked woman?
No, this time it's a poster contest.
It's soap advertising.
Tell Neco to come up here!
He and Alice are always in bed.
Good morning, children.
Neco come up,
they want to talk to you.
There will be a
general strike tomorrow.
There's something to be
solved on an American ship.
It's only going to stir trouble.
You're beautiful, you know?
I manage.
When can I see the model?
From that friend of yours.
It's because I'll participate
in a poster contest.
But I will only be able to pay you later.
As soon as I win the prize.
How do you know that
you're going to win the prize?
Can you see the future?
Don't you think this
strike will end badly?
And who told you to
get involved with them?
Just mind your own
business and that's it.
And what about you?
Don't fool my friend
with that payment story.
How much is the prize worth?
Two bucks.
But it is not money that matters.
Come Neco!
I'm coming!
With the ship there,
we can't do anything.
Come with me!
Pedro!
Go to the beach, hurry!
Let's drink something.
I think I need it.
Come, just a drink.
We can talk in the meantime.
Two beers!
How's your poster going?
Alice's model saved me.
Don't you think it would be better
for you to work as an illustrator?
I heard that the salary is good.
And if it were in Rio it would be
better than the contest.
They offered me a
place in Rio to study,
but I don't want to leave yet.
Maybe sometime soon.
If I was lucky enough
to get out of here...
Who arranged that for you?
It's not a matter of luck.
It was a friend of mine
who works in politics.
But don't tell anyone.
I don't know how to do anything,
not even draw.
The English woman wouldn't say that.
I'm sick of this.
So why don't you go to Rio?
There you can get a good job.
If you went there,
you would soon get a job.
With me it would be different.
They say that everything is easy,
that everything will work out.
But that's not true.
We know how it really is...
Nobody wants anything to be
associated with the strike.
Neither Pedro nor Pitanga.
Tomorrow I'll go to Alice's house.
To work on the poster.
You will end up
ruining that woman's life.
Neco is enough trouble already.
He got her in all sorts of trouble.
He's in love, don't you know?
Let's go home.
Wait just a little longer,
After here I'm going to
the English woman's house.
What do you see in her, Tonio?
She has no money, she has nothing.
People think she is wealthy.
She helps me from time to time.
But I'm getting sick of her.
She likes my color.
They despise and loathe us,
but in bed, we're good enough.
Every white woman says
it's to help us, to save us.
The English woman always says that.
You wouldn't understand, you're white.
With me it's the opposite.
They want me because I'm white.
It's always like that.
Wasn't it the same thing between
your father and your mother?
This talk of color is nonsense.
This place would be better
if everyone collaborated.
They no longer respect anything.
These scumbags have even
forgotten about Christ.
And the children will be even
worse than the parents.
Parasite scum!
They want to be the boss
without working. Poor country.
I'm talking to you! Listen up!
You will stay here for a month.
If you make a fuss I'll hand you over
to the federal authorities!
If you have common sense and speak up,
we'll fix you up!
This country will be straightened out!
Five dockworkers are hidden!
They're agitators on the run!
I want to see their names tonight and
we'll see which one of you has brains!
Another strike...
Just what we needed.
And now even dead bodies.
You're looking sad.
A letter arrived from London.
I'm so fond of Jennifer.
We got married almost at the same time.
Her husband was a fire chief.
Funny, isn't it?
Poor thing, he died so tragically.
She was so shaken that Peter and I
invited her to stay with us.
That way she would be distracted, you know.
I was still living with Peter at the time.
We helped her because she
was in a financial crisis.
In those days,Peter would agree with
everything I suggested.
Poor little thing, she was so shaken
by her husband's death.
She's your type.
But she quickly forgot
about her poor husband.
You should have seen that.
You know how those women are...
It's hard to find one that is sincere.
Jennifer continued to live with us.
And one night
while we were sleeping...
Peter didn't hear a thing,
he slept very deeply.
She brought all kinds of people over.
Even sailors.
Naturally, I never told Peter anything.
If he even suspected...
Sometimes, from my bed,
I'd hear footsteps. And voices.
Tonio, are you distracted?
Yes!
Listen, there was money in my pocket
and now it's missing.
I'll go to the police
and you will be a witness.
Don't be an idiot,
I took the money!
I needed the money.
Five bucks?
If you sleep here on Saturday,
we could go on a trip in the morning.
It's no use pouting!
No one's to blame!
Didn't we have to steal to eat?
Am I telling any lies?
What will become of us without Pedro?
I will not be able
to provide for our home.
Talk and talk, but when it comes
to leaving this place
nobody has the courage!
Where's the courage now?
Is there anything holding us here?
The dockers are hidden
in the Candomblé house.
They'll go into the woods,
to catch the midnight freight train.
The train will stop
near the slaughterhouse.
You're going with them.
Mother, this is my salvation!
Who arranged this?
Don't you worry.
Go away and leave the rest
for us to take care of.
Go away!
Here you won't ever achieve anything!
You're useless, even with our help.
Aren't you so smart?
You better go, that way you'll solve
your problems and that's it.
No one here is smart!
I just need to get out of here!
Why don't you go as well?
Who's holding you back?
Nobody!
So shut your mouth!
No need to shout.
Shouting will do no good.
You know I could have
left if I wanted to.
I didn't leave because I didn't
want to leave everything.
But I will learn to live by myself.
Get out of here!
Scoundrel!
The train will stop
at five in the morning.
You'll have to climb on it quickly,
in the last train car.
Ten minutes before passing in Monte Azul,
The train will slow down
and you'll have to jump.
May God be with you.
Two cups of coffee.
What a beautiful day.
At least close the door!
Leave it open, Tonio is coming up.
Can I sleep here?
Of course.
Did you read the newspapers?
These people...
They will all be caught, you'll see.
Murderers...
Instead of laying low,
they prefer to fool around.
Thankfully the train
driver told on them.
Imagine if they got away...
At least the driver is honest.
Which reminds me of Europe.
Enough!
And they haven't found
everything out yet.
They are looking for
whoever helped them escape.
If only I wasn't a foreigner...
Do you want to go to the
same hotel as last time?
What are you thinking about?
Nothing!
I don't feel like talking.
Are you crazy?
You've arrived, miss.
Is it too hot in Bahia?
Very!
Room eleven.
How long are we staying here?
We're going to stay here for a week.
But if you want to,
we can go back sooner.
Nice way to show your gratitude!
I took you off the streets.
And that's what I get.
Where are you going?
I'm going to take a walk.
When I think of my homeland,
I miss it so much.
Tonio, we could get along better.
We could have fun.
What's missing for you?
I already did everything I could.
Do you think a person
can live like this?
You hate me, don't you?
You have no heart.
When I first met you I immediately
opened up my house to you.
It has nothing to do with love.
I thought we could understand
each other better.
I thought you didn't
have anyone else either.
What's going on in your head?
What you really like
is life on the streets.
Tonio, you're an unhappy
person and you know it.
if I could live alone...
If you were another person,
things could be better.
It was foolish of me
to get you out of the mud.
Finish that beer right away.
Can't you see that people are staring?
Have you paid for it?
These Negroes...
Are you sleepy?
I've already told you, I'm tired!
Tired of the trip?
One can't always stay in Bahia.
Even if you could be with me every night,
I couldn't stand being there all year.
I think I'm going away.
What will you do?
I'm going to São Paulo.
Everyone wants to get out of here.
When are you going?
Soon.
I won't see those people
you don't like anymore.
You know I can't go to
São Paulo right now.
And how would you go without me?
I don't need you!
You don't need me?
Easier said than done.
What about the money you
took out of my pocket?
I can see how you don't need me.
That money wasn't for me!
So who was it for?
It's no use in talking about it.
You wouldn't be able to understand.
You think I don't
know what it was for.
If you're curious,
I'll tell you now.
Sleep peacefully,
I'm not gonna tell anyone.
If they arrested you,
what would become of me?
But I should turn you in.
You deserve it.
Acknowledge that it was foolish to
try and help those people.
You're just inconsequential.
You are not a communist,
so why did you join them?
You know as well as I do
that they are against the law.
Which law?
Look, even if you don't
want it to, the law exists.
Come here, give me
a kiss before bed.
Leave me alone!
I want you, come here!
You're nothing but
a nasty black.
You!
Don't let him out!
Hey! Put that shirt on!
Where have you been?
I already made up my mind,
I'm going to São Paulo.
I could help you.
I don't want to
talk about it anymore.
Hey!
The water is great, come on in!
Where have you been?
Traveling.
I broke up with the
English woman and came back.
I decided that I'm going to São Paulo.
This is so good, especially
after that hellish trip.
Tonight we're going
to the gafieira dance.
Everyone will be there.
You're coming too!
Tonight I'm paying for everything!
I'm rich!
How come?
Who is the girl you're taking?
She's sixteen. She works
as a maid in Canela.
Is she still a damsel?
I don't know.
Hey, Matias!
Tonio left the English woman.
So many people are looking
for a woman like that,
And you just let her go.
Tonight we won't talk about business.
He is rich.
Let's all go to the dance,
I'm paying.
The girl is coming too.
Tonio!
Don't come after me, please.
You will regret it.
Tonio, it's the girl.
Hey, Manuel!
Why hasn't she come in yet?
Get in there,
I'll be going in a minute.
I'm sorry Manuel,
I couldn't come up.
Why?
I'm not feeling very well.
Come, I want to
introduce you to my friends.
You're going to like them.
No. I'm tired, Manuel.
Please, come with me.
I already told you,
I'm not coming.
Look, I'm not feeling very well
because I'm pregnant.
Don't be so sad.
You have no obligation.
We are not engaged or anything.
I've been like this for three
months, before I met you.
Tonight, I'm paying!
Is Manuel out there?
We didn't see him.
I think his girl didn't
want to come out.
How are you?
Long time no see.
What have you been up to?
Just traveling a bit.
Right...
Night shift.
Wait a second.
It's a foreigner.
I think she has some information
about the workers strike.
Pay attention to Neco.
Be careful, he might find out.
I'll take care of it.
Neco is the one I like.
I only go with Matias
to pass the time.
Now and then we need an older man.
We are angels compared
to these people.
Look at that girl over there.
I bet you she wants to go down South.
They say that women are victims.
You just have to offer something and
they'll do whatever we want.
Do you think I'll be tied to someone?
I just want to have fun.
I'm not a child.
I know these men very well.
What is it?
Go home. I need to tell Sabina
about what happened.
Let me go, you know
Tonio is underage.
I'm glad that's none of our business.
It can get worse.
Don't worry, I'll take you home.
It's not the first time your
family has given us trouble,
but this was the worst of all.
I know you don't care about the
laws that we respect
and use to maintain social order.
I want to warn you.
Your grandson is involved with the strike.
A serious offense, according to our laws.
Do you understand that?
He ran away when he was little.
I have nothing to do
with him and his life.
Instead of doing rituals,
You should take better
care of your family.
At your age you should
have some common sense.
It was my daughter who
gave birth to him, not me.
Since the child was born,
I never saw her again.
She's been ill for many years.
So you are the only one responsible
And you know this as well as I do.
His father disappeared many years ago, right?
Yes, sir.
Have you heard from him since?
What does your grandson do for a living?
I hope you know that at least!
I think he works. How would I know?
He never came home.
Listen, lady.
This country already
gives us many problems.
Few people are concerned with the
progress of this land.
You look like victims,
but you are parasites.
In any case,
he will remain
here for a few days.
I just want to know the whereabouts
of the agitators he helped get away.
If he cooperates, we'll
leave him to your care.
Since your daughter is incapable.
In which case you are officially
responsible for him!
Get up!
Follow me!
Listen boy, there's no time!
You're a minor.
Otherwise, you'd already be in jail.
Your grandmother was here
and said she doesn't know
anything about your life.
You will be delivered to her
within a month.
But only if you talk.
If you don't talk you'll stay here
until we find those scumbags.
In that case, you'll
go to a reformatory.
Let's go!
Spill the beans!
How did that escape happen?
Speak at once!
What can I say?
I don't know anything!
Why did you arrest me?
Don't play a fool.
I'll refresh your memory.
First, you stole five bucks.
Want me to remind you from whom?
It was used to help in the escape
of the murderers of a poor soldier!
You have plenty of imagination.
You forgot that by helping them,
you endanger the lives of innocents.
People who don't care
about strikes.
People who don't
need strikes!
I don't know anything!
Speak now, or
regret it later!
I will not tell on anyone!
This one wants to be a martyr...
This will be bad for everyone.
No doubt.
When the cops went in the club,
everyone knew it was about the strike.
This is no laughing matter.
That boy...
Have some manners, woman!
What can we do?
Wait for him to be released.
Do you want more trouble?
I hope it doesn't escalate.
I spoke to Sabina yesterday.
She said she doesn't
know anything about it.
Tonio is a minor,
but he's never lived at home.
We have to do something.
Wait...
What about Crispim's friend?
The politician.
What?
You think an influential
person will get involved in this?
Involved with communists, no less!?
You're insane.
Tonio is not a communist!
I know you, Manuel.
You're not going to get us into this.
This is Tonio's business.
Let him handle it.
You know very well that we
are all compromised here.
Your good will might
get us in trouble.
What a surprise! Come in.
Take a seat.
I'm going to Rio.
I'm going to study there.
In the meantime
I have to finish this poster.
It's not for the prize,
but for satisfaction.
It must be difficult
to enter the Academy.
But with a big shot
it should be easier, right?
It cost me a little, but I did it.
Did you know Tonio was arrested
because of the dockers' escape?
It was bound to happen.
But Tonio of all people...
You liked him the most, right?
Yes.
If only we could lend him a hand...
He might end up in a reformatory.
If you came to ask for favors,
I'm sorry.
I would like to help, but
I can't get mixed in that.
Especially with politics involved.
Politics?
Don't play stupid.
Why would I take that risk for
someone who never helped me?
Nobody helped me when Pitanga
expelled me from the group.
Remember?
And that would be
easy to solve.
Now, with police trouble,
word gets around fast.
Everyone should
lay low for now.
Don't forget I am a minor.
And I don't live with my family.
When are you going to Rio?
Soon.
But I'll keep this house intact.
I can't bring myself to do it.
It's so beautiful.
Why don't you stay for coffee?
Can we live here?
What would that be like?
I can stay at my employers' house
until the child is born.
After that, I already
told them I'm leaving.
And I can work.
Me too. But I want to live here.
Wait Neco, wait!
Don't do this!
Go back inside, woman!
My goodness!
Neco! Neco!
Now you'll learn not to mess with
other people's wives! Scumbag!
Get out, before I thrash you!
What's happened, Matias?
I'm done!
I'm going away. By myself!
What's the use of
having a woman?
There's nothing else
to keep me here.
I stayed because of her,
because I liked her!
Whenever I wanted to leave,
she'd beg, "No! No..."
Now I know why she
wanted to stay.
I found them both in that bed!
It was not because of him.
I don't care about Matias.
I like him. Don't you see?
Love is nonsense!
What am I going to do now?
Telegram.
What shall we answer?
Send everyone to the inquiry
five days from now.
They have arrested
the agitators at the border.
The country may be large,
but it doesn't hide bandits.
Hello, how are you?
Everything in order.
They've just arrived.
I think there can be
no serious consequences.
For better or for worse,
the boy has a family.
The interest of the case is relative.
It's no longer
relevant, politically.
What about the union?
There is no union.
Besides, I have too many children
to take care of.
Have you made any statements
about the boy?
It's for the best.
Call the grandmother
and give the boy to her.
The real issue
is the excess of children...
You darned boy!
You got me in trouble.
My own troubles are enough!
Let's go home.
I don't live there and I don't
want to hear from you!
Look.
They made me sign the paper.
You have to come home for a few days.
Until they forget about you.
You better go see your mother.
She got worse in the last
few days because of you.
Mother.
Hey. You are Tonio, aren't you?
I'm Manuel's fiancee.
Manuel told me
you're headed down South.
Now that you're free,
you're going. Right?
No, I'm not going anymore.
Where is Manuel?
Looking for work.
I'll meet him at the port shortly.
We'll live together
when the child is born.
I'll see you later.
I come here quite often.
Manuel, don't!
Stop stealing, Manuel!
Why?
Stop stealing!
You shouldn't steal anymore!