Provided by explosiveskull
https://twitter.com/kaboomskull
Bamdad Film Presents
A kapFILME Co-Production
In the Name of God
Amir,
leave all this and get the van.
We'll wait at the road.
Thanks man.
A film by
Manije Hekmat
The refinery at
Hur al-Alzim is now under water-
- as a result of the terrible
flood in Khuzestan province.
In some areas of Khuzestan, the
flood waters have drowned the t.
Twenty villages near Shadegan a.
Three have been evacuated.
The camps are reportedly
handing out care packages,
but they are in dire need
of many staples and items.
Is this a flood or a monster?!
It has devoured everything!
- Did you reach Mitra?
- I'm trying, but the lines are.
If she doesn't answer,
let's go straight to Tehran.
Amir! If the dam bursts...
We can sail from the
Karkheh river to the Rhine, bro!
We'll earn Euros and spend Toma!
Shut up!
Imagine you're floating.
No worries! We'll pass the floo,
and drive straight to Tehran.
We'll rock that stage my love!
We'll finish first! Trust me!
We'll be on our way to
The Pages of History!
Even though all their possessio,
home and hostel were lost in th,
Lady Mahla and her "Bandar Band"
made it just in time to Cafe Ste
for an exhilarating performance!
It was from this very stage that
they went on to world fame-
and found audiences in Paris,
Berlin, New York, Bangladesh-
and Amsterdam.
Let's listen to
a folk song by this band.
The road is closed up ahead.
I think we should turn around.
Hello.
Where does this road go to?
North of Hamidieh.
- So there’s a way.
- Where do you want to go?
We want to go to Tehran.
- Tehran?!
- Yes.
This is not an actual road.
It’s a jungle. You will be stuc.
- Your tablet is ringing.
- Navid, get the tablet.
Navid, get off your lazy ass
and get that tablet.
- It's Ms. Khoshdel.
- Give it here.
Pull over.
- Hello Ms. Khoshdel.
- Hello, Mahla dear. Are you in?
- We'll be there soon.
- You're not here yet?
You have to be here by 6pm.
- The show starts at six.
- We'll be there.
You won't believe what's happen.
Our home is flooded.
The roads are closed.
Everything's messed up.
There's water everywhere.
But we're coming
as fast as we can.
Okay, dear. Just be on time.
Try to get here early.
- We'll be there.
- Let me have it.
Hello, good day to you.
Is there a way you can send vids
of the performers we're up agai?
I'll send you their links.
Just don't be late!
Thank you so much.
See you.
- Goodbye, Ms. Khoshdel.
- I love you all.
Bye-bye!
You're such an idiot!
Links?
- To see our competition.
- When will we get there?
- We'll get there.
- We better not be late.
Don't stress over it.
We'll get there.
And inshallah you'll get 1st pl.
- Everyone is waiting to hear y.
- Definitely 1st place!
She'll rock the show,
my sweetness!
Mommy Mahla...
"My sweet-heart, my cutie-pie"
Next!
- She's too traditional!
- Who cares?! It's about how yo.
What we have is fresh.
Have a little confidence.
Don't worry.
Yeah, I sing better than her.
Hold your horses!
We're all equally great.
You're great, and I know it.
But she is also great.
You need to be confident.
Go to the next one.
Let me see her.
This one's singing solo.
The next one.
There'll be two others there.
A guitarist singing Hip-Hop and-
- this one singing
a traditional solo, right?
Wait, this is another one.
All of us have to fit here.
Amir, you in the corner, me the.
Mahla, you stand
a bit closer than this girl.
With confidence.
This girl isn't anything specia.
It's just two chords.
Don't worry.
We'll pick Davood up.
Us three, with three chords,
will win their hearts.
That's the way.
With Davood,
all our problems will go away.
Just don't you worry.
Just remember all that I've
told you, and we'll be fine.
Amir, slow down.
Amir, you drove us into the sea.
Amir, drive.
This way.
More.
This way. Don't be afraid.
Good, stop.
Turn around.
Come on.
Stop.
Turn it.
Come. Come.
I'm standing on the asphalt.
You're doing it.
Stop. Stop.
Come.
Come, come.
Stop.
Perfect.
Just take this to the main road
I swear to God it’s safer.
We can’t even tell the differen
between the main or the side ro!
It’s all mixed up.
Then at least
turn on that damn radio.
You and your radio radio!
When does the radio ever tell t?
Whatever they say we’ll
do the opposite, it’ll work out.
Alright stop. I know this side
that’s better than all the othe.
Amir, I can’t handle another
side road to nowhere.
Please Amir!
No more side roads.
Mahla!
I know the way!
Sure. You know.
Mr. Know-it-all!
...And all this heavy
raining has led to this disaste
Is that Abed's car?
It's Abed.
Yeah, it's Abed Stop the car.
It's Abed!
Amir, stop and help him.
I can't just press
pause on this crappy van!
Oh look, he's stuck in mud.
Poor thing!
His parents are with him too.
Abed!
It's such a mess.
Amir, go help them.
If we keep making stops,
we won't make it to Tehran in t.
Mark my words.
Stop whining.
They're stuck for good.
Open the door
so they can come and sit here.
Amir, a cable.
I have a cable.
- They seeded the clouds.
- Who did? You?
They made it rain.
- Are there any tourists?
- Do floods bring tourists?
- Are you going to Tehran?
- We'll stop at Mitra's first,
and then check on our own place.
I'm taking my folks to Dezful.
It's too damp here.
You're the one who needs help.
A girl in her state
shouldn't be traveling.
Don't worry about us.
Get your car out of the mud fir.
Off to Tehran we go,
We three fools...
- You’re off beat.
- On purpose.
She made a mistake.
Let it go.
Can we win first place like thi?
The three idiots.
Look at us.
When we go stage you just
move your lips and I’ll sing.
- Agreed?
- Okay.
I have a great voice.
"When your eyebrow
calmly twists together  "
How can you make fun of me
when you don’t even know the ly?
Sing Mahla.
Show him what you got!
Okay, sing it.
I want you to sing.
"When your eyebrows
calmly twist together  "
Our prize will be a lollipop.
It’s better than getting
kicked out with nothing.
- And you can’t even sing one l.
- They’ll kick you off the stag.
- But I'm super talented!
- Shut up! Amir, you sing.
I'm on the road to fame.
Navid, be quiet.
Amir, you sing instead.
Me?
Start and I’ll sing.
Sir, come here.
Their only assistance is blocki.
This road's closed.
Turn around!
Salaam.
Sir, sir.
Come here.
We live here.
We can't turn around,
my wife is pregnant.
Please let us through.
They're delivering supplies.
Will you listen to us!
I live over there.
I'm a local.
Will you please let me through?!
Turn around.
Only emergency vehicles can pas.
Let me deliver the supplies.
I know the way.
Thank you, man.
Do you know the area?
Yes, we're from here!
Go forward and
turn left at the rugs.
Iran really does have
the world's best rescue teams.
We have floods and earthquakes,
forest fires and plane crashes.
- What would we do without you?
- Stop here.
Come and put these in their van.
Brother, what's your name?
Navid.
Tie down the rugs
and the blankets on the roof.
Put those on the roof.
Enough, we're full.
- One more.
- No, no, no.
Mahla, get in.
Enough, we're full!
Why did you get out?
I wanted to see what they had.
Amir, let's go before
he changes his mind.
God bless him.
Are there a bunch of diapers?
There's everything.
What should we do?
Wait a minute.
First let this tractor through,.
Sorry.
We can go now.
Okay.
Take these to the tents.
Thank you.
- Oh, my God.
- Oh, God help us.
Mahla, don't look.
Thanks.
We'll save these for baby Nila.
Why not keep it all for Nila?
Here, take these.
Here.
And these.
Look, refugee tents.
It's like a village of tents!
They're flood victims too.
Let's just give it to them.
Here you are.
Take this.
Water.
Diapers, please.
Diapers.
Who wants diapers?
- Diapers.
- Shampoo.
I'll unload the top.
[Folk song]
I swear you're wrong,
she's probably in those white t.
Mitra will be fine.
I didn't say she wouldn't be.
They're up to their necks in mu.
What sane person lives here?
I need her clothes.
One-track mind!
All these cars are stuck.
He's right.
There's a mudslide.
How can we get by?
And all you talk
about are her clothes!
They're all leaving
from where we're headed!
Why did you stop?
This bridge is too weak to cros.
Let me out, I'll go.
Bring the watermelons.
Mahla, wait.
Maybe there's nobody there.
Maybe she won't be there.
Amir, say something to her.
I can't.
I know this is a waste of time.
There's nobody in this mud.
Lock the doors
and turn off the engine.
Lock this door.
Mitra!
- Have you seen Mitra?
- Mitra!
She's there.
Mitra!
Auntie!
Everything's gone!
I can't believe this!
Have you seen Mitra?
I hear Mitra's voice.
Be careful kids! Calm down.
Here, take my hand.
What are you doing here?
Amir, help get the kids.
Wait for me.
- Hi!
- What are you doing?
Take care of the girl.
He lost his shoes.
Hold his hand.
Do you have your van?
Listen to me.
Go back to the bridge.
Take all these kids
to the relief workers there.
Go under the wire.
Put them in your van
and take them to the tents.
How are you?
Why did you come?
Don't be afraid.
Pay attention to these two.
- Navid, count them.
- We'll watch them.
- It was hell getting here.
- Stop yelling.
Don't let go of me,
you'll get stuck in the mud.
- Why did they come here?
- I was going crazy, the lines .
Don't fall.
Amir, do you remember Aunt Zohr?
Her son's here.
Wait, my shoe's stuck.
Where are you staying now?
Did they give you a tent?
Come on up and see.
- So where are you staying?
- Be careful, there's a well ov.
Let me go first.
Count them, Navid.
Make sure no one's left behind.
Hold on to me.
- What are these?
- Food for the kids.
Farideh, come here a minute.
Do you have boots on?
Can you pass these out?
I can't move.
Take these too.
So did you get a tent?
Yes, they did.
And the school?
It's full of mud.
What are you doing here?
I came to get a dress.
Don't laugh!
My clothes are all gone.
Look in the closet.
- What should I do?
- What's the dress for?
I'm going to perform on stage t!
- Really? Tonight?
- We'll pick Navid's guitar up .
- Your dress is fine!
- No it's not! It's embarrassin!
You don’t have any dresses.
I’ll put on some make up and g.
- You look like a rockstar!
- No, I don't!
- Have you rehearsed at all?
- A little, with Navid.
Don't embarrass us!
Let me hear you sing.
I was really worried about you.
Yeah right!
I thought you're here for my cl.
- Don't you think you're too pr!
- No, I'm not!
Don't move around so much.
Is Mr. Mansour playing?
- He's not well.
- What's he playing during a fl?
He's lost his mind.
The road is closed.
He says it's closed.
- He said the road's closed.
- I can see that.
I can't turn around.
I said it would be closed.
I have to turn around.
What's going on here?
It's so crowded.
It's a 'Wailing Song.'
When did he get out?!
The flood wanted to make us wee.
But we built levees
and made the flood cry.
How's it going?
Don't get stuck up ahead.
- I know my way around here.
- Have you been here before?
Yes, I have.
I know it well.
Thanks.
Amir, is this the right way?
Yes, it is. I know the way.
Ask somebody.
Turn around here.
Let this guy pass.
Hello, does this road go throug?
Where are you headed?
Straight to Tehran.
You have to turn around.
I told you we were lost.
- Did you go through the flood?
- Yes.
All the roads are closed.
Follow me.
- We will.
- Turn around and follow.
Why do you say you know the way?
You were getting us lost.
Could you be quiet for a bit,
or not?
He won't listen.
See if they have any water.
Do you have any water?
My wife is pregnant.
Can you give us some water?
- Take this bottle. .
- Thanks.
- Do you need cups?
No, no.
We were dying of thirst.
- Don't drown us.
- I can see the road, my love.
I can tell from how you drive.
God knows where
you were taking us.
Lalalalala...
Do not be afraid, no one is com.
Do not be afraid,
no one will bother us.
When your eyelashes
calmly come together.
And they intertwine like vines,
and they calmly become one.
Your eyelashes calmly intertwin!
I feel like I can hear
them in the dark, calmly.
Calmly, calmly Oh, so calmly.
Oh my God!
This is our luck!
The same day we need to go on s,
all the roads are washed away.
Amir, will you
please stop whining.
I can't stop seeing this.
You're getting on our nerves.
I say this can be good for us.
Stay positive and this
will lead us to our big break.
We will rock the house.
And if we promote
ourselves on social media,
we'll become famous
and rock the world!
We'll go abroad, earn Euros and
go play music in Latin America..
and live the life.
- Where in Latin America?
- Brazil, bro! Columbia. Venezu-
The Venezuelans are starving!
They're all leaving their count.
Have you seen Venezuela?
Yes, I've seen it.
- Seen what?
- You haven't even left our pro!
Let me show it to you.
Give me a cigarette.
- You want to smoke?
- Just a puff.
Did I put up all these 'No Smok'
signs for random tourists?!
It's a craving.
One puff won't do any harm.
What an idiotic craving.
Listen to this cool song.
You might have made it big
but you'll never change.
Mahla, didn't you know?!
Navid's been around the world!
Only you know that.
Now give me a puff.
Throw that damn thing out.
It's gone.
Hello Mrs. Khoshdel
we're running late.
Can you hear me?
It's disconnected.
Brother Davood, Brother Davood,
You can never be replaced by anr
You sweeten our tea,
you fill us with glee
You're our David Gilmour,
our band's navigator
Brother Davood, Brother Davood!
You come before and after.
You fill us with laughter
Our band's navigator
David Gilmour, Brother Davood...
Mahla, be careful my love.
Think of our baby Nila.
Becoming a dad is awesome, righ?
Too bad, I wasn't so lucky.
If not, I'd have four little ons
running around us right here.
- Navid!
- What?
Maybe I'm not thinking straight.
My home, my life,
the hostel... They're all washe.
Don't think about it.
You're too hard on yourself.
The hostel was part mine too.
When we get back where will
my wife and kid live?
In my place.
Or maybe out in nature.
Enjoy life.
Imagine raising you kids out he.
- They'd love it.
- Under these conditions?
You don't understand me.
The road is open and it goes ard
Bandar Band never loses its soud
Mahala, we'll be there
a half an hour early.
If you step on the gas
we'll have time to practice.
I'll step on it.
Amir go faster, floor it!
Don't drive like a turtle.
You jerk!
Am I driving like a turtle?
- Just like a turtle.
- Watch me grow wings and fly.
There's no more water.
No more flood.
The road's wide open.
Just step on the gas.
Stop saying 'water' and 'flood'!
You'll jinx us.
When we get to Tehran let's
have a watermelon shake.
Melon yes, water no!
Every way we went,
they'd turn us back.
Do this, do that.
Do that, do this.
I was losing my mind.
Come on, bro, step on the gas.
I'm flooring it!
Oh, oh! Slow down.
It's the cops. Don't stop.
- Why shouldn't I stop?
- They'll confiscate the car.
Don't stop Amir!
If they chase us,
we lose the van.
Oh, God. Amir, we're screwed.
What's the rush?
- License and registration.
- But, why?
Why?!
Your license and registration!
- Come on, buddy.
- I was only going 60.
Buddy?! Get out!
This guy is crazy.
Amir, I told you not to pull ov.
Listen to what I say.
Sir, we have everything under control
The flood hasn't reached us yet.
We are well-prepared for any pr.
We just need reinforcements.
I haven't seen my family in fiv.
Hello Mr. Shapoori.
How can I help you?
How are you?
- Driver?
- He is the driver.
Our radar clocked you at 160 km.
This van can barely do 100 km/h!
And my wife is pregnant.
Your wife is pregnant?!
Your excuse is worse than your .
You want to kill yourself
and your wife and baby!
- His home was washed away.
- So was mine. That's no excuse.
Sir, we're late for a concert.
We're going to perform.
We have to tow your van.
Give us the keys.
- Do not touch me!
- Officer Shapoori, please.
We have to go on stage.
I swear to God,
we are performing.
Are you actors?
We're musicians.
I'm a singer/songwriter.
He's a great musician.
Do you sing? What's your name?
Navid. I'm not famous yet.
But soon you'll want a photo wi!
- Let me hear you sing.
- I can't like this. I need my .
- Go get your instrument.
- Are you serious?
Officer Shapoori told you
to go and get your instrument.
Don't touch me!
- Can he really sing?
- He's going to be famous soon.
We'll see.
- What's happening?
- Everything's gonna be all rig.
Take a back seat
Let me accelerate
Let's travel the world
I can't wait
Stay where you are
Accept your fate
Learn how to behave
We have no manners
Will somebody hold me back?
To get my baby back.
I'll become the Pink Panther
I might not have the answer
But I need to make things right.
Will somebody hold me back?
Don't end things, it's time to t
Even with my pretty face
You broke my heart
So glue it back in place
Will somebody hold me back?
Over there.
Here.
Clean it.
Clean this windshield.
We'll be with Davood soon.
Don't embarrass me.
Let's practice your singing.
Faster.
What's up? Again!
Open the door. Hurry.
Is anybody there?
- Amir!
- What?
No one is here.
I don't know what's going on.
I'm going to pick Davood up.
I'll be right back.
- Amir! Nila is kicking.
- Our lovely baby.
La la la. Don't be afraid.
No one's coming.
La la la do not be afraid,
no one will bother us
When your eyelashes
calmly come together
And they intertwine like vines
Your eyelashes
calmly intertwine
I feel I can hear
them in the dark, calmly
Calmly, calmly
Oh, so calmly.
Check it out.
It's Davood.
Let him be.
He's turned into a raft.
A rifleless rider has no strengh
He needs a rifle to ride away
Let's go, Navid.
They say horses are wartime fris
We say rifles are better friends
A rifleless rider has no strengh
He needs a rifle to ride away
I sold my silver-handled rifle
I sent my love a cashmere cloak
And my love sent it right back
My silver-handled rifle,
Is there no justice?
Amir, stop.
I feel sick.
Navid!
Let me go! Get lost!
- Amir!
- What?
Yes?
Amir, where's Nazgol.
She left.
With who?
With Saghar.
Saghar?
Who's Saghar?
Abed's ex-girlfriend.
We may have
given him too many pills!
I think in someone's
dream, Iran is flooded.
In someone's deep sleep.
I think we're in his dream.
If he wakes up
the flood waters will drain.
I think he's also late.
He's taking a boat to Tehran.
We're always in
a hurry to arrive in Tehran.
This is the first
pastime of our lives.
And I suppose afterwards,
Berlin, Paris, Los Angeles.
As if this land is such
that the further away you get,
the more of
an accomplishment it is.
It's sad.
I wish that fellow wakes up.
So the flood waters can drain.
Wet travelers and...
wet traveler checks
Traffic cops in water
up to their necks
My horse got all wet
slipped from my saddle
A drainpipe grew from
my aching collarbone
Rain pours down all day long
from the roof of this song
From my knee cap
to my guitar strap
It's not rain, it's spears
Six feet long spears
Both the water is scared
and the kettle's pipe
It comes down to kill
shaped like a thrill
It pours down completley
On the city's architecture
The rain said something,
The rain chanted a spell
The people are crushed
when the ceiling hits the floor
This rain is thick
and hard as a brick
Rain rain falling pain
rain rain, again and again
Rain rain, pain pain
again and again
Rain and pain again
Provided by explosiveskull
https://twitter.com/kaboomskull