[man] You're out of chances, Kaem.
Sutthiphong died almost a month ago.
You're still doing less than
half the work he did.
Yes, boss.
Well...
As far as I'm concerned,
no one could finish this job on time.
Doing the annual budget summary
in less than a month?
Besides,
it's not part of her job.
All right.
If you can finish it before January 2nd,
we'll promote you
as a replacement for Sutthiphong.
What about...
What are their names?
Our interns.
[woman] Jack and Phraeo?
Yeah, whatever.
Tell them to help her.
Thank you, boss.
Okay.
Anyway, Happy New Year.
[suspenseful music playing]
[unavailable signal]
Where the hell is he?
[clanking]
Get that thing out of the way.
[sighs]
[dialing phone]
[line ringing]
[hangs up]
[door beeping]
I'm so sorry, Miss Kaem.
Miss Kaem?
Well...
Please don't tell my boss about this.
If you file another complaint,
I'll probably get fired.
Please.
Is that all you can think of?
You're working so late. Aren't you afraid?
[mysterious music playing]
Afraid of what?
Mr. Sutthiphong.
He sat next to you
and died from being overworked.
If I were you, I'd sit somewhere else.
Wait.
Lamduan didn't come into work
the other day.
She said it was because
she saw Mr. Sutthiphong
in a Santa Claus suit
sitting next to your desk.
[elevator dings]
I'm not surprised
you're just a security guard.
[eerie music playing]
Phraeo.
How's work?
[Phraeo] Well, I...
I tried to contact Miss Fon,
but she didn't answer the phone.
[sighs]
You have to get in touch with her
at any cost.
Oh!
If you don't,
you can find yourself a new internship.
[slow music playing]
SUTTHIPHONG THARAB
MANAGING DIRECTOR
[typing]
[wind rushing]
[sighs softly]
[continues typing]
[man] Why did you want me dead?
[intense music plays]
[Kaem screaming]
[breathing heavily]
[door opening]
Are you okay?
Yeah.
What do you want?
May I go out to get some coffee?
Who with?
Alone.
Get me a large nonfat cappuccino.
What are you waiting for?
I don't have enough money.
Your coffee is almost six dollars.
I don't want it anymore.
Hurry back.
Yes, ma'am.
[sighs]
[intense music playing]
[slow music playing]
[phone dings]
MOM - ARE YOU SURE
YOU WON'T BE COMING HOME?
I WOULD HAVE LIKED TO.
[mysterious music playing]
I PROMISE I'LL GET OUR HOUSE BACK
IN THE NEW YEAR WITH MY BIG BONUS.
[mysterious music playing]
Why are you so moody today?
Jack.
You startled me.
Give me a smile.
How can I smile?
Work is so stressful.
If I can't finish this project,
I'll be in big trouble.
Don't worry. I know you can do it.
Get back to work.
Phraeo might see us.
Give me a smile first.
-Please.
-No.
[chuckles softly]
Happy?
You're so cute.
Go.
Jack!
[water running]
[sighs]
[intense music playing]
[eerie music playing]
[woman screams in distance]
What was that?
I'll go check.
[thrilling music playing]
[banging]
Jack?
[eerie music playing]
Where's my cell phone?
[party MC]
Now, let me tell you
about the festive atmosphere over here.
The place is crowded.
I have to speak very loudly
because it's just so noisy here.
I have to shout just to be heard.
There's barely any place to stand.
There are locals and tourists here,
so many people,
and everyone is excited.
The countdown is going to start
in just a few minutes...
[MC continues, indistinct]
[eerie music playing]
-[intense music plays]
-[gasps]
I'm sorry, Miss Kaem.
You scared the hell out of me.
Miss Kaem,
did you need something?
Right. Have you seen Jack?
Jack?
Jack? Jack?
Jack,
the intern.
I haven't seen anyone.
What do you mean?
Well,
I've been sitting here
and haven't seen anyone come down.
What about Phraeo, the female intern?
No.
If she came down, she couldn't
have left the building anyway
because I have the keys and the keycard.
[sighs]
THIEF
[eerie music playing]
[Kaem gasps]
[elevator door closing]
[thuds]
[eerie music playing]
[sighs]
What are you doing, Jack?
[Kaem screams]
[breathing heavily]
[intense music plays]
[footsteps approaching]
[gasps]
[intense music plays]
[busy signal]
[Kaem yelps]
[thrilling music playing]
[music stops]
[music continues]
-[elevator dings]
-[Kaem screams]
[thrilling music continues]
[screams]
[elevator dings]
[Kaem crying]
Help me!
Help!
[sobbing] Help me!
[crying] Help!
[MC continues]
[panting]
[mysterious music playing]
[elevator dings]
[door creaking]
[muffled sobbing]
[breath trembling]
[gasps]
[eerie music playing]
[Kaem screams]
-[intense music plays]
-[gasping]
[crying]
[thrilling music playing]
[crying hysterically]
[Kaem screams]
[screams]
[thudding]
Help me!
Help!
Somebody help me!
[sobbing]
[breathing heavily]
Help me!
Help!
[clanking]
[intense music plays]
[door creaking]
[sighs]
[sobs quietly]
[sobs]
[door creaks]
[breathing heavily]
[elevator dings]
[screaming]
[Kaem grunts]
[exclaims]
[thrilling music playing]
[Kaem crying]
[shouting] Stop!
Don't come any closer!
[Kaem crying]
One more step and I'll shoot you!
Don't come any closer!
[stapler clicking]
[screaming]
[thrilling music playing]
[crying hysterically]
Please don't kill me.
[panting]
Phraeo?
Is that you?
[screams]
[intense music playing]
[screaming]
[Kaem crying]
[sighs]
Phraeo, you can come out now.
[panting]
Thank you, Jack.
Let's finish off the slut.
What do you want from me?
"If you can't get in touch with Miss Fon,
find yourself a new internship."
Fuck you! You killed our father!
[intense music plays]
I didn't kill him.
You know, Phraeo,
I'd only been working here for four days,
and she had sex with me in the bathroom.
Fucking slut.
You know, Kaem,
we used to spend New Year's Eve
with our father.
After you intervened,
my life was ruined.
You had an affair with him.
You used him and worked him to death.
You seduced him
and pressured him to break up
with my mother.
How could you do that?
[yelling] Didn't your parents
ever teach you
not to steal someone's husband?
-[intense music playing]
-Father?
Are you siblings?
Yeah.
[crying] Jack... Jack...
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Please don't kill me.
I'm begging you. Please.
[Kaem crying]
[Kaem shuddering]
[Kaem sobs]
[Jack shushes]
Give me a smile.
[sobbing]
[grunts]
[Jack] Let's send her to hell.
[crying]
[Kaem sobs]
It's five minutes to midnight.
Do it.
No, Phraeo.
-[Phraeo grunts]
-[Kaem screams]
[Kaem crying]
[heart beating]
-[Kaem grunts]
-[thudding]
[thrilling music playing]
[elevator dings]
[panting]
Help me.
[crying]
[MC talking indistinctly]
[MC continues]
[Kaem crying]
[MC] It's almost time
for the countdown!
[sobbing]
[Kaem sobbing]
[beeps]
[Kaem crying]
[sobs]
[beeps]
[door creaking]
[elevator dings]
[MC] All right,
let's start the countdown!
-Ten!
-Somebody help me!
-Nine!
-Help!
-Eight! Seven!
-Help me!
-Six! Five!
-Help!
-Four! Three!
-Help me!
-Two! One!
-[shouting] Help!
-Happy New Year!
Happy New Year, everyone!
[ax slicing]
[eerie music playing]
[intense music plays]
[man] Welcome back to the show!
Our next story
is a horror story about a movie theater.
Are you curious now?
Let's talk to Miss Phraeo.
-This is her story. Hello, Phraeo.
-[Phraeo] Hi, Puk.
[Puk] All right, Phraeo,
please tell us your story.
[Phraeo] Okay.
First, let me tell you that,
before it became a movie theater,
the building used to be a Hindu temple.
It was later made into a movie theater.
So it seems to have some demonic powers.
It originally had five theaters,
which they cut down to four.
But the fifth one
still shows films all day and night
without an audience.
[eerie music playing]
[knife slashing]
[Puk] Has anyone ever taken a peek
or snuck into
this fifth theater?
Is there someone
or something inside?
[Phraeo chuckles] No one dares.
The staff unanimously decided
that we shouldn't go in there,
so it's strictly prohibited,
or else...
[tsks]
[girl] Hey!
[Phraeo] Nun, stop it.
Stop kidding around.
You're so lame.
Hey! Hey!
Come out.
Nun?
[eerie music playing]
Phraeo.
Working a night shift alone?
Yes.
My friend
asked me to switch shifts with her.
She's scared of ghosts, so--
Nonsense.
There are no ghosts here.
I'm okay though.
I can work the night shift.
I'm not superstitious.
It's not an issue.
You should go home.
It's getting late. It might be dangerous.
[mysterious music playing]
-But I haven't finished--
-Do it tomorrow!
Yes, ma'am.
[intense music playing]
[electronic music playing]
♪ What a handsome, cool guy ♪
♪ What a sexy guy ♪
♪ Yo! Give your heart to me ♪
♪ Come on ♪
[phone dinging]
Shit!
He doesn't look like his profile pic.
[beeping]
Ek!
Are you Oi?
-Yes. You're Ek, right?
-Yes.
I was waiting on the first floor.
I didn't know that
you were waiting up here,
and I didn't recognize you.
The movie is about to start,
so I thought I'd wait here.
You didn't answer your phone,
so I thought you'd stood me up.
I wouldn't do that.
My phone battery was low,
so I came here
to find a place to charge it.
I didn't even know that you would be here.
Oh! You're very pretty.
-Even more beautiful in person.
-Aw.
I've never been on a date
with a beautiful girl.
I'm nervous.
That's so nice of you.
What a sweet talker.
You're a real charmer.
How many girls have you met
through the app?
I just started using it recently.
I don't believe you.
You did a very good job
of editing your photo.
But I think
you look way better in person.
Oh! It's all about the camera angle.
♪ Yo, yo ♪
♪ Give me your heart ♪
♪ You won't be disappointed
I'm begging you ♪
♪ Have mercy on me
Come on, come on ♪
♪ Like me
♪ Love me
Come on, come on, be with me ♪
♪ I'm a good guy
I'm the one ♪
-♪ Who will always love you ♪
-[record scratch]
[eerie music playing]
[man, in movie]
I feel like every time I'm near her,
I'm so happy.
But I'm not sure if she's happy.
My heart pounds whenever I'm near her.
It pounds harder
and harder every moment.
[heart beating]
-[Oi] Let's go!
-[Ek] Where are you taking me?
[operatic music playing]
[Oi] Have you heard that
those who go into this theater
never come out?
OUT OF SERVICE
Now here we are...
right in front of it.
You want to go inside?
Why not? Are you afraid of ghosts?
No, the security guard.
If you don't come in,
you'll miss out on something fun.
I think...
it's going to be
fun in here.
It turns me on. I like it.
[clicks]
[intense music playing]
Hey! Since you're so nervous,
want me to start?
Wait! Wait!
What is it?
Please go easy on me. It's my first time.
Wait! You've never had sex before?
[inaudible]
Are you sure?
[intense music plays]
Hey!
There's someone behind us.
What? Really?
Yeah. I don't know who it is.
Who?
[breathing heavily]
[eerie music playing]
Someone's there.
I saw her with my own eyes.
An older woman.
She seems low class.
They let people come into this theater?
This one shows films all day.
If we can come in, anyone can.
And now...
[tsking]
...they might see me. I'm naked.
Where's my shirt?
-[intense music plays]
-What's wrong?
[Ek panting]
What's wrong?
-[Ek panting continues]
-You startled me!
Can we get out of here?
Are you crazy? I don't have my shirt on.
I can't go out like this.
Use your brain.
Is this the movie
we were just watching?
[intense music playing]
[Ek exclaiming]
What are you doing?
You want me to put this on?
Okay, whatever you want.
[Oi exclaiming in annoyance]
Hey! Wait!
Hey! It's not quite on yet. Take it easy!
Hey! Hey!
Hey!
What the hell are you doing?
Look at me!
[both breathing heavily]
Where's my cell phone?
I think we should call the staff.
Ask them to help us find it.
No! I want it now.
It's my dad's phone.
Could you get it for me?
What? Why don't you go in yourself?
Man up, will you?
Just go in there and get it for me.
You're such a...
Ek.
Please.
Please go get my cell phone for me,
and then we can go to my place.
Seriously?
We can continue this at your place?
Why not?
Please.
Go get it for me.
It won't take long. Please.
Please.
Jerk!
So annoying!
[eerie music playing]
[intense music plays]
[intense music playing]
[Oi gasps]
[gasps]
[intense music playing]
[thrilling music playing]
[Oi yelling]
[Oi screams]
[screaming]
[woman laughing]
[woman laughing maniacally]
[laughing continues]
[Oi breathing heavily]
[music increases in tempo]
[breathing heavily]
[thuds]
[screaming]
[man laughing]
[footsteps approaching]
[door creaking]
[door clicks]
[intense music playing]
[breath trembling]
[woman] Miss? Miss?
Please.
Help me. I'm stuck in here.
[woman] Calm down.
Please help me. I'm stuck in here.
[woman] Miss,
it's okay.
He chose you.
[crying]
[intense music plays]
[shouting] What do you want from me?
What do you want?
Get out!
[thrilling music playing]
[screaming]
[electricity buzzing]
[crying]
[footsteps approaching]
[eerie music playing]
Excuse me.
Um, this theater is out of service.
My friend is in there.
She hasn't come out yet.
[eerie music playing]
Please wait.
I've already asked someone for help.
It won't be long. Please wait.
Don't you work here?
Can you go get her?
[woman] Absolutely not!
I mean,
please wait until the movie is over
to not disturb the other customers.
But that theater--
[intense music playing]
[breath trembling]
All right.
We should go in together.
Seriously though,
what's in there?
[Ek] This is Oi's shirt.
[eerie music playing]
[breathing heavily]
[intense music playing]
[Phraeo singing]
[tsks]
[girl] Hey!
[Phraeo] Nun, stop it!
Stop kidding around.
You're so lame.
[eerie music playing]
Wait! That's Oi's cell phone.
Where is she? Oi!
Hey!
[Ek mumbling]
[shushes]
A new movie is about to start.
We must leave.
[Ek muffled]
[guard] We have to leave now.
[eerie music playing]
Hey! Hey!
Come out!
Nun?
Hey! I'm trapped in here!
Help!
Hey!
[eerie music playing]
Can you hear me?
Help me!
[woman] Phraeo.
Working a night shift alone?
[Phraeo] Yes. My friend asked me
to switch shifts with her.
-[Oi] Hey!
-[Phraeo] She's scared of ghosts.
Nonsense.
There are no ghosts here.
Don't go!
Come back!
Hey! Don't go! Help!
Help me!
Hey!
[intense music playing]
[Oi] Help me!
[eerie music playing]
[screaming]
[ghosts laughing]
[Oi screaming]
[screaming]
[Phraeo] That's when I learned
that the theater used to be a Hindu temple
and that they were showing movies
as an offering.
When they turned it into movie theater,
it gained demonic powers.
Many things happened.
They lost money.
But the worst thing was that
people kept disappearing,
so the owner turned the fifth theater
into a shrine.
[thrilling music playing]
[gasps]
[screams]
[knife slashes]
[Phraeo] The dolls from the old shrine
were probably gone,
so the owner summoned the god
into a new doll.
[rock music playing]
-It's fucking hot.
-Yeah.
Come on.
-Lat Phrao, please.
-Sure, but that's three dollars extra.
Of course it is.
Everyone knows that.
Get in, city girl.
Put your bags in the back.
Let's take a selfie.
[camera shutter clicking]
Hey!
My fucking cell phone!
[heavy metal music playing]
Start. Okay.
Pretty.
[message dinging]
Hi, everyone!
I'm in Bangkok now.
Safe and sound.
If you know of any cool places to hang in,
please let me know.
I really feel like partying.
Oh!
If you want to order something,
please DM me.
If you need it soon,
I'll send it to you first,
but there'll be an extra charge.
If you're not in a rush,
wait until I get back home.
I won't charge you very much. Promise!
VIEWER:
WHY DOES SHE LOOK SO GRUMPY?
You ask her.
It's not my business.
Hey!
They're asking what's wrong with you.
Someone stole my cell phone.
Now I have to buy a new one.
It's hard to make money these days.
STOP BITCHING, HOOKER! IT'S JUST A PHONE.
But you're a millionaire!
It's none of your business!
I don't live off my parents like you!
You should fix your brain
instead of insulting me!
Use your brain, not your pussy!
You're probably using free Wi-Fi
at a café, trying to be a hipster.
Mind your own business!
Try making my kind of money,
then you can judge. Ugh!
Unfriend me! I don't care!
Don't judge other people!
You piece of shit!
Blathering moron! Dumbass!
You psycho!
You condescending shit! Asshole!
Got it?
Anyway, to the customers,
don't forget to buy!
And make sure you pay.
Or I'll block you all!
-Bee.
-Hmm?
Could you cut? I'm upset.
But it's my live video.
You don't have to say anything.
I'll just chat with my followers, okay?
Anyway, so--
[beeps]
[dog barks distantly]
[dog howls]
FOR RENT
PAY AFTER YOUR STAY
"Pay after your stay"?
You bitch!
Where's my deposit?
I used it to buy lottery tickets.
I got some lucky numbers from the mediums,
and then I dreamed about the numbers,
but I haven't won anything yet.
I'll pay you back if I win. Okay?
Bitch!
It better be soon!
You said you told them to clean it.
I did, but I guess they didn't do it.
It's not my fault.
Help me find the TV remote.
Shorty!
Before watching TV,
shouldn't we clean the place first?
[huffs]
Why is she so angry?
[coughing]
[birds chirping]
What a lame picture.
Look at those kids.
They don't even look alike.
They probably had different fathers.
Or maybe the old hag is his second wife.
You have such a foul mouth.
Let's take a selfie.
[mysterious music playing]
[beeping]
Guess they want a selfie, too.
Yeah, right.
You wish!
[camera shutter clicks]
[intense music playing]
HOUSE OF HORRORS
5 PEOPLE MURDERED - LAT PHRAO
Look.
This is creepy.
That's good.
We can use this haunted thing
as an excuse to leave here early,
so we don't have to pay the rent.
Perfect.
-Are you serious?
-Yeah.
But if you're scared,
you can get rid of the picture.
No!
They'll charge us.
I don't want to waste money.
You're right.
You're getting smarter, shorty!
[mysterious music playing]
[eerie music playing]
[camera shutter clicks]
[beeps]
[dings]
Hi, everyone!
Today we're gonna do some yoga.
Are you ready?
First pose.
Right.
Second pose.
Like this.
[intense music playing]
[messages dinging]
WHERE DID YOU GET THAT SHIRT? SO SEXY.
All right, now we're gonna do
some stretching.
Like this.
[sighs]
That's not gonna make you taller, shorty.
I'm going to buy a new cell phone.
Let's continue!
[intense music playing]
Oh.
Just a second.
[Shorty sniffling]
[sniffling]
Very luxurious...
and really fucking expensive.
Whatever!
I have to have it.
It'll make me look classy.
I don't want to look cheap.
[phone beeps]
Why did you bring this?
You're so superstitious.
-Shorty!
-[sniffles]
[sniffling]
Shorty!
What's wrong?
Who hurt you?
Tell me!
-I'll make him pay.
-[sniffles]
Tell me!
[sighs]
I'm reading about what happened here.
I feel so bad for them.
The father killed the whole family,
then he killed himself.
[exclaiming scornfully]
Don't trust the Internet!
It's all bullshit.
[phone dinging]
[phone beeps]
Time to make some money.
And you're going to help me.
[sniffling]
[moaning in pleasure]
[dance music playing]
[music stops]
[mysterious music playing]
[eerie music playing]
I want an omelet.
A crispy one.
With lots of fish sauce.
I like salty food.
[rhythmical creaking]
[eerie music playing]
[cell phone ringing]
Hello. Who is it?
[man laughing on phone]
Nat?
What is it?
[Nat] I miss you.
When can we meet?
[Nat laughing]
I want to see you.
I've just been busy lately.
I have to make money for university.
[thudding]
[intense music playing]
Fuck...
[banging]
Shut the fuck up!
I want to sleep!
So angry.
One second, Nat.
[eerie music playing]
Hello, Nat.
Yeah.
Well, I...
I've been having some problems.
I don't have any money for university.
If I don't pay on time,
I might have to drop out.
And if I do that,
I won't be able to graduate
at the same time as my friends.
[Nat] How can I help you?
[Nat laughing]
I wouldn't want to bother you.
We've only known each other
for a short time.
I couldn't let you do that.
[Nat] Just give me your account number.
I'll transfer you the money.
[Nat laughing]
Go on, tell me.
It's 6952024777,
Purple Bank, $1,000.
[Nat] I'm happy I can help you.
Thank you so much
for always helping me.
I don't know what to do.
Nat?
Nat? Hello?
[cell phone ringing]
[dings]
$1,000 TRANSFERRED TO YOUR BANK ACCOUNT
[Nat] Study hard and graduate soon.
I'm here for you.
Thank you so much.
Love you!
I'm going to bed now. Good night!
[Nat] I'm not sleepy.
Can you stay and talk to me?
I have to wake up early tomorrow.
I have to wake up at 4:00 a.m. for work.
[Nat] That's all right.
Tonight I'll dream about you.
Good night, Nat.
How did I get down here?
What? Where did this come from?
[creaking]
[intense music playing]
Holy Mother of God,
if I did something wrong,
please forgive me.
[intense music plays]
[sighs]
[creaking continues]
[intense music plays]
[music stops]
[breathing heavily]
[eerie music playing]
[gun clicks]
[gunshots]
[woman] Where are you?
You think you can get away from me?
Come out!
Where are you?
[intense music playing]
[door creaking]
[urinating]
[mysterious music playing]
Bee!
-Mmm?
-Wake up!
Shit! I'm sorry.
You're so disgusting, shorty!
Didn't your parents teach you better?
I'm scared.
Of what?
Ghosts! There are ghosts here.
Where are they?
[Bee] Where are you going?
[mysterious music playing]
[Ann] Come on!
I'm going to find one.
And if I don't find a ghost, you're dead.
-No! No!
-[Ann] Bee!
No!
[Bee whimpering]
[Ann] Come on!
-Come on!
-[Bee] No!
I don't want to.
No! No!
Bee, come on!
[Bee crying]
Ow!
Where are you?
Huh?
Show yourself!
-No!
-She wants to see you.
No, I don't!
Where are you?
Please stop.
Ann.
-Stop! I'm scared!
-Where are you?
Show yourself!
Don't show yourself!
Where is it? Look!
Did you see one?
-No!
-See it?
-Look!
[Bee crying]
-Come on!
-Please, stop!
-No, Ann!
-Come here!
Come on!
No!
-Come on!
-[crying]
-[intense music playing]
-Where's your ghost?
-Look!
-No!
It's there.
What?
Where?
I don't see anything.
Look!
It's there.
Where is it?
I don't see shit!
Fuck!
Look!
It's there.
The toilet is for urinating,
and the bed is for sleeping.
Come on!
No, I don't want to.
No! No! No!
No! No!
[thrilling music playing]
[Bee screaming] Open up!
Stay in there!
You need to learn your lesson.
[Bee sobbing] Let me out!
Open the door!
[breath trembling]
[sniffling]
-Bee!
-Yes?
Why didn't you turn off the TV?
You're paying the electric bill
this month.
I won't last a month.
I'm so screwed.
Why am I friends with a loser like you?
So annoying! I couldn't sleep.
Why did you turn it on?
I didn't. The remote is there.
[intense music plays]
Seriously?
[eerie music playing]
Okay.
The TV isn't even plugged in.
[Bee whimpers]
[Ann] Bee!
Why did you put the picture back?
Is this a prank?
I didn't.
[eerie music playing]
-[intense music playing]
-[both scream]
Come on! Run!
[both panting]
Help me!
[knocking at door]
[doorknob rattling]
[thumping on door]
What should we do?
[doorknob rattling]
-[thunder rumbling]
-Just like in a horror movie.
What should we do?
[both scream]
[thunder crashing]
[breathing heavily]
What should we do?
I don't know.
You're smarter than me. Think!
You're the superstitious one,
you think!
What?
[intense music playing]
Hurry up!
[Bee] One second! Don't pull at me!
Okay!
What is it?
A charm.
Are you crazy? You want to charm them?
[intense music playing]
[Bee] Don't pressure me!
Okay! Here it is!
-[Ann] What is it?
-A charisma amulet.
You want to be popular with ghosts?
Idiot! Throw it away!
[thrilling music playing]
[yelling] Hold on! Hold on!
This is it! This is it! There you go!
A talisman.
That's good.
We're okay now.
It's a talisman.
The most sacred one.
My ex gave it to me.
[exclaiming]
[thrilling music playing]
What about the Buddha image?
Hold on!
Hurry up!
Here!
[music stops]
Birth control.
[Ann] Which one?
The morning-after pill.
[both laughing]
They're afraid of that?
I guess.
We're safe now.
How is that possible?
[cat meowing]
[intense music playing]
-[Bee screaming]
-Bee!
-[Ann] Bee!
Get out!
How?
You locked the front door.
[intense music playing]
-Ann...
-[retching]
[Ann retching]
Ann!
[intense music playing]
You nasty bitch!
I'm sorry.
I won't do anything bad ever again.
If I'd known this place was haunted,
I wouldn't have come here.
[intense music playing]
You brat!
You're a bad influence on my daughter.
I don't know your daughter.
Stupid ghost!
Filthy mouth!
Watch what you say!
What's your name?
Kaeo.
All right, Kaeo.
Now I know your name!
You brat! Piece of shit!
You think I'm afraid of you?
Idiot! Asshole!
You haunt people.
Even hell doesn't want you!
So your whole family is stuck here.
I guess no one prays for you.
Pathetic!
You bitch!
Show some respect!
Stop your whoring!
Study hard!
Stop being a bad influence on my daughter!
Don't call her "shorty."
I don't like it!
[groans]
You moron!
I'm not afraid of that pill!
Don't you get it?
I tricked you.
[thrilling music playing]
Get off me!
Get off!
[Ann running]
[Anne] Fuck!
[Ann crashing]
[thudding]
Ann!
Ann?
[birds chirping]
[woman 1] It's downtown
and very convenient.
The rent is quite cheap, too.
[woman 2] Here's a deposit.
[man] Do you like the color?
Please excuse me.
-Okay.
-Yes.
[Bee sighs]
Mom,
I transfer the merit to you.
Ann,
be good to my mom.
She's fierce.
Otherwise she might kill you again.
I have to go now.
Bye.
[cell phone ringing]
[beeps]
Hi, Uncle.
Everything is okay.
They signed the contract.
Okay. Talk to you later.
[beeps]
I have to go now.
Okay.
-Bye.
-Let's look around.
-Go ahead!
The lamp is still new.
[hip-hop music playing]
♪ You might get played ♪
♪ So be careful ♪
♪ Either you or me ♪
[in English]
♪ Hello, BKK ♪
♪ You will not notice
Next thing you know ♪
♪ It might be too late ♪
♪ Yo, Bangkok, Bangkok
My city is not shitty ♪
♪ Bangkok, Bangkok
So many good things I wanna share ♪
My city is not shitty ♪
♪ Bangkok, Bangkok
So many good things I wanna share ♪
♪ No real friends here ♪
♪ Fuck society
Only care for rich people ♪
♪ Using fake photos ♪
♪ Because you don't wanna be a loser
Make yourself look better ♪
♪ So you might get lucky
Yes, yes ♪
♪ Yo, yo, yo, yo ♪
♪ Bangkok, Bangkok
My city is not shitty ♪
So many good things I wanna share ♪
♪ There are no thugs here
Taxi drivers are good ♪
♪ They only use the meter
And will go anywhere you want ♪
♪ Hey, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ Hey, that's right
Yo, yo ♪
♪ Bangkok, Bangkok
We are real ♪
♪ Fake tour, fake company
The ticket you buy is fake ♪
♪ We had an election
But the results aren't out yet ♪
♪ We have an election commission
But no results yet ♪
♪ You might get played ♪
♪ So be careful
Either you or me ♪
♪ You will not notice ♪
♪ Next thing you know ♪
♪ It might be too late ♪
♪ Bangkok, Bangkok
My city is not shitty ♪
So many good things I wanna share ♪
♪ Bangkok, Bangkok
My city is not shitty ♪
So many good things I wanna share ♪
♪ Fake lottery, full of shit ♪
♪ Be careful when in Bangkok
You might get a dick, not a pussy ♪
♪ Your profile pic is fake
Using it to get money from me ♪
♪ Even your YouTube view count is fake
Why do you mess with me? ♪
♪ You might get played ♪
♪ So be careful
Either you or me ♪
♪ You will not notice ♪
♪ Next thing you know
It might be too late ♪
♪ You might get played ♪
♪ So be careful
Either you or me ♪
♪ You will not notice ♪
♪ Next thing you know
It might be too late ♪
♪ Bangkok, Bangkok
My city is not shitty ♪
So many good things I wanna share ♪
♪ Bangkok, Bangkok
My city is not shitty ♪
So many good things I wanna share ♪
♪ No real friends here
Fuck society ♪
♪ Only care for rich people
Using fake photos ♪
♪ Because you don't wanna be a loser
Make yourself look better ♪
♪ So you might get lucky
Yes, yes ♪
♪ Yo, yo, yo, yo ♪
♪ Bangkok, Bangkok
My city is not shitty ♪
So many good things I wanna share ♪
♪ There are no thugs here
Taxi drivers are good ♪
♪ They only use the meter
And will go anywhere you want ♪
♪ Hey, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ Hey, that's right ♪
♪ Bangkok, Bangkok
We are real ♪
♪ Fake tour, fake company
The ticket you buy is fake ♪
♪ We had an election
But the results aren't out yet ♪
♪ We have an election commission
But no results yet ♪
♪ You might get played ♪
♪ So be careful
Either you or me ♪
♪ You will not notice ♪
♪ Next thing you know
It might be too late ♪
♪ Bangkok, Bangkok
My city is not shitty ♪
So many good things I wanna share ♪
♪ Bangkok, Bangkok
My city is not shitty ♪
So many good things I wanna share ♪
♪ Fake lottery, full of shit ♪
♪ Be careful when in Bangkok
You might get a dick, not a pussy ♪
♪ Your profile pic is fake
Using it to get money from me ♪
♪ Even your YouTube view count is fake
Why do you mess with me? ♪
♪ You might get played ♪
♪ So be careful
Either you or me ♪
♪ You will not notice ♪
♪ Next thing you know
It might be too late ♪
♪ You might get played ♪
♪ So be careful
Either you or me ♪
♪ You will not notice ♪
♪ Next thing you know
It might be too late ♪
♪ Hey, yeah, yeah ♪
[music ends]