US Marshall Service.
Patch me to the
Marshall, Hugh Tanley.
What's this regarding?
Tell him it's Billy Burke.
Billy?
Tanley.
What's going on?
I wanna move.
Move, move where?
Anywhere.
Have you talked to her?
You can't just take the
kids and disappear, Bill.
What not?
'Cause you can't.
I wanna start over.
You did it before,
you can do it again.
It doesn't work like that.
Then explain exactly
how it's suppose to fucking work
'cause as far as I can
tell all you people do
is yank a guy out of his life
and toss him in
the fucking barrel.
Calm down.
Don't tell me
to fucking calm down.
Where would you be
if you back in Boston, huh?
The river, the ground,
or stuffed in snowbank
with your teeth knocked out
and a slug in your temple?
We saved you, Bill.
Just keep your head
down and live your life.
You're not Billy Burke any more.
You gonna pay for that?
Just dock it.
Dock it from what?
You're two hours late.
I had to stay after school.
Fuck.
Hey.
The school has obligation
to look into any
accusations of this nature.
What exactly
is he being accused of?
I'm sure you're aware
of the incident that
occurred last week?
What does that have
to do with Darren?
Several students came forward
and said that he was
the one responsible
for providing the narcotics.
That's ridiculous.
- Miss Greenwood...
- Darren's a
straight A student.
Miss Greenwood, I understand...
And who the hell are these
students you're talking about?
I can't give you that infor...
What makes their word
better than my sons?
Maybe you ought
to look into them,
instead of the kids they're
trying to dump all the blame on.
I don't believe that's the
situation here, Miss Greenwood.
Based on what?
Based on Darren's behavior.
He's been absent 22 days in
the last 40 days of school.
His grades are plummeting,
he flunking three subjects,
he's hanging around with
a different group of kids.
Why hasn't anyone
contacted me about this?
We did, I have a, I have
a signed progress report
from two weeks ago
from both of you.
Who do you think you are?
I scribbled a name on
a piece of paper, Carol.
Why?
To avoid this.
Avoid what?
You losing your fucking
mind over nothing at all.
He's a kid, kid's fuck up.
He doesn't need to hear from
you when you're like this.
Did you even hear
what was said in there?
Two kids died, Mitch.
They were on pills
for Christ sake.
They was friends.
And now they're dead.
Darren will be next if
we don't do something.
Do what, Carol?
What the fuck do you wanna do?
You wanna ignore
this whole thing,
act like it didn't happen?
That's right.
You're pathetic.
Two of his friends just died,
whether he sold them
the pills or not.
You think now is the
time to talk about this?
If he was your son,
we wouldn't be having
this conversation.
When you're finished with that,
start stocking the shelves.
I got to go pick up your brother.
What can I get ya?
Pack of reds.
Billy.
Yeah, on the the corner.
Be right there.
You got your mother
in a panic, you know?
I should charge you gas money
for all the driving around
I just did looking for ya.
What are we doin' here, Darren?
Waiting for a train.
Where you goin'?
Nowhere.
Then what are we waitin' for?
How long you been here?
Since the store closed.
I don't know, but I
think a couple of trains
have come by since then.
Don't be a dick.
I'm just saying.
I tried all right?
Throwing yourself
in front of a train
ain't something you
try and fail at.
You either do it or you don't.
I'm gonna do it.
All right.
You can't stop me.
Fine.
Wanna talk about it?
It ain't your fault,
you know that right?
Those kids were gonna do
whatever they were gonna do
whether you helped them or not.
It happens.
No it doesn't.
Well it did.
A lot of people
done plenty worse.
Yeah, like who?
It'll go away, you just
got to get it out of your head.
You think it's that easy?
What's the worse thing
you've ever done to somebody?
If it was anything like this,
you'd know this
isn't going away.
Come on, let's get outta here.
You gettin' hungry?
Nah, I'm good.
Got a coupon for
a pizza in here.
I was thinking
'bout grabbing one.
If you get it, I'll eat it,
but not really that hungry.
What did you get your
mother for Christmas?
Nothing yet.
Better get on that.
I don't know what to get her.
Well, you better
get her something,
she's you're mother
for Christ's sake.
What did you get her?
Nothing yet.
So what are you giving
me a hard time for?
I'm just her husband,
you're her suppose
to be on top of
that kind of stuff.
Well, I don't
know what she wants.
Got any ideas?
I was kinda hoping
you had something.
Well, maybe we'll get
her a gift together,
but it's got to be a good one
or she think we got lazy and
screwed her out of her present.
Isn't that what's happening?
Not if it's a good one.
How 'bout we get
her a gift card?
No, we can't get
her a gift card.
If we get her a gift card, we
might as well get her cash.
Get her cash, we might as
well get her nothing at all.
How 'bout one of those
elliptical machines
she's been talking about?
No, she'll make me use it.
You know what?
We can get her one of
those, one of those vacuums
that cleans the floor by itself.
Those exist?
Yeah, they got 'em
at the department store
down the road.
What time they open til?
Bout another half hour.
It's a good idea, why don't
you run up there and grab one.
And when you're done,
swing by and pick me up.
You sure?
Mom hasn't been letting me
drive the past couple weeks.
No, I trust you.
Just pick me up
when you're done.
Thanks dad.
What can I get for you?
Newports.
Anything else?
Ten thousand.
Ten?
On average.
But that varies depending
on the particulars.
What particulars
you talking about?
Well, the casket, for instance.
An average casket,
it'll set you back
about two and half grand,
but that price fluctuates
depending on the quality
of the specific casket
that you chose.
How much for that one?
That one's around four or 5,000.
I only got two.
For the casket?
For everything.
Have
you thought about cremation?
No, no.
Well, if you'd like I could...
I'm not burning my mother.
She's gettin' buried.
I understand
where you're coming
from, but cremation...
It's not an option.
She wants to be
buried, not burned.
That'll
be impossible with only 2,000.
Look, I can give
you a couple of days
to figure something out,
maybe ask a relative
if they mind pitching in,
but these are the prices
you're gonna find everywhere.
I'm sorry.
Hey, Nicole.
Derek.
What are you doing here?
I'm sorry, I didn't
wanna just show up,
but you were suppose to
call after your appoint.
What's up?
Hi.
What's all that?
I, I got it for you
because of the doctor.
Could we talk in the
other room for a minute?
You can't just show up
without calling, Derek.
I've been calling all day.
Well, my phone's been dead.
Well, how am I
suppose to know that?
You gonna tell
me what's going on?
I have no idea what's going on.
That's why I'm here.
I mean how did it go?
How did what go?
You know the,
the test.
What, what's wrong?
Nothing, it... I'm fine.
Fine, what's that
mean, what's fine?
I mean, I mean they
didn't find anything.
That's, that's great.
So?
So, they didn't find anything,
where's that leave us?
What do you mean?
I mean, are we getting
back together or?
You said you only
wanted to break up
because you might have cancer.
You said you didn't
want me to be the guy
with a sick girlfriend
and you needed some time.
I know what I said.
So, are we back together?
I don't, I don't get it.
Um, you said you only
wanted to break up
because of the cancer.
It ain't gonna get any easier.
Eddie.
You look like shit.
Gee, thanks.
I'm just saying.
Yeah, well, you're no
fucking prize either pal.
Where the hell you get a dog?
She's my mother's.
How's that goin'
with your mother?
That's why I called.
Yeah, I figured.
So you got something or what?
Yeah, I got something.
Any good?
Could be.
A shot in the dark, though.
Oh.
Well, if we get
done, it's 15 a pop,
but I ain't sure
I like what it is.
15 a piece?
Is it coming from Lou?
I think so, but I
didn't talk to him.
I talked to a Jackknife.
Oh, well let me know.
You ever heard of Billy Burke?
He used to run around
with Bobby Green.
Pulled a couple of
scores back in the day.
Billy Burke used
to own that store
on Seymour Street when
we were kids, right?
That's the one.
I remember him, what
ever happened to him?
Fucking rat.
About eight years ago
they found his brother
stuffed in a snowbank
down on the waterfront.
Billy flipped with the feds
and vanished not long after.
What are you saying?
Got a couple of friends of
ours put away for a while.
You been a, been watching
the news last couple weeks?
A little bit.
You hear about that body they
found up in New Hampshire?
A couple of weeks ago
some old bombs got dropped
outside a Sheriff's station,
a middle east bonfire.
Yeah?
Yeah.
So what?
So they ID-ed the body
day before yesterday.
Gordon Belkin.
Gordon Belkin?
How?
Someone dug him up.
What the purpose
somebody dig him up?
I don't know, but Jackknife
says only two people
knew where Belkin's
body was buried.
Bobby was one of them,
everybody knows that.
Yeah, but Bobby's got
another year left at Walpole,
so they don't know
it wasn't him.
Who's the other person?
Billy Burke.
Burke's in New Hampshire?
Right in the middle
of East Bumfuck.
And you wanna go get him?
15 a pop.
You're a retarded
motherfucker, ain't ya?
I hope not.
I'm just out here and
listen to you ramble
for five minutes and that's
all you came to tell me, man?
Yeah.
I need eight grand by the
end of this week, Derek.
So what the fuck are
we doing standing around
and talking about it?
Let's go get him.
He's a wuss sack,
you fucking dumb ass.
He's got a new name,
he's got a new life.
We don't even know if
he's inside the town
or inside the state.
There's only one
way to find out.
What the fuck you waste
my time with this for, man?
I got to get out of here, man.
A weekend away sound good
and 15K sounds better.
I need a sure thing.
Well you don't have one.
What else you got?
Ma?
What are you doing here?
Ma.
That sounds like Lake Ossipee?
Think it did.
I went to camp up
there one summer.
Lake Ossipee.
They used to have this program
where they'd round
up all the kids
running around the projects
and ship 'em up
north for two weeks.
I thought I remember
you being there.
The older kids were
fucking pricks.
I remember they used to,
they used to take
these tube socks
and fill 'em up with baby powder
and whip us with 'em.
Felt like getting hit
with a fucking rock.
Got these white marks
all over you clothes.
I remember this one night,
I was sittin' in the cabin
with some older kids.
I don't know what I
was doin' in there,
'cause I wasn't hangin'
out with any of them,
but any way, I'm
sittin' in there
and I hear 'em all talking
and they're talking about how
they're gonna wail til we
all fall asleep that night
and then they're gonna run in
and beat the shit out of
us with those powder socks.
So I hear that and I
think not me, right?
But I don't know what to do
because there are six of them
and there's one of me and I
don't want to get my ass kicked,
so what I ended up
doing was, I stood up
and I walked right through
the their little powwow.
You know, just get
their attention, right?
Then I go over into
the corner of the room
and I grab this, there was
a wooden broom stick there.
I kicked it and snapped
it right in half.
Look at the sharp
end for a second.
Then I go over to the
other side of the room
and I got a, there was a metal
folding chair laying there,
so I grabbed the
piece of the metal
and I twisted and twisted
and snapped it off.
It was a little metal pipe,
I tucked in my sleeve.
So then I go back over
and I sit down with them.
I got the broken
broomstick in one hand,
the metal pipe up my sleeve.
I look 'em all square
in the face and I say,
if any of you come
near me tonight
I'll stab you in
the fucking chest.
They didn't bother
me after that.
You sure you weren't
up there with us?
No.
Probably would of liked it.
I remember my a, had my
first girlfriend up there.
Leah Donahue.
She's from Dorchester.
We used to go tubing
out on the lake.
What's wrong with you?
What you mean?
I mean you been
staring out the window
for the last half hour.
Aren't that windows are for?
Really?
You gonna be like that?
You don't wanna
talk that's fine.
It's just a long fucking drive
for me to be sittin' here
talking to myself the whole way.
Do you ever think
about eternity?
What?
You know like,
what happens after you die.
What are you talkin' about?
I just told you.
Yeah, but.
Wonder if this is it?
No heaven, no hell.
Just this.
And nothing and then we're sad.
There's nothing.
I been trying to wrap
my head around this.
Was just suffocating.
Just shut the fuck up
and stare out your window.
Derek.
Where'd you put it?
Threw it out.
Where?
Well, it ain't in that dumpster.
You ain't gonna
find it in there.
Get a hold of yourself.
There was $300 worth
of booze in the cooler.
Oh yeah?
Look like the good stuff.
You think this is funny?
No, I don't.
You owe me $300.
Oh yeah?
Yeah.
Well, you owe me
two hours it took me
to find your drunk ass passed
out on the fucking dock.
And then you owe me
another half hour
it took me to drag
your drunk ass
back to this fucking frozen car
that you left me in.
And then it took me two hours
to walk to the nearest
fucking gas station
and it took me two
hours to walk back.
Are we done?
Yeah, I get the gist.
We're almost in.
Can't stay here.
Why not?
Fucking GI Joe in there
says no dogs allowed.
I already checked
three other motels
and they all said the same shit.
You serious?
Let's think of something later.
Can't afford to waste
no more time up here.
Where you going?
I'm gonna talk to him.
Told you he was an asshole.
There's a Bed and
Breakfast up the road.
It's the only place in
town that allows dogs.
Where'd you hear that?
The guy just told me.
The guy in there?
Yeah, who else?
Well how'd you get
him to tell you that?
I asked him.
You don't think I asked him?
Yeah, well you tend to be
a little fucking
abrasive sometimes.
You should try
listening to people.
See how it suits ya.
What's the breakfast look like?
Here is dog.
Maybe God sent that.
No, I'm all right.
All right.
Tell me if you
want anything else.
So what's next?
Huh?
What are we doin'?
Where we goin', how we
finding Billy Burke?
None of that, settle down,
you're giving me a headache.
Derek, I didn't come
here to no fucking cereal
in the bum's backyard.
What's the plan?
We're gonna make a plan.
That's what we're doin',
we're brainstorming.
Brainstorming?
- Yeah, brainstorming.
- Brainstorming?
I'm gonna drown this hangover.
We're gonna eat our breakfast
and we're gonna
come up with a plan.
Right now, together.
So shut up and eat your cereal.
It's soggy.
Well that's no good.
All right, so we're up here.
Now what?
We find Burke.
Good.
How?
Well we start by
leaving this shit hole
and start looking for him.
All right, you wanna
wing it, we'll wing it.
I figured you'd
wanna make a plan
since you're the one
sitting here bitching
about breakfast and everything.
You thought I want some
god damn cold cereal, Derek?
I mean fucking I didn't
think it was that bad.
Quit wasting time, let's go.
Do you remember
what he looks like?
I think I'd know
him if I seen him.
And I won't.
I'm gonna poke around a bit.
All right.
Excuse me, can I
get a beer, please?
Thank you.
How much?
Mind if I sit?
I'm not gonna be here long.
Yeah, me ah, me either.
I'm only in town
for a day or two.
Hmm, that's so?
Mm-hmm.
What brings you into town?
Just checking out the spots.
I like this one.
In this spot?
What's to like?
I don't know.
Something about it.
Basically, there's just a
bunch of bars around here.
There's a bowling
alley down the road,
but that's about it.
Bowling alley,
which way do I head?
Like down that way.
That way.
Take a left, you can't miss it.
I'll ah, I'll have
to check it out.
Derek.
He ain't here.
It was nice talking to you, uh?
Shannon.
Nice talking to you, Shannon.
I didn't order anything.
We should head back to that bar.
No sense in waste those clothes.
I'll drive if you want.
Why you ask me to
come up here, man?
Huh?
You heard what I said.
You need the money,
I'm looking out for you.
You ain't looking out for me.
If you came up
here to find Burke,
you wouldn't have spent the
last 36 hours fucking around.
I only got two more
to find the money.
I told you from the beginning.
I said it's a long shot.
You knew I had no choice.
Tell you what, I'm only
here for one more day,
then I'm going back home.
How you gonna find the money
if you're back in Boston?
It doesn't matter.
At least I won't be
here wasting my time.
All right.
Here's what's gonna happen.
I'm going out tonight
and when I come back,
I'm gonna have a plan.
Once I have that plan,
we're gonna make you that money.
All right?
Trust me, I got this.
Jesus.
That's a lot of chicken.
Yeah well, I figure
if I don't eat 'em,
then they died for
nothing, right?
Yeah, maybe.
You want some?
No, sir, man.
You sure?
I ain't gonna eat
'em, so might as well.
No, really, thank you, man.
You wanna a beer?
Eh, no, I really shouldn't.
You shouldn't, why not?
Heh, my fiance
got me on this diet.
It's torture, man.
I've been eating
salad and smoothie
for the past month and a half.
Just here for the game.
What kind of diet?
One of those low-calorie diets?
Low-calorie, low-carb, no fun.
All right, I got you, man.
Hey, can I get
some vodka down here?
Low-calorie.
So then I look them
all square in the face
and I say, if any of you
come near me tonight,
I'll stab you in
the fucking chest.
And they believed you?
Yeah, I meant it.
Can't let 'em walk all
over you like that.
Sometimes you got to
break a broomstick
and act like a fucking nut case.
All right, tough guy.
Last call, gentlemen.
All right, I'm gonna
head to the bathroom.
I'll alert the media.
What's that?
This?
It's beer.
Where's mine?
Yours?
Gotta order one.
I got to order one?
Yeah.
That's how it works, isn't it?
You order a beer,
they give you one.
That's funny 'cause the,
the last four times I ordered
a shot, they gave me two.
Pretty sure they charged me
for each of them as well.
Every time I ordered two
shots and paid for two shots,
I slid on of them
in your direction.
Yeah.
Thanks.
No problem, what
I'm gettin' at is
I bought you four
shots just now.
I heard what you said.
Good, then you see how this
seems a little fucking rude.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
You think this is right?
I duck out for two
seconds, I come back
and you bought yourself a
drink and didn't get me one.
I didn't ask you to
buy me four drinks, bro.
You didn't have to ask, bro.
That's what I'm talking about.
Do you want a drink?
I'll buy you a drink.
Don't talk to me like I'm
begging you for something.
It's common fucking courtesy.
All right, all
right, sweetheart.
You want a drink,
I'll buy you a drink.
So now you're gonna be a
fucking smart ass about it?
I'm just buying you a drink.
Isn't that what you wanted?
You know what?
I don't want your fucking drink.
Then what are you crying about?
This one's on me.
Drink it.
Thanks.
Don't thank me.
It's common fucking courtesy.
Fucking cheap ass, Derek.
Got me all the way out
here in these fucking woods
cleaning up all
this fucking beer
this motherfucker done drunk.
Fuck.
Hush.
Oh, shit.
Derek.
Sadie.
Sorry.
For what?
I don't know.
Well you gonna come and sit down
or are you just
gonna stand there?
You're pretty good at that.
I know.
So you always go around
pulling guns on people?
I wasn't gonna hurt him,
I was just gonna scare him.
He was being a prick.
Yeah, well he's
always been a prick.
We went to school together
when we were kids.
Oh yeah?
Yeah, his family owns the
only decent asian restaurant
in 60 miles though.
It's one of the ones that they
cook food in front of you.
It's a hibachi place?
Yeah, whatever it is, it's good.
I don't go there though.
His whole family is ass holes.
Yeah, I believe it.
This is little Shannon?
Mm-hmm.
That your dad with you?
This is his place?
It was.
Oh, sorry.
He's not dead, he's just sick.
Dementia, he's at an assisted
living place down the road.
Dementia, that's like uh,
that's like Alzheimers, right?
They're basically
the same thing,
but you can't be
diagnosed with Alzheimer
until after you're
dead, so until,
they say you have dementia.
Sorry to hear that.
It's okay.
So this is your place?
Mm-hmm.
I have the mortgage
bills to prove it.
That sucks.
Yeah, it does.
Cops get a decent
pension though, right?
That's got to help.
That doesn't even cover
his assisted living.
No?
What do you do to
pay for it all?
I'm a Dental Hygienist.
No you're not.
Yeah I am.
I knew there had to be
something wrong with you.
You have a problem
with dental hygienists?
It's not the, it's
the whole teeth thing,
showing my teeth
kinda freaks me out.
Oh my God, you're
one of those people.
What's that suppose to mean?
Nothing, I just think
you're a bit of a wimp.
I'm not a wimp,
but I just don't like
when people mess
around with my teeth.
What about the dentist?
You don't go to the dentist?
Never.
That's horrible, you should
be ashamed of yourself.
I brush my teeth
everyday, I'm not filthy.
I just like to do it on my own.
Open your mouth.
Why?
Just do it.
What are you gonna do to me?
Nothin'.
I don't trust you.
Come on, quit being a
pussy and open your mouth.
Looks fine.
That's it, I'm good to go?
Mm-hmm.
That's the dental
hygienist stamp of approval?
That's why they
pay me the big bucks.
I'm gonna go get some coke.
Do you want some?
Ah, I'm good with this for now.
Thanks.
This ah, is this
Old Orchard Beach?
Uh, probably.
I used to love this
place when I was a kid.
They use to have this big
carnival up at the 4th of July.
Oh yeah, we used
to go there for that.
Really?
Mm-hmm.
Oh shit.
What?
Nothing, I just, I
thought you meant, you know.
You thought I meant
like coke, coke.
Uh, yeah.
It's funny how that
doesn't happen more often.
Yeah, I guess.
Well, I'm sorry, I didn't mean
to freak you out or anything.
No, that's fine.
I just wasn't expecting
it, that's all.
So you don't mind if I?
No, that's cool, I really,
it doesn't matter, I just, it
caught me a little off guard.
Well, okay then.
Do you ever do blow?
Ah, I used to a bit,
but my ex wasn't big
into that kind of stuff,
so I kind of gave it up for her.
You always do what
people tell you?
What was your name again?
Eddie.
That's a good name.
I'm Pat.
You like my name?
Yeah, I mean sure, I guess so.
Eh, I never liked
it, too, too plain.
Now my brother
had a better name.
Here.
Nah, I'm all right, man.
You do this often?
Most nights.
Why?
I like it.
I like space.
You like space?
I guess so.
You know I really don't
know much about it though.
Nobody knows much
about anything.
What's that one right there?
That's the North Star, isn't it?
Good.
It's Polaris.
Polaris?
Yeah, for now,
it's the North Star.
But the purpose
of the North Star
is that it's always
the same star.
It's always in the
same place, right?
Sailors use it like a,
like a compass, right?
That sort of thing.
It's been the same
for 5,000 years,
but before that it
was a different one.
And another one before that
and another one before that.
13,000 years from now,
it'll change again
and again and again and again.
How far does that go on?
Forever.
My brother liked space.
That's how you got into it, huh?
How, how did your brother die?
If you don't mind me asking.
He died in a fire.
You remember what you did?
What do you mean?
I mean like how,
I mean how'd you get over it?
You don't get
over things like that.
Batman, peanut butter?
Nine eleven.
Nine eleven?
Okay, shut up, you're
not allowed to talk.
All right.
Stevie Nicks?
Rain dance?
Seizure?
I don't wanna do this any more.
Oh come on.
You just, you're
not even trying.
You're making me stand up here
and I look like an idiot.
This ain't, this
ain't fun for me.
What?
It's embarrassing.
You were doing so good though.
Don't patronize me,
you're making it worse.
Fine.
Patronize sound
like patron eyes,
like the eyes of a patron.
No one ever talks about that.
Probably because
it's not interesting.
What word did you have any ways?
I don't wanna tell you.
Squid?
Leave me alone.
Have you ever even seen a squid?
I think I'm gonna
head up to bed soon.
Yeah.
Mm-hmm, you can crash on
the couch though, if you want.
The couch?
After what you just
put me through?
That's right.
It's a comfy couch though.
It is a comfy couch.
What time is it any way?
Aw, shit.
What's wrong?
Ah, nothing, it
just I told my friend
I'd come back with a plan.
Plan for what?
He needs money.
I told him that I might
be able to get him some,
but doesn't look like
that's gonna happen.
That sucks.
Yeah.
He'll probably fucking
disown me after this.
Well too bad you can't
call your buddy from the bar.
Who?
Peter Cheung, the Asian guy.
What about him?
Well, he's rich.
I don't know if he is rich,
but his family's rich.
I thought you said his
family owned a hibachi place.
Yeah, like five
other businesses.
They have more money that
they know what to do with.
You wanna rob a hibachi place?
Just shut up and
hear me out, all right?
The guy who owns this place
is a local fucking monopoly.
He's got six businesses
and he stashes all the cash
in his office at the restaurant.
And how do you know this?
A friend of mine
used to work at his a,
at his flower shop when
she was in high school.
What friend?
Nevermind, what friend.
Look, she said that when she
worked in the flower shop,
she used to make daily
runs to the hibachi place
'cause the guy keeps the
cash from all six businesses
stashed in the, in a safe
in the back office there.
You wanna tell me what the fuck
that is over there?
That's the get away car.
The get away car?
Yeah, the get away car.
You wanna tell me
where the fuck is the car
we're suppose to drive home in?
It's at my friend's place.
- What friend?
- Nevermind what friend.
You and that shit.
What does that have
to do with anything?
Look, I got this thing
at the junk yard.
It was 500 bucks plus
200 to fix the engine,
but we'll talk about that
after we hit the restaurant.
If we hurry, we can go now
while they're getting
ready to open.
What about Billy Burke?
Fuck Billy Burke,
it's like you said,
we're never gonna find that guy.
I mean you need, you
need the money, right?
You need the money, you said
I come back with a plan,
this is what I got for you.
What do you say?
Hands up.
- I don't know, I don't know,
- Open the fucking safe.
- The code man.
- What do you mean
you don't know the fucking code?
- Its my dads.
- That's a fucking lie.
Fuck you're fucking dad.
Put the fucking
money in the bag.
- I don't know the code, man.
- Put the fucking money
in the bag!
What's going on out here?
Oh shit.
Shit, shit.
I knew that
fucking, I knew that...
Eddie, you okay?
Don't say my
fucking name, dumb ass.
I leave you just two fucking
seconds this is what happens.
She's got a
fucking shotgun, Derek.
Yeah, I noticed.
Eddie: You see that
bitch is got to a gun.
What do you think I gave her.
Fucking pistol?
She's got guns, how
is this my fault?
All right, let's go, let's go.
Let's do it on three, ready?
Three.
That wasn't three.
I didn't get the safe.
Fucking, the kid
didn't know the code
and then all the
shooting started,
so I didn't have time
to figure it out.
What'd you get
from the register?
A couple hundred.
It's all coming
together white car.
You think it's a
fucking joke, don't you?
Just trying to lighten the mood.
You trying to lighten
the fucking mood.
That's what you were trying
to do this whole time,
trying to lighten the
fucking mood, huh, huh?
It was a joke all
right, I'm sorry.
You ain't sorry, so don't
fucking at like it, Derek.
Oh so, now you
what I'm thinking?
You ain't sorry, Derek.
You fucked up is what you are.
You've been drunk since
before we left Boston,
and now you fucking snort coke
in a fucking catering truck.
Is there a point
you're trying to get at
or are we just talking shit now?
My point is you
got to a fucking problem
and it's starting to affect...
That's my fucking point.
Oh, I got a problem?
Yes, you got a fucking problem.
And what about you, huh?
What's your excuse?
I'm fucked up, okay.
And what about you?
'Cause as far as I can remember
I haven't forced you to do shit.
You chose to come up with me
and you chose to come
with me this morning,
so don't fucking try to pin
it all on me when it's...
there's something in your head
making you make those choices.
Holy shit.
What the fuck was that?
How far is the car?
About five miles that way.
Where you going?
I need a minute.
For what?
I'm gonna pick up the car.
Call me when you're ready.
You all right?
Well look who it is.
There you are.
I was wondering where
you took off to.
I went to see my father.
Yeah?
How is he?
Hi.
Hey.
You all right?
What do you mean?
I mean you almost did
a face plant just then.
Ah, it's just
these stupid boots,
they're real hard to balance in.
I smoked a bag of
fuel on my way home.
Oh, all right.
Where you headed?
Uh, I was thinking
about heading home.
Home?
Yeah, my friend's been
having gone with a rough time
and well I'm up here on a
bit of a wild goose chase,
so I figure I should
probably get him back.
Look, I'd rather stay here
and hang out with you,
I just, I got to
run, head into town
and pick up a few things
before we hit the road,
so I'm sorry.
It's, it's, it's all good.
I understand.
You wanna a, you
wanna come with me?
Come where?
Into town.
You want me to come?
Ah, yeah if you want.
I just got to run by the place
we've been staying
and pick up the dog.
I won't be able to
give you a ride back.
Not cause I'm lazy
or I don't want to,
I just, I don't know
what time, you know,
my friend's gonna call
me and I'm gonna have to
go pick him up and
I don't wanna say
I'm gonna give you a ride now
and not be able to do it.
It's a, you know,
I was actually gonna
go into town anyway,
so it works out.
- Yeah?
- Mm-hmm.
Ah, shit.
What's wrong?
It's just you're not suppose
to keep this out of
the cold for too long.
Do you mind if I throw
it in your freezer
when we get there?
Ah, sure, what is it?
I already told you, it's PCP.
When the hell did
you tell me that?
I told you I smoked a
bag of fuel on my way home.
That's what fuel is?
Yeah, what did you think it was?
I don't know, I thought
you meant weed or something,
I didn't think fuel was PCP.
I didn't even know that
shit was still around.
Yeah, it isn't.
You've got to drive all the
way down in New York City
and go into to
Harlan to pick it up.
I know a guy who makes a
trip every couple weeks.
So, um, do you
mind if I throw it
in your freezer
when we get there?
Ah.
Nah, go for it, I guess.
And it's not,
god, it's not like that.
You're totally tripping
out over nothing.
Like we can talk
being out tomorrow.
It's my dad.
I know, I know it
wasn't cool, I know.
No, I'm not high.
Ah, shut up.
Dude, you're like, just...
I can't talk right now.
I can't do this shit right now.
I got too much on my,
on my plate, dude.
You got to go, I got to go.
Yeah, fuck off.
You hear from your friend?
Nah, not yet.
Something wrong?
Nah, it's just this guy.
We used to date.
Kinda, but...
We're suppose to meet up
and smoke the rest of
this bag later, but.
You don't wanna?
I don't know.
He can just be real
creepy sometimes
and I don't know if I
wanna hang out with him
when I'm all fucked up.
Then don't go.
Well, I mean I don't know,
it might not be that bad.
I don't wanna smoke
it all by myself.
You wanna, you
wanna smoke it here?
Really, you don't mind?
No, it's cool.
Okay.
Thank you, man, you're
a real lifesaver.
This guy's a real weirdo.
Last time I hung out with him,
he spotted me some money for gas
and that just means that
the next time I see him,
he's gonna try to swing that
in some weird favor, you know.
You know like we didn't
even do anything crazy ever.
He just, he's always
trying something.
We only dated for
like a minute and...
I don't know.
It's just real
annoying to be around.
Thank you.
Hey, be careful.
Oh shit, sorry.
Now what were we talking about?
Oh, yeah, that, that douche bag,
yeah, he's a weirdo.
You ever been on
a duck boat tour?
Ah, nah, I've seen
'em around though.
Yeah, one time my
dad brought me up,
out to Boston on one of
those duck boat tours
and I really wanted
to see the ducks
and ah, I didn't know there was
some floating car tour, so ah,
you can imagine I
was pretty pis...
Shannon, watch out.
Relax, man, she's fine.
I mean people always feel
like they got to say something
or they got to do
something, do something,
we're like no.
Ah, do something when
people say things
or a, they don't, people
don't think to think
to think about themselves.
Hey, come on, you're
gonna hurt Sadie.
You can't sit there.
Can't sit where?
In the chair.
What chair?
The one you were
just sitting in.
It's yours?
Let's go for a walk somewhere.
You can't tell me what to do.
What?
What are you a
dictator or something?
What are you,
what are you saying?
Derek, Derek, Derek, Der.
I'm stuck.
Are you fucking with me?
Shannon.
I don't wanna be stuck.
Am I gonna be stuck?
This looks horrible.
Fuck, fuck, fuck, fuck.
Ah, aah, what the fuck?
Okay, Sh, Shannon, I'm gonna,
I'm gonna unstick you.
Okay, on three.
One, two, three.
Fuck.
Shannon, Shannon,
Sha, Sha, Shannon.
Fuck.
Come on, Shannon, Shannon.
Shannon.
Yo.
Slow down, what happened?
You can still catch
the end of it.
No, I just wanna
sit here a bit longer.
I've been thinking about
what you said the other day.
About what?
About eternity.
I don't know why the
fuck you listen to me for.
I don't what the fuck
I'm talking about.
No, man, what if she's right?
What if this is all there is?
And there's just nothing.
I guess that mean every
second you spent with her
means that much more, right?
You know, the North Star
wasn't always the North Star?
What the fuck are
you talking about?
North Star, it changes
every couple thousand years.
Before we had this one,
there was another one,
and before that one,
there was another one.
In a couple thousand years,
there'll be another one.
It's gonna keep going
like that forever.
Both directions.
What does that have
to do with anything?
So you can talk about this shit,
you got to realize that
the amount of time
we got is so fucking
small, it's microscopic,
it's smaller than that, it's...
We're talking about
infinity, man.
So what are you saying,
that a, we're so fucking
small and insignificant
that none of this
really matters?
- That's not what I'm saying.
- That's what it
- sounds like.
- That's not what the fuck
- I said, I'm not saying that.
- And it ain't fucking helping
- me out right now.
- Well, I'm not saying that.
It just not what I'm saying.
I'm saying that we're
only here for a moment
and every part of that moment
is specific to a certain
place and a certain time.
It's not that we don't matter,
it's the opposite, it's
every second of our life
no matter how small,
no matter how painful,
every second is special.
Every second is one in infinity.
Got any ideas?
I was kinda
hoping you had something.
Well, maybe we'll get
her a gift together,
but it's got to be a
good one or she'll think
we got lazy and screwed
her out of her present.
Isn't that what's happening?
Not if it's a good one.
How 'bout we get
her a gift card?
No, we can't get
her a gift card.
We get her a gift card, we
might as well get her cash,
you get her cash you might as
well get her nothing at all.
How 'bout one of those
elliptical machines
she's been talking about?
No, she'll make me use it.
You know what?
We can get her one of
those, one of those vacuums
that cleans the floor by itself.
Those exist?
Yeah, they got 'em
at the department store
down the road.
What time they open til?
About another half hour.
That a good idea.
Why don't you run up
there and grab one.
And when you're done,
swing by and pick me up.
You sure?
Mom hasn't been letting
me drive the couple weeks.
No, I trust you.
Just pick me up
when you're done.
Thanks dad.
What can I get for you?
Newports.
Any thing else?