NETFLIX PRESENTS
Now!
Good! Good, Tomek!
Go, go, go, go!
And… yeah, keep your hands up.
Hands up! Yeah.
-Left!
-Hit him!
-That's it, Tomek!
-Good!
Breathe! That's it!
Listen. Drink? He's getting weaker.
Left, left, right, yeah?
And keep the hands up.
Tomek. You're better than him. Better!
Okay. Come on, come on. Come on!
Go for it, Tomek, go for it!
Bro, you got him. He's done.
Come on!
That's it!
Tomek! Hands up!
Left! Tomek, left!
Tomek!
Keep your guard up! Tomek!
Tomek! Hands up… Tomek!
Hands up!
Paweł! Stop the fight! Paweł!
Keep your guard up!
Stop it! Stop the fight!
ZAKOPANE, SIX MONTHS LATER
Boss, some guy is causing a ruckus
at the entrance.
Can I treat him to some pepper spray?
Just wanted to ask.
Okay…
Come on, man, don't you get it? Steppy D!
Steppy D is here! Steppy D! Ya get it?
Steppy D!
Boss!
I never wait in line, jerk-off.
Welcome to Opium. Good evening.
Steppy D.
I hope you have a great time.
Yeah, so do I.
Jackal, be so kind as to escort
Mr. Steppy D to the VIP section.
That's more like it!
Girls, we're coming in!
See, get it? You all stay outside,
we're coming in!
Oh, yeah, one, two, three!
Thanks, homie, very good!
That's what I'm talking about!
Please, feel welcome.
It's not wopium, it's Opium!
And we're inside this Opium.
Ah! Like in opium for the masses?
We got trouble in the VIP section.
What's up?
Come, take a look for yourself.
Leave me alone!
What? What's up?
Okay, okay, okay.
Two bottles for us, okay?
And come back, doll.
Hey, what's your name?
So are you gonna sit with us?
What name do you like?
Don't you get it?
Hey, take it easy!
Hey, buddy!
Buddy!
Jesus! We have our own security, okay?
Listen, move the party to a hotel.
You're such a limp dick!
Come on, dough!
Buy yourself a new personality!
And fuck off.
What are you doing?
-Chojecki!
-Chojecki! Fuck them up!
Take him away.
What the hell?
Easy. We were just leaving!
Steppy? Steppy?
We're not coming back!
We won't come back here!
Hey, guys, take it easy, let's talk,
we can work this out. Come on! Boss!
Hey, listen! This club sucks!
There's no point going in!
Don't wait in the line!
It's shit!
We're gonna meet again!
We're gonna meet again! That's it!
Come on, Steppy! Come on!
This is shit, not a club!
Steppy, Steppy?
Wake up. You can go back to sleep later.
I heard you roughed up
a celebrity last night.
What's going on?
You leaving already?
Thanks.
I've got something for you.
Must burn a lot of fuel, right?
Yeah, but it runs well.
Ah… runs well…
At least something runs well.
Coach had one, right?
No. What are you babbling about?
The coach had an old Polonez.
Come on, he had this one.
No way, he had an old Polonez!
I'm pulling your leg!
Of course he had an old Polonez!
For me, it was like a Mustang.
Did he lose a lot?
Coach? On your fight?
More than he had.
He bet with the wrong people.
They came to get what's theirs
and burned down his gym.
They say he's holed up getting loaded.
Bro, I don't believe you were doped.
The tests showed I was.
Fuck the tests!
What did you come for?
Like really come for.
I said I've got something for you.
In 1974,
Muhammad Ali beat Foreman in them.
You don't say? Beautiful.
But they were made in 1982.
Yeah, but only we know that.
What are you up to?
Come with me.
So not just chitchat about old times.
Come with me. What's keeping you here?
You know, the wolves
will be in a pack together again.
We'll split everything 50-50.
You'll train the bouncers.
Thanks, bro, but no.
Why not?
'Cause I still got a lot to learn.
Wait.
Yeah?
Okay, set it up.
Yes, at 2 p.m.
When I say I'll be there at two,
I'll be there at two.
See ya.
What's up?
Club stuff. If you come with me,
you'll find out.
I know nothing
about working in a club. Thanks.
Keep them. And keep training that fist.
I love you, brother.
I love you, too, asshole.
Are you coming for All Saints' Day?
Always.
Hi, Mom.
What-- Mom, what happened?
Yes, Auntie.
Thank you. See you on Thursday.
Almost everyone knows.
Mom, do you know
where I can find Dominika?
CITY HALL
Hey, babe.
Such a nice girl walking alone?
Sorry, but you ain't my type.
I'm just giving back the bag.
Please don't hurt me.
Any finder's fee?
Apparently, you're it.
I saw the video.
Don't wait in the line!
It's shit!
Everyone has their five minutes of fame.
More like 26 seconds.
Why haven't you called all this time?
You must have gotten my messages.
I… I don't have a good answer for that.
Well, how about a bad one?
You found me for a reason, right?
He's hitting back.
No way. It's over.
And one…
And…
Man, how did he do that?
Did you see that?!
You beast… Beast!
You're getting wasted again?
At least I didn't run away
with my tail between my legs.
Wiktor's dead.
Car accident.
Pull yourself together.
The funeral is on Thursday.
Just make sure you come sober.
Or don't come at all.
When we were kids,
our parents had a lot to deal with.
Most of all, you and me.
And our adventures.
Always together.
We could always rely on each other.
Maybe I relied on you a little more.
I remember when
I walked onto thin ice on a lake…
like an idiot. You hit me on the neck.
When I stole comic books
from the old man's shop.
When I drank too much
for the first time. When…
I could talk for hours.
And now you're with our dad, bro.
I love you, brother.
Hi.
-Elegant.
-Elegant and sober.
Did you have to? Even today?
My little daughter…
Thanks for dropping by,
but you should be going now.
Bartkowiak.
You fit in here really well now.
You ran away.
Did you have to get juiced up
before the fight?
So even you buy that?
Even if I had, you shouldn't have
bet your life on one stupid fight.
Watch it, sonny boy.
I ain't too old to kick your ass!
So what are you waiting for?
You ain't getting any younger.
Tomek! You don't know shit!
I lost everything.
Go back to fucking Zakopane!
Ever heard of Sparta?
They had a leader - Lycurgus.
To stop corruption and greed,
he ordered the minting of pelanors -
coins made of normal iron,
not precious stone,
like, I don't know, gold or silver.
Pelanors were big and heavy,
but they had no value.
So, you see…
…stealing and hiding a large amount
of pelanors was practically impossible.
Blyat'!
I told you the putter is good for nothing.
If euros were so heavy, perhaps
you wouldn't have been tempted, Vadim.
Now you're going to build for me.
Thank you.
And what about the club?
I'll stay here, take care
of the formalities. And then…
You could keep it.
Wiktor…
His dream…
He told me not long ago
that all this
should belong to the two of you.
Which means now it's yours.
I'll stay here until I sell the club
and then go back home.
I'm sorry, Mom.
But remember this is your home.
This is the Woźny Tower,
a project that will soon become
the fastest growing
office center in town.
This venture is going to revive
and invigorate the old district,
which will also give it a new spirit,
new energy and
completely new opportunities.
Simply great. It's pure poetry to my ears.
And now a few words
from the president of Sanstal,
the man who's going to create
our city's second center.
Floor is yours.
Gentlemen, the old district
is going to lead our city
on its way to modernity.
We're going to build a conference center--
The area zoning plan has so far protected
the district and its monuments
from such developments.
Thank you, Dominika, for mentioning that.
Obviously, we cannot turn our backs
on the past and tradition
when we are making
a step towards the future.
It is necessary to unite them somehow.
Personally, I believe that Woźny Tower
is going to be a perfect example
of how great the connection of the old
with the new can be,
how well it can blend.
Go through the back door! Quick! Quick!
Good morning.
Can I get some beef brains, please?
But we don't want to sell this shop.
You understand.
Yeah.
Why don't we negotiate?
Come here!
Leave him alone!
Get over here. Get over here!
So? Will you get me my beef brains?
Sign it!
Don't get it stained!
Yes, hello?
Good morning.
I'd like to talk about the club Ring.
Good morning, but I'm not looking
for any real estate agents.
Dear sir, we would like
to make you an attractive offer.
How much?
We could agree to two million.
But have you even seen it?
It needs a complete overhaul.
Sign the contract on Thursday?
Good.
Then… come by the club, please.
Let's say, at 11 a.m.?
Great, so we're meeting on Thursday.
See you then.
SOLD
CARPENTER
Can I help you?
No. No need. Really.
No problem.
You're selling it?
What happened?
Ah…
That's none of your business!
It's our problem.
Have a good day.
Sign here, please.
Thank you.
I thought the buyer
would like to see it first.
So you're from Sanstal?
You are the ones buying my club?
No.
We only provide purchasing services
on behalf of Fieldstar Group Limited.
We are the representative
and general contractor
of construction projects for this client.
Anything wrong?
What are you doing?
The offer is off the table.
Wait a second.
Why don't you think about it calmly?
We're talking about two million here.
SURE. TOMORROW.
OKAY, WILL DO.
ON MY WAY.
BE THERE IN 15.
CLIENT
If Kołodziejczyk doesn't close in a week,
we'll need to take care of it. Him, too.
Your friend doesn't want to sell.
Dialogue, Repeć.
Talk to him first.
Then we might move on to other measures.
I'm going to keep Wiktor's club.
What happened now?
I've got to find out why
they want to buy everything around here.
-What?
-They want to put office blocks there.
Well, they won't put them there for now.
Tomek?
You were the one trying to convince me.
But this is not about the club.
I don't know some of you well yet,
but I hope that's going to change soon.
This is Dominika.
She's going to help me
manage the place for a while.
If there are any questions
for me or Dominika, feel free to ask.
Something funny?
Today, I'm just going to be watching,
so, please, just work as usual.
Okay. We're opening in 45 minutes,
so let's get to work.
So what do you think?
Great! Plenty of customers.
We gotta talk.
So talk.
It's your last day working here.
And yours, too.
Don't be such a prude.
You want in on the action?
Scram.
I need to find new employees.
I'm going to call Zakopane.
I know the right person.
Maybe give him a chance?
Come on.
Start, please.
Need a ride?
Actually, why have we never…
Your father would have killed me.
That was the only thing stopping you?
Such a tough guy, but afraid of my father.
Of the coach.
Well trained in the martial arts.
I have an invitation from my boss
to the theater tomorrow.
Why theater all of a sudden?
It's a cover to meet with people
he does business with.
Pick me up at six.
Okay.
Who's that guy?
It's my boss.
And the guy who wants to buy the club.
And the one with the phone?
No idea.
Irek has a lot of, let's say,
business contacts.
I'll be right back.
I hope you understand
the gravity of the situation.
I'm not supposed to be here.
Do you think I'm enjoying myself?
We're having some complications.
Minor ones.
Have I ever let you down?
No, you haven't.
That's why we're talking.
Otherwise, we wouldn't be.
Appreciate that.
I do.
Seven days left.
In seven days, all that
must formally belong to Fieldstar.
Or some pretty important people
will be pissed off.
And we don't want
them to be pissed off, do we?
We'll cover it up in the media
with protests.
You will have plenty of free rein
to take action.
-Everything will be ready in time.
-Well, I hope so.
'Cause what you're doing
is more important than it seems.
As I said,
everything will be ready in time.
I have a splendid loge for us.
And a bottle of good wine.
You know, it's forbidden here.
But not for us.
And after the show,
I'm taking you out to a reception.
This famous actress is going to be there,
only I just forgot her name.
Irek. Please meet Tomek.
Hi.
Hard to believe I failed to notice you.
Ireneusz Parzych. My boss.
Well, then…
Yeah, my friends are waiting for me.
So… I should just say
I hope you have a great time.
Thank you.
Hi, gentlemen.
Bruised, as usual?
You know me.
Boss!
Hi!
And this is Dominika.
Jackal and Highlander.
Thanks for agreeing to help.
Are we expecting trouble?
It's more like we might be the trouble.
So keep an eye on everything here.
We're planning to install CCTV
and record audio after hours.
Questions?
Great, follow me.
I'll show you around.
Oh! Tommy!
What do you want?
Just taking a look.
I heard the place is cool.
Wanted to see how you're getting on.
I heard about your brother.
My condolences.
And you know what,
I also came to give you advice.
Tell me,
why the fuck do you need this place?
Haven't you had enough problems?
Yeah!
Time to go.
Tear this place apart.
Hey!
My beer! Bartender!
I want a free drink!
Somebody spilled mine!
Hey, pal! Try not to ruin your evening.
It's up to you how it's going to end.
Escort them out.
All right, buddy, you're done.
Get your hands off me!
What?
Gentlemen, it's not worth it.
I understand
you came to fuck up the club.
It's not worth it.
Hey, dude, he's crazy. Let's bail.
Perhaps we could consider that
to be a job interview?
I know nothing about working in a club.
That's exactly what I said to Wiktor
the last time I talked to him.
I want you to help me find out
if my brother was murdered.
The whole thing stinks, doesn't it?
You can count on me.
Two more of the same.
I know that smile.
What are you up to?
Follow me!
Should I be happy or worried?
Come on! Hi, gentlemen!
Gonna be cool tonight.
It's gonna be good, huh?
Hard times are coming. You might need it.
That's it! What's up?
Sorry.
Surprise.
Like a… surprise, surprise.
Welcome to the Ring.
So, what do you say we end this beef?
Respect, homie! Respect!
So you work in this shithole?
You had it better in Zakopane.
It's my club.
Seriously? Awesome!
All the world, all the world, a problem
All the time, all the time, a problem
In my head, in my head, I have a problem
In my heart, the heat that lets me live
No problem
Hey! You! Bartkowiak!
Sorry about last time.
I got a little carried away.
You know, that's the job.
You did what you had to do.
Okay. Let's forget about it.
Anyway, gotta move forward, yeah?
So?
Thanks.
And listen…
if you need someone to work here,
let me know.
What, Steppy doesn't pay enough?
No, it isn't that.
I'd like to learn a couple of things.
Besides, sometimes the boss says things
that make people around here
wanna kick his ass.
Yeah? Like who?
Like me.
Good job.
Thanks. Can you stand this?
All the time, all the time, a problem
In my head, in my head, I have a problem
In my heart, the heat that lets me live
No problem
I just wanted to say there was no brawl,
and all that was a marketing stunt
promoting his newest album, Rebel.
In fact, we're very good friends.
Yeah, and Steppy D
is the craziest guy I've ever met!
Bang!
Chojecki!
The land your club is on
is going to be worth a fortune soon.
Like everything around it.
Wiktor had problems with the club.
He didn't want to tell me about it, but…
but I know
Repeć was trying to intimidate him.
They failed,
so it ended with an execution.
No other option.
Do you think the police are involved?
Somebody pays them to look the other way.
A few companies and shops
in the area are closing.
Those left
are clearly afraid of something.
Nobody does anything.
So where do we start?
Sanstal.
Their truck killed Wiktor.
The club wasn't even up for sale
when they tried to buy it.
Sanstal.
Sanstal applied
for the construction permit!
They're constructing the Woźny Tower.
I'll try to find out more at work.
WOŹNY TOWER
PARK REVITALIZATION
ACCESS DENIED
POLICE STATION
WOZNY TOWER
PRESENTATION CORRECTED
THE CHANGE OF THE DESIGNATED USE OF LAND
OTHER FILES
I've been looking for you.
I never said thank you
for the invitation to the theater.
Yeah?
I liked it a lot.
Perhaps one day
we can see a show together.
You stepped a bit out of line
during the presentation.
Maybe I was wrong. I can admit my mistakes
and change my mind.
Very good.
You intrigue me.
I'm going sailing over the weekend.
Maybe you'd like to join me?
Of course, there's no hidden agenda.
I'll think about it.
See you around.
I'm here. What happened?
We'll have to put out a few flames
before a fire breaks out.
What fire?
They started sniffing around.
Who?
Bartkowiak and that drunken coach of his.
There's also a problem
with buying out the club.
And the fucking clock is ticking.
Well, yeah. A must is a must.
Can I help you with that somehow?
Just send your assistant
on a business trip.
To the lake. Just the way you like it.
Dominika?
I assure you that is not necessary.
Irek, now you're telling me
what is necessary and what isn't?
I assure you, she's not a problem.
I talked to her,
she admitted she made a mistake.
She's pragmatic.
Dominika is pragmatic. I vouch for her.
You vouch for her?
Yes, I vouch for her.
Hey! Put it down!
Put it down!
You, too!
What's your name, kid?
Olaf.
Olaf?
Take a hike, Olaf.
Tomek.
I was following this guy Ireneusz a bit,
and his friends are peculiar.
I saw Scar, I saw Kołodziejczyk.
And who is Kołodziejczyk?
Thanks.
I've learned a lot.
Strange guy, dangerous.
I was stupid.
I lost a lot betting with his boys.
They say…
I know…
he's a hit man for the special forces.
Bartender! Where's our bottle?
Hey! Hey!
You want me to come and help you?
Relax, take it easy.
What were you talking about?
Stay calm!
We don't want any trouble.
How can we help you?
All our life…
Tommy?
We don't want any trouble.
You killed Wiktor.
Fuck off, leave it alone!
Ooh, I'm being nice, and you're so angry.
So when are we signing the contract?
Tell me, what's the point
in repeating your brother's mistakes?
Isn't it better to get along?
Live in harmony?
Tommy, so what do you say?
I did some digging.
More than 40,000 companies
are registered in this building.
Forty thousand?
I talked to Repeć.
It's him…
…with Kołodziejczyk.
Go on.
Cayman House.
The Cayman Islands live off that.
And where are the employees?
Offices? There are none.
They are all companies registered abroad
serving as a front.
Fieldstar Group Limited, too.
Your boss gave them the permit.
The president of Sanstal,
he's also one of Kołodziejczyk's men.
We saw them in the theater that night.
Kołodziejczyk's father got rich
when the system collapsed.
Many people disappeared back then -
politicians, business people, military.
People say it was him.
And now the son has taken over -
the methods, the contacts…
the job.
He's untouchable.
He knows too much, and he's too valuable.
Tomek, isn't that why
the police turn their heads the other way?
They have orders from the top.
Get out of here! Get out of here now!
Guys, it's not worth it.
C'mon, not worth it!
I understand
someone told you to come here
and fuck the place up,
but it's not worth it!
Hey.
Dad!
Daddy…
Baby, what a day to stop drinking, huh?
Dad!
Jeez. Call an ambulance!
They're on their way.
Was Mr. Paweł Sozoniuk
provoking the guests?
What?!
Did you see what happened?
It's pretty clear what happened!
They fled. Soon they'll be too far away.
Stay calm, please.
We need to establish the facts first.
And alcohol causes aggression.
I'm sorry, miss, but we need to wait
for the reports of the victims.
Victims?! What victims?!
My father is the victim!
They ran into the club and--
Ah, yes. About the club.
We received claims
concerning some irregularities,
and we need to take a closer look, so…
someone is going to be in touch with you.
Motherfuckers!
They want to set us up.
We're all alone.
Did Bartkowiak get the message?
Uncle, we should've wasted him
just like his brother.
They're covering everything up,
as promised.
His brother wasn't that famous.
If we don't get it done in a week,
I'm gonna have problems.
And if I'm in trouble,
everyone's in fucking trouble.
Now you can go visit
that little bitch of his…
just like you wanted.
PEOPLE HAVE HAD ENOUGH!
PROTESTERS ARE HEADING TO THE CAPITAL CITY
Highlander and Jackal are dead.
Mom's not answering.
I'm scared.
Let's not get deeper into this, please.
Let's just let it go.
But I can't.
I'm with you.
Check on your mom. I'll lock up the club
and we'll think about what to do next.
Why do you choose annoying boyfriends?
Easy, baby. It's nothing personal.
But this is going to be personal!
Dominika!
Don't shit yourself!
You think I need help taking you down?
Just like I didn't in the second round.
But my uncle wanted to be sure.
Say hi to your brother.
When he was dying, he squealed like a pig!
Did you take care of the girl?
No. No, he didn't.
What now?
Rafał Kołodziejczyk.
Do you have a plan?
Your boss. Kołodziejczyk trusts him.
I'll convince him to help us.
Oh, no, no, no. This is not a good time
and not a good place.
We know about you and Kołodziejczyk.
Everything's fucked up.
Get out of this town.
And never come back.
Bring him here. This is your chance!
Chance? Fuck. Chance!
Kołodziejczyk owns politicians
and the police.
He does whatever he wants.
If you think you can stand in his way,
you are fucking wrong.
Call! And get him down here.
Fuck, kids, I wanna help you.
That's why I told you
to get the fuck out of here!
Call him!
Tell him the permit has been revoked.
We have a visitor. Mi casa es su casa.
Come!
I'm sorry.
Going somewhere?
I'm not surprised.
Young piece of ass messed with your head.
Everybody makes mistakes sometimes.
Say no again.
You killed Konrad. You killed my family.
And you're wasting my precious time.
Am I in time for the party?
This is all they had.
I didn't mean to get you involved.
Or Dominika.
Give me the fucker's address
and leave town.
Paweł, we may not come back.
Are you nuts? She's my daughter.
We're coming with you.
All of us.
I know one hotshot
who really wants to help.
I wanted to learn something, but
I'm going straight into a master class.
To bring out the natural beauty
of a shrub,
you need to trim the pieces
limiting its development.
The cut has to be decisive,
but also very precise.
Oh, yes, much better.
Otherwise it would grow like a weed.
A good gardener
does not allow weeds in his garden.
It's a shame how few people
appreciate the art of gardening.
There's so much strength and power in it.
What does a gardener do?
My father used to say it's correcting
the unfinished work of God,
hence taking his place.
He was right.
Fuck you.
Beautiful, but poisonous.
Datura.
It smells and looks best at night.
Some can cause hallucinations.
And some can kill.
The miserable species of man
is like a weed!
A shapeless pulp which does not create,
only devours and then dies,
turning into manure.
This is the greatest art -
to die beautifully. With dignity.
Can you do that?
No, you are not a samurai.
You are manure. A base for me
to build something beautiful!
THREE MONTHS LATER
Left, right, head, good!
Left, right, head, great!
Oh, yes, head, head, head, head!
And left, right, head, good!
Wojtek, go to the changing room.
With gloves like those,
winter is no threat.
Ali beat Foreman in them.
Yeah. I gave them to Wiktor.
Only we know that.
Acquitted?
Perhaps you'd like to coach the boys, huh?
Hey, sweetie!
Hi!
You'll have to work hard to convince me.
Very hard.
Subtitle translation by:
Marcin Piechota