This film is a fiction
loosely based on real events.
A Monkey Town production
BASHING
Upon returning home from Iraq,
those taken hostage were
shunned by society.
Hello.
Hello, reception.
Yes, sir.
Miss Takai...
If you please...
What is it?
I haven't finished.
You are dismissed.
Here's what I owe you.
Since you arrived,
the atmosphere has changed.
One of your colleagues
has the internet and
he likes to surf the web.
He says there are
all kinds of insults about you.
He's shouting it from the rooftops.
Your pay up until today,
there's no need to stay.
It's inconvenient.
It's inconvenient for me.
I need the money.
Not to go back over there at least?
Let me give you some advice.
Don't ever go back there.
If you were kidnapped again,
you'd be in real trouble.
- Welcome.
- I'd like some soup.
One tapioca, one tofu, one fritter.
Each one separate.
Separate?
One per bowl please.
With lots of sauce.
More.
As much as is in the others.
What the hell?
What happened?
Yuko...
I got fired.
And some stupid idiots ruined dinner.
What's wrong with everyone?
Is what I did so wrong?
Good grief!
Say something!
Yuko isn't here?
She isn't eating?
Did something happen?
She got fired from her job.
Why?
No idea.
Hey, Yuko!
We're not here right now.
Please leave your name
and message after the tone.
Hello?
You little idiot. You just do
what you like Takai Yuko.
Now listen up.
I'll have your hide, you bitch.
Hello?!
I've had enough!
Where are you going?
To buy some soup.
Yuko!
Welcome.
I'd like some soup.
Okay...
I want two tapioca,
two tofu and two fritters.
In separate bowls.
With lots of sauce.
Yuko...
Tell me, why were you fired?
You know why!
You don't have to ask!
Mr. Takai!
Come and see me during your break.
I want to speak to you.
Thank you.
So... are things calming down?
What do you mean?
Are there as many
anonymous phone calls?
How many per day?
I've never counted them,
but about a dozen, I guess.
That many, after all this time!
Haven't you considered taking action?
Action?
Changing your phone number
or even moving house...
Make your mind up!
Why don't you change your identity?
You know that our director,
Mr. Ando, arrived yesterday.
He summoned me this morning.
To talk to me about you,
find out what you were doing.
To ask me what you were doing!
How should I know?
But it's crazy, you know!
The company still receives
abusive phone calls and emails.
Even Head Office is harassed.
It's true, everyone knows about it.
The receptionists can't cope
with this situation.
Tell me what it is you want to say.
Do you want me to resign?
I wouldn't go that far...
But when I see the harm caused
to the company's management,
it's quite beyond me.
If I resigned,
where would I find another job?
Anywhere.
There's plenty of work around.
Think it over.
You will get your severance pay in full.
But do it without delay.
I'm counting on you
to handle the formalities.
Mr. Ueki...
I beg you.
I beg you to keep me on.
I can't resign.
I beg you. Look!
Going over there as a volunteer!
You've spoiled her.
My daughter...
is a victim.
She was taken hostage.
Why must she be persecuted?
I beg you. It's the truth!
I'm begging you.
We're not here right now.
Please leave your name
and message after the tone.
Hello...?
You're there aren't you?
Don't act innocent.
Answer me!
Hello?
Ever thought about the term,
"self-responsibility?"
You will know the Lord's vengeance.
It's crazy.
If you'd been killed,
you'd have become a heroine.
No, certainly not in Japan.
Anyway, you came home.
Without any shame!
Are you listening to me?
It's a very important question.
Couldn't you at least answer me?
Mrs. Takai, please.
A family matter.
- It's me.
- What's wrong?
I've just...
handed in my notice.
What?
Mr. Ueki told me
he'd been summoned by the director.
It was over Yuko.
They're still bombarded
with abusive phone calls
and emails about her.
He was ordered to find a solution.
A solution...
What solution?
Well, he was told to fire me.
The company's image was at stake.
He didn't want to keep me
any longer.
I realized I was done for.
I knew it would happen one day.
So, I wrote my letter of resignation
and gave it to my boss.
You've handed in your notice?
Yes, I have.
But why?
You could've talked to the union...
The situation would've been unbearable.
Maybe, but...
Where are you now?
Outside the factory gates.
My head's all messed up.
I need to get my head straight,
but I wanted to tell you
before I did anything else.
But what's all the rush?
Sorry I decided this on my own.
But you know.
I got down on my knees.
I couldn't stand it...
"I love you. I love you all."
Yuko?
Hello.
What?
You've answered at last.
Why this "what?"
What?
Let's meet up.
So we can talk things over.
You've been back for six months
and we haven't seen each other once.
Let's meet up, OK?
One of these days...
Is that you, Yuko?
I know you're home.
Why won't you answer?
I threw away the phone.
What happened?
Did you answer the phone?
Did someone say something?
I wanted to talk to you
about your father.
I threw it away!
Yuko...?
Want to meet up?
Where?
It's been a long time...
What do you want to tell me?
You want us to split up, right?
If so, there's no need to meet up.
You've changed.
In what way?
I haven't changed at all.
That's exactly what I mean.
You're more and more stubborn.
You don't listen to people.
It's always been the same...
You think of no one but yourself.
Me?
Yes.
I only think of myself?
How do you mean?
Didn't you go over there to die?
A dangerous country at war...
What was the sense in that?
All you did was embarrass everybody.
Me?
I embarrassed people?
Who?
Everyone.
The whole of Japan.
Can't you even see that?
So, you disapprove of me too?
Why go to some foreign country,
and help the people there?
If you have so much time
there's this country,
this town, that you could look after.
I don't think we speak
the same language.
What're you talking about?
That's what I've always hated about you.
Volunteering
is OK for people with the
time and money.
It doesn't suit you at all!
Okay...
Not at all!
I said OK!
I get it.
Enough.
Evenin'.
I got fired.
I handed in my notice
as a matter of form.
But I got fired alright.
It's totally crazy.
Two unemployed people in this family!
And both at almost the same time.
When I left the factory,
I called your stepmother.
I told her everything,
and afterwards I hung up.
I wondered what I was going to do.
To help me think,
I thought of going to a bar.
But I came straight home.
The fear of doing without no doubt.
Just the idea of being out of work...
I didn't have the courage
to go for a drink.
Even so,
being fired just like that
after 30 years in the same firm...
It sure hurts.
Is it because of me?
You condemn what I did?
You're wrong.
Am I?
Why am I wrong? Tell me.
Why are you looking at me like that?
Listen...
Is it wrong to establish links with people?
Is feeling connected to others that bad?
- It's a good thing.
- Well then...
I told you.
I don't condemn you in any way.
Didn't I support you from the start?
Being a volunteer
is a hard choice to understand.
After what happened, it's even harder.
Didn't you expect disapproval?
You congratulated me though.
You said:
"I'm glad you came back."
"It's not your fault,
nor that of others over there."
That's true.
We've been over all this
for long enough now.
I'd just like a bit of comfort today.
What'll we do...
now?
I have no idea.
I want to die.
They say that those who
talk about suicide never do it.
But I'm different.
Don't talk silly!
I'm useless.
I tell Yuko she must be strong and live.
But when it's about me,
I'm completely useless.
Let's wait.
Just wait and see.
Time will sort everything out in the end.
Even waiting...
is hard.
Let's wait.
"IN MOTHER TERESA'S WORDS"
Isn't that Yuko?
It's been a long time!
Say, you had a narrow escape!
Still living with your father?
Just look at you!
You look like an artist.
Babies...
Yeah, this one's mine.
They're the same age.
What about you?
Not getting married?
What's your boyfriend's name?
- Mr. Iwai.
- That's right, Mr. Iwai.
Weren't you going out together?
I left him.
No!
Mr. Iwai's got another girlfriend.
Really?
Yuko, you did know, didn't you?
They're getting married soon.
It's true.
Sorry for being so indiscreet.
You should have an arranged marriage.
Get married, have a kid.
That'll make you see sense.
Don't be silly, Yuko has
always refused a life like that.
Her world is nothing like ours.
Right, Yuko?
You'll carry on with your work, won't you?
Yuko's a good person.
We couldn't do what she does.
Absolutely.
We couldn't go and help other people.
We wouldn't have a clue where to start!
Yuko!
Hey, let's go for some tea!
I heard your husband lost his job.
So, it's true...
Is it over 'you-know-what?'
It must be that, mustn't it?
What on earth is "That?"
You-know-what-
Answer me.
What's "That?"
What's wrong?
You're weird, you know.
It's hard...
Waiting.
Want some coffee?
I'll make some.
The insurance...
Dad's life assurance,
how much is it?
Why do you ask?
I think I'm entitled to it, too.
I want to leave.
Go back over there.
They're all waiting for me.
I need some money.
Drop it, will you?
I'm going to need
that money.
Idiot!
Give him back to me!
My husband!
Give me back my husband!
I'd like some soup.
Some soup.
I read the paper.
Doesn't it bother you?
You killed your father...
And it doesn't affect you?
Don't come back here.
I forbid you to.
I'd like to book a flight to Amman.
Via Moscow.
Mother...
I've booked a flight.
I'm leaving next Tuesday.
I won't be coming back.
Are you really going?
Nobody needs me here.
Everybody hates me.
It's obvious to me.
It's been like that since I was a child.
At school, I was a bad pupil.
I had few friends.
I didn't even have a best friend.
I was dumped by my first love.
I even failed to get into university.
I wanted to design clothes,
but I couldn't get an apprenticeship.
I failed everywhere.
I may be a dead loss...
But even so,
I was useful for the first time.
Beneath the bombs and amid the wounded,
holding a pregnant woman's hand
reassured her.
Japanese candy
made the children so happy.
They'd crowd around me.
"Yuko!" "Yuko!"
They'd kiss me.
I want to live with
those children's smiles...
Otherwise I...
I do realize, you know,
that I'm just doing as I please.
Dad told me.
With charity work
and selfless acts,
at best you embarrass people.
And you never get thanked, that's for sure.
He told me that if I felt ready,
he would support me.
He'd do all he could to help me.
And now...
I'm begging for my share
of the insurance money.
I know I'm saying terrible things.
But you know...
I can't stay here.
I don't want to.
People here are so cold.
I have to act cold too.
And if I stayed,
I would have to become cold.
Just thinking about it...
makes me not want to go on living.
Over there, you feel good.
I feel good.
I loved Dad a lot,
but he was weak.
I'm going to carry on.
I'll always side with the others.
Maybe I've acted cold too.
Without realizing it.
It's the first time...
the very first time...
you've called me "Mother?"
I'm so pleased.
Here...
For the journey.
Thank you.
I won't go with you to the airport.
I understand.
Soon we won't see her anymore
The train is leaving
That's it, we can't see her anymore
The train has left, she has gone
When the sun rises, I will return
One time only I will return
When the sun rises,
One time only
I so liked that girl
But she doesn't live here anymore
But she doesn't live anywhere anymore
I heard she was all alone
I found out she was all alone
I thought that this town was very sad
And I fell asleep
Before leaving this town
I shut the windows
And I fell asleep
Screenwriter and Director:
KOBAYASHI Masahiro
Yuko:
URABE Fusako
Her father:
TANAKA Ryuzo
Her lover:
KATO Takayuki
The father's boss:
HONDA Kikujiro
The hotel owner:
KAGAWA Teruyuki
The stepmother:
OTSUKA Nene
Cinematography:
SAITO Koichi
Song:
HAYASHI Hiroshi
Editing and post-production:
KANEKO Naoki