I am sure that our weapons
is of the best quality.
And the SM corporation
has the highest competence.
Especially in the production of laser weapons.
True, our company always fulfills the
of the contract.
It always delivers equipment on time.
And we guarantee the military as well as important officers a
a very attractive offer.
I think they offer you ladies an excellent product.
General Kane.
This anti-tank weapon, which the SM corporation
offered us last year.
Well, I think it was not so bad.
Let's order 10,000 pieces.
By.
So my ladies.
We are finalizing.
Let's not kid ourselves, I'm terrified.
Change is not easy. But I am proud,
That I had the courage to do it.
Are you writing a book?
This may sound idealistic....
But especially in a politics and government steeped in
cynicism in politics and government.
This is where I hope to do something
valuable for my country.
To contribute something from yourself.
And be proud of it.
That's great to hear.
People still only criticize.
What happened to this country?
They are ashamed of the greatness,
that we have achieved.
Are you writing an article for a newspaper?
- No, this is just my diary.
- A diary?
- Easier than writing in a diary.
Would you like a drink?
- No, thank you.
My name is Bill Slater.
- Melinda Griffin.
Where are you from?
- From a small town in Ohio.
You've never heard of him.
From where.
- Ashtabula
- No kidding.
You probably won't believe it, but my first girlfriend,
first love.
She came from Ashtabula.
Unbelievable.
I fell in love with her.
She was the girl of my dreams.
Then suddenly she disappeared.
With my things.
- It's sad.
- I missed them.
She was not as pretty as you.
- Pardon?
Will you have dinner with me tonight?
Melinda.
What are you doing here?
- Forgive me, I am so ashamed.
- Don't be ridiculous,
What are you doing in Washington?
Well, I decided to take you up on your offer.
- That's great.
What kind of offer?
- Do you remember when we talked on the phone,
about a year ago?
You said it was like being in Washington,
then I would live with you.
- A year ago?
I don't remember.
- Didn't you get a letter?
I wrote that I was coming.
- I never got it.
- Didn't you get it?
Would you be so kind?
This is Mark Drysdale, a friend of mine.
Or rather, a partner.
Mark, meet Melinda Griffin,
my best friend from home.
Hello, very nice to meet you, Melinda.
I am really very sorry,
That I have disturbed you.
- But you didn't interfere at all,
I only came here for...
I have to go now.
Have you checked with these papers?
"International Singles Rally.
"Computer Dating with Captain Hill."
"Performances at the Millionaires' Club."
Did you take advantage of everything?
- No, just from a date with Captain Hill.
See what I found.
Sorry, can't believe I missed it
I'm really happy to see you.
- Me too.
Gosh, you look great,
- Thank you.
You also look good.
I put something on.
Then how long did you come for?
- Forever.
- As much as that?
It's too long, my roommate will be angry.
- I'm not talking about your apartment, Debbie.
But about Washington.
I left Ohio for good.
It was a great pleasure to meet you, Melinda.
Look what happened to me.
Cheryl!
This is my friend from home,
Melinda Griffin.
It's nice to meet you Melinda.
- Nice to meet you too, Cheryl.
Don't be surprised, this is normal with her.
But he's a great guy,
He has everything I've always dreamed of.
He is rich, strong, sensitive,
caring and rich.
You got to know each other two days ago.
- But for that, in-depth.
Lester Chadsworth III.
He teaches me accounting.
- Accounting?
- He likes my potential.
- That's nice.
Cheryl, do you mind,
to have Melinda stay with us, for a while?
- But no.
If you don't mind the couch.
I don't want to cause trouble.
I'll find some housing.
- Are you kidding, do you know what prices are
in this city?
You will stay with us.
- Yes.
Thanks. And as soon as I get some work,
I'll contribute to the rent.
Do you type?
- Yes, 80 words per minute.
Maybe we can get you a job.
We both work at the Pentagon.
- Pentagon?
I would love to work there.
This is the most stimulating work
in Washington.
- Stimulating?
We are just secretaries.
- No matter what, you are working for the country.
Right.
They are doing it again.
What do they do?
Mark believes this makes you burn calories.
Well, let's celebrate.
Here's to Melinda's new life in Washington.
I'll drink to that and the three P's.
- What three P's.
Kisses, caresses, fucking.
And for having fun.
As much fun as possible.
- Here's to having fun.
And for a better government.
Sorry.
The top?
- No, the bottom.
Thank God.
Hi Melinda, I talked to my boss,
He will definitely find you a job.
Really? That's wonderful,
I don't know how to thank you.
- Don't thank me just him.
Come on.
I'm not going to work here?
Hi Mark, remember Melinda?
I did not recognize the gentleman without the cap.
Sit down please.
Lieutenant Cranston, this is Captain Drysdale.
- How are you doing, Mark?
There's the young lady I told you about at my place.
Melinda.
So maybe I'll send it to you.
- What does it look like?
We're talking through a microphone, jerk.
His office is the third door away.
Lt. Cranston.
Thank you captain.
- Pleasure on my side.
I show her the city,
So we won't meet today.
I can't meet either.
- Really?
Why?
- What difference does it make, you can't anyway.
- Where are you going?
- And I ask you?
- After all, I told you.
So you don't need to ask.
- No matter what.
- I'm going to miss it.
I studied political science,
so I have the required knowledge.
Let's get something straight, Melinda.
This is the Public Information section.
Our main function is
Preparing information worthy of publication.
Showing the army in a positive light.
And passing them on to the media.
This sounds equally fascinating.
Let me show you something fascinating.
In short, it is not hard work.
Quite relaxing.
If you know what I mean.
It's all about the best possible stories,
That can be shared with the media, right?
Let me take care of it, okay?
- Sure.
Can I ask you a personal question?
- Of course.
Are you married?
- Don't.
Mistake.
So Melinda doesn't mind
Working on weekends?
Not all of them, of course.
Only when necessary.
- No, it can be.
Is the boyfriend okay with it?
- I don't have a boyfriend.
Such an attractive woman doesn't have a boyfriend?
You must be feeling lonely.
- Do you have any more questions, Lieutenant?
Let me ask you Melinda,
what do you think about the population in India?
- What's wrong with her?
They have overpopulation, so they could probably use a
birth control program.
And they have one. They have clinics,
where they teach birth control methods.
And where they hand out contraceptives.
I'm glad you support birth control.
What methods do you use?
- I don't think it's related...
- It's nothing personal,
Just government procedures.
If you don't want to answer...
Well, I guess that's it.
- So what should I do now?
Go home and wait for a call?
- Don't.
Take these press releases,
and get to work.
You mean I got the job?
- That's right.
15 thousand a year,
medical care and raises.
That's great, thank you.
Good luck Melinda.
We will definitely fit together.
Thank you.
You guys are finally done screwing around,
While I'm talking...
Lieutenant Cranston?
What the hell are you talking about?
General Kane... it was just...
such a joke.
No sir, this will not happen again.
- That's a good thing.
Thank you very much.
One margherita. For me, too.
And for me.
At my expense.
Next on mine.
I'm Sidney, this is Michael,
and that one is Steve.
I'm Debbie, this is Cheryl
and Melinda.
Pleasure.
It's hard to talk through the noise.
It doesn't hurt to go out anyway.
I haven't seen you here before.
- We go out a lot.
But mostly to very expensive
restaurants.
Melinda is here for the first time.
She has just arrived.
- Where from.
- From a small town in Ohio.
In the south they go to bed early.
- And what do you do for a living?
We work at the Pentagon.
- That means we should know you.
And what do you guys do?
- We are lawyers.
"Casey Hubbell & Smith.
Which ones are you?
- None, they are the owners, they are dead.
Where are you from?
Attention, someone here is targeting a permanent relationship.
- We accepted.
Remember he needs motivation.
I thought we had two bachelors,
But there are three.
Yes Melinda, tell them.
Yes, for the three P's. Kisses, caresses, and....
- Fun.
Oh Sidney, I don't want to live without you anymore.
Tell me more about your mother.
- I'll be right back.
- Wait, where are you going?
- I have to go to the bathroom.
- Will I see you again?
- You will see me when I return.
I would like you to handle my case.
A week ago I tripped on a slippery floor.
My case is quite like this one.
Mason vs. Janowicz. I researched it.
What is with you?
- Nothing, and what should be?
- What do you think was going to happen
After arriving here?
- I thought we would sit down, talk,
and get to know each other better.
After all, we are talking.
But I think we could get to know each other
even better.
Like our friends.
- I don't like it that way.
I don't go to bed with someone
whom I hardly know.
- Don't you know?
I told you the story of my life.
My parents' divorce.
How I had surgery as a child.
About my brother's alcoholism.
How my dog died.
How I walked 5 miles to school.
Through the snow.
And you say you don't know me?
- Michael, it's nothing personal.
I just ...
I don't believe in casual sex.
Why do you think God put us on earth
as male and female?
This is what we are supposed to do.
That was God's plan.
- But not mine,
I want to do something else.
You are so beautiful, I'm serious.
Someone already told you that?
See how tense your neck is.
Let yourself get a massage.
My neck is fine, Michael.
I can read from your hand,
take a look at this line.
Te jes unusual...
- You squish my hand.
Are you injured?
We'll remedy that right away.
Don't you ever give up?
I'm surprised you live alone.
Just trust me.
I will do anything for you.
Hello, I need to fix my typewriter.
It is not working.
Two weeks?
This is ridiculous, I work
In Public Information.
Yes.
Official notification of the defect?
In three exemlpages?
Yes, I understand.
Sorry, Lieutenant, but I reported
typewriter repair.
Can I do something in the meantime?
Whatever you feel like.
Hi Melinda.
I'm going out, all right?
- Yes, I just wanted to arrange the file.
- You can take a break.
- Am I taking a break? I thought it was important.
- What's important, Melinda, is reciprocal relationships.
Sit in my chair.
For everything to work smoothly,
we need to be one team.
One for all
And all for one.
This is the most important principle, do you agree?
- I agree.
We are the American team of the
Department of Defense.
We are like the "Devil's Cowboys."
I'm the quarterback, and you....
you're on defense.
We need to get to know each other.
To be able to adjust and synchronize the work of the
of the two bodies.
To make it work as one. Do you understand?
- Yes.
Right.
You have to receive the signals that are sent.
- You are the boss.
When I throw the ball, you catch it.
- Yes.
And if I catch,
I'll catch it hard.
Like in soccer, you know?
- I never played, but checking the records....
Leave the files.
I'm talking about playing, I'm talking about catching.
Catching balls
Send signal. 1, 2, 3.
How about a Chinese evening?
How about you Melinda?
- It could be.
Can I ask you guys something?
- Sure.
Does everyone here work like that?
- You mean?
My work actually consists
of doing nothing.
I arranged the file and sent the materials
to Roldex.
But I mainly spend my time defending myself
from a sex maniac.
- And what did you expect?
- Probably something else.
- Relax Melinda, you don't work for the government.
- I don't think anyone works for him.
What's going on?
Disappeared. All information on the
Russian defense system,
simply disappeared.
- All of them?
- The ones from computers.
About the number of their submarines
in the atlantic.
Military deployment in Eastern Europe.
I'm sick of it.
I'm telling you, it's the work of a spy.
Smart and well-trained.
- Double clever.
Someone as unscrupulous as you,
should not use such words.
Now listen, it's top secret.
There must be no leaks.
- Absolute confidentiality.
- This is good, I like it.
Absolute confidentiality.
I heard that someone last night
cleared out the computer archives.
- You are joking.
- I'm not kidding.
It has dusted off all information
on Russian defense.
- Who could have done it?
- A wily treacherous mole.
Hey, how's it going?
When I saw that it didn't work,
I remembered...
That I had the same.
Thanks a lot.
Do you know what happened in the computer archive?
- No, what?
Some spy broke in,
and deleted all the information,
About Russian defense.
- It's scary.
Absolute confidentiality.
If the machine was messing up,
call me.
Hey Melinda!
- Debbie, I've already heard the terrible news.
Some Russian spy broke into the
into a computer archive,
And deleted the data.
- I know, the manicurist told me about it.
Don't worry,
we have no control over it.
For that, I just met the sweetest guy.
- What.
- He was waiting in my office for Drysdel.
He is a major, having just returned
from West Germany.
He conducted exercises at the Frankfurt base.
He has been married for eight years and has two children.
But he wants to leave his wife,
He is not happy with her.
She is frigid, hasn't had an orgasm in years
and it's driving him crazy.
She is also a terrible hostess.
And every time she comes home
she has curlers in her hair.
He's tall and we have similar intimations.
We both enjoy swimming
And going for long walks....
You learned so much,
While he was waiting in your office?
- Drysdale was about five minutes late.
Debbie, sometimes it's hard to believe.
Great, I'll be right there.
We will talk later at the gym.
If you haven't run away with it by now.
This is very important.
It will go to staff, major news and the Pentagon.
"Dear Colonel Rogers.
Army swimming championship.
They cannot be held at Camp Drummond this year.
Because they don't have a pool there.
As a result, the army decided,
That the championship will be held in Fort Culver.
Where they have a swimming pool."
Lieutenant, I can't concentrate,
when you do that.
Focus on the team, Melinda.
Should I read it to you?
- You don't.
The most important thing is the division of roles,
so that everyone does their own thing.
This will allow us to increase the chances.
And achieve success.
Under this garment you must hide
a magnificent body.
Soft and firm to the touch.
Lieutenant Cranston.
You hired me as a secretary.
My responsibilities include,
typing,
Taking care of files, answering phones,
And the rest of routine office work.
On the other hand, kissing and groping me,
do not fall into this category.
When you are ready to finish this letter,
I'll be outside.
I heard that Paul is
very angry.
- Is he mad at me?
I'm the one who's mad at him.
You have to be careful what you do.
Such a job is very difficult to get,
and very easy to lose.
- Do you know what he did?
While dictating the letter
He grabbed me by the breast.
- He could catch me whenever he wants,
He's such a cool teddy bear.
- Cheryl, this is my job,
I can't work like this.
He is my boss, not my boyfriend.
I have not encountered anything like this anywhere.
Melinda, we are not "nowhere".
Only in the US capital.
You won't need it.
You have certain responsibilities here,
that you don't seem to understand.
And I don't mean coffee brewing.
- Is there anything else I can do for you?
- Yes, get undressed, and do it now.
- What?
Attention!
Lt. Cranston prefers that you do not come
next week.
So at the end of the week
you can collect your paycheck.
Ms. Perkins, I would like to clarify.
- This will not be necessary.
- It's not my fault.
- It never is, is it?
That would be all.
I will take the key to the bathroom, if you can.
- I'll bring.
Is that what you've been doing all morning?
- No, this is my costume for the weekend party.
See this?
- What are you talking about?
Masked Ball at "Cassie Hubbel & Smith"
- They are dead.
- I know.
Lawyers whom we sptk arranged them.
Michael has already forgiven you for your broken head.
- As nice as it is, he better
not cancel the ambulance.
What's wrong with her?
- Today she was fired.
What, you didn't want to pretend to be a prisoner of war?
- A prisoner of war?
- He plays along with all the secretaries.
This is the only way you can satisfy the lieutenant.
In any case, you must come to the party,
Friday night.
I have to change my clothes.
I think I just figured out,
How you can get your job back.
Bounce the ball.
- How.
- File a lawsuit with a firm of dead lawyers
For sexual harassment?
- Give it a rest.
One thing Cranston doesn't like,
is when a girl accosts him.
He always has to be Mr. tough guy.
He's nuts about it.
Start molesting him,
and he'll get as soft as a teddy bear.
Turn it into a puppy
- I can't do it, Debbie.
It's not my style.
- That's fine, do as you please,
But you are unemployed.
Think about it.
- How do you know he doesn't like it?
- Trust me, I know.
I can't say that.
And I won't be able to even in a million years.
That's not me.
- Just pretend to be someone else.
Like Mata Hari, or Mae West.
- I can't do it.
- You can.
- I can't.
- You have to. Do you want to get your job back?
- Yes.
- Do you want to work at the Pentagon serving the country?
- Do you want to teach Cranston a lesson,
And overcome your own fears?
- Yes.
- So you can do that.
- I can do it.
Show him.
Am I talking to Lieutenant Cranston?
- That's right.
- I have an obscene call for you.
Do you agree to pay for the call?
- Is this some kind of joke?
- No, it's not a joke.
- Very indecent, or just a little?
- Wonderfully indecent.
- I agree.
I would like to... slowly undress you.
And I would like to wander with my tongue.
All over your body.
On your shoulders,
your chest.
I would lick my way lower
along your belly.
And finally just then
I would take it in my mouth.
And I would go further
But don't worry, I'm licking on.
In the stifle of your leg.
And then the other.
And then you explode.
And I'll take into my mouth everything....
What you give me.
Is that all you're going to tell me?
Who is talking?
- Melinda, your former secretary.
Please be at the office tomorrow,
at nine o'clock.
- I'm looking forward to it.
That's until tomorrow, boy
Dear Diary, I will say goodbye for now.
It was nice to record all this
over the years.
But I have a feeling,
I'm going to be very busy right now.
Washington is now in a
A terrible mess.
So starting tomorrow I'm going to start
to do some cleanup here.
Melinda?
In the flesh.
Sexy enough, lieutenant?
- So very sexy.
- Right.
I like guys who are as hard as a rock.
What's the matter?
Don't you like how I kiss?
Is that all you're going to say?
I thought I was attractive to you.
- You don't play fair.
- Did I do something wrong?
I'm the quarterback, remember?
I send signals.
- Bottom line.
So start playing out.
Send the signal.
I'm waiting for the ball to be passed.
You don't understand anything,
I can't play like that.
I'm the one who sends the signals,
And we play by my rules.
Sit down.
- What?
I said, sit down.
That's an order, Lieutenant.
Here you have correspondence from...
1968, it's shameful.
Let's do some work.
- Right
Completed.
Quite.
- Still last year's correspondence.
Now we will play my game.
My favorite.
A prisoner of war.
- And yes, a prisoner of war.
- That's right, you'll like it.
- Really?
- Yes, you have just been captured
Middle Eastern guerrillas.
- Yes?
- Exactly.
Interpol has prepared a rescue operation.
I stand at the head of it.
I will save you.
- It's okay, boy.
You'll have to do your best.
Count to 50.
One Mississippi, two Mississippi....
Breaker 10-4, this is Pixie.
Come on Melinda, are you there?
- Yes, Lieutenant, you have to help me.
They did terrible things to me.
They want to hound me.
- Don't let them.
Help me!
Hurry up lieutenant,
Before it's too late.
- I'm on my way, Melinda.
Help is on the way.
I'll rescue you, where are you?
- They are already doing it to me. Not so hard!
I can't take it anymore.
Faster Lieutenant.
They torture me.
- No, don't let them.
Where are you?
- I'm at the bottom.
Bottom Line.
Did you understand?
Yes, I want it, yes.
- No!
I'm going to kill everyone!
I think someone shouted
On the third floor.
You'd better check it out.
- I will.
My God. Succinct.
Code red.
They detected us!
Smash them.
That's right, sons of bitches.
Whoever you are,
come out with your paws up.
- Let my secretary out first.
You are supposed to fire her.
We have another one, bring on the straitjacket.
Drop your weapons and hand over my secretary.
- You throw yours then we will too.
- I do not negotiate with terrorists.
It's my game, so you throw first.
- Then maybe we'll drop our guns at the same time.
I'll count to three and we'll put it away.
Ready?
- Do you promise?
- We promise.
I will get you.
No please, let me go.
I'm not a crazy person.
- We know. Do you work for us?
Yes, in the information section.
Melinda, I will save you!
Don't say anything to them!
Too many bullets here.
In the corner.
Excuse me.
- Melinda?
- Do we know each other?
- It's me, Michael.
I told you the story of my life.
- Yes. I'm sorry for the blow.
Sorry, I have to find Debbie.
- Wait, maybe we'll have dinner.
Would you like to hear more about my life?
Debbie, I did it, ripped into his game.
- Then what are you doing here?
- I decided to drop in.
- I like your costume.
Who was it?
- It was Major Magnus, head of military intelligence.
- This major? That's it for now.
Sorry, I want you.
I think you are the most beautiful woman
I have ever seen.
- Thank you.
- My name is Abdul Undine
- Pleasure.
- I am a direct male
I would be honored if you
accompany me after the party.
- I am a direct woman.
Forget.
- I can solicit you much more.
- Really?
- I can give you money, diamonds,
yachts, carpets, everything.
Let's do it darling.
- Right.
But in the pool.
Sorry.
I think you are the most beautiful woman,
I have ever seen.
My entire staff is working on it.
They comb through the files,
they check every shred of backup,
On Russian defense.
How long will it take to put this together?
- Not so long.
- That is, how long?
- About three years.
- Three years?
It is necessary to sort it all out.
- What will we do with Russia during this time?
- We are working on it.
Okay, how long will it take you?
- A few years.
- What about our spy satellites?
- The problem is that we can't
reprogram them.
But we are working on a plan.
We will send out new satellites
and we'll get everything we want.
- Okay, how long will it take?
- Several years before they get everything ready.
It's a disaster.
- I know that.
There must be something we can do now.
I will probably never sleep again.
- Neither will I.
Now I regret that I am responsible for being
a responsible patriot.
Twice you said "responsible."
- Of course, with someone as responsible as me,
this word should be used twice....
Major.
- Yes?
- I have confidential materials for you.
- Really?
- How did you know?
Major Magnus' office.
Melinda, the new secretary, said.
The major is just busy.
I will definitely be able to help.
I have access to secret data.
Sorry agent Bluedevil,
this code is inactive.
Please check the access code
of the new package.
Yes, I will inform the major.
Sir, the press corps is here.
Can they come in?
- Oh, yes.
I'll be right there.
Please click here.
Who goes.
- The press corps, sir.
They had an appointment at 10;00.
O 10;00.
So I will accept them.
Major Magnus, is it true,
That the pentagon
lost secret data on Russia?
Secret data? But why?
We have the right to know everything,
that goes on behind that desk.
- Nothing happens behind that desk.
You are very tense,
Is something bothering you?
- No, no, everything is fine.
Recently, the military has dragged
the country into a major affair.
You are not in good shape major.
It seems that officers spend too much time
spend behind a desk.
- But I like my desk.
We wanted to find out what happened
With the pentagon's computer archive?
- Rubbish.
- How do we communicate this to the
American public?
I apologize to you, but Mr. Major
is indisposed today.
He seems to react strongly to something....
What he could eat.
Tomorrow afternoon he will certainly answer
all your questions.
Now please forgive me.
Please do not get up, we will hit the exit.
I am linking to Melinda Griffin's office.
Melinda wants them to be rigged.
Melinda asks for data from the computer.
These are reports for Melinda.
If you think you can change
the prevailing work rules here, young lady.
That's not going to happen.
- Ms. Perkins.
If someone here distributes functions.
Or is hiring.
This is me.
- I know.
The chain of command applies here.
And I will not let it be broken.
Colonel Brian's office.
He is busy at the moment.
I may be able to help.
The Pentagon has its standard procedures,
and top-notch staff.
Composed of the best experts in the world.
I would rather not disturb
General Drake.
I will speak with the Secretary of State.
I warn you, young lady.
Never do it again.
Yes senator,
now we need this information.
General Watson and I are on our way.
Bergen doesn't appeal to me.
General Watson. I can't believe it,
how high you've gone.
- You could, too, if you wanted to.
- I don't know,
maybe one day.
Watch how you drive, jerk.
- First, learn to drive.
- Do you think I'm undoing the first time?
- The mistake was me undoing it.
Melinda, tell that bastard,
Who reversed first.
- I don't know, I haven't seen it.
Don't we know each other?
- Come on, buddy.
Do you think we were born yesterday?
Ashtabula.
- That's right, Ashtabula. How's it going?
How's it going?
- Great, how about you? What are you doing at the Pentagon?
He is responsible for traffic accidents.
Can I see the driver's license?
I work here.
- No kidding, that's great.
I was counting on you to succeed.
Well, sure, you will pay for the damages
Slater?
- That's right, Bill Slater.
You also look familiar to me.
- It was actually my fault.
Nothing has happened.
Let's go, or we'll be late for the opera.
- Opera? Debbie, after all, we ...
- Debbie Ross.
Do you know Debbie?
- Yes, she's the one who took my clips.
Well, I wanted to give it back to you.
- You can keep it.
I would really like to go out with you,
But I have a date...
- That's okay, I'm going out with Melinda today.
- Seriously?
- Seriously.
I had a great time.
- So did I.
We will have to do it again.
- Maybe we could have a cup of coffee?
- Rather not.
It's late, and I'm up in the morning.
I like you.
I want to get to know you better.
Will you call?
- Yes.
You will disappoint me,
If you don't.
- I will call.
Good night.
General Kane.
- Thank goodness you are.
I don't know what to do.
- What is the problem, sir?
- This is a key issue in terms of
security of our country.
- Really?
According to our data, you are the
the most competent,
and a trusted Pentagon employee.
- Thank you, sir.
You can't squeak a word
about what I'm about to tell you.
This is top secret information,
Ms. Griffin.
- You can trust me, I won't say a word.
Two months ago, a spy
broke into the computer room,
and deleted all data
on Russian defense systems.
- Yes it's terrible, I've heard about it
When they repaired the typewriter for me.
- Do they know, too?
The press is asking questions.
You shouldn't, General.
I have to, I'm in serious trouble.
And I need help.
Please sit comfortably and relax.
What should I do now?
They will probably take away my stars.
I already know, sir.
Please listen.
I must have an invitation to tomorrow's party,
For the Russian ambassador.
- Of course, whatever you want.
Thank you.
Well Boris, you look healthy.
You have to introduce me
This beautiful woman.
I would like to introduce you to Miss Melinda Griffin.
Melinda, this is Mr. Boris Nabokov,
Russian ambassador.
It is a great pleasure for me
to get to know such an extraordinary being.
- Thank you, Mr. Ambassador.
And this is my secretary Tania,
with a name that is too long,
To pronounce them here.
Pleasure.
Say Boris, it's true,
That a few of yours have escaped
From the Bolshoi Ballet during performances here?
- Please, today is not the time for business,
Only for pleasure.
We can move our mutual relations
by a big step forward.
Boris, meet my friend.
An excellent chess player.
I see you have caught the eye of my boss.
You speak excellent English.
And also French, Hebrew,
Moroccan, and Italian,
In sign and party language.
- And are you a secretary?
But also a political advisor, astrologer,
oriental masseuse,
tennis coach and sex instructor.
- A sexual instructor?
- All Russian diplomats
have sexual instructors.
This means that you do not provide
such services....
For their country?
- I often give tips, but mostly
I work behind a desk.
- Probably for a good tip.
We have a lot in common,
we should get to know each other better
- Of course.
Even if you smash with missiles
western europe.
Still ours will get you.
And actually we all want the same thing.
I guess you won't deny it?
- Yes, of course.
- What's that?
- Meaning that I...
- That you agree with us?
Then why don't you accept our
zero option?
- If Melinda is that option....
- He will certainly agree to anything,
In the service of the country.
She is a true patriot.
- In that case, I am in favor of it.
This means you will support disarmament,
and start dismantling
European installations,
If we do the same thing?
- I will talk to the prime minister later today.
But I'll have to see what Melinda says.
I will end the cold war for you, Melinda.
- That would be great, Mr. Ambassador.
I just found out,
That the rules at the Pentagon,
Are the same as in the Kremlin.
I suggested for you to
end the Cold War.
- You are teasing me, and that is not nice.
- I'm serious.
Fly to Bermuda with me that night,
And I will withdraw the stupid missiles from Europe.
- It's impossible,
I have to go to work tomorrow.
- No Bermuda.
I told you,
American girls are not
so liberated.
That is, no Bermuda,
then maybe let's go to my place.
- Just a moment, maybe I'll give you a number,
and you will call me....
And have breakfast together.
What can I write on?
If Comrade Khrushchev saw you,
he would no longer let you go.
Do I look good?
- Fantastic.
You look great, go now.
- I know, I just think,
Bill is special.
- I always knew he was cute.
Where it takes you
- Sightseeing.
- For a date?
Some women are pleased
The presence of a man.
Without flaunting money
- I've had that happen, too.
If the ambassador calls,
Let him leave a message.
Do you think Lester
would take me sightseeing?
Come on, they close in 20 minutes.
- Tyko put the briefcase in the trunk.
What's going on?
Who are you?
Let me go.
Help!
Good evening, Melinda.
I'm glad to see you.
Now I would like you to satisfy
my voyeuristic tastes.
Please take off your shoes,
and show me your feet.
- I don't think so, Excellency.
Please without titles,
call me Boris
Why don't you show me your shoulders?
- No chance Boris.
How about a piece of the belly?
- What kind of girl do you take me for?
I think you know,
That we both know that Melinda.
Let me show you.
How do you like my outfit?
- Charming.
Do you like it when men watch
As you undress?
I can organize it.
- Not necessary, but thank you.
You mean to say...
What are you actually trying to say?
Are you teasing?
You're fast, Boris.
I hope you will satisfy me.
Because you see...
I have to confess something to you.
No American has ever managed to
Satisfy me.
- What a shame, Americans are such faggots,
they lack balls.
- Sad, but true.
Americans can do this
for two, maybe three hours one night.
But a real Russian Cossack
Even by...
10 or 11 hours
won't let me get there.
You remind me of Cossack, Boris.
- How many hours were you talking about?
- It's not just about time,
but also volume or range.
- Range?
- After all, it's no problem for you.
I know that all rusks
have tank barrels there.
- It's not always hammers,
sometimes sickles.
- Don't worry.
Jetem sure you will confirm in full,
your reputation.
That's my next point Kevin.
We have to assume that she was abducted by the Russians.
Although for now we are treating it
as a possibility.
Not necessarily true.
- Because there is a possibility,
that only
They were impersonating Russians.
Trying to put the blame on them.
Let's order more avocados and tomatoes.
- The press can't find out,
Until we are sure
Who is behind it.
I said no tuna.
I ordered ham and cheese.
I would like to see these treasures of yours.
Take off your clothes, please.
- I'm not cheap, Boris.
- So name your price.
- It's a secret.
- If you don't tell me,
how will I know.
- This secret you
must reveal to me.
- To you?
I don't understand.
- If I have to take off this blouse....
And show you the firmest titties
in this time zone.
Remove.
How many do you have in the Atlantic
Nuclear ships?
- It's secret,
I can't tell you.
Now I understand.
I can't say.
My lips are sealed.
- How badzo?
- Very.
- Nothing can be done?
- Not a bit.
How many ships...
How many nuclear ships?
So she may know some secret information,
When she worked for the Pentagon.
- The Russians know everything anyway.
- Maybe it's a jealous lover?
- Or some kind of pervert.
Before I pull down my panties,
you must see this pair of legs,
And see where they lead.
- I really want to see them.
Give the location of the radar station
tracking our bombers.
- I can't tell you that.
Over my dead body.
- No?
- Never...
New top-secret installation.
Where is it?
Here you go.
In Yarkutsk, Siberia.
I think it might have been the Russians,
to sabotage my entire operation.
- Are you serious?
Here is mayonnaise, and I said,
I don't want it.
I hate mayonnaise.
Surely you know the access code,
to the Kremlin's military computer.
- I can't.
Even if you were to electrocute me.
Or she burned with cigarettes.
I can't say that.
Never.
- Don't you want to try a soft, sweet...
Access code for a military computer.
Exactly.
Access code.
This is the date of Karl Marx's birth.
She may have been spying for the CIA.
The Russians have discovered this
and are holding it as a hostage.
They will exchange it for one of the ones held with us
their spies.
We have several of them, don't we?
- Yes, but none with such boobs.
Now it's time to warm up.
- I thought we had already done it.
- I have my toys here.
- That's cool.
Let's have some fun.
What do you feel like doing?
- I think for.
I love rough play.
American women are so perky.
Come on.
You will pay for it my little Tsarina.
What happened to free love?
That's what I like.
- Agreed, Boris.
Be it to you.
- What are you doing?
- I'm going home.
Help.
Hello gentlemen.
Here you go.
I have been quite busy lately,
conducting reconnaissance.
Friends helped me copy
in triplicate,
all the lost information
from our computers.
- In addition, we have developed a strategy
to paralyze
Russian radar system.
Tracking our bombers.
- This maneuver has a 100% success rate.
We have a willing staff and a guarantee of
lack of retaliation by the Soviet Union.
- The goal is.
Jarkuck in Siberia.
Dimitri.
- Is that all you have to say?
Won't you take care of something else?
- It has been 7 years, 9 months,
and 22 days.
7 years, 9 months, and 22 days
without a woman.
You don't even know.
- Stop it already...
What is it?
- Probably a penguin.
- A penguin, or maybe a Koala bear.
Need to check.
We have a problem, Vladimir.
Wait, let me zoom in.
It seems to be an invasion.
Paratroopers everywhere.
By the spirit of Lenin, we are already dead.
They are everywhere.
Oh my......,
- What happened?
- This is exactly what we dreamed of.
- About the attack?
Just look at those tits.
- Show?
The sky is full of them.
- Flooding.
This one will be mine.
- Please.
I love you.
- I plead with you, Dimitri.
I need to see.
I want a blonde.
- Get those paws off.
America is beautiful.
And what, should we shoot?
- No, we have to check it first.
I'm quitting this job.
- Me too.
Evening.
Officially announced by the Pentagon
passive action,
code-named "Sky Beavers."
has proven to be extremely effective.
Apparently, radar operators
throughout the Soviet Union.
Under mysterious circumstances
they abandon their posts.
Many ask about the reasons for their behavior.
Here's another seemingly unrelated one,
but surprising
telegram from the White House.
The president has asked Congress
for approval of
new cabinet member.
It looks like we will have
the first female
As Secretary of Defense.