Strategy Planning Committee
Section chief's here. Gather round.
Section Chief...
Let's get this investigation underway.
Mr. Aoshima, it's not an investigation.
You're right...
Let's get this office relocation underway.
Our new precinct is ready at last.
We only have 3 days to move.
To make it in time for the
opening ceremony
we must be quick and
efficient and get it done.
Such are the orders from on high.
Make your reports.
Cardboard boxing of personal
effects is on schedule.
Phone lines and
data networks are in place.
Okay, casualty status?
Casualties?
A traffic bureau member sustained a
finger wound lifting a locker.
He's undergoing treatment.
That's not important.
It's very important.
The transfer of vital records
wasn't properly monitored.
Who was responsible?
Community Safety Bureau.
Some records were found
mixed up in the trash.
There must be evidence.
Get forensics on it.
Find who dropped the ball
Aoshima, my lad.
Time's running out.
Let's wrap it up.
Guys, I need an all-out effort to
locate the suspect.
There isn't one.
An all-out effort to execute the office move.
Precinct Relocation Strategy
Planning Committee.
Good job,
Relocation Strategy Superintendent.
Thank you
I'm going to nail this damn thing
Chief, the tourism bureau's copier
sustained heavy damage.
What the heck...
Damage control. Deploy repair unit.
Huh...
Okay, let's roll!
The Bayside Precinct move is
underway at last.
I wonder if that man's a detective?
Looks like he's running away.
Good morning, everyone.
You can chuck those out.
Thanks, guys.
Ogata, not packed yet? You're behind!
The most behind is you, Chief.
Maybe
Things you want to take, go in here.
Stuff you're dumping, in here.
This is for trash, eh?
That's easy.
I don't need this.
Gross
Kuriyama, shall I start packing for you?
Mashita's old sweater? Oh, well...
Do I need this?
It's up to you to choose.
There it is.
Is that all junk, then?
Seems so.
Untidy guys... never get the girl.
Only take the bare minimum, okay?
One box each to keep costs down, okay?
You guys, please have health
check-ups by month's end.
Can these go in your box?
One's not enough.
You've that much stuff?
Of course.
Just chuck it out.
Can't live without 'em, buddy.
Section Chief Aoshima.
How impressive. Pardon me for
being rank-and-file.
Will you help, Ms. Onda?
Some people hold up promotion
Aoshima, my lad!
It's all on schedule, sir.
No, it's your health check-up.
Doc wants you to call.
What for?
Accounts asks if today's
noodles are on expenses?
Noodles?
Of course not. I'll go tell 'em.
The chief's on his way.
What about the doctor?
Tokyo Metropolitan Police
New Bayside Precinct.
Tell me about the new facility.
It's close to the airport to
protect visiting dignitaries.
That's what they say.
And close to infrastructure sites
that terrorists might target.
That's what they say.
Wow...
It has the ultimate in
anti-terrorist security systems.
In an emergency,
the entrance and other vital areas.
Detective Bureau
can be sealed from intrusion by a
solid metal shield.
That's what they say.
This is where we hold
investigative meetings.
Will there be administrative changes?
The chief and deputy are to retire.
It's unknown who'll take over.
That's what they say.
What?
Is that right?
Nobody told me.
The rumor is everywhere.
Only a rumor?
You sent a chill down my spine.
A successor was unofficially announced.
Then it's a done deal? We're history.
Ms. Onda,
the local bank's reporting a robbery.
At a time like this?
Let's go, Sumire.
Nobody touch my stuff, okay?
Keep working, okay?
For chrissakes...
What a mess he makes!
Goddamn section chief...
What about noodles?
Noodles?
The rookies should learn it's tradition to
eat noodles when we move.
Police H.Q. To all forces.
Reporting a bus hijacking near the
Rainbow Bridge.
One city bus involved, heading west.
Chief!
Stop the packing. Let's go.
Hey, Kuriyama!
Where's my coat?
Where's my damn coat?
Bayside Precinct, Robbery Division.
This way.
Thank you for coming.
An employee found it open this morning.
The lock isn't broken.
How did they open it?
It can be unlocked through our network.
Anti-theft system?
No alert to the security company, either.
The network was probably cracked.
Another thing.
Nothing was stolen.
Let's wait for forensics.
Wait here, please.
If you open it, steal something,
for chrissakes.
That's the bus.
Let's wait for the higher-ups.
No way.
But we're not armed.
Think of the hostages.
Natsumi, it's dangerous.
They're being held.
Where's the perp?
Gone?
Where did they go?
They left a while ago.
They left?
Are you okay?
How many were there?
Five... wearing masks.
They pulled out knives.
Not knives... scalpels.
Like doctors use.
They made us give up our wallets.
Then they took 'em.
No, they're here.
They left without taking them.
Search outside.
Nobody hurt?
Are you okay?
Hijack a bus so at least steal something.
Official Personnel Only.
Sir, this is the internal affairs bureau.
This place is impervious to any
external threat.
Really? But we walked in easily.
Now you mention it...
Strolling around like this,
we must look very suspicious.
Right... how come we got in?
That door's open, too.
That's just asking to be robbed.
What's in there?
Looks interesting...
Yours, too?
And yours?
Mine, yes.
Victimless crimes.
Perfectly executed.
Many similarities, well-coordinated.
But how weird that nothing was stolen.
The crooks gave us a
break because of the relocation.
Not a time to joke.
Careful with my instant ramen supplies
I'll take care of it.
Sorry to trouble you.
Is this criminal affairs?
That's right.
Help me, Aoshima.
Anyone seen my coat?
Sorry to bother you.
Section Chief Aoshima?
Have you seen my coat?
Who are you?
Sorry not to say. My name is Waku.
Waku?
Did you say "Waku"?
Your long-term colleague,
Detective Waku
was my father's brother;
in other words, my uncle.
Really?
Today I was assigned to
the serious crimes section.
Here's an introductory gift.
Guys, he's Mr. Waku's nephew!
Turn to the side.
So Mr. Waku's nephew
became a cop, too?
What a coincidence you came here.
Superintendent Muroi
suggested I work under you.
He did?
Here's today's schedule.
The public safety commissioner will be
here soon. This is the agenda.
National Police Agency
Commissioner-General Secretariat.
Lunch is with the deputy commissioner
and the justice minister.
Which restaurant do you prefer?
I'll talk to the section chief.
We finished the bus hijack survey.
Well done.
No-one saw anything
before or after the crime.
No physical evidence, no prints.
What about your report?
You look busy, I'll e-mail it.
I'm just a trainee.
Here's your health report.
Listen, everyone.
There are similarities with the bank case;
maybe it's the same team.
Right?
Follow up on it.
There are no victims. Let's move office.
I'll have you know...
"All crimes are of equal importance!"
Isn't that right, Mr. Aoshima?
Exactly. Way to go, kid.
What's that?
I got this at my uncle's funeral.
Mr. Waku's notebook?
That line was in here.
Want to read it?
Is that okay?
What's all this?
Detective bureau, you're falling behind!
Finish up here and move.
Show me later, will you?
Aoshima, will you please call the doctor.
I will.
Guys, don't forget health check-ups.
But keep working, though.
Have you drawn-up the night-duty roster?
I will.
It's tough being in charge.
Shall I take over?
New equipment is here, everyone!
It acts as your security card, too.
It'll improve communication
during investigations.
You can have open-channel
conversations network-wide.
What a pain to carry two.
Now I don't need to buy a new one.
Some of them have a projector function
Aoshima... Aoshima...
Quiet!
Aoshima... Sumire...
Come with me.
Pistols?
Mislaid in the chaos of the move.
You mean lost?
Everyone will find out
but for now it's a secret
3 are missing; yours...
...Chinese trainee, Mr. Wang's, and...
Mine?
Don't tell anyone. It's strictly secret.
No time to talk, let's find 'em.
Send out an alert to catch the thieves.
Precinct Chief!
Akiyama, this occurred during
the relocation, right?
Indeed it did, sir.
And Inspector Aoshima's responsible
for the relocation, right?
Indeed he is, sir.
Not my responsibility, is it?
Indeed not, sir.
Keep it under the carpet
until the move is over.
It'll come to light during the
new chief's watch.
It's only 3 pistols, after all.
Grab some confiscated weapons
and hide the loss for the time being.
Nice whitewash, sir.
Don't describe it like that.
Excuse me.
I'm home...
Welcome back.
Here's the receipt.
I bought some snacks.
Not for me, thanks.
Is this real?
It's amazing.
Don't touch it.
Can I help at all?
Box this up
3 pistols lost at the Bayside Precinct.
No way? What are the cops doing?
How could that happen?
Fully-loaded, too.
Another police foul-up.
It's totally unforgivable.
We're going to find these weapons,
right?
Access to the gun room is by
serving officers and
...movers. I'll fetch the guy in charge.
Let's track down any sketchy characters.
"Don't trust hearsay, go see for yourself"
it says here.
Right, get ready to pull an all-nighter.
Can you guys show more enthusiasm?
Not really. We've no experience...
For chrissakes...
We all have to begin somewhere.
Try to kick-off with a bang.
Not literally, Mr. Wang.
What's up, guys?
This smell takes me back
Mashita, what are you doing here?
This place is for demolition, eh?
Still in the negotiations bureau?
Meaning HQ knows about the pistol theft?
I've been let go from negotiations.
What pistol?
It's nothing.
Oh, the pistol thing on the news.
The news?
Reporting from the new Bayside Precinct,
still in mid-relocation.
This morning, in response to a
citizen alarmed at an internet report
the Metropolitan Police confirmed
the loss of 3 fully-loaded pistols
from the new precinct.
We're busted.
Precinct Chief Kanda is due to
speak at any moment.
He looks tired.
Responsibility is a heavy burden.
No, it's make-up.
And that's acting.
Regarding the loss of the pistols during
our move to the new precinct...
I will now make a statement.
He's over-doing it.
Whether the pistols are lost or not
is currently under investigation.
Are they really missing or not?
Is that true or is it not?
Is it or isn't it?
Maybe they are gone,
maybe they aren't gone.
It may be true that we don't know,
or that may not be true.
What's he saying?
Is it unheard of for guns
to go missing this way?
While extremely rare, it's not impossible.
Were precautions taken?
While extremely rare,
we were fully prepared.
It's more than extremely rare.
How will you assign responsibility?
The issue of responsibility...
as precinct chief...
Are you okay, sir?
Our press conference is now over.
How was I?
They're just as my uncle described.
This way.
Here's their main guy
the list of employees...
Who handled internal affairs?
It's here...
This many people?
Including part-timers, we're over 200.
Many from a temp agency.
There are no names here.
Temps are given numbers instead.
We communicate via text.
So you don't know their names?
Many give false names anyway.
A body's been located on a moored boat
in the Odaiba district of the Bayside ward.
Coastguard has secured the location
and requests police investigation.
A body's been located on a moored boat
in the Odaiba district of the Bayside ward.
Coastguard has secured the location
and requests police investigation.
It's a long way.
Let's swap.
No way.
Mr. Aoshima, welcome back.
What's the registration number?
Not mine.
It can't be my fault, can it?
Have you seen my coat?
The investigation is now open.
We heard of the incident at 8:05 today.
Victim profile?
Kazuhiko Kamimura, 25 years old.
No permanent employer but
registered with a temp agency.
Inquiries reveal he was involved
in the precinct move.
He was working here yesterday.
He was shot through the chest.
Death was instant.
We checked for prints and witnesses
but have nothing yet.
Regarding the gun that was used
ballistic profiles match those on file.
It's one of the guns stolen yesterday.
Pardon me for asking,
why is that man standing?
Is it the new precinct chief?
What about the theft?
Officers moved their own guns,
so it didn't occur in transit.
Theft occurred after transport.
The gun room opens with a key
and remotely via network.
The network may have been cracked.
Let's have an all-out search to
locate the suspects.
Only federal investigators will take part.
Local cops must relocate in time for
the mayor's ceremony in 2 days.
Wait a minute. Let us join in.
They were our guns
Aoshima, sit down.
Our guns killed someone.
That was your fault!
So let us join the investigation.
Silence. We don't need you.
Get on with the move.
That's the kind of work you're fit for.
What do you mean by that?
You insisted we build this place for
the non-existent Olympics.
"Be proud of the work of foot-soldiers"
What other work can we do?
You don't know the local area!
Everyone calm down.
I get it.
I know how you feel.
Will you leave things with me?
Anyway, let's sit back down, shall we?
Okay guys, sit down.
I'm administrative liaison, Torigai.
I apologize for any thoughtless words.
After consulting the supervisor
and the precinct chief
the local precinct will join the investigation.
When the Bayside detectives relocate,
so will they.
Federal and local investigators
will buddy up.
How about it, everyone?
Superbly done.
Does he outrank the supervisor?
He's more like an aide.
Probably studied "servant leadership"
Yeah, that servant thing...
Thank you
I look forward to working together,
Mr. Aoshima.
You studied servant leadership, right?
Yes. Federal and local
cops are always fighting.
So a regulatory role like
mine is necessary.
Federal and local cops think different,
act different.
They need steering
towards the same goal.
I appraise their relative strengths
and balance them.
What did you say to the higher-ups?
I suggested the supervisor
make use of you locals.
I told the precinct chief, teaming with the
feds would be good politics.
It's all about calculation.
And using what's at hand.
I see. Mr. Muroi doesn't think on that level.
I wonder about him.
Placing too much faith in the local precincts.
It's a romantic notion but not exactly smart.
Hello
Thanks for letting us in.
You're the landlord, aren't you?
Is something up?
Nothing much...
Since I got the sudden call, I did wonder.
I bet You were surprised.
A computer says a lot about someone.
What are all those files?
Game files... 148 of them.
Chat software, too.
He's into MMORPG's,
massive multiplayer games.
I see...
Our suspect is addicted to online games.
Mr. Aoshima...
This is for you.
Please Do It today.
Chief?
Mr. Aoshima? Sign this, please
Aoshima, lad... did you call the doc?
I know.
I need next month's budget.
You're section chief now.
Don't fob me off.
Relocation supervisor, please sign this.
Done already?
This is the security system manual.
So this is the new place? Smells so fresh.
You're from the traffic bureau...
I'm Taguchi.
I was in the TV show,
"Police Negotiator", it's great.
Who are you?
I can't reveal that yet.
Excuse us.
Don't you know it? It was huge on cable.
Wait a moment...
Bring the mislaid boxes to the
detective bureau, please.
Sort out your desks
then let's hit the investigation!
Mr. Aoshima, found your coat?
Mr. Aoshima, your box arrived.
Here's the manual for the security system.
That whole emergency stronghold thing,
right?
I think you should read it.
It's huge...
Young Mr. Waku...
Study hard.
Yes, sir.
Wow, is this the new investigative bureau?
You guys are...
Kuroda of the traffic bureau.
Here's a DVD of a show I was in.
Check it out.
I was the police advisor.
Hello there. Long time, no see.
You're all negotiators?
So many of you?
Young Mr. Koike!
You negotiate now?
Why are you here?
Former department chief...
Department Chief...
He ditched the glasses.
The victim has logged 10,000 hours
on "Battle of Combat"
There's a community page
on which gamers can chat as they play.
I'm accessing it now.
Anyone want to play?
I'll read it out. "Hello"
"Who are you?"
"Anyone know this guy?"
"I'm Shiora's friend.
Heard about the killing?"
"So what?"
"Who are you?"
"Any of Shiora's friends here?"
"Why?"
"Guys, ignore him"
"Leave him alone"
"I'm a friend of Shiora's"
"What's up, Wild Dog?"
"I'll send you the server. Let's chat direct"
Hi, there.
What's your name and job?
I'm with internal affairs...
He's requesting voice chat.
Here it is.
Wild Dog?
You're a policeman, right?
I need your help.
I want to ask about Shiora.
Did he have any enemies?
Any recent trouble online?
I was waiting for you.
I got a message for you.
There are 2 more guns.
Was it you who stole them?
A crap security system like that won't do.
Bastard
He's accessing through a proxy
relayed via the Philippines.
Proxy settings leave no blog.
We can't get an address.
Hey, Wild Dog...
If you don't meet my demands,
the other 2 guns will soon get busy.
What are the demands?
I've put a file on the server.
Download it from the URL.
It's done. Printing now.
I'll read them out.
"To the Bayside Precinct"
"Set the guys loose"
National Police Agency.
The release of inmates?
If not, the stolen guns
will be used indiscriminately.
Online game buddies,
right? It's just a prank.
Below the mugshots are 2 numbers.
The registration numbers of the 2 pistols.
What do you think, Muroi?
The investigation's just begun.
We wait until it's complete.
But we don't yield to their demands.
We didn't fly you back from the
provinces for a textbook reply.
I told you, I'm too busy.
The doctor made the trip himself.
Here he is. Get in.
Thank you, Doctor.
It's something important. Sit.
Mr. Shunsaku Aoshima...
I thought it best to talk directly
about your check-up results.
There may be a serious issue.
Please look at this.
A half-inch shadow here.
Shadow?
Is it a tumor?
We don't know without a follow-up.
But if it is malignant...
Malignant?
You should see a specialist
at a major facility.
I'll write a referral.
Please don't waste any time.
Okay?
I'm sure it's nothing.
Chief, investigation supervisor is
asking for you.
Chief... Chief...
Why is the suspect demanding the
release of your arrestees?
You arrested all these, right?
Get the car, please.
Mr. Aoshima...
Are you okay?
Drive me again, please.
Mr. Aoshima?
It's a secret though.
He's got a lump, this big.
But don't tell anyone.
Of course. I'll keep silent
Aoshima?
Just between you and me.
He doesn't have much longer.
No way? Where did you hear it?
Doctor told him directly.
A matter of months, apparently.
The chief did look pale.
Really? Oh, dear...
He's been coughing a lot.
Soon gets out of breath, too.
I thought it was strange.
Central Medical Detention Center.
Gather the inmate records, please.
You are Manami Hyuga, right?
Mr. Aoshima?
You talk to her, please.
There's been an incident.
We received a demand from the suspect.
To free these guys.
I want your opinion.
Why does he want you all to be freed?
What does he want with you?
When will my death
sentence be carried out?
How many years must I wait?
That's not up to us.
You got life imprisonment, anyway.
Best not to look her in the eyes.
That's a beautiful picture.
You're section chief now, huh?
How do you know?
But you're not well.
Maybe the new job's too taxing?
Want me to operate on you?
Didn't eat yet, huh?
Everyone's exhausted from the relocation.
Ogata's flat out on the sofa,
sleeping like the dead.
Like the dead?
Sorry... not like the dead at all.
Hope our pistols don't get used.
Mr. Wang claims he's not bothered
but he's depressed, too.
If someone gets hurt with my gun
I'll just want to die.
To die?
Sorry, you mustn't think of dying.
You know...
Forget it. It's nothing.
Eat up
I haven't eaten all day. This is to die for.
Don't mention dying!
Aoshima...
Forget it.
Seafood kimchi ramen, unusual, eh?
Is the shelf life okay?
Shelf life...
I wonder about mine...
Actually...
To tell the truth...
Nah...
Maybe there's something I had to tell you.
What was it?
There's something I never told you
Aoshima...
What?
Justify people's faith in you.
If you know what I mean.
Are you releasing them?
We won't act unless we understand.
You want my motive?
It's not that people cause crimes...
Alright...
I like researching past crimes
I realized that superior criminals
encounter superior cops.
So the criminals Aoshima caught are a
cut above the rest.
I thought it'd be cool to
let them loose again.
A criminal geek, huh?
Let me set a limit on my offer.
The show begins tomorrow at midnight.
Indiscriminate killing.
You jerk. We won't swallow that!
Supervisor!
What did you do?
Hey, Wild Dog?
It's mine.
It's mine, right?
You didn't pull the trigger.
Mine's next...
The dinner's at Daruma.
Chief, I have an update on Aoshima.
I know. It's severe, huh?
I got it from public affairs. In confidence.
The span of a life.
Pardon?
Living life that fast,
I figured he wouldn't last.
The doctor called.
He re-checked the x-ray.
The shadow was just a
problem with the film.
Aoshima's not ill after all.
Heck, really?
We must hurry and tell him.
Poor guy's lost his gusto.
Lost his gusto, has he?
Totally down in the dumps.
Hardly the same guy.
Lost his gusto, huh?
I'll go tell him.
No need.
A gusto-less Aoshima
may be less of a nuisance.
I see your point.
He always quarrels with the feds
and we take the heat.
A gusto-less Aoshima may be just right.
But sir...
We won't tell him. He's to stay sick.
Here are the mislaid boxes
you asked about.
Thanks
Mr. Aoshima, shall I sort this out for you?
How come the 2nd victim worked
for the removals company?
Is it a serial mover murder case?
Sorry to bother you.
Investigation meeting in 5 mins.
Kuriyama, did you hear that?
Mr. Wang, You understand?
Sorry
Chief, are you okay?
Sorry, I feel lousy. I'll skip the meeting.
Is he okay?
Aoshima...
Pull yourself together.
It was my gun that was used
I feel so sick...
I'm in pain, too.
Not mentally... physically.
Where I was shot.
It's throbbing.
Join the investigation.
Forget it.
You're dying anyway.
I know that you're ill
and running out of time.
And so what?
In that case live to the fullest.
Value the remaining time.
Live out your life in true Aoshima style!
Don't let the suspect use your gun.
Please give it back
Mr. Waku wrote amazing stuff!
Be careful with it.
What does this mean?
Natsumi, what do you think?
Which one?
"When your life's on the line
then you really live"
What does that mean?
It's hard to make sense of.
Mr. Aoshima,
you should sort through this