Look Beautiful and Shut Up
Disappear for an hour or two
before going to Raphael's.
I'll go to the movies, boss.
I hear there's a good police film.
Perfect. I'll go to Maxim's.
- OK, at Maxim's.
Who did it?
- We don't know. - Of course.
Inspector Morel has an idea.
- That's more like it.
He thinks it's "Charlemagne".
- Quick! Call the paper!
Who's Charlemagne?
If we knew, we wouldn't
call him Charlemagne!
"Charlemagne returns:
50 million in emeralds stolen"
You can't stand there, sir.
It's forbidden by the police.
Who are you after?
What did she do?
- Silly things.
Like what?
- Two escapes.
From jail?
- No, the "Bon Pasteur".
The Bon Pasteur?
- It's a reformatory.
Too bad. Such a sweet girl.
Yes, she's an orphan and a minor.
She's been sent to the orphanage
but she won't stay there.
That led her to the reformatory...
But this time she's headed for Doulens.
Doulens?
- Yes, the prison.
Virginie Dumaillet?
- Yes? - Police.
I should have known with your ugly mug!
Can I get dressed?
- Yes, I'll take you to the Bon Pasteur.
You're lucky we still have an empty bed.
Otherwise you'd sleep in the dungeon.
It's not nice to lie, Sister
Get in bed. Be quiet.
In bed!
What's wrong?
Oh! The sheets are cold!
You've become too fussy.
Try to sleep.
You're facing the judge tomorrow.
I wish you good luck.
Thank you, Sister.
Sister!
You're not going to kiss me?
You don't deserve it.
What is all this?
You plan to escape?
- Yes!
You're crazy!
Sheets are dangerous!
They come apart too easily.
Like that!
You'll kill yourself.
- I have to get away.
It's much easier with keys.
Oh! How did you do that?
It was nothing!
10 years of practice.
Can we escape together?
Wait! I just arrived.
And I don't know where to go now.
- I do.
I have friends waiting for me.
Then we have a deal.
Get me out of here and I'll hide you.
Agreed.
I'm Olga.
- Virginie.
When do we leave?
- At 11 PM... after their rounds.
Hey...
Who are your friends?
- Serious guys.
What do they do?
- They travel.
They'll take me abroad.
- You think they can take me too?
I can't work in a French circus now.
I'll ask Loulou.
- Who's Loulou? - The big boss.
He's my boyfriend.
- You have a boyfriend?
Why... don't you?
No... not yet.
Open! It's Gino.
Well?
You've seen the papers?
- Already?
Special edition.
- It's always a pleasure.
Here!
Shit! Charlemagne!
They know it's the boss!
Not a big deal since no one knows
who Charlemagne is, not even me.
Not bad, eh?
That's too nice!
- Meaning what?
Difficult to sell.
But you have to hurry.
The boss can't wait.
OK but this time I take 40 percent.
Watch it, Mr. Raphael.
My boss is dangerous.
Me too.
So what do you want to do?
Do I handle the stones?
It's not for me to say.
Do it the usual way.
I'll ask the boss about your percentage.
OK. Let's take stock.
Throw me a fag [cibiche]!
This isn't 1935!
You can't say "cibiche"!
You have to say "Gimme a smoke!"
I'll write it down!
- Forget it, she's too dumb!
Loulou! Telephone!
- In the booth.
I want to play.
But I have no money.
Oh! Twenty francs now!
Wait! Wait!
Pierrot!
Olga has escaped!
Go on sweetie!
I'm not alone.
I promised my friend that we'd hide her.
She got me out.
We'll help her.
But keep quiet about our business.
We'll pick you up.
On a scooter?
Out of the question!
The cops will spot us
at the first corner!
Get a car!
A car?
You're crazy, I don't have one.
Madame wants a limo service!
We could "borrow" Raphael's car
for an hour.
He owes us big time.
- Right!
Don't move. I'll cross the sound barrier
and be there now.
I'll be back in a minute!
- Olga is out!
Geez! - Don't say "Geez", say...
- Shit!
Oh, my Loulou!
This Virginie.
- There's no time. Hurry!
Let's all sit in the front!
There! You've got guts, Mister!
No "Mister" between friends.
I'll buy you a drink.
You deserve it.
It can't be! It's been stolen!
What? My car?
- Yes.
Where did you leave it?
- Here, as usual.
You left the keys on the board?
I thought that in a yard... Oh shit!
Is that all?
- No, the weapons are in it!
Weapons from the robbery?
- Yes, it's a disaster!
I'll take care of it.
I'll report it to the police.
Don't worry, they'll believe me.
I'll say it happened before 7 PM.
I wouldn't want to be
in the shoes of that thief!
I think we're done for.
- We won't even spend a night together.
Let's not all get caught.
Stop the car.
You two get out.
I'll lead them away.
She's right. I don't want
to see the coppers now.
Thanks, Virginie.
I'll repay you for this.
Change places!
See you later if you make it!
Are you crazy?
Isn't this our meeting place?
This is no time for joking!
Show me your papers!
I don't have any.
- No papers? A driver's license?
Look, a machine gun!
That's a new one!
You think it's a real one?
For sure.
Come on, I'll explain it to you.
[Police] Let's go!
[Virginie] Hey, there's no reason to...
Where's Morel?
I don't know, boss.
- He's never here!
That's his method:
elusive as a phantom and...
fast as a Jaguar!
Yes, but Jaguar or not,
you must find him immediately!
He has to go to the
Kremlin-Bicetre precinct now.
We found a stolen car
with a machine gun and a 7.65.
The weapons from the robbery.
Here's the report. Go now.
Boss! Who was the driver?
An 18 year old girl!
(intentional gibberish)
Of course you don't give a damn.
Eighteen! Another genius!
Perfect.
Something is wrong here.
Very good! Thank you, Sister.
So two of you girls fled from
the Bon Pasteur. - That's right.
Why didn't you say so?
It's your job to find out.
That's what you're paid for.
Inspector Morel is here, Commissioner.
Good, I'll see him in a moment.
The Commissioner will see you right away.
Take a seat there.
What did you do?
I'm innocent.
Come on, I'm not a snitch.
Robbery?
- No.
They intend to keep you?
- Yes.
How long?
Barring anything unexpected...
about 30 years.
Let's go now.
- What?
Too risky.
- Child's play.
The Commissioner's ready.
- OK.
Come on, now.
Too bad.
We'll do it another time.
I said now!
- Alright.
What's the rush?
And you. In the cage.
You know Inspector Jean Morel?
Not yet, but I've
heard a lot about you.
Commissioner, you're too kind.
I'll show you the report.
That's all she confessed to me.
I wish you good luck with her.
Will I have to spend the night here?
- Probably yes.
Oh.
- Yes. - Yes.
With your permission, Commissioner,
I'd like to try an experiment.
Ah! You have an idea?
- Yes, an idea.
Are you sure it's a good idea?
Yes, I believe this girl
could lead us very far. Listen.
Say, could you play the bad cop?
Yes.
What are you doing?
Getting ready for the night!
Let's go!
Come on, punk!
- That's enough!
Who do you think you are?
He wants a lawyer!
We'll make you talk, you little bastard!
Shithead! You'll see...
It's a trick we're using.
We're going to have fun with you,
you bastard!
Watch what you say!
Give me a cigarette.
Now you want to smoke!
Prisoners don't smoke here!
Go away now.
Good! Stay here and don't move!
You see how I treated him?
With strength and authority.
Come over here.
Take my cigarettes.
What are you waiting for?
In my pocket.
If you keep on provoking him,
you'll get him really mad.
Don't worry...
I prefer women
who obey without talking.
What? You're smoking?
I'll make you regret you were born!
Let's go, asshole!
- What did you say?
I just said...
You said "asshole".
Me? I said "asshole"?
Of course I could have said
"carrot" or "teapot"...
but I said "asshole"?
Yes... too bad you said "asshole".
I'll remember.
I never forget friends... or enemies.
I'll get you for that!
Let's go! I'll teach you!
Threatening the police now!
Just my luck!
I've waited 18 years to fall in love...
and when it happens...
I have to wait 30 more to know
if he's the right man for me!
To resume... you don't like the police?
They make me puke.
- Ah, yes.
There are nice policemen, though.
- Hmm!
Hmph!... Don't make me laugh!
- You're wrong.
Some are really nice sometimes.
You know, I could help you a great deal.
Huh... yes!
In another life, maybe.
It's not my day...
Here's your big chance.
I shut my eyes...
and you run away.
Ah! One couldn't ask for more!
You don't want to escape?
- No, don't bother.
It's the first time
someone refuses to escape!
You think I don't know your plan?
You want to book me
for trying to escape!
I want you to escape!
- No!
You'll do it now!
- No! No, no!
No, no! Go, go!
- No!
Go, go! - No!
- You need to go now!
She ran away?
I don't understand. She was here...
She escaped! Run after her!
Let's go! Quick!
They must be on the boulevard!
The Palace of Miracles tour...
starts in a few minutes.
A free tour.
The only one in the world.
On the first floor, the Palace of Miracles!
Don't ask anything.
I bribed that cop...
the inspector you saw yesterday evening.
I paid for both of us.
Those pigs are all corrupt!
Don't believe it.
It's rather unusual.
This one is scared of me.
How much does a cop cost?
I might need to know one day.
Let's not discuss it.
Because... it was a gift.
So you left your keys in the car
with the doors unlocked?
In my yard, Inspector.
Nothing ever happened before.
You think you're right and you're not!
Can I get my car back, Inspector?
I need it for work.
I'm a modest photographer.
Yeah, yeah, we'll give it back to you.
You left your handgun in it, by the way.
My gun?
- And your machine gun.
In case you were looking for them!
But I've never had
any weapons, Inspector!
So why did we find them
on the back seat? Why?
Of your car! Why?
I don't know, Inspector!
I'm a humble taxpayer...
whose car was stolen!
My mother will die of shame!
No, no, no. Don't worry.
I know you had nothing to do with it.
I know you suspect me.
You're an honest man... I can tell.
The only one who ever really...
helped or understood me...
That's you.
You don't like to be thanked.
I think you're hiding something.
You escape with a girl but don't
know where she lives. - I love you!
You save a young crook
but don't know who he is.
You talk about meeting them
but don't know where.
It doesn't make sense.
I can't trust you, Virginie, if you lie.
Yes.
Does Loulou really exist?
- Of course.
I'll make a call to find him.
Telephone from here?
The place is deserted now.
I'll be back in 5 minutes.
You'll have time to think.
What do you mean?
I'm not a kid, you know.
Don't try to get me going.
That won't work on me.
No pretense between us
or I'll dump you.
It's your decision.
Whatever happens, stay right here.
Hello!
I was starting to worry about you.
What?
Tell me... Loulou!
Yes... Loulou. Wait, I'll write it down.
Loulou...
Around twenty...
No, I have no idea.
And you know I have a great memory...
even if you don't agree with me!
That's all you got from her?
After all I've done!
I think she's telling the truth.
She's not part of the
band... or she's very clever.
I'll shake her a bit.
If she doesn't talk now,
she never will.
It won't be long now.
That's it.
What's wrong?
I'm playing the game.
Isn't this what you wanted?
Yes... but maybe you read
too much into my thoughts.
No pretense between us.
That's what you said.
Yes, yes. Of course.
You like to be obeyed, right.
- Naturally, yes.
A man like you could have any woman...
not waste time on some kid
who wanted to escape unless...
you have a good reason.
What reason?
- That's the point. I don't see.
So there's just one explanation:
That you really love me.
Swear that you don't like me at all.
You can't swear it?
No.
You see... I was right to trust you.
I waited for the man I would love.
How I dreamed of him.
And how I feared...
finding a woman who'd
make me lose my head.
And you found her?
Yes, I'm afraid so.
She came at the most unexpected time.
It's a bad start.
Yes... worse than you think.
Get dressed.
Get dressed, I said!
Why?
We're leaving.
- The museum's closed.
That doesn't matter.
What are we doing?
We're going to jail.
That's not funny.
You should be ashamed.
More than you think.
Whether or not you believe it...
even though I'm taking you there,
I'll do whatever I can to get you out.
OK, let's go.
Hands up!
This is a mistake. We're not thieves.
I'm Police Inspector Jean Morel.
Disgusting! An inspector with a woman
in the Du Barry's room.
No stupid comments, please!
Don't try to shut me up!
- Yeah, yeah.
This is a temple of history here...
not a hotel.
Olga's address.
- Can't you be careful!
Sorry, I slipped.
Nothing broken?
- No, thank you.
In a room of the Grevin Museum!
- That's a lie!
You believe what the girl told you?
No, but the museum guard
said the same thing!
I told you it's a lie!
He wants to file a complaint
and write to his deputy!
He's a war hero.!
That whole story's nonsense.
But if the press speaks,
one must stand up to it.
What do you mean "if the press"?
By tonight it will be in all the papers!
Perfect... in that case, I resign.
- Me too.
That won't stop the scandal.
Our reputation is bad enough already.
We help minors escape
and seduce them in museums...
the scandal will ruin us all!
The prefect, me, you,
we'll all have to resign.
The little bitch is really mad at us!
After what I did to her,
I can understand.
You admit it?
- No!
But she's a good girl.
I was wrong to trick her.
Now he's on her side!
We should have
left her in the circus!
She doesn't belong in jail!
It's you who belong in jail!
She was arrested driving a car
with the robbery weapons!
She wasn't involved in that case.
She'll still go to prison!
And we'll all be out of a job!
At my age!
After all I've done for you!
I put you here!
You and your smart ideas!
You better find one now, Mr. Morel,
to get us out of this mess!
I have one.
So tell us, Morel!
I have four kids to feed!
I'll marry her.
And then?
- What?
The juvenile court doesn't deal
with married women.
And the museum?
Lovers don't look at clocks...
whether in the museum or the woods.
You think he's joking?
No, his ear didn't move.
Morel, just one word: thank you.
Pardon me!
Wait, wait. She hasn't agreed yet.
I'll take care of that.
Where is she?
I summoned her.
She's waiting in Room B.
Wait next door.
Send in Virginie Dumaillet.
It's time to beat me up?
Come in.
Sit down, kid.
So you don't like jail, eh?
I'd like to see you there!
That's true. It was a dumb question.
You said it.
- I've had enough, OK?!
Sorry I yelled. Force of habit.
I want to show you that policemen
aren't that bad...
and sometimes even conscientious.
No pep talk, please!
OK... in order to save you from prison...
an inspector wants to marry you.
He's crazy!
- Yes! No, not at all.
I understand your surprise
and the joy you feel.
You're lucky.
He's very handsome.
And you know him...
Inspector Jean Morel.
Marry him? Never!
You don't want to marry him?
No, I want to send him to jail.
And he wants you to avoid jail!
Good, then I won't meet him there.
You will please accept him!
Jerome, stop pacing like that.
I can't stand waiting.
I'll go get the news.
I'm going.
Why does he want to marry me?
I told you. To save you from prison.
He's ashamed of his behavior.
He wants to help you.
That's all?
- That's all.
So he doesn't like me!
- Yes he does! A lot!
So... it's yes?
No! I can't marry a cop!
It doesn't fit with my sense of honor.
Too bad for you!
You can spend your life in jail!
And if I marry him?
I go back to jail?
No! You'll be free.
I'll sign your release immediately!
Really... that changes everything.
Tell your cop that I've made up my mind.
I accept his proposition.
- Bravo!
Until you get married,
put her with someone you trust...
Your grandma, for example.
Yes, my grandma, sure.
What shall I tell her?
That she just left the convent.
Olga Babitcheff
Bar le Zenith
Rue de la Gaite [Montparnasse]
Paris
I want you to know...
That I'm not just doing this
to help you.
Let me be the first to congratulate
the future couple!
Can I kiss the fiancee?
- No. - No, OK.
Thank you for your enthusiasm.
Anything for the mail?
- No.
Be careful!
- I must have slipped.
Thanks a lot. Don't bother. Thank you.
OK... thank you.
Here's the plan:
we'll marry in 2 weeks,
time for me to fill in
the paperwork for the police.
And meanwhile...
you'll stay with my grandmother.
The one who thinks you're a good man?
Yes... but she knows me.
So sweet and clever.
You can tell she's a convent girl.
Yes, she was in a very modern one.
Ah, you're lucky!
I would never expect such a nice girl...
to accept being married to a cop!
My parents would not have allowed that!
Police are so vulgar!
Thank God...
he didn't pick for his fiancee...
a jailbird!
You know, he's capable of anything!
Ma'am, please let me wash up.
No, I want to leave you two alone.
Don't say no.
I've been watching you...
You haven't kissed Virginie once
since she arrived a week ago.
Of course he has!
- No.
Once you're married,
I'll leave you this apartment
go live in Chantilly with my sister.
I won't see you anymore!
Don't you see that I'm...
an old friend
who's warmed by your happiness?
What are you waiting for?
What?
Have you no heart?
Kiss me!
Is she still there?
Yes.
Jean...
What, darling?
I really like your Grandma.
I was just sparing her feelings...
so don't imagine anything else.
Don't worry.
I have no imagination.
Our marriage is a deal:
I get out of jail
and that's a lot.
And you get me.
That's not bad either.
But let's not discuss it.
I completely agree.
And I've decided you won't be mine
until you love me.
You can wait forever!
- Don't be hasty.
Maybe one day... who knows?
- But... - I said maybe.
Just come to me then
and scratch at my door.
It will mean:
"I'm dishonored but I love you."
Hello?
Jerome! Yes, I'm listening. Yes.
Virginie, can you open the door?
- Of course.
What is this, Miss?
A feather duster.
Bravo, Miss! You just won first prize
in our radio contest.
Next question:
You want to see Olga?
You're the guy on the scooter!
Right. Meet her in 10 minutes
on St. Gregoire St.
Correct, Miss!
Napoleon did die on St. Helena!
Bravo, Miss!
With the compliments of Dustatom,
the feather that tickles the dust!
Thank you!
Here come 50 shrimps!
Yes, I'm coming!
What's that?
- My own recipe.
So... you seduced a cop?
Yes. And now I have to marry him.
Never!
We'll rescue you.
Is he wild and menacing?
No, he's rather handsome.
I'd rather die.
I wouldn't go that far.
You still want to leave the country?
Yes.. but the wedding's in 3 days.
Don't worry. We can fix that.
- Let me tell you...
Who's doing the talking?
Loulou, you're the boss...
but I'm a better talker, eh?
We smuggle old cameras.
We carry them over the border...
and bring back hot stuff...
with nothing for the customs tax.
You could come with us and
stay on the other side. OK?
OK... but you think that in 3 days...
Tomorrow I see Raphael.
I'll talk about you.
Give me your attention, please!
A bit to the left, madam...
A bit to the left... there!
Sir, over there, over there!
Don't move any farther!
Umbrellas!
Attention... 1... 2...
3... Thank you!
When will it be ready?
- Tonight, Miss... er, Madame.
But we'll be in the country!
- Give me the address, I'll bring them.
Hurry up, Darling. We'll be late
at the church. - I'm coming!
At Leopold's near Chantilly.
Leopold... write it as you hear it, OK?
Now come on!
Are they ready?
- Yes, they're all dry. I can leave now.
Here it is. You'll get a new camera
in exchange at Lausanne.
Bring it back and be careful.
- I've never failed you, boss.
That's just the point.
Don't rest on your laurels.
This is a big deal!
When do you leave?
We'll stop at Leopold's Inn near Chantilly.
I'll pick up Virginie
and we'll drive all night.
You'll reach the border in the morning?
- Yes, noon at the latest.
Call from the border...
to make sure our custom man is on duty.
Do I call you here?
No! Never call me here
when you're on a mission.
Call me at The Zenith.
- OK.
Hey! Hey!
You're late!
- But we're here, that's what's important.
You found the inn?
- Yes!
They're all there.
Virginie looks great in her wedding dress!
- Who cares!
I'm going there. Wait for us
here and pitch the tents.
We must look like real campers!
- OK.
Pierrot will wait with a scooter
behind the garden door.
Escape as soon as you can.
And watch out for the dog.
Look. We're smuggling this one.
This isn't fair to my husband.
Don't back out now! You know
what's waiting for you...
A convict dress.
Aha, my fellow!
I caught you, eh?
- Yes, sir.
Are you flirting with my wife?
As punishment, I'll feed you.
You seem overcome by emotion.
Well, naturally!
Look at this, boss!
It's older than the Ark.
And heavy...
Listen! Must be something inside.
You look strange.
Let's get something to drink.
So you act as if I didn't like
champagne, too. - Not at all!
Look, this one's my favorite!
Leave Grandma alone
and she's surrounded by men!
When one marries such a lovely girl...
- You keep her for yourself!
How sweet!
I'll play a tune on the piano.
No, not the piano!
- The piano, yes!
I'm leaving!
I can't stand all these cops.
See you later.
One minute, sir.
When do we get the photos?
The photos... in 48 hours, sir.
Thanks...
Bring them to the police station.
The police station?
- The police station.
Certainly, Inspector.
- Very good.
Jean, come look at this.
- Yes, Grandma.
What's going on?
You wanted to see the boss,
Mr. Raphael? Here he is.
Nice to meet you.
I've just returned from abroad
and I don't like what I'm hearing.
And I will no longer require your services.
We can always negotiate
about my percentage.
I never negotiate.
Where are the stones?
They've gone to Rotterdam.
How annoying.
Get them back.
It's too late! - Get them back now
or too bad for you!
You'd be sorry, too...
because... no Raphael, no emeralds.
I don't give a fuck what you're saying.
I'll never again work
with people I don't know.
My carriers will call me tomorrow
before going through customs.
They'll call you here?
- Yes.
Then we'll wait together,
if you don't mind.
Fine. I had no plans for tonight.
You know my room is next door.
It's simple. If you love me...
I'll see you in a minute.
If you don't love me... sleep well.
Look! That's her!
She's about to escape.
Quick! Flash your lights!
Go, Pierrot!
- I'm off.
And us?
- We take down the tents.
No key!
- Shit!
You have the camera?
- Yes.
Damn that dog!
Climb over the wall.
I'll catch you on the other side.
What's happening?
Dirty beast! Let me go!
Pierrot! You're crazy!
Not here, there's a pond!
Pierrot!
You're perfect.
I said to come to the door
and you pass through the window.
So you do love me.
I don't think we made a mistake.
I'm sure we'll be very happy together.
Are you crying?
- No.
Yes, you are. Why?
You're so kind.
- That's no reason.
It's salty, eh?
- A little.
I swear to make you happy all my life.
What's the matter, darling?
I love you! I love you!
I love you!
Good morning.
- Good morning.
Been awake long?
No.
- "No."
Listen...
I don't know.
I already forgot "before".
So?
- Nothing yet.
We're not gonna get anything
but pneumonia!
It's too early to call Raphael
at the Zenith.
Call his house.
- He said not to.
It's an emergency.
- OK.
Poor girl, what an awful night
she probably had.
Maybe she's getting used to it.
Pierrot, come down!
Ten thousand more. Four aces.
You win.
Sorry there's no extension.
Just tell them to come here.
Yes?
We're still near Chantilly.
We couldn't...
Don't worry. Counter offer.
Come back fast, all of you.
OK... meet at the place
where you're waiting?
Exactly. Hurry.
They'll be here tonight.
They're at the border.
It's hot in here.
Shall I open a window?
Go ahead.
Not much of a game.
It's not over... until tonight.
You like big shots?
- Yes.
So much the better!
Don't shoot.
I want to know where he's going.
Hurry! We're leaving!
- Where to?
The Zenith.
- You sure?
Yes, the planned meeting place.
- Did he yell at you?
No, but he's going to!
- Speak for yourself.
Meet us later.
Try to get the camera back.
Why do I always get the risky jobs?
Yes, why does he?
Rebelling? You
want to die young?
Sometimes I wonder who's the boss here!
Loulou!
Get the camera back or else!
What's that camera?
Where did you get it?
It belongs to the photographer.
He simply forgot it.
Give it to me.
Since you're going to the station,
take it with you.
Give it to him
when he delivers the photos.
Darling, we'll finish this...
then leave right away.
One club soda... no, two!
Coming right up!
The bill, please!
- Right away, Mr. Morel.
And then, as you found...
The bill, Mr. Morel.
We had 33 bottles of champagne?
No.
- You were here, of course.
I had only one, maybe two...
Jerome!
How much for the sodas?
- 160 francs.
There are too many cops here for me!
My darling... want to go
to the arcades this afternoon?
No, I don't like them!
- Really?
No... ouch!
- You'll go anyway! Come on!
Bravo! That's how to tame women!
Darling, do you want to go
to the arcades with me?
Yes, my darling!
- Very good! I like your obedience.
What's going on?
- Ya-ya-ya... no gas!
Why didn't you fill it up?
I didn't have time!
I have to think about everything!
I tried to help but you don't
have the brains to be a leader.
Give me a break! If you're not happy...
- Yes?
Walk back!
- OK, watch me walking!
Hey! Hey! Hey!
Bitch!
Can you give me a ride, please!
- Sure, get in. - Thanks.
Where are you going?
- Paris. - Me too.
Haven't I seen you before... eh?
Yes.
Thought so. Where?
On the road two minutes ago.
You remember?
No... I've seen you somewhere else...
Thanks again.
I can't remember where I saw you...
You're so sweet!
Goodbye just like that?
I'll never forget you.
Nor will I.
Goodbye, mister.
- Goodbye.
Sometimes I like being a cop.
Hey, Mr. Raphael!
- Where's the camera?
We lost it.
Are you crazy?!
Don't get upset.
Maybe Pierrot will find it.
Maybe!
If not, we'll buy you another.
I want this one!
Let's wait for Pierrot.
A light...?
Well?
Virginie is here with her husband.
She nodded to me...
she doesn't have the camera.
Where is she now?
- At the bumper cars.
I want to know where it is!
Go ask her where it is!
Her husband will see me!
- Do it! Quick! Quick!
I'll explain...
I put the stones in a camera.
- Uh huh... That's intelligent.
And the camera got lost.
- That's too bad.
But we'll find it. The Inspector's wife
is taking care of the problem.
Doesn't sound too serious to me.
What are you doing?
- Corpses should be nameless.
Hey! What are you doing here?!
Where is she?
- There, with her cop.
I'll talk to him.
- Are you crazy?
I'll tell the Inspector everything.
His wife's involved, he'll deal with her.
At least I'll be safe in jail.
No, don't go! You have no right!
Hey! Inspector!
You have a shot!
You know him?
- No!
Stop! Stop!
I'm Inspector Morel.
Call the police.
Don't move. Stay in your cars.
It's nothing. Don't move.
Don't drive. Stay in your cars.
Is there a doctor here, please?
Don't move. Don't move.
I'm Raphael...
It was I who...
Jean!
I searched him. No ID.
Scared?
The killer might still be here.
I'm here, too.
Did you know him?
Huh? No!
He waved at you.
No, not at me!
It was you he waved at!
Maybe... but are you sure
you've never met him?
No.
Don't stay here.
See you at home for dinner.
You don't get killed
for smuggling cameras!
Wasn't Virginie supposed to get killed?
Never!
- You said so!
That was just talk.
This is a real murder.
Right... what are we mixed up in?
Here she is.
Do they know?
- Yes, I told them.
Did you see it?
- Everything.
And the murderer?
- Yes.
Do you know him?
- No.
And Raphael?
- They haven't identified him.
Jean asked if I knew him.
I said no,
so you wouldn't get caught.
I knew you'd be loyal.
We're in deep trouble!
- Yes!
Let's take the scooters and
get out of Paris! - Yes!
Not me!
- What?
Not you?
I'm not leaving Jean.
Now this!
Yesterday you wanted to go away.
Yesterday I didn't know...
I love him.
Love a cop... you?
And you love him?
Yes!
Well, good for you!
Well, it's good that he likes you...
because when he knows
you worked for Raphael...
He'll never know!
That's what you say.
He has all our names and addresses!
And the wedding negatives.
I'm going!
- Are you crazy?
Jean mustn't know I worked for Raphael!
But he loves and trusts you.
He won't trust me anymore.
Love solves everything!
Not if I lose my husband!
And I don't want to lose him!
The police will be waiting at Raphael's.
They haven't identified him yet.
I'll get there before them.
How will you get in?
Through the roof.
You might fall and kill yourself.
I'm a professional.
You can't go like that.
Give her your bottoms!
My what?
- Your pants.
No! I don't want a bare ass!
Raphael was killed in public,
in broad daylight.
With incredible boldness.
Don't you recognize the style?
- What do you mean?
It has the mark of Charlemagne.
Jerome... wasn't it Raphael's car
that was stolen?
Exactly.
He's linked to the robbery.
Probably.
Was he interrogated?
- Yes.
No results?
- Nothing.
Who questioned him?
- I did.
Now I understand.
Let's go to Raphael's, boss.
Let's go.
What are you doing here?
I'm just tidying up.
Sure... you stroll over the roof,
see an open window...
and decide to tidy up.
That's it.
Why are you burning these papers?
I don't want anybody
to know that I knew Raphael.
Really... why?
I posed for photos...
You know what I mean.
Yes... OK.
Can I see them?
You're Inspector Morel's wife?
Yes.
You know Raphael's just been killed?
Yes!
And how do you know?
The police just called me.
I was Raphael's lawyer...
And his best friend.
Poor fellow.
We knew each other as children.
Believe me, sir, you have all my sympathy.
Thank you.
What are you doing here?
Can I trust you?
- Absolutely.
All right... I was working for Raphael.
You worked for Raphael?
I was smuggling cameras.
Illegally!
That's very serious.
But I still have one camera.
- Where?
At the police station.
Isn't that silly?
Very... Can you get it back?
Of course.
Get it to me fast.
I promise I won't say a word
to the police or your husband.
Oh thank you, sir!
You're a real pal!
Don't mention it.
Call me at this number.
OK.
Now...
Who is this young person?
- It's Olga.
She can be very useful to you.
She saw Raphael's killer
You don't say.
That's very interesting.
Where can I meet her?
At the Zenith bar on Gaite street.
Thanks.
Can I finish burning this?
- Sure, go ahead.
Thanks.
Open up! Police!
My husband! Don't open it!
- I won't. Run!
Hey! Don't forget the camera!
Fire! Fire!
Sorry. - It's me. - Excuse me.
- After you. - May I?
What a charming gentleman!
It's amazing.
He ran away so fast I couldn't catch him.
Don't worry, it's not your fault.
Well... do you know anyone who
can walk roofs like they were sidewalks?
No... none of my relatives.
But I do.
- Where are you going?
Home! Then I'll know for sure.
When you're finished, meet me there!
Just a minute, old man!
What are you taking away?
Ashes from the stove.
You must learn that to the police,
ashes talk.
Virginie!
Yes! Come in here!
Guess who I'm disguised as!
Joan of Arc?
You guessed it right away!
And you?
You're disguised as a chimney sweep?
Yes, I chased an acrobat on the roofs.
An acrobat?
Yes, an acrobat.
That's strange, no?
Very.
Did you catch him?
No, darling.
I'm no acrobat.
I'll teach you.
I'll get it.
Not in that costume!
No one must know you're mad.
They'll find out eventually.
Go and dress like a lady.
Look what I found in the stove.
Don't show that here. Hide it.
You have some nerve!
Coming by at meal time!
Do you expect us to feed you?
Nice try! Nice try!
Now show me.
I'll show you pictures
of the famous Olga.
Mysterious invoices...
for scooters bought by Raphael.
And there it is.
Look and compare
with the picture on her ID.
The irony is that she hitched a ride
with me this morning.
Where was this?
Near the inn.
- Yes.
I dropped her at a bar on
Gaite Street called... the Zenith.
The Zenith on Gaite... I know the place.
Good. What's cooking?
Look! What is this!
Pants?
You're on a diet?
It's overcooked.
Wait...
Virginie steals Raphael's car...
Raphael is killed near Virginie...
and Olga poses for Raphael,
so she knows about Virginie...
A young man runs across a roof...
then these pants in Virginie's pot.
What would you do?
I'd talk to Virginie.
- Don't be stupid.
Virginie!
Yes, my darling!
Listen, Virginie...
The roof acrobat that I was chasing...
was a girl.
And you know her well...
Olga!
Your fellow escapee
from the Bon Pasteur.
Poor girl.
Arson, burglary...
trespassing and above all...
Above all, accessory to murder.
At least 10 years.
She wasn't as lucky as you.
Jerome and I will catch her in a bar...
the Zenith.
I must be going.
Don't wait for me.
Hope you're not too upset.
Why?
This was our first newlywed dinner.
Let's go, Jerome.
Goodbye.
- Goodbye.
Go back to her.
Say anything but stay with her
for 15 minutes, then leave.
What should I tell her?
Quick, before she gets to the phone!
Jerome, what do you want?
I forgot something.
- What?
I've forgotten what.
But I must find what I've forgotten.
And when I find it,
I'll know what I've forgotten.
A hat?
- Yes! No! Not a hat.
Your coat?
- Maybe.
Well, it's not here.
- Yes, I see that.
Your glasses?
Yes, that's possible!
I couldn't see too well, so I thought...
I must have left them...
but I was wrong...
because they're on my nose.
I have a superb memory,
but I can't remember...
what I'm looking for.
Say, Jerome... where's the old camera
you saw at our wedding?
In my office at the station.
- Perfect.
I still can't remember
what I'm looking for...
But what are you looking for?
My god, I must be going!
How time flies!
I'll have to try harder.
Sorry I disturbed you!
It's not really important... I guess.
OK, bye now.
- Good evening! Goodbye.
Pierrot, quick!
Telephone! Hurry!
Yes, it's me... Virginie?
They're coming? No!
OK, we're getting out of here.
The police!
- Let's get out of here!
Where's Loulou?
- At the garage.
We must get to him, too.
Come on, hurry up!
Police!
Don't you know who I am?
- No.
Of course you do... Inspector Morel.
Let's sit down.
A whiskey, please.
No one else should hear
what I'm going to tell you.
Sit down.
Say... you have a nice skirt!
Shut up!
So you're the gang!
How much is it?
- It's on the house.
Cigarette, anyone?
- No!
I came to talk about Virginie.
Do you know her?
No!
Your loyalty is touching.
Who's the girl that escaped with you
from the Bon Pasteur?
I don't know.
Never saw her again.
She's my wife.
- Congratulations.
What's her connection to you?
Nothing!
- Nothing?
Well, that's enough.
This here, you know it?
- A little.
Why did my wife try to burn
these pictures? - I don't know.
Why did she just call here?
- Nobody called.
I'll tell you why...
She telephoned to warn you
that I was on the way here.
And you're guilty.
I'll arrest all of you
unless you tell me
the connection between
Raphael, my wife and you.
I just posed for photos.
- Really?
And your scooters?
Did they pose for photos, too?
What's this, Pierre Voinquel?
I want the truth now.
Can I ask you a question, Mr. Inspector?
Go ahead.
Will you arrest your wife, too?
Yes, if she deserves it.
That's a good way to go.
Take a look at these.
No! I'll tell you everything!
- Don't you dare!
Stop playing and let her speak!
Speak.
Pierrot, don't be angry.
So, you see...
You've had enough!
I'll kick his ass! I hate cops.
- Stay here! Don't go!
You'll see when he goes out!
We don't want to see!
- I'll make mincemeat of him!
That's all.
We didn't know it was so serious.
We mainly wanted to travel.
How much did Raphael pay you
to smuggle the cameras?
50,000.
Per person?
- No, for all of us.
That's a good price for cameras.
So... my wife has the one
that should have crossed today.
Yes.
Well, then...
You're assholes to risk jail
for 50,000 francs!
You three are in big trouble.
I'll try to get you off lightly.
Stay here and wait.
Don't move until I return.
If you do, I'll get you
the maximum sentence.
See you soon.
Hey you!
- Sit down.
Pierrot, put on a record.
Bitch!
Leave her alone!
- Then you'll pay for her!
I'm sick of you! Enough!
Olga, phone call from Virginie.
Good! I'll tell her how you chickened out!
Hello? Yes, it's me.
A message from Virginie, Miss Olga.
Meet her right away at the corner
of Gaite and Sebastien.
Come quickly. It's urgent.
Yes.
Are you crazy, Olga?
You know what the Inspector said!
Pierrot...
- What?
It's no fun being gangsters.
No! Let me go!
Say...
When you were with her earlier,
did my wife mention the camera!
Umm... no.
- Don't lie.
Well, she spoke about it casually
but she certainly...
didn't know what was inside it.
- You think so?
Yes.
Then why are you lying?
Uh...
Good. Get me some fake emeralds...
from the evidence services.
But make sure they're perfect copies
and get them fast.
What if they're closed?
Find a way!
I can't do everything!
Sorry.
You must be miserable.
Yes... very.
Where are you taking me?
Let me go!
If only I'd listened to that cop!
Put me down!
There... the best copies. Be careful.
They're worth 5,000 francs.
The real ones are worth 50 million.
Just like with women...
You can't tell between
the fake and the real thing.
Don't mix them up.
- Yes.
Hello?
Virginie?
Darling, I won't be home for dinner.
I have to work all night here.
It would be very nice if you brought me...
some sandwiches...
and some coffee.
Yes... unless you're in bed already.
That's very kind. See you soon.
What are you doing?
Setting a trap.
Wouldn't you rather be frank with her?
Of course... but I want to know
where these stones are going.
So yes or no?
- No!
Hello? Ah, it's you, Virginie.
I'll give you the camera in half an hour
at the corner of Pont St. Michel
and police headquarters.
Then things will be OK, eh?
All finished?
Of course, sweetheart.
I'll send my driver.
- See you soon.
I locked my office
so she has to go through yours.
It's very simple.
She won't take risks
for an old camera...
but she will
if she knows about the stones.
Big risk for her.
Very true.
What about you two?
If she takes the camera,
I won't see her again.
Don't say that.
- Never again!
Is that you, Virginie?
- Yes.
Be nice, go through Jerome's office.
I forgot my key. - OK.
Go and hide downstairs.
Follow her when she leaves.
I'll join you later.
So, Jerome, did you find
what you'd forgotten?
Yes! No!
I wanted to tell you
that your husband loves you.
I know!
See you later, then.
Oh, Virginie!
- Yes?
And you... do you love him?
- Yes!
Then tell him. And never hurt him.
- Of course.
Jean! Open the door!
Look at your ideal wife!
Pastrami and cheese sandwiches,
a big apple and coffee.
Wake up!
It's me, your wife!
Come on, eat!
I'm no longer hungry.
Come over here.
You love me, right?
Oh yes, I love you!
You wouldn't lie to me?
Me? Never!
Well... even if you did,
your mouth would open the same...
and your eye would have
the same expression.
Nonsense! I'm a very bad liar.
You'd never hurt me?
Me? I'd die for you.
That's nice to know.
You don't believe me?
It's hard not to believe you.
Well... nothing else to tell me?
One thing... I'm very happy.
And you?
I can't believe it's happening.
Go home now.
Work to do?
- Yes, a lot.
Making progress?
Almost finished.
Great! I'll go.
See you later?
- See you later.
You make me lose my head.
I almost forgot my bag!
Well?
She got into a Cadillac and...
- Why didn't you follow her?
Because the Cadillac blocked the way...
Listen, Jerome. Go back to the office
and wait for my call.
I'll do that.
I think it's the best I can do.
Where's my wife?
- I don't know.
Where's Olga?
- She left right after you.
Your wife phoned her.
I swear we tried to stop her.
What a bunch of idiots! Where are they?
- The cops! - Huh?
Let's stop playing.
The women we love are in danger.
Will you help me?
It would hurt me... to help a cop.
You know where they are?
Yes... but I won't tell you.
With Charlemagne?
- Who?
Yes.
3 Glaciere Street
Wait for me here.
I wanted to keep you out of this
but I'm not sure I can now.
Look... if I don't call in 30 minutes,
call Inspector Jerome at the station...
Send him to 3 Glaciere Street.
I'm counting on you.
- Yes.
Feel better?
There?
- Yes.
I'll go.
- I'll go, too.
It's dangerous, you know.
- Yes. But I'm afraid for our girls.
Right.
Take this.
And remember:
the police never shoot first.
And you?
- I have what I need.
OK.
Where are the emeralds?
The real ones!
I don't know anything!
Don't make me angry, Virginie.
Screw you!
Scream if you like.
No one will hear you.
Go downstairs. We may have visitors.
I'm not here for anyone.
She told us all she knows.
Now it's your turn!
Let me go!
I'll go inside the house. You hide
in the garden. - Yes.
Stay there until I call you.
- OK.
Where's my wife?
- I don't know.
You're going to talk!
- My shoulder!
Where?!
Come on.
Maybe we should enlarge your mouth
to facilitate the conversation.
I've told you all I know.
OK... Gino, you can start...
very slowly.
I'll leave.
I can't stand the sight of blood.
Good evening, Charlemagne.
Good evening, Mr. Inspector.
Drop the gun and put your hands up.
- That's all?
Gino...
Count to three. If the Inspector doesn't
drop his gun, you can start cutting.
If you do that, I'll kill your friend.
You don't need to bother.
I abhor incompetents.
Shoot him, Jean!
Won't worry about me!
Drop your gun.
Go on.
You took me for a ride.
No, Jean. No!
You must have really laughed
when I married you.
No, Jean.
Shut up. You disgust me.
So, Mr. Inspector...
Where are the real stones?
In a safe at the police station.
I have the receipt with me.
Boss, if he's here,
the police will be here soon.
Yes, you're right.
Are we done?
If you have any last words
for your relatives, say them now.
We're leaving.
Watch the Inspector. I'll be back soon.
I have things to do.
You know me, boss. I'm a real nurse.
Are you happy now?
Nice adventure, eh?
Like in the movies.
Don't cry. No time for that.
Jean... I beg your forgiveness.
- This isn't the time.
I didn't know about the gems.
- I don't believe you.
Why should I lie before I die?
She's right. She didn't know.
Nobody knew.
You won't believe me?
I don't know. I'm lost now.
Tell me what happened.
You don't mind?
- No, I've got my paper to read.
Time to call the police.
- Yes.
They'll go easy on us...
but it's still jail
until we're legal age.
We'll meet when we get out.
That's right.
Let's go then.
Pierrot...
Give me a magic kiss.
Maybe it will all work out.
There...
I hoped after I returned the camera...
I could live in peace with you.
Is that all?
Yes! I beg you to forgive me!
I took it... and I lied...
because I love you.
And I love you...
I don't care about the rest.
Too bad we have to die now.
Yes.
May I kiss my wife?
Alright but no tricks.
Look...
Keep him busy.
Goodbye, Jean!
Goodbye, my love.
Van Mechlen Will Play
For France Against Spain
To read this before I die!
What?
Van Mechlen [a Belgian]
playing on the French team.
The worst possible news
on my last night alive!
What's wrong with him
playing on the team?
He can't play soccer. He's a clown.
- What are you talking about?
You know how many times he
scored last week? - I'm not interested.
Five goals!
And he's not a soccer player?
Five goals. And who was playing with him?
Three French players...
Of course... with their help, he just
has to kick the ball...
at the right time!
A guy like him needs no help!
Open the shutters and call Loulou!
Hurry! Hurry!
Loulou! Loulou!
I'm coming!
Don't move.
All of you up against the wall.
I'll miss you.
Hands up!
Shoot, Loulou! Shoot!
Get him on the way out!
- I'm going!
Bravo, Loulou!
Hands up!
Don't move.
Come downstairs.
That's all. Just a habit.
Are you OK?
- I'm fine.
You're not hurt?
- No, no, no.
You can lower your arms now.
- Thank you very much.
Don't worry. It's not even loaded.
- Really!?
Little punk!
I know him from somewhere.
Don't touch anything!
This one could be loaded.
I know you from somewhere.
Of course. At Raphael's this afternoon.
Right... of course...
And your name is?
- Charlemagne.
That's very nice.
You'll be bored without me.
Is he injured?
I just put him to sleep.
Very smart. He just saved our lives.
How could I know that?
Feeling better?
You were great.
Jean!
Jean! Jean, are you hurt?
- No.
I was so scared, Loulou.
Oh, my Loulou!
How do you feel?
- Better now.
That was a close one.
The Inspector saved your life.
- Thank you, sir.
I only did my duty.
Now that we're not going to die...
do you still forgive me?
- Yes.
I'll be your slave.
I'll do anything for you.
You can ask me anything.
I ask just one little thing...
- What?
Look beautiful...
and shut up!
Subtitles by filmnutz @ KG
December 2023