Subtitles by explosiveskull
www.OpenSubtitles.org
The fires are getting worse.
Every year it's getting worse.
I say let it burn.
Let it all burn.
I owe you for this one.
Warner Hayes is back in town,
back in The Network.
I won't fight him.
Hayes, stop!
Stop!
You were out!
Why are you doing this?
I got no choice!
If he comes for me...
You were out.
There is no way out.
We are who we are.
Stop! Stop this. Just stop.
No!
If he comes for me...
I won't fight him.
He's the closest thing
I have to a brother.
Save yourself.
Beckman!
We know you're in there!
Come on, get it open!
Come on, hurry up!
Come on, spread out!
Watch the body!
I need to get out.
There's got be a way out.
This is the life
you chose, Beckman.
There's no way out,
no retirement plan,
no pearly gates. Accept it.
I don't know what to do,
Lord, I...
Guide me.
I have to choose.
Medicine or the church.
It won't be long before it's...
my medicine or my home.
Please guide me.
I need help.
God! What happened?
- I'll call an ambulance.
- No, don't!
Please.
A donation. 350,000.
It's yours.
I need help.
This is a house of God.
I know.
I believe this
is from you, Lord.
"As far as the
east is from the west,
so far does he remove
our transgressions from us."
We've been over this before.
I've got it.
Do you?
Why'd you take me in?
If it wasn't for the money?
I have my personal reasons.
That's between me and God.
I'm here.
I want to believe, I...
You're not ready.
You have to let go.
Allow the Almighty
to control your life.
That person you were before...
that person has to die.
And are you ready
to let it all go?
All the people you harmed?
Be honest.
Father, forgive me.
God forgive me.
In the jungle...
15 miles west of Khe Sanh,
I killed 11 men.
Boys.
They never stood
a chance. They...
They gave me a medal
for that.
When it was my time
to go home, I... I stayed.
I don't know why.
Maybe somehow I thought
I could make things right.
I was lost, completely lost.
That's when God finds us.
When the lies, denial...
ego is gone.
And there's nothing left
between you and your creator.
Remember
what you've learned.
Promise me.
I promise.
Death.
That's what it took
to get through to Pharaoh.
The death of his infant son.
So he let Moses
and his people go.
But then his grief
turned to anger.
And he sent the chariots
after Moses.
But when God saw that
his people were safe, he...
drowned the entire
Egyptian army.
An army couldn't deter
God's will.
An army couldn't
stand against...
God's might.
So what makes you think
you can?
You can't fool God.
He knows who you are.
He knows what you've done.
He knows.
That's it for today.
Reverend.
You going somewhere?
Sorry, Abby. I...
I don't...
I'm not fooling anyone.
I don't belong here.
I don't know
what I was thinking.
You're having a bad spell.
- We've been through this.
- Philip was wrong.
I don't deserve forgiveness.
I'm not worthy of it.
The dreams are back.
They never stopped.
They're always there.
Staring at me.
The people you wronged?
- Reverend.
- Philip was the reverend.
Do you trust me,
that I know
what I'm talking about?
I have known
my share of men.
Kind, evil,
everything in between.
You are a good man
and a good preacher.
Just hang on.
Whoa! Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Uncle Philip, I'm sorry.
I know I'm not supposed
to come here, but I need help.
And I... And I am
in really big trouble.
Okay. Okay.
Slow down. Slow down.
I'm... I'm not Philip.
Am I in the right place?
Your uncle died
almost a year ago.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Stay with me, stay with me.
Well, what's...
What's your name?
Tabitha.
Well, welcome.
What kind of trouble are you in?
I don't wanna talk
about that.
I... I don't ever
wanna talk about it.
Philip said that
if I needed help,
that I could come here.
I...
I can drive you
to the emergency room.
Forget it.
Wait.
Just wait.
So Peter got out of the boat,
and he walked on the water.
He saw the winds approaching,
and he became afraid.
And he took his eyes off of
Jesus, and he began to sink.
And he cried out to the Lord,
saying, "Lord, save me!"
And Jesus reached out his hand.
When life is a tumultuous storm,
look to him
and keep looking to him.
And now our very own
adopted daughter Tabitha
wants to inspire us
with something
she's been working very hard on.
Let's give her a hand.
♪ Rock of Ages, cleft for me ♪
♪ Let me hide myself in thee ♪
♪ Let the water
And the blood ♪
♪ From the wounded side
That flows ♪
♪ Be of sin the double cure ♪
♪ Save from wrath
And make me pure ♪
Thanks, Bobby. Appreciate it.
Hey, thank you very much.
Thank you.
Oh, thank you.
Tom. Hey.
- Hey.
- Hey, how's your grandmother? I...
Does she need anything?
I haven't been over there in a few weeks.
Oh, no, she actually moved to
assisted living, in Valencia.
Oh. Well, you got
the whole place to yourself.
- Yeah.
- Can you afford that? Is it okay?
Yeah,
I'm doing all right.
- Good.
- Yeah.
It was a really good
sermon today.
They've been
really good lately.
- Really? Lately?
- Yeah.
What's this about?
Oh, this?
Oh, just a rough night.
I really wasn't
paying attention.
Nice job, Reverend.
Ah. You too, chipmunk.
Proud of you.
Wow. Hope you gave
as good as you got.
Oh, no. It wasn't like that.
What was it like?
I... I don't know.
Ah... Hey, but I...
I gotta go.
Hey, wait.
How'd that video turn out?
Oh.
Um... Yeah, yeah.
It turned out really good.
Um... You're really talented.
You... You wanna see?
Here...
is my number.
Send it to me.
Okay. Thanks.
Listen, I really gotta go.
I'll see you next week.
All right. Bye.
Don't tease him.
You know he likes you.
I'm not gonna ask him out.
Those are the rules.
Oh.
What's wrong?
Nothing.
Nothing's wrong.
Hands! Show me your hands!
All right.
Uh-huh.
- Pizza!
- Ooh, yay!
Did I tell you
how proud I am of you?
Only, like, 20 times.
Okay.
Tell us something about yourself
that would shock us
or move back four spaces.
Mmm. We do not have
that kind of time.
- Miss Abigail!
- Don't you know who you're talking to?
I was a singer
in the '70s.
I toured with all the greats.
I was hot stuff.
Waist like this,
skirts up to here.
Oh, forgive me, Lord.
You know, they
called me Baby Thunder.
Oh, whoa! Too much information!
Too much!
Oh.
- Huh.
- Wait, is that...
It's got some weight to it.
Might be the one.
Okay, open it.
No, don't open it.
Just do it.
Hey! What is this?
There you are,
my little dreamer.
I missed you.
You were the most loved.
- Above all the others.
- Get out of here right now!
- Hey, back up!
- I'm sorry. I didn't know!
You tore out my heart
when you left.
But I knew the universe
would bring you back.
We're bound, you and I.
Don't touch me.
You're confused.
You're in pain. I see that.
I taught you what freedom
was, true freedom.
And it scared you.
That's natural.
I thought you were ready,
but I pushed you
too hard, too fast.
The unprepared mind
will do anything
to come back to this prison,
with its rules and comforts.
- That's enough. Don't say one more word!
- Don't try me.
Do you remember that night?
When all was in balance.
Underneath all those stars.
You pledged yourself to me.
The ritual night
is upon us again.
I pledged to be your guide,
and I will, my child.
We must finish
what we started.
She's not going with you.
I don't care
how many guns you have.
You will do nothing but offer
poisoned words to enslaved minds.
Shame on you.
Tabitha, no.
It's time to go.
- No, no.
- You are in God's house!
You leave that child alone.
No!
What, preacher, what?
What are you gonna do?
If you make me
drag you out of here,
it'll be so much worse.
Come.
We're done here.
- Let me go!
- Don't give me any trouble.
Tabitha?
Tabitha!
You won't get away with this!
I'm calling about Abigail.
No, I'll... I'll tell them.
Yes. Send it to me.
I'll pay for the funeral.
I'm so sorry.
I'm sorry.
Talk.
I'm so sorry.
Abigail's dead.
What?
Who were they?
No, no, no.
- Talk.
- It's Erik!
I...
He was the one who hit her.
Look, I just met him
at work last month.
We started talking.
I just needed some rent.
I just drove a truck.
I didn't ask...
I didn't ask what for.
So I just asked him
for some advice about girls.
You know, I showed him
the video of Tabitha.
I guess he knew her.
And they threw me in the truck.
I don't know.
- What else?
- What?
What else?
What else do you know?
Nothing. I don't...
He just... He had
a tattoo on his arm.
A spider.
I'm sorry!
Mr. Beckman.
Welcome back. Or should I
call you "reverend" now?
Just Beckman.
As you wish.
What can we do for you?
I need an address.
And weapons.
Mr. Beckman,
you remember the rules,
the price?
I'll pay it.
Very well.
Whenever you're ready.
His name is Erik.
Five foot ten,
black hair, spider tattoo.
Hands!
Show me your hands!
Hands.
Where is Erik?
Where's Erik?
You.
Where is she?
Man, you don't know what
you're getting yourself into.
Go back home
before you get hurt.
Last chance.
Where is she?
Help.
Help me.
911,
what's the nature of your emergency?
Hello?
Hello, is anyone there?
Okay, I have your location.
I'm sending out a unit.
You've reached a number
that has been disconnected
or no longer...
Hello?
Listen to me.
I think we were followed.
We need to move Tabitha
right away.
- Where is she?
- What?
I haven't seen her in over a year.
I'm sleeping.
Who is this?
My love.
I'm sorry,
but he said it's urgent.
Something about Tabitha?
All your life
the world insists
you punish yourself
for being inconvenient.
You never need
to apologize to me.
Okay.
Erik, I hope you have some idea
how disruptive this phone call is.
Erik won't be having
any more ideas.
The preacher.
Pay close attention.
My name is Aaron Beckman.
You ask around about me.
And when you find out who I am,
you're gonna
let Tabitha go unharmed.
It's your only chance
to survive what's coming.
Your actions, your threats,
they mean nothing to me.
My future will be
as it was revealed to me.
As it always has been.
Solid like iron.
Unchanging.
You will fail.
You always fail.
Let her go, now.
It's impossible.
That one's journey has ended
as it was meant to.
The desert drank her water.
And she has returned
to the void.
I'll see you soon.
- No, I can't.
- Just hang on.
I can't do it.
You can do it.
Just a few more hours.
Hang on. You can do it.
Help!
Reverend?
I think
I'm feeling better.
Do you think I could
get some breakfast?
Sure. Yeah, come on in.
I... Yeah, here.
How... How do you like
your eggs?
I don't care.
Why are you doing this for me?
Why'd you take me in?
I had my personal reasons.
That's between me and God.
And open.
Oh! Is that mine?
- As soon as you pass the test.
- I love it.
- How'd you afford this?
- Well, you earned it.
We're very proud of you.
Uh, I got something else.
It's not exactly the one
that you wanted, but close.
No, it... it's great.
It's really great. Thank you.
And not brand-new,
but it's yours.
I can... I can pay you back.
No, no, you don't...
you don't have to pay me back.
Nothing...
Nothing's ever free.
I don't mean to be ungrateful.
It's just...
No, it's okay. I get it.
This is new for both of us.
You being a daughter...
me a dad.
- It's weird, right?
- Yeah.
Yeah, I don't know
what I'm doing.
But I promise you...
I'll never, never hurt you.
And I'll always protect you.
I've heard that before,
you know.
And I...
I wanna believe you.
I just... I need time.
"Dear Tabitha, it's been my great honor to
inform you that you've been acc... accepted.
Admission..."
Mr. Beckman.
Were you satisfied with your service?
- Yes.
- Excellent.
You now have one week
to repay your debt
to The Network.
Keep the phone charged.
When it rings, answer
and do exactly as instructed.
I know.
Is there any other service
we could provide...
No. No, nothing at all.
- Hello?
- Hello, sir.
I'm Fred Shapiro
with the post office.
You have a package here
that was damaged.
The only thing I can read
is a phone number.
Uh, address starts
with a 2-6.
Oh, no, it's 1-9.
Oh, wow. Yeah.
Not even close.
Yeah, if you can give me the correct address,
we'll have this out to you tomorrow morning.
Uh... Oh, sure. It's 1975 Comstock
Drive, Glendora, 91741.
Hey, I'm not expecting
a package. Who's it from?
Hello? Hello?
Hello? Do I know you?
Inside.
Okay.
You... You can take
whatever you want.
We got money.
There's a safe.
- Who else is here?
- No one.
Is someone at the door?
Call her.
Honey, will you come out
to the front room by the door?
One sec.
Janice, where's my shovel?
Who else is here?
It's my brother-in-law Kirk.
- Sit down.
- Okay.
Janice, what is happening?
It's a misunderstanding.
Just do what he says.
Both of you, sit down.
- Hands on the table.
- They're not involved in this.
Sit!
You think this
is the first time
someone pointed a gun at me?
Just sit.
That doesn't belong to you.
What? What is he talking about?
Who is he?
Just shut up!
- Is she dead?
- Don't tell him anything.
I don't know.
Where did you take her?
I don't know where she is.
What is happening?
What is going on?
Where is she?
I... don't... know.
Raise your right hand.
Raise your hand.
Kirk.
What?
Don't run. Don't shout.
- Sit down.
- Okay, okay.
Mister, we have children.
Please.
Where is she?
- You're insane.
- Where is she?
I don't know.
Raise your left hand.
What?
No. No, no, no, no.
No, no, no.
What is happening?
Raise your hand.
Okay.
Reese took her. Frank drove them.
That's all I know.
Where is this Reese?
- I don't know!
- Then where is Frank?
He'll kill me.
Erik is dead
and his whole crew.
Now, I'm here.
There's only one way
you survive this.
This has to be a mistake.
Say something.
Sweetie? Answer me!
Look, can you just let me out?
I'm not a part of this.
I don't even know what this is. I
promise, I won't say anything to anybody.
Shut up!
Mister, we have a 12-year-old son.
His name's Edward.
He's at school right now, and I'm supposed
to pick him up. And... he's anxious.
Tabitha was 17.
My daughter.
What?
What have you gotten me into?
I'm your husband. I deserve to know!
Shut up, Dan!
Will you just shut up?
Janice, look out!
Give me your...
- There's no way out.
- What's your name?
Tabitha.
I am in really big trouble.
Man, you don't know what
you're getting yourself into.
Under all those stars.
Where is it?
Hey. You don't wanna
be late your first day.
My necklace, can you
help me find it? Please.
Uh... Okay.
- What about...
- No, no, my necklace.
The blue one, right?
The one your mom gave you?
I already
looked over there.
Okay.
Could you please just move?
Please, please, just move.
- What?
- Please move. Please.
Please, just get out of the way.
Get out of the way! Stop!
Okay, okay.
Hey.
You wanna talk about it?
- Why'd you take me in?
- Why are you doing this for me?
I already told you, I don't
ever wanna talk about it.
We're bound, you and I.
When will this feeling go away?
I just wanna tear it out.
- We're done here.
- Let me go!
Tabitha?
You won't get away with this!
You always fail.
Don't make any noise.
No one's gonna hear you
except for her.
- Janice?
- I don't know her name.
Sometimes her brother
comes down.
But she's much worse.
Hey.
It took me two days.
What's your name?
Wendy.
Beckman.
Quiet.
Frank is coming with Reese.
He's instructed me to keep
you here and not kill you.
He didn't say anything
about hurting you.
I'm gonna hurt you now.
For my husband.
For my children!
For my brother.
He protected me.
He was the only one
who knew me.
Hey!
Keys! Get the keys!
I can't.
I think I can get them.
I'm gonna be there
when Reese takes you apart
piece by piece.
I'm gonna watch.
Keys. Grab the keys.
Keys.
Is she dead?
Get my handcuffs. Quick.
- What now?
- Help her.
Don't come up till I say.
Come on, come on.
No.
No!
- What?
- We are not enemies, Mr. Beckman.
I have no enemies.
All I have is love to give.
By fighting, all you've done
is deprive yourself
of a very special journey.
The ritual night is upon us.
- My students have gathered to witness the true...
- Shut up.
Nothing's
gonna save you now.
Not words, not money, not guns.
You are a dead man.
All you care about
is the mortal flesh.
Life is so much more
than this, Mr. Beckman.
I only wish I could have
shown you my paradise.
Very well. If death is all
you understand, all you value...
then I will
rain it down upon you
and everyone around you.
Give it to me.
You need to get out of town
until this is all sorted out.
The ritual
will not be postponed.
You're not listening!
You can play
cult leader anywhere.
Just get on your jet and go.
This guy is serious.
He's a real psychopath.
I looked into it.
The Koreans, you know
what they call him?
Agma. The demon.
You understand the price?
It's all clear.
You can come up now.
Mister, is she dead?
Did I kill her?
Keys.
Give me five minutes.
Then call 911.
What do I tell them?
The truth.
Tom's phone. Leave a message.
Tom! You have to
get out of the apartment.
Go to a safe place, somewhere where
no one will think to find you.
Don't answer the phone for anybody but me.
I'm on my way.
Tom?
Connor.
Isabel.
Beckman.
You don't
look so good, Beckman.
Come on, man.
You think we're amateurs?
What do you say?
Love you, Papa Bear.
Love you, Mama Bear.
Clear.
Hey, Beckman.
Word is that you got out,
found religion.
Not going so well, is it?
Clear.
It's good to see you, Aaron.
Sorry it has to go like this.
A hundred thousand will get us
out of a tight spot. Clear.
Clear.
Window.
Isabel! Isabel!
Isabel!
Reverend?
What's happening?
Wait, Tom!
Tom!
Wait!
Tom, stop!
You're in trouble.
He was there to kill you.
- What? Why? I didn't do anything!
- I know.
Trust me on this.
If you stay here,
you're dead.
- It's all my fault.
- It's not your fault.
None of this is your fault.
Well, what if he was lying?
What if she's not dead?
- She's gone.
- How do you know?
I need you to focus.
Worry about your own skin.
- Well, where are we going?
- There's this guy I know. Owes me a favor.
You're not gonna like it, but it'll
keep you safe until I can fix this.
How?
Only way to erase a bounty is
to bury the man who posted it.
Whoa, whoa. Okay, okay.
I can't... I can't hear that.
You're talking about murder.
Reverend, you shot that guy.
- He knew the risk.
- What?
You're a man of God.
You killed that guy.
I didn't have a choice.
I got no choice!
- Please, we can go to the cops.
- The cops can't help.
- Please.
- The cops can't help you.
You're in it now.
Do you understand?
You're marked.
What am... What am I in?
The life. The other world.
The underworld.
You're in it now.
Real killers, thieves,
darkness, evil.
Listen.
You haven't spilled blood.
You haven't taken money.
You can still get out
if you do exactly what I say.
What is it?
Who is that?
They call him The Administrator.
What does that mean?
No one's lived long enough
to ask him.
Oh, pshh.
Okay, well, we can go to the police.
They'll protect us.
It's not gonna happen.
Okay, well, let's go, go, go!
We can lose him!
Only idiots
get into car chases.
- You work around here, right?
- Yeah.
- The... The brewery up on Battery Street.
- Okay.
- Where?
- To the right.
Here. Unscrew the suppressor.
- What? Is this loaded?
- This, unscrew it.
- Where?
- It's up here on the right.
- Get the keys?
- Yeah.
When I say go,
you get out fast.
Unlock the door.
I'll be right behind you.
Go!
Do not
disappoint me, Mr. Beckman.
Do you have more ammo...
or a second firearm?
Very good.
I've always hoped
we'd have a chance
to test each other.
You were injured
before we started.
So this was not
a fair contest.
Hard day.
You were out.
And now you're back
with a considerable price
on your head.
You must have a good reason.
Yeah.
Before I complete
every assignment,
I ask this question.
If I let you live,
what will you do?
What will you do, Mr. Beckman?
There were four of them.
Traffickers.
Came into my house,
killed my daughter.
All she did was escape them.
That was her sin.
She had just been
accepted to college.
She was starting a life.
There were four of them.
Now there's only two.
I'm gonna finish what I started.
That's what I'm gonna do.
I have killed 436 people...
and I spared only four.
I believe that
because of my actions,
the world is a better place.
You...
will be number five.
Mercy is a rare
and powerful tool.
I believe
the world will be a better place
with you alive.
But if I see your name
on the boards again,
Mr. Beckman,
you will have no mercy.
You will not
even see me coming.
Favors, all these favors.
I'm running
a business here, Beckman.
- You're positive no one followed you here?
- No one followed me.
Yeah, every two-bit banger
with a gun is gonna be
after that hundred grand.
I'm tempted to shoot you myself.
And I don't need the money.
You know that, right?
I run all this on favors.
No, no. Just kidding here.
- What is this?
- Huh?
- What?
- What is this?
What is this? Oh, sweet.
He don't know.
Look, I just need you
to hold him for a few days.
Days. You sure you want
days with this kid?
Yeah, I'll give you
all the time in the world.
What? This is a prison.
You see? This is where you're
gonna spend the next five years.
No, no, no.
Look, do you wanna be safe
or you wanna be dead?
No one's gonna bother you in
there, my guarantee.
Wait.
I just wanna say something.
To him.
Killing those men
isn't gonna bring her back.
- Go to the cops.
- I can't go to the cops.
- You can.
- Tom.
This?
This is because of you.
This kid got in my face
at a party.
I could have beat him.
But I thought about
what you taught me.
"Blessed are the meek,
blessed are the merciful."
I just let him hit me.
And he kept hitting me until...
I don't know, he just
kinda got freaked out.
But he came up to me later.
He wanted to know
why I didn't fight back.
So I told him.
He told me he was sorry.
He wanted to change
his whole life around.
You helped that happen.
When life is
a tumultuous storm...
- I know what I said.
- So stop.
Remember who you are.
Reverend!
I need ammo. I'm out.
Hey, look.
You know the rules.
I stay completely neutral.
This guy who wants
you dead so bad,
you know how to get to him?
- Not yet.
- You know my cousin's a broker downtown.
Off The Network.
I could give you credit.
No. I know who I need
to talk to.
What?
No. You got exactly
what you paid for.
You hired me
to crack the firewall.
"I will take care of the rest."
Your exact words.
That's right, Mr. Kerrigan.
I record everything.
I can't help that you're too
basic to get past the encryption.
Oh, you wanna dance?
Let's dance.
I've got your fingerprints,
I've got your DNA,
I've got your socials,
pin numbers, transcripts.
I will burn
your life down in minutes.
You're just a tourist
in my world.
Kara!
I just wanna talk.
Wait!
I'm just passing through.
- Whatever this is, I'm here for...
- Kara.
Yeah.
She's gonna pay us eight grand
to make sure you don't find her.
You gotta be kidding me.
I just wanna talk.
Wait, that's the guy.
I saw your picture
on the boards today.
Boys, he's worth
a hundred grand.
This is gonna be a good day.
It's a good day.
Let's get to work.
The drill. Get the drill!
Yeah, yeah.
Hey, man,
it's just business, huh?
It's nothing personal.
What?
Is he dead?
Are you sure?
Gun.
I just wanna talk.
Lane must have hired you.
That was a setup. I...
I wasn't even there.
I just need information.
It's not about that.
I don't wanna die.
I'm not gonna shoot you.
I don't believe you.
It's what you do.
It is.
I was out for three years.
Hayes was right.
We are what we are.
Save yourself.
He was a good man.
That was you?
So how is it on the surface?
It's beautiful.
You're not afraid,
not trapped.
You're just... free.
Free to believe.
Care about someone.
Must be nice.
I had a daughter.
They killed her.
She was just 17.
You would've liked her.
For old times,
do me this one favor.
Two more men need to die.
They're the last.
After that...
What was her name?
"Blessed are the merciful.
Blessed are the peacekeepers."
Are you ready to let it all go?
Why are you doing this for me?
Remember what you've learned.
Hey.
Come on up.
- You found them?
- Bad news first.
Your boogeyman,
Reese Saladurus.
Real name
Paul Robert Kettle III,
heir to his daddy's
telecom fortune.
He is worth billions.
He was kicked out
of Dartmouth in '86.
Reason redacted.
Police records redacted.
He spent a few years
in the psych wards.
Hospital defunded.
Poof. He's gone.
- Where is he now?
- I...
Off the grid.
There's no permanent address.
Look, all I know is that
he pops up every now and then,
he rents houses for cash
in the desert.
He's there for a few weeks
and he's gone.
That's all I know.
If you want any more,
use the black phone and take your chances.
- Good news?
- Frank Keetus.
Known trafficker
and all-around giant dirtbag.
He owns a fancy restaurant
in Malibu,
- but it's a front for the business.
- Which is what?
You know what it is.
You know I work with a lot of
hard-core, evil individuals,
but I won't touch
anything like that.
Do me a favor.
Kill him twice.
Sir, you can't
park your car there.
Sir!
You Beckman?
Boss said to break your arms
if you try to get in.
So?
What do you wanna do?
Hit end.
Please.
Take me to Frank.
Leave the phone.
I told you they would
be good this time, huh?
The best yet.
Who's this?
Who are you to invite
yourself to our table?
This is private meeting.
Go away.
Meeting's over.
Gentlemen,
my deepest apologies.
You could follow Samara
to the bar, have a drink.
In my business, I am the boss
and the complaint department.
Nothing to worry about.
This will just take a few minutes.
- Do you think I should call the...
- No!
Don't call the cops.
How stupid are you?
You don't look so hot,
preacher.
Let's go in the back,
have a talk.
- We could talk here.
- Get up.
You're the guy with the gun.
Oh, why don't we skip the part
where this shocks you.
You're no civilian.
I know exactly what you are.
You know what I want.
- Where is he?
- Polecat Ranch.
About ten miles
north of Piru.
He's there right now running
one of his crazy rituals.
You'd give him up that easy?
- I don't buy it.
- You're in my place with a gun to my head.
How do I need
this aggravation, huh?
Over one dead kid? Nah.
You go up there, pop him in the head.
What do I care?
He's crazy.
Money ain't worth this.
You think this gets you
off the hook?
You're part of it.
You should probably answer that.
Go on.
- Beckman.
- Good evening, Mr. Beckman.
Are you prepared to fulfill
your debt to The Network?
- Mr. Beckman?
- Yes.
Excellent.
Listen carefully.
The contract on your life
has been suspended.
To fulfill your debt,
you are to cease any and all
acts of retribution
towards Frank Keetus,
his clients, employees
or known associates.
Do you understand
what I've said?
Mr. Beckman, are you there?
Would you like me to repeat it?
- I got it.
- Good.
Do I need to remind you
of the price
of defying a Network order?
- No.
- Then the book is closed on this transaction.
We hope to serve you again.
You'll be lowering that gun now.
Sit down.
Hey.
It's over.
Killing those men
isn't gonna bring her back.
Hey.
Put the gun down.
Hey, put the gun down.
I'm in trouble.
I'll always protect you.
Whoa. Hey, it's over!
What do you want?
You want me to say I'm sorry?
I am sorry the world's rotten.
A stinking open sewer.
Not my fault!
I didn't invent this game.
I am not responsible
for all the evils of the world.
Why don't you ask God
about that, preacher, huh?
Who is responsible for
creating this whole mess?
I didn't ask for this.
To be born into this.
No. I came up from nothing.
I am just playing
the garbage hand I was dealt,
trying to make a dollar
like everybody else!
And you don't get to judge me,
the things you've done.
Oh, come on! These girls,
they were never gonna make it.
You know that.
Not one of 'em.
Orphans, addicts, homeless.
Now, we only sell
to the best select clients.
Millionaires, billionaires!
We did these girls a favor!
You can't do this.
You know you can't do this.
Now, wait a minute.
Stop! Just stop!
You were out!
Why are you doing this?
You're a man of God.
You killed that guy!
I didn't have a choice.
Two more men
need to die. They're the last.
- Save yourself.
- There's gotta be a way out.
You have to let go.
A new cycle begins.
The blood is set free
to pass through the flame
and is transformed, purified.
Where there was once
sickness and decay,
there is now light,
energy, purpose.
The spirit passes
through the flame,
and it is transformed
and purified.
Where there was once
confusion and suffering,
there is now peace.
The mind is set free
to pass through the flame,
and it is transformed, purified.
He's gonna hurt the teacher!
Stop him!
No! No!
Stand back!
Stand back and have no fear.
No fear.
This man has come
with a very specific purpose.
Haven't you, preacher?
To transition me
into the flames.
To end my journey here
as Reese, your teacher.
No, teacher, you can't!
- Reverend!
- Remember what you've learned.
Now, are you ready
to let it all go?
All the people you harmed?
Killing those men
isn't gonna bring her back.
Do it, preacher.
Mercy
is a rare and powerful tool.
Tabitha.
"Blessed are the peacekeepers.
Blessed are the merciful."
I know what I said.
So stop.
No.
You live with yourself.
Your judgment
will come soon enough.
I knew it.
I knew that you would fail.
Run away, preacher.
You liar. You fraud!
You failure, you two
deserve each other!
The both of you, you're weak!
Undisciplined! I have no
more use for you or her!
You take her, you hear me?
Take her!
That's right.
You take her and go!
She's being punished
down in the barrels.
She might even still be alive.
I hope she is!
Because you two
deserve each other.
I want you two to live
your lives out together.
Your small,
boring, pointless lives!
Never growing, changing,
never expanding your minds!
Just living day
by pathetic day,
working, praying,
mediocre, impotent,
obedient to your
corporate masters!
I could think
of no greater punishment.
Do you hear me?
Tabitha?
Tabitha.
Oh, God.
Tabitha. Tabitha?
Reverend?
Hey.
I knew you were coming.
How'd you...
How'd you find me?
I almost didn't.
Almost didn't.
Is it over?
So, who will be next
to speak into the flame?
Daisy?
Come on up here.
Who is that?
- Teacher!
- Who is that?
This is private property!
You are tres...
Don't shoot! I'll give you money!
I swear. Anything!
It's done.
And Beckman?
He's not here.
Find him. Finish it.