Paris, please.
May I see your passport
and ticket, please?
Attention, please.
United airlines
announces the departure
of flight number 327
to Chicago.
Tony. Tony,
my little bambino.
Going to be
a fine priest.
Mom, I have years of study
before I'll be a priest.
But when you finish,
you'll be a good priest.
You hear?
That is what
he and his friend Gregory
will be studying for,
mama Lugacetti.
Peaches, Tony, for you and Gregory.
Tell the man who flies
the plane to make them hot.
Thanks.
Poor Tony, he's loved not enough,
but too well.
A skill with which only the
Italians exceed the Irish.
Yes,
that's quite a family.
You'll have a few days in Paris, Greg,
before you go
to the seminary.
I've cabled my old
friend father du rocher.
I'll give
you the address
of his church
in the montmartre.
Ha ha,
you know that man,
he's been over
30 years in Paris,
and he still disapproves of the place.
What are
you thinking about?
Why the shadows,
hmm?
What inner mountains of
doubt do they reflect?
Hills, father,
not mountains.
I guess I'm scared.
Oh, you've been
scared before,
in Korea, as a prisoner of war.
But not like this.
The things I saw
there made me...
Scared and strong
at the same time,
gave me courage
to want to go on
and become a priest.
But now, I don't know.
It's only natural to
be suddenly appalled
at the enormity of the
responsibility to God,
to ourselves.
But I'm flesh, father,
flesh more than spirit.
I'm lost in the theories
and philosophies.
I only come to roost
when I translate
in terms of people.
Suffering and despair
don't make me humble.
They make me angry.
Beauty and compassion don't
make me humble, either.
That's why I'm scared.
Greg, for a long time
you've led one life.
Now you're going
to live another way
to which
you'll add control,
self-denial,
discipline.
Elevation
is never easy.
But being
born a second time
is no more difficult
than the first.
Do you think
I'll make it, father?
I think you have.
Attention, please.
Panamerican world airways
announces the departure
of flight number 90 to Paris.
Good-bye, mama.
And don't
get drunk.
Thanks.
Tony, you hear,
you be a good priest.
Take care
of yourself, ma.
Arrivaderci!
Excuse me.
Greg, I've solved
the mystery,
and documented it.
The one with the 4,000
yards of mink and 50 bags
who smells like
an Egyptian princess
is francesca.
My acquaintance with Egyptian
princesses is very limited.
Who is her highness?
Who is francesca?
Greg, how unworldly can you get?
She's the famous
designer,
the celebrated
couturier.
That's
who's francesca.
Here,
take look at this.
Here...
"Certainly the natural waistline
bores me," says francesca.
"The long look is
newer than the new look,
"combined with the
renaissance of the bouffant.
You will fight it,
but you will succumb."
She has courage,
that one,
and a high
sense of art.
She's also
quite a dish.
The full set.
Boy, what my sister
wouldn't give to meet her.
You know, my sister's
also in the rag business,
on seventh Avenue.
She's an operator
of machines,
but she studies design
at night in Brooklyn.
How many sisters
do you have?
9.
And one brother,
Frank.
Hey, do you know
what it means,
2 boys in one house
with 9 sisters?
Frank joins the marines
and I become a priest.
I like your family.
If you like
action, yes.
Take my mother.
Mama Mia, there's a woman for you.
Filled with
pasta and wine,
and per favore,
11 children.
Oh.
Still bad?
With luck,
not for long.
Keep your head up.
Breathe through your mouth.
Would you gentlemen
like your dinner now?
We're serving
shrimp cocktail,
filet mignon with...
Oh, please,
lady, stop.
I'll wait until
he feels better.
You can be served in the
bar below, Mr. Fitzgerald.
Go ahead, Greg.
There are times when a tenth
child wants to be alone.
Go, sir.
Oxygen is indicated.
May I?
Mm-hmm.
Merci.
Adequat.
You speak French?
Just enough to make
myself misunderstood.
Much more clever.
In my experience,
complete understanding
leads to boredom.
That is a very
French point of view.
I am French.
I figured that out.
I figured out
you are American.
Omaha, originally.
Then Trenton.
My name's
Gregory Fitzgerald.
Paris, originally.
Then Paris.
I'm madame francesca.
I know.
A natural waistline
bores you,
and you're putting all
your money on the long look.
You think the American
women will succumb?
Certainly not,
but I have to say something outrageous.
Why?
It is expected.
Why do you make me
so uncomfortable?
Well, I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to.
You stare.
No, not stare,
search.
And your eyes
are very blue.
And you have
a face like a man's.
Why, doesn't everybody?
I mean men.
No.
No, men look like
mice or bats or owls,
and sometimes like boys.
But only rarely,
very, very rarely,
like men,
like you.
You are married,
of course?
No.
Divorced?
Mm-hmm.
Arrangement?
Well, you could
say arrangements.
Not probably
the way you mean,
but certainly
arrangements.
Your fiancee is beautiful, I suppose.
Of course you know, I
hate beautiful women,
just as I adore
beautiful men,
like you.
You mind
I say this?
No, not at all.
As a matter of fact,
I was a very
beautiful baby
and I have a picture
on a fur rug to prove it.
Your fiancee,
she will not mind
if you show me
that picture?
No?
My fiancee understands
everything I do
or say or think.
Good.
The front of the card,
an invitation
to my collection.
The back of the card,
my apartment in Paris.
All right,
all right.
Madame francesca?
I'll have no peace
until I introduce you to Mr. lugacetti.
I'll give you no peace
unless you do.
How do you do,
Mr. lugacetti?
I don't do well at all,
madame francesca.
I could hardly
wait to stop flying
and I find
I still am.
You must go
to your hotel at once,
drink very dry champagne,
and eat herring.
It will absolutely
cure you.
I think I'd better
get him on a bus.
Nonsense.
I have a jalopy.
Be my guest.
We don't want
to crowd you.
Don't be silly.
That is exactly what I want.
You're sure you won't
come for a drink
right this minute?
Thank you very much, but
it really isn't possible.
You've been
very kind.
Very,
thanks a million.
Good-bye.
Thanks again.
You're
father du rocher?
Yes.
Your name's lugacetti?
I'm Fitzgerald.
This is lugacetti.
Father.
I had planned to say
welcome to France,
but it's clear you have
already had a welcome
exceeding any possibility
I might extend.
Who was this woman?
A fellow
passenger, sir.
Tony wasn't
feeling very well,
and she was very kind.
Perhaps it will teach you
not to go against
God's will.
Man was not meant to fly.
You agree?
Yes, now you agree.
Tomorrow when you're
feeling better,
you will not agree.
How's my old friend,
father Cunningham?
He's well?
Well.
Yes?
What's this?
Do you know
that in Europe
you're a nothing,
a nobody
without a passport?
In Europe, only cats
do not have to
show their passport.
Now we go to my room.
I have put in
two mattresses on the floor.
Perhaps a hotel,
father, would be better?
A hotel?
It would be foolish
for you to
pay at a hotel.
Priests must learn...
You're very kind,
father,
but Tony isn't
feeling very well
and it's only
for two nights.
You will be robbed.
However, if you insist,
I know the name
of a respectable one,
the Remy.
Fine.
Let's get a taxi.
Taxi? Who do you think
you are,
the baron Rothschild?
We'll take the Metro,
the subway,
bottom of the hill.
Come on.
Monsieur.
And from here,
monsieur,
you have the most
excellent view of the city,
if you look
in this manner.
Whoop.
Merci.
And look.
You see?
How much?
1,400 francs.
O.K.
What?!
1,400 francs
for this room?
For this...
Look, the carpet
is a rat's dinner.
And there,
the ceiling,
it leaks.
You call this a room?
But I am
a poor man.
1,300.
800.
Ah, no, no, no.
1,200?
1,100.
Tant pis.
But only one hour
of hot water.
You see?
Was I not right?
1,400 francs.
Ha. Do you realize what
one can buy for that?
Dinner for three
with a decent cheese.
And perhaps
even a peach.
If I have one weakness, gentlemen,
it's for
the peach of normandy.
The pink fuzz, the
light blush of the meat.
And the juice
so sweet and delicate.
You will need food.
If you gentlemen
are not planning
to spend $25 apiece
at the tour de Juneire Maxim's,
perhaps you will be
good enough to meet me
at the restaurant
la camubier
la what?
La camubier.
It's only
a few blocks from here.
At 9:00
on the stroke.
Au revoir.
And welcome to Paris.
That's
a tough cookie.
Did you see his face
when he talked
about the peach?
He's not as tough
as he makes out.
How about a peach, Tony?
Oh, nothing.
Just let me
lie here.
I'll change my clothes
and have a look at Paris.
Don't wake me
when you get back.
Um, pardonner mol,
monsieur.
Sorry, I can't
speak French.
Le restaurant
de la camubier?
Straight down.
10 streets,
then you turn a la gauche, this way,
two streets more,
then you arrive
on the boulevard.
You turn right,
this way, and then...
You understand?
No.
You take me.
Oh, pardon,
monsieur.
I'm sorry.
I don't speak French.
Oh, no, not an American.
What a piece of luck.
Could I have
your cab?
I've been looking for one
for a half-hour and I'm late.
All right,
let's share it.
You don't have to cash
so many traveler's checks.
It's all right if we're
pointed the same way.
It's not out of
your way. O.K.?
O.K.
Thanks.
What a city, Paris.
So much to see and only
three days to do it.
I could spend a year
in the louvre alone.
I was only able to give
the Mona Lisa 10 seconds
and
the winged victory 15.
But what about
that Venus de milo?
Huh?
Well, I liked it.
What I'd like now, mister, is
practically no conversation.
Have a cigarette.
Thanks.
I didn't mean anything
by that last remark.
I'm just beat.
Anything wrong?
Nothing.
And don't mix in.
Hey wait,
your bag!
Thanks.
Here you are.
I want to speak
to Monica, please.
Is she expecting you?
Just through that door.
Thank you.
Entre.
Well.
Fell out
of your bag.
I don't know
how you managed
to get through
all that traffic
without
St. Christopher.
It's uh-sort of
a good luck charm.
That's the second time
you've been nice tonight.
Thanks a lot.
Good night.
Is there
something I can do?
You seem rather upset and I thought...
I told you before
not to mix in.
Why don't you go look
at some more statues?
Entre.
Monica Johnson?
Oul.
Police.
Identification
papers.
Where are you staying?
Hotel Remy. Why?
Bonsoir,
mademoiselle.
Bonsoir.
A bientot, monsieur.
See, darling.
Scatterbrain, but hopeless.
Forgot completely to renew
my alien labor permit.
Three months ago,
I sang at the call club
in London for two weeks
before I remembered
I was supposed to be
at le sardine d'or
in cannes.
Hand me that bottle of
perfume, will you, darling?
Thanks.
Oh, you understand French.
A word
here and there.
"A bientot," that means see
you again very soon, doesn't it?
It's so much more
charming in French.
Even when
a detective says it?
Especially when
a detective says it.
I don't like cops.
Why did he want to
see my identification?
Maybe because
he envied you.
And not because
you'd told him
you'd spent the last
couple of hours with me?
Maybe that's why
he envied you.
He said he'd see me
again very soon.
Don't you think I'm
entitled to an explanation?
Yes, you certainly are.
But what's the point?
If the cops come,
you just tell them
exactly what happened.
You won't get hurt.
If you want to lie a
little for me, o.K.,
but I'm not
asking you.
Do me one
more favor, huh?
Then you can tell
all your friends
about your crazy
night in Paris.
Put me in a cab, huh?
Just that,
and then au revoir.
I have a very large
lump of curiosity.
What kills cats
can also kill Americans.
Do you...
Want to carry
the luggage, Porter?
Uh...
Just to make it
a better story
when you tell it
in the states,
we're going out
the back way.
Complete with
cobblestones, alley,
and suspicious characters
lurking in the dark.
Let her go!
What's that?
Where I live.
If he followed you here,
he'll follow you there.
I have to go,
I have to.
I don't know what I would
have done without you.
Let me give
you some advice.
Just get out of
this cab and forget it.
You're hardly in a
position to give advice.
What have you done,
Monica?
Why the cops?
Why that man?
What do you care?
Because I'm angry.
I don't like
being hit,
and I like even less
to hit back.
You're pretty good at it.
What are you,
a prizefighter?
No, I'm not
a prizefighter.
And you're not in just a little trouble.
You've got big trouble.
What is it?
What's that got
to do with you?
How about taking
your hands off me?
O.K., o.K.
I'll feel better
if I admit it.
Everybody
feels better
when they relieve
the pressure.
It's an old and very
famous cure.
You're a strange guy.
There are lots of
people like me.
I've never met any.
I think you have
but didn't know it.
The black stuff on your eyes is running.
Is it smeared?
Less than before.
Listen mister
whatever your name is,
I don't know
you from ac/dc
and you've probably
got a highly developed angle,
but you're right, I've got
trouble and I need help,
the ask no
questions kind.
Well then, there's no
point in asking questions.
Anyway, the only
truth that matters
is the kind
you have to tell.
What can I do?
Stick with me until I get
a plane and shake this town.
Oh. I've got somebody
waiting for me.
Could you call them?
Haven't you got
anybody else?
No, not right now.
Well then, I have no choice, have I?
Can I have
that suitcase?
Telephone
your friends in here.
Here's the phone book.
I'll make it fast.
We'll be out of here
in two minutes.
Where are you going?
As far as I can get.
Home?
No, I don't think so.
Cuba, maybe.
I'll be a sensation.
Wait'll you catch my samba.
You have a curious way
of facing reality.
You deny it,
bury it under a joke.
I thought that was
supposed to be good.
Not always.
How long have
you been in Europe?
I don't
understand you.
Oh, I see.
I ask you, "where is she?"
That's what
I'd like to know.
Why?
For my own reasons.
What are yours?
I suspect you know them.
You're obviously
a good friend of Monica's.
Is she here?
Isn't this
a waste of time?
You can see for yourself she isn't.
Good night.
Perhaps I have
a misunderstanding.
How did you get in?
With a key.
The key?
Yes, with a key
you could get in,
a key like this one.
Now show me yours.
No. You do not
have a key.
You came here with her.
Now tell me,
where is she?
I don't know.
So again,
how did you get in?
You've got it all.
I will tell you.
You came here
with Monica Johnson.
Do not be difficult.
Do not be noble.
It makes me feel unkind.
So please,
please!
Hello?
Qul.
Lugacetti?
How dare you call me
at this hour?
Who?
Gregory?
Here?
Certainly not!
No, I did not see him.
Oh. Don't worry,
Mr. lugacetti.
To stay out
all night in Paris
is amusing.
The worst that can
happen to him
is that he will have
a bad hangover.
Well, thank you,
madame francesca.
I'm sorry to
have bothered you.
Good-bye.
Not there.
She hasn't seen him.
That's not what she'll
say in a confessional.
I believe her, father.
Gregory wouldn't do this.
You don't know him.
He's dedicated.
To the flesh,
perhaps?
Let's review the circumstances then.
We were supposed to
have dinner at 9:00.
He doesn't come.
I came here
at midnight
when I should
long be in bed.
We wait.
At 6:00, we call to see
if there's an accident.
There is
no accident.
Now we call the only other
human he knows in Paris.
She denies
seeing him.
What is the logic
of the situation?
Something's the matter.
Yes,
but what?
If it is not folly,
it is certainly
irresponsibility.
Either fault is
a serious defect
in one who would
be a priest.
Perhaps it's better he
should find out so soon,
before he embarks
upon a course
for which he is
clearly unsuitable.
Who are you?
What are
you doing here?
I'm the husband
of the concierge.
Miss Johnson
asked me to go in.
What did you say
about miss Johnson?
She-she telephoned.
She-
she wanted her purse.
Where is she?
Um...
I swore not to tell.
But you must tell me.
I'm her friend.
No, no.
I don't know you.
But I tell you
I'm her friend.
How can
I convince you?
Are you catholic?
Catholic?
Yes, I am.
Well, I'm going
to be a priest.
Ha ha ha ha!
Look.
Read it.
I believe you.
Then where is she?
Napoleon.
Napoleon's tomb?
Oh, yes! Yes, sir!
I'll take it to her.
Americans.
Faster, faster!
Pull over
to the curb and stop!
What are
you doing here?
I wanted to find out
if you were safe.
Look at your face.
What did they do to you?
There's nothing broken.
I'm all right.
I'm so sorry you got
mixed up in this.
Why don't you just
go away and forget me?
Where did you go?
I went out the balcony,
spent the night
in the Metro.
Soon as
this place opened,
I paid my old friend
Napoleon a visit.
How did you know
where I was?
The concierge's
husband.
He swore
he wouldn't tell.
I found a way
to persuade him.
There was
a letter in...
He took it
last night.
Who is he?
Trevelle, that's his name. Trevelle.
What does he want?
Just to kill me, darling,
just to kill me.
But why?
Because he doesn't like
the color of my eyes.
Last night
before I met you,
I had the best seat
in the house at a murder.
And now...
Did they follow you?
They tried,
but I got away.
You're sure?
What do you mean,
a murder?
A man, a friend,
his apartment.
I don't remember much,
a door breaking open,
noise, guns.
When I looked up,
he was on the floor dead.
Then I ran.
Then you got
into my taxi?
Was it trevelle?
No. I don't know.
Just shots and guns.
I...
Can't you identify
the man?
No, but trevelle
thinks I can.
And he takes no chances,
no chances at all.
Why didn't
you tell
all this to the police last night?
Because I was
still kidding myself,
thinking no one would know
I was in the apartment.
That's why I lied,
told them I was with you.
All right. You must go to the police.
I'll go with you.
You must tell them
your life is in danger.
You're such a child.
Suppose I go?
They look me up.
They'll find a singer in a
nightclub without a work permit.
I'm a foreigner,
I've broken their laws.
Think they'll give me a
guard of honor like Napoleon?
Oh, they wouldn't
believe me.
You don't
know the police.
And they wouldn't
touch trevelle.
He's a big shot
in Paris,
well-known,
well-connected.
Don't you see?
It wouldn't do any good,
any good at all.
O.K.
We've got to see about
getting you out of Paris.
Merci, monsieur.
Merci.
Monsieur?
A reservation
to uh-Brazil
or any flight en route
leaving immediately.
The most immediate
is to Lisbon.
For yourself,
monsieur?
For a friend, a lady.
We can accommodate
madame on flight 95
leaving orly tomorrow
afternoon at 6:30 P.M.
Nothing sooner?
Nothing.
Nationality?
American.
Madame's name,
please.
Monica Johnson,
but for private reasons,
no publicity.
She's traveling under
an assumed name,
say uh...
Mary Jonas.
Of course,
I understand.
But the passport is in
the name of Monica Johnson?
Yes.
May I see it,
please?
I don't have it
with me.
Can you remember
the number?
No.
But I'll get it.
You go ahead
and make the arrangements.
Lisbon tomorrow night,
and then Brazil.
Nothing sooner?
And what about tonight?
My hotel.
It's out of the way
and respectable.
Now I've got to
have your passport.
I haven't got it.
Where is it?
Quite safe and neat in the
middle drawer of my desk.
You see how careful
and methodical I am.
You've
got to get it.
Sure. Let's pick up some
clothes at the same time.
Only trevelle's chums
are hiding in the closet.
No. I'll go anyway.
No, no.
I won't let you.
If they're there, it'll be
last night all over again.
I can get in and out
and they'll
never know it.
Take this taxi
to the hotel Remy.
I'll be back with the
passport and ticket.
Have a little faith.
Hotel Remy.
Get me
the American embassy.
Embassy?
Why the embassy?
Your passport's
been stolen.
Oh. That's par
for the course.
I don't know
what's in here,
but it's gotta
be better than that.
Thanks.
Telephone,
monsieur.
Let me take it.
I'm an old hand
with embassies.
American embassy?
Passport division,
please.
Hello?
Can I have
some information?
What happens when
an American citizen
mislays his passport?
I see.
Can it be done
in Paris?
How long
does that take?
Thank you very much.
Hopeless.
Maybe not
so hopeless,
once you've had a cup
of coffee and a bath.
I'd like a room
for the lady, please.
For miss Johnson?
How did you know
her name?
There have
been inquiries.
Always they ask for miss Johnson.
The police?
They say they are the police.
But when one is making
inquiries, who does not?
Well, that eliminates
this hotel,
and probably
a lot of others.
Sorry it wasn't
more fun.
But you've
nowhere to go.
Check.
I can't stay here,
and I can't
leave the country,
get a passport
without
an act of congress.
Is there someplace
where I...
I don't mean
to intrude,
but perhaps uh-
I can be helpful?
You know we have strange laws in Paris.
Hotels require
passports,
but sometimes when it is inconvenient,
citizens must make
their own arrangements.
They are
of course...
Expensive.
But if you know
the right man...
Do you know
the right man?
He is the right man.
Perhaps for...
20,000 francs...
What does that buy?
Privacy,
discretion.
Where?
I have an address.
Do you know
where it is?
No, but I bet I can
describe the neighborhood.
Do I have
to have a password?
20,000 francs, you will
be expected and welcomed.
I can imagine
in this outfit,
too welcome.
Is there someplace
where I can dress the part?
Stop the jokes.
This doesn't
make sense.
You don't know
where you're going
or what you'll do.
Just what
would you suggest?
The least you can do
is to face the facts.
I've been beating myself
over the head with facts.
I'm thinking
in circles.
Wait.
Maybe we can work this out together.
I'll go with you.
Who appointed
you my...
Private guardian?
I don't know.
Certainly somebody.
Tell him thanks.
I won't be long.
Are my friends here,
father du rocher
and Mr. lugacetti?
No, they are out
looking for you.
They think
that you are
at the bottom
of the seine.
Tell them
I'll be on schedule.
Well, in any case,
not to worry.
We're from
the Remy.
Yes, I know.
Come in.
Romantic, isn't it?
The money.
Oh.
You understand,
only until
tomorrow night?
Dacor?
Oh, uh-um...
American plan,
food, wine.
300 francs?
Oul.
I'll bet
it's delicious.
Here.
The service
wasn't included.
It's vinegar
and acorns.
But it's
warm and good.
Want some more?
It may be bad for
some people's livers,
but it's great for mine.
I feel better.
Well,
at least you can say
you've seen
the part of Paris
that isn't
loaded with tourists.
Oughtta make
quite a chapter
in your "my trip abroad" diary.
Look at this joint.
Not exactly
the ritz, is it?
I usually
do better than this.
The Dorchester in London,
grand in Rome,
verjahr in hamburg.
At least
one piece of luggage
in every hotel
on the continent.
The story of my life.
Could I have
a cigarette?
Why don't you tell me
about the Monica Johnson
who once had all her
luggage under one roof?
Well, the story I usually
tell to susceptible gentlemen
is the one about
the drunken father
with the mother
he used to beat.
And then, oh, I add 6 or
7 brothers and sisters,
and do a charming little sketch
of myself bringing them up,
a model of patience
and womanly virtue.
What does
that get you?
A good dinner.
And occasionally,
a souvenir.
A diamond bracelet
or a mink coat?
You wouldn't happen to have
either around, would you?
No.
Then you get the truth.
I haven't told it
in so long
I can hardly
remember it.
I was born in
willow falls, Nebraska,
well over
21 years ago.
My real name
is Jenny corbell.
My mother and father,
very nice people.
I was a stinker.
I looked like an angel
on a Christmas tree,
and boy crazy
right from the beginning.
My first boyfriend at 12,
the second
boyfriend at 12,
my third boyfriend at 12.
At 17, I smiled
at the right bald head
and won the local
beauty contest.
Dissolve, New York,
Paris, Rome.
That was 8 years ago.
Are your parents
still alive?
You need them
badly now.
I need a miracle,
darling.
Nothing grand.
Just a small spit
of a miracle will do.
There are no small miracles, Monica.
You're very nice.
Why didn't
you go home?
Oh...
I'm little girl turtle,
darling,
carry my home
on my back.
And darling...
You know why I call
you darling or mister?
I don't know your name.
Gregory.
Yes.
That feels right.
I...
Find you very warm,
Gregory,
and full of a quality
I've never known before.
I don't know
what it is.
Only it's exciting,
and a little marvelous.
You're so distant.
Don't be.
I'm closer than you think, Monica,
far closer than if I
touched you or held you.
You're a strange guy,
the oddest I've ever met.
Don't keep
saying that.
I hit a nerve.
What nerve, Gregory?
What makes
you so different?
I'm not so different.
I'm exactly like
any other man,
only I...
I'm...
Thinking about how to
get you out of here.
When it's dark, I'll
see about getting a car.
Then we'll go.
Sure. When it's dark.
What did he say?
He said there's someone
downstairs waiting for you.
Knows you're here,
won't go.
Who is it?
Where are you going?
I want to
talk to him.
It's all right.
Hello, Tony.
Hi, Greg.
How did you find me?
Easy. I bribed
the Porter.
Why are
you hiding, Greg?
What are you doing?
You wouldn't believe me if I told you.
Call it an act of mercy.
An act of mercy?
Greg, I know the cops
are looking for you.
You're hiding out
in the slums.
There's a woman they keep talking about.
What kind of an act of mercy is this?
Let me help, huh?
Don't get involved,
Tony.
Well,
somebody's got to!
Look, you're in
a strange country.
You don't even
speak the language.
I know you're doing
something you think is right.
Maybe it is.
But you can't handle
this load all alone.
Talk to someone,
get some advice.
From whom?
Father du rocher.
I can't
involve him either.
Then francesca.
She's
worried about you.
How did she know?
Because
I called her.
Look, Greg,
if you can't ask me,
why don't
you ask her?
I've got to work this out by myself.
O.K.
Tomorrow, the train
leaves for the seminary.
Do I go alone?
I don't know, Tony.
I don't know.
Who was he?
A friend of mine.
How did he know
we were here?
How do I know
I can trust him?
I'd better get out.
No, Monica.
Tony's all right.
We're safe.
How do I know
I can trust you?
You don't know how,
but you know you can.
We've got
another chance.
My friend
gave me an idea.
There's someone here in
Paris who might help us,
maybe get us a car.
You really believe
there's a chance?
Of course I do.
"Evening falls on Paris
like a velvet scarf."
I didn't make that up.
That's a lyric from
a song I used to sing.
Never caught
my act, did you?
I'm not Jane Powell,
but I manage o.K.
Mostly phrasing
instead of a voice.
The customers
like it.
That accordionist down
there is pretty good.
I used to sing that.
Yeah.
I wore that slim black
job with the red stole.
When I'm feeling
lost and low
embrasse,
embrasse-mol bien
when my heart
has lost its glow
then kiss me
once again
you're the one
that
makes my life
my breath,
my heart, my soul
forget the day
that come what may
embrasse,
embrasse...
Gregory.
I'm not
brave anymore.
I'm not even
gonna try.
I'm dead in my shoes
and I'm too stubborn
to admit it.
I give up.
I've had it.
I'd like to see
madame francesca.
Will you tell me
your name?
Gregory Fitzgerald.
Just a minute,
please.
You have been
a very naughty boy,
making us all
worry about you.
And you look
the worst for it.
I'd like to talk to
you alone, if I could.
For the moment, I must
keep my body in the salon
to encourage
the buyer.
But we shall
have a corner.
Now, what do
you have to confess?
I need a car,
francesca,
in confidence.
I want to get someone over the border,
someone without
a passport.
But you sound like
the Scarlet pimpernel.
What is this
extraordinary melodrama
in which
we are engaged?
Well, I met a girl.
What girl?
I'd prefer to...
You don't imagine
I would help a girl
whose name
I don't know.
Monica Johnson.
Monica John...
Oh, yes, I know her.
She sings
in a cabaret.
Yes,
that's the girl.
Yes, I made
a dress for her.
Yes, she's a connection of trevelle's.
Do you know him?
Yes, he's a customer
for many years.
He buys
dresses for many girls.
He stole
Monica's passport.
Stole her passport?
Ha ha.
Dear Gregory,
somebody's
pulling your leg.
No. I know
it sounds corny,
but it's
deadly serious.
She witnessed
a murder
and he's mixed
up in it.
That cannot be so.
I don't like this.
You are lying to me.
I've no right
to ask your help,
and you've every right to refuse.
No, no, darling.
Don't be so
hasty with me.
I shall help,
of course,
but I think we shall
have to consult someone.
Yes, with a friend.
Let me call him
and we shall go together.
Hmm?
Thanks.
I knew
you would help.
Where is he?
I saw him here
yesterday.
Well,
he's not here now.
He is coming back?
Now look,
just a minute.
Let me ask
a couple of questions.
What are you doing here?
Why do you want him?
We used to be
his friends
before he met you.
That's your problem,
and his.
Look, lady,
let him go.
Don't stop him from doing
what he came here for.
I'm not stopping
him from anything.
How could I?
I don't know what he's doing
or where's he's going.
You tell me.
Gregory and I,
we're on our way to enter a seminary
to study for
the priesthood.
Priesthood?
Maybe that's what
he was trying to say.
It's hard to believe.
I mean...
To be a priest.
I don't know
what I mean.
He told Tony
he was performing
an act of mercy.
And that must mean you.
Now, you in turn
must perform your own
and send him back
upon the path
to which
he was dedicated,
and with
the grace of God,
perhaps still is.
Come in.
What is this?
You wouldn't have come
if I had told you
where I was bringing you.
Francesca
brought you to hear
some things
you ought to know.
Please, come in.
You can hardly
expect me to come in
after our last meeting.
I am sorry for that.
Please.
Sit down.
I shall be candid.
Two nights ago,
my brother Michel
was killed by a person
or persons unknown.
He was dear to me.
I shall miss him.
So will his wife
and young daughter.
You cannot
think it odd
if I seek to find the
cause of his death,
and by what hand,
can you,
Mr. Fitzgerald?
I didn't know
it was your brother.
Odd.
I should have thought
Monica had told you.
She was,
as a matter of fact,
very fond
of my brother.
For a year,
they had seen
each other
a good deal.
What's that got
to do with it?
She was in my brother's apartment
when he was shot.
For reasons known
only to herself,
she refuses
to come forward
and tell
what she knows.
The reasons are obvious.
She knows nothing
and she's afraid of you.
Perhaps, they are
more complicated.
I propose
to find out.
Where is she?
I'll never
tell you that.
Why not?
She is an accessory
to the fact.
You are duty bound
to aid in the solution of a crime.
Yes, you are,
Gregory.
It's not the police
who want her, Mr. trevelle,
it's you.
My brother's death
is a private affair.
I intend to
handle it privately.
Perhaps, you will
be kind enough
to give Monica
a message for me.
Tell her to be here
at 7:00.
You may go if you like, Mr. Fitzgerald.
And don't worry, you
will not be followed.
I am depending
entirely
on your conscience
and good sense.
I give my word.
Good-bye,
francesca.
You meant well.
But I don't think
I'll see you again.
Trevelle,
you said you would
not follow him.
Certainly,
I said it.
And certainly,
I didn't mean it.
I've made
a fantastic mistake.
But, of course.
You're a woman.
I've been
waiting for you,
and hoping
you wouldn't come.
Silly, isn't it?
Monica,
I saw trevelle.
Trevelle?
We've both had
social afternoons.
How was Mr. trevelle?
Is it true
about...
You and his brother?
Yes, it's true,
me and his brother.
Or it was until I found
out he was married.
You carefully didn't tell
me any of this, did you?
You didn't lie,
but all I knew of you was a half-truth.
Half-truth?
And what did
I know about you?
Not a tenth
of the truth.
Not a suspicion of it,
father Fitzgerald.
Oh, yes, I saw your father du rocher.
I played Mary magdalene
very prettily.
Or was it jezebel?
Whatever it is,
I interfere
with you no longer.
You let me fall in love
with you. You know that?
And I'll bet you 6-2 and
even you're in love with me.
Oh, why did you bother?
What was in it for you?
Very happy to have
made your acquaintance.
I doubt we'll see
each other again.
We don't play
the same games.
Oh, yes we do.
Only we have
different rules.
The way I learned
is you play until
the game is over.
We'll get a lawyer,
Monica,
then go
to the police.
Oh no, we won't.
You're gonna have a collar
that goes on backwards,
and I'm gonna
try and survive.
Looks like the score's gonna
be posted pretty quickly now.
Trevelle's boys
have followed you here.
He gave me his word.
Trevelle's word,
not exactly a gilt-edged
security.
They're back
there, too.
Not much time.
Go over the roof.
All right,
let's go.
No, I've got a better
chance without you.
You've got
no chance without me.
Come on!
Father,
we need refuge.
Come with me.
What can
I do for you?
There's so much
to explain, father.
You said
you need refuge.
Yes, father,
for her.
Mademoiselle.
She'll take
care of you.
Come, sit down.
Are you hungry?
No, father.
How can I help you, my son?
You've already helped,
more than you know.
Perhaps,
I can help more.
What are you to
this tragic girl?
Nothing.
Search your heart
and find the truth.
The church asks you
to make your decision
out of
your free will.
You can still
live and love
as other men,
my boy.
There's
no hold on you.
Decide well.
I have decided.
Come.
I'll show
you your room.
Monica.
This is all
very strange to me.
My mother and father
used to scrub me up,
try and take me
to Sunday school.
When I cried and didn't want to go,
they gave up,
and I stayed home.
They said
it was a sin.
What is sin?
The willful breaking
of the law of God.
Can we be forgiven?
By penance.
God does not punish the true
penitent here and hereafter.
Power to forgive sin,
how wonderful.
How wonderful.
There is forgiveness,
but we must do penance.
How do you do
penance for...
Taking the life of
another human being?
Trevelle didn't
tell you everything.
I...
I killed his brother.
And he knows it.
I also loved his brother.
Let's face it,
I'm not a schoolgirl.
I wanted any kind of
love he could give me.
I did not know
he was married.
That's
the cornball truth.
And when I found out,
I tried to leave him.
I met another man.
I had a chance for a new
life with him in London.
He wanted to marry me.
Michel destroyed it by
telling him the brutal truth.
My friend wrote me
a terrible letter.
And that was that.
I'd let you read it,
only that's
the one trevelle took.
Then I faced Michel
and tried to tell him again
it was finished, over.
He wouldn't let me go.
He threatened me,
meant the threat.
In escaping, I...
I shot him
with his own gun.
In any court, Monica,
that's self-defense.
Trevelle has
the letter and the motive.
They'll never believe me.
I believe you.
Thanks, Gregory.
Now I'd like
to start being alone.
You'll
never be alone.
Whenever I'm afraid,
I'll see your face.
It may be
through your eyes
what I haven't
seen for so long.
Would it be all right
if I kissed you?
It would
be all right.
Good night.
In the morning,
I'll go for help,
the police.
Monica?
Help me.
Oh, my God,
I am heartily sorry...
Heartily sorry.
For having
offended thee,
and I detest
all my sins...
My sins.
Because I dread
the loss of heaven
and the pains of hell.
But most of all
because they offend thee, my God,
deserving of all my love.
I firmly resolve with
the help of thy grace
to confess my sins,
do penance,
and to amend my life.
Amend my life.
Amen.
This is no small
decision you make.
You not only
choose a way of life,
you choose a way
of eternity.
What does it mean
to be a priest?
To live in the midst
of the world
without wishing
its pleasures.
To be a member
of each family,
yet belonging to none.
To share all suffering.
To penetrate all secrets.
To heal all wounds.
To teach and to pardon.
To console and bless always.