C'mon, c'mon, fast.
Let me see your stuff.
Here's the money.
Zolo will be pleased.
I'm sure he will.
Stop!
Halt!
Hold it!
Get back!
He got shot.
I'm so sorry, Inspector Kumar.
So sorry.
See this gets locked
in Drugs and Narcotics
- Good afternoon, Sylvia.
- Hello.
Now, where did I...?
- The plane tickets? Sam!
- Of course.
And the agency
recommended a nanny...
Yes, her name's Amba and she'll
be waiting for you at the hotel.
And there'll be a car at the airport
just near the baggage claim...
you know, with one of them signs,
"Dr. Richard Avery."
- Come on, Sammy, your snack's ready.
- Amba's a nice name.
- Hey, Dad!
- Hey, buddy. How was school?
- Good.
- Really good?
- Really good.
- Come on.
Eat all this supper and I don't
want any milk left, all right?
So, Sam, are you excited
about Christmas in India?
I've got Sam's bags all packed, so
you won't have to worry about that.
I guess that's everything, isn't it?
What would I do without you, Sylvia?
I really don't know. But I am glad
you've decided to take him with you.
He needs some time with you.
I'm glad, too.
Mommy?
Sam?
- Sam, wake up.
- Mommy?
You just had a nightmare.
You okay?
You sure?
- Are you looking for anything?
- A grizzler.
Is that like a bear?
You're not gonna find any up here.
Bears hate to walk upstairs.
- Are you sure?
- Trust me, I know my grizzlers.
Let's get you back to sleep.
We've got a long flight tomorrow.
Here, put Charlie in charge. You
won't have more nightmares tonight.
Good night.
- You ready?
- Not all the way, please.
How's that?
Well.
- Good night, Sam.
- Good night.
Thank you for choosing Flight 114
to Bangkok, and on to New Delhi.
Dad?
What happens if the plane
can't get off the ground?
Then we get our money back.
Here we go.
Dad?
Is that what it looks
like when you die?
Like you said, with Mom.
No, Sam.
No, it's much different.
That way.
- Doctor?
- No, I'm not Dr. Yevchenko.
- You go to the medical conference?
- Your bags...
I'm not the doctor on your sign.
I'm looking for my driver.
I'm Dr. Richard Avery.
- I'm driver.
- No, I understand that, but...
- Do you speak English?
- Yes, I speak.
All right, terrific.
Thank you. Thank you very much.
- Everything looks so old.
- It is old.
Some of these buildings
are as old as me.
No way!
Good morning, sir.
- Cool.
- Come on, let's see what's inside.
- Nice!
- Yeah, very nice.
- How may I help you, sir?
- I'm Dr. Richard Avery...
...I believe I have a reservation.
- We've been expecting you, sir.
- Great.
- Did you have a pleasant journey?
Yes, pleasant but, uh, long.
Yes, sir, it's quite a distance.
I hope now that you're here...
you'll be able to relax and enjoy
a very pleasant stay with us.
I don't suppose a woman by the name
of Amba has been looking for me?
- She's a nanny from the agency.
- I'm sorry, sir, not that I know of.
May I see your passport
and a credit card, please?
Yes, I understand that but...
I don't feel comfortable leaving Sam
with someone I've never met...
or seen references for.
All right.
8 a.m. in the lobby,
with references.
- Okay, thanks.
- Sylvia didn't forget.
Sylvia never forgets.
Dad, we don't need a nanny.
We can talk about later.
Come on, let's get you to bed.
- But I'm not tired.
- But we got a big day tomorrow...
and we gotta get an early start.
Besides, it's 8 a.m. back home.
Dad, I'm always awake
at 8 in the morning.
A funny guy, huh?
- Know what happens to funny guys?
- Thank you, you can go now.
You better watch it!
I got you!
Will you excuse me
just for a moment?
Thank you.
- Is she all right for you, sir?
- Dunno. There's something about her.
It's just... I don't really feel
good leaving Sam with her.
I understand perfectly, sir.
I send her on her way.
Would you like me to try
to find somebody else for you?
I don't know, I don't know.
Ma'am, I think you have to go.
Sorry.
So... can I go with you?
I don't know, Sam.
It's just for adults.
- Real boring.
- You're gonna leave me again?
Mommy wouldn't leave me.
I don't get this.
You promise to be good?
Do everything I say?
Put your hands on top of your head.
Cross your heart.
All right.
But you gotta change that shirt.
Pretty amazing, huh?
You gotta sit tight and no wandering
around when the lights go down.
It's like a movie.
I'm gonna be right up there.
I'm the first speaker.
- What are you gonna say?
- Some really big words.
- Young man, what did I say?
- I'm not bored, I'm not bored.
You sit tight.
I'll be back real soon.
How do you do, sir?
Ladies and gentlemen, esteemed
colleagues, fellow doctors...
I'd like to welcome you to the
International Health Organization's...
Third Annual Biomedical Seminar.
And now it's my great
privilege and pleasure...
to introduce Dr. Richard Avery...
who has come here all the way from
Hollings Institute in San Diego, US.
Welcome, Dr. Richard Avery.
Thank you.
I am honored to have been asked
to give my opinion here today...
even if the topic is inherently
terminal to your livelihoods.
As the 21 st century begins...
the medical community find itself on
the verge of a scientific revolution.
While the last century
belonged to pharmaceuticals...
and to the technological gold rush...
the new millennium will be the era
of genetics and bioengineering.
Now it's easy to become caught up in
the excitement of this new frontier.
When Celera broke
the human genome code...
it was widely accepted that...
a wellspring of
medical knowledge...
medical knowledge,
understanding...
and cures would spring forth.
There is however... a parad...
Excuse me.
I'm sorry. Just a moment, please.
Excuse me, there was
a small boy sitting here...
Sam?
Excuse me.
- Did you see a small boy here...?
- Sorry, sir.
Thank you.
Excuse me, you were sitting close
to my son. Did you see him leave?
Your son?
Are these stairs to the bathroom?
Did a small boy go to the bathroom?
You're sure?
Nobody came by here?
- Sam?
- Dr. Avery?
My son has disappeared. He was
sitting here, now I can't find him.
- I'll call security.
- Will you, please? Thank you.
Sam?
Dr. Avery? Perhaps he's just
outside, he couldn't be too far.
Thank you.
- Sir.
- You on security, Steadman?
Excuse me, Dr. Avery.
This is Senior Inspector Kumar.
How do you do, Doctor?
- I'm Julia Hyde.
- You're American.
Yes, I am. I've been assigned here
as part of an anti-terrorist unit.
You think Sam was kidnapped
by terrorists?
Well, we cannot rule that out
at this moment...
but kidnapping for money
is very common in India.
Inspector Kumar works
in the Narcotics Division...
but we've both had previous
experience with situations like this.
So I've asked for his help.
- Where's the kidnapper's note?
- Have you called your wife?
No, I'm a widower.
I'm sorry to hear that.
"I have your child.
Answer your hotel phone tonight
for instructions.
Call the authorities and he dies."
Bullshit.
If they find out you're here,
they'll kill my son.
As a general rule they all say that.
It doesn't mean anything.
I don't care about general rules.
- Listen...
- You found the note under the seat?
Security did, yes.
Did anyone sitting here
see who left this?
It was dark.
Guess they were all looking at me.
Did you and your son
meet anyone last night...
or was he talking to anybody
that you can recall?
No one who would do
something like this.
You cannot be sure about that,
Doctor.
We'll be at your hotel tonight when
he calls, see if we can get a trace.
I can't risk that.
You're letting your emotions get
the better of your judgment, Doctor.
It's your decision,
but you should hear the facts.
Which are?
When the police are not involved,
most victims are not returned alive.
And if I do decide to go it alone?
It's police policy to respect
the wishes of the parent.
If we were to intervene and something
should happen to your son...
well, that's something nobody wants.
You're not making this easy on me.
Unfortunately,
there's nothing easy about this.
Doctor...
if I gave you medical advice,
you would say...
"leave it to the experts."
I think you should do the same.
It' s your decision.
Wait.
One...
two...
You let me down, Doctor.
- What do you mean?
- You have already disobeyed me.
Do not insult my intelligence again.
- That's not my intention.
- You play games, Doctor.
- Games?
- This one is called "Guess."
Your room is full of wires
running across the floor...
and a police man is listening
to our conversation...
smoking a cigarette.
Am I correct?
Keep in mind if you lie to me,
I will kill your son.
So tell me, Doctor, am I correct?
- Yes, you're correct.
- Very good.
I made a mistake.
Just tell me what you want.
No more police. I'll call again
later when we are alone.
If I even think you are talking
to the police, it's over.
When? When will you call?
That's my decision.
You just need to be ready.
- I don't want to wait.
- You've been given a second chance.
There will not be a third.
- I understand.
- One more thing:
The policeman just stamped out
his cigarette.
He wasn't bluffing.
- Did you get a trace?
- Not enough time.
What do you mean, not enough time?
All this time!
And did anyone check to see
that no one saw us come in?
Okay, let's just settle down.
- Next time I want you to work from...
- No. You had your shot.
- I just need to keep...
- Forget it, okay?
This is my son's life.
I'm not gonna risk it.
Big mistake. Trust me.
I did trust you. You can leave.
Listen, Doctor, this...
Come on, let's pack our things
and leave. Come on.
Here's my card if you need us.
Come on, come on.
Sleeping well?
Where's my son?
He's asleep now.
He asked me to tell you hi.
How do I know he's all right?
- Can you read this?
- Read what?
This. Can you read it?
"An e..."
"An eye..."
"For an e..."
"In the battle a...
against the terror."
Very good.
He's a smart boy.
What do you want?
I have money. I can do...
No. We will discuss that later.
- What is this?
- A beeper.
That is your son's lifeline.
Do what it says and
he will come to no harm.
I am good with the blade.
I have no interest
in killing a small boy...
but I will do what is necessary.
If you harm my son in any way,
I swear to God...
You will what?
Hunt me down and kill me?
You will not. You don't know
who I am and you never will.
You think you can keep searching,
but this is India, Doctor.
One child's life, more or less,
is nothing.
You will grieve and that is all.
Tomorrow, I will send instructions.
Follow them.
I will. I promise.
I hope you do for the sake
of your son.
This is the place, sir.
Wait here.
English?
Good book.
This, good book.
Here. No, thank you. Thank you.
- Sir?
- Rings?
Yes, this?
Sorry, sorry.
I gotta get that...
I'm a doctor.
I'll pay for it.
Take it all. I gotta go.
You want the jacket?
- I'm a doctor. It's an emergency!
- Money!
Don't hang up!
This was a test. Next time you will
be instructed to bring the money.
Pity about your jacket.
It suited you.
- No use looking for me now.
- Where's my son?
- He's not with me, but he is fine.
- What have you done? Where is he?
I'll call you tomorrow.
No, not tomorrow.
Let's do this now.
Tomorrow night.
You will be contacted at midnight.
Do as you did today and you will
have your son by midnight.
No, no...
The beeper.
My God!
Excuse me.
That's mine.
Please.
I have nothing. I have...
I'm sorry.
Money? No?
Money?
Please. I've lost...
I've lost my son.
Please.
The train station is about
45 minutes from here by taxi.
These other numbers...
I really don't know, sir.
- I wish I could be of more help.
- Thanks. Thanks a lot.
There's the taxi. Right on time.
What the hell's the doctor
doing here?
I thought Kumar said
Johnny's going to pick up the bag.
Quick, inform
the station of the trade.
45...
Is this for me?
Money.
No one told me to bring any money.
I never got a message
about any money.
Zolo.
Yes, Zolo. Right.
Is this for me?
He's got the bag with the goods.
And guess who comes out of the taxi?
This American doctor.
The one whose son was kidnapped.
And five minutes,
he comes out with the bag...
- Full of opium.
- You've got that, man.
Good morning, ma'am.
Kumar?
- What do you want?
- You ordered surveillance of Avery?
- That's none of your business.
- It is, and I want an answer.
Hyde, just leave it alone.
Do you realize you're putting
that child's life in danger?
I've been on this force
for 18 years...
- Then you should know better!
- You wanna tell me how to work?
No, you're up to something
and I'm going to figure it out!
Don't fuck with me!
Kumar, Miss Hyde,
I want to see you both in my office.
- What's the problem?
- This city woman...
- Excuse me?
- Kumar!
This Hyde woman is not only
interfering in my case...
she's also coming and
questioning me about my work?
He's tailing the American doctor,
which happens to be my case.
The doctor asked us not to interfere.
Yes, he did.
And if the kidnapper sees us now...
We have evidence that
he may be dealing in drugs.
What evidence?
He was seen picking up
3 kilograms of opium.
- Whose opium?
- It was a bait.
Sir, it was a bait for Zolo
and the American doctor took it.
- Okay, assuming it's true...
- It is! We have photos to prove it.
There must be some explanation.
Maybe the kidnapper's using him.
- Avery is no trafficker.
- Whatever! I can't take that chance.
Why is that?
Sir, Zolo and the doctor
are both Americans.
We all know it. Many parents stage
kidnappings for their personal gains.
This is Avery's first time in India.
He's a respected doctor...
he has no prior record,
it just doesn't make sense.
I've been working on Zolo's case
for a very long time...
I cannot let this go now.
I request you, sir,
we must continue the surveillance.
I'm sorry, Miss Hyde.
Kumar, you may carry on.
But be careful.
I don't want the kidnapper
and the doctor to know.
Thank you, sir.
All right.
- It must be her time of the month.
- Kumar!
Sorry, sir.
Can I come in?
I asked you not to come here.
No, you asked me
to stay off the case.
- Why are you here?
- Because it's still my case...
and because I don't want to see
anything bad happen to you or Sam.
And if you try and do this alone,
chances are something will.
I'm sorry, Julia,
I've made my decision.
Look, the police do things differently
here, and it's not always...
I understand.
Does that include Inspector Kumar?
I'll respect your decision.
But you'll at least need someone...
to talk to, someone who has more
experience in things like this.
It's my personal number.
You can call me anytime.
Is Sam your only child?
You have kids?
- They really do change your life.
- Yeah, that's what I hear.
Maybe I just haven't met
the right guy.
Well, that's what my mom says
anyway. I work a lot.
I understand.
When we had Sam, I said...
well, maybe this will make me
a better person.
Has it?
No. Not really.
But I was hoping this trip
would make me a better father.
Well, maybe it has.
I'm gonna get Sam back.
You need to get that.
It's probably someone from the
conference to check on things.
I'm sorry.
Be careful.
I will.
Julia, thanks.
There's a club called Y.I.A.
It belongs to a man called Zolo.
- What kind of club?
- I believe it's a disco, sir.
The true name is
Youth In Asia - Y.I.A.
- How do I get there?
- I'll get you a taxi, sir.
But be careful. Some of the crowd
out there is not the most desirable.
All right.
- What can I do for you?
- Gin and tonic.
Buy you guys a drink?
I'll take that as a no.
Maybe you can help me out?
I'm looking for someone.
And what makes you think
that we can help you?
- I got something he wants.
- Who? Who do you mean, man?
- Zolo.
- Zolo?
- Who is he?
- Who's Zolo?
Zolo who, man?
Who's Zolo?
He's gonna be really mad
if you guys don't help me out.
- Now you are making me mad.
- Don't make us mad, all right?
- Now you are making me crazy.
- I've got his beeper.
- Where'd you get this?
- You Zolo?
- How did you get that?
- I'm only talking to Zolo.
Are you stupid?
I got something he wants and I think
you know what I'm talking about.
No. Why don't you tell me?
I got his goddamn opium,
for Christ sakes. He paged me.
Come with me. Come.
- You have something for me.
- Yes. Let me explain.
- Bring it to me.
- I will. My son...
- Bring it to me. Now.
- Can I explain the circumstances?
This is very simple.
Do you have my merchandise?
- Then bring it to me. That's it.
- That's not it.
You want to barter... with me?
- No, I just want my beeper back.
- Your what?
My beeper. Whoever you
were paging has my beeper.
I need it back. It's important.
It must be.
It must be very important.
And you're right.
You have no choice.
I'm not negotiating over a beeper.
Get another one.
If I don't get it back,
I might as well be dead.
All right. What's so important?
You had no business
seeing that doctor today.
- I don't work for you.
- You work for the department.
Don't worry, I didn't tell him
you were following him.
So you stopped by for some chai?
Or something else?
- The man's son is missing.
- My drugs are missing! He has them.
And you know that very well.
Maybe too damn well.
If you have something to say, say
it. Otherwise, I have work to do.
Yes, I have something to say.
Next time you want to play doctor...
just call me.
Now that's some story.
I just have to get that beeper
back by midnight...
which gives me less than 5 hours.
- We're talking about half a million.
- We're talking about my son.
- I can't afford to care.
- You better care about my son.
Look, let's get one thing straight:
Blackmailing me isn't the
smartest move you can make.
- I don't have many moves left.
- All right.
Tell you what, bring me the bag
and I'll see what I can do...
I can't do that.
I don't see that you have
many options left.
Half a million ought to buy me
at least a couple of options.
What do you suggest?
You and I go get the beeper
from that guy...
then we get the bag.
Sound fair?
You have balls, Doc. That's
the only reason you're still alive.
Okay, let's go.
No one knows where Johnny is?
I know you wouldn't hold out
on me, right?
One more stop.
- Hello, Miss Hyde. You still here?
- Yes, I am. What's your excuse?
- I have to finish up this paperwork.
- You guys are big on it.
Amazes me so many forms and
signatures. Are those the Zolo files?
- Yes, they are a mess.
- I can see that.
And with the opium it's even worse.
10 pieces of paper and 6 signatures.
And if you miss anything,
you've had it.
- Is there paperwork missing or drugs?
- Well, it's a mess, a big mess.
I'm sure if anyone can sort it out,
it's you, Ganesh. Goodnight.
Thank you, ma'am. Goodnight.
- Sir.
- What did Miss Hyde want?
Nothing, sir.
Nothing?
- What was she looking at?
- Zolo case files, sir.
- What's this place?
- A place you'd never come.
Wait here.
Unless you see something you like.
Very funny.
- I'm here with Zolo.
- I'm here, too. Wanna play with me?
- No, thank you very much.
- Are you from America?
- She coming with you?
- What's your...?
- What was that all about?
- Now I'm angry.
Something's not right. Johnny has
just disappeared. No one's seen him.
- This whole thing has a bad taste.
- Maybe it's your opium backing up.
You joking?
I don't do opium. It's addictive.
You're a doctor, you should know that.
I can't believe I'll give it to you.
Not after seeing who you sell it to.
Save the morality lesson.
I get enough from my mother.
- That girl was just a teenager.
- Not anymore.
You think you're better than me?
We all deal something doctor,
some lie or injustice, some vice...
to get what we want.
Trying to save your son
with a bag of opium.
We all got our reasons.
So where is he?
I don't know.
- What time is it?
- Almost nine.
Look, Doc, I've done all I can.
So, let's get my stuff
and say goodbye.
That is not our agreement.
The only agreement we have is
I'll kill you right here, right now...
if we don't get my shit this minute.
I don't care about the money.
I will not be made a fool of.
We still have a couple of hours.
Wrong answer.
- My son is just...
- Fuck you.
Johnny's at home.
It's your night, Doc.
You're a lucky man. Get in.
Sorry, Miss. Sorry, Madam.
Sorry. Sorry, Madam.
Sorry, Miss.
- Johnny's got some place, huh?
- Why didn't we come here before?
Because he's never here.
Wiseass.
You want a drink?
No. Thank you.
I do.
Here. We celebrate.
Here's to you still being alive.
Here's to your son.
Thanks.
You know, seeing you makes me
maybe want to have a son.
I think you might be
in the wrong business.
You don't think I know that?
You think I do what I do
out of choice?
Well, we all make tough choices.
If I stopped tomorrow,
I'd be dead by sunset.
And I don't want to die,
you understand?
Yeah, but living isn't
just about surviving.
- Now it's your turn to survive.
- Come here. Hand it over.
When you give me my opium.
You'll hear it if it goes off.
Good evening, sir.
Jesus.
- This is your work, isn't it?
- I do what I gotta do.
So, where is it?
Son of a bitch.
Don't take it personally.
Call housekeeping.
They'll clean it up for you.
Oh, man. This is beautiful.
Police! Police!
Make one move, Mr. Zolo,
and I will be eternally grateful.
Bad move.
Kumar, what the hell?
This guy here invited me up
for a drink.
Salim.
Show me. What is inside that wall?
You know my son is in trouble.
Just bring the drugs out.
- Drugs? I had no idea...
- Shut up!
Let's go. Show me the drugs.
- I want to speak to Julia Hyde.
- Fuck Julia! I'm in charge here!
What the hell is going on here?
No booze?
Where's the opium?
Where is the drugs?
- Arrest these men!
- On what charge?
- You live in a sheltered world, Doc.
- Move!
We agree you picked up the drugs
from the train station.
And then?
I've told you ten times.
I went to the hotel.
Look, my son will be dead if
I don't get out of here right now!
You tell me the truth and
we can both help each other out.
I've told you the truth.
You don't want it.
Look, let me talk to my consulate
or something.
I've got to get out of here!
Dammit!
- Where is the opium?
- I don't know!
My son's life is at risk,
you bastard!
A thousand children's lives are at
risk because of Zolo and his drugs...
...and you work for him!
- No, I don't!
- You work for him!
- I don't!
- No, I don't! No, I don't!
Kumar!
Outside.
You can go for now.
And join your other friends.
Let's go backwards,
each one of us...
I didn't set you up.
- I didn't set you up.
- No shit. You had me cold.
So who saved my ass?
I don't know.
Then I don't owe you.
Everybody out.
All right, let him go.
- I want my beeper.
- I want my goods.
It's 11 o'clock for chrissake.
Tension's high, isn't it?
What the fuck?
I'm not fucking around this time.
- You even know how to use it?
- I think so.
Now empty your pockets.
You've been watching
too many movies, Doc.
Here. Now get the fuck outta here.
It's not the right one.
- It's the only one I got.
- I want the one Johnny had!
Johnny's dead!
They found him a couple of hours ago
with a bullet in his head.
That's the one Tiger
got from his house.
If that's not the one, then
I don't know where the fuck it is!
Why don't you put that gun down?
I'm doing what I could for you.
One of my own's dead.
Yours may still have a chance.
You fuck, who you think you are?
Jerking me all over town
for that shitty little beeper.
That's not Johnny.
What?
That's Johnny.
- The man we've been looking for.
- Not the guy I met in the market.
- Then how'd you get his beeper?
- I don't know.
I think we're both being
jerked around here.
We better do something about it.
Sleeping on the job, are you?
- I lost the beeper.
- You're not a responsible parent.
- Figured you'd come for the ransom.
- At least you're a clever man.
- Or are you?
- I think so.
You have the opium, don't you?
What? No witty comeback?
Come on, you've been watching me.
You're the only one
who could've seen me hide it.
So tell me...
...am I correct?
- Sit down.
I don't think so.
Drop the gun.
Drop the gun. Now!
- Now where's my son?
- He will be dead...
...if I don't get back in time.
- Who the fuck are you?
Watch the window.
Get out of the car.
Here. Take it!
Go for the tires.
Forget the tires.
- Shoot the guy!
- I don't want to kill him.
Get my ass on this guy,
I'm gonna...
Let me guess.
That's the guy from the market.
Sorry.
Car's gonna blow up.
That's gonna blow. Come on!
Thanks for coming.
- I need your help.
- Sure. What's going on?
- I think I know who kidnapped Sam.
- What?
It's all with the police and
I'm pretty sure Kumar's involved.
Okay, but how?
It's all about the opium.
I think Kumar kidnapped my son...
got me to steal the opium,
stole it from me...
and now's trying
to collect the ransom.
Do you have any proof?
It's the only way
all the pieces fit.
- Look, go back to the hotel.
- Julia!
Richard, please.
Let me help you with this.
There's some things about Kumar
that haven't set right.
I can get Sam back.
- All right.
- Go back to the hotel...
I will call you
in an hour. I promise.
Julia?
Thanks.
- So?
- So she thinks it's Kumar, too.
She wants us to go wait for her
at the hotel.
Give me your phone.
Sanjay?
Sanjay, is that you?
It's Julia.
The lady cop? You're shittin' me.
He just pulled off, Inspector.
Quite fast. We are in pursuit.
- Let's go?
- Let's go.
There she is. Right there.
Dad? Where's my dad?
- Where's my dad?
- Sam!
- I need you to go and sit down.
- But where is he?
Sit down. Sit back down.
Stay there.
Sam, I need you to be very quiet.
Can you do that?
- Dad!
- Drop it!
- Don't!
- Please!
- I'm not fucking around!
- Drop it!
Don't be an asshole, Zolo!
Drop it! Drop the gun!
- Drop it!
- Please.
Now your car keys.
Now I want both of you
to move over there.
Move it!
- Richard, move it!
- Just leave Sam.
- I'm sorry. I can't do that.
- Julia, please.
Do as I say and I'll call you
at the hotel let you know...
where you can find me.
Julia, why?
- Is it all about the money?
- Isn't it always?
Police! Stop!
It's Agent Hyde.
I just rescued the boy from Zolo.
Stop her!
- She's got the drugs in the bag!
- Arrest them. We'll sort it out.
- Don't move!
- She kidnapped Sam.
- He's right. She is lying.
- Shut up.
- Come on.
- No, I'm not going!
That's far enough, Miss Hyde.
Your game's over.
Hand me over the child.
Vasu, arrest her.
- Get the gun from her.
- Give me the gun! The gun!
Salim, get the child.
- Stop or I'll drop him! I swear!
- Dad, help!
I said stop!
I swear to God, take one more step
and he's dead.
Dad, help!
Give me back my son.
I want everyone to get in their cars
and drive away.
I want safe passage out of here.
- Agreed. Give me the boy.
- Don't fuck with me, Kumar.
- I'm not leaving without the boy.
- Dad! Help!
- Stop it!
- Dad, help!
Julia, I know you.
I know you wouldn't hurt Sam.
- You trust me?
- Help!
Julia, enough.
It's over.
There's no way out of this
and you know that.
Please. Let Sam go.
I'm gonna count to three.
Either you do what I say or he dies.
- One.
- Dad!
- Two.
- Okay.
Okay. You will get what you ask for.
We are leaving now.
Everybody out now. Doctor, leave.
Salim, get a car ready for her.
Is the boy okay?
I think so.
It's okay, buddy. It's all over.
I knew you'd come.
I knew you would.
You're getting soft
in your middle age.
You're just getting soft...
in the middle.
Come on, boys.
Nice looking boy.
Your daddy loves you.
You be a good boy.
Look for the bags.
- Can we go home now?
- Yes, Sam. That's a great idea.
CAPTIONS BY VIDEOLAR
Ripped by McLane