TRANSMISSION
Paulo, let's go.
Do you hear me?
I'm talking to you!
One...
Two...
Two and a quarter,
don't let me get to three...
Two and a half,
I'm warning you, Paulo!
Three.
Give it to me!
Give it, Mom!
Come on!
Give it to me!
Careful!
I'm sorry,
I'll get you another.
- I don't want another one.
- It was an accident!
Paulo!
How was school?
You're never going to talk
to me again, is that it?
That's a shame...
I bought that chocolate ice cream
you love,
but since you're so mad,
you won't want it, will you?
- Who is it?
- Isabel!
- You're going out again?
- I'm going out with a friend.
Hello?
Yes, yes, come up.
Happy birthday to you
Happy birthday, my dear
Paulo...
I'm waiting for my kiss.
Mummy'll be sad.
Goodnight then,
sleep well, my angel.
'Night, mom.
- See you later, Isabel.
- 'Bye, Teresa, have fun.
Paulo...
There you are!
Good morning!
Are you still asleep?
Mom,
what happened to grandad?
Nothing!
Not that one,
the other one, dad's dad.
I don't know,
I haven't seen him for ages.
But why don't I know him?
I'll tell you one day,
when you're older.
When? When I'm your age?
Why can't I know now?
Finish your breakfast
you'll be late.
Go on, mom, tell me.
Your grandfather lives a long way away,
that's all.
- But I want to meet him!
- That's enough!
Get a move on.
I tell you, he moved!
I just have to meet him.
- But won't your mom let you?
- Didn't you see the ball, stupid?
It's your turn.
What's that?
My mom's working during the holidays,
she's signed me in this summer camp.
But I'm going to look
for my grandad instead.
- What if she finds out?
- I'll take my mobile.
When she rings,
I'll pretend I'm at the camp.
But I'm going to need your help.
Take lots of pictures.
I wish I could go with you,
can't you fit me in your bag?
I can now.
I've got a present for you.
- Well?
- Yes! You look great!
Here. Don't put it all
in the same place.
This is to eat on the bus.
Okay...
Wait.
I'm going to miss you.
Let me dress,
I'll come down with you.
It's all right, mom.
André and his mom and dad
are waiting for me downstairs
and we're already late.
That's the one I owe you
from the other night.
Off you go. Be good!
What did I tell you? It was easy.
Easy for you, you didn't have to
persuade my brother to bring the car.
- Come on, hurry up!
- Nice one, how did you do it?
I caught him bumming fags off dad,
I said I'd tell mom if he didn't.
You owe me one!
Where are you going today,
Mr. Salgado?
There're so many possibilities,
it's hard to choose!
Well... I'm off.
See you later.
A ticket to Estremoz, please.
Well? Where did you go today?
I went to Seville to see Cordobéz.
He was magnificent... magnificent!
Excuse me,
I'm looking for Monte da Ribeira,
Mr. Miguel Salgado.
Well now...!
We have a visitor!
Look at you, you're not old
enough to drink even!
How old are you, young fella?
- Ten?
- What if I am?
If you are, it's no age to be out
on your own! Where's your mom?
I'm looking for my grandfather.
Your grandfather?
Who is your grandfather?
Mr. Miguel Salgado
Come on, I'll show you the way
to Mr. Salgado's place.
Right then!
Just follow this trail,
it'll take you straight there.
'Bye.
Thank you, Mr. ...
Corvo.
Lúcio Corvo.
Hello?
Hi, mom.
What?
Ah, it's because
I'm playing hide and seek.
I'll 'phone later.
Yeah...
Mom, I already said yes.
Yes, I miss you, too.
Oy! What are you doing here?
I... I'm looking
for Mr. Miguel Salgado.
What do you want with him?
He's very busy at the moment.
He... he's my grandad.
Your grandad?
Little Paulo?
Let me look at you!
You're so big!
Come, come with me!
Mr. Salgado...
I've got a surprise for you!
- It's a bit small for a surprise.
- I'm not small.
What's the matter, is he lost?
Tell him who you are!
Who are you?
It's me, grandad.
- Don't you like the soup?
- It's fine.
When's your mother getting here?
She had to stay in Lisbon,
working.
But she knows you came?
Sure...!
And why didn't she tell me
you were coming?
She thought a surprise
would be nicer.
You don't want more soup?
All right.
Make up a bed in Carlos' room.
Come on.
Well?
What do you think of the colour?
It's red.
Taste it.
Go on, try it! Go on!
Put it in your mouth, swill it
round then spit it out there.
Go on!
Don't go near that one,
he's got a temper.
This one here's much nicer.
- You can even go for a ride.
- I never rode a horse!
On his nose, stroke his nose,
they like that.
Come on, let's go.
- It looks like new. Is it broken?
- No, it's in mint condition!
Always ready to take off.
- Grandad, it'll never take off from here!
- It doesn't have to, it's special!
It'll take me anywhere I want.
- But what happened to it?
- Nothing.
No, no, come here.
No one sits there.
But grandad,
we'll never get anywhere like this.
It depends where you want to go.
- To Lisbon?
- No, not there.
Too many people, lots of buildings,
too much confusion!
- And what about going to the clouds?
- Ah, that's different.
These cars are very good for clouds!
In fact, the angels use these cars!
It's true, I've seen it!
They have no wheels, no indicators, the
roads are wide, there are no accidents!
I don't believe you.
You don't?
That's bad. At your age you
should believe in everything.
All right, take me.
No, not now.
We're going home now,
Irene will give you a bath
then we'll have dinner.
- Oh grandad!
- That's enough, come on, let's go!
- Hello, grandad.
- Hello.
You're just in time,
you can finish this for me.
Grandad.
If I wash the car,
can I go with you?
Let me see....
No.
It's true,
we're really in the sky.
You can see it?
- How'd you do that, it was so cool!
- I didn't do anything.
It happens.
Grandad, can we go again?
What do you think you're doing?
Don't you know kids your age
don't drive? Out, get out now!
I'm sorry.
Promise me you'll never get
in this car on your own again.
No, no,
I want to hear your voice.
You have to realize
that words are important!
I promise.
Now if we behave ourselves...
... this afternoon
we'll go for a spin in the car.
Come on, son.
Is grandad a magician?
Well, I don't think so, I've never
seen him pull a rabbit out of a hat.
It's not that. It's the car,
how does he make the car do that?
- He took you in the car?
- Yes, it was amazing!
You're luckier than me, he's taken me
once or twice and nothing happened.
- The car didn't budge an inch.
- He said he'd take me again.
Grandad, if my dad was alive,
do you think he'd look like you?
He was much slimmer than me.
But do you think we'd all
have lived here, together?
Of course, of course we would.
It's a house we could have all lived in,
there was enough room for everyone.
Who decides things like that?
I used to think no one did.
Not anymore.
Now I'm not so sure.
- Grandad, what happened...
- Stop asking questions!
You want to know too much!
What happened, how it happened...!
I'd really like to know
what might've been...
- Hello.
- Hi!
Hello!
Hi, grandad!
Jorge, show Paulo your drawing.
- Dad!
- Hello, son.
Hi, honey.
- How was your day, son?
- I... dad...
I've got great hopes for the wine
this year.
Me too.
When production really gets going,
we'll have the best wine in the Alentejo.
Shall we eat?
Come on, love, you too.
- What's the matter? Trouble at school?
- No.
What's wrong?
Stop it! It's not real!
Grandad, what happened?
You lied to me about your mother.
She doesn't know here, does she?
- We'll talk tomorrow.
- Grandad, please.
Paulo...
Come with me.
Take my hand, ok... there!
You're heavy.
See you later.
Give me your hand...
I want you to have this key.
From now on,
the car's as much your as mine.
But you must be careful,
there's only two.
Mine and yours, no one else's.
Promise me one thing.
As long as I'm alive, you'll never
drive this car on your own.
I promise, grandad.
Grandad...
What's going on?
It's time for you to go back home.
But I want to see my father again!
You've already shown me you're a man.
Don't try and get round me by whining.
Please, grandad!
No, come on, let's go.
Goodbye, kid.
- See he gets to Lisbon safely.
- Don't worry.
Blast you!
I've put petrol in, checked the oil,
the spark plugs, what more do you want?
Have it your way!
Stay here on your own!
Are you tired?
Don't worry, I'm tired too.
So, you fixed the car then?
Are you going to tell grandad
I'm here?
No, of course not.
- Thank you.
- You're going to tell him.
What's this?
Didn't I tell you to go home?
I'm very disappointed in you.
- What am I going to do now?
- I tried to start the car.
I know I promised I wouldn't,
but it works, it's not broken!
Never mind that.
Ring your mother
and tell her where you are.
It's the voice mail.
Leave a message.
Mom, it's me Paulo.
I've got something to tell you,
but don't get mad.
I didn't go to summer camp,
I'm in the Alentejo with grandad.
Paulo, what's going on?
Yes, he's looking after me.
Let me speak to him, now!
Mom, I saw the house
you lived in with dad.
Paulo, pass the 'phone over,
do you hear me?!
She wants to speak to you.
Hello?
Hi.
No, l... I even put him on the bus,
but he got off.
All right, see you tomorrow.
Just a minute.
Did you really get the car going?
See?
Let me try.
Go on.
How did you do that?
Go on, in the back,
no one sits there.
Look, grandad, look who it is.
It's you!
You're making it all change.
I never wanted it to be like this,
never!
- Oh grandpa, I want to see him!
- No, Paulo, it won't help!
But he's my dad!
I'm glad we've arrived!
Come on in!
Carlos, come with me.
Excuse us.
I was starving!
- You won't get married before the harvest?
- We haven't thought about it yet.
For the love of god, get a move on!
I don't want an illegitimate grandson!
You know we want to go to Lisbon
and I thought you could help us.
- Just until I get a job.
- What's this nonsense?
Haven't you got a job here? And land?
And a house? You're having me on!
Why will you only help me
if I do what you want?
I'm the only one who makes
you see sense, that's why!
Do I have to spell it out? I want
to be me! Not an extension of you!
No way! No way!
I'll only help you if you'll stay here
on this land that belongs to you!
If you don't,
you can count on me for nothing!
Dad's becoming impossible,
he's getting more and more pig-headed.
Calm down, we'll decide what to do
when the baby's born!
How you manage to stay so calm?
What's your the secret?
It's very simple.
I think of some names.
Joana, Filipa, Hugo,
João, Diogo, André.
If you say them fast enough, it sounds
like a lullaby. Do you want to hear?
Joana, Filipa, Hugo,
João, Diogo and André...
If it's a boy
I want to call him Paulo.
- How come you get to choose the name?
- Because I'm the man!
I'd like to see a man
carry this around for nine months!
Joana, Filipa, Hugo,
João, Diogo and André...
Hello?
Mom!
Half past ten?
Yes...
Okay...
See you...
Do you want to go and fetch her?
Or shall we ask Francisco?
Ask Francisco, that's best.
Francisco?
Where's Paulo?
Paulo's waiting back at the house.
Mr. Salgado sent me to pick you up.
- How is he?
- He's fine.
Mom!
Hello, my angel!
I've been so worried about you.
- I'm fine, mom.
- I've missed you so much.
Hello, Teresa.
Look at you...
you haven't changed a bit.
Hello, Irene.
Paulo's been very good.
It's lovely having a child
around the place.
It's done Mr. Salgado good, too.
Mom, I saw the house
you and dad lived in together!
And you know,
grandad's got a magic car!
A what?
Where's grandad, Irene?
He must be in the study,
he'll be out shortly.
Let's go in...
Can I get you anything?
Yes, yes, thank you.
Mom's here!
Hello, how are you?
Very well, thank you.
Would you like some coffee,
I've just made it?
Mom...
I stuck the labels on,
just for you.
By yourself?
- Why don't you have it at dinner?
- Not for me, I don't like wine. Here...
I have a present for you.
Thank you.
Not here Paulo, outside.
I know that...
You know that what?
I should have told you straight
away that Paulo was here, but...
But what?
But I...
I was knocked out.
I've been a grandfather
for the last ten years...
But the fact is...
... I never behaved like one.
Sit here.
We need to talk.
I've always trusted you...
you lied to me.
I'm sorry, mom.
Promise you won't lie to me again.
I promise.
- I've missed you.
- Me too, mom.
Let me show you round.
This is the magic car.
- I can't believe he kept this car!
- What is it, mom?
Nothing.
Come on,
perhaps you can go with us.
I don't want you to get
in this car ever, do you hear?
What's going on?
What's the matter with you?
Mom...
I saw dad when I was in this car.
I don't know what you've
been filling his head with,
but this is the last time
you'll see my son!
Teresa... it's all in his imagination.
The car broke down ages ago...
Have you at least
told him what you did?
Don't you think if I could have
changed all this, I would have done?
I was right
to keep Paulo away from you.
Joana, Filipa, Hugo,
João, Diogo and André,
João, Diogo and André...
If you say them fast enough,
it sounds like a lullaby.
How did you...?!
Only your father and I knew...
Now do you believe me?
This was the day you were born.
Are my mom and dad inside?
No.
Just your mother.
- This is it! I'm scared, Irene!
- Everything's fine, it'll be all right.
Where is he when I need him?
- Carlos!
- We have to go!
Tell Miguel to go and get him!
I need him here with me, now!
Mr. Salgado, there's no point
hanging around here worrying.
Teresa just wants Carlos here
with her.
But is she...
- All right?
- Yes, she's fine!
Don't think about
what happened to your wife!
It's not that, it's...
I get nervous.
They'll take care of her,
you'll see.
Go on, she's almost there,
it'd be better if Carlos got here
before the baby's born.
What are you doing here?
Can't you see I'm busy?
Have you thought that right now a child
is being born in the hospital here?
A child who happens to be yours? Is this
how you want to remember his birth?
I'm not ready!
Do you think any man's ready
for something like this?
Do you think when you were born,
I was ready?
Listen.
I've been thinking.
There's the old barn,
that's not being used for anything.
We could do it up for you,
make a bigger house...
More spacious,
add one or two more rooms.
You never know, might make
me a grandfather again.
How many times
do we have to go through this?!
We're going to Lisbon
with our son! That's final!
And what are you going to do with him?
Send him out begging?
Grandad...
Grandad!
You're going to be fine.
It was just a scare,
now you have to rest.
- Look after yourself, Miguel.
- Thank you, 'bye.
- He's resting.
- Well, doctor?
It could have been
the onset of a heart attack.
- Is that serious?
- I don't think so.
What was he doing?
It was some foolish game
in the car with my son.
He shouldn't drive for a while.
Don't worry, doctor,
I'll take care of that.
Goodnight.
Paulo,
the doctor says he'll be fine.
But it's my fault,
I made all that stuff happen.
I don't know how, but I did.
No, it wasn't you.
There's always some reason
why things happen.
Hi.
We're going now,
Francisco's taking us to Lisbon.
I know.
Goodbye, Miguel.
Paulo wants to talk to you.
Sit here.
I've got something for you.
- No, I can't take this, not this.
- You can drive it in bed.
I'll take it on one condition.
When I get better, I give it back.
Not that I don't like your car,
it's great!
I'm just more used to my own.
Something else?
- Did you do this?
- No, I got it from my dad's house.
But how?
I don't know, I think it's because
I really wanted it to be true.
Didn't you like my father?
You're saying that because you
heard us arguing from the car?
Do you remember I told you once
you have to be very careful with words?
Sometimes...
... we say things we don't mean.
But it's so hard to take them back!
So hard, dear god! Well...!
Tell me something.
That key I gave you,
the famous key.
Is it safe?
It's safe, grandad.
'Bye, son.
'Bye.
Irene?
- Are you all right?
- Yes, but...
I need you to go to the chemist,
I've run out of these.
Get off with you.
I don't want to leave you
on your own.
Don't worry about that.
I'm bad, but not that bad.
I just don't fancy another
sleepless night, that's all.
Go on!
- We have to go back!
- Don't be silly.
He's going to try to start
the car again, I know he is!
- Calm down, Paulo!
- Irene hid his key.
He took mine! Mom!
We'll phone Irene to check,
okay?
Hello?
Miguel?
Where's Irene?
Oh, all right.
Well don't get out of bed.
Yes, wait, Paulo wants to speak.
Grandad?
Are you still in bed?
What are you doing?
All right. 'Bye.
- He's lying!
- What?
He can't be in bed,
he doesn't have a 'phone in his room.
- If we wait much longer...
- He might be right.
You never know, you might
make me a grandfather again.
How many times
do we have to go through this?!
We're going to Lisbon with our son!
That's final!
Did you hear what I said?
Teresa and I are going to Lisbon
with our son, whether you like it or not!
You are my only son, I'll do what
you want, I'll stand by anything!
Miguel!
- Well, doctor?
- All we can do is wait. Excuse me.
That's the second time today
you've washed that car.
I should never have taken you away
from your grandfather, I'm sorry.
Mom...
Yes, my angel.
I saw the accident.
It wasn't anybody's fault.
It wasn't grandad's fault.
Mom! Mom!
Happy birthday, my dear
Happy birthday to you!
Happy birthday, angel.
I've got a surprise for you.
How long does it take to get to Lisbon?
- About three hours.
- So much? When do we stop?
- We just left! Are you fed up already?
- There's nothing to do...
Think of something and time will fly.
Joana, Filipa, Hugo,
João, Diogo, André...
How do you say it?
Joana, Filipa, Hugo,
João, Diogo, André...
Say it fast enough
and it becomes a lullaby...
- All together now!
- Joana, Filipa, Hugo, João, Diogo...