I can't ask anymore from you.
No coach could.
Nobody.
And you'll win or not because of this,
because of who you are,
and how special you are.
How special you are to me.
You will win tonight.
Because it's meant to be.
Good morning!
It's 65 in Oklahoma City.
Feels like 99 this morning.
And you'll dive in heatwave,
worry nothing.
...given up, but he will appear on
the South Dakota ballot this Fall.
Republican presidential nominee,
Barry Goldwater,
has termed low morality.
♪ Come to Mommy, darling ♪
♪ Please, do not cry ♪
♪ Daddy's gone to heaven ♪
♪ Way up in the sky ♪
It's KADA farm report,
brought to you by
the Wimbash Funeral Home.
This lousy drought,
that about says it all.
With hogs and feeder cow
prices down 8 percent.
Goat wheat down 2 cents to 2.32.
Milo at 2.48.
Corn 1.09 to 1.29 a bushel.
Grape at 41.
Four-leaf staple cotton
averaging 33 cents.
Heat is still in the 100's every day,
and boy, that humidity.
But hey, look on the bright side.
Our FFV Chapter was named winner...
in the State Farm safety contest.
How about that?
We also took second...
in the electrification contests
for the southwest district.
So, don't tell old Jerry Dodd...
that things ain't looking up
in Middletown.
In other local excitement is too.
The football of junior high
that goes to extreme.
Hey, easy on Mama's table.
You boys be careful with that.
Yes, sir.
Now, I know
it's not as nice as I...
- I, I made it seem.
- Shh!
It's our very own first home.
Jean, are you sure
you're gonna be okay...
- with all this?
- Honey, stop.
- Stop worrying.
- I mean, it's not...
- Shh!
- what you used to.
I'm sure.
Yes. It's...
it's what you worked so hard for.
I think, it's gonna be lucky here.
Clayton Driscoll from Fairfield,
Miss Rogers, reporting for duty.
- Just a minute, spooky dear.
- Good Lord.
How long does it take
to find the budget?
I got places to go.
B, Miss Rogers.
- B for budget.
- Yes, sir.
Now, how many times I'm gonna
have to point this out to you?
- Yes, sir.
- Never again.
John has his own system.
Just, just give her a second.
Principal Moreland, Clayton Driscoll,
the new boys basketball coach.
Oh, here, I found them
where I looked the first time.
Excuse me, excuse me.
I'm supposed to see Mr. Bannister.
- Ellis, this is Clayton Driscoll.
- I, I know who he is.
Just sit down, son.
Take a seat.
Wait your turn like everybody else.
And, uh, you're not
the new boys basketball coach.
Job went to somebody
better qualified.
Driscoll, wait!
Hold on!
Driscoll!
John Bannister had
a heart attack yesterday.
Bad one.
He's in the hospital.
- Will you stop by my house, Susan?
- I will.
Two young kids.
We're all turned around.
Oh!
I'm sorry, Mr. Moreland.
I didn't know.
But, that man in there,
- he was--
- I, I know, I know.
It was wrong how he did that.
That's just his way.
Ellis Brawley.
He runs the school board.
And most everything else
around here.
His family has forever.
What's he mean about me not coaching?
Well, you, you know, uh,
big Vern Hooper, played at OU?
- Yeah.
- Well.
He's who Brawley hired
to coach boys.
He's, he's a nephew of George Brand.
President of Brawley's bank.
Deacon at his church.
Brand's on the school board too.
He can't do that.
I got contracts.
That's right.
Nothing's changed.
That's good part.
You're still a coach.
Teaching history.
Same salary.
Jean's got a job
over the county agent.
I'm still coaching.
That's right.
Well, who then?
You out of your mind?
- Just, now, wait.
- No!
- Just wait till Bannister's back.
- Are you kidding me? No!
Me, coach girls basketball?
Clay!
Not for a million dollars,
Mr. Moreland.
Just check the contract.
I'm sure it says: History teacher
and boys basketball coach.
But, it's got to say: Boys.
Oh, man!
Just plain coach.
Oh, Jesus! I sure wish
I had something, Clay.
But, it's September.
We're all hired up.
Hey, try Farrell Handerson.
I already did.
Thanks, Joe.
Why me, Jean?
Why me?
- Seven years, second fiddle.
- I know.
- I finally get my shot.
- And now, this?
And I know you.
And I know
you'll make this work.
I don't wanna coach girls.
I think, Mrs. Bannister...
and her children got
a way worse deal than us.
And what's wrong with girls?
Didn't I play girls basketball?
Not here, you didn't.
Here, it's a joke.
I went around and I asked.
What did Joe Brody say?
Go see Bannister
when he gets better.
He hired me, he'll make it right.
It's good advice.
What if he doesn't get better?
Did he really say: Ball?
Is this girls basketball?
Yes, it is.
And I'm Mr. Driscoll.
I'm the new--
Sorry.
I'm the new coach.
Go get dressed.
We only got an hour
before lunch.
Come on, now.
Up!
It's, it's right, 2 times, over.
Two times.
One,
two,
over.
Helen, pay attention.
Quit laughing, Helen.
One, two, over!
You just pass the ball.
When you get the ball, pass it.
Next screen. Come on.
Pass. Go behind.
You alright?
You sure? Alright.
It's not fun move.
It's anything but funny.
Hey, relax, Coach.
It's not like it's
for real or anything.
Get out now.
Nobody ever said,
they couldn't watch.
Thought, it was a free country.
Not from 11 to 12, to me.
Come on.
Next screen, come on.
Pass. Go behind.
Pass. Not bad.
Pass.
Next drill.
Get the ball.
Get the ball, get the ball.
Get the ball!
Women get to be fast!
And rebounding.
That means "conditioning".
Too slow now.
Pick it up.
You're gonna be in
the best shape in your lives.
No one's gonna out-hustle you.
Come on, bring it home.
Come on.
Helen, some time today.
My daddy says,
you're supposed to coach boys.
You don't even want this job.
He says, you'd never been
a head coach before.
Your daddy has a lot to say.
He works for Mr. Brawley.
He runs his oil company,
and likes me to shoot a lot.
Well, that's good to know.
I want five baseline laps,
and 20 more free-throws before lunch!
Come on now.
Well, three more quit today.
All I got is 8 girls
to start the season with.
Mr. Moreland called me
into his office.
Mm-hm.
Their daddies aren't happy.
And neither is Mr. Brawley.
He made a point of it.
It's the drought.
Clay, it's got everybody upset.
Yeah, he said that to.
Mr. Moreland knows
what you're up against.
It's a different challenge with girls.
Jean,
I only know one way to coach.
Yeah?
Well, you know,
there's only one color of red,
but a whole world
of different shades.
Stop being so damn wise.
Okay, I want, I want
patience on offense.
Alright now, constant motion
using those screens,
and get the ball down low.
Now, uh, on, on defense,
we're gonna start man-to-man,
and fall back to a zone.
I want 2-3, depending on those matches.
Now, always look for motion.
You're always looking for the screens.
Now, we have no size.
That means, we have no depth.
We have no depth means,
if you foul, you're out.
I can't have that.
So, be, be tough.
But, but be smart about fouls.
Don't foul.
Questions?
No questions?
Alright, look, uh, look,
I, I know I've been tough.
And probably, a lot less
forgiving than you used to.
But, uh, um...
that's, that's, that's who I am.
I never had a break
in my whole life.
And I wasn't born with
much talent, only will.
So, I had to work my tail off at it.
Winning came hard.
But, it sure felt better than losing.
It's, uh,
it's all I know.
It's all I could share.
Coach,
you can't yell loud enough
to run me off.
I've been playing three years,
and we've never won nothing.
I stink and I know it.
But...
I like the way you coach...
'cause, even though,
we're not boys, you still care.
So,
play me or not,
but don't worry,
I'm staying.
Me too.
Come on. Follow me.
Oh, no, no, no.
Come on, come on.
Come on, get off.
Don't get on there.
Come on.
You're supposed to--
Pride! Pride!
They're supposed to be on this.
They're not on the right side.
They can do it.
Let's see it. Pride!
Pride! Pride!
Stop the ball.
Stop the ball!
Put your hands up.
No more, ladies, no more.
We're dying on the vine.
Come on, now.
Yeah!
Coach, I'm trying.
Hey, you're doing good.
Last year, they scored 90 on us.
Two minutes.
Gather around.
Let's go.
Get on out here.
Listen, I wanna tell you something.
Next--
We, we got to work harder.
We just have to work harder.
- You know what I'm talking about.
- Yeah, but...
- Jean has nothing to do with this.
- I don't care.
I did not bring my daughter out here...
to sit like a nun on a log
on that bench.
- Hugh, that's not why he works.
- Uh, John, look, look.
- You know, it ain't easy.
- Just take it back a notch.
Good, you're here.
Why not tell him yourself?
I would. You--
Mother, get in the car.
- Tell me what?
- You,
you can't coach worth a damn.
- Hold on, John.
- That's what.
- Slow down.
- Whatever that offense was.
Our daughter, Portia, is a scorer.
He's used to her being
a shooter since junior high.
Well, that's not our system here.
Yeah, I'm gonna tell you one thing.
Ray Burnsides was right about you.
These are small town girls.
This is not some big-time
college program.
It was just her first game.
Ah-ah-ah-ah.
Know what?
It was her last.
Portia, get in the car.
- Come on. Come on.
- John.
I don't want to hear about it, Hugh.
- I don't want to hear it.
- John, look.
♪ Born to lose ♪
♪ I've lived my life in vain ♪
♪ Every dream ♪
♪ Has only brought me pain ♪
♪ All my life ♪
♪ I've always been so blue ♪
Take the ball.
- ♪ Born to lose ♪
- Frances.
♪ And now I'm losing you ♪
- At least, they try real hard.
- Come on, girls.
- Too cautious.
They're tentative.
They're thinking too much.
They're worried about fouling out.
They should just play.
Keep moving.
Well, they're doing
what the coach told them.
- Come on, Ginger!
- ♪ Born to lose ♪
♪ And now I'm losing you ♪
Jean, please,
don't tell me how to coach.
- I'm not telling you how to coach.
- Come on.
- I'm just asking you to listen.
- I just shouldn't have to take the job.
That's the problem.
The girls are taking you
too literally.
Please.
You say: "Don't foul",
and what they hear is
"don't foul ever".
Even if it means
conceding a basket.
You show them a play,
pattern's got lots of variations,
but all they remember is
the diagram you drew.
And run it every time,
automatically.
Like doing a box step
they learned in the dance class,
instead of,
you know,
rocking and rolling with it.
Rocking and rolling.
Heck, everybody can coach
better than I can.
Fine.
Think, Chubby Checkers are available?
We could hire them.
Well, thank goodness, at least.
I thought you lost
your sense of humor completely.
Clay.
Honey.
Come on.
Pull over.
Come on, pull over.
It's not about coaching.
It's about how boys
and girls are different.
Especially, country girls.
I should know.
We're like our mamas.
Aiming to please.
You?
Clay.
Clay, honey, boys can do
what they want and always could.
You have that freedom.
- Well.
- But not girls here.
Unless, you're given.
Their mamas wash the clothes...
and cook and help in the fields...
and sew and raise the kids...
and never complain.
They're tough.
Clay, and their daughters are tough.
They won't break.
I, I practice them just
as hard as I practice boys.
Let them play...
by the same rules as the boys.
Give them permission
to be who they are.
Think for themselves.
Some girl bumps 'em,
let them bump 'em right back.
Hard.
Go head.
Press, press Ruth, Susan.
Come on.
Push it in. Push it in.
Wait, whoa, whoa.
What, what are you doing?
You said to pass it to Liz.
Not if she's not open.
I'm guarding her now.
But, you said to--
Well, you don't just pass because...
I said so.
Girls, sit down.
What I'm trying to--
Uh.
Okay. Alright now.
Alright. Uh...
Look.
Who here likes dancing?
- You mean, like--
- Yeah.
Yeah, like dance dancing,
you know, um...
Elvis?
It's the stroll, you know?
Yeah.
Yeah. Who likes to dance?
Okay, we need a little
more dancing on this court.
Or a little more Rock-N-Roll, okay?
Let's try some out, okay?
Think things like
you're dancing out there,
not like you're doing some box step.
Alright, come on.
Come on, work it in there.
Go ahead, run it in there.
Come on, Liz,
move off that screen.
Come on, now.
Come on. That's it.
Good pass. Good pass.
Hey.
That was, uh...
cute what you was doing that, uh...
- whatever it was.
- Whatever that was.
Anyways, Clay, uh...
Bannister is not coming back.
I spoke to his wife.
They're moving.
He needs better hospitals.
Don't tell me that.
Now look, Clay.
I, I know you're disappointed.
Now, just, just listen to me.
- Hear me out.
- Oh, Hugh.
I think, we have
another option here.
Just, look,
let me tell you about the JV's.
Well, not again.
At least, watch one game.
For what?
Here, freshmen are eligible
for the district tournament,
once their season ends.
That's 10 days before the Varsity's does.
So, you could put up to 4 of
the best players on your squad.
Kids in junior high?
Clay, I'm telling you.
These gals are super.
Well, with them on your team next year--
Next year?
It's for your next coach,
and it won't be me.
Hush!
Comes September,
I'm coaching boys,
we both know our service.
Not as the losing girls coach,
you won't.
Maybe, assistant again.
But, no way.
Boys Head Coach?
At least, not from here.
Hyah!
What's the problem there?
Mr. Brawley.
Need a hand?
What couldn't wait until Monday?
My team, sir, the girls.
There's only so much
we can accomplish.
Practice in an hour
before lunch. We...
we need a better time.
And we need new balls
and shoes, sir.
Maybe, new uniforms, and...
and warmups, not those
old castoffs from the boys.
Just for the girls...
to be successful.
To have...
to have pride in themselves.
Where'd you say you're from again?
Fort Gibson.
It's, it's just outside Muskogee.
And then, the Marines,
and then, Norman.
But,
not from here.
No, sir.
Not here.
You see all this here?
- Yes, sir.
- Been in my family...
for six generations.
The town too.
Lived on it, died on it.
So, don't try and tell me
how it works.
I'm sorry. I'm not
trying to do that, sir.
What I'm, what I'm all,
all I'm asking--
You've never laid the first
brick to mortar here, boy.
You're as transient as the wind.
We're talking about
the girls, sir, not me.
Well, their mamas and their daddies...
of these girls,
they sure as hell know
there's a drought going on here.
I can't understand why you don't.
I know there's a drought, sir.
Well then, who's supposed
to pay for it all?
Well.
I mean, you want to tell me that?
What should we do?
- I mean, the only solution...
- I...
- I can come up with is...
- Somebody's...
- let's just stop buying the books,
- let's stop buying the light bulbs.
- buying the boys the new gears...
and, and, and the, and the...
and, and, and
hot meals after games.
- The boys,
- And the slick new poster...
- the boys win.
- I saw down on Main street.
- The boys make money.
- Yes. Yes, sir.
Okay?
I'm just asking you
to give the girls a chance.
That's it, sir.
Well, I'll tell you what?
When you and your girls...
start making money,
maybe.
We'll see.
Come on.
Post up! Post up!
- Come on.
- Look at that.
- Ref, you got to call it.
- Come on!
You're all bunch of losers.
That's all you'll ever be, is losers!
Well, she's clear enough.
Let's go!
Hey, 24, nice legs!
That's enough out of you.
- What you're gonna about it?
- I'll sit you down and shut you up, boy.
- That's what I'm gonna do now.
- You want to take this outside?
- I'll take you anywhere you want.
- Frances.
Let's go if you want some.
- Come on.
- Frances!
- Okay.
- Ginger, focus out there.
- Be patient.
- Come on.
- Okay, make it happen.
- Playing hard.
They just not get the call.
Why don't you run back
to your girlfriend?
Oh, my gosh!
Oh-oh-oh-oh!
Watch inside!
Oh, come on now.
That was a hacking.
You got to call one foul on them.
You shut your mouth.
Ref.
Clay.
It's always like this here.
Look! Sadie, help out, Sadie.
Help out!
- Go. Go!
- There you go!
Time.
Time out! Time out!
Middleton's time out.
Come on, now. Come on,
you're not dancing out there.
Find the open man and
run him ragged with motion.
Coach, we tried, but
they keep on pushing and...
shoving every chance they get.
- There's nothing we can do.
- Shoved me in the back.
Alright, alright, alright, alright.
Alright, enough of this.
Listen up.
Let's see how they like it.
Ginger, move the ball
over to the strong side.
And Sadie,
with one eye on the ref,
shove off your man
just like they do.
Ruth, would you be so kind
as to set her a pick?
Girls, you now have the permission.
Whatever they dish out,
you give it back twice as hard.
Twice as hard!
- One, two, three. Pride!
- Pride!
Move the ball!
That's it.
Okay, make it happen.
Come on, come on.
Make it happen.
- Yeah!
- Oh, yeah, that's it.
Move back, move back.
Frances, she can't go to her left.
Over play the right hand.
Over play the right hand!
Oh! Hey!
Come on!
Oh! What?
A fight.
Clear out.
Ref, this side fouls.
Come on, clear out.
Come on, come on now.
Don't you ever talk to me like that.
Hold on, hold on!
Alright.
Alright, alright
Personal foul!
2-4, red!
Ref, I think that girl's second foul.
- She's struck my girl!
- Go away, and fall out.
What kind of coaching
you do with your girls there?
It ain't my fault,
they've never played.
You alright?
- Coach, I'm sorry.
- Don't apologize.
- They deserved it.
- Are you okay?
- Yeah, I'm okay.
- You alright?
You alright?
- Coach, that was fun.
Well, that's I call:
Rocking and Rolling with it.
- Alright, this is it.
- That was fun.
Alright, come on now.
I can't wait for the next dance.
Frances Bonner!
Frances Bonner.
We always said, your natural
inclination was sinful.
And that Price boy being here
tonight is the proof of it.
- No, Daddy, you are not--
- That...
vulgar half-naked display.
We never should have allowed it.
- Preacher Bonner.
- Get in the truck.
- Just wait.
- Get in the truck now.
- Hold on, sir.
- Coach.
- Hold on.
- You're abetting this.
- You're abetting this!
- Sir.
- It was you.
- Mr. Bonner.
Like all these girls,
Frances is and has always been...
a fine and respectable young lady.
You get on that bus,
- don't bother coming home.
- Mama.
- Mama, please!
- Frances, it's alright.
- I'll drag you by the hair if I have to!
- Hold on now, sir.
- She's still my legal responsibility.
- No more, she's not.
- Hey, hey, hey, you can't do this.
- What?
- Please, let me go!
- You're coming now.
No, let me go!
Father, be reasonable.
- Coach.
- Now!
Open that door!
- Father, please, I don't want to get in!
- Get in!
- Mama. Mama.
- Get in.
Shut your mouth and
get in the truck, Frances.
Never, never again.
Amen.
Pride.
King Solomon in Proverbs teaches us:
"In the mouth of the foolish
is a rod of pride."
Remember, friends.
Pride goeth before destruction,
and cometh crashing before the fall.
Hard times are the Lord's
test of character.
Coach!
Mr. Driscoll!
I want you to meet
Frank and Dorothy Thompson.
- Fans of yours.
- Howdy.
Hey, their daughter, Pat,
is star of the JV team.
Frank and me, we'd like to invite
you and Mrs. Driscoll for supper.
- Maybe, come see the Little Twisters?
- That's what they call them.
Our girls are 10 and 0.
Eligible for the district
tournament in a month.
It's terrific.
Those girls care?
Frank, how'd the well do?
It did.
- For water drips.
- Well, that's good.
You get any problems, Frank,
you call Brandon down at the bank.
You got his number.
You know one thing,
we all better remember,
we are in this together.
We got to stick together.
Fair enough?
You all have a real nice Sunday now.
That son-of-a-bitch.
- Anyhow, Coach, the Twisters--
- Whatever. Ma'am.
Clay?
Goodness! He's--
I'm sorry.
Don't you apologize.
It's them that should.
Mr. Brawley, the Pastor?
Frances Bonner ran off
and married the Price boy.
And they're blaming your husband.
Now the kids,
they're somewhere penniless.
And I hear, she's pregnant.
Oh, don't.
Don't blame yourself.
- This place, this place--
- It's not this place.
It's a few...
stupid people.
Hell with them.
I'll let the JVs play.
- Melva Johnson.
- Candy Brown.
Mr. Brown, how are you, sir?
- Dorothy Crossett.
I need few more players.
Alright. I think we, uh--
- Pat Thompson.
- How are you all doing?
- She's amazing.
So, teamwork out there.
Use your heads and grit.
Ball movement.
- Constant motion away from the ball.
- Hey, Coach?
If we win tonight, will you stay?
Please, don't go, Coach.
- Say, you won't go.
- Coach, you have to stay.
Please, stay.
Coach.
We're gonna be better next year.
Stay back.
It's okay, it's okay.
It's alright. It's alright.
Time out. Time out!
Time out!
Let's go, get in.
Come on, now. Hustle.
Alright. You four out, you stay in.
Little Twisters,
I'm gonna put you in.
- You know my offense?
- Yes, sir.
Move the ball around,
see if you can unclog that middle.
Bring it in.
- One, two, three, pride!
- Pride!
Yeah!
Yeah. Yeah!
Saint Margaret is one
of the best in the county.
You played tough.
Coach.
Look, I'm gone.
I'm senior.
But, these girls,
if you quit now,
it's just gonna go back
to the way it was.
They need you.
You'd be proud of yourselves.
I am.
It was a good season.
Here's how it works
since they let me.
Next two years, three tops,
- you assist with Joe Harold.
- No.
- Joe--
- I know.
But once he retires,
we'll try to make you
the boys head coach.
The best I can do,
you coming off a losing season.
How's Jean with all this?
It's nearly 700 less.
All we offer is a one-bedroom.
She's fine with it, Joe.
Well, can't promise anything, but...
maybe, secretarial.
Can't guarantee that.
Okay.
- It's that you, Joe?
- No, no, sir.
It's Johnny Price.
Frances Bonner's husband.
Johnny Price?
Did I hear you're in Texas?
No, sir, we...
we live here now,
have been.
Place out near Dale High.
And Frances wanted me to find you.
Me?
- Why is that?
- Well.
Right now, she's,
she's having a baby, sir.
And, uh...
we don't really have much.
And...
I'm no use.
So...
she said to call you.
Frances?
See?
I got him.
Frances?
Coach.
I'm a month early.
It hurt.
Oh, God!
Oh.
Okay.
Alright. It's alright.
Johnny, I need you to go
get my wife at the county agents,
and tell her to bring
the doctor, okay?
But, sir, we can't pay. We,
- we don't have any money.
- Go on, now. Get!
- Johnny, go.
- Go on, now.
Oh-oh.
God! Oh, God!
Okay.
Okay. Alright.
I'm scared. It hurts.
Come on, now.
That's a contraction, alright?
- It's gonna go away in a second.
- Okay.
So, you're gonna be just fine, darling.
You're gonna be just fine.
I need you to do
something for me, Frances.
I need you to time...
- between when these happen, alright?
- Alright.
I gotta go outside
and get some kindling.
Hold on.
I'll be right back.
- Hold on.
- Coach?
I need it come.
- You'll be just fine, darling.
- Okay.
Okay.
You take that real good.
Would have done better
with you, though.
Can I...
can I ask you something?
Something personal?
Sure.
How come you don't have kids?
I mean,
people say stuff, but...
you'll be such a good daddy.
You know, I want to real bad.
But, Jean and I...
I got something wrong.
I did all these tests.
Doctor says, I can't.
Jean wants to adopt.
Don't you?
Oh.
Ow, ow, ow!
Ow!
Shh-shh-shh-shh.
They're both fine.
They're asleep.
You might wanna
check on Frances.
He's like a little bird.
Choo-choo!
Hey, Mrs. Grove.
- How is she?
- She's just fine.
Good.
I brought a corn casserole,
and she's got some baby clothes.
Hey, Frances.
- Hi.
- Let me see him.
You know,
Mama was about your age
when she had Raymond Jr.
Ain't that right, Mama?
You 17?
Yes, ma'am.
Mm-hm. Yeah.
Welcome to the club.
Why don't you and Clay
go on home?
He looks worn out.
Frances.
Alright.
I'm, uh...
I'm gonna leave you with far more
responsible company than me now.
- I'm gonna get on home.
- Ask, ask him.
Uh...
Well, we, we were
just wondering if...
well, if it would be alright
if we named him after you.
Clayton as his middle name.
That'd be alright.
Yeah, I guess.
Thank you.
Now, you go on.
Let her get some sleep, okay?
- Alright.
- Alright?
- Go on.
- Okay.
Well, we-- Okay.
You did good, Coach.
Okay, okay.
Okay, yeah, okay.
Okay.
God bless.
But, even if we pass this test,
battle will not be over.
- What happens--
- Oh, man.
I shouldn't say what
it looks like outside.
Might jinx it.
Mm, something smells good.
What've we gotten?
The ham.
- Get on out.
- What?
From the Yorks.
Monday, it was...
strawberries and catfish
from the Thompsons.
You're being bribed.
What's, what's this.
Uh, it's...
from Joe Brody, I'm guessing.
What does it say?
Job is mine if I want it.
Money is what I told you.
Assistant two years
instead of three, Joe hopes.
- And?
- Come now, he says.
Holy cow!
Clay.
Oh, my God!
Would you look at that?
Whoa!
Oh, jeez!
More!
- Woo hoo!
- Woo!
- Oh!
- Let it rain, please!
- Hey!
- Woo!
Finally!
I hope it rained
for two weeks like this.
Honey, what about Ada?
This is crazy!
Oh!
Maybe, I'm just a girls
basketball coach after all.
Mm.
Woo-hoo!
Oh, finally!
Woo!
Come on, let's go.
Come on.
Let's go!
I'll be back in an hour, Jean.
Come on.
Oh, come on.
Driscoll.
John Stovall.
- Portia's dad.
- I remember.
She wants to play again.
But, I don't want her
taken advantage of.
- How so?
- Treated unfairly.
- Because of last year.
- She wasn't treated unfairly.
Look, there's not
any reason to get all--
You see, I'm a lawyer and I--
Daddy.
I apologize.
She works hard, she plays.
Same as everyone.
That's all I care about.
Good enough. Thank you.
I appreciate it.
Thanks, Daddy.
Can I go to the team meeting?
She heard about it
from her friends.
This is where the team meeting is?
Well, ask them.
They called it.
Now, who said you could do that?
Hello, Coach Driscoll.
The reason we did this
was to set training rules.
Training rules?
Like boys have.
Real teams.
You know?
Like what we need to do,
and, and do without
to win this year.
Like what we eat, and what time
you want us in bed at night.
A team curfew.
And how many nights before
a game shouldn't we date?
Or does it matter?
And what about cherry cokes?
You're, you're joking right?
If you're gonna treat us like boys,
we wanna prepare like boys.
So, what we're saying is that--
Let's go ladies.
Keep it moving.
Nice.
Push that ball.
Snap it, snap it.
Let's play, baby.
God, it'll...
it'll last maybe a week,
but I went along with it.
Starting in November,
no soda pop and just
one candy bar a week.
Bedtime, they, they voted,
would be 9:30,
except, on Saturday night.
I said, get serious.
Girls.
Softie?
Clay, it's time.
It just needs your signature.
Aren't you happy, Jean?
You know, it's not that simple.
Yes.
No.
Sometimes.
Honey, there is no shame.
None.
It's nobody's fault.
It's just biology.
So what if it's not our blood?
If it is meant to be,
that's just as good.
Just as right.
Maybe...
- Maybe--
- No, no.
No "maybe".
You know,
part of why you coach,
there's a daddy in you,
you never had.
And now,
there's a child out there,
maybe, right now,
that needs us...
as much as we need him.
A son.
Your son.
Our...
son.
Okay.
Thank you, baby.
Tonight, we open with Ideal,
who whipped us twice last year.
Whipped us good.
Six.
What does that number mean?
How many wins
we had last year?
- Six.
- Six wins.
That's the most...
any girls team
from Middleton's won...
out of 22 regular season games.
Six.
Not even a tournament win.
Ever.
Now, ask yourself.
And measure this against
who you think you are in this life.
Is 6 an acceptable number?
No.
- Is it?
- No, Coach.
- No, Coach!
Then, show me.
Come on, let's go!
Let's go, girls.
Let's go!
Right here, come on!
Yeah! Woo hoo-hoo!
Yeah, that's it.
- Mrs. Clay Driscoll?
- Yes.
Lucille Shumard,
State Welfare Department,
your adoption application.
Oh, my God!
Just one second.
Good Lord!
Jean, where's my pants?
Goodness!
We do apologize.
You caught us by a surprise.
That's the idea.
I'm Jean.
This is Clay.
Ma'am.
Shouldn't take an hour. I'll, um...
Look around,
take some pictures,
and we'll visit. So...
I hope, we start
trucking it over to here.
Looks like Russian
needle to put in.
Coach.
It's personal.
Excuse me, Hugh.
It's my shorts.
They splitted last game.
And Mama sew them back,
- but the stitches...
- Mm-mm.
just gave again.
Get down!
Let's try it again!
Come on. Come on!
- What's wrong?
- It's these damn old uniforms.
Candy hanging out of her pants.
I gotta go get Mama.
Now, the school board meeting
of October 19th in session.
Public comments?
Next item.
Approval of minutes for
the September regular meeting.
Do I hear motion?
- So moved.
- Wait.
- Second?
- Uh, wait.
Um, it says in the agenda:
Public comment comes first.
It did.
Well, the meeting is called for seven,
and, uh, yeah, I have
seven now, a minute till.
- Mine says different.
- Come on, Ellis.
What, there are six,
seven people here?
- Let him have his say.
- Not personal.
- Mile Gerson from the Meritt.
- Sir.
Motion passes.
Next item:
Approval of District
warrants and claims.
You'll want to see, uh,
superintendent, Spainhower,
about that, son.
Uh, he told me to come here.
You already did.
Next item.
No, sir. It was just you
I talked to last time, not them.
Anyway, that was last season.
And this year, it's worse.
Our girls need new uniforms
and warm-ups bad.
Uh, rules recommend two sets
for home and away,
and all we got is one.
That's maybe seven years old, and...
been hemmed so many times,
they split on my two-guard
at Medfield Friday.
Uh, warm-ups,
we don't even bother with.
They're boys' hand-me-downs, and...
about two sizes too big.
Half of them,
the zippers are broke.
We look like hobos.
Now, you said last year,
you couldn't on account
of the drought,
and girls don't draw.
Well, the droughts over.
Thank God.
And people are paying
to see us play now.
Plus, and no disrespect,
Mr. Brand,
our team is 6 and 1...
while your nephew's boys,
uh, 2 and 5.
Now, you ask anyone,
these girls are the finest,
hardest-working,
the most unselfish kids in school,
and they deserve
what everybody...
takes for granted in this county.
They've earned this.
Alright then, Mr. Driscoll,
- we will consider it.
- When?
Public comments are just that.
You've had your two minutes.
If there's a board consensus,
we'll put it on next month's
conference agenda.
Gentlemen, item three is up.
- Next month?
- Approval--
Well, that's almost December.
- It'll take at least a month to get--
- Approval of District...
- warrants and claims.
- It can't wait any longer.
Sit down, you.
No.
Clay.
- Clay.
- No.
I'll pay for them
out of my own pocket.
If that's what it takes.
But, these girls have gone
without long enough.
Item three is: Approval of District
warrants and claims.
Discussion?
Fine.
The reason he can afford to is...
we're the only district...
generous enough
and stupid enough...
to be paying a boys
salary to a girls coach.
Write it down scripe.
Pride! Pride!
Pride! Pride! Pride!
Fifty two.
Hands up, hands up!
- Yeah!
- Good job, Candy.
Watch your pick right there.
- Candy!
- Ow!
- Hey!
- No! That's foul!
- Ow!
Candy, honey, you alright?
Come on, Ref.
You gotta call those.
It's my knee.
We, we take care of you.
Now, don't you worry.
They'll take care of her.
- Ow!
- Next's up, girls.
Clay, someone here to see you.
Who is it?
Dreaming of "the fast",
look what shows up.
Hi, Coach.
She's got something to ask you.
I sure like to play basketball again.
- Make that next time.
- I will.
Come on, now.
Just because you're a mama,
it ain't no excuse.
Come on, now.
Oh.
Do it again.
Hugh, I've, I've a crazy idea.
And, uh, I was wondering
if you could help me.
Say that again.
Yeah, with Brawley,
I should have seen it coming.
Well, with Spainhower, that little...
Yeah.
So, they trumped this policy up.
Rescind my bonus.
Cut my pay.
Their way of firing me.
Knowing I wouldn't stand for it.
And, and your wife?
Well, she's still at Wilson.
But, they won't renew
her contract in June.
Aw. So, you're gone.
Yeah. Both of us.
After 30 years.
Oh, I feel awful about this.
You've been so good to me, Hugh.
You've been so good to the girls.
No.
They're lucky to have you.
Whole town is.
You've done a heck of a job.
With you sit right next to me.
Nah.
You be careful, though.
Who they're really after is you.
Mm.
Brawley told Spainhower
last September.
Find a way.
You ticked him off, Clay.
You and Jean, both.
Since the day I showed up.
And what's it about me
that he so can't stand?
Hell, you're young,
you're hard-headed.
You won't kiss his ass
like he's used to.
You know, times are changing.
But, not for him.
Not for Ellis.
And never here.
I know, what you're thinking.
I bet, you don't.
I bet, you thought that first day,
what a mistake it was
you coming here.
You're wrong.
What then?
No.
Come on.
Winning district.
Maybe, regionals even are coming close.
- But, I couldn't ask--
- Clay.
Spit it out.
We're 9 and 5
since Candy got hurt.
We could have won,
what, two, three?
- Four. Maybe, four.
- Yeah. Maybe, 4 of those games.
But, sparks are missing. Now...
with Frances Bonner
wanting to play again,
she might be just what we need.
Now, I know her rotten
deal with classes, but...
Hugh, can you help me out
with just one last time.
After what I just told you?
Son, are you out of your mind?
Help me get this girl
back on the team.
You know the ED code,
the policies,
the technicalities.
I don't, I don't know
nothing about that.
Wait. Wait a minute.
Is this for you,
or about Brawley?
It's about "winning".
That's what this is about.
You want it that bad?
Don't you?
What is this Frances Bonner business?
What it says it is.
I won't be threatened.
It's no threat.
Mr. Spainhower,
Frances is a good student.
She makes A's and B's,
team parents know her situation,
they're okay with it.
All they're saying is
they'll write letters of support.
If the request is denied.
Oh, well, John Stovall
in particular, I see.
- Well, he's a parent.
- Well, so is Frances Bonner.
But, there's no legal rules
stopping her playing.
You know, from the state, I mean.
- But, board policy is clear.
- Aside from board policy.
According to civil law
on the education code.
You know, that sort of thing.
Right, Mr. Spainhower?
- I'm not the district counsel.
- Well, you can ask them.
Legal opinions cost money.
Have the board do it then.
You know very well,
Mr. Brawley's at his place in Mexico.
Then Mr. Brand.
I'm warning you, Driscoll.
Don't push it.
Fine.
In the meantime,
as long as it's not
on school property,
there is no jurisdiction over...
Frances practicing with team
as I can interpret.
As you can interpret.
Am I wrong?
♪ You can change the name of an old song ♪
♪ Rearrange it and make it swing ♪
♪ I thought nothing could
stop me from loving you ♪
♪ But time changes everything ♪
♪ Good luck to you, may God bless you ♪
♪ I can't say I won't love again ♪
♪ You've gone your way ♪
♪ And now, I'll go mine ♪
♪ 'Cause time has changed everything ♪
Go in.
You want to see me,
Mr. Spainhower?
I want no part of this any more.
Too many people are upset.
If I can't make the ruling,
I'm leaving it up to you.
You can play the Bonner girl
if you want.
You're right, there's no
code violation involved.
So, I'm, uh, not gonna stop you.
I also won't give you my permission.
Just the authority to decide.
Congratulations, Driscoll,
it's your call.
I do...
I do wish you the best.
But, I wash my hands
of the whole thing.
Mr. Driscoll.
- Mr. Driscoll.
- Yes, ma'am.
I have to warn you.
Mr. Brand...
Mr. Brand came by the office earlier.
Normally, Mr. Spainhower
has me place all his phone calls.
But, they made one without me.
And I eavesdropped.
I feel terrible, but I did.
And...
they were calling Mr. Brawley
down in Mexico.
He's staying down there on purpose.
They want you...
They want you to decide.
They want you to play Frances.
So, the board can fire you.
Mr. Brawley said,
you and Mr. Moreland
were troublemakers.
They had gotten rid of him,
and now, it was your turn.
Be careful, Mr. Driscoll.
It might not be worth it.
Thank you, Miss Rogers.
Mm-hm.
Hey, Coach!
Uh, Frances is inside.
You, you come about her play?
Uh, yeah, Johnny.
Um...
Well, she just made some coffee.
Come on in.
Well, uh, no.
Uh, uh, no, thanks, Johnny.
You tell her...
You go on in there,
and you tell her...
um...
you tell her...
you tell her,
she's going to the regional.
She's playing in the tournament.
Yeah! Man, oh man!
I knew it, I knew it.
I knew you'd do it, Coach.
I knew you'd do it.
Come on inside.
Come on in and tell her.
No, you go on and
you tell her yourself.
Thanks, Coach.
Frances!
Bring it in.
You've won more games
than any Middleton girls team ever.
Thirteen.
What number is acceptable now?
We're behind you.
- 1, 2, 3, pride!
- Pride!
Come on, Frances.
Push it, Frances.
Well, who had ever thought,
our Lady Cyclones
would whip Ideal, Thursday.
Okeene, Friday,
and win the district 2
tournament, Saturday,
stomping Bing, 57-51.
Now, it's on to the regionals
with the big dawgs.
Go, you Lady Cyclones!
Pride!
Oh, my God!
- I bet, color TV.
- No.
Oh.
I am dead and gone to heaven.
Oh!
You won't believe this.
Look down there.
Well now, I have seen it all.
Mm-hm.
And good evening everyone,
from Lawton, Oklahoma.
Both are the division 2
girls high school basketball,
western regionals.
Now tonight, our final pits
the highly talented...
Ridge Raiders red vets
from over Cordell...
against the Lady Cyclones
from Middleton.
The team that frankly,
up until now,
not many folks had ever heard of.
They're #4 seed in their own
district tournament,
and these Middleton kids with
their second year head coach,
Clay Driscoll, had knocked off...
five straight higher ranked teams.
Now, here they are,
matched up against this deep...
and talented Ridge Raiders
red squad...
for a chance to go on
to Oklahoma City...
- Are these girls something?
- to play for that...
- Woo-hoo! Yeah.
- They can't wait.
And hey, Middleton down
by only 5 point-ish...
Ridge now with the ball,
and they bring the ball down...
Oh, good shot and wow!
That put Raiders up by 3.
That could be the back breaker.
Under two minutes. Now,
lots of noise in the gym tonight.
Here come the Lady Cyclones.
They just won't go away.
Selman with the rebound
and put it right back up.
- Pat?
- Pat just couldn't stand up.
She grabs her right ankle,
and it does not look good.
Well, 18.94 tonight,
a big for Pat Thomson.
What is it?
My ankle.
Look, it could be the end
of the playoff road...
for the Lady Cyclones.
It's alright, it's alright,
it's alright.
Now, listen to me,
all of you.
Focus.
Tune everything out.
Forget everything.
You're here because you earned it.
Settle down.
Get in there and show them
how Middleton play.
- 1, 2, 3, pride!
- Pride!
About 20 seconds now,
and Ridge up by 1.
Put the pressure on defense now...
- from the Lady Cyclones.
- Check the ball.
Working on that,
and that's stolen by Grove.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
It's only a second.
Coach Driscoll cannot believe it.
Lady Cyclones cannot believe it.
What you say?
- We're going to the state!
- They go on to State Championship.
We're going to the state!
Well, newspapers in Stillwater,
back in Norman,
good Lord, everywhere...
seems to be interested in
the Lady Cyclones.
Even TV.
No, it's not going to his head.
His head is already too big as it is.
I will.
Yeah, you too, Curtis.
Bye.
You know, you could
answer once or twice.
Calls are all for you.
I'm too busy.
Oh, Clay Driscoll, basketball genius.
Uh, come here.
I want to show you something.
I was thinking,
"Edward Wade Driscoll",
you know, from my mama side?
Or maybe, "James Dale Driscoll",
you know, from your dad.
You know, nice,
strong names for a boy.
Well, I was thinking more of...
Paul Newman Driscoll.
From me.
Let's go.
Get on the bus, girls.
Alright, get.
- Good luck, Ginger.
- Bye.
Bye.
- Pat, you're limping awful bad.
- I'm fine.
Alright. Come on.
Come on, now.
We'll never get straight.
Come on.
Susan, Liz, come on.
Good luck!
♪ Hold me ♪
♪ Never let me go until you've told me ♪
♪ Told me ♪
♪ What I want to know
and then just hold me ♪
♪ Hold me ♪
♪ Make me tell you
I'm in love with you ♪
♪ Thrill me ♪
♪ Walk me down the lane
where shadows will be ♪
♪ Will be ♪
Go ahead.
Coach.
- This is for you.
- Thank you.
It's from us.
Thank you all.
Well, the team wanted me
to say something.
Especially, the seniors.
So, uh...
We know, you never wanted us.
You wanted boys.
And we understand.
Girls don't get scholarships, or...
play in the Olympics or Pro's.
Most of us won't even go to college.
So for us, this is it.
Our one-moment to compete.
Put on spotless new uniforms, and...
represent Middleton.
And be proud of us more than just
future farmers' and rangers' wives.
Though, there's nothing wrong with that.
But, it's the other you gave us:
"The more than that."
Now,
open your gift.
Okay.
Oh.
For you.
For believing in us.
For this season and last,
no matter what happens tomorrow.
For the games we won...
and lost.
For treating us the same as boys.
Expecting more,
and making us get it.
From all of us.
We love you.
Uh.
Well.
I'll always, uh,
I'll always, uh...
I don't know, I don't know.
Well, at least,
it's better than yesterday.
Coach, I can play.
Really.
Show me.
Take in your hole.
Let's go.
Come on, come on!
Go, go right.
That's good, that's good.
Come on back.
Closer. Let's do it.
Good, good, good.
Come on.
Crossover.
Baby, are you alright?
I'm fine.
I'm fine, doggone it!
What?
Fans, we're few minutes
to tip-off for the state final.
And unlikely, a senior...
Please.
We just come to say
"good luck" to Ginger.
I'm sorry, Coach.
Come along.
I asked Middleton's coach,
Clay Driscoll,
"How they got here?"
"How'd it take his effort?"
He said, his girls hatched challenge,
and "no quit" at all.
But this, he, he laughed.
He said, he couldn't
really explain it himself.
Maybe, a combination
of heart and pure luck.
I call it old-fashioned grit.
Hard work and great coaching, folks.
Well, tonight, these kids will
need something extra special...
with their best forward,
Pat Thompson,
down with an ankle
injury that she got...
in that hard-fought regional final...
against Ridge High School
in Cordell.
Now, I asked Dellaplane coach,
R.C. Pruitt,
"How'd he prepared for the game?"
R.C. told me, never...
underestimate the country girls.
But, don't you underestimate
this Dellaplane program either.
Under that great Coach Pruitt,
they got three state championships.
And the winningest
girls record in Oklahoma...
over the past decade.
So, here we go.
Big versus Little.
Country versus City.
A classic matchup,
certainly great for
soon ladies' prep sports.
Middleton High, with 18 and 6...
against Dellaplane, with 23 and 1,
led by their 6-foot-3,
all-state center,
Lucille Overlander.
All-state guard and
district scoring champ,
Tammy Sharp.
That girl can run.
Marvella Qualls is another
all-star in the wing,
and 6-foot Delma Loftus
in the low post.
A powerhouse, folks.
Indeed, speed, strength, great touch.
And the Dellaplane
high-tempo system.
We get an exciting game for you.
So, run your noses,
and pull up a chair,
get ready for the Oklahoma...
- high school girls state final.
- Use the arc but slow down.
Be yourselves.
And don't get rattled
when the bullying starts.
Because it'll start quick.
You just remember
who you all are out there.
You're my girls.
Bring it in.
State champions.
- Pride!
- The highly favored...
Coronets from Dellaplane
in the familiar gold silk,
and Middleton in grey and maroon shorts.
Thanks for joining us...
for this Oklahoma
high school girls final.
Official, Eugene Owen,
just about ready to tip it off.
Big Lucille Overlander
of Dellaplane has about...
six inches on the Cyclone,
Melba Johnson.
Coronets win the tip.
No surprise there.
And Qualls gets to Hillary Pratt,
who puts in for easy 2.
And Middleton with the ball,
Johnson tosses to Ginger Selman,
gets to Frances Price.
Price missed most of her senior year
when she went off to get married.
Dribbles it across mid-court stripe,
and holds the ball, setting up
the play for Middleton.
Now, right now, this is not
what we expect from Middleton.
Gonna let the air out of the ball.
But you have to slow down.
They're just hamming up the horses
to run for this very athletic Josephine.
Alright.
Now, you can get
the boomers to come out.
Middleton gets the ball, moving
it finally to the pass-up high.
Price plays it off to Selman
on the right side.
#11, Selman brings it back,
across, right to left.
- Slow down, slow down, slow down!
- Sadie York coming across the other way.
Looks like they play
the game of four corners...
with keep-away out there.
Driscoll wants to stick
with his slow-down.
Pass left, dribble right.
Pass right, dribble left.
Price and Selman play catch.
There's a toss to the end
of the top of the key.
Then, back out to Price
who holds it up again.
Somebody needs to tell the Cyclones...
that you've got to score
sooner or later.
Just call them foul.
It's okay.
We're gonna get it.
Cyclones play with this slow-down,
that's the only way they've got a chance
against this running gun, and, uh...
Forward left to pass to left side.
York dribbles over
to the right hand side.
They're still playing keep-away.
Looks like Selman back over
to the left, back out.
Here in mid-court,
dribble, dribble, dribble.
That's what you get
with this slow-down.
Dribbling, uh, right to left.
And York with the ball.
Pass over...
to the right hand side again.
Back to Selman.
Selman throws it inside
to Johnson who puts it up,
works it in for two.
It's taken about a half of the quarter,
but they did get some
into the basket there.
Alright, I think, uh,
Cyclones slow-down playing,
I think they couldn't
hold the ball all night.
All-state guard, Tammy Shaw,
brings it up for the mighty Coronets.
Surprising number of
backers here for both teams.
Looks like the whole town of Middleton
hopped on the Greyhound, maybe, here.
You can fit the whole school
on two buses.
Fans don't handle the ball,
but over and out of there.
With that, the Coronets have the lead.
Go set the game now.
Brings the ball up for Cyclones.
Bad pass tipped away
by Dellaplane big center.
She runs the court,
gets the ball back,
and puts it up for two.
Real contrast between the coaches here.
R.C. Pruitt with the state's
best record of the past decade.
And Driscoll,
the new kid on the block.
Dellaplane now leads 8-to-4.
Same thing, same thing.
Slow down, slow down.
Selma brings the ball up slowly,
trying to control the tempo...
and had it stripped away
by the Coronets.
They put it up,
but rolls off the rim.
And Dellaplane
puts it back up for two.
This Middleton team
is just overmatched.
There's a pass inside,
and another turnover.
Tammy Shaw, the Coronets,
puts back to her squad...
for a pass inside...
for two.
Coach Driscoll sends in a play,
but there's another steal.
And another quick two
for Dellaplane.
Coronets' fans are out in force here.
And I think,
the Cyclones are rattled.
They're not used to it.
This hornet Coronets defense
has got the Cyclones...
tied up a knot of frustration.
Girls, you gotta move the ball.
You have to work the ball around.
Just lost focus.
Having a tough time
running with these big girls...
from the Coronets.
Come on, move back.
Coronets are still dominating
with their size and quickness.
The fact that they've
been here before...
definitely starting to show
at this point.
Long down court pass,
and that one is picked off.
She just cleared out.
Once the confidence goes,
the shooting can't be far behind.
Another one clanks off
the rim for Middleton.
And Dellaplane has the confidence
all going their way.
The wheels seem to be
coming off of the Cyclones.
And the Coronets are
outscoring them by nearly 3 to 1.
28-10, Dellaplane leads.
Well, this has been
a one-sided half of basketball.
And the Coronets are
running at all cylinders,
whereas the Cyclones
are one half away...
from ending their Cinderella season.
Well, that was quite a first half.
Alright, listen up.
Come on now.
Everybody knows how good Dellaplane is.
And they just showed it.
And right now, maybe,
nobody out there thinks
you measure up.
Look.
History teaches us,
there's no measuring the human heart.
People are capable of anything
if you have the will.
You have that will.
In buckets.
I've seen it.
In here.
I can feel it.
About last night.
What I didn't know, till now.
I didn't want boys.
It was you who I wanted all along.
No boys could ever do what you have.
I can't ask any more from you.
No coach could.
Nobody.
And you'll win tonight because of this,
because of who you are,
and how special you are.
How special you are to me.
You will win tonight for your mamas,
and your grandmas.
And your sisters.
And all girls in Middleton,
and everywhere else
who never got the chance.
You will win tonight.
Because it's meant to be.
Back to second half action.
Middleton with the ball.
Cross-handed to Johnson.
Oh, she puts it up for two.
Yes!
Alright, get the Cyclones.
Stovall brings it up this time.
She shoots it herself,
and makes it.
Looks like Middleton
gets a load of energy.
They start the second half on fire.
And get the crowd excited.
But, it's got to take more
than a couple of baskets...
to get them back in this game.
- There's another one.
- Woo!
Cyclones seem like to have found
the key to this tough 4-2 defense.
R.C. is not too happy
with the officiating,
but his girls are flat being
out-muscled right now.
Qualls brings it in,
battles for position underneath.
That's the pass inside.
Overlander goes over,
knocking Johnson to her back.
I thought that might have been a foul.
Fans, if you just join us,
you're seeing an entirely
different Cyclone team...
than what we saw in the first half.
This is getting really very
physical game underneath.
And that might play into
the hands of the farm girls here.
She's, she's clearing out, Ref.
She's clearing out with her elbow.
Come on, Ref, look inside.
This, uh, this Middleton team's
got some fire in their belly.
I think, maybe, the Coronets thought
they had it won at half time.
And so did just about
everyone in this arena.
Game's getting very physical.
The Cyclones appear to be
taking most of the punishment.
Liz Blair at the line.
She looks a little woozy...
after that last altercation.
Looks like, uh,
she can't barely stand.
The Coronets are just
wearing down the Cyclones.
She's got one shot,
and she bangs it in.
The Cyclones are trying
to make it run here,
but the Coronets are
still holding them at bay.
Tammy Shaw into Henley,
Henley over to Marvella Qualls...
who puts it up for another two.
That play run to perfection,
and, uh, it's this that
we get a battle here, friends.
The Cyclones have
managed to pull closer.
Center, Pat Thompson,
is still on the bench with a bad leg.
They can sure use her size inside.
Cyclones are still giving up
a good six inches...
at Center and Forward.
Coach, they're too big.
They grind us down.
Both their forwards,
I can beat them.
- Put me in and let me run.
- Ruth, go in for Portia.
You double up on the center.
You get us back in this game.
With no more than 4 or 5
minutes left in the game,
we're 4 down, 5 down,
they will not throw pad now.
I'm ready now.
Dad brought two tests.
- I feel fine, Coach.
- No.
Not yet.
Cyclones driven away as we come
to the end of third quarter, and...
Coronets are still up by 12.
But, Middleton's gonna make a run.
That's their signature.
They got precious little time to do it.
That's not gonna help.
Missed shot, pulled out by Dellaplane.
They take it to trip
to the home for two.
Come on, girls, you know this.
This Tammy Shaw of the Coronets
is just unstoppable.
And she splits the defense
for another two points.
Coming down the last few minutes.
Here's the Oklahoma girls state finals.
This has been a see-saw
battle in the second half.
Much better game than
anyone would have expected...
out of this girls team
from the farmland.
Uh, vastly different styles
between these two coaches,
Pruitt and Driscoll.
Shaw climbing to the hole.
Come on.
Alright.
Half shuffle,
full press, over for Liz.
Pat Thompson has been
the Cyclones' go-to girl all season.
Pat Thompson!
Not expected to play today.
But with the game on the line,
Coach wants to test that play.
They line up for the free throw.
Now, I could call that the other way.
That definitely looks like a charge to me.
But, they call for block.
And Dellaplane is at the line.
First one rattles out.
Oh, my goodness!
Maybe, she's feeling a little bit
guilty about getting that free call.
This is the girl you want on the line?
With the game on the line.
The district scoring champ puts it out.
And another good one.
Oh, that hurts, for the Cyclones.
Two minutes.
All over right handside.
Coach calls in a play,
stifled by the Coronets' defense,
Time running out the Cyclones.
Grove trying to get it
down low to Thompson.
She puts it up and it's good.
Her first two points of the contest.
Defense has really
picked up on fullback.
Dellaplane puts up a shot, but misses.
Grove took off,
freaked out a little bit.
Looks like Grove is trying to go solo...
all the way down the court, and...
she puts it up for two.
Now only four minutes to play,
Coronets up by just six.
Completely intensity
building in this arena.
And Shaw brings the ball up.
Middleton needs a stop here.
Shaw has down low to Lockett.
She drives to the hole,
and puts it up.
It's good for two.
And Johnson brings
the ball in for Middleton.
To Grove.
Just over three and a half to go,
Cyclones now down by eight.
Grove brings the ball up
for Middleton.
No, no. Top, top.
Come on, get the ball.
Watch for somebody inside.
- Good.
- It's a pass over to left-hand side.
Hard into Johnson.
Give and go, back to Thompson
who puts it up for good two.
And this game is going down to the wire.
Dellaplane's guard, Shaw,
running away from the Cyclone defense,
just like she did all night long.
She's gonna try to get it
inside over the right,
which she dominated inside.
Meanwhile, Thompson, what a way
to play under this Middleton team!
And she's doing a darn good job.
Looking inside.
Pass to the right-hand side.
Henley to Qualls
who puts it up for two.
Middleton brings the ball up.
Again down by six.
Just over a minute forty to play.
And the chess man
takes the team to see.
Evenly matched coaches continues.
Number 35, Crossett brings
the ball up for Middleton.
Pass to the right-hand side.
Nothing to do over there
but Coronets defense.
Thompson at the top of the key.
Thompson tries to make it.
Yes!
This game is not over yet.
Just four points apart with
a minute twenty-six to go.
Coronets bring it in.
And Middleton goes to a press.
She's got no place to go.
And pass and it's stolen
by Thompson who takes it in for two.
Whatever was wrong with
that ankle seems to be fine now.
A minute fifteen to go
and it's a two-point game.
Who to bucket?
Coronets bring the ball up.
Johnson holding her own inside.
But all-state center, Overlander,
gets very rough in there.
Lots of banging down in the paint.
Pass right side into the paint.
And it's stolen!
She presses it over to Thompson.
Picked up by Middleton.
A pass to midcourt at the top of the key.
Over looking on the left-hand side.
Over to Barney.
12-pointer on the left-hand side.
- Yeah!
- It's good.
Twenty-three seconds left in the game.
Middleton has tied it up.
Is this something?
I can't even hear myself talk in here.
Dellaplane with the ball.
Under twenty, and Shaw brings it up.
Now it's the Coronets time
to play a little snowball...
and go for the last shot.
The worst they can do
at this point is a tie.
Shaw and Overlander, right side.
Back on to Shaw.
Over to the left inside the paint.
Sixteen seconds. Fifteen.
Look out!
Overlander is dominating here all game.
Goes up for the shot and
it's blocked by Thompson!
Ball goes underneath into the treble.
Ten seconds.
Nine seconds.
And Johnson comes out with
a football-pass down to midcourt.
Six seconds.
Thompson's got it.
Time for one shot, but oh!
Ow, it looks like she's going down
that might put her right ankle.
Four seconds. Well fans...
Looks like we're headed to overtime.
Thompson puts up a play from mid-court.
It's good!
It's good! Unbelievable!
Middleton wins!
David has taken down Goliath.
Middleton puts up last one by two
to take the state title.
Who would ever believe it?
I'll tell you who.
Middleton believed it.
These kids never said that.
And you better believe it.
You made that shot!
Good job!
We did it, Danny, we did it.
Thank you so much.
- I miss you.
- Oh.
Hey, Mama, we did it.
Monday morning,
I expect your resignation in writing,
both as coach and history teacher.
For what?
You use a married girl
without permission,
which is against board policy,
leaving me absolutely no alternative.
Bullshit!
- What these girls want--
- Monday morning, sir,
Mr. Spainhower is going
to write four letters.
And those letters are gonna say,
Middleton High School is gonna
forfeit three games,
including tonight's state championship!
You can't do that.
I can't do that?
Watch me.
Okay. Let's...
Clay?
Phone, honey.
- Hey, Coach.
- Hey, John.
Hey, ah-ah-ah, now,
that better not be
what I think it is.
It's the only way.
What he wants is,
is me leaving.
If I give him this,
maybe, he'll let the girls
keep the championship.
Never happen.
It's my decision.
Oh, you think so?
I don't.
Old law school buddy of mine works
at the Attorney General's office,
and I was on the phone
with him all night long.
A big basketball fan.
Nobody is taking the state championship
away from our girls or this town.
- Nobody.
- No.
- Right, nobody!
I'd just love to see him fight this,
and end up in the New York Times.
Pride!
Mr. Spainhower,
Miss Rogers, you are witness
to this civil disobedience...
Mr. Driscoll has incited...
to intimidate you and the school board.
- Pride! Pride! Pride!
- Enough!
Enough!
Enough.
You get back to your classroom.
What do you think this is?
California?
Miss Rogers, would you be
good enough to call the station,
check and be sure Sheriff
Blessingame is on...
- the way.
-  I don't need a damn sheriff.
You made it real easy, Mr. Driscoll.
You're fired.
No, he isn't.
You have no authority
over Mr. Driscoll here.
He did nothing wrong.
Frances Bonner Price is
and always was eligible.
Says who?
Says the Attorney General
of the State of Oklahoma.
Whose granddaddy caddied
for my granddaddy.
You are way out of your depth.
Hold on now.
I thought you said,
we were all in this together.
Those are your words.
That Sunday in church,
when you tried to humiliate me...
in front of the entire congregation.
I came out to your ranch and
I asked you if you needed any help.
You never asked if I did.
He said girls don't draw.
Thousand showed up.
You didn't believe
when we went all the way,
and we won state champs.
And you weren't part of it.
That's why you want
to take this away from us.
This is a great town.
These are great people.
They taught me a lot.
We need each other.
But you,
you don't need anybody.
And the pity is, Ellis...
I feel sorry for you.
All of you,
my bank holds paper on your homes,
your farms,
- on your tractor.
- Hey.
Who is threatening who now?
Whatever it is that
you think you're playing,
there's not enough firepower...
- all of you can bunch.
- Coach!
Mr. Brawley.
Where the hell have you been?
I've had civil disobedience here since--
Mr. Brawley, you're hereby enjoined...
from forfeiting the state championship.
Writs of mandamus...
signed by the district judge.
Well.
We'll see.
Who knows which judge?
Oh, I don't think you need
to worry about judges.
These are from
the Attorney General's office.
Two separate opinions.
You know what?
For once in your life, Ellis Brawley,
I believe you've been overruled.
♪ Calling out around the world ♪
♪ Are you ready for a brand new beat ♪
♪ Summer's here and the time is right ♪
♪ For dancing in the street ♪
♪ They're dancing in Chicago ♪
- That's my mom.
- ♪ Down in New Orleans ♪
♪ In New York City ♪
♪ All we need is music ♪
♪ Sweet music ♪
- ♪ There'll be music everywhere ♪
- We won!
We won, darling, we won!
We did it, we did it!
Clay, the state office called.
They have our baby in a Tulsa hospital,
200 miles from here.
And I said, we'll be there in an hour.
There's just one thing.
It's a girl.
Girl?
- A girl?
- Mm-hm.
It's a girl.
- It's a girl.
- Mm-hm.
It's a girl!
Come on, let's go get her.
- Oh.
- Come on.
♪ Dancing in the street ♪
♪ Oh, it doesn't matter what you wear ♪
♪ Just as long as you are there ♪
♪ So come on ♪
♪ Every guy grab a girl ♪
♪ Everywhere around the world ♪
♪ There'll be dancing ♪
♪ They're dancing in the street ♪
♪ Way down in L.A. ♪
♪ Every day,
they're dancing in the street ♪
♪ Let's get our big strong long ♪
♪ Get on time ♪
♪ They're dancing in the street ♪
Ladies and gentlemen,
we're doing something
a little different during this take.
- Jim.
- Yeah.
- Would you take this seat right here?
- Coming.
Right here.
Just sit right here.
Jorene, sit right there.
And I think, your uh, your basketball girls
have something to present to you.
We're the original team gym team of...
My goodness.
Jim Keith, and he is
a legend in our state.
And we want to thank all of you,
particularly our coach,
for letting us relive...
a magical time in our lives when...
we were young and...
and we thought that
anything was possible.
And it's, it's due to this man, Jim Keith.
He is a legend in the state of Oklahoma,
and because of this film,
he is going to be a legend...
in the world in girls basketball coach.
Mr. Keith has a birthday this month.
- Oh.
- And...
Coach, from all of us...
- We love you.
We love you.