Provided by explosiveskull
https://twitter.com/kaboomskull
It was St. Sebastian's feast day.
I got caught in a blizzard.
I headed for Grand Baou,
where there's a shelter.
That's when I saw her.
It's my first.
Same here.
Save him. Save my child!
Help!
Save him.
Push.
What are we going to call you?
Saint-Martin, January 1948
Stop!
Sebastian!
Sebastian?
Stop it!
We said, not in your room.
Sure.
Stop it.
Well?
Well, I've no idea how they got here.
Yes, I bet.
Belle!
We said, not in my room.
Come and give me a hand.
Come on.
WORLD'S BRAVEST DOG
Gives Birth to Three Puppies
Watch out, it's César's honey!
Let go of that. Stop it!
Let go, I said.
No, you stay there.
You're kidding!
Where's number 3?
Sebastian?
Everything ok?
Great!
That's sweet. Good girl.
Belle, get the salt ready.
Stop it, I said.
No!
No, let them get in.
The closer they get...
the better sheepdogs they become.
Sebastian, you're late for school.
Dad, not today. Please!
Today, tomorrow, every day. School!
What is this?
Can't you talk to him?
He's right. Go!
Sebastian, now.
Hurry!
A farmer harvests eight apples
and seven pears a day.
Every month,
he sells his harvest at market.
If one apple costs three francs...
How big are they?
About that big.
You still haven't found names for them?
If you need some ideas...
Mistouflette!
- What?
- Who'll you give them to?
To no one.
100 lines.
"I must not talk in class."
100 lines?
200, why not!
Good idea. 200 lines!
I'd like you all to take a copy.
Martine, please.
Hand these out.
Try to read five pages every day.
Are we agreed, Sebastian?
The Three Mosquitoes?
Musketeers, not mosquitoes.
Please!
See you tomorrow.
- Something wrong?
- No, why?
I'm 12.
I don't need picking up at school.
I thought it's a nice day
to go up to Grand Baou.
- But if you don't want to...
- Sure, I do.
You have no homework?
No.
Race you!
I'm beat!
I don't believe it!
Any ideas?
You lose.
Come on, don't brag!
Not so long ago, I always won.
That was before.
I'm listening.
- Feels great here.
- Yes.
Fly through the clouds in a plane
and the sky's amazingly blue.
Pierre and I are in love,
you know?
Sure, come on!
What I wanted to tell you is...
Pierre and I are getting married.
I want to be sure...
He's your father.
I'm your aunt.
Not my real aunt.
That's true.
So it's all good.
Just one thing.
Yes?
I won't have to call you mommy?
- 'Course not.
- It'd feel weird.
Absolutely.
BELLE AND SEBASTIAN 3:
THE LAST CHAPTER
About time!
You may kiss!
Here.
To defend the house
while we're gone.
You know this changes nothing.
What? The knife?
No, not the knife.
Here. It's tradition.
Or it only cuts friendship.
She's beautiful.
You already slept with her?
You bet.
So you know she snores.
- Keep it under your hat.
- OK.
Dare you.
You don't dare!
Good?
Yucky.
I understand, obviously.
And Sebastian?
What about Sebastian?
What does Sebastian say?
We haven't told him yet.
We're going for two weeks
to land a contract
and a place at university.
If all goes to plan, we move in May.
What did you tell the boy?
That it's our honeymoon.
You agreed?
Your little savage going to Canada?
Sure I agreed.
His place is with his father.
Even so! Montreal's a big city.
Nothing like Saint-Martin.
He can't spend all his life here.
He's a lucky boy.
Getting to see the world.
To wedded bliss!
Good health!
If the mini-Belles
take after their mother, goodness!
Yup.
Something else, those dogs.
You'll keep one for me?
Dream on!
Those babies
are out of your price range.
Even if you win,
and let's admit it, that's unlikely.
They're not for sale.
Anyway, they're not his.
You never wanted her.
But you'd profit from her pups?
Their place
is with their mother.
No?
Will you listen?
When they've been weaned...
Come on, play!
Don't worry, it's only two weeks.
We'll talk to him when we're sure.
Trust him.
He'll understand. He's 12.
We should've told him the truth.
If he sees you happy, he'll be happy.
Happy?
Let's see. Much better.
Let's go, Pierrot.
Stop that.
I won't go.
They're liars, don't you see?
I know you're not asleep.
I only have 30 sheep.
Four sheepdogs is a lot for 30 sheep.
You know I don't give a fig about money.
Even Belle knows her pups
will leave one day.
Not tomorrow but...
One day. That's life.
It's how things work.
You'll leave too, one day.
You'll be celebrating.
Getting rid of me.
What are you talking about?
What will you do here?
Be a shepherd like me?
Why not?
You deserve better.
And you don't deserve better?
I had no choice.
I never went to school.
Never saw the world?
Sleep well.
César's place, you know it?
I'll take you if you want.
And I won't say no.
- Is it American?
- No, it's a half-track.
Belonged to a German colonel.
My dad stole a German plane.
This isn't stolen. I won it.
Won it?
With that.
Can you play?
Pick them up, they won't bite.
How about a bet?
You roll a die
and if it comes up 1, 2 or 3,
I guess your first name.
4, 5 or 6,
you guess mine.
Go on, where's the risk?
Beginner's luck.
I'm Joseph. Now let me guess...
Your name is...
Your name's...
Can't get it.
I give up, Sebastian.
When I saw the newspaper,
I couldn't believe it.
Just imagine, four years,
looking all over for my dog.
What's he say?
Four years is a long time.
I thought she was dead.
What proves she's yours?
See, she recognizes me.
She's hardly overjoyed.
Sorry, but you turn up
out of nowhere
claiming she's your dog!
Tell me another!
All patous look alike.
Not all patous have a scarred left ear.
A V-shaped scar.
She got it as a pup
climbing a fence.
Garbage! I bet you did it!
André told me you tied her up.
And beat her.
Me?
I'd never harm a dog.
I'd be a monster.
She was rake thin when I found her.
You found her? So she's not yours.
But...
You did a great job.
I can't thank you enough.
Sorry the kid grew attached...
Bring me my shotgun.
I advise you to leave.
You're taking this all wrong.
Think it over a few days.
Give the kid time to say farewell.
To the dog.
We'll come up with a solution.
Don't worry. She's staying with us.
Trust me.
Belle isn't yours.
And never will be.
Want to bet on it?
What did he say?
Nothing.
Come on inside.
Why Belle? He never loved her.
Those dogs are worth money.
- It sucks.
- You're right, it sucks.
César. We have a big problem.
Look...
I don't want to cause problems.
Give me my dog
and this goes no further.
The gentleman
has signed statements from his village.
They all say Belle's his dog
and mention the scar in her ear.
That proves nothing.
It proves the dog is mine.
Dogs aren't property.
They follow those they love.
About the pups...
The pups?
We can't give him the pups!
Remember what André said?
He beat her, tied her up, starved her!
We'll ask him to write a letter!
André likes a drop to drink, you know.
You won't stop this?
Blame the law, not me.
The dog stays here.
Fine. I'll be back with the police.
We'll be here.
I don't write the laws.
Too bad.
Wait here.
Wait here for me, I said.
I'll buy her off you.
I'll give you 10,000 francs.
That's a lot of money.
Isn't it why you're here?
You'll have to sell your house.
- My problem.
- 30,000!
20.
20,000?
How much for the pups?
You scumbag!
Listen to me...
Don't worry,
I'll come up with something.
You will?
Your dad won't allow this.
My dad comes back in ten days.
We'll play for time.
I've helped the police out plenty.
I'll explain everything.
We have no choice.
Stay there.
Belle, we need to take vegetables.
You'll wake César.
Taking a vacation, Sebastian?
Why the long face?
Some you win, some you lose.
Some days you're alive...
Some day you're dead.
Whatever happens, you don't choose.
Ever.
Well played!
Let's go, Belle!
Sebastian, time to get up!
You said I'd have to leave one day.
That day is now.
No way!
What are you doing here?
Where have they gone to hide?
Your boy took my dog.
Where are they?
You're on my land.
Beat it!
The dog ends up in my half-track.
Believe me.
We'll hide out at Molines.
They'll never look there.
Look, it's just behind that mountain.
Coming straight at us.
We gotta hurry.
Keep going!
Come on, Belle!
You can do it, Belle.
That's right, Belle!
Keep going!
Belle's with him. He'll make it.
No thanks to your stupid laws.
César...
Stay with me.
Mom?
Don't sleep, my son.
Don't sleep.
Thank you, Belle!
You saved us.
Look!
We're there.
We did it.
Just perfect. Great, isn't it?
I have a plan.
We stay here till spring.
Then we cross into Italy.
Over there, I'll find a flock
to herd in the mountains.
We'll earn our living.
In winter, I'll do odd jobs.
People always need a handyman.
The following spring...
The following spring, we start over.
Stop that!
You're stopping me working.
Come on, out the way.
Get off me!
No!
That's not food.
Walnuts,
cheese, jelly...
Chestnuts
and dried sausage.
One slice for you.
Tomorrow, we go hunting.
Dad and Angelina...
You think they'll make babies?
"This is the gentleman I will fight,"
said Athos,
while pointing to d'Artagnan
and saluting him with the same gesture.
"I shall also fight him," said Porthos.
"Not before one o'clock,"
replied d'Artagnan.
"I am also to fight this gentleman,"
said Aramis,
coming over to them.
Yes, Mr. Mayor, a big patou,
pups and a kid.
That's the word, "extraordinary."
If you see them,
call me back right away.
Whatever you do,
don't tell them anything.
I appreciate it.
We keep going.
It's more than two days.
- Shouldn't you tell his father?
- I can't reach them.
Well, now, next!
Next up, Saint-Vincent-sur-Jabron.
Here we go.
Didn't you get the plan?
Numerous sheep
played
safely
in the yard.
Numerousss... sheep
pla-yed
sa-fe-ly
in the yard.
As a result,
the shepherd
was reassured.
What's up?
What's wrong?
Why'd I suggest
taking turns in the bed?
Four days he's been missing!
My dad says he's dead.
Come on, children. Inside!
Town Hall
All right...
Thanks, Hubert.
Call me if you hear anything. Thanks.
That's the whole list.
Every village
within a radius of 40 km.
Tell me there's more we can do.
Picture it up there.
Minus 30º at night.
Too much snow to start a fire.
Horrific!
If there's an avalanche...
If he encounters a wolf...
You know?
Yes.
Molines!
Later, Louis.
Why didn't I think of that?
We stayed in summer with the flock.
Sebastian loved it.
What do we do?
Break out your Supermini.
Promise me you'll accelerate sometime.
The brake's not the accelerator.
My mule would've gone faster.
Be quiet!
- What?
- I can't concentrate!
To drive at 2 km/h?
- Turn!
- I've lost control!
You're kidding me!
It's your fault.
Making me drive like a lunatic!
Do you know where we are?
Do you know?
Somewhere between
Larcueil and Rougemont.
Nowhere! That's where we are!
Don't get out!
- Let me help you.
- Leave me alone!
Leave me alone!
- I'm trying to help.
- Leave me alone!
- Pain in the ass!
- You pigheaded...
- The salesman told you what to do?
- Do what?
Reassure me...
You can change a wheel?
Stop, you'll scare them off.
Got one!
We said we'd stock up.
What's up?
I promised to protect them.
No, it's me...
It's my fault.
He'll kill her.
He'll kill her to get back at her.
He followed me.
He's always a step ahead.
I'm too old.
No, I'm too little.
Good job for a little kid.
See, I have my uses.
Why let them take me to Canada?
Under the table at the wedding,
I heard you.
Why let them take me to Canada?
A boy's place is with his dad.
You're more than my granddad.
But I'm not your dad.
You'll travel.
I wish I had at your age.
Sure, but I'm not you.
There are shepherds in Canada.
All I want
is to be a shepherd here with you.
And Belle.
If I go, it'll never be the same.
It could be better.
We'll get them back.
From his place.
His place?
We won't let this go.
I came as fast as I could.
C'mon, let's hit the road!
Let's go!
How about a rest first?
Well...
Aren't you happy to be home?
Make the most of your pups.
Your time's short.
You were right.
A little gem, this car.
At Ormières, what's the plan?
Like musketeers, head down and charge.
It's against the law.
Is that a problem?
Not at all.
Accelerate.
We knock on doors
till we find Joseph.
Let's go.
Not like that!
It's hardly difficult.
Not like this, boss?
You don't put it to proof yet.
How many times have I told you!
Belle, wait!
What's up with you?
Village School
What's here?
What are you doing there?
Your dog led me here.
My dog?
What have you done now, Alba?
What did you do to her?
She's acting strange.
It wasn't me, honestly.
That's enough. I'll call the police.
No, wait!
I'm looking for Joseph.
He stole my dog.
You've lost me.
- What dog?
- Mine!
She looks just like yours,
except for the black eye.
The liar said she's his!
Joseph?
Your dog...
You had her 4 years, since summer '43?
How do you know?
She's her mother.
I see now
why she sniffed you like that.
She's Belle's mother?
You called her Belle?
Wonderful.
That's my grandfather.
With our mayor.
Here I am!
Where did you get to?
We were looking all over.
Hello.
Ma'am, sorry, I was scared for the kid.
Urbain.
César.
He's not a kid, he's 11.
12.
The name's Madeleine.
Is that Belle?
Her mother.
Belle's mother?
Yes, not mine.
- We're...
- I know.
- Where can...
- Follow me.
- You've known Joseph long?
- He came to Ormières pre-war.
This is where he lives.
Gravedigger.
That figures.
She got your scent.
Don't worry, Alba,
we'll get her out of there.
I've had it with him.
What will you do?
With your arm, you'll be super useful.
She's not wrong.
Joseph isn't like you and me.
We can't just do nothing.
- We need a plan.
- Head down and charge.
A real plan.
Where we don't get caught.
In the eyes of the law, the dog is his.
No, she's not his!
Come with me.
What did you say you do?
I'm a schoolteacher. Why?
No reason.
He was Belle's master.
I gave him her
when he lost his sight.
She was tiny.
But she knew René couldn't see.
That summer, she did it all.
Led the flock.
Took the sheep out.
And then...
René died.
Without an heir.
The local shepherds
divvied up the sheep.
Joseph snatched Belle.
- Nobody stopped him?
- You mean me?
I'd have liked to see you try.
Have you looked Joseph eye to eye?
He has this blank, deathly stare.
And during the war,
he stood with the Krauts. I was scared.
Everybody's scared of him.
And after the war?
He stood with the Resistance.
Miracles of the Armistice.
Joseph's a smart cookie.
How did Belle escape?
She didn't. I let her go.
She never stopped barking.
But I couldn't keep her.
He'd come for her. I told her to run.
She has something different.
I was sure some day
she'd meet someone.
Like you.
There he is, going out.
You all know what to do?
You can do it?
Keep him busy long enough?
You know what your problem is?
You underestimate me.
I hear you're a hotshot at cards.
Little savage is here, too?
He's taken to his bed.
Cold and grief, a nasty combination.
Especially at age 12.
Sure, it's a fragile age.
With an arm in a sling,
his granddad can't look after him.
You should head home, too.
Before you have an accident.
Renault Supermini.
Play you for it. Five rounds.
If you win...
the car's yours.
If I win,
I leave here with the dog and her pups.
Why'd I bite?
They're my dogs and I have a car.
Turns out, you're scared.
Scared of what?
Scared of losing.
Let's play!
Don't shout!
He's alone in there!
We're here.
I see.
Stubborn.
Stubborn as an ass.
It's over. I'm here now.
You recognized us.
You remember us.
Damn thing!
Leave it to me.
Nearly there.
What if Urbain flops?
Urbain's unbeatable.
There we go.
Two rounds to none.
In double-quick time.
Let's play.
Bolt cutter's useless!
Do you need a hand?
I know now why I never wed.
Unbelievable! The bolt cutter's useless!
Come on, my turn.
What are you looking at?
You gotta be somewhere?
No.
If my dog's gone,
you and your Supermini
are going over the edge.
Time's up!
We'll be back for them, I promise.
If he catches us and moves them,
we'll lose him for good.
What are you doing? Let's go!
Not without her.
We're inseparable.
Stubborn. Just like his granddad!
Where'd you learn that?
Practicing on locks at school.
- That's cheating.
- Who cares!
Go that way. Quickly!
Hide with the dogs.
Where are they?
What are you going to do? Kill us?
It's all over.
The dog isn't yours.
She never was.
You want us to call the police?
They'll help you find them!
Don't do anything stupid!
If you touch a hair on his head,
I swear I'll kill you!
What now?
We pray
that Sebastian found a hideout.
Want to play hide-and-seek?
Not a sound!
It's a dangerous game in a graveyard.
You could stumble on a corpse.
You ever see a corpse?
Don't make a sound.
Know what it's like, a corpse?
At first...
it's terrifying.
But very soon it becomes fascinating.
Emptiness.
Nothingness.
Silence.
Found you!
I know you're in there.
I'm sure you're in there.
You're there!
Let me see you.
You're good at this.
Don't move. Stay right there!
I'll be back for you.
You can't escape me.
Hurry!
Go on, Belle.
Go on, Belle. Run!
Please! Don't hurt her.
Go ahead.
What are you waiting for?
Go on!
Come on, beauty.
No!
We haven't got all day.
It takes the time it takes.
There we go.
That's pretty nasty.
- What's that?
- Disinfectant.
Stinks.
Stinks, but it's necessary.
- Look at this wound.
- Nobody asked you to.
Of course!
You'd prefer it to get infected?
Hold still!
- Try being more gentle.
- What a softie!
Unbelievable!
Softie, stubborn as an ass.
Promise me,
you have some qualities.
When you gave her to the blind shepherd,
weren't you sad?
There comes a time
to part company.
You sound like César.
And a time to reunite.
Your grandfather talks sense sometimes.
Just not very often.
You're lucky,
going to Canada, flying there!
You found names for them?
Athos, Porthos...
And Aramis?
Who's he for?
What'll I do with this?
It won't stop growing
and making a mess.
Madeleine will help you.
She's good with dogs.
Yeah.
When I was caught in the blizzard,
I saw my mother.
Your mother?
I know but...
I saw her.
She saved me.
I believe you.
I'm here.
I'm not going anywhere.
Sir, it's time to go.
Go on, hurry.
No tears, okay? This isn't goodbye.
Look after him.
I know you'll keep him safe.
Don't forget the maple syrup.
I heard it's delicious.
You think it tastes of trees?
I love you!
The End
Provided by explosiveskull
https://twitter.com/kaboomskull