[FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING]
It's two o'clock and, uh...
the summit's up there.
But if you don't
leave base camp,
you'll never get to the top.
K2 has been
a boyhood dream.
TONY: Why do people
do extreme sports?
It's to test themselves.
It's a sense of achievement.
It's a sense of overcoming
the elements.
one of the most awe-inspiring
things in the world.
[FRED SPEAKING FRENCH]
[KOBI SPEAKING SWISS GERMAN]
[ALL CHANTING]
KOBI: It's an unbelievably
spiritual place to be.
MIKE: I love big expeditions.
I love great challenges.
[ENGINE REVVING]
[BELLOWING]
To travel with a car
from your front door
in Switzerland
all the way to Pakistan
crossing 13 countries,
I like the challenge
of the expedition.
And I like to
overcome this challenge.
[ENGINE REVVING]
[SPEAKING SWISS GERMAN]
MIKE: I was never really
interested in Everest
because everybody
seemed to always want
to go to the highest.
I wanted to go
to the most difficult place.
You don't have to be someone
to do something.
You have to just be yourself.
[CROWD SINGING
AND CLAPPING]
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
We kind of become these
creatures of comfort at home.
But to step out
of that comfort zone
can only help you in life.
[EXCLAIMING EXCITEDLY]
[CHANTING]
[CHUCKLES]
This is maybe
not a place that everybody
wants to spend a lot of time.
Because it's rock, it's ice.
It's wind, it's snow, it's rain.
And as soon as you
leave the comfort zone
of airplanes, cars
and you have to put on
your walking shoes,
then there's complications.
It's not only difficult
terrain, with rocks
and boulders
that you have to pass.
It's psychologically difficult
for people, as well.
And if you really
want to climb K2,
you have to start
with just getting there.
The choice of driving
to Pakistan by car
never really entered
my mind before.
It was always
getting the plane,
fly to Pakistan
as quickly as possible,
get to K2 and climb.
And then what?
So, what I thought was,
"How can you make this climb
even more interesting?"
How can you add
an "unknown" factor to it?
How can you learn more
from just coming here?
And that's when the idea
of driving to K2
just came into my mind.
[ENGINE REVVING]
Usually, when you fly
over the countries,
you don't really
experience the countries.
And traveling
is about meeting people.
And the more people you meet,
the better you
understand the country
actually going through.
[ALL SINGING]
I thought you
couldn't drink here.
The process is too long.
[ALL SINGING LOUDLY]
Smile!
Cheers!
This is the best day
of my life.
[WOMAN CHUCKLING]
Switzerland, Germany, Poland,
Lithuania and Latvia.
The fifth country
in two days.
We just crossed the border
from Latvia into Russia.
Sometimes,
if you have to wait,
and you don't see
the importance of waiting,
then you can get frustrated.
They wanted to take
my license away.
But, Dima
spoke to him and said,
"I walked around Russia."
and he said, "Okay.
Then give me a souvenir."
Now, we can go again.
The police stopped us again.
In less than two kilometers,
we were stopped twice.
The first one, we negotiated.
This one, I didn't
speak one word of Russian.
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
English.
[BOTH LAUGHING]
MIKE: This is going
to take a long time.
We stopped now
for the third time...
in a very short...
We need a lot of souvenirs.
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
MIKE: My two daughters,
Annika and Jessica,
could join part of the trip
simply because I would like
to share what I experience
as an explorer with the people
that surround me.
I knoW about your trip.
It's wonderful.
But it's very, very difficult.
The Russians seem to be cold
when you see them
the first time.
Actually, when you
get to know them,
they're extremely warm.
They're extremely giving.
And they will give you
everything and more
than what they can
afford or have.
My daughter.
Jessica.
Hello.
My other daughter, Annika.
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
We've kept going non-stop,
that was day after day,
to cover over
11,000 kilometers
in about ten
and a half days of driving
sets the pace.
[ENGINE REVVING]
[TRAIN SIGNAL]
[SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
MIKE: It is comfortable
that we had the shower.
Our first shower
at base camp of K2.
Every ten days,
we have a shower.
And now we're waiting
for the mountain
to get rid of the snow.
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
[FRED SPEAKING FRENCH]
Now, patience becomes
the biggest enemy.
You all right?
All right!
[SPEAKING SWISS GERMAN]
MIKE: Yes!
The weather is not great,
but we're slowly
but surely acclimatizing.
Yes, yes.
And that's all we need
to do at this stage.
And we don't need great weather.
[SPEAKING SWISS GERMAN]
[FRED SPEAKING FRENCH]
Look there. Avalanche.
Both sides of the ridge,
going down the avalanche.
Big one, the older avalanche.
You see? They're crossing
all the tracks down.
Today is the third avalanche.
MAN: What happens
if you're in there?
You die. You die.
One avalanche like this,
you can put a building,
and they will break it.
You can't imagine the power.
Because it's coming
maybe from 2,000 meters high.
They can have the speed
at maybe more than 200 kmph.
And right down there,
there's massive power.
If I want to cross
the valley from there to there,
maybe 45 minutes to one hour.
And the avalanche
is ten seconds.
[FRED SPEAKING FRENCH]
MIKE: We're in Kazakhstan.
And Kazakhstan is exactly
how you can imagine it to be.
Flat, small little
towns and villages.
Certain parts of the road
were completely destroyed.
DMITRY: I'm in Kazakhstan!
I drive through
the fields and dust.
This is my New Zealand
driving license.
I'm not sure if I am
eligible here or not.
Because I have only
New Zealand driving licence.
Only Russian.
But I think
it'll be really cool.
We're getting closer.
K2.
But this is only the fuel
and we're only in Kazakhstan.
In the way that we'd
traveled and been stopped,
and our plans had to change,
and the route
has to be changed,
and people get tired
and people get irritated
with each other.
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
Then you,
all of a sudden see, but,
"Wow, we're all
just human beings
trying to make it work."
Fifty kilometers of bad road.
I thought climbing up to
8,000 meters will me tiring.
But trying to cross the border
between Kazakhstan
and Uzbekistan
took the whole day today.
We drove through the night,
over 1,100 kilometers.
Then it took us
over 14 hours
to go from Kazakhstan
to Uzbekistan
to this restaurant.
I think now we are double-sated.
We appreciate food much more
because we spent
all day waiting
and waiting and waiting.
And we did not even know
if we will be able
to leave Kazakhstan today
and enter Uzbekistan today.
[MEN SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
People have always asked me
what exploration has taught me.
Today, I can honestly say
that exploration
taught me a lot of patience.
And I am ready for the next
lesson down the road.
["FADE" PLAYING]
♪ In the old ways ♪
♪ Before the dark days ♪
♪ Came to change our life ♪
♪ Man and money ♪
♪ Milk and honey ♪
♪ We could all decide ♪
♪ For we live
for dreams ♪
♪ And all our babies ♪
[GIRLS SPEAKING TURKISH]
We're in Turkistan, and I
brought some friends along
to go with me today.
[ALL LAUGHING]
Okay, let's go.
♪ We all have been working
For a reason ♪
♪ Men are hardly made
to gape ♪
♪ 'Cause we're all
Part of something bigger ♪
♪ He can't do anything ♪
♪ Anything but fade ♪
MIKE: Wow.
What an amazing place, man.
Such beautiful mountains
rising out of this plateau.
It's one of the most
amazing views I've ever seen.
K2 asks one thing from you.
You need friends.
You need not only to know
your own capabilities,
but the capabilities
of the friends
that actually climb with you.
[KOBI SPEAKING
SWISS GERMAN]
The speed limit
is 80 kilometers.
And we are already at double.
[CHUCKLING]
MIKE: What I really like
about working together
with Kobi and Fred
is the trust.
That trust
that can never be broken.
We have one common goal.
But to reach that common goal,
we have to respect each other.
Now, we're really stuck.
[SPEAKING SWISS GERMAN]
With Kobi and Fred,
they like it.
They think it's a joke.
But I don't think it's a joke,
because we have
to get to Pakistan.
[ALL LAUGHING]
[SPEAKING SWISS GERMAN]
MIKE: Fred would give
a strong opinion,
Kobi would give
a strong decision
and I'm the tourist
in the group.
I'm just there
to kind of bond
everybody together.
In a way, we've become
this triangle of friends
that dream about the same thing.
[WOMEN SINGING]
[ORIENTAL MUSIC PLAYING]
[SPEAKING SWISS GERMAN]
In Kashgar, China.
[ROOSTER CROWING]
[CHEERING]
[WATER FLOWING]
MIKE: Many people come to K2
and think it's like Everest.
It is a mountain that I
would like to conquer.
But you cannot
conquer a mountain.
The mountain allows you
to go to the top.
It's welcoming,
but it can be very cold.
And a very dangerous spot
to be at the wrong moment.
But it's the human being
that actually makes
the mountain dangerous.
You prepare yourself
for the challenge.
And you're willing
to make certain sacrifices
to get there.
Then, you can start climbing.
And that, to me,
is a metaphor in life.
[FRED SPEAKING FRENCH]
And then come to here.
[MAN SPEAKING SWISS GERMAN]
[FRED SPEAKING FRENCH]
[MIKE SPEAKING SWISS GERMAN]
[FRED CHUCKLING]
We are quite comfortable.
It's four o'clock.
The sun is still out.
But we're going
to have a sleep
of more or less, I think,
12 hours, now, no?
FRED: Yeah. Good, uh?
Taking the shoes off.
And then sitting
on your mattress.
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
And at this stage, we don't
have to close the tent
because it's too warm.
[FRED SPEAKING FRENCH]
MIKE: So, tomorrow we are
going to go to camp three.
And try to get up
to 7,500 meters.
We arrived here
in the heat of the day
at about one o'clock.
And now we've had
a couple of farmers
or only one farmer.
One.
That's what we're
eating tonight.
And we had, uh...
Yeah, we boiled some water
and we had
a cup of coffee.
And a little bit of soup.
Yes, and that's it.
And that's it.
Look, my dinner.
You know I dream about what?
A big hamburger and it had
a lot of mayonnaise and ketchup.
[BOTH LAUGHING]
Mmm.
All right.
Yeah, all right.
FRED: That's life.
That's life in the... K2 lane.
But it's just...
Be a little bit patient
and see what happens
tomorrow evening
and then we'll get down
this mountain very quickly.
And then go
and have chapatis.
[CHUCKLING] Yes! Oh, yeah.
I love chapatis.
Chapatis and rice.
Chapatis and rice and dal.
And dal.
Hmm.
And we'll finish like this.
MIKE: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
["THE ONE EXCEPTIONS" PLAYING]
♪ Butterfly flying
Into the storm ♪
♪ I brace myself
For what's to come ♪
♪ You're a sight
To behold ♪
♪ A story yet to be told ♪
KOBI: The most
impressive impact
and power of nature
that I've seen
on this whole trip
was when half a mountain
slid down and created
this massive lake
that covered the road.
And people were
stuck on the other side
so they had to invent
in two seconds
a different way
of transport.
So, we arrived with our cars
and we see these
little wooden boats...
[KOBI CHUCKLING]
...with pieces of wood
put across them.
And we asked,
"Where's the ferry?"
And there's no ferry.
FRED: And I saw Mike
going in the plank,
which is almost
the size of the wheels.
MIKE: Yeah, yeah.
Driving like this.
On the boat.
And I was thinking,
"Where is the boat for me?"
And they said, "You have
to go to the same boat."
[ALL LAUGHING]
KOBI: Yeah.
How you can put two cars
in a small boat like this?
Slowly, slowly!
Tip-top?
[ENGINE SPUTTERING]
[MOTOR REVVING]
FRED: It is amazing
how these guys
actually just did it.
From one day to the other,
life continued.
MIKE: Thousands of houses
were underneath the water.
Whatever they had
was no longer there,
and taken away from them.
And they're happy, smiling
and still loving life.
Like nothing happened.
Only in Pakistan,
500 captains.
[ALL LAUGHING]
MIKE: If it had
to be done in Europe,
it will take about 15 years
to work out a system,
but here they work it out
in five minutes.
[CHUCKLING]
[GROANS]
[CAR HORN HONKING]
MAN: Come on, come on,
come on, come on.
It's all okay.
Okay, okay, okay.
Come on, let's go, slowly.
Okay, go.
[MAN SPEAKING SHINA]
FRED: We are on
the way to Skardu.
It is still 100 kilometers
to go there.
So, we're gonna
rest somewhere else.
Careful...
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
MAN: Okay. Okay, okay!
Go, go, go, go, go!
[SHOUTING]
[ENGINE SPUTTERING]
MIKE: Okay.
[ALL CHEERING]
[ALL LAUGHING]
A lot of power.
But, you know,
now, another problem.
Now, the car. My car.
Oh, another car also coming?
Yes.
The problem is...
But the problem
wasn't my car.
They're not your four
wheels working.
That's because four wheels
were not working.
Now, we're going to do it!
[ENGINE REVVING]
[ALL CHEERING]
[LAUGHING]
We made it. [LAUGHING]
Hello, everybody.
My name is Khalil.
I'm a cook
from Swiss expedition,
Mr. Mike Horn,
in K2 base camp.
Our teams love to party.
So, today I make them...
How to make chapati,
I show them.
MIKE: Khalil.
You're welcome, sir.
Today, I give
the chapati lesson.
Oh, yes.
Because each time I go home,
I tell my daughters
I eat very good chapati.
And they say,
"Make chapatis."
I say, "I don't know how."
KHALIL: So, you come
and sit here.
Your hand is very clean.
Very important
to clean your hands.
You need one pot like this.
Clean up. Very important.
Then you need flour.
Then you need salt.
Then you need water.
MIKE: Pour the water.
That is just mixing.
[SPEAKING SWISS GERMAN]
KHALIL: We have
one dough ready.
Mr. Mike, you keep this one.
And Mr. Fred, you keep this one.
Mr. Kobi, you keep this one.
Thank you.
KHALIL: Not too much!
MIKE: No, no, no. Don't worry.
FRED: How's that now?
It's becoming smaller,
not bigger.
[ALL LAUGHING]
Khalil, what's next?
[CHANTING]
[KHALIL SPEAKING SHINA]
FRED: It is better
I bring water.
Khalil, how do we
cook this chapati?
Okay, sir, now you put it.
Then appear the chapati.
MIKE: Oh, no.
[ALL LAUGHING]
The chapati
is completely destroyed.
[SPEAKING SWISS GERMAN]
Oh, nice and brown, eh?
[ALL LAUGHING]
KHALIL: Very good!
FRED: All done!
Cheers!
That is tip-top.
Now, we have to give
a little bit of the chapati
to Khalil to taste.
And he will decide
who has the best chapati.
Okay, Khalil?
And the next one.
[EXCLAIMS]
I think these two is very best.
[LAUGHING]
[INDISTINCT]
[ALL LAUGHING]
It's how is made the chapatis!
[SERENE INSTRUMENTAL
MUSIC PLAYING]
♪ If I run into the world ♪
♪ When I stand up
to the fight ♪
♪ Would I live
Inside the moment ♪
♪ Or would I pay the price? ♪
♪ Will I fly? ♪
Okay, okay. All Good.
[SPEAKING SWISS GERMAN]
[ALL SHOUTING]
[WHISTLING]
Hi.
Yeah!
[SPEAKING URDU]
That's right!
[YELLING]
[BIRDS CHIRPING]
Stop here.
MIKE: This is where
one of the high-altitude
porters come from,
according to Fred.
He's called Ali,
and he's saved a lot
of people up on K2 already.
He lives here somewhere.
And he said
he's gonna find Ali.
MIKE: How are you doing?
MIKE: I come.
I come to visit you, huh?
MIKE: I know him long time.
ALI: How are you?
How are you? Come here.
KOBI: Good.
You are happy?
ALI: Yes, yes.
MIKE: Everything okay?
Very good.
FRED: In this village,
there is local porters.
They carry load
from Askole to get
to base camp.
Quite heavy loads, 35 kg,
25 personal material
for the Swiss expeditions
and maybe 50 kg
from the sleeping bags
and the food you have
to eat from all the way.
I think they are tough guys.
These are the most important
people to do expedition.
[CAMERA SHUTTER CLICKING]
In our side,
we choose one woman.
Yeah.
Yeah?
We married this woman,
and we are in my life.
She is life.
Together, whole life.
In Europe, this is
little bad things, you know?
You are change every time,
change every time.
[ALL LAUGHING]
This is amazing.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
But, Fred never change.
Me? Me? I never change.
FRED: Yeah, yeah.
Dima, changed
six times already.
[ALL LAUGHING]
And Kobi never change.
Never change?
KOBI: No.
MIKE: We've been
to Pakistan about five times
and each time we cross Ali
on the mountain.
He's a HAP,
a high altitude porter.
And in 2013, when we decided
to turn back at Chengdu,
it was with Ali that we
decided to turn back.
ALI: After we at base camp,
then after one day,
there was avalanche problem.
We thought that the mountain
wasn't ready to be climbed,
and that's when
the whole expedition
moved down the mountain
that nobody summited.
I'm lucky,
and thanks for you
and Mike and my friends,
we are safe this time.
[CONVERSATION
IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[ALL LAUGHING]
KOBI: Can you eat that?
You like sugar, sir?
MIKE: No, no, no.
ALI: No salt?
FRED: No.
KOBI: Just like that.
Milk.
ALI: Just milk?
MIKE: Yeah.
[SPEAKING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
FRED: Big boss.
First, big boss.
If he still alive, we drink.
But if he die...
[LAUGHING] If he die,
we don't drink.
[LAUGHING]
We look at his face first.
Because he have a stomach
like African stomach, you know?
MIKE: Oh, this is good.
This is very good.
[SPEAKING SWISS GERMAN]
Like home.
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[SPEAKING SWISS GERMAN]
We've decided to walk up
the mountains a little bit,
to get a little bit
of altitude, first of all,
and to get the legs going.
We're sitting in this alpage.
It's completely just made
out of stone and rock,
drinking warm caramel.
It's quite cold,
but this is really
the most amazing moment
of the trip so far.
Just gaining altitude
and the simplicity
of the whole situation
is wonderful.
[SHOUTING]
Many times
without wife here, sir.
Uh, many time.
MAN: Getting crazy.
He's now 25 days
without wife here.
Twenty-five days,
no wife here?
[MAN SPEAKING INCOHERENTLY]
[ALL LAUGHING]
Good. Good.
[ALL CHUCKLING]
Kobi is a person
that I appreciate
simply because
his knowledge
and what he has done in life
prior to meeting him
put him in
a different category.
If you take action
as a criteria
to trust somebody,
then you base yourself
on a solid foundation.
And that's what Kobi has.
His action is so solid
that everybody trusts
that foundation.
So, looking in
behind the tooth,
I can see an area of abscess.
But the fact that you have
some tenderness on that tooth
makes me think that
you might have a problem
from an old root canal.
And if you continue
to have pain like this,
then I think maybe
the chances for the summit
are 50-50, maybe.
But we'll give you some pills
to get you by.
With the altitude,
he has the pressure changes.
But also, the...
um, nutrition is such
that you're more prone
to dental infections.
MIKE: Frustrations,
you'll always have in life.
If you think for one second
that you're so important
that everything must go
exactly according to plan,
then you're making one of
the biggest mistakes in life.
We've been stuck
in Skardu, Pakistan,
for over 12 days, now,
waiting for our permit
to come.
Nobody can give us
any information.
The big problem is that
the other expeditions
that do climb with oxygen,
they don't need as much time
at base camp as we do.
And that's why it's important
for us to leave early.
We've missed the first
weather window,
because we will now
only be able to do
the summit push
towards the end of July.
And towards the end of July
will be our last chance
to climb.
And, um, this is
getting to a stage
that it's putting
our whole expedition
on the balance.
And all we're waiting for
is one guy
signing a piece of paper.
Very important.
Maybe other day...
To reach camp three,
we need time.
Yes, sure.
And after sleeping
in camp three,
we need two, three days' rest.
It's impossible.
There's not enough time.
We need a fucking chance.
We need to have
one good weather.
"If there is a good window
14, 17, 16..."
It's only for rocky mountains.
Yes.
Sure.
We have a chance
end of July.
Yes, but end of July
is only four weeks.
We arrive here.
Yeah.
After that it's one week,
two, three, four weeks.
Only have one chance,
end of July.
All right.
[BIRDS CHIRPING]
[SPEAKING SWISS GERMAN]
FRED: Let's be positive.
[MEN TALKING]
[FRED SPEAKING FRENCH]
We have to be realistic.
Yeah.
[SPEAKING SWISS GERMAN]
I know Fred since
18, 19 years old,
and straightaway,
I could see something
very special in him.
I was a teacher,
teaching mountain guides
in Switzerland
how to do canyoning.
And straightaway,
I saw somebody
that was really passionate
and interested
about life.
He has his moods,
like we all have.
But before he climbs,
he sorts out his problems,
and then he climbs
with freedom.
And that's what makes him
a very special person.
MIKE: He trusts his knowledge,
and he's a lovely person
to live with.
[LAUGHING]
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
MIKE: You need
somebody like that.
We all need to be
people like that.
Whoo!
Over the ridge!
[FRED LAUGHING]
[GRUNTS]
[LAUGHTER]
MIKE: Uh, Fred, do you like
driving off-road?
Of course. [LAUGHS]
FRED: He was trying to
drive a little bit under water.
When you follow Mike,
and you see the car going...
[MAKES GLUGGING SOUNDS]
So, Fred coming up,
the car straight...
Stuck.
Back.
[SPEAKING SWISS GERMAN]
MIKE: Go!
[PRAYER ON LOUDSPEAKER]
[HONKS]
Good luck!
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
MIKE: In daily life,
it's all about ourself.
It's all about who you are.
It's all about
what car you drive.
what house you live in.
But, yeah, that doesn't matter.
Change is something
that makes people afraid,
simply because it means
I have to go into the unknown.
The unknown adds spice
to life.
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
Without friendship,
without teamwork,
without the ability to
laugh and cry together,
without the ability
to help each other,
you could never do it.
It's impossible.
It's just too much.
So, we are in between
camp two and three now.
We passed
the most technical part,
but first, now, let's cover
the previous tracks.
And the only thing
we have to do now
is to push on slowly, slowly.
And then we will, um,
eventually make it
to camp three,
where we will set up a tent.
And tonight, we would like
to sleep at 7,100,
and tomorrow,
push to 7,500.
Then, we're ready
for the summit push.
This camp three.
Tomorrow, we'll move on
to 7,500 meters.
Inshallah.
Inshallah, yes.
And then, uh, we'll...
From there, we will
make a U-turn
and go straight down
to base camp.
He's the serious man.
He wants to share every
single bit of passion with us.
It definitely brings you
a lot closer,
and gets us to
understand him a lot more.
MIKE: This was an opportunity
for them to bond with me.
To be able to understand
how I think,
to be able to understand,
why would I want to go
to the top of K2.
♪ Happy birthday to you ♪
MIKE: And Kobi gives me
a biberli.
Yummy.
Mike.
[SPEAKING SWISS GERMAN]
One, two, three, four.
♪ Happy birthday to you ♪
♪ Happy birthday dear Mike ♪
[CHEERING]
Okay, we've got this
beautiful cake here...
with jelly and everything.
Now, taste.
FRED: A speech, a speech.
Yeah. Thank you...
You're welcome, sir.
...everybody, for being here.
Yeah.
And, uh, hopefully,
this is my last birthday
on K2.
[LAUGHING]
Inshallah, we can summit.
Yeah, inshallah.
And then we can go
to Broad Peak, no?
Yes, sir.
Then go forward, yeah.
One peak for Fred first...
Yeah, yeah.
...and then Nanga Parbat, no?
Ali Ahmed, you coming with?
[LAUGHS]
Just like that, eh?
Cheers, guys. Thanks a lot.
Cheers.
So, what we actually have here
is, um, all the equipment
that we'll take up
to base camp.
We need the meat.
I was afraid...
A lot of dried meat.
They're lovely, lovely pieces,
look at them.
[SPEAKING SWISS GERMAN]
Tomorrow, we'll be leaving
for the trekking.
And it's quite long there,
and I want to buy maybe
two pieces of chocolate
for the walk.
Which one is the best one?
Sulphur.
Sulphur, yes.
They use sulphur,
this one, natural?
Natural, yes.
SELLER:
Ismail, do this please.
This is the number one stock?
Two piece. Okay?
Okay.
Any more?
How is your cherries?
Cherries, 200 rupees a kilo.
Two hundred rupees a kilo?
Kilo.
Oh, too much.
[SPEAKS HINDI]
[SPEAKS URDU]
But why Pakistan
not make better roads?
No, no.
Pakistan... Look, Pakistan...
No?
No.
You want Pakistan road.
[WHISTLE]
The crampons are good,
the shoes for you are good,
packs for you are good.
Fantastic.
BOTH: Yeah, we're back again.
Look at us!
Ready for hiking
up to base camp.
At long last, Fred will tell you
what happened.
It's one of his happiest days
in the last...
16 days.
Because today,
as you can see behind us,
we are actually going to go
up to Askoli.
Inshallah.
You are never sure
until you are there,
you know, in Pakistan.
This is the team.
And Dima, and Nils,
our cameraman,
he's obviously
behind the camera.
We're ready for lots of
arduous walking up a hill,
which is going to be
very interesting,
I can assure you.
Oh, yeah.
MIKE: This is not
the G-Class,
because the road
has actually been blocked.
Now, we have to
take the cars halfway...
unload them,
carry all the equipment
to the other side of the road,
where the road
has been blocked,
and then load them
in other jeeps.
So, this is where
the G-Class stops.
And these guys
only do a shuttle
there and back,
there and back.
Let's try and see if
they will get us there safely.
My name is Tony Buckingham,
and I'm from England,
and the reason I'm here
is because of Mike Horn.
MIKE: Sometimes, you can
take people away from
the life that they're living
and open up another life
so that they can find answers
that they can apply
in the way they live daily.
That's why I'm sitting here,
at the base camp of K2,
looking at, possibly,
one of the most
awe-inspiring sights
I've ever seen.
MIKE: For me to be able
to share what we've done
with Tony was a privilege.
I think the Baltoro
teaches all of us
different lessons.
To have a friend like Tony
that said,
"Listen, Mike,
if this is a dream,
this can be a dream for me,
to be able to get to
the base camp of Baltoro
as well."
We started sharing
this dream.
He said, "We're going
to K2 together."
I said,
"You've gotta be joking."
"You're a madman."
I said, first of all,
I don't climb.
Secondly, I'm afraid
of heights.
And, thirdly, no.
He said to me,
"You know, Tony..."
He said it's going to be
"completely flat."
He said, "It's like
a walk in the park."
He said, "You don't have
to worry about anything."
He said, "Really easy."
See if anyone calls that flat.
[LAUGHS]
And, of course, like an idiot,
I believed him.
What the fuck
am I doing here?
How much more of this
am I gonna walk over?
Jesus Christ, the terrain
is just so lethal.
Is there a quick way
out of here? [LAUGHS]
And you realize, no,
there's no quick way
out of here.
So, you gotta put your head down
and you gotta keep going.
Not easy going.
It's really something else.
You're starting to feel
the altitude slightly,
with fantastic scenery.
But it was hard.
It was hard.
It's not for the faint-hearted.
MIKE: This guy is unbelievable,
carrying that weight
up here.
Not for one day,
for seven days.
We're very fortunate.
Very lucky.
You can't really
see the glacier,
so it's covered with gravel
and massive rocks.
You can easily
lose the way as well.
ALI: This year, the route
is hundred percent changing.
This year, very difficult way.
Glacier is up, down,
up, down.
I'm, every year,
coming this way
but I don't know
where is the way now.
Completely changed.
MIKE: But if you just
follow the donkeys,
and the horses,
you can always
find the camp
because they know where
they can get water and food.
This is the most important
man of everybody.
He's called the "sirdar."
And the "sirdar..."
Sardar Ali.
...is the person responsible
to distribute the loads,
distribute the food
of everybody around you.
He goes all the way
up to base camp with us.
So, this guy,
you have to be his best friend.
Otherwise, when he goes
on strike, you're stuck.
Huh?
Yeah.
Fucking glacier.
I hate the blasted place.
ANNIKA: Eat something nice.
We'll rest a little bit.
And then we can attack again.
Only two more hours,
and we'll be at that camp
for the night.
Thank God.
MIKE: What's very important
to understand
is that nothing goes to waste.
We might be for animals,
or against killing animals
to feed human beings.
But without animals,
these people cannot live.
And if they have to carry
vegetables up here,
it will be rotten in two days
in the sun.
So, they only way then can
actually feed themselves
is by actually making
the animals walk with them.
[SPEAKING URDU]
They've slaughtered two goats.
And as we're going
up the glacier,
they'll have a hard time
to find food.
So, the porters will have
the last real big meal
divide all the meat in between.
They've got a hundred
porters that's left.
They'll come together
and each one
takes his portion,
heads off,
makes his little fire,
and cooks his last
real meal.
[SPEAKS URDU]
From here on, it'll only be
chapati for them.
FRED: They invited me to eat
some chapati,
but I think
I don't want to eat
because they have
only that, you know.
We may have
a big dinner over there.
I don't want to take
the food from them now.
Because, these guys,
they are very strong.
They walk hours and hours
with only a few chapati
in the stomach,
it's amazing.
Baltoro chapati.
Eh? Baltoro chapati.
That's the best.
[SINGING]
TONY: You've really got to
get out of your comfort zone.
You've really got to feel
uncomfortable occasionally,
to appreciate what it's like
to be alive.
MIKE: So, we've just arrived
at Concordia,
an iconic spot where
you can see the mighty K2.
It's taken us five days
to walk up here.
We've had very,
very good porters
that have actually
helped us to get here
much quicker than what
we've expected to get here.
Now, from here, we have to
trek across the glacier
and then we'll follow
the moraine
all the way up to
the K2 base camp.
Just look around.
Unbelievable.
Base camp's on a moraine, so,
the moraine goes up and down.
To put our tents,
we have to level
the moraine a little bit
and put the finer gravel
right over the bigger rocks
so that we can sleep
more or less flat.
This is gonna be
an interesting meeting.
We are finding the source
of the weather.
Do you see the cloud?
Yeah, yeah.
Do you see this light gray
or light green?
This is a high overcast
that we're getting now.
There's 26, when you see
lifting up like that.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
I'm sure we have
thunder and lightning,
or a storm here.
MIKE: We're not gonna wait
until August.
I'll need little gappers,
basically, now.
MIKE: Wind, five knots.
Ah.
It's almost perfect weather.
MIKE: Fred, what time
do you wanna start?
Midnight, two o'clock,
something like this.
Yeah, okay.
Two o'clock, but now
it's warm, yeah?
After two o'clock,
no fell down, stones...
Usually, we are right between
10:00 and midday.
Okay, yeah.
Okay.
We can rest all day
and we can start again
at midnight
to camp four.
Okay, I think we're gonna spend
another six hours
to reach the shoulder.
Oh. The snow...
In the snow.
Yeah, or ten hours.
Yeah, yeah.
Worst case.
Worst case, ten hours.
We're gonna reach camp four
shoulder at 10:00 a.m. again.
And we can start again
at 10:00 p.m. that day.
On the same day.
I think that's
a very good idea.
Okay. This is the schedule.
We're gonna be on the summit
around 11:00 a.m.
or something like that.
Yeah.
Yes.
Uh, 25.
Yeah.
And it's supposed to be
the best day,
totally clear
with no precipitation,
and the best temperature.
Okay?
FRED: It's 55.
MIKE: If we see the cloud coming
over Chogolisa,
coming in quickly,
um, we just go back.
We go, and every day,
we look what's happening.
We go, we go, we go,
and if it's not possible,
we go down.
Yes.
That's it.
The earlier we get
to the summit,
the more time we have
to get back to camp three
in bad weather.
Yeah.
Yes.
MIKE: This mountain will,
from the bottom to the top,
it will take maybe
two days to climb
and one day to get down.
It's like a lifeline.
And if you get to
a moment that you doubt,
then you're doing
something wrong.
K2 gives you a very small
weather window to climb.
If you're not
100 percent ready as well,
then the mountain's
gonna kill you.
Ali.
You want to go back
to Nepal?
Uh?
It's better, sir.
If the mountain doesn't
allow me to climb,
I'm not going to take
one risk to get to the summit.
Because my life today
has a different meaning.
Maybe you lose your wife
like I lost my wife,
but you've got two
beautiful daughters
next to it
that will enrich your life
as much.
So, Kobi,
big gloves, you have?
Yes.
Small.
Small gloves.
Gas?
Gas, one, yeah.
Water bottle?
Two bottles.
MIKE: The conditions are good.
It's warm,
no snow,
and, uh...
we have a very good chance
of getting up to 8,000 meters.
Okay, bye, guys.
Bye.
Before all big travels,
you have to sit a little bit
and think.
And I like to sit
and think a bit.
And then when I start
thinking, I go...
Yep, base camp.
Don't run!
Everything boils down
to making the first step.
And this is just
what's happening here.
It's two o'clock,
and the summit's up there.
But if you don't leave
base camp,
you'll never get
to the top.
ALI: Base camp, camp three.
How do you feel?
Mike saab.
Now, I think we all work well.
Yeah.
And now, pitch the tent,
eat, sleep and go.
FRED: The conditions have
changed a bit now.
For me, too much snow.
ALI: In the mountain, yeah?
Yes, the whole mountain
has snow.
Heavy snow, yes.
Heavy snow, yeah.
Yeah.
You've seen only that.
Yeah, if we strong enough,
then make possible, yeah?
Yeah, it's the summit.
There is no summit. [LAUGHS]
I don't know.
Me, yesterday,
I was very tired.
And I don't know
if I have the power
to make the trek till there.
And if I have the power, after,
I don't know the next day,
to the top.
I think the chance is quite...
Small.
Thick snow... [PANTING]
Strong winds made us
turn around.
Unfortunately,
it didn't work out
like I wanted it
to work out.
But, um, we're all alive.
We can all try again.
This year K2 didn't open
its doors and windows
for us to get through.
But such is life.
If you don't try,
you'll never know.
MIKE: How can you
discover new land
if you never leave home?
To learn, you have to step
out of your comfort zone.
This way.
Now, we really stuck.
The machine...
Can't go back.
Kobi is trying to
dive into the water
without going too deep,
because he says there's
rocks underneath it.
So, he wants to go "flop".
[LAUGHTER]
[PANTING]