- Hello?
- Hi, honey. I'm at the hospital.
Sorry for not answering your call earlier.
It's fine. I only wanted to tell you...
...that Dr. Rahma is sick,
so she can't attend to patients.
- But they have another doctor.
- What should we do then?
People recommended Dr. Rahma to us.
We're already 10 days late.
We can't postpone our appointment any longer.
Okay, then. As long as you feel comfortable.
- The doctor's young and good.
- A woman or a man?
A man, single, handsome.
That's not what I mean, honey.
I have no problem
if the doctor's a man or a woman as long as...
I'm kidding. It's a woman.
I'm more comfortable with a woman anyway.
I'll call you back later, okay?
Okay. Bye, love you.
- Nurse? Is the ob-gyn here yet?
- Yes, Ma'am?
Ob_gyn?
That's Dr. Cathalina.
Hannah?
Oh, dear! You're Hannah, right?
- I am.
- Oh dear. It's really you.
Han...
Don't you remember who I am?
I'm your high school friend, Han.
Cathy.
Cathy? Oh, dear! I didn't recognize you.
- You look so different.
- Do I?
Your hair was short back then.
You're so pretty now, and you're an ob-gyn.
- Let's do your check-up then.
- You're going to do my check-up? Seriously?
What do you mean? You have doubts about me?
- Or do you want to cancel your appointment?
- Maybe I should.
Don't. I'm new here.
I'm kidding. I'm happy
that you're the one doing my check-up.
Hang on. Should I call you "Madame Doctor" here?
What are you talking about? Relax.
Call me Cathy or whatever, just like we used to.
I should call you "Meow" then.
About your problem,
the sickness and the dizziness...
That's due to your high blood pressure. 143/165.
I'm going to give you pills for that, okay?
But if you're still dizzy after that,
I'll refer you to an internist.
Okey dokey, Madame Doctor. Whatever you say.
By the way, are you married yet?
Please, we can only discuss medical issues
in this room, Mrs. Hannah.
Oops, sorry.
Let's start.
How's my baby?
- A boy?
- He is.
You must be so happy.
The fetus' weight is normal.
See? The placenta is also in the right place.
It's good.
And the fetus' head is near the birth canal.
The growth is slow, but we'll find out the cause.
Han, you don't need to worry. This is common.
It's usually because
the mother doesn't get enough nutrition.
Yes, Madame Doctor.
For me to eat a lot, I have one condition.
Madame Doctor must come and eat with me at my house.
This is the first time
I have a patient giving me a condition.
But you'll do it, won't you?
- Let me think about it first.
- Oh, dear. What a busy doctor.
Hey, your husband did not come with you?
He had a meeting.
But I think he's on his way here.
By the way, I don't know who your husband is.
Who is he?
We can only discuss medical issues in this room.
- Okay. You are using my own words against me?
- Who said that earlier?
Okay. Thank you, Sir.
- Hi!
Welcome! Finally, you're here!
Come in.
Han, you have such a nice house. Great ambiance.
Thank you. Let's go to the back
to meet my husband.
He's cooking us dinner. He won't let me get tired.
Here he is. Honey, here's my doctor.
Oh, yeah.
Titi?
Malik?
Surprise!
- Happy? Are you happy now, Mrs. Hannah?
- I am.
No wonder she wouldn't mention
who her husband is. It's you.
Hannah didn't tell me either
that you're her doctor friend.
I did it on purpose.
I wanted to see your reactions.
You still love to play around, don't you?
Hang on. You guys talk.
Hannah? Where are you going?
Just a minute. Just chat a bit.
Do you know?
If I start to grumble and get angry,
he can't take it. And he would instantly say...
..."Honey, I married you because you're funny.
You're not funny anymore if you're angry."
Does he think I'm a comedian?
He married me just because I'm funny?
It's not that, honey. But you make me happy.
Honey...
These kinds of things melt my heart.
But where did you meet again?
We met again in Jogja
because we were studying at the same university.
We were just friends back in high school.
But because Jogja has romantic vibes, so...
...the rest is history.
But who didn't like him back in high school?
Every girl had a crush on him.
Including you, right? You had a crush on him
back in high school, didn't you?
So cute.
Do you have a husband?
Not yet, honey.
Can't you see? A doctor, pretty, successful.
Guys are afraid of her.
It's not like that. You're exaggerating.
I just haven't met the right guy.
Your standard is too high.
What?
Excuse me, I need to get this.
Please.
Hello?
Yes?
What?
Mrs. Dewi?
Okay. I'll be there in a second.
Wait for me, okay?
Hannah, Malik, I'm sorry.
I need to go to the hospital for an emergency.
It's okay. You got here by taxi, didn't you?
Honey, take her.
- No, it's fine. I can go by taxi.
- No way. It's dark. The hospital's not far anyway.
It's okay. Let me take you. I'll get ready.
- Okay.
- But...
It's fine.
Han, you're okay with Malik taking me to the hospital?
It's okay. I trust you.
There's no way a woman like you would
want to be with another woman's husband.
Malik?
- Hey, Cath.
- You're still here?
I was waiting for you.
The weather is bad.
I will be worried if you took a cab.
But I have ordered one.
You can cancel it, right?
I still can't believe you're a doctor now
since you were afraid to see blood.
- Good evening, Uncle.
- Good evening.
Good evening, Aunty.
Mom, do you still remember him?
I'm Malik, Aunty, Uncle.
Oh, Malik! Oh dear!
Why are you here together?
I'll tell you later. He better go home now.
His wife is waiting for him back home.
Oh, you're married.
- Do you have any children?
- My wife's pregnant.
Here's the doctor.
Thank you for bringing Cathy home.
I'm leaving, Uncle, Aunty.
- Okay. Thanks.
- Aunty.
I'll drop him to his car.
Hey. Don't be nosy.
What are you talking about?
Na?
Nana?
Nana? Oh, dear. Hannah!
Hannah?
Nana?
Na?
Oh, dear. Hannah?
- Hannah.
- Morning, Doctor.
How are you doing? Are you okay?
How do I look? I look fine, don't I?
Still looking pretty?
I'm fine, Cath.
They checked the baby last night.
Thank God, all is safe.
And what did Doctor Mulia say?
We're going to get a CT scan now.
- Okay.
- I have to be okay...
...so I don't die first and you remarry.
- What? What are you talking about?
- I won't allow it.
Enough. Let's go to the radiology.
- Excuse us.
- Can you accompany us? You can't?
- I can't.
- Stop it.
- But let me know the result.
- Okay.
- Okay, bye.
- I'll call you. Bye, Cath.
Are you okay?
I'm okay.
How did it feel
when you came to know Hannah's husband is Malik?
I bet you wanted to pull her hair.
Ra, you're overthinking.
Cathy isn't like that. Am I right?
See? She's silent. It means she agrees with me.
Cath, does your heart still hurt?
What should I say?
My heart's not hurting anymore. But...
...when I saw his face...
...I wanted to scratch his face.
See?
I'm with you.
- Do you still love him?
- What are you talking about? I'm only kidding.
- You're exaggerating.
- I don't love him anymore, okay?
Can we change the topic?
I'm sick of talking about this.
I'm not even thinking about it too much.
Okay. You say now you don't want to talk
or think about him.
But you know, deep down,
the names Malik and Hannah are in your mind.
That's the reason you haven't moved on yet.
You still want to be single, don't you?
Me being single right now...
...one thing for sure is
he's not the reason for it.
Because you haven't found a guy like Malik.
Guys, I have moved on. Okay?
How is it, Doc?
I'm sorry.
But I have to tell you this bad news.
The CT scan result shows...
...the presence of cancer.
Doctor, are you certain?
Any possibility of a mistake?
This is not what we hoped for.
The biopsy shows
that Mrs. Hannah has stage 3 brain cancer.
What should we do now, Doc?
Because you're pregnant,
you need to be handled with special treatment.
Chemo is the most suitable treatment.
I'll discuss it first with the ob-gyn.
I've read about it and found out...
...that chemo poses a high risk for the fetus.
So, I'm not going to do it.
Honey, if you're not going to do it,
It’s very risky for you.
If I do it...
...it's very risky for the baby.
And the most important thing now is my baby.
But if something happens to you,
it'll affect the baby.
I'm going to have the chemo
after my baby is born. End of story.
You have to be serious about it.
It's your life we're talking about.
I don't mind losing my life,
as long as my baby is born safely.
Oh, dear.
Honey, don't be stubborn.
- Just this time, don't be stubborn. Think about yourself.
- Don't you love your baby?
- I do.
- Hannah, Malik.
Stop it.
Don't get too emotional. Calm down.
The situation must be hard for both of you.
Han, as a patient, you have the right
to reject a medical procedure.
But you also need to understand...
...that a doctor's recommendation
is based on a patient's medical record.
That's why a patient and a doctor
need to be in agreement.
Then only can the medical procedure be done.
In your opinion...
...as a good friend...
...not as a doctor...
...what should we do?
As a good friend...
...I want you to get through
the medical procedure, Han.
For your own good.
Honey... Do it, okay?
Just leave.
- Bye.
- Mbok, take care of her. She's unwell.
- Yes, Sir.
- Bye, honey.
- Bye.
My husband never kissed me when he left,
he kicked me instead.
Ma'am, what's wrong?
- What's wrong?
- I'm fine.
I'll call Mr. Malik
to take you to the doctor, okay?
No, he has just left.
You know, it's only because I'm pregnant.
I see. I was like that when I was pregnant.
- Yeah?
- Yeah. Dizzy and sick...
...of seeing my husband not have anything to do.
- Not that angle.
- How should I do it then?
- My face looks big. A bit lower.
- Oh, dear.
It's usually the photographer
that gives the direction, not the model.
Good evening.
- Aunty, Uncle.
- Erol.
How are you?
It's been a while since you came here.
- Good evening.
- Erol.
I just got back from a two-month trip around Europe.
For business.
- Amazing.
- With your dad?
With my dad.
But I handle a lot of Dad's business now.
Cool. That's how it should be.
Youngsters nowadays have to take part,
not be standing behind their parents.
- Give my regards to your dad.
- I will.
Let's drink some tea.
I made some great cookies.
Thank you, but not for me. I'm only picking Cathy up.
It's okay for me to take her out, isn't it?
Of course. Call your sister.
Big sister! Erol's here!
- Oh dear!
- Erol's here!
Don't scream. Go in and get her.
- That's not how you do it.
- Kids nowadays.
I could hear your loud voice all the way inside.
- Hi, Cath.
- Hi.
Mom, Dad, I'm leaving, okay?
Okay.
- So pretty.
- Cathy.
Don't come home too late at night. Okay?
And Erol? Take care of my daughter.
Bring her home in one piece.
For sure.
You're still joking.
- Aunty, Uncle.
- Yeah.
Bye.
The restaurant is great,
but why are there no other customers?
I booked it just for the two of us.
Rol, isn't this a bit too much?
No way. It's for you.
I also have ordered the food for you.
Is that okay?
It's okay. I trust your judgment.
When I was in Europe...
...Dad urged me to make a choice immediately.
He said I need to make a commitment
to a partner...
...before he gives his business to me.
Well...
...someone who is married
is usually more capable to make a commitment.
That's why I want to make a commitment to you.
I want us to not only be friends.
So, that's what your dad wants?
That's what I want too.
- Why are you laughing?
- Nothing. I just want to laugh. Can't I?
So, what do you think?
So...
No.
No?
Yes, no.
Please tell your dad sorry.
No problem. It's fine.
If I can be honest,
I'm more comfortable if we're friends.
Me, too. As long as you're comfortable, right?
Thank you.
Okay.
Let's eat.
Hello?
Okay. I'm on my way there. Hang on.
Rol, I'm so sorry. But I need to go to the hospital.
There's an emergency.
Okay, but eat first.
They can wait, can't they?
They can't.
Someone's life is in my hands.
I need to leave now.
You don't need to take me, I'll get a taxi.
Cathy, sorry for this.
It’s ok. It's my job. How's Hannah?
I don't know.
Doc, how's my wife?
There's no other way.
We need to deliver the baby now.
But with the patient's condition, it'll be risky.
Excuse me, Sir. Your wife's asking for you.
Okay.
- Doc...
- Please.
Doc, I'm sorry, but I...
I know.
You have an emotional attachment to the patient.
But if you mind,
another doctor can take your place.
But the surgery needs to be done soon.
At least one life will be saved.
Okay, Doc.
I'm ready, because there's no other option, isn't it?
I don't care what's going to happen to me anymore.
I need your help.
Save my baby, Cath.
Han...
...everything's going to be okay.
Okay?
I hope...
...I can die in peace.
I know I won't make it.
I'm sure you actually know it too.
Honey...
You'll be healthy again.
Got it?
Cathy, Malik...
...I know both of you
still have feelings for each other.
Han...
- Don't think bad thoughts about me.
- I'm not having bad thoughts.
For me, it's good.
I will be in peace and happy...
...if you get married.
Han, I'm sorry, but it's not funny.
Ti, sorry, Hannah's mind is down, so...
That's why she's talking nonsense.
I'm serious.
- Honey, what are you talking about?
- I'm serious.
Cath, I want my baby safe...
...and taken care of by someone right.
Malik is also a good husband.
I don't want him to marry the wrong woman.
Han...
You know I care so much about you.
But I'm sorry...
...I can't do what you are asking from me.
I can't.
You better rest now to calm your mind.
Ti, sorry...
Honey, what's wrong with you?
Stop it. Don't talk nonsense.
I never asked anything from you.
Only this.
I want my baby safe...
...and taken care of by someone right.
Malik is also a good husband.
I don't want him to marry the wrong woman.
You can ask anything you want.
But not that.
I don't want anything else.
Just that.
Ti.
I agree to do it.
Seriously, Cath?
Ti, let's talk.
Hey. What for?
She's ready to do it.
Honey, listen to me.
You're going to be healthy again.
I have a feeling.
And I'm sure it's going to come true.
Cath...
Say what I'm about to say.
In the name of Allah...
Honey, it's impossible. Okay?
Titi has a different belief from us.
Stop it.
I'm also a Muslim, Malik.
I should be able to do it.
You had to break up
because of your different beliefs.
But there's no more reason
for you to not be together.
Cath...
Say what I'm about to say, okay?
In the name of Allah...
Cath...
Come on, Cath. You promised me.
"In the name of Allah..."
In the name of Allah...
"I will...
...marry your husband."
Go on. Say it.
Cath.
If God permits it...
...I will marry...
...your husband.
Thank you.
You could always calm me down.
I want to see you get married before my surgery.
Han, it's impossible.
I'm willing and I will do it
if what you're worried about really happens.
But if not...
...I can't.
So how will I know
you're going to keep your promise...
...if I'm not here anymore?
Enough. It's not right.
Take back your request. Okay?
But Cathy has sworn.
This is the only thing that will keep me calm
during the surgery.
I'd like to be your marriage witness.
I think Hannah knows
that you only want to make her happy.
But don't you worry, okay?
Don't think about it.
Let me take care of this.
I'll talk to Hannah.
I'll try to make her understand. Okay?
Let's do it tomorrow.
What?
Let's get married tomorrow.
What are you doing this for, huh?
I don't want you to sacrifice your future
just because you pity me and Hannah.
We...
...are doing this...
...for Hannah.
That's the only reason?
What other reasons do you want?
Because...
Because I still love you?
Because when you left me...
...I felt lost and I still had hope
to get back with you again?
Is that what you mean?
I...
...have no feelings for you anymore.
And I'm going to marry you...
...just for Hannah...
...and the baby in her womb.
One more thing.
I didn't become a Muslim because of you.
I became a Muslim because I wanted to learn Islam.
And I learned about it when I studied in England.
We were broken up at that time.
So whatever my decision is...
...I am doing it all from my heart.
It doesn't have anything to do with you.
And I'm certain...
...Hannah...
... entrusted her kid to me...
It's God's doing.
If you make that decision...
...then you're no longer my daughter.
Honey, think about what you are saying.
- So, you agree with this?
- I don't.
I don't agree to our daughter marrying a married man.
But Cathy will forever be our daughter.
A daughter who disappoints us...
...because she changed her belief
to chase Malik's love?
Mom, I became a Muslim not because of Malik.
I had broken up with him back then.
So, it had nothing to do with him.
Stop it. Don't say anything anymore.
This matter is clear.
We don't need to continue talking about this.
Mom...
Dad...
I'm sorry...
...for...
...always disappointing you.
But I have a reason for doing this.
Whatever your reason is, I don't get it!
We put you in school to be a smart woman!
And what's the result?
You're going to become someone's second wife.
What sect are you following?
So, can we start, Sir?
Yes.
In the name of Allah.
I marry off and I wed off
Malik Al Fateeh bin Muhammad Yahya...
...with Cathalina Gilia binti Paul Wijaya...
...with the dowry a set of prayer kits, in cash.
I accept Cathalina Gilia binti Paul...
Go on.
What do you think? We go back from the start?
In the name of Allah.
I marry off and I wed off
Malik Al Fateeh bin Muhammad Yahya...
...with Cathalina Gilia binti Paul Wijaya...
...with the dowry a set of prayer kits, in cash.
I accept Cathalina Gilia binti Paul Wijaya's in
marriage...
...with the dowry in cash.
Witnesses? Legitimate?
Legitimate.
Thank God.
Mom, Dad...
I'm leaving.
Cathy.
May I ask for permission from your parents
for us to leave?
Let's just leave.
I'm sorry for ruining
your relationship with your parents.
It's okay.
I knew that it'll end up like this.
Let's go.
I'm sorry, Sir. I fell asleep.
It's okay. Have you cleaned the guest room?
I have.
Come in, Ti.
I'll take you to your room.
That'll be your room.
Let's go.
This is Hannah's and my room.
You can sit and relax there if you want.
Sorry if it's not comfortable.
This is more than enough for me. It's clean.
I'll leave you, then.
I'll put your things here.
If you need anything, just call me.
Thanks.
- Sir.
- Yes?
Your tea.
- I didn't ask for that.
- It's okay. It's my initiative.
Okay, then. Just put it there.
Okay.
Sir...
- Sorry.
- Yes?
The guest will stay here?
She will.
Sorry again. But the guest is a woman.
Does Mrs. Hannah know about this?
Here's the thing.
Let me tell you this to avoid any misunderstanding.
Her name's Mrs. Cathy.
She's Mrs. Hannah's best friend.
She's her doctor.
And she's also...
...my wife.
Sir!
It's not my birthday, you know.
There's no need for a prank.
No, I'm serious.
Oh, God!
Mrs. Hannah is sick.
How could you marry another woman?
Does she know about this?
This marriage is what she wished for.
It's impossible.
Which woman wants to be cheated on?
I'm your living example.
I once got cheated on.
My husband married another woman.
I wanted to hurt that other woman.
I never agreed to that.
Madame Doctor. I'm sorry.
I was talking about my husband, not you, seriously.
Okay, then. I'm going to go pray. Excuse me.
To ask for forgiveness.
- Sorry about that.
- It's okay. Mbok Ipah is not wrong.
Being a second wife is a catch-22 situation.
I can't defend myself.
I’m sure everyone will understand.
It's only a matter of time.
Actually, I came here to ask you.
Which is the direction of qibla?
It's over there.
You... I haven't prayed, too.
Oh dear.
I should've reminded you since I'm your Imam now.
Sorry.
- Do you want to pray together?
Operation Room
Thank God.
Your baby has been delivered safely to this world.
Oh God.
What about Hannah?
For now...
...she's in a coma.
Be a pious kid, okay, son?
Congrats.
What's his name?
Khaltan Maliki is his name.
Hannah gave him that name.
It's a good name.
I hope she can see her baby soon.
- Here, Ma'am?
- Yes.
- Sun rays.
- Let's go in.
- Peace be upon you.
- And upon you, too.
How is it? Good?
It's good. You did the cooking?
No. I did the ordering.
Malik, I'm sorry.
I should've prepared all this for...
Your husband?
Still...
Still hard to say it?
Well...
How can I say it? I honestly still can't believe
that this is our situation.
It still feels like a dream for me.
For me, too.
Do you want me to make you tea or coffee?
- Yes please. Black coffee.
- Okay.
Coffee.
Over there. The coffee's there.
- There.
- This? Okay.
The mug...
The mug. Over here.
Sorry. The mug's here.
Do you want sugar in it or...
No sugar.
- Two spoons of coffee.
- Okay.
Do I need to boil some water or...
- No. Just use hot water from the dispenser.
- Okay.
- Let me. It's okay.
- No. Let me.
Sorry. I forget the spoon.
Ti...
I think we should...
...start...
...familiarizing ourselves to...
How do I say it?
We should familiarize ourselves...
To be husband and wife?
Right.
It's still hard for you to say it.
Honestly, it's harder than when...
...I professed my love to you back then.
Can I drink that?
- You can.
- Thanks.
Be careful, it's hot.
I mean...
- Sorry, I forget to tell you.
- It's hot. It's okay.
It's okay.
Do you want us to share a room tonight or what?
Aren't you supposed to stay the night
at the hospital?
You're right. I...
- I need to go to the hospital.
- You better go to the hospital so you are calm.
Ti, sorry, I...
I didn't mean to...
It's okay. I totally get it.
Right now you don't need to think about me.
You have to put Hannah first.
- Just go. It's late.
- Okay.
I'll get ready.
I'm going to put the coffee here.
I was cleaning and I saw your husband's photos.
But the pictures aren't with you.
Sumi, why do you ask that?
You're not mad at me, aren't you? I'm sorry.
It's okay. I'm not mad.
She's his first wife.
Her name's Hannah.
She's in the hospital.
She's in a coma after delivering Althan to this world.
Does that mean you're the second wife?
But you're beautiful, nice, a doctor.
Why did you want to be a second wife?
Sumi!
I believe...
...that our soulmate is God's mystery.
And Allah must've prepared
the best destiny for me.
So I can only surrender to His will.
But do you love your husband?
Forgive me. I won't ask any questions again.
If I didn't love him...
...I wouldn't be here right now.
Sir.
Ti, the car is here.
Okay. I'm ready. I can leave right away.
I'm going to post it. The hottest babysitter group.
Great!
Oh, dear! So handsome.
Hey!
Who are you? How dare you touch the baby?
Have you washed your hands?
- Hey! I should be the one asking who you are.
- Sumi.
You're new here. I've worked here longer.
I took care of this baby's mother.
And I'm responsible for this baby.
I even ask his father to wash his hands first.
You ugly Sundanese!
Oh, God. I know you're old, but you're racist.
You can't be racist, you know!
Who's racist here? It's you!
You took selfies. You took your own pictures.
Your face won't change at all.
Old people won't understand
the difference between racist and narcissistic.
- What's going on?
- It's her fault.
It's hers. This babysister
didn't allow me to touch Mrs. Hannah's baby.
Sister? If you want to touch the baby,
you need to wash your hand. Am I right?
Mbok, she's right.
- Is Mrs. Hannah good?
- Pray for her.
For sure.
Sumi, this is Mbok Ipah.
- She has worked here for a long time.
- Yes, Sir.
Hear that?
I'm a senior here.
Seniority is outdated.
It's a thing of the past. How old are you?
Stop fighting. You're making so much noise.
Poor Althan.
- I'm late.
- Drive safe.
Today's seminar was long.
By the way, aren't you going to join us for dinner?
Sorry, but I can't.
I have to make a call in my room.
Who are you going to call?
I'm going to call the babysitter,
to check on my child.
- Babysitter?
- You get it.
The newlywed.
You can't stand being apart from your husband, can you?
What are you talking about?
- Okay, then. See you tonight, okay?
- Okay. Bye!
- Bye.
- We're leaving. Let's go.
Hey.
Malik?
What are you doing here?
You won't believe this.
I also have a meeting here.
- Okay. A coincidence?
- Yes.
- We happen to have meetings here.
- Yes. What a coincidence.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
See? You don't believe me.
No, I believe you.
But what about Althan?
He's home. He's calm with Sumi.
Are you busy tonight? Let's have dinner.
I see.
Are you here just to ask me
to have dinner with you?
Is that it?
No. I really had a meeting here.
You happened to be here, too. So, why not?
- Okay.
- So...
I'm going to wait in the lobby, okay?
But why should I wait in the lobby?
Since we're...
- Husband and wife?
- Husband and wife.
Is it still hard for you to say it?
Well...
So? Where should I wait?
It's up to you.
Let's go.
You look different.
Different...
...how?
Beautiful.
Thank you.
Look like who?
- Not similar like you.
- Really?
- Of course.
- His handsome.
How are you, big sister?
How are you?
I'm good.
How are Mom and Dad?
They're good.
Honey...
Get in if you don't feel well.
You'll get sick.
It's nice here.
I brought you medicine. Drink it.
Just put it there. I'll take it.
Okay.
Cathy?
It's Cathy, honey.
Is that my grandson?
Hello!
Call me Grandad. Or is it Grandpa?
Honey...
Cathy's here.
What's his name?
His name is...
...Althan.
Althan.
Mr. Malik, your wife needs to keep using the
extracorporeal membrane oxygenation machine.
Medically, she's still alive
with the help of the machine.
But there's nothing else we can do
until she recovers from her coma.
Be strong and be patient.
I know you've done your best for Hannah.
But if she's not out of this condition...
...it'll be a pity for her.
Oh dear. Sorry to keep you waiting this long.
- It's okay.
- Let's go.
What's wrong with you?
What do you think?
Are you asking me as your wife?
Or as a doctor?
Both.
As a wife...
...I will always support my husband's decision.
But as a doctor...
...medically, the only thing
that is keeping Hannah alive right now...
...is the machine.
Hey.
Honey.
It's okay.
Hey.
It's fine.
You don't need to force everything.
If you can't, don't do it.
It's okay.
Honey, I'm sorry if what I did is wrong.
I'm sorry.
I just don't want you to suffer any longer.
I bear witness that there is no deity
(none truly to be worshipped) but Allah...
...and I bear witness
that Muhammad is the messenger of Allah.
I bear witness that there is no deity
(none truly to be worshipped) but Allah...
...and I bear witness
that Muhammad is the messenger of Allah.
Hannah?
Honey?
Thank God.
God has shown His greatness.
Nothing is impossible for Him.
Come with me.
Hannah?
Na?
You're awake.
Hi, honey.
Thank God!
Why am I here?
Did you forget?
But you remember me, don't you?
Malik.
Hi, Han.
Who is this?
Honey, this is Cathy.
Cathy?
- She was...
- I'm...
...your doctor.
Because you’ve just woken up from your long coma,
you need to rest a lot.
Excuse me.
Cathy.
Why did you tell Hannah...
...that you're her doctor?
Well, I am.
I mean...
...I was going to say that...
...that you're my wife.
I talked to Dr. Mulia.
He said that...
...Hannah is having amnesia anterograde.
She can't remember what has just happened.
She can only remember information
or events that happened in the past.
That's why she can't remember who I am.
And why she forgot that...
...we're married.
I'll try to tell her.
Malik, don't.
For now...
...don't burden her mind too much.
Let's just wait...
...until she fully recovers.
What do you mean?
I doubt...
...that Hannah's decision to ask us to marry...
Maybe she didn't fully realize it.
I'm scared, Malik.
I'm scared that when she remembers everything...
...she can't accept that we're married.
But everything has happened. You're my wife now.
And I want you to still be there
for me and Althan.
Hey.
Nana, what are you doing?
- I'm going to check on Althan.
- He's... Stop it.
- You can't be tired. Don't move too much. Take rest.
- The baby's crying. That poor little thing.
- I want to see him.
- Let him be, honey. Titi's there to take care of him.
Titi's there already.
Cathy is your doctor, honey.
She was also our friend back in high school.
While you were in a coma,
she took care of Althan.
So all this time...
...she has been living here?
She has.
Sometimes she needs to stay the night
because Althan can't be left alone.
Don't think about it. Just rest.
Why is she willing to do that?
If you were in her position,
I'm sure you'd do the same thing.
Because you have a big heart.
Help me.
- Your legs...
- They're so weak.
Hi, Han.
Hi.
You still can't remember who I am?
Han...
...I'm Cathy.
Your friend from high school.
We often hung out together back in school.
Hang on. I think I still kept our photo
from back then.
Here. See? It was a long time ago.
It's okay.
Okay, I'm Cathy Meow.
Meow.
Cathy...
Cathy Meow.
Cathy... Cathy!
Cathy! Oh God!
Yes, I remember.
So sorry. Oh dear!
By the way, thanks a lot.
Malik has told me.
You took care of Althan while I was in a coma.
Han...
...I love Althan so much.
And if you allow me...
...I'd love to keep taking care of him.
For sure.
Hello, Mother. Your son is sleeping.
- He was sleepy after his bath.
- Honey. Come here.
Hello, Son.
There are always lies in polygamy.
Our boss asked us to lie, didn't he?
Right. But it's for the good of everybody.
Look at Mrs. Hannah, she's still unwell.
They'll tell her slowly. Be patient.
- You bad woman.
- Why are you hitting me?
You're the doctor's supporter. Team Cheater.
I'm not on anyone's team. I take no side.
Let it go. Let's just pray that they get along well
and be happy. Just look at them.
Hey. Cut your ear if they get along well.
I've had experiences with being cheated on.
It hurts so much here.
Look. She can smile on the outside,
but I bet she wants to choke her.
Don't choke me.
Sorry, Bi Ipah.
Don't think everyone is the same as you.
Look at them.
They're educated, smart, and able to think.
They have brains. Got it?
You think I have nothing inside my skull?
- It's not like that.
- You ugly Sundanese!
What? Ugly Sundanese what?
- What?
- Nothing.
You'll think of me as a narcissist,
talking about an ethnic group.
Not "narcist"...
I'm tired.
I'm also tired.
Do you know?
My biggest reason to stay alive is you.
I want to stay with you forever.
I want to be with you until I'm old.
Okay, honey. We're going to grow old together.
Honey...
Hello, Son.
Hi, honey.
It's me, your mom.
- What's wrong, kid? It's your mom.
- It's me, your mother.
Cath...
Honey, it's me, your mom.
What's wrong? Oh, honey. It's okay, kid.
It's okay.
It's okay, kid.
Cath, if you want to eat something
or if you crave anything...
...just ask Mbok Ipah, okay?
Okay, Han. Thank you.
I promised Titi to cook her my fish recipe.
It'll be so good.
You call her Titi?
I do.
I usually call people by their last syllable.
Just like I call you Nana. Am I right?
That's how I call my other friends, too.
Do you forget?
And what do you call him?
I...
...call him...
...Malik.
Malik, honey.
I thought you call him "Liklik".
So funny.
"Liklik".
Malik, I can't keep doing this.
I’m feeling more guilty every day.
It's time for us to be frank with her.
But what if she can't accept everything?
She'll accept it.
We're going to find a good time to talk to her.
Okay?
I'm fine.
- Morning, Mbok.
- Morning, Madame Doctor.
- Morning, Han.
- Morning.
- Morning, Ti.
- You don't need to. I'm fine.
You look pretty today. Fresh.
Did you sleep well last night?
Yeah. It rained last night, so I slept better.
Oh.
It's okay. I can do it myself.
Mbok, change the doctor's bed sheet.
I did it yesterday.
It's still clean anyway. No need to change it.
It's fine. Just change it.
To keep it clean all the time.
Nana is worried that you're not comfortable.
If you don't like it here,
she won't have her own private doctor.
Am I right?
Who is worried? Me or you?
If Titi's not here anymore...
...it'll be hard for you
to take care of me and Althan. Am I right?
No. It's okay. Carry on with your breakfast.
- But Althan's crying.
- He's my son.
Can't I take care of my own son? I'm her mother.
- Carry on.
- Sumi is there.
No. I want to take care of him myself.
Okay.
Hey, Malik...
...from now on,
you don't need to take care of me that much.
I'm fine. I can do everything myself. I'm healthy.
Okay?
Carry on with your breakfast.
Have a nice breakfast.
Althan, my son, come here. Why are you crying?
Come here.
Honey.
Ti?
Hey.
Why did you ask me to meet you here?
What's going on?
I want everything to end, Malik.
Yes, I also want everything to end.
I'm tired of pretending.
Let's talk to Hannah tomorrow.
That's not what I mean.
I want...
...Hannah to remember me as just her best friend.
So, I'm going to leave your life.
No.
No one's leaving.
Malik, you need to understand.
I love you.
But there's someone else
who is more deserving of your love.
I'm truly happy with you.
But it's more important for you
to make someone else happy.
I am your wife.
But there's someone else
who needs you more as a husband.
So, you don't need me?
- You regret this marriage?
- Malik, I will never regret our marriage.
Marrying you was what I have always wanted.
And I will remember you forever.
Forgive me.
But this is the best thing for all of us.
You can't just disappear from my life.
Because now I love two amazing women.
- Sumi? Mbok? What's going on?
- Ma'am.
Althan is crying inside.
But I don't dare to go inside.
But he's been crying for 30 minutes.
Help me. I'm scared.
- That's right. The baby can be possessed.
- Right.
Wait, no. Not possessed.
What are you talking about?
- Not possessed. Help us.
- Okay, okay.
Han?
Who's there?
It's me, Cathy.
Can I hold Althan for a while to calm him down?
Sumi, Mbok...
- Take care of Althan.
- Yes, Ma'am.
Be careful, Ma'am.
Althan needs to familiarize himself with me,
or else there'll be distance between us.
Han, there's no way that
there'll be distance between the two of you.
You're his birth mother.
But in reality, he's closer to you.
Let's sit.
Cathy...
You can take my husband.
But not my son.
- Han, what are you...
- Sit.
Sit down.
I didn't expect it, you know...
...for you to be that evil.
Diabolical.
- Cath... No.
- Let me explain.
I saw it myself.
I saw it clearly.
You and Malik.
In your room together.
Under this roof.
How could you?
- You betrayed your own best friend.
- Han...
- Hannah, please.
- You made my house dirty.
- Han, please.
- I should've known...
...that you can never stop loving him.
Listen to me.
You can take Malik away. Be my guest.
Be my guest, Cath.
I don't need a cheater like him.
But don't take my child away from me.
In the end...
...a traitor...
...will also meet a traitor.
- Ma'am.
- Ma'am, where are you going?
Mbok Ipah, Sumi, I'm leaving, okay?
Please take care of Hannah and Althan.
Oh, dear. I swear to God,
it wasn't me who told her.
I used to be Team Mrs. Hannah,
but I've realized that you've done no wrong.
I know, I believe that.
Thanks for helping me all this time.
It's okay.
Sir!
The doctor was just leaving,
bringing all of her things.
- Leaving?
- And Mrs. Hannah asked me to pack her clothes.
She said she was going to leave, too.
Oh, dear. Hannah...
That's why you shouldn't do polygamy.
- It's not good.
- Bibi!
- What are you saying?
- That's the reason for all of this!
- I know!
- What should we do?
- Poor Mrs. Hannah and the doctor.
- Sir!
Hannah, hey. What are you doing?
Leave me alone!
Hannah, wait.
Let me go!
- Hannah, listen to my explanation. Don't cry.
- Let me go!
I'm not crying because of you.
You're not worthy of my tears.
I'm crying because
my thoughts of who you are is all ruined...
...by the reality of who you actually are.
- Hey, hold on.
- Malik, let me go!
I'd like to show you something. Hold on.
Hold on.
Look at this.
Here.
Why was I there?
Forgive me for not explaining it to you earlier.
The marriage happened
because you gave us permission.
"In the name of Allah."
In the name of Allah.
"I will...
...marry your husband."
This marriage would never have happened
if Cathy and I didn't want to make you happy.
And why are you telling me just now?
Because you have amnesia.
Cathy didn't want to tell you too soon.
She wanted to wait for you to fully recover.
You were the one
who asked for this marriage, Hannah.
You were a witness. You gave us permission.
But now Cathy yields.
She doesn't want you
to ever remember this marriage.
She sacrificed herself for your happiness.
And now she just wants...
...me to be with you and Althan.
We got married for you.
And now Cathy chooses to part from me for you.
Forgive me, Cath.
I'm truly sorry.
You're an amazing woman, Cath.
Forgive me for having bad thoughts about you.
I'm so ungrateful. Forgive me.
I begged you...
...to marry Malik.
And now I'm here...
...to beg you once more...
...to come home.
To our home.
For your husband.
For me.
And our son, Althan.
Okay?
No woman wants to be a concubine.
Every woman dreams of being the first
and the only one loved by the man we love.
But sometimes destiny tells a different story.
What's important is how we deal with it.
How cute.
One, two...
Because happiness is not what we fantasize about.
But what we're living.
Clap your hands.
Ti.
Tell her.
Later. Or you tell her.
- You should tell her.
- Tell me what?
Cath?
What?
Cathy pregnant.
Seriously?
You're pregnant, Cath?
Thank God.
This is truly a miracle.
Althan will soon have a sibling.
Although it's not from my womb.
Congrats.
Thank you.
Althan will soon have a sibling.
And with Malik and Hannah,
I can feel the happiness of sharing.
We fill each other's lives, we learn from each other,
we give to one another, and we love each other.
And we can be happy in our own way.
Good morning, my loves.
I'm happy to see you.
So beautiful.
I bet you're happy to see me happy
with my husband.
With my son.
With my husband's concubine.
Hannah?
Oh, dear.
Hannah? Oh, dear!
Oh, dear! Ma'am!
- Hannah?
- Malik.
She's still unconscious.
But how is she doing?
The doctors have checked her and...
Let's hope she wakes up soon.
Malik.
Hannah?
Cath?
I'm thankful that God has given me time...
...to meet Althan.
To play with him.
And I'm certain...
...my husband...
...and my son...
...will be happy with you.
I'm ready for God to call me to His side.
Han...
Don't say that.
You have to remember...
...I will always be with you two.
I will always love you two.
And we...
We will always be together.
Hannah.
Although we live together
only for a short time...
...but you give me a lot of lessons.
About love...
...sincerity...
...and sacrifice.
And I will tell our son...
...that he's lucky
to have had an amazing mother.
Han...
...I'm a nobody compared to you.
And until the end of time...
...I can never replace you.
But I will try to fulfill your wish...
...to care for...
...and to love Malik and Althan...
...as much as you love...
...and care for them.