Hey! Wait!
Wait for me!
Who are these guys?
Come on, come on, come on!
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Don't overdo it.
Handbill says alive.
Morning, Zeke.
That's Mr. Tyler to any
bastard who pistol whips me.
Somebody
woke up feeling prickly.
Oh, I was just dreaming
about a beautiful girl
I know down at Saltillo.
Imagine my disappointment
to wake up and see you.
Anyone ever tell you you got
a face like a burned boot?
Now that other horse is gone,
there's no sign of
the third rider.
Well, I don't
suppose you unfortunate boys
have any clue who it is
you're robbing, do you?
We ain't bandits.
Clear as day, but I
don't see no badges.
'Cause we ain't lawmen.
Bounty hunters then.
And from the looks of it,
some of the worst
I've ever seen.
That's mighty bold
coming from a man
on the ground
looking up, friend.
He prefers Mr. Tyler.
Oh, I'll be sure to
have them carve that
in the tree they're probably
gonna hang you from.
Neither one of you know, huh?
I am astonished.
Some bounty hunters,
you two can't tell
the difference between
a skunk and a house cat.
Dutch, I got the feeling
he thinks we're
missing something.
Yeah, I'm picking up on that.
Hey, why don't you quit beating
the devil around the stump
and just fill us in
on your little secret?
Information isn't free.
Neither are you.
So we understand each other.
We do.
And you're a man of your word?
I am.
You won't go back on it, now?
Never do.
Alright, here it is.
I see the both of you
just standing there
grinning at me when not
30 paces to your backside,
there's the real prize.
Well?
Well what?
You shot a hole clean
through his face.
I can't make him out at all.
You couldn't have aimed lower?
Oh, well excuse me.
It didn't seem
important at the time
when he was trying to kill me.
Who is that?
Gentlemen, allow
me to introduce you
to the dearly departed
Benicio Morales.
That's Moonshine Morales?
Lizard's Tooth himself.
What'd he say?
He says that's Benicio Morales.
This is Benny the Stallion?
How do we know you're not lying?
You know the stories?
Anyone wearing a six
gun knows about Morales.
Then you probably heard the one
about the Quechan natives
who inked a little scorpion
just above his heart?
Providing you didn't
blow a hole in it.
Hey, take a look at his chest.
He got a scorpion alright.
If this here's Morales,
who's that other guy?
Useless.
Well, I be damned.
I outgunned the Rio
Rattlesnake himself.
Did you hear that, Waco?
We were all riding
pretty quick there.
You coulda hit him by accident.
Oh, you horse's ass.
That was marksmanship
and you know it.
And they'll sings of your glory
all throughout the heartland.
Now, if you two
would just untie me,
I'll take one of them
horses and skedaddle.
Now, why on God's green
earth would we do that?
Because you said you would.
Waco, did you ever hear
me make a deal like that?
Nope.
But you said you was
a man of your word.
I am, but it's not my fault
if you infer
something incorrectly.
You've got
to be kidding me.
That body over there
has gotta be worth
five times what I
am alive or dead
in any county west
of the Mississippi.
That's true.
It is.
And you are in hostile
border country.
We are.
-Yes we are.
-So?
Any bounty hunter with a lick
of sense north of his ears
knows that the move here
is to take that body
and hightail it to the
nearest town sheriff.
I'm only gonna slow you down.
Your chances of being
robbed and killed out here
and me escaping is
not worth the price
on my meager little handbill.
Yeah.
You know, that, that
does sound smart.
So you'll let me go?
Nope.
Not a chance.
Ha. I figured it out.
Oh, we're in for it now.
Well, I recognize the name
but my head's a bit
scrambled from earlier.
You's the Waco Kid, ain't you?
Bare knuckle boxing champion?
Yeah, I am.
You are famous!
Oh!
My daddy took me to one
of your title fights
when I was just a boy.
Oh yeah? Which one?
The one you lost.
He don't have to talk when
we turn him in, does he?
Well isn't this just
a day for celebrities?
We got a dead one and another
whose career's just as dead.
Say, what exploits
was you known for
when you were younger, Dutch?
Kind that daddies don't
bring their boys to see.
You know, he's right though.
We can't camp out
here in the wide open.
Not with a body this valuable.
What was that town we
passed a while back?
Oro, Oro Lindo, Beautiful Gold.
We keep riding, we can
be there by nightfall.
What do you think?
Boom town with a name like that?
Sounds like a blast.
Somebody forgot to put
the boom in boom town.
More like doom town.
Looks like the sheriff's
office up ahead.
Evening gentlemen.
What can I do for you?
You the sheriff?
Afraid not. Deputy Elijah Stone.
Well, Deputy Stone,
would you be so kind
as to round up the sheriff?
We've got some turkeys to trade.
Zeke Tyler. You back so soon?
Well, what can I say?
It's hard to keep an
angel outta paradise.
How's your sister, Eli?
She can still drink your
sorry carcass under the table.
Well you tell her I'm sorry.
The doctor promised it would
clear up in a few weeks.
Well, I can see you
two are acquainted.
Yeah, old Zeke here,
he's been staying in town
the last season or so.
Well it looks like
he ventured out
and got himself into
some trouble again.
He's been a wanted man
a whole lot longer
than a season.
Mister, we don't have
bounty hunters around here.
Some folks just like
to be left alone.
Yeah, well you do tonight.
Charges are listed.
Whoa, hold on, one of
these is handwritten.
We couldn't find a law office
between hell and this town,
but I think you'll
recognize the name.
Trying to tell me
that that stiff there
is really Benicio Morales?
Pale Rider himself.
Tattoo and all.
Old Bullwhip Ben. I'm impressed.
Still in all, you're all gonna
have to wait 'til tomorrow.
Sheriff don't pay out except
from sun up to sun down.
Don't suppose he'd
make an exception here?
This one's been baking
in the sun all day
and this one's been running
our patience down so far,
he's in debt for it.
Well, you're just gonna have to
endure their company
until tomorrow.
But you don't have to worry
about losing your catch.
This here's a nice,
safe, sleepy little town.
If it's so safe, what was that?
Bullfrogs.
Uh-huh?
Now I don't suppose
you could recommend
a place for us to
sleep for the evening
that ain't got no bullfrogs?
Everything this
side of the border's
closed up for the night.
But, on the south side of
town, cantina's still open.
You boys should
head on down there,
soak up some of the local
flavor until morning.
Go, got it, got it, yeah!
Two whiskeys, please.
Gracias.
Hey, you wouldn't have a place
we could stay for the
evening, would you?
I have a room upstairs.
That'll do great. Gracias.
Hello, darling.
What's a tiger lily like you
doing in a cow trough like this?
Oh, don't mind the ropes.
I was just practicing
my career as a escapist.
Wouldn't mind tying you up.
They say I'm a real artist.
Sorry ma'am.
If his brains were dynamite,
he wouldn't have enough
to blow his nose.
Certainly seems
explosive either way.
Oh, now who's
feeling prickly, huh?
Can a condemned man have
a few simple pleasures?
Which whiskey's mine?
The one you pay for.
You're making a
bounty off of me.
And until we do,
I'm afraid we can't
afford any more drinks.
Dos whiskeys, senorita!
"Dos whiskeys, senorita!"
Boom, one, two, three.
He says, meet me
outside the mine,
I said, you keep
running your mouth.
He didn't think
I would go there.
He had it
coming, he had it coming.
Hola, amigos.
Say, I don't suppose any
of you boys is boxers, huh?
Boxeo? El luchador?
Si, we can box.
Are you asking us to fight you?
I don't think you
would win, my friend.
No, I was just having a
little private conversation
with my famous friends
over there, Waco,
that's the Waco Kid by the way,
for those who are wondering,
and he was just telling me
how fond he was
of Mexican women,
so if any of you
have mothers or wives
or sisters or daughters there,
you better watch out, this...
Dios mio, hey, it is him.
Please, Mr. Waco, I love to box,
could you show us
some of your moves?
I'm sorry, kid, my
brawling days are over.
Please, just, just
one quick round?
Like a warmup? For me,
it would be my honor.
It's not gonna
happen, kid, sorry.
We're exhausted, we're
heading up to our room.
Let's go, Waco.
His honor.
Nothing serious.
Just a little warmup.
Exactly, yes, just a warmup.
A warmup with a champ!
A little slap box.
Yeah, okay, sure, sure.
Don't overdo it.
Alright, let's
see what you got, kid.
Oh, what in the hell is this?
What?
Now. Don't you go nowhere.
I wouldn't dream of it.
Evening, ma'am, pardon
the interruption.
I think it might be best
if we move you to another table.
Oh. Is there going
to be an exhibition?
I guess you could call it that,
but sometimes these
things get a little rowdy.
Understood.
So, what is that you're reading?
"Dracula". Bram Stoker.
Ah.
Yeah, I just finished
that one myself
about a month and a half ago.
Really? How'd you like it?
I quite enjoyed it.
I guess my favorite part was-
Oh no, please! I
only just started.
I understand.
My name's Dutch Langford.
Rosemary O'Rourke.
Pleasure to meet you, ma'am.
Likewise.
What brings you to Oro
Lindo, Mr. Langford?
My partner and I are
traveling through,
we're doing a little
bounty hunting.
Ah, exciting.
Are you on the hunt?
Not at the moment, no.
In fact, we got us a nice little
high dollar bounty
earlier today.
I see.
And that high dollar bounty
wouldn't be the man making it
for the door right
now, would it?
Oh no, he's dead. He's
tied up on the horses.
No, that other idiot is Zeke...
Hey. Waco, get him!
Huh?
Okay.
Excuse me, ma'am.
Get back here!
Whoa, hey!
Come on!
You got this, you got this!
Are you done now?
-Get your hands!
-Calm down.
No, I'm not gonna calm down,
now get me out of this chair!
Get me out of this chair.
-You got this, you got this!
-Come on!
-Get me out of this chair,
-Calm down!
Get me out of this chair!
Dutch, outside.
Oh, sh-
Shut up! Waco!
Hold on!
Get back here! Where
are you going with that?
My dead body.
Let go of it.
Waco, can you help me over here?
Get out!
Get outta here!
Sheriff's ready to
see you boys now.
Body inside yours too?
Nope.
He's useless.
I don't think he likes you.
Think they'll refund our room?
Not a chance.
Now, you ready?
-Yep.
-Oh.
Be careful!
Really? Waco?
So, who's the body
stinking up my porch?
Benicio Morales.
The Slim Reaper?
The Sideways Scorpion.
He preferred The Tabasco Knife.
And I'm the man that killed him.
Sure did.
Well unfortunately boys,
I can't pay out a bounty
that size in one day.
You boys are gonna have
to wait around a while
until I can scrounge
up enough cash.
I thought this was a gold town.
So, how long do you
expect that to be?
We weren't planning
on staying long.
That will be when
Thaddeus Vincent
decides to make
his next deposit.
Hello, gentlemen.
Sheriff Pearlwood, I
do hate to intrude,
but I'm afraid I must insist.
I have had quite a time
trying to get an
audience with you
and the matter that I
need to discuss is urgent.
Well, be that as it may,
you're gonna have
to wait your turn.
See, I'm having a conversation
with these fine gentlemen.
-Sheriff, I understand-
-Now, please,
no need to send her
away on our account.
Our business here is done.
Anyway, hey Deputy,
why don't you,
why don't you show us
over to the undertaker?
I'd love to
show you to the undertaker.
Ma'am.
Good luck.
Thank you.
It appears you have an
opening in your schedule.
So there is.
As I mentioned in my letters,
my name is Rosemary O'Rourke.
Mhmm.
I work in close connection
with an orphanage in Boston
that has sent hundreds
of children out West
on the Orphan Trains, and
my job is to follow up
on the children's wellbeing,
make sure they're in
loving, good homes
with thoughtful families-
Yeah, I've read your letters.
Superb.
Then you know that there are
several Orphan Train children
that I have not
been able to locate
despite my considerable effort.
It's a large county.
I've traversed much of it.
With a lot of farms.
I've been to all of them.
Those children did
not leave Oro Lindo.
This is a border town,
people go missing all the time.
Yes, but these are
children, Sheriff.
Children have gone
missing. And that matters.
Dismissal of the subject is
most out of the question.
Now, it would be very helpful
if you could provide
me some sort of list
of local citizens or shop owners
that may have taken someone in.
I assume your benefactor,
Mr. Thaddeus Vincent
will be on that list as well.
Sure, Miss.
We can get you a list.
But it'll take us a day or so.
In a day or so.
Much obliged.
Thank you, gentlemen.
You've done it this time.
Well, you know, I'm
impressed as hell
that Thaddeus can shave an
ape and teach it to talk.
What other tricks do
you know, monkey boy?
Can't wait to squash you.
You better buy me flowers first.
Besides, you know
you can't touch me
unless the master lets
you off the leash.
Move.
All the families in this town,
we understand the
way things work.
We are not blind whose name
is written on the wood beams
every time a new
building goes up.
I wouldn't have a home
if not for the loans
that you provided.
And I am more than happy
to pay for them back.
My brother Caleb as well.
He works in your
mines every day.
He doesn't complain, he
doesn't make trouble.
But I do see his
pain every morning
and I watch him drag
himself home every night.
I have no illusions for
charity in this world.
My brother doesn't
know I'm here.
But I come to say that
we are good people
who want to see a
real step forward
for all our hard work.
Not a step back.
A small leniency on
the interest, even.
As a self-made man, I'm
sure you understand that.
My, my, my.
Miss Salazar, that is a
display of passion and rhetoric
I've not seen from a
politician in years.
And believe me, they
come by the wagon load
to this humble little
country house of mine.
That was quite the performance.
Mr. Vincent, I did not
came here to perform.
Only speak the truth.
Yes, of course.
Everyone endeavors
to speak the truth.
But the truth is
like anything else
between heaven and hell.
It is entirely
subject to the whims
of those who are in
possession of it.
Truth, Miss Salazar,
is like a tool
to get what one wants.
To fire at someone.
Mr. Vincent, there's
nothing I'm asking for here
that will deprive you.
Ah, wait,
wait, wait, wait, wait.
There it is.
You've now gone from
the realm of your truth
into the realm of my truth.
Your truth, Miss Salazar,
is based upon what you see,
what your people see.
And that is not what I see.
You see a cow and
know it to be a meal.
I see a cow and know
it to precede a herd.
You see a hut and
know it to be a home,
I see a hut and know it to
precede a thousand just like it.
Your people saw a
hole in the ground
and said, nay, thou
shalt not go there
because there be demons.
But not I.
Because I knew what God
left in there for me.
Gold.
We are not alike and
I do not understand.
So, the subject of
your half-brother.
Your half-brother is a
drinker and a rabble rouser,
you know, maybe perhaps
if he were to spend
a little less of
his leisure time
working on his right hook,
he would be less desperate.
But.
I can see that he is a
special prize to you.
I could treat him as one
of my special prizes.
Say my prize horse.
Do you know what I do
to them, Miss Salazar,
when they no longer
perform for me?
I put a bullet in their head.
I put them out of their misery.
And I replace them with
something that benefits me.
Am I clear?
There'll be no change
to your payment
schedule, Miss Salazar.
I do not care one continental
for your disposition.
You and your people
will pay accordingly.
Be blessed on the way out.
Hoo! That is one
feisty chili pepper.
Ah, ah, ah, do not sit
in the furniture, Zeke.
How did everything go?
Oh, it, you know, it
went great.
Well, that's great.
Send in Benicio.
Yeah, about that.
Benicio is, he's, he's, he's-
Is he indisposed?
He's presupposed, that's
the word I was looking for.
And well, see,
complications arose
and things being
what they are, he's-
Dead as a door nail,
collecting flies
in a wooden shed
behind the undertaker's
shop, you desert canary.
You nailed it.
Is that what you call real
great, you incompetent fool?
I paid a small fortune
for that killer.
I'm forced to endure
37 asinine nicknames
anytime somebody
whispers about him and-
Well, there's more than that.
And lo and behold,
lo and behold,
not even a legend
can survive riding
with the likes of you, Zeke!
Please.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
Not the face!
How many teeth, boss?
No, no, no, wait a
minute. Wait a minute.
Well, now, wait, wait!
We was bush whacked
by bounty hunters.
They popped off a
lucky shot on Morales.
But I wasn't lying before.
Well, that was afterwards.
See, we did the job
we were sent to do.
We got the deed.
The farmer's not gonna
be a problem anymore,
I promise you that.
The farmer's dead?
That's right.
I did it myself.
Popped him right there.
I dropped his ass
down a well! Oh.
The land is yours to dig, boss,
but I would not drink the water.
That was my favorite
uncle growing up.
My condolences.
But you didn't tell
us that part before.
He should've sold me
that land years ago.
Family is only a title of import
as long as you give
it leave to be.
Zeke, you remember that.
I always said that.
I've always said that.
Where's the deed?
Well...
It's a cute story.
You're gonna laugh.
It's in my saddlebags
and the bounty
hunters have those.
But if you send the
bearded lady and me,
we'll take care of
it, lickety split.
No, not right now.
But I want you to
keep an eye on 'em.
We'll do it when
the time is right.
Send in the other boys when
you're on your way out.
And Zeke? Do better.
I'm trying my damnedest, sir.
Can I have my gun
back, please?
Well, that's just being
rude and spiteful.
I'm gonna have to pick those up.
Ammunition is
expensive these days
and you're just being careless,
what if the boss steps on 'em?
That's, alright.
Hey, hey, hey, hey!
What you reading there, boss?
Love letters from a
concerned citizen.
Oh, there's
this girl in Abilene,
she used to write to me twice-
Nope. Never heard of them.
Oh. I see.
The cobbler and the blacksmith
both told me you adopted.
I truly hoped that I'd
find these children here.
Well sure, I adopted.
Had great success
with the Orphan Train.
Two little boys
and a little girl,
raised right here in this shop.
Poor things, barely knew
their folks back East
before the cough took 'em.
I wasn't ready to
be no daddy, though,
I'll tell you that.
They called me
Gabe, same as any.
I raised them right, though.
They're good kids, all of them.
That's wonderful to hear.
Are they around?
They haven't been
around for years.
Around here, we tend to
bring them up pretty quick
and they let out the second
they feel like
they're old enough to.
Like I said, I'm no daddy.
I couldn't have kept the shop
afloat without 'em, though.
'Cause Lord knows Mr. Vincent's
got us all up to our
damn ears in debt.
The girl.
Her name wasn't Violet was it?
No, no, her name was Sarah.
I see.
Well, I'd still love to record
all their names and
ages if you don't mind.
You mentioned Mr.
Thaddeus Vincent.
I've heard his name mentioned
multiple times, today alone.
And I have found it quite common
for a person of means to
adopt quite frequently.
Have you ever seen Mr. Vincent
or one of his representatives
at the train station
when the orphans arrive?
Oh yeah, they're out
there every time.
You know what, ma'am?
I must be mistaken.
I am old, my memory
does slip often.
I just don't think I
can help you today.
-Come on, let's go.
-Alright,
let's get outta here.
She's over there!
Hey, I'm trying!
Get my hat, put it on my head.
It's heavy, it's heavy!
I know it's heavy,
you're heavy too.
I will cut you in half!
Get off me, get off me!
Get outta here.
He does that to me too.
Oh! Oh!
Oh my Lord, I am so sorry.
Are you okay?
Be as sorry as you like, Miss.
You'll never be as
sorry as a mining man.
-Here, let me help you.
-I don't believe I ever saw
a nugget like you
in this town before.
What's a town like you
doing in a woman like this?
Really, sir, the
day is far too young
to be in such a state, do
not lean upon this man.
What state?
This is the state
of Thaddeus Vincent.
Where men are things
to be leaned upon,
he knows it as well as I do.
And you, you can lean on me
anytime you like.
I'm real hands, handy.
How about you hold onto these?
Oh! Ah!
Why don't you put that
toothpick away, son,
before somebody gets hurt?
You wanna remove your hand?
Don't overdo it.
What?
Thanks.
Lookie what I found.
Get her, Concho.
Not to me! Whoa!
Oh, oh God!
Come on.
Night night.
-Hey.
-Whoa.
Hold it right there, son.
You don't want this.
Yeah, that was a
fine scrap and all.
But you skin leather,
becomes something
totally different.
It's not a fight
you wake up from.
You ain't that fast, old man!
Well.
That was quite the fandango.
Well, good afternoon,
Miss O'Rourke.
Dutch, Waco.
-Ma'am.
-Lovely to see you both.
How are you enjoying your stay?
Fair enough, I reckon.
Although I am beginning
to notice a pattern.
Yeah, every time she's
around, I get hit in the face.
That wasn't what I
was referring to.
Well, seems you gave quite
a bit more than you got.
First rule of a fight.
Indeed.
I have worked up an appetite.
What do you boys say to
joining me for a bite?
Southways a bit.
I don't care too much
for the hospitality
on this side of town.
Oh, here, let me.
I feel the manners improving
around us already. Ma'am?
You should start a charm school.
So, how do you do
that? You just?
-You just, yeah.
-It's cool.
Roy.
These men,
these boys got themselves
something to report.
It's a street fight, Eli.
That ain't what they say.
So you want me to take testimony
of a man who loses a fight
yet claims otherwise?
I do that, I'm gonna
have to take testimony
of every pair of
hands in this town.
We have ourselves a duty to act.
Don't you?
Pearl. I am so glad you're here.
I would like to report a crime.
Pearlwood.
Right.
More importantly, there's
been a vicious attack
on men in my employ.
Initiated with their
backs turned, no less.
The cowardice of some men,
it never ceases to sadden me.
I trust, Pearl, Sheriff, that
you will treat this crime
with the severity and
sentencing that it deserves.
I would like to introduce you
to my daughter,
adopted daughter.
Lizzie, come child.
It's okay, take my hand. Good.
We need to uphold the
laws in this town,
if for no other reason,
do it for the children.
I'm glad to see that you're
taking justice so seriously.
I've taken the liberty
of forming you a posse.
Starting with myself.
You're welcome.
I'll order us something.
You boys grab us a table.
Well boys, deal me in.
Better yet, pass me
the California Bible
and let me have a shuffle.
Have you ever heard
of Three-card Monte?
Another time, Waco.
We got grub coming.
Well, they had stew,
stew, and stew.
I didn't know what you prefer
so I went with the stew.
Hope that's alright.
I guess it'll just have
to stew.
So, Miss O'Rourke-
Oh. Rosemary is just fine.
Rosemary, you know what
Waco and I are doing here
but we never had the
chance to ask you.
Care to share?
Not to pile on, but I'm
quite curious myself.
Well, have you ever heard
of the Orphan Trains?
-Mhmm.
-Sure have.
I've heard 'em
called Mercy Trains.
Always wondered if
that was strictly true.
Well, it mostly is.
However, I have recently
found the records lacking
as to the wellbeing
of those children
once they're adopted
off the trains.
So I have taken it upon
myself to follow up,
make sure they're
properly cared for.
My sister and I,
we were sent out West
in an Orphan Train.
So I know firsthand just how
rough of a life that can be.
And therefore I am doing my best
to prevent other children
from having rough lives as well.
Yeah, well, as
heavy as that seems
that's a mighty
fine cross to bear.
So, what about your sister?
Does she work with you?
I am sure she would.
So, are there children
from the Orphan Train
here in Oro Lindo?
And have you found
them? Are they okay?
As it turns out,
there is suspiciously
little information
I can find regarding
their whereabouts.
The sheriff and the deputy
are about as useful as
a couple of songbirds
in an orchestra.
Yeah, we've got a
similar opinion.
Hmm.
My only lead is the
troubling encounter
I had with the shopkeeper.
He was very forthcoming,
right up until
Thaddeus Vincent's men
made their appearance.
So this Vincent character,
you think he has something to do
with these children missing?
His name keeps popping up
in all the worst places.
I am not sure,
but I have decided
I am not leaving
until I find them.
I apologize for intruding.
But I know where
the children are.
What? You do?
Who are you?
Oh, I'm sorry, that
was a little rude.
What I mean is,
what is your name?
My name is Lita Salazar.
I live in town with
my brother Caleb.
He works in Mr.
Vincent's gold mines.
So there is gold in this town.
Hardly.
The town itself never sees it.
The gold is mined by its people,
but it stays hoarded
with Senor Vincent.
That and half of the towns debt.
And the children?
The mines.
That's where the children are.
What? That can't be.
It's true.
Most people in town don't know.
Mr. Vincent tries
to keep it a secret.
But my brother
Caleb has seen it.
Caleb!
Oh, Senor Waco! So
good to see you.
My spine is crooked.
Yeah, I think I
left a tooth or two
on the floorboards over here.
Very fun, ah, we should
go another round.
Easy. Only the
first round's free.
Ay.
Caleb, it's
time to be serious.
We're talking about Mr. Vincent.
What do they wanna know?
Is it true that he has
children working in the mines?
It is.
I've seen them with my own eyes.
Only certain workers, those
of us who go in the deepest,
have seen them.
Mr. Vincent uses the children
to get into the crevices
and other places that myself
and the other adults
can't fit into.
We try to make it as easy
as we can for them in there.
Sometimes we even
squeeze ourselves down
to keep them from
doing anything.
But it's dangerous and
we're watched closely.
Sometimes his men come
down with us and, well,
when that happens,
sometimes the children
don't always come back out.
And you've never done
anything to stop him?
It's not that easy.
It must be!
I'm sure you've
heard the expression
don't bite the hand
that feeds you.
Well, I doubt that
applies to evil hands.
Something must be done.
No offense, senorita,
but that's easy to say
as someone who
does not live here.
My brother is right, his
name is in everything.
He owns the land. He
owns our livelihoods.
He owns the law.
Anyone who stands up to
Vincent ends up dead.
But you are right too.
I am tired of just surviving.
If I am going to live, it
has to be for something.
We have to stop Vincent.
Win or lose, we have to try.
I've known bad men all my life.
I've rode with them and
I've chased them down.
But one thing I
know for certain,
a bad man that's got away
with something for so long
ain't gonna stop.
It's gonna come down to a fight
and when it does,
you got Waco and me.
Damn right.
Ain't nothing worth
getting up for
like putting bruises on a bully.
I'm in.
A lot of people are scared.
But if anyone can
lift this town up,
it's Lita and I'm with her.
Well.
Then we have our team.
And we start by
rescuing those children.
That's him. Mr. Vincent.
Looks like a snake on stilts.
That's Lizzie.
She's one of the
missing children.
Ooh, that vulture!
Better.
Miss O'Rourke, I presume.
Thaddeus Vincent.
Charmed to meet you.
Mr. Vincent.
Normally I'd say pleased to
make your acquaintance but-
Yes, of course you are.
My acquaintance
pleases everyone.
Dutch, are you pleased?
Nope.
I can assure you, gentlemen,
that you will not be a jesting
mood when we are through.
I shall address you last.
But first, I came
all the way down here
to allay the lady's fears.
I would like to present
to you my daughter,
whom I love as if she
were my own blood.
Lizzie, come say hi
to Miss O'Rourke.
Shake her hand like a lady.
Hello.
Hi, Lizzie.
It is very nice to meet you.
Are you quite happy in
your home with Mr. Vincent?
Her father.
And yes she is.
She has everything that
she could want or need.
I was speaking to her.
Lizzie, when you arrived
at that train station,
you were with other
children, right?
-Yes, but-
-Oh, my dear Miss O'Rourke,
I'm sure you do
not mean to offend,
but you are dealing with
things you do not understand.
It is quite callous of you
to bring up the children
in front of my sweet daughter.
I try to shield her from having
to think about such things.
However, since the
subject has been broached,
I can see that you will not be
satisfied until it is aired.
The children, they were naughty.
Thieves. Runaways.
Isn't that right, Lizzie?
Go ahead and tell them.
Tell them about how
they woke you up
in the middle of the night.
About how they were going
to steal from your father,
catch a train to Wichita.
About how they wanted
you to go with them,
but you would never dream
of doing such a thing.
It's a shame to see them fall
into infantile selfishness.
But, kids these days.
What are you gonna do?
It's so hard to find a good one.
Now that you know the
truth, Miss O'Rourke,
I trust that we will never
have to speak of this again.
You can see how it
hurts my daughter so,
and that breaks my heart.
She's been through
so much already.
Wouldn't you agree?
Good.
I am so disappointed in you two.
I thought you were more
than these criminals.
But I can see that I was wrong
and that is something
I do not say often.
So, I'm going to
purchase this rat hole.
It'll cost me what
I have in my pocket.
Maybe a little less, look at me.
Look at me.
I will have you dismantle this
place with your bare hands
until there's nothing
left but rock and rubble.
And when your friends
and family see it,
they will know that
you destroyed
a part of their community
because of your selfishness.
Old chums.
Last and most certainly least,
you ride into my town
like barbarians of old
to harry a civilized world.
Barbarians. I like that.
It is befitting.
What was that?
Live by the sword, die by the
sword? I believe that's it.
It's time to put your
metal where your mouth is.
Step outside. Settle this.
Like men.
Shall we?
Don't come out, they'll shoot!
Come on.
Sheriff, ready to do your job.
We have to go after them.
We will.
We need to take that
kid's warning serious.
Waco, you wanna go take a look
and see how many partygoers
we need to plan for?
He is an absolute monster.
And he means every word.
If we get out of this,
we need to get you
out of this town.
I am not leaving.
Don't look good.
He's out there with the
sheriff, that snake deputy,
and a whole mess of men.
They're armed to the teeth
and they're ready to shoot.
Maybe they would listen to me,
maybe I could reason with them.
You got a way with words
but he wouldn't listen
even if your tongue
was made of pure silver.
He's right.
Vincent only speaks
one language.
Gold.
We could go out fighting.
We have the advantage
being in here.
We can start shooting
and see what happens.
Slow down, Poncho.
Absolutely not.
That would risk Lizzie being
caught in the crossfire.
Come on out, boys!
If gold is all he understands,
I say we go speak his language.
Okay.
I think I like where
you're going with this.
-You with me?
-'Til the end.
What are you doing?
If we walk out
there wearing irons,
we'd be dead on the doorstep.
This is the only way
we're gonna get close.
To the what?
Bargain.
You ready?
Let's do it.
Wait, if I'm dying, I'm
going out an honest man.
Oh, shit,
Waco.
Alright, let's not go
out there too pretty.
Rub some dirt on your face
and let me do the talking.
Alright, we're coming out.
We ain't wearing guns.
Alright.
We just wanna talk.
Well, come talk.
Now, Sheriff, you used
to be a gunfighter.
Used to be.
You still fast?
One way to find out.
Alright, listen, we're
gonna come closer.
What I got to say
is for your ears
and for Mr. Vincent.
Come slow.
But we're in your care.
On your honor, as a lawman,
and a fellow gunfighter.
Shoot 'em.
They're unarmed.
Sheriff.
They're unarmed, Mr. Vincent.
Alright, that's
far enough, boys.
Keep them hands up.
Speak your piece.
I don't think we have
to argue our innocence.
Any doubts on that front,
our boots would be
kissing the sky already.
So for now, we'd just
like to make a deal
with Mr. Vincent.
And why would I
wanna waste my breath
with you gone goslings?
You know who my partner is?
I do not.
I do.
I'll bet you do.
It's the Waco Kid.
Bare knuckle boxer.
Old champion.
I'm not that old.
Too old. One foot in the grave.
I only need one foot
to dance around you in
the ring, big fella.
Looked up to you 'til you lost.
Got no respect for losers.
You gonna write a
man off for one loss
after a career of wins?
You're dumber than you look.
And you look like you
got a knife so dull
you couldn't slice
through hot butter.
Ah, ah.
Alright, somebody
want to please explain
the value of an old,
broken down boxer
to Thaddeus Vincent, hmm?
You may not have heard of him
from behind your ivory walls,
but I'd bet high
that all these men
and all the men in your
surrounding counties
know who he is.
Sheriff?
Yeah, I knew him on sight.
I saw him fight a while back.
Yeah, he's got
something special.
Well, shit. I might blush.
So you announce a prize fight,
come back of the Waco kid.
I promise you,
you'll see more money
and more people flowing
through this town in one day
than you've seen in years.
Hmm.
And the opponent?
The big guy seems up for it.
He is big.
Long way to the ground.
He'll kill you.
I've heard that a lot.
So if I agree, what's
your end of the bargain?
Now, first off, we walk away
and you leave all these
folks in this cantina alone.
Me and Waco started this fight.
We'll finish it.
And?
And if Waco wins, you pay
us the Morales bounty.
No matter what happens, you
keep all the fight money,
you never see us again.
What's to keep you
from rigging it?
Ah, Waco's too bullheaded
to throw a fight.
By the look in his eyes,
he knows he'll never
get this chance again.
I don't know how to take that.
It's okay.
What of Miss O'Rourke and
her concerns for my...
My family?
It's not our problem.
We just came here
to make a buck.
You want this town?
It's all yours.
We just want what we're owed.
Alright. What's your
answer, Mr. Vincent?
Well, I do love money.
Yes you do.
Let's have ourselves a prize
fight, what do you guys say?
-Yeah!
It would be a very bad idea
to double cross me, boys.
We'll keep that in mind.
Hm.
Kill him in the ring.
My pleasure.
That's my boy.
Well hello there, mastermind,
how's the plan going?
Good. I suppose.
That is to say we have one.
But...
I don't know.
I'm sure you and Dutch
have had many an adventure
where death was on the
line, but this is my first,
and I have to admit,
I'm quite nervous.
Nervous is a good thing.
It means you're smart enough
to worry about staying alive.
Are you nervous?
Every time. You
just get used to it.
If I'm being honest, I'm
most worried about you.
Me? Why me?
Well, to hear Dutch
and Lita talk in there,
there's no gate you
wouldn't storm, but,
you'll be all alone
to fight that monster.
I got Caleb in my corner.
You know what I mean.
To be honest, I'm
never alone in there.
Maybe my first fight as a kid,
but after I lost to that
guy, he was with me up here.
And then the next fighter
joined, then the next.
Win or lose, they all tell
me how to beat the next guy.
I imagine it gets
pretty crowded in there.
You can't never have
enough good ideas
going around in your head
when those fists
start to flying.
Ma'am, is this
fella bothering you?
Oh, no more than usual.
Did I miss anything?
Ah, not really, they're
just discussing the details.
Ah, I'd better go play referee.
-Gentlemen.
-Ma'am.
Is it a good plan?
I would say it's south of good,
but it's north of dying.
Better than most, I guess.
But I like our chances.
Ever the gambler.
I just trusted my gut.
That's what led me to you.
No, actually a
bulletin for a hot meal
is what led you to me.
I was hungry, but
I trusted my gut.
You know, if it goes to hell
for either of us tomorrow,
I'd be proud to say I bit the
ground doing the right thing.
Well, here's to trusting our gut
and staying above snakes.
Amen. Alright, pick a card.
Come on down! Come on down.
The prize fight of the
year is happening today!
The one champion of this
territory, the Waco Kid
is gonna make his triumphant
return to the ring!
And his opponent, woo!
That's the unbeatable,
unstoppable,
and yet undefeated
king of the ring,
our very own Killer
Connor Murphy!
Get back here, you scram!
Gah! Third time today!
Well, he definitely got
the crowds out for you.
Man's good at two things,
making money and being
oilier than snake shit.
Well, you got any last
nuggets of wisdom for me?
Wait, I know, I know.
Don't overdo it.
Are you kidding me?
You seen that Clydesdale
you're fighting?
Yeah.
You overdo the hell out of it.
Yes, you're right,
good afternoon
and it's going to
be a good afternoon.
It's good to see
you on this fine day
filled with first-rate
entertainment
provided, I should acknowledge,
through the generosity
of Mr. Thaddeus Vincent.
Now, I know that we've got
a big prize fight coming up
and so do you, but
that's coming up
in just a little while
because the first bout
on today's match
will be this one,
featuring a young man whose
fists are as smooth as honey.
I'm talking about Sweetie Pete.
Yeah!
And in this corner,
his opponent.
Your man's in the prelims too?
Well maybe ol' Sweetie
Pete will knock him out,
I'll win, won't even
have to throw a punch.
At least you can see
what you're up against.
Alright, fellas. Shake hands.
And give me a head start.
Alright, fellas.
And, fight!
And the winner!
Looks like you have to
fight your own battles.
I wouldn't have
it any other way.
Me either.
Sorry I'm late, what did I miss?
Just a little glimpse
into my future.
What?
Nothing.
Listen, I need you to make sure
you take care of this man, okay?
Alright.
Wait, wait, wait.
Hold this.
-Alright.
-And remember-
I know.
I got it from
a girl in Texas.
-Yeah. Let's go.
-I got you.
-Here we go!
-Let's fight, alright!
Alright.
Hope you got right
with God, old man,
you ain't leaving this ring.
All I've heard is bark from you.
Let's see if you can bite.
Why don't you save
it for the fight?
Ladies and gentlemen,
this is the moment
you've been waiting for
for hardly any time at all.
You've got yourself a couple
of real contenders here.
Allow me to introduce
our challenger,
the Bare Knuckle Beast himself.
The man with fists like
a pair of six guns,
here to make a
wallop of a comeback.
We have the legend of
the frontier himself.
The Waco Kid.
I think your town likes me.
Okay, come on in, shake hands.
Now, show God you've
got some talent
before you go to meet him.
Alright, that's it,
and gimme a head start.
Fight!
Yeah! I'm faster than I look!
Psst, Dutch, over here.
There you are.
How's Waco?
He's fine. Fight just
started when I left.
Don't you worry about him.
He can take care of himself.
How far is the mine from here?
Not far. Look.
Boy, it sure would be
nice if those two fellas
were the only ones
I had to deal with.
Safe to assume they're not.
Dutch, you think
you can handle them?
Did Caleb say whether
or not these boys
know anything
about the children?
They know. There will likely
be more of them than usual.
Yeah, well, that ain't
gonna be a problem.
Good.
We'll make our way
to the holding cell
and meet you back here
with the children.
Alright. Now listen.
You two wait for my signal.
When you hear it,
you move, got it?
Be careful.
The mine's closed, old man.
You boys might wanna get heeled.
Hey, hey!
Watch the corner!
Hey, hey, hey!
The holdings should be over...
How is he still asleep?
You see the keys?
Ooh, how to get them?
Let's find a stick.
Good idea!
Keep your eyes out!
He's over here!
Where'd he go?
Oh!
I must say, I have gotten
quite handy with these.
That's not quite what
I meant by stick.
Oh.
You seen that Dutch fella
around here anywhere?
I'm just watching the
fight, same as you.
Let me guess, you have
absolutely no idea
where he coulda gotten off to.
Nope.
You have no spine.
Miss Rosemary, you came!
Of course I did.
Get to your corner.
Get off of him!
Come on, get off of him!
Now, let us hurry.
We haven't much time to spare.
Everyone, my name is
Rosemary and this is Lita.
You'll need to do everything
exactly as we say, alright?
Keep your heads down.
We'll be moving very quickly
and we're not stopping
until we reach
the train station.
Let's go, be quick
and quiet as you can.
Alright,
get outta here. Get!
-Get up, Waco!
-Is he okay?
-Is he alright?
-He's fine!
I think you almost had him.
I feel like I'm hitting
the broad side of a steer.
His ribs?
No, his jaw.
He's not slowing down either.
But I, I don't think I can
last too many more rounds.
Have you seen anything fishy?
I saw the the deputy head off.
You think he's
headed to the mines?
I dunno, but Dutch can
take care of himself.
Hey! Whoa!
Depu, oh!
-Back off me!
-Sorry, you were crowding me.
Deputy said you'd
be here.
What?
Kids okay?
Good. Good job, ladies.
Was that the last of them?
Yeah, I reckon so.
Should be smooth sailing
from here on out.
Follow me.
Yoohoo!
Hello, boys and girls.
You ready to meet your parents?
Your uncle Zeke's been dying
to shoot this thing.
You're supposed to duck.
Run!
Here she comes, Dutch!
What in the hell was that?
Somebody trusted that
idiot with a Gatling gun.
How are we supposed
to get out of this?
You can hide behind that rock
all you want, you coward!
I got enough ammo and grit to
blast a hole clean through ya.
There are two ways back to town.
I want you to take
the kids the long way.
I'll keep his head down.
Pardon me.
We can't just leave you here!
You have to.
You said it yourself,
these kids are the
most important thing.
Now, I want you to wait
for my signal and just run.
Alright, children. Get ready.
Ready?
Go!
Go, go!
Ha.
I got the boy, I see ya.
You died out there in
that desert, Dutch!
You died the minute you crossed
the infamous Zeke Tyler!
Where are you? I got ya.
Get up, Waco! No!
Son of a bitch.
Winner!
The winner!
Shoot him.
Yeah! Waco.
No, no! Get to the kids!
Waco!
I'm afraid I'm all you get.
Your friend's as good
as worm food already.
I'd be more than happy to
arrange a reunion if you'd like.
Damn shame.
Old Cowsbane Morales,
taken out by a no-good bounty
hunter the likes of you.
That boy rode with
me for a long time
before I picked up this badge.
Taught the boy
everything he knew.
Always figured I'd have to test
myself against him one day.
But I reckon you'll have to do.
You ready?
You gonna let me
check this pistol?
Make sure I got bullets?
Well, now that's another
real goddamn shame, ain't it?
We go when this hits the ground.
Don't overdo it.
Huh?
Now I see why Waco
likes to do that.
What'd I miss?
Your cue.
I'm sorry. People kept
trying to kill me.
What about the
children? Are they safe?
They are.
Well hell, we about
actually saved the day.
Dutch?
I'm empty.
How hard?
How hard is it for
you nimpent, jasper,
vagrant sons of
bitches to understand?
What's that mean?
I have no idea.
Well, it's, I'll explain later.
I am civilization!
I have put too many of
you into the ground!
What's three more?
Nice shot, kid.
Think this is enough to
cover Morales' bounty?
That's more than enough.
I'd say that'll do.
But are you sure the
folks around here
ain't gonna need this to help
y'all get back on your feet?
No, senores, you freed
this town from debt.
We get to keep all that we
have and all that we earn
and we'll never
forget you for that.
It was an honor working
with both of you.
You too, Caleb.
-Ah!
-Oh, you.
Hasta luego.
How're we supposed
to carry this?
Maybe they'll let us
keep the wheelbarrow.
How're we gonna pull a
wheelbarrow with our horses?
Seems as you boys can
afford a wagon now.
Dutch, Waco.
I just came to say goodbye
and to thank you both.
We did a good
thing in this town.
Because of you both, we've
saved children's lives.
Oh, stop it.
People are gonna think
we're going soft.
Or tenderized.
Look, we just did
what was right.
You know, if enough
of that goes around,
might be a good
country after all.
So, what's next for you?
Well, I must say I have
been a bit inspired.
Not that I didn't
expect adventure,
but this little journey
has excited me to my cause.
There are still plenty
of children to find
in plenty of towns,
so I am catching a train
to Oklahoma tomorrow.
And who knows, maybe our
paths will cross again.
Well, I hope so.
Me too, Miss Rosemary.
Dutch, I feel like we
did a whole lot of good.
Almost like, almost like
we're lawmen ourselves.
Yeah, maybe.
And who knows, maybe
this place will become
the safe, sleepy little town
the deputy said it was gonna be.
Yep. I imagine the next
sheriff won't have any trouble.
Alright, enough chit-chat.
Let's find some bags
to put in this...
-What happened to our gold?
-What?
Son of a!
Langford take three.
Ow!
Don't come
out, they'll shoot!
Reset, Caleb
had a problem there.
Alright, so Caleb's
mess up was way worse.
Yeah, it was.
I blew it, man, I'm so sorry.
Cut.
I was just dreaming
about this girl
I know down in Saltillo.
She can do things
with her one good arm
that'd make you forget
about that harelip.
This is the wordiest bit.
Still rolling.
Five, acting
chops, take one.
-Actors' chops!
-Alright.
10, Hubert, take one.
Hubert. Wah, wah, wah, wah, wah.
Let's wait for that.
Yes. Incomposed,
that's right, and.
I told you once,
you son of a bitch,
I'm the best there's ever been.
We need to uphold the
laws in this town.
If for no other reason,
do it for the beeping that
you hear in the background.
I would agree.
Can I have my gun back, please?
That's just reckless.
What if he wakes up at midnight,
he wants a glass of warm milk,
he comes in here,
steps on a bullet,
he's gonna blame me,
but it's your fault.
Just remember that.
Symbolized
by bloods and so on
is to destroy the Christ idea.
Heather, stop reading,
you're gonna summon
a demon or something.
Alright, here we go.
Love letters from a
concerned citizen.
Oh, there's this
girl in Abilene,
she used to write
me twice a week!
Cut.
But I know
where the children are.
What?
-Let's reset.
-You do,
I always forget the.
Let's hold for a second,
we'll wait for the
worst of that plane.
You mother.
Wah.
That was good, we
got both of those lines.
They're provided for...
Sorry.
You went a lot
longer the last time.
Let's reset from the top.
Actually, no.
Bulletin.
No, actually a
bulletin for a hot meal
is what led you to me.
And hold for a second.
My gut, I'm telling
you, David, I'm on point.
We go when this hits the ground.
You dropped the coin.
Scene 28, evil, take three.
Calling me evil?
-Camera set.
-That's just rude.
Hello.
Hello, Katie.
Katie.
Resetting, resetting.
The cowardice of some
men, it saddens me.
I completely did that backwards.
The gold.
-Sorry.
-It's okay.
You wanna take it from the top?
I said it backwards!
And that entertainment
is provided
by a very special host,
and I'm talking about our
friend Francois Parsouneman.
-No.
-Let's hold rotate.
It's Thaddeus Vincent.
I couldn't
remember his name.
Now listen here, you mother-
Hello, boys and girls!
You ready to meet your parents?
Your Uncle Zeke's been
dying, nope, nope, nope.
Your Uncle Zeke's...
Let's reset.
-Argh!
-That's okay.
-Speed.
35, direction after slate
was called, take three.
-Oh!
-What?
No live fire?
No live fire, I'm just
shouting bang like an asshole.