Have a good trip, pretty lady.
WARSAW, NOVEMBER 1941
HITLER THREATENS TO ANNEX GDANSK
JUNE 1939
-I'm finished, can I turn it in?
-So quickly?
There's still 45 minutes,
maybe you want to add something?
No, there is no need.
I wrote everything I knew.
Perhaps I can check it and grade it now
unless you're in a hurry.
No, I'll be happy to wait.
Please.
-Give me your grade-book, please.
-Here you are.
-Born and raised in London?
-Born and raised.
-And you speak Polish so well?
-Because I'm Polish.
My father does business in London,
but my family lives in Tarnopol, Poland.
Congratulations, this is excellent.
-It ought to be published somewhere.
-Thank you.
-Goodbye.
I gave it my all.
Will you miss me?
I don't want to miss you.
-I don't want you to go.
-You know I have to…
but it won't take long.
-But I will go crazy here without you.
-So stay the night.
No way!
They'd throw me out of the house.
They think you really only
teach me English.
Don't I?
Do you think a war is coming?
BASED ON THE NOVEL BY JANUSZ MAJEWSKI
Listen, folks
To the sad tale I sing for you…
WARSAW JEWISH GHETTO
NOVEMBER, 1940
BLUMENFELD OUTBUILDING ON THE RIGHT
-Mr. Grodecki?
-Do you know the password?
Blumenfeld.
Here.
How much is there?
As agreed but you can count it.
No.
Please sign for it.
More documents, not all are
believable but you can verify it.
Filthy Jewish brats…
you want potatoes, eat shit!
Stop! Stop!
Careful! Not so fast, young man!
Leave him alone!
Are you German?
No.
I'm a Pole.
-But you speak excellent German?
-Well, it happens.
Forgive me, but your accent intrigues me.
I truly am Polish,
although my name is Holzer.
I am a lawyer, my office is here.
Maximilian Graf von Fleckenstein.
It is a pleasure to meet you, counsellor.
I heard Saxon notes in your
excellent German pronunciation.
You are a linguist or have perfect pitch.
You're right,
my great-great-great grandfather,
Theodor Christian Holzer,
was from Dresden.
In that case, you are German.
No, Count,
I am fourth-generation Polish.
I must assist you.
It's just how I was raised.
Please leave it.
Thank you very much.
Is the boss very busy, Mrs. Stefa?
That street vendor just bought
professor Zieleniecki's villa in Żoliborz!
The times we live in!
Yes, you can go in now.
-Coffee?
-Yes, please.
Just a moment.
Counsellor, the world has no idea
what's happening there.
Even people in Warsaw have no idea.
I see it with my own eyes but my mind
says: "no, that's not possible."
Diseases, starvation,
corpses on the street,
can you imagine,
about sixty nightclubs.
Caviar, champagne and whores.
So why do they sign and stamp everything?
If we get caught, we'll hang, all of us.
They need it for those sellers.
They show them all the papers so it's
legal and open.
Not in front of the Germans,
only among us.
That means nothing,
if we are caught,
the Gestapo will beat it all out of
us anyway.
But we won't get caught.
Because I'm just lucky.
Today, an SS officer saved me
from a roundup.
She's not here, she hasn't returned.
You keep coming for nothing.
She went to Tarnopol just before the war.
To be with her sick grandfather.
How can she get back
with the Russians there?
I don't know but…
I'll keep coming by.
-Maybe she'll come back.
-Her former flat is locked up.
Some German wanted the key but I told
him I don't have it.
Let them break in. Thieves.
Why do you call it her former flat?
I wish you the best, but don't
believe in miracles.
Mister, listen to what my wife is saying.
Don't come around, someone might see.
ONE YEAR LATER
NOVEMBER 16TH, 1941
-Is the egg too soft, Sir?
-No, it's exactly how I like it.
I wanted to make scrambled eggs
the way you like but your wife said…
She said that soft-boiled are healthier.
And we don't have any butter.
Good morning.
How are you doing, Mr. Klamka?
Well it's about the new
registration forms, sir.
And my name is Klamocki.
Then I apologize,
I didn't know Mr. Klamocki.
You know, I'm in a bit of a hurry.
I need to go to the office,
so I'll fill it out this evening
and Cesia will bring it to you.
Fine, there's no rush,
if she brings it then…
-Goodbye.
Remember that Max is coming
for coffee tomorrow?
-Yes.
-Good.
Maybe you two could bake a cake?
If we can get flour.
Thank you.
I'm leaving now. Mrs. Stefa,
you should close up and go home too.
It's cold in here.
It's past three already!
They should turn on the heating soon.
What they will use for fuel, I don't know.
Alright, goodbye.
Goodbye, sir.
Krystyna?
Krysia, are you here?
Krystyna!
Cesia.
Hello, police station?
Inspector Rafał Król. Did you call us?
Yes, Karol Holzer, attorney.
The victim is here.
Who was she?
She was my wife.
I found her like this when I returned
from work.
And I called the station immediately.
She was killed about two or three hours
before your return.
Rigor mortis has set in already.
Was she alone?
No, she was with the maid,
but when I came
home, Cesia was not here.
I got here at half past three as
usual, for dinner.
To prepare dinner for half past three
one needs to start cooking no later
than between 12 and 1 o'clock.
So she was murdered around noon as
indicated by rigor mortis.
Our maid always
cleans the apartment, then goes shopping
and later starts cooking dinner.
The groceries are here,
the place is cleaned…
No signs of cooking.
Where did she sleep?
Here, it's the maid's room.
Suitcase,
her clothes are here as well.
What was her name and how old was she?
The blade entered precisely
beneath the shoulder blade.
And punctured the heart,
hence such hemorrhaging.
This indicates that the perpetrator
knew his stuff.
Nice looking lady, pity.
But will she go to heaven?
She probably wasn't baptized.
Broken middle finger of the right hand.
Probably no rape occurred.
We won't need to check.
A beautiful woman.
Anything missing from the apartment?
Money, jewelry, documents…
Nothing's been touched.
Do you have a building supervisor here?
Yes, he lives in the outbuilding.
Why are you banging on the door
you fucking lout?!
Klamka, good to see you.
Weren't you in prison?
Mr. Inspector?
Please, please come in.
They let us out from Rawicz
on September 2nd. I have the certificate!
Everybody was yelling:
"hooray for the war!", but not me.
I'd have preferred to do my time.
I only had a year to go.
Mr. Inspector, I didn't kill her.
On my honor.
Klamka, let's not talk about honor here.
Who didn't you kill?
That attorney's wife,
from the second floor.
Mrs. Holzer?
She was murdered? How do you know that?
Inspector, sir, please don't toy with me.
I confess, I saw her
lying on the floor
with a knife in her back.
So you were in the apartment?
You broke in.
God forbid! I was sweeping the stairs,
because my whore wife, says that her
back hurts, but she goes to church anyway!
Calm down, or I'll give you a beating,
you'll be hurting until New Year's.
Tell me what happened!
Well, I was sweeping the stairs
and I saw that
on the second floor, at the lawyer's,
the door is ajar.
I thought that Cesia
was taking out rubbish.
Well, I stuck my head in the open door
and I shouted: "Cesia".
But there was silence.
Then I shout: "Mrs. Holzer!".
Again silence.
So, I thought I should go in because
something must have happened.
-Where did you go first?
-To the kitchen.
And I saw her right away,
she was lying face down, the knife
sticking out from her back.
I thought she was still alive,
because her eyes were open,
but then I saw that there was
nothing in those eyes anymore.
And then something tempted me.
I could not resist.
What did you do?
Talk, you pig, what did you do to her?
No, it's not what you think Inspector…
I just took it off her finger.
Because I could not stop myself,
Inspector,
because there's a
voice in my head.
It makes me.
Shut the fuck up, Klamka!
You killed her to rob her!
I'm arresting you on charges of murder.
And this, this is material evidence.
No, Inspector.
Sir, I stole a lot in my life.
But I never killed anyone. Anyone.
-Fine, fine.
-No one…
Well, you'll confess to the Gestapo.
When they beat your mug
into steak tartar.
-Mr. Inspector, Sir…
-Well, unless…
Unless we have a talk…
-Sir, good morning.
-Good morning, Mrs. Stefa.
A plainclothes officer was here
a moment ago.
He was asking about you,
about what time you left yesterday.
-And if it was at the usual time.
-And what did you tell him?
That, as usual, after three.
And he asked if you weren't
an ethnic German, Volksdeutsche,
because of the name…
And?
I said that my maiden name is
de Champois and I am Polish.
He must be Volksdeutsch himself,
if he's in the "blue police."
Listen please,
something terrible has happened.
Yesterday there was a crime
at my apartment,
a murder.
Jesus and Mary!
Someone murdered
my former student, a Jew.
With a knife, in the back…
I was hiding her at my place
using my wife's papers.
For how long?
I know, she's been here before, right?
Yes.
That's why the policeman came by.
He was checking my alibi.
I immediately called the police.
Are there any suspects?
Cesia, our maid, has disappeared.
Cesia? How would Cesia
be capable of something like that?
With a knife?
Where would Cesia get a knife?
Where? From the kitchen.
I'll make you some tea.
Mr. Grodecki, you will go to the Major?
Tell him what happened. Let him decide.
Fine, but I think that for
as long as we can,
let's behave as always.
Come in!
Good morning, sir. Inspector.
Well, what is it, Klamka?
I don't know if it matters.
This old count lives in our building.
He stops me in the hall and asks:
"Mr. Klamocki, what happened
at the lawyer's place? The police came."
So what?
So I said it was none pf my business,
but he was more insistent than ever.
And before he was too proud
to give me the time of day.
I think that you should interrogate him.
Klamka, you better not think what
I should and shouldn't do.
Nothing else? Nobody hanging around?
No, no. Some time ago,
a young man was loitering
in the doorways across the street.
But it was a long time ago.
Fine.
-What is the name of this count?
-Przewiedzki.
Unbelievable!
Really unbelievable, Inspector.
The times we live in!
Whores are reading Pascal.
Once, she would have have left behind
a Pitigrilli or something similar.
And now, does she think she will
impress me?
Sugar? Milk?
No, thank you.
Count, did you ever meet Mrs. Holzer?
Yes, indeed. Once, briefly on the stairs.
What impression did she make on you?
Well, a beautiful woman. Well-bred.
I think also in the modern meaning.
Meaning?
She had a slight accent,
as if she was not Polish.
Do you mean to say she was Jewish?
Possible,
but that's not what I meant.
-So maybe she was German?
-Maybe. Like Holzer the attorney.
Is he German?
Well, the surname is certainly not Polish.
Besides, he entertains Germans.
Very often an SS officer visits them.
Is it noticeable?
Oh, you know,
what does an old
bachelor have to do these days?
There is nowhere to go,
sometimes he gets whores,
but he is bored all the time,
so he spies on his neighbors.
Through a telescope?
I beg your pardon?
You have a telescope on the balcony,
Count.
How did you see it?
I noticed a flash when I was
examining the body.
So, maybe you saw the murderer?
No, Inspector,
I swear I didn't see anything.
Here, I'll show you, nothing can be
seen from there.
Please. Come along.
Inspector, patience is
the primary virtue of a hunter.
I've spent many days in the hunting box
so I could shoot a trophy mountain goat,
but I waited and waited patiently.
And for what?
Once, while on duty here,
my eye to the telescope,
and suddenly I see that
the milk set on the stove
begins to boil,
that it will boil over in a moment,
and then she runs into my field of vision,
Mrs. Holzer, naked as the day God
made her,
and at the last moment she removes
the pot from the stove
built like a goddess, wonderful,
you can see that the breasts are firm,
the hips divine, long legs
as if finely turned.
Simply a miracle.
She must have been in the bathroom
and remembered about the milk.
But this is not the end.
Imagine that something
falls to the floor, a teaspoon perhaps?
She leans down to pick it up,
she presents her divine derrière to me,
and what do I see? That wonderful place,
this corner of paradise, this treasure,
for which we would go
to the ends of the world,
that narrowed eye of providence,
the heart of all and final matters,
her triumphant cunny!
She, as we used to say
in my childhood,
just shot me with her bottom.
Then I went mad, I was crazy about her.
I decided to get closer to her somehow…
Close enough to stab her
with the knife?
Excuse me?
Did you kill her, Count?
Say what?
Kill her?
All powerful, eternal God,
because it is not Thy will that
anyone of the meek be lost,
but You gave Your only Son
for the salvation
of the lost and through Him you gave…
Give me the fifty.
…against all ambushes and dangers,
by Jesus Christ.
Amen.
I'll make you pay for all of this.
Give it here. Give me the grenade.
-No!
-I will shoot you before you throw it.
-Then we will both die!
-But they will survive.
Two instead of seven. It's worth it.
Give it to me!
Maybe I will hold it
and you will put the pin in?
You ever see two guys thread a needle?
Catch!
Cadet Vulture.
What is this?
A grenade.
Answer like a soldier, not like a cunt!
Defense grenade, type O, model 33.
-The so-called "pineapple".
-"Pineapple"!
Do you know this one:
"Dad bought three bananas,
ate them all and flipped us off"?
And you, cadet, you flipped off
the regulations, the dignity of a soldier,
of the Home Army and common sense!
What did you want to achieve?
Who did you want to kill? That German?
Or the Poles present,
including the pastor?
Thank you for coming.
How could I not?
A friend in need is a friend indeed!
You had a lecture on the power
of a defensive grenade,
it would have been a massacre,
there would be no one left alive.
Including the two of us.
I did not have any other weapon,
and I found the grenade,
in September at the cemetery,
and I wanted to kill
the SS officer and the lawyer.
I wanted to punish them…
Punish them? For what?
For Aneta's death.
She died because of them!
Cadet Vulture!
Before the war, in my regiment,
for such tomfoolery you would scrub
the latrines for a month.
And today, what can I do to you?
Dismissed!
I'm sorry.
You know, he is my Godson.
In fact a good boy,
but his generation was raised
reading Polish romantics, Conrad…
But I will come up with a punishment.
I apologize to you too, because
I also took you for a Volksdeutsch,
but I could not know that
you were the Major's man.
Although…
I had a vague impression that
I know you from somewhere…
I also had such an impression.
Maybe we met at some trial in the past.
That's it then!
You were at the Gorgonowa trial.
You were called in as an expert witness.
I took part in dozens of trials,
but that one really
caused me some trouble.
I became recognizable,
and you know, in my job…
Yes.
I'm very sorry, Mr. Rafał.
It seems that I will have to tell you
everything from the beginning.
Aneta was not my wife, she was my
student before the war.
The best student
at the School of Economics.
I hid her at my place.
She had a rich father in London,
but she came to study in Poland,
because her father wished it.
He came from Podwołoczysk
near Tarnopol,
where Aneta's grandfather was a rabbi.
The family's patriarch
was nearing death
and called the family to his side.
But the Germans beat him to it,
then the Soviets.
The whole family was killed, except Aneta.
When the German-Soviet front
moved east,
Aneta moved to Warsaw.
SEPTEMBER, 1941
Jesus Christ!
Miss Aneta is alive?
-Did you escape from the ghetto, Miss?
-No, I was never there.
So you're not Jewish, Miss?
Where will you go now?
The Krauts took over your apartment.
Do you have any relatives, Miss?
No, not here. I do in England.
So you're English.
We've always thought you a little odd,
Miss.
A boy came by here
looking for you, Miss.
Young, handsome, asking about you.
Came by often, maybe for a year or longer.
He was here.
Well! Come in, Miss. Spend the night.
Tomorrow we'll find a place.
My old man knows a lot of people.
Come in, Miss.
Jesus, I'm sorry.
I just wanted some water.
Heartburn is killing me.
Take some soda
at the end of the knife.
It's in the cup on the sideboard.
I will go see my aunt in Bródno,
She might find a job for you,
and a safe place.
You can't stay here,
too many Krauts live here.
Thank you very much.
So, don't let anyone in,
do not go out anywhere.
My old man gets home
from work after two.
And one more thing, if he gets a seizure,
put something hard between his teeth.
He's an epileptic!
But don't tell anyone, Miss,
or they'll fire him from the tram company.
It's scary to think what would happen
if he had a seizure
behind the wheel…
That would be something.
Well, I'm off.
At the beginning of October,
Aneta Landau came to my office.
Sir, a young woman is here.
She says she was a student of yours.
Show her in.
Come in.
I don't know you remember me, professor.
Of course I remember.
Professor, I need your help.
She had nowhere to go.
She felt threatened by these people.
A building full of Germans,
the caretaker clearly
reluctant to help.
How long did you stay there?
I stayed with them since Tuesday.
But I've already decided.
If you do not help me,
I will go to the ghetto.
Out of the question.
You have no idea what it's like there…
For you the most important
thing is a new identity.
So-called Aryan papers,
and then a safe place
and some income.
I still have some valuables.
I can also work.
I can give English lessons.
I can do anything…
Excuse me.
Here you are.
-Here you are.
-Thank you.
Thank you.
I might have an idea,
but I don't know if you'd agree.
You would have to become
Krystyna Kawecka,
and this would be
your baptism certificate.
Krystyna Maria Kawecka… Born on…
Who is this?
It was my wife.
-Was?
-Cesia never saw Krystyna.
Besides, nobody has seen her here.
Because it was supposed
to be my surprise,
she was to see this apartment
after returning from vacation.
When we came back
from a cruise to Finland,
I came to Warsaw,
to get the flat ready.
And she was still in Jastarnia
with her father,
and when the war broke out,
they fled by plane to Sweden.
And Cesia served my mother,
she stayed with her until the end,
so I hired her out of pity.
It's raining, at least
we do not have to wait until it's dark.
You're right, professor.
Don't call me professor from now on.
And don't you forget it!
You must call me Karol. Understand?
Karol!
You will have to come alone.
We will have to pretend to have
a happy reunion.
Then a bath, dinner,
and a shared bedroom… Unfortunately.
But do not worry, there are two beds.
I understand everything. Karol.
Lwowska Street 3!
Come in. Now take the stairs to the attic.
Wait there for ten minutes.
And then go down to the second floor,
across the hall.
And remember, you're Krystyna.
Krystyna?
Karol!
You're back!
When we are alone,
should we still be on a first name basis?
We have to get used to it.
Krystyna.
Did you call your wife Krystyna?
I would not dare otherwise.
Good night, Karol.
Goodnight, Krystyna.
Good morning.
Maxi, you're back at last!
Yes.
I was in such a hurry
that I neglected to go home to change.
-Welcome.
-Where is our beautiful Krystyna?
Well, she probably heard you come in
and is powdering her nose.
She is not, she doesn't need to.
How wonderful, I just baked a cake.
-Thank you.
-Please, sit down.
I still have a meeting at Szucha Street,
but I wanted to drop by,
with a little something.
Caviar? Really?
-Coffee…
-Brazilian…
Well, thank you very much.
A piece of Sichertorte…
You were at Sicher's!
-And are the beautiful ladies still there?
-You know, husbands away at war…
But Vienna, carefree as always,
they play Strauss in the cafes.
And most importantly:
Martel.
Cordon Bleu?
Well, thank you very much.
Hail the black market!
For God's sake, finish already!
I have a splitting headache!
And you think I don't, Madam?
I didn't buy this contraption.
Go get some painkillers.
The ones with the rooster are best.
Do you hear me? Cesia!
Chop-chop!
In my previous employ,
carpets were properly beaten.
And not cleaned with some stupid machine!
I'm going to go mad.
Stefan, it's her! Her!
As God is my witness, it's her!
I looked for her for two years.
Understand?
I was going crazy for two years!
And she did not look for you,
but she could.
Give yourself a break.
Be happy that she is alive.
She does.
She lives with professor Holzer.
Now I'm sure he is a Volksdeutsch.
-Maybe this is the price.
-Of what?
-That she didn't have to go to the ghetto.
-And the SS officer?
Like her best friend!
Four days I stood on Lwowska street,
he visited three times. For what?
For what?
Holzer wasn't home.
Four days? Jedrek!
A policeman could have seen you.
You would tell them everything! They'd
arrest us all because of your foolery!
It's not foolery. I won't let this go.
Stefan, lend me the Vis, will you?
I have to finish this as soon as possible!
You want my gun?
You've gone completely mad.
-Hello?
-Karol?
This is Max, hello!
Maxi!
You disappeared again.
You were supposed to come to dinner.
Your dessert is still waiting, untouched.
Forgive me, too much work.
Today I decided to relax a little,
let's go have some fun, what do you say?
Where? Adria again?
No. You'll see. It's a surprise.
I'll pick you up after eight! Ciao!
And what of it?
I'm scared.
Be careful.
Krystyna apologizes,
she has a migraine unfortunately.
Oh, what a pity! I am sorry.
But not to worry…
We'll have some manly fun.
-Halt!
-But this is the ghetto!
Your papers please. Thank you.
Where are you going?
Leszno Street, number 22.
Yes, sir. Captain!
You have at least two hours, Hans.
You can go to a brothel.
Fit for every budget.
I can't get infected, Captain.
I have a young wife.
Besides, I'm very religious.
Please follow me, gentlemen.
-What champagne do you have?
-Heidsieck,
Mumm and Veuve Clicqot, 1929.
We'll take Mumm. And salted almonds.
I was told about it,
but I didn't believe it.
Where do they get it from?
Ladies and gentlemen,
and now a great surprise.
Our star, Madame Magnez, will perform
the famous Petersburski,
Friedwald and Brodower hit:
"This…
is the last Sunday."
I know her.
She was very popular before the war.
Before the war, I listened to her records.
We came to see her tonight.
But Brodower is still alive?
I didn't know you were such
a music lover!
You do not know much about me yet.
Now is not the time for excuses
the fact is, it's over,
today another came,
richer and better than I
and along with you
stole my happiness.
I have but one request,
perhaps the last,
the first in many years,
give me this one Sunday,
the last Sunday,
then the world may end.
This is the last Sunday,
today we will part ways,
today we will separate,
for all times.
This is the last Sunday,
so save it for me,
look tenderly at me
for the last time.
Excuse me, I'll be back in a minute.
You shall have enough
of such Sundays,
and what will become of me,
who knows…
This is the last Sunday,
the dreams I've dreamt,
the happiness so yearned
for has ended.
Are you the attorney?
Yes.
You don't know me,
but I know who you are.
I work with Grodecki.
We did not know you would come here.
-Neither did I.
-Who is your companion?
-An officer of the SS.
-What?
Don't be upset. He brought me here.
As a surprise.
-I do not understand anything…
-It doesn't matter.
Grodecki knows
everything, he'll explain.
This is the last Sunday…
today we will part ways…
today we will part…
for all time.
This is the last Sunday…
Beautiful music, but I don't
understand the lyrics.
If you understood, you would weep.
Ladies and gentlemen,
due to the curfew,
we wish you a safe return home.
Are you closing?
No, we're open until eleven
for those who have permission.
Papers!
If after seeing my papers, Sergeant,
you dare to come to attention and
salute me,
you will be sent to the front.
Understood?
Yes, Sir. Captain! Here you are.
What about the other one?
Get the fuck out you Jewish swine!
Now!
Get the fuck out!
Ear plugs. Put in your ear plugs.
Yes, Sir, Captain.
You see Karol,
I suffer because I'm
here on orders of the people
I hate with all my soul.
Although I was proud of the SS once.
Proud of the uniform.
Because it is beautiful, isn't it?
Exquisite styling, do you like it?
I prefer you in a suit.
The thoughtless elite,
to which my family also belong…
saw in Hitler an opportunity
for profit and expanding influence.
Not until the barbarians
started burning books,
did the lament over
the fall of German culture begin.
The fatherland of philosophers and poets…
Why are you telling me all this, Max?
What do you expect of me?
I was only trying to tell you why I want
you to think of me as your friend.
-Goodnight.
-Karol. Karol, wait, please.
You probably think that I come here
because of Krystyna.
But no, I come here because of you.
I thought that we…
Max!
Counsellor, sir…
I brought you some coffee.
I'm sorry Mrs.Stefa
but I had a sleepless night.
Mr. Grodecki is here.
-Please show him in then.
-Here's your coffee.
Thank you.
Please come in, the counsellor
will see you.
Good morning.
You really gave our people a scare
at The Muse last night.
When you told Kugelman
in the restroom
that your companion is an SS officer,
he almost shit himself, sorry…
Well he was in the right place for it,
you know?
I was most afraid that professor Langman
would greet me as a friend.
But he isn't much of a waiter.
I didn't know you knew each other.
But, counsellor, Max really shouldn't
come to The Muse.
Unfortunately, I'm afraid he will.
He's the one who brought me there
after all.
You befriended an officer of the SS?
NOVEMBER 22ND, 1941
He was the perfect cover
for me and Aneta.
But also for our covert activities.
With my notary friend, we sell Jewish
real estate to Poles
on this side of the wall.
We falsify deeds and records
and sell as legal ones,
and the proceeds go to the ghetto.
Yes, I know, the Major told me.
You know,
when it happened,
and it was just the day after our evening
escapade and his homosexual advances,
I was wondering how hard it
must have been for him
to overcome shame
and to finally call me.
I got drunk the day before yesterday
and said some silly things,
I don't even remember what…
There's nothing to talk about, Max,
especially since something
terrible has happened.
Krystyna is dead.
What?
She's dead?
She was murdered.
What?
When, by whom?
Why didn't you call me?
I called the police, the so-called blues,
since it's under their jurisdiction.
Right.
Do they have any leads?
None.
Well, there is one, Cesia,
the maid has disappeared.
This is horrible.
I so admired Krystyna.
Such a beautiful and wise woman.
I am very sorry for your loss.
-I will do whatever I can for you.
-Thank you. Thank you, Max.
Yes?
Good evening, Madam.
Is your husband home?
Good evening. My husband's out,
driving a tram. What's this about?
I have a letter for him
from a friend in the army.
-The army, from Kozłowski, right?
-Exactly.
Probably more trashy stuff again.
Sir, he is the biggest pervert I know.
He sells bornography
at the Kercelak market.
-Pornography, you mean.
-That too maybe, I don't know.
Good morning.
Wielgat, Szymon?
Yes, what is it?
You are detained
to be questioned as a witness.
A witness?
Enter!
Inspector…
Thank you, dismissed.
Have a seat, please, Mr. Wielgat.
Mr. Wielgat, this week you are
working first shift.
So that last week
you were on the second shift.
-What time do you leave for work?
-A quarter to two.
And what did you do before work,
last Thursday?
Did you go out anywhere?
Just a moment…
I just went to see a friend in Służewiec
to borrow a long staff,
because I promised
the parish priest that I would play
St. Joseph
in the nativity play and we were
already rehearsing.
No, that's not it, that wasn't on
Thursday but on Wednesday.
Fine.
And is the name
Aneta Landau familiar,
she used to live in a studio
in your building.
Not at all.
Not at all familiar.
Not at all?
I… I don't know…
She slept in your kitchen,
you don't remember?
Well, yes… Well…
She stayed one or two nights
with us and left.
Why did she leave?
I don't know.
She went to Lviv supposedly,
maybe the Germans detained her.
-Do you suffer from some illness?
-No.
I mean yes. I have acid reflux.
Get heartburn often…
I see.
And due to this heartburn, you entered
the kitchen where the girl was sleeping?
What are you saying?
How do you know this?
My wife told you,
the crazy old wench!
No, not your wife.
Maybe you told
about your night time foray
in search of the golden fleece.
I'm done with all of that,
I confessed to the priest
about jacking off and the pornography
and I received absolution.
And I do not commit those sins anymore
and I will not have new ones!
You're lucky that
you are a moron, Mr. Wielgat.
Go back to your wife
and instead of soda, use bromide.
I don't want to see you again.
Yes?
Here you are.
-Be real, be clear…
-Yes, yes, of course.
Do you still wear your favorite
Ambra Nera?
I'll never forget your
shining eyes when you
spread a drop of Ambra
on your wrist and said:
this is a thoughtful scent.
My Dear, my Ange!
-Good evening Max, have fun.
-You too.
Madame?
Egon! You bastard.
You tricked me!
You should be an actress!
Why do you wear this?
You want to be more manly?
You already are.
Harry Pile, by the Nile,
washes his balls with Persil…
Who is he?
It turns out that it's
a friend of our Max,
I found out where he lives by accident,
because Max's black Mercedes
is often parked
by this villa in Mokotów.
It's there.
Weird, such a big shot lives there
without security.
Are you still following this Max?
-I was just passing by.
-Really?
Yes.
Cadet Vulture…
Vulture,
if the Major finds out,
he will kick your ass
from here to Sunday.
I won't rat you out.
I know nothing in case.
But I won't defend you, this is the army,
not some private mission.
And what brings you, count?
Good evening.
Inspector, I didn't tell you everything
during our conversation.
That's what I thought.
Thank you.
I'm listening.
You see, that scope on my balcony,
I set it up to spy on that Cesia.
And I did, for months.
So young, lustful and flirtatious.
And in truth it was she who "shot" me
with her behind.
And she had no clue that the Count
was peeping on her?
I don't actually know.
She made faces, danced.
She'd put a pot on her head,
and walk around,
you know, in just her panties,
and those
wonderful tits would swing…
Anyway, I proposed that she visit me,
offered good money,
she refused every time.
Once she even scorned me most
cruelly, but then,
in the kitchen,
she would prance and tease…
Oh well…
Mostly, I came to tell you that,
on the day of the murder,
I saw a man
walk Cesia out of the apartment.
He walked her out?
Inspector, there was a round-up in
the street.
I don't want anyone to think
that I denounced her out of revenge…
I may be an old whore aficionado but, sir,
I am no low-life snitch.
Did it look like an arrest?
It seemed so.
I was taking the elevator down
to take out the rubbish
and saw them for just a brief moment.
His dark back, her face,
and it seemed that she was crying
and he was holding her strongly
by the arm like he was pulling her along,
like he wanted
to force her to go with him.
I present Inspector Rafał Król.
The correct pronunciation is Rafał Król.
Ernst Kluge, Kriminalrat.
Thank you for coming.
It is my duty.
You speak excellent German.
I am from Galicia, sir.
I served in the army
of Emperor Joseph
through the entire war.
You had that privilege, me too,
but just at the end.
And we both managed to survive.
Willi, shut the door!
Inspector.
You are investigating the murder
of one Krystyna Maria Holzer?
Sir, in accordance with the
leadership's decree,
Polish criminal matters are
under our jurisdiction.
This is why
we didn't report this to you.
Yes, I know.
I'm interested in the name Holzer.
It sounds German.
Why are you leading the investigation
and not the Wilcza Street division?
Even before the war, I was regarded
as a specialist in murder cases
and besides, ironically, there are
few murders lately of a civilian nature.
The atavistic human need for blood
is being more than satisfied.
Every day.
Who was the victim?
Krystyna Holzer was the wife of
counsellor Holzer, unemployed I believe.
Leads?
The one person who might have been
a witness or the perpetrator
has disappeared.
It was their maid,
a young village girl
named Celina Ratajczak.
Besides, we asked the Gestapo in writing,
if they have any information about her
but we received a reply that this person
wasn't registered in any document.
You applied in writing
and someone called back.
Did they identify themselves?
No, the operator took the call
and she didn't dare ask for a name.
Very well, thank you, Inspector.
If something new turns up,
please inform me.
As a matter of course, sir.
The German Kripo is
interested in the case.
I was interrogated by criminal
counsel Kluge.
He is a professional.
I know he won't let it go.
I was afraid of that.
You must leave Warsaw, immediately.
I'm prepared for that,
I even have a bag packed.
Do you think I should call Max?
No, don't do that, remember
about the Major's operation.
You can come back
when this blows over.
Goodbye.
Everyone, please come in here
for a moment.
I mentioned once that
I might have to disappear for some time.
I must leave Warsaw immediately.
Please bring me my bag.
Take care of ongoing cases yourselves
but do not start new ones.
Close the office under the pretense
of renovation.
Here are three months salaries.
Mrs. Stefa, this is the address of
dr. Tschervinka in Zakopane.
Send correspondence there please,
but only the really important ones.
Besides that, you know nothing,
I fell ill and went to a spa.
Left no address.
May the Lord guide you, sir.
Mrs. Stefa, the Lord…
Does God not see
what is going on here?
Do you think He might take
an interest in me?
Inge, connect me
with Pawiak prison command.
Willi brought the translator,
they're waiting here.
Let them in and you connect me.
This is criminal counsel Kluge.
Please bring the female prisoner
here for interrogation.
Ce-li-na Ra-taj-czak.
Yes, Ratajczak.
Very well, I'm waiting.
I need you to urgently translate
some documents as soon as I finish.
Willi, close the door.
Yes, sir.
To Auschwitz? When? November 20th?
All the Count saw was his back and hat,
it could have been anybody.
And he was probably right
that it was that undercover cop.
There was a roundup,
Cesia was running away
but he was adamant to catch her
and put her in the truck. That's all.
I pity her,
but thousands of our countrymen
experience these things every day.
That's true but if Mr. Traube says that
the poor thing got sent to Auschwitz
we've hit a wall. No motive at all.
He mentioned that name
but he was informed
that she had been sent away.
I remember clearly, Celina Ratajczak.
Hans, take three, four days off.
I'm taking the car.
If anyone asks, say that
I had important family matters.
Thank you very much.
Please take care, Count.
Good morning, is Karol here?
No, unfortunately,
the counsellor is not here.
He's gone out of town.
When?
A week, ten days?
Where to?
A spa, he is ill.
Where is this spa?
I don't know, Busko?
Ciechocinek, Krynica?
Address! I must have the address.
I don't have it, he didn't leave one.
Mrs. Stefa, he is in danger.
I must save him!
-He didn't leave an…
-He's in danger, I will hide him.
You surely have an address here,
please look for it.
Please go in, I will look for it.
Mrs. Stefa?
Dr. Tschervinka? Here?
Tschervinka? Over here.
Highlander?
Say what?
I don't know, I'm from Chabówka.
-What's going on, Józek?
-Hi.
Hello?
Come in! Come in please.
Good morning, Max,
I'm a friend of Karol Holzer's.
Doctor Tschervinka. A sick doctor.
Isn't that something?
How can I help you?
He gave me your address but wasn't
sure where you would assign him.
A terrible thing has happened.
Mrs. Krystyna is dead.
I was at her funeral.
He asked me to bring photos.
They've just arrived
from the photographer.
Who is this woman?
Because now she is also dead.
Karol's secretary, Stefa.
But I saw her before I left.
She's dead?
That's what it looks like, sir.
How do you know?
That's it exactly.
I don't know how I know.
I had this even before the war.
Friends would show me
photos of their wives,
and I would tell them…
Excuse me, I would like to go
hiking with Karol today still.
You have to go to Kościelisko,
to old Styrczula.
Last cottage in the village.
-Styrczula.
-Stier-tschula?
Very well, goodbye then
and a speedy recovery.
Goodbye.
So it looks like we might have motive.
He also shot her in the crotch…
Possible rape attempt?
Let's see if she scratched his face.
It doesn't look like she did.
What was in this frame?
A photo from the funeral.
I brought it to him myself from the Major.
The counsellor, Mrs. Stefa
and that German were in the photo.
Did Mr. Holzer leave you
the address where he is staying?
Yes, I remember he gave Mrs. Stefa
a piece of paper with the address.
Mrs. Stefa then put it in the safe…
but the paper disappeared.
Someone took the piece of paper
with the address, but left the money.
So we know almost everything now.
He killed her, didn't touch the money,
took only Holzer's address
and the photo from the cemetery.
So it was someone who was looking for him.
-Are there other photos from the cemetery?
-But who is looking for him, Inspector?
Yes, of course, there should be some.
Here.
This elegant fellow.
Please connect me
to criminal counsellor Kluge.
Max.
What are you doing here?
A little visit.
How did you find me?
Finding people is my specialty.
To tell you the truth,
I needed to be alone.
Which is why I left the address
only with the office,
-Mrs. Stefa said she wouldn't give it out.
-She gave it to me.
So, do you feel well-rested?
Yes.
I'm bored stiff.
You know, I love the mountains.
I read about some caves in a valley
which name I can't pronounce.
Want to go?
This is Mr. Grodecki, the notary.
Works with the office owner
counsellor Holzer.
It was Mr. Grodecki who called me.
Polish swine. Butchered.
Call for an ambulance with a doctor.
We'll need a certificate.
Yes, Sir!
Who are these gentlemen?
This is counsellor Holzer, and this is an
acquaintance of the counsellor.
Probably close, since he came…
I don't know him.
And later? After the ceremony?
You didn't guess from their exchange
who could this man have been?
A relative?
A friend, acquaintance?
I didn't listen in.
I just heard them talking in German.
-Heil Hitler!
-God bless.
-Good day.
-Sieg heil! Germany above all!
My sincere apologies, sir.
I have a huge favor.
I lost a bet with my fiancée,
and as punishment
I must clean up this square,
she walks to school through it.
Clean up…
So rake it up if you're such a sucker.
Is that a way to hold a rake, Mister?
It's not a violin or a cello.
Grab it like a man grabs a wench!
A little better now.
Yes, yes…
Intelligentsia…
You know,
when I got the news that you are
either a prisoner of war or dead,
I became despondent.
I felt very lonely.
I met this Karol and started to
spend time with them.
I loved this music before the war.
Today, I am not allowed to listen to it.
You are allowed here.
What song is this?
The more cruelty around me,
the more sentimental I become.
It is a strange mystery
of the German soul.
I did not seduce her, she seduced me.
And I was smitten.
Our trysts became regular.
I started to find ecstasy in them,
but because
I found fulfillment in inflicting pain.
Whenever she collapsed
exhausted and whispered.
I can't, I just can't…
Yes, more… Don't stop
Don't stop… more…
As time went by she became more
insatiable, impatient,
she wouldn't even let me
take off my coat.
Didn't care that my belt buckle
was painfully hitting her spine.
Once I was even able to imprint on
her beautiful back,
our war motto, in a negative, of course.
Lie to me my beloved,
tell me you'll take me away,
to the end of the world,
that we'll live in a hut on a sand dune,
that at dawn you'll sail away
to cast your nets,
and that I will wait on a little
bench in front of the hut,
shading my eyes
and searching for your boat
on the horizon,
and listening to that little heartbeat
in my balloon-like belly.
Tell me that's how it'll be,
lie to me but tell me.
So I lied,
lied brazenly while inside I laughed
at her wistful female stupidity.
As it turned out,
the ridicule was untimely.
Listen.
I have news for you.
Someone is coming who will change
your life and mine,
will change our lives,
Jesus?
You're right, he will be a god.
The god of our family.
I will take you to the Wehrmacht
hospital for the abortion.
They do it all the time.
Unless the father and mother
belong to the master race.
I am, but you?
Polish mother?
Me? I am a Jewess.
You didn't know?
You knocked up a Jewess.
I planned it.
Because I couldn't take
the fear anymore.
And to live as if in a prison.
And you will be the father
of little Saul or Moshe.
And if they're twins? Or triplets?
There will be a Sarah too!
The boys will be circumcised
and the girl will have it
sideways, like her mommy.
Mine is sideways, isn't it?
And I will have it!
I will give you a Jew!
You hear me?
Because the war will end.
And you will lose!
And then my father will come,
little Saul's grandfather.
And little Saul will inherit his wealth,
so much that you could buy
fucking Pomerania with it!
So much that when you find out
just how rich I am, you will grow a beard,
go to the ghetto and
ask to be accepted by the kahal!
Take your pants off, you SS swine,
you faggot!
You think I don't know you're in love
with my husband?
You fuck me but you only
think of his ass!
Take them off so I can circumcise it
and make you a Jew!
A little Jew…
A certain Kluge from Kripo,
damned if I know why,
suddenly got interested
in this maid of the Holzers.
It made me nervous,
I couldn't leave any witnesses.
This is the address of the doctor
in Zakopane.
Only he knows
where the counsellor is.
Do you like it?
What?
It is the scent of Ambra Nera.
That's it.
Watch out!
Watch out? But you intend to kill me.
Where did you get such an idea?
Why did you bring me here?
You know Max,
I got a flash of insight suddenly.
I understood that you killed Krystyna.
I don't know why you did that.
But I know it's you.
Yes, I did.
I had to.
You had to?
Yes, I had to.
I had an affair with her.
She got pregnant…
You had an affair with her?
I, Captain Maximilian
Graf von Fleckenstein
was to be father to a Jewish bastard?
This would dishonor the entire family!
It is the times we live in Karol!
-Did you know that your wife was a Jewess?
-She wasn't my wife.
But you shared a bedroom.
She wouldn't make love in there.
I thought that
she suffered because she loved you.
-And because you loved her.
-Yes, I loved her.
But I never told her.
We were both pretending
that we're married because
we knew we had to fight against this
love, we couldn't afford it.
Oh well, Max.
It's the times we live in.
Karol, save me.
You know Max,
I had fatherly
affection for you sometimes.
I killed Mrs. Stefa,
I killed that doctor from Zakopane,
because of you.
And now,
accept my death.
You can still be happy!
Max!
-For you!
-Max!
Karol…
I loved you so…
So you whacked him. Very good.
He could have made trouble for you.
You have to leave for some time.
Go to Pomerania and hide so nobody
sees you there.
Tell the family that you are on leave,
and I will spread a rumor here
that I gave you a secret assignment
to complete,
and when everything settles down,
I will come for you.
I need to go for a while but I'll be
right back and I'll finish it.
Gotta take a crap?
I'll put in your travel orders
dated yesterday.
Around 10, there is
an express train to Berlin,
but in Posen, you will transfer
to a train to Kolberg.
From there,
you won't have to far to go home.
Max, get it together!
You feel better now?
A little, but I have to go home.
Tummy ache.
Take a swig then.
-I can't, I'm a boy scout.
-Boy scout!
This is a stomach remedy, from apples.
Thank you, sir.
If you're bored, come do some raking!
You always have my permission.
WARSAW
CENTRAL RAILWAY STATION
Two to Gottenhaffen.
First class, discounted.
Which discount fare?
Volksdeutsch and
a school ticket for my son.
Heil Hitler!
Hey you, I got some business.
What?
Lend me the bag and the newspapers.
I'll pay you well and leave a deposit.
-How much?
-However much you want.
What for?
I bet my brother that I can sell papers.
-Are you both nuts or what?
-Not dangerous though.
So, what do you want for an hour?
A hundred. For the rental.
And a hundred for the deposit.
Have a good trip, pretty lady.
21, 22, 23…
a moment longer,
28, 29.
30!
For Aneta! For Mrs. Stefa!
Out of the way!
Stand back, back!
Idiots!
Sisters! Get to work!
Many thanks, gentlemen.
She is dead.
Maximilian von Fleckenstein,
captain of the SS…
This was in the pocket.
Now, the Gestapo will have to
make the whole case disappear.
But they'll manage.
What about counsellor Holzer?
Did your people find him?
No, he must have gone underground.
I'll tell them the case is closed
and not to look for him.
But I advise you to disappear
for a while.
The Gestapo can be overzealous…
I'll take it under consideration.
Thank you.
And one more thing, I got that Celina
out of Auschwitz and interrogated her.
She should also disappear.
I advised her to be sick.
She is simulating typhoid.
They placed her at the
infectious disease hospital
in the city so as not to cause
an epidemic in Pawiak prison.
She'll be fine, she's a smart girl.
I've never seen her.
Your loss, she's perfect.
Goodbye, Inspector.
Goodbye, counsellor.