Hey, let me tell you, man,
she taste like watermelons.
Watermelons?
Okay, grapefruit.
Hey, don't touch the jacket, man.
Didn't I tell you not to touch the jacket?
That's $400, eh? Four hundred dollars.
Bitch, you killer blind and Scrooge.
So that's him, the big man.
Look, it's wearing a dress. Ha, ha.
Yeah, he's really a sweetie.
How you doing, mama? Looking fine.
Look at that.
That's his bitch.
Not bad.
Definitely prime cut.
Harry, you wouldn't know
what to do with that if you had it.
What will it be?
Beer.
If you have any clean glasses.
How about you?
- I would like Scotch on the rocks, please.
- You got it.
Thank you.
Hey.
Hey, babe.
I like that one even better.
Does she remind you of your old lady?
Yeah, a little, in the hips. Ha, ha.
How much she cost for the night?
More than you can pay in a year.
I got a credit card.
Harry, that's for gas, not for ass.
- All right, 50 bucks, is that fair?
- Ha-ha-ha!
Fifty bucks, honey. Are you worth it?
Your pimp boss doesn't seem to think so.
Tell your friend to cool it.
I don't own him.
Why don't you relax, friend?
That's what I'm trying to do.
Harry, you be careful of this guy,
because he's really tough.
Yeah.
Probably real tough
with some limp drunk.
Just want things to be cool.
Listen, I want a piece of that up there.
If I have to,
I'll take a piece of you with it.
- It's your move.
- Hah!
Look out, look out, look out.
Oh, no. This kid can fuck you up.
That man been Samsonized.
Here it come. Here it come.
No deal.
I just can't take him anywhere.
He... He's a menace.
Not anymore.
No, he certainly isn't.
Just keep your people out of here.
What...? Well, you run a bar here.
You have a license.
You have to serve anybody
comes in here, don't you?
Yeah, but they may not get
what they order.
This is a lousy bar with lousy service.
I'll sure buy that.
Samson, I'll see you later.
Nappa.
Take your garbage with you.
I'd hate for you to get fined for littering.
Okay.
That's right.
Eat your feet, white boy. Get out.
- Bye.
Fuck him.
Right on out the door.
Willie. All right,
let's play some groovy music.
Oh, that's beautiful, baby.
Oh, you're really beautiful, man.
You really done great.
Hey.
He almost broke his stick on your head.
Look, Harry, you take this.
You take this and you get a cab
and you get out of here.
Get out of here really quick...
...because this neighborhood
can close down on you.
Okay, man?
Hmm?
Hoodoo.
He's getting faster.
Okay, that's enough, brute.
How you doing, Henry?
What you holding, man?
I'm ready to boogie.
Broke it up.
That's okay, Henry,
we'll clean it up in the morning.
It's a damn shame, Mr. Samson.
That was a good table.
- Baby, let's go, I'm really tired.
- Okay.
Well, I-I gotta be finding myself
a place to flop, uh...
- I'm getting too old for this night life.
- You can stay here.
- Couldn't do that.
- Sure you can.
There's some food back there.
You can make yourself something to eat.
- There's even a little bed.
- I appreciate the food and the bed.
Then you're on.
You sure that lion don't eat at night?
No, Henry. He may roar a little bit,
but that's about it.
Oh, I ain't scared of him. No, sir.
You just get yourself some sleep,
and you can be my night watchman.
That's the ticket, Mr. Samson.
I always like to pay my own way,
so to speak.
Okay. Come on, baby.
Mr. Samson.
You are a righteous man.
- Good night, Henry.
- Good night.
Now, listen here, lion.
I don't want no shit out of you,
understand?
I hope you understand.
Because I'm from
an African background too.
And we know how to handle cats like you.
Catch on?
Oh! Goddamn it. Don't do that.
Don't you do that.
Should have left you in Africa.
And me in Peoria.
Good morning, darling.
Good morning to you, baby.
Where are you going so early?
I'm going to see the old man.
You're gonna leave me for an old man?
That's right.
Can't you stay just a little while longer?
Baby.
Baby, you are starting to bug me.
Johnny.
I'll miss you.
Shut up and get my coat.
You look terrific.
I'm serious.
See you later.
Hey.
What am I supposed to do?
Well, get out your crayons
and work on your coloring book.
Come on.
- Straighten up, here come the main man.
- The main, main man.
- I'm clean.
- Good thing we're all cool.
- Samson himself.
- How's it going, Deadly?
Right on, straight as your stick.
- Come to the club and I'll buy you a drink.
- I'll do that.
- Right on.
- Got a smoke?
- Yeah. There goes a righteous dude.
He keeps the honky motherfuckers
off the street.
- For how long?
- I wouldn't fuck with him.
No, sir.
He comes down with all the weight.
Then you start hitting
on a 13-year-old kid.
Putting the stuff on him.
Who sent you there?
I don't know.
What are you doing, man?
Messing with our people, killing them.
Just to keep your ass in gear.
Huh?
You ain't gonna tell the cops, are you?
They'll throw the key away.
That could been your head.
You wouldn't have been able to crawl
to a connection.
I'm gonna try to help you.
No cops.
But you gotta try
to get it together yourself.
That's Samson's turf, right there.
That fat piece.
Right in the middle of everything.
That reminds me
of one of those little countries...
...like Liechtenstein or Monte Carlo.
Neutral, untouched.
It's untouched.
Lots of profits in an area like that.
Yes, sir.
But it's not only that.
It's like a symbol, a special place.
Not good public relations.
Well, the word is, uncle,
that Arthur and his niggers, uh...
...will be moving in there very soon.
That would be very bad for our business.
Very bad, stupid.
Yes, sir, that's what I mean.
All I need is your permission.
I don't like rough stuff.
It doesn't pay anymore.
You are a good boy, Giovanni.
The longer he keeps the area clean, uncle,
the harder it is going to be for us.
We must move gently...
...explore, offer, reason together.
Yes, sir.
But Samson is not that type.
Don't look for trouble.
Be patient.
Bribe here, move a little there.
But intelligent, you understand?
Intelligent.
Yes, sir.
Now, I don't want you to worry
about a thing.
Our motto has always been,
as it was with my dear departed father...
God rest his soul.
- that the family shall not be troubled
at this most unfortunate time.
This is my business card.
On the back I have written
my home telephone number.
Now, should you need me for anything,
anything, don't hesitate to call me.
Bless you, Mr. Haven.
Bless you.
C.T., would you escort the lady
to her car?
Ooh, ooh, ooh...
Oh, nigger, what you laughing at?
"My dear departed father."
Shit.
- Whoo. What are you doing?
- How y'all been?
I'm fine.
How's business?
Oh, people keep dying,
just like a bad habit.
- Oh, I mean the other business.
- Oh, that one.
Mm-hm.
Now, that one,
that one's doing just fine, you understand.
I mean, that one just kind of sits in there
and cruises like the Hydra-Matic, baby.
It's better than ever.
I mean, look,
I can hardly keep up with the demand.
Word's out that you got people
on my street.
No, sir.
What's the matter,
somebody hustling you around?
Somebody pushing,
somebody hustling smack.
Well, he's not one of mine.
But maybe them white boys
is nibbling at you.
Maybe.
Yeah, well, there's rumors like that
floating around, ain't it, C. T?
So you know what old Arthur gonna do?
Get high.
I'm gonna stay cool.
Just gonna stand by the sidewalk and...
...watch it all go down. Ha, ha.
Just so long as you stay
on your sidewalk.
You know, we both grew up
in the same neighborhood.
And we both know exactly how it runs.
So now I'm gonna tell you
a little piece of advice.
Sooner or later, those white boys
are gonna move in here.
I can see that. So you had better get ready
to hold on to what you've got.
You on one side and them on the other.
Where are you at?
I stay out as long as they stay out.
When they make their move
and the war comes down...
...well, then I'm picking up the pieces.
Business is business.
Witness to the fact.
What about our people?
With me,
it's the law of supply and demand.
And with you...
You let me tell you something.
When Joseph Nappa brings his boys down
into this neighborhood...
...you are gonna be the only people
on that street.
That's where you're wrong...
...brother.
Ah, these dance-hall girls,
they come and they go.
They are a dime a dozen.
What are you looking for?
Just looking around.
Well, Samson's not here.
Oh.
He's got the easy life, huh?
Sleeping late.
But you, you're, um...
You're a hard worker, aren't you?
Not very.
You gotta be crazy
to try this in a nigger neighborhood.
The streets are almost empty.
And that alley, even emptier.
Know what you need?
You need yourself a big house.
Big house with people waiting on you.
Bringing you breakfast in bed, baby.
And flowers...
All right. What is it that you want?
Could I get a beer?
We just closed.
Shucks, just my luck.
Say, I'd like to tell you something.
You know your boyfriend, Samson?
Well, he doesn't like me.
Ha, ha. And I gotta admit,
I don't really love him either.
But he has got himself
in some bad trouble.
Ah.
I didn't know I could still do that.
Come here.
Come here, baby.
You're hurting me.
- Come here.
- Stop it.
- You don't touch me.
Get out of the way.
Well, I don't really understand. I, heh.
I come in here to give you some advice.
When I want a pinball machine
or a jukebox, I'll come to you.
You understand?
Times are changing.
You'll have to show me.
Mm-hm.
What can I do for you?
I want some information.
If I have it.
I've got some heavy dealers
sniffing around my street.
Why not go to your black friend, Arthur?
I have.
I assure you,
I'm not interested in your street.
I've given explicit instructions
to my associates.
How about Johnny?
Giovanni? He understands the situation.
I hope so.
Why make things so difficult?
My friend, I have the resources
to crush you in a matter of hours...
...if I wanted.
What would I gain?
A few people?
Trouble? Arthur?
I'm too old for that.
I wonder.
Import and export, that's my business.
Just so you don't import on my street.
You have my word.
Okay, we'll try it the old man's way.
It's a good deal, straightforward.
You better make a good pitch,
or I'll take care of that nigger my way.
Johnny, Mr. Nappa wouldn't like that.
Even a suggestion of violence.
Don't think.
You are not paid to think.
You are paid to talk.
And another thing, you fucking worm:
My name is Mr. Nappa too.
Mr. Nappa.
Don't you forget it.
I swear.
What do you want from me?
Excuse me. Are you Mr. Samson?
That's right.
I'm Michael Briggs.
I'm an attorney.
I understand, uh, you're the man
to talk to around here.
Well, uh, that depends.
Well, I represent a party
that has a business proposal for you.
Keep talking.
Well, it's, uh, rather confidential.
Okay, uh.
I know some place that we can go
and get by ourselves.
- Certainly.
- Follow me.
My lips are moving.
I think I'm talking. See if I'm talking.
Uh, I come up here a lot.
Come up here to think?
No, I just come up here.
Reminds me of when I was a kid,
you know?
When I wanna think,
I just heads off for the desert.
Heh-heh. That's a quiet place.
Well, it's more than that.
You know, you can get down
to what you really are.
Yes, sir.
There's my people down there.
All those souls
scrambling around, hustling...
...trying to make a living,
get a good time.
Mr. Samson?
Spit it out.
Mr. Samson,
it's a fact that you control this area.
Well, that's strong.
In any case,
I represent clients in the service business.
The Nappas.
I'm not at liberty to say.
Okay, I'll try to guess.
Well, my clients
want to open up your area.
And they're prepared
to make a very generous offer to you.
How much?
Fifteen percent of the gross.
Cash?
Can run as high as $200,000.
That's a lot of money.
It certainly is.
Well, that's the area down there.
Take a good look.
- What?
- Come on, take a closer look.
You're crazy!
Look at that shit.
Are you taking a closer look?
Please!
- I could drop you by mistake.
- Unh.
I can offer you 20 percent! Unh.
You don't understand.
I want these streets clean. Real clean.
I want you to go home and tell your clients
this neighborhood ain't for sale.
- I can't do that!
- You can't do that, huh?
Okay.
You can't do that,
your head's gonna open this cement.
Okay!
I don't want you to ever come back,
or I'll drop you.
You've had a rough time, Mr. Briggs.
You need a rest.
- How you doing?
- Just fine.
Haven't seen you in a long time.
You gotta look for me in the shade, man.
Uh, I might have some work for you.
Any time, any place, two bills.
You're the only thing
that hasn't gone up in this city.
Just give me a shout.
This door is my office.
That ought to keep you awake.
I'll be waiting to hear from you.
- Stay cool.
- Easy.
Hi, honey.
Hi.
You're new.
Today is my first day.
Do you know who I am?
Yes.
Tell the man I'm here.
I'm sure you know the way.
I would like to see you move.
My uncle is gonna keep you around here
a long time.
A very long time.
She's very easy to look at, huh?
You playing around, Uncle Joe?
A quick peek down the low-cut dress,
that's about all I am allowed these days.
Very sad, huh?
What the hell is all the money good for,
hey, Giovanni?
No charge.
Uncle...
...the gentle way didn't work.
Gentle way?
With the nigger, Samson.
Too bad. Stubborn.
He's an animal.
I couldn't do anything. Nothing.
We're losing face.
Don't make me laugh.
As long as he controls the streets,
our men can't be there.
Do you have something personal
against this man?
No.
He thinks he's a tough guy, that's all.
Maybe he is a tough guy.
- There's one way to find out, isn't there?
Giovanni.
Sometimes it is the measure of a man
to be wise and avoid a small trouble.
To take extreme measures,
that's a big step.
One cannot turn back.
There is no end until it is finished.
You're getting old.
Where is your pride?
You are talking to me that way? Pride?
What do you know,
with your fancy clothes and fancy women?
Are you suggesting that I,
Guisseppe Nappa, am afraid?
Do you want me to give you permission
to parade and play games?
I am suggesting that the black gangs
are nibbling at our territory.
I am suggesting there is one area
in this city that is unorganized.
We can take it.
We can take it and get back our territory.
Young blood.
It's always the same, testing themselves.
The smell of death, Giovanni,
it is not a nice smell.
I'm sorry.
If there were any other way,
I wouldn't have said a word.
Well, smart guy, you handle it yourself.
But if you get burned,
don't come running to me.
I won't.
It's a piece of cake.
Yeah, a piece of cake.
I know a man
who choked on a piece of cake.
Good crowd. Friendly people.
Yeah, not like last night, I'll tell you.
Forget about last night, okay?
All right.
If everything's fine, what's wrong?
Henry didn't show tonight.
Oh.
You're tired. Why don't we go home
and get some rest?
Get in bed with you and rest?
Hey, brother, could you spare a quarter...
...or some change or something for me,
babe, you know?
Samson!
Samson, stop! You'll kill him!
Stop it!
Stop it, you'll kill him!
Please.
You all right, baby?
You won't ever come back
on my street again, will you, brother?
No. No, man, no.
There's the quarter you asked for.
What are you drinking, baby?
Wine.
Rosé for a rose.
You know, Playboy says champagne
over peaches is the thing.
Now, you stop that.
Mama always said
dynamite came in little packages.
Psst.
Come on, baby.
Come, baby.
My love is coming down, mama.
Come here, mama.
I love the way you walk.
Love the way you move.
- I love you.
- I know.
- Hey, relax.
- Ha-ha-ha.
That was Johnny Nappa in the bar
the other day, wasn't it?
Yeah, that's right.
He's a bad dude.
So they tell me.
It's fact.
Don't worry about him.
You give him a pizza and he goes away.
You don't take anything serious, do you?
I take you serious.
I don't believe you.
Well...
...whatever we got, it ain't bad.
It's bad all right.
You're the bad man.
One, two, three, four.
You've got to help yourself
to lose those extra pounds.
They'll kill you.
- Oh!
- Ha, ha.
Baby, I think it's time you went to work.
- Me, go to work?
- Yeah.
- You like to dance, don't you?
- Sure.
Well, a fella I know needs a dancer.
- Are you kidding?
- Mm-mm.
What's it about, hmm?
Well, I wanna find out about this guy,
a nigger.
A nigger named Samson.
Ha, ha. A nigger?
Come on, Johnny.
You always said
you wanted to help me, baby.
And now here's your chance.
What can I do?
I want you to find out
about him. Everything.
I wanna know his habits, his patterns.
I wanna know where he goes.
I wanna know who he sees.
You're looking good. Really looking good.
I wanna know what his weakness is.
You understand?
- Sort of.
- Have fun, girls.
Just don't go playing around with him.
All right?
Why would I do that?
Three, four.
I'm just warning you in front, baby.
One, two, three, four.
More, more, more.
One, two. Now, let's sit up and rest.
And while we're resting,
let's just tuck into that double chin.
Chin up. Great. That's it.
It was three, four, five,
come up in my dream.
Samson.
Hey, Shine.
Hey, man, you're looking clean and mean,
all flash.
- Always, brother. Look, I owe you one.
- You don't owe me nothing.
Look, I know what I owe you.
I've been rubbing around uptown.
Hustling a little pool,
a few chicks, and listening.
There's trouble coming.
They put one out on you.
What did you hear?
Oh, not much.
But enough.
Now, I don't know where
and I don't know when...
...but it's a contract job,
I could smell that.
Hmm. I appreciate this, Shine.
Shit, man, if it wasn't for you,
I'd be making license plates.
One thing, brother. Watch your back.
Because if they nail you,
they nail an awful lot of little people.
Hey, girl, what are you looking for?
Mr. Samson.
He's right over there.
Watch out for that lion.
Thank you.
Well, now, where did you come from?
- I hear you're looking for a dancer.
- That's right.
I'm here for the job.
Okay, let's see what you got.
Now?
Up there on the stage behind you.
- Henry.
Yes, sir.
You think you can play something
she can dance to?
Yes, sir, real funky.
That'll do it.
She's good.
Mm-hm.
Damn good.
Yeah.
Uh, knowing you like I do,
I'm sure you gonna give her a job.
- Sure am.
- Ha, ha.
Hey, hey.
Man, that white girl's almost got rhythm.
She sure foxy.
Shake your ass, baby. Shake it again.
Lay it out, mama.
Oh, no.
The reason I come in here
was to get away from the old lady.
What do you mean, "love"?
I mean love.
Who set me up?
Fuck you.
- Was it Johnny Nappa?
- Unh.
Was it Nappa?
- Well, take him a message for me.
Unh!
- Want a drink?
- Yeah.
- Thanks, baby.
- Ah.
Wish we could always be like this.
Soon.
I just got a little more easy work to do,
and it's all gonna be mine.
What are you talking about?
Talking about that nigger.
Oh, he's not so bad.
What does that mean?
He's nice to me.
How nice?
Come on, Johnny,
I didn't mean anything.
He just talks to me.
You ain't found out nothing about him.
That's because there's nothing
to find out.
Come here.
Face up. If I find out
that you fucked that nigger...
...l'm gonna carve you nine ways.
- You remind me of him.
- Yeah.
Yeah, you know who signs the checks,
don't you, baby?
I sure do.
That's good.
All this worry
about some guy who runs a bar.
- Who's worried?
- All he cares about is that bar.
And Leslie.
He treats her like a queen.
Oh, yeah?
How does Johnny treat his baby?
Sometimes he's not too nice.
We won't forget that, will we?
What the hell do you want?
I need to talk to you.
Out, Tina.
Out.
I told you not to come around here.
I had to.
Start talking.
We missed.
Isn't that too bad?
How about a drink, Charlie?
Yeah, I could sure use one.
You know, it's really getting
to be a bad situation we have.
- We hire these people, and then nothing.
- Uh-huh.
Next time.
Next time?
There ain't gonna be no next time, Charlie.
Unh! Somebody cued him.
You cunt, you bitch!
Johnny, no!
You told him.
You told that nigger bastard.
Johnny, no, I don't know anything!
I didn't do anything!
Johnny, please, I don't know...
What's the matter, baby?
Oh, Samson, you know.
What do you want me to do?
I want you to get out of their way
before they chop you to pieces.
Well, that sounds good.
Then why not?
The streets are clean.
The people trust me.
The people?
Your brothers and sisters
ain't gonna do no dying for you.
Look, Samson,
let's say you get by for a month.
Two months, a year.
They'll get you.
Sooner or later.
They never give up.
You're just one man!
When you're dead, they're gonna move in
and just take over anyhow.
If I thought I could back off, I'd back off.
All you got to do is pack and get out.
It's not that easy.
This is the last chance
for our people to stand up.
Stand up and be a target?
Are you trying
to be some kind of martyr?
That's it, you wanna die, don't you?
Well, I don't wanna love a dead man.
That's sick!
I don't wanna sleep with a corpse!
A walking, talking dead on arrival.
I've got to hang on.
I can't watch it.
I don't wanna lose you.
Well, I can't make it work.
You've got to understand.
Well, I don't understand, baby.
- Sounds funky, Henry.
- Thank you.
Real funky.
Love that bourbon whiskey.
Yes, sir, in the hour of need,
it's the best friend a man could ever have.
You can take it with you anywhere.
You can take it for the blues.
Or the good old times.
Yes, sir, Mr. Samson...
...you're the only one
who still love to hear me play.
That's not true, Henry.
You still got it.
Hands like chicken claws.
They hurt.
Play that "Bama Dust."
Oh, that "Bama Dust," that's real music.
I don't know where I learned that.
Oh, shit.
People don't listen no more.
They've forgotten.
But there used to be a time.
The war made them forget.
It run them crazy.
I'm going back in the kitchen
to get me something to eat...
...if that's all right with you.
Yeah, that's all right. Go on back.
Thank you.
I just wanna tell you
something heavy is coming down.
Something heavy on the streets.
It's aiming at me, and I ain't running.
I just wanna tell you
so you can stay out of the way.
We know what's happening.
It's gonna be rough,
and it ain't your hassle.
It is our hassle, brother.
One way or the other,
it's coming back down in the streets.
At least, that's the way I see it.
And you've been handling the load
for too long.
I just want you to think about it.
We'll be around.
We'll be there, Samson.
I'm gonna have a good time tonight
if I have to kill myself.
Yes, baby.
Hey, baby.
Sure are looking fine, Leslie.
- Thank you, C.T.
- Good to see you again.
Arthur got your message.
Samson, my man.
Take care, brother.
Get happy, girl, get happy.
Well, if you loved me, baby,
you'd buy me some champagne.
Shit, if you loved me, you'd ask for beer.
- Hey, Samson.
- Yeah?
- Where's the dancer?
- Well, she didn't show.
She didn't show?
Jesus, white people are shiftless.
lt'd be okay if you were smart.
I am smart.
Why are you talking to me?
You a fine-looking woman.
That fine-looking shine
hanging on the wall...
...is my old man, and he ain't small.
He mean?
Meaner than that lion.
Busy as usual.
Where's the queen bee?
She's not around.
Not around?
You didn't do no doodah to that girl?
Ha, ha. No.
Well, I'm looking
for another place to flop.
Well, you can't stay here, Henry,
you understand?
Things are not cool.
l... I understand, but whatever. It's okay.
Here.
Go to a hotel and get some rest.
Hotel? Shit.
Well, what are you gonna do?
Live salty and die happy.
- Okay. Okay, Henry.
- Ha-ha-ha.
That Samson's a tough dude, man,
tough and straight.
I saw him mop up the floor
with two big apes right here.
No kidding?
Samson, mellow place, mellow.
Come.
Leslie, how you doing?
What's happening, Arthur?
I'm moving, mama.
Hey, it's been a long time.
I need some help.
I'm listening.
Samson's in trouble.
I know that.
I thought you said you needed some help.
I do. For him.
- Oh, bullshit, mama.
Hey, he dug the hole, let him fill it up.
I warned that nigger.
Now his ass is on the line.
And you're just gonna sit back
and watch everything, huh?
You got it, mama.
Just like old Satchel Paige,
I don't never look back.
You dirty motherfucker, you.
Ooh. Mama, say it again.
Oh, you'd just love to see Samson down,
wouldn't you?
That's why you won't help.
Shit on him.
Hey, wait a minute,
what do you think is going on out here?
You got some idea
that this is some little honky kids...
...with some cap pistols or something?
There is a war happening, baby.
There's a whole army
pulling up out there.
So, what can he do?
He can get the hell out
or he can get some help...
...because the rest of it is jive bullshit.
- Listen, I thought for old times' sake...
- No, no, no, wait a minute.
Now, you and I both know...
...that there ain't nothing staler or flatter
than somebody's old times.
And you and I both know
that he's not gonna ask you.
And I ain't about to hang my ass out there
for nothing, you understand?
Is there anything
that would make you change your mind?
Well...
Well, if you was to come over to me...
...well, then I just might save
that nigger's ass.
Do you want me?
I always wanted you.
But I don't know about now.
What would make it
worth your time, Art?
Something sweet and soft might help.
Hold it, mama.
Put them back on. I can't make it.
- I thought you said...
- Yeah, well, I thought too.
That's bullshit.
It's just a free fuck.
And I can't even do that for you now.
As for your friend, Samson...
...well, he's just gonna have to be as big
and as bad as all those people think he is.
Because if he ain't, his brains
are gonna be all over that sidewalk.
So, what you're telling me is,
is that you're not gonna help.
I'm telling you is that I am not a believer.
If he falls, tough shit.
But what if he wins?
Oh, well...
...in that case,
I'll plan the parade myself.
C.T.
You take care of yourself,
you understand?
Escort the lady out the back way.
You owe him something, C.T.
I'm Arthur's man,
and I can't solo it, mama.
Everybody's number comes up sometime.
Everybody's.
Let's get out of here.
"Go to a hotel."
Shit, I'm gonna take that money
and go do me a flophouse.
Know that lion is waiting for me.
How you do, pussy?
This is Henry.
It's me.
Hope Samson don't get mad.
I'll put it back.
Kitty, you know Henry is fair and square.
What the hell was that?
What kind of shit going on?
Oh, shit, C.T.
C. T?
Shit.
Old Henry boy.
He blew the whole goddamn place.
Motherfucker.
Henry's dead.
Coming down on the wrong man.
Well, what's Samson gonna do?
They own it all.
What the hell
is that damn boss doing down here?
So you've come to pick up the pieces.
The bastards are sure moving now.
- Why don't you ease up?
- Come on, Hoodoo.
- Yeah, brother. Come on, Hoodoo.
What, do you think I play like this?
They got me too.
They shot C.T. He's dead.
And they grabbed your woman.
Watch it, champ, I haven't got her.
She just came up to my place
to get me to bail you out.
They just grabbed her.
- Do you know where they took her?
- Hell, no.
Wherever she is now,
she's just bait in a trap.
- So it's me they're after, huh?
- You got it.
Well, where are you at now?
I'm studying the situation.
Look, Samson,
will you try and stay cool?
Will you try and make a deal?
They own the game.
Let's go, Hoodoo.
Harry.
I certainly hope you're comfortable.
You guys hold her hand.
He'll be coming along sooner or later.
Let's move it.
Oh, wow.
Wow, you really look
a lot better today, baby.
Well, I feel fine.
- How do you feel?
All right.
Where to, Mr. Nappa?
Oh, I don't know, uh...
Just around.
Yes, sir, darling,
I think you're gonna be all right.
Just don't be so mean to me.
Mean?
- You know I'm sweet.
- Sometimes.
Hey.
Hey, say:
"Johnny Nappa is a sweet guy."
- Johnny Nappa is a sweet guy.
- Ha, ha.
Thank you.
Jesus Christ, did you see that shit?
- Somebody just dumped her.
Just take it easy.
Nigger-loving bitch.
She's pretty, isn't she?
I bet she knows a lot about a knife too.
Tits.
Nice tits.
Hmm.
Nice ass.
Too bad.
We gotta decorate them
for your boyfriend.
How you doing?
- I'll get by.
- Yeah.
- Samson, you know why...
- I know. Johnny Nappa.
I knew it from the beginning.
Look, it didn't matter.
You couldn't have told him anything
he couldn't learn from the streets.
But they've got Leslie.
And they're setting it up for you.
Do you know where she is?
Will you tell me?
Please.
Hank, Wade, Billie, upstairs.
All right, rest of you guys,
outside with me.
It's that nigger bastard!
Look out, look out, watch it!
Hey, hey!
What the hell is going on?
Come on, get him.
Get out of my way.
Come on, let's get him.
Billie.
What the hell is going on in there?
Get him!
- Baby.
- Samson.
Goddamn it, answer me!
What's happening?
Get moving.
I think I'm about to cry.
- Come on, let's go, hustle.
- Come on, let's go.
Come on.
Come on, let's get him, team.
Fucking crazy asshole!
What the hell is wrong with you?
I don't know what the hell you're doing.
That's my car.
Hey, give me my car!
Give me my car back!
Watch out!
Move! What the fuck?
Look out, here comes another one!
Goddamn Mario Andretti.
Get on it, damn it, get on it.
What the fuck are you doing?
Men, he's on his way.
Don't panic, move it.
I need everybody.
Get that car moving.
Come on, move, move, move.
Get inside.
All right, all right, come on.
Are you okay? Move it.
Now you get the truck.
Come on, people.
All right.
Didn't you see the fucking truck,
you idiot?
Goddamn it, get it started!
He's getting away!
Move this fucking thing!
All right, move, you guys!
Into Samson's bar!
Back in that hotel.
Get up, Cord!
Hey, Johnny, what's happening?
- Come on.
There's nobody in the buildings, Johnny.
- Where is everybody?
- I don't know where they went.
I'll look in here.
- Get out here!
- Come on, Johnny, what's happening?
Samson, Samson, Samson!
Hey.
Yo, bring me that sink over there.
Honky having it.
Drop the damn thing, man. You got it.
Hit it.
I'll throw the whole
motherfucking building down on his ass.
Goddamn it!
Look out!
Bombs away.
Come here, white boy.
Out of my way. Bring them down.
Look out, look out.
He's going down.
Look out.
I got you now, you white motherfucker.
I'm going down.
Johnny!
Hold it, man. Hold it there.
Hold it, hold it. Don't throw nothing.
Wait a minute.
Get him.
They're gonna get it on.
You keep smiling, motherfucker.
Come on, kick the shit out of him.
All right, you piece of black shit.
It's come to this, huh? You and me.
- Like you wanted.
- Yeah, just like I wanted it.
We're gonna do it, and I'm gonna put you
on your knees in front of your people!
All of them!
Come on, nigger.
Watch out.
You see him step on that sucker's head?
It's all right, baby.
I know.
I'm gonna...
I'm gonna get you out of here.
I don't wanna go anywhere.
Well, I thought...
I thought we'd go away
for a while, and...
No, you were right, Samson. It's here.
Everything is right here for us.
You did it, ma... Oh, I'm sorry.
I can't believe all of this.
Is it coming down to me and you?
No way, not a chance.
Look here, can you get us a bottle?
I sure can.
I suggest that you do that, we take it,
go over there, have a drink...
...and talk about all this mess.
Like the old days?
Just like them, brother.
Come on.
Look at what these people
have done here.
Would you, uh, take care of this,
man, please?
Look at this. Look at this.