Double up now.
There you go. That's the way.
How's your wind?
Good. I'm up to five miles.
Add wind sprints.
OK.
Curious on
who you're gonna fight?
Doesn't matter.
Right. Double up.
Black Cloud.
Welcome, folks,
to the fourth annual...
Hey, Tyler, do you want
a snow cone or a cotton candy?
How about some popcorn?
I don't want him eating
all that sugar.
Aw, your mom's no fun, is she?
That's all right, buddy.
I'll take care of you.
Can I get him
a snow cone and cotton candy?
Ride 'em, cowboy.
Better bring in our next cowboy.
From Gallup, New Mexico,
we're talking about Eddie Young.
Come on.
Do we have any Eddie Young fans
out there?
Ladies and gentlemen,
I'm telling you...
this cowboy just qualified
for the nationals.
Outside.
Look out, cowboy!
But he's OK. Let's give him
a big round of applause...
for putting on quite a show
out there, folks...
and he's our winner right now--
Round Number One.
-Yeah!
-All right.
At the end of Round One,
it's a tight race, folks.
Here's our cattle.
You want me to come?
I was wondering
if you'd stop by.
I thought you might like
to see your son.
He's older than I thought.
It's been two years, Eddie.
It's been that long, huh?
Well, how you been?
We're doing fine.
Well, I'm glad to hear it.
Hey, I qualified for the finals.
Yippee.
There's my girl.
I got a free night.
What do you say?
Go to hell.
Damn, I miss your fire.
I don't miss you.
You sure about that?
Maybe just a little bit?
Don't you even
want to know his name?
What's the point?
Tyler, that's your father.
This is the last time
we'll see him.
ls he gonna turn left or right?
-Why you asking me?
-Because you know.
He's gonna fake left
and go right hard.
Navajo Nation.
Outside!
Yeah!
Hey!
Hey! Yaah! Come on!
Ha ha! Yeah, yeah, Jimmy!
Jimmy White.
Even losers get lucky sometimes.
Where's Sammie sitting?
They don't need you.
Heh. And she needs you, huh?
She's sweet meat, ain't she?
I'm going to forget
you said that.
No. You need to remember
who was there first.
Want to settle this?
Mine's the red Dodge.
Legs in.
Let it ride, Eddie.
-Come on, now.
-Outside!
Black Cloud,
how's the boxing going?
All right.
Heard your daddy was
laying in the road last night.
Sounds like him.
Nicely done!
His score is 35.
Listen...
Eddie's just passing through.
It's best
you stay away from him.
Sure.
All right.
Good ride, son.
Eddie Young, pardners!
Hem you OK?
No, I'm not.
Some things you can't change.
I'll meet you
at the chapter house.
What are you doing?
I'll catch a ride with Jimmy.
Don't worry.
All right.
Well, look who showed up.
If you want that slut,
you can have her.
I'm done with her.
It's time
you were taught a lesson.
And you're the bad-ass Indian
who's going to give me it.
Are we talking or fighting?
Enough. Enough.
Enough.
They're all whores, you know,
including your mama.
You need to learn
when to shut up.
Aah! Aah! Aah!
Aah!
Now, our brothers
who own casinos...
have invited us over
for a visit.
I suggest that we take them up
on their offer...
and see what kind of effects
it has had on their people...
and their land.
I say no to casinos.
The Navajo can prosper
only in righteousness.
That's right.
You are a wise man,
Joseph Ness...
but my heart and thinking
are different now.
Where is it written that being
sick, poor. and uneducated...
are better for our souls?
All right, enough. No more.
Go bother your parents.
Don't blame me
when your teeth fall out.
You're mean.
You got one for me?
The schools,
the medicine, the housing...
What happened to you?
I bumped into a wall.
You're not funny.
You all right?
I'd be better off
with a brownie.
Have you seen Bud around?
Not here. Lucky for you.
Does it hurt?
A little bit. You're good.
You want to be my corner man?
Ow!
Why do you do this?
You're better than Eddie.
I know that, but he doesn't.
Well, he does now.
One day...
you have to grow up.
Only if they make me.
Go home.
Get some rest, OK?
Hey, Black Cloud, man! Whoo!
Give me five, man! My son!
Whoo!
Here, have a drink, my man.
Come on.
Come on, join us, man.
I wanted to be simple
To be silent...
Why you disrespecting
my friends?
Here, have a drink.
Party with us.
It's time to send
your friends home.
Oh, I see. The party's over.
Black Cloud
says the party's over!
Come on! Come on!
Double up, man!
No, we have a good team.
Don't worry about it.
I got a few holes to fill
but we'll fill 'em.
I'll fill 'em.
No, just a lot of brawlers.
No skill.
Oh, listen, I got to go.
Rocket's here.
Yeah. Part of the game
I hate, but...
Listen, I got to go.
-Whoo!
-What's up, baby? Knock him out!
That's it. Keep your hands up.
That's right.
Hey, Rocket, it's
your favorite Olympic scout.
-How you doing?
-You know I'm doing good, man.
Move around!
Jam him, Cloudy! Come on!
Whoo!
Get your punk ass
back in your corner.
OK, come on.
Your rain man's going down.
Oh, yeah?
How much you want to go?
-Two hundred.
Breathe.
You can't hurt him
unless you throw him.
Black Cloud,
you can take this guy, man.
He's strong.
You're strong.
Hey, man, what's up with you
trying to holler at my man?
You know how many kids he got?
You're talking about money.
I'm talking about the amateurs.
There's no money
in the amateurs.
We're talking about
Olympic gold, Rocket.
Do you know what
it's like when it's mad cold...
you ain't got no heat, hmm?
At Christmas time,
there's nothing under the tree?
You know what that's like,
Norman?
OK, OK, OK.
Hold on, hold on, hold on.
What about this, OK?
I'll get you a car.
We'll talk to
one of our corporate sponsors.
-We'll get you a deal.
-You can get it for free?
Come on, Rocket.
I can bend the rules.
I can't break them.
You can't break the rules?
Rules are meant to be broken.
This is the amateurs.
And my boxer ain't no amateur.
He's a pro.
You remember that punk cowboy
last weekend?
You got him.
You got this guy, man, OK?
You get out first.
Don't wait on him.
Stay on your toes.
I'm going to go inside on him.
Good. Take a deep breath.
Get some gas.
Again.
Right.
Remember, stay on your toes.
Deep breath.
BOX!
Know how much more marketable
you're gonna be if your face...
is on a box of Wheaties
after he wins the Olympic gold?
Them suburban moms don't want me
in their kitchens.
They want me in their beds, kid.
If they saw a boxer-
Who is that kid?
That's Rocket's cousin...
the number one ranked
light heavy.
No. I'm talking about
the Indian kid.
Black Cloud
from the Navajo Nation.
The kid's got heart.
He got more than heart.
Overhand fight, Damon.
Come on, baby.
Yeah, let's go, Damon.
That's right. He out of here
like last year, baby.
Come on, Cloudy!
Cloudy!
Stop!
-Whoo!
-One...
-Yeah!
-Two...
Three...
Where the hell
did you come from?
Six...
Medic! Somebody calla medic!
How long before I'm on again?
Two hours.
That kid was a good fighter.
He almost had me for a second.
Oh, man.
You can't believe the buzz
about you out there.
Black Cloud this,
Black Cloud that.
"Who the hell is Black Cloud?"
Nobody knows, but I told them
they're going to know...
when you walk away
with this tournament.
All right. but you better cover
what you bet...
because I ain't got nothing.
Don't you worry.
I got it covered.
Oh, hey, I just ordered
this George Foreman grill.
Three payments of $19.95.
What's the matter with you?
You trying to get us
kicked out of here?
That's low rent, Jimmy.
I'm just trying to pay
the rent, Bud.
All right. all right. but when
you don't have gas money...
and need a buck for a Coke,
you don't come crying to me...
because I'll tell you
to die of thirst.
Then you can ride that mustang
around the rez.
And I ain't canceling
the George Foreman grill.
OK. How about
you get us burgers?
Oh, I see how it is.
You want me to be your slave
and carry your bag...
and get your burgers
and not get paid for it?
Want some fries?
Me and him been friends
a long time.
Yeah. They're hard to come by.
Let me look at you.
Yeah.
The swelling"; coming down.
You don't even know
when it happens, do you?
What?
What happens in the ring?
I don't know. I just fight.
Crossing over
into the spirit world...
is a powerful thing.
What do you mean?
Where you went...
Our ancestors called for you
and you answered.
There was this one voice
that rose above the rest.
You are chosen.
Figure out
why they're calling you.
Great.
I thought only medicine men
had to deal with this.
Excuse me, guys.
I don't want to disturb you.
I'm Norm Olsen.
I saw you fight today,
young man.
Black Cloud.
Nice to meet you, Black Cloud.
How long you been boxing?
I've been fighting
my whole life.
What is it you want, Mr. Olsen?
I don't want anything.
What's your name?
-Bud.
-Good to meet you.
No, I just--I saw something
out there today...
that I haven't seen
for quite some time.
Oh, yeah? What was that?
I'm sorry.
I didn't get your name.
Jimmy.
Look, I saw raw talent today...
combined
with clarity of purpose.
And I was just wondering-
You know, you got a gift.
What you plan on doing with it?
What's it to you?
I'm just a man who doesn't like
to see talent wasted.
Oh, I see.
Unless I play by your rules,
I'm a waste.
You ever think of boxing
in the Olympics?
The question's never been asked.
Well, he should.
He's incredibly talented.
And a man only gets so many
highlights in his life...
and I guarantee you...
you box for your country
in the Olympics...
it'll be one of them.
And your interest?
I'm an Olympic boxing scout.
Aw, forget it.
I ain't interested.
Cloudy, let's hear
what he has to say, man.
No. I ain't interested in what
the man has to say.
Well, why's that?
Because it's lies.
It always is.
I'm sorry.
I'm not following you.
It's in their soul.
They don't know any better.
And why should I fight
for your nation...
when all you've done is murder
and imprison my people, huh?
Black Cloud.
I didn't invite you here.
You're not welcome.
Black Cloud, I've done nothing
to your people.
Look, there's
an Olympic trial in Vegas.
You should be there.
I fight for the Navajo Nation.
Fine. Nice meeting you, Bud.
See you around, kid.
What are you doing?
He's the stallion
the elders talk about.
How did you catch him?
He caught me.
Come on.
I got someplace to show you.
I can't just leave the kids.
Jackie-'ll Watch them, right?
-Sure.
-Come on.
Always thought
that I could be John Wayne
Come sunset,
I'd sweep you away
But I don't feel much
like him today...
It's magnificent.
He's free.
How do you find these places?
Finding grass for the goats.
When there's a drought,
you look everywhere.
I like to call this place
the Valley of the Gods.
I think this is where
they would visit.
Do you ever get scared out here?
There's nothing to be scared of.
The Winter Wind, maybe
That'll kill you...
if you're standing around,
looking stupid.
That's right. I forgot.
You're a big, tough brave
who's not afraid of anything.
There's one thing I'm afraid of.
Really? Let me guess...
losing a fight to a white boy.
Heh. Never gonna happen.
The dentist?
Never really needed one.
What?
Losing you.
That's the sweetest thing
anyone's ever told me.
I love you.
I love you more.
I guess I really need
Something I can see
Something I can hold
Someone to hold me
I guess I'm trying to say
That you're the only way
You're the only one
Button your top button.
And fix your tie.
My tie ain't gonna make
a difference.
Could you please
just try and be nice?
I'll go wash behind my ears
in case he looks there.
Hi. Can I help you?
I have a housing appointment
with a Mr. Turpin.
Your features are too delicate
to be a Hopi...
and the way you carry yourself-
too refined for a Ute.
No. No, neither tribe is
privileged to call you theirs.
You're a Navajo.
I'm Turpin.
Let's see how I can help you.
Come on in.
OK.
I read in the paper
that a housing project...
with 600 homes might get funded.
Do you have any idea
how long that waiting list is?
I, uh, I can't see
you getting a house for...
three to five years.
However...
if you would
like to have lunch...
we could explore other options
that I'm sure would cut
that time down considerably.
You are of legal age, correct?
Turned twenty-one last winter.
That's fantastic.
What an exciting time
in a woman's life.
You're so full of power
and freedom over your choices.
Would you care for a drink?
No, thank you.
Are you sure?
It's cherry schnapps.
Goes down really easy.
Oh, you know, I just remembered.
There are several homes
that are currently unoccupied...
because they're being renovated.
Do you have an application
I could fill out?
Sure you wouldn't like a taste?
Yeah, what do you want?
Are you OK?
I'm fine.
Mr. Turpin was just telling me
our options for a house.
Uh, yeah, I'm Ron Turpin.
And you are?
Black Cloud is my boyfriend.
Oh. Well, that's interesting.
Look, Why don't the two of you
just Wait outside, and I'll--
I'll deal with this after lunch.
Boy, how time flies.
Things took
quite a bit longer...
as I had unexpected company
for lunch.
Mr. Turpin, we've had a long day
and we have a long drive home.
We'd like to do what we need
as far as applying for housing.
Oh, sure. I'm sorry I took up
so much of your valuable time.
But rights to benefits
is a black-and-white issue.
Or, should I say,
a red-and-white issue.
Heh.
Do you know your bloodline?
I know my mother and my father
and my grandfather.
Yeah, well,
that's not surprising.
Most of you don't know
more than that.
But then, lucky for you,
it's all recorded.
Here's your certificate of
Indian blood. Looks good.
Now, your C.l.B.
is very interesting.
Your mother, Victoria Ness--
Who's deceased, correct?
was the daughter
of Joseph Ness...
still alive-
and Mary Bahe--deceased,
who were the children of
Joseph Ness and Elsa Johnson...
who were the children
of White Wolf and Nanebah.
And that's as far back
as I need to go...
because that's where
your trouble lies.
White Wolf...
also know as Hans Schroeder,
born in Hamburg, Germany.
I've walked with blue eyes
in the dream land.
Well, next time
you and Gramps go for a hike...
maybe you can tell him
to keep it in his pants...
or you can punch him
in those blues eyes...
and make 'em black because
boy, you are a mixed-blood"...
and your name
on this application...
pushes Miss Haskie
to the back of the line.
You're a small man.
You hide behind your fear.
-Excuse me?
-Let's go.
You took what
you had no right to take.
Look, I think
it's time for you to go.
-Listen to your woman.
-You stink with fear.
Look, I don't have
to listen to this.
Out! Get out!
Before I call the po
i--
They say TO Pity 3/0'-I
Turn it off.
Are you gonna be OK?
I'm gonna be fine.
It doesn't matter to me,
Black Cloud.
It matters to me.
Please don't do this.
If you don't want to be with me,
I'll understand.
Listen to me.
You gave me hope
when I had none.
Tyler and I love you very much.
You're everything to us.
So, please...
don't bring it up anymore.
Good night.
Good morning to you, too.
It's been a long time
since you stayed a night.
It's good.
So, how you been?
We're just fine.
No wolves about today?
No wolves for a long time.
Last wolf, three toes.
You sure there's no white wolf?
Somewhere in the darkness?
Where's my keys?
Where's my keys?!
In the bedroom, maybe.
Where in the bedroom?!
Hey, Mom.
Hey, baby. All right.
Look at that move.
You got the move, baby.
Ohh, look at that.
Snag. Snagaroo. Ha ha!
I can't find my keys.
Party's over! Everybody out!
I've kicked you out before.
You're done messing
with Indian women-
Hey, bro,
she was touchin' me, too.
All right, all right!
I'm goin'.
Hey. boy. BOY
Boy.
Whose house
do you think this is?
It's the white man's house.
It's not yours.
Everything we have isn't ours.
What are you saying now?
I'm saying you disgust me.
You shame our family
and you shame our people.
What the hell happened to you?
I know about White Wolf,
and why we're cursed.
White Wolf who?
Forget it. Where's my keys?
You're not getting the keys
till you fix my stereo.
Come on, you ain't so tough.
Come on.
This ain't the boxing ring.
Just give me my keys!
All right.
Don't bite the hand
that feeds you, huh?
You're smart.
Not like your mother,
who always talked too much.
What the hell you doing
wearing her ring, anyway?
-You show me?
-Yeah.
Hold it.
Can you tell me why there's
two sheriff's cars pulling up?
What?
Get inside.
Ya-te-hay, Sheriff.
What brings you out here?
Well. if I said
it was the beautiful scenery...
I'd be
yin', wouldn't I?
How'd the army treat you?
Saw some things.
Some good, some bad.
You were f
yin'
one of those tank killers.
What do they call those things?
Apache.
Isn't that funny?
A Navajo f
yin' an Apache.
Ya-te-hay, Sheriff.
What brings you up here?
Well, that's the second time
I've been asked that...
so I guess I'd better answer.
I'm looking for the driver
of that truck.
Gym room.
Go get him, boys.
Hold it.
No disrespect intended, Sheriff.
Why don't we talk out here?
Step aside now
and let my boys do their job.
If they have a job to do,
I won't get in their way.
Now, why don't you tell me
what's going on?
You got any firsthand knowledge
about this?
'Cause if you don't,
we got nothin' to talk about.
Please call Lieutenant Yazzie
and ask him to come out here.
OK, Chief.
Now, Bud,
Why'd you have to go...
and complicate things
like that, man?
Look, I've got the victim
in the hospital...
and I've got three witnesses
to the attempted murder.
Attempted murder?
Right.
Who's in the hospital?
Bud, We're not in the habit of
divulging victims' information.
Lieutenant Yazzie's
already headed this way, honey.
What happened, Black Cloud?
I taught Eddie Young a lesson.
That's bullshit, son.
You tried to kill him.
He'd be dead
if I wanted him dead.
ls that a fact?
Why don't you get in the car...
so we can go downtown
and clear this up?
Stand still until
we talk to Lieutenant Yazzie.
You got no power on the rez.
You and I both know you can't
stay on the rez forever.
Say, isn't your sister
married to a Young?
Yeah. That's my nephew
lying in the hospital.
Not smart.
What are you doing?
You know you're supposed
to give me a heads-up...
when you're on the rez.
See? You have no power here.
Son, don't be ta
kin' shit
you can't back up.
Now, get in the car.
Shut up.
We have an attempted murder,
we have a positive ID...
and we want Black Cloud
for questioning.
Black Cloud, get a lawyer...
and we'll go in
for questioning tomorrow.
No deal.
We think he's a risk for flight.
We want him now,
we want him confined...
and we don't want him
running around the rez.
Question him now.
Without a lawyer?
What do you want to know?
Where's the bat
you assaulted Eddie with?
No bat. Just these.
Cliff, this sounds like
a fight went wrong.
This wasn't just a fight, Bud.
My nephew's
laying in the hospital...
with a pierced lung
and he's fightin' for his life.
You crossed a line, son.
Attempted murder follows you
anywhere you go.
Now, get in the car!
I ain't goin' nowhere!
This incident...
happened on the rez.
Don't pull that shit, Bud...
cause it'll come back
to bite you.
You people don't live in some
self-sufficient world out here.
Sooner or later,
you gotta go into town...
cash your check,
and pick up a six-pack.
I think I've heard enough.
I'll look into it.
There were witnesses.
I'll let you know what I find.
All right.
You played this one wrong.
If that's the way you want it,
that's the way you'll get it.
I'll be seeing you.
Black Cloud...
if Eddie dies, there ain't
a man in this world...
that can protect you, son.
That's a promise.
Stay out of trouble.
What's wrong with you?
You've got everything.
Why do you want
to throw it away?
Eddie had a chance.
This stops now.
Now, here's the deal...
you live under my roof...
or we can't work together.
That ain't gonna work.
I come and go as I want.
I'll be seeing you.
Black Cloud. What's going on?
Not much. ls Sammie around?
Yeah, she's inside.
But let's talk about something
out there for a second.
So, what's up?
A complaint came into
the tribal office...
from Mr. Turpin
at Indian Affairs...
while you were gone.
Yeah. Me and Sammie
went up to Gallup...
to apply for rez housing.
Mr. Turpin says
you assaulted him.
He pushed Sammie.
Did Eddie--who's lying in
the hospital--push Sammie, too?
I'm seeing a side of you
that I don't like.
This doesn't only
just affect you.
You need to think
about Sammie and Tyler's future.
I'm sorry, Black Cloud.
I really am.
Don't feel sorry for me.
I'll be all right.
Tell Sammie I'll be seeing her.
I want you to stay away
from Sammie.
Don't make this harder
than it already is.
Hey, Black Cloud.
Somebody give him a beer.
Give him a beer, man!
What are you guys up to tonight?
The question is,
can you keep it up tonight?
Damn, bitch. Are you in heat?
I'll go look for him
in the kitchen.
I'll look over there.
Sol hit him over and over.
When I finally quit...
the whole side of his face
was, like, mush.
Ha ha! That's awesome, man.
Awesome.
The best part
about beatin' the white...
is the shock in their eyes.
Deb, what are you doing here?
Hey, Jimmy,
you want to be my stud?
This guy's so lame.
Look,
when your brother finds out...
you're gonna be in trouble.
They don't care what I do.
Go home.
Who invited Black Cloud?
I did.
And he's staying the night, too.
Can't let him
drink and drive, you know?
Black Cloud.
What are you doing here?
What does it look like
I'm doing?
Having a good time.
Yeah.
Why didn't you call?
Since when do I need
your permission?
Move.
What the hell is going on?
What do you mean?
Since when do you hang out
with these losers?
This is my tribe.
They're not losers.
We're the Mixed-blood Clan!
Mixed-blood!
This is my new family.
Black Cloud, you're nothing
at all like them.
You're special.
Why are you doing this?
Because it's in my blood,
Sammie.
My blood is poison.
There's nothing
I can do about it!
I don't care who your
great-great-grandfather was.
You don't want to be
with a mixed-blood...
or have mixed-blood kids.
Look what happened last time.
Last time...
I got Tyler.
Do you see it bothering me?
Don't you get it?
This isn't gonna work.
We're not gonna work,
so get the hell out of here!
Here's your beer, Black Cloud.
Hi, Sammie. It's been a while.
I'm not looking back.
Bud, open up! Bud!
What gives you the right, huh?
To sit up all high?
You're just as bad as they are!
I thought
you weren't coming back.
Well, I'm back. So what?
Where you been?
Partying-
What's to celebrate?
Custer, that white prick.
Heh. I'm ce
ebratin' him.
They took it all, Bud!
Fuck.
You're right. They did.
You're gonna let that
ruin your life?
I'm taking it back.
I'm taking it all back!
Well, put down your beer
and come on in.
Bud, I can't remember
what my mom looked like.
She was pretty, right?
She sure was.
Yeah, I thought she was pretty.
Your mom and my wife were
the two everyone was after.
And I was lucky I got one.
I'm a mixed-blood.
Yeah. I know.
Sammie.
I thought you were dying.
Well, I am, without you, baby.
Please go away.
Hold on, Sammie.
Now, I know
I haven't treated you right...
but I'm here
to make it up to you.
Eddie, too many things
have changed.
Can't a guy get a second chance?
I mean, to make it right
with his--his family?
Hey.
Taylor, buddy. I'm your daddy.
What do you want, Eddie?
You don't know how many times...
I picked up that phone
to call you, but...
I just didn't know what to say.
But I swear to you, baby...
I thought about you
all the time.
I loved you once.
But I don't even
recognize you anymore.
Well, let's go out
and do a little dancin'...
a little drinkin'.
You'll remember me then.
Sammie, you're the only one
that's ever done it for me.
The last time we went drinking,
we made Tyler.
He's the last good thing
you'll ever do.
Look around you, Sammie.
This is your future.
It's pretty, ain't it?
I told you I'd get you.
I guess you were right.
I can't stay on the rez forever.
Had to get my beer.
Well, you'll find
I'm right about a lot of things.
So, are you gonna pull me out
and beat the piss out of me?
I might.
What are you waitin' for?
You know, Eddie's ignorant...
but he didn't deserve
what you did to him.
Eddie got the girl.
He's all right.
Beat me 'cause you Want to.
What are you doing?
Resisting arrest.
Get back in the truck.
Make me.
What happened to you?
I'm who I always was,
just another drunk injun.
So come on! Open my head!
You are drunk. Do you know
who you're ta
kin' to?
Sure, you're the cowboy.
I'm the injun.
Come on, John Wayne!
Time to take me out!
This isn't a movie, son.
If I take you down,
it's gonna hurt.
So hurt me already.
Come on!
So, you like John Wayne movies?
So do I.
I remember watching
John Wayne and his boys...
take out them injuns
by the hundreds...
makin' it safe
for all the wagon trains.
Things were a lot simpler then,
weren't they?
Yeah.
Till one day, I'm sittin'
in front of the TV...
shootin' down injuns
with the Duke.
Then I stopped 'cause
I realized I was one of them.
That's the day you started
hatin' the white man.
That's the day I became ashamed.
Son, we're all dealt
different hands in life.
The sooner you learn to play
yours and stop b
uffin'...
the quicker
you'll find your place.
Are you gonna beat me or not?
Come on, pussy!
Where you goin'?
I'm here! Come on!
Go home, Black Cloud.
Don't know what it is,
but the little girls love it
I like it, I love it
I want some more of it
Hey, Black Cloud!
Yo, you going to sit
on the couch all night?
Come on, man,
get up and help us out.
Sing us a tune, man.
No, I'm fine right here.
You have fun.
Yeah. Argh!
Aah!
Yee heel
You know,
I want you to know...
that I forgive you
for breaking my stereo.
Yeah, I'm sorry about that.
In fact,
I want to thank you...
cause if you hadn't, I Wouldn't
have gotten that beauty.
I'm ho
din' umbrellas
and openin' up doors
I'm takin' out the trash
and I'm sweepin' the floors
Dad, do you remember
what Mom looks like?
I'm like this
cause I like it
I love it,
I want some more of it
I try
Come on.
You're dropping your hands.
I can land those all day.
So, you're a mixed blood, huh?
Big deal.
We're all mixed up some way.
Shut up.
You and Sammie split up, huh?
Where'd you hear that?
It's written all over your face.
She's better off without me.
First smart thing
I heard you say.
Why's that?
First sign of trouble
and you run.
It's best now she knows
what kind of man you are.
I said shut your mouth!
Shut it for me.
See? You can't even put
one foot in front of the other.
You can't think.
You're so full of fear!
What are you afraid of?
Shut your mouth!
I already told you
to shut my mouth...
and you can't even do that.
Your daddy's a drunk,
and your mama died...
and you're a mixed blood.
Poor, poor Black Cloud.
What do you know about shit?
A lot of people who have it
harder than you don't quit.
You betrayed your nation.
You fought for the whites!
If you want to hide behind
your ignorance, go ahead.
You're the ignorant one.
Come and shut
this ignorant mouth.
Come on, kid. Shut my mouth.
That's it. That's it.
That's it.
Look...
we'll beat this.
I've been expecting you.
You leave tracks easy enough
for a blind man to follow.
Things have changed.
I can see it in your eyes.
I'm a mixed-blood now.
The truth was always the truth.
Now it is known, and it is good.
It's good I lost my girl?
That I'm at war
with the white man?
You have to lose yourself
before you find yourself.
I can't find crap.
It's all decided for me.
Are you done whining?
Let's walk.
Where are we going?
To the past.
So, you want to hear
about White Wolf?
In the last days...
a girl named Nanebah...
took a pony
to a special place...
where she would pick flowers
for her wedding dress.
Three white men came upon her.
Nanebah was found wandering
with her head full of demons...
by a white hunter.
He became White Wolf,
your great-great grandfather.
He brought great honor
to our people.
We accepted him as our own.
Did you meet White Wolf?
Rest.
I will be waiting
on the other side.
What the hell was in that tea?
Where do you want to go
with the herd today?
I was thinking
that little box canyon...
with the spring?
Grandpa?
Grandpa.
Thanks for coming.
What?
Where are we going?
Thanks, friend.
Black Cloud, what are you doing?
I need to talk with Sammie.
Daddy.
I'm sorry. I've done nothing
to dishonor us.
I have nothing to be ashamed of.
My blood is good.
ls this how it's gonna be?
'Cause my heart can't take it.
I'm sorry.
I'll never leave again.
You better not.
I will love you forever.
I love you.
I love you more.
I know I don't have much...
but whatever I have
I will give to you.
What are you doing?
I know you could do better,
but I promise you...
you'll never regret
giving me a chance.
You sure?
Will you marry me?
Yes!
Hello.
Hey, Bud, it's Norm Olsen.
You still coming?
Yeah. We'll be
pulling in around 3:00.
Great. Just make sure
he's in shape...
'cause he's gonna be facing
one tough kid.
I hope he shows up, 'cause
my guy's ready to be seen.
Hey, he's never
done this before, right?
-Uh-uh.
-You sure he's up to it?
This one's different.
He doesn't fight for attention.
He fights because he needs to.
The sun on my shoulders
And the wind at my back
Bound and determined
to get back on track
To where the heart is
Where it's been all along
Sometimes you don't know
what you got till it's gone
Gone, gone, gone
And I've been out there
searching
For a place where I belong
And on my way I heard my song
Let it sing me home
Be sure to bring my fianc
home in one piece, OK?
That's up to him.
I remember the night
before Bud fought...
for the army championship
in Germany.
I was pregnant with Christopher
at the time...
and I was so afraid for him.
I didn't know you had a son.
Our son was killed...
a long time ago
by a drunken driver.
I'm sorry.
Hey, what's up, everyone?
This is Missy Bitsui,
and she's raised traditionally
so she's not down
with the English.
Isn't she great, man?
I think I'm in love.
ls this what you guys feel like?
Where you guys off to?
Gonna shoot some pool.
She's the one. I can feel it.
She's gonna pop me out
a lot of good kids.
Jimmy, she doesn't even
speak English.
How do you know?
Body language, Cloudy.
That's the only language
that doesn't lie.
Having some fun, baby?
Say exactly how you feel
Right now
you're free to sail off
There is no one here
to judge you
I only love you
You're free to close
your eyes and fall
You can trust me
This is real
Say exactly how you feel
Tell me...
I know we're not married yet...
but I was wondering
how you felt about having kids.
What do you think?
I asked you first.
I don't think
we should rush or anything.
The only question in my mind
is how many.
I love you so much.
I love you more.
Be ever
Mine
Hey. you guys want a Coke?
Don't forget to breathe.
I'll be right back.
I'll meet you at the table.
Well, I gotta give it to you.
You kicked the crap outta me.
You're out of the hospital.
That's good.
It's not good for you.
Eddie, look, I'm sorry
for what I did to you.
But I didn't know the things
I know now.
When we're done with you,
you won't know nothin'.
Well, what do you know, boys?
Caught us an Indian.
-ls that him?
-Yeah. That's the one.
Hey there, red man.
We don't have
no plastic L.A. friends
Ain't on the edge
of no popular trend
Ain't never seen
the inside of that magazine...
My neck's always been red
My collar"; still blue
We've always been...
Jimmy.
Jimmy, Black Cloud"; gone.
I think something's going down.
You've always been
Red, white, and blue
-Yeah!
-Let's get him!
Feels good, doesn't it?
Come on, red man!
How's that feel, huh?
Unh! Aah!
Who'll save you now, huh?
Who's tough now?
Go! Get out!
Come on, get out!
Jimmy?
Jimmy! Jimmy! Lay still, man!
Lay still!
Somebody call for help!
Lay still.
It's gonna be all right, Jimmy.
It's gonna--Somebody call
for help! Oh, my God.
Jimmy. Jimmy. Jimmy.
That boy bled a lot.
Kid's touch and go.
Doesn't look good.
Shit. Hell of a night.
So, you want to tell me
your side?
Eddie shoved a bottle
in Jimmy's throat.
Same Jimmy that's been beatin'
on people with pool cues?
They were gonna kill
Black Cloud if he didn't.
Boys were just giving him
a little payback.
Got a little carried away.
But the way I see it...
it's just--just
an unfortunate accident.
Fight gone wrong.
Isn't that what
Bud called the last one?
Those cowboys
are going home tonight.
It's funny the way
justice works, isn't it?
It don't care who pays...
as long as the scales
are evened up.
They're not even,
and they never will be.
You're right.
Guess it means we'll be seeing
each other again.
Black Cloud...
hear you're headed to Vegas.
There comes a time
in a man's life
A challenge will come
You either stand or get whacked
Got your back against the rope
But there's still hope
If you gotta go, leave swinging
Makin' sure the whole world know
There comes a time
in a man's life
A challenge will come
You either stand or get whacked
Got your back against the rope
But there's still hope
If you gotta go, leave swingin'
Makin' sure
the whole world knows
Now, I got
Nike, Puma, and Adidas...
ready to holler at my man...
and y'all want him
to stay amateur?
This guy's crazy.
We're talking about one year
out of your whole career.
The money'l
be there, bigger,
after the Olympics.
Man, don't listen to this idiot.
His kids can't eat
no Olympic medals.
Now, what we're gonna do is,
we're gonna win the tournament,
you're gonna knock him out,
we go pro, and that's that.
It's up to you, bro.
I mean, it's your call.
Show me the money, man.
Shit.
'Cause I spent too long
a poor nigga, you understand?
No. Know what I understand?
I understand you just made...
the biggest mistake
of your whole life.
Man, what do you know?
You don't know shit about me
or where I'm from.
-Hey, Norm.
-Nice to see you guys.
Hold up. Fall back, man.
We havin' a meeting, all right?
No. Our meeting's over.
-Over?
-We been dismissed?
Not unless you want to meet who
you'll be fighting in the final.
-Who, Tonto?
-Yeah.
Hey, knock it off, man.
Calm down.
Show respect.
Chill out, chief.
We ain't even ta
kin' to you.
Shut up.
Oh, come on, red man.
Shut my black mouth up.
OK, OK. I'm white,
you're black, he's red.
Now that we have that resolved
for our color-blind friends...
Rocket,
go on with your day, man.
Go on with your day.
You better hope we don't meet!
Yo, Dusty,
you better talk to him.
Come on, dawg.
Sorry about that, man.
It's not your fault, Dusty.
You tried, I know.
Yeah.
How's the hothead?
Hothead's hotter than ever,
as you can see.
Yeah. Thanks
for getting me registered.
What changed your mind?
I'm seeing things clearer.
Made some peace.
You didn't turn into
a flower child, have you?
OK, this is the way
it's gonna go.
You're gonna be fighting
the best in the country.
If you win,
you go to the Olympic trials.
Any questions?
When do I start?
Ahh
Now, everybody ready?
All right, here we go
To the tribes, reservations,
all my nations, check, check
Where my natives
with the bomb at?
Who them natives left
these long tracks?
You love hangin'
with this warrior?
Hell, yeah
Do these goddesses ignore you?
Hell, nah
From the east to the west,
who the best?
Who on the rez
got honeys with chest
Who got 'Vettes,
spark the gets
Catch sack rats
in matching sets
Do you lean back
when you ride?
Flip the switch
from side to side
Three wheel
make big dawg smile
Do it again,
but let me slip on in
Did you see that?
I didn't see a thing.
He's way too quick.
He's gonna sleep awhile.
Neutral corner. Neutral corner.
By unanimous decision...
Black Cloud!
Black Cloud,
where do you come from?
I'm from the Navajo Nation.
And what's the Navajo Nation?
It's our homeland.
Bud, where'd he get his name?
In the summertime...
when those thunderstorms
roll in with black clouds...
you'd better duck.
Ooh.
You like to throw a double
hook-uppercut combination.
Where'd you learn that,
Jack Dempsey?
No. I, uh, I fought
a big cowboy on the rez.
It's the only thing
that worked on him.
Ain't you funny?
But I ain't no cowboy.
I'm a nigga from the hood.
You ain't never seen
someone like me!
I guess we'll see about that
tomorrow, huh?
Tomorrow you're gonna be
runnin' till I catch you...
and you be cryin' for your mama
while I'm hurtin' you!
Hey, Rocket,
when you gonna take him out?
When am I gonna take him out?
After you beg me for more...
then I'll take him out.
Black Cloud, what do you have
to say about that?
A big mouth is
a sign of fear and ignorance.
I'll take you on
right now, Tonto!
You, the Lone Ranger, Silver,
your whole goddamn posse!
-Let's go.
-You ain't shit!
Tomorrow.
You ain't even
in my same league, dude!
I got some-thin' real
for your ass in these hands!
Cut off the ring
and bang on his arms.
Are you ready?
I'm good.
How's your hands?
They're sore.
Just one more to go.
This is the one I wore.
It's yours if you want it.
Land of the free
And the home
Of the brave
Come on, baby!
Yeah! Let's go!
-Come on, Rocket!
-Let's go, dawg!
OK, guys, this is
for the championship.
Congratulations
on making it here.
I want a clean battle.
Keep your hands up,
protect yourself at all times...
and listen to my commands.
All right?
Touch gloves
and go back to your corner.
I'm gonna enjoy this.
I know I will.
Pay attention.
Fake right and drop him.
You are the baddest southpaw
ever were.
This man is a dog.
You gotta go fight your fight.
He does not belong
in the ring with you.
We got a lot of paper
riding on this thing, baby.
-Sit your ass--Sit down!
-Let me--
Remember what it took
to get here...
and remember who you are.
Navajo Nation.
Yeah!
-Yes!
-That's it.
Stay on him.
Give me some more!
Get off the ropes!
Man, gotta cut him off.
Break! Break! Break!
Rocket, keep the punches up.
Let's go! Box!
Yeah, Rocket!
Come on, Black Cloud--Unh!
You ain't nothin'!
Come on, honey.
Stop! Stop!
You're goin' down!
Go back to your tribe!
Whoo! Whoo!
Cause I'm the best!
He's fast. He's fast.
You want to slow him down?
Go to the body.
Use your right hand.
Every time he goes southpaw,
use your right hand.
Step inside his jab
and hit him with that right.
Knock his ass out.
He is a dog.
He does not belong
in the ring with you.
Look at me now. He's fast.
You're strong. You go down.
You take his right out
and go down on him.
Let's go, baby. Let's go.
Game time.
I got him.
He just don't know it yet.
Stay out of the corner.
Keep your hands up on the break.
That's it! Whoo!
-Down!
-Oh!
-Stay down! Stay down!
-One...
We can smell that money, baby!
Two...
-Stay down!
-Neutral corner!
Three...
Four...
Five...
Get up. Get up.
Six...
Seven...
Let's do it!
-Where are you?
-The championship!
You ready to go? You OK?
-Uh-huh.
-All right.
BOX!
Ha ha! You're done! Ha!
So...you had enough?
Black Cloud!
Stop! Stop!
Go to your corners!
If that happens again,
I'm gonna stop the fight.
Let him decide it, ref.
That didn't go so well, huh?
Didn't go so bad.
Still standing.
Breathe. Breathe.
Any ideas?
How bad do you want it?
Then you gotta take it.
Come on, buddy! Let's go!
-How you fee
in'?
-I'm fee
in' good.
-What's your name?
-I'm Rocket.
Get in there
and tear his ass apart.
Go get him.
It's my turn!
You should've stayed down!
I'm gonna make you suffer!
Yeah! Knock him down!
Hit him with the left hook,
baby! The left hook!
Knock him out, baby!
Yeah, Black Cloud!
Got him now.
Down! Neutral corner!
Neutral corner!
One...
Two...
Three...
Hi, baby.
Mama?
You're so beautiful, Mama.
Just like I remember.
My time with you was short.
I was needed here.
I need you.
I know, baby.
You're on the right path, son.
You'll find the way.
If darkness surrounds you,
ask your father in the sky...
and the way will be shown.
I'm scared. I'm alone.
You're never alone.
Can I stay here with you?
ls it nice here?
It's paradise.
Four...
It's hard back there.
Five...
I know, baby.
You have much to accomplish.
You know I'm with you always.
Now...go back.
Fulfill your destiny.
Can I see you again?
Anytime you need.
Go, Black Cloud.
Go.
Six...
Seven...
Eight...
Nine!
You want to go on, kid?
Was Custer scared?
Let's go. Box!
Yeah!
Yeah! Stay on him!
N01
Whoo!
.Ye$!
Get up! I got too much paper
riding on you!
Whoo!
You're champion!
Where the hell's
the Olympics anyways?
You were right.
My mom is beautiful.
Mile upon mile got no direction
We're all playing the same game
We're all
ookin' for redemption
Just afraid to say the name
So caught up now in pretending
What we're seeking is the truth
I'm just looking
for a happy ending
All I'm looking for is you
YOLI came LIpOl'l I116 wave OI'! wave
You're the reason I'm still here
Am I the one
you were sent to save?
When you came upon me
wave on wave
I wandered out into the water
And I thought that I might drown
I don't know what I was after
Just knew I was going down
That's when she found me
Not afraid anymore
You said, "You know,
I always had you, baby"
"Just waiting for you to find
what you were looking for"
YOLI came LIpOl'l I116 wave OI'! wave
You're the reason I'm still here
Am I the one
you were sent to save?
And you came upon me
wave on wave
YOLI came LIpOl'l I116 wave OI'! wave
You're the reason I'm still here
Am I the one
you were sent to save?
You came upon me wave by wave
Wave on
I fell by the wayside
I fell on my knees
Crying
Why was I so hard to please?
I stood at the crossroads
Took a long look at me
Sometimes you don't know where
you're from till you leave
And I been out there searchin'
For a place where I belong
And on my way I heard my song
Let it sing me home
Sun on my shoulders
And the wind at my back
Bound and determined
to get back on track
To where the heart is
Where it's been all along
Sometimes you don't know what
you've got till it's gone
Gone, gone, gone
And I been out there searchin'
For a place where I belong
And on my way I heard my song
Let it sing me home