(cheerful orchestral music)
(upbeat music)
(tiger roaring)
- Smile.
Well, you finally got
to see L.A. Zoo, Debbie.
- Yeah, it was fun, Lori.
- That's one of the reasons
we're stewerdesses, right,
to see places and people?
- Right, Lori.
That reminds me, I gotta go back to my
apartment and get ready
for my next flight.
- And I want to get a birthday present
for my boyfriend, Chuck.
- Chuck, oh he's that
guy from San Francisco.
- The guy, Lori, the guy.
- Oh, he's cute.
Let me drop you off at Olvera Street,
you could get a real nice present there.
J' Would you like for me to
take you out for the night J'
J' To have a good time, go
dancin' in the moonlight J'
J' Just a look at you, it
makes me feel all right J'
J' Do you wanna be with me tonight J'
J' You look so good to me J'
J' And to everybody else
around, yes, around J'
J' You makin' me happy, girl J'
J' 'Cause you're turnin'
everyone up and down J'
J' You know how I want you baby J'
J' Would you like for me to
take you out of the night J'
J' To have a good time, go
dancing in the moonlight J'
J' Just to look at you, it
makes me feel all right J'
J' Do you wanna me with me tonight J'
J' Now we can spend all
night lost in each other J'
J' So let me hear you say, I want you J'
J' And you want me J'
J' So we can be together
la la la la la la la J'
J' Whoa oh whoa oh J'
J' Would you like for me to
take you out for the night J'
J' To have a good time, go
dancing in the moonlight J'
J' Just to look at you, it
makes me feel all right J'
J' Do you wanna be with me tonight J'
J' I wanna kiss you, yes I'm
helpless in your charm J'
J' In your charm J'
J' I already miss you, girl J'
J' And I haven't even been in your arm J'
J' Don't you know how I want you, baby J'
J' Now would you like for me to
take you our for the night J'
J' To have a good time, go
dancing in the moonlight J'
J' Just to look at you, it
makes me feel all right J'
J' Do you wanna be with me tonight J'
J' Do you wanna be with me today J'
- This little piggy went to market.
This little piggy stayed home.
This little piggy had roast beef.
This little piggy had none.
And this little piggy
went wee wee wee wee,
all the way home.
- Hey look let's try
something different tonight.
- What do you want me
to do, stand on my head?
- Now this is different.
Pressure.
- Chuck.
Chuck?
Chuck, are you asleep?
Chuck, are you here?
You bastard.
- Debbie?
Oh shit.
Debbit, Debbie wait a minute.
It's that what you think, Debbie.
She's my cousin.
Debbie, Debbie?
Debbie, Debbie, Debbie.
Debbie, wait a minute,
it's not what you think.
- Stick this with the rest of them.
Maybe this'll cool off your hot pants.
(phone ringing)
Yeah?
- [Ben] It's Ben Brewster.
' Who?
- It's Ben, Ben Brewster, how are you?
- Look Ben, this is a bad time to call.
Do you think you could
call me later, please?
- Now look Debbie, this
is strictly business.
Nothing personal.
I've got a charter coming out to my ranch.
Now if you and your friends are free,
you could work the flight for good money
and a two week vacation on the house.
Now how does that sound?
- Hey, it really sounds
like a good idea, Ben.
I'd like to, thank you, bye.
(upbeat music)
(phone ringing)
- Hello, who's there?
- [Debbie] Debbie.
- Debbie, hi, how are ya?
How's Chuck?
Oh.
- I got a call from an old friend of mine.
He's invited me and a couple of friends
for a free two week
vacation at his dude ranch.
- A ranch?
With horsies?
- Yes, but he wants us
to have a junket flight.
He's putting in a gambling casino.
- Gambling, that's naughty.
- Be at the Mountain Airline
counter at 8:00 tonight.
That's where we'll meet the man.
- Man, that's nice.
- Now Lauren, I want you to be good.
- Oh, I'll be good.
I'm always good.
- Promise?
- I promise.
- Okay, I'll see you at the airport.
- Okay, bye Debbie.
(orchestral music)
- You work for Brewster's
Lucky Dollar Ranch?
- What do you guys want?
- This is gonna happen to anybody working
for the Lucky Dollar.
(screaming)
(upbeat music)
" Ben?
You're gonna pluck them
clean just as soon as
the gambling starts, huh?
- It could be.
- Now come on you old fox.
You've got a gold mine
here and you know it.
I just hope you believe
in sharing the wealth.
- Meaning?
- Well meaning I hope you're
not gonna be selfish about it.
- Now look, Trask, you're a foreman here,
but I'm running this operation
and don't you forget it.
Now if you don't like it here--
- Wait a minute, Ben.
- No, no, you wait.
- Like to get your hands
on that wouldn't you?
Well eat your heart out old-timer,
you haven't got a chance.
She buys and sells guys like you.
She buys them cheap
and sells them cheaper.
- Don't bet on it.
- You two at it again?
- Oh it's nothing unusual.
We're all a little bit
edgy after last night.
- Oh I heard about that.
Can you believe it, hooded riders.
Somebody's been watching
too many late movies.
Anything I can do to help, Ben?
- No Honey, but it was nice of you to ask.
That's what neighbors are for,
besides I have a special interest here.
Ben, you sure you can trust him?
- Frankly, no.
Hey you know Honey, maybe
I ought to try your racket.
- Ben Brewster, you don't
have my natural talents.
- Well that's for sure.
(Playful music)
- Hey, hey, here.
Hey, let's do the leg thing.
- The leg thing, the leg thing.
- It's your leg, it's a bad leg.
Hey, hey.
Get off, get off.
Here's another one, I got it, I got it.
_ Help, help.
Over here, help.
- Hey, wait a minute.
Help wanted.
Lucky Dollar Guest Ranch, five miles.
- Well, let's give it a shot.
We might get lucky
- Let's go up there, come on.
(upbeat music)
- Hello, are you enjoying your flight?
Good.
Hello, I've got your drink.
- Thank you.
- Good.
Hello, how are you today?
Oh, I know what you want, there you are.
And of course, to make it real, real good,
that goes with it.
Oh, you little rascal.
Hi, whoops, hello.
Hello, hello, can I get you a drink?
There you are, there you are.
And what would you like?
Oh, no you can't have that,
but you can have this.
Hi.
- Miss.
- Hi.
- Hey I'm really glad
you guys could make it.
I hope this trip isn't a mistake.
- Where there's men, money, and action
it's never a mistake.
- She meant that Brewster's
just another rich old man.
- But some rich older men are lots of fun.
It depends what angle you view it from.
Horizontal or vertical.
- A lady never tells,
at least that's what the ladies tell me.
- [Man] Miss.
- Well, I once knew rich old men in Miami.
$1,000 a month penthouse, four cars,
and he didn't even charge me
and my girlfriend any rent.
- And he treated you like a father.
- But how do you know?
He had me call him daddy.
- And I bet only wanted
to do was to spank you.
- Oh, you know him too, huh?
- Well say Debbie,
what's the story on this?
- You know, it's like
the free trips to Vegas.
We get the big spenders to
roll their money at the tables.
That's all.
- No one can ever accuse
Brewster of not having an angle.
Oops, a customer.
- And I have a pilot
waiting for me who needs
some encouragement, S€€ YOU.
- Lori, what are we gonna do for fun now?
- With a plane full of men?
- Wow, I see someone interesting, later.
- Whoops, whoops, oh.
- Miss.
Miss?
- Your coffee, sir.
- Excuse me miss, where's the restroom?
- To the rear of the plane, sir.
- Thank you.
- Watch your step.
- Hi, I'm Debbie.
What's your name?
- Bob, Bob Travers.
- I think I'll call you Bobby.
Let's get acquainted,
tell me about yourself.
- I don't usually like
to talk about myself.
- Okay I'll tell you about myself.
- That would be much nicer.
- Well I was sold to white slavers,
but my wicked stepfather
when I was only 5 years old.
- Hi guys.
Hey, listen guys, I don't really need you.
There's lots of action
back there, you know.
- No Jackie, we need you up here.
- Well since you guys seem to
have everything under control,
I'll go check the Bombay.
- But you're bomb already.
- This isn't the high
and mighty, you know.
After all it takes guts
to fly in this war.
- I know, I know.
Just bring me a Cutty
Sark, will you, please?
- And watch the zeroes.
They like to sneak in out of the sun.
- Get lost, will ya?
Oh what a way to be flowing on the job.
- Are we coming on schedule?
- Making outwith you, you
I think I'm losing my head.
- When are you going to
bring the landing gear down?
J' They had only one more time J'
(upbeat music)
(Playful music)
- Say Captain, are we on time?
- He's about a quarter of the three.
(sensual music)
- And then I joined a gang of girls,
and then we made an oath
in blood and it was awful.
I'm only joking with you,
I'm just putting you on.
- Yes I know.
That must be turbulence.
Everything's okay, isn't it?
- Don't worry, it's only Jackie.
- Jackie?
- Emergency.
Give me a tall scotch in a short water.
- Oh, you're flying higher
than we are already.
- Near turbulence, just turbulence.
Where's yours.
- You kidding?
You went for a booze down at
drunken Indian, now would ya?
Oh my goodness.
Oh Debbie, Debbie.
Oh, you're making any luck, aren't you?
Jimmy, stop it, stop it.
Jimmy, Jimmy, here, here, here.
Now you take this to
somebody who needs it, okay?
- Open up, open UP-
This is your captain speaking.
AI, AI.
- Okay, but wrestling's off limits.
- Hold this.
It's really stuck.
- Well, pull it.
- I'm pulling it.
- Here.
- Turbulence.
- No, Jackie.
- Oh, I wanted to get you alone.
- I knew it, it's a bad, bad dream.
You let me help you.
Yeah, oh let me get your little button.
Oh, the one little button.
Oh, now your tie.
- Get me out of this, get me out of this.
Get me out of this.
Get me out.
- I don't mean to make anybody nervous,
but who's flying the plane?
(soft music)
- Well folks welcome to
the Lucky Dollar Ranch.
- Hi, hello.
Have a good time now
Hey, Honey come here a minute.
I want you to meet the
girls I told you about.
- New recruits?
- I say it's more like competition.
Girls I want you to meet Honey Morgan.
Honey, this is Debbie Stewart,
Barbara Watson, Lori Winters,
- Hi.
- Hello girls, welcome.
Well now, we want you to
have a good time and relax.
Ben here's an old friend of mine
and I'm gonna take care of you.
- Just like a mother, huh.
- Exactly.
Rodeo starts in about an hour.
We're gonna have a high old time.
- Oh, a rodeo, terrific.
Here's Bobby.
- Hello.
- Bobby, I'd like to
introduce you to Honey Morgan
and Ben Brewster.
- Hi.
- Hello.
- Come on girls I'll
show you to your room.
Now we need a pretty girl
to ride in the parade.
Any takers?
- Listen, I'd love to.
I've been taking riding lessons.
- Your first time out West Bobby?
- Not really, I get around quite a lot.
- I bet you do.
Well I think you'll find
people real friendly
in this neck of the woods.
- That's very nice.
- Could be nicer.
If things become too quiet at Brewster's,
why don't you stop by the
Beehive and say hello.
Beehive, Honey, dig?
- Thank you, not ma'am.
- Oh, not ma'am, madame.
J' Getting back to Georgia J'
J' Gonna pull myself together J'
J' And I hope your heart
will let me stay around J'
J' 'Cause without you I got nothing J'
J' Are you gonna put me down J'
J' Have I lost the day I found J'
J' Can you realize that I've changed J'
J' And my plans didn't work out right J'
J' But they're over now J'
J' I'll admit I tried not
to think of you, love J'
J' But the thought of you was too strong J'
J' Getting back to Georgia J'
J' Gonna pull myself together J'
J' And I hope your heart
will let me stay around J'
J' 'Cause without you I've got nothing J'
J' Are you gonna put me down J'
J' Have I lost the day I found J'
- Barbara, Debbie.
Hi, you guys.
Hey, come on and teach
me how to play some golf.
- Lori, we don't even
know how to play golf.
- Oh, she just wants to
teach us a new way to swing.
- Ha ha, well, come on.
I'll teach you guys then.
I see them play it on TV
all the time, come on.
- What about the rodeo?
- [Lori] We got time.
- Play them all, I'm hungry.
- That's not how you play golf.
- That's baseball.
- Yeah, that's right.
- Playing golf, eh?
- No, they're playing basketball.
- Don't be a wise guy, will you.
Now look, let me show you how
to address the ball, right.
Now you hold, just bend over a little.
Just, I'll tell you.
Hold this little this stiff, you see?
This arm, oh boy.
Hold this arm very stiff.
Arm, hold it, that's it.
Now and this leg also has to be stiff.
Come back, that's it you see.
That's it.
And this arm has to be stiff.
And this leg has to be stiff.
You don't mind, do you?
- No.
- But he does, so don't forget.
This arm stiff and this leg is also stiff.
Now, come back very slow.
Wait, I'll tell you what you do.
You stand over there and I'll show you how
to hit the ball, right.
- These are two handicap.
(Playful music)
- It slipped, I'm sorry.
Le me try it again.
- He's a two handicap.
Will you hit the damn ball.
He's a 22 handicap.
- Let's go to the next tee.
- Here we go again.
Hey, that's our golf club.
- No, you gotta stay on.
You're not allowed to fall off.
Leave him alone, you get nervous.
Tanks, I said Tanks.
Oh, Tanks.
Tanks, you've got to stay on, I'm sorry.
Tanks, stay on, damn you.
Now he hears me.
Maybe he likes my dialect.
(applauding)
Ride him, ride him, Tanks.
Atta boy, hey Jacks, keep going man.
- How do you know it's Tanks?
- I know its Tanks.
And you know, I feel
bad for him, you know?
- Why, Wm'?
- I got his underwear this morning.
Oh, he's in a tight spot.
Hey, Tanks.
- What's the matter, sweetheart?
You look down in the mouth,
not enjoying the rodeo?
- Oh nothing's wrong.
- Oh come on, you can lay it
on the line with mama Morgan.
- Well, you see I rented
this new apartment back east,
but the people who live there
didn't move out in time.
So I let them stay
there and I got a motel.
- That was nice of you.
- But that was three months ago,
and they still haven't paid the rent.
And now I owe for my rent
and I owe on my car payment,
and I owe for my motel and
I don't know where I'm going
to get the money.
- Lori you came to the right person.
You heard about my place, the Beehive?
- Oh, the Beehive, Ben told us about that.
It's a--
- It's a gold mine.
You need money?
You're not alone, lots of girls come over
and work a few days, make a few dollars.
Stewardesses too.
Why give it away?
- Oh I couldn't do that,
but I'll think about it.
(upbeat music)
- Yes, ma'am.
- Hot dog, please.
- Hot dog.
- Hot dog, why of course.
- Thank you.
- Hamburger, please.
- Hamburger.
- hamburger, sure.
Hamburger for the
gentleman, there you are.
- Fried egg sandwich, please.
- Fried egg, fried egg sandwich?
Make him a fried egg sandwich.
Comes in here with a fried egg sandwich,
he has to make a fried egg sandwich.
- You give him a fried egg.
But you'll have to let me
know when they're done.
- I'll give you a count down.
_ okay-
- One.
Two.
Three.
Foun
Five.
Six.
Seven.
Eight.
Nine.
One.
Ten.
- They're done.
- Good, let him have it.
Don't you know what you're doing?
- I want to welcome you all
to the Lucky Dollar Ranch.
I'm Honey Morgan, your
friend and neighbor.
Ben Brewster asked me to
act as sort of a hostess
and provide a little entertainment.
Most of you know that I'm
pretty good at hostessing,
and as far as the entertainment goes,
well you could be the judge of that.
(soft music)
J' Oh it was easy J'
J' So very easy J'
J' To run around and
cause you all the pain J'
J' Our friends all left behind your back J'
J' When I became a clown they
never said a word to me J'
J' They always put you down J'
J' The things that I needed J'
J' There beyond our door J'
J' I found them all and
tried them on for size J'
J' You told me that they wouldn't fit J'
J' And I called you a name J'
J' You didn't cry, I wondered why J'
J' I thought it was a game J'
J' Now the game is over J'
J' And I've added up the score J'
J'All I ever needed is
standing in this door J'
J' Oh it was easy J'
J' So very easy J'
J' You stay away and make you stay alone J'
J' The price was right and it was fun J'
J' While living in the sky J'
J' But when I fell I hit so hard
the price became too high J'
J' Now the game is over J'
J' And I've added up the score J'
J'All I ever needed is
standing in this door J'
J' Yes all the time the
only thing I needed J'
J' Was to hold you in
my arms, to be there J'
J' To be close J'
J' ls it fair for me to
ask that you forgive J'
J' My wandering and believe I
changed my life, well I have J'
J' And it's bare and
it's sad, do you care J'
(applauding)
- Gee, I wish I could be like her.
- No, you don't want to be like her.
- What's wrong with that?
- You wouldn't understand, doll.
- I'm a big girl, now Mike, try me.
- Okay I'll V)' Y0“-
Honey Morgan, that's who
I'm talking about, the user.
She devours people, men and women alike.
Uses one against the other,
and when she's through
with him she drops them,
just like that.
And man I know.
When I think of what
I'm doing for that dame,
ah forget it.
- Oh I get it, you're sweet on her, huh?
- Yeah, I'm sweet on her.
How'd you guess?
You know something, doll, you're nosy.
(Playful music)
(audience applauding)
- Folks, I have a small
announcement to make.
I guess you all know by now
that my gambling equipment
has been delayed, but the
trucks with the equipment
are on the way.
By tonight there'll be plenty of action.
(suspenseful music)
- The truck's about three miles away.
There's nothing ahead of him.
Go get them, Eric.
Get those cars in place.
Just stay out of sight
and stay out of danger.
Well, you win a few, lose a few.
- We missed you over at
the Beehive, stranger.
And I extended a personal invitation too.
- I didn't mean to be impolite.
I really did mean to come.
- You did?
(soft music)
- It's warm here, isn't it?
- It's even warmer at the Beehive.
- Hey, steady b0)'-
How'd you like that kiss, steady boy?
You get a charge out of
that, or didn't make you mad?
- Mr. Trask, you should be more careful.
- You better be more careful, steady boy.
You're gonna get yourself in big trouble.
Big, big company-
Met your match, steady boy?
Hey, I'm talking to you.
You listen to me.
Don't you walk away from
me when I'm talking to you.
You listen to me.
Listen to me.
You listen to me, you listen to me.
You listen to me.
Sushil animus pig.
I said I was talking to you, now get up.
Get up and fight.
Come on, hit me, hit me.
Hit me, hit me.
- Mr. Trask, I think you've been drinking.
- You think I've been drinking?
He thinks I've been drinking.
You yellow belly.
Don't walk away from me, damn you.
What did I can I do to
make you hit, damn you?
Give me a damn you.
Damn you, damn you, damn you.
- I can't understand why
that man was so angry.
(sensual music)
- That's it, Kenny, I've had it.
I quit.
Okay, how am I doing?
- Barbara, you're not
exactly Billie Jean King.
- Bobby, I like you to meet
my tennis teacher, Kenny.
He's the pro around here.
He's teaching me all the tricks.
- [Bobby] If I taught you all
the tricks, you'd be the pro.
- When I do learn, watch
out, Billie Jean King.
By the way why don't you two try it?
- No thank you.
- I think I'll let you play, Barbara.
- Chicken.
- Hi, Ben.
- Hi.
- How are things going?
- Not so good.
They got all my gambling
equipment, this could be it.
- They seem you know what
you're doing before you do it.
- Yeah, you're so right,
but I've still got a couple
of tricks up my sleeve.
- That's the way to go, Ben.
- Ben, have you seen Lori today?
- Last I saw her, she was
headed for the Beehive.
You know I think our little Lori is doing
a little moonlighting.
Well I got things to do,
kids, I'll see you later.
- Well that little dingbat.
- Oh God, we can't leave
her alone anywhere.
- Come on, let's go over
to Beehive and get her.
- I've got into drive into town anyway,
can I give you a lift?
- Thanks a lot for the ride, Bob.
I appreciate it.
I'll see you later.
- Thanks Bob.
- All right girls, settle down.
Do pass these out sweetheart.
Well, I always like to have a little talk
with my new girls.
It leads to a better understanding.
Now we're all here for one thing, money.
And may be a little fun.
Now that paper that you have
lists all the do's and don'ts around here.
I run a tight ship so I
want you to learn them.
Memorize them.
- I'll wash out for sure.
- One more thing, very, very important.
You're not in business for yourself,
so there's not to be any wallet boosting
and there's not to be any
con about your sick kids,
and you're not to pry
into the personal lives
of the customers.
This is the class operation
and I'm paying you top dollar.
And I want you to make
sure that the customer
wants to come back.
Now our motto is you tease
them, you please them
and I fleece them.
Melody.
Girls, I want to introduce
you to a Beehive exclusive.
Girls, meet Mabel.
- Hello, Mabel.
- Hi Mabel.
- Babel handles the drunks.
You get a drunk that's too far gone,
just hand him Mabel in the dark.
There's a Mabel, nude of
course, in every closet,
in every room.
One old minor liked Mabel so much,
he bought her and lived
happily ever after.
Does this doll really work?
- Of course.
If they're drunk they
can't tell the difference.
- Does she have, you know, everything?
- Well, sweetie not everything you have.
- No, but she makes a lot more sense.
- All right, girls dress rehearsal.
I have a customer waiting.
Now let me see.
- Take it easy, will you please lie down?
- Oh you should mouth shall pretty.
Can you turn a damn light on in here?
I get scared in the dark.
- Listen don't be afraid, I'm here.
I'm here, okay?
- Are you awake?
- Oh, did We do it?
Was I good?
- You were great.
- Oh goody, let's do it again.
- Come here.
- It's do it again.
- Excuse me.
- Don't go away.
- I'll come back.
Listen you just practice
and take care of yourself.
You need the practice.
What am I gonna do now?
- I don't know.
Maybe he'll pass out soon.
- No.
- Hold it, I got an idea.
- Give him Mabel.
- That's a terrific idea.
I'm back.
- Oh yeah, oh yeah.
You feel better than you did before.
- Oh, it sounds like they're
having lots of fun in there.
- You little dingbat,
you're the reason why
we're here in the first place.
Come on, I'm gonna get you
back to that Lucky Dollar--
- No, I don't wanna go.
- Oh yes you are, we're going back.
(folk music)
- You don't talk much, do you?
What's the matter, honey?
You need some rolades?
Honey, it's all right.
I'm not mad at you.
Honey...
Anybody got a pump?
- Well Mike, what did you
want to talk to me about?
- Brewster's making another shipment.
The boys are ready to take it.
- Good.
Anything else?
- Mm-hmm, I got a funny feeling.
Brewster's up to something,
I want to call it off.
- You want?
You work for me, it's what I want.
- I thought we were in this together.
- You thought, look this is just a job.
Take it or leave it, don't
try to make it personal.
- Personal?
It was personal once.
We were good for each other, Honey.
We could be again.
- Mike, you just don't want to understand.
It's over, we are over.
- Honey, please.
- Mike, just play your cards right.
When the word gets around that there's oil
under all this land that
we've been grabbing--
- Okay, okay, I get the message.
- You ready to go in?
- Yeah.
- Me too.
Lori? - Yeah?
- Lori, come here.
okay
What do you want?
- Hey, let's go to our rooms now.
- But I like it here.
- No, you don't.
- I don't?
- No, besides we can't leave you here.
You can't even swim.
- We've got lifeguards right over there.
- Yeah, what trouble can she get into?
_ okay-
- See you later.
- See you guys later.
- But you stay right there.
- Yes, mother.
(Playful music)
- We're right in the middle.
(upbeat music)
- Help-
Help, I'm drowning.
- Somebody's drowning.
- Nevermind her, just throw a card.
- But somebody is drowning.
- Help, I'm drowning.
Help.
- Will you throw a card?
That's it, gin.
Now let's go get her.
- Help, help I'm drowning.
- We'll be right there,
we'll be right there.
Stop screaming.
- It's cold.
- Let's go get her.
Not there, by her legs.
It'll be all right,
everything will be all right.
Everything will be all right.
This kid is not a feather.
- Resuscitate her.
- What?
- In front of everybody?
- Blow in her mouth, blow in her mouth.
No, closer.
- Closer?
- My prince charming.
- What the hell's happening?
What do they want?
- Beats me, man.
You know, I'm beginning to
believe there's some truth
to those old legends.
- Oh, legends hell.
Legends don't steal gambling equipment.
I'm gonna get--
- Sure Ben, sure.
If there's anything I can
do to help you, let me know.
- You haven't been a much help
lately, I'll tell you that.
- You once told me that you
wanted to run the operation.
Okay, you run it.
I'm just your Foreman, remember?
I ain't a cop.
(soft music)
- You know, I'm hungry.
- Well, it's lunchtime, let's eat.
- Where's the salami?
Salami's down here.
- Where's the pastrami?
- Pastrami's down here.
- We can put in one place.
- Where's the Swiss cheese?
- Swiss cheese is over here.
No, pickles.
- Yeah there's some
horseradish down there.
- Tomatoes, oh to get some soda too.
- Oh you want a soda?
- What's the difference, eat.
It's all on there.
- Where's the sardines?
Got some sardines there?
- Sardines here?
- Somewhere there.
(soft music)
- Any salami left?
- One more piece, right here.
- Oh good.
- Oh enough here, buddy.
This is all we have.
Any cheese there?
- Cheese, cheese right there.
- Right there?
That's good?
- Where's the corned beef, any left?
- No more corned beef.
- No more corned beef?
(soft music)
- I'm sorry.
- Excuse me, have you
gentlemen seen Mr. Brewster?
- Brewster went after
hoods with the hoods.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
- Who's that?
- That's Bobby.
' Who?
- You know, Bobby Lipschits.
(orchestral music)
Bobby, is that you?
- Bobby, is that you?
- Name is Bob.
Which way they 9O?
- They went that way.
(whistling)
- He's witty, isn't he?
(intense music)
- After him, get after him.
- Hey look out, here comes
the truck, the truck.
Back up, watch the truck, watch it.
- Hold it, okay, you proved
your point you're a stet.
Now you're not gonna whip me,
and I'm not I'm gonna whip you,
so what do you say we call it a draw?
Okay?
No, better still, you win.
All right?
- I like that.
- Honey child, I want to talk to you.
- Ah, sit down, Ben.
- And you know I've always wanted to buy
into your operation, right?
- Right, but I'm still not selling.
- I kind of think you will.
Now that is Mike Trask's
signed confession.
Now if we become partners,
that goes into my safe.
Ifnotu
- Looks like you got a partner.
- I'll take that.
Shake partner.
- Sure I can't persuade you to stay?
- Thank you, ma'am.
My work here is done.
- Oh, I don't know.
I think maybe we have a
little unfinished business.
- Come on, Honey, come on.
- Bye.
- Are you sure he's the same
man we saw in the plane?
(soft music)
- Who is he, really?
- He never says Honey, he never says.
- Where in the heck is Lori?
Look.
- Damn it, she knows we
got a plane to catch.
- Knowing Lori, she's got a live one.
- Sure has.
- Hi girls.
Come here, come here.
Hi, Debbie, Barbara.
I want you to meet my new daddy.
(intense music)
Oh come on, come on, come on.
- Bye.
- Well, blew anotherjob.
- Well sure don't blame me,
it's your fault, not mine.
' My fault?
It's your fault.
What do you want from me?
- What do I want from you?
You always blow the job.
- Oh, shut up, will you?
- What do you mean, shut up?
We'd of had a job yet if it wasn't--
- I didn't know, I didn't
know it was his wife.
- Well who'd you think
it was, his daughter?
- Stop ad libbing, will you?
Oh gosh, I'll tell you
something, I don't know--
- You listen to me.
We'd of been there yet if hadn't been--
- Don't holler.
- I'm not hollering.
I'm telling you we'd of been there yet.
- Don't holler.
- You know we'd of--
Please, don't holler.
- Every time I take you.
I'm not hollering.
- Please, don't holler.
Don't holler, please don't holler.
- And furthermore, I'm hungry.
Hungry?
Fine, I got a snack for you.
- You got a snack for me?
- Sure.
(Playful music)