BLEAK STREET
Damn, I didn't see you.
I didn't see you at all.
I swear you had
the mask on already...
...you are so fussy
and paranoid, damn it.
Tell Death to pay up.
I asked him yesterday,
but he played dumb.
Don't wake her or
she'll keep me up.
Do you have a fight today?
You bet. It's Wednesday.
Careful!
You know your mask
frightens her.
She'd better get used
to it while she's little.
How is she to know it's a mask?
Hey, when you get home tonight...
...wake me and I'll tell you...
They made a fuss at the daycare...
...because I still breast feed her.
Can you believe it?
Those dirty minds!
You can tell me tonight.
I'm leaving now.
You fight tonight?
Come on, boys, kneel over here.
In the name of the Father,
the Son and the Holy Spirit...
...may Divine Providence give you
a home, clothes, health and food...
...may the Holy Mother of Heaven
give you blessed victory.
Go on ahead.
I'll send your father
in a while.
We were up really
late last night.
Drunk out of your gourds.
Respect your parents, child...
...or the Almighty
will burn your mouth.
Yeah, ma, but you
should quit boozing.
You know dad is supposed
to be our manager and all.
Your mouth will dry up
if you talk like that...
...about the father
God gave you!
Especially today...
...when you have a fight...
lest you summon bad luck.
Did you bring my allowance?
I tell you, no sense asking
about the uniform gloves...
...they went on
a bender last night.
Wear the other ones,
the leather ones. From the gym.
If I do, Death will kill me.
You know how finicky he is.
You're such a wuss.
I may be a reflection
of AK-47...
...but we treat each
other with respect.
He's not going to mess
with me over my costume.
That's not my lot. I wasn't
born to be bossed around.
Stop your bitching. You
and I were born to be equal.
Identical twins.
But if you keep letting
people bully you...
...you must like it.
Be like me.
Whatever, but in the end,
Death is right.
Being a reflection is
serious business.
No laughing matter.
The uniform is the uniform.
Adela...
...did you forget?
No way, godmother.
I was looking for you.
No, Adela.
You can't try to put one
over on Mérgara...
...with all my boys looking
out for me and my interests.
Can I have my corner
tonight, the usual one?
Oh, Adela, dear...
...don't you know I want
it for a young girl?
Doesn't experience count?
Truth be told, no.
Weren't you supposed
to give me the money?
In awhile, child.
We were up late last night.
You knew I had to pay
for the phone early today.
Why did you stay out?
You really are...
She whored all night so you
could pay for the phone...
...you dumb shit!
Ma
tell that man not
to talk to me.
He's pissed you're
buying me a phone.
For your information,
I am the daughter.
And if she owes
anyone, it's me...
...not you, you
fat ass freeloader!
I'm coming.
I just told you I was up late.
That's what we agreed on.
Don't rile him.
Can't you see he's my husband?
What about me? Am I just
supposed to take it?
That's what you've told
me since I was little:
Suck it up, he's my husband.
This one or the others.
And this one repays you
for supporting him by...
...screwing your girlfriends.
And you just suck it up.
He doesn't even give us money.
Money isn't everything.
You'll understand one day.
So? ls there proof of
purchase for the phone?
I don't want you
getting into trouble.
Rig ht, proof of purchase.
Sure!
Don't you know where
he got them from?
You love to play
dumb, don't you?
And can I pay it in
easy installments?
You shit little midget!
Are you blind?
Take that, asshole!
There it is!
Yes, indeed!
What's up, man?
You wanna fight me?
Take that!
Feel it, asshole!
No, fuck!
What's up, shorty?
Is your father sleeping
it off again today?
He's coming.
We saw him today.
Your old man is a drunk.
That's why you are diminished.
Diminished?
Do you want to have
a go with me?
Don't fall for it.
Death just wants
to get you going.
The midgets are pissed.
He got to me.
Stop bugging Little Death.
Mascots are a part of one.
Aren't they, Little AK?
You bet. AK-47 and me
get along great.
You should, too.
Otherwise you get
your asses kicked.
We have never ever
had our asses kicked.
No matter how pissed we get.
Breathe. He just wants
to get your goat.
Well, he did.
We work as their mascots.
We have to be righteous mascots.
One of these days, I'm leaving.
Leaving? No fucking way!
You and me together.
And when we're not together,
what will happen?
When they pit us
against each other?
Don't even think it.
If some entrepreneur finds
out, he'll love the idea.
Brother against brother.
A fig ht between twins,
to the death.
The perverts!
You are a dumb shit.
Pretending to be asleep.
It takes more than that
to fool me.
Get smart with me and one
of these nights...
...I will douse you with
gasoline to warm my dawn.
I can smell deceit.
I can smell it a mile off.
It's over.
No sweat.
Stop snorting, you'll
keep me awake.
Jeza!
Jezabel!
I forgot to give you your
allowance. I'm leaving.
Hurry LIP...
Sit up sol can put
your shoes on.
Cooperate!
Where do you expect me to
get food money on my own?
You taught me...
...that only old women
are good for begging.
Come on, cooperate.
You may be old and scrawny,
but you sure are heavy.
The kids are coming
to help us out.
Are you taking her out
to beg again?
Can't you see the state she's in?
Have you no mercy?
This is senior abuse.
I'm going to report you,
wait and see.
Yeah? Who are you going
to report me to?
Human Rights.
They protect senior citizens...
...and I'll tell them there
are minors involved, too.
They come because they want to.
And because I give them money.
Is there no freedom?
That's child labor, its
a crime under the penal code.
And you have the old woman
trussed up like a pig.
That's her safety belt
so she won't fall.
I'll tell them you have her
bare assed, without diapers.
Human Rights and the
District Attorney's Office.
You buy her diapers!
Do you know what they cost?
- Where would I get the money?
- Work.
I work.
Work in something that
still delivers.
I deliver...
And for your information, she is
bare assed for ventilation.
I don't want her to chafe!
Go on!
Is she really going to report
you to Human Rights?
For what?
Tell me, what for?
I feed her, I dress her,
I cuddle her.
I take care...
...she has to help me out.
She doesn't even understand.
She understands I do it
for both of us.
Right, old woman?
She doesn't turn her nose
up at begging.
She's the one who
taught me the trade.
To paint sores.
To whimper.
All of the tricks.
Adjust her seat belt. We don't
want her falling on the street.
Place her coin can.
What if Human Rights
finds out about us...
...that you're
perverting us?
You tell them I am
teaching you a trade.
Thanks.
My clothes!
In my clothes! God damn!
In my clothing, Maximino?
No way, man!
Paid merchandise
all pawed over.
You're screwed and that's it.
You're crazy, hitting him.
Crazy!
It's not me, everyone knows.
Crazy nut case.
You should be tied up.
And I am Max, not Maximino,
once and for all!
My clothing, asshole!
In my clothing, you bastard!
The clothes that put
food on our table.
Now it turns out I'm good at
opening my legs like plumbing...
...so you can live easy,
and just look!
My best skirt, you bastard!
It doesn't even fit you.
You ruined it!
What? Did you pay admission?
My clothes, you inconsiderate fuck!
But you'll see!
Didn't I tell you?
Out of your gourd!
Ready for a straight jacket.
Those are my magician
clothes, you bitch!
Weren't mine work clothes?
The ones I earn the money
for your sweets with?
With this skirt...
...you faggot pussy!
You think you own me
for three fucking pesos?
Think again.
I'm leaving right now.
Do you know why
I'm running away?
To forget the pestilent cunt...
...you force me to shag.
We don't say shag
in this country.
I do.
Shag, shag, shag,
just so you know!
And we're done!
Let some other poor bastard
put up with your scenes.
Not with my clothes!
Let go of me!
Everyone said so.
Your husband is really queer.
And me breaking my ass.
Like a dumb fuck.
I put up with a bunch
of broads...
but now you bring me a faggot.
No.
Not that.
That's a no go.
Was it really me?
I mean, I'm not
a complete fright.
Not like I used to be...
...but I give the
clients full service.
They leave happy, satisfied.
Anyone can satisfy them.
What really crossed
the line, Maximino...
...is you wearing
my work clothes.
Once and for all, don't
call me Maximino...
...I'm Max.
And as for your clothes...
...I'll get you some later.
With what?
I'm going to give you
an allowance so you...
...can buy me clothes?
Your magician's rags, take
them to the cleaner or tailor.
I'll pay for it.
For how long, Max?
Why do you want to know?
You really fucked up, Max...
...I mean, in my clothes.
Truth is, this makes more
than a long night...
...on a street with no clients.
And with that piss stench
of yours they don't...
...want to get close enough
to see if we robbed them.
I'm going to get food
for you and for me.
Remember...
Be still.
Don't try to get smart with me.
A person needs a helper and the
old woman doesn't cut it.
A helper?
My old woman, you know?
She was really good when
we started working together.
Professional, serious.
Now she's just a bag of bones.
And as for whoring,
well, that's out.
Don't tell me you can still
make it on the streets?
Sorry.
The golden age has
passed us all by.
But I have some tricks.
I look at the young
floozies and I tell myself:
The years will fall
on you, too.
I won't tell you
what I'm into...
Today I went out to work.
You know I do some begging...
now that I'm low on clients...
...and a friggin neighbor
says to me:
I'm going to tell Human Rights
and I don't know what all.
The pious ones give themselves
airs and give us sermons.
They are the worst!
Just tell me and
I'll beat her up...
...teach her to
mind her own business.
That's my Dora!
Come, let's get a drink...
...and hate everything
and everyone.
Oh, little Dora,
I have missed you.
Years pass, but
affection runs deep.
What do you say, woman?
Shall we warm our lungs?
I pass.
You know I'm a dainty young lady.
Well, as for booze,
I don't have any.
Only rubbing alcohol.
How did we meet?
You're lucky you have
no one to look after.
What about this
damn beggar woman?
I know what it is.
What?
Why we care for each other.
Because of the drops.
All the times we worked
together as droppers.
Yeah.
Giving the customers
drops and taking their dough.
But we were really stupid.
We worked for a hag who
took the fruits of our labor.
We care about each other...
...because of the holy sweat
of labor fulfilled.
Hey, are you really doing
poorly at the trade?
I keep on going.
It's the trade that has left me.
Don't tempt the devil.
Thank God this trade
is like mange...
...it never ever leaves you.
Not even after I had this done.
Like the young whores have.
It didn't do any good.
Damn Mérgara said to me:
You're rusted.
No matter what you put on.
Mérgara has no compassion.
With her being a dyke and all...
...she couldn't hack the trade
and ended up pimping.
Always surrounded by
a brood of queers.
Anyone would feel a big shit
under those circumstances.
Why do you have it in
for faggots today?
Because of what I told you.
And because they are
never our clients.
I have some pending business...
.otherwise I would
stay and gossip.
Remember the time we put
the fat guy to sleep...
...and your hand got stuck?
And when he woke up,
he beat the shit out of us.
See?
It's broken.
Now, it's nothing but worries.
Distress.
And that bastard Max
in my clothes.
In your clothes, in your
clothes, in your clothes...
I know I already told you...
...but it just isn't fair!
The life you lead.
Without any ties.
I'll see you, I'm late.
Dora is wrong.
I take care of you.
And people say I have
no one to care for.
Hey.
The manager heard about
the scene this morning.
And what's it to you?
Besides the brouhaha this
morning, I could tell him...
...about your daughter sneaking
a boy up by the water tanks.
Just so you'll know
and take precautions.
Then don't act all surprised
when she gets knocked up.
My husband may be a faggot, my
daughter may be a slut and all...
...but I'm the tenant!
You have to put up with me!
Everyone is sucking my blood.
Everyone!
You'd better go back.
I told you...
You told me I could on
Wednesdays which are slow.
Can I have my corner?
It's been mine forever.
Used to be, not anymore.
How can that be?
You're looking at it.
And if you can't see it,
you will.
What can I do?
Crochet.
Come on little ones,
you've found your momma!
The party is set for
after the fight.
Did you tell her how it works?
What do you think?
Besides, she knows us.
Because she's already
done the job.
She only blew it once.
Once, but it was bad.
Midgets, I mean sending
us two midgets!
That was out of line.
Midgets! You and I
are Lilliputians.
Midgets are for circuses.
You and I are wrestlers.
Her mother is a midget!
Stop brooding on it.
It's not fair. Everyone
bugging me. I've had it!
My sainted mother and dad...
...are normal, as are
my children and yours.
I am short...
...so my fuse is very short.
And how much is this
cheap brand?
The one that washes out.
What it says.
That's what hair dye costs here.
For grey or whatever.
Whatever brand.
But this says it only
lasts three weeks.
Over time it doesn't add up.
How can it?
I don't set the prices.
It's a different story
in the supermarkets.
Go to the supermarket, then.
Do you have Neurocalm?
That's a controlled substance.
You need a prescription.
Well, you can keep your
dye for grey hair.
You probably want a
prescription for that, too.
Dear merciful Lord...
crush the enemies of my boys...
...may Satan fall upon them
and their strength not prevail.
Holy, holy, holy,
Lord of the armies, amen.
Don't try to sneak off
after the fight.
No way.
You give me your pay
check before you go party.
And when you get home tomorrow...
...tell the women to come
for their house money.
Hey, ma...
Death says my uniform
is unworthy of me.
He says it's made of cheap cloth...
...and is a rag.
I had it made by the seamstress
who makes his, just so he knows.
What about the fabric?
The fabric...
That was your father's doing.
Don't you know him?
Didn't he stand you up
yesterday...
...when you were meeting
with the new second?
You know how he is.
One of these days...
...I'll take charge of
everything myself.
How can you?
You in the dressing room?
We'll be a laughingstock.
Make Dad shape up, Mom.
We take the business seriously.
Your dad turned out a drunk.
It's God's will.
Don't gripe...
...or you'll lose for
all your griping.
Hey, ma...
Today's our day for hanky panky.
I'm going to give you
that little bonus right now.
After the fight we'll
be in a hurry.
Better now.
That way no one knows
you have money.
Take care.
You know there are some
sly ones in the ring.
We're not missing any limbs.
Not limbs...
...brains!
Go on, get to work.
When will we have the new capes?
When you're rich...
and give me money for brocade.
Go on ahead.
I'll catch up with you
with your dad.
It's not fair. Death's woman
buys and spends and...
...her husband doesn't complain.
But when the time comes
to share...
You get squat!
You wuss!
It's time you looked
out for us, for your own...
...instead of drooling over your
famous brother and his wife...
...and the children of your
fucking undersized brother...
...because he is shorter
than you, I've checked!
You'll see!
A big man to hit your wife!
Take off your mask.
Dare to show your face!
Fucking faggot!
You have a hard-on
for your brother!
Midget on midget!
You dumb bitch!
Do you want him to fight
with his spirits in the dumps...
...feeling like a midget?
What do you think feeds you?
Does it bother you
that he loves his brother?
Adores his mother?
What joins my two boys
is stronger than you.
They are united by
blood and destiny.
Born the same day, the same
blood, the same struggle.
The same everything.
Nothing and no one can
come between them.
Accept it and calm down.
Leave them alone.
Today they work so you can eat.
The money isn't for me,
it's for your granddaughter.
Momma's boys!
Sissies!
Midgets though it hurts.
Midgets!
If I'm with him it's only
because I'm not choosy.
If you had listened to me.
But who listens to their mother?
When you're in show
business, no family.
And if you're horny, then get
it on the side, no commitments.
But as for my permission...
...you didn't even
ask my damn blessing.
What are you looking at?
Do you want to get between
me and my boys, too?
I'll wait outside.
Get this through your head!
Whatever happens...
...you two, like in my belly...
Q 0 tog ether!
No matter how they try
to separate you.
Did they give you
all the dough?
Don Ramiro will give me
the rest later.
Depending on how they do.
Adela, Adelita.
Give me a break.
I've got to get
this off my chest.
Maximino and me are still mad.
Come over here
there are a bunch of
snoops and gossips down there.
Gossips?
Because of the profession?
No, it's not that.
They just like to
screw with people.
It's just today.
One day is one day.
Don't look at me
like I'm an idiot.
You should be glad
yours turned out gay.
You can get out of
fornicating at home...
...and still service
the clients.
It's not the same.
I just wanted to be like them.
Watch TV, talk about my day,
be normal.
Like the ones in the tenement.
Like other people.
God protect you!
They are a bunch of assholes.
I told you before and
you shined me on.
You haven't changed the gloves.
If you're going to be my shadow,
you have to get cracking.
If I say gloves...
...I mean your little gloves.
If I say cape,
I mean your little cape.
And so on.
If you can't keep up with me
and you give me a hard time...
...I'll take the franchise away.
I told you, next time.
Why the face, bro?
Little AK,
tell your brother to chill.
Come on
stop pouting.
Little Death is
really stubborn.
I told him what the
gloves should be like...
...and he had them
made around here.
Get your shit together.
Imitations show.
Soon, mom is making them.
Mothers should stay at home.
What is that about her
blessing you at the arena?
Tell your old lady...
...to
keep family fights at home.
You can go at it there.
I build a reputation...
...only for this diminished
version of me...
...to tear it down.
Stop it already!
Let's go outside.
You crossed the line, man.
How will the little ones fight
after you chewed them out...
...in front of everyone?
The assholes are smug.
They know they move people.
That's why they do as they
please and get away with it.
Maybe they rely on their luck.
Here.
Don't worry, no problem.
So?
Nothing...
...I mean...
...nothing.
Adela.
I told you so.
With a little help
you're like a kid.
Why are you looking so happy?
I fixed things up with my Max.
You forgave him
for being a fruitcake?
That's nothing to forgive.
What pissed me off
was my clothes.
But the worst anger
comes to an end.
Did you find the
old prescription?
Let me see if it came
in today's shipment.
That's what eye drops cost?
Child, don't you have something
the same but cheaper?
They've really gone up.
It's not fair.
Give me the rest.
It's not enough.
These are the only ones.
We'll take them.
So we don't mess up,
God forbid.
And we're in no condition
to waste money.
Put those damn drops away.
We don't want to make a
fuss and draw attention.
It's not like we
were beginners.
The times we did it
just fine, thank you.
I'm doing it for you.
What a life!
With all this distress,
our makeup ran.
- Let's touch ourselves up.
- What for?
So we don't turn them off.
That's different.
You see? You're not
so messed up.
You just needed a little help.
Look who's talking.
At least I look like a female.
I mean, I've got
flesh on my bones.
We're both pitiful.
Neither you nor I can cut it.
Honey.
You look just like
Dolores del Rio.
Max, my husband, says my
problem is I have no bones.
You have a good skeleton
underneath you.
Just look...
...there's a silver lining
to your man being a pussy.
I thought you said
he wasn't queer.
Once doesn't count.
But if you want to
turn a blind eye...
I was born with a blind eye
and still have one.
Better blind than alone.
You think?
Hey.
Do I really look like
Dolores del Rio?
Just look! High cheek bones.
I told you, they may be
small, but they're stars.
You see?
They're on the poster.
Why don't we sneak into the
locker room and wait there.
To get out of the cold.
Time for the main event,
and AK-47 and Death
are climbing into the ring...
...with their shadows,
Little Death and Little AK.
And here come Earthquake with Tremor,
and Geppetto with Little Pinocchio.
How big do you think they are?
Like this or tiny?
If it's little, all the better.
As if a lost mosquito
got inside of you...
...and that's it. You
don't feel a thing.
They pay for the hotel.
Well, we sure aren't.
The same one?
They closed it. There's one
on the corner of the arena.
Sometimes they don't like
independent operators.
They're going to pick
and choose customers?
This neighborhood is
really run down.
I'm nervous.
As if it were my first time.
Rather than nervous,
you should be happy.
How long has it been since
you had a decent one?
With a trade.
Bathed.
Smelling of Sanborns lotion.
Sanborns lotion...
...I had forgotten about that.
You know why I got
an attack of nerves?
I mean, what if they like
us and grow fond of us...
...and give us an
allowance and all?
I like your pipe dreams.
They really are taking
their time.
What if there's another
exit in the back?
I told you.
Let's go, girls.
Who's paying?
Them or you?
Them, what do you think?
Payment is in advance.
Thanks.
And our money?
If we want anything else,
we'll let you know.
Are you always like that?
With the mask and all?
I mean, just to see your faces.
No offense, I mean
we are what we are.
First let's give the
evening some flavor.
Otherwise, it's bad luck.
Shall we strip now?
Or later?
Dance for us.
Yes, girl, dance for us.
No, no, no. With light.
With light.
Pretty, dance pretty!
Like that. Pretty!
Paint your mouth, you
look like a zombie.
And pour the guys a drink.
Alright. It's up to you.
Cheers!
Aren't you going to take
the masks off even for that?
It's creepy...
You look like those little
plastic wrestlers...
...they used to sell at the
market when I was a kid.
No, we don't take them off.
It's a professional thing.
We see no faces.
But we know what's in the heart.
To each his own.
They're identical.
I don't mean to pry...
...but is it always like
this, a twosome?
It's their thing.
I told you.
You don't understand.
You just don't understand.
I didn't say I understood,
that's why I asked.
Well, let's get to it, girl.
Cheers!
The thing is they're
downcast after the fight.
No way are we downcast!
For your information, we won!
I told you, it would have been
better for them to see the fight.
Then we could talk to them.
We saw it, I swear!
If you saw it, what
did they sing to us?
It's not as if one remembers
everything one ever heard.
You big liar!
Knock it off, bro!
Now let's get to it.
The midgets got pissed...
'cause someone pinched
the midget Miss...
They got small,
and they got big.
Then they circled like a pig.
The midgets got pissed...
'cause someone pinched
the midget Miss...
They got small,
and they got big.
Then they circled like a pig.
The midgets got pissed...
'cause someone pinched
the midget Miss...
They got small,
and they got big.
Then they circled like a pig.
The midgets got pissed...
'cause someone pinched
the midget Miss...
They got small,
and they got big.
Then they circled like a pig.
I'm out of breath.
The little ones did
themselves proud.
That's all they have!
And they won!
They're short and stupid.
But nice.
To each his own.
They treated us like ladies.
We are ladies, dummy.
They creep me out.
I don't know if it's their size
or because they're twins.
But they creep me out.
Don't wake them!
You peeper!
We all have our little things.
They like to do it together
with their masks on.
It's their life.
Just look at them!
They look like two angels, with
their little masks and all!
Leave it on, or they might
notice and catch us.
Hurry up, we don't want
them waking up.
Those drops just knock
you out for a while.
They aren't anesthesia.
I felt sorry for them.
What the fuck! Let's go!
Come on, what's it to you?
Just a quickie. Come on.
And I won't bother you again.
What about the other day?
That was the other day.
Today is a new day.
You grabbed me by the hair
in front of everyone!
What about my honor?
And worse yet,
what about yours?
What the fuck do I
care about my honor?
Weren't you out whoring?
You should have had enough.
Go to sleep already.
Do you think some so and so
whose face I can't even see...
...is the same to me as you?
Fucking is fucking.
Calm down already.
Close your eyes.
Everything is alright.
If it's hard for you to
do it with me physically...
...then think of him.
Of who?
The kid from the other day.
There you go again!
You can borrow my clothes.
I swear. All of them.
I'll stretch them out,
they won't fit you.
They had it coming.
That wasn't worth
running away over.
Hey, listen,
we need more policing.
This is a never ending story.
Every night there's a crowd.
This was bound to happen.
Drunks, yelling, streetwalkers.
Hey, is it true it was
the little wrestlers?
Come in here.
I want to ask you
some questions.
Don't go all crazy.
Just tell me what you know
and what you don't.
I only know this is a
by the hour hotel.
And the neighbors are
not happy about it.
And with the scandal
about to break...
What scandal is that?
Do you really not know
who they are?
So it's really true.
Stop handling the evidence.
Then the coroners
give me a hard time.
What?
How? How?
How?
They killed our boys.
My children!
Where did they spend the night?
Where is my little boy?
How should I know why
he didn't come home?
They're your children,
you knew them first.
Tell me he's here!
That it isn't true.
That what they are saying
out there isn't true.
Not my children!
Why would I ask?
In this life, they teach
you not to get involved.
Yes, ma'am, I understand that.
But you also have to
check out the customers.
It's your responsibility.
Why me?
How was I to know those
midgets would bring the press?
Ah, so you did notice
that they were little people...
...and you must have also
checked out the harlots.
I already told you they were
two messed up old women.
I didn't see their faces.
They were wearing masks.
And if I had seen them,
it wouldn't have mattered.
I don't know anything
about wrestling...
...boxing or any of that!
God save me from being
involved in such crap!
Did you know the women?
Were they regulars?
Did they use your establishment?
Didn't I tell you
they were wrecks?
The Laredo Hotel is
a serious hotel.
Ha, the Laredo!
Where are my boys?
I've come for my boys!
My children!
My little boys!
Tell me they are OK,
that it was just talk, untruths.
Ma'am, who are you looking for?
Swear it isn't true!
That it's a joke.
A joke to break
your heart in two!
Alright, let's start
at the beginning.
Who are your children?
Little AK and Little Death,
the shadow wrestlers...
...of AK-47 and Death.
Don't say their names!
It's like calling
fate and saying:
Com e, come take them!
Then how will
he understand you?
Are you really their parents?
You, ma'am, are you the mother?
That's me and this
is their father.
Normal as I am.
But my little twins
came out small.
How do you explain
their peculiar tastes?
Don't talk to me
about peculiar tastes!
They were good sons,
good husbands.
They both had normal
children, healthy ones.
With good size, their children,
all of them are tall.
What have they done to them?
Ma'am, go home quietly
with your husband...
...while we investigate the case.
I am very sorry, really.
My condolences.
What good are your condolences?
I want justice!
Justice for my children!
I demand it!
Don't tell me what to do!
Go to hell!
Lady, go home.
I will call you.
So?
Two senior sex workers
from the area...
knocked the famous look alike
wrestlers out with eye drops.
Insecurity in the area scares off
clients of ordinary businesses.
The facial composites
will be released soon..
Hey, what's the name of the
policeman who's always at the café?
I don't know,
there are lots of them.
I'll be right back.
It'll blow over in a couple
of days. You'll see.
In this cursed city, no scandal
survives the weekend.
It's not about what they
did, you fool.
It's about the droppers.
The TV keeps saying that's
the method all the whores...
...in our area are using.
The whole city has
thieving harlots.
Yeah, but these are droppers.
They say it's a mafia.
That they knock out their
marks with eye drops.
Just five or six drops.
Wait!
I know!
I just thought of it.
They used the normal
dose on the midgets.
That's why the morons
killed them.
They overdid it!
Morons!
Of course...
...but that
changes everything.
They didn't want to kill them,
they were just dumb.
Therefore, there is no plot...
...no mafia, no accomplices.
And everything will calm down.
If the press come,
that's what we have to say.
I'm going to give them a rosary
to accompany them to heaven.
There's only one.
They asked for this.
Dressed alike...
...as always.
With their little
wrestling outfits.
All gold thread.
Take a picture of me.
Take a picture of me with them.
Why do you do it?
Did you see them fight?
Or were you seeing
one of them on the sly?
Or what?
Because they were little.
The wrestling world is
dismayed over the death...
...of the twin wrestlers.
These Lilliputian gladiators...
...known as Little Death
and Little AK were, in life...
...the replicas or mascots
of the master grapplers:
Death and AK-47.
The police announced...
...that the hotel video made
possible a police sketch...
...of the sex workers
who accompanied the brothers.
Inside sources revealed that,
though of poor quality...
...the tape sufficed to
identify the sex workers.
Did I ever show you
my little angel?
Touch it!
Don't be shy.
It won't bite you.
No one ever touched it.
Can you believe it?
Hey!
I thought we were splitting up.
They are on TV and everywhere.
You'd think we did
in two big shots.
- Little shots.
- Don't joke about it.
They've caught us.
I don't want them to torture me.
What will be, will be.
Juanes, let's go.
We have them.
Mérgara!
You know what they say.
Just relax and enjoy it.
You know all the
whores in the area.
I don't deny I know them...
...but those two don't
work for me anymore.
Are you going to tell me
where I can find them...
Or play hard to get?
I swear I had no part in it.
Do you think I'm going to
let them be so stupid?
You see, Mérgara?
Always so cooperative.
Juanes.
Let's go get them.
Ma!
Some policemen
searched the room.
Of course I saw.
Yes, they've left.
You're back to your old ways,
but you sure chewed me out.
Of course I'm going to
leave, I'm not stupid!
I'll call grandma and
catch the first bus.
Send me money.
You old fool!
You get into all kinds of trouble
and don't know how to get out.
And what about me?
What about me?
No, Adela, we are in
this to the end.
If I run, you run with me,
that's all there is to it.
And why is that?
Why what?
Didn't you hear what Jeza said?
They went looking for me.
And they will soon come for you.
And if they catch me,
they catch you...
...no matter if
I'm far from home.
I have never been a snitch.
For your knowledge.
And this won't be the first
time I've been in the joint.
You act tough.
At the first shock you'll
spill everything you know.
You'll go down and take me down.
- Well, don't tell me.
- What?
Just don't tell me
where you're going.
They come, they shake me
around and that's it.
Because I have nothing
to tell them.
What if you make something up?
To make it worse?
No way, José.
You split and I tell
them this conversation.
And there's an end to it.
I'm too old to be on the run.
Look.
After a while in jail,
they forget about you...
...and you get along fine.
You eat, have a roof
over your head...
...a blanket.
It's great.
Rig ht, just dandy.
I don't know why
I hang out with an idiot.
Adela, come off it!
Come on!
I don't want to leave you.
I left my husband,
and now Jeza.
I can't go looking
for her for years!
Why get her involved?
But I wasn't meant to be alone!
Come on. We can
make it together!
Alright then.
After all...
...you and I have always
walked on Bleak Street.
Adela, this is no time
for a performance.
Let'; go!
I hate to leave her there,
like furniture.
Someone is bound to
come up and find her.
Besides, you're already on
TV and in the newspapers.
They're going to come
looking for you.
They love a disturbance.
You're lacking Christian charity.
And you're lacking brains.
Let's go.
Leave the dead to
bury their own.
Do you know Salina Cruz?
I don't know anyone
who has ever been there.
That's the best recommendation.
Do you have any drops left?
Come off it.
And leave my old woman
to die here like a dog?
No. I wouldn't do that
to anyone.
Especially not my old woman.
How could I just leave
you like that?
My old woman.
Goodbye.
I have to go.
You think you're smart...
...but you were dumb enough
to hold onto the drops.
They were expensive.
That's them.
Just because they were midgets.
If they had been normal...
...no one would have balked.
Next time, I'm steering
clear of freaks.
If you hadn't been saying
goodbye to the old woman...
But you always did have
a screw loose.
I know. Sooner or later
they were bound to catch us.
But I'm really scared.
Hey.
Don't be mean.
Let me say goodbye.
Who knows when we'll
see each other again.
She's my family...
...she's all I've got.
What did you want?
I just wanted to tell
her not to be distressed.
That it was fate.
That all things pass.
BLEAK STREET