- Deux Dames.
- I gotta pee.
- I'll find
a garage or something.
- No, just, just pull over.
- I'm just curious, what,
what was your plan back there?
- I dunno.
- I mean, if I hadn't
chased after you,
what would you, what
would you have done?
- I just didn't think that
far ahead, to be honest.
You're pretty out
of shape, though.
- Hey.
I could never keep up with you.
Turbo.
You must be hungry.
Are you hungry?
I'm hungry.
- She's off, steady.
- Down,
and she gets flipped.
Perfect 10.
Oh, wrong strategy there.
- Uh,
take two of these.
- You got ID?
- Oh, they're, uh,
they're for him.
I'll just get a pack of 27s.
- Could you just
put this together?
Mm.
Want a bite?
- I'm vegan.
- You're vegan?
Since when?
- Since I was 15.
- Oh.
You know they bring drugs
into the country using
animals, don't you?
They literally shove the
cocaine up their asses.
- That's so interesting.
But I don't really
do cocaine, so-
- Oh, yeah.
You're more of a benzos
and opioid sort of girl.
What a relief.
- Benzos.
- Right
field, caught!
A no-hitter for Lucas Giolito.
He no-hits the Pirates.
It's the eighth time in
the modern era the Pirates-
- You only got candies?
- Hmm?
- Okay.
Well, we'll go to
a proper restaurant
before we get to the motel.
- Motel?
- Yeah.
It's, it's like a 14-hour
drive to get to Santa Fe.
- So, what kind of art
does this guy even do?
- Um, all
sorts, I think.
He, he's the guy, it's the,
remember that chef with the,
the metal plate in his head?
- What?
- He, uh, from that breakfast
cafe you used to like,
the, um, Cool Cats Cafe
and they had those amazing
chocolate chip pancakes.
Uh, well, it's his brother.
Uh, that, that, that's the
house that we're going to.
Anyway, I thought it
would a, you know, hey,
it's a destination and we
could go and hang out there
for a couple of
days and then, um,
and maybe you could tour
his studio and, you know,
you'd be inspired to start
painting again, maybe.
And then we'll go back.
- Why do you care if I paint?
Can you pull over?
- No, I'm not running
through the desert again, sorry.
- No, I'm seri, I'm serious.
Please pull over.
That's the entrance.
- You okay?
I know, I know this feeling.
I know how badly you're hurting.
You know I've been there,
so the last thing you need
from me is a lecture.
But your mommy told me that,
that your face turned blue.
I mean, do you know
what that means?
This, this is serious, you know?
Sweetheart.
Ugh.
Very good.
What, are you trying
to enter some kind of lung
cancer competition or something?
Can't you get it to work, no?
- Fuck's sake.
- Hey, not the truck.
Don't kick the truck.
That's a shame you can't
get that cigarette lit.
- Isn't it?
- Oh, shit.
Oh.
Fuck.
- What?
- I'm losing power in the truck.
Hold on.
It's all right.
- Oh, come on.
Fuck.
- You don't happen to have a
screwdriver with you, do you?
- You've gotta
be fucking kidding me.
- You can blame your mom for
your over-active bladder.
When you were potty training,
she used to give you like a,
an M&M every time you
went, and I swear to God,
you went 50 times a day.
That sweet tooth
you got from me.
- Is that all?
- Hmm?
- Is that all I got from you?
- Somebody order a stripper?
Hah!
I'm just messin'.
And it's not just
your star sign.
I can guess anyone's age, too.
It's a gift I've had
since I was a girl.
I guessed everyone in my town.
Yeah, the paper reported
on it back in '64.
Got my picture taken
and everything.
I was the biggest thing to
happen here since that UFO.
- There was a UFO sighting here?
- Oh, hell yes there was.
There's all kinds of crazy
extra-terrestrial shit that goes
on in these areas.
All righty.
I'm gonna guess now, okay?
Okay.
Hmm.
Let's see.
Libra?
25.
Sagittarius.
Eh, 37.
- No.
- Close, close.
I'm a Libra, but I'm 20.
And he's an Aries and he's 47.
- Shit!
- It was close, it was close.
- Eh.
- You got it very close.
- But you know what?
I practice ancient
Vedic astrology.
I don't go in for that
Western hipster shit.
They don't even take into
account the wobble of the Earth
and I think that's where
the disconnect happens.
- Right.
That makes sense.
- 47?
Ain't no judgment here.
I mean, love is love, man.
- Oh, no.
- You know, my parents
were together for 72 years.
They died when they were
90 years old within seconds
of each other.
- Oh, there's something
beautiful about that.
- Mama died first 'cause
she was sitting on the front
of the motorcycle and
took most of the impact.
And Daddy got
flung off the back.
- Oh, I'm sorry.
- Oh, man.
- Yeah.
I'm sorry about that.
That was bad.
Oh, well.
Hey, you two mind if we
make a quick pit stop?
- Oh, well the thing is, we're
on a bit of a tight schedule.
We need to push on
really, I'm afraid.
- Are we?
- It'll only take but a second.
Can you do me a favor and
reach in the back there
and grab that package?
- Oh.
- Ah.
Ha-ha.
She's a beaut', ain't she?
Oh, don't worry, the bullets
are in the birthday card.
- Okay.
- It's a gift for my nephew.
- Right.
- Hey, you know, my
brother has been working
on cars his whole life.
I bet he could fix her up
for ya and it would only,
it'd be cheaper and a,
and a lot faster than-
- I think a-
- The joint that I'd
have to take you to.
- Well, I should
probably just go to the,
some professional place.
I wouldn't want to get-
- No!
I'm telling you, his garage
is a car mechanic's heaven.
- Okay.
- Works for me.
- Okay, thanks.
- My nephew
is gonna love it.
- Yeah, that's a beauty.
- Big guy.
- That's a lovely gun.
- Yeah, you keep it.
Not ours.
- No, it's not loaded.
It's not loaded, right?
- Are you deaf?
I said the bullets were
in the birthday card.
Now, don't make direct
eye contact with anyone.
Come on.
- Don't you think
it's a bit ironic?
- What?
- Well, you know, you take
me on this trip to, what,
keep me out of danger,
and then we end up in
a truck with a stranger
and a gun in the
middle of nowhere.
- I'm not, I'm not
just taking you
to keep you out of danger.
I, I'm happy to be
with you, you know?
- Hi.
How you doing?
- Hello.
- How are you?
- Hey.
- To meet you.
- Nice to meet you.
It seems very dear,
classic truck there.
- Yeah.
It's an old '80s, uh, Sierra.
We've got a problem
with the radiator.
- All right.
There we go.
All right, you said you
wanted a, what do you want?
You said you wanted
a little puppy?
Bet you can't get my nose.
Bet you can't get my nose!
You want a dog or what?
Here.
This, one, one at a time.
One at a time.
Hold up.
Hold on.
You gotta let me
make it first, dude.
You gotta let me make it first.
Stop.
Stop, stop.
- My birthday's coming up.
- Yeah?
My, uh, aunt makes me do
this every year, so...
All right, all right, all right.
Can I get ya anything,
like, uh, you want a burger
or like a, I think we got some
potato salad or something.
- I'll take a beer.
- We can get ya
back on the road.
And I got quite a bit
of tools in my garage.
- Oh, great.
- Yeah.
A GMC cla, classic, huh?
- A friend of mine had one
of these beautiful trucks.
- Oh, he did?
- Yeah.
And tells me about-
- Yeah?
- Going on a road
trip, yeah, together.
They sure perform good.
- Oh, that's cool.
- Yeah.
- Well, we just need to
get it down and off the,
uh, tow truck.
I don't know how to do that.
- Oh.
- Is Elsie, is she a
relation of yours, Elsie?
- She's a sister-in-law of mine.
- Oh, okay.
- Yeah.
- Elsie!
- She brings me abandoned cars.
man.
Nice truck.
Nice GMC.
- Yeah, yeah.
- Yeah, beautiful.
- Welcome to mi casa.
Yeah.
Here you go.
So, you paint?
- Yeah.
- That's cool.
That's cool.
I paint a little bit
myself, actually.
- Mm.
- Yeah.
Well, I mean, graffiti.
Yeah, me and my boys
actually just, uh,
tagged the old Dollar General.
- Mm.
- It said, "Anarchy is
democracy taken seriously."
- Nice.
- Real big.
Yeah, it's kinda dumb.
But whatever.
So, uh, what do you paint?
- Oh, I don't, I don't
really paint much anymore.
- What?
Why not?
- Just ran out of
inspiration, I guess.
- That's fucking bullshit.
Just saying, like it's, you
should keep fucking painting.
I actually make music
for inspiration.
I'll play you something.
I'm a musician.
Yeah.
Yeah
Shit.
- Hey, can I-
- Hmm?
- Can I use the, uh,
do you have a
bathroom I could use?
- Yeah.
Yeah.
Right down the
hall.
- That, that
was really good, though.
- Thank you.
- Yeah.
Wanna take some shots?
- Hmm.
Nice.
- Oh, fucking hell.
- Beautiful color.
Why, why the sticker?
- Well, it's my, the
name of my business.
You know, I'm a, a, like
a landscape company.
It's just a little one.
- Yeah?
I think the truck looks
a whole lot better
without it.
Yeah.
- Cheers.
- You want another one?
- Yeah.
Ah.
I like your house.
- Oh, yeah?
Wait, you wanna move in?
- Yeah.
Sure.
Why not?
- So, like what do you do?
Do you like model or something?
No, I'm just kidding.
No, but seriously,
are you a model?
Just tell me.
- Pass.
Next question.
- Okay.
Are you single?
Pass.
Next question.
- Geez.
Are you fucking with me?
- Pass.
Next question.
- Oh, okay.
All right.
So,
be honest.
Do you think I'm sexy?
- Pass.
Next question.
- Is that your
boyfriend outside?
- God, no!
Why does everyone
keep assuming that?
- Oh, hey.
- Oh, okay, let's go.
- No, we're just
having a conversation.
- Now!
- Excuse me.
- We're leaving.
I fixed the truck.
Let's go.
- Well, I'm not going with you.
- Yes, you are!
- No, I'll get my own
ride back to the city.
- I can give you a
ride if you want.
- He'll give me a ride.
- I'm not
leaving you here.
- Well, I'm not going with you.
- Okay, relax, dude.
All right?
- Look, why don't you just
mind your own fucking business?
- Hey, don't speak
to him like that.
It's his house.
- You can't speak to me
like that here in my house.
- Are you used to serving
underage girls in your house?
- God!
Dad!
- Underage one here?
- Yeah, she's not 21.
- Okay.
I didn't know that.
- 12 hours ago, 12
hours ago you OD'd!
And here you are fucking
drunk and God knows what else.
- I'm not drunk!
- Okay.
Okay look, I'm on parole
right now, kinda, so I-
- But we weren't even drinking.
So-
- That's not true.
She-
- Oh, stop.
- No, no, you had one
beer and two shots.
- Stop talking, stop talking.
- Whoa, hey.
No, no.
- Fucking dick ass!
Why did you even
come this morning?
- Because I'm your father!
- Since when?
- Whoa!
God.
- All right.
- Sorry to step out.
Thank you.
- Leaving already?
- Oh, Amos.
Yeah.
- I got something
that I'd like you to have.
- Oh, that's all,
you're very kind, we-
- Oh, I insist.
I insist.
- Oh.
- Okay?
- Yeah.
Thanks.
- I grow this myself.
And we'd like you to have.
A gift for you.
- Nice to meet you.
But I, this is too much.
We, we don't need-
- Ah.
But it's my pleasure
to help you.
- Well, thank you so
much and thanks for
your help with the
truck and that.
Thanks for the pumpkin, yeah.
I'll put it in here.
There we go.
Okay.
Thanks, guys.
- Safe travels.
- Take care.
How much did you have to drink?
Hello!
Oh, no jokes for me now?
Okay.
You have no idea how
lucky you are to be alive.
Turbo?
- Oh, fuck no.
I'm not going in there.
I don't even believe in God.
- It's an AA meeting.
- - Yeah, I know.
They try to turn you
into some Jesus freak.
I'm not going.
- No, they don't.
I think it would do us both
good to go to a meeting.
- Us?
No, I'm good.
You go ahead to your cult-y
little group meeting.
- Look, if you don't
like it, then, you know,
we can leave early.
We don't have to, But I
haven't been to a meeting
for a while, and I think it
would be good for both of us.
- If I go in, will you
take me back to San Diego?
- Why would you want to
go back to San Diego?
- Because it's my home.
- Yeah, but you don't really
have a home there just now.
- I, I have options.
- It really doesn't
seem like you do.
- Well, you really
don't know me.
So, I don't see how you would
have any concept of that.
- Well, I would like
to get to know you.
That's why I'm here.
I, and I would like to
think there's a hint
of a chance that you'd
like to get to know me too.
- No, thank you.
- Wh, when you woke up in the
hospital room this morning,
did that feel good?
Look, I know you don't, you
don't wanna hear it from me,
but trust me that this path
you're on, it's not worth it.
- Why would I ever trust you?
- Oh.
Oh, okay.
Okay.
- Go ahead, then.
- Uh, it's, it's
really fun, isn't it?
I mean, it wouldn't be so hard
to stop if it wasn't fun, right?
Getting high and, uh,
drinking and partying.
I mean, it's, it's fun.
Uh, until it's not.
And then things
start to slip away.
Uh, slowly at first, my life
started to slip away from me,
um, and then all
of a sudden, it,
it just turned to shit
really quick and, um, I,
I don't like to
think back to then.
I, I, I wish that it didn't
have to have been a part
of my story, but it is.
And, uh, I was, um, well,
I was acting like a child,
but, but I, I, I had a child.
And, uh, I just guess I
d, I didn't really know
what it meant to be a father.
I remember this one
time I was coming home.
Uh, the sun was coming
up and I was walking out
of a blackout.
I had no idea where I
was, uh, had been or, uh,
no idea who I had been with
or what I'd been up to.
But I came into the house
and, um, my now ex-wife
was with my little girl, and
she was only four or five.
- And I could never forget
the way that she looked at me,
that, she was just trying
to figure out what
was wrong with me,
but, uh, but at the
same time that she was,
um, she was frightened
of me, you know.
Uh, I was a stranger to her.
But even though that kind
of thing would happen,
and even though I didn't
want to drink anymore,
it did, I hated it.
I, I, I, I hated the way my
life felt to live that way.
I couldn't stop.
I tried all, probably all
the things we all did,
you know, like cutting
down or I'll only drink
on a Thursday and a Friday
and if I drink all day
Thursday and all day Friday,
you know.
I just couldn't stop.
I couldn't do it.
And, uh, it just sort of
led me to the point where I,
I think I felt like if
I run away, you know,
if I like blow my life
up, then I'll stop...
- So, you
are religious now.
- No.
Not particularly, no.
But I do like the
idea of something
greater than ourselves,
you know, like a
higher power, like,
I've been waiting to tell you-
- I, I see two new faces.
Glad you could join us.
- Thank you for having us.
- Hey.
Shiloh.
Is this your first meeting?
- Yeah.
- Do you
have any questions?
- Not really.
- Do you
wanna join the program?
- No.
- What brought
you in here today?
- He did.
- Oh.
Well, no one can
want this for you.
You gotta want
this for yourself.
- Right.
- What do you want?
- Honestly?
- Thank you.
All right.
Aren't you hungry?
- I thought I was.
I really hate those meetings.
The public speaking.
I just, I just
could never do that.
- Oh, yeah?
- Yeah.
Just talking to
everyone like that.
- Well, I wasn't
talking to everyone.
I was talking to you.
- So, how'd you sell me to him?
- I'm sorry?
- Your friend.
What was your pitch?
"Hey man, I know I haven't
seen you in a decade,
but my daughter just OD'd
and I have no idea what
to do with her.
Anyway, see you tomorrow.
Hide your booze."
- Okay.
- You know, I'm really not
addicted to this stuff.
Like I, I don't need
it all the time.
- Then stop.
- Well, I,
I don't really see why
I would if it's not-
- I should take this.
Sorry.
Really sorry.
I'll be right back.
- Oh-ho-ho-ho-ho.
Ugh-huh-huh.
Ah-ha.
Ugh!
- I don't think that was yours.
- Excuse me?
- Don't play dumb.
- Oh, um, well, I just assumed
that no one would
come back for it, so-
- Yeah.
No, well, 30 days.
Is that the minimum?
Okay.
No, no, no, no.
Out-patient, that,
it won't work for us.
She needs, she needs
to to stay there.
- I'm gonna need to see some ID.
- Uh, I, uh, I
don't have it on me.
- Okay, I'm
just gonna have to talk
to your father about this.
- No, no, no.
No.
Please, please don't do that.
Um...
Um, should we get going?
- Yeah.
You okay?
Yep.
- Could I get this in
a box, please, to go?
Thanks.
- You're j-j-jammin'
with the hottest disc
jockey, disc jockey.
- Oh, wait a minute.
Oh, come on!
- Come on.
Come on.
- Oh.
Sorry.
Hello?
Oh, hello, my love.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Of course.
Hello, wee man.
What did you do today?
Oh, that's, well, you'll have
to show me when I get home.
I, what book are you gonna
read with mommy tonight?
Oh, yeah, that's a good one.
All right my wee man,
I love you so much.
I lo, yeah, bigger than
the whole universe.
Why, thank you my darling.
Yep.
Yeah, yeah, it's good.
Great.
I'll call, I'll call you, I'll
call you when we get there.
All right my darling, bye.
They'd really like to
meet you, you know.
- I'd really like to pee.
- Ow.
- Do you want me
to pull over again?
- No, I'm fine.
- Throws
it into center field.
And then close.
- Oh, that's right.
The Pads are playing
the Braves tonight.
- Okay.
- Do you remember
that game we went
to when The Cowboy hit the
homer and you caught it?
Like it, it, it literally came
down in your little hands.
Do you remember?
- Nope.
- Oh, yes, you do, Turbo.
You, we, we had an
amazing time that time.
- Can you stop calling me that?
- Backup
ball and slipped.
- I wanted to, um-
You okay?
- Yeah, I'm fine.
- Yeah, I just, I
felt like I, I, I should, uh-
- I...
- What's happening?
- I don't know.
I got stung or something.
- What?
Let me have a look.
- God, no.
It's, it's down there, okay?
I-
- What do you mean down there?
- I mean, I was peeing
and I don't know,
something got in, up there.
Whatever.
- Oh, my God, is
it, is it burning?
Is it swollen?
- I don't know, dad.
I'm not gonna, I can't-
- Well, what, you have to
have these things checked out
because there's all kinds of,
there, there could have been
a, like a poisonous insect
or it could have been a snake.
Did you see a snake?
- Jesus Christ, dad.
Stop freaking me out.
- Well, did you see
something like a snake?
How are you feeling?
- I, I-
- Oh, my God.
- Like I'm gonna die now.
- Okay.
I'm gonna find us a,
um, a pharmacy, okay?
Don't panic.
- But don't pa, I wasn't until
you told me that there could,
the poisonous stuff out there.
- Well, there is
poisonous stuff out there.
I'm sure it wasn't that,
but we can't be too careful.
- Oh, am I gonna be okay?
- Pharmacy near me.
- Am I gonna be okay?
- Shoot.
- Dad.
- Pharmacy near me.
Oh, come on.
- Oh, god.
- Pharmacy near me.
- This is how I go.
- Eight miles.
- Dad, I, uh-
- Okay, this is not how you go.
Don't be silly.
Okay.
- This looks closed.
- I know.
But there might
be someone inside.
Let me see.
- Fuck.
- Shit.
Fuck's sake.
- Hi.
- Oh, hi.
Do, do you know of
another pharmacy nearby?
I need to get this one thing
for my daughter and this,
this one's shut and
all of these seem shut.
- No.
No.
Sorry.
- Goddammit.
- I don't.
You're not from
around here, huh?
- Uh, no.
- Yeah, everything closes
around here at seven, sharp.
Except for me.
- What do you do after that?
I mean, what if I,
I just need this,
Look, this is shut.
That's shut.
This one's like nine miles away.
- Like you seem stressed.
- Well, I, I am stressed.
- I could relax you.
- Oh.
Um, no, that's not necessary.
- Are you sure?
- Yeah.
Yeah.
- I can be really fun.
- No, no, I'm sure.
I just, I need, uh, I need
a doctor or a pharmacy.
So, that's what I'm looking for.
Uh, good night.
- Well, um, I'm no doctor,
but I can take a look.
- Maybe you could have a look.
Uh, I would just need you
to look at my daughter's,
um, her lady area.
She had, she got bitten.
- Oh.
- By a something.
It, we, she was peeing
at the side of the road
and she got bitten
by I don't know
if it was a snake or
a spi, that's my worry
is that it was a snake and I-
- Okay.
- She won't let me look,
so if you would look.
Hey, darling.
Um, this kind lady's offered
to take a look at your bite.
- What?
No.
- Well, it's, she's sort of
like a professional person.
- Yeah, no.
- Yeah.
Yeah, that's a spider bite.
It's not too bad though.
I would say it was either a
wolf spider or a tarantula.
- Tarantula?
- Relax.
They get a worse rep
than is warranted for.
Contrary to public belief,
tarantula bites are not deadly.
It's more like a bee sting.
- How do you know
all of this stuff?
- Um, my dad was a park ranger.
So-
- Oh.
That's cool.
- I-
- Oh.
Oh.
- She's gonna be just fine.
- Oh, great.
Thank you so much.
- Told her to ice it.
- Right.
Okay.
- Yeah.
No stranger to having my
pants down on the sides
of these roads.
Gotta be careful.
- Uh, wh, what do I owe you?
- Uh, you guys heading north?
Ooh.
Pancakes.
I love me some pancakes.
- Help yourself.
- Thank you.
- So, do you live around here?
- Uh, yeah.
I was, lived here my
whole life pretty much.
- Oh, really?
- Mm-hmm.
Mm.
And I'm saving up
to move to New York.
- What's in New York?
- I'm gonna be on Broadway.
- Cool.
- Mm-hmm.
- Wow.
- Yep.
I got some plays
that I'm gonna sell,
and then I'm gonna
be a famous actress.
- That's so cool
you wrote a play.
- Several plays, actually.
- That's funny.
- Are you in school?
- Uh, no.
No, I, I was, but not anymore.
- Mm.
I never really liked school.
What did you study or-
- Uh, painting.
- But what
kind of painting?
- I mean, I don't, I just
don't really paint anymore.
- She's an amazing artist.
Amazing.
- I was okay.
- No, no.
Look, let me show you.
- What are you doing?
- I've got a, yeah.
If you scroll through there.
You'll see that she's
really got a gift.
- Oh, wow.
- Right?
Beautiful.
- This, I like these.
Oh.
- That's all her.
- Goodness.
Wow.
- Yeah.
Unique.
- This is so cool.
Dude, why did you stop?
Look at this one.
- Mm.
- As like the background of
one of my sets on Broadway.
You got it.
- You know?
- It's all yours.
And then, um, I'll have
you come on opening night,
sit front row.
They'll ask how did you,
this incredible
playwright slash actress
meet this phenomenal painter?
I'll tell them that
I stared directly
into your pussy years ago
without ever even
knowing your name.
Uh, oh, you know, can
you, right here is good.
- Oh, really?
Okay.
- Yeah.
Great.
Thank you.
- No, thank
you for your help.
Thank you.
- For the ride.
And, um, you should get
some ice on that bite.
- Yeah, will do.
- I will see you
in New York City!
- Okay.
- See ya there.
- Take care of yourself.
- She
took the pumpkin.
- You know back
there at the church,
when you were around
all the candles,
I had this idea for a portrait.
- I didn't know
you did portraits.
- I didn't.
- Well, what was your idea?
- You were just surrounded
by all these strange
religious knick-knacks
and you had this
really intense red glow
from the candles reflecting
all over your face.
Just contrasting with this
really icy blue around you.
- So, I look like a demon?
- No.
Happy.
You just looked happy.
Hey, look at the lighthouse.
- Great.
- All right.
Oh, I'm gonna take a dip.
- No, no, no.
The, the pool area's
closed it said.
- Yeah, well, the
temperature's perfect, so-
- Okay.
Enjoy yourself.
- What, are you afraid
of getting in trouble?
- No, I'm just tired.
I wanna go to the room.
Do you want me to take your bag?
- Yeah.
- Okay.
Have a nice swim.
- Look at you.
All grown up now.
I remember you used
to be way more fun.
- Oh, shut up.
- And here we are at the game.
Who's team are you cheering for?
- Our team!
- Yes!
And are they doing well?
- Yeah.
- Oh.
- Ah.
- Come on.
- Whoa!
- Woo!
Oh, my God.
You scared the shit out of me.
- Oh, my God, it is real nice.
- I told you.
- Oh, my God, what is that?
- What?
- Ah, there's a cockroach.
- Oh, no.
No!
- It's okay.
The chlorine will kill it.
- No, no, ah!
- Oh, my God.
- What?
- It's in your hair.
- Turbo!
Turbo!
- Stop it.
- Excuse me.
Can you not read?
- Oh, sorry.
- Sorry, sir.
- Sorry, sorry, sorry.
We didn't see that.
But we thought maybe, uh-
- Get out.
This is a serious violation.
- Sorry.
- I'm sorry about that.
- Sorry, sir.
- Take your time.
- Oh, we, we, we will get out.
- We'll get out.
- Yeah.
- Sorry, sir.
Whatcha doing?
- Oh.
Just looking for something.
How's your bite?
- A little itchy.
- Oh.
Oh, I'll get you some ice.
There's a machine outside.
- Oh, yeah.
- Okay.
- Thanks.
- Cute.
- Hello?
- Hi.
- Uh-
- Hey.
- Hi.
- S, uh, sorry, my,
uh, my dad ran out just
to get some ice but, um,
for, yeah.
- Oh, no problem.
Yeah.
Hi, hi.
- Hi.
- So, you
made it to the motel?
- Yep.
Yep.
We, uh, we did.
- Good.
That's, that's great.
I was just, I just wanted
to check and make sure.
- I, I can get him to
call you right back.
- Oh, no.
No need.
I, I don't wanna interrupt
your time together.
Um, so how are you?
- I'm good.
Um, I'm great.
- Oh, great.
Oh, good.
I'm, I'm so glad to hear that.
And how's the motel?
- It's really nice.
Um, really nice.
- Oh, good.
- I mean, I, I, I wouldn't
shine a black light
in here, but-
- Yeah.
Yeah.
Bet, better not.
Yeah, no.
Um, well, anyway, uh, I
just, I want to say, and I,
I know it's not my place and I,
I hope I'm not crossing a line
but I think it's very brave
of you going to rehab.
- Yeah.
Uh, totally.
Um, I, I hope to finally
meet you afterwards, if,
if that's something
that you'd like.
- No, yeah.
Uh, after...
- Okay.
Well, good night.
- 'Night.
- Got your ice.
I couldn't remember if you
were, uh, a Reese's person
or a Snickers person, so I,
I got both and some chips.
Some Cokes.
You're gonna have to
wrap this ice in a towel,
though, before you, uh,
Are you in the bathroom?
You okay?
- I spoke
to your new wife.
- You spoke with her?
- Yep.
She wanted to tell me
how proud she was of me
for going to rehab.
Wonder who she got that from?
- Do you
wanna come out?
We can ta, uh, talk about it.
- I really didn't know
that your painter friend
also ran a rehab center.
- I was gonna,
uh, I tried to tell you.
I, uh, uh, just come out.
I didn't know really how to
deal with all this, you know?
- Fuck.
I can't believe this.
What the fuck am I doing here?
- Look, when your mom called
me, she was so terrified,
and I was terrified, too.
- Oh, and you thought
you could just kidnap me?
- No!
You're an addict.
- Oh, geez.
Don't put your shit on me.
Okay?
I'm not like you, dad.
Everybody does drugs.
Everybody drinks.
- Not everybody OD's at six
in the morning and wakes up
in a hospital!
- Oh, so I make
one little mistake
and all of a sudden, what,
you think you can
be my parent again?
- No, you don't get to
call it a little mistake.
A little mistake is like
not setting your
alarm or something.
Your heart stopped!
You almost died!
- And so
what if I did, huh?
What do you care?
You've never cared!
Mom doesn't care!
I don't fucking care.
- What are you talking about?
Well, of course we care.
What do you mean?
I care for you more
than I can even a,
I care more than I can
even express to you.
I ca...
And when we when my
little boy was born,
all I wanted was
for him to know you!
So, you could do things together
and, and protect each other
and be there for each other
and experience life together.
- Oh, my God, of course.
- What?
- Your new fucking baby,
your new fucking life,
your new fucking wife.
- Look, all right, the, uh-
- No, you're just
a phony fuck, okay?
I don't know you.
I don't want to know you.
- Okay, let's calm down.
Calm down.
- No.
- Now let's calm down.
- I, calm down?
What, all of a sudden you
get to tell me to calm down
'cause you're some,
my parent again?
You're not my parent.
You've never been
there for me, dad.
You fucking left.
You left me!
You left us, okay?
You made that decision!
And now you're trying
to make it all nice
for your new fucking wife
and your new fucking baby,
so and hopes the baby she
doesn't see what a fucking,
fucking piece of
shit you really are!
- That's not fair.
- Oh, it's not fair, is it?
- Oh, what,
are you gonna joke
your way out of this?
- No!
You're a fucking asshole!
- And you're trying
to kill yourself!
You're gonna kill yourself!
- Guess who I fucking
learned that from?
- Oh, fuck's sake.
- Oh, yeah.
No, it's too much for
you now, isn't it?
- Yeah.
- Yeah, just fucking go-
- Okay.
- Like you always do.
Just fucking go.
Like you always fucking do.
What the fuck?
- I was
just messing around.
This guy went crazy though.
- What
happened to your face?
- Yeah, yeah, he
kicked off of me.
Don't you think it's kinda cute?
- No.
What is wrong with you?
What's wrong with you.
You can't say you
want to stop drinking
if you're going out every night.
- Hey, Turbo.
- She didn't know.
What the hell?
- Oh, shit.
Oh, my God.
I am so sorry.
- No, it, it's not your fault.
I should have, um, well,
I should have told her.
- Okay, well,
what, what's going on now?
What's, what's happening?
- She's so angry
with me and I, uh,
I can't even speak to her.
Like I, uh, now I know what
I would liked to have said,
but in the moment,
I'm just like I get,
get frozen and I can't
think of what to say and I-
- Yeah, of course.
She's gonna be angry.
Okay?
She's gonna push back.
She's struggling with
serious addiction.
- Yeah, I know, but
it's more than that.
Like I haven't, I haven't,
uh, I haven't seen her
or spoken to her in ages, and
she thinks it's because I,
uh, I don't try or
that I didn't want to.
And well, maybe I didn't.
- I understand.
I understand.
- I know, but I don't
think you really know
what it was li, what I was like.
It was, I was bad.
I was like a terrible father
and, uh, spending time
with her now is just bringing
it all back, you know,
and I, I hate it.
I fucking hate who I was then.
- Yeah, you're
not that person anymore.
You're not.
- I know, but she, she
thinks that I am.
Shit.
- Come on, come on, come
on, come on, come on.
Come on, come on, come
Come on.
Fuck.
Hey man, sorry.
Um, uh, I'm ju, just
wondering if, um,
do you know where
I can get high?
- Um, I didn't know
girls still got into cars
with with strangers.
I'm not strange, but, you
know, you know what I'm saying.
Um...
- Oh, excuse me.
Did a young girl, a girl
or a woman come in here?
Probably about five
eight, brown hair.
She's 20 years old.
She's wearing a,
a brown sweater.
- I wish.
- Okay, thanks.
- Yeah, it's been a while.
Like, I'm just, I just get
sort of like scratchy eyes
and like a runny nose
and then you see hives.
I don't know, I just fear
it's worsening, you know,
'cause like cats, they're
just fucking adorable.
Yeah.
Um, uh, you can just,
no, you, uh, you wait,
wait here for a second.
Fuck.
Rain, rain, go away,
right?
Ah, ladies first.
Ooh.
Hey.
You, um, you sit on
whatever you want.
- I ask you to get some
milk and cigarettes,
and you bring back
a whole ass girl.
- I'm an over-achiever.
- You want a soda?
- Uh, sure.
- So, what do you want?
- Oh, whoa, hey.
Um, baby, um, where
are your manners?
She, she's our guest.
She just got here.
Let's, let's have
our manner hat on.
- I was just making
sure she knows
she's not getting any freebies.
- She's not getting
any freebies.
- Okay.
- She knows.
- Now, why don't you
be a good little girl
and get that globe?
- What
am I, the butler?
Hmm?
- Just get it.
She's not
always such a cunt.
- Oh, it's, it's okay.
- Um, you like music?
- Yeah.
- So,
where are you from?
- Uh, San Diego.
- I see you.
And, um, they don't tell
girls in San Diego not
to get in cars with strangers?
- That's what I said.
Fuckin' great minds.
Um, yeah, she's lucky.
She could've ended up
with a real weirdo.
- Um, what is it?
- I don't know!
- Is it coke?
- You tell me.
Yeah, yes.
- Well, don't hog it all, babe.
Come on.
Woo!
Yeah.
- Oh, yeah.
Oh, yeah.
Put some pep in that step.
- Come dance with me.
- Oh, no.
I'm, I'm good.
- Oh, come on.
- Hey, you think I
can get another one?
- Oh.
I knew I liked you.
- I'm sorry everyone.
I'm sorry to bother you.
I'm just trying to
find my daughter.
We, we became, uh,
I wondered if maybe she
came in here earlier.
She's 20 years old.
She's got brown hair.
About this high.
She's a sweet girl.
She's quite, she's quite funny.
Does anyone seen her in here?
She might be a bit upset.
Uh, no?
She might have come in here.
We had a bit of a argument,
but, do you think she
maybe came in earlier.
- Hey.
So where are you staying?
- Huh?
- Would you shut up?
Be nice.
- I'm just saying.
We haven't even seen one
dollar or heard one thank you.
- Thank you.
- She's gonna pay.
She's gonna pay.
Isn't that right?
- Do you have a
bathroom I could use?
Oh shit.
- Hell no.
Nah, you ain't
getting off that easy.
Oh, for fuck's sake.
- You'll be fine.
- Oh.
Cash, grass, or ass.
No one rides for free.
- Have a nice day.
- Bye.
- Go on.
- Hello?
Honey!
Hello?
Okay.
Oh.
Oh, thank goodness you're alive.
- What's wrong with her?
- Psst, mm-mm.
How did you get there, honey?
Do you know what day it is?
Oh, dear.
what, maybe we should
call an ambulance.
- No, no.
No, please don't do that.
I, I was camping and I, I went
to pee and I think I fell.
- You sure there
isn't anybody we can call?
Maybe your mom?
Pretty fun.
What do you think?
Come on, not last in space.
- Mom?
- Are you okay?
Your dad called me.
Where are you now?
- Yeah.
I'm okay.
I'm physically okay.
I just, um, I, I just
lost, I just went
for a walk after our fight
and couldn't find my key
so I slept by, by the pool.
I'm just borrowing someone's
phone who's staying
at the motel.
I'm, I'm really okay.
I just, Mom, I just want,
I just wanna come home.
I know I fucked
up, okay, but please.
Mom, say something.
- You need
to talk to your dad.
- You're such a hypocrite.
- Because-
- You know, I don't get it.
I don't get why you
still want him around
after everything
he's put us through.
After, after everything
he's done to you,
why don't you hate him?
- Hello?
- Dad?
- What are we doing?
- Well, I just assumed
you'd need to pee.
Turbo, don't be too embarrassed
by your old dad's diary.
You are like me,
but better.
But I love you more.
Dad.
Here.
Okay.
That's it.
Yeah, you got it.
Just now put your arm
up on the, that's it.
Slouch down a bit.
Yeah.
Now you're looking cool.
- Yeah.
- Love this one.
- Okay.
- So, where are we headed?
- What do you mean?
- Well, you're the driver now.
- Yeah, right.
- Yeah, where do you wanna go?
- I feel like
this is some kind of trap.
- It's your decision.
You can turn 'round and go home.
We can do that or...
- Um, do you have to
sign me in or something?
- No.
It's all you.
- Okay.
- I'll see you in a few weeks.
- Yeah, you will.
I...
- I know.
- Hi.
Welcome.
And Congrats on the first step
to your journey of recovery.
You've already done
the hardest part,
which is walking
through the door.
You should be so
proud of yourself.
- Come on.