Extracted by\Nll sCarLet ll\N@wahab_94
Please don't tell anyone about this.
The whole neighborhood already knows!
The whole neighborhood?
Who told you?
Forget it. Nobody knows.
Exactly.
Half the neighbors did it.
I didn't do the job for them.
They extended it themselves?
Who told you?
- Nobody.
- I'm doing this as a favor.
Is this a tree clipper?
Just let me work!
What's wrong?
Why are you barefoot, darling?
It's too dark inside.
Wasn't dinner at my parents
better than this?
Why are you mad?
I already told you I have an important
meeting tonight.
You always have important meetings!
You have to visit my parents,
they want to see you.
I can't tonight, at all.
But I already told them
we're coming tonight.
Apologize to them.
Apologize again?
Then don't apologize!
There'll be no mercy in this game!
It's the fifth time he's calling.
I don't know what to tell him.
He's already waited for three weeks,
he can wait another day.
You've been saying this for 3 weeks!
I can't make a living because of you.
I'll solve it tomorrow.
The custom's guy promised
that it will be done by tomorrow 10 am.
If you don't pay him under the table,
the laptops will rust
and you'll be wasting your time!
You're right, Abu Sameer,
you have to pay him,
and that's why you'll pay the price
with this King!
Should I be stuck with this card?
Who else, me?
- Good for you.
- You don't know how to play.
Do you have diamond cards?
None.
Show me.
Forget about my cards,
you don't know how to play!
I swear, I won't play with you.
Come on, man.
No way, I won't play.
I'll still write down your score!
Here comes the nagging!
My wife is calling.
Why is everybody grumpy tonight?
Hello. Yes, darling.
What's wrong with Mom? Why?
Ok, lock the door, I'll be home soon.
Ok, bye, darling.
Is everything ok?
As usual, my wife got mad.
We were supposed to visit her parents,
and we didn't.
The girls are home alone?
Yes.
We're done for tonight! Leave.
Don't forget about tomorrow.
The guy filed a lawsuit against me.
Don't worry.
Make some room, guys.
Please, guys.
- Hello.
Your ID, please.
Who are you?
Criminal investigation.
Can I see your ID?
Sure, it is your right.
Never mind.
Here you go, sir.
- Ahmad Taher?
- Yes.
Can you please come with us?
What is wrong?
We need you at the station for 5 minutes.
Those 5 minutes will become a year!
You'll be out in an hour.
Can I make a call?
I want to inform my wife
and I have stuff in my car.
- Is it urgent?
- Yes.
Hello.
Cousin, listen.
I don't have time for hellos and all that.
Come take the car, its next to
the juice shop opposite the phone shop.
The key is inside.
Where am I going?
It's your fault!
I got dragged by the ants!
Sir, can I have a cigarette?
I wish it was up to me
but it's not allowed,
do you see the camera up there?
Will I go to court today?
It won't be till tomorrow.
What?
I'm staying here till tomorrow?
No. I'll take you to a bigger cell
downstairs.
Can you take me now? I want to sleep.
You need to wait till someone joins you.
You ruined my life!
You know the law, it's your fault.
Stop it now.
Didn't you see me coming from behind?
How could I see you? I wasn't in the car!
It's your fault!
You hit the rear of my car!
Stop it, guys.
Not a single word.
Don't talk till I ask you to.
Tell me what happened.
Sir, I was driving all peacefully,
and he suddenly popped out in front of me.
I was parked there for 5 hours!
You think I can afford wasting 5 hours!
Do you know how much it costs for a taxi
to park for 5 hours?
I hit the brakes 5 meters away
from your car.
You wrecked it after I fixed it.
The bumper was new sir!
I followed the rules.
According to the law, it's your fault,
since you hit my rear!
And who dripped the oil on the street!
I don't know about the oil.
Guys.
- It was like a new bride, sir.
- You suddenly popped up in the street.
- You hit my rear!
- Stop it, guys.
Guys, just relax for a minute.
I think it's the mechanic's fault
for dripping the oil.
Need anything, old man?
Yes, a cigarette, please!
Give him a cigarette, sir.
He's sitting there like a chicken.
Have some mercy, he's a human being.
Stop blabbering,
another word and you'll be joining him.
Wait outside for the patrol officer.
Not another word.
Give me a 100 Dinars
and I'll call it a day.
- Good evening, sir.
- Good evening.
God! Finally someone joins me.
What brought you here?
I finished a year's sentence yesterday.
What were you in for?
Forged checks.
You spent a year inside?
Was it worth it?
The checks bought me 4 cars.
If I worked a whole year...
I won't even be able to buy a tire!
That's true!
What about you?
Nothing serious.
I'll be out tomorrow,
when my cousin pays bail.
Good morning.
Good morning!
Just in time, your papers are ready.
Really?
Yes, it's just missing
the manager's signature.
Your file is on his desk.
It's just missing one signature.
Ok, get it signed.
He's off today.
It's his son's wedding today.
I wish he was here,
I could have congratulated him.
He would've liked that.
Listen
I've been running back and forth
for a while and it's a new story everyday.
Please help me get the laptops released.
It's not up to me, you know that.
But it's in his hand now
and he's busy with the wedding these days
and Eid holiday is coming up
and he has to get lots of sheep for feasts
for a lot of guests
and the sheep should be local
because imported sheep are tasteless
and the local markets
only have imported sheep.
You're right, no point of a feast
without local sheep!
- It's an embarrassment.
- Exactly!
You're right!
- It will be fine.
- God willing.
So, Salameh, where did you find
the Islamic center receipts?
I found them on the street, sir.
You found them on the street?
Cut the crap, smart ass!
Listen, Salameh,
I'm a civilized and an understanding
District Attorney
but don't make me jump on this table
do a couple of somersaults
and go back in time 4,000 years
and become a savage monster
and stomp on your stomach.
So, don't push me too far,
and tell me the truth.
- Where did you get them from?
- I printed them, sir.
You should've said that from the start.
You scumbag,
you scam in the name
of the Islamic center?
Go scam women who drive
fancy Jeeps instead!
Zuhair.
Take him, please.
Move it!
What do you do?
A contractor.
Did you take 1800 Dinars
from the plaintiff?
- Yes, I did.
- But I wanted to...
- So you took them?
- Yes, I took them.
That's all I want to know.
Sir, give me a couple of days...
You can ask the judge for that,
not me,
I can't help you at all.
Take him officer.
What are you in for?
Fraud.
God bless you!
Put your arms up.
Here you go.
Just knock on the door for anything
you need, I am available.
What do you do?
A contractor.
Man...
I started building a room on my roof
but ran out of money.
I don't know what to do.
I'd help, but I'm off to prison.
I'll keep them standing
till a miracle happens!
Sir, can I make a call?
It's not allowed, but here, make it quick.
Hello.
Tell my cousin to come
to Tareq station urgently.
Guys, I'm collecting money
to buy us dinner.
Each has to pay 2.5 Dinars.
It will get us a decent dinner.
Let's all pitch in, so we can eat.
Do you want to pay for dinner?
No, thanks.
As you like!
Did you check that apartment for rent?
I did, but it has no balcony.
The balcony isn't important.
We need to leave this apartment.
But this one is closer to Mom's house.
That's why we should leave.
Ahmad Taher Farraj.
Is my cousin here?
What cousin?
Didn't you ask me for food?
Yes, food and cigarettes.
So give me 7 Dinars.
5 is enough.
No problem, you'll get the food soon.
But don't tell anyone that you paid me.
Why, is food illegal here?
Just do as you're told!
How much did you pay him?
5 Dinars.
If you paid me you
would've saved a lot.
- He pockets the rest!
- So what.
Osama Melhim Qaddoura.
- Did you take the goods?
- Yes, sir.
Did the plaintiff drop the charges?
No, sir.
Your sentence is 8 months.
This isn't fair.
8 months is good,
you already got the money! Go!
You, come closer.
- Ahmad Taher Farraj.
- Yes, sir.
Swear on the Holy Quran to tell the truth.
I swear to tell the truth
and nothing but the truth.
Were you paid to build the wall?
Yes, sir.
Did you build the wall?
I couldn't build it, I had a situation.
But I can repay the plaintiff.
So you took the money,
but didn't build the wall?
Exactly.
Why didn't you pay him back then?
Your sentence is 3 months.
You have anything to say?
3 months?
Sir, I want to appoint a lawyer, please.
Why?
It's only 3 months.
It's fair.
But I have the money, I can get out today.
Pay and I'll let you go.
Next.
Please wait for 10 minutes.
My phone battery is dead.
Can I use yours?
Sorry, I don't have credit.
Where can I recharge mine?
You want to recharge it?
Let's take a walk.
What are you talking about?
I just got sentenced.
We'll look for a charger.
I'll find you the best charger.
Do you have internet on your phone?
No.
Do you have a Facebook account?
No, I don't.
Can you create a Facebook account
without the internet?
You can't create one
without the internet.
I heard that one gets to meet people
from any country.
What do I need to make an account?
You need electricity, a phone, a landline
and a decent picture.
What are you looking for? The girl left.
What girl? I'm looking for a charger!
- Hello.
How much are the sheep for?
- What kind?
- A local one.
I have one.
For how much?
150 Dinars.
I need a discount.
What do you mean?
130 Dinars is fair.
- Do you think I stole it?
- Of course not.
- Do you want it?
- Yes!
Then pay 150!
- That's your best price?
- Yes!
Don't worry. I trust this guy.
Tell the driver to go faster we're bored.
And turn the fan on.
How about I get you air-conditioning?
Let me take this.
Hello. It's all fine.
We didn't expect to get off this easily.
Much better than we thought.
What are you guys in for?
Have you heard of the stock market case?
Yes.
We are the stock market guys.
You did a great job!
Goodbye.
Can I use your phone?
Sure. And take your time.
Thanks!
This is a touch phone.
Wait.
Hello.
Cousin, I got sentenced.
What?
One second.
The sheep! Wait.
God damn you.
Just a minute.
What sheep? Hello!
Attention!
Where are the stock market guys?
Stand at the other side.
There are rules you must follow here.
Calls are absolutely forbidden.
No visits for the first 6 months.
No integration with prisoners. Understood?
What do you want?
I am not with them, sir.
What are you in for?
Fraud.
Why are you standing with them then?
Get the hell away!
Are my rules clear?
Give me your hand!
Your prints. The first finger.
The second here.
The third here.
The fourth.
Your thumb here.
Change your clothes.
Put your belongings in the safe
then go to cell 6W.
- Move it.
- Next!
Higher.
AHMAD TAHER FARRAJ - FRAUD
Turn right.
Sir, I need a drink of water.
After dinner!
I'm really thirsty.
Can't you wait till after dinner?
Do you want to end up in solitary tonight!
Everybody stand up!
Stand in line. Next to the wall.
- Welcome sir.
- Hello.
- How are you?
- I'm well.
- Welcome, sir.
- Thanks.
- How are you?
- Good.
What are you in for?
Fraud.
Welcome, sir. Let me take this.
Are you joining us for a long time?
- I hope not!
- Be patient.
See the Friday flee market there?
That man is our cell leader.
Fine, but I need to sleep.
Go see him first.
- I'll do it, sir.
- I want to sleep.
Mor, here is Tuesday's batch, one piece!
Come here.
Have some coffee.
Bis, make us some coffee.
- You have plenty of time.
- Hello.
Hello.
Welcome.
What brought you here?
Fraud.
Did you benefit from it?
Not really.
God bless you.
This is my shop.
It's all at your disposal.
All these prisoners are my customers
and now you'll become my customer too.
Give me 15 Dinars to open
an instant account for you.
Plus 1 Dinar for cleaning service.
Now?
Yes. Why are you scared?
Come on.
I have 20. Give me back 5.
20?
15 plus 1 for cleaning,
then you'll have 4 on tab.
So you're in for fraud?
Not a big deal.
Just 1800 Dinars.
What?
Yes.
An old man like you in prison
for 1800 Dinars?
I don't know what to say.
Did you confess?
Yes, I did.
Why did you confess?
I swore on the Holy Quran.
You are a moron
for doing this to yourself!
Yes, I'm an idiot!
But I couldn't lie with my hand
on the Quran.
Bis prepared your bed, go have some rest.
God bless you, my dear.
Sir.
- What?
- I prepared your bed.
What do you want?
Can you believe I had no visits
in the past 6 months?
Can you please give me some cigarettes?
Take 2 from under the pillow.
Get some rest.
If you want cigarettes, just call me.
You took the whole pack?
- You want the pack?
- Of course I do!
- I was guarding it for you.
- I told you to take 2.
- It's your turn.
- I pass!
How come? Who has the Jack?
Pass.
- Here's a 7.
- What's the use of a 7!
I have the 9! Just play.
- Pass.
- Just focus, Dead Man!
Shut the hell up!
Turn the light on, old man!
How am I supposed to sleep?
That's your problem.
Why did you sleep up there?
Turn it on and let the night go in peace
or I'll come up to you!
Wait, I can't see.
Turn it on!
Turn on the damn light.
Just ignore him, man.
How can I ignore him,
I can't see the cards.
Come on, play.
- I don't want to play!
- Come on, play!
Don't ruin the game, don't be a child!
Go to bed!
He drove me crazy!
Cell count!
Turn the light on.
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7...
Did you turn off the water tap?
Of course.
From now on,
always keep the water running.
Why waste all that water?
Are you paying for it from
your own pocket?
When you leave it running,
the bathroom stays clean.
One can have a clean shower
and feel fresh.
So keep it running next time!
Fine, no problem.
Pass the ball.
I'm so sick of this,
please get me out of here.
It's almost over, cousin!
Just pay the 1800 Dinars. I've had it!
What did the lawyer tell you?
What lawyer?
Who asked for Ahmad Taher?
Hello.
Are you my lawyer?
Yes, your cousin appointed me
for your case.
You'll get the money in the coming
couple of days.
I know, just sign the proxy
so I can start working.
My fees are 200 Dinars, 100 is due now
and 100 is due when you get out.
Is my case easy?
As simple as a drink of water!
I don't even consider this a case.
I'll be out before Eid?
For sure, just like I can see you
right now!
You'll dress up and celebrate
with your kids.
Sign here so I can start working.
- Here you go.
- May God bless you.
Let's hope so!
Please walk me to the door.
Don't be sad, darling.
Smile for our guests.
I'm so scared, Mom.
Don't be scared.
He's your husband now.
What if he beats me up?
Oh, my God!
Where did you get such an idea?
I'm scared, Mom.
Why would he beat you up?
- Come greet your guests.
- I'm coming.
Coffee. Coffee's ready, guys.
Sugarless, semi-sweet
and sweet coffee.
It's hot and ready.
Coffee, guys.
Get the hell out of here!
You're all watching this series now!
I won't leave till this thermos is empty!
- Coffee is ready, guys.
- Bis, no one has time for you.
- Coffee is hot and ready.
- Bis! We don't want your damn coffee!
Coffee, guys. Coffee.
Damn you!
Coffee.
Cell count!
Turn on the light.
It doesn't work.
Why?
There is no starter.
Where is it?
I don't know.
- You don't know?
- No, I don't.
Ok.
Search for it in every hole!
Search over there.
There's the sheep! Get it!
Wake up.
Wake up! Hurry up.
Get up. Faster.
Put your hands on the wall.
You don't want to admit
who took the starter?
So it grew legs and ran off?
This starter is your responsibility.
You will all be punished for this!
One of you, man up and confess!
The cell is ready for inspection, sir.
Sir, they don't want to admit
who took the starter.
Repeat after me, guys.
Long live his Majesty the King!
May he live!
May he live.
Long live his Majesty the King!
May he live!
Are they dismissed, sir?
They may go.
Dismissed!
Quickly.
Come here, boy.
Where is Abu Haitham's house?
This is his son.
- You're his son?
- Yes.
- Where is your house?
- Over there.
- That one?
- Yes.
Please get your father.
Welcome.
Hello.
- Welcome.
- Thanks.
Praise God. Is it local?
Local, like you wanted!
- Please come in.
- Thanks.
Praise God.
Local, like you requested.
Fouad Mohamed Abdel Majeed.
Yes.
You've been released.
Bring your things and follow me.
Wait?
Where are you going?
What's up?
You think you can just move to that bed?
I have a bad back.
I can't climb up to the high beds.
You think I can? I am a monkey in a circus
jumping around all day?
You're not a monkey or anything, but...
Put back the mattress,
I've been here longer so it's my turn.
- Ok.
- Stop!
You had a bottom bed, but you broke it.
If you care about him, give him your bed
and get rid of your shopping mall!
What? You want my bed? It's better for you
to go back to your bed.
You care about him because he buys
a lot from you?
- Shut up.
- To hell with you and your mall.
Shut up and go to your bed.
- He pays you always so you care for him!
- Shut up.
- Mor, ignore him.
- I've had it with you!
I got the bed, no issues.
What is Dead Man's story?
He bought himself a life insurance policy.
And next day faked his own death
and issued his own death certificate
and in return got 100,000 Dinars!
Wow!
How did he fake it?
He spoofed his brother's identity.
He looks a lot like him.
There is no evidence
proving he's still alive.
He agreed with his wife
that she'd collect the money.
When she found out that he made
his brother the only beneficiary
she went insane, so she reported him
and he ended up here.
He's an idiot!
An ass, a mule!
That's why we call him Dead Man.
The problem is he's worthless
and arrogant.
A bed wetter and wants
to sleep in the middle?
Good one!
Guys, the warden is coming for a visit.
Listen carefully and focus.
Let's all sing together.
Don't ask vague questions.
Let's be organized and talk one at a time.
I have great suggestions
to make our lives better.
Therefore, I should be first to speak. Ok?
You always do this!
You only ask for extra calls for yourself.
That's not true.
Who got you extra calls last time?
As usual!
Come on, guys.
Cell W6, attention!
Long live his Majesty the King.
May he...
- How is everything?
- We are well, sir.
Any requests?
All is good.
If you allow me to speak.
I really need to call my wife.
- Let him make a call.
- Yes, sir.
I need a call, too.
Let him make a call, too.
Let 10 men make calls.
The ones that didn't call last time.
God bless you.
It's our fault!
Yes!
What's up, guys?
I haven't called my wife in 3 months.
What a liar!
You keep promising to fix my computer
but doing nothing.
I'll fix it soon, be patient.
Please fix it,
I want to call my sister online.
Don't worry, I'll fix it soon.
10 NEW LAPTOPS IMPORTED FROM
CANADA FOR SALE FOR 6,000 DINARS
Please give me some good news!
Great news!
The laptops were released
from customs today!
I wish I could believe you!
It's been over 3 weeks.
I placed an ad in the newspaper
asking for retail cost.
I swear I made no profit!
I'll sell them soon and bail you out.
Are you sure?
Come on, cousin, I'm trying my best.
I'll keep you posted.
- Play, old man!
- Pass!
You pass more than you play!
We can't see, how can we play?
Cut this crap!
I won't switch on the light
and the cafe is closed. Go to bed!
Would you just cut the crap
and switch it on now!
Do it, before I force you to do!
Force me? You want the light? Sure.
Here, I switched it on.
Now get your ass over here!
I don't mind going to solitary tonight!
I said switch on the damn light!
Who the hell do you think you are?
He'll switch it on
whether he likes it or not!
You want the light?
Here's your light!
- Who the hell do you think you are?
- Calm down, you guys.
No more playing cards! All of you to bed!
Go to bed!
What's all this shouting?
- He broke the light, sir.
- Who broke it?
- I broke it.
- Why?
They play cards all night,
we want to sleep!
Get your blanket and follow me.
Solitary is better than this shit hole.
Where did you get them from?
From Canada.
- They're all the same?
- Yes, you can check them if you like.
- The money is ready.
- Great.
Follow me to my office?
Sure.
How about you ride with me
rather than taking a taxi?
- That would be better.
- Fine, get in.
We'll move them to your car.
Wait here. I'll get the money
and come back.
Sure.
- Hello.
Yes, I can hear you.
Why don't you come up, sign the contract
and take the money.
What?
Can you see me?
Yes, I can see you.
The fourth floor, come up.
Are the laptops safe here?
Yes, I'll lock it now.
See, it's locked.
Ok, I'm coming up.
What are you still doing here?
Waiting for my lawyer.
If he wanted to come,
he would have by now!
Let's wait for a bit.
You can't wait any more,
I'm locking the cell in 10 minutes.
Get up! Come on.
The number you're calling is currently
switched off, please try again later.
You still didn't fix the computer.
I told you I'll fix it! Stop nagging!
What's this?
Open it!
Thanks, darling.
Looks like you're spending Eid
here, old man.
Mor, go see what's wrong with him.
What's wrong, my dear?
You don't seem to be good.
What's wrong?
Nothing's wrong.
Have some faith.
God is great and merciful.
I deserve what happened to me.
Stop it now. All will be fine.
Stop sulking.
You'll be out in no time.
It's only a few days.
They'll fly by in no time.
Believe me, when you get out...
you'll miss the prison days.
I don't know how my family is managing.
Eid is coming up.
Have faith in God.
Don't worry.
They won't die without you.
Let's go wash up for prayers, come on.
All praise is due to Allah,
Lord of the worlds
The Entirely Merciful,
Sovereign of the Day of Recompense.
It is You we worship
and You we ask for help.
Guide us to the straight path
The path of those upon whom
You have bestowed favor,
not of those who have evoked
Your anger or of those who are astray.
Amen.
By the morning brightness and
by the night when it covers with darkness,
Your Lord has not taken leave of you,
O Muhammad, nor has He detested you.
And the Hereafter is better for you
than the first life.
And your Lord is going to give you,
and you will be satisfied.
Did He not find you an orphan
and give you refuge?
And He found you lost and guided you,
And He found you poor
and made you self-sufficient.
So as for the orphan,
do not oppress him.
And as for the petitioner,
do not repel him.
But as for the favor of your Lord,
report it.
- God is Great.
Finally! You've been promising
me to call for 2 months!
When you buy a dongle here,
it works as soon as you get home!
Put your hands up. Don't move!
What the hell is going on?
- Search the house.
- What's happening?
How did you subscribe to the internet?
I used the family extract.
Very smart of you!
What's going on?
Get up.
Ibrahim!
What's happening?
Somebody answer me!
Wow.
What delicious lentil soup.
What a great chef.
Nothing's missing
just a clove of garlic
a pinch of salt
and a squeeze of lemon.
Where to...
to the garbage bin!
God damn you,
this is diarrhea soup!
You really love that woman
you're always calling?
Please, Ahmad, don't poke my wounds.
Don't remind me of her.
You're head over heels.
You call her a lot!
I call her at any chance I get.
She's completely in love with me!
Then marry her!
When I get released.
I'm waiting for the pardon.
Which one is he?
The second one to the right, sir.
Fine. Please follow me.
Mor, you never told me what you're in for.
Spying.
Why are you sunbathing with the frauds?
Leave me alone. I can't get her
voice out of my head.
Looks like you're head over heels!
Why doesn't she visit you?
I wish...
I'm sure her family won't let her.
- Don't you want to see her?
- Please find me a way!
What's up, guys?
The whole country's naked
inside and outside!
But, outside, people are hairless!
Ahmad, your cousin rotted while
waiting for you.
Forget about him.
Come sunbathe with us.
Sunbathe?
You can call this wheat bathing
or sweat bathing, hair bathing.
Whatever. Just come.
Give us a break.
Give you a break?
Mor, what's all this beauty?
What a beautiful sight! Where were
you hiding this silky white skin?
Just come, relax, you're always tense.
I would've joined if it wasn't a slumber.
I'll put on my one-piece swimsuit
and come back.
Get naked.
Politicians in Custody for Fraud Win
Seats in Parliamentary Elections
Technology is amazing!
With this tiny dongle...
you can connect to the internet
and see anything in Jordan.
That's enough now,
take it to the safe department!
How do you create a Facebook account?
What, Facebook now? Enough!
Let me be just a little while longer.
Always in a hurry!
Who has some extra bread?
Who has extra bread?
What the hell?
Are we in Somalia!?
I need bread, not a blood unit!
Come here.
Why didn't you say something earlier,
you heard me asking for the past hour.
Speak up! Say I have some.
You stole a 100,000
and you're looking for a loaf?
You talk as if you stole a million!
You're an old man with grey hair...
and thick glasses in jail for 1800 Dinars.
You should be ashamed of yourself.
In this country,
the only way is to hit and run.
You're a man if you don't get caught.
But you got caught.
You think they were smart enough
to catch me? It's my damn wife's fault.
I hope I get rid of her.
From trust comes betrayal.
The end of a...
A betrayed man, my dear!
Dance with me!
Guys, let's hear some noise!
Jaloul, come. It's an orphanage over here!
Cell W6! Attention!
The cell is ready for inspection, sir.
How are you today? Need anything?
Everything is fine, sir.
But I have family issues.
I'm desperate for a call
to solve the issue, if you please.
This is not fair, sir.
He always makes calls.
We all have families too!
We all want to make phone calls.
That's true, sir.
There will be no calls for you this time.
Yes, sir.
- Let 10 men make calls.
- Yes, sir.
Any other requests?
Sir, the food is a bit salty.
Is that all?
- Get the kitchen to cut down on salt.
- Yes, sir.
Jaloul...
You owe me 18 Dinars from 3 months ago.
Let's see if I get money today.
I want the cash.
- I'll see what I can do.
- Find a way.
- Excuse me.
- What?
You owe me 35 Dinars.
Don't forget this time.
35? Do they hatch and multiply?
Details are here!
- Your whole shop isn't worth 35 Dinars.
- Everything is written here.
Find a way.
- Yeah, whatever!
- Find a way!
Ahmad, come here.
- Please do me a favor.
- What?
Keep an eye on Jaloul and Dead Man.
See if they receive money during visits.
Sure, don't worry.
Watch them closely.
I'll be on them like a hawk!
- I'll have a treat for you.
- I'll let you know.
God bless you.
Hello.
How's my little Nasnoos?
She sends her regards.
Will you be home next week?
Your cousin did nothing to get you out.
I borrowed money
from our neighbors' market.
They let me take groceries for free.
Not completely free, but till you get out.
They'll wait till you get back
on your feet,
but they won't wait forever.
And the girls need new school uniforms.
Electricity bills Ahmad...
Welcome our hero!
Come on, cousin.
You really thought I'd forget about you?
3 minutes and you'll slip away forever.
Cousin, I really don't know what to say.
Don't say a damn thing!
You ruined my life!
I'm still stuck in here!
I swear a guy stole all the laptops
except for one.
You deserve it!
You should be here! Not me!
I'm so sorry.
I'll pick up the last laptop tomorrow.
When you get out,
I'll pay all that I owe you.
Did Jaloul and Dead Man
get money at the visit?
I'm sure they did!
They get visitors everyday
Did you see them receiving money?
Listen, Mor...
it's not a matter of receiving money
or not.
They just don't want to pay.
I think they don't take you
seriously anymore.
I have the same feeling. You're right.
If I were you, I'd remind them
who is the boss here.
Act quickly before you end up
with nothing.
You think so?
That's what I think.
You owe me 7 Dinars from last month.
Pay me, I've had it with you.
Get me the money.
Ok.
Sir.
You owe me 35 Dinars
Pay them now and I'll close your account
and won't deal with you anymore.
I'm the one who doesn't
want to deal with you.
Please close my Swiss account!
Watch your mouth, and pay what you owe.
You watch your mouth, and don't shout.
Who do you think you are?
You're nothing
You're worthless,
you're dead in the first place.
I'll pay you back and give you
a slipper on top of them.
- Leave me!
- Calm down.
Today's your end.
I should've beaten you up a long time ago.
Come here, you bastard.
I'm going to squash you.
I'll have you for breakfast!
Kick his ass, he deserves it.
I'll teach you all a lesson.
I'm your boss whether you like it or not!
Welcome back!
Thanks. You're here?
Of course, where would I be?
You were out for 2 months only,
why are you back?
I came to relax for a while.
Relax all you want.
You just missed a fight!
Old man, get up!
Bis, get up. The shop.
Wake up!
Ahmad, get up!
You haven't smoked in a month!
Move it.
What are you bastards doing?
What's happening? Bastards!
Our beloved Mor, our darling Mor.
The best shop, that once was a shop.
Let's hear, the robbery!
Listen
If you need a job once you're out,
I'll find you one.
I'm not blessed with honest money,
how about with dishonest?
Dishonest?
You think I was born a fraud?
My first time in jail,
I was falsely accused.
Aren't you tired of this life?
I tried and I am not supposed
to be here now.
It's my wife's fault!
She got me tracked from the new internet
connection she got.
Damn that dongle!
Like an idiot, I got her a new laptop!
Don't even mention laptops.
They ruined my life.
Look at me, I'm here cleaning rice!
I got a golden opportunity,
10 new laptops, I couldn't resist!
10 laptops?
The idiot imported them from Canada.
God damn you! You screwed me over!
What's wrong, guys?
Calm down, Ahmad.
- What's wrong?
- He's stole the laptops from my cousin!
- Calm down, guys.
- Calm down.
Here's your tea.
Get the hell out of here!
- I don't want tea.
- Fine, don't drink it!
Get out of here!
What's up with you?
You didn't go to the yard today.
Come on, Mor, cheer up!
The Holy land has been taken
and no one got upset
and you're upset about a tiny shop?
- Hello.
- Welcome.
Sir, I'm here for my laptop.
Come in a week.
Why after a week?
I am sure you have the laptop.
It's in the safe department.
Look? All these are robbery
inventory files and this takes time.
Please help me.
I can't keep running around.
The officer told me I'll take it today.
Come back in 3 days.
This is a personal favor to you.
Leave now.
Don't huff and puff. Leave!
We have work to do!
Ahmad Taher Farraj.
You're released.
YOU'LL ALWAYS BE MOR, OUR LEADER.
CELL W6, AHMAD
Will you help me finish building
the room on my roof?
Buy the materials
and I won't charge you for my fee.
How about you buy the materials
and I'll pay you back in installments.
Of course not?
That way I'll be plowing on a rooster!
Then I'll leave them as they are!
How are you?
I remember what you used to do
to our teacher in school?
Look at you now, you became a mayor!
I didn't expect you'll become a mayor.
I'm still aiming for even higher ranks!
Your biggest ambition was to be
a mechanic or a car electrician.
I have no idea how you became mayor!
- Remember the good old days?
- Of course I do!
- Ahmad Taher Farraj.
- Yes, sir.
You and the likes of you
are ruining our country.
I'm giving you 3 months probation.
I didn't ruin anything.
I know a man in prison if he gets out
he'll ruin the country!
Get the hell out of my face!
Stop. Give me your hands.
Why? I got released!
I have to hand you back to the station
I received you from
and from there you can go home.
It'll take an hour
and you'll go back home.
Why are you in a hurry? We're having fun.
- Ok.
- Ok?
What are you guys in for?
National security.
Sir?
I should be transferred under minimum
security, why am I with them?
You're right, but they are on our way!
Hello.
Yes.
Raise your voice!
What?
Hello.
What did you say?
Guys, please put on your handcuffs
before we get to the station.
Hello.
Raise your voice!
What did you say?
Is he mad because you took off your cuffs?
No, we always do this, we want to smoke.
I'm on my way.
Don't touch a thing.
Damn, I'm screwed!
I'm screwed!
Are you ok?
How can I be ok? My house got robbed!
Oh, Salem! You're screwed!