A bottle of sulfuric acid was dropped
from a high place
to Mongkok's pedestrian zone last week.
This is the third case already.
The number of casualties are over 100 now.
This grave offense has prompted the police
to offer a reward of 900,000 dollars
for anyone with any information
about these cases.
Please contact 277-117-77.
May I help you, miss?
Three cups of lychee juice with honey.
More lychees, fewer bees.
I mean more lychees, less honey.
Also, get me some yogurt,
chocolates, apples,
mangoes, blueberries,
and watermelon sorbet.
They're all mine. Thank you.
Hello.
Johnston?
Where are you?
I'm working on a case.
You're not free?
I want to give you a treat.
I'm working on a case.
Ho?
Do you copy?
Yes. Mission accomplished.
I got everything. I'm on my way.
Wait a second.
Do you see the blind man behind you?
Where?
At your seven o'clock.
The one in a dark blue suit.
Yes, I see him. What's up?
Follow him.
Follow him?
Chief Szeto, the sorbet will melt.
You have to drink it when it's still cold.
Follow him. Find out what he's up to.
Yes, sir.
I'm off duty, honey.
I'll go and buy some groceries for dinner.
Are you coming back for dinner?
You haven't come back for two days.
Return my call.
Chief Szeto, the blind man
is following someone.
Who?
A fat guy in a white-striped shirt.
Bitch!
You think I know nothing
between you and the driver?
You fucked him in a truck!
You seduced him!
Go to hell! Don't ever come back!
We're finished!
What is he looking at?
Check it out!
Honey, forgive me.
You may fuck him in the truck.
Remember to roll down the window.
It's dangerous to inhale the fumes.
Honey, I'll wait for you.
Come home.
Do you want a plastic bag?
Yes.
The fat guy is the suspect.
Don't lose him.
We'll be right there.
Time for some action.
Call for backup.
Excuse me.
Yes?
Is this orange juice, gorgeous?
It's sulfuric acid.
Thank you, gorgeous.
He followed the fat guy
into the Wing Mansion.
I'll be following them inside.
Team A, disperse the crowd.
Team B, shut down all exits.
Team C, follow me.
Evacuate! It's dangerous here!
Organized Crime Triad Bureau.
I have very reliable sources.
My name is Johnston,
ID card number, G196262.
Freeze!
I'm Szeto Fatbo, Chief Inspector of OCTB.
It hurts!
Watch out for my face.
Looks is important
for handsome guys like me.
Okay!
A lady cop?
You're under arrest.
You have the right to remain silent.
Anything you say may be used
against you in a court of law.
Good martial arts, better than Susan.
Szeto Fatbo!
Chief Szeto, how was this case solved?
Our team teamed up with
the Criminal Intelligence Bureau
to set up surveillance
around the pedestrian zone.
Tonight, we spotted the suspect,
so I promptly sent an officer
to follow him.
He was later found on the rooftop.
As soon as I arrived there, I took action.
I dispersed the crowd in the area
and captured the suspect.
We finally arrested him.
Was there any resistance
during the arrest?
Hello.
So you're Johnston,
«the brilliant detective?
My name is Ho.
Johnston.
Are you all right?
Do you realize how dangerous it was?
Luckily, we arrived on time.
Tell me, who was the suspect?
Pick up my shoe for me.
Who was the suspect?
I was the suspect.
I'm the one you followed
to find that fat guy.
I solved the case, right?
Yes... No.
I solved the case.
Because I'm smart.
I'm smart in knowing you're smart.
Cut that crap.
How about the reward?
You called OCTB at 7:40 p.m.
But I issued my order at 7:30 p.m.
We took action
before you reported the case
Also, you didn't give any details
on the phone,
except for your name.
You fucked up everything.
- Don't do that.
- It hurts.
Sorry.
My juniors are all looking.
I spent nine months in Mongkok.
It all came down to nothing.
You'll get a good citizen award.
Award, your ass!
You police officers with three stars
are being paid 80,000 dollars a month.
But we, disabled people,
make a living only on these rewards.
I'm over here.
I'll treat you.
I'll treat you
with some red wine and good food.
Let's go.
It should be worth at least 100,000.
Worth at least 100,000 dollars?
I'm earning only 80,000 dollars per month.
I have to feed my family.
I don't care.
I need to eat 100,000 dollars
worth of food.
My treat. Call it a celebration.
What?
Coming.
How are you, Johnston?
I'm Ho.
Thank you.
- Put it here.
- Sure.
Are you driving later? Give me your glass.
There are very few female cops
as good as you.
You got good training?
Yes. I was stationed at the airport.
Do you run fast?
My record is 2.4km
in 9 minutes and 17 minutes.
How about shooting and combat?
I'm good.
I trained in close quarters combat.
Why do you have
to put down your silverware when you talk?
I'm actually a bit scared of you.
I'm no good at all with investigations.
I lack a detective's mind.
That's why I'm envious of my colleagues.
They would only need to think
for a minute,
then they solve a case instantly.
You're absolutely brilliant
despite being blind.
I admire you so much.
You're really my idol.
I secretly called you
the God of Cracking Cases.
Very agile.
One more bottle.
Do you live here?
Nice neighborhood.
It's quiet.
Over there.
The first one across the street.
Are you okay?
Yes. I'm completely sober.
Tell me about the case.
Minnie is my junior.
Three years younger than me,
she was in Grade 7 back then.
She was living with her a foster family.
She's a bit weird.
She has self-esteem.
She's unsociable and friendless.
The boys always bullied her in school.
I'd always defend her.
Maybe that's why we became good friends.
She used to follow me home after school.
We did our homework together,
played together, ate junk food together.
Get to the point.
One day,
she told me in tears
that she was afraid she'd be like
her grandma and mom who killed for love.
Turned out her father
had an affair shortly after her birth.
Her mother was so angry,
that she murdered him
and preserved his body in salt.
She was raised by her grandma.
When she was in elementary school,
her grandma became some guy's mistress.
The guy was a creep.
He refused to divorce his wife
and dumped her grandma.
Since she was infuriated,
her grandma murdered the guy.
She even deep-fried his body.
So, you were shocked when you found out
and distanced yourself from Minnie?
It's only natural.
I avoided her.
But she came and waited for me
at that spot.
She waited for the whole night.
I was absolutely horrified.
I hid behind the window.
Thinking back,
she must have been heartbroken.
But I was really scared,
I didn't dare to come down.
I never did.
After standing there for five nights,
on June 20,
she disappeared.
She was just a little girl.
Where could she have gone?
She's been missing for over a decade.
The truth can be very harsh.
Are you sure you want to find out?
Yes. I want to look for her.
No problem.
Give me 500,000 dollars.
The plastic bag.
Here you are.
Where's the toilet?
Shit, does this place have to be this big?
- What are you doing?
- I want to pee.
- I'm taking a bath!
- Where's the toilet?
- Toilet! Where is it?
- I'm taking a bath!
There's a toilet in your room.
Tell me where it is.
Over there.
- Which direction?
- Your nine o'clock.
Relax.
I'm blind. I can't see a thing.
I'm not blind though.
Don't look.
Why am I here?
You were drunk last night.
I brought you here.
Thank you.
Are you totally blind?
Yes. Pitch black.
I can't see a thing?
It's 3,000 square feet?
No, 3,600.
On what street?
Durham Road.
Kowloon Tong, low-density housing.
It must have cost
more than 20,000 per square foot.
About 70 million dollars?
Do you accept bribes?
What do you mean?
I inherited the money from my parents.
I'm the only member in the family now.
My dowry is secured.
You'll help find Minnie for me, won't you?
Yes.
But it will be expensive.
One million dollars.
- I thought you said 500,000 dollars.
- Are you kidding? No way!
I'm the God of Cracking Cases.
- Do you have any problem?
- No.
Apply for your leave.
Why would I do that?
You can learn from me.
I'll teach you a few clever tricks.
Free of charge.
- Thank you, thank you.
- My pleasure.
Listen to this case.
Homicide case.
April 17, 1992.
Wednesday night.
Kowloon public morgue.
Police!
You'll be Kau. I'll be Tak.
- Tell me I'm stupid.
- How?
Brainless! Moron!
Use your imagination.
- Brainless!
- Do you think with your ass?
Pig!
Do you think with your ass? Pig!
Again, fiercer.
Dickhead!
Pig!
Kau is from Chiuchow. Use the dialect.
Dickhead!
Pig!
You know nothing!
You aren't human!
You're as stupid as a pig!
You know nothing!
Dickhead!
Moron! Have you left your brain at home?
I've told you. You imbecile!
Let me tell you, you're worse than a pig!
As stupid as a pig!
Your brain is full of shit!
Asshole, have you finished?
What?
It doesn't break.
I'll throw it harder.
Let's swap roles.
I'll play Tak, and you'll play Kau.
Asshole, have you finished?
What happened?
It didn't break.
Forget it.
Let's start again.
Asshole, have you finished?
Did you bring your brain to work?
Wait!
Wait a second.
A person like you who has learned
martial arts won't be able to do it.
Let's swap.
But you can't see.
It's okay. I'll manage.
Crawl! Hurry!
Faster!
Tak is coming from behind,
like someone insane.
He hit him nine times.
One, two...
Stop!
Kau was seriously injured.
He couldn't have crawled so fast.
Back to the original position.
Act slowly this time.
You're badly injured.
You're doomed.
Keep crawling.
You're a piece of dead meat now.
Stop!
What?
You're inconsistent.
You were mad just a while ago.
Why are you acting like that now?
It's not right for you to strike him,
and then waited
before you hit him
nine more times outside.
What happened in between?
The delivery man came?
Who ordered from us?
Diarrhea?
What's more urgent than killing a person?
To kill another person.
There's a third person.
A third person entered the scene
after Tak had hit Kau once.
Tak had to leave Kau behind
and chase after that third person.
I need a third person.
Here!
Let me play him.
Wait, no!
The police didn't find
any other bloodstain at the crime scene.
Tak didn't kill with a hammer.
The victim was strangled to death.
The timing fits.
Get one of them to play Kau.
- Me.
- You! You raised your hand first.
- Yes.
When I start strangling, start crawling.
Can I struggle?
Of course. That's normal.
It hurts!
Ouch!
You can't strangle me like this.
Let's swap.
I'm blind!
All right!
Again?
Yes.
I'm blind!
I know. One, two, three.
Sorry. I played it for real.
After him!
One, two, three, four, five,
six, seven, eight, nine!
Dead!
The time matches!
Johnston?
Who's the one being strangled?
The police didn't find his body.
That means you've disposed of it.
Why did you dispose of this guy
but not him?
Where have you been
in the last two decades?
Higher. Ready? Drop it.
Right. That's the way it was smashed.
But why smash the TV?
What triggered such behavior?
What program was aired on
Wednesday nights 20 years ago?
Enjoy Yourself Tonight.
What about in other channels?
Live broadcast of horse-racing.
I understand now!
I completely understand.
Let's go and eat.
We won't need these. Thank you.
- Here's the change, two dollars.
- Thanks.
Two bowls of noodles.
Long time no see. I thought you were dead.
KEI KEE
This is super delicious.
I used to come here with Szeto.
Do you see
that there is a dance studio
on the second floor behind you?
Do you see it?
Yes. Tango Blue, right?
Go check if she's there.
- Go.
- What's the case about?
A big case. Go.
Okay.
- Don't fuck it up.
- Yes.
She's coming down.
Who?
The lady, what shall we do?
Don't look. Pretend to eat.
Calm down.
Seems like you're the nervous one.
Who's she?
A wanted criminal?
She's getting in a cab.
Shall we follow her?
Johnston?
No need. Mission accomplished.
Two more bowls for takeaway, please.
Okay.
Hey, take off your shoes.
I just washed the floor.
What's up?
Why are you so excited?
She's back.
Who?
This is nice, who are you talking about?
What are you eating?
Gizzard.
What dance am I dancing?
Tango.
Your future wife?
Right. My future wife.
Don't you remember?
You helped me find her back then.
But she went away.
I've never thought
I'd run into her four years later.
I'm destined to marry her.
Have you ever thought
your future wife might have married?
You have a foul mouth.
She's probably someone else's wife.
It's been a long time,
and she's 30 already.
It's perfectly normal to get married.
A beautiful woman like her
must have a lot of suitors.
Right.
Harder!
Okay!
It's all mold and rot.
One can't live here anymore.
I'm not used to work outside of my house.
But this is a complicated case.
I need to move out and feel things.
No additional charge.
Sure. Thanks a lot.
My pleasure.
Where's my room?
What do you think, Johnston?
Is everything okay?
It will do.
I'd like my wardrobe
to be set up just like the way at home.
Suits on the left and shirts on the right.
Casual wear and pajamas in the bottom.
Let's watch TV together, Goldie.
Johnston?
- Johnston.
- I'm thinking about something.
You were looking at Minnie from here?
She was standing across the street.
Go down and shout to me.
I'd like to experience it.
Okay.
Johnston! I'm here!
Good.
Hello?
Did Minnie behave strangely
while she was waiting for you?
She came here right after school.
She did that for several nights.
But I remember that on the last night,
she was raising her hand at me.
I didn't know what that meant.
She slit her wrist.
She wanted me
to know she was very unhappy.
Why didn't I realize that?
And yet you knew right away.
I'm blind, but I can read people's mind.
Why are you blind?
I was on a case
four years ago,
I was waiting for the suspect
to show his face.
I started to see dark patches
on the seventh day.
But I didn't pay any attention to that
since I wanted to solve the case.
The next day, the suspect showed up
I chased frantically after him
until I caught him.
But I became blind after that.
The doctor said it's retinal detachment,
and it's too late.
Which one is Minnie?
Check whose feet will fit the sneaker.
Minnie's feet have grown so much?
I gave her a pair of red shoes.
This is the police. Line up.
Take off your shoes, one by one.
Left foot, please.
What's up?
Coach, it's the police.
We're on a case. Step aside.
What's wrong? What happened?
The coach ran away.
Chase after her.
- Okay!
- After her.
Bingo. I can't believe it.
Take a break. More policemen are coming.
Hello?
I told you, Szeto.
That big-foot who robbed
five jewelry shops in a row
three years ago is a woman.
Come quickly.
Minnie!
Are you okay, miss?
I lost her. I only picked up a shoe.
Why do you give it to me?
I thought you're a sprinter?
She was much taller than me.
She doubled my strides.
I even broke my heels.
Why didn't you shoot her?
You also mentioned your marksmanship.
I can't shoot at Minnie.
She's not Minnie?
Nobody said she was!
You assumed by yourself!
I'm Chief Inspector Szeto Fatbo.
Where's the suspect?
Gone.
Go check him out. Get a police dog.
Send someone.
We're talking
about the one-million bounty.
Johnston.
You're actually investigating
your own case.
You're not looking for Minnie.
Well, I'm doing both.
You cheated me
to help you get your bounty.
What do you mean by cheating you?
Who do you think I am?
Who do you think Johnston is?
I'm cheating you?
- Come on, her feet are all swollen.
- How do I cheat you?
What do you mean?
I'm teaching you to be a good cop
and help you improve.
What did you say?
They're like roasted pig knuckles.
My parents didn't want me to be a cop.
But I didn't care.
Because I really wanted to find Minnie.
I felt I was responsible
for her disappearance.
I've applied for a ten-day leave.
I still have a week left.
You're a madcap, aren't you?
I was raised in a broken family.
Is Minnie's mother still in jail?
She killed herself in prison.
How about her grandma?
She was released a few years ago.
I asked her about Minnie.
She's doesn't know anything.
Bring me to her.
Watch out!
Granny!
I'm Ho.
Are you there?
- Excuse me.
- I don't know.
I don't know her.
I never saw her.
Don't ask me.
Call her.
Granny is here.
The perfume is intoxicating.
Pang.
Come out!
Come out, you nymph.
You can't desert me like that.
I helped you change the light bulb
out of kindness.
But it turned out
I have to run for my life
I don't like you at all.
But I like you.
I've fallen in love with you.
For God's sake.
Leave him alone.
- Leave my father alone.
Leave my father-in-law alone.
Shut up!
Pang, my love for you is true.
But you've treated me like trash.
You've dumped me.
I'll make your life miserable.
You're out of your mind.
Run!
- Let's go!
- Don't look!
Close the door.
I won't let go of you.
Granny went to the stairs at the back.
- Go after her.
- I'm on it.
Help to put everything onto the truck.
Forget everything. Leave them behind.
Let's get into the truck.
Let's go!
Where is she?
This way.
Pang, wait for me!
Wait for me!
Pang!
Hey!
Granny is getting a taxi.
Follow her.
- Hurry!
- Taxi! After the truck!
Let's go. Hurry!
- Hurry, follow the truck.
- Come here
Go after it!
Hurry!
I can't live without him.
Granny, this is Johnston.
He's looking for Minnie.
We have some questions for you.
I know nothing.
Leave me alone.
- Hurry! Drive faster.
- Granny.
Minnie is your granddaughter.
She has nothing to do with me,
dead or alive.
Leave me alone, or you'll be sorry.
I can be vicious.
Hurry!
This woman is intoxicated with love.
Leave her alone.
It will expire very soon.
What?
The reward money.
Even if I solve the case,
I won't get paid.
Granny got in the truck.
She hid in the closet.
What should we do?
We'll go to Macau.
Is eight points a sure win?
There's no sure win in gambling.
Give me a three-line.
Three-lines.
Come on.
Are you making a fool of me, Szeto?
I've checked all the casinos.
Are you sure he's in Macau?
Please take the bill.
Cut the crap. It's all your fault.
The reward money
for the morgue murder will soon expire.
Extend it for me.
I don't care how you will do that.
You came here
on the pretext of Minnie's case.
But you're actually working
on your own case.
You never wanted to help me.
Minnie is human.
She has a human life.
How about the other victims?
How about Kau? Are they humans?
Do they have human lives?
What kind of cop are you?
After I went blind, I kept thinking.
Why on earth did God make me blind?
Then I understood.
I became blind
to look into old cases
which no one cares about,
go after those murderers
who have evaded the police,
and bring justice to the victims.
Sorry about that, Johnston.
It's fine, as long as you understand.
Let's find him.
I've got him.
Where? Why didn't you tell me?
He's playing baccarat.
The one who just sneezed.
He's leaving.
Follow him.
Hurry!
Wasn't Tak the murderer
in the morgue case?
How is this fat guy involved?
Don't tell me he is Tak.
He has gained that much weight?
Do you want
to be the Goddess of Cracking Cases?
Yes.
To solve a case,
one must have an imaginative mind.
You must learn to be creative.
Brodmann Areas 37, 39, 40
of the cerebral cortex.
What areas? Where are they?
Here, here, and here.
Here, here, and here?
Close your eyes.
Done.
Where are you?
In a restaurant.
Do you want me to beat you up?
Imagine yourself
in the office of the morgue.
The date is Wednesday, April 17, 1992.
There's a live broadcast
of the last horse race on TV.
The commentator is very good.
Heading in the final round
is Warlord, followed closely
by More Treasures.
Kau and Tak betted on a six-up jackpot.
They had won five races in a row.
This was the decisive one.
But there was a third person at the scene.
Who?
Imagine it was yourself.
Number eight, hang on.
You used to chip in on their bets.
But not this time.
Damn! Every time I chipped in, you'd lose.
When I didn't, you'd win.
Well, this proves that you have bad luck.
Why complain?
We had asked you to chip in, jerk.
The six-up jackpot is a record-breaking
5,209,010 dollars.
What a big prize. Yes!
Over two million for each of us.
Kau, we can quit our job.
You simply couldn't accept it.
You were overwhelmed with anger.
I see. Tak was the victim, not the killer.
He's Lee Tak Shing,
a day-shift colleague of Tak and Kau.
After Kau's death
and the disappearance of Tak,
Lee collected the five-million jackpot
from Jockey Club
and started his own business.
But he soon lost all of the money.
Once a murderer, he wouldn't mind
committing more crimes.
In recent years, many gamblers
in Macau were hit on the head
and robbed.
It must be him.
Shall we arrest him?
Of course. But how?
- Do you have a credit card?
- Yes.
- Do you have a credit line of 300,000?
Bet against him.
I'll pretend to join.
Trap him. Piss him off.
Make him hate you so much
that he wants to kill you.
All by myself?
Of course. Just be confident.
Find a crude person to imitate.
In real life,
- there's always a crude person around.
- Six.
- Three lines.
- Seven.
- It's six. Seven.
- Three lines.
- Seven.
There!
Shit!
King or Jack?
Thirty thousand dollars on Banker.
One hundred thousand on Player.
Hey.
I can't see.
Please place my bet on Player for me.
No more bets.
Number five for Player.
- Number seven for Banker.
- Give me the cards.
- Player, Banker.
- I'll kill you!
- Player...
- Banker.
- I'll slice you into pieces!
I'll slice you into pieces!
Seven. Sure win.
Seven, your ass!
- Seven for Player. Show your hand.
- I'll kill you.
- Eight.
- TV screens.
Kill!
Three-lines.
TV screens.
Right. Two TV screens.
One for TVB. One for i-Cable.
One more card.
Banker draws.
TV screens.
Three-lines.
Go to hell.
Come on.
Yes, one more TV screen for now!
Seven for Player.
Zero for Banker. Player wins.
I've won.
Player.
Banker.
- Banker.
- Fuck off!
Banker.
Player.
You should follow the winner.
I'll bet on Player.
Banker.
Nine, I won!
Four. Give me a two-line.
- Two lines.
- Beat it.
Shit.
Blow it.
- Do you want that?
- No.
Shit!
Nine. I won!
What was that? Do you want to hit me?
Come at me.
This guy is going to beat up a woman!
Thank you. I've won again.
- I'd like to buy some.
- Which flavor?
A little bit of each.
Hello?
Johnston? I don't think he's following me.
Impossible! I'm sure he will.
Don't look back, though.
You should go to a remote place.
Somewhere secluded.
Secluded?
Trust me.
You were so annoying.
He lost all his money because of you.
Also, you're a woman.
He'll surely beat the hell out of you.
Just call me after it's over.
Curry Restaurant, Taipa Village.
Let me try the egg rolls.
You found him?
What did you think?
I'm sure it's him. You're blind.
It's easier to follow you.
I told you he didn't come after me.
You're very smart. Now what?
You're in great danger.
He'll attack you.
What shall I do?
Where are you?
I'll come to your rescue.
That's nice. Hurry, then.
Thank you.
We've arrived? How much is the fare?
It's 68 dollars.
Help! Murder!
Help! Where the hell are you, Ho?
Come down, blind man.
You haven't paid yet.
I'm just a cab driver.
You think I'm stupid?
You're holding a hammer.
You're the one behind
all the recent murders in Macau.
Arrest this murderer, Ho!
Who's Ho?
Who are you?
I'm here to arrest you, Lee.
You killed Tak and Kau.
You thought no one would find out.
The cold-blooded killer's here, Ho!
Who's Ho?
What else do you know?
You dismembered Tak,
mixed the body parts with other corpses
to hide his corpse
and make it appear he's on the run!
He's absolutely ruthless, Ho!
Who's Ho?
There's no way you would have known.
I was the only one there.
What's that in your hand?
There's no way you would have known.
I was the only one there.
You son of a bitch! You'll die!
He wants to silence me, Ho!
Stop! Go back a bit.
Ho!
Call the police.
I'm dialing.
He wants to silence me, Ho!
Where are you? I'm dying.
Ho, help me!
I am dying, Ho!
I'm coming!
Hit him.
Ho?
What happened?
He passed out.
That hurt.
It's okay.
You're in a very good mood.
Of course, it's because
I'm one step closer to my dream.
What dream?
To see again.
There are researches
on using stem cells for retinal implant
and tests on electronic eyes.
Although chances are still remote,
there's no harm to start saving money now.
Johnston,
how do I look in your imagination?
Maybe similar to Officer Susan.
Officer Susan?
Who's she?
She works in Kowloon West District.
You can dance really well.
That's because you can lead.
Are you free this Saturday?
Well, yes or no?
Yes.
Let's go.
You've grown taller.
A little bit.
How much is a little bit?
Watch out.
Where are we going, Johnston?
Tango Blue, the dance studio opposite
the food vendor last time.
Got that.
Bring me to her
and you may leave.
Me, leave? Who is she?
You may leave upon bringing me there.
You want to catch the suspect by yourself?
No, you must not...
What culprit? She's my dream girl.
I had fallen in love with her
before I became blind.
I dreamed of seeing her again.
What do you think of her? Pretty, right?
Isn't she's gorgeous?
A good match for me, right?
The drawing is upside down.
What a perfect match.
Only a great beauty like her
deserves a handsome man like me.
We're born for each other.
Is my tie crooked?
Well? Do you see her?
She's dancing. At your twelve o'clock.
Go there.
Come on.
Should I wait for you here?
No need.
- I can pick you up when you're done.
- No need.
Should I wait for you?
Will you be back for the night?
Should I lock the door?
Go away.
Where do I go?
How are you? I'm Johnston.
Hi, I'm Ding Ding.
May I dance with you?
Don't worry. I won't step on you.
Am I doing okay?
Yes, you're great.
I've been waiting
for this moment for four years.
My friend and I used
to eat gizzard downstairs.
I fell in love with you
the first time I set my eyes on you.
I fell in love with you right away.
Isn't the girl dancing up there great?
KEE KEI
Not bad-looking. Small boobs, though.
Hey!
She's going to be my future wife.
I'm sorry.
I was thinking to introduce myself
after I finished my case.
- I never thought that I'd go blind.
- That hurt.
- Sorry.
- No problem.
I asked my friend
to look for you afterward.
But he failed.
I'm so lucky to see you again.
- That hurt!
- Sorry.
No problem.
I understand I'm being rude.
But please give me a chance to date you.
Am I too late?
Yes. I'm married.
Sorry for bothering you.
Johnston, I have bad news.
Keep calm and listen.
What's the bad news?
The reward money is gone.
You didn't extend the deadline for me?
Or have you forgotten?
It's not my fault.
The Finance Department declined.
I'm not the boss.
I'm just Chief Inspector Szeto Fatbo.
You think I can do magic?
- Hubby.
- Darling.
Have some gizzard.
Sorry, my boss is looking for me.
I'll go first. Bye.
You got married?
You and her? You married her?
I tried to tell you
in your home last time.
I asked you to be a go-between,
and you married her.
What kind of friend are you?
Let me explain.
Come closer, and I'll beat you up.
Wrong direction, three o'clock.
Don't pity me.
Excuse me, buddy.
Is Officer Susan here?
I'm Susan,
but I'm not your buddy.
What's the matter, Johnston?
I figured it out.
When I was walking on the street,
feeling heartbroken,
I suddenly recalled a case about
a missing woman in 1996.
She was dumped by her boyfriend
and disappeared on the same night.
What does that have to do with Minnie?
Wasn't Minnie kind of heartbroken
before she disappeared?
Yes.
There lies the similarity.
Heartbroken then disappeared.
You mean there might be
a psychotic serial killer
who targeted heartbroken women?
I'm almost certain.
Szeto Fatbo.
This is not a truce.
I won't listen to any of your explanation.
You want to go on? I'll hang up.
Listen! Find all missing females' files
in the last decade.
Check out those who had been jilted
before they disappeared.
Bring these files to me. Hurry!
What's going on?
Let's go.
So you are heartbroken,
walking on the street alone?
That son-of-a-bitch betrayed me.
He stole the love of my life
and married her.
Forget it,
maybe you'll find a better lady.
It's not an easy job.
A great woman is rare to come by.
You can't see her anyway,
even if she looks like Susan.
She'll make me lose face
in front of my friends.
Johnston, I'm here.
You ordered so many dishes.
Thank you.
And shark's fin soup, too.
Abalone?
Try some.
- Just rice will do.
- Okay.
Here.
Here are the files you wanted.
They are hard to come by.
I've spent several nights compiling them.
These are all confidential.
It took a lot of strings to get them.
Give them to me.
They're heavy.
I know I did something bad to you.
You have every right to be mad.
But please listen to my explanation.
I don't love you. Go to hell.
How does that feel?
Nothing.
Come up here.
I'm coming.
Are you making a movie? So many pads.
I'll get hurt.
That's the point.
I want you to feel their pain.
Remove all of them.
- Can you do it?
- Yes.
- Are you sure.
Hold on.
Dickhead, did you dump me for her?
Of course.
I'm prettier than you,
my boobs are bigger.
Sorry.
Go on!
You're not jumping?
Let's go get a room.
Watch out! Take it easy!
Can you get into the character?
You can do it, right?
What's wrong?
I can't get into character
if I restrain myself.
Let's play it for real. Just once.
All right.
Why?
Why did two people so much in love
would end up like this?
Breaking up is always ugly and nasty.
The opposite of love is hate.
But Susan and the likes of
you won't understand this,
because you have never been in love.
Right?
You're done?
I'm full.
That's right.
Keep up that attitude.
Let me finish it.
Johnston?
Are you sure I have to get a tattoo?
Does it have to be "Forever Valentino"?
The statement said the missing girl
had such a tattoo.
It's awful. I don't know any Valentino.
And I don't love Valentino.
Even the tattooist reminded me
to think twice.
I'll be stuck with it
Then forget it.
We'll stop investigating.
Vinci Lai.
Where did you go after you got the tattoo?
May Wong, where did you go?
Kay Yeung, where did you go?
Karen Man, where did you go?
And Sylvia Choi, where were you?
Where
did you all go?
The murderer is a cab driver
Where are you going?
I'll find the taxi driver.
How will you do that?
Tell me the date when they went missing.
Hannah Leung went missing
on February 1995.
Speak clearly.
For the past few days.
I was dumped by you for ten times.
I'm heartbroken.
But I'm trying my best.
Hannah Leung, February 7, 1995.
May Wong, October 11, 1996.
Karen Man, May 22, 1997.
Lilian Lee, December 28, 1998.
Haley Cheung, September 9, 1999.
Fanny Chan, February 14, 2002.
Kay Yeung, March 19, 2003.
Hilda Ko, August 25, 2004.
Vinci Lai, November 30, 2005.
Sylvia Choi, January 12, 2006.
And Minnie, June 20, 1997.
The murderer didn't commit
any crime in 2000 and 2001.
And no more such cases after 2006.
What happened to the murderer?
Did I have enough money for the taxi?
You're heartbroken.
It didn't come across your mind.
Why was I heartbroken?
These other girls broke up
with their boyfriends.
I'm unlike them.
You're close friends.
You're heartbroken
because she avoided you.
You waited for her
until midnight and took a taxi.
You must have fallen for her secretly.
You're a lesbian.
Not uncommon
for an adolescent girl like you.
You must be.
Hello, Szeto Fatbo.
Hey, this is not a truce.
Listen, find taxi drivers
who quit driving between 2000 and 2001.
Bastard! He didn't come himself.
I volunteered to come. May I sit down?
Szeto is very unhappy.
I don't want him to stay like that.
It was not quite like you thought.
There were things even Szeto didn't know.
The truth is,
when I first saw both of you,
Szeto was the one I was attracted to.
I fell for him immediately.
I planned to go after him
after the dance contest.
But I haven't seen the two of you again
until that day.
Sir, who are you looking for?
You're not allowed into
the ladies' changing room.
The man is quite well-built,
wears a leather jacket, smokes a cigar
and acts arrogantly.
Do you know what he wants?
KEE KEI
Hey, are you all right?
It's not my fault.
She suddenly dashed out.
Call the ambulance.
Don't be afraid.
I'm Senior Inspector,
Szeto Fatbo.
Don't be afraid.
It turned out the man I admired was
a Dirty Harry type of cop.
At that moment,
I decided to be with that man
for the rest of my life.
He's my one life, one love.
That's enough.
I get the picture.
But may I ask one question,
you said when you saw us,
the one you got attracted to was him.
Why?
He's cool.
Tell me, who's more good-looking?
She must be blind.
She told you she's infatuated with Szeto.
It's you who thought otherwise.
It was just your wishful thinking.
Stand still.
Eye on the window.
Imagine yourself as Minnie.
Slit your wrist.
It's a real knife.
You've got nothing to lose
with looks like Susan.
There will be scars.
Scars are bad for pretty girls, not Susan.
Okay!
How was that?
How did that feel?
I overreacted, I must say.
I do feel sad, but not heartbroken enough.
It felt a bit forced.
Got it.
Once more.
Just imagine.
Minnie took after her grandma
who has completely lost in love, okay?
You're Minnie. At school...
you had no friends, but it's all right
because you only cared for one boy.
You secretly loved him.
You really liked him.
Finally, you two started a relationship.
You guys were happily dating each other.
But soon, he grew tired of you.
He decided to break up with you.
He dumped you,
you were deeply hurt.
It hurt so much,
you started to mutilate yourself.
Enough.
Stop, Ho!
Stop!
Minnie wasn't waiting for you.
Was someone living upstairs?
- It's been vacated for a long time.
- I mean, when Minnie used to come here!
Yes.
Was it a boy in the same age as Minnie?
Did he study in the same school?
Was he good-looking?
Yes!
Where is he?
Grilled Jumbo Prawn. Please enjoy.
Thank you.
This way.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Do you want a drink?
- Iced sake, please.
- Sure.
Thank you.
Did you live in Hong Kong?
Durham Street in Kowloon Tong?
Yes.
Are you Joe?
You are...
- Ho, I lived downstairs.
- Please enjoy, sir.
Darkie?
You looked completely different.
You have fairer skin now.
Almost unrecognizable.
What are you up to?
You're still picking fights?
No, I tripped.
Are you still going after cats
with air guns?
Of course not. That is kid's stuff.
Please pick your choice.
The Beef Set, please.
Thank you.
Didn't you emigrate to Brazil?
In 1997?
I returned three years ago
and started this restaurant with a friend.
- Okay.
- Zhuhai is a good place for business.
Hey, around the time you left,
Minnie also disappeared.
Did you know Minnie?
Minnie Lee?
She studied in our school.
She was in the same class as you.
I can't recall anything.
I probably didn't know her.
Not at all?
She used to hang out at my place.
No, it doesn't ring a bell.
Fried rice, sir. Please enjoy.
Excuse me, one more Grilled Jumbo Prawn.
Of course.
Johnston, do you want to eat again?
Joe knew Minnie.
How did you know?
He was making the fried rice
when you mentioned Minnie.
I had a taste. It was too salty.
So I ordered two more dishes.
Grilled Jumbo Prawn. Please enjoy.
The prawn was too dry.
Scallop, please.
Coming right up.
The scallop finally tasted right,
which means he got distracted
at the mention of Minnie's name.
I smell something fishy.
You think I was just enjoying the food?
What should we do? Should we follow her?
Keep an eye on him.
He's coming out, holding a rat cage.
He's drowning it.
He's the one who killed Minnie.
He dismembered her
and threw the body into a trash bin.
We've been sitting here for hours
reading magazines.
Who is he waiting for?
He's not waiting for someone to come.
He's waiting for someone to leave.
He's also watching somebody.
Joe's partner is coming down
from the opposite building.
He settled the bill.
Let's do that too.
Bill, please.
- Bill, please.
- Right away.
Hurry, give me the bill.
Excuse me, please wait for a moment.
Joe went to his partner's building.
What now?
Let's go and see.
What about the bill?
Leave the money on the table.
He's after the manager of the restaurant.
Wow, they're making out!
- What do you like to drink?
- Dragon Well tea.
Sure.
He's fucking your wife.
Come back quickly.
Is that the girl who wanted the bill?
Yes, she's pregnant.
Is Joe's partner coming back?
He's running back.
The pregnant woman is Joe's wife.
Stupid! He's hiding in the balcony.
Stop fighting.
The pregnant woman ran outside.
Stop fighting. Come down.
Joe has fallen down too.
Darling!
My dear, are you all right?
I got scared.
I'm fine.
The pregnant woman has gone crazy.
Go and help, quickly.
Roger.
Miss, you'll kill him.
Você me trai,
vou perseguir você até a morte.
Why did you lie?
You knew Minnie and had dated her.
You lied because you killed her.
Is that right? You killed Minnie.
- No, I didn't.
- Excuse me.
Are you crazy?
This is a hospital!
You molested her, a minor.
I was a minor too.
It was a mutual decision.
What are you looking at?
I didn't kill her.
I really didn't kill her.
We dated each other for a month.
I dumped her after I had my fun.
I was getting ready to emigrate,
so I didn't go to school.
She kept pestering me.
She waited outside my house every night
and mutilated herself with a knife.
She's crazy.
The night I went to Brazil,
she kept chasing after the bus.
We have five cab drivers as suspects.
Choi was jailed
for hurting a passenger in 2000.
He now lives in Wong Tai Sin.
Then there's Law.
He underwent drug rehab in 2000.
Now he lives in Tsing Yi.
Tsui
went to work in China in 2000.
He lives in Shek Pai Wan.
Then there's Chan Kwong.
He stayed in a mental hospital in 2000.
He now lives in Yuen Long.
The last one is Ng.
His license was suspended
for reckless driving in 2000
and now lives in Kwun Tong.
So? Who should we pick first?
The one in Yuen Long.
Chan Kwong? Why?
Yuen Long has lots of good food.
Hey, don't eat them all.
Don't finish all of them.
Leave some for me.
You're driving. Concentrate.
Try some.
Is it tasty?
Who's that?
Chan Kwong? Police!
Open the door.
Chan Kwong.
What's wrong?
He's naked.
He's only wearing a tennis skirt
and a pair of female sneakers.
Watch out.
Be on alert.
There are many female clothes.
Bras, panties, high heels, and handbags.
Where did you get
all these female clothes?
The pretty chicks left them behind.
Do you remember picking up a young girl
wearing a tennis outfit
on October 11, 1996?
In 1996? Wearing a tennis outfit?
Like the one you're wearing.
Yes.
What happened?
She got in my cab.
She was in tears. She looked very sad.
But she's very pretty and attractive.
And then?
What did you do to her?
Did you drive her here, raped her,
and killed her when she resisted?
No, I only ate her eyes.
Where is she?
Where did you hide her?
Where?
There's a skeleton
in the trunk of the cab.
Is that her?
No, not this one.
I'll go upstairs.
There's another one here.
No, not this one either.
What do you see?
Many wine jars.
Not this one.
How troublesome!
I give up. Go find it yourself
They're all here.
Call for backup.
What's up?
Dinner time.
You've killed many people.
Did you pick up Minnie?
On June 20, 1997,
did you pick up a young girl
wearing a school uniform
and a pair of red shoes in Kowloon Tong?
The dishes have turned cold.
I'm very hungry.
Where's Minnie?
You have very beautiful eyes.
May Wong,
help me.
You're indeed my idol.
Your marksmanship is excellent
despite your blindness.
Thank you.
Are you okay?
Cut the crap.
Is it serious?
My waist, I feel dizzy.
I can't drive.
No signals.
I'll drive.
To your left.
Your right.
Hang on!
Don't fall asleep. Stay awake.
I never thought
that I would die in this way.
Hey!
Do you have something to tell me?
Don't you like me?
You knew? How embarrassing.
I should die faster.
Nonsense. There's no need
to be embarrassed.
I suddenly realized...
I suddenly realized
that I love you too.
But I look like Susan.
I'm blind anyway.
You'll lose face in front of your friends.
I don't have any friend,
I've only got one,
that Szeto bastard.
You love me
just because I am rich.
I love your wealth all right.
But I also love everything else about you!
Even if you're penniless.
Johnston,
I didn't get "Forever Valentino"
tattooed on my shoulder.
I got "I Love Johnston" tattooed instead.
How gross. It'll be there for
the rest of your life.
That's nice.
Don't sleep!
It's for life!
- Do you know how to drive?
- Are you blind?
- You're so reckless. You scared us.
- Can't you see all these cars?
Help!
Call the police!
Hey, is the operation over?
- We didn't find the young girl.
- What?
Minnie wasn't there?
We found ten skeletons at the crime scene.
All victims were proved
to be female adults.
That is to say, Minnie's not among them
Impossible.
Did you search thoroughly?
Yes, we searched every corner.
Why are you so sure?
I told you
I didn't have any cash for the taxi.
Where did I go wrong?
It's not Chan Kwong.
How about Joe? Did he kill me?
How is she?
The doctor said the operation went well.
Thank you, miss.
What's wrong?
I'm fucked up.
I was so desperate that I told her
I love her.
She doesn't love you?
Shut up!
She loves every inch of me
from the very beginning.
Congratulations.
Too bad she looks like Susan.
Which Susan?
Officer Susan in Kowloon West District.
The woman who looks like a man.
You're blind, buddy! What's your problem?
That's what I thought.
But you know, medical advancement
may one day cure my blindness.
How can I look at her?
Come here.
Touch her.
You're crazy! No!
- I don't want to find out.
- Trust me, man.
I know where I went wrong.
Where?
I was wrong about you.
You didn't take a taxi.
You went on a ship.
You've finally realized.
Hello?
Johnston.
Have you woken up?
Does it still hurt?
A little bit. Where are you?
Sorry, I was on the wrong track.
Chan Kwong didn't kill Minnie.
But I have new clues,
I'm going to find Joe
and ask him something.
What? You're going alone?
Don't worry.
Rest well.
I'll have good news for you.
What did you say?
I'm going to find Joe.
Not that,
I mean, your last sentence.
Bye-bye.
Ladies and gentlemen,
welcome aboard the Cotai Water Jet.
We'll arrive in Zhuhai in 75 minutes.
I've found out that you lied.
The truth is...
Minnie kept pestering you,
so you killed her
and dismembered her, right?
RAT POISON
The number you have dialed
is cannot be reached.
Mr. Johnston, add some black pepper.
It will be more delicious.
Go ahead.
Oh, my goodness!
It hurts.
But it really tastes good.
I'll die for it.
Get out of my way!
Anybody here?
Excuse me.
Is Joe here?
Hello?
My name is Johnston.
I'm looking for Joe. Is he in?
He's not here.
I had a fight with him.
He ran away with that woman.
I want to confirm something.
You can probably help me.
I'm in a bad mood.
Please leave.
In that case,
may I have a glass of water?
Sake is better. Thank you.
Thank you.
I analyze a case by imagining myself
as the characters,
then making deductions.
Listen to this story
and see if I guessed right.
Minnie was afraid she would never see
a certain boy again.
She didn't even know
where to look for him.
But she did not give up.
She told herself she must stay strong.
Stay strong.
She never thought
she would be hiding
in the closet for 27 days
and end up in Brazil.
But she knew if she showed up
in front of the boy,
she would only
scare him off.
So she left.
She got adopted by the locals
and changed her name.
But she always stayed near the boy
She later changed her look
by plastic surgery
and succeeded in winning him back
But the man himself was unfaithful.
He had many affairs with other women.
No matter how hard Minnie tried,
the marriage still fell apart.
Você me trai,
vou perseguir você até a morte.
This is a Portuguese saying, I've checked.
This is what it means in Cantonese,
"You betrayed me.
I'll make you suffer like hell."
These words were from your grandma.
But one must not be blinded
by stubbornness.
It can drive one to kill.
Your mother was an example of that.
Same with your grandma.
You resemble your grandma too much.
I came not only for the truth,
but to ask you to let go.
I guess I'm wrong again
I should go home and study more.
I'll go now. Thank you.
No need to see me out.
Thank you for the sake. Thank you.
Help me!
She's lying. Ignore her.
My water just broke!
Help!
Calm down, take a deep breath.
Take a deep breath.
Come on!
Johnston?
Johnston!
Help!
Murder! Ho!
- Murder!
- I'm coming!
Help!
Help me, Ho!
Ho!
Johnston!
The baby...
- Johnston!
- Save the baby.
She's Minnie.
Minnie?
Minnie!
Hang on there, Minnie!
Hang on!
Push!
Sit up!
Minnie, push harder!
Okay, one, two, three. Push!
Deep breath. Do it again.
One, two, three, push!
Great!
Harder!
It's coming.
The baby is coming.
Johnston!
Is it a boy or a girl?
Johnston! It's a girl.
A little Minnie.
I don't want strawberry flavor.
I want mango flavor.
Mango flavor is sold out.
Don't be stubborn.
I want mango!
Be a good girl, Little Minnie
Mommy will buy you
mango ice cream later, okay?
I'm disciplining my daughter!
Big Foot!
Honey, be careful.
Uncle Szeto.
I've found Big Foot.
Moody Road in Tsimshatsui East.
Say "thank you."
Moody Road. Come quickly. Thanks.
If you don't want to eat it, Daddy will.
You must not eat someone else's ice cream.
Then eat it.
No! I don't like strawberry!
I want mango!