Edition www.trigon-film.org
Cinema Iberica millimeter film
with the support of
Georgian National Film Center
in collaboration with Tato Film,
Nemo Films, Barrandow Studios
BLIND DATES
That is her.
But she is alone.
lali?  - Yes.
I am Iva
I'm pleased.  - This is Sandro.
My pleasure.
Sorry we are late
We waited upstairs.  - Everything OK.
I have only just arrived.
Where is Maka?
Maka didn't come.  - Why not?
I don't know,
she didn't come to the station
I called her
but she didn't answer.
Then my cell phone went off.
I didn't know what I should do,
so i came alone.
Maybe she has
took the next bus.
We can wait, I don't know.
Call her from my cell phone.
Maybe she'll answer.
Are you sure it's her?
In the photo she sent,
she had a different hairstyle.
I don't like this online thing.
Do you have an alternative
Do you have?
She was't feel well and
she couldn't come.
We can meet another time.
Your decision.
No why?  What you can get today
don't put that off for tomorrow.
Let's go.
I have to go.
Aren't you coming?
No, I had an unexpected call
I have to go.
But I'll leave you
in very good hands.
Can I talk to you for a minute
Hi.  are you Tamilla  - Yes.
I am a friend of Iva.
He reserved two rooms.
Where is Iva?
You should have come an hour ago.
Yes we are late
We don't need both rooms.
Iva can't come.
Why?
I don't know.  He can not.
Then who pays for the second room?
Probably Iva.  He'll call later.
Do you know where the room is?  - No.
Third floor, down the hall.
Thank you.
Let's go?
Do you want to drink something?  - No thank you.
Some fruit?  - No thank you.
Should I switch?  - Up to you.
Maybe some water?
Yes.
Thank you.
A bit more?  - Yes.
Do you work anywhere in Gori?
I am a nurse.
And you?  - I am a teacher.
And in your free time
you come with women to this hotel?
No.
Actually, this is my first time here.
Oh yes?  - Yes.
And Iva?  - What about Iva?
Has he been here?
I don't know.  Probably yes.
Have you known Iva for a long time?  - Yes.
Since my childhood.
We grew up together.
He was a soccer player, right?
Yes, he was a good player.
He even played for
Tbilisi Dinamos B Team.
Then he stopped.
I persuaded him
to work as a coach at our school.
He agreed because of the long vacation.
The salary is low
but the holidays are long.
Also, the kids love him.
What's happening?  - Nothing.
Any more water?
What are you doing there?
What?
I'm sorry.
It's already OK.  - Excuse me.
It's okay.
Are you feeling better?
I don't believe you.
Smile at me.
Yes.
Which posters?
They're in the car.
Fine, I'll bring her.  OK.
Would you like to see a football game?
at the stadium?
I don't like football.
Not the usual football.
Women's football?
Girls don't play football in Gori.
In Tbilisi they do.
Manana, give me the poster.
The rattle too.
Stand next to me
Manana is your conductor.  It's simple.
The posters work
if you pick them up at the same time.
When our girls attack
you lift her up.
Take them down
If they score a goal.
Shake the rattles.
Again please.
Please collect the posters
after the game again, yes?
You look great.  - Thank you.
When the headmistress
speech is finished, pick it up.
Iva!  - I'm coming.
As you know,
women's football is
a new sport in our country.
Until recently, only men played.
But times are changing.
The role of women in
of society as well.
We become more active
energetic, ambitious and mobile.
We want to score more goals in life.
I hate it,
to leave my child alone.
How old is your child?  - 13
A boy or a girl?  - A boy.
Where is his father  - In Gori.
What's his occupation?
Nothing.  He drinks and
then goes crazy.
Are you divorced?
Yes, for two years.
It's impossible to live with him.
He smashes everything.
He hit me.
Last time he came by
and ruined everything.
He cut himself in one piece
glass and bleeding everywhere.
My son was scared.
The bus to Gori departs.
The bus to Gori is about to leave.
I can come next Friday.
Do you want me to come?
Yes, of course.  - Do you work on Friday?
I work until 1:40 p.m.
Should I come at three?
I'll bring Maka too.
That would be nice.
Is he drunk?
I don't think so.
I am not drunk.
You are not?  Good for you.
Where have you been so long?  - He says nothing.
At school.
Our girls team had a game.
A famous Polish
Soccer player was there.
A woman?  - Yes.
Does she look good?
I don't like
muscular soccer players.
Don't mention her in front of me.
Marina's son married a Polish woman
and she turned out great.
Does she play football?
No, she is a doctor.
A doctor is good.
But will he marry a doctor?
He just roams around all day.
I don't stray.  - Yes, you do.
I have met a woman
today at the stadium.
Is she polish?
No, she is from Gori.
Why do you meet women from Gori?
Why is it important where she comes from?
It is important.
You were from the provinces too
when dad married you/
Was that a problem?  - Yes it was.
I had to teach her everything.
It was probably the other way around.
I taught you table manners.
How to use a fork.
No comment.
What is this woman doing in the stadium?
She wanted to watch the game.
What?  - She watched the game.
She came specially from Gori,
to get in and
watch girls soccer game?
Is she crazy?
She wasn't there just for the game.
Why then?
She came to meet someone.
Did she go back?
Yes.  - Did you accompany her to say goodbye?
Yes.  - Is she coming back?
We will see.  Perhaps.
And if so, will you see her?
Probably.
He just says maybe
probably.
We will see.
Do something my son.
We are getting old.
He's getting old too.  He's already 40.
Did you park the car
Yes, at the marketplace.
Not in the garage?
I'll put it in the garage tomorrow.
We'll get a ticket.
Again.  - I'll pay it.
You never do.
I'm paying all the time.
I'll pay this time.  - You will?
When get my salary and pay.
I have never seen your salary.
Who would have thought,
that you're still single at 40.
Stop mother
When you become a father
you will understand how I feel.
Can I eat in peace?
Do you want more?  - No thank you.
Otar, let's go.
Now you can't wake him up.
Help me.
Otar, get up.
I finally fell asleep...
Did you take her to the train station?
Yes.  - And?
She wants to come back on Friday.
Does she bring her friend with her?  - Yes.
Great.  We will have fun.
I am not coming.
Are you crazy?
She's coming for you.
I think she fell in love with you.
That's why I won't come.
Do you think you're better than them?
Let's go to Kobuleti.
I'm fed up with Tbilisi.
What should we do in Kobuleti?
The weather is nice there.
We breathe fresh air.
We can sleep at my uncle's.
Dad, can I spend the weekend?
Borrow the car?
Where do you want to go?  - To Kobuleti.
Kobuleti in November?
Are you sane?
Few people, nice weather.
Maybe you can even swim.
You catch a cold
when you eat cold tangerines.
If you go swimming now
you'll get pneumonia.
Don't get involved
to the life of a 40 year old.
Don't you interfere in our conversation.
If you want him to marry
leave him in peace.
Last year they took my car
and broke it while drunk.
Uncle Otar, we're not drinking this time.
We breathe fresh air and get fit.
Then we will accompany you.
Why?  - Fresh air
will do us good too.
Also, we'll be careful
that they don't drink and screw up.
I can smell the sea.
How are you?  - Good, and you?
What a beauty
you became!
How are you doing?  - Good, and you?
Hello cousin.
Hello Avto.  - Avto, how are you?
How is the family?  - Good.
This is my friend Hatuna.
My cousin Sandro.  - My pleasure.
This is Sandro's friend Iva.
What a lovely girlfriend you have!
Why did you hide them from us?
He's already flirting.
Hi.  - I'm pleased.
This is my wife.  - My pleasure.
See you in the evening
correct?  - Sure.
She comes over.
OK.  Bye.  - Until this evening.
We're going to the beach, are you coming with us?
I'm waiting for a girlfriend/
Maybe later.
Is she coming too?  - Yes.
What a beautiful place we have landed on!
Isn't that Anna?
That is her.  What is she doing here?
Anna!
Coach Iva, Mr. Sandro, how are you?
We are fine.
What are you doing here, little one?
My mother is here
I am on a business trip.
How are you doing?  - Good.
Is your mother there too?
Yes, I'll get her.
I am so happy to see you!
We are happy too.
Can we join?
Naturally.
How are you?  - Good.
I'm glad to see you here.
My best soccer mom leaves me
no alone, not even on vacation.
What are you doing here?
A friend has here
closed her beauty salon.
She gave me her accessories
and I'm here to get them.
Do you work in a beauty salon?
Yes, I am a hairdresser.
Anna, throw the ball.
Let's play?
Come on.
Anna, protect the ball!
Let's play!
My mom and I against both of you.
Anna, bring bigger stones.
This is our gate.  - This is ours.
Looks a bit small.
It's okay.
Ready?
Where are you?
Both mother and daughter.
And pass!
Goal!
Let him.
I have to stop smoking
He scored a goal.
It's good.
There are no compromises in sport.
I taught her that.
It's not badminton, it's football.
What did I teach you
Did I teach you that?
Come on!  Anna!
Pass, I'll let you shoot.
Goal!
I don't like it any more, I'm tired.
Congratulations
Can't you play better?
Let's go eat
Should we
take rain gear?  - Why not?
It doesn't matter where we sit.
Thank you.
Sweet! Bring us please
Chacha (Georgian vodka)!
Then Khachapuri and double lemonades.
Manana.  - Yes?
Did you collected the posters
after the game?
Yes, but it was difficult.  - Why?
Two guys didn't want to give their up
without getting my phone number.
And what have you done?
I gave them my number.
Did you know about my jealous
man, if they hadn't asked for it.
You're married?
Yes and no.
He is in prison.  We have
a phone date once a week.
Yes, father?  - Where are you?
Aren't you ashamed?
We met friends
and got stuck.
What friends?  - These girls here
been waiting for an hour.
We're almost there.  - Come immediately!
Just hear how they sing.
Anna, come here, you're getting wet.
When are you leaving?  - Tomorrow.
Too bad.
We could have a little
can go for a walk.
I have a shift tomorrow
so I have to leave early.
I wish I could stay.
We could have gone fishing.
I've never been fishing.
Long live this place!
Bravo!
Sweet!
Let's go?
Have you paid?
Goodbye.
A beautiful girl
waited with her friends
for five hours on you and that
might have changed your life.
But you'd rather roam around
and get drunk.
We're not drunk.
Yes, you are.
So tell me,
what do you want?
What is this behavior?
Look at me I'm talking to you.
What kind of people are you?
Where did you grow up
I would really like to know.
What is your goal in life?
Father, calm down.
What do you want to do with your life?
I would really like to know.
Otar, don't drink.
Did you say something
You mustn't drink.
There is tea.  - We are coming.
Tea will not help us.
Hello, how are you?
Good and you?  - Good.
How was the ride?  - Good and you?
I'm a bit tired.
Did you come back late
Not really.
Did you bring the posters?
Yes.  Where is Iva?
No idea.  I'm waiting for him.
Let's bring the posters
to my classroom.
Okay.
That's quite a few.
Too many?
Do you have class today  - Yes.
Am I disrupting?  - No.
School is great.
What school did you go to
To night school.
In my final year of school
I didn't go to classes.
Why?
I was pregnant with Anna.
I've been skipping school all the time.
I even had nightmares that the teacher
takes me to the blackboard as punishment.
What are you doing here, mother?
I brought the posters over.
Go home.  - Are you crazy?
Go home.  - Anna!
I said go home!
I hate these posters!
Why are you all silent?  Who is this?
King Erekle.
Which one?  - Erekle II.
Erekle II was one
of the most popular Georgian kings.
The people loved him.
They even gave him a nickname.
Do you remember?  - Little Kachi.
Right.  Why little?  - He was small.
Actually...
there is a folk song about this king.
I would like to recite it.
But I forgot it.
Can you refresh my memory?
Manana I would
like to hear it from you.
Our king is called Little Kachi.
He donned his armor
and tore them to pieces with his bare hands.
Thank you.
Can I ask you for help again?
Who is this?
This is my great-grandfather Nikipore.
Do you know why his ear is bandaged?
Once he ran through the forest,
and a beautiful woman called his name.
But he couldn't hear her.
In the evening they met at a party.
And she scolded him for
that he hadn't heard her.
Nikipore was a hothead and cut
cut off his ear with his dagger.
He said the ear was useless
if he can't hear it.
Would you care to
cut off your ear  for a woman?
That depends on the woman.
What if I called you?
Call me.  - Sandro!  - What?
I don't want you to hear me.
OK.  Call me again.
Sandro!
Shall we meet tomorrow?
I can't.
My husband is out of prison.
He was sentenced to four years
but he comes out early.
He is 36 and was
twice in prison.
The first time because he
stabbed a childhood friend with a fork.
He thought the guy
would have flirted with me.
How did you meet?
I went to school.  I was 14/
He saw me on the street
and I liked him.
I liked a lot of guys back then.
But after Tengo started
to accompany me home
and to give presents
all other admirers disappeared.
Then I got pregnant.
Anna was five when he was arrested.
He got four years, then he came out.
This year he was arrested again.
What happened this time?
He got into a fight.
Do you love him?
I used to love him.
Now I'm not sure anymore.
I'm sick of these problems.
He's trying to change
but he never succeeds.
He's probably unhappy too.
I don't know it.
I will talk to him.
I have never felt so good
like with you.
Never.
I am my whole
drive to the sea for life,
but I only remember the day
that I spent with you
I don't care who your husband
stabbed with a fork.
If you want it,
we will be together
I'll talk to him myself.
But not now.
I need time.
I'll drive you to prison.
Okay.
I have to go now.
Sandro.
Please leave as soon as I get off.
Would you like some Khachapuri?
No thank you.
OK, I'll have something.
How much does it cost?  - 80 Tetris.
Thank you.
Is Khachapuri good?
Not bad.
You see, give me some money.
How much does it cost?  - 80.
Take that.
Let's go to the station.
We'll see the bus
also from here.  Sit down.
The khachapuri is good.
Is this for me?
It is beautiful.
Do you like it?  - Yes.
I got the boys inside
asked to make it for you.
Thank you.
As my cellmate
saw it, he liked it so much
that he let it do it too and
asked me to give it to his mother.
I'll do everything right this time.
Do you believe me or not?
What is he doing?
Who cares what he does.
What is he looking for?
He locked himself out.
I'll go and help him.
Where are you going?
I'll help him.
Leave him, he'll be fine.
What's wrong with you?
I'm just helping him.
Leave him, he'll do it.
He will not.  - We'll miss the bus.
Calm down, don't stress around.
I'm not stressing, come back.
I said,
you should calm down.
To hell.
Is it closed, dude?
Yes, I left the key inside.
Wait a minute.
That too, please.
Hot Khachapuri.
Buy hot Khachapuri!
Khachapuri!
Damned.
Here please.
Thank you.  - No problem.
Are you driving to the town?  - Yes.
Can you take my wife
and me with you?
Okay?  - OK.
Manana, come on.
What's happening?  - Nothing.
Then kiss me.
What is wrong?
Did not you miss me?
It makes me feel uncomfortable.  - Why?
It's normal for someone
fresh out of prison.
He's busy driving.
Relax yourself.
Do you have a cigarette?
Thank you.  And a lighter?
Thank you.
Are you a part-time taxi driver?
Once in a while .
I need a car today.
I'll pay you and give you
extra money for gas.
Where are you going?
You just got out?
Can't you stay home today?
I have to go, it's urgent.
What's happening?
Why is that important?
It's business.
I want to know.  - Relax yourself.
So what are you saying?
It's good.
Wonderful.
I feel sick.
What's happening?  - I don't know,
I need fresh air .
Please stop!  - We're almost there.
I said I'm sick
and I need fresh air/
Hold on.  - What's wrong with you?
I feel sick.  I need air.
Thank you.
Damned.
Wait in the yard I'll be right back.
Throw the ball here.
Ready?
Good performance.
I have a great daughter!
You know how to catch it properly?
Don't let it
slide out your hands.
I'm still falling because of you.
Do not worry.
Natia!
How are you?  - Good.
Don't you feel cold?
Let's get in the car.
The sun is shining.
Come on!
Hi.  - Hi.
This is my friend Sandro.
My pleasure.
Sandro, can you please leave us
alone, we need to talk?
How are you doing?  - I'm good.
In which month are you?  - In the third.
Does the family know?
Yes.
Do they know about me?  - No.
Does my wife have any idea?
No.  - Really?  - No.
Natia, listen to me.
I hate talking about it
but you have to understand me.
I can't take full responsibility
for this baby.
I will of course help you.
I can't do much.
I just got out of jail.
I have no job and no prospects.
Everything is so messed up.
What can I say,
I hate abortions.
But do we have
another option?
I will not have an abortion.
I don't want that.
I understand that, but
is there an alternative?
I don't know but
I will not have an abortion.
I'll get the money.
I'll take you to the best doctor.
You're safe, don't worry.
I don't want your money  - Listen.
OK, you don't need money.
OK, you don't want to have an abortion.
I hate it too but
it's the only way.
What else do you suggest?
I will not do it.
Listen to me.
Let's go to this address.
My sympathies.
My sincere condolences.
Are you Zaza's mother?  - Yes.
I'm a friend of Zaza's.
I just got out of prison.
He had done this for you,
and asked me to bring it to you.
How kind of you. Many thanks.
Call Nuzgar.
How is my son? - Uncle Nuzgar.
Uncle Nuzgar, Natela is calling you.
Thanks, you
made so happy.
Look how caring my son is.
What happened?  - Zaza
sent me a ring from the prison.
This man is his friend.
Good day.
You were in jail with Zaza?  - Yes.
When did you come out?  - Today.
Congratulations  - Thank you.
Hi.
Have a moment
to talk about Zaza?
Sure.  - Please come.
What's the matter, Nuzgar?
He was in prison with Zaza
and came out today.
Come in.
I'll be right back.
Girls, leave us alone for a moment.
Because of that
called meat?  - That's soso.
How are you doing?
I just got out,
enjoying my freedom.
Nuzgar, look at that beautiful fish.
Something very special.
We will
serve funeral feast.
Look.
It's very fresh.
He gave me a special price.
How much?  - First he said 20 lari.
But we agreed on 18.
As for the catfish,
tomorrow we'll get
it fresh from the Alasani.
The fish is good.  - Good, but expensive.
We need
at least 20 kg, right?  - Yes.
You can't get it cheaper.
Let's talk about that later.
The fish seller's
waiting for my answer.
He'll sell it
maybe to someone else.
It still seems expensive.
The fish alone costs 400.
With the catfish...
... it makes it 800. - And off we go.
What should we do?
Maybe we should buy carp.
I'm sorry if I interfere
it's none of my business.
I think they are coming
also with a kind of fish.
Why?
Zaza needs money in prison.
Zaza needs money in prison?  For what?
He lost at cards.
He has to pay today.
Zaza played and lost?
He's a believer, it can't be
that he is playing.
He often visits the priest.
I know, but he played anyway.
I have to visit him in prison.
He hasn't played in ages.
How could that happen?
Go see him.
That's why I said yes.
I know you're short on cash.
Two types of fish are not necessary.
One is enough.
Besides, we can then
think about something else.
It's a delicate thing.
I saw the coffin at the entrance.
And?  - It's an expensive coffin.
Maybe you could
exchange for a cheaper one.
What the hell are you talking about?!
Let's think about something else.
Where's the funeral feast?
In a restaurant.
How much is this per person?
20 lari.  - 20 laris?
And we'll bring our wine.
20 lari with your own wine?
This is too much .
How many people are invited?
250th - 250?
Could a table be set up in the courtyard?
You have a yard right?
Yes.  - Over there.
Let's see.
Let's set up a tent in the yard
Who still uses tents today?
Why not?
The weather is nice. It has a lot of space.
We'll bring wooden chairs and benches.
Cover them with paper.
400 lari will be enough.
I'll get the benches.  - Well, then?
250 guests times 20 lari
per person, that's 5000.
In the yard it would cost only 500.
That would save you a lot.
You would help Zara
and there would be some money left over.
Don't tell us what to do.
We can manage on our own.
Listen brother
I won't tell you anything.
I'm here to help.
If you don't need me, I'll go.
OK, don't be mad.
He was just stating his opinion.
Yes, but it was rude.
Your son sent me here.
Our family is in a bind!
I see that, but do you think
my life is rosy?
I came out of jail.
Here are my discharge papers.
I have more important things to do
than discussing funeral feasts.
I'm only here to help Zaza.
It is your decision.
Let's help your son.
The priest is there to
hold the funeral ceremony.
I'll be there in a minute.
OK.  I'm leaving now.
Should I come back in an hour?
Okay.
I'm also trying to get some money for Zaza
to scrape together, but without guarantee.
See you later.
Oh my God.
Excuse me.
Sorry.
Let's stay a bit
Thank you.
How are you?
Why don't you say hello to Sandro?
Hi.
We have 30 minutes.
Please make us beautiful.
No thank you.  - Come on.
She's the best hairdresser in town.
Sit down.
With him, however, you
can't do much.
Would you like to wash your hair?
No.  - Of course he would.
You changed the shop here, didn't you?
No.
Were these photos
always here?  - Yes.
Are you sure?  - Yes.
Then that's fine.
Please don't smoke here. Go to the back.
Hello Natia.
How are you?
I'm glad to see you.
I have good news.
In an hour
I'll have 2000 lari for you.
I'm serious.
I'm not forcing you to have an abortion.
You must also understand my situation.
I just got out of prison.
But I already have 2000 lari for you.
We'll take care of the rest later.
Where is the problem?
Just calm down, OK?
Manana, where's the ashtray?
It was somewhere here.
What are you doing there?
Here's your pay for this week.
Don't come back
Now get outta here.
What are you doing there?
Change outside.
What's happening?  Did something happen?
You caress my cleaning lady
in my presence!
Are you crazy?
A few hours outside.
What do you want?
Are you sane?
Nothing happened.
Look at me!
Nothing happened.  Got it?
Tengo, please go. - Why should I?
Out!  - I swear.  Listen to me.
Come here!  - Get out!
Do not touch me!
Calm down.  - Out!
Do not touch me!  - Calm down.
I said don't touch me.
I'll hit your head
with the iron.
Are you crazy?  Come on, go ahead.
Be quiet.  We are not alone.
How can you be jealous
on a refugee like Natia?
Are you really crazy or what?
Tengo, leave me alone.
Just relax.
Let go of my hand.
I'll relax when you go out.
Are you sure?  - Yes.
For sure?  - Yes.
Do not hit me!
Then get out!
You act like
a crazy.  - Out!
You are really stupid
Crazy.
Don't sit there.
I won't cut your hair.
Are you married Sandro
No.
If you ask me - never marry.
Why?
I landed in jail
because of my wife.
I don't know,
what to do with this Natia.
She is pregnant
and doesn't want to abort.
What should I do?
What about Zaza?
He played against Rezo and lost.
Do you remember Rezo?
Yes.  But Rezo has a phone,
why didn't he call himself?
He has none.
You found it
and gave him four more years.
For unauthorized phone possession,
and for gambling.
Why did they let you out?
You know I'm telling the truth/
I will find out.
Listen, Nodar.
The prison administration knew everything.
That Rezo had a cell phone and was playing.
That he forced people
to call their families on the phone
to ask for money.
The guards came and said
that they who
don't report gambling
will get two more years.
Everyone was afraid of Rezo
and shut up
but I was fed up.
If you're fed up with Rezo,
then why do you care about the money?
Also, Zaza has stopped playing.
He has become a believer.
I really need money right now.
And how you will make money?
You know I'll pay it back
as soon as I can.  You know me.
I'll talk to you now
and you'll disappear.
Immediately.
You bastard!  - Don't touch me!
hands off me!
Hey you let him go.
He is the driver.
Go to the car  - Let me pass.
I said go to the car.
Get off him.
I'll kill that bastard!
Get the other one over there!
Take your hands away!  - Stand up.
Take your hands away!
Spread your legs!
He's not to blame.
Let him go!
I am his father,
let me explain
Wait a second.  - He's his father.
Let him explain.
He was released today
from prison.
He came to the funeral and said
my son has gambling debts.
Hold him still, I can't hear anything.
Check his papers.
He said my son did
lost 2000 lari in jail.
He said I should give him the money.
He came out today.
Put him in the car, I'll find out.
My father in law died.
His grandfather.
Please take off his handcuffs.
Otherwise his mother will get
a heart attack.
Her father is dead, the elder son
in prison and this one in handcuffs.
Let me.
Nodar, you are a hero.
You saved us  - Thank you.
We won't forget you.
Nodar, thank you.  - No problem.
We are forever in debt to you.
What did you need the money for?
For the family?
Yes.
I have money.
I'll bring it to your family.
Give it to the guy
who came with me.
Here, take this.
Bye.
Sandro.
Bring this to Natia.
She lives with the refugees.
And take whatever I owe you.
I don't want the money.
Thank you.
Hi guys.  - Hi.
Do you know where Natia lives?
Natia who?
The thin one
working in the beauty salon.
What do you want from her?
I should give her something.  - What?
And who are you?  - Her brother.
What should you give her?
Some money.
Come along.
Gela, is everything OK?  - Yes everything is OK.
This is my father.
Dad, that's... - Sandro.
Irodi, sit down.
Is Natia here?  - Natia is
shopping, she'll be back soon.
Sit down, Sandro.
Dad, stay and listen.
What's the matter, son?
Dad, this is the father of Natia's child.
I hardly know her.
I've seen her only twice,
for ten minutes.
Twice for ten minutes, huh?
And you made it
to impregnate her?
Are you saying that
my sister is a whore?
We're her family, okay?
Think before you speak.
Calm down my son.
You made her pregnant
in ten minutes?
Gee, what's up?
Tell him you aren't
pregnant by me.
Gela, what do you want from him?
He has responsibility.
Take responsibility for your actions.
What are you talking about?
I don't even know him.
What is he doing here?
How should I know?
You said that
Tengo's boyfriend got you pregnant.
That's what you said, right?  - Yes, but...
Did you or didn't you?  - Yes.
Well, there he is.
If he is not,
what is he doing here then?
Since when do Tengo's friends visit you?
And bring money?
What is that?
Is that all you offer?
We are refugees
not worth it to you?
You sleep with our women
I'll tear you to pieces!
Come on, go!
I said I'll tear you to pieces!
Wait.  Wait a minute.
Aunt please help me!
What's going on here?
Hold still for a moment.
Wait, I'll tell you.
Tell me everything.  - I'll tell you.
She is pregnant by him.
What did you say?
He got her pregnant.
And he doesn't want to marry her.
Is she pregnant by him?
Yes.
Is what I'm hearing true?
Aren't you ashamed?
You refuse to be a father?
Wait, don't interrupt me.
Aren't you ashamed?
Are you abandoning your child?
How can you reject your child
and this angel?
Be quiet!
How can you disown her?
Answer me.
You should be ashamed of yourself.
An expectant father,
An honorable man.
A real Georgian.
A real Georgian
don't behave like that.
You should conquer mountains
for your child.
It's right here under your nose
and you don't want it?
Look into my eyes!
We trust you Sandro.
Take care of yourselves.
Have my blessings, children!
God bless you.
Don't turn off your phone, Natia.
Gee, is everything OK?
Yes, everything is okay.
Why they hold their hands?
That's how women walk around.
Hi.  - Hi.
How are you, Lali?  - Well, this is Maka.
Iva.  - Give him your hand.
My pleasure.
Did you have a good trip?  - Yes.
And how are you?  - Not bad.
Shall we?  Our car is over there.
Come on Maka, sit here.
Sit down, Lali.
It doesn't work.
Is it locked?  - Probably.
Sit down.
Hello, I'm calling from the 408.
The balcony door does not open.
Why do I want to open them?
I just want them opened.
What do you mean by that,
Did you finish?
Listen, I'll pay for the room
because of the balcony and the view.
I don't care.
I want the view.
I need the view.
Find Tamil
and send someone.
I need the view!
Idiots!
They say it's cold
and they locked the balcony.
It doesn't matter, I can see the view
anyway.
Just describe what you see.
It's more interesting that way.
What do I see from here?
I see the old town of Tbilisi.
The city of many balconies.
The Kura.
It also flows through Gori, right?  - Yes.
Here it is different.
It has more curves.
Baratashvili liked to walk here.
Alone?  - Alone.
I can
see Trinity Cathedral.
You describe well.
Come sit with me.
I can't stay here.
Can you walk with me?
I'll take you to the train station
If you want.  Sorry.
Maka, I'm going.
I'll wait for you at the train station.
Iva, will you take her there?
Of course.
I'll take the bus number 7.
If you can't make it, call me.
Then we'll meet in Gori.
Bye.
Do you want to drink something?  - No.
Some fruit?  We have apples.
Yes, I would like one.
Should I peel it?
No, I'll do it myself.
Really?  - Yes.
I need the room.
The Azerbaijanis are coming soon.
They want to eat khinkali on the balcony.
I'll give you another room.
No thanks, we're leaving.  - OK.
The balcony door is locked.
I'll open it.
They said,
we have to leave the room.
I heard it.
Shall we go?  - Soon.
Hi.
Let's talk a little about the noises.
Listen to the city and walk.
Shall we dance?
But we don't have music.
Never mind.
Are you coming with me?
To where?  - To Kobuleti.
My mother asked me
to pick her up.
What do you need me for?
To keep you awake while driving?
Yes.
I had a terrible dream.
I had a crew of
trained blind soccer players.
I was strict.
What's wrong with you?
Are you still depressed?
Seems so.
Did something happen?
Nothing important.  - Tell me.
A friend of mine was arrested.
His girlfriend is pregnant.
Which friend?
I am your friend.
I still have one.
We studied together.
He'll probably get five years.
I feel sorry for his girlfriend.
She is pregnant and
doesn't know where to go.
I took her with me.
Is there a woman in
your apartment right now?
Yes.
And she's staying for five years now
with you until the guy comes out?
Why don't you marry her?
She seems ready.
I have to tell you something.
What's happening?
We have a guest
A woman - a friend of mine.
She's staying with us for a while.
Who is she?
Just a friend.
You would too
can thread differently.
What do you mean by that?
She's just a friend.
A friend lives with you
for a while.
Of such a friendship
I have never heard.
Do you know her?
No.
Who are her parents?
She is not from Tbilisi.
I'm fed up with this
from your country girls.
By the way, a wise man should
marry a provincial girl.
Roger that?
Why marry?
I will not marry her.
Then keep it to yourself.
How old is she?
Around 25.
How are you?  Are you bored?  - No.
Mother, this is Natia.
I'm glad, I'm Lia.
You can call me Aunt Lia.
And this is Otar.  - Hello, my pleasure.
Hi.  - Hi.  - This is Iva.
Let's have dinner..
I brought all kinds of goodies.
But you have to go shopping.
I'll help you.
No thanks, go watch the TV.
Help is not necessary.
Lia takes care of everything.
Mom, what should I buy?
Bread, tea, peas.
Sandro, bring me glasses for this.
Where did you get that?
From your uncle.
Do you want to watch football
or should I switch?
Let it be.
Do you like football?  - Yes.
It's a Bundesliga game
but I don't recognize the teams.
Hamburg and Dortmund.
Wow.
Do you like German football?
No, Italian.
Girls like Italian football.
handsome guys in shorts,
running after a ball.
It's not about that.
I just like the style.
I like the focus
on the defense.
And what do you like about it?
They always play defense.
It's always dangerous
in front of their goal.
It is excited
when you see them play.
I like that tension.
But it's not just the excitement.
You score goals too, don't you?
Oh yes they do.
Pass it!  Make a pass!
What is he doing there?
That's why I don't like
German football.
What could he have done?  - He should have
play the ball to the right.
Right or left?  - Right.
You know something about football.
Come here for a moment.
Just look at him.
This boy has problems.
Then talk to him.
What should I tell him?
Does he really
betrayed a grieving family?
He didn't cheat on her.
The son of the family
had gambling debts.
Without your husband the guy
would be in a bind now.
He would have problems in prison now.
He behaved very bravely.
He was attacked by 20 guys
but he was fearless and clear-headed.
You are a good man.
And you will find a good wife.
Bring her here too.
For a hairstyle.
I cut both men
as well as women's hair.
Unisex.
Sandro: ANDRO SACHVARELISDE
Manana : IA SUCHITASHVILI
Iva : ARTSCHIL KIKODZE
Tengo: VAKO CHACHANISDE
Sandro's father: KACHI KAWASADSE
Sandro's mother: MARINA KARZIWADZE
Lali : MARIKA ANTADSE
Natia: SOPHO GVRITISHVILI
Natia's brother: JANO ISORIA
Zaza's father: MARLEN EGUTIA
Nodar: LEWAN GHLONTI
Director: LEWAN KOGUASHVILI
Screenplay: BORIS FRUMIN,
LEWAN KOGUASHVILI
Production: SULIKO ZULUKIDSE,
LEWAN KOGUASHVILI, OLENA YERSHOVA
Camera: TATO KOTETISCHWILI
Production Design: KOTE JAPARIDSE
Costumes: TINATIN KVINIKADZE
Cut: NODAR NOSADSE
Production management: KETI MATSCHAVARIANI