Provided by explosiveskull
https://twitter.com/kaboomskull
I've never
been off the island, John.
Neither has your imagination.
Stop.
Where would you travel?
Boston.
No, I mean, if you could go
to South America or Europe?
Boston.
Really?
What is it?
I'm hungry.
You've no more money.
Ah.
Are you looking for someone?
I need a room.
Just for a week or two.
Do you have
family on the island?
I do not.
I'll take you for a night.
After that, you're on your own.
There's rooms out by the
five corners. Guinea town.
Sh.
Jake.
What brings you here?
The war.
You tell him.
Tell him what you need.
His doctor stopped giving him
medicine.
Is your leg still hurting?
Just give us opium,
doctor. I beg you.
I only wish to know the
man's condition, good woman.
Give him what he needs,
or I won't stay with him.
Not another night.
This is the last
of what I've got.
I want to see him back
here if he needs help.
Way I hear it, you're about
to pull up stakes anyways.
Only to another part of town.
Here.
Good morning, Mrs. Rivers.
What you
doing holding a chicken?
Rent.
Although, my landlord
apparently prefers pork.
I'm getting evicted.
Where will you go?
You need your chemist.
I gave away the
last of that opium.
You still owe me for it.
Well, first I need
to find a new office.
What are you
gonna do with that chicken?
Make a good soup.
I beg your pardon.
Uh, Mrs. Roland?
Yes?
Don't make me guess.
I'm looking for
a Dr. Peter Roland.
Ah. Why?
Are you unwell?
My husband was a captain in
the war. They crossed paths.
A captain?
Well, Peter doesn't
talk much about the war.
Is he expecting you?
No, but I have
traveled a long way.
Mm.
Women delay
the start of everything.
Not very polite to our
visitor.
Oh. Apologies all around.
Now can we simply get in the
boat?
Oh yes, I would like to
introduce you.
We'll make
our introductions later.
After we've tried to at
least catch a single fish.
Work here can be
dreadfully dull for a woman.
Unless you like dipping
candles or cleaning fish.
Quiet.
All right, watch this.
Christ.
Charles.
They don't bite at all.
Only men should go fishing.
Father, please.
Without even a bite in
two hours, why bother?
The lazy brutes have taken
their siestas in the sun.
Well, you've had plenty of
good sport.
How many did he hook?
Four.
A silver heap of clammy
scales and struggling fins
breathing in the fatal air.
John has a way with words.
And, you are a doctor?
Not really.
You were not
a doctor in the war?
I was.
Lucia says her husband was a
captain.
Also that he knew you.
Only briefly. At Antietam.
Your husband was in the Navy-
I hope we're not gonna
turn a family fishing trip
into a reenactment of
the Battle of Antietam.
I am sorry, Mr. Roland,
but perhaps-
Peter was a
brave union soldier.
First lieutenant in the
20th Massachusetts infantry.
That's all you need to know.
He saved men's lives
and brought glory to the
good name of Nantucket.
You have a husband?
He was killed at Gettysburg.
I insist we stop this.
I missed the war. I slept
through it.
The place to be, I would say.
My husband told me he was
treated by a doctor from
Nantucket who
appeared to him as an angel.
There were no angels at
Antietam.
I came to find you.
I would like to know why.
Now is not the time.
I agree.
You're interrupting.
I haven't had the chance to-
- The race is over, John.
Will you walk with me?
I should go back to town.
I found a rooming house in
Guinea.
No. Have, have dinner with us.
Peter?
Tend to Mother, old boy.
Let me see.
Josephine'll have dinner ready.
We'll join you at the house.
There may be more to this
young woman
than we care to know.
It pains me to ask,
but I need to borrow $5.
John helped himself to the last
of my cash
and I need to be solvent for the
move.
Of course, but don't be
so hard on your brother.
We need to help him to
find his way in the world.
Which will never happen if
this goes on.
The girl is stunning.
Though her pretext for her
arrival at our doorstep
just takes my breath away.
I wouldn't judge her for that,
not yet.
Is there something
you're not telling me?
You have your eye on her.
We don't keep secrets.
Oh, it's only you.
Only? I pay your keep young
lady.
No, I mean, there was
a fella here earlier,
seemed in a hurry to see you.
Well, tell me, who was he?
A gentlemen. Called twice
while you were away fishing.
And what did the gentleman
say?
He was from the notary.
He said attorney Bennett would
be here himself this evening.
What can it be?
An attorney means bad news.
We still owe for storm damage.
Or money.
But there isn't a single
person on this island
that will give or leave us a
nickel.
Not that we haven't
tried to cultivate one.
Do you remember your Uncle
Joseph Le bow's second wife?
Yes, a Donovan girl.
Daughter of a paper hanger.
They had money, and they liked
us.
Yeah.
And he was in poor health.
Have they any children?
Oh, I should say so.
Four or five.
In my opinion, this important
business
has to do with a marriage
proposal for John.
Why me? You're the elder.
Besides, I do not
wish to marry yet.
Oh, so you are
then a ladies' man?
Isn't necessary to be a
ladies' man
to say that one does
not wish to marry yet.
Ah good. That explains it.
"Yet," you're waiting.
Fine. I'm waiting then, if
you'll have it so.
What fools we are to bother
about this.
Attorney Bennett is a friend.
He knows that Peter's looking
for a suitable new office
and he's found one.
Meal will now be served.
I hope we have finished
discussing family matters.
Ms. Childs, tell us all about
you.
My story is of little
interest, Mrs. Roland.
Won't you tell us from where
you come?
I'm all ears.
Cuba, originally.
My family fled when I was
just six, to St. Augustine.
Why on earth?
My father was hunted in Cuba
for his work against slavery.
He opposed the Spanish
rulers of my country.
If you were against
slavery, then why the hell
did your family settle in a
slave state?
Charles, please.
No child bears the burden
of what their parents do.
My family wished to stay out
of the war.
Many people did.
Oh, I'm sure.
What about your husband?
You said he knew Peter.
Did he fight for the Union?
Stop it, Charles.
And don't answer him, Miss
Childs.
It's all in good humor.
Robert E. Lee brought
20,000 slaves with him
to Gettysburg, young lady.
And he grabbed and shackled
every free Negro he encountered
on his march through Maryland
- and Pennsylvania-
- Miss Childs said
that her family opposed slavery,
Father.
Or, weren't you listening?
Well I'm guessing that she
married a Confederate officer
who defended slave owners.
Am I wrong?
Yankees built and profited
from the slave trade
for 200 years, Father.
Our family, including you
young man, were abolitionists.
This island established
the first Quaker meeting
in the world opposed to slavery.
While some island Quakers
held onto their slaves
for another 50 years.
And the Newport Quakers made
their fortunes from slavery.
Why did you fight in the war,
son?
I didn't fight.
I tended to the dead and the
dying.
And yes, because I opposed
slavery,
as does Miss Childs, or Mrs.
Childs,
which is something we have in
common.
Now that everyone, except our
John,
has finally established their
bona fides,
could we forget this nonsense
and enjoy our flounder?
My father said-
And that includes you, Miss
Childs.
Yes, of course.
I do not know what is next for
me.
I need to settle a bit.
I hope I will see you.
I have only one request.
What are you even saying?
Just this time, Peter.
She's what I dreamed of.
This talk is absurd on the
face of it.
You act like she's
available for the taking.
Listen Peter-
I heard you the first time.
Believe me.
I don't disbelieve you.
Hup!
Hup.
Good afternoon, Josephine.
Are the Roland's at home?
Yes, counselor.
Right this way.
Good evening, sir.
Do you know a certain, a
Mr. Leon Marshall of Boston?
Mm-hmm, we do indeed.
He's a friend?
Best of friends. Formerly
a Quaker, same as we were.
Now a devoted Bostonian who
never leaves Beacon Hill.
He made a good deal of
money selling whale oil.
Mm-hmm.
Mm, I've not
seen him in years.
I must tell you,
Mr. Marshall is dead.
Oh dear.
He wasn't any older than I am.
Well, my notary in Boston
has communicated with me
this morning, the principle
condition of Mr. Marshall's will
by which he makes your
son John his sole heir.
How will the
inheritance be executed?
Charles, please.
Oh, I'm sorry, uh,
uh, how did poor Marshall die?
Well, I only know he has no
other heirs,
and he has
bequeathed his entire fortune
to your second son, who
he had known since birth
and judged to be
worthy of this legacy,
which now produces an
income of $17,000 annually.
And should John refuse,
the entire fortune reverts
to a charity in Boston
for abandoned children.
Christ, what a generous man.
I am very happy to have
brought you this good news.
Your good news is the
death of my parents' friend?
Forgive me, of course.
He was very kind
to my brother and me.
He invited us to
dine with him sometimes.
I don't remember much,
except he always hugged me
when we met.
You'll have to pardon me.
Of course.
Good evening, Mr. Bennett.
Peter.
And there are
no possible challenges
or difficulties to the will?
No, none at all.
It's all very clear.
It just requires
John's acceptance.
Well, you lucky devil.
Ain't you gonna kiss me?
It hadn't
struck me as indispensable
to the transaction.
Ah.
At last, a stroke of fortune.
Did you know
Mr. Marshall well?
Yes, we did.
The day you were born, it was
Leon who went for the doctor.
We were breakfasting with him
when your mother took sick.
In his haste, he grabbed
my hat instead of his.
We had a good laugh
afterwards.
It's likely he remembered
helping bring you into the
world.
Come in.
Uh, it is best
we talk in private.
Indeed.
Please, sit.
First, I would uh, I
would like you to tell me
on what errand you've come
here and uh, and why now?
I thought I had the privilege
of asking the first question.
Excuse my bluntness.
A Confederate widow needs
to be very discrete here.
You fear my presence here is
a danger to your reputation?
Simply stated, yes.
73 men from
Nantucket died in the war.
Please, do not
doubt my discretion.
I see this is not a good time.
No, I, I came here to talk.
Your words to your
family at the dinner table
reveal you to be the kind
of man I expected you to be.
Did the attorney
bring you good news?
Did he find you an office?
No, he came with the offer
of money, to my brother, John.
A family friend left him
a substantial inheritance.
Not to the both of you?
No, though it seems odd.
An old bachelor with no
heirs leaves his fortune
equally to both brothers.
That would be
simple and natural.
Oh, I am sorry.
I do not mean to intrude
in your family matters.
And I am equally surprised
that I'm telling you this.
I hardly know you.
Nor I you.
Though, your brother's
inheritance
does have a certain logic.
What do you mean?
He is so unlike you.
Even, uh-
Even what?
Nothing.
Let us just say that he has
better luck than you or me.
I can't think. I uh, I
don't belong here right now.
Oh.
Excuse me, but I don't feel
comfortable saying any more,
except that I trust that
you will keep my confidence.
I should say
the same thing to you.
You have not revealed anything.
Surely, we will
talk again soon.
Forgive me, Miss Childs.
No, there is nothing to
forgive, on the contrary.
Please.
May I join you?
Of course.
I love it here.
When I was in the war,
I used to get through it
by imagining I was other places.
I would think about the
times I came down here,
seized by the desire to be on
the boats
to countries with roaming lions
and exotic hummingbirds
and stunning girls.
You won't have to work now.
You can travel
wherever you choose,
and find a fair-haired
Swede, or a Southern beauty.
Though I think you would
rather land the widow, Lucia.
Though she's
clearly here for you.
You are delusional.
Now also rich.
Yes, dear boy,
you are a rich man.
I'm very glad to
have come upon you,
to tell you how
pleased I am for you.
How, truly I congratulate you,
and how much I care for you.
Thank you, my good Peter.
Now I'll leave you to
dream about the future.
It's me.
What's the matter?
I just wanted
to say good morning.
You're up so early.
I've got patients.
Just a minute.
Come in.
Will you be home for dinner?
I don't know.
I have my sights set on a new
office with a place to live.
The widow's
found a boarding house?
She has, the Atlantic House.
In New Guinea.
Miss Childs says
she wants time alone.
It's really nothing, Peter.
It's just, I'll only offer
her as much help as she needs.
By the way, mother, I
remember when I was a boy
I think I saw a little
portrait of Leon Marshall.
Yes, it could be.
Do you know what became of it?
Uh, let me think.
I'm not absolutely sure.
You know, maybe it's in my desk.
You look striking.
Do you think
you might find it for me?
I'll look.
Why did you want it?
I thought it'd be only
natural to give it to John,
so he can have a picture
of his benefactor.
I will search for it,
after breakfast.
Well, I immediately
thought of this place,
seems quite
fitting for a young doctor.
Yes.
Yes. It's very nice.
I've had my
eye on it for some time.
It's perfect.
Well uh, two doors open
onto two different streets.
There are two drawing rooms,
a glass corridor where
your patients can wait,
and a garden out back.
I can't
imagine a better place.
I'm sure you'd have many
callers.
Yes, I am
expanding my practice.
How much might it cost?
1,500 for the year.
It's a three-year lease.
What are the terms?
Half down, and the
balance in four months.
Do I have time
to think about it?
Well, you seem to like it.
I want it, I just
need three or four days
to assemble the deposit.
Well, I'll see
what I can do, Doctor.
Do you mind if I just
make some sketches?
Oh, be my guest.
Just drop this by my
office when you're done.
Thank you.
Where's the new office?
32 Water Street.
I'll make plenty.
How much will
the chemist make?
More.
I'm sold.
And each morning, I'll
look out at the harbor,
I'll take a swim, I'll go
downstairs.
I'll see 10 patients a day at
$5 each, that's 12,000 a year.
And in the afternoons
I can see old friends,
war veterans, maybe, maybe
I'll just take $2 from them.
Special.
I'll be richer than my
brother, Smoke,
and more eminent, knowing
I've made it on my own.
I'm looking for Miss Childs.
The widow?
And now with
her and your brother-
Is that where she is,
with my brother?
You could use a girl,
in your office.
I can work for you, mind my own
business.
I don't earn
enough to pay myself.
I'd get them to pay.
I would like you to give
this to your new boarder.
It's just to let her know where
I am in case she needs help.
Good day, Miss Ross.
Not if it hurts my brother.
The simple thing would
be to refuse the money.
Why?
Believe me,
you will find it useful.
Yes, how many times
do you say to yourself,
"Damn, if
I only had some money."
Wouldn't you agree, no
woman wants to marry a man?
Marry?
I would rather
be a mole than a wife.
You're not marrying again?
You came here to Nantucket
with no thoughts of marriage?
You plan to live as a
widow, a single woman.
John, I simply
came out for a walk.
I just meant it,
it won't be easy.
I didn't mean to suggest-
We both know what is going on.
You hid in the bushes all
morning,
waiting for me to come
out of the boarding house.
I don't mean to be forward.
Your eyes are shrinking.
Lucia.
I would set myself up in a
handsome home
that makes
people open their eyes.
You also ought
to ride on horseback.
People will notice.
Select one or
two good cases to defend.
Make your mark in court.
And you do not want to give up
the benefit of your studies.
A man ought never to sit idle.
Fiddlesticks.
You don't agree, Charles?
I just want him to get his
own apartment. Now he can.
But we're not beasts of burden.
The smartest thing in
life is to take it easy.
There, you and I disagree,
Father.
He'd be a fool to work
himself into the ground.
11 grueling years on a
whaling vessel taught me that
and nothing else.
It's not John's wealth
that gives him worth.
In the hands of some men,
wealth can be a powerful lever.
Those men are few though.
Oh.
If John wants to be
a truly superior man,
he needs to
show it by what he does.
Tra-la-la.
Pardon, Father?
When you have a large income
you would be stupid to work.
Again, we differ, Father.
I have a request
for John though.
Surely, what is it?
I need a loan, or at
least the money back
that you've borrowed.
I need it soon.
We have a full afternoon
planned for your brother.
Won't you join us?
Let him do as he wishes.
Surely you
weren't expecting me.
Peter.
You're awfully
frosty this morning.
Father is wrong.
The smartest thing in life
is not to take it easy.
is to avoid dangerous emotions.
How?
I have complete faith in you.
Come home in time for dinner.
Help us plan a celebration
for your brother.
I've got a patient who's
asked for an overnight call.
What is it, Peter?
You'll get your new
patients, your new office.
I don't have to worry
about you like I do John.
He doesn't have your drive.
What is to
become of me, Mother?
Miss Childs.
I got your note.
I'm a bit late.
My comment about you
and John was uncalled for.
I hadn't thought of it.
But uh, now,
I think you're right.
We do look different.
My brother
should refuse the money.
You have never wanted money?
Of course.
In fact, I need it
now to secure a place
before I lose
my practice entirely.
So you
understand John's dilemma.
I just think
there's more to it.
My brother would do
better to give it away.
Dr. Roland.
What is it?
Do you mind, sir?
We're looking for you.
Well, my hours commence
at one. What's the problem?
A girl, she's been hurt.
Where?
Just up the street.
What happened?
A carriage ran right over her.
We need to leave her here.
Her artery's ruptured.
What do I do?
My surgical tools
are in a glass case.
There's a bone saw. The
chloroform is marked.
Okay.
Lucia?
Come in.
Thank you.
Luck that you are here.
I can ask for tea.
No, thank you.
I am concerned about Peter.
Why? What happened?
Oh, why am I telling you?
I, I assumed that you
might know something.
Things get inside him and they
stay there.
Can I help? I care deeply.
Please.
He suspects that I
have turned against him.
It probably seems strange
why I came here to find him.
I'm sure he needs
someone to make him happy.
That is not my intention.
Well what are your intentions?
I am not sure.
And what about my poor John?
He has his faults, but
the look in his eyes
when he sees you.
Yes.
May I?
Photographs of your family?
Friends.
Women who
lost their lovers in the war.
Like I have.
It sounds awful, Peter.
The girl probably
didn't have a chance.
Still, if I had
gotten there sooner.
You can't assume that.
God, I need a drink.
So where were we?
You need a loan.
I'm ready to start a new
practice, John, but I need
money.
Of course. I'll help.
Thank you.
I don't have an exact figure
for what you borrowed,
but uh, now that you-
What's the money for?
A new office.
A grand place that can get
my business going again.
I need $750.
I'll pay what I can.
But I can't immediately,
I've already paid the deposit
on a new place on Water Street.
You've what? Where?
32 Water Street.
32 Water Street?
It's a splendid place, Peter.
Two drawing rooms,
a grand glass corridor,
and a fine garden.
It's a little elegant for my
taste, but,
well you never know.
Can you afford this?
You know you owe me money.
I'll pay you
back what I borrowed
but it's not more than 300.
It's more than 300.
I just can't pay it all now.
Settle down, brother.
Settle down?
You know that I have
been looking for a place.
You were right Peter.
I need to set myself up.
Become a superior man.
Mother's two sons,
both superior men.
You bastard.
Hm. This little
discussion, making me hungry.
Goodness man, we've not
yet found your cure.
You won't.
The cottage is available for
$12 a month for six months.
Will I like it?
Until it gets cold,
I think you'll find the island
just fine.
You remain a
mystery to me, Miss Childs.
You presume that I tended your
husband on the battlefield,
but nothing you say convinces,
and nothing explains why
you've made this long journey.
I killed a Union soldier,
Peter.
I had to.
Please.
And I conducted espionage
for the Confederacy.
I came here to find comfort.
I had nowhere else to go.
For reasons I can't fathom,
you have come here to expose me
and to ruin
what prospects I have.
No.
What
consideration do I owe you
that I did not already unduly
show your husband at Antietam?
Peter.
I feel that I am accumulating
debts for a payment
that I never promised to make.
When I was a girl, Peter,
Union soldiers invaded my
family's home.
There were only three of
them, but that was enough.
They beat my father
and they took him away,
accusing him of
financing the rebels.
He was a
Cuban expatriate and a farmer.
He had nothing
to do with the war.
They wasted no time with us.
First night, they took my
sisters upstairs
and had their way with them.
And they
were only a landing away.
And I could still hear them.
My sisters were strong,
and they fought and they cursed
these men.
I hid in the stables.
And when the
third soldier came for me,
I killed him
with my father's pistol.
I road on horseback and
I found a rebel outpost,
and I offered to
find Yankee troops
and report their location.
I bartered for my survival.
As for my husband,
he was my contact.
A captain I
informed of what I saw.
And he was killed?
Yes. In Pickett's Charge.
I saw it,
and I heard the sounds.
I am cold.
When the war began, there
were few doctors on either side,
and thousands
killed and wounded,
sometimes in a single day.
I enlisted, after
going down to the dock
to see the first steamboat
coming back from the battlefront
carrying island soldiers.
Everyone turned out. It was a
holiday.
Until we saw the steamer coming
into port,
its flag at half-mast.
And there were six young
island men on board in caskets.
I went to the front to
serve the Union cause.
Almost immediately I wanted out.
I tended to Southern soldiers,
yes, and more than once.
I suppose I saw a dying
soldier as no longer the enemy.
Armed and upright? Yes.
But, crying
out at night in a field
with thousands of dying men, no.
You did see my husband,
Wilbert Childs?
I tended three rebel
fighters at Antietam,
and one was a captain
in Lee's Virginia Army.
I found him huddled in
stark terror in a culvert,
buried under
a dozen dead soldiers.
Hours after the battle, I
heard him crying out for mercy
and I went to him,
not knowing if the voice
was from the North or South.
You amputated his left arm.
I thought he would live.
To fight another day at
Gettysburg?
Well, he promised me
he wouldn't fight again.
That was my condition.
Even if I didn't
always believe him.
My family doesn't
know this about me.
No one on this island does.
I became a medic because
I refused to fight.
But I am a patriotic
veteran of the Union army.
I held a dozen island boys in
my arms and watched them die.
And I saved many more.
I don't sleep much.
I'm certain my sisters'
attackers have not forgotten me.
I have not forgotten them.
Is that why you're here?
You're running, is that it?
The ceasefire did nothing for
the South.
Teachers killed.
A Negro man
refuses to tip his hat,
and he is
shot dead in the street.
Why would I stay?
I could not go back to Cuba.
And your kindness to my
husband drew me here.
Where's Peter?
He's always late.
I say we begin without him.
Look at this man.
A whaler retired long ago,
with neither thighs,
chest, arms, nor neck.
I, on the contrary, am as tight
as an egg,
and as hard as a cannonball.
Oh.
May I?
You may.
Ah!
To all of us.
Lift your glasses.
To the man
with a bank draft
in his new account.
17,000 per annum,
free and clear.
Dinner is served.
No, no, no, no. Tonight
everything is for John.
Ah, well.
It's all right.
And then I just
, I saw,
I was 10, and there
was Christ right there,
standing on the clothes.
And then I saw the oddest
looking fish.
With its gold goggles
and, and fat, red belly.
And its fan-shaped fins, and
its, at the bottom, a tail.
It was crescent-shaped, the
tail.
And there it was, and it
was starting to go away.
Away, oh, ah-oh,
there it is now.
What the devil?
I should have
eaten at the Sea Shack.
Peter, we kept the soup warm.
Last time I ate at the Sea
Shack I was sick for two weeks.
I like that sound
better than a pistol shot.
It may be more
dangerous for you.
How so, lieutenant?
Because the bullet might miss,
but the wine is dead certain
to hit you straight in the
stomach.
And then what?
Then it scorches your
intestines,
shocks your nervous system,
and makes your circulation
sluggish,
which can lead
to an apoplectic fit,
which threatens the end
for a man of your build
and temperament.
Ah, these damn doctors,
they all sing the same tune.
Eat nothing, drink nothing.
Cut the gamahuching. Keep
your bawbles in your pocket.
Well sir, I have practiced all
of these forbidden pleasures
and more, wherever
and whenever I pleased.
That's when I did it.
Here, here.
And I'm none the worse for it.
All bon vivants
talk as you do,
until the day when they
can no longer crawl back
to tell the prudent
doctor, "You were right."
Peter, think what a wonderful
occasion this is for John,
and for all of us.
You're mean to, to spoil it.
You really think this will
kill me?
I'm sure of it, but drink it
this once.
Not too much.
Ah.
I propose a toast to
celebrate the ascension
of John, the rich.
Here, here.
Peter.
My only desire is to fly
away from these people,
to leave their
idle talk and silly jests.
And their joy. You are
jealous, that is all.
I'm not jealous.
You are, it is shameful.
Don't leave.
You are in
my good graces John,
because the
wine cheers my foul temper.
And prevents me from saying
what I would like to say to you.
Which is what?
I don't remember.
Well, we are here tonight
to honor our dear friend John.
It is said that
fortune is blind.
I say she is simply
shortsighted,
and has lately acquired one
hell of a good pair of glasses,
so that she may see our
remote little island
and the son of our worthy
comrade, and my friend, Charles,
captain of the Little Pearl.
Thank you captain.
I and my son will not forget
you, or this occasion.
I drink to your wishes.
Sit down. It's my turn.
It is I who should
thank my devoted friends,
who today give me touching
proof of their affection.
But it is not with words
that I will show my thanks.
I shall prove it tomorrow, and
always, through my actions.
Well said, my boy.
Miss Childs give us a
toast from the fairer sex.
Let us offer our
thoughts to the fond memory
of Mr. Marshall.
It takes a woman to pay
so delicate a tribute.
Who the blazes
was Marshall, anyway?
You must've been
quite intimate with him.
The finest kind,
like a brother.
Such a friend
we won't find twice.
He dined with us, took us
to the theater in Boston.
Need we say more, Louise?
Yes, Charles,
a faithful friend.
I've had enough.
Evidently.
Excuse me.
Peter.
Peter, come to
your senses and calm down.
Go back inside.
I will not go back inside.
Don't talk to me in that tone.
Have you found your
photograph of Leon Marshall?
Where did you find that?
Did you deceive my father?
This honest and mediocre
man.
Oh, I'm sure you married,
as young girls do,
the man with a promise of a
fortune from stripping oil.
The boy was not cut out for
years on end on the high seas
chasing a vanishing,
reluctant prey, was he?
And what of this tender woman?
Shut up for years in his absence
and tied to him when he returns
to drink and smoke cigars,
and, and talk of money, boats,
and fish.
And then one day a man appears,
as lovers do in novels,
and he speaks as lovers speak.
Of course, you
found love in his arms.
- Oh, Peter.
- And of course,
you allowed him to draw up a
chair in another man's home.
This, this, this man of means,
growing rich from brokering
whale oil
pretending to be a family
friend while making a fool
of my father, myself, my
brother, and yes, you.
What?
Did you give yourself to him?
This man, who even now,
faraway and grown old,
leaves his fortune to your
son, your son with him.
Perhaps you
should forget all of this
about your
brother and the money.
Why pursuit it?
Why? Because of the
obvious hiding and cheating.
Why didL eon Marshall not see
this result
of causing chaos in my family?
Why did my father not feel it?
And he is nearly giddy.
Why does my mother pretend
that this is something
other than what it is?
No, the way in which
this unexpected fortune
has arrived now, so fills my
mind that there is little room
for other thought.
To whom should it matter?
To the public, of course.
To our neighbors.
Why should anyone care, Peter?
When they're speaking
of the Roland sons,
will they not ask,
"Which is the truth
and which is the false one?"
Walk with me, please.
All of our endeavors are like
the laborers of these urchins.
How I might
like to beget two or three
of these little creatures,
watch them grow up,
mindless of all that we endure.
Perhaps I long for marriage,
Miss Childs.
Is this a new feeling?
You know, I know very little
of women.
A man is not so lost when he is
not alone.
Just to feel someone stirring
beside me
in hours of doubt on
uncertainty,
to feel the presence of a woman.
A woman's kiss,
the touch of her hand,
the rustle of her petticoat.
The soft look in her eyes.
To calm my needful heart.
I do not want to kiss you.
You know that I am fond of you.
You prefer John.
Your mother says not to
expect you for the picnic.
Lucia'll be here shortly.
Are you going?
Maybe not.
You look cross.
No. Should I be?
I'm happy you're home,
but you shouldn't fight with
your brother.
We've been lucky enough to
receive this inheritance.
Yet, it's as if we're in
mourning.
I am in a way.
You are?
Who for?
A woman. No one you knew.
Well, I won't pry.
Though it's obvious.
I hope you recover.
Do you understand
what I'm talking about?
Do you? Think
what you're doing.
I've heard enough.
Louise.
You look terrible,
for god's sake.
Can't you see
that your mother's not well?
Will you do something?
I'm just tired.
Let me see.
It's nothing, really.
I'm going to find some
vinegar.
I'm not afraid of you.
Come on then.
Your pulse is quite fast.
You should take something
to calm you down.
I have pills in my bag upstairs.
What is it, Louise?
I've never seen her like this.
She'll be fine, it's just
nerves.
The fresh air will do her good.
You'll come on the picnic
with us, just in case?
I'll go upstairs
and get the pills.
Low tide is three o'clock.
Your mother and I are
gonna go look for clams.
Watch that Lucia doesn't
get dizzy in the cold water.
She'll be fine, Father.
You look so severe.
Look closer.
In a trance?
I oughta make up my mind.
Fun is good but, love is better.
I'll leave that up to you.
I'll meet you later.
You're exhausted, Louise.
And you're still too
involved with the boys.
I'm not allowed?
Well, I know I can't stop you.
Well then don't. Encourage me.
Look me in the eye.
Do you think Miss Childs
is serious about our John,
or just playing with him?
I can feel yo
fighting all this.
Though I confess, I don't
know what's to become of us
with Peter and John gone.
Here, take this.
I'm going.
What is it? What do you see?
I'm taking lessons.
I'm learning how a man prepares
himself for being a cuckold.
Who are you talking about?
John. He's laughable.
You're so damn rigid.
I know you're hurt, Peter.
But why hurt others?
Your brother
couldn't hope for more.
I'm sure she's perfectly
honorable.
Of course, all women are
honorable,
and all men are cuckolds.
What do you see?
I see your face.
How pretty you look.
If that is all you see,
you will miss all of this.
It's what I prefer to look at.
John, you are staring.
You're cruel.
You're stunning.
Stop.
I'm thinking of only one
thing. You.
Will you be quiet?
I love you.
I can no longer hold my peace.
You intoxicate me.
My dear friend, you
are no longer a child,
and I am not a young girl.
If you have made up your mind
to declare your love for me,
I assume you wish to make me
your wife.
Why yes, I do.
I managed to snag an eel.
Oh!
Father will be nearly
vindicated.
He will not.
Oh.
Guess what I've done, Mother.
I don't know.
Guess.
I've told Lucia
I want to marry her.
Marry her?
Yes. Don't you think
it's the right thing?
Yes, she's charming.
Of course.
So you approve then?
Yes, I, I approve.
Is she with child?
Do you mean to say
that you're not pleased?
No, but I am. I am pleased.
Lucia's not with child,
she barely lets me touch her.
As it should be.
What does she say about this?
I cannot do better, I'm sure.
You haven't answered my
question.
She didn't reply. That means
that she's thinking about it.
Oh , is that what it
means?
Come, talk to Lucia.
She likes you. Maybe
you can encourage her.
I'm sure she
gets all the encouragement
she can manage from you.
Miss Childs.
I think I'll see if Peter
and Father have wandered off.
Do you intend to marry my son?
I like John.
I enjoy him, and I
admire his good fortune,
and his desire to share it.
He says he loves me, and
he wants to marry me.
So I will marry him.
Girls are raised to marry.
They're not always made to
understand the compromise
until later.
Of course we are.
We sell to the right bidder
and pray for love to follow.
You were married.
Betray yourself and you will
find yourself betraying others.
I understand.
Good.
What do you think?
Gorgeous.
This is where we'll live.
Christ almighty.
Truly grand, son.
Counselor.
If humanity alone, if our
instinct of natural compassion
we feel towards all who suffer,
were the motive for the
acquittal we ask,
then I shall appeal to your
compassion,
gentlemen of the jury.
To your hearts
as fathers and as men.
But, we have
the law on our side,
and it is
simply a question of justice
we shall submit for your
judgment.
Bravo.
What about
women at the jury?
How well my
voice carries in this room.
Would you like a little tour?
Excuse me.
What do you think?
Does it please you?
Yes, it does.
The bed is so white.
Did you choose this?
I did.
Welcome to the family, Lucia.
I'll leave you.
Fit for a king, I'd say.
This has all been such a
delight.
I will take my leave now.
Charles. Charles.
Would you accompany Miss
Childs to her boarding house?
Ah, yes dear.
Shall I come back for you?
No, no.
Peter will see me home.
- Mother?
- Mm-hmm?
Would you excuse us?
Oh, of course.
The widow
certainly looks all-in.
The widow?
What has happened to you?
You've made quite an
impression.
I'm really getting tired
of your attitude towards me.
Towards you? How dare you.
I know that
you're jealous of me.
Oh, jealous, good lord,
jealous of what?
Of your looks, of your brains?
Your apartment?
It drives you mad that
Lucia prefers me to you.
Oh really? Jealous of you
and that shrewd little goose?
You're bursting with jealousy.
Shut up.
No, and you torture
Mother as if it's her fault,
as if everything is.
Shut up, right now.
No. I've wanted to
tell you what I think.
I demand a little respect.
Me, respect you?
Yes, me!
Respect you?
You who's dishonored
us all with your greed.
What did you say? Greed?
Go on, dammit. Tell me how I've
dishonored us with my greed.
I'm saying you don't
accept one man's fortune
when you're supposed to
be the son of another.
What'd you say? Say that
again.
I'm just saying what
everyone else is whispering.
Are you stupid?
You're the bastard son of the
man who left you the money.
Here's your father, Leon
Marshall.
No man with any respect
would accept the money.
Not when
it dishonors their mother.
Peter, please. Please,
let's discuss this.
Peter help me.
I am a swine to
have told you this.
Sit down.
What Peter said is true.
Why lie about it?
You wouldn't believe me if I
denied it.
Hush.
I have nothing more to say.
What are you doing?
Where are you going?
I don't know.
Mother.
Well,
what, what? John, John.
You will not go.
I love you.
Oh it's impossible.
Tomorrow, even
you will not forgive me.
How can I live
between the two of you?
Of course you can.
How can I avoid
thinking of this
when I see you
and your brother every day?
It does not matter.
But you would think of it.
My child,
we must try to be calm.
If I were to hear, even once,
what I heard from your brother,
if I was to see in your
eyes what I read in his,
- I will be gone.
- Stop.
You don't have to forgive me.
There's nothing so
wounding as forgiveness.
But you must owe me no ill
will for what I have done.
You must be
strong enough to accept
that you are not Charles' son,
without blushing and without
despising me.
You must say to yourself
that although I was
your father's mistress,
I was more truly his wife.
Before God, I love no one
but him and you two boys.
Stay, Mother.
I can be with you.
At least for tonight.
That is out of the question.
Come, I will take you home.
I won't share it with anyone.
I don't know
what's happening to me.
There was this kid in torn
clothes, trying to walk,
but he'd fall down.
And he'd get back up,
like this island boy
at Cold Harbor, where
artillery shot cut him in half.
You'd had this before?
Never like this.
My heart beats like it's going
to pound through my chest.
What about
your wife? Have you told her?
She left.
May I come in?
Do you think me a wretch?
What's the
matter with your eye?
What did you and mother say
to each other after I left?
Nothing.
Mama and I sorted linens.
I somehow doubt that's all-
Peter.
Since I am
the son of this other man,
since I know it and
accept it, is only natural
I should accept his fortune.
Since I'm not the son of the
man I believed to be my father,
I can accept nothing from him.
Neither now, nor after he
dies. It would not be right.
I shall renounce all claims
to the family inheritance,
and leave it to you.
It is only right.
It is also just that I keep
the money from my own father.
If I were to
refuse my father's money,
it would only invite hardship,
which would serve no one.
I understand, John.
Good, which brings
me to the next matter.
What is that?
It's a delicate point.
It involves your presence here.
And in the family. Is
that what you're suggesting?
Not at all.
That now that
I am the sole heir,
I should leave
the Roland family?
You should leave
the island, Peter.
Your presence hangs like
a cloud over everyone,
most of all, you.
There's a schooner, a freight
schooner, leaving for Boston,
and then Baltimore.
I know the captain, and
I'm prepared to provide you
with the funds
you'll need for six months
in either city as you
work to set yourself up.
John.
No.
Good morning.
Are you not
coming down to eat?
There is a
great deal for me to do,
because I see
now that you were right.
Yes?
It is time for me to leave
this house.
It no longer feels like a home.
And these people who no
longer feel like my family,
we are bound by
the thinnest of threads.
I torture you and Mother
with my mere presence.
And clearly, I torture myself.
It is unbearable.
We'll wait for you.
Is she, is Mother down there?
Yes. She sent me to fetch you.
Very well, I will come down.
It's a handsome schooner
that's come into port.
It's the Tyrone. Life is
very pleasant on these ships.
Hm.
I am planning
to sail with her.
What on earth do you mean?
I spoke to the purser
and I will sail
with her on Thursday.
I have my heart set on it.
Is this true?
Louise?
All the
arrangements have been made.
Well, huh, then perhaps
you can take me on board.
I've been wanting to see
the insides of that boat.
Certainly I will.
Have you got money, Peter?
I have sold my watch.
I'm happy to give you-
I'll be fine.
Are you sure
that you have enough?
What of all your plans?
What's to become of them?
I'll work on board.
I'll make new plans.
Hm, what do you think Louise?
I think that Peter is right.
Why, I'm happy you agree.
I know John does too.
Father?
In a couple of years
you'll have a practice
and some money,
and you'll be on your way.
Will you promise to write,
Peter?
No, thank you, Josephine.
I'm too nervous this morning.
Hm, well.
Excuse me, everyone.
So, Mama, will you come
with me to calm Lucia?
Yes.
Yes, I will come.
I think I'll gather some
flowers from the greenhouse.
You see, Peter was quite
ready and willing to go away.
Poor boy.
Why do you say, "Poor boy?"
He will be happy
onboard the schooner.
No, I know.
I have things to take care of
upstairs.
Well, you'll be
needing some things.
But I'm at a bit of a loss.
I ordered your underwear,
and I went to the tailor for
the rest of your clothes.
But, do you need anything else?
No. Nothing else.
Maybe things that I haven't
thought of?
No, thank you.
It's all done.
Hello?
I hope we're not too late.
We want to
spend some time with you.
Step inside.
You don't get
much air down here.
Well, you even
have your own pharmacy.
Maybe I'll be called
upon to help someone.
Yeah.
Ah, sooner than I thought.
Well, we best be going.
But must we? Already?
Sounds like
she's about to sail.
Well, goodbye son.
Heh. Let's go.
I thought Lucia might come.
You look disappointed.
Will you say goodbye for me?
Have you made plans?
We know what we'd like.
We'll have
a lot to talk about.
Provided by explosiveskull
https://twitter.com/kaboomskull