Provided by explosiveskull
https://twitter.com/kaboomskull
I won't be long, I'm just
going to check on my daughter.
Excuse me. Excuse me,
everyone. Sorry...
Has anyone seen Olivia?
Claire, what's going on?
I think you'd better
call the police.
So after everything
that's happened,
are there any new suspects?
There's a few, yes.
A search of the local area
has taken place.
As of now, nothing's been found.
We're urging anyone
with any information
to please come forward.
Thank you.
It's been two weeks since the
disappearance of Olivia Truman.
Olivia went missing from
her home in Greater London
during a family birthday party.
The nanny put Olivia to bed
and when I checked
later that night...
She was gone.
There was a large
gathering that night.
Police interviewed
everyone at the party.
And nobody saw a thing?
Nothing. She just vanished.
From her bed?
From her bed, yes.
Right under our noses.
I need as much info as you got
on a Roma Bernard.
Roma.
As in Romeo, Oscar,
Mike, Alpha.
That's it. And Bernard, err,
Bravo, Echo, Romeo,
November, Alpha,
Romeo and, yeah,
D for dickhead. That's it.
Everything you've got on him.
I'm speaking to the parents
first thing in the morning
so I need everything by then.
Can you do it?
You legend.
Cheers buddy.
All right,
I'll speak to you soon.
You coming to bed
or you sleeping on the sofa
like every night?
Yeah, I'll be up in a minute.
You can take a break you know.
Your daughter misses you.
You hear me?
What do you want me to do?
Can you see what's going on?
Have you seen this case?
I crack this one...
That's chief inspector.
It's nice to see
what's important to you.
Good.
I'll be up in a minute.
Don't bother.
Oh, fuck.
I don't trust the parents.
Why not?
I dunno, there's something
not quite right about them.
What would you do
if Lucy went missing?
I don't know what I would do
if they took my son.
I do feel for the Trumans.
Yeah? Well my nose never lies.
And that's why I'll make
DCI and you won't.
Really?
We'll just see about that.
You have a lovely home.
Yeah.
How are you coping?
Staying positive.
Thank you.
Have you any new info?
What? What is it?
We need to speak
to your nanny again.
Mariam? She's gone back
to Romania.
Yeah, we heard that.
It's unfortunate considering
we told everyone
not to leave the country.
Well, she missed her daughter,
as I'm sure you understand.
Why would I understand?
We've heard about you.
Good things.
We need to contact Mariam.
Why? What have you found?
We can't discuss that.
Don't give me that!
Don't.
I'm sorry-
- Just tell us something,
please.
Anything.
Some things have come to light
which involves your sister too.
Liz?
What has she got to
do with this?
Have you seen her recently?
No. Why?
You haven't spoken to your
sister since the night
your daughter disappeared?
No.
Have you spoken
to her boyfriend Rob?
Yeah. Yeah, we've spoken to him.
I thought I should call you guys
because, um,
well, on reflection, there are
a couple of things that happened
that night that even I
can't make sense of.
And you're just telling us
this now?
Well I didn't think anything
of it at the time, did I.
But now...
What?
Liz is missing.
I don't know where she is.
She's not answering her calls.
Liz relapsed at the party.
She's an addict?
Yeah. Well, she was. Erm...
She'd been clean
for three or four months now.
Then something
happened that night.
I don't know what.
It all started when she spoke
to that fucking nanny.
God, I'm bored.
Let's fuck.
I think people might see us.
On Claires bed?
No, absolutely not!
Rob, come on.
Don't be so square.
Hey, I am not square.
I'm actually very well rounded.
You're lucky you're funny.
Or what? You wouldn't
date my ugly arse?
I like your ugly arse.
Like. I see.
'Cause I love yours.
What the fuck is she looking at?
Who?
The nanny.
She keeps staring at me.
Maybe she fancies you.
Probably.
This is so weird.
She's waving me over.
Go tell her we don't mingle
with the help.
Okay, I better go
and see what she wants.
Do you want me to come with you?
No.
Fine, I'll just mingle
with myself.
They went outside for a chat,
a cigarette, I don't know.
And, um, when she
came back, she...
it was like a light
had switched.
She started spiralling.
Hey, hey, hey, slow down.
What happened?
I don't wanna talk about it.
Come on, Liz, caring
is sharing, remember.
Fuck off, Rob.
I'm worried about her.
Liz has been known
to hang out with some pretty
dark, shady people.
What kind of shady people?
Dealers, addicts, loan sharks,
you name it.
Fuck sake!
Damon!
I knew it, they want Liz, she
owes them money or something.
I'll call her.
Yeah, call her. Call her now
and tell her to get over here!
Did you speak to her that night?
Briefly.
Liz, call me when you get this.
It's urgent.
I'm worried about you.
Call me back. It's Claire.
What did she say
to you that night?
Hey big sis, how's tricks?
You okay?
Mhmm, I'm great.
I am fucking hunky-dory.
I'm Elizabeth.
Roma.
Homer.
Ro-ma.
Roma, oh.
Ha, ha, ha, you're French.
Oui.
And this must be your dad?
He's my lawyer.
Oh.
I need me one of those.
Pfft, why is everyone
so fucking serious?
This is supposed to be a party!
Loosen up!
She absolutely humiliated me
in front of Andre.
Remind me who Andre is.
He's a French ambassador.
We were lucky
to have him in our home.
How did you meet Damon?
At a Pharma conference in Paris.
Oh, so you're into
pharmaceuticals then?
Sometimes.
Yeah.
Me too.
Excuse me.
It's the wife.
Judge Judy's just finished,
she'll probably be bored.
So.
Do you mind?
Tell me more about Roma.
I'm sorry, why do you
want to know about Roma?
'Cause Liz stole his phone.
I'm sorry what?
She stole his phone.
Hi, I, uh, sorry to interrupt.
Liz, can I have a minute?
Robert, can't you see I'm in
the middle of a conversation?
Yes, I noticed.
Roma.
Hi, I'm Robert, Liz's
long term boyfriend.
Ugh.
What's with all the labels, eh?
Do you mind if I
steal her for a second?
Please.
Thank you. Liz, a quick word.
I'll be right back.
I won't keep her for long.
What do you want?
What is this?
What's what?
What's happening? Even for you,
this isn't normal.
Then get with the
fucking program.
Ooh!
Rob.
I'm never gonna be
who you want me to be.
You are who I want.
You don't know me.
I know enough.
You don't know my past.
Your past is what makes
you who you are,
the person that I love.
Robert.
You're a nice guy.
And you think people
are good inside
but they're all fucking rotten.
I'm rotten.
Hey, hey, no, no, no,
you are not rotten.
Look, fuck off, Rob.
Liz, open up.
Liz!
You need a leash, no?
It's not what it looks like.
Then what the hell is it? Hm?
Shh! It's a honey trap.
Liz, what the fuck is going on?
He is a very bad man.
Fuck sake! Fucking
phone's locked!
What's on his phone
that's so important anyway?
Mariam?
Keep it down, Olivia's sleeping.
Why do you want Mariam anyway?
What you doing?
Where the fuck is Mariam?
Why did Mariam
go out that night?
Didn't she already
tell you this?
Mhm.
We'd like to hear your version.
Something about a boyfriend.
Why what did she tell you?
Just that she went
to the cinema. Alone.
Well, why would she lie?
An even stranger
question would be
why would she ask Liz to steal
Roma's phone and then leave?
Do you have a way
we can contact her?
I've dealt with Romanians
in Vice before,
they're absolute scum.
Bit fucking racist, innit?
Racist? You have no idea what
these people are capable of.
All right, 'cause I
was born yesterday.
Danny, they're major
human traffickers.
He's a weird cunt, ain't he.
That's the victims father.
Exactly.
Careful, Danny.
We have her online.
Okay, so run us through
everything that
happened that night.
I told you everything.
Well tell us again.
I don't have much time.
Well, make time.
Or we'll have your
Romanian police
ship you over here so fast,
you won't even have time to
take the Goulash off the stove.
Why must you speak to me
like this?
Probably because
you hopped on a flight out
during a major investigation.
I had to see my daughter.
Yeah, lucky you.
I put Olivia to bed.
Do your parents
let you use that?
They don't care.
I care, delete please.
Now.
Time for bed, Mariam.
Darling, how do I look?
Good. Very good.
You sure?
You look perfect.
Ready?
I loved her
like my own daughter.
Loved?
Love. Yes.
No, you said 'loved',
past tense.
My English is not so good.
Yeah, it sounds pretty good
to me. But please, continue.
What is it?
I had an accident.
I should inform your mother.
She's busy with her friends.
She doesn't care anyway.
I don't think that's true.
We need lady pads. You know?
Maybe check her bathroom.
I changed her bed sheets.
I gave her the tampons
and she went to bed.
And I didn't see her again.
Because you went out?
Yes.
To the cinema?
What did you see?
Nothing.
Nothing, good film that.
I think I might have seen it.
I had something to eat instead.
A nice slap-up meal with the
boyfriend? What's his name then?
I don't have a boyfriend.
Hm, no labels?
Well it is 2020 after all.
What?
Claire said...
that you went out
to see your boyfriend.
What? No. No, I was alone.
So she's lying?
Yes.
This is getting
fucking interesting.
Wait. You think I did this?
Of course, blame
the poor Romanian,
we are all peasants
who you cannot trust.
Sorry, the race card isn't
gonna work with us, Mariam.
Well, this country did vote
for fucking Brexit, didn't it.
You know nothing.
I was trying to help Olivia.
Mama.
Who's that?
My daughter.
Can we see her?
No.
You really want
to know what happened?
We really, really do.
You think you do,
but do you really?
What is this a trick question?
Yes, we really do want to know.
And you swear you will
protect my family?
We pinky promise.
Assholes.
Okay, here is the truth.
Well, we're strapped in.
Where's Olivia?
Ask her fucking parents.
This is a nice house Mr. Truman.
Thank you. Could be better.
Okay, let's discuss.
We've considered a price.
Good.
Twenty thousand per meeting.
No, no, no, this is too much.
Really? I think
we all know it's not.
For me, Olivia
is nothing special.
Well, if that was the case,
you wouldn't have
travelled all this way.
She's good isn't she?
We just want a good deal.
Fifteen is a good deal.
Seventeen.
Seventeen and we'll
prep and drug her.
She won't remember a thing.
That's a funny story.
Of course, who would believe
an immigrant woman
over a respectable
British family?
I do.
I do!
But then again I love
a conspiracy theory.
You know, like, 9/11
was an inside job.
You mock me,
but there is evidence.
I know, like the steel beams
and the thermite,
I've seen all the documentaries.
I know all about it.
No. Roma's phone, idiot.
Seventeen. Agreed. Now,
this phone has recorded
everything we just said.
So if we go down, you go down.
C'est compris?
People don't understand
this kind of thing.
We have to be careful.
I do.
My sister and I were given
this kind of love
from our own father.
We were always careful.
Champagne?
You see this?
This is my shocked face.
And this is my
'I call bullshit' face.
I knew no one would believe
me, so I needed evidence.
You think this is funny?
Mary - what's your name?
Mariana, you call me Mariam.
Mariana, Mariam, whatever.
In this country, we
don't sell our children.
Where are you from?
Romania.
Romania. Do they sell
children in Romania?
Probably.
On eBay, right?
They do everywhere.
Now, why are you telling me,
of all people?
Because you know what it's like.
And how would I know
what it's like?
You were abused by your father.
I heard Damon
tell it to the men.
Yeah, they recorded
everything on their phone.
Just fucking be quiet
for a second.
Okay, sorry. I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
Who are you?
What?
I said who the fuck are you?
I'm the nanny.
Who sent you?
Nobody!
Did they send you
to fuck with me?
Nobody sent me!
I'll burn your fucking
eye out you fucking cunt!
Stop, please! I just
want to help Olivia, okay!
Damon is doing
the same thing to her.
I just want him to stop, okay.
Fucking liar!
Are you lying to me?
No. No!
Come on. Please.
I fucking love this Liz.
Jesus Christ!
Don't she know I go to work
to get away from her?
Take five, ladies.
Carly, what's the emergency?
You working?
No, I'm on a beach in Barbados.
Yeah, well I
wouldn't put it past you.
What's the matter? You bored?
'Cause I can throw these quips
at you all day long if you want.
I'm sure the little girl
will find herself.
And what about
your child's missing father?
Oh, brilliant.
I'm actually in her
room right now.
Whose?
Olivia's.
Poor girl.
Yeah, the decor's awful.
The parents are monsters.
I got a phone call today.
Oh, yeah? Well I've
had about ten from you.
Oh, well fine.
I won't tell you.
No, go on.
I'm on the edge of my seat.
No, just forget it.
Babe.
No, look, if you wanted
to marry your work,
then maybe you shouldn't
have married me.
Twat!
Sorry about that.
Right, where were we?
Big-wig paedophile politicians.
Oh, my favourite.
Come on, indulge me.
What?
Give me what you've got.
What's wrong with him?
Many things.
Tell me more about the nonce.
Holloway, fuck off, will ya!
What?
Who was the man that
you went out to see?
There is no man.
Come on now,
you're a pretty girl.
There's no significant other?
No friend with benefits?
I don't have time for this.
See now, what I really
want to know is
if you claim to care
about Olivia so much,
if you love her like a mother,
then why the fuck
would you leave her
in a house full of pedophiles?
Because he -
Speak up, please.
Because he
threatened my daughter.
Who did?
That evil piece of
shit Damon Truman.
What are you doing?
She was thirsty.
I'll take care of her.
It's all right, daddy's here.
Goodnight, sweetheart.
Can we talk?
We have a strange request.
We need you to go
out for the night.
Cinema, or something. My treat.
Why?
Well, after the party, Claire
and I would like
some alone time.
For my birthday.
I won't bother you.
Sure, sure, but
we'd just like to have
the house to ourselves
for a few hours. You understand?
No.
No, you don't understand? Or -
No, I'm not leaving.
Well, Mariam we pay you.
To protect Olivia.
So I will.
Protect her from who?
Her parents?
She doesn't need protection
from the people who love her.
You may have people
fooled but not me.
What does that mean?
I heard everything.
Everything?
Everything.
Okay.
How much?
How much money do you want?
I'm not for sale.
Two thousand pounds.
Get out of my way.
Three.
Four thou-
Move or I'll scream.
I know you have a child
at home that needs the money.
How dare you speak about her?
How dare you talk
about my daughter!
A child deserves love,
have you none in your heart?
Oh, I love my daughter.
You don't know how to love.
Wait!
Get out of my way!
And if I don't?
I'm calling the police.
Don't scream.
- Don't!
- No, please!
Don't fucking move!
Now, I don't wanna hurt you,
but you are not gonna be the
downfall of my family.
Those men, they're
not just anybody.
Andre,
well let's just say his family
are considered
royalty in France.
Roma, he's a bit shadier.
He protects people like Andre,
he protects them
from regular people
like you.
When people like you
meddle with people like him,
all sorts of horrible
things happen to them.
They fall down elevator shafts.
They're shot by
some crazed gunman.
Many commit suicide.
See, what you are doing, Mariam,
is you are committing suicide.
And then, who knows,
your daughter might
fall into the wrong hands.
Please.
Take the night off.
Wow. Wow, wow, wow.
God, I'm loving this case.
I'm loving it!
Aw. You dropped the cakes.
How much did you hear?
Only the part about us
being psychopathic pedophiles.
Mm, these are good.
You know she's lying, right?
I suspect so.
Andre is a very decent guy.
We are decent people.
Were you abused by your father?
Excuse me?
Sorry- were you
abused by your father?
That's a bit crass!
Of course I wasn't.
And neither was Liz!
My father loved us.
It depends what you call love.
Holloway, can I have a word?
What the fuck do you think
you're doing?
What? I'm hungry.
I haven't had any breakfast.
Is this a joke to you?
Little word of advice.
Don't get too emotionally
attached, it's only gonna
cloud your judgement.
You could be a wee
bit more delicate.
Do you think a bloodhound
lets its feelings
get in the way of its nose?
No.
You're no bloodhound,
and you're acting like a prick.
The parents are
the victims as well.
There's only one victim
here and she's missing.
No!
What's happened?
Turn the telly on.
We're live in Claygate
where police have
discovered a body.
Chief Superintendent Hanson
is making a statement
now. We'll pass you over.
One of the search and rescue
teams found a body
in the wooded
area of Claygate.
We've sent our forensic team
and pathologist
to try and identify the body.
However it is yet to be
confirmed whether
it's the missing girl
Olivia Truman or not.
Chief.
Is it her?
Probably. Are you
with the Trumans?
Yep.
Try and keep them away
from the press.
They're not going anywhere.
I've spoken to the nanny.
And?
She's claiming
it was the parents.
Pretty fucking convincingly too.
Any evidence?
No, not yet.
Right, then do me
a favour. Back off.
You're great at finding people
but this is national.
All eyes are on us.
The parents are the victims.
Yeah, well there's a
kooky little demographic
in this country that
agree with me
and think they're
suspect as fuck.
I'm not gonna have my people
come under fire
for harassing the victims.
Babysit the parents
but do not pursue
any line of questioning
with them. Clear?
Crystal.
Fuck.
I just found these upstairs.
Oxycodone, whose are they?
Mine. I've got sciatica.
Damon, you're a chemist -
I'm in pharmaceutical sales.
Same thing.
What's the side effects
on a drug like that?
There's many.
Let's say on a child.
Drowsiness. Sleepiness.
Death?
In some rare cases.
Holloway, the body
hasn't been identified yet.
Oh, that's right! 'Cause
she's still out there, eh?
'Cause Romanian traffickers
came into your house,
in the middle of a party, and
took her from under your noses.
Bloody immigrants,
first they're taking our jobs
and now they're
taking our children.
Is this funny to you?
I can assure you it's not.
I'd like you to leave my house.
You know, it's almost like
you don't want us to find her.
Let's hope you
never have to pull
your daughter out of the ground.
We should leave.
I'm telling you, they did it.
You've lost your mind.
Clearly.
You know, this is
what happens
when you let a psychopath
gaslight you.
So, you agree. He's a cunt.
I was talking about Mariam.
I saw it in his eyes.
Do you know what a young
British girl with blonde hair
and blue eyes is worth
to human traffickers?
Take a guess.
I dunno, a million rubles?
A hundred grand.
They use nannies like
Mariam to research their hosts
for months and months waiting
for the right time to strike.
And what better time
than the night of a big party?
A night when dozens
of people will be suspects.
Olivia just happened
to go missing
on this night of all nights.
What you're seeing in his
eyes is anger, Danny.
Anger that any man would feel
for losing a child. Even you.
Fucking hell.
I gotta answer this.
You all right, babe?
Not really.
Look, sorry about earlier.
I know I've not been around
much, it's just this case.
Yeah, look, it's not what
I called about.
I had an odd phone call.
Go on.
Some bloke asked
"how's your daughter?"
What?
Yeah.
Carly, where's Lucy?
She's at school.
Do me a favour.
Go and get her from school.
Take her straight to your mum's.
Should I be worried?
No, there's nothing
to worry about.
Listen Carly, go upstairs,
right hand side of the wardrobe,
top shelf,
there's a little
case in the corner.
The key to that case
is on the little elephant,
my side of the bed.
Don't freak out but
there's a gun in there.
Jesus, Dan!
Listen, it's just a precaution.
I'm sure it's someone just
playing silly buggers.
Can't you come home?
Go and get her. Okay?
I'll get back to you
as soon as I can.
Yeah, got it!
What?
Rob's called, Liz is back.
Right.
Here, get that down you.
Come on.
That's it. There we go.
Can we ask you a
few questions, please?
This isn't the best time, is it?
Oi! Wakey wakey.
Roma's phone. Where is it?
Rob, who are they?
We're your ghosts of Christmas
past, love. Time to wake up.
Do you have Roma's phone?
Liz?
Liz, there's probably
nothing on that phone.
And it's possible Mariam
just sent you
on a wild goose chase but
we need to verify it.
To clear your sister's
name and also
start the process of extraditing
Mariam back from Romania.
But what if -
but what if there
is something on it?
Well, is there?
It was locked.
I can unlock it.
Yeah, I can just plug it into
my laptop, run some software.
There's Gecko, Redsnow.
You're a bit of a geek, yeah,
kinda got that. Well.
You get the phone, you
grab your laptop. Chop, chop.
Don't you have your own
people to do this sort of thing.
Yeah, well, you've offered now.
I just wanna make sure
I'm not breaking any laws.
As far as you're concerned,
I am the fucking law.
Then you'll know
all about privacy
and investigatory powers then,
won't you.
Just unlock the phone.
Okay.
Hanson.
Yes, sir?
At Rob Tyler's flat, sir.
They asked us to leave.
Why, what's happened?
Is it her, sir?
Right. Okay, keep me posted.
He wants us back
at the Truman's.
He's gonna meet us there.
I'm not leaving this here.
Pack it up. You're
coming with us.
What's happened?
Police have confirmed
that the body is that
of a young girl between
the age of ten and fifteen.
But they're reluctant to say
if it's Olivia Truman
until it's been identified by
the pathologist and the parents.
It's not been confirmed yet.
How many dead children
do you know that are
in those woods?
How long's this gonna take?
I dunno. It's a
fingerprint lock
which makes it a little
more complicated.
I thought you were an expert.
I work in IT, not GCHQ.
Yeah, well you've
got ten minutes.
I'll do my best.
Ten minutes or I'll arrest you
for withholding information.
And what information
is that exactly?
The information on that phone.
Such a dick.
Liz.
Mariam told us you were
abused by your father.
Is it true?
Danny, I don't think
now's the time!
Am I not being delicate enough?
Listen to me, Liz,
I like you. You're honest.
You know, apart from
banging that slick Frenchman
in the toilet behind your
boyfriends back of course.
But I know why you did that.
It was to get that phone.
Because you've got integrity.
See, Liz, despite all your
flaws, you're a good person.
Now, I need to know
whether your father
molested you or not,
which will bring me straight
onto my next question -
how the fuck would
Mariam know that?
I was asking the same
fucking question.
Hey.
Enjoying yourself, I see.
It is a party, mommy.
You know, Olivia has your hair.
Claire.
Yes?
You haven't told anyone about
what happened to us, have you?
About what?
You don't speak...
about our past?
What past?
Dad.
What about him?
You know, his ways.
What ways?
Look, I know we've
never talked about it.
Talked about what?
Claire... he abused us.
What?
You're my sister,
you don't have to lie to me.
I think those therapists have
been messing with your head.
Don't. Don't. Don't.
Don't do that-
Do what?
Make out that I'm -
that I'm crazy.
Tell me.
You can... tell me anything.
Connect with me.
I need to get this
cake to Damon.
Do you think he'll like it?
It's not something
I wanted to discuss.
Especially not at my
husbands birthday party.
So it did happen?
That's none of your
fucking business!
Who removed the red ribbon
for Andre?
Was it you or Damon?
You know,
I'm thinking it was you.
Thirty percent
of all abuse victims
become abusers themselves.
Or they end up with one.
You piece of shit!
Whoa! Easy Tiger!
You're lucky I don't kill you.
Well I wouldn't be
your first, would I?
I want you out of my house.
I'm not going anywhere.
Get out of my house!
Admit what you did!
You drugged Olivia.
What are you doing?
She was thirsty.
Then she slipped into a coma.
She didn't wake up.
Then she died.
Then you called your little pal,
Roma, to help you
get rid of the body.
You even opened a window to
make it look like a kidnapping.
And then they buried her
in the woods.
Go on, admit it.
Set your soul free...
if you've got one.
I'm not speaking
with you anymore.
From now on,
you can talk to my lawyer.
Danny, stop it.
Hello, sir?
Are they sure?
I'll let them know.
It's not Olivia.
What?
It's not her.
Are they sure?
The pathologist confirmed it.
You seem almost disappointed.
So it wasn't Olivia?
Is that not done yet?
It's not far off.
Do you really think Claire
and Damon did all that?
I mean, I actually think they're
the most boring couple I know.
Shut up.
Danny!
What? What's the matter?
Where've you been?
I've been ringing you!
What is it?
Danny.
It's Lucy.
Where is she?
I don't know.
What do you mean you don't know?
She wasn't at school.
The teachers thought
that we'd given her a day off.
I don't understand.
Carly, where is she?
I don't know, Danny,
she's missing!
Danny, I'm scared.
I'll call you back.
Danny-
What?
They found the
girl's ID with her.
Right?
Hanson wants you
to go down there.
Why does he want me to go?
Danny.
Costa, what is it?
They think it's Lucy.
He protects people like Andre.
When people like you
meddle with people like him,
all sorts of horrible
things happen to them.
Who knows, your daughter
might fall into the wrong hands.
Let's hope you never have to
pull your daughter
out of the ground.
Meeting in London
with Slaughter and May,
Leila, have the contract
ready for my departure.
That should be Hanson.
I'll get it.
That's it.
What did you expect?
Is that the phone?
Aye.
And there's nothing on it?
Just some legal stuff.
Nothing with Damon.
Jesus Christ! How could
he get it so wrong?
I don't know. He's been
making jokes all day.
It's all a joke until
it happens to you.
Well, the good news is Olivia
may still be out there. Alive.
We're extraditing
the nanny right now.
Her ex-husband is associated
with known Romanian gangsters,
drug smugglers and even
people traffickers.
He probably helped her
set the whole thing up.
This is a French ambassador.
Damon is friends
with his lawyer.
The sister is unstable.
She was probably abused
as a child. We can use this.
How do you know she was abused?
I know from personal experience.
Well, you are going
to be the first person
that the police will suspect.
So you must
create a story to turn
their attention
onto the parents.
Plant the story like a
seed and watch it grow.
The whole world will believe
that the parents did this.
Take this.
It will help you sleep.
Go in when you are ready.
Is she asleep?
Yes.
It's a billion pound industry.
We're at war.
I tried to tell Holloway
but he just wouldn't listen.
You did your best. I'll be sure
to put you forward for DCI.
Thank you, sir.
You deserve it.
Hi.
How's my baby boy?
Yeah... I'll be home soon.
I know.
I just didn't think
they would go this far.
So, you're saying that your
daughter was killed
to stop you from
investigating this case?
That's exactly what I'm saying.
Surely, that would only
put more pressure
on the criminals, wouldn't it?
Not if they were trying
to send a message.
A message to whom?
Everyone. Every detective,
every judge. Everyone.
And what's the message?
Not to meddle
with powerful people.
But I sent them my own message.
And what message was that?
So, after everything
that's happened,
are there any any new suspects?
There's a few, yes.
The police have widened
their search to Eastern Europe.
So the police believe that
she's part of a
child trafficking ring?
They believe so.
Then it's likely
she's still alive.
Yes, it's the only good thing
to come out of all of this.
Of course. It must be
a relief knowing that.
Knowing that she's
out there gives us hope.
Do you believe
that you'll still find her?
I believe we will, yes.
I have to.
Damon?
I think as long as we can
continue our search globally,
then... yes, we'll find her.
One day.
We'd like to thank
the public... for all the
support they've shown
us over the last few weeks.
And how can others
show their support?
We have a company now
set up, The Olivia Foundation.
You can find us at
theoliviafoundation.com
and donate through there.
Any help you can give
will help us keep the search
active because... the police
can only do so much.
And if Olivia was listening now,
what would you say to her?
Stay strong, darling.
We will bring you home.
Damon?
Just -
I love you.
Keep that pointed at me!
I'm gonna tell
you a little story.
See, I'm no better
than the Trumans.
I cared more about my progress
than I did my own child.
But not any more.
The Romanians didn't do this.
There's a very powerful
network of people
buying children straight
from their parents
and I'm coming for all of them.
And that includes you, Costa.
Okay, that's enough, cut there.
Provided by explosiveskull
https://twitter.com/kaboomskull