Executive Producers: Ryuzo Shirakawa,
Akira Sato, Mitsuhisa Ishikawa
Planning and Original Concept:
Production I. G
Planning in Cooperation
with Mamoru Oshii (Team Oshii)
Character Designer: Katsuya Terada
Screenplay: Kenji Kamiyama
Technical Director: Shinji Takagi
Please take all your
belongings with you.
This will be the last train
going to Asakusa.
Animation Director: Kazuchika Kise
Art Director: Yusuke Takeda
Director of Visual Concept:
Hisashi Ezura
Color Designer: Katsue Inoue
3D CGl: Tokumitsu Kifune
Filming: Miki Sakuma
Post Production Supervisor:
Keiichi Momose
Music: Yoshihiro Ike
We will be stopping at Asakusa shortly.
This will be the final stop.
Director: Hiroyuki Kitakubo
So the tap was still running
when you found her.
Calm down.
You don't have to cry.
l'm not too sure, but l heard Mari
was going out with an American soldier.
Mari from Charade's
committed suicide.
Stupid girl.
She didn't have to kill herself.
Maybe she's got the "clap."
You can't get upset over
a minor thing
if you're doing business
with American soldiers.
Did you hear about the suicide
at the base school last month?
There seem to be
a lot of them lately.
Apparently, everybody's really
uptight about it.
How terrible.
l hope this doesn't affect business.
It can't be helped if we're going
to make a living off the base.
Huh?
It can't be helped if we're going
to make a living off the base.
Aren't you Japanese?
You are not a student here, are you?
Did you pass through the office?
Hey, hold on a second!
Where is the principal's office?
Huh?
So, this is their "dining room"then.
Oh, you scared me.
What were you doing here?
Nothing. L thought l had a headache.
But it"s gone now.
Oh. Wait!
Hold on a minute!
You...
Hey!
Listen to me!
Listen, just forget what you just saw.
Why... What is this...
You are...
Linda wasn"t feeling well.
She was just sleeping...
Linda...
What? What is this?
Hey, Mama-san, where"s my beer?
Oh, l"m sorry.
Excuse me. L"ll be right back.
What are you doing?
Run for it!
Run!
Go inside.
What did you just do?
What are you trying to do here?
Shut up!
Listen! Anyone who is
marked by "them" or
anyone who has seen "their" real form,
isn"t allowed to live.
So, we"ve got to kill "them"
before "they" get us.
What are "they"?
Demons. They live off human blood.
Shit! Isn"t there something?
Like what?
A weapon.
Here...
That won"t kill them.
They won"t die
unless they lose enough blood
in one blow.
Then what is this gun for?
You may need it.
You can kill yourself as a last resort.
Don"t!
Why me?
Who are you?
Why did you help me?
You"re lucky. L can"t kill "humans."
Shut up!
Wait! Don"t shoot!
l can"t take this anymore.
Don"t give up!
Get the car!
Run the doors down!
After all,
l never understood what l saw.
That girl Saya and the creatures
she killed all remained a mystery.
Only two students were noted
as having left for other schools.
Could she still be somewhere
around the base?
Is she still fighting those creatures?
Just as we humans continue
to kill each other.
That beautiful,
yet dangerous living thing