Hey, catch the ball.
That's like it!
Hey, Ranjith!
Can you see the relay?
Are you able to watch?
Moron, I have to take a shower.
Bloody mug-face!
Stop yelling continuously.
-Sister, please bear with me.-Don't' shake the antenna.
Hey, Aathur woman.
My boy has been begging to you.
What's the hurry?
Why can't you take a shower later?
Hey, old hag. Let Susila akka come...
-I'll tell her about this.-Hold it right there.
-Susila is not a Queen of England.
-Granny...
-I can handle her.
-...please stay calm!
Calling me an old hag!
As if you are young lady...
-...and we're holding your youth.-Granny, calm down.
Make the run.
Hey, hold the antenna!
-Some sons I have, I say.-Hey, hold it right there!
Laying all day in the house is useless,
with no jobs.
Get down from the roof!
Bloody! You would've hurt yourself.
Always watching TV.
-Hey!-Stop chiding only me.
-You don't question the eldest.
-Get lost!
Ma, how many times should I ask you
to get cable TV?
Of course, you see money is raining.
Children of God should not watch TV.
I don't have fifty rupees per month
to waste on cable TV.
Ma, it's best you get cable TV.
I can't be holding the antenna
on the roof.
I don't care about it.
I'm not the help in this house.
Hey, you too watch the match.
Hey, you'd know if you climb the roof.
-Eh?
-You don't even tell me the score.
The roof can't bear my weight.
As if you're Mike Tyson!
Why can't you get cable for the house?
I will bear the charges
from my pension money.
Listen, I've told you many times.
Don't you dare interfere
when I'm disciplining them?
They never touch the books.
Whether it's inside or outside the house...
All they care is about cricket.
I keep tearing them down,
and you keep putting up posters.
I will continue to tear them down.
One day, I will break the bat
and use it as firewood.
This is a challenge from Children of God.
[sings "Unnai Paartha" - Kadhal Mannan]
-Amma!-What is it?
Please come over here.
What is it?
I think it's going to rain.
Ask Kamatachi to bring down
the clothes from the terrace.
Kamatchi!
It's going to rain.
Go and bring down the clothes.
Get lost!
Hey, Kavitha, please come with me.
Yours Truly,
Sachin Rajesh
Kamatchi, did you see my Maths notebook?
It's surprising to see you look for books.
You see...
Tomorrow the teacher won't be
coming to the class.
So, he asked me
to teach the class tomorrow.
I have to prepare for it.
My brother is a Maths genius!
Oh!
He's very fluent with "Two" tables.
Rajesh, why don't you teach Kavitha too?
Poor thing does not know anything.
I'll have my revenge when you get caught
with your boyfriend.
My brother is not good at Maths.
But he's an amazing at cricket.
He just not plays the sport.
He plays it to win!
He'd do anything to win.
He's a cricket fanatic!
But yeah... he's a little crazy!
Is the bus late today?
Brother, drop me at the SR gate.
They don't seem to get caught.
-Machi, that girl is checking you out.
-I'm checking her out too.
♪ Step aside, my dear ♪
♪ If brushed against,
Fire will catch on ♪
♪ Taking the opportunity ♪
♪ We boys want to show off
With swag! ♪
♪ Arakkonam ♪
♪ We are Arakkonam folks ♪
♪ The sassy folks you see at the market
Are my people ♪
♪ Welcome, my Chief
Take a seat ♪
♪ We gonna throw the ball
Strike it ♪
♪ Show your might ♪
♪ If someone troubles
Give them back ♪
♪ In the Panchayat meeting ♪
♪ Show them your brawn ♪
♪ Show them who you are
They cannot ignore you ♪
Hey, stop the car.
We must clear this ground and level it.
The former owner has been
fooling people...
into thinking the land belongs
to the temple.
We should keep up the charade!
Do you see the bullock cart?
-From that point till here.
-Fine, work up the deal.
♪ Cross your legs and sit
You belong to the clan of Ravana ♪
♪ It is time you rise
Do it right away ♪
♪ We are gonna stand on the roof
With the trophy that we win ♪
♪ Let us dance to the music ♪
♪ Cross your legs and sit
You belong to the clan of Ravana ♪
♪ It is time you rise
Do it right away ♪
♪ We are gonna stand on the roof
With the trophy that we win ♪
♪ Let us dance to the music ♪
It's okay you continue.
I'll wait for you.
Tomorrow I need to come early.
-What time will she come out?
-It's time!
-What's your name?
-Thaenmozhi!
-Your name?
-Anandhi!
-Where do you live?
-Perumbachai!
Do you know Ranjith?
I know him!
That Anna is an amazing guy.
Whenever he rides the bus,
we have fun!
Give my regards to Ranjith.
Okay!
Machi... Hmm....
♪ Step aside ♪
♪ Step aside I say ♪
-Here, take it.
-Ma, this is atrocious!
♪ We are the mighty ones
Don't you challenge Blue Star ♪
♪ Come on. Throw the ball ♪
♪ You shouldn't indulge ♪
♪ We'll skin you upside down
Off you go ♪
-Hurry up!
-Anna, 100 grams for me.
-Hey, we'll go inside and eat.
-Hey, hide it well.
♪ Where's Arakkonam?
Right here! ♪
♪ Come on! ♪
♪ Where's Arakkonam?
Right here! ♪
♪ Oh, no! ♪
♪ Where's Arakkonam? ♪
-Hey!
Get lost!
♪ Issa railway gate-u ♪
♪ Issa dangerous route-u ♪
♪ Create a scene ♪
♪ This is Blue Star bat-u ♪
♪ Hey, train to Madras
We're important people ♪
♪ If we pick head,
We get tail ♪
♪ This is Arakkonam style-u ♪
Hey!
♪ Cross your legs and sit
You belong to the clan of Ravana ♪
♪ It is time you rise
Do it right away ♪
♪ We are gonna stand on the roof
With the trophy that we win ♪
♪ Let us dance to the music ♪
♪ Cross your legs and sit
You belong to the clan of Ravana ♪
♪ It is time you rise
Do it right away ♪
♪ We are gonna stand on the roof
With the trophy that we win ♪
♪ Let us dance to the music ♪
Hey, Paruthi, I told you to bowl offside.
You never pay heed to me.
I get you.
But I don't know to bowl offside.
Hey, what's wrong with you guys?
Come here, now!
Vivaan!
Your body alignment is off!
Your body alignment should be
in line with your leg.
Are you cow herders?
Don't you have any sense?
This is last warning!
Bowl well.
If you continue to play this way...
Under 16 district level...
No!
That was a super ball!
You bowl well!
-Are you a cow herder?
-No, sir.
I'll throw you out!
Understand?
Don't you have any sense?
If you continue to bowl this way...
I will throw you out!
Got that!
Son, come over here.
Your body alignment is not
the issue; you bowled a wide.
It's in the right posture.
When you release the ball
your bowling arm is wavering.
How do I fix it?
Your bowling arm is natural.
So don't worry about it.
How do we use the non-bowling arm?
To aim!
If you sharply aim the stumps...
When you release the ball,
your non-bowling arm should follow
the bowling arm.
Like this!
Okay?
Understood?
-That was a super ball!
-You bowl well!
Hey!
Hey, I've been waiting for you.
-Give it to me.
-Let go!
What happened?
You completely ignored me!
Like you didn't notice me at the station.
Hey, I was discussing the match
with the boys.
So I didn't realize it.
Why don't you talk to me
about cricket?
It's not like I don't watch cricket.
Since childhood I've been watching cricket.
Is it?
Out!
Fine, tell me,
who's your favourite player?
I like Chris Gaines.
So, you do watch cricket!
Why do you sound surprised
at anything I say?
Is cricket reserved only for boys
to watch and play?
-I did not mean it that way.
-Please explain then!
You'd know a woman's prowess
if you let us play cricket.
Why do you like Chris Gaines?
More than a batsman and a bowler...
I like the all-rounder the best!
You don't say!
I'm an all-rounder, too, Anandhi!
That's why I like you a lot!
Hey!
What?
You called me a...
Don't speak like this in front
of my Amma.
Listen, I can't watch my mouth.
I speak my heart.
And I have no regrets.
My dear, it's your mouth and your wish.
You speak your heart!
But my Amma is way above you.
Hell's going to break loose.
Have you ever watched me play?
I have seen you play.
You run fast after hitting the ball
like Michael Bevan.
Hey!
It's fun to watch!
Tell me something.
Why do you like to be a keeper?
A keeper has a clear view of the ground.
When a new batsman arrives
and taps the bat on the ground...
I can judge in which direction
he's going to bat.
Based on that I'll change the fielding
and bowling line up.
That's why I like to be the wicket keeper.
It's fun!
I'll inform when I play at Welfare School.
Would you like to come and watch?
As if I'd get permission.
Even if you play for Indian team...
I can only watch you play on the TV.
You're going to play at the
playground in the next town.
I won't get a chance to watch.
Listen, Ranjith...
do you wish to play for Indian team?
I have better business to tend to.
I want to play for our town.
-It's a long story.
-What? Tell me.
Every week on Sunday my mother
will take me to the church.
But my heart will only yearn to
play cricket at the playground.
Every year, during the temple carnival,
they organize a cricket tournament.
In that tournament, our team Blue Star...
versus town's team Alpha
is a huge match to look for.
Are you folks ready?
Please chant with me!
Because this match is considered
equal to the India-Pakistan match.
It will be sensational!
The match fell on a Sunday.
Hey, look to the front.
And I was stuck in the church.
And I was a substitute in the match.
When they asked everyone
to close their eyes to pray...
"Hey, Ranjith, now is the time."
"Get up and run."
And I ran to the playground.
Hey!
My brother, too, followed me.
If you ask me cricket or Jesus?
I pray to Jesus that Blue Star team
should win the match.
On that day the ground was
swarming with people.
The Alpha Boys who always feel
they're above us...
When it comes to cricket...
every time they taste defeat.
The main reason for it is Emmanuel Anna.
The reason why I am crazy about cricket...
I would say
it's because of Emmanuel Anna.
Not just me...
But boys from neighboring towns
and cities...
love the game of Emmanuel Anna.
He's our Kapil Dev,
Vivian Richards and everything.
His game is fantastic!
The wickets were raining down.
Kaali Anna was hurt on that day.
As I was a substitute
they sent me in to play.
At first, I was very nervous.
I could not play.
Emmanuel Anna came to me...
He asked me not to fear.
He asked me to play stroke
and he'll handle the rest.
His words of wisdom gave me courage.
And I started to play.
I was running to score a run...
I got run out.
I was full of tears.
But he never complained.
Instead he came and appreciated my game...
and gave me a pat on my shoulder.
Awesome!
Gopalan was anxious
that Emmanuel would win again.
He wanted to win this match
at any cost.
Last two balls
and we need six runs to win.
And it's the last wicket.
The bowler bowled the ball.
Emmanuel Anna played an amazing shot.
The ball was flying high in the air.
Everyone is looking at the ball.
Vinayagam fielded in straight
and caught the ball.
But he stepped on the boundary
while he caught the ball.
All of us saw him step on the boundary.
He too knew it.
-Out! Out!-But he swore he did not step on it.
The entire crowd is saying it's Out.
But our team said it's a six!
The umpire was clueless.
If the umpire says it's Out,
the colony folks will fight.
And if he gives it a six,
the village folks will fight.
But the umpire went neutral...
and declared it dead ball.
Emmanuel Anna said he'll handle it
and stood in the ground.
But the Gopalan...
knew it's impossible to win
with Emmanuel
and instigated a fight.
He instigated a fight
and asked to beat them up.
And people from the other side
came running to fight.
On seeing it, our folks,
too, started to run.
A huge fight broke out.
The village and the colony folks
fought each other.
In this riot,
Mani hacked Emmanuel Anna's leg.
Don't spare anyone.
Beat them all.
Since that incident the two teams
were banned...
to play against each other.
A written order was issued by the Police.
After that, there was no cricket
tournament during the Temple carnival.
Even if we play cricket on that ground,
it'll be at different times.
The team that first places the stone
on the ground can play.
It does not matter who.
At present,
I'm the Captain of the Blue Star team.
Rajesh is the captain of Alpha Boys.
Rajesh is a good player.
But he is quite weird.
Alpha Boys claim to be
the best players in town.
I want to defeat them.
We do play with other teams.
Until now we both never played
against each other.
I'm waiting for that day.
I'm not getting a chance.
I'm waiting for the right chance.
No matter where a match
is organized
they won't even prepare a chart
that involves us.
They claim as far as Emmanuel Anna leg
was fine Blue Star won...
And they mock us everywhere we go.
The match where they hacked
Emmanuel Anna's leg...
I want to play against them
in a Temple carnival's match...
And make them realize hacking
Emmanuel Anna's leg was wrong...
Also, prove them Blue Star is still
a winning team...
...as a captain!
I want to show them we're
the best team in Arakkonam.
That's enough for me.
Wait! When shall I teach you cricket?
Yeah, right! My folks won't approve.
It's not going to happen.
Shut up and leave!
-Hey!-Too much you are.
Hey, Anandhi!
Ma!
-Ma!
-What is it?
Why did he take my shirt?
-Oh, God!
-Does he not have a shirt?
I neatly wash and press my clothes.
And he wears them after my hard work.
Hey, he's younger to you but keeps
his clothes washed and pressed.
You don't seem to change.
Hey, it's your brother.
Let him use it.
He has two pairs of hands and legs.
-Too much!
-Step aside.
One day I'll get you.
It's a never-ending fight for clothes
between you two.
As if anything good comes out of it.
If I see you both near the playground,
there is no food for you guys.
Stop nagging the boys all the time.
They never pray to the Lord.
Only then will they be blessed with a
career in medicine or become a collector.
No one in this house fear the God.
How often should I ask you to
get me a pot of water?
You don't seem to move.
Damn!
It's best you stick to
what I asked you of.
If I find out you were gawking
at women...
-As if you'd spare me.
-Appa, get one for me too.
All of you pile on chores for me.
Some children I have.
Susila!
Why did he come here?
Even a day late,
they send men home for collection.
Do I have to remind you?
My, Mama, sent for as you did not
pay last month's interest.
I missed my payment this month.
I'll pay you next month without fail.
You have an excuse every month.
You know to borrow money
but don't pay on time.
I'm facing a crunch this month.
I'll pay you next month.
I'll be back tomorrow.
It's best you pay up.
I will pay up!
Why are you glaring?
Ma, why did you borrow from him?
In this area, no one else
is ready to lend money.
Ma, how much did you borrow?
It's mere one thousand rupees.
I consolidated the previous petty loans
and borrowed from him.
But you see...
Ma!
Month end the scholarship money
will be credited.
Pay him with that money.
Hey, I have to pay donation to church
with the scholarship money.
Stop glaring and go take a bath.
The water is getting cold.
What happened?
Why do you have a long face?
I have mentioned earlier...
about Rajesh!
I think my mother took a loan from him.
He came home....
and called my mother by her name.
He is as old as me.
How much do you owe him?
I will give you my chain.
You just replace it with a fake one.
I'll manage.
Thank you for asking though.
Why can't you keep smiling?
But you keep a sour face like Dravid.
Hey, don't you have any sense?
Why are you being close with him?
Is this why you deck up in the morning
to meet him?
Aren't you ashamed?
Why are you yelling at me?
I know how to carry myself.
You shut up!
-Ranjith, look.
-I'm talking to you!
Hey, Anandhi, you better listen to me.
Stop! Shall I tell your parents?
Go ahead! I'll handle it.
-I'm talking to you...
-Hey, what's your problem?
Hey, I'm speaking to my cousin.
What's to you?
-Get lost!
-How dare you push me?
Pipe down!
Hey, get lost!
You made a mistake by hitting me.
Stay right here! I'll mess you up!
Hey, get lost!
Anandhi, come on, let's go.
You go ahead. I'll follow.
Hey, how come they're playing?
I have no idea.
Why the hell are they playing?
Did you place the stone last night?
Hey, Ravi!
I did place the stone.
What do they think of themselves?
My uncle renovated this playground.
-Hey!
-Looks like they're planning a meeting.
Why are you people playing now?
What's the matter?
They placed the stone first
and claim to play first.
Hey, who threw away the stone?
We placed it first!
You, people, threw it away
and kept your stone.
-Hey, don't point fingers.
-What else do you want me to point?
What the hell?
Can't you see we're talking?
You too talk!
Don't act too smart!
I'll break your jaw!
Hey, don't you understand?
We placed the stone first.
It's best you guys pack up and leave.
-Before I lose it.
-Hey!
-Didn't we place the stone first?
-Yes we did!
Let them wait.
You threw away our stone...
You must've done it on purpose.
Fine, let's come to an agreement.
Let flip a coin and decide.
Let's play three balls each team.
Whoever scores high...
they'll get play first on the ground.
-You have a point.
-Okay?
Rajesh, don't agree.
Hey, they're talking nonsense.
Hey! They're scared!
Look at them chicken out.
-Hey!
-Look at their faces!
Hey! Hey! Hey! Calm down!
Calm down!
Obviously, they'll be scared.
-Poor thing!
-Hey, who said we're scared!
Flip the coin!
Tails!
Heads! We choose batting.
Bring it on!
Hey, get lost!
Hey, give me the bat!
I said give me the bat.
Don't spare them.
-This is our chance to beat them.
-I'm going to ram them!
I'll show them the prowess of Alpha boys!
Hey, bring me the bat!
Hey, we'll handle them.
Awesome Anna.
Let's play.
Here you go, Sam.
Come on, Sam!
Come on! Come on, bowl!
Come on, bowl, Sam.
Bowl!
Damn!
Hey, catch it.
Super! Super, Rajesh! Well played.
Hey!
-Get lost!
-We'll get him in the next ball.
Sam, don't get worked up.
Calmly bowl.
We'll get them!
Sam, that's good bowling!
Good bowling! Sam! Sam!
Machan, catch the ball.
Damn!
Get lost!
Yeah!
Machi, don't worry.
We'll make it.
Yeah!
8 runs in 3 balls.
How do we make it?
Susila!
We have to make it.
If not, it'll be embarrassing.
The match is not over yet.
Come on, Ranjith!
Nail it brother!
Come on, Ranjith.
You can do it!
Come on, Ranjith!
Don't spare them!
Hereafter, we'll be the first ones
to play on this ground.
Come on, Rajesh!
Come on! To this side.
To this side.
That's about it. Perfect!
Come on, Ranjith! Come on, Ranjith!
Come on!
Come on! You can do it.
Don't worry.
-Oh, no!
-There goes your chance.
Get out of the ground!
Rajesh that was amazing.
Guys eat dust!
Current, the bat is broken.
What would they do now?
They're done for good!
Hey, German!
-Hey, where's he going?
-We're doomed!
I pity them!
-What is he doing?
-I don't know.
-Look at him.
-Did he get him a stump?
What the hell is he doing?
Come on, Ranjith!
Ranjith, Anna, don't spare them.
Come on! Come on, Rajesh!
Machan, bowl hard!
Hey, Current, don't lose the catch.
Damn!
Now, do you realize which team
is incredible?
Aren't you ashamed to be proud
over a three ball match?
You could not even win a three ball match!
I dare you to play another match!
If we defeat you here...
the people won't know
about our achievements.
Shall we play a match
during this temple carnival?
Are you ready?
Until there's a competition,
everyone is best in their own eyes.
Instead of locking horns in vain.
Let's play a match,
and we'll know who's the best.
What do you say Ravi?
Sure let's play!
Do you think the people will agree
to a match during the carnival?
That too between these two teams!
Hey, I'll speak to my Mama.
We have to play a match
during the carnival.
I will defeat them!
I will defeat them in front of the people.
This is to inform the people
of the village...
Tomorrow in our village
there will be a panchayat meeting.
All the men, women, elders, and youngsters
are requested to participate...
and grace the meeting with your presence!
Ranjith, we should somehow play
a match against them.
Hey, Emman Anna is coming.
Let me talk to him.
Hey, Ranjith!
-Huh!
-I heard you came looking for me.
What's the matter?
Anna, after your last match...
there was no tournament conducted
on this ground.
You should convince the elders
to organize a match.
Please Anna!
During this carnival,
we have to organize a match.
The old case is still unsolved.
Despite graduates,
they're not able to find a job.
They're affluent.
Why do we have to poke the bear?
During that incident
we should've ended it good.
We missed it!
-A cricket match is crucial!
-He is right!
Our boys are at each other's throats
as there's no opportunity to play.
The problem that originated during
a match should end with a game.
Sports bring discipline.
Understood?
This carnival there should be
a cricket match.
Yes, there should be a match!
Are you not happy
that the village is at peace?
Hey, calm down!
It's not like only a match
will cause fights.
Like Emmanuel mentioned
sports brings discipline.
Also the boys will keep order.
Many have landed a job
because of sports.
Listen sports is important.
Fine, do as you wish.
Hey, that's awesome!
As far as there's unity
it's good for the village.
I hope you don't lose to them.
Sister, donate as much as you can.
It's for the God. Please donate.
Listen Gopal...
you should handle everything this time.
No matter the cost I'll bear it all
for the deity's ritual.
-Go ahead tell him.
-This time, there's folk dance...
a band,
-And cricket...
-What?
My nephew did mention about it.
-On the temple's ground?
-Yes!
Is it imperative to organize a match?
Yes, Mama!
We need to play against them.
Didn't you renovate the ground
for the boys to play?
-Inspector is your man.
-So?
Request him to provide security.
Fine, you people carry on!
-I'll discuss and get back.
-Sure!
Look at him glare at us.
We'll handle him during the match.
Hey, will you pass the exam this year?
You don't go to coaching class.
But you're punctual as a Romeo.
-Anna, one ink pen.
-Sure!
Anna, this is the twenty bucks
I owe you from before.
-Thank you, Anna.
-I don't want it.
Let's go!
Hey, what are you doing?
Anna, don't touch this currency.
I will go home and bring another currency.
-Hey!
-I promise!
-You can keep my watch.
-I understand.
I see you daily. I understand.
You can keep it.
You can pay me tomorrow.
"The moment when your fingers
touched this lifeless twenty bucks."
"The twenty bucks would double up
with joy."
"But I am alive, and when will you
grace me with your touch."
We've seen them play with other teams.
We should not underestimate them.
All of the them are good players.
They call themselves a cricket team.
Ranjith!
Sam!
And Bharath!
If we get their wickets,
we're good.
Rajesh!
Venkatesh!
And then Current Kunji!
A match after years of gap.
Let's not worry and play with grit!
Weren't you waiting for this day?
Stop showing your teeth!
I'm talking about something else.
Ranjith...
You and your team have a weakness.
What is it?
Your fielding is off.
Fielding is off?
Care to explain?
When a fielder throws the ball
to the stumps
another fielder does not cover him.
-Throw here.
-You're giving away an overthrow.
And to catch the ball only one is running.
Only if two run to the ball
one can get it and throw.
But during a wicket
everyone run to the ball.
And lose the catch.
During that time if one says "leave it."
The others should move away.
I may not be right.
Cricket is not going to put
food on the table.
It will!
If you play well, it will.
He will get a job at ICF.
I will make the application.
Wait and watch the appointment letter
will come home.
When the coal dispenser's son
gets appointed as a Railway officer,
it brings pride.
Yeah right. That too in this village.
Pride is in abundance.
You speak about pride in vain.
You pride will be pissed on.
It'll be embarrassing to lose to them.
Where are you throwing the ball?
Throw to the stumps.
-Hey!
-Hey, that's it!
Hey, look at him.
Bowl!
That's a doughnut, my friend.
It's a delicious treat to eat.
What the hell are you doing?
Can't you follow the ball?
If you're not interested
don't come to play.
Look at them losing it.
Hey, Mathi, don't run your mouth;
focus on practice.
Hey, they're looking.
Don't go!
Hey, come on bowl!
Hey, Ravi, you've been bowling wide.
Are you not interested?
Now do you realize
who's the best team?
We have to chase them away!
Our victory is confirmed.
How can you tell?
Come to the playground you'll know.
After this they won't be able to face us.
Hey!
Hey, watch out!
Parents send them to study
and they're romancing.
Could you give me your picture?
For what?
My nephew is refusing to eat food.
I'm going to use your picture
to scare him. So that he'll eat.
You're incorrigible!
I hate the weekends.
Hey, don't you love me?
I asked for you picture.
Can't you ask for mine?
Impressed!
-Hey!
-Let go of my hand.
-Come on...
-I have to go home.
I'll get my friend's bike
and drop you home.
Drop me home?
Why don't you stay at my place
for a couple of days?
Let go of my hand.
I have to go home.
Hey!
What happened?
Hey, I'm speaking to you!
Ranjith!
Hey!
Ranjith, freshen up and get ready.
I have to pray today.
I'm speaking to you
and you're ignoring.
Get up! I said, get up!
-I said, get up!
-Ma! Ma!
Hey, what is it?
How dare you raise your voice?
For sure the God will intervene.
Watch out for the judgement day.
What's wrong with you?
All these years you were
fighting with him.
Now when I threw water on him
you're reacting.
Ma, you threw water on my book.
Show me. Hey!
Hey, where did you get the twenty bucks?
Did you steal it from your
Appa's pocket?
Since morning your Appa has been
eating my ears off.
Ma, do I look like a thief to you?
If I ask Appa is going to give me money.
It must be your eldest son.
Ask him.
Always nagging me.
What would you do with so much money?
-Give it to me.
-Let go. I'm leaving.
Eventually you will come to me.
Sam, granny bought you many things.
Buy me some betel nuts, son.
Get lost, Gran!
Hey, why are you getting dressed up?
-Nothing Ma.
-Bring me a pot of water.
Ma, is Ranjith home?
I'm coming!
Are you guys headed to the playground.
No Ma!
I heard about a match on the carnival day.
Please don't participate in it.
There are evil people out there.
I will take care of him.
Don't worry!
Ranjith, if I see you near that place...
Ma, don't worry.
Don't go over there.
It'll end up in a fight.
At least you buy me betel nuts.
I will surely buy it
on my way back home.
Hey! Hey!
If I diligently pray...
there will be no match
and everyone will be wasted.
In Arakkonam district, Perumbachai village
in accord to
Maariamman temple carnival
cricket tournament is organized.
What makes it important is...
due to an incident six years ago
a decision was made not to
conduct any matches.
I'm sure everyone is aware of it.
As two villages are going to
come together.
-Mano, you pad up.-Due to Annan Gopalan's effort...
the people and the elders of this village
have decided to conduct this match.
Aasir Annan is felicitating
Annan Gopal with a garland.
The next match...
It's between Perumbachai colony
Blue Star team
versus Perumbachai's Alpha team.
Who are these guys
in white uniforms?
Boss, over here. Over here!
They look like league players.
Hey, where did you bring us?
You can park here!
Anna, who are they?
Who are they?
This is new!
Welcome, Boss. Welcome!
I request you to play for our team.
Hello, we are league players.
-Hear me out...
-Wait! Who are the opponents?
They're colony boys from our village.
If we play in your team
they won't stand a chance.
That's what we want!
They brought in league players.
How can they bring in league players?
It's specified in the form that we can
bring in players from outside.
Hey, we'll handle them!
We don't have a kit.
But nothing to worry.
We can face anyone we want.
We'll play the game!
Take this as advance.
After the match I'll pay you balance.
Where do we sit?
-We're running out of time.
-Over here.
Team captains come to the field
and toss the coin.
Hey, Ravi, Vasanth, hurry up!
-Get going.-The other teams are waiting.
-Come on. Hurry up.
-There's no space over here.
The match is about to begin.
If you speak to the boys.
They'll be inspired.
-Hello!
-You mean these guys?
No need. We can handle it.
-I think he did not ask before.
-If we win the toss pick batting.
Ask both the captains
to come to the field.
-Head or tail?
-Head!
The coin is being tossed.
Play well.
Hey, give them a new ball.
Anna, did you lose the toss?
Can't you make it on time?
Opening batsmen:
Nandagopalan-Sunil
Bharath is bowling now.
-That's fantastic bowling!
-Super Bharath!
Bharath is a star bowler.
-Next ball...
-Great bowling.
This is a fantastic ball, too.
Super Bharath!
I thought he'd strike,
but he missed it.
The game is getting interesting.
It's been a while
since a match this interesting.
-The batsman is checking the soil.
-Why is he checking the soil?
Come on, come on, Bharath!
Maintain offside!
That's a fantastic shot!
The ball flew over the boundary.
-It's a Six!
-Awesome!
Super Boss!
Nandagopalan scored the first six
of the match.
Let's wait and watch
Nandagopalan's game.
Come on, keep bowling.
Machan, we're going to win!
Come on, Bharath!
Good shot!
Catch the ball.
Four!
Strike!
Hit it!
Sam, think before you bowl.
It's so funny.
Playing with these kids is like
net practice for us.
-It's boring.
-You play your game.
Watch me now!
Come on! Come on!
Keep it up!
Come on, keep up the pace!
Bowl!
That's it! You nailed it Sam.
-Hey!
-Oh, no!
As expected, for his team...
-What's wrong with you?-...he made a wicket.
Sam is rocking with his performance.
The next batsman is, Venkat.
What is it?
Over here.
Howzzzat! Yes!
-That's great, Bharath!
-Hey!
The score is at 58 for 2 wickets.
Come on, Rajesh!
The next batsman is the captain
of Alpha team, Rajesh.
He's a fantastic right-hand batsman.
Sam is bowling.
There goes an amazing boundary.
Rajesh, keep it up.
Keep scoring!
Throw it here!
Continuous boundaries!
Super!
He scored on all sides of the field.
Fantastic shot!
-Stay there.
-Boss, we can score.
That's it!
-Another single...
-Boss, 1 run?
-There he goes again.
-Make the catch.
That's a sixer!
Nothing to worry.
Sam, let them score.
Don't worry.
It was a fluke!
In this tournament,
Alpha team is playing a great match.
Sam is getting ready to bowl.
Here comes the next ball.
-It's going to the off side.
-Catch Ranjith!
Great catch, Ranjith!
In 10 overs, the Alpha team
is at 96 runs for 3 wickets.
Nandagopalan is scoring...
left, right and centre
to make up for the loss.
Last ball.
Nandagopalan, a great shot.
This, too, is a sixer.
Nandagopalan has scored
half a century.
-Well played.
-Come on, keep it up!
Alpha team's innings end
with 3 wickets in 12 overs...
That was a good game.
Awesome!
The first innings has come to an end.
No one has scored this high
on this playground to date.
Alpha team has scored 120 runs.
From Team Blue Star...
Boss, what about a fielder here?
...the batsmen
have arrived on the field.
Team Alpha looks excited.
Bala is bowling the first over.
Fantastic ball. Amazing bouncer!
-Play patiently.-That was a fantastic bouncer.
Next ball! They're not able to
face Bala's bowling.
Next over...
Play with your bat.
They're swinging the bat
but no contact.
-These people are rough.
-You're right!
Next ball from Bala to Mani.
-Out!
-Howzzat!
Go wide. Come on, go wide!
-Don't you understand? Go!
-That's it. Bowl!
Bala is bowling.
Hey, fantastic ball!
Super!
-His height is a great advantage.
-It was an easy wicket.
Machan, awesome!
Ranjith, you go and bat.
Blue Star's game is sloppy
at the moment.
Here comes Blue Star's Captain, Ranjith.
-You go to square leg.
-Shall we put him here?
-He's good at...
-Hold on, what is it?
Can't you see I'm setting up fielding?
-Do you need another fielder over there?
-Come on!
Fantastic bowling!
-They can't face it.
-Ranjith lost his chance.
Let's see if he's able to
play next ball.
That was an amazing length.
That's great.
They're not able to play.
-Blue Star is in a dire situation.
-I could've played.
Let's wait and watch
if Ranjith can make a difference.
Now we have Bala returning to bowl.
Ranjith is going to bat.
The ball is charging towards
the boundary.
Sixer! Sixer!
That's a fantastic sixer by Ranjith.
With the first sixer,
Ranjith is boosting the team's score.
The next boundary is on the offside.
-Hey!
-What's wrong with him?
Ranjith is scoring on all sides
of the field.
-Keep running!
-Ranjith, slay the pitch!
Let's try one over.
I know this batsman well.
Thank you.
They're discussing
who'd be bowling next.
The next over is by Captain Rajesh.
Out! Get out of here!
Captain Rajesh, that was fantastic bowling.
Rajesh has proved he's a captain.
Move to the front.
Next batsman is Ammukutty.
Move to your right.
He's an aggressive player.
Current catch the ball!
Ammukutty got out as quickly
as he got on the field.
Hey, Current don't overdo it.
Hey, have patience.
For now play singles.
Later we can score higher.
-Please listen to me.-Next batsman is Sam.
Who's going to bowl the next over?
Give me the ball.
I wonder who's going to bowl?
Ravi?.
Bala, he will bowl.
Learn from him.
Come on!
Are you a fool? It's just the first ball,
and you're swinging.
Hey, stop swinging!
Play patiently.
-The next is a single run.
-Come on, make a run.
Run!
Sam and Ranjith are playing
a good partnership.
Oh, damn!
There goes another boundary.
Ranjith is rocking.
He's bowling to the leg-side.
The next ball is going to be a sixer.
Keep bowling to that side.
Ranjith is ready to face the ball.
-Ranjith is injured by the ball.
-Damn!
-Hey! Hey!
-Well bowled!
Hey, Ranjith, what happened?
-Can you play?
-Are you okay?
Can you play?
He needs first aid.
He's done. He's badly hurt.
Take him away.
Where are you going?
You're next!
Ranjith is retired hurt.
Fantastic bowling.
Well bowled Bala. Keep it up!
Did you see his delivery?
It's a fantastic win for Alpha Team.
Unable to face Bala and Sriram's bowling...
The Blue Star team lost by 35 runs.
On behalf of the organizing committee
and the people of the village...
Hey, Sam, did you see that?
-I don't know how to face people.
-It's humiliating.
To lose like this, they were showing off.
You were showing off
but nothing to prove.
Alpha team won by 35 runs
against Blue Star team.
Thanks a lot, Boss.
If not for you...
Will we get our payment tomorrow?
For sure!
Let's go!
Come on, machi. Let's go.
We request the teams to be ready.
I will bring it in the morning.
I hope it will be in tomorrow.
Boss... Boss, thanks!
Get ready for the toss!
Shortly the next match will begin.
I was afraid you guys might lose.
-We wouldn't, Mama.
-You guys rocked!
-Thank you.
-Awesome!
-I'll take a leave.
-Okay.
-I'm leaving.
-Sure, Anna!
Anna, you worked hard
to clean up this ground.
But you let the boys play cricket.
I don't get it.
The ground is always ours!
You did watch how our boys
chased them away.
You're right!
Ranjith, winning and losing
is part of the match.
Hey!
Oh, God!
Hey, we should not have
lost to them.
-Anna!
-Hey, Ranjith!
How's your hand?
The swelling is still there.
It's hurting a bit.
You'll be fine.
Does your mother know about the injury?
She must've been mad!
-She was crying.
-Why?
She believes her plea to the God
punished me.
After that they played two more matches.
The opponent team had four league players.
But nothing compared to our match.
Anna, we shouldn't have lost to them.
Ammu, refrain from pondering
to whom you lost.
But figure out why you lost.
Important thing is to rectify the mistakes.
Okay?
Can you come to the tea shop
near MCF at 09:00 a.m.?
We'll head to Puttur and get you plastered.
Okay.
-See you in the morning.
-Sure, Anna.
You're here to fulfill my needs.
There are 100 others out there
who are ready to replace you.
Understood!
Understood?
If you don't get it.
Then understand and continue to work.
-Idiots!
-Shankar, I'll be back after a tea.
Careful!
Hey, stop!
-Hey, Velu, please raise the volume.
-Okay, Anna!
-Hey, Ranjith!
-Anna!
-Hey, Mano!
-Come, come.
Hey, what is this?
Anna!
Looks like the swelling didn't go down.
It's better! Better than yesterday.
It's best we get it checked.
-Velu, three teas.
-Sure!
Did you take permission from work?
-Good shot! Good shot!
-Why is he coming over here?
Who is he?
Remember the local match
from last week.
-Hi!
-He's the captain of that team.
-Boss...
-Welcome!
-As promised, we won.
-Right!
I was afraid Ranjith will win it.
But you got his wicket.
But Ranjith was able to play your bowling.
Oh, no, I forgot about it.
Sorry for the delay.
-Here you go.
-Take it.
-Is it all there?
-Yes it is.
-He won't leave I think.
-Let him be.
Let him watch us play.
You bowl.
Well bowled.
Listen, bring your foot to the front,
and play.
Play with front foot.
He's bowling above.
You're doing it wrong.
You'd know if you play.
Sure I will.
What are you doing Bala?
He's talking too much.
Let him play. He'll know.
Why aren't you playing front foot?
You step forward and play.
Go ahead and play.
You'll know.
He should not touch a bat again.
We must show him who we are.
I'm ready!
Hey, Bala, knock him out.
Don't spare him.
Teach him a lesson.
-Come on!
-Now you're talking!
Come on!
That's an amazing length.
That's the length!
Hey, be gentle, dude!
How dare he asked me to
step in the front to play?
Hereafter, he won't bother us.
What's happening here?
Who the hell is he?
Don't you have any sense?
Who gave you permission
to let him in here?
Sorry sir!
This is not a place
where anyone can play.
-You idiots!
-Sir!
I'm not anyone.
I'm Nandagopalan's friend.
Sir, he's not my friend.
I don't know who he is.
Hey, first...
First, ask him to get out.
Hey, get out!
Get out!
Hey, go! Out!
Sir, don't you lay your hands on me.
I said get out!
-I said get out of here!
-Sir, don't push me.
Go!
Security, call the Police
and throw him out.
Did you call the Police?
Go! Get out of here!
Go! Out!
-Let go!
-Keep him out of here!
Get out! Get out from here.
Let go. I'm going.
I'm telling you.
What did I do wrong?
You stepping in here itself is wrong.
-Get out!
-Anna, let go!
Hey, hold this for me.
-What happened?
-I don't know.
-Let's go and check.
-Throw him out.
-Let go. I'm just talking.
-Get out!
How's it wrong to play two balls?
It's wrong that you stepped in here.
I am asking why.
Sir, why are you being
hard on him for no reason.
You're not doing your job
that's why they're stepping in.
-Get lost!
-Anna!
-Hey!
-Bloody rascal!
How dare you lay hands on me?
-Why did you beat him?
-Don't mess with me.
I'll thrash you!
This is what happens
when you let the strays inside.
Throw them out.
Bloody rascals!
You people should remain where you belong.
What the hell?
-You're creating a scene out here...
-I'll kill you!
How dare you raise your hand on me?
Hey, close the gate!
Bloody rascals!
-Sir, first give us a chance to explain.
-Sir, beat them to pulp.
Shut the bloody gate.
Creating problems at the playground.
How dare you lay hands on me?
Do you think the Government
will sit ducks?
Sir, arrest them!
It's not that easy to play at this ground.
To play at this ground...
you people should be qualified.
Qualified!
Hey!
If you dare to return to this ground.
This will be the result of it.
-Get out of here!
-Come to the station and speak.
-Step away.
-Sir, please let them go.
Sir, please let them go!
Sir, please let them go. Sir!
You people are not allowed to
step inside that ground.
Eh! Not did you step inside the ground...
but got into a fight.
Sir, they are students!
You're planning to file a case.
Students should remain students.
But they laid their hands on him.
For what they did I would've
remanded them for 15 days.
Sir, I'll fulfill the formalities
you ask of.
Hey, come along!
Not you both. Just you!
Come on, get up!
Come on!
Gopal, where's Ranjith?
Listen, I convinced the Police
not to file a case.
Pay him 1000 rupees
and they'll let him walk.
Let's go!
-1000 rupees?
-Why would I pay for him?
In my family, no one has step foot
inside the Police station.
But my son indulged in a fight...
and never in my wildest dreams thought
he will pay a visit to the Police station.
Ma, I did not beat anyone
neither did I indulge in a fight.
I went to sign the register.
As if you're the President
who went to sign it.
Listen, "Whoever conceals his
transgressions will not prosper."
"But he who confesses and forsakes them
will obtain mercy."
I did not quote this.
But psalm 28:13 quotes it.
Here you go!
You can fool me.
But God is watching you.
Be careful.
Some husband I have.
As a father, you should be
responsible to fetch him a job.
But this family has a mind of its own.
I don't really get you.
Our son has received a call letter
from the selection committee.
It's a huge thing.
Are you aware or not
about the sports quota?
ICF will be grab him
for his spectacular performance.
Yeah right.
As if they were waiting for him.
Appa, the shoes are tight.
They're tight is it?
Once I get my salary I'll buy you
new ones. Adjust for now.
Okay, Appa.
Hey, Ranjith!
Please read the prayer.
-Appa!
-What is it?
I don't want new shoes.
I don't want anything.
Why bother when they don't respect us?
Why won't they respect us?
If you're talented,
they'll respect you.
Listen, go and give your best.
I'm sure you'll get selected.
If you land a good job you and
your future family will be happy.
Look at me.
Working with iron in railways
has damaged my hands.
I'm saying it because
I want you to have a good life.
They will pick you for your talent.
Go and play, my son.
Go ahead.
-Okay, Pa.
-Go!
Play well!
-Your name?
-Ranjith!
Ranjith!
-Batch number?
-Seven!
Seven!
Sit over there. They'll call you.
Sir, two bowlers and two batsmen.
Ashwin, come here!
Come, come, come. Hurry up!
Go and get ready to play.
Let me check with him.
Please keep it over there.
-Sir!
-What do you want?
I'm from Batch-1 when will you call me?
Just because you have a call letter
we can't let you play right away.
Go and wait your turn.
They don't understand at once.
They issue call letters to every moron.
And they make our lives difficult.
It's the committee's fault.
60 and 70 are batsmen right?
Where are you going?
Hey, they won't call us.
I'm leaving!
Murugesh!
-Did we send in next player?
-Yes!
Next, send in...
Sir, that's the third batch.
Third batch?
I think it's the second batch.
Just play. It's all fixed.
Welcome. Vanakkam, sir.
Good morning, sir.
-Send in two players.
-Okay, Sir.
-How many are required?
-Two batsmen and two bowlers.
And one all-rounder, sir.
Give, sir, the details.
Here you go, sir.
-Check the list.
-Note down his name.
Hari...
-Sir!
-What is it?
Sir, I was here before them.
I said, I will call you.
Go and wait out there.
Just because you have a call letter
we can't let you play right away.
We'll call you when it's your turn.
Go!
Not that they'll nail it
if we let them play.
They issue call letters to anyone
and everyone.
It's become a headache handling them.
I wonder where they come from.
Who's on the next list?
Both are bowlers, sir.
Hey, catch the ball!
Hey, what is he doing?
-Who is this joker?
-Oh, god!
-He couldn't catch a ball.
-I wonder why they even try.
-Incorrigible...
-Look at his face.
As if he's going to catch the ball.
Hey, pick up the balls.
Isn't that why you came here?
Hey!
This is not a place
where anybody can play.
Only the qualified should play
on this ground.
Son, I'll pay next month.
Okay, Anna!
Please have some more.
Enough?
Where's your ring?
He must've given it to someone
as engagement ring.
-You shut up.
-Hey, can't you shut up?
I'm pissed as it is.
Pipe down.
Get lost!
What happened to you?
Hey, girl, can't you stay quiet?
Always picking fights with him.
He's not your only child.
Was I adopted?
Yeah right you were adopted.
Finally you found out.
You never help me with chores.
After years we played
in front of the village and lost.
And at the Police station...
Emmanuel Anna begged to the Police.
Did I embarrass myself in the selection
that my father pinned his hopes on?
When I told him...
his face went pale, Anandhi!
My team had too much faith in me.
As a captain I lost.
I got defeated.
Oh, God. Hey!
Look at me!
Look at tears in your eyes.
In ITI you failed too many times
in different subjects.
Never have I seen you get so emotional.
Come on. Don't cry.
If something makes us cry...
that means we are true to it.
But they made you wait at the selection
and humiliated you.
Even I am pissed to even hear about it.
It's not like they're great players.
I swear...
Those guys are nothing compared
to your prowess in the game.
In a way it's a good thing
you guys lost to them.
If you win at the first chance,
you won't know its importance.
Anandhi, you're talking like Emmanuel Anna.
Good people speak the same frequency.
You idiot!
-Oh, God!
-Yeah right!
-Ma!
-Come on!
You should scream, Anandhi.
-Hey!
-That's all you care about me.
Hey!
Look, I'm going to pinch you again.
You should scream, Aa-Anandhi!
Aa-Anandhi!
Anandhi...
-Close you eyes.
-Why?
You close your eyes and I'll tell you.
Wow! You were right here with me crying.
When did you get this?
-Give it back. If don't want it.
-I want!
-Do you like it?
-Yes, I like it!
-Hereafter, don't buy anything.
-Why?
I'm not fond of jewellery.
What are you fond of?
Tell me what you like, I'll get it.
It's not something you can buy
from a store.
What is it? Hey!
Tell me what you like.
I'll buy it for you.
I wish to bat at the playground.
Really?
-Come on.
-Hey!
-Come with me.
-Where are you taking me?
Come with me.
Rahul, let me play give me your bat.
Come on, play.
Wow, Anandhi!
What is it?
♪ Reecho of the train
Is searching for you ♪
♪ Like a ringing drum
The heart is pounding ♪
♪ Your swinging hands
Your signals ♪
♪ Is throwing me
Into the Eden garden ♪
♪ In the rails
That cross your place ♪
♪ My life seems to end ♪
♪ Words that I have not even uttered
To my mother ♪
♪ Are floating in my mind ♪
♪ Within the blanket of dreams ♪
♪ I try to stop the time... ♪
♪ ...passing by ♪
♪ Like the rain water running
on the ground... ♪
♪ I am slipping by ♪
♪ You shower kindness on the heart
that is in pain ♪
♪ You care ♪
♪ Amongst all the redolence
that graze me... ♪
♪ Only your scent stirs my soul ♪
♪ Even after the earth vanishes
The only rail lines that do not vanish ♪
♪ ...is Love, my dear ♪
♪ My love ♪
Current, you sound excited.
I'm nothing less than Mark Waugh.
Emman, hey!
We welcome our respected brother
Poovai Murthy...
on behalf of the family
and the music troupe.
I've heard many names in Tamilnadu
There's no one greater
than Poovaiyar Annan.
If you did your work.
You must fight and win it.
Brave leaders. Be ready!
The future is waiting for us.
Kill the cowards in your hearts.
That's it!
I wish the bride and the groom
a blessed and prosperous life.
Welcome, Anna.
How are you?
I hope the children are studying.
They should speak English fluently.
Hey!
-Hey, Sasi.
-Dude, I don't get any of it.
The boy who I mentioned
who is behind Anandhi....
-He is here with his boys.
-Who is it?
-is that him?
-We should not spare him.
The dancing guy in green shirt.
Come on, Anna is calling.
Hey, wait, bring the gift.
Anna, come on. This for you.
-Hold the gift.
-Come on!
-That's enough, Ranjith.
-Everyone please have your meal.
Hey!
Hey, can't you watch out?
How dare you?
I'll kill you. Where are you from?
Hey, don't you dare?
It's okay, you arrive before them.
How does it matter?
How dare you raise your voice
in my territory?
Hey, what's your problem?
Hey!
Hey, son, let's not fight
during new beginnings.
-Guys leave.
-Come with me.
-Can't you hear me?
-Anna, what's the problem?
-Nothing to worry.
-Don't create problems.
I said don't create problems.
I'll handle it you leave.
-It's best you leave.
-Come on, let's leave.
-I ought to!
I dare you to cross Arakkonam station.
You overthink of yourself.
It's better you stick to your business
shut up and leave.
If you don't we'll kill you!
Listen, don't speak out of your turn.
Hey!
Shut up and leave.
If you don't then you won't
make it out of here.
Bloody, how dare you?
Hey, don't fight!
Let go!
-Let go!
-How dare you run your mouth?
Hey, I'll kill you!
Don't bring area into it.
Hey, thrash him!
Stay right here. We'll be back!
Hey, please hear me out.
Hey, Rajesh!
Hey, Ranjith, calm down.
Hey, why would you?
We'll sort this out in the morning.
Come on, let's go!
Go! Go safe!
We'll discus this in the morning.
Let me tell you all something.
They've announced a tournament at MCF.
Why don't you both teams
join hands and enroll?
If the both the teams combine...
no league player can defeat you.
Due to the incident at the ground
they fired me.
Are you serious?
It's a freaking lawnmower job.
We need to prove our worth to them.
We should not spare them
for humiliating us.
On the day of the selection not just me
but many were humiliated.
My point exactly.
They look down on us as street players.
We are not to be looked down upon.
Huh?
Will you both join hands and play?
Today when you joined hands
no one could beat you.
We must unite!
That's it! That's it!
What do you say?
Please stop here.
How could you agree
to join hands with them?
That too we have to play
under their team's name.
What's in the name?
Hey, Ranjith, how can we play
along with them?
Let's enroll as our team and win it.
The hell you'll win!
We did observe their game.
Every shot looked like we watch on TV.
We've been yearning to play
in this tournament.
Last time you used money to fix it.
Similarly, fix it for tournament too.
Why should we join hands with them?
You saw what the
league players did to us.
If two teams join
half the players will be idle.
How are you going to select the players?
Everyone is a good player.
We'll be playing the cricket ball
not the cork ball.
I'll select players based on their
performances with cricket ball.
We'll know during the practice.
Anyway, your brother will be
on the team.
Of course,
the elder brother is the captain.
Hey, I won't be biased.
We must practice.
Best performer will play in the match.
Even if I don't perform.
I'll step down.
Let's join hands with our people.
When did they become our people?
Venkat, you're an important player
of this team.
How can you not trust me?
Hey, consider sports to be sports.
Let's play one tournament.
Please.
Don't take this tournament lightly.
This is an opportunity.
We should not miss it!
Hey, come with me.
-Vanakkam, Anna.
-Welcome Rajesh.
What's all this?
Shake hands with each other.
Do you want individual instructions?
Shake hands.
Hey, go ahead.
Go ahead!
Ranjith and Rajesh!
They have printed a form
for the tournament.
Here, read it!
All the matches will be played on the mat.
Mat?
Anna, what does it mean?
-It says mat!
-What is a mat?
We're not used to play on the mat.
This tournament will be played on the mat.
Practicing is not important.
But we have to practice on the mat.
Only then you can play
with the cricket ball.
Okay?
How much is a mat?
To buy a second hand mat
it will cost you 2000 rupees.
2000?
Did you say 2000 rupees?
Anna, I'll buy the mat.
It is not the right thing to do.
It's best every one pitch in.
Then the mat will be owned by the team.
Let's all pitch in and buy it.
Ranjith and Rajesh, at Chepaulk...
you can find a good deal on the
second-hand mat, Raghav says so.
Go over there.
-[in Hindi] Where are you going?
-Gurkha bhaiya!
-Can we buy the mat here?
-No, no! Get going.
How dare you ask us to leave?
Hey, calm down!
Aren't we out-of-towners too?
I wonder what hardship he's going through
to come here for a job.
And you're troubling him.
He can't understand matriculation
Hindi. And you expect him to get you.
Listen, come over here.
-What do you want?
-Cricket mat!
Are you okay with a second hand mat?
-How much is it?
-How much do you have?
First, state your price.
A new mat at the store is 5000 rupees.
I have two mats with me.
It'll cost you 1500 rupees.
It will be as good as new.
Super mat! Okay?
-What do you say?
-Okay!
Have you decided?
-Okay, show us the mat.
-Come with me.
They're here to buy the cricket mat.
Listen, give 500 rupees advance.
Anna, we'll check out the mat
and then pay him.
Pay up front if you need it.
If not off you go!
-They're thinking too much to pay.
-Fine, pay him.
Anna, mat should not be torn.
We can check it out later.
First pay up advance.
It's all there, Anna.
-Don't speak too much.
-Come on, let's go!
-That boy speaks too much.
-He's still a kid!
-Trust is important.
-It's a good mat.
-Be patient and get it.
-Ramesh!
Go ahead!
Anna, where's the mat?
It's over there.
Where is it?
It's on the ground.
Can you not see it?
Ramesh, sell it to them.
I'm leaving.
Anna, what's this?
Once they clear the coffin,
take your mat.
Sit over there. Please wait.
And you expect to watch my words.
There's a demand for this mat.
Serve tea to the boys.
-Here you go tea!
-How long would it take?
-Be careful.
-Hey, hold it right!
-Hey, hold it tight.
-Hold it tight!
Hold on, we'll fix it.
Hey, Bharath. Go to that side.
-Here you say!
-Venkatesh, come to this side.
-Hey, I will stand here.
-Come on, bowl.
Hey!
Come on, Rajesh, bowl.
Rajesh!
Bowl!
Everyone gather.
Come to the mat.
Come on!
What did you observe?
Erm.. when we bowl in sand
the ball travels low.
But on the mat it's fast and bounces.
That's it!
All this while we played on sand.
-But now mat. Okay?
-We get it!
-We get it, Anna.
-Come on everyone.
Hey, come on everyone.
You can't hold cricket ball
like you hold a cork ball.
This is the stitch.
Your two fingers should be above it.
If you bowl now the ball will seam.
If it pitches in the seam
the ball will travel faster.
One is in-swing.
Another is out-swing.
If you hold the seam and
pitch it in it's a in-swing.
Likewise if you pitch it outside
it's an out-swing.
Understood?
♪ Let you be controlled
Let you be stopped ♪
♪ Creating obstacles in your path
Let you be spoiled ♪
♪ Let you be hated
Let you be sidelined ♪
♪ To have patience, to refuse
Let it give way! ♪
♪ Come on! ♪
♪ If we go to war,
Who is there to conquer us? ♪
♪ This is Budhdha waging the war
after learning valor ♪
♪ To whom? To whom? ♪
♪ We will announce to the world ♪
♪ Give us the way
As we walk ♪
♪ Quit the path
Quit the path ♪
♪ You should know who you are ♪
♪ Change is evident ♪
♪ It is enough if the elephant knows
its strength ♪
♪ You should know who you are ♪
♪ Change is evident ♪
♪ It is enough if the elephant knows
its strength ♪
We're playing to defeat the Giant-11 team.
We should not lose to them.
I can understand your anger.
Like us they don't play twice a week.
They play on all the days in a week.
Like you perceive MCF tournament
is not so easy to play.
It's an important tournament.
If you play in this tournament,
you may get selected in Ranjit Trophy
or even in Indian team.
This tournament is an eye wash.
To make people believe
that the selection is not biased.
Otherwise,
there's no other purpose to it.
More than winning this tournament...
it's a big deal to even play
in this tournament.
In the 5 tournaments,
11 Bullets have won twice.
The rest of the three years
Team Giant-11 won the trophy.
It's not easy to win against that team.
To compete with them
we need more practice.
Come on! Come on, boys!
Come on!
Once we lock our opponent...
in all aspects we need to
work more hard than them.
The hard work will give us
courage and confidence.
♪ Be patient and focused like a leopard ♪
Super ball. Sam, great bowling!
♪ We are the birds
That begins the war ♪
♪ If you understand,
Even a drop becomes an ocean ♪
♪ Let us hold our heads high
And surprise everyone ♪
♪ Seeing your game,
Let us oppressors become silent ♪
♪ Game is also a challenge for you ♪
♪ Don’t be submissive
Do not let your heart break ♪
♪ Take the first step
Prove them wrong ♪
♪ Keep repeating it ♪
♪ Give us the way
As we walk ♪
♪ Quit the path
Quit the path ♪
♪ You should know who you are ♪
♪ Change is evident ♪
♪ It is enough if the elephant knows
its strength ♪
♪ You should know who you are ♪
♪ Change is evident ♪
♪ It is enough if the elephant knows
its strength ♪
-Thamizh machan.
-Hey, that's my cousin.
-That's my cousin.
-Hey, Venkat!
Hey, have you teamed up with them?
I told you!
Come on, let's go!
Team Blue Star and Sputnik...
Please come to the field
to spin the toss.
Rajesh, you go.
Let's win the toss.
Tail!
-Hey, that's super.
-I picked batting.
Who do we send as openers?
Let Babu and Venkat open.
Venkatesh and Babu are going to open.
The first ball has been bowled.
Venkatesh is playing stroke.
-He's a pro at playing stroke.
-Is he good bowler?
Nah, I'm just whiling away time.
You play well, don't you?
That's a fantastic ball.
Hey, let's go for another run.
There goes a wicket for Blue Star.
He got him out on purpose.
Fantastic!
Keep up the bowling.
In 2 overs, 2 wickets and 2 runs.
Ranjith, come on, play.
Ranjith is down for batting.
That's a wide ball.
Next ball... That's a great ball.
That's a four!
Excellent shot, Ranjith!
Hey, maintain this.
Ranjith's first ball fetched him
a boundary.
Hey, come on!
Hey. Venkat, make the run.
Why the hell is he not running?
-He will do it.
-That was an easy run.
I won't run for it.
Suriya's last ball.
Hey, don't come. Go back!
Throw it here!
-Howzzzat!
-They got the ball.
-In 3 overs, 7 runs, and 2 wickets...
-He picked up the ball.
...team Blue Star.
-Why did you run?
-He did it on purpose.
That's why I asked to bat.
But you let an outsider play.
Hey, don't you dare call us outsiders.
This is our team.
But you clanged on to win the match.
It won't work
if the partnership is not correct.
Ranjith is ready to face the next ball.
♪ Back on the streets
Are the Blue Star Boys ♪
♪ Who's got the balls?
Who's got the… ♪
♪ ...Yeah! ♪
♪ Back on the streets
Are the Blue Star Boys ♪
♪ Who's got the balls?
Who's got the… ♪
♪ ...Yeah! ♪
♪ You guys are a no-ball ♪
♪ Declared by the dude, Gopal ♪
♪ This's a law-ball ♪
♪ A game-changing Blue Ball ♪
-Good game!
♪ We're gonna play
Cricket... Cricket... Bro! ♪
♪ We won't go astray ♪
♪ At twenty-two yards... ♪
♪ ...we're the Cricket Guards ♪
♪ We're the Gully Gang boys
Now coming like a Boss ♪
Ey! Who's the new player
on the field?
♪ Blue Star! ♪
♪ Everything quakes
When the Chief arrives ♪
♪ Blue Star! ♪
♪ Even foes tremble in fear ♪
♪ Fireworks will rain ♪
♪ Blue Star! ♪
♪ There's none but us! ♪
♪ Make them play
Make them run ♪
♪ Sending people to look for them... ♪
♪ You messed with the wrong bunch ♪
♪ It's a different kinda Cricket! ♪
♪ A kind, hard-to-comprehend ♪
♪ Try figuring it out ♪
♪ Lock horns if you dare ♪
♪ It's a Blue Star Cricket ♪
125 runs, 5 wickets in 16 overs.
Will the Sputnik team achieve this target?
Let's wait and watch
if they'll achieve the target.
You go straight.
You go to the mid-off.
The opening batsmen from
Sputnik are Parthiban and Sathish.
-Hey, catch it.
-Throw it!
Well fielding!
It's a tight fielding by Blue Star.
Rajesh bowls again.
Howzzat!
Sputnik lost their first wicket.
Next batsmen, Surya.
And bowler, Bharath!
Good length!
Looks like a maiden over.
Oh, bowled!
In 4 overs, 2 wickets down,
and is at only 6 runs.
Dinesh is batting.
Sixer!
Oh!
It was my ball.
Why did you come for it?
Scram! Stop yelling.
Amazing partnership between
Dinesh and Surya.
-Hey!-Another boundary!
Hey, Venkatesh!
-Go to the end.
-I don't have to listen to you.
Let the captain say it.
Hey, like he said. Go to the end.
The batting is in full form.
In 12 overs, the score is at 95 runs.
Hey, catch! Catch!
Leave it!
-They dropped the catch.
-That was my ball.
The players are indulging
in useless arguments.
What the hell?
I told you it was my catch!
-How dare you?
-Why are you fighting?
-Go and play.-Team Blue Star has no unity.
Had they broken their partnership,
they would've won.
Last over 14 runs needed.
They're at 111 runs in 15 overs.
-Hey, Ravi, throw it in.
-Okay.
-Okay, go.
-Rajesh, let Bharath bowl.
Fine by me.
Bharath!
Bowl well.
Checkout the scoreboard.
-Bowl well.
-Ravi, give me the ball.
-Hey, give me the ball.
-They've changed the bowler.
-Bharath is going to bowl.
-Come on, Bharath!
First ball!
-Catch it.
-Sixer!
First ball, six runs!
I think the match will end soon.
That's a four! Boundary!
The length is correct.
But keep it offside.
He's good with leg side.
You go to the boundary.
The Sputnik Team needs 4 runs
to win this match.
Next ball...
Well bowled, Bharath!
What is it? What?
Bharath, let it go.
-Go ahead and bowl-Come on, Sputnik team.
You have a great winning opportunity.
Again, Bharath!
We're waiting to see what happens next.
Catch it!
That was a fantastic catch
by Rajesh.
They need 3 runs in 1 ball.
2 runs will be a draw.
And 3 runs will fetch them victory.
-Bharath is about to bowl.
-Hey, Bharath!
Throw a short ball.
He plays only one shot.
Keep it offside.
Techniques should've been used earlier,
not now.
Come on, Bharath!
Bharath, bowling from Thiruteni corner.
-Suriya hit a shot.
-Hey! Hey!
Keep it right! Keep it right.
-Venkatesh missed it.
-Throw it to keeper.
Throw it over here.
Hit it!
-Howzzat!
-Out!
Verdict is out!
Team Blue Star has won the match by 1 run
and is moving up in the league.
-I'm leaving.
-Come on, hurry up!
Let's go!
-Come in, Rajesh.
-Mama!
-Did you call for me?
-Yes!
I heard you're playing
in the MCF tournament.
Yes!
But why did join hands with them?
Tell me what kind of league players
you want.
I'll get them for you!
Mama, if both the teams
play together we'll win.
Hey, what is it?
Don't you understand?
I'll make sure no one plays cricket
in the town.
Anna, first, we'll see if they stay united.
Hey!
What happened?
Where are you going?
It's not time yet.
Where were you?
I'm talking to you.
Have you gone deaf?
Hey!
Hey, have some coffee.
He is my grandson.
To him, education is life!
I concur he will only stop
once he becomes a Collector.
You don't feel like meeting me,
do you?
Hey, Ranjth, what happened?
Why are you sitting out here?
Let's go.
Nothing happened!
Why didn't you come for practice?
-Hey, Sam!
-I'm speaking to you.
Why are you taking it apart?
Hey, I'm speaking to you.
Why is he using my stuff?
-I don't touch his stuff.
-He's your brother.
-What's wrong with you?
-What are you doing?
Hey, why are you undoing the thread?
Give it to me.
Hey, why do you use my stuff?
-Sam! Sam!
-Hey, it's my wish!
I'll come if I feel like.
If you say something,
I'll kill you!
How dare you?
Just for a bat you'll beat your brother.
Hey, Sam!
Hey, Ranjith! Ranjith hear me out.
He can't take our beatings!
-I'll break your jaw.
-Break it off!
-I said break it off.
-Why is he beating him?
How dare you?
-I'm being patient with you.
-Don't do it. I said, don't do it.
-Hey, Ranjith. That's enough.
-I'll break your hands.
-I'm warning you!
-Hey, go away!
He's a small child!
Let your father come.
I will handle you guys then.
Did he beat you hard?
Listen, Sam!
-Son, please listen.
-Sam!
I'm shivering!
Is this why you guys are crazy
about cricket?
-I've been looking for you.
-I wonder how they drink this?
Sam, you're already soft.
Hear me out. Don't drink.
It'll be embarrassing.
Hey, to whom it'll be embarrassing?
Without me you would've lost.
At least I'm having a beer.
For losing the tournament my brother
and Rajesh will have poison.
Go and save them.
Go!
Hey, who said we lost.
Hey, Ranjith! Where's Sam?
He won't come.
How can you be so casual about it?
Sam was doing well.
What happened to him?
We'll handle it!
Where did he go?
Sevapaer team opened strong!
2 overs 24 runs.
-Zero wickets.
-Howzzat!
Rajesh bowled third over.
A clean tip on the bat.
-Ranjith got the catch.
-Howzzat!
-Sir, that's an out, sir.-Umpire denied it.
We thought it was a one-off.
For Bharath, the umpire gave a wide
for a non-wide ball.
After that, he kept giving wide
for all the balls.
Your brother did an amazing stumping!
Howzzat!
But the umpire did not approve it.
-Sir that's a out!
-He did not step in.
Why did you let it go?
What else can we do?
The organizers was yelling.
Then Rajesh and Bharath
tightened the bowling.
Still they made 110 runs.
We didn't give up!
Current and I opened and scored
a lot of runs.
Hey....
You don't believe me, right?
I swear. You can ask anyone.
Our partnership was rocking.
Current was not out.
But the umpire gave out!
After that, we kept losing wickets.
You should've been there.
Then who played?
Ranjith is about to bat.
Your brother and Rajesh played.
Very good. Square cut.
Smashing shot.
-What happened next?
-Then Rajesh played.
The ball went over his head.
It was a clean no-ball.
But umpire said it's not.
Your brother and Rajesh did not agree.
We were talking and the opponent
team player pushed your brother.
Then both the teams stepped into the field.
A huge fight broke out!
Why is there an umpire?
Let's put a toss.
Whoever wins the toss is the winner.
Why should we play toss?
We won't agree.
If they're talented
then play a game and win.
Hey, arrogance is it?
What Anand? Arrogance it is!
I'm not an employee here anymore.
To listen to your nonsense.
Give respect and take respect.
Stating this as an excuse
they said both teams can't play.
And asked us to get out.
They did not budge!
You know what your brother did?
Come on! Everyone sit down.
Sir, they're asking to change the umpire.
Sir, the issue is going out of control.
I don't care do as you please!
Then they changed the umpire.
A new umpire was sent in.
After that the match resumed.
Rajesh and Ranjth's partnership
won the match.
Then why did they overdo it
in the last match?
We did win his match.
But their attitude did not change.
Hereafter, Ranjith is captain.
Hey, no need. It's going well.
You assigned bowling to Bharath
at the right time.
And you changed the fielding
Also, you stayed longer on the pitch.
You are a captain.
It's the right thing to do.
If you were there,
it was an easy win.
You better come for practice tomorrow.
I'll speak to them.
Get lost!
I'm not coming.
I care a damn about you people.
I came to meet you. You could've
bought an extra beer.
Hey, come over here.
Sam, why are you not
pressing your clothes?
Are you not well?
Playing deaf is it?
Sam I brought you breakfast.
Please eat.
Your pampering has spoiled him.
Ma!
Come in!
Come in and sit down.
Here, open your month.
Drink some water.
I will pay on Saturday.
I'm not here for that.
-I came to meet Sam.
-Oh!
Sit down. Would you like
to have breakfast?
No thanks. I had.
-You came to meet him?
-Yes!
He's being stubborn and difficult.
Have more.
-What are you doing?
-I found him at the ground...
he was hurt,
so I brought him home.
Sam, why did you not
come to the match yesterday?
I'm talking to you.
Had you been there,
it would've been great.
Hey, he came all the way
to meet you.
Give him a reply.
I never promised.
Why are you being rude to mom?
Damn it! You escaped last time.
-It's best you pipe down.
-Calm down.
They don't even let him
eat in peace.
Tomorrow's match is important.
It's semi-finals.
You have to come.
I'm not coming.
You can take someone else.
-Sam.
-What is it gran?
You said it was over.
I bought it for you.
Use it.
The old hag is embarrassing me.
Gran, don't piss me off.
Hey, Sam, please hear me out.
Tomorrow you have to come.
I told you, right?
He's the oddball in this house.
You carry on. I'll convince him.
We'll manage!
-It's getting late. Come to practice.
-I'll come.
-Hey, it's Sam.
-Where was he all this while?
Wait let me talk to him.
Sam!
Sam, stop right there!
Take this.
Give this letter to your brother.
What?
In the end,
you made me the messenger.
First read what's in the letter.
Read it!
To my beloved lover, Ranjith...
Anandhi...
Anandhi?
Hey, what about the letter
you gave my brother?
On that day, too,
Anandhi asked me to pass the letter.
Damn!
I'm leaving. Let's go!
Hey! Hey, Thaen!
Thaen!
What is it?
Why is that you don't understand
my feeling?
How long do you expect me to wait?
Next month 7th is your birthday.
I will give you my answer.
How come you remember
my birthday?
Every year you distribute chocolate
and pin a poem with it.
I've read it!
You've never read my letter.
I wonder how you read my poems.
You don't spare any festivals.
You even give me a card on
death anniversary holidays.
I've read them all.
I remember the poem
from your last birthday.
Shall I recite it?
"How many are aware?"
"You are the December flower
that bloomed in November."
How do you even come up
with these poems?
I've never seen you smile
like this before.
Hey, forget about it.
Do you even have feelings?
Anandhi looked sad
when she gave me the letter.
Hey, he's not a person
who takes these things seriously?
Except for cricket he does not
take anything seriously.
He has no time for love and feelings.
Oh!
So, you mean to say
stalking is serious love.
Of course!
If I find you stalking me again...
I'll file a Police complaint.
I'm warning you.
File a complaint.
But file a robbery case against me.
Why?
Because I stole your heart.
Oh, God!
Are you always like this?
Today is an unforgettable day
in my life.
Go and give this letter
to your brother.
Go! Get going.
Please turn around.
Turn around!
Yes!
Every ball may or may not
hit the boundary...
but it's surely heading towards
Giant-11 team's victory.
In the finals,
for sure Giant-11's team...
Now come the ball...
Wow, that's a great shot!
Giant-11 wins by 4 runs.
Next match is between?
Blue Star Vs Youth 11
Let the Ballot be.
Change the opponent team.
Okay, sir.
Team Blue Star, can you hear us!
The upcoming semi-finals match
is between...
Blue Star Vs 11 Bullets
Not between Blue Star and Youth 11.
Why did you change the opponent
for no reason?
You don't say!
You should not question us.
Sir!
Why did you change the Ballot last minute?
Last match because you asked
we changed the umpire.
-We did change right?
-Yes, sir!
How's it related?
Your opponent is not
in the position to play.
Please... Please adjust and play.
-Are you scared?
-Anna!
Anna, we'll handle them.
It's not an easy task to play
against 11 Bullets.
Anna, no matter who it is
we'll handle them.
-He's right. We'll handle them.
-Yeah he's right.
That's not the case.
There's a player Bullet Babu
in 11 Bullets team.
He has scored 4-5 centuries this year
in different tournaments.
Everyone expected that he'll play
for the Indian team.
But he brutally rejected the offer.
Why did he reject it?
He only likes the West Indies team.
He's adamant to play only
for West Indies.
If we get his wicket we're good.
But it's not an easy task.
One - he never got bowled out.
Two - he never got run out.
Because he never runs to make runs.
If you bowl leg side
he'll score in off side.
Likewise if you bowl off side
he'll score in leg side.
Before you figure which side he plays
the match will be over.
Spectacular player!
♪ Leg Side ♪
♪ Off side ♪
♪ In side ♪
♪ Out side ♪
♪ It's Babu's side ♪
♪ Full Shot ♪
♪ Late cut ♪
♪ Cover Drive ♪
♪ Sweep Shot ♪
♪ It's Babu's shot ♪
♪ You never saw the devil haha ♪
♪ My batting is the answer hoho ♪
-Look at the guy in the front.
-Hey, Mano!
-Go!
-Go, go, go!
Hey, Sam, come on.
Good you came.
-Ranjith, look he's here.
-I knew he will come.
-Why are you late?
-How did you come over here?
-Here you go.
-What is it?
Whatever I'm here now.
Where are my whites?
To grace this competition
and to make it sensational...
popular cricketers
from Madras Chepauk Stadium have arrived.
To my beloved Ranjith,
this letter is from Anandhi!.
I'm in tears while writing this letter.
I don't how to explain.
My family has fixed engagement for me.
I definitely won't marry him.
I feel like meeting you.
I'll be waiting for you
at the railway station.
I don't know why....
I want to meet you once.
If you could please come and meet me.
I want to discuss a lot of things with you.
In all the final matches till date...
Giant-11 and 11 Bullets
were up against each other.
Giant-11 team is scared
of 11 Bullets bowling.
Now you know why winning
against them is tough.
Their bowling is tough.
Make sure to get Bullet Babu's wicket.
Somehow get his wicket.
Understood? Go ahead!
All the best! Play well.
11 Bullets team has arrived
on the field.
The reason for excitement
is Bullet Babu.
Hey, are you okay?
Venkatesh and Babu
are opening for Blue Star...
Bullet Suman is going to bowl
the first over.
First ball...
-Hey!
-Bouncer!
Fantastic bowling.
-Damn it!
-In two overs, we'll be done.
Suman's bowling is like Ambrose's delivery.
Next ball is to Venkatesh!
Can he face it?
-Catch it!-In the air!
High up in the air.
-Come on, boys!
-Wow, that's a very good catch.
In the first over, there were no runs,
and lost a wicket...
...team Blue Star!
The next batsman is captain, Ranjith.
Ranjith, play well.
He's facing his first ball.
-Good ball! Good ball!
-Bouncer!
Another bouncer!
Suman's bowling...
is dangerous.
Stay and play.
Another bouncer!
Before he could lift the bat,
the ball went to the keeper.
Super, Suman!
Maari is going to bowl next.
Maari's bowling...
Wow, that's a four!
Hey, that's fantastic!
A catch on the leg side.
Another catch,
and Blue Star loses another wicket.
Blue Star is at 5 runs...
in 2 overs and 2 wickets down.
You can't play in all the matches.
That's how the game is.
Let it go!
-Let's wait and watch.
-Is everything okay?
Bala's next ball...
Third down, Sam!
-Lovely bowling.
-Super!
A meticulous defense.
Sam instead hitting runs
you're playing stroke.
Didn't you guys asked me not to
hit all the balls?
That's why I'm playing defense.
Go ahead!
Next ball...
Caught behind!
Blue Star lost Ammukutty's wicket.
Super! Good job!
Next down is Rajesh.
Keep it in control.
Don't let them score.
Next ball...
-That's a super ball.
-Good bowling.
Hey, what happened to you?
He's not a player who plays defense.
Hey, Ranjith,
ask him to start hitting runs.
Anna, ask him to play.
Hey, we're running out of overs.
If you continue this form
we can't make it.
If I tell him he won't listen to me.
Just tell him this.
-Do you want water?
-I don't want it.
-Hey, bowl!
-Hey, Sam, start hitting.
What the hell is wrong with you?
Start hitting!
Sam, you keep playing defense.
You don't have to score.
He's bowling really fast.
You may get hurt.
Take care and play patiently.
Start hitting dude!
That's a sixer!
Fantastic shot!
-Did you see that?
-Come on!
There goes four runs.
Super! Super!
Come on! Come on!
Parthi, be cool and bowl.
-Bullet is advising the bowler.
-Come on!
Let's wait and watch.
Oh! Inside edge bowled out.
Sam's game dwindled in Mani's bowling.
Current, caught out!
Bowled!
Just stay and play.
You don't have to score.
Blue Star's game is slipping away.
There it ends, Blue Star.
98 is the score.
98 is an easy target for 11-Bullets.
-Th opening batsmen will finish the match.
-What happened?
It's not like the match has ended.
We can't easily win all the matches.
Boys, don't lose hope.
Let's try.
Come on!
Even if we lose, it's okay.
Let's go!
-Come on!
-Come on, boys!
Come on.
Let's get to the game.
11 Bullets team batsmen are coming in.
First over is bowled by Rajesh.
-First ball is a sixer on the leg side.
-Catch it! Damn!
Catch it!
Oh, no!
Shall we give Sam an over.
Hey, Ranjith!
Put your head in the game.
It's semi-finals.
Hey, sorry. We'll get it in line.
Come on, boys! Come on!
Sam, come on bowl.
Sam is about to bowl.
Catch! Catch! Catch!
Caught and bowled by Sam!
11-Bullets have lost 3 wickets.
For your information,
the match is about to begin only now.
Star player!
With crackling fanfare!
Now arrives Bullet Babu.
Bullet Babu! Bullet Babu!
Hey, Qasim, you move behind.
Hey, you sit down here.
Machi, take down this wicket.
Amazing shot!
The ball flew high in the air.
A ball from Thiruteni's corner
returns to the corner.
♪ Leg Side ♪
♪ Off side ♪
♪ In side ♪
♪ Out side ♪
♪ It's Babu's side ♪
♪ Full Shot ♪
♪ Late cut ♪
♪ Cover Drive ♪
♪ Sweep Shot ♪
♪ It's Babu's shot ♪
♪ You never saw the devil ♪
♪ My batting is the answer ♪
♪ My batting is the answer, baby ♪
-Next ball!
-Catch it!
-Fantastic bowling!
-They dropped the catch.
-Dropped the catch.
-That's my catch.
Don't you have any sense?
It was coming toward me.
Another ball. And it's a sixer!
Bring me some water.
Someone, please get the ball.
How many are we going to lose?
-Anna!
-What is it?
Why do you not want to play
for Indian team?
It's because it's Indian team.
Anyway they won't take me in.
It's best not to get humiliated.
Why do you like to play for West Indies?
That's my country!
You call our players, players?
They mix too much politics in sports.
Bloody beggars!
I'm waiting for my Visa.
Soon, Lara and I...
will be opening batsmen.
That sounds amazing, Anna.
Over there! Over there!
Run out! Murugan returned
to the pavilion in no time.
The last run cost them...
-Come on, Bharath!
-Hey, Venkat, come here.
We're in team discussion.
Wait for a bit.
They're overdoing it.
They keep switching between them.
-Catch it.-Wicket keeper Ranjith missed the catch.
They missed a great opportunity.
-Don't you know how to catch?
-Hey!
It came directly to your hand.
-Get moving!
-I'm sorry!
Come on, keep it up.
-Damn!
-Hey, what happened?
I'll tell you later.
Ranjith, it's okay.
Rajesh, keep it out.
Ranjith switch the over to Rajesh.
Will this make any difference?
Bullet Babu is getting ready to bat.
Howzzzat! Howzzzat!
Fantastic catch!
Hey, that's amazing.
Sir, it's clean out.
You're being unfair.
Sir, I could hear the nick sound.
Umpire declared it not out.
-Hey!
-How come it's not out?
Sir, it's out!
Sir, umpire, sir. It's clean tip.
Blue Star don't argue with the umpire.
Bullet Babu agreed it's out.
He agreed, nicked the bat,
and walked out.
This is true sportsman spirit.
This modesty is what makes
a great sportsperson.
Bullet Babu is out.
No point in watching the match.
Come on, let's go.
This is true sportsman spirit.
Fantastic fielding, Ammukutty.
-Howzzat!
-That's a run out!
That was handed to them.
They need 7 runs in 5 balls.
Ranjith is making some changes
in the fielding.
This is a crucial time.
Here comes the next ball.
Saran hit the ball!
96 runs with 9 wickets down...
11-Bullets need 3 runs from 4 balls.
Will they hit a 4 to finish the match?
Or will Blue Star get lucky?
3 runs in 4 balls!
As it's the last wicket...
the semi-finals is coming to an end.
It will decide who will be
entering the finals.
Will Blue Star win the match?
There goes the ball!
-Strike!
-Catch! Catch!
It's mine. Leave it!
Catch!
I ended it, Ranjith!
It's a historic moment.
For the first time, Team 11-Bullets
have lost the semi-finals
and did not make it to the finals.
Super! Super!
You guys are amazing players!
But you don't have unity.
If you continue to bicker...
anyone can destroy your team.
Everyone unite and play.
Only then you can win.
Okay! Okay!
Well done. At least in the
next match play united.
-You guys should win the trophy.
-Come on, let's go!
Hey, Ranjith!
We have a match tomorrow.
And you're here!
What happened?
Hey, why do you look upset?
I feel like meeting her one last time.
Shall we?
Let it go!
You said today's her engagement.
I don't think going there
is a good idea.
It will call for unnecessary problems.
Everything went wrong.
That girl did profess her love to you.
Then why did she do it?
Women can't be trusted.
That's not the case!
We never expressed our love
to each other.
I don't even know what is she
going through.
But I can't agree to the fact that she's
getting engaged to someone else.
If I just meet her once...
I will be happy.
She's my dream!
Hey! Hey! Ranjith!
You're crying like a small kid.
First time love failure?
Fine, you want to meet her.
Come on, let's go!
Come on. Get up!
Anna, give me a cigarette.
Hey, I'm going to take a leak.
Anna, two teas.
Please stand on the other side.
Can't you see I'm cutting onions?
♪ I am walking on an unknown path ♪
♪ For I do not have a company,
I talk to my own shadow ♪
♪ Longing to see your face ♪
♪ Listening to your voice
in the breeze ♪
♪ Hey! The cloud
that pushes the train ♪
♪ The crow
that cuddles the rain ♪
♪ The love monster
that pinches the soul ♪
♪ Why am I Going in search of her? ♪
♪ Getting tortured by worry? ♪
♪ Dreaming and becoming a mirage? ♪
Just because we let you walk.
You stepped into our area.
-Hey, hit him.
-Come on, hit him!
Don't spare him. Hit him!
Hey, don't spare him!
Hey, who the hell are you guys?
Hey! Hey, who are you guys?
Hey, break it off!
Hey! Hey, break it off!
Who the hell are you guys?
I'll kill you all!
-Why do you support him?
-He's my friend!
To hell with your friendship.
Would you stay calm if someone
pursued your sister?
Or would you invite him for dinner?
You'd know if it's your sister.
If I see you guys again in this area...
I will be your worst nightmare.
Hey let's go!
♪ We are like two poles ♪
♪ On the two sides of the sky ♪
♪ My truth is looking
for your shadow ♪
♪ When the horizon becomes colorful ♪
♪ After the train leaves its place ♪
♪ I am going to sleep alone
in the evening ♪
♪ I followed her into
an unknown path ♪
♪ Now I'm hurting in solitude ♪
♪ Hey The cloud
that pushes the train ♪
♪ The crow
that cuddles the rain ♪
♪ The love monster
that pinches the soul ♪
♪ Why am I Going in search of her? ♪
♪ Getting tortured by worry? ♪
♪ Dreaming and becoming a mirage? ♪
♪ Hey The cloud
that pushes the train ♪
♪ The crow
that cuddles the rain ♪
♪ The love monster
that pinches the soul ♪
Would you stay calm if someone
pursued your sister?
Or would you invite him for dinner?
What is happening?
-Anna, what are you doing?
-Dig in!
Hey, soon begin work.
Gopal, what's happening?
You're well aware who owns this land.
-Sir has bought this land.
-Why?
He's going to build a petrol bunk.
As per the astrologer...
we need to start the foundation work.
We have to begin work from today.
You people don't waste our time...
and please leave the ground.
Gopal, you know this is the only ground
our boys have to play cricket.
That's why I let them play till now.
Our boys have made it to Finals
in MCF tournament.
So?
How could you do this
during their practice sessions?
Anna, what's this?
-This is our ground.
-How's it your ground?
It's because of me he did not interfere
in this matter.
-Where do we play?
-I don't care!
Go and play in the forest
or somewhere else.
We can't go over there.
We will play over here.
This is our ground!
Hey, arrogance is it?
Do you realize who you're talking to?
Anna, give respect and take respect.
Hey!
-Hey!
-Hey, how dare you?
-Hey, Ranjith, calm down.
-Gopal...
I was going to take my time
to start work.
Tonight I'm sending bulldozer
to clean the ground.
I challenge you!
Do you think we'll sit ducks
and watch it happen?
Times have changed. Scram!
-Hey, Sam!
-What the hell?
Gopal, let's not do it today.
It's not a good day.
I'll consult with the astrologer
and pick a different date.
Come on! Don't get angry, Gopal.
I thought it will be smooth.
But looks like there are
too many conflicts.
Fine, when they return
we'll handle them.
Huh! Come on, let's practice.
Anna!
Ask them why they were silent?
Hey, what is it?
Is it okay, if you don't have
a place to practice?
You guys were silent throughout.
No matter who it is.
Learn to speak with respect.
I know who and when to respect.
-What?-He's incorrigible.
To hell with you!
You guys don't deserve cricket.
I thought playing together
will unite us.
But your heads are filled with nonsense.
Anna, we deserve this and more
for playing with them.
What do you mean by "them?"
Answer me?
Where does this hate come from?
Hey...
Both the teams playing together
itself a victory.
But you proved me wrong
that it's not possible.
Get lost!
Hey, listen closely to what
I have to say.
Hate will lead you to destruction.
But patience will teach you volumes.
Once I returned from the hospital...
I picked up a knife
and went to kill Mani.
I stopped and thought for a moment.
If I kill Mani...
his family will suffer.
That moment of patience saved his life.
If I had killed him and went to prison...
People from both factions would've
fought and killed each other.
It would've stirred a riot.
I would've been a different example
to you guys.
I believed sports will bring us together.
I believe as we played
eventually things will get better.
I don't know.
I don't know what to do.
Remain like this
and eventually die in the end.
Did you notice their arrogance?
They were raising their voice to me.
You guys are to be blamed.
They stood as equal to us!
There's nothing left to say.
My own blood is not with me.
It's all because of him.
Listen closely, Rajesh...
I will arrange a ground
for you boys to play.
If you still go and play with them...
It's equal to have slippered me.
Understood?
Hey, how dare you raise your hand on me?
-Bloody rascals!
-Mani Anna!
-Nothing!
-Come on. Let's go home.
The place I work...
were praising that you boys
are playing amazing cricket.
You're right. Let's go!
You know how happy I am.
They say it's a huge tournament.
That's right. We are playing.
Play well my boys.
Play united!
-Sure we will.
-United play is good.
Everyone play together.
But you should not
fight with each other.
-Okay?
-We won't fight.
Go home safe.
Learn from my life.
Go home and sleep.
You guys are students.
-Be good...
-Watch out!
Had I been educated
I would've lead a good life.
They hollow praised
and turned me into a mess.
In this 6th year
of MCF cricket tournament...
Youth 11 scored 120 in semi-finals.
There goes a sixer.
Giant-11 won the match
and have entered the finals.
The buzz is they will win
the trophy this year.
Super! Maintain the bowling.
Well bowled.
Maintain the bowling.
-Hey, you play.
-Come on, bowl.
-You play. I'm not feeling good.
-What happened?
Had we spoken amicably,
it would've not been worse.
Hey, it's okay if they don't want to come.
His Mama behaves as if he's a big shot.
Why is he coming over here?
Don't you remember
he disrespected your Mama?
Shall we go? It's the finals.
Hey, Current, it's not possible.
-Shut up!
-It's all because of you.
If anyone dares to go,
that's it!
To play on this ground
they need to be qualified.
They did not just insult me.
They, too, know the match is
very important.
They should remain where they belong.
Just because you're holding a bat...
Maximum 10 overs!
11 novice players.
Destroy them!
If you still go and play with them...
It's equal to slippering me.
-Why are they doing this?
-Anna!
I don't care who turns up...
We'll play!
If you throw a stone at the dog...
it'll get scared and run.
Try throwing a stone at a beehive...
we will run in fear.
Do you know why?
Because they unite and chase us.
Similarly, if you're united
you can win anyone and everyone.
Understood!
When the society discriminated
as an outcast...
the Lord took us in like a baby goat.
With his grace we've been blessed
a life with self-respect.
We want our children to excel in education,
economics and politics.
Is the sole purpose of this congregation.
The young boys of our village.
Specifically, Ranjith!
The boys of village have participated
in a huge cricket tournament...
and are on the path to victory.
They have entered the finals.
This is a proud moment for our village.
We should appreciate our children
for their efforts.
Things that are beyond their reach...
the Lord will bless them
with the wisdom to achieve.
Let us all pray
for their well-being and success.
Mama, look our boys picture
is in the newspaper.
I thought they were fooling around
with the bats...
-Impressive!
-They made it!
On this day, we have gathered
as a congregation...
to read the verses for the Lord to hear.
My Lord, bless this this congregation,
its people...
and the neighboring villages.
Young boys of this village are entering
finals in the cricket tournament...
Please bless them to play united
and win this match.
For three successful weeks
MCF cricket tournament is going on...
the finals of 6th year tournament
is going to begin shortly.
People from different cities
have arrived to watch.
Successful league players from Madras
are going to arrive.
We request the fans to co-operate
with the organizers.
Many-time winner Giant-11
is expected to win this time, too.
The situation too seems like
it's going to happen.
But we can't jump to conclusion.
We have to give it to the
Blue Star team...
A small team from a village
has reached the finals.
It's a great achievement.
I don't care who is going to
come with me.
Win or lose we'll play
with the players we have.
Bear this in mind...
Hate will lead you to destruction.
But patience will teach you volumes.
This world has given many reason
not to stay united...
But to stay united,
there's only one reason.
Find out that one reason.
♪ You should know who you are ♪
♪ Change is evident ♪
♪ It is enough if the elephants knows
its strength ♪
Hey, Ranjith, look over there.
♪ You should know who you are ♪
♪ Change is evident ♪
Rajesh, what took you so long?
Nothing! On our way,
we hit a slight snag.
Where is Venkatesh?
He must be on the way.
-Come on, everyone!
-Hey, Bharath!
The critical player on this team
is Nandagopalan.
He can play any shot.
He may play for Indian team.
Drive, cut, defense, hook...
he plays them all!
Second - Sunil.
It's not a good sight see him play.
As far as he's on the crease
the score board keeps ringing.
Following them, Qasim, Hari, and Abinav...
will perform one after the other.
But that's not an issue.
The issue is their bowling.
In their team, there's,
Ashwin, Sriram, and Bala.
One is a King of swing.
He will assign a slip
and take down wickets.
Another will bowl yorker
and break the sticks.
Finally, Bala.
He's a Ranjith Trophy player.
We can face his bowling.
Still we will lose wickets.
He'll bowl to the body.
But we can win them.
If we focus and play.
-Super!
-Come on, everyone!
Shortly they will spin the toss.
Rajesh, will Venkatesh come?
Anna, how long do we wait?
We'll manage!
Final call for the captains.
Team Blue Start where are you?
They're about to spin the toss.
Hey, win the toss.
Both the team captains
have arrived on the ground.
-Fine, fight for it.-Will Giant-11 win the 6th year...
Will they win?
It's a big deal our boys
made it to the final.
Hey...
This opportunity was not served to us.
All these years we were waiting
for this day.
Whether we win or lose...
we need to play united.
We should not give until the last ball.
Get it?
-Come on! Come on!
-Come on, boys!
-We need to nail it!
-Come on!
-Come on.
-Let's bring it on!
Don't miss it. Win this match!
Hey, win this match!
Awesome boys!
The much-awaited final match.
Give me the ball.
On the ground rules are same
for everyone.
You arrived late.
-Bharath, you bowl.
-Okay, Anna.
First ball of the match.
-It's an easy wicket.-Bharath to Sunil...
From Thirutheni corner,
Bharath to Sunil.
That's a good ball.
-Why don't you hit the ball now?
-Get lost!
Well bowled. Come on!
There goes on the leg side.
That's 4 runs!
There rises their score!
Giant-11 is playing a good game.
They've scored 15 runs for 0 wickets.
Next ball to Sapthaseelan.
-Hey!
-Let's make double run.
That's a fantastic boundary.
Ranjith is making changes
to the fielding set up.
Sapthaseelan is batting...
-That's a shot!
-Catch it!
Giant-11 is at 19 runs.
Significant moment in the match.
The playground is about to shatter.
Here comes Giant-11 captain,
Nandagopalan.
We are aware of Nandagopalan's game.
Come on, Rajesh!
Excellent shot! First ball, sixer!
The fans have started
to enjoy the match.
They've been continuously
scoring boundaries.
Well played!
From all directions, this partnership
is scoring boundaries.
Excellent shot!
Four runs in the covers!
The fans are all excited.
Next over...
Rajesh!
from Thiruteni corner to Sunil.
Come on, Rajesh!
Blue Star it's high time
you get your bowling in line.
Rajesh to Sunil.
-Amazing bouncer.
-Catch!
They got his wicket.
Giant-11 lost its second wicket.
Match it not yet over.
We need to keep order.
Tighten the bowling.
Every ball counts.
Come on, let's do it!
-Ravi, you bowl.-6 overs, 53 runs, 2 wickets...
They've created a great partnership.
-Come on, Ravi!
-Come on, Ravi, don't lose it.
Ravi is bowling to Nandagopalan.
Ravi, that was great bowling!
-Ravi, keep it up.
-He just bowled one ball.
Let's see!
Once again, Ravi for you...
-There it goes on the leg side.
-That's an excellent shot.
Another 4 run on the off side.
Six!
Nandagopalan has scored
half a century.
Catch! Keeper catch!
-Fantastic catch by Ranjith.
-Super Anna!
-There goes another wicket.
-Super!
5 balls are up in the 16th over.
The score is at 145 runs for 3 wickets.
Now comes the last ball.
-Bharath is bowling the last ball.
-Come on, Bharath!
Oh!
There's a sixer spiraling to the pavilion.
-Beautiful shot!
-What a shot!
151 runs for 3 wickets in 16 overs.
Giant-11 played a good game.
Giant-11 team looks excited.
Mano and Babu are opening batsmen
from Team Blue Star.
Captain Nandagopalan is setting up
a strong fielding.
Here comes the first over...
from Thiruteni corner,
Bala to Babu.
That's good bowling.
We have a nick name for Bala.
It is Bouncer Bala.
Wow!
Please wear a helmet and play safe.
-Hey, where's the batsman?
-Well bowled, my boy.
Sriram to Babu!
Ah... Howzzatt!
Blue Star lost its first wicket.
Next arrives the team captain, Ranjith.
He's a good batsman.
Last match was not good for Ranjith.
Bala's over. It's a bouncer!
Fantastic shot!
Keepers! Keepers! Keepers throw.
Another one on the leg side.
That's an excellent shot!
Hey!
-Hey!
-What?
First, hit the ball with your bat.
I've noticed you when you play a match.
If the opponent bowler yells at you...
you yell at him back and get out.
Smile at the person who glares at you.
Get lost!
In these moments,
you be like Tendulkar.
Show your anger in the game.
Excellent shot. It's a six!
-A sixer on the leg side.
-Super shot!
Ranjith is playing a fantastic game.
He's playing a patient and composed game.
-Five slips?
-Come on, bowl!
Only on TV do we get to see
such a setup.
They have a strong set up.
Qasim to Mano!
Howzzatt!
Next ball to the power hitter
Ammu Kutty.
-Straight drive!
-What kind of bowling is this?
He's proving his mettle. Next shot!
Howzzatt!
Next batsman is Rajesh.
-Don't rush. We have time.-I hope their partnership works.
Ranjith and Rajesh's partnership
is fantastic.
It's a super shot on the leg side.
With this, Ranjith scores half century.
In 10 overs 81 runs and 3 wickets.
Guys you're rocking it!
Only now can we a relief on the
faces of the team and the spectators.
He's a left-hand-spinner like Ravi Shastri.
Very technical.
Ah!
-Amazing ball.
-Hey!
Hey, what happened?
-Umpire, please check on him.
-Hey, Ranjith!
Injuries are common in matches.
Why did you throw the ball
to the body on purpose?
You got to be careful and avoid injuries.
-Hey, Ranjith...
-Hey, hey, hey...
It's hurting!
Machi, be careful.
-Take him to the hospital.
-Please take him!
This is common in sports.
Players should understand and behave.
Ranjith is stepping out as retired hurt.
Please send in the next batsman.
-Ranjith, don't worry.
-They're doing it on purpose.
The game is in your hands now.
Play well!
-Don't lose the wicket.-Sam is about to face the ball.
-That's a good bouncer.
-Well bowled!
-Keep moving. Watch out for the next ball.
-Sam, let it go!
Excellent shot!
That's a sixer. Excellent shot!
Sam has started to smash.
Run! Run!
Sam is smashing,
yet playing it composed.
If players are not patient,
they'll lose the wicket.
Sam is well-aware of the technique.
In the air!
Sixer!
-Super shot, Sam.
-Fantastic shot. 2 runs!
-Smashing!
-Keep it up!
Sixer! Two more runs!
Rajesh scored an amazing sixer
on offside.
-120 runs in 12 overs...
-Come here!
Blue Star has lot 3 wickets.
Don't you have any sense?
What's happening out there?
We can win, sir.
Nobodies are smashing
and you're doing nothing.
Only after winning can you step out.
Understood? Go!
-Get in and tighten the bowling.
-Come on, boys!
-Keep up the batting.
-Bowl well. Don't try new things.
We don't have an option.
The Thiruteni corner, Sriram to Sam.
-Howzzatt!
-Keeper caught the ball.
They have appealed for out.
Sam's great batting ends
because of caught behind the wicket.
Careful, play well. Score a single.
Whether they'll pass or fuse out...
-Howzzatt!
-...only time will tell.
Caught by the keeper!
Hey, give Rajesh a strike.
That's it.
Rajesh will take care of it.
Bharath is facing Bala's bowling.
-Bowled!
-Well bowled!
-Come on!
-Oh, God, no!
Team Giant-11 is getting back to form.
By losing wickets back to back...
team Blue Star is losing its form.
Oh, catch!
There goes another wicket.
Damn!
Another bowled!
Team Blue Star lost their 8th wicket.
They're down to the last 2 wickets.
A unique player is entering the field.
He wore a helmet to bat.
Clean bowled!
There goes another wicket.
Blue Star has lost 9 wickets.
I swear...
Those guys are nothing compared
to your prowess in the game.
Hey, Ranjith, can you play?
-Don't worry, Ranjith. Be patient.-MCF cricket club's
The cricket ball tournament
-Just stay!-Here comes the last leg of the match.
They're left with only one wicket.
Will Blue Star win the match or not?
Ranjith is team Blue Star's hope.
Will he able to play?
We will know shortly.
Come on!
Smash it to win it!
Sriram bowling from Thiruteni end.
Fantastic bowling.
Ah! What happened?
You will have your moment.
Wait for that moment.
Don't miss it!
Team Giant-11 back in the form.
Come on, make a run.
Keep running!
They ran for a single.
There goes another single.
Bala bowled an amazing bouncer.
-Ranjith is struggling.
-Keeper!
Another single.
Fantastic fielding by Qasim.
They're going for another single.
They blocked a boundary.
Fantastic fielding is happening.
They're trying to make another run,
but it looks impossible.
-Good decision.
-Good throw.
It's a risk to go for another run.
That's a good decision.
They need 13 runs in 6 balls.
Here comes the most crucial part
of winning this match.
First ball from the last over.
Come on! Come on, Sri!
Fantastic shot. Fantastic!
That's a four!
It's a 4! Fantastic boundary.
We'll take him down in next ball.
They need 9 runs in 5 balls.
Who will win?
We'll know shortly.
Come on, make a run.
-Go for a single.
-Single run is enough.
Stay! Stay!
They need 8 runs in 4 balls.
-Run faster.-Ranjith is in the strike position.
-Come on, Ranjith!-Ranjith is facing the ball.
Woah! That's fantastic bowling.
What a delivery!
8 runs in three balls.
Who's going to win?
Blue Star or Giant-11?
4th ball of the match...
Sriram to Ranjith.
Ranjith strikes!
Up in the air
victory is marching towards him.
What a match!
What is happening?
Every ball is an experience.
It's fantastic!
Hey, do something and win it!
Do you get it?
Come on! Come to this side.
Come close.
You come to the front.
You too!
-You stand in the close.
-Come on, Sriram.
-Another strike.
-Come on, run. No stay!
-Stay! Stay!
-Nandagopalan good fielding.
-Come on!
-He did a great job.
2 runs in 1 ball.
Score 1 it's a draw.
-2 runs they'll win.
-This is the last ball.
Keep it in. Don't bowl out.
One ball. You can do it.
Come on, play!
-Come on, Sri.
-Same one, Sri!
Last ball and two runs needed.
The match is gaining momentum.
Ranjith is ready to face
the last ball of finals.
Whether Team Blue Star will win...
This last ball will decide.
Here comes the last ball.
Winning the finals will become
an inspiration to your village.
Sriram is about to bowl
from Thiruteni corner.
You've been waiting for this day.
Smash it!
They will select you for your talent.
Go and play, my son.
Young boys of this village are entering
finals in the cricket tournament...
Please bless them to play united
and win this match.
You should be qualified to play
at this playground.
Qualified!
Ranjith, let's go for another run.
The keeper did not pick up the ball.
-Rajesh!
-Hey!
Come on!
Hey, lift him up.
Lift his head.
Guys come here.
Rajesh pick him up.
Please be careful with him.
Come on!
Everyone must have a doubt.
Did Blue Star win or lose?
Hey, it's a four!
That's a smashing win Blue Star.
A team hailing from a village
took part in MCF and have won...
giving hope and paving way for more.
♪ Cross your legs... ♪
♪ ...and sit ♪
This is a historic moment!.
An era to remember.
♪ Cross your legs... ♪
♪ ...and sit ♪
♪ It is time... ♪
♪ ...you rise ♪
♪ BLUE*STAR ♪
♪ We gonna smash! ♪
Gopal, on that day, they were apart...
but now the village and the colony
have united.
Bring it on!
-Come on! Bring it on!
-Come on!
I dare you to step in.
You believed
they wouldn't unite at all.
Now bring it on!
I dare you to lay your hands on us.
Come on!
No one will return alive.
Try stepping in. You'd know.
I dare you to lay your hands on us.
Anyone who dares to
mess with the playground is doomed.
Hey, below the blue sky...
tress, birds, animals and humans,
everyone is equal!
Beep.