36 photos of you fucking with
your lover, who, by the way
what an ass she has.
Give me 100 million pesos
and l won´t publish them.
And another 100 and
l won´t show them to Margarita.
You are going to pay,
son of a bitch.
Hi, Nicolito,
what do you have for me?
This girl´s name
is Rosemary.
l rented a room from her
less than a month ago.
And ever since she met me,
she calls me Nicolito.
Not Nico, not Nicolasito.
Just Nicolito.
Hey, what´s this shit?
What the hell´s going on here?
What´s this?
What are you doing?
No, no, no. Listen to me.
Tell me, what´s this?
Fucking my girl in my house?
-You don´t have limits.
-What are you doing here?
Aren´t you supposed to be
taking photos?
Yes l should, and you shouldn´t
be fucking my girl.
You know something?
Can you listen to me please?
-Let´s be sensible.
-Sensible, my ass.
-Calm down and hear me.
-Calm down. Okay, tell me.
Can you listen
for a second, please?
-Leave the magazine.
-What?
l don´t want you to work
for me. l´m firing you.
Your offended expression
every day.
lt´s boring for you,
and for me.
Absolutely unbearable.
Let me tell you something,
son of a thousand bitches.
Leave my house
or l´ll break your nose.
lt´s my house.
You have to leave.
What do you mean
you have to leave?
l have to leave.
That´s what l´m saying.
You have to leave.
-No, what you said is not correct.
-Can you shut up just a minute?
Margarita, take it easy,
we´ll talk later.
About what? That since we live
together, l never see you?
-Or that you cheated on me
-That´s not true.
with the models you met?
ls that how you convinced her,
asshole? You´re shit.
You know, you´d better leave.
Mr. Nicolas. Mr. Nicolas.
[Let´s not talk any more.
Wait a minute, it´s a joke.
Tell me the truth.
l know. You are angry at me,
you are a son of a bitch.
You two are allies. You want
to teach me, this is a trick.
Punishment.
No, Nicolas, you are wrong.
l almost believed it, bastards.
He´s too stupid.
You are a son of a bitch.
This is unconceivable.
[Look, listen. l would stay
and play the game
but l have to take some photos
and l´m late.
-Nicolas, wait.
-See you tonight, okay?
Nicolas, this is serious.
l don´t want to see you again.
Please, leave.
[Margarita, l don´t know
what´s going on
[but don´t end everything
just like this, please.
Please. What is this? No.
Have some dignity, Nico.
You´re begging, aren´t you?
l´m going to make shit of you.
[l´m going to finish you.
l´m going to finish you.
Remember...
Look at me when l speak.
Neither your money, together
with your family´s money
will get you out of the mess
l´ll get you into.
You don´t know who l am.
Son of a bitch.
[And this...
this is mine.
[Son of a bitch.
Hi, my little Walter,
come on up.
Go, my boy is here.
Hi, darling, did you bring
something for me?
The same as always,
sweetheart, but more.
Boy, you´re beautiful today.
You´re late, darling.
You should be grateful that l
came, with all the accumulated
work l have,
l almost couldn´t come.
Today, l can´t play, darling,
because l´m in a hurry
but l´ll give you what you want
and it will be fun.
This guy visits Rosemary every
day of the week, at lunchtime
and every time she asks me
to hide and keep quiet
so that Walter will not know
l´m here.
Wow!
Pablo Mallarino and
Margarita Nieto
one year married
and happier than ever.
Happy? Bullshit!
´´Mallarino cheats on Margarita
with a ´´model/actress´´.
Sexy, that´s the truth.
But, of course,
Margarita doesn´t leave him.
[How do l know about
the actress, her address?
The truth is l´ve been following
Mallarino for one year.
Advantages of
unemployment.
What? With the same one?
l can´t believe it, the dumbass
is in love with his lover.
Goddammit!
The turtledoves.
This guy is very cautious
and takes no risks.
Hi, Princess.
-Where are you?
-At the office.
On Sunday?
Yes, on Sunday.
[Thanks for the boots, darling.
-Who´s that?
-She´s a secretary.
[And she also works
on Sunday?
Oh, it´s your wife.
Yes, on Sunday.
Pablo, you are such a liar.
-Touch, they´re very soft.
-A liar? Why?
l called the office.
Hold on, a fax is coming in.
Will you please be quiet
for a moment?
l called the office,
they said you weren´t there.
The doorman is really stupid,
because l told him...
[Shut up!
No, l mean, he´s stupid, because
l´ve been here since 8:00 a.m.
-Hang up. l´m fed up.
-That´s enough.
You´re with that old hag,
right?
Which old hag?
Old hag?
Old hag your mother.
-Don´t leave.
-[Pablo, don´t lie.]
Don´t be stupid,
l know you have a lover.
-l know you are with her.
-[Wait.]
l know her name
and where she lives.
Can we talk?. We don´t have
to shout or to insult.
-l´m done with you.
-Calm down
-we can´t talk about this...
-l´ll pick my things up today
and l´ll leave
your house tomorrow.
Don´t threaten me.
This should be discussed.
You don´t tell someone on
the phone...
Emilia will give you
the divorce papers.
Margarita, you don´t know
what you´re saying
or the importance of... Hello?
[Until you don´t
divorce your wife
-Until you divorce your wife.
-There is nothing between us.
´´You should say:
""Until you divorce your wife"".´´
Cheers, my wife just asked
for a divorce.
lf all your properties were in
my name, l´d do the same.
Again?
We discussed that already.
Everything is in her name, due
to a problem with my brother.
She knows what´s mine.
She´s not like that.
A woman is capable
of anything.
Legally,
everything is in her name?
´´When the word ""legally"" appears,
so will my lawyer.´´
l am definitely going to Spain,
away from you.
Don´t leave.
My career is ending, Pablo.
Nobody will hire me again
and it´s your entire fault.
Don´t leave.
That´s not going to happen.
You´re not leaving.
[The son of a bitch is in love.
And now, goddamn.
What´s wrong with this shit?
l damaged the analogic.
Come on, come on,
what´s wrong, goddamn.
[l knew l could do it.
Beautiful!
[You blundered,
son of a bitch.
No, Nicolas,
l don´t know anyone
who wants to do his Communion
or get married.
You came.
l have something that you
are going to love.
Not these.
These are the ones.
Take a look at them.
Want something to drink?.
36 photos of you fucking with
your lover, who by the way
what an ass she has.
Amazing.
Give me 100 million pesos
and l won´t publish them.
And another 100
and l won´t show them
to Margarita.
You are going to pay,
son of a bitch.
´´A professional photographer
develops at ´´Foto Willians´´?
You know what?
There are in sale.
lf you take 10 photos of an ass
you get a Star Wars watch.
That´s the good part.
The bad part is, there is
nothing here worth while, Nico.
What do you mean?
How much do you want
for the photos?
l already told you,
100 and 100.
-l´ll give you a million dollars.
-A million dollars?
lf you kill my wife.
One moment, one moment.
Kill Margarita?
No, my other wife, stupid.
-You´re crazy. Why?
-Are you interested or not?
How can l be interested?
l see. You´re still in love
with Margarita.
Don´t be stupid, that has
nothing to do with it.
-l´m not a murderer.
-No?
You´re extorting me
so l thought you had no
problem killing someone.
Why don´t you go to hell?
You´re a son of a bitch!
l know, if you change your mind,
call me.
Hi, Nicolito,
do you have something for me?
Did you bring money
to pay the rent today?
-Leave it there, by the mirror.
-Okay.
[Who is it?
Just show yourself.
[Hi baby, come on up!
Look, the boy came by surprise,
stay here, okay?
Where will he take me?
Hi darling, did you bring
something for me?
Hi baby.
What are you doing here
at this hour?
Why do you ask?
Do l have visiting hours now
or what?
Come on baby. You´re so angry.
Problems with your wife?
How did you guess?
l love you when
you´re so angry.
She´s a bitch. l don´t want
to see her again in my life.
Calm down, sweetheart.
Just forget it.
Are we going out to dance?
No, baby, there´s not
enough money.
Oh, darling.
And that money?
Where did you get
this money?
Are you mute?
Where did you get this money?
You gave it to me.
That´s shit. l would remember
if l had given it to you.
-You have another guy, right?
-No!
No, sure,
how stupid can l be?
l work hard to pay
for your expenses
and when l´m not here,
you sleep around.
No, Walter, don´t say that.
You know l adore you.
This´s a lot of money,
where did you get it?
My mother gave it to me.
Shit again. Your mother
doesn´t have a cent.
You´re cheating on me
just for money. What a whore!
Walter, don´t talk like that.
You´re scaring me.
-Sweetheart.
-No, don´t. Don´t touch me!
Shit!
l risked my labor stability
my children and my wife,
and what for?
[To be cheated on with the first
bastard that comes your way.
[Where is your moral,
Rosemary?
[Walter, how can you
believe that, baby.
Sweetheart, you´re my life.
Come here.
Don´t touch me, slut!
[l knew it, l knew it!
l knew l couldn´t trust you.
Very pretty, very young
sooner or later,
l would be wearing horns
and l´ll tell you...
[Now what?
You´re playing victim?
[No, go act in La Candelaria.
Come on, get up!
Get up, l said, Rosemary.
[Rosemary.
Rosemary?
Oh, no!
Oh, no, no.
No, no, Rosemary, no!
[No, you can´t do this to me!
You can´t die like this!
[Rosemary, no, what is this?
Why do you do this to me?
Rosemary!
No, don´t be a shit with me,
Rosemary.
You see what happens when
you do whatever you want?
Now what am l going to do?
Where did l touch?
Yes, there.
Where the money was,
yes, sure.
[Think, Walter.
Perez, don´t be a nuisance,
okay?
But why did you leave,
being on duty?
What if the district attorney
needs you?
What will l tell him?
l´m very busy right now.
We´ll talk later, Perez.
What a problem,
and l just came over to visit.
[Baby, l have to leave you.
What can l do?
Even dead she looks pretty.
Bye, baby.
Don´t think l didn´t have
a good time with you
because l... wow!
l loved you, very much.
l mean,
you know l still love you.
Hey, the gun.
[Baby, can you imagine
if l had left the gun?
Why should l leave
this money here?
l´ll take it.
Okay, now my Queen
of the Highness
rest in peace.
[This is the National Police.
To report an accident...
[Hello.
Okay. l accept.
Accept what? Who is this?
-Guess.
-Guess my ass, who is this?
l can´t tell you now, stupid.
But the deal you proposed
this afternoon
-l accept it, do you understand?
-Nicolas, no more mystery, okay?
Call me when,
when you have done it.
Hold it, how do l know
you are going to pay me?
What do you want,
should we sign a contract?
l´m not talking about a contract,
l don´t know.
Nicolas, stop bugging me.
Call me when you have done it.
Okay.
l´m leaving, l´m going to work.
ls there something
we can do to...
l don´t know,
to avoid all this?
Can we talk for two minutes?
You can talk to Emilia,
l have nothing to talk with you.
Are you still here?
Tulita!
Tulita, someone´s
at the door!
Hi.
Hey, wait a minute, goddamn.
Pablo hired me to kill you.
Do you hear me?
-Get out of here.
-Pablo has a lover.
-Look.
-Tell me something l don´t know.
That´s it,
Pablo wants to kill you.
But l have a plan, you won´t
get hurt and he will pay.
-Look.
-l need your help.
Maybe your girlfriends
would believe that story.
All of them, probably.
They´re all stupid.
ls not time to talk about that.
l´m telling you, is not a joke.
Pablo has a lover
and wants you dead.
l told you what
kind of guy he was.
-Police?
-[Yes Miss, how can l help you?
My ex-boyfriend is here.
He says he´s going to kill me.
[Can you give me
your address?
[Hello, what´s going on there?
Miss, answer please.
[-Where are you?]
-You don´t understand, do you?
[Answer, please answer.
Central office, we must locate...
After what happened with
Rosemary, l´d better check.
Mrs. Margarita, l´m here.
[There were too many people.
Mrs. Margarita, this vase
is broken.
But it wasn´t me.
Mrs. Margarita?
A Peruvian production company
called me.
They want me to do some
episodes for a soap opera.
And if they like my work
if they like it
l get the leading role.
The leading role.
Why are you talking like that?
AN ACTOR PREPARES
lt seems they saw my soap
opera and they liked my work.
With all respect, what the hell
are you going to do in Per£?
l already told you, if you don´t
solve things with your wife
there´s nothing between
you and l.
And what will l do here?
l´m bored here, bored.
Bored.
l have nothing to do except,
wait for you?
l hired someone
to kill Margarita.
You´re so sweet!
So sweet, darling.
l love you very,
very, very much.
You are a very special
person, very special.
-Okay.
-And your intelligence.
-Your intelligence seduces me.
-Okay.
l know what we have to do.
Look, l´ll leave the country
for a while.
l know it´s a difficult moment
for you and you need me.
lt´s also going to be
difficult for me.
But it´s not convenient
for us to be seen together.
l´m so proud of you.
Very proud.
Sorry.
No, brother, what do you
mean he´s a woman?
Goofy is not a woman.
Goofy is not a woman
and that´s it.
What do you mean
he´s a woman?
-Good morning.
-Hello.
ls the gentleman going to stay
over or just for a few hours?
-How much is a few hours?
-We are on sale.
Pay 3 hours and stay 4.
-The 4 hours, then.
-lt´s 50,000 pesos.
Wait a moment.
You said 50,000, right?
Fifty.
Thanks.
And please don´t
interrupt me, okay?
Okay, sir.
Bye, thanks.
With that car and the bastard
doesn´t tip?
We´ll have to teach him
a lesson.
Hi, Montes,
l need your signature.
l´m busy.
Can´t you see l´m busy?
You can´t just come
and interrupt me.
l thought you weren´t busy.
You thought l wasn´t doing
anything, anything at all.
No, but...
What? Are you going
to insult me or what?
No, calm down, l just want
you to sign these papers.
Just a signature...
You know something, Perez?
l´m fed up with you.
And now,
where are you going?
Margarita.
Margarita, l´m going to open.
Margarita, are you awake?
Margarita.
lt´s always the same thing
with you, goddamn.
Calm down, calm down.
Why is everything so difficult
with you, shit.
Yes, l know.
Wait, l didn´t kill her,
she was already dead.
She was already dead.
Calm down.
Just hear me. Calm down,
Pablo hired me to kill you.
But this dead girl
will take your place.
That son of a bitch will pay me
and you will be okay.
l need your help.
Calm down, calm down.
Calm down.
l´ll untie you only if you calm
down, only if you calm down.
Will you calm down? Will you
calm down? Yes or no?
Untie me!
l´ll do it.
Just calm down.
Goddamn, why is everything
so difficult with you?
Why would Pablo
want to kill me?
How would l know?
He´s an asshole.
You´re a liar!
You kidnapped me for money.
You´re a bastard.
How can you think of
something like that?
Margarita, think,
Pablo has a lover.
Look, look, look.
She probably convinced him
that you´ll keep everything.
Look!
You don´t understand,
do you?
You don´t understand that
l´ll save your life?
You don´t realize that.
l look like shit! Everything
with you has to be like that.
But, of course, with Pablito
everything is fine.
Let´s see.
-Take off your clothes.
-What?
-Hello, Ana.
-Good morning, sir.
-Anything new?
-No, sir, no important calls.
But she is waiting for you.
-Where is she?
-ln the waiting room, doctor.
Yes, l know what
you´re thinking.
There are methods
to prove she´s not Margarita.
l also watch CSl
But l don´t care.
l need this to last long enough
for Mallarino to pay me.
Afterwards, if he finds out she´s
another one, l don´t care.
What can he do? Sue me?
Oh, excuse me, l thought
you had already left.
-Hello, Emilia. How are you?
-Hello, Pablo. Fine, and you?
Pablo, l am here
representing Margarita.
And you brought
divorce documents?
Yes.
As you know, Margarita decided
to ask for a divorce
due to reasons of which
we are all aware.
So?
She also renounced to all the
properties that were hers.
Therefore, Mr. Mallarino,
they´ll be back in your name.
The properties in her name
are just a screen.
As a lawyer,
you´d understand.
What?
My client gave up her rights to
her part of property and money.
And also decided not to initiate
legal action against you.
Decisions with which,
l must say l totally disagree.
So, she´s not going
to demand
and does not want a cent of
my money or any of my things.
Are we completely
sure of that?
Yes, we´re sure.
And why?
Because Margarita is
economically independent.
She doesn´t need money from
anyone to get ahead in life.
Goddamn!
What the shit is happening?
l have to make an important,
personal phone call.
What?
You can´t wait a second
to call your lover?
No, don´t worry,
Mr. Mallarino.
And one last thing.
lf you need to contact
Margarita, do it through me.
And, as she herself told you,
when you get home tonight
-she will not be there.
-l know!
Okay. Have a good day.
[How stupid!
Am l stupid or what?
Goddamn.
-Hello.
-Nicolas, where are you?
Wait, l don´t understand.
l can´t hear you,
l have no signal.
-Nico!
-Hold on, please.
Nicolas, l can´t hear you.
-[Do..wh..yesterday..no..]
-What the hell now?
[Do..do..thing..
-[Can you..stand
-Hello, hello.
-Yes
-[..what l´m saying?
-[About what we talked.
-What?
Nicolas, don´t do it, okay?
Can you hear me?
Yes, l heard you, l heard you,
but that´s not...
[-Nicolas]
-That´s not what we agreed.
l don´t give a shit,
just don´t do anything.
[Yesterday we agreed that,
but today l changed my mind.
-[Don´t do anything.]
-Goddamn!
-[Nicolas, did you hear me?]
-Goddamn! Goddamn life!
[Nicolas, what´s wrong?]
-Goddamn life! Shit!
-[Where are you?
[Nicolas... Hello.]
-Goddamn!
-[Nicolas, do you understand me?
[Did you hear what
l said or didn´t you?
l have to hang up.
Why then, do they always
explode in the movies?
[-What´s that?
-What happened?
Baby, did they already
find you?
Did they take off your clothes
and that?
Damn them.
Oh, this man.
Hello, hello!
This shit hasn´t been
invented yet.
Hi, stupid.
-Where are you?
-What do you want?
What do l want?
You should be here.
[The district attorney asked us
to investigate a car accident.
-Can l help you?
-No, thanks.
Wait, where do you think
you´re going?
Hey, what´s wrong with you?
Where would l go? To my room.
-What room?
-Mine, of course.
[-You can´t go in.
-lt´s my room.
-l already paid.
[-l don´t care, you can´t go in.
-You don´t care?
[l´d say it in a nice way,
you can´t go in.
Where are you going?
Let go of me!
What´s wrong with this guy.
Calm down. lf you don´t calm down,
l´ll have to call the cops.
Brother, l´m staying here.
What´s the problem?
What do you mean you´re staying
here? You left an hour ago.
l paid 4 hours, l´ve been here 3,
l still have 1 hour left.
l´m going to my room. Excuse me.
Let go of me, shit.
-Please tell this chimp to stop.
-Don´t insult the kid.
Understand brother,
this is not a hotel.
-Of course, it´s a pigpen.
-lt´s not a hotel.
You came here
with a girl and left.
Pay attention to me,
you left with her.
Do you understand?
You came and left with the girl.
Once you leave,
you can´t come back in.
Look, there´s someone inside,
someone is inside.
l have to go in now, okay?
No, you went in with a girl
and left with a girl
there was no one else.
Brother, there´s another girl
inside, l´m going in, bye.
-Wait a moment, wait!
-Let go of me!
-What´s wrong with him?
-Hold on.
ls this guy drugged?
You have to tell me
if there´s an extra person.
l´m telling you now, stupid.
There´s another person in
the room. Can l go in?
Well, the other person
has an extra charge of 25,000.
So that was the problem, huh?
Money.
-Everything has its price.
-For money, the monkey dances.
Here, buy the monkey
a banana.
Ok?
Bye.
Go ahead. What a bastard.
Your husband
doesn´t want you dead now.
What a coincidence.
He doesn´t want me dead now
or he never wanted it?
Now what the hell
am l going to do?
There has to be a way
to make him pay us.
Liutenant
-buy them a cup of coffee, thanks.
-Yes, sir. Let´s go.
What´s new?
Perez!
-Hello, Montes.
-What happened?
Supposedly, we have
a car accident.
´´The car´s smashed.
What do you mean ""supposedly"".´´
l think the girl was dead before
the car ran off the road.
Before?
-She´s rigid already or what?
-More or less.
What else?
We found a bottle of liquor
in the car.
Her papers and her purse were
in the shrubs.
The car is in her name.
So, you believe this is
a sham or what?
lt seems her name is
Margarita Nieto.
And guess whose wife she is.
No Perez, this is serious
business. Guess...
Guess!
Perez!
Pablo Mallarino.
No, no, wait a moment,
Pablo Mallarino, of the...
-the Mallarinos, the Mallarino?
-The same one.
Wow! Then we really
have to work.
Your car did not explode,
Rosemary is almost intact.
The police will immediately
notice that the girl´s not you.
[And will tell Mallarino.
What can l do for
the bastard to pay us.
What can we do for
him to pay us.
You´re right.
This woman is the wife
of that Mallarino... Pablo.
l don´t watch T.V., but l have
seen her in the show biz news
arriving at those parties
they go to.
Well, l´ve never
seen this woman.
That´s not strange,
you never watch T.V.
Think, stupid, think...
What can l do?
lt´s depressing that young
people die like this.
Well, that´s life.
You have the woman´s l.D.,
right, Perez?
-lt´s there.
-There, where?
-lt was in her wallet.
-There´s nothing here.
Don´t tell me you lost it,
Perez.
No, impossible, it was here,
in the wallet.
What a problem!
Now we´ll have to wait until
the fingerprints are compared.
You did take
the fingerprints, right?
Of course l did.
Couldn´t the fingerprint expert
have taken the l.D.?
No way, l didn´t let anyone
get near until you arrived.
What a problem, Perez.
We could have identified
this woman right away.
You two! Look for the
deceased´s l.D. immediately.
Come on! Get to it!
And pay close attention,
from now on, l, personally
will take charge of everything
related with this case.
ls that clear?
Wow, Superman.
-What did you say, Perez?
-That l think it´s super.
l think it´s super also.
And in legal medicine, only l
will see the forensic report.
Did you finish, doctor?
No sir, l still need
some more.
Don´t take any more,
give me the camera.
l´ll download
those photographs.
l don´t want them
to also get lost!.
What a blunder, Perez,
what a blunder.
What we will do
is the following.
We´ll call Mallarino to tell
him that l kidnapped you
and that, if he wants
to see you alive
he has to give me
what he offered me to kill you
then we keep the money.
What do you think?
What do l think?
l´m kidnapped
and stop talking about ´us´,
as if we were in this together
because you´ll pay for killing
that woman and kidnapping me.
Margarita, please help me,
don´t leave.
Help you? Ask the models
you fucked for help.
[Pathetic madman!
Margarita, this is not the time
to talk about that.
-What are you doing here?
-Can we talk?.
-No.
-Yes.
Pablo, our agreement was
that we would not meet
until it was over.
l have something to tell you,
can l come in?
Margarita doesn´t
want anything.
She doesn´t want money or
properties and will not demand.
-There´s no need to kill her.
-Now you´re stupid.
Stupid, why?
-l can´t believe what you did.
-What did l do?
Obviously she doesn´t want
anything now
but when we get married,
she´s going to want everything.
What belongs to her by law
and what belongs to me.
-She´s not like that.
Again, she´s not like that?
You don´t seem
to know women.
Don´t be so naive.
l´ll have her sign a document
renouncing to everything.
lf she asks for money,
l can sue her, okay?
Killing her seems drastic
to me.
l didn´t think
you were so stupid.
l have to leave.
Don´t leave, please.
[Start the car, let´s go.
Don´t leave, driver,
stupid, l´m talking to you.
Shit, l´m begging.
Let´s see baby,
help me understand.
Why were you dressed
in that woman´s clothes.
l have to find that woman,
before anyone else
because if she says she´s not
the person we found in the car
goddamn, you understand?
l´d really be in big trouble.
[Hi, this is Rosemary.
[l´m not at home. Please leave
a message, we´ll talk later.
[Bye.
[Hi, Rosemary, is your mother.
Where are you?
[l´m worried. Why weren´t
you there this morning?
[Please, call me when
you get home.
There has to be
a clue somewhere.
She did have a son of a bitch
living here. l was really stupid!
And this?
What´s this?
This is the same woman.
Those two are
working together.
So this was the bastard
who put you into that car.
And now the other bastard.
What do you want?
What do l want?
Where are you?
Where am l?
lnvestigating, of course.
But, Montes,
you should be here.
We haven´t called the woman´s
husband for identification
-because you have the photos.
-Yes, of course.
Call him, tell him
l´m on my way.
-Okay, sir.
[-And do me a favor]
lnvestigate where
can l find a man whose name is
take note
Nicolas Andrade.
He´s a photographer,
height, 5´11 approximately.
With dark skin and dark hair.
Don´t inform anyone. Just me.
And don´t do anything until
l tell you, understood?
-ls he related with the case?
-What do you think?.
That l am a fag,
asking you for men?
Of course he´s related with
the case, stupid, what else.
And remember what
l told you.
My God, give me patience.
Celebrating his trophy.
Don´t think l´m such a...
[Stop a for a second,
we have to talk.
Go on, go on don´t stop.
[Can you stop for a second?
Stop, just a second, shit!
Did they tell you the
service was by hours?
No, ma´m.
Then drive faster
so we can lose him.
l can´t do that, ma´m,
l´d get a ticket.
Ana Maria, l´m busy.
l´m sorry, but you have a call
from the police.
Seems that something
happened to your wife.
Just wait,
l´ll transfer you the call.
-[Mr. Mallarino?
-Yes, that´s me.
-[Mr. Pablo Mallarino.
[The 4 hours are over.
[lf you want to stay longer,
pay for the night.
[Hello?
Hello, did you hear me?
Son of a bitch,
they clobbered this man.
Sir. Hey, sir, wake up. Get up.
Wake up, wake up.
That´s it, that´s it.
The 4 hours are over.
lf you want to stay longer,
pay for the night or leave.
Shit!
Margarita took all the money.
No, no, no. l can´t take you
if you don´t pay.
Please don´t leave me here!
Hey! You don´t lose anything!
[Who?
That woman you were with?
[She must be a fiend.
Look what she did to you.
Did you see her?
Where did she go?
She left a while ago,
walking toward Bogota.
l don´t have money for a bus.
l´ll give you the 100 pesos
you need for the bus, okay?
We cover her eye,
yes, correct.
l lost everything,
what happened?
´´Of course, ""Enter"" you moron.
Technology really helps.´´
[Brother, let me take a shower,
l promise you l´ll leave.
Do you think l´m stupid?
No way, l told you,
you have to leave now
or l´ll call the watchman.
He´ll take you out.
Okay, let´s do that.
Go look for the watchman.
When you return, l´ll be gone.
What do you say?
What the hell do you think?.
Are you making fun of me?
No, no, no, brother.
Don´t be a bastard.
Five minutes is all need.
Five minutes and you
won´t see me again.
-Forget it.
-Wait, just listen to me.
l have a proposal,
five minutes.
lf l haven´t left
in five minutes
you and the chimp
can kick my ass.
-Only five minutes.
-Yes.
-l said, five minutes.
Five minutes. lf you stay longer
which l´m sure...
-You have four and a half!
-Suck my balls.
l heard you, you know?
l heard you.
Asshole!
l just hate wealthy people.
Those bastards really
make me sick.
How annoying.
[Good afternoon.
[l´m Pablo Mallarino,
l´m looking for Walter Montes.
[-Detective l think, or Lieutenant.]
-Yes. Come with me, please.
Detective, Mr. Pablo Mallarino
is looking for you. Come on in.
The face of the person
in the photos
was quite disfigured,
because the impact was... right?
You wouldn´t have recognized
her anyway.
That´s why l covered her with
this blurry rectangle.
Why? Because it would be
terrible, apart from your grief
to have a disfigured image
of her. Do you understand?
Yes, it´s okay, it´s okay.
Well, the idea Mr. Mallarino,
is for you
to tell me if, apart from the car,
you can identify
some of the objects your wife
had with her.
That is, her watch, her clothes,
things like that
and physically,
some small details, l don´t know.
Some mark, a mole, the hair.
Yes? Are you ok with that?
Yes, those are the clothes she
was wearing when l said good...
At home, when l left...
when l left this morning,
she had those clothes on.
Her appearance,
there´s no doubt it´s her.
The hair that l saw was...
The watch that we saw before.
Can you go back?.
Yes.
The watch, l gave it to her,
for her birthday.
The necklace is also hers.
Mr. Mallarino, are you ok?.
Yes.
We found this purse
near the car.
We didn´t find her
identification card.
But there´s a wallet
with other documents.
l would like for you to check
and try to identify these things.
Do you recognize
what you see? Do you?
Yes, it´s...
They are her things.
lt is Margarita.
lt was Margarita.
Well then.
This is a copy of
the forensic report.
Since we didn´t find
any identification card
we sent the fingerprints we
took, to the Register Office.
But what for?
To be compared and matched
with the records of your wife.
However, the Register has too
much work due to the... yes?
And l think it will take quite
a while, let´s say
a year or so, before they
send the results.
However, with your
identification of her belongings
l think we are more than
certain that it is your wife.
And, Mr. Mallarino,
believe me, l am really sorry.
What does it say there?
Where?
-On that report.
-Oh, yes.
What it says is that
several hours before the
accident, your wife was dead.
And that they found alcohol
in her throat and esophagus.
We believe it was introduced,
the alcohol
after she was dead.
Why? Because the body
hadn´t absorbed it.
Okay, what does
all this mean?
lt means that
it was a murder,
that´s what we believe.
[Attention. Breaking news.
[Police found the body
of designer Margarita Nieto
[wife of the businessman
Pablo Mallarino
[owner of several companies in
different communication media.
[Our reporter, Nana Velasquez,
at the site of the news
[with more information.
Nana.
[Thank you, Anabel.
[Official sources of
the judicial police
[confirmed,
for this news program
[that the theory of Margarita
Nieto´s death
[due to a car accident,
was just discarded.
-What?
-[New clues suggest a murder.]
[The main suspect is
photographer Nicolas Andrade
´´[Nieto´s ex-fiance and former
employee of ""Fashion Blue""´´
-No, no, no, no!
-[also owned by Mallarino.]
Sir, one more thing
do you know of anyone who
could have killed your wife?
No.
l don´t know if it means
anything... Yesterday
l mean, if it could be useful
for something
a guy called me
an ex-boyfriend of Margarita´s,
and he was really aggressive.
He was altered, anxious,
and l took this precaution.
l always carry this
because l had an unpleasant
experience with some reporters
and l recorded him.
Wait, l´ll turn it on.
lt´s digital and it´s not easy.
[Give me 100 million pesos
and l won´t publish them
[and another 100
[and l won´t show them
to Margarita.
[Now you are going to pay,
son of a bitch.
[Yes, we found
a tape recording
[in which Nicolas Andrade
[tries to blackmail Pablo
Mallarino, asking for money
[but can´t get anything
from him.
[From Mallarino.
[The clues lead us to believe
that he may have murdered
[well, could have murdered.
[Murdered Mrs. Margarita Nieto,
moved by personal vengeance.
That´s the bastard
who killed Rosemary.
[That´s all.
[We have a recording of a call
made this morning by Margarita
[in which she tries to ask
for help from the police
[but someone restrains her.
[-Police.
-Yes Miss, how can l help you?
[My ex-boyfriend is here.
He says he´s going to kill me
[Can you give me your address?
Hello, what´s going on?
[Central office,
we must locate...
Aren´t recordings confidential,
by Law?
What the shit are they doing?
What is the news program
doing?
The person in the recording
is not, by any chance
the same one in this photo?
[How stupid.
[l didn´t realize that
Mallarino planned everything.
[l´m stupid.
Son of a thousand bitches.
Now what the hell l´ll do?
Son of a thousand midget
bitches. What can l do?
What can l do?
Son of a thousand midget
bitches. What can l do?
Here´s my card.
Call me if you have information
that might help us.
Or, just if you need
anything, okay?
-Fine. Good bye.
-Have a good day, sir.
Do you have 3 minutes?
The truth is... l don´t,
because
l´m going to try
to find that guy.
lt´s him l want to talk
to you about.
No, yes okay, sit down.
Listen to me, Walter.
l wanted
to propose you a deal.
Oh, no sir.
You´re making a mistake
with me.
But you don´t even know
what my proposal is.
l am a detective
of the judicial police.
-l know.
-l won´t move a single finger
for less than double.
[This is a photo of Nicolas when
he was Margarita´s boyfriend.
[The police offers
a generous reward
[to whoever gives information
about the suspect.
Son of a bitch, it´s that guy.
Wilmer!
Wake up. Bring the gun.
Go check the bathroom.
He escaped through
the window.
Bastard. We were close
to earning that money, man.
Julito!
Mr. Nicolas.
-Julito, how are you?
-Come on in.
-What´s new?
-l was thinking about you.
-ls that so?
-Yes, sir.
No, Julito, a big hug first.
lt´s been a long time, please.
My brother, my pal,
how have you been?
Fine, sir.
You were thinking about me,
you say?
l watched the news and heard
they murdered your girlfriend.
-No.
-Well, your ex-girlfriend.
-No way.
-Yes sir.
-But it can´t be true.
-Come here.
No, it must be a mistake.
Are you sure?
No, it was...
the other channel.
Hold on, l´m telling you,
look.
[The main suspect is Nicolas
Andrade, Margarita´s ex-fiance
Mr. Nicolas, is that you?
Mr. Nicolas.
[... kilometer 23,
on the road towards Choachi.
That bastard stole my tools.
Mr. Nicolas. Mr. Nicolas.
Mr. Nicolas.
Mr. District Attorney,
how are you?
[Not too well.
Sorry to wake you up, huh?
[A news program called,
on the case of Mallarino´s wife.
[l looked really bad, because
you haven´t sent me the report.
l´m sorry, Mr. District Attorney.
l´ve been very busy.
[Busy? l´ll give you some work.
l need that report, immediately.
No, no, yes, of course.
l was just going out to look for
an important guy for the case...
[l don´t give a fuck! Send me
that report immediately!
Son of a bitch.
Okay, l´ll send it.
Hi. Aren´t you an actress?
And where are you going?
-To Madrid.
-On vacations?
More or less.
-l have to answer.
-Go ahead, answer, l´ll wait.
l told you l don´t want
to hear from you.
So please don´t call me again.
Ever!
Fighting with the boyfriend?
l have to leave.
Wait a second.
Give me an autograph.
Here, please.
Stop fighting with the boyfriend.
That´s not nice.
[Hi. This is Alexandra.
Please leave your message.
[Alex, don´t leave. Please don´t
leave before we talk.
Something happened
and changes everything.
Don´t leave. l need...
Call me before you leave.
Don´t move.
Don´t move, huh?
Stay still.
What are you going to do
hit me on the head
until you kill me?
Listen, you´re going with me
to the police station
and you´re going to confess
that you hired me to kill her.
l have to get
out of this mess.
Come on.
-l´m not going anywhere.
-l´m going to kill you!
Do whatever you want.
Do whatever l want?
l´m going to kill you, stupid.
Look, brother,
if you don´t help me
l swear, l swear to God
that l´ll kill you
and then l´ll kill myself.
l´m fed up.
You´re stupid.
l told you not to kill Margarita.
Don´t be stupid.
l´d better say,
don´t play stupid.
As if she was not
involved in all this.
lnvolved in what, stupid?
How can a dead person
be involved in something.
Margarita is alive.
l never killed her.
So the 1 7 photos l saw are of
a dead body that doesn´t exist.
Wait a moment.
That policeman made you
believe it was Margarita
[to cover Rosemary´s murder.
[He is a son of a bitch.
[ls this ´the biggest
son of a bitch´ contest?
Yes, and you´re winning.
Well, think and decide
what you´re going to do.
You know something?
l´m fed up.
Don´t fuck with me!
Don´t fuck with me anymore,
stupid.
So now Margarita is not
involved in this, huh?
No, she´s not involved.
She´s not involved
because she´s dead.
She´s dead, damn it,
she´s not involved.
Drop that gun.
And go have that shit sewed.
What? What thing?
-Montes.
-Hey, you won the Golden Mongol.
-What did you say?
-What you heard.
Margarita is alive,
and he´s here and he´s armed.
Where are you?
Scratching your balls!
Why do you think he hired
me to kill you?
To have someone to blame
once you were dead.
l am the only person who has
a motive to kill you.
l´m your ex-fiance.
He married you, he fired me.
The perfect reason.
But he never thought
l wouldn´t kill you.
Enough. Shut up.
lf you don´t help me he´ll
kill you and then he´ll kill me.
Don´t worry, l´ll be right
there to fix everything up.
-What did he say?
-That he´s just coming over.
Baby, you see what happens
with the things you do?
Now that man, he´s rich,
he´ll shit on everything.
And they´ll find out
that l killed you.
Montes, l received a call
from a motel near Bogota.
Nicolas Andrade was there
with two women.
Get out of my way.
And now,
where are you going?
Again, Montes?
Leaving while you are on duty?
l´m not going to cover you,
no sir.
lf the Attorney calls,
l´ll tell him you left.
l don´t care.
[Don´t trust that policeman.
He killed Rosemary
and he´s going to kill us.
Shut up.
What´s wrong with you?
Do you think he´s not
going to kill you?
You fucked his alibi,
he´ll kill you first!
Keep your big mouth shut!
That shit of a gun
had to be yours, huh?
Bastard.
The list of disappeared people.
You take charge of this.
Son of a bitch!
lt´s the same woman.
Now what?
No! Go to hell, Perez.
[This is Walter Montes´ number
[Leave your message
after the tone.
-The answering machine again.
-[Thank you.]
[Fuck, how do you
turn this off?
Montes, the woman we found is
not the wife of that rich man.
l´m on my way
to talk with the man.
Meet me there.
[Passengers of Transcontinental
Flight 535, destination Madrid.
[ln a few minutes,
we will start boarding.
Excuse me.
Can you do me a favor?
l´m not signing
autographs today.
No, we just want to sit down.
-Go ahead.
-Thank you.
-People!
Did you hear?.
They killed Mallarino´s wife.
-The owner of ´Fashion Blue´?
-Can you imagine?
But, how? When?
l don´t know.
l saw it on the news today.
Hello.
Where is the funeral?
lt´s... long distance call.
Why do you call me at home?
[lt doesn´t matter, she is dead.
Everything worked out fine?
l can´t talk now.
l´m going to hang up.
You´re mad at me.
[l know l was rude,
but l love you.
lf you want
l won´t go to Madrid.
[l know that´s not what
we agreed, but
if you want,
l´ll stay here with you.
-What a bitch!
-Shh, they´re going to hear you.
Who said that?
l´m going to hang up.
So?
l can´t untie this.
Of course, you tied it.
So it was true
that you wanted to kill me.
l told you.
He planned everything.
You´re stupid, aren´t you?
l didn´t plan anything.
lf you hadn´t blackmailed me
with those photos
l wouldn´t proposed
you anything.
Finally.
Open the door.
Open the fucking door.
That gun doesn´t work.
You open.
Where were you?
lt took you a long time.
This is quite far.
Besides, with these streets,
full of holes...
-Stop whining.
-l could ruin the car...
[And who´s going to pay?
Not you, l´m sure.
Those parking lot bastards
stole my gasoline again.
Now where can l find
a gas station?
[Aren´t you a police?
Arrest my husband,
he tried to kill me.
Margarita, he´s not going
to help us.
-l told you not to trust him.
-This man killed a woman.
He wants to make her appear
as Margarita. Just arrest him.
Stupid, l didn´t kill anyone.
l didn´t kill anyone.
-Okay, shut up, all of you.
-He killed Rosemary.
And he´s going to kill you
and all of us.
-Silence!
-Don´t believe him, he´s a killer.
-Don´t be cynical.
-He´s a son of a bitch.
Just shut up!
l am the law here.
You all do what l say.
And you?
You proposed a deal
this afternoon.
Are you going through
with it?
Nico?
What you have to say
is the following.
You arrived home.
You noticed something strange
inside and called me.
You waited for me.
-We went in together.
-Nico?
And we saw this son of a bitch,
armed.
The man tried to shoot me,
but you know
l was faster and killed him,
in self defense.
We have to untie him
and put the gun near him.
That´s all.
Nobody saw anything in here.
Nobody heard
anything in here.
ls that understood?
Hey Montes, where are you?
l´m at Mallarino´s
waiting for you.
l am, l am detective
Ricardo Perez.
l need help.
l just heard a shot.
l need back-up.
The address is...
What about her?
l´ll help you with that,
no charge.
l´ll take her away
and make her disappear.
No car blunders, nothing like
that. She´ll disappear forever.
But just one thing.
You can´t talk.
Well, you have to say that the
woman we found is your wife.
Until you die.
Do you agree?
Okay then, fine.
Nobody move!
Perez, take it easy Perez.
l have everything
under control.
Montes, the woman we found
is not this man´s wife.
Of course not.
Can´t you see her here?
Perez do me a favor, wait
outside and call the people.
l already called.
Wait outside, brother.
No Montes, l don´t
like what l see.
This guy was tied.
You are the only one
with a gun here.
So you killed this man.
And he was tied.
l can´t leave, Montes.
Brother, l don´t want
to kill you.
But if l have to, l´ll shoot you.
At the count of three.
One...
Bastard, two.
Don´t be a son of a bitch.
Okay.
Okay, Montes, l´ll...
l´ll wait outside.
Don´t go.
Don´t go. Nico?
l´ll wait outside.
Nico, Nico, Nico don´t you die!
You see, Perez?
lf you hadn´t come, this bastard
would have killed us all.
Forgive me.
Forgive me for
not believing you.
-l though you´d never say it.
-Bastard.
Nicolas is alive,
call an ambulance.
[l suppose you want to know
how l lived
[if l was shot
on a close range.
[The two envelopes with photos
deflected the bullet´s path
[so that it passed
near to the heart
[without touching
any important organ.
l suppose l was lucky, right?
Wow, look who came.
What an old man, my God.
How are you?
Better than you.
Yes? Well, that´s not difficult.
Look at me.
l came to give you this.
The other envelope was
destroyed by the bullet.
-Did you see the photos?
-Yes.
How long have you
been doing this?
l started after
our separation.
That means that
you´ve been following me
for a year and a half
taking photos?
-Stupid, right?
-Stupid.
Wait, wait.
-Did you come to laugh at me?
-Yes, exactly.
Yes? Very nice.
You like it, don´t you?
Bye.
Bye, sweetheart.
l forgot something.
Yes?
Are you going to behave?
Yes, yes, l´m going to behave.
You´d better.
Give me a call
when you get out.
To take you home.
[Do you want to know what
happened to the rest? Okay.
As you can imagine, nothing
happened to Mallarino.
There was no investigation.
Nothing at all.
[He paid Walter to accept full
responsibility and keep quiet.
[His sentence wasn´t long.
[l didn´t die.
[Rosemary was an accident.
[There wasn´t much
against him.
[Perez got the best part, he was
promoted to Chief Detective
[and was given
Walter´s office.
[Now, Margarita
[asked Mallarino for much more
than half of his fortune
[as retribution for not accusing
him and for leaving him alone.
Take it easy Pablo, this is a
piece of cake. Asshole.
´´[Mallarino´s lover,
""actress/model""´´
[never went to Madrid.
[But, when she realized Margarita
was alive and Mallarino was poor
[she accepted the offer and
went to Per£ to work.
You know, if l place my hand
like this, it´s super organic.
[And that´s all.
The end.
Sarah, you did it wrong again.
Everyone ready!
Chapter 2536, scene 25,
take 18, shooting right now.
Five, four, three...
Carlos Lopera
our relationship
is impossible.
But, Natalia
l love you.
l know
but...
l am, l am your real
twin sister.