That'll replace your Adam's apple
from the front of your neck
to the back.
Now a leaping, flying body press,
and that is going to be illegal
because he got him with an elbow,
but they're
not gonna call anything.
This referee might as well
be home watching T.V.
Harry Smilac looking on,
pounding in disgust,
now he's trying to get to his feet. Now,
here's Rick, staggering around.
Oh, look at this!
It's an overhead body slam!
T #
# Body, body body, body r
# body, body body, body #
# I shouldn't be here
touching you #
# and I shouldn't love
the way you feel #
# I know you've got somebody
waiting at home #
# I tried so hard
to tell you no #
# but when you touch me
like you do #
# my best intentions
keep falling apart #
# oh, lord #
# and just when I find
the strength to leave #
# you put your magic spell
on me #
# and baby, I can't hold on #
# my body keeps
changing my mind #
# keeps changing my heart,
keeps changing #
# I lose control #
# my body keeps
changing my mind #
# keeps making me
break down, baby #
# I can't say no #
# my body keeps
changing my mind #
# keeps changing my heart,
keeps changing #
# I lose control #
# my body keeps
changing my mind #
# keeps making me break down
in my heart #
# you control me
when you're around me #
# I'm on fire
# I take me higher #
# I feel just like a fool #
# I can't get over you #
# you know the way I feel #
# I never felt before #
# your love is so unreal #
# keeps me knockin'
at your door #
# you know the way I feel #
# I never felt before #
# your love is so unreal #
# keeps me knockin'
at your door #
# body, body body, body #
# body, body h'
I'll take it, pal.
Yeah, right. And, uh, listen,
uh, don't park it
near anyone, buddy.
I, uh, I don't need any dings on the doors,
do you know what I mean, uh?
Message for you, Mr. Smilac.
Ah! Great.
Hey! Hey, you!
Brooks, get me my lawyer, ok?
Get me Sheldon Brockmeister
on the phone.
Did you forget to sent him
a check last week?
So what?
By now that baby'll be
bouncin' all over his office.
Well, that'll just give him a very
good reason to see me, won't it, huh?
Oh... will you just call
Sheldon's secretary?
Oh, and, uh, tell her
I'm... I'm racing right over.
Your dime.
2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8. Yeah.
Back, 2, 3, 4.
Bigger circles. Come on.
Right. Forward, 2,
3, 4, 5, 6, 7, and 8.
Take a break.
Whoo!
See that?
Gimme 3 weeks,
I'm gonna look just like that.
Well, I can hardly wait.
Uh, Shelly, what... what
employment agency do you use?
Talk, Harry. I know it's serious,
or you wouldn't be here.
Especially after
that check you sent me.
Oh, that was just
a bookkeeping error.
All I do is put
the check through again.
But look, I need your,
uh, expert legal advice
on a few minor matters here.
Before you go on, you should know
I'm charging $400 an hour
to listen to this.
$400?
Uh, right.
Ok, number 1: My car has
been repossessed. Again?
Shapiro's gonna evict me
if I don't get the rent by Friday.
I was handed a subpoena.
Harry, you know,
I just don't understand you.
You're a smart guy.
For a while,
you had the midas touch.
I mean, your acts were winning grammys,
people really liked you.
But lately, excuse my French,
everything you handle
turns to caca.
Shelly, I've just been a little
down on my luck lately. That's all.
No, you do it to yourself, Harry.
You're always looking
for the easy way out,
the shortcut, the quick fix.
It's just like that loan you took out
from that Korean savings and loan.
Who does things like that? How was I
supposed to know it was for 30 days?
The loan documents were
in Japanese. Korean, Harry.
You're just lucky
I beat it on a technicality.
You always have some excuse. Well,
I don't have an excuse this time.
All right, Shelly, you gotta help me,
please? Give me a hand.
Just take a look. I'm in a
real jam. I'll see what you got.
There, you see? Yeah, I see.
Yeah
phew! There's a lot of stuff
here. I know that, Shelly.
Oh, boy.
You know, maybe we can
help each other out.
Yeah? Yeah.
I could handle the credit
card subpoena. Yeah?
Take care of Shapiro.
If all goes well, I can take a
crack at getting your car back.
I'll tell you what.
I'll even advance you a couple
of thousand as sort of a loan.
Great. And, uh,
what do I have to do for you?
Do you remember,
uh, bits y Vandervagen?
No, I... I, uh...
Vandervagen, department stores,
one of my biggest clients.
Oh, right, right.
Well, bitsy's been appointed
chairperson of
the finance committee for Norton
Wilshire's campaign for governor
I was appointed co-chairman,
and I am now appointing you
entertainment chairman.
Norton Wilshire?
I can't believe this, Shel.
I mean, you've always had
impeccable taste.
Norton Wilshire, I mean,
he's a pompous, phony windbag.
He's... he's... he's dickless.
Harry, cool it, all right?
I'm not asking you to vote
for the man. All right, go ahead.
I just want you to do what you do best,
just arrange the acts.
You know, this could be just what
you need to get back on your feet.
"Back on my feet."
I start calling in favors
for a Norton Wilshire fund raiser,
I'll be history
in the music business.
Harry, I'm giving you a chance here... no,
no, no, no. I can't do it.
I am sorry. I just cannot do it.
You know, I have a few
principles left. Yeah. Well-hidden.
Ha, ha.
Harry.
You don't take my deal,
what are you gonna do?
What I always do. Manage.
You seem bigger onscreen,
Mr. Eastwood.
I know, thanks for the lift, huh.
Don't do anything to it,
just give her a bill.
She'll never know the difference. Hey,
Scotty, how ya doin'?
No, no, whatever it is,
the answer is absolutely not!
Hey, what? Every time you
come in here it costs me money.
Oh, what are you talkin' about?
I... listen,
$1700 for the Ferrari.
What, you didn't get the
check? No! Check? Come on.
There's $4,000
the insurance company
had to pay for the loaner car
that you wrecked.
And then,
there is the little matter
of my waiting in a restaurant
for hours and hours and hours
for some Hollywood starlet
who was supposed to show up
and spend the night with me!
This is unbelievable.
You know, I tell you,
I come here to do you a favor,
and you jump all over me
with all those ancient history.
You're gonna do me
a favor? That's right.
I just happen to have
4 tickets and 2 dates
to a Bruce Springsteen
concert tonight.
I immediately thought of my
good friend Scotty, you know.
Thought maybe we could double up and,
uh, you know, have some laughs.
But, no, no, no, I don't want to
cause you any problems. So forget it.
Wa-wa-wa-wait.
Springsteen?
Himself.
Uh, what does, uh,
what does my, uh, date look like?
Scotty, Vegas showgirls.
Beautiful!
You can have your pick.
Well, ok.
It's a deal. All right.
Got it. Thanks, Scotty. Really.
I gotta pick 'em up at the airport,
comin' in in 30 minutes.
Ok? All right. All right.
Oh, god!
God, I got the Ferrari,
it's only got 2 seats.
Ah. Yeah.
Hey, wait a minute. Isn't that
my landlord Byron Shapiro's car?
Yeah.
Well, what's wrong with it?
Oh, there's nothing wrong
with it. It's ready to go back.
Wait, no, I got it. Oh, no.
No, no, look.
I'll do you a favor.
Let me use the car
to pick the girls up,
and then I can return the car to
Shapiro himself tomorrow morning.
Oh, gosh, I don't know.
Oh, come on, Scotty.
It'll be our little secret.
Shapiro never has to know. Huh?
I don't know, Harry.
Great! Great!
Scotty, your wife's on line 1.
Scotty, Angeline is on line 2.
What? Harry.
Yeah. Uh, just for old time's sake,
uh, I'll hold the tickets.
Oh, Scotty, when are you
gonna learn to trust me?
Scotty, Angeline is on line 2
please.
Son of a bitch.
Well, that's the truth.
You're kidding. Uh-uh.
You never told me you were the one
who told Madonna
to wear trashy lingerie.
Oh, sure.
Helped her pick it out, too.
Really.
Tell you what,
why don't I go turn on the jacuzzi?
- You're on.
- Ok.
Oh, listen, if I got
a great white wine...
Mr. Smirac.
I am Mr. Kim from
the Pusang savings and loan.
Vice president, corrections.
Corrections?
I correct money
from deadbeats like you.
You owe us considerable sum.
Ah, uh, honey,
why don't you go on ahead in?
I'll be there in just a minute.
Ok. Yeah.
Look, Mr. Kim,
you guys, you remember,
you took me to court. You lost.
You have a good lawyer,
Mr. Smirac.
I know. But in my country,
we have a saying...
I understand, but what can I do?
I mean, uh, the judge
made his decision.
It's legal, even in Japan.
Korea, Mr. Smirac. Not Japan.
Korea. Oh, whatever.
Different eyes,
different language.
Mr. Kim,
what do you want from me?
$67,811.19,
to be very specific.
Tell you what I'll do.
How about records
for you and the missus?
How about this, Mr. Smirac?
Ah, well, no problem.
Records for them, too.
Ah, no, 0k, ok.
Well, uh, maybe some concert tickets,
how about that?
No? All right, uh, uh,
t-shirts for the kids?
Ah, you... you guys have any kids?
No? All right.
You know, this isn't funny.
$67,811.19!
You know, I have powerful
friends in very high places!
Mine powerful, too, and closer.
Ah. Hey! No!
I got to push this
back in the city.
This is an exotic car
I got here...
Oh, Christ! That's just...
Do you know whose car this is?
I was probably a little hasty,
calling him dickless.
I'm sure he's quite well...
Shelly, I give you my word,
I will go down to the
convention center this afternoon
and arrange everything. Really.
The... the lighting, the stage,
the sound system, everything.
Smilac! Smilac!
Smilac, are you in there?
I'll get you, Smilac!
Uh, listen, Shelly,
I, uh, have a feeling
that Shapiro's
trying to reach me and...
I'll get you! You bastard!
My car.
Hi. Harry Smilac
to see Tom McMillan.
You missed your appointment.
You were supposed to be here
an hour ago.
I love the color
of that blouse, it...
Mr. McMillan has somebody
with him right now.
Why don't you just
have a seat right over there?
Right.
So, uh, what's his name?
Who wants to know?
Well, my name is Harry.
And whom might I have
the pleasure of speaking to?
Nobody.
My uncle Ricky says old men
who talk to little kids are perverts.
Roberts, what's your problem?
There's something here
that is not right.
I don't understand.
I got 20 guys that'll sign
this thing in a minute.
Well, then you get them
to sign the contract!
Oh, come on, let's not
get difficult here.
I'm not being difficult!
Make up your mind. We're gonna
do this with you or without you.
Hi, I'm Harry Smilac.
I need to talk to you about
the Norton Wilshire fund raiser.
What is this? A country club.
What do I look like,
I'm on my coffee break?
I am tied up right now.
I understand. No, no, no,
no. I will get to you when I'm ready.
All I need is 5 minutes. Out!
Out! All right, all right.
Did you... out!
OK, 0k.
All right, Roberts,
what's it gonna be?
I don't understand this.
You're paying me the exact same
money as you paid me in Frisco,
only the gate's twice as much.
I told you,
your manager made the deal.
My manager... I forgot to
mention Sheldon Brockmeister,
my lawyer, he's a close personal
friend of senator Norton Wilshire...
Terrific, terrific. Give 'em both
my regards on your way out.
Wait... wait a
minute. I just... out!
If I could...
Very simple, Roberts.
Either sign the paper,
or follow that jerk out the door.
Damn it, I've been drawing
good crowds here!
The fans here, they like me, man!
How many people are we
talkin' about here? 10 to 15,000.
And you're the featured act?
What is this?
Now, now, now, wait a minute.
With that kind of a draw, we'd have
to have a guarantee. W-w-w-w-wait...
Now, now, now,
you just wait a minute.
My man gets his own
dressing room. You like that?
Oh, and a piece of the
concessions. Because you see...
You! You're outta here!
Just hold on there.
Who is this guy?
I like the way you talk.
Go ahead.
Surely. Right.
So, tell me,
does my man have a t-shirt or a shoe deal?
Oh, my god.
Hey, mister. Yeah.
I'd like to thank you,
that was a nice thing you did in there.
My pleasure. My name's
Rick. Rick Roberts.
This is niece, Missy.
What'd you say your name was? Oh,
uh, Harry Smilac.
Funny. I never heard of you.
You never heard of
M. Harry Smilac?
Personal management?
No, no, sorry.
But the way you handled
McMillan back there...
You know, that guy has been
playing hardball for a long time.
Ah. You did great.
You gotta know how to handle
guys like that.
Believe me, I've been
negotiating deals for a long time.
That guy McMillan,
strictly minor league.
You know what I mean?
You know, I've been looking
for a manager to care about me.
Me first.
You would be interested
in something like that, maybe?
Well, uh, you have to understand,
I usually only handle
really big acts.
No offense.
But, you know, major stars.
See, I give my people
real personal attention.
That's why I get 15%.
That sounds ok.
Well, that's against an advance of,
uh, $500 a week.
Deal. Ah.
Hey, what kind of stuff
you doing these days?
Straight rock 'n roll,
heavy metal?
You're not new wave,
are you? No.
- Oh, well, great.
- Roberts!
Sugarplum, you go to the car.
I wanna know what's going on.
McMillan tells me some
baby freak creep showed up,
made a deal for you.
That's right.
What? That's right.
You think you're leaving me?
Captain Lou Morano,
the man who made you?
I took you out of nowhere!
Hey, don't touch the Captain.
Now, you listen to me.
No, you listen. We got a deal.
We ain't got no deal on nothing.
I got somebody else
doing my talking for me.
You tell me who.
And I'll tear his head off!
Who you sign with? David Wolf?
Jimmy the weasel?
Smilac.
Smilac! Smilac! What is that?
A stomach disorder or a disease?
It's my...
Harry.
Really it's M. Harry Smilac,
personal management.
At your service.
You're kidding.
You... you're a manager?
Yeah. Yeah.
Uh, uh, well, uh,
hey, I'm smokin' this here! Wh...
What I do is, uh...
What I do is...
OK, 0k.
Ugh.
You'll regret this,
Roberts! Come on, Harry.
Hey, you got my shoes wet.
Harry, come on.
Yeah, right, I'm coming.
I must be missing something here.
This isn't the way we usually
do things in the music business.
You'll be back, Roberts!
You'll come crawlin'
to the Captain!
And that weak manager won't
last a week in professional wrestling!
Professional wrest...
Norton's a fabulous man,
I've known him for many years.
Harry, where the hell have
you been? I told you 3 o'clock.
Oh, yeah. I'm sorry, Shel, I had to,
uh, bang a few heads together
at the convention center and I...
Now, look, they're all waiting.
Now, please, Harry. What?
These people are really important to
the campaign, and to me personally.
Ok. I'm counting on you
to make a good impression.
I know that I will sleep
a lot better at night
with Norton servicing me...
As governor.
Well, but enough about that. I see
that Sheldon's here with his friend.
And I'm sure that they have a lot to
tell us about the big fund raiser. Sheldon.
Thank you. Thank you, Bits y.
Thank you. I am happy to
introduce you to my friend.
He's been at the
convention center all day
making the arrangements
for the big event.
So, Harry, why don't you step
right up here and tell us all about
"a night for Norton."
Harry Smilac.
No, no, no,
please, please, please.
Well,
Norton Wilshire.
A special man who
deserves a very special night.
Let me just tell you
some of the entertainers
I have lined up for this.
Oh, on second thought,
let it be a surprise, huh?
That's all very lovely,
Mr., uh... Smilac.
Yes, but... but what plans
have you actually made?
Well, we're not just
talking plans here.
We're talking concepts.
Videos trying to reach that
all important meat market...
Uh, youth market.
I'm sure we can leave it to the pro
here to handle all the details, huh?
We want some details, Harry.
Bits y, darling, uh,
Ross has set up
all the artwork in the solarium.
Why don't we all adjourn there
and take a look, ok?
Ladies, shall we?
Have you lost your mind, Sheldon?
This guy's a real bozo.
What happened to the circus theme
that we were talking about,
where we're all elegantly dressed
for contrast? Don't worry. I'll handle it.
Hi. Hi.
May I? Sure.
Uh, forgive me,
but, uh, have you ever
considered a career in modeling?
Because I handle
many of the top faces
and I think
you have real potential.
As opposed to what?
Unreal potential?
No, no, no.
I mean, you have
such marvelous cheekbones.
A-a-a-allow me
to introduce myself.
I'm Harry Smilac,
personal management.
As I stand here gazing at you,
I can't help but remember
the first time I spotted Christie.
Christie who? Brinkley.
Oh, Christie Brinkley. Yeah,
one of my many finds. Yeah.
It was long before Billy Joel.
Still had braces on her teeth.
Of course, we had to find a
way to work around that, and...
You see, so much
of what shapes a career
is in the management,
and that's what I do.
You mean like
this, um, this little event
you're putting on
for Norton Wilshire?
Yeah, Oh, it's just a little favor
I'm doing for Bits y
and the swingers.
My mother and her friends.
Oh. You mean, Bits y...
Mrs. Vandervagen to you.
Ah. Right.
I'm telling you,
this guy is great.
I saw more green last night
than I ever saw with the
Captain in my entire career.
If you need management,
you need this guy. He's got all the moves.
Oh, well, Rick, we all have moves.
I mean, yours are in the ring,
mine just happen to be
at the bargaining table.
Oh, but enough about me.
Tell me something about yourself,
Tom. I mean...
Tonga Tom.
Tonga Tom, right.
I need someone who takes no crap.
Tough.
Tough, right.
Well, that's me.
Personal management
at its toughest.
Yeah, take your time.
But, uh, are you sure it's
all right to sign this guy?
I mean, Captain Lou, he...
I'm tellin' you, Harry,
it's 0k, it's ok.
All right, well... nice card.
Oh, thanks. Glad you liked it.
So, let's, uh, let's talk
about financial arrangements.
You see, Tonga, we have something in the,
uh, management business
that we call an advance retainer.
Never heard of it.
Of course you haven't.
But what it is, you see,
is you give me $500.
And what I do...
OK, thank you.
Hey, sugarplum. Come on.
I need some help. I need a 170
pounds on me. No more, now.
You got it? Yep.
Ok, let's do it.
You've got a problem, Roberts.
What might that be?
I hear you left the Captain.
So what? The Captain's mad.
That's his problem.
It's not my problem.
It's gonna be yours.
Because the Captain doesn't
like when his wrestlers leave.
And we don't like it when
the Captain doesn't like it.
And if we don't like it,
you won't like it.
I got a new manager now.
I got somebody else
doin' the talking for me.
And you know
the best part about it is?
I don't have to be around
wonderful human beings like yourself.
Axe, can you believe it?
3 sentences in a row.
The man can actually speak.
And all the while,
I thought he was brain-damaged.
No.
A check will be fine.
As a matter of fact,
I'll pick the check up in person, and...
Oh, no, Tonga,
you don't have to thank me.
It's just another Smilac service.
It's a deal, Harry. Right.
I'll be seeing you later,
brother. Ok.
Be cool. Fantastic.
Boy, this is...
Oh, hi, guys.
Uh, you lookin' for,
for, uh, management?
Is your name simlac?
Well, no, actually it's Smilac
at your service.
We got something for you.
What's that? Pain!
And lots of it.
Yo!
I hear something about pain?
It's the brain-damaged kid!
We'll see you later.
Idiots.
Uh, wait a minute.
What was that all about?
Ah, nothin'.
But friend,
you don't wanna be messin' with them guys.
Mess... they are bad news.
Me, mess with them?
What are you, nuts?
I mean, who are those guys,
anyway?
Axe and hammer.
The world tag team champs.
Huh. Better known
as The Cannibals.
Captain Lou's pride and joy.
Wait a minute.
- How much is that?
- 510 pounds.
Let me ask you.
What did me mean by, uh,
"we'll see you later"?
Great, great.
I should have stayed
in the music business.
Harry.
Your lawyer assures me
he's sending over a check
to cover all the back payments.
Oh, good. Good.
And it better happen, too.
Or else he's back on the job.
Count. 1, 2...
All right.
Hold onto him.
Get him over here and tag.
Grab him! Grab him!
No! Slam! Slam!
1,2,3!
Ladies and gentlemen!
The winners of
tonight's main event,
and america's newest tag team,
together for the first time ever,
Quick Rick Roberts and Tonga Tom!
All right.
Fantastic, guys, fantastic!
Great teamwork, just great!
There's just a couple of little
things that we need to work on.
Nothing major,
nothing we can't fix, but, uh,
wait a minute.
You're not hurt, are you?
Never felt better in my life,
Harry. Great.
Now, look, Rick, you gotta,
you gotta tighten up on the, uh...
Arm bar. Right.
Oh, and listen, we have to...
Have to talk about outfits.
You know, I mean, my wrestlers
have gotta have style.
I mean, after all...
Oh, wait... wait a minute here.
Maybe I can talk to Nike
about a tie-in.
Vic Carson.
Vic Carson?
Who's that, another wrestler?
Because you know, I'm...
Vic Carson, Harry.
Has another talk show on T.V.
T.V.? Right.
Oh, you mean Johnny Carson?
No, Vic Carson.
Host of ring talk.
You don't realize, Harry. What?
You're a new manager. You've
created a stir second to none.
They want you down there
this Wednesday.
Well, you know, I'd have
to check on my calendar.
I mean, I'm... I'm booked
pretty tight here, you know.
Well, I understand
if you're not interested.
It's the #1 talk show
on television.
Right.
Uh, wait a minute, wait a minute,
wait a minute here.
What... what night was that?
Wednesday night. Oh, Wednesday night,
I'm free on Wednesday.
Tonight, from Hollywood,
California,
it's ring talk, america's
favorite wrestling program,
with your host, Vic Carson.
Now, here's Vic!
T #
Oh, thank you!
Good evening,
ladies and gentlemen.
Welcome, wrestling fans,
thank you.
Well, we have a wonderful
crowd tonight.
Thank you!
Ladies and gentlemen,
tonight, we're gonna begin
our show with a special segment.
That's right.
Devoted to wrestling managers.
And we have right here in this
ring the finest in the business.
I've got an old pro,
I've got a specialist,
and I've got a newcomer,
and we're gonna learn just
what their approaches are.
Let we welcome my first guest,
ladies and gentlemen.
This man has done more
for the rubber industry
than good year.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the fantastic Captain Lou Morano!
Lou, you are undoubtedly
the most outstanding
and successful manager
in the wrestling game.
May I say, I am so honored to have
you on the show. Ah, it's your pleasure.
Thank you. And my next
guest is a giant in his own right.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the magnificent Tim Mcclusky!
Hey! Here!
Welcome to the show, Tim.
Now, Tim handles the smaller
wrestlers in the business.
And I know, Tim,
that my viewers are very anxious to hear
the long and the short of it.
No more midget jokes,
geekface, or I'll deck you!
Tim, you are a card.
And now, ladies and gentlemen,
my last guest.
Wrestling's newest manager,
direct from the music business.
Let's have a big warm welcome
for Mr. Harry Smilac!
Ladies and gentleman,
Harry Smilac.
Such a pleasure
being on your show, Vic.
I can't tell you...
Thank you, Harry.
Welcome to the show. May
I say that this is stunning.
Ah, thank you. I...
But, gentleman,
we only have an hour,
so let's everybody
just take a stool.
T #
So, Vic...
Get up from there! What
you... what you doin' there?
Hey! Hey! Hey!
You short little midget, you!
That was my seat!
Well, I suppose that
the natural place to start
would be with our newcomer here.
Harry, what made you forsake the
music industry for professional wrestling?
Oh, well, uh, let me correct you there,
Vic, baby, if I may.
See, I still manage many, many,
many famous music groups,
I just sort of, oh,
branched out into
uh, the wrestling world.
Because there's
such a desperate need
for good, really good managers.
So it is your opinion, Harry,
that there is a shortage
of mangers in
the wrestling profession?
Uh, well, not necessarily a sh...
Ah, don't!
I mean, wrestling needs
someone with new ideas,
someone with new approaches,
someone who isn't all tied up
in the old way of doing things.
Well, you certainly don't mean
any of the old pros
that are on our show here
tonight, do you, Harry?
Well, if the shoe fits.
If you're talkin' about me,
butt face,
I'll break your neck.
Do you mind?
Captain,
what is your response to all of this?
I don't give a rat's ass about
anything this moron has to say!
This pencil-neck's been
in the business 2 minutes,
and he thinks he knows everything.
He's an idiot! He's a... faggot.
Yeah, everybody knows
these musical sorts
are into all sorts of
strange stuff! Really?
They don't belong
in a red-blooded,
all-American sport like wrestling!
We don't need wimps
in funny-looking clothes
telling us how to run
our business!
We don't need... faggots.
Yeah, Tim.
We want this beanie-bag
out of wrestling!
Hold it, hold it, hold it.
I gotta admit, Vic,
I'm new to the sport.
Let me tell you what I've learned.
Wrestlers need a new deal.
Yes, sir. Because they're the talent,
they deserve the bucks.
By the way,
uh, wrestlers out there,
my number is 213-555-1334. So...
Wait a minute! H-H-Hold it,
wrestling fans!
Now, those are mighty strong
words to the old vicar here,
and I'm sure the Captain has some
mighty strong words in response.
But before we hear from the Captain,
let's have this message.
You know damn well
I'm the Captain.
Why, I'm the best manager
of all time.
Man, you ain't done!
Who you talkin' to?
What the hell?
3,2,1.
We're back, wrestling fans.
As Harry was say...
Where's Harry?
Oh, Vic.
Let me assure you, ladies,
everything is under control.
I have been in touch
with so many stars
that they are coming out of... uh,
Harry. The names, please.
All right.
Big names. They're big.
Uh, that would be good, yeah.
We're talking, uh, Frank,
Neil, uh, Barbara, Julio,
uh, I could go on.
Oh, this is gonna be
the most fabulous show!
Yeah.
Oh, yeah, what else!
Nice rear end.
I beg your pardon?
Well, uh, they don't, uh,
they don't make 'em
like this anymore, huh?
Oh. Hmm. Great body, huh?
Mmm-hmm. Solid.
Yeah, it's my mother's. I'm
using it while mine's in the shop.
What...
Oh, no, this is nothing.
I... I'll be all right.
Can I give you a hand?
May I?
Yeah.
Are you always such a gentleman?
Well, your beauty
brings out the best in me.
God, you sound like a soap opera.
Oh, you questioning my sincerity?
And your integrity.
And maybe your decency
and certainly your ability
to get the entertainment
for the fund raiser.
Hmm. Well, I'm working under
some very difficult circumstances here.
Tell me. What could be so difficult
about getting a little entertainment?
I could get entertainers to
appear at a P.L.O. fund raiser
before they'd help out
Norton Wilshire, you know.
Why won't you trust me, huh?
I'm really a very nice person.
Hmm?
Opening a gate and
picking up a few packages
does not necessarily
qualify you as a nice person.
Hmm. How about dinner?
Oh, no. No, I don't think so.
Uh, lunch?
I don't eat lunch.
In-between-meal snack?
My dentist wouldn't approve.
Well, bring him along.
Huh? Strictly business.
We can go over the lighting and
sound system for the Wilshire event.
Look, we'll go to a very noisy,
unromantic spot.
You can even drive.
T #
Well, thank you.
Well, you're really
on your best behavior.
Of course. What did you expect?
I won't tell you.
Well, I admit,
the first time I met you,
I, uh, I might have
come on a little strong.
A little strong?
Does that "I'm gonna make
you a star" routine really work?
Nah.
You know, I was just...
Seeing someone
as beautiful as you,
my mouth went on automatic pilot.
Well, I think your sincere
approach is a lot nicer.
Really.
Approach?
Wait a minute. You think
I'm coming on to you now?
Probably.
Stiffed on car payments
by some creepo?
Call the folks at reliable repo!
Oh! Oh!
Are... are you all right?
Oh, I don't...
Does that really hurt? Oh, yeah.
It gets worse at night, too.
I mean, sometimes
the pain is so intense...
I wonder, could you
drop me at my place?
I'm afraid to drive.
If I had an attack
behind the wheel, I...
What... what are you gonna do
about your car?
I don't know. I'll just
have to get it later. I think...
The best thing right now is just,
to get, you know, into bed.
I sure appreciate this. Ow!
Harry!
Oh, my... my... ow!
A spasm or something!
Oh, my god, are you 0k?
Oh, oh!
Oh, you know... are you ok?
I think instead of bed,
what we... I should do
is take a jacuzzi.
Do you suppose you could...
Sure, sure.
Oh, smirac.
Mr. Smirac, we meet again.
Did you screw over
someone else, too?
Look, Mr. Kim,
don't you guys have anything better to do
than hassle me over
some small consumer loan?
$67,811.19 is not
a small consumer loan.
Excuse me. How about you
fellas taking this up in the morning?
You know,
during business hours? Yes.
In Korea, females do not
interfere in such matters.
I beg your pardon, but it...
Oh, that... that's all right,
Candace, I'll handle this.
Handle this? You're in no
condition to handle anything.
I know, but... Mr. Smirac,
I'm losing my Patience.
You pay or n0 DEV?
Watch my lips...
Watch my friends.
Oh. My god! Harry!
That's my mother's car!
Oh, my god!
Oh, my... look, Candace,
it's not so bad.
I... I think you can write
this kind of thing off. Really.
If not, I know a good body man.
I don't care
what you say, Sheldon,
I want him off this committee.
I never want to see him again.
And you stay away from him, too.
Mother, I think
you're overreacting.
It was not Harry's fault.
It most certainly was his fault.
I think he deserves
another chance.
Look, Bits y, if we fire Harry now,
who will we get to replace him?
It's too late
to find anybody else.
That's your problem.
All right. Tell you what.
Suppose I supervise him
personally?
Believe me, I'll watch every
move the man makes like a hawk.
Ok. Fine.
You got it. Nice puppy.
Cute.
T #
# Live on the brink,
shout it out loud #
# it's the American way #
# yeah, yeah #
Nice car.
Nice ass.
# It's the American way #
# yeah, yeah II
Hello, Harry.
How ya doin', Chris?
Hey, that is a chartbuster!
Definitely top 40, maybe gold.
Maybe platinum!
Harry, we know our stuff is great.
What we need is management help.
Yeah, like somebody
who will pay us,
instead of the other way around.
Guys, you wound me!
What do you think is the number
one thing on M. Harry Smilac's mind?
M. Harry Smilac.
No, no, no, no, no.
The future of Kicks!
That's what. You know,
I never stop thinking,
day and night, night and day,
thinking of ways
to make you guys famous.
Harry, bottom line.
Do we have a gig, or don't we?
Well, uh, you might as well
start thanking me now
because I am working
on a major, but major gig.
Oh, but enough
of this success talk, huh?
Come on, let me hear some of
the new numbers. What do you say?
I want to hear a little
more about the gig.
Oh, Todd, baby,
come on. Trust me.
The last time we trusted you
we played a dairy queen opening.
True, but, uh...
Come on, we gotta practice anyway.
Listen, this is really gonna
put Kicks on the map!
Thanks again for bringing me. Mom,
this is so exciting.
Seeing all these stars
on one stage!
Well, darling, that's the only
reason your father coughed up $500
for a putz like Wilshire.
Uh, Harry.
Well, you, uh,
you pulled it off, right?
Did you ever doubt it? Huh?
Yes. Especially the way you've been
avoiding me the last couple of days.
Shelly, Shelly,
you know me better than that.
What, are you kidding?
Look, uh,
my job is done, ok? So...
They're all backstage,
right? I mean,
Frank, Barbara, Julio...
Don't worry, Shel,
it's gonna be a super show.
Yeah, but I just want to,
you know, straighten out...
Isn't this our dear
little friend Larry?
Harry, mother.
Yes, dear. I hope he's better at
stars than he is at Rolls-Royces.
Have you met our senator?
Norton Wilshire.
I want to thank you
for your assistance
and dedication to our campaign.
It's the workers like you and
Sheldon here who make it possible...
Oh, that's enough.
That's enough.
For men like me to serve in
high public office... Don't go away.
I've been, uh, thinking
about our relationship.
What relationship?
Uh, well, the one
we should be having.
Yes, in fact, I was thinking
that we should
get out of here right now
and start working on it.
And miss "a night with Norton?"
Yeah, well, I'm more interested
in a night with Candace.
I gotta hand it to you, Harry,
you just don't quit.
Hmm. The secret to my success.
No more Koreans? I promise.
Well, then, let's go.
Harry, Harry,
where are you going? Harry!
Wow, what a night, huh?
Oh, ladies and gentlemen,
I know that you can't wait to hear
from our favorite senator,
Norton Wilshire, right?
Uh, well, then, I guess we better,
uh, get right on
to our fabulous
entertainment first.
Who do you think will be
first? Frank or Barbara?
Julio.
Hmm.
T #
Oh, my god!
Oh!
Sheldon!
Hello, this is M. Harry Smilac.
I'll be in Rio de Janeiro
for the next year or so,
but if you want, at the tone,
leave a message.
Harry, you better
make an appointment
with a plastic surgeon,
because if anyone sees your face,
you're a dead man.
Harry, it's Candace.
Wherever you're hiding,
stay there,
because mother's ready to kill.
Yo, lady!
The powder room's down the hall.
Right. Look, Missy,
if Bits y Vandervagen
or Sheldon Brockmeister call,
I'm not here, all right?
Sounds like Harry.
Don't look like Harry.
Now, look, guys,
there's a very good explanation
why I'm dressed like this.
Sure. Sure there is
and I'd love to tell ya,
but we've got a wrestling
match in 5 minutes,
so come on, let's go, huh?
What, you wanna take a picture,
you two? Come on.
Harry, do you want your messages?
No.
Yeah, who called?
Well, your lawyer called.
He was really mad. He said they had to
give back all the money from last night.
Yeah? Who else?
The band "Kicks" called.
They weren't too happy either.
Also...
Wait a minute.
You mean, there's more?
Yeah. Who?
Senator Norton Wilshire called...
Oh, no! Don't tell me,
don't tell me. I...
Uh, Roberts, Tonga,
you're on. Uh...
You, uh,
you want me to get a seat
for the lady?
No, thank you.
From Evanston, Illinois,
america's heartland,
Quick Rick Roberts!
And his partner,
from that magical
south seas kingdom of Tonga,
Tonga Tom!
Hello, everybody, I'm Chick Hearn,
along with Jay Johnstone,
ready for tonight's big match.
I don't know about you,
but I'm really looking forward to this
because since they merged
as a tag team,
Quick Rick and Tonga have been very,
very impressive.
In fact, I think
they could go all the way.
Well, they shouldn't
have any trouble
with their opponents tonight,
the invaders.
We've had a substitution
on the card.
In place of the invaders,
we have 2 new opponents.
We have,
a combined weight of 580 pounds...
Axe and Hammer, The Cannibals!
Wait a minute!
They can't do that!
All right, Roberts!
You're gonna pay tonight!
Hold it! Hold it! Stop!
Excuse me! Hey!
Come on, let's get in!
Here we go! Come on!
We're ready, now get in here!
I wanna tell you, Jay, it looks like
there's real trouble brewing here.
And when the Captain's
doing the brewing,
you know it's gonna be
a bad cup of coffee.
Hold it! Hold it! Hold it!
What's going on here?
We didn't agree to this!
We're not goin' through
with it! Ok? Harry!
Or should I call you Harriet?
This is for you!
You're out of wrestling
tonight, Smilac!
And so are your 2 bums!
Anybody milked you lately,
huh? Come on, idiot.
Ow!
Oh, there goes the referee! And
they come over with their chains!
I got a canary with a
bigger brain than yours!
You cannot control
animals like this,
particularly when they're armed
with lethal weapons
such as chains.
Tonga!
Ugh!
You son of a...
Aren't you supposed
to be in there? Come on!
Tonga!
You can run, sweetie,
but you can't hide!
Well, that's really nice,
Captain Lou,
come over while he's half-unconscious
and kick him in the head.
Meanwhile, in the ring, they're beating
ferociously upon the body of Quick Rick!
I don't know if the kid
can take this or not!
Certainly, no human is
supposed to take beatings like this,
not in the ring,
not anywhere in the world!
Ladies and gentlemen,
they've got him half unconscious now!
Oh, they catch him with a necktie
with that chain! Can you believe this?
Come on! Let's go! Ok!
Give me a little hand!
Here you go! Over the top!
Oh, fans, this goes back
to the neanderthal days!
I don't believe this!
They've gotta stop it,
somebody's just gotta
stop this match!
Tonga's trying to get ready to come
back. He'll just get hurt some more!
He dives! He misses his man!
Look at the blood
on that kid's chest!
Look at the kid's face!
He's in excruciating pain!
Now they lift him up
onto the top rope, face down,
dangle his feet there,
The Hammer supports him
from the cuff,
coming off the top buckle,
here comes Axe!
This is gonna be
big trouble, fans!
It's illegal! Oh, god,
that's a paralyzing blow!
Look out, here comes, oh,
the double elbow! A double elbow!
Even this capacity crowd
wants this thing stopped!
They paid their money,
that's true,
but they don't want to see
these animals in action anymore!
Somebody's gotta stop this!
Where's the police?
Somebody, anybody!
You're absolutely right!
The gendarmes have
gotta step in here!
This is setting wrestling
back a thousand years!
There you 9!
Oh! Did you see that?
This could be the demise
of Quick Rick and Tonga Tom!
All right, all right,
all right, right now!
Ladies and gentlemen,
you don't like it, Harry?
This is illegal! Wait! Wait! Wait! No,
wait!
Oh, they're gonna
send him on a trip!
Just a sec... no! No! Please!
Be right back, 0k? Sit tight.
Uh-huh.
Hey, Smilac!
Oh, no! No, wait!
Wait, pl...
Oh! Oh, oh, oh...
Oh, I'm sorry,
I didn't... I didn't see... oh, oh, oh.
Oh, my goodness.
Are you... you all right?
Fine.
Ok. Well, get well soon, huh?
Uh-oh.
Oh...
No!
On, poor guy!
Well, at least
he's close to the hospital.
"No, you don't!
"We will stop you no matter what!
"You will never stop me,
Captain chaos,
because I have
the secret formula!"
Oh, no!
I bet they'll get it back.
Hey, Harry.
Hi, Harry. Hi, Harry.
-
I, guys. Missy.
How'd you like the fight?
Ah, well, you know...
I'll tell you, guys, I...
I feel real bad.
You look pretty bad, too.
Oh, no, no, I mean, I...
I let you down. I blew it.
Aw. Harry, go on!
It wasn't your fault.
We just got our butts kicked.
I mean, you guys have been
wrestling a lot of years,
nothing like this
ever happened before.
This whole thing happened
because the Captain outsmarted me.
We just got off to a bad start.
You didn't finish
too well, either.
Don't worry, Harry.
We'll get 'em next time.
There won't be a next time.
Not for me.
Why not?
Well,
'cause it, uh, doesn't feel too good having
people I like get hurt on my account.
So, uh,
well, I never thought
I'd hear myself say this,
you guys...
You need another manager.
Here's your contracts.
Harry, wait a second!
I thought we were doing
great! Come back here!
Hi, Harry, how you doin'?
Hi, har.
M. Harry Smilac,
personal manager, I do believe.
What are you doing here?
Oh, I'm just looking
for my manager.
I thought I told you
to get somebody else.
Harry, you're my man.
I don't want nobody else,
you're the best.
Well,
I used to believe that.
Not anymore.
You know, Harry,
you stood up to the Captain.
If you get out of wrestling,
do you know that anybody that
makes it in wrestling from now on
is gonna be
one of the Captain's men?
Rick, you're wastin'
your time, all right?
You know, there's only 2 things
in my life that matters, Harry.
That's wrestling,
and my little Princess,
little missy.
And I'll tell you what made that
all possible. It's wrestling, Harry.
Wrestling made that possible.
And I'll tell you somethin',
if you're gonna quit on me
and I've gotta go back
to lickin' the Captain's boots,
well, mister,
you know what I'm gonna do?
I'm gonna be just like you,
I'm gonna quit, too.
Rick, even if I wanted to,
which I don't,
but even if I wanted to,
I couldn't book us a match
in a major arena anywhere.
No one's gonna sign with us if
it means bucking the Captain.
You mean to tell me there's not
one single arena in the country
that doesn't
kiss up to the Captain?
Not a major arena.
I mean, maybe some 2-bit place
like my bands used to play
when I was just starting out.
You know, road tours...
That is really dumb.
Dumb? Come on! This could...
This could... this could
be very good for you.
Major publicity!
Yeah, like the Wilshire fund raiser,
right, Harry?
My parents, to this day,
won't speak to me.
They think I'm a communist agent.
Look, I think this could
be very good for you.
Now, what do you say
we give it a try, huh?
See, I can promote concerts for you guys,
book matches for my wrestlers.
Come on, come on. Look, give me
a couple of weeks to put it together,
then if you're not happy,
you can find yourselves
another manager. Hmm?
Hey, Harry, are you ok?
You seem sincere.
I mean every word of it.
I'll be right back.
You know, guys,
I think he really means it this time.
We've heard this story
time and time again.
Maybe he's on the level,
maybe he's not.
I'll even provide
first-class transportation!
"First-class transportation."
Meals, too.
T #
# The sun comes up #
# but it don't look no lighter #
# it's hard to be alive
every day #
# then you get up I
# and dig a little deeper #
# oh, I'll be back
that's the way #
# runnin' down, hittin' bottom #
# doesn't mean that's
where you've gotta stay #
# then you get up I
# and dig a little deeper #
# go out and be a fighter
every day #
# Push! Push! #
# Oh, you can do it, baby #
# I said, push! Push! #
# I know you can do it, baby N'
Elmo, you can't do this to me.
I've got posters up all over town,
advertising 2 different shows
on 2 different nights.
Look, I'd... I'd
like to help you,
but we're booked up solid. You
got the 15th, 4-h has got the 16th.
Well, look, how about
right after the 4-h, huh?
I mean,
farmers go to bed early, right?
No, that's the hog auction.
That's a wild one. They
don't finish up till about 9:00.
Then we gotta pick up all the
droppings and then air the place out.
Elmo! Elmo, pal,
look, I'd be real grateful
if you could find a way
to move the pig act.
I mean, I'm sure the pigs
won't mind, right?
Well, we could call it
a clerical error.
Well, you might call it that,
but, you see, my partner wouldn't.
Oh, Elmo, Elmo, Elmo.
Come on, I've posted $1000
guarantee. I've got musicians to pay.
What am I gonna do
with only one night?
Well, you know,
my daddy used to say,
if you only got $10 and you're
goin' down to the cathouse,
you better get the most bang
for the buck.
You get it? Bang for the buck?
That's a good one!
I'm gonna have to run down and tell
Floyd and the boys at the barbershop!
Bang for the buck!
Bang for the buck.
Wait a minute.
Bang, buck.
Now, uh, remember,
rock and wrestling all in the same night.
Yeah, rock and wrestling.
Let's go!
Yeah!
T #
# Push! Push! #
# I know you can do it, baby #
# I said, push! Push! #
# I said push! Push! #
# I know you can do it, baby #
# I said, push! Push! #
# I said push! N'
Whoa, whoa!
Thank you!
We got a real Hummer for
you tonight at the rock concert,
and we've gonna have now,
the wrestling match!
T #
Now, tomorrow night, don't forget,
we got the big hog auction.
And then the next night
we got the...
Now, that's terrific, Elmo.
But we gotta keep things
going here, folks.
That's right 'cause it's showtime!
Introducing, uh,
Quick Rick Roberts
and Tonga Tom!
Now, this is a very,
very special exhibition match!
Now that means $1,000,
that's right, 1,000
good old American dollars
to any 2 local boys
who think they can pin
either Tonga Tom
or Quick Rick Roberts.
So, what do you say? Who do we got here,
huh? Don't be shy.
Number 1 on the list
is pee wee Hutchins.
Where are you, pee wee?
Here I am, Elmo!
Come on down, pee wee.
Harry, I can't do this.
You wanna lose $1000? No.
And joining pee wee is his brother
little will Hutchins!
All right! Let's get to it!
Woo-hoo!
All right, little will,
you gonna get 'em!
Wait a minute! Wait a minute!
Ain't we supposed to shake first?
Whoa!
T #
Come on, Rick, get up! Come on,
baby, get up! Get up, will you?
Come on, Rick, let's go! Get up!
Harry! What?
Do something!
I'll be right back. I'll go out
to the bus and get the papers.
Papers?
Yeah, we'll sign this guy!
Get serious!
Right, ok, ok, we won't sign him.
Come on, Rick, get up!
Stay right there.
All right, listen.
Hey, hey, hey, hey! Listen!
That organ is killing us!
We need some sounds of our
own. What do you want us to play?
What do I want you... I don't care,
anything, something.
Just give me some decibels, ok?
OK.
T #
Turn him around!
Turn him around and back him up!
T #
Harry, do something!
Go!
Now, you listen to me.
You don't wanna be
messin' with me.
I'm tellin' ya,
I will send you home to your mama.
Ugh!
You're all right, buddy!
What a show! I've never
seen this town so excited!
How about a repeat on the 24th?
Well, you know, we're real...
Available.
It's been a pleasure doin' business
with ya, Elmo, we'll be in touch.
Great!
Appreciate it.
See ya later, Elmo.
All right!
Hey, uh, hold it!
It can't be the 24th!
That's artificial
insemination night!
How about the 25th?
T #
# Ooh, ooh, ooh a'
# I need a man who always
takes care of business #
# I need a man who can
take care of my dreams #
I just give me someone #
# that's extremely
armed and dangerous #
# my love is dangerous #
# and you know what that means #
# I'll fight for you
if it comes to that #
# no one else can have you #
# and that's a love fact, yeah #
# body slam #
# take me to the limit
if you can #
# don't want a boy,
I'm lookin' for a man #
# I understand
the job he's got to do #
# body slam #
# I think you could fit
in my plans #
# you shake my love
with just a tempting glance #
# you throw me for a body slam #
# body slam #
# take me to the limit
if you can #
# don't want a boy,
I'm lookin' for a man #
# I understand
the job he's gotta do N'
H, excuse me, miss, I, uh...
Hi, I'd like a chivas and soda.
Could you make that 2?
Mr. Smilac? Yes.
I'm herb brown. I'm a writer.
Oh.
I'm interested in this rock 'n
roll wrestling business of yours.
Well, who isn't?
Looks like a big success.
Well, I'd use the word
"enormous."
If you don't mind, I'd like to take
just a few minutes of your time
and maybe that of your
wrestlers and your band Kicks.
Actually, that's "Kick," no.
What happened to the "s?"
Well, you know, when you're in the
big time, you need a big-time name.
I mean, whoever heard
of the Kisses, or the Whos?
How about the Beatles?
Yeah, right. Look,
I'm real busy now, so...
This won't take long.
Uh, what we'd like to do
is run a piece
in next week's issue
of Rolling Stone.
Oh.
Rolling Stone. Yeah.
Yeah, well, you see, it,
uh, it, uh, really all began
when I realized a crying
need in this country, herb,
for, uh, you know, good,
old-fashioned family entertainment.
I just reached right out there
and took the public's pulse.
Uh-huh, ok. Now sign it,
"your favorite
personal manager, Harry."
No, no, no, wait,
make that "love",
your favorite personal..."
Etcetera, etcetera.
Why don't you just call Candace
instead of sending her postcards?
I tried, missy,
but I keep getting the
housekeeper or her mother,
and they just hang up.
Will you just mail the, uh...
Good.
Hey!
Would you look at this?
Yeah?
Harry, I knew you could do it!
You have brought us
to the top, man!
Well,
almost.
Almost? Would you...
Page 72, look at this right
here. There it is. Look, it says,
"they have created
"the entertainment
event of the year.
"Have changed
the face of wrestling,
and possibly music."
What more do you want?
The championship, Rick.
That's right,
world tag team title.
Now, the question is,
can the two of you
take The Cannibals?
I give you my personal guarantee.
But what good's that gonna do?
Those guys have had the belts
for 5 long years.
The Captain ain't gonna
give us a shot at it.
Especially if he knows
we're prepared.
Aw, hey, guys...
"Trust me."
And now, here's Vic!
Hello, wrestling fans.
Good evening.
Pull up your stools
because we have a great show
for you tonight.
I'm sure you all remember
a couple of months ago
when Captain Lou, here,
and Harry Smilac were on the show
and they had
a slight disagreement.
Well, they are back again tonight,
so who knows what's gonna happen?
In the last couple of months,
this is wonderful,
you have truly changed
the entire face of wrestling.
That's right.
Well, the real credit lies with
wrestling fans everywhere.
Yeah, all I did was, uh,
give 'em a chance
to see a great sport
in a way that's refreshing, inspirational,
provocative, entertaining...
No, no, no! You know,
you took a chance,
combining rock and wrestling.
I-I-It's wrestling for wimps!
You don't need music to wrestle,
you need balls!
Big ones!
Thank you, Tim.
Captain, do you have
any thoughts on this?
Uh, these rock 'n wrestling concerts,
they're like junk foods.
They're all wrapped up
in a pretty little package,
but too much of it makes you sick.
Just like this guy, Smilac,
makes me sick!
Well, Harry, it looks like
your colleagues, here, Harry,
are not exactly your biggest fans.
But gentlemen,
you cannot argue with the numbers.
That's right. And Smilac's
shows are drawing.
Harry, do you have any thoughts
about bringing it to the big city?
Well, I'm glad you asked...
Hey, man, nobody would
come out and see it.
Oh, hey, wait, I take that back.
Maybe, uh, some of Smilac's
old boyfriends would.
You know the type I mean,
the ones with earrings.
Faggots.
Earrings, huh? Like the one
you're wearing in the old, uh...
You know everyone's fed up
with your act.
It's old style,
boring, passe, baby. Even the
wrestlers are fed up with you.
You're bad-mouthing
the Captain! Why, you...
You're a dinosaur, your days are
numbered! Settle down. I think that...
Oh, yeah? Oh, yeah?
Sounds like we have a slight
disagreement brewing here.
You're a dead man, Smilac!
You and your boys,
I am gonna put you out of wrestling!
All right, that's fine, I'll tell you what,
I'll give you the chance.
One match, winner take all.
Have you got the guts for that?
Whoa! Sounds like we are talking
grudge match here on ring talk!
Let's get this straight. If my guys win,
you leave the wrestling business.
That's it? Fantastic!
Isn't he smart?
Any time, pencil-neck!
Great, ok. How about
2 weeks from Saturday?
And the tag team belt
goes along with it. Whoa!
I didn't say nothin'
about the championship belt!
See that? Blimpo finally
showed his true colors. Uh-huh.
Right here on your show,
Vic. In front of millions of people.
He can't fool the public.
Hey, I'm not tryin' to fool
anybody! I never back off a fight!
Oh. But let's make sure
there's no way to weasel out.
Especially from a welsher like you,
Smilac! Whoa!
So we put the belts on the line
and our wrestlers' contracts,
winner take all!
You've got it! And you heard it here,
folks, on ring talk!
4 of the greatest wrestlers,
2 top managers!
I don't know about you,
but I can't wait for this one!
Tim, what do you
think about this, huh? Tim?
Faggofl.
If you don't find that dog,
Debbie,
start looking for a new job.
Yes, what is it?
Buenos (has. Candace Vandewagen,
por favor.
Oh, please. Candace,
this is for you.
Ok. Got something for me?
Uh, yes, an apology.
The voice sounds familiar,
but I just can't place the face.
What, you don't
like pussy willows?
Look, I'm takin'
a terrible chance coming here.
But I wanted to see you.
I've been thinking about us.
Thinking about us? For 20
cents you could have called me.
I did call! Honest!
From every 2-bit town
between here and Phoenix.
But y-your housekeeper
wouldn't put me through.
Must have had training from
the Sandinistas. But I did write.
You call those crummy postcards
written in crayon "writing?"
You didn't like those?
Candace!
Quick! Quick!
Harry! An elevator?
Drop the flowers!
I can't reach the...
You know, I'm...
I'm so happy that you
came out with me here today.
Why?
Well...
Mmm...
I, uh,
I have a little something
here for you.
Funny, it doesn't look
like a diamond.
No, actually, it's, uh,
it's for your mother and her friend,
Norton Wilshire.
Really? Yeah.
It's, uh,
it's my end of the purse,
if Rick and Tonga win.
I mean, there are enough
bucks there to more than make up
for the little problem we had at
the Norton Wilshire fund raiser.
What if they don't win?
Well, I'll, uh,
I'll think of something.
Hmm.
Ladies and gentlemen, what a night
we have for you here this evening.
It's like the super bowl,
the world series,
and the academy awards all rolled into one,
right here.
I mean, it's incredible,
the stars are here, the beautiful people...
Get out of my way!
Ah...
Mr. Kim!
Well, well, well, well,
now, what could possibly
bring you out here tonight?
What you think, smirac?
Some business.
How about if I call you Harry?
Oh, I don't know, I've kind of
gotten used to smirac.
Ok. No more Mr. Nice guy!
I know you're making
big bucks tonight.
You pay up, or else.
At stake this evening,
the world wrestling tag team
championship
and the survival of 1 of 2
top managers in wrestling.
Speaking of which,
we have Captain Lou Morano.
Let's got get a word with him
right now. Come on this way.
Captain Lou, can I get your...
Outta my way,
kid! Outta my way! Just one. Please?
Hey, sign this, Lou!
Captain Lou, any predictions
about tonight's big match?
Smilac's dead!
Uh, have you ever seen a tremendous
crowd as we have this evening?
Smilac's a dead man!
Any special instructions for
your wrestlers this evening, uh...
Smilac's dead!
Well, that was, uh, certainly a
meaningful conversation, wasn't it?
We had... I don't believe this,
what a surprise.
We have one of California's
gubernatorial candidates here.
Good to see you.
Senator Norton Wilshire.
How are you?
What do you think
about this evening?
Well, it's not really...
No, as a matter of fact,
these are my kind of people.
The grassroots of America.
I'm proud to be here
on this special occasion.
Listen, Kim,
you know, you... you're becoming
a real pain in the ass, you know,
so, here's the way it's gonna be.
You're gonna get off my back
and stay away from my cars.
Now, this beauty here
cost me $85,000.
Now, one little nick on that baby,
and you'll be back in Japan
before you can say "egg foo Yung."
Egg foo Yung
is Chinese, Mr. Smirac!
Korean different!
Excuse me.
3,2,1...
Well, wrestling fans,
now we get down to that moment of truth.
4 men in the square circle,
fighting for
their professional lives
and the right to wear
a championship belt.
And just look at that great
crowd down there tonight.
Virtually a who's who
in wrestling history.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the N.W.A. World champion,
Ric Flair.
Next, the one and only
"Classy" Freddie Blassie.
Always a gentleman.
I can see true legends
at ringside.
Don't tell me. You're reason
for birth control.
And there's wrestling's evil genius,
Sheik Adnan El Kassey.
Professional wrestling's
living legend,
15-year world champion
Bruno San Martino.
Oh, and by the way, I myself
will be doing the blow-by-blow and,
oh, and here joining me for some
color commentary is a man you all love.
You've seen him many times
on my show ring talk.
Let's welcome Tim Mcclusky.
Oh, thank you very much, uh, Vic.
And ladies and gentlemen...
Tim, you know these 4 men,
you've watched these 4 men,
how do you see this match, Tim?
Well, all 4 wrestlers are great athletes,
uh-huh.
And the difference
in this match is...
That's very interesting, Tim,
but let's go to ringside now
and catch them with that great
music by that wonderful group Kick.
Hey, bozo, you cut me off
one more time and I'll deck you!
T #
# Another hard-working kid #
# listen, show us what you got #
# and it's just what I do #
# ain't saying that
it'd be easy #
# no one said that
it'd be free #
# I earn my living
in the U.S.A. #
# There's no place
that I'd rather be #
# can't you feel it
in your bones? #
# Runnin' through your veins #
# it's the American way #
# and it's never gonna change #
# you get up early
and go home proud #
# lemme at 'em, lemme at 'em #
# land of the free,
shout it out loud #
# it's the American way #
# yeah, yeah #
# all right #
# runnin' at the work site #
# I've got a job to do #
# flex a little muscle #
# until the job is through #
# but you know within our work #
# now I truly have to say #
Well, guys, uh,
this is it.
Harry, we know what we gotta do.
There's no 2nd chance for us.
You lose our contracts
to the Captain,
we're out of wrestling.
We're gonna do it, too, Harry.
# Lemme at 'em, lemme at 'em #
# land of the free,
shout it out loud #
# it's the American way #
# yeah, yeah #
# it's the American way H'
Get these freaks outta here!
This is supposed to be
a wrestling match!
I like it that way, fat man.
I don't give a rat's ass
about this program.
Your guitars need tuning.
Oh, my god.
This is ridiculous!
This is the worst thing
I've ever seen in my life!
What? It's great.
Look at those cannibals.
Why don't they let the kids play?
Well, they're wrestlers.
They're not...
Get out of the ring, Lou!
They're better than the kids!
Will you shut up, for god's sake?
I'm gonna go down
and talk to the kids myself.
Hey, hey, you! Hey!
Hey, hey!
Hey, Smilac, you better get
out there. Your band's in trouble.
What do you mean my band's in...
Captain Lou and... and
The Cannibals are... oh, great
ladies and gentlemen, uh,
Vic Carson can't be with us right now.
He has a slight headache.
But joining me is one of
the great sports announcers
to help me with the blow-by-blow,
Chick Hearn!
Well, thank you very much, Tim.
Ladies, and gentlemen,
it took me a little while
to get up from ring side.
But here we are.
The fight
has just gotten underway.
About 4 and a half months ago
they retained their world championship
by using every dirty trick in the
wrestling game, including chains.
And tonight they're coming
out without their chains,
but they're starting to apply
every kind of unfashionable hold
that the wrestling world
has ever seen.
And so far,
despite that punch by Tonga,
it has been
pretty much The Cannibals.
There's an arm sling,
and out of the ring goes Rick!
Rick is on the cement,
outside of the ring!
Ahhh!
Ugh.
Harry!
A close line. Ooh,
a vicious close line to Tonga.
Look out for this one.
And down goes Tonga!
Tonga may not be able to
get up for a while.
They go outside of the ring
and they floor Rick!
There's all kinds of trouble here.
The world champion tag team looks
like they're gonna successfully defend
without too much of an effort.
But here comes Rick into the ring.
But look at this,
an overhead body slam!
Ooh, that hurts
all the way up here!
That's a body slam by Tonga.
Beautiful move by Tonga.
Is he gonna get the count? Nope,
he hasn't got a one-count.
But that shows them that they
might be back in this fight.
The world championship
is on the line.
Oh, The Hammer delivers a vicious
2-handed blow to the head of Tonga.
Off of the top strand of the rope,
he's gonna try a body press!
But he missed it,
Tonga moved just in time.
He's gotta give the hand to Rick.
He's gotta touch Rick because
Rick's got to get in the fight.
And he does get to him!
Is this some kind of a match?
We hope you're enjoying it.
Oh, there's Tonga,
and he pulls a 2-man pass with it.
And Tonga right now
is a little bit angry himself.
They're gonna try
a double bulldog!
I don't believe it.
A double bulldog!
Ooh, that'll put
your wallet in place.
How about that?
Now, both men are on the floor,
so are The Cannibals.
Why don't they finish 'em?
Because the want to meat out
the same kind of punishment
that put them in the hospital
4 and a half months ago.
Whoo! Tonga flew through
the air like a b-747.
A chance for the pin. 2, 3!
We did it! We did it!
You guys were beautiful!
T #
# I shouldn't be here
touching you #
# and I shouldn't
love the way you feel #
# I know you've got somebody
waiting at home #
# I tried so hard
to tell you no #
# but when you touch me
like you do #
# my best intentions
keep falling apart #
# oh, lord #
# and just when I find
the strength to leave #
# you put your magic spell
on me #
# and baby, I can't hold on #
# my body keeps
changing my mind #
# keeps changing my heart,
keeps changing #
# I lose control #
# my body keeps changing
my mind #
# keeps making me
break down, baby #
# I can't say no #
# you know it hurts
so deep in me #
# watching you run
to him again #
# sometimes I think
it's just not worth the pain #
# then you go back
you're teasing me I
# and loving me like
nobody can #
# you get me falling
all over again #
# and just when I am sure
I can walk away #
# you touch me once
that's all it takes #
# baby I can't hold on #
# my body keeps changing
my mind #
# keeps changing my heart,
keeps changing #
# I lose control #
# my body keeps changing
my mind #
# keeps making me
break down, baby #
# I can't say no #
# do you control me? #
# When you hold me I'm on fire #
# take me higher #
# I feel just like a fool #
# I can't get over you #
# you know the way I feel #
# I never felt before #
# your love is so unreal #
# keeps me knocking
at you door #
# you know the way I feel #
# I never felt before #
# your love is so unreal #
# keeps me knocking
at you door #
# body, body, body, body #
# body, body #
# My body keeps
changing my mind #
# keeps changing my heart,
keeps changing #
# I lose control #
# my body keeps
changing my mind #
# keeps making me
break down, baby #
# I can't say no #
# my body keeps
changing my mind #
# keeps changing my heart,
keeps changing #
# I lose control #
# my body keeps
changing my mind #
# keeps making me
break down, baby #
# I can't say no II