This place is perfect, upscale,
not a meat market.
Full of married, successful men.
You always have to go
for a married guy?
If you can, because they usually
don't even report it.
Don't you ever feel bad about that?
Lauren, I don't hold a gun
to their head, okay?
It's their choice.
They're gonna do what
they're gonna do.
And if they're going to play,
they're going to pay.
You really need to get rid
of this conscience...
if you're going to do this.
I know, I just... I have a hard
time accepting that.
What?
Steal from people.
If you don't wanna to do this,
that's the door.
I owe you too much.
You don't owe me a damn thing, okay?
You're here on your own free
will or not at all.
Look, when the time's right...
and it's your turn, you'll do
just fine.
And you'll see how sleazy
these men are...
and how they get what they deserve.
And who knows,
what we do to them...
sets some of them back on the
path of marital fidelity.
He's interesting.
Either he's new to town
or just passing through.
Well, h-h-how can you tell?
This place is for executive types...
and he's obviously not one.
No wedding ring, either.
So, uh, not what we're looking for?
Look again.
Gold watch, expensive leather
jacket, Italian jeans...
and maybe a hundred-dollar haircut...
and he's really happy about something.
He can't keep that silly grin
off his face.
Which means...
he's looking to celebrate.
Yep, he'd like some company.
Oh, god.
Right there.
He just ordered a
twenty-year-old Scotch.
That seals it.
Hey?
What?
You got protection?
Always.
Just please be careful.
This isn't exactly the first
time I'm doing this.
I'll call you.
Okay.
I'll have what he's having.
Mm.
Another one please.
It's on me.
That's not necessary.
Well, anyone who enjoys it
as much as you do...
it's my pleasure.
In that case... cheers!
Cheers.
Bartender, another round.
This one's on me.
Uh, no, I got this.
It's only fair.
I'm Scott.
Vivian.
I was thinking if we could go
someplace more... quieter.
I don't believe this.
You've never had a one-night
stand before?
Mm, not with anyone like you.
Let me tell you a little secret.
Now and then, every woman likes
to get a little... freaky.
Hey.
What are you doing?
It's time for me to go.
No, no, stay till morning.
It's already morning.
No, look, I don't want you to go.
I think you're the perfect woman.
The perfect woman is a fantasy.
So in a manner of speaking,
you're right.
I wish I could stay in town,
but I can't.
Damn.
I don't want this to end.
Have you forgotten the meaning
of a one-night stand?
Come with me.
What?
I mean it.
Where?
Do you want to sip Mai Tais
in Tahiti, huh?
Just take off with you?
Forget about my job, my family,
my friends?
I'll make it worth your while.
I'm serious.
Yeah, right.
Yeah, you're right,
I'm just being crazy.
Thought so.
One for the road?
I'll never forget you.
I guarantee it.
Not bad.
Now, what were you looking
at in the closet?
Now we're talkin'.
Erica?
I'm almost done.
Bring the car around.
What took you so long?
I was getting worried.
I can't have a little fun
once and a while?
No way.
Oh, my god.
How'd it go?
What's that?
Early retirement.
What?
Drive.
Oh, my god.
How much do you think
this is worth?
If the quality's as good
as I think it is...
altogether, a million.
Probably more.
But who would leave a million
in diamonds in a hotel room?
Someone up to no good who needed
them close at hand...
in case he had to move fast.
Who's bound to come after us.
So? I was careful.
I'm always careful.
Well, he knows what you look like.
I like it.
Don't worry, we'll play it safe.
We'll head to the safe house,
lay low for a couple of months.
What do I always say?
It's good to be bad?
So very good.
Hey, what's the matter?
Not another attack of conscience?
I'm just scared, Erica.
This is a little more than
stealing from a guy's wallet.
He's never gonna come after us.
You should be jumping with joy.
We hit a jackpot.
Come on, cheer up.
Let's go.
Henry. How you doing?
Erica!
What are you doing here, beautiful?
It's the wrong time of year.
I just needed to get away
for a while.
Uh-huh.
This is Lauren.
Oh, hi.
Better watch out, she'll get you
into all kinds of trouble.
Oh, don't I already know that?
You got me all wrong, Henry.
I guess you wanna make a trip
out to the island?
If it's not too much trouble.
Well, you know,
it is such a long way aways...
and I'm not scheduled to go out
there 'til the end of the week.
I'm sure we can make some
arrangement, Henry.
Uh, let me help you
with that luggage.
Oh, thank you, Henry.
Welcome to Isabel Island.
This is really where you live?
When I'm not on the road.
To the locals,
I'm a divorcee from New York.
Erica, what?
We'll come up with your
back story later.
It may not look like much...
but it's the only real home
I've ever had.
Home, sweet home.
It's.. it's nice.
All the comforts,
even satellite broadband.
Spare room is back here.
What are you doing?
Searching for any news about
the diamonds.
You think he called the police?
Depends on where he got them.
What? What's wrong?
He's dead.
Who's dead?
Purcell.
What?
"Investigated, named Scott Purcell...
"Found dead in his hotel room."
Oh, my god, Erica.
You think he's dead because
of us?
No. He was obviously involved
with some dangerous people.
That's nobody's fault but his own.
And what if those same people
just come after us.
We're safe here.
We didn't leave a trail.
We got away clean.
"The victim was last identified walking...
"Down the street with a blonde woman."
That's nothing, that's less
than nothing.
Nobody knows who we are.
Nobody's gonna come find us.
Oh, my god, he's dead, Erica.
He's dead.
Listen to me.
This had nothing to do
with what we did, okay?
What's done is done.
We'll stick together and get
through this, understand?
Mm-hm.
And when this is over,
we'll go far, far away...
and forget this ever happened.
I don't think I can forget
something like this.
You'll be surprised...
at what you can teach
yourself to forget.
We'll bury the diamonds
until we need them...
and get rid of the case.
Well, where are we gonna
put the case?
I know this isn't the most
exciting spot in the world.
I like a little peace and quiet.
Why did you pick me?
What?
Why did you make me your partner?
It's good to have someone
to watch your back.
And since I don't trust men.
You weren't my first partner...
but you could have been the best.
With a face and body like yours...
men would have lined up
to be ripped off by you.
It's too bad you didn't get
to try.
It's quite a rush in the beginning.
So this was just a business decision?
Not entirely.
It's good.
It's good you're getting out
even before you begin.
Before you turn into a cold,
heartless, bitch like me.
It's not who you are.
You're a poor judge of character.
You would have never made it
in this business.
Morning.
Mm.
I'm sorry,
I didn't mean to startle you.
Oh.
Are you okay?
Yeah, I-I-I'm fine.
I'm fine.
I'm Mike Frasier, the, uh,
local peacekeeper.
Of course, if this place was
any more peaceful...
they would all be asleep.
I didn't know they had, uh,
law enforcement on this island.
They didn't until recently.
Um, I transferred into the
Isabel substation.
Oh.
Your tax dollars at work.
Tourist?
I'm just staying with a friend
who has a cabin out here.
That's nice.
How long are you staying?
Just a couple of months.
Wow... what job has that kind
of vacation plan?
Uh, hey, I'm sorry.
I'm not trying to give you the
third degree, just..
Just making conversation.
Oh, no.
I don't think I caught your name.
Oh, it's, uh.. uh, Lauren,
um, Lauren Hailey.
Pleasure to meet you, Lauren.
Maybe I'll see you around.
Yeah.
Who was that?
Uh, just some new sheriff or something.
What are we gonna do?
Nothing. We're law-abiding
citizens, remember?
But, why did he come up to me?
Because you're the most gorgeous
thing around here on two legs.
Ugh.
Except for me, of course.
Aw! You.
Oh, I'm just kidding.
No, it's, y-you're funny,
that's what you are.
Yeah, well, someone has to be.
Have you thought about what
you'll do...
with your cut of the money?
I don't know.
I'm heading to the Caymans...
to buy a little bungalow
on the beach.
You're welcome to come along.
I'll think about it.
Whatever you decide to do,
remember one thing.
Don't become attached to anything.
Want anything?
No, I'm gonna take me a bath.
In the middle of the day?
What's wrong with that?
That guilt you're carrying around,
won't just wash off.
Hi, there.
Oh gosh.
Sorry, I seem to have done it again.
I have a knack for scaring you.
What are you doing here?
Ah, just hiking around the island.
Getting to know the place.
Hoping to hell I didn't make
the wrong decision coming here.
Where's your uniform?
Uh, I'm always on duty, luckily
I don't have to wear the gun...
and the badge 24-7,
if I don't want to.
Which is a good thing, because
it is a bitch in the shower.
I see we're kinda heading
the same direction.
Care for some company?
Sure.
You know, um,
I'm an amateur naturalist.
Oh really?
Oh yeah.
So see this thing over here?
Mm-hm.
We call this a tree.
Is it really?
Yeah, yeah.
Wow. I would have never known.
Thought about taking some day
trips out to the mainland?
I'd love to, but, uh...
Erica says, we should probably
just stay on the island.
Erica?
Oh yeah, uh, that's the friend...
I was telling you,
I'm staying with.
So do you always do everything
Erica says?
I understand this is the highest
point on the island...
Old Fort Jackson.
You don't wanna get too close
to the edge...
'cause it is a long way down.
Oh. This has been really great
but, you know...
I should probably be getting
back.
Uh, yeah, yeah, of course.
You heard about that restaurant
over on Harbor Row?
I hear it's the best one
on the island.
I hear it's the only one
True... true.
Anyway, I was, um, just wondering...
if maybe you'd like to try
it out sometime.
Okay, why not.
Then I'll take why not,
pick you up at 7:00?
I can't wait.
Walk me back?
Absolutely.
Have you gone crazy?
I have got to get out of this cabin.
It's been a week already and
the walls are closing in on me.
I've gotta get out and get
things off my mind for a while.
With the sheriff?
He's a deputy.
Oh yeah, that makes it okay then?
I'll be careful.
I'm not gonna change your mind,
am I?
Nope.
Stick to the back story.
Better still, don't talk
about your life...
and keep him away from here.
Look, I can handle it, okay?
Uh, I don't know about that.
You still got feelings and
that's gonna get you in trouble.
Hey, Francine, how's it goin'?
What'll it be?Tequila.
Ooh... rough day?
Hey, who's the hunk?
I don't know, he came
in a few days ago...
but I do know he has
a very nice boat.
Interesting.
Think of a card.
Got it.
Got it?
Queen of diamonds?
How did you know?
I know that I have a beautiful
queen in front of me.
And I also know that every queen
deserves to find her king.
Look, give me your hand.
Did you feel it?
Feel what?
Magic. Take a look.
Can I offer you a drink?
Who are you?
My name's Tom.
Erica.
Nice to meet you, Erica.
What brings you to Isabel Island?
Checking out some real estate.
Trust me, check somewhere else.
Do you live here?
Couple months out of the year.
Well, there must be something
you like about this place.
The privacy.
So a big developer that comes along...
is not exactly your idea
of a good thing?
I prefer the magician.
Really?
What do you do for a living?
I like to play with fire.
Oh, well,
I'm sure fire loves to play you.
Thanks for dinner.
I, uh,
I really enjoyed getting out.
So did I.
Thank you.
So, your friend...
Mm-hm.
Erica... you must be close.
You see, not too long ago,
I went through this really...
bad time and she really
helped me out.
You both from New York?
Yeah.
See, that's your problem.
New York is too big, too many
people, too many distractions.
You need a simpler lifestyle.
And, uh, how do you know
what I need?
Well, I know that you are a
very stressed young lady.
You're so wound up...
I'm surprised you're not
bouncing on the sidewalk.
I-I don't know what you mean.
At first, I thought it was me,
that you get nervous...
hanging out with such a charming,
handsome guy.
But somehow, I don't think
that's it.
You ask way too many questions.
And you don't like giving answers.
Lauren, look, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
Hey, hey, I got a big mouth,
all right?
I forgot, the goal of a first date...
is to actually make a good impression.
Is this a first date?
I hope it's not our last.
I want to get to know you.
And I think that might take a while.
You're right.
Uh, about what?
I, uh, I do have something
bothering me.
But, I'm not going to tell you,
not ever.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
That is like a really long time.
Well, you're just going to have
to accept that.
Don't be so sure about that.
Well, I have to say, you're
something else.
So I've been told.
You don't have to leave.
Yes, I do.
When can I see you again?
Don't get any ideas.
This was a one-time deal.
Hey, I'm perfectly fine with that,
it's just that..
In that case...
I'll let you know.
Was it intentional?
I don't know. It could have
been a drunk driver.
You said no one could find us here.
I mean, you were gone for so long.
Yeah, I was just out having
a few drinks.
Alone?
With a guy.
What guy?
Some guy with a boat.
Erica.
What?
After all the grief you gave
me about Mike.
I can keep things from getting
serious, but you...
I see you like Mike and it's
gonna get us in trouble.
I'm going to bed.
Don't wake me up before noon.
Ow.
What's the matter?
Hurt my back last night.
Ooh, dodging the car?
Riding the waves with Captain Steve.
Oh, my god.
Oh, god no, here comes
Captain Love Struck.
Afternoon, ladies.
Mike.
What do you two have planned
on this lovely day?
Uh, nothing special.
Just another day in paradise?
You need to look up the word paradise.
Well, since you don't have
anything special planned...
today, maybe you'd like to do
something later?
Uh, I'll let you know.
Shouldn't you be out protecting
the innocent or something?
Are you saying you aren't innocent?
She's...
I think I'm gonna go.
Oh.
I'll call ya later.
Okay.
Last night, did you two...?
No.
You're gonna hurt him, you know.
Like I care.
Lauren?
Yeah?
I want you to be real subtle
about this...
but there is a guy across the street.
I want to know if he looks
familiar to you.
I don't recognize him.
What are you thinking?
I don't know, I guess
I'm still seeing...
those headlights coming at me.
Maybe we should leave the island.
You're saying you're willing
to leave your darling deputy.
Erica...
I know what we are
and what we've done.
I already know what
I signed up for...
and I have accepted the consequences.
I mean, it's never going
to be over...
because no matter what, we'll
always have some stranger...
looking at us, or we'll always
have to be on the move...
because we'll never be sure.
So my question to you right now...
is what do we do?
We stay put... for now.
Let's go.
What are you doing here?
I thought I'd surprise you.
I don't like surprises.
Well I was in the neighborhood
and I thought I had a chance.
I thought we had an understanding.
Anyway, how did you find me?
Well, it's a small island.
What do you want?
Well, I want many things...
but the question is what
do we both want?
This is what I get for messing
around in my own backyard.
You're not staying long.
It's up to you.
I hope that rated as a good
experience.
It was wonderful. You were wonderful.
Mike?
Yeah?
There's something I have to
tell you.
I don't think I'm gonna be
on this island any longer.
I thought you were gonna
be here a couple of months.
Erica and I, we decided to leave.
It's for the best.
For the two of us, I mean.
There's no chance it could've worked.
You don't know that.
Yes, I do. I'm not the person
you think I am.
Mike, I have done some things...
Hey, it can't be that bad.
It is.
I take it this is the stuff
you can't talk about.
Lauren, look, whatever it is,
it's in the past.
Right?
Hey, I know you well enough...
to know that you're not a bad person.
I wish that was the truth.
But you won't let me help you.
Because there's nothing
you could do.
Not if I don't know
what the problem is.
I, uh, just want you to know
that I am..
I'm really glad that we met.
For the time that we have left
on this island, I really...
think that it's best that
we just don't see...
each other anymore, 'kay?
If that's what you want.
I think it'll just make things
easier for when I have to go.
Erica?
Hello?
Um.. um, Tom, Lauren.
Lauren, Tom.
Hey how is going?
So you broke up with the deputy?
He deserves better.
Oh, come on.
Don't put yourself down like that.
It's the truth.
You'll thank me later.
Are you still angry about Tom?
No.No?
You don't really care about him.
You're just using him.
Now you're getting it.
Don't ever let them
get close to you.
Never ever.
Then you can forget them
and move on.
Erica, look.
What?
The current must wash around
here from the fort.
Oh, my god,
we'll have to bury it.
Oh, my god.What?
What is it?
It's a tracking device.
Someone could have tracked us here.
What do we do?
I'll have to destroy it... now.
What do we do? Do we run?
If someone knows we're here,
we've got to find out who it is.
But surely if someone found
anything out...
he wouldn't necessarily
know it was us.
Oh, it would be easy to find out.
We arrived right after the
diamond theft.
So, why hasn't he made his move?
Maybe he already has.
I want you to go online and research...
everything about your
ex-lover boy deputy.
Check his story.
You can't be serious.
From now on,
everyone is a potential threat.
Check out Tom Shepherd as well...
he's supposed to be in real
estate in San Diego.
Close the doors and windows...
and don't let anybody in
and I mean anybody.
You look beaten down.
How can the best and worst day
of my life be the same day?
You want to talk about it?
No.
Good, I get so tired
of pretending to care.
You want another whiskey?
No, I'm good.
It's Deputy Frasier over on Isabel...
I need you to run a name for me.
Erica Tate.
Mid-twenties, 5'6",
could be from New York.
Yeah, any warrants or arrests.
Also, um,
run the name Lauren Hailey.
Yeah, mid-twenties.
Nah, take your time.
Try all the databases and fax
me what you find.
Thanks.
About time you got back.
What are you doing here?
You surprised me yesterday,
I thought, I'll do the same.
Magic, huh? You want more?
Always.
Well, I haven't even started to
show you what I'm able to do.
What happened?
You've been gone so long.
Nothing, I got delayed.
What did you find out?
Well, their backgrounds check out.
I found reference...
on Mike working at the
sheriff's office in Phoenix...
and Tom being a developer
in San Diego.
That doesn't mean we can trust
them. Tomorrow we'll go out...
and find out everyone
who's new to the island.
How?
Strangers stick out on Isabel.
You need to get some rest.
What about you?
I'm not closing eyes until
this is over.
Hey, you, a bit early, isn't it?
I didn't peg you for a morning person.
Who's arrived since I've been
here and stayed.
Only the hunk.
No one else? Are you sure?
Wait a minute, there is this
other guy.
He's only been in here once and,
I've seen him around.
Does he have a boat?
I don't think so...
he came in the same day
Henry did the supply check.
His name is Bill Teague.
What's this about?
It's about forgetting that
I ever asked.
You got it, girl.
Thank you.
His name is Bill Teague.
He's the same guy we saw
from the café.
Erica, maybe no one is after us.
Maybe Scott Purcell put the
tracking device in the case...
and not his killer.
Are you willing to bet
your life on it?
I'm gonna keep digging
until I'm sure.
There he goes.
I want you to follow him.
Okay.
Don't let him see you,
I'll check his room.
Wait, how will you get in?
It's not exactly Fort Knox.
Lauren?
Mike?
We need to talk.
Uh, I'm sorry, w-we really have
nothing to talk about.
Yes, we do... Erica Tate.
Oh, god.
She has quite the rap sheet
there, Lauren...
but I'm guessing you already
knew that.
Now, I don't have any idea
what you've done...
but as far as the law is concerned...
there are open warrants on her.
Mike...
I told you I was not the person
who you thought I was.
I don't care what happened
in the past, all right.
All I'm worried about is
right now.
Get away while you still can,
just walk away from her.
Look, I don't know if you'll
believe me...
but I have already made the
decision to do that, okay?
Yeah, I believe you.
I have to do something, okay?
I- I have to finish what we started...
and I can't let Erica
do it alone, I can't...
so just take this.
Leave me alone, just, uh,
stay away from me.
From the both of us, okay?
I'm sorry. I-I lost him.
It doesn't matter, he's our man.
There are photos of the night
I was with Purcell.
But how?
He had to be tracking Purcell
when we showed up.
And now he's tracking us.
We're gonna draw him out here,
get him away from the town.
You mean, kill him?
That's the only way.
And what about when he goes missing?
We'll clear out his room.
Leave some money on the dresser
to cover the bill.
I doubt anyone will ever ask
any questions.
Well, what if he has friends,
uh, families, partners?
We'll be long gone, pick up
new identities on the way.
It'll be over.
I can't do this anymore.
I want out.
Lauren, I told you...
the days of picking up guys
in bars are over, okay?
We'll have enough to..
I don't want the diamond money!
Look, I know you're upset, okay.
But he came after us and he'll
keep coming until we're dead.
I am not running out on you, Lauren.
Get down! Go! Go!
Go. Go!
What are you going to do?
Stay here.
Lauren! I asked you to wait inside!
I think I lost him.
Let's get back in.
Did you see who it was?
He was too far away.
I don't think he was trying
to kill us.
What?
He was trying to scare us
thinking we'll grab 'em...
and go and that's when he'll
get us.
You're gonna have to stay,
after all.
'Cause if you leave now, he'll
think you've got the diamonds...
and he'll go after you.
Wha.. what do we do?
The plan hasn't changed.
We kill him before he kills us.
I'm going to keep an eye on Teague...
we've got to be ready
the next time he shows up.
Let me go with you.
It's easier to follow him alone.
Here.
Oh no, you take it.
If I miss him,
use it like I showed you.
Please, be careful.
Hello?
[OM] Hey, it's Tom.
Well, listen, I just wanted to
tell you that I'm leaving.
What?
I have to go back to San Diego.
I'm sorry, my dear...
I didn't want to go
without saying goodbye.
It was fun, Erica,
we had some laughs.
So did I.
Hey, I promise you next time
I'll be back, I'll look you up.
You do that.
See you soon, baby.
Mike, you shouldn't be here.
I just found these a couple
yards from the cabin.
They'd just been fired.
You wanna tell me what the
hell's going on?
Can't you just leave me alone?
Where's Erica?
She's not here.
Okay, I want to talk to her.
No, you'll only make things worse.
I can help you.
You can't help me and still be
the person that you are.
Lauren, look...
just forget that I'm a deputy
sheriff, all right?
Whatever trouble it is, my only
concern is for you.
Look, if you really have
feelings for me...
please just don't get involved
in this.
I-I gotta take this.
Deputy Frasier.
What?
'Kay, calm down.
How badly are you hurt?
Hello?
Some hiker's hurt himself
out at Fort Jackson.
Look, I gotta go,
but I'll be back, okay?
Erica!
I'm outside the motel, but I
haven't seen any sign of Teague.
So be on the lookout.
Mike came by.
What did he want?
He wants to talk to you,
he knows something is wrong.
What have you said to him?
Nothing.
Things are getting way...
too hot around here, we'll have
to take our chances and run.
I'll head back.
Get ready to move fast.
I'll call Henry for a lift.
Hello?
Are you ready?
I'm almost packed.
Forget that, we have to travel
light and fast.
We'll take the clothes on our
backs and the diamonds.
What's that?
Uh..
It's Mike's SUV.
What is he doing here?
I'll deal with him, get ready.
Deputy Frasier?
Erica!
Erica! Erica!
Lauren!
Go!
Is he still following?
I don't know,
but we need to keep going.
Hold it right there.
Don't move.
No, no, no, I..
I'll give you the damned
diamonds, just let us go.
Wh-wh-what the hell are you
talking about?
No, no, no, get back
to the cabin, let's go, go.
Move! Faster!
Who are you?
You don't remember me, do you?
So how many has it been?
Dozens? Hundreds?
Oh, my god.
How many lives have you ruined?
That's right.
Am.. am I coming back to you?
Let me refresh your memory.
Saint Petersburg, Florida?
Three years ago?
I'm not good with names or faces..
Bill Teague, pharmaceutical rep,
I was there for a convention.
I never cheated on my wife.
Never!
That's what this is about?
It couldn't have been that much.
Get over it.
When you left that night, yeah.
That's right,
she found out what happened.
Do you know what you took
from me?
Everything!
You took my wife!
You took my kids!
You took my job, you took my life!
Do you know the pain
that you caused me?
Do you even care?
Do you?
Well, I'm gonna make sure...
that it never happens again...
to anyone!
Move! Move.
Under there.
Move!
How did you find me?
I saw you in Atlantic City
four weeks ago.
Hair was different,
but I knew it was you.
I've been following you ever since.
But, why kill Purcell?
I don't know any Purcell.
I've only killed one person,
so far.
You know, it was surprisingly easy...
when you have nothing to lose.
What are you doing with Mike's SUV?
Won't be needing that anymore.
No... no.
You're lying.
Oh, I would have killed
your lover, too.
But he got away before
I could get to it.
You sick freak.
I wanted you to feel the loss
that I felt.
Take everything from you,
like you took everything from me.
I think I did your wife a favor.
Move!
I'll be back with a shovel later.
She wasn't with me then.
She wasn't a part of it.
Well, she's a part of it now.
And you obviously care about
her very much.
Answer it.
Hello?
I called for a boat earlier.
You tell him that you won't be
needing it any longer...
but you know somebody who will.
Henry, there has been
a change of plans.
I'm staying, but I know someone
who needs off the island.
Yeah, he'll pay what I pay.
You tell him I'll be there
in a couple of hours.
Can you wait for two hours?
He'll meet you at the dock.
I can make you a very rich man.
Those diamonds I mentioned
earlier..
I don't care anything
about any diamonds.
We're talking about millions
of dollars.
That can buy a lot of forgiveness.
Think of it...
you can rebuild your life,
your family, everything.
I'll make the deal even sweeter.
All the money, if you let
Lauren go...
and you can do what you want
with me.
Erica, no.
Shut up, Lauren, Bill's right.
I've done some very bad things
and I deserve to be punished.
No, I won't let you sacrifice
yourself for me!
It's my life.
Erica, he's psycho!
So what!
Please!
Shut up, you heard the man,
shut up.
Shut up! Shut up, both of you!
Shut... up.
Tie him up.
I'm gonna get the rope.
It's in Mike's SUV.
What are we gonna do with him?
Oh, what do you think?
Oh, no.
Lauren, he's crazy.
He killed Mike and he won't stop
until we're dead.
I am not going to have blood
on my hand anymore.
He knows all about us.
The police, the FBI, everybody
will be after us.
I don't care.
I'll go get the diamonds.
We'll talk when I get back.
Lauren!
Lauren! Lauren!
Tom?
I understand you're a bit
of a con artist...
but I'm pretty sure you were
not expecting...
to be conned yourself, right?
Where's Lauren?
She's here, with me, on the boat.
Let me talk to her.
Talk to your friend.
Go to hell!
Oh god, fuck! Fuck.
I have what you want,
you have what I want!
Let's make an even trade, right?
Where?
On the boat.
No.
Well, I'm not gonna do it...
in the middle of town!
Fort Jackson.
Where is it?
Lauren knows the way.
You've got thirty minutes.
It's better for you if your
friend shows up.
You know that?
You fucking sicko.
Toss the gun!
Slowly.
Stop.
You searched my purse.
You checked my boat.
It was you, all along.
Magic, right?
Where are my diamonds?
Who are you? Tell me.
Tell me or I swear,
I'll throw them.
You know, becoming your lover
was not part of the plan...
but I did really enjoy it.
Problem is that when I shot
at you at your home...
you were supposed to grab the diamonds...
and come running to me to get
off the island, but you didn't.
Running to a man isn't my style.
Oh no, your style is stealing
from a man.
Who owns these diamonds?
One of my men stole them from me.
Purcell... you killed him.
Now, give me my diamonds.
Stay back.
Show me the diamonds are
inside there.
Satisfied?
Give it to me.
Close enough.
How much money do you think
I hold in my hands?
Twenty thousand? Thirty?
Stop it! Stop it, for god's sake.
How would you like
to lose them all?
All right.
Lauren, take the Jeep and go, now.
No, please,
I'm not leaving you alone.
You're wasting my time!
Give me my diamonds!
Wasn't it all a waste of time?
You saying you faked it.
Erica!
Hey, Tom.
Catch!
Mike!
Not so tight.
Let's get you up, okay?
Okay.
I heard everything.
What happens now?
Well, I call the Sheriff's office...
and I report I was in an accident...
coming back from Old Fort Jackson...
after discovering that someone
fell off the cliff.
Really?
Yeah.
Thank you.
What about Bill Teague?
Who?
That man that Tom killed,
who was also after us.
I think he's going to disappear...
along with everything else
in his motel room.
Is there anybody else?
That should do it.
Ladies, I'll give you guys
a moment alone.
Thank you.
I'll take your bag.
I'll see you on the boat.
All right, baby.
So, uh, I guess this is it.
I guess so.
What are you gonna do?
What I always do... survive.
You could just go straight.
I'll give it some thought.
Take care of your lover boy
and enjoy your normal life.
You're not supposed to get
attached to people.
Get going.