If they only were Rudy,
I wouldn't take another step.
- But there's only one Rudy.
- She's bit all light.
She's driving me completely mad,
that's for sure.
Just one Rudy. And so many
millions and millions of us.
Let's get out of here.
Hurry up, they are coming.
The car.
Be my sheep and ride with me
over the sand dunes.
Kiss me, Rudy.
Kiss me quickly.
- God, I could have loved her.
- I could have too.
Do you realize that tomorrow
we are finally free.
We can actually ride across
the sand dunes and be loved.
Actually lie down and be loved.
We're so overdue,
as we both know too well.
Everything in its time. We are the
most educated women in this country.
But in the ways of love
we're kindergarten toddlers.
Cat, fantastic idea: let's not start
our graduation trip in Paris.
- Oh God. - Look, let's start...
- I love this.
Galloping across the burning sands of
Morocco in the arms of a real sheik.
Listen, we can spend our nights
learning of ecstasy.
What a beautiful word, ecstasy.
Ext...
- No. E-C ecstasy.
- Let's go on it.
- Mac, I don't know. You're serious.
- Do the backstroke in it.
- You are serious.
- Then you'll go?
- Do I have a choice? - No.
- I don't like choices.
Congratulations to you, Miss Pipps.
Tomorrow the Sahara.
Blood on the sand.
Well done, Miss McGillvary.
Oh, Cotton. Stop the car.
Sorry. I just have to do something
that I've been dreaming of for years.
I'm sorry.
Yes!
- Who was that?
- I believe that's the attorney.
- What's he so happy about? - He
probably liked the entertainment.
Cotton. I'm so sorry.
I've embarrassed you.
How awful for you. But, you see,
I just had to do this. I had...
I had so many years of being
so very proper, I got claustrophobia.
You're terribly embarrassed.
Can you ever forgive me?
- That's not my position.
- Not your position?
No, Miss.
Because you drive that big car,
you can't forgive me for something?
- That more or less covers it.
- Because you drive the car.
- Yes. - Then I'll drive the car.
Can you forgive me now?
You'll drive the car?
Does that mean that I'm fired?
If that's what it takes
to allow you to answer.
I haven't been without a job
since I was thirteen years old.
Okay, what was the question?
Do I forgive you for embarrassing me?
That was the question.
- At first I was puzzled. Then“
- You were embarrassed.
- No.
- I'm glad.
How was amazed how much you changed
since the last time I say you naked.
- Naked? - I thing you were three
or four. You've grown well.
I think that was nicely said.
Would you like your old job back?
- Is it still available? - It is if
you'll be my friend and talk to me.
- I haven't much to say.
- But you'll say it?
Let's get the hell out of here.
He's a pretty spiffy
looking attorney.
Today is the day I become
an excessively rich little bitch.
- You'll still be my friend.
- If that's the way to keep my job.
- Unit's the only way.
- Pretty tough way to keep the job.
I'm told life is not easy.
Hi!
Miss McGillvary, I'm Robert Stewart,
your father's armour solicitor.
I mean you no disrespect. Not at all.
To the contrary.
I wish when I graduated, I'd been
cheeky enough to do what you did.
I give you my diploma,
and you give me what?
Gee whiz it's Cotton.
I think I own the whole world.
At least all the good parts of it.
Now we must watch our steps
in every sense of the word.
As we wind our way
through the casbah. Come.
We should have a policeman with us.
Don't you think we should have one?
They wouldn't be welcome here. It's
more dangerous for them than for you.
Life is not without its risks.
A ponder a bit more in the casbah.
Hey, Mohanmed. Look, look.
I'm still scared.
Cat, I'll protect you with my life
if necessary.
Protect me? You're half naked.
They'll get you first.
- No. They'll what?
- Make you not a virgin
Isn't that what we're here for?
This door, it may this very night
hold in its bosom your sheik.
Wow.
Shall we see? We can ask Allah
for one authentic sheik.
If you'd be so kind.
I like that.
Don't you like that, Cat?
Yeah, I like it. Come on.
So sweet.
Catalina, look.
Look!
- What do the camels do?
- They are for sale.
- Cotton, wouldn't you just love one?
- "Phat may be too strong a word.
Allah is kind. Mliss, your sheik.
- Miss? Your sheik!
- Sheik?
Yes, he is a young one.
A pop you might say.
He comes from the south,
across uncountable miles of sand.
- His father is a great pasha.
- Catalina, do you see him?
- No.
- Well, look.
Hey, Mac, he could be your sister!
Miss, would you like to meet
the sheik now?
I'll wait here, thanks.
If you're still with me, Cotton.
- We'll stay here. - You're not
going to pass on a real sheik?
- There's only one. - Being that's
probably enough for both of us.
But if you are too scared,
I'll brave this one myself.
Okay. We wait. Go.
Honourable sheik. Allow me to
introduce this American lady to you.
She has come all the way
from her country just to meet you.
How do you do?
- Well, thank you. And you?
- You are a vision.
- Thank you. You may go now.
- Miss McGillvary?
Thank you. I'll be fine. Tell my
friends I'll rejoin them in a minute.
As you wish.
Sit here, if you like.
Please.
I never dreamed
that there was anyone,
anyone on this earth like you.
If there was,
I shall never look upon her.
- And now I am Allah is too kind.
- No, it's you that is too kind.
What did that man say?
You've come to meet me?
- Yes.
- Why? May I know why?
- Well, it's along story.
- Does it have a short answer?
- Yes, it does.
- It is possible that I may hear it?
Well, it's going
to sound so stupid now.
I've come all this way to give
you something you may not even want:
my virginity.
I've never been given
this before. Is it ?ue?
Will you take the gift?
This very night. You'll come with me
to my palace and I will take
your gift with great happiness.
I had dreamed of a beautiful tent
and desert.
I can give you the whole
golden Sahara and a thousand tents.
- We'll leave tonight.
- It's not too far?
- I have an aeroplane.
- You have an aeroplane?
- How else could I fly you?
- Of course. Could we go tomorrow?
- I'll be carrying the same
with me? - Only a day older.
- Do you think I'm mad, Cotton?
- No, not mad. - Or maybe bad?
- The truth?
- Can I take it?
- I envy your spirit.
- Thank you.
This is a parachute.
I'm going to buckle it right here.
- I don't want you to use it.
- No.
- But if you have to, you pull this
little right, right there. - Okay.
- I'll save the biggest piece
of the cake for you. - Mac.
That's because I love you and because
this airplane scares me too much.
I'll rather you were going
on a camel.
This is a magnificent aircraft.
It's at least five years
ahead of its time.
An experimental design.
It's magnificent.
Everything's all light.
Hold on fight.
The sun's completely gone.
Her fat's in the fire now.
I don't know about that. She should
not have troubles handling that boy.
May I have the pleasure?
No, thank you. I don't wanna live
my husband alone. Thanks for asking.
- Dance with the gentleman.
- You don't mind?
You know how much I like to see
my wife have a good time.
- Go on. Hurry. Tell me.
- Cat, all right.
Well, we ?ew over
a billions miles of sand.
Remember, Cat,
how in the moving pictures,
Valentino rode the sand dunes and
swept the heroine off her feet.
- Yes.
- I asked my sheik to do that to me.
You should have seen him.
It was so sad.
Every time he would try to be
Valentino and sweep me off my feet,
his horse would go to the other way.
What happened?
- What's the matter?
- I hate horses.
You can't hate horses.
You are a sheik.
I know I'm a sheik.
I had an English nanny.
- He had an English nanny?
- The nanny was all right.
I go to school at Oxford. I've been
here three times my whole life.
- I'm a poet.
- You're still a sheik.
It will be hard to keep us
with this for the rest of my life.
Do you realize that no man on this
earth will ever again know the joy
that you
will bring me this night.
You're like a most precious ?ower.
Your blooming can only be enjoyed,
once. just once.
His tent was a dream
It was gigantic.
Filled with servants
and dancing girls, and belly dancers.
They do incredible thing
with their stomachs, Cat.
What? What do they do?
Fantastic. What happened then?
- He kissed me.
- What?
- He lay me down so gently, but
positively. - I'd have died.
- And then, he undressed me.
- What?
Everything? I mean, everything?
- Everything. - Was everyone still
there? - No. He had them sent away.
Every time he went for the honey,
my stomach would sort of rise
to meet his lips.
- Why would your stomach rise?
- I guess it was inviting him.
- To where, Mac, to where?
- Catalina! - There, of course.
- What? - Cat? - What?
- I have been lying.
Lying!
I don't know, when we were...
When it should have happened...
No, Mac. He went to sleep?
It's all right.
My ego tells me the sleep was from
the magic smoke, not me.
Oh, Rudy.
Why are they all counterfeits?
Look at me. I'm all undressed up
with no place to go.
Mac, Mac. Now what do we do?
Well, we try again.
Not this place. Scares me.
Couldn't we go some place
like Switzerland? Or Sweden?
- Holland? It's a nice place.
- Holland? Cat...
It should be warm and sultry and dark
eyed when you give virginity away.
Like Italy or Spain
Italians scare me too much And Mac,
I can't give my virginity away
in Spain. I am Spanish.
I know you are Spanish
And you can't go to Barcelona.
So we won't even go near Barcelona.
Hello, Toro.
- Matador.
- You're a matador.
- Too many seasons ago.
- It must have been magnificent.
I hate some afternoons.
My God, what's he doing?
The horse could be killed.
This is a kind of festival.
You see the bull's hams?
They're capped. But even in the big
bull ring, you never kill bulls.
If you go used to fight
without the blood. Nothing.
Me is not so popular with the people.
I like little bit of blood.
Cotton, did you understand
what he said?
Yeah He never the bull kills,
never the blood sheds.
Therefore he's not very popular
with the people.
I think I'm going to enjoy it.
- Does all this make the ends of your
boots curl up? - Tight as a drum.
- Who's that?
- She is his gypsy shadow.
- Cotton, did you...
- She's his gipsy shadow.
Mac, what's wrong?
I'm gonna see the duke
who's half man half horse.
- Where do I find him?
- In the chapel. - Okay.
See you later, everybody.
- I'm sorry.
I just wanted to say I've never seen
anything so beautiful.
Nor have I.
Do you think it's possible
could I see your horses?
With pleasure.
You know horses.
I love them.
I was raised with them at school.
But ours were different: they would
run and jump and go around the field.
But yours are magical. They're like
Pegasus. Aren't you like Pegasus?
I would consider it an honour if
you would join me at dimer tonight.
- Thank you. But I have two friends.
- Bring them.
Thank you.
You didn't have to invite them to
our private moments for family only.
It's bad enough that
that gypsy child is always with you.
We never have any time alone,
with you living in the country.
You never come to the city.
- Why don't you put butter on your
mouth? - I didn't come here to eat.
That's too bad.
That was very fine chow.
He hasn't spoken to us all night.
Hardly even a look.
Did you invite enjoy the fight,
Cotton?
- He's sending you messages?
- You noticed?
- That's a pretty big message.
- Feels like it.
It's nice, Cat?
- If that's what you want.
- Come on, Cat, have some fun.
Send someone a message.
- Who I see there?
- Him.
Angel, Angel. She looked at me.
- Mac, God.
- lust practice on him
Yeah, you're mad.
I could be if someone
would just give me the chance.
She knows a real man when
she sees one. Now it's your table.
Take care of the woman.
See Mama home.
- You must come to see me more often.
- I will, Mama.
Goodnight.
Mama.
- Where's he going?
- I know where he goes.
I know you know.
That's why I'm asking. Where?
- Why do you care where he goes?
- I want to see him.
I don't think he wants.
- What's your name.
- Paloma.
Paloma, do you think
we could do business with this?
- The mirror is for me?
- It is if you take me to him.
- Do you accept? - Is too much.
For you is nothing.
No, for me is very beautiful
and very valuable.
- For me, too.
- Good, then it's done?
- Sure.
- Okay.
- Now, are we going to be welcome?
- You are no welcome,
because for a gipsy
no stranger is welcome.
But you are with me.
So will be all light.
- Okay. Sorry.
- I think.
Angel, Angel.
I have the rich lady.
- Why do you bring her here?
- She gave me this.
- What lady? - The blond lady.
Angel and Ramon say
she is the most beautiful woman
in all the world.
You want to go to the bed
with my man?
- None of us want to go to bed
with your man. - It's true?
Do I look so dishonest?
- It's hue?
- I think your man is very beautiful.
You say good. And do you want
to take him to your bed?
- I think. - I think no.
I'm the woman for his bed.
And there will be no other.
No other.
- Tres du may.
- Hey. How long has he been with her?
Since her thirteen years birthday.
Is me next.
Soon he's going to take me.
- He'll do what?
- Take me. I'll be his woman.
You'll be his what?
- Woman.
- Oh, damn
It looks like you're all out of luck.
The little firebrand
is taking her man to bed.
You know something? I think
it's time we all went beddy-bye.
Why he do that?
He do no even like her anymore.
Thank you Paloma. It's been
a very interesting experience.
- I hope your 14th birthday come
soon - You're not going to town?
Like Cotton said,
we are all going to bed.
- Where will you sleep? - Wherever
they sleep, I sleep on the ?oor.
You've got a deal.
- Get out of the tub.
- I wanna stay here forever.
I'm sorry, that's not possible.
What a mess. Look at you!
What are we going to do today?
Am I going to help you?
- Absolutely. Here we go, up.
Stand up. - No.
- What are you going to do?
- I'm going to rinse you off.
- But why?
- So you don't itch.
- But...
- Look at you.
I am woman. Ready.
Juicy too.
We're not up here, freezing our tiny
titties off,
because you just want
to buy a house today.
- We are not?
- No, Miss McGillvary, we are not.
You want this beautiful yan
to quickly beg your virginity.
That's why we're freezing up here
in the dumb car that won't 11111.
I might kill two birds
with one stone.
Don't you have to be in love
with him to do that?
I don't know.
I've never done it before.
Oh my God.
All light. Very slowly,
everybody back into the car.
- Okay.
- But he could break this car.
I'll hit it between the eyes.
- Cotton, there's a bull.
- There's a lot of bull.
What are you doing way up here?
She said you may be in the mountains
for a week. I couldn't wait.
You came to see me?
Some of your bulls had run up
into the mountains after cows,
and you're to get them before
they froze. Was that one of them?
He was.
Why did you want to see me?
- I want to buy some of your horses.
- I don't sell horses.
- Not even young ones?
- I sell wine and bulls.
- I don't sell horses. I'm sorry.
- "Phat seems so final.
I'm sorry. I feel so badly.
I would like to offer you
the hospitality of my home.
But it's so far away
from this mountain top.
Well, if you found all you wayward
bulls, you'd ride in the car with us.
- That would be very nice of you.
- It's our pleasure.
Raphael? You were supposed
to bring back all the horses.
Assuming you owned one of my horses
right now.
- What should you do with it?
- If I owned one of your horses now?
I'd tell him I am not your owner,
I'm your friend.
Gracias, Raphael.
These horses are nothing
without the bulls.
Can you really see yourself
doing this?
I can. But then some people
think I'm crazy.
You're sure there's no amount
of money that can buy that horse?
- No amount. - But isn't it said
that everything has its price?
My wine does. My horses don't.
- Mac, that's a beautiful horse.
- I know. I want him.
Sure you do.
May I invite you to dimer tonight,
trying to change your mind?
I would enjoy such a dinner.
But I have planes I cannot cancel.
- What a shame. You're sure?
- Sadly it's hue.
- What if I were not to talk about
horses, but wine? - Even more sadly.
I surrender.
I've run out of what it's.
If we get back to the hotel,
we'll dine with the old gang tonight.
I think I'm just going to go
to bed and lick my wounds.
You just lost a battle.
You didn't lose a war.
Mac, do you think Cotton believed
your little wounded lady story?
I think so. It was partly true.
Why I can't come with you?
Because an Appian den is not a place
for little girls.
You can stay there and bath,
I mean swim in the tub.
I'm no little girl.
Mac. Do you know
anything about opium?
Next to nothing. Except
that it sounds romantic.
The textbooks say
that opium has two faces.
First a face: killer,
in large amounts.
Second a face, a love potion,
in small amounts.
Well, then it seems
as long as we're going to use it,
it should be exclusively
in the romantic amount.
Paloma.
Are you sure Angel's
going to be in this place tonight.
Sure he's going to be.
If he not there tonight,
I'll give you back...
mirror and pearl.
Please!
All right. I make exceptions
for you and your friend.
- Thank you very much
- Do you know the puppy well?
- We are acquainted.
- May I offer to guide you?
If you would be so kind.
A love potion, in small amounts.
Are we really going to do this?
- I am.
- Well I hope we have a good time.
Oh, shit. I can't.
It's so hot.
Mac?
Can you feel yourself going or gone?
Definitely. Can you?
Nice, really.
Nice? Oh, Cat,
it's more than nice.
I know.
The lady said: move slowly.
Always slowly.
I think it's time to find Angel.
- Is something wrong?
- No.
We were expecting Angel Sacristan.
I see. If you wait a minute, please.
Of course. We'll wait.
It looks as though our little gypsy
was light.
Seems he is here.
If he is, what are you going to do?
- Lie down and say: hi?
- Hi?
I don't sell horses.
Only wine and bulls.
How many bottles of wine
would you say you had?
Maybe a million.
What? Nobody has
a million bottles of wine.
I wonder how long it would take to
count to a million bottles of wine.
What happened? About three hundred
bottles... I mean, this...
- We got... And this is no way?
- What? No.
- Twenty...
- Was I light?
One 1111111011,
two million, five million?
Angel, how much would it take
to buy everything you produce?
- Everything that I produce?
- Yes.
- Do you know about wine?
- Catalina's family has vineyards.
- Look, Angel, can you excuse us
a minute? - Of course.
Mac, buy it.
You have too much money. Buy it.
I'll run it. If I was a boy,
I was supposed to run ours.
- Please do it. I'll divide up
the profit. - Yes.
I'll accept whatever two out three
local banks value my wine it. Fair?
Fantastic!
You must immediately close the deal
with the bank
because they hold
the paper on the wine.
They're saving their position.
Go to the lab: we leave immediately.
Tell the bank that we're coming.
Fantastic. Wow! Fantastic!
Fantastic! God!
Well...
now that that's behind us,
why don't we talk about
that honey coloured horse?
I'm sorry but
I really don't sell horses.
Maybe the word sell is where
we're having our problem.
Maybe.
- It was wonderful. Did you freeze?
- Didn't you?
I was warm as toast. I think
I'm intoxicated by your horse.
- Your horse.
- Of course, my horse.
I never dreamed there was such a
beautiful horse. What am I smelling?
- Hot cinnamon wine.
- Oh, I'd love some.
- Didn't I smell something
chocolaty... - Angel!
You gave her the golden horse.
- Hardly, I...
- I don't speak to you.
- Natty, she is my guest.
- Your guest.
- Goodnight, Natty. - You bitch.
- All light. That's enough.
You bitch. Bitch!
- Now I kill you, I have to kill you.
- No more, Natty. No more.
- You're going back to camp.
- Love me tonight.
Stop it, please.
Please stop it, Natty.
- Now I have to kill you.
- Shut up. - You shut up.
- I kill you for sure.
- Then go get you knife.
Please, Natty. Go home.
Hello.
I apologize.
I think
I've known her too long.
You've know her, I believe
since her fourteenth birthday.
The gypsy world is very different.
Fourteen years is very different.
Does this interest you?
I'd be lying if I said I didn't.
Fine. Why don't we go to a more
comfortable room,
enjoy some chocolate cake
and investigate the difference.
And then he fell asleep. So now
you have the story of my sheik.
Maybe you should
have come to Spain first.
Maybe I should have.
And now would you consider
giving this burden to me?
Would you be interested in taking it?
Please.
Rest. And I'll join you here
at sunrise.
Sunrise.
Now seems just perfect.
The fruit is about
to fall from the tree.
That was beautiful, thank you.
I'll rest in here tonight.
Make sure to wake me exactly,
and I mean exactly
half hour before the sun rises.
Well, tonight you make baby.
He's either very clever
or very cruel.
Because I'm going mad with wonder.
Angel. Angel. It's time.
Angel. You awake?
What are you doing?
I thought you should be
as scared to death as I am
- You are a ghost who is afraid?
- It's about to wet it's pants.
I was so secure
when I came in here last night
but then I was also
as high as a kite. Angel?
Angel? What are you doing?
Have you gone?
Are you still here?
Angel, are you still here?
I knew this sheet was a dumb idea.
I shouldn't done the...
Oh my God.
You are as naked
as the day you were born.
That's true. But only because
it's been found to be
the most practical way to make love.
- Are you gonna kiss me?
I thought I was.
- May I kiss you instead?
- Whatever you like.
Okay.
- Where would you like us to be?
- I don't know.
The bed. The bed would be nice.
- Is there anything I can do to help?
- I don't know...
Yes, lie down please.
Could you lie down please.
I think that
would make it even better.
I've always imagined this would be
a fabulous kiss.
Put your head down, please.
Now close your eyes,
and keep them closed.
Remember, this is my kiss.
You do nothing.
Was my imagination lousy?
Was it a blah kiss?
- It was a great kiss.
- I'm sorry, it was a blah kiss.
- It was a fabulous kiss.
- I'm sorry.
Angel, now. Right now.
Will you show me everything?
Do everything to me?
Show me everything I can do to you.
Am I too greedy?
You must be greedy.
The bed is a selfish place.
In it we seem to give only
so that we may receive.
Is there enough I can give to you,
so that you can give ecstasy to me?
That we will have
to look for together.
Do you mind, Marie?
Marie? Do you mind? Please!
Gracias.
Open.
No, please. I'm sorry.
I'm not a virgin anymore.
Ola? Si, diga me.
Si, un momenta. Angel, the telephone.
He wants you.
- Ola. Catalina. Que tal?
- Hello.
Hello.
- Gracias. Do you like it? - It's the
most beautiful thing in the world.
I have to go to the bank.
Sign papers.
- I'll go with you.
- You will not.
You will enjoy your horse
and when I return tonight,
we will celebrate your horse and
the entering wine business. And...
I see here you're holding
several valuable items.
1924, Rolls motor car and some art.
Why do we take care of these as well?
There you are gentlemen.
Here.
Come on!
We did it, Angel! We did it, Angel!
- Angel, he go to your bed?
- No.
- I think he go.
- No, Paloma.
I went to his bed.
All right, enough talk. Out, out.
Bitch! Bitch! American bitch!
- Bitch! Damn it! [at me go!
- I got it.
Bitch. Let me go.
- Now what are we gonna do? - leave
her there. No like her anyway.
Miss McGillvary? Come out, come out.
Come out wherever you are.
Catalina!
- Olé, Paloma.
- Olé. - I'm sorry.
We're going to have stop dancing
and get some rest.
Horses and bulls ship out tomorrow.
And the following day I fight.
- You do?
- Yes, and from the look of things,
your friend can't ?y.
So, everybody will stay here.
It's awful for him.
No one comes to see him.
- Can't they see the beauty in that?
- This is too different for them
It's always the other way
with the killing.
He should be in a beautiful ring with
thousands of people cheering him.
Not here with a few people wondering
what he is.
They want the killing man.
They want the blood.
Marie, go home. Go home, Marie.
Marie, please shut up.
Go home, go home.
How is the horse? Is he hurt?
- Fine, fine.
- Are you sure?
- Take Marie home.
- What? Do what?
The dog, Marie. Take her home.
I'm all light.
- You're all light? Really?
- I'm fine.
He's alive and I just don't care.
Mac, I know I sound cruel
but that's romantic.
- It's not. - You don't care if he
can never make love to you again?
No, I don't care.
Mac, one time in your life.
That's going to be it?
- It looks like it may be.
- This is crazy.
- This really stinks.
- No...
It's all right. In a couple of weeks
he'll be as good as new.
Not really.
All they said was he most probably
won't be able to...
Probably. That's means
there's a chance.
That's a pretty strong probably.
Okay. Forget about how you feel
for a minute. What about him?
Can you imagine what's going on
inside him right now?
Do you see? Do you see?
I can't. I'm just not gonna believe
what they say.
- Okay, tiger. Okay.
- Okay, tiger.
I'm going to be one.
May I come in?
- Do you have a minute?
- I have a minute.
Now pay attention and concentrate
on what I'm about to say.
- Are you concentrating?
- I'm trying.
All right.
Now give me your hand.
Will you marry me?
Pay attention.
I'm proposing.
I will ask you again.
Will you marry me?
I would marry you in a minute, in
a second. But as I'm sure you know,
I've no light to. Not now.
- Because of...
- Yes, because of!
All right. Okay.
Consider this then.
You teach me everything you can do
with these horses...
and watch me... and grow to love me
more and more each day.
And soon the predictions of the
dooms-day doctors is no longer true.
Then you can sweep me into your arms,
drag me to the altar
and then we can live
happily ever after.
Can't we make a deal to do this?
Some of it, for sure.
I'll accept that for now.
Do you like the outfit?
Don't answer that.
I may never take it off.
That thing is going to work.
I guarantee you this.
Hello! Hello!
- Excuse me.
- You calling me?
Miss McGillvary told me
I'd find Catalina Terry.
- And the winery. Are you she?
- Yeah, that's me, that's me.
That's me, that's me.
How do you do? I'm sorry.
- That's okay.
- Who are you?
- Robert Stewart. Pleased to meet ya.
- Nice to meet you. I...
I'm one of Miss McGillvary's
solicitor’s.
- Attorney, solicitor?
- Oh yes, she told me about you.
Hey, you're handsome.
So handsome.
Are you gonna help me
to make a big company out of this?
I shall try my best.
What do you wear under that thing?
Everybody jokes about that.
Aye. To know that, you must
get to know me much better.
- What?
- To know me much better.
Do you like virgins?
- I don't understand.
- Virgins. Do you like virgins.
- Virgins?
- Yes.
I'm afraid I'm not
a connoisseur of
Are there connoisseurs of virgins?
How strange.
Why won't tell me
what you have under that skirt?
What is under your skirt?
If we'll be friends, you won't call
this kilt a skirt any more. Clear?
What? What, tell me.
Don't call the kilt a skirt. It isn't
a skirt, it's a kilt. Is that clear?
Yes, very clear.
Absolutely.
Eight days and that sulking,
pouting, little boy
stays in his room like Scrooge.
Put a thing, so I can put a thing.
- It's not easy. - Sure it's easy.
- Put the best one.
Okay, let's see what you can do.
Easy. I win.
- No? - You win yes.
- And now I'm going to go to bed
and cry. - let's take a walk.
Me too. I go to cry.
Cry Angel.
Every night.
CW Angel.
No, really, Cotton.
I'd rather be in bed crying.
- A very short walk.
- Very very short.
I know. But you may be wanting
marriage because of this
rather than in spite of it.
That's pan of what I'm going
to go cry about.
If you let me go to bed.
As long as you understand,
then you're dismissed.
- I love you, Cotton
- Me too.
You were really a cowboy?
I was until I got so big the horses
figured they were going to ride me.
Did you kiss your horse?
Like in the moving picture.
I kissed 'me better than anybody.
I was a really good kisser.
You wait.
Basa, Paloma!
- Well? - It must be her.
She's not in her room.
Evita, get the men. Give them guns.
Get the guns. Now!
- Hurry. Now!
- Really, they stole her?
No key.
- Mira, mira.
- The truck. Come on, Paloma.
Paloma! Come on!
What are you waiting for?
They was stolen her
because she's so rich
I hope so, Paloma.
I hope that's all it is.
Why are you doing this to me?
You still have your virginity,
I want it.
- I don't have it anymore.
- Unit's sad for me.
But no matter. I want you
to live with me forever.
- No. - I take you now,
like my father took my mother. - No.
Cotton! Cotton!
Oh, yes.
Oh yes, Cotton! Thank you.
Oh, no! No, Cotton.
You, S...
My sheik.
Your thought is very beautiful.
And I'm very ?attered.
But I'm in love.
Down there I'm in love.
I'm sorry, but I too have my needs.
It's a chauvinistic world.
What I do is correct.
I know you have your need.
We all do.
But I'm very ?attered
that you consider me one of yours.
But I must be selfish
and think of myself first.
No, no.
I say he was stolen you
because you so rich.
No, he was stolen me
because I so cute!
You know, Angel walk.
Alta, Marie.
You should come out into the sun
Maybe look around. Watch me ride.
You know you're days and days behind
in your loving me.
Thank you. But Marie and I
are learning new tricks.
Hello, Marie.
As you wish. I brought you some more
sweet, little companions.
Oh, I'm so sorry.
I'm so sorry.
- Did the lovebirds send you my
message? - I got your message.
Oh, I did it!
Today he let me hug him
and he even hugged me back.
And now he's back in his room
like a hermit.
A hug beats a kick in a butt.
And Rome wasn't built in a day.
I know.
Who said that? I never said that.
- Do you want I give you some more
hot chocolate. - Oh, yes, please.
- Put two spoons of patience it.
- Of what?
- Never mind.
- Do you want I give you some too?
Okay, goodnight everybody.
I'm going to bed.
Why do you go to bed so early?
No, Paloma.
For me it's very very late. Night.
- Good night.
Thank you for taking them off first.
For you, it's a pleasure, Catalina.
Fantastic. I can't believe
we are doing this.
I can't believe I am happy
we are doing this, God.
But to do it properly, you're going
to have to take off your clothes.
Listen, why don't you do it for me?
- Take your clothes off, you mean?
- Yes.
I hope you think I am as beautiful
with my clothes off
as I think you are.
This is unbelievable.
I love it. And the hurt,
I love the hurt.
- You do?
- Yes.
- Do you love me?
- I do.
Right now,
I really do love you.
I know light now you love me.
And listen,
if I want, I want your love,
we'd better not stop doing this.
That would be the most wonderful way
to spend forever.
I don't think I'm up to it. I'm not
a freak. I can still hold you.
You're a hard man to seduce.
Oh, listen Angel.
We made a deal for over 300.000 bottles to the United
States.
We ship them out next week. I mean,
next month. Can you believe it?
It's fantastic.
Listen, Catalina.
I've the feeling you haven't kept me
just to show me your sales report.
No, as a matter of fact, I haven't.
Mac asked me to keep you away
from the ling for awhile today.
I think I've done very well.
Why would she want me
away from the ring?
I've done this to get
your undivided attention
to tell you
I will see you at sunrise.
You do remember sunrise, don't you?
This better work. I sure wanna be
the Duchess of Piores.
I'm sorry Paloma,
but if this works my way,
I promise I'll find you a lover.
I'll give him to you.
Tonight be good night.
Angel be a man for you.
Happy sunrise.
- Mac, this is not going to work.
- Hold it, right there. Hold it.
Damn. Come on Marie.
Out you go. He's mine now.
Come on. Out you go.
Hats are bad luck on beds.
You ought to know better than that.
Did I ride the horse marvellously?
Even more marvellously than you?
I did, didn't I?
All right. Off the bed.
Come on. Off the bed.
- What you doing? - Off the bed.
- What you doing?
Come on.
That's not the way
we did it last time?
But then I was a little girl.
Now I am a woman.
Do you wanna taste my blood?
Damn you. Don't do this to me.
Don't take it out on me just because
you got cute with the damn bull.
This is a very strange vigil
we all seemed to have gathered for.
- What are we here to do?
- We're here to help Angel and Mac.
We cannot help Angel.
Angel has to be a man.
Is no problem
You said that we never found ecstasy.
That it was like quicksilver,
always promising next time.
Angel, I want ecstasy.
- Let's find it.
- Make me whole again.
- I'm sorry, I couldn't hear you.
I guaranteed it.
Fourteen. Shame on you.
Was she wild then?
Did she scratch you?
Long wicked scratches?
She did, didn't she?
And you loved it.
I think this seems like a perfect
time to tell you that I love you.
And an equally perfect time for you
to tell me the same.
I do. I'm sure.
Beyond your wildest dreams.
Well, my dreams take me
beyond infinity.
What love you must have for me.
I guaranteed it.
- Bravo.
Oh, look!
X. I was right.
Angel. Angel, my foot is cramped.
Angel, give me back my foot, please.
Oh, God. I'm sorry. Thank you.