-Nice knife.
-Beautiful, isn't it?
Very nicely done.
And totally made by hand.
And here are other specialties...
crafted by my own handiwork.
Everything done by me.
And, well... I'm selling them.
-Is this a marble handle?
-No, it's not marble.
It's made from a bone
from the leg of an ostrich.
And this one's walnut.
It's only found in San Luís.
It's a special tree.
-Found only there?
-Yes, only in San Luís.
I have relatives who work there
and sent it to me.
-Hard wood, right?
-Very hard.
-Fantastic.
-Very beautiful.
Makes a nice souvenir.
That 's why I'm offering it.
It's a rare wood, right?
It's from a ship that
sunk in the year 1800.
-You don't say!
-I found it on the shore.
Well, it's a handle
full of history.
-How much?
-The work alone's worth 100 pesos.
-100 pesos?!
-Yes. But look at the finishing.
It's not easy to earn 100 pesos.
lf I had that much,
I wouldn't work here.
-Well, it's that...
-No, it's too much money.
-I could take 80.
-No, no, no.
-80, how about that?
-No, no.
No? Okay, let's go on.
Let 's see if anyone likes
this one here.
-I like them all.
-Yeah.
Make me an offer and
I'll tell you if I take it.
-This is how I make a living now.
-This is very nice...
very nice for
crazyman Contreras.
Not nice enough for you.
There it is!
Make me an offer, guys.
Come on.
-let 's go back to work.
-What do you think?
We gotta get started.
Let 's get to work.
-Well, guys...
-Bye, old man.
I'm ready.
Coco, we didn't sell anything today.
Things are looking bad.
Hey, listen!
Those are excellent knives!
I mean it!
Good morning, pal.
Good morning.
Haven't you seen the sign
on your way in?
What sign, mister?
I didn't see it.
You're on private property, pal.
I'm sorry, sir.
It's just that...
I came to try and sell knives
to the guys there...
Under whose authorization?
No one's, sir.
You'll have to follow me.
Papers, please.
Just a minute, please.
I don't think I have them here.
I forgot to take them
when I went out.
I'm sorry.
Must have left them at home.
How much for this one?
-This one?
-Yes.
You can keep it.
Listen, signs are made to be read.
Yes.
That 's what I'll do next time.
You may go, pal.
Hey, Villegas!
How are you doing?
-How now, Sabino?
-How are you?
All nice and clean, huh?
Just because I got fired!
They want to reopen
in the spring.
I have your things there.
-Thanks.
-What about the knives?
I think they're
a little too pricey.
-Pricey?
-I'll try to bring the price down.
Well, they're importing Brazilian
knives now, they're much cheaper.
But mine are handcrafted.
The only thing people
care about is that they cut.
-How's Rosa?
-She's fine.
Seems that an employment agency...
found her work at a hotel,
as cleaning lady.
It's easier for a woman.
Besides, she's young.
What are we to do?
I'm hanging on for now,
but sooner or later...
I guess it'll be my turn to get
a swift kick in the butt.
There are your tools
and a box with your belongings.
-Sit down.
-Okay.
Let 's have some tea.
I'll give you a mattress.
You can keep it. lf I need it,
I'll ask you to return it.
No. I left it there because
I didn't have any place for it.
Where's Borzi now?
-He went to Rosário, to his brother.
-Wasn't his brother in jail?
And he'll stay there,
because he got about 30 years.
Seems Borzi was kinda
fond of his sister-in-Iaw.
So, is everything of yours there?
Nothing missing?
Yes, but that doesn't matter.
It's okay.
Tell me, that agency
where Rosa got her job...
what 's the address?
-Name?
-Juan Villegas.
-Villega?
-Villegas.
V-I-I-I-E-G-A-S.
But everybody calls me Coco.
Profession?
Mechanic.
Well, light mechanics.
-Are you a mechanic or aren't you?
-I am. You can put ''mechanic'' there.
I used to work at a gas station.
-And what happened?
-Well, it was sold.
The gas station was sold recently.
I did a bit of everything there.
Lubricated...
Hello?
Listen... listen...
It's not my problem if they don't
pay you what was agreed upon!
No, no, no...
our company is not liable for
problems with third-party employers.
Read carefully
the contract you signed.
No, I'm not interested
in what you think!
No! I'll delete you from the
system, that 's it! Simple as that.
You do whatever you want!
-Age?
-52.
Is that a problem?
No.
Well, in this country,
anything can be a problem.
-Married or single?
-Married.
But you can put ''single''.
I haven't seen my wife in 20 years.
-I'll put ''single''.
-Single.
-Residence?
-I'm living with my daughter...
in Fitz Roy.
Things are getting difficult.
Okay, you've been added
to the system.
How will it be, then?
-May I contact your daughter?
-Yes.
But since I'm always
around here anyway...
No. Here's my card.
-There's my phone. You call me.
-Mr. Barreiro...
sometimes, in my spare time,
I make knife handles.
lf you're interested...
lf you want, I can show you.
No, no. Not now.
-But they're right here.
-No, not now.
Okay.
Where's the bottle?
Look, the milk's gone sour!
Hush, love. You haven't
even been cleaned yet. Yeah, baby.
I gotta do everything around here.
0n your feet, lazybones!
Nice example you're setting!
-Are you going to the bathroom?
-You can go, but don't take long!
Here, watch her a bit!
Watch your daughter, come on!
Milk for the baby, come on!
Come on, hurry,
you're gonna be late for school!
Come, Tucumano, get a move on.
Take care of the baby.
Quick!
-Wanna check the oil?
-No, no need to.
That 'll be 28.50.
You been working here long?
No, not for very long.
-Do you like the work?
-So-so.
I've worked at a gas station
for almost 20 years.
Cool.
Your change. Thanks.
Wait, I almost forgot.
This is a special offer
from the gas station.
You have to scratch it
with a coin.
-The coin you gave me?
-Exactly.
-Here?
-Yeah, right there.
-There's something written there.
-let me see.
You've won a liter of oil.
Come with me. See?
And you also won
a pair of sunglasses...
like the ones in the movie
''Men In Black''.
-Have you seen that movie?
-No, I don't think so.
-Come in. Here.
-Thanks.
Mario, he just won a prize.
Congratulations, sir.
How do you do?
Go fetch the prize from the back.
-Right away.
-Here it is.
I'll write down your name
and give you your prize.
-Today's my lucky day.
-Indeed, it must be.
You know if they need
a mechanic or a gas clerk here?
No, we don't have any openings.
-Have you tried the Gypsy's garage?
-No.
It's near the exit for Cañadón.
They're always hiring there.
Anything will do.
Getting a job is what counts.
Excuse me.
I brought the oil and the glasses.
-Here they are.
-Great.
-They must be worth a lot.
-Yes.
Put them on,
let's see how they look.
-You look like a man in black.
-I bet you can't see a thing.
-Are you gonna put them on now?
-No, I'll put them away.
GYPSY'S TIRE REPAIR SHOP
What do you want?
-Is your boss around?
-No, he's out to lunch.
-Can I wait for him?
-What for?
It's personal.
You can wait outside, if you want.
Okay, thanks.
Look, if you're selling something,
nobody here's gonna buy anything.
No, I'm not selling anything.
Shit!
Tribilín, who the hell
parked in the driveway?
I'm sorry,
I'll move it right away.
Haven't you seen the sign?
What did I paint it for?
N0 PARKING
Goddamn.
Let 's go, quick.
Keep the TV down, baby's asleep.
Mauro, later, I want you
to show me the grade you got.
-Okay.
-I already know about it.
-What are you doing?
-I'm fixing the plumbing.
-I'll find something to mend it.
-I think...
it would be best to replace
the pipe. Then it'll be perfect.
And how much
is that gonna cost me?
I don't know.
How much should I charge you?
It's not expensive.
I'll take care of it.
Listen, Dad...
Earlier today, at the gas station,
they called me back.
They told me to scratch a card.
I scratched it and I got a prize.
A can of oil and sunglasses
like the ones you see on the TV.
I almost asked for the prize in cash,
but I didn't have the heart to do it.
I'll see if I can buy a grindstone
with my severance pay.
You keep spending your money like
that, you'll end up selling your car.
The knife business...
won't work if I don't
make them. It's no use.
Why don't you get a job
doing what you do best?
Look... there are so many
new gas stations around.
Well, I'm going to Vasco's store
to buy a new length of pipe.
Otherwise, Lucia,
you won't have water today.
-Good morning. Something wrong?
-Actually, I don't know.
I heard a noise, like something
cracking. I stopped to take a look.
Don't worry,
I'll check it out for you.
Thanks.
-Is it bad?
-No.
The fan pulley is cracked.
It needs to be welded.
You can see it was
already badly welded.
It happened to my dad.
This car belonged to him.
-Is it easy to fix?
-Well, if I had a welding arc...
But around here...
I have a welding arc down
at the ranch. They always use it...
but it's 150 km from here.
We're gonna have to tow it.
There's no other way.
Look, it's 150 km.
It's not nearby.
-Have you got the time?
-That 's the one thing I've got.
Do you live around here?
No. I'm living in Buenos Aires now.
I was born in Telken.
I'm from Patagonia,
even though it's hard to tell.
-Do you mind if I smoke?
-No.
-Dou you wanna smoke?
-Thanks, I don't smoke.
I'll smoke now,
because my mom won't let me.
I'm 33 years old,
but she still yells at me.
And now your dad is going
to yell at you because of the car.
No. My father is dead.
-I'm really sorry.
-No, it's okay.
He died 18 months ago.
What do you do for a living?
Well, I used to work
at a gas station.
-Now I carve knife handles.
-Knife handles?
-Take a look, they're in my bag.
-let me see.
They're very beautiful.
What 's this one made of?
A special wood
from the Misiones forest.
A friend of mine who lives there
sent the wood to me.
This one looks like a face.
Is it a face?
It 'll be the head of a puma.
So you're an artist!
No... well... thanks.
I'll go see Mom,
she must be worried sick.
Can you tell me
where the welding tools are?
Look in the shed.
Must be there.
Good afternoon.
Good afternoon, ma'am.
-Nice to meet you.
-Nice to meet you too.
So my daughter dragged you
all the way out here.
It doesn't matter.
Things that happen.
-Especially on the road.
-When this one sets her mind...
She's so stubborn. She insisted on
going to Comodoro to sell the car.
Nobody drives it.
It 'll end up going to waste.
But this isn't just any old car.
-Yes, it's a fine automobile.
-Exactly. See?
You can't just sell it like that!
Is it anything very complicated?
No, Mom,
he's just welding a pulley.
Let him explain.
I just have to weld this
pulley and it's done.
Then we'll put it back...
Isn't that gonna cost me?
With the present situation...
I still don't know.
We'll see later on.
-Think about it when you sell it.
-To repay you for your trouble...
you could stay
and have tea with us.
See this?
It's made here. All homemade.
-Very difficuIt to find in town.
-Delicious.
Dad was a specialist
in fruit jams, wasn't he?
I could never make them
like he did. Try the cookies.
Those over there.
The recipe's from a family
who lives nearby.
I'll fill two jars of jam
for you to take home.
Great. Thanks.
What did your husband
do for a living?
-Well, what he didn't do!
-Everything, except politics.
Yes, but he always liked
to be on top of current events.
He was the first to bring Hereford
livestock to Patagonia.
He organized wild hog hunts,
planted native fruits...
He always had some project going.
Couldn't stand still.
But, in his own way,
he lived happily.
His last endeavor was with dogs.
He wanted to breed
Argentine dogos and export them.
But he didn't live
long enough to do it.
Have you seen that breed?
They're big, white dogs.
-Yes, I think I've seen them.
-They're fighting dogs, aren't they?
lf you raise them to do that.
Otherwise, they're as gentle
a creature as any.
Mom, they were genetically
bred to be fighting dogs.
-No one is born evil.
-They're not evil, they're fierce.
No! They're just hounds.
Listen, wouldn't you like to take
the one we have here with you?
A dog?
I guarantee that, as soon as
you see him, you'll want him.
It's just that I'm going
through some dire straits.
-And to keep a dog...
-They're rustic beasts.
It's no problem at all.
They adapt easily.
My husband bought him
to set up his kennel...
but he died shortly after
the dog arrived.
He's the puppy of a famous dog.
Yes, of a great champion.
It's a thoroughbred dog.
I have his pedigree.
Breaks my heart to see him wandering
around all day, poor thing.
You see, I'm in no condition
to take care of a dog anymore.
Take a look. Could be a great
company to someone lonely.
You'll find him sad. But he was
very happy when he got here.
I'd be happy to know
he's with someone like you.
I found his papers.
Look, here's the name of his father:
Quilapán de los Andes.
-A great champion.
-Here's his registration number.
And the vaccination schedule.
Here it is: Le Chien Kennel.
''Le Chien'' because
my husband was French.
You'll see what
a fantastic dog. Come.
Careful, there's a ditch there.
Everything was left
unfinished here.
Come in.
LE CHIEN KENNEL
So, what do you think?
Classy dog, isn't he?
Out. Out.
Out.
Let 's go home.
VACCINATION SCHEDULE
DOGBREEDERS' FEDERATION
OF ARGENTINA
Come on, Le Chien. Come.
Let 's go home.
Come, Le Chien.
Mom, come see!
There's a white dog outside!
What? What do you mean, a dog?
Honest! There's a white dog there.
Where did that dog come from?
Tucumano?
What dog is that, Dad?
He's on a leash.
He won't do anything, dear.
What is that dog doing here, Dad?
-I brought him.
-What kind of idea is that?
-Mom, he's trying to break free!
-See? Are you insane?
Tucumano, Tucumano!
Take that dog away from here!
You've never wanted a dog in
your life! What idea is that now?
What 's gotten into you, Dad?
Tell me!
Take that dog away, Tucumano.
I can't even hang my laundry to dry.
I don't want any dogs here!
Understand?
Okay?
I don't want dogs here!
-It's done, sir.
-Thank you.
That gentleman there
wants to talk to you.
-Which one?
-That one over there.
-Good afternoon.
-Is the dog yours?
-Yes.
Well, I have a warehouse
full of wool...
and I need some surveillance.
Well...
Just for three or four days.
Until the wool is transported.
I never leave my dog alone.
No, no, no. I'll hire you as
a guard along with your dog.
I'll pay you 30 pesos a day.
What do you say?
-I think it's okay.
-Come with me.
lf one Galván,
the previous guard, shows up...
and he's drunk,
do not let him in.
lf he wants to get his things,
tell him to come back tomorrow...
in the afternoon, when I'm here.
And if he insists too much,
sic the dog on him.
All right?
You have my permission.
No problem.
Come in.
You may unleash the dog.
It's his first day,
better not yet.
Whatever you say.
This is where you'll stay.
It's a little grimy...
however...
Well, come in.
There's a heater and food.
Now help me close
the gate, please.
Open up!
The wind's blowing!
Down, Le Chien!
Stay down!
Get that dog away from me, pal.
Brother, please.
I'm asking you. Please.
-Are you Galván?
-Yes.
I have orders
not to let you in.
You'll have to come back to get
your things in the afternoon.
I can't come back
in the afternoon, brother.
Those are the orders I have.
It's just a handful of things.
I'll gather them and I'll go.
It won't take more
than ten minutes.
Please, I'm asking you.
I'll get everything
in five minutes.
Can you carry all that?
I'll get a plastic bag
or something.
I have such bad luck!
Such bad luck!
Sorry.
Hey, where are you going?
Galván is inside.
He wants to talk to you.
What?
You can't go in the bank
with that animal, sir.
It's quick, I'll be in and out.
Nothing personal,
but the dog can't go in.
Crap!
lf I let him tied over there,
would you keep an eye on him?
I can't.
What if it bites someone?
No, he never bites.
He's a hound, he's tame.
Well, so be it.
But I didn't see anything.
Come on, Le Chien.
Come on.
We have to draw some money.
-Good morning, Roque.
-Good morning, sir.
You let your headlights turned on.
Thanks.
Regulations again.
Excuse me, is this dog yours?
Yes.
-It's a beautiful animal.
-Yes, very beautiful.
-What 's his name?
-Le Chien.
May l?
Yes, of course.
Touch him.
Could be a fine hound.
-Have you tried him with hogs?
-Not yet.
Could be a fine hound.
Because of his bite, you know?
Got one heck of a bite.
Yeah, I think he does.
And he could do fine
on a show too.
Can I have a look?
Let 's see.
Nice hind legs.
Beautiful animal.
-Really good, isn't he?
-Yes, it's a fine specimen.
You could take him to a show.
Do you have his pedigree?
Yeah, I got it.
Why don't you prepare him?
I know someone who could
train him for you.
-Were you going to the bank?
-Yes.
-Come, I'll give you the address.
-Okay.
-Sir, your headlights.
-I forgot again.
Please, turn them off for me.
-Of course.
-Thank you. Let 's go.
-You were going to the bank, right?
-Yes.
-What were you going to do?
-I need to cash a check.
-Give it to me, I'll see to it.
-Thank you very much.
-Good morning, Marta.
-Good morning.
-Cash this check for me.
-Okay.
Come in, make yourself
comfortable. We'll talk.
Well, let's see.
The man I was telling you
about is called Walter Donado.
-Is that so?
-Yes.
He's the best dog wrangler I know.
It's just that I don't know anything
about dogs. It 'd be great...
Don't worry, this man's the best.
He lives in Trelew.
I'm looking for his address.
He'll be easy to find,
he's the manager at the racetrack.
Let 's see, here it is.
I'll write his address...
on one of my cards.
Here are his address
and his phone number.
Tell him that Zacarias,
from the Santa Cruz Bank, sent you.
-He owes me a lot of favors.
-Thanks.
While we wait for your money...
take a look at this animal.
It was my favorite for years.
Such a big dog!
He fell 300 meters
struggling with a wild hog.
He died, but we had to break
his jaw to pry the hog loose.
Look at this one.
He was gutted by a hog.
We put everything back inside, sewn
him up and he was up and running.
They don't feel pain.
They're totally
insensitive to pain.
You know what?
They're from another planet.
-Excuse me.
-Come in.
l brought the money
from the check.
-Is it yours?
-Yes.
I'll need you to sign here.
-Of course.
-Pick up a pen.
Here.
-Here it is.
-You're very kind. Thanks.
-Please count it.
-No need to.
-Thank you, miss.
-Thank you, sir.
Very well.
Every month, we go out to hunt
on some friend's grounds.
This month's Dr. Recabarren's turn,
down in Laguna Grande.
-Okay.
-My friend, as soon as you can...
just call me and
you'll go with us.
And, of course, bring your dog,
so he'll begin to learn.
I know very little about dogs.
Almost nothing.
Don't worry, you'll enjoy it.
Yes, on behalf of Zacarias,
accountant at the Santa Cruz Bank.
No, that 's not why I'm calling.
I don't work at the bank.
Well, I've got a dog,
and Mr. Zacarias told me about you.
I'd like to know whether
we can do something with the dog.
Yes, the dog's father is called...
Quilo de los Pan.
Quilapán. That 's it.
Trelew's racetrack?
Yes, I know it.
Yes, I can be there today.
Wait here, Le Chien.
-Good morning.
I'm looking for Walter Donado,
the manager.
He's not here.
He went to Trelew to buy some parts.
I'm told he lives around here.
There, right by the office.
I'll show you.
-Good afternoon.
Excuse me, I'm looking for Walter.
He's not in.
He went to buy some parts.
-Yes, I know.
-But he'll be back soon.
Then I'll wait for him here.
-Wouldn't you rather come in?
-Won't I disturb you?
-Absolutely not.
-Well, thanks.
Please come in.
Come say hi, Mabelita.
Sit down.
Would you care for some tea?
Thank you, ma'am.
Hi, cutie.
Are you studying?
Poor thing, she's so nervous
she lost her voice.
Nervous?
It's because she has a presentation
Thursday at City Hall.
That 's why she's like that.
When she was little,
she recited poems like an angel.
Now she gets nervous
and her voice disappears.
Recite it to him, Mabelita.
The dark swallows will come back
To hang their nests on the balcony
And again, with their wings
To their crystals...
I don't understand. She gets so
nervous. She knows it by heart.
Come on, Mabelita, slower.
''The dark swallows will
come back...'' Come on.
No, not like that,
with a dry throat! We can't hear you.
I can't.
See?
That 's how she gets.
-She's nervous.
-Yes.
And I'm tired of that.
My God, what a disgrace.
You don't need to tell me!
I saw him in the car!
You have no idea what kind
of a dog this gentleman has.
-Nice to meet you.
-Nice to meet you. Walter Donado.
-You've got pure gold there!
-Did you like him?
Come. Let 's sit down
and go over his papers.
That 's it.
You got his vaccinations too.
That 's very important.
Of course! His mother is
Diosa Cristal de los Apóstoles.
Didn't he belong
to that French guy?
Yes, his widow gave him to me.
What are we sitting here for?
Let 's see him right away.
You wanna know?
With this dog well trained,
we're going to make some noise.
You think so?
-Have you thought about selling him?
-I didn't think about it.
What a head you've got!
Wanna do me a favor?
Take me to Gesei's house.
He's president of the Association.
Yeah, let's go.
I want him to see it.
His jaw will drop to the floor!
To exhibit a dog at a show
is not a snobbish thing, Villegas.
It's an art. You gotta choose the
right time to make the dog's debut.
It's like a soccer
player's career.
lf you don't work well on it,
it'll be over soon.
That 's why the dog should be
shown first at small shows...
local ones, and only after that
go to international ones.
I've known about
badly presented dogs...
whose careers were ruined.
And they were great dogs!
That 's why it's important
to build the dog's name.
You need people to know him,
start asking questions.
Then his breeding services
will begin to be sought.
lf memory serves,
a week from now...
there's a show in Bahía Blanca.
3 general contests and a grooming
contest. Shall we sign him in?
-A week from now?
-A week!
In a week, with a dog like this...
we can make him perfect!
He needs to stroll,
to learn to raise his head...
...and to stand still.
-You know...
...I've never been to a dog show.
-I'll show you what it's like.
When we get back home,
I'll show you on a magazine.
In 1994, we've been in Tampa, USA.
It was a hit!
I'm in one of the pictures.
Remind me to show it to you
when we get back home.
Problem is,
I'm kinda short on money.
I'll tell you what.
I'll prepare the dog...
give you food and lodging,
and we'll split the profits in half.
What do you say?
-Well...
-Deal?
Deal.
Partners!
-Chip off the old block, isn't he?
-Beautiful.
-He looks fine.
-What do you mean, ''looks fine''?
Must be from the litter of
that female of Rocatagliata.
-Yeah, the one a French guy bought.
-let's get him on the ground...
so you can take
a good look at him.
Come on, Le Chien.
Come, Le Chien.
Le Chien, come.
-Ieave him. He'll get down alone.
-Yeah, he always does that.
Come on.
Don't embarrass me.
-He's kinda nervous, right?
-Le Chien, come on.
Careful.
-Jesus!
-Did he bite you?
Just a scratch.
It's okay.
It's nothing.
-You think he's got rabies?
-These dogs don't have rabies.
Looks like this dog
has character.
Our friend has just had
his initiation.
No self-respecting
dogo owner is without scars.
Look, he did that
because he likes you!
Look at this. Compound punctured
fracture pulling two dogs apart.
Radius, elbow and five tendons.
And it wasn't even on purpose!
Welcome to the club, pal.
Okay.
Come, Villegas.
Come in, dear Villegas.
I want you to feel at home.
This is never used, except
on Saturdays and Sundays...
when some freak wants to test
his car. 0r when there's a race.
Come with me.
I'll put your mattress here.
This will be your room.
I'll fix your mattress here.
-let the dog loose.
-Won't he escape?
Here's what I promised you.
You'll see how incredible it is.
Take a look at this.
Tampa, Miami, 1994.
Look at this fantastic show.
This is Argentina's delegation.
See any familiar faces?
Look closely.
-It's you!
-Yes.
There were 60 of us up there.
We almost won the first series.
And you took the dogs there?
Of course! Would we go
to a dog show without dogs?
Dumb question!
You can't imagine how much
money flows around this thing.
In the US, there are
80 million dogs...
and they're only
the first minority.
0n top of that, there are still...
the sponsors, balanced
dog foods, laboratories...
vaccines, collar manufacturers...
the money behind all that is huge!
I'll tell you more:
when that dog of yours takes off...
we're gonna need a sponsor.
Nowadays, without a sponsor,
you can't do a thing.
But first things first.
First comes Bahía Blanca.
Rest. Tomorrow, early in
the morning, we'll begin training.
-Thanks.
-See you tomorrow.
See you tomorrow.
There's a flashlight. Ten minutes
from now, I'll turn the lights off.
Thank you.
Left, right, left.
Left, left.
Very good.
We're doing fine, Villegas.
Make him stop, Villegas.
No, Villegas. No.
Turn around.
Stroll him now.
Come on.
Make him turn!
Pull him!
You gotta pull hard, Villegas!
Be firm! Use your strength!
Very important: the head.
Control the leash in your hand.
Then, highlight the head. It's the
head we wanna sell, the dog's head.
Why a towel?
The wet towel is to clean him up.
That way, the dog goes
to the show brand new.
See how this covers it all up?
Hold him tight and keep
some distance.
Keep him on a short leash.
You're gonna do fine
in Bahía Blanca.
-You really think so?
-Walter has an eye for these things.
This is the big day, gentlemen!
That 's it!
-What time is it?
-It's 3 in the morning...
but we have
a long day ahead of us.
I borrowed these clothes.
And this cap... is a present.
Come have tea with no sugar
to wake you up, Villegas.
What elegance!
-How do I look?
-You look like an exhibitor.
WELC0ME - R0YAL CANIN
GR0WTH AND RESPECT
Wait here. I'll check
our position. Stay with him.
Good morning.
Are you the dog's owner?
-Yes.
-Here's your pin.
-Thank you very much.
-You're welcome.
-Bye.
Villegas!
Look what I've brought!
The catalog.
Look who's here.
Bombón de Le Chien.
Walter Donado.
Juan Villegas.
See the guy in the yellow shirt
brushing a white dog?
-You see him?
-Yes.
With that mutt, he won 3 national
and 2 Pan-American championships.
Enough money to buy his wife a car...
and make a down payment
on his home.
And all that with
the shit our country is in!
Goes to show what
this dog business is like.
Argentine dogo,
male category...
...please, step forward.
-There's our call.
We're ready.
Gotta take him to the circuit.
Come on, champ, knock 'em dead!
-What do I do?
-Show what you can do.
-No, you stay here.
-I stay here?
Watch and learn. We're gonna
bring you the prize. Come on.
3RD BAHÍA BLANCA D0G SH0W
Hi, handsome. Are you okay?
That 's it. Good dog.
There's a pal.
Okay. In circles, please.
That way.
Come on, Le Chien.
Very good.
There, behind him.
Secretary, please.
Show the number.
703...
And the winner of the aduIt male
Argentine dogo category is...
You. First place.
Second.
-Third.
-Thanks.
What did I tell you?
Moderation. That 's how you
celebrate your first round.
But what did the judge say?
-Was it good?
-What do you think?
We've won the first round
and we're in the finals.
Dear friends, this is the most
anticipated moment in the show.
The moment of choosing
the three best dogs...
-What are you doing?
-Here, take him up.
Quick, they're calling him!
Do you want to get us disqualified?
Run, run! Go, Le Chien!
Sir! There, sir!
Sir! Wait, sir!
You have to stay here.
There.
Straighten him up.
Well, the president of our jury...
Mr. Martín Collazo,
is performing...
his customary visual inspection...
of every category's winner...
in our 3rd Bahía Blanca Dog Show.
All these...
formidable specimens from
the foremost breeds in our country.
Well, we're close
to the final result.
Let 's decide.
Mr. Collazo and Dr. Renazzi,
secretary in this show...
are going over the last details.
The judge is getting the trophies
from his collaborators!
Well, now walk around.
Now they perform the traditional
walkaround of the chosen ones.
First prize goes
to the poodle toy...
number 769.
-Second prize goes to...
-Second.
...the Belgian shepherd...
number 767.
-Third prize...
-Third.
...to the Argentine dogo
Bombón de Le Chien...
number 703.
Excuse me!
I knew it! I knew it!
We got third place!
I told you!
And I've already sold
an insemination!
-From the dog?
-Of course! Who could it be from?
We gotta call this guy tomorrow.
He's got a female in heat.
-Great!
-We can charge him some 600 pesos.
Without blinking.
Yes, 600. People in this business
know he's worth that much.
I don't know what kind of a dog
could do the job for 400 pesos.
We can offer you a discount.
500.
450. That 's my last offer.
I've got everything.
Even his brucellosis test.
It's a healthy animal.
Don't worry, he's got it all.
Yes.
-Here's your order.
-Don't worry.
Tomorrow we'll be there.
I've got the address.
Well, see you tomorrow.
-Okay. How much?
-7.50.
-Put it on our tab.
-No, you gotta pay cash.
What do you mean?
In Miami, we never had to pay cash.
What 's going on here?
Give him eight pesos.
He can keep the change.
I've got it.
Let 's make a toast...
to the future.
To this partnership,
born to be a success!
And also to Le Chien.
To Le Chien!
Do you like that chubby girl?
She sings fine.
Yeah, sure.
She reminds me of a girlfriend
I had 30 years ago.
-Could it be her?
-I don't think so.
I'll bring her over
so you can make sure.
-This is Coco Villegas.
-Nice to meet you. Susana.
He's the most important
dog breeder in Patagônia.
One of his dogs just won
first prize in Bahía Blanca.
-How nice! Congratulations.
-Thank you.
The dog should be congratulated
too, but they wouldn't let him in.
-Do you want some cider?
-Yes.
Waiter, a cider, please!
Your work is
interesting, isn't it?
You're always traveling
and going to dog shows.
Well, actually, he's the one
doing most of the traveling.
Sometimes, we need
to take a dog to the US.
How nice.
It's a very important business.
There are 80 million dogs in
the US. They're the first minority.
-Must be very thrilling.
-No, no. Pour it here.
Well, let's ask for
a moment of silence.
Let 's make a toast, shall we?
I'd like to ask for silence
and propose a toast...
because we have here the owner
of the best dog, who has just won...
the Bahía Blanca Dog Show:
Mr. Coco Villegas!
And also to Le Chien, the best dog,
who they didn't allow in here!
You sing very nicely.
-I thought you were Arabic.
-No.
When I was a child, I worked for a
Lebanese man who owned a store...
...and I always heard this song.
-Must be difficult.
Not when you like to sing.
I mean, it must be
difficuIt to understand.
I wouldn't know.
I sing it phonetically.
I don't really understand,
but I always check first...
that there aren't any foul words.
This is a family place.
Go, fatso!
Cognac and a show for everyone!
Give her money,
you fat cheapskate!
Okay, who's the asshole?
You like to throw bread around?
-Stop, it, fatso!
-Enough!
Get outta here, you idiots!
Out!
Don't worry.
They'll hold him at the police
station just for a few hours.
Tomorrow he'll
be released, surely.
At these parties, there's always
someone who drinks too much.
-It was this one who won the prize?
-Yes.
He's very handsome.
I had a little dog when
I was living in Buenos Aires.
-A Pomeranian.
-Did you live in Buenos Aires?
I've lived there for two years.
I sang at the Horizonte Club.
It was a Syrian-Iebanese club,
but it was a posh place.
Its patrons were very wealthy.
We're close.
It's five blocks from here.
Whenever you want to throw a party,
call me. I'll organize it for you.
Shayla is my trade name.
I'll hire the musicians, everything.
Even a dancer, if you want.
Let 's have a coffee.
I don't want to disturb you.
It's very late.
Disturb me?
You brought me all the way here.
Have a coffee,
then you can go back.
Come in.
-Allow me.
-Make yourself at home.
I'll brew the hot coffee
I promised you.
Thank you.
-Do you like Turkish coffee?
-Well... today's Turkish food day.
My dad built this house some months
before he got married to my mom.
-It looks well preserved.
-Not exactly.
I need to fix the roof, there are
some leaks. What are we to do?
You make the Turkish
coffee in here.
In this pot. Look, copper on the
outside and pewter on the inside.
-Careful, it's hot.
-Thanks.
-Something's left on your tongue?
-Yes.
It's the dregs. When you finish
drinking it, it'll be in the cup.
Do you want me to read them?
-Read them?
-Yes, you can read coffee dregs.
Really.
They tell about your future.
-Okay.
-I'll tell you how it's done.
You put the cup here.
Cover it.
Now turn it upside down.
-Turn it?
-Yes. Keep it here.
Leave it on the table.
That 's it.
Now lift it carefully.
You fooled me.
You are the one who travels a lot.
-And you'll keep on traveling.
-Really? Are you sure?
Yes, I can see a big trip here.
To buy a farm.
Is that possible?
0r a bit of land.
A little bit of land?
Yes, could be a little bit.
-There are nice places around here.
-Really?
lf you want, I can show you.
He's got a clean record.
Chief gets here only in the morning.
Nothing can be done until then.
He got a bit carried away,
but he's a nice guy.
Then I'd advise him
to get a grip.
-You want to see him?
-If it's possible, yes.
Come with me.
-There he is.
-Ask him who started it!
-Ask him who threw bread around.
-Are you crazy?
What difference does
it make who threw bread?
I was dancing, I wasn't bothering
a soul, and all of a sudden...
somebody threw bread at me.
Not just a bit, a whole bun!
-Only five minutes.
-Thanks.
Listen.
Take the dog to this Pascual guy.
To do the job.
-You got his phone number?
-No.
Here.
Make him sign
the work order first.
The dog shouldn't mount her
without him signing first.
I know this business.
It's full of wiseguys.
-Yes?
-Mr. Pascual?
You're a bit early.
Well, come in.
In here. I've already taken
Pamela's temperature.
She's almost ready.
Have you brought his papers,
vaccinations, test results?
Yes, it's everything here.
Sit down.
Bombón de Le Chien.
Is that the dog's name?
No, Le Chien.
''Bombón de Le Chien''.
Le Chien is the kennel.
Who in the world
would name a dog Bombón?
Well, I'll take Pamela's
temperature again.
The big guy said
you had a lot of dogs.
He told me you were
expanding your kennel.
Well, as a matter of fact, we are.
Wait a minute.
I'll be right back.
Pamela, come here!
It's a thermometer!
Come on, Pamela, come out!
Come on, out!
It's only a thermometer!
-It's time to introduce them.
-Come, Le Chien.
I hope he likes his bride.
-It's her first time. What about him?
-I think it's his first time too.
What do you mean? The fat guy
told me he was experienced.
Well, then, it must be true.
-That fat guy is a crook.
-No, he knows his business.
In you go.
See?
Told ya.
Now we have a problem.
Let 's leave them alone to see
if they understand each other.
Nature is wise. Come.
That dog is a coward!
He won't even come out!
I'll miss her heat.
I'll have to wait six months more.
Who's gonna pay for her food and
my lost profit? Who? You guys?
Why the hell did I do
business with you?
Now I know why he's called Bombón!
And I had her already fixed with
a three-year-old male, a stud!
Where am I gonna find
a male now?
Curse the moment I let
that tub of lard convince me!
Where the heck is that fatso?!
How did it go?
So-so.
The dog got scared.
-Scared? What happened?
-I don't know.
-The dog couldn't do it.
-What do you mean?
He just laid there and
didn't want to do anything.
You should have helped him.
The dog doesn't know.
Besides, the guy got mad.
What a jerk! The dog doesn't know,
you need to help him.
-They're just like teenagers.
-What do we do now?
We look for an experienced
female to teach him.
For instance, didn't anybody
help you in your first time?
-What will we do if he can't do it?
-Of course he can!
Our business is
dog reproduction.
We get them busy and we produce
them. It's just like a factory.
Here it is. El Entrevero.
Stop when you see a payphone.
Last year, this guy had
some fantastic females.
Wait here.
I'll call Omar and I'll be right back.
-Hi there.
-Good afternoon.
-How do you do?
-Fine, and you?
Same old, same old.
Did they close your gas station?
Yes, a while ago...
...and I got fired.
-You're at another gas station now?
No, I've changed professions.
-You've changed professions?
-I'm a dog breeder now.
I'm an exhibitor.
-A dog exhibitor?
-Yes.
-Who would have thought it?
-I've got one right here.
Beautiful animal.
Very well groomed.
-Quiet, Le Chien! Down!
-Holy shit!
I need a dog just like this one.
We get about three
burglaries a month here.
Would you have a dog
like this to sell me?
In the future. Soon.
Save a puppy for me.
I want a male.
-See you.
-Okay. Don't you forget.
Well, everything is settled.
I've just spoken to Omar.
He's got a bitch in heat.
She's perfect, because
she's old and experienced.
She went through two heats
without being mounted.
He's gonna impregnate her
just by looking at her!
What dog was that guy
talking about?
-He wants a puppy from this one.
-What did I tell you?
They sell just like hot cakes. And
after he develops a taste for it...
She doesn't have a pedigree,
but she's fine. I guarantee it.
Old and without a pedigree?
Then you'll have to pay me.
No, buddy. lf your dog doesn't learn
with her, you may as well give up.
-Carmelo, is Malena in heat?
-Her heat has just started.
Bring her. Pamela is her daughter.
lf he doesn't learn with both...
-What a party for you, you big lug!
-Carmelo, bring her here.
Help me, Villegas. Release him,
he's going crazy already.
He's going nuts.
Go, Le Chien! Attaboy!
Let 's see this female.
Look, Le Chien is mad.
Go, Le Chien!
That 's it!
-He went inside.
-Well, this is a new breed.
There's something
wrong with this dog.
Must've been traumatized because
his owner died when he was a puppy.
Let 's help him mount so he'll
understand how the thing works.
-I don't get it.
-He just needs a hand.
I'll help you.
Come on, Le Chien!
What 's his problem?
Come on!
With him, nothing happens.
That 's impossible. Come on!
We're gonna have to use
artificial insemination.
That 's for wealthy dogs.
Everybody will laugh at me
at the Association.
Looks like you'll have
a dog just for show.
Come on, Le Chien!
What 's his problem?
He's a beautiful specimen.
The only problem is his libido.
He hasn't got one.
I've had similar cases...
but this one is extreme.
You need to remember
that he's already an adult.
What about the celery
treatment, the...?
No, those things...
they're like...
Those are Chinese folktales.
You can't trust them.
However, he's a
wonderful specimen...
with a great character.
He's got a lot going for him.
He can be trained to do
a lot of things...
like bringing your newspaper.
He's a very docile dog.
He'll be fine at home.
That guy may be a vet
or whatever...
but this dog's gonna
surprise us at any moment.
Things that happen
in the animal business.
Look, Villegas, stay here
in Bahía Blanca. Find a job.
You're a mechanic, man.
Don't worry about the dog. I'll take
care of him for a few weeks.
I won't even charge you for that.
What 's wrong, Villegas?
Can't you keep in touch by phone?
When you're all nice and settled,
you can take him with you.
Relax. You know
I'll take good care of him.
I almost forgot!
I paid to sign him in
at the show. 25 pesos.
Keep the receipt.
It's a record, anyway.
-Here.
-Thanks.
TOURIST CENTER
''LAS TONINAS''
Here comes the bus, Villegas.
-Can you open it down here?
-Is it a dog?
He's used to traveling.
Behave, Le Chien.
You can close now.
Don't worry,
I'll take care of him.
-Okay, thanks.
-As soon as you're settled, call me.
-Of course.
-Bye.
-Good morning.
-Hi.
-Do you have a payphone here?
-No, we don't have one.
-How much for these alfajors?
-Seis pesos.
Here.
I brought it for you.
I can't accept this.
You must have worked
very hard to make it.
It doesn't matter.
-All right.
-You can use it in the kitchen.
But it's not a kitchen knife!
0r you can just keep it.
Well, thanks.
I'll keep it dearly.
Looks like...
It's a cat, isn't it?
-Right?
-It's a puma.
-Yes, a puma.
-A puma.
What about the dog?
Walter kept him.
Walter, the fat guy.
He's got space at his place.
I just love dogs.
But it's hard to travel around
bringing dogs along.
I told you about the dog
I had in Buenos Aires, didn't l?
When my father got sick, I came
here, and I left her with a friend.
Then I was told she got sad and...
she died soon after that.
We get used to their company.
It's just like two people
who are in love.
We never notice we care
so much for someone...
until they go away.
-Good morning.
-How are you, ma'am?
-I'm fine.
Walter?
Every time you come here,
Walter isn't home.
He's awfully busy, because
there's a race this Sunday.
-You came for the dog?
-Yes.
Walter wanted to call you, but he
didn't know where to reach you.
The dog's escaped.
What do you mean, escaped?
He must have escaped really early.
About 5 AM. I got up at 8
and he was already gone.
Poor Walter.
He was so worried.
-Hi.
-Hi, mister.
Have you seen the white dog
Walter, the manager, had?
I saw him a few days ago,
when he was training it.
-Haven't you seen the dog today?
-No, not today.
-It's a nice dog, isn't it?
-Yes.
-What breed is it?
-Dogo.
Maybe it was stolen, chief.
Watch out for the people
who live in El Progreso, chief.
People there are kinda dangerous.
I heard they eat dogs there.
Kid, have you seen a huge
white dog around here?
Have you seen a huge white dog?
No.
Not here.
Look for it near
the brick factory.
-The brick factory?
-Yes.
-Where that smoke's coming from?
-Yes, around there.
Thanks.
Hi. I'm looking for
a big white dog.
-I've seen him there.
-Well, thanks.
Bombón!
Bombón?
Have you seen
a white dog around?
He must be behind those bricks.
-That way?
-Behind those piles of bricks.
Thanks.
Le Chien!
Bombón, here!
Le Chien?
Bombón!
-Good morning.
-Are you going to Viedma?
-No, to Bahía Blanca.
-Could you give us a ride?
-Of course. Hop in.
I'll put the dog in the back.
-Doesn't he bite?
-No, he doesn't do anything.
Thank you, sir.
Are you gonna stay long
in Buenos Aires?
We hope so.
We don't know.
We're going because
there are more jobs there.
We're gonna try our luck.
-Have you been there before?
-No. You?
No.
I've never been there, and now...
What do you do?
-I'm a dog breeder.
-How nice!
I'm an exhibitor.
What does an exhibitor do?
Takes his dogs to dog shows.
The prizes are really great.
Have you got a lot of them?
Right now, I've only got this one.
But we'll see if things
get better in the future.
No, I was asking whether
you have a lot of prizes.
Yeah, I've got some.
-But not many yet.
-Okay.
www.makingoff.org