A DAIEI PRESENTATION
THE SON
(BONCHI)
Produced by:
Masaichi Nagata
Planned by: Hisakazu Tsuji
Based on the novel by: Toyoko Yamasaki
Written by: Kon Ichikawa and Natto Wada
Cinematography by: Kazuo Miyagawa
Sound: by Masao Ôsumi
Lighting by: Kenichi Okamoto
Art Direction by: Yoshinobu Nishioka
Music by: Yasushi Akutagawa
Film Editing by: Shigeo Nishida
Assistant Director: Kazuo Ikehiro
Cast:
Raizô Ichikawa Ayako Wakao
Fubuki Koshiji
Mitsuko Kusabue
Tamao Nakamura
Isuzu Yamada
Haritoshi Hayashi
Ganjiro Nakamura
Kikue Mori
Mayumi Kurata
Tanie Kitabayashi
Machiko Kyo Eiji Funakoshi
Directed by:
Kon Ichikawa
Hey, old man! Careful!
Watch where you're walking!
Come in, since you're here.
There's no need for ceremony.
Hello!
Thank you for welcoming me.
- Greetings!
- Hello!
My name is Haru Danku.
I don't mean to disturb you, but...
since you always help me a lot...
Let me introduce you.
This is my elder son, Saijiro,
and the younger one is Taro.
Really?
Taro is your son too?
We're not similar, right?
That's not what I meant...
That's because we have
different mothers.
Father, are you really spending
money on him?
I'm putting this money
to good use.
It's been 49 days since your
wife has passed away.
Don't think I'm immodest, but allow me
to burn incense in her honor too.
That's why I like him.
He's always so polite and
well-mannered.
Unlike most people in Osaka.
Come on, brother, it's time.
Come on, don't hurry up.
Let's honor mother first.
Bow a couple more times and that's it.
She's not your real mother, anyway.
All father's wives are our mothers.
These are just meaningless
ceremonies.
Father can manage on his own here.
It's better to get back to work.
So, the deceased was
Taro's mother?
- No, no.
- Huh?
You have time to spare, though.
I have more free time than
you, brother.
I can see that.
Get back to the office and tell
everyone I'll be there soon too.
Yes, I'll do that.
Goodbye, dad.
Thanks for your visit.
Give my regards to your wife.
Tell her to honor your mother too.
We'll see.
She's too far into pregnancy now.
How is brother going to manage
with a child on top of everything?
His salary is barely enough.
But it can't be helped.
I guess family planning isn't in our genes.
And where's Otogi?
She's always up to something.
Otogi!
We have a guest.
Is there any food left for him?
I didn't know we would have guests.
I ask you to forgive me.
I was working in the backyard.
Is there any sake left, at least?
I'll bring it right away.
Maybe I shouldn't say this in front of the
deceased, but you're a real ladies' man.
Including this lady just now,
how many wives did you have?
This one is just a maid, though.
Do you have a maid?
We're a fourth-generation tabi
salesmen family, after all.
So, your ancestors were merchants?
That explains everything.
I represent the fifth generation.
Merchants are a thing
of the past.
And I'm fed up with women.
What a drag.
Every 1st and 15th day of the month,
you have to put new clothes on me.
And for that, three seamstresses
have to work all year round.
This is your family's tradition.
And no business is complete
without them.
Both madams are here.
You're dismissed.
You wanted to see me?
Kikuji, you've gone too far. Don't you
think you should stop fooling around?
And you're not even the head of the family yet. It
would be one thing if it stayed within the family.
But even people at the store
know about it now.
Either you stop fooling around with all those
girls or you find a wife. The choice is yours.
Kikuji!
I urge you to take this seriously.
I'm listening to you.
We want to hear what
you have to say.
Whatever I say, the outcome
is always the same.
So, you refuse to listen
to your grandma?
Don't be so impatient, mum.
If you explain it to him gradually,
he will understand everything.
He's very spoiled.
He only does as he pleases.
I don't remember raising you,
my only daughter, like that.
I'm sorry, mum.
Come on, Kikuji, please
apologize to grandma.
I'd rather watch you keep playing this game
of mother-in-law and daughter-in-law.
Kikuji!
I'm sure it was Kihei
who taught him to talk like that.
Call Kihei!
Mum, my husband is a
well-mannered man.
How dare you?
Don't you dare tell me anything about him.
Maybe marriage is not
such a bad idea.
If you get married, you'll inherit the house
of Kawachi and become the head of the family.
It's still not too late to
start a family.
I'm only 22 years old.
Exactly. Stop messing around
and find yourself a wife.
Or, even better,
let us find you a wife.
- There must be no mistakes.
- Yes!
Two hundred fifty two...
I'm calling about a mistake
in the contract.
Unfortunately, we have to put
the processing order on hold.
Yes, this is the last shift.
Good.
We won't disturb you again.
Thank you and goodbye.
Is anything wrong, master?
It's nothing.
Is Kikuji here?
Yes, he's just come.
I didn't see him.
He must have used the back door.
Good that he's here.
Our partner from the Takano family was able
to afford the purchase of a sugar factory.
We must uphold our reputation.
Usually it's good to save money,
but sometimes it's worth the expense.
We have to show people
that our store...
is doing well and business
is booming.
That's true, mum. It's no longer
necessary to dress haphazardly.
I checked the wardrobe...
but I couldn't find your
favorite red kimono.
I was really surprised.
Thank you, Sei!
Look at yourselves.
You're ridiculous.
Mother, I didn't know you were here.
Sorry for not noticing.
Who cut the radishes so big?
It was me.
You have to chop them into
small cubes.
But the young mistress said it
was good enough like this.
So, you're the one who let
her cut those slices?
I said the same.
So, why didn't you fix it?
It takes too long to chop
them into small cubes.
The dish doesn't have to be flamboyant,
but it has to look good.
A handful of small cubes look better
than two or three large pieces.
It makes the dish look bigger.
Although these are small things,
they are the key to success.
Only stupid, rich people can
afford to cut like this.
Hiroko, in our family there are strict
rules even for food.
Even pickles need to be cut in a special way. If you
want to stay here, be sure to respect our traditions.
Otherwise, you're out.
Do you understand?
Young mistress!
Don't do that!
Not yet?
It seems like it.
That's so strange.
Why is it so late this month?
Excuse for my intrusion.
What are you looking for,
young and old mistress?
A wallet fell in earlier.
We were trying to find it.
I'll help you look for it,
if that's the case.
Then, look carefully.
I don't feel comfortable showing my
feelings in front of the shop staff.
What's wrong?
Are you lonely? Come on, tell me.
Such a beautiful neck,
so smooth...
What's wrong with you?
What happened?
Tell me!
Your grandma...
She... just now...
Can you speak more clearly?
She...
She was spying on me to see if
my period had started.
That's humiliating.
It's horrible.
Both for me and the child.
I'll end up losing it.
A child, you say?
Are you pregnant?
I think so.
What, it's a boy?
Send Hiroko my greetings.
Yes. Wait for me.
Father, it's a boy.
Is that so?
We'll finally have an heir!
Who is it?
It's me.
I just spoke to the Takano
family on the phone.
And then?
A baby is born.
Whose?
Well... it's Hiroko and mine's.
Don't you just stand there.
Come inside.
Have a seat.
I have kidney problems.
Don't make me stand up.
Is that the reason you
came back last year?
We suspected there was something wrong
with her and we were worried.
Were you?
According to an ancient
family tradition...
we must make an offering
to the ancestors before a baby is born.
How can you act so recklessly?
I'm sorry, mum, I didn't explain it
to my daughter-in-law.
It's not just your fault.
It's mine too.
I can't face Hiroko now.
She should be taken in by her mother.
I wanted to suggest that too.
Will she go back to her family
to raise the child?
Not only for that.
She broke the rules of this house.
You wanted me to get married sooner.
And now you're dissatisfied, grandma.
Kikuji, you have to make up
your mind.
Tell me...
is the baby a girl or a boy?
It's a boy.
But it's women's day today.
She gave birth to spite us.
Right?
Thank you for coming even though it's
unbearably hot today. Please, take a fan.
The matchmaker's offer
was clear to us.
Otherwise, we wouldn't
have agreed.
But engagement with someone from a
salesmen family might hurt our reputation.
We'll take her.
Since you say so,
we also have something to say.
If we do this wrong,
we might lose credibility.
We are very much aware
of that too.
Hiroko asked to be taught about
our family traditions...
but none of the women here took a
responsible approach to her training.
What?
Has Hiroko already complained
to you?
What else...
Young master, it's enough now.
And don't interrupt anymore when
we're discussing family matters.
You'll have a word when you
become the head of the family.
As for now,
you're just creating problems...
and getting on our nerves.
Is that so?
What do you mean, "is that so"?
Why should our girl suffer?
Don't you think it's too much?
Everything will be inherited by the son,
but Hiroko does not receive any benefits.
Kikuji is only the young master and
he doesn't have to get married.
I understand. If you're honest, take a
list of her things and send them to us.
We'll take everything that
belongs to Hiroko.
Enough now.
Women are too emotional.
There's nothing more to discuss here.
We're taking Hiroko and that's it.
I'll call her right away.
I heard everything.
You don't have to say anything.
You didn't even let me
hug you last night.
We're strangers from now on.
Saijiro is still so little.
His wet-nurse seems to be a caring
woman, so I'm relieved.
Will you forgive me?
OSAKA NIPPO NEWSPAPER
KANSAI SHIMBUN NEWSPAPER
No need to shout!
Everyone, calm down!
Hey! Don't be violent!
Calm down!
It's so hot.
I'm so sweaty,
I can't even hold a needle.
Wipe your hands. If the clothes are wet,
we'll get in trouble again.
Hot springs are probably
colder right now.
Don't even dream about those. Only the
young and old mistress can bath in them.
And the young master is looking
after his father now.
That's why he's not here.
Kikuji, how much do I have?
How much what?
I'm talking about my property.
I want to know what
I've made in my entire life.
I never counted that.
And now that you're sick,
you decided to think about it?
I've been working in Kawachi
since I was 15.
When I was 26, I got married.
It's been 25 years.
My fortune could have doubled.
I can count everything tomorrow.
Some time ago, before this
whole bank thing...
I made a small deposit.
That's why Kawachi didn't
suffer any losses.
Grandma and mum are
going too far.
They've been ignoring Saijiro
for two weeks.
And they left you here alone.
I'm glad you care about him.
They treat Saijiro like a girl.
There's nothing we can do.
Say, father, aren't you and mum
husband and wife?
Didn't we give birth to you?
So, why is it like this?
When she lights up...
a lantern in the next room...
I can see its light from here.
Then, she opens the door...
and quietly gets under the
blanket next to me.
There's been nothing between
us for a long time.
Really?
So, that's how it is.
That doesn't matter.
I only care about my work, anyway.
According to the rules, women
are not allowed to interfere in business.
Did grandpa live with his
wife's family too?
I always thought he hated me...
because he saw in me...
his younger self.
It doesn't look like I'll be living
in my wife's house.
So, do what you enjoy, then.
Be a good son and develop
your spirit...
and abandon the worldly life.
Kikuji, I want something sweet.
I don't like what this
nurse cooks.
Is that so?
Let's find you a better one, then.
Evening!
Sorry to intrude.
Good evening!
Thank you so much.
Thank you, madam!
Good evening. Excuse my tardiness.
But if it isn't the young boss
of the Kawachi family!
I see you have Fuku and Taiko here,
but don't forget about me either.
Which is Fuku and which is Taiko?
We haven't been introduced yet.
Looks like you've drunk enough.
Do you want more?
We're busy.
Thank you!
I'm so tired.
Would you like to leave?
- Then, we will accompany you together.
- Thank you.
All these geishas are so similar
to each other.
I couldn't tell the difference
between them.
You didn't spend a lot of
money today.
But you had your fun with women.
You should spend every night
like this.
You're a thrifty woman.
I'm also a caring one.
Can I ask you for a favor?
If eventually the health of the
master gets worse...
could you help one person
to take care of him?
You mean, my father?
She's been seeing the master
for 8 years.
Eight years?
Would you like to meet her?
Right now?
I'll go fetch her immediately.
Eight years?
Incredible.
Father never ceases to surprise me.
What I wouldn't give to see mum's
and grandma's faces right now.
My name is Kimiko.
The senior master took care of me.
It wouldn't be right if I didn't
take care of him now.
Father, I've found a great nurse for you.
Let me introduce her.
Kimiko?
Food for the patient will have to be
prepared by the nurse, as well.
Kikuji, this was unexpected!
Sir!
It's something to think about.
What's there to think about?
Unions are getting bigger.
But not here.
We should hire experienced workers...
and produce stuff for
the Kawachi family.
- It will allow us to increase salaries by 3 sen.
- By 3 sen?!
Well, maybe by 2 sen.
It's better to have something
than nothing.
Large factories are
closing everywhere.
If we increase salaries,
we'll go bust too.
That's true...
We're going to the bathroom.
Don't take long.
I've designed a new model
of tabi.
No one has anything like it.
I'm sure they'll be popular.
Good idea.
These days, tabi are sold
for 10 per pair.
That's way too cheap.
They have no choice.
But it's cheap.
It's even lower than the cost price.
We have to take this niche and
sell the goods as quickly as possible.
Yosuke, find out more about it.
What are you doing?
Welcome back.
Thanks for taking care of Saijiro.
What do you mean, "welcome home"?
You don't have to pretend.
What are you talking about? While
we were working, you left to have fun.
Then, tell us, who's that woman?
Which woman?
We came in through the back door,
then went into the bathroom.
And, then, we saw some woman
in a robe sneaking into Kihei's room.
Oh, she's looking after father. The
doctor said he needed to be taken care of.
Something definitely smells fishy here.
You're overthinking.
I am not overthinking.
There have been rumors before.
But I didn't believe them, then.
You shouldn't take them
seriously.
Kikuji, if you have anything to
do with this...
how will your mother and I be able to
look people in the eye?
You have nothing to worry about.
This often happens to merchants.
Since my father is seriously ill,
he doesn't care about women at all.
She's just his nurse and
nothing more.
Kihei lives in his wife's house!
And who told you that father's nurse
is a woman like that?
Otogi, what do you
think about her?
You are the one who manages the
house in our absence.
You should know something.
I'm sorry, but I don't know
anything about her.
Mum! Please, stop!
Mum!
Quick!
Hurry up, the patient got worse!
The doctor sure is late.
I think unfortunately...
this is serious disease.
No one in the family...
has ever been so ill before.
I'm deeply sorry.
Father!
Sir... this is so sudden...
It figures, you did depend on that poor
excuse for a husband of yours.
Stop your crying.
It's so inappropriate.
HAMAYU RESTAURANT
We're glad to welcome you.
Kawachi trade house is happy to
present its new production line!
Oki-san, an umbrella!
- For me too, Ofuku!
- Yes.
Your gifts are a great indicator of
your hospitality.
But we have enough of our own tabis
at home, so keep these.
They're too expensive for me.
Really?
Too expensive, you say?
I apologize for the inconvenience.
I hope you didn't get wet.
The gift packaging might have
gotten wet and torn.
Please forgive me,
I overlooked that.
We're always looking forward
to your visit!
What a well-mannered woman.
I've heard her name is Ofuku.
She's the senior maid.
That's right. She's got both a
inward and outward beauty.
If I were a man, I would like to
have a child with someone like her.
But since you're a woman,
you'll keep harassing me.
Why are you so upset?
I can't bring an ordinary woman
because of our family rules.
It's going to be a beautiful ceremony of passing
the house of Kawachi to the fifth generation.
And your mother and grandmother are
going to survive to witness it.
And it would be so nice if Ofuku
was there too.
Stop talking about her already.
Good evening.
Oh my, young master!
Thank you so much!
I'm so glad to see you again!
Again?
I've never seen you before.
How so? We met at the party in Hamayu
recently. Have you forgotten already?
Were you at that event, too?
I was, but I guess I shouldn't have
been so happy about it.
It was raining that day.
Do you remember, young master?
It was such a big and noisy event.
Don't say that, I'm no longer
a young master.
I'm the head of the family now.
I'm sorry, I didn't know that.
Any ideas to have fun?
Hold on!
Look what I have.
And also this.
Do you like rings?
Yes, they are so beautiful.
You have a lot.
I put all of these on every time.
It would be better to wear one of them at a
time. It looks vulgar when they're all together.
But if a guest gives me a ring and I don't
wear it, he may be upset.
These five I got from a
sumo wrestler champion.
But do you, at least,
wear them in turn?
Yes, I started to when I
had too many.
Now I choose depending
on who I am meeting.
What's your name?
I'm Ponta.
Glad to make your acquaintance.
How old are you?
I tell everyone that I'm 20
but, in fact, I'm 18.
Why do you do that?
To be honest, when some clients
find out my real age...
they think I'm too young
and don't want to get involved.
Ponta, please wear only
one ring from now on.
Huh? Only one?
Thank you.
But I want a favor in return...
Sorry for the intrusion. It's so hot.
I'll come in for a minute.
I'm from the Koharu family
in Echigo.
Please, let the Madam know I'm here.
Go to the house and inform them.
Yes.
This is the first time we meet.
It's so hot outside.
Ah, welcome.
Have a seat please.
I'm Ponta from the Koharu family.
I wish prosperity to your family.
And thank you for your help.
I came here on purpose today...
to offer this gift as a sign
of my gratitude.
I'm good at keeping
trade secrets.
How is your health?
Thanks for worrying. Even when I have a cold,
I don't spend more than three days in bed.
That seems very good.
When did it start? At what age?
I mean, your period.
At 12 or 13?
Well, at 12, I guess.
Really?
That was very early.
Our family already has a
seven year old heir.
So, you can't get pregnant.
I understand.
Where are you from?
From Kobe.
Where are your parents?
My father died when I was little.
My mother raised me.
Your mother had to go through
the military turmoil?
That's right.
She was a second-generation geisha.
Really? Being a second-generation geisha,
she must have had a lot of popularity.
How much do you earn a month?
Thank you for your concern. I earn
enough, about a thousand yen a month.
What? I gave her 1200, so why did she
decide to keep silent about the rest?
This heat must have tired you out,
but it was nice to meet you.
Thank you for your warm welcome.
I was also pleased with
our acquaintance.
Why are you in such a hurry?
It's so hot.
I'm thirsty.
I wasn't even offered tea
in your house.
I told you, you shouldn't have come.
I'm sorry, but didn't you say
they might like me?
They said what was required
by those stupid family rules.
Everything else depends on their mood.
I thought you understood that.
If you want our relationship to be public,
you should be more concrete.
Then, you could send me my monthly
allowance openly. Decide who I am for you.
You're a geisha. Your position
in society isn't as high as mine.
Wow!
They offered me a piece of white silk?
Thank you!
Who are those people who are
greeting each other down there?
Those are girls from the Tomino family.
I know them.
The Tomino family?
She's their foster daughter. She has
difficult relationships with her mother.
Interesting.
I didn't know about it.
May your business prosper!
I'll be praying for you!
May the crisis end!
May it end!
Welcome!
You're early today.
I was passing by
and decided to come.
Why are you dressed like that?
The weather is good today.
I was putting the blankets out to dry.
The master has come. There's no need to
sweep the floor. Just clean up.
I don't know what she's doing
the whole day.
Oh no, I spilled a little.
Sit down.
Let's eat together.
You're running here and there.
Makes me feel like I already got married.
I'm sorry.
Before you get married...
you should build me a house.
So, you can keep visiting me.
Are you eating or not?
- I can't.
- Why not?
I don't feel comfortable sharing
such expensive dishes with you.
You shouldn't spend so much
money on me, master.
I was raised to be a geisha.
I'm not like Ponta, I was trained
into this profession.
You know about Ponta?
Yes.
She seems to enjoy your attention.
You're young and wealthy, after all.
So, I'm lucky to have met you.
Stop flattering me, silly.
I'm serious.
Last year, you invited Kimiko...
to take care of your father.
You cleverly came up with everything
and paid her extra for it.
Now, with those savings, Kimiko
opened a store in Shikoku.
Enough! Enough! How come women
find out about everything?
I can't keep anything from you.
It got untied as if by magic.
It was tied like that on purpose.
Tie it again.
I want to see.
You don't need to know.
Where did you learn this?
I invented this method
myself to entertain you.
Kikuji!
Don't get your clothes wet.
What are you doing, grandma?
Are you nuts?
You're the one who's crazy!
Ponta is about to give birth.
The contractions started unexpectedly
and the midwife isn't at home.
- Their maid just called.
- What to do now?
I know you're my grandson,
but cover yourself.
I told her you're in the bathroom, but that
you'd figure this out. And, then, I hung up.
That poor girl...
How could you hide it from us?
If you're going to her, take money with you
and solve everything right away.
What do you mean?
If it's a boy, it will be 50 thousand,
if it's a girl, it's 10 thousand.
Then, you can break off
the relationship.
Money for the umbilical cord?
The umbilical cord is put in a paper bag
on which the parents' names are written.
If you don't do it now,
there might be problems later on.
When the baby grows up a bit,
it will be given to the foster parents.
And that's it?
Not yet, no.
A child born out of wedlock
cannot get your ancestors' last name.
Stop with that.
Don't you know she's just a concubine?
Acting like a man now?
You're starting to look down
on your mum and grandma.
When your father was dying, he also thought that
the problem with that woman would just go away.
In any case, I'll act according to the
rules of this family.
When you abide by the rules,
any business becomes stale and boring.
But not this time.
Nothing can disrupt our business.
Except, we don't have an extra
50 thousand to spare.
If we take the money out of the business,
it might backfire on us.
Unless that's what you want?
Then, write a receipt first.
A receipt?
It's just a piece of paper.
The rules are the rules.
Fine.
Otogi, bring ink and paper.
Ponta, it's me.
Thank you for coming.
Did the birth go well?
Yes.
Oh boy!
That yelling scared me.
Must have fallen asleep.
Since it's over,
you might go to sleep too.
I had a very hard time
before giving birth.
Is it a boy or a girl?
A boy.
"For a boy, it's 50 thousand."
But 50 thousand for what?
I don't have that kind of money
on me, so I wrote a receipt.
With that kind of money, I would have
no worries for the rest of my life.
This money is to break off the relationship
between me and the baby.
The least you could do is think
of a name for him.
A name, huh?
That's difficult.
I know! What if we take the second
kanji of your name? It'll be Taro.
That's too predictable, don't you think?
Do you have any better ideas?
This name will ensure he's healthy.
It's decided.
FIGHT COURAGEOUSLY FOR YOUR COUNTRY
After what happened in Manchuria,
business has been going downhill.
That's why such cheap establishments
are flourishing.
Is this your first time here?
I haven't been beyond the
Dōtonbori bridge much.
So, why did you decide
to come today?
My life has become boring.
I want some fun.
No wonder such places
are growing in popularity.
Why are you sad?
Do we bore you?
She's always like that when she
doesn't fancy something.
And what does she fancy?
She's interested in
very expensive things.
Precious stones?
What, then? How will I know
if you're silent like a doll?
- Horses.
- Horses?
Race horses.
So, you like gambling?
Not at all.
It's not the same as gambling.
Buying a race horse
and betting wisely...
can give you a huge profit.
And if your horse is winning, on top
of that, you can make a fortune!
What's this?
I'm sorry.
I cut several fabrics to make belts.
I took three of them,
each with a different color...
and set aside seven
other colors.
I've heard that bright colors help to
overcome grief.
If this is such a burden for you,
why did you decide to give birth?
I guess it's easy to give a new life,
but it's hard to rebuild your own.
I am well aware of that.
You're so conservative.
I'm an old-fashioned woman,
that's true.
Do you feel alright?
You look pale...
I have so much on my
plate right now.
I can't afford to get sick.
Don't despair and don't
give in to superstitions.
I'm giving birth at 33 for the first time.
I need more than a colorful belt.
I need everything rainbow-colored,
even tabi.
Rainbow-colored tabi?
Rainbow-colored...
I have some work to do.
I'll come back later.
Excellent colors!
Yes, the dye is very good.
Red violet and sky blue
for women.
The other three colors for men.
Master!
In the past, it was customary for
men to wear black tabis only.
Producing colorful tabi
is a great idea.
But even if we start now,
we might not make it before winter.
So, we need to speed up and produce
the first batch as quickly as possible.
Because of reduced imports,
we won't be able to freely produce...
and sell them like before.
If we think about that,
we might as well just shut up shop.
In times of crisis, people want
to buy high-quality goods.
I know how customers think.
I'm sure it will work.
Everyone thinks I'm a womanizer,
but I know a thing or two about business.
Great! It's my horse!
It's my horse!
The one I bought you?
It's the other way round.
I know that.
It's number five.
I see.
Oh no, the others are overtaking it.
What a shame!
Next year, we'll definitely win.
Are you not cold?
Me? Not at all.
My idea of colorful tabi was a failure.
Maybe that's why I'm so cold.
Maybe you caught a cold?
I want to see our horse.
Here are the final standings.
Number three came first.
Number five came second.
Don't look.
I need to clean up here.
Okay, I'll take off my coat.
Here, this is a present from me.
A cigarette case made from deer skin.
I wanted to give it to you
in the restaurant.
I shouldn't have bought it,
should I?
It's the first time in my life that I got a
present. Thank you. Thank you so much.
How many women did
you have before me?
I like women which
money can't buy.
And I like your extravagance.
My extravagance, you say?
What is it? Are you sick?
You have a high fever.
It's not a good time
to get sick.
Wait, can't you get up?
You really caught a cold,
after all.
Come on, stand up.
What shall I do now?
He's over there.
Good evening.
We apologize for the late intrusion.
This is so presumptuous,
but let us go to the master.
Wasuke, maybe we
shouldn't move him?
But the madam ordered us to
bring him home.
Put this on, please.
Hold him tight.
We have to go, goodbye!
Saijiro, come in.
Come closer.
- Next year, you're going to kindergarten.
- I won't go.
Grandma says other children will bully
me, so I don't need to go there.
Dad says you're going,
so you're going.
Stop crying like a little girl.
We're taking care of him now.
You two should get along.
Saijiro, go over there.
Grandma has something for you.
You seem to be getting better.
I can't get up yet.
Don't wear business suits
anymore.
When you wear them, you look like
a walking straw scarecrow.
You were unconscious for two days.
We didn't know what to do.
You gave us quite the scare.
I'm sorry.
I've heard you were seen with
a beautiful woman.
We just spent the night together.
I guess that went according to the rules.
Ponta and Ikuko...
both get their monthly
allowance from our store.
If you hook up with another woman,
it won't do us any good.
Grandma!
I'm over 30 already. I don't need you getting
involved in my relationships with women.
I'm just saying to be careful, that's all.
The third one might also want a family.
Plus, there's also our reputation.
If I were afraid of public disapproval, I
wouldn't have decided to get married again.
Did you find a wife?
It will be better for my son.
But if you disapprove, I won't.
And, one more thing, I don't want to
take part in your women's intrigues.
You think that, apart from
a woman from the Kawachi family...
no one is good enough
for me to marry.
Outsider women are not suitable
for the role of my wife.
But they are allowed to
bear my children.
At the same time, they're not a burden to
our family, so there's no need to fret.
No wonder your name means "eternal joy."
Okay, we won't worry needlessly.
I made some inquiries and found
out that Ikuko gave birth to a child.
A baby was born?
Why didn't she tell me?
You'll have a chance to
ask her that yourself.
But, right now, you can't
leave this house.
That's another son and
another 50 thousand.
Horrible news!
Something happened to Ikuko.
What happened?
All of the sudden, she died...
What a shame.
She was such a nice girl.
This is the first time a woman
has died because of me.
Kikuji, you're not going anywhere.
These are the rules of our family.
The head of the family cannot see the concubine's
dead body or be present at her funeral.
I can't go even if I wanted to.
Not with this fever.
Let Wasuke handle the affairs regarding
the burial. And try to sleep.
I am sleeping already!
Can't you see?
I have nothing against
your mistresses.
They not only bring you pleasure...
but they also bring sons
to our family.
I hope, one day, a nice girl
will give you a daughter too.
It's better to talk about
that next time, mum.
I was in Hamayu today
and met Ofuku.
I hope she will be the one to give
you a daughter.
She's just not capable
of conceiving boys.
And after the girl is born, we can think
about finding a suitable husband for her.
After all, the Kawachi family has been thriving
up until the third generation thanks to heiresses.
Men join the family only
after getting married.
Let Saijiro be the head of the family, but let Ofuku's
daughter bring a worthy husband into our house.
When that happens, I can rest.
Are you sure Ofuku will
give birth to a girl?
Ofuku is predisposed to give birth to
girls. Besides, she's in excellent health.
Look. She has the same
body type as me.
That makes me so jealous!
Your body is more beautiful than mine.
Ikuko has already left us.
Thank you for helping me. At least,
this way I can say goodbye to her.
I couldn't show my face
at the funeral.
A prostitute...
can break off the relationship...
with her patron at any time.
Hug me. Hug me tight.
I can't stop myself from crying.
Don't cry.
It's not good for you.
Just another woman died.
That's all there is to it.
I need to forget about her. Otherwise,
I can't be the head of the family.
But I can't forget her.
And it makes me feel so helpless.
Master.
If you don't mind,
I can try to comfort you.
I can't.
I wanted the third one to be the last.
But, on the day of Ikuko's funeral,
it's happening for the fourth time.
It was an accident that I was here,
so it doesn't count.
- An accident?
- Yes.
Didn't my grandma send you?
The old mistress told me...
that before getting you a baby...
I should ask if you want it.
But I'm sterile.
You can't have children?
That's right.
Even though I'm in excellent health,
strangely I can't conceive.
You can't.
But grandma doesn't know it!
Sorry, I almost stumbled.
It's so dark.
Look where you're walking, idiot!
And turn off that stupid flashlight!
Who the hell are you?
I'm from the tabi store in the port.
And what is a tabi salesman doing
here at this hour of the night?
You're in great physical shape.
Which fores are you in?
I'm in the people's guards.
And why are you there with
such a strong built?
Since you can't answer me clearly,
maybe you're a spy?
No.
I need to visit a sick friend.
A sick friend?
What's his name?
I mean, the illness is
not so serious...
If that's the case, why visit someone
during the emergency period?
Because the patient has no one else to
rely on and I'm worried.
So, where are you headed?
To Sennen.
There's nothing but whore houses there.
Are you going to see a woman?
Is she your lover?
No...
Having fun with whores in these
hard times? You scumbag!
Come with me!
To the station!
Sorry for the trouble.
Sorry I called you so late.
Not at all.
I was happy to help.
They said that, according to the rules,
there has to be a guarantor, so I chose you.
I heard you're responsible for supplying
uniforms, so you should know what to do.
You have so many things!
Let me help.
Don't worry.
They are just tabi.
Tabi?
If we can exchange them,
we can get the necessary things.
I'm planning to come more often.
What size?
I'll go to one more house, just so
I don't have return with these.
They say you're still taking care
of your women.
And that's why you
didn't run away.
I'm working hard.
I heard your grandma and
your mother were evacuated.
I asked them to stay in Kawachi,
but they said they'd feel lonely there.
So, you were left alone?
It's just Wasuke and I.
So, it's all over now.
I like this kind of freedom.
There are no more women's intrigues...
Wasuke!
The phone is ringing.
Hello? It's the Kawachi family!
Oh, it's you?
What? What about Taro?
Huh? Speak clearly!
After school, he hit one of his
classmates with a schoolbag.
Then, the other kids mobbed him
and beat him up.
Is he badly hurt?
He needed a few stitches
on his face.
Don't cry, no one died.
How much longer?
We're almost there.
I'll feel better if you come with me.
Come in, please.
Sorry for the mess.
Thank you.
Mum! You've arrived!
Taro!
Your dad is also here.
So, you're my father?
That's right.
Why did you start it
if you can't fight?
There were too many of them.
Maybe seven or eight?
Does it hurt?
Mum will take care of you now.
What were you thinking?
When I grow up, I'll be a owner of
a tabi shop. They will all be jealous.
Even though I was born out of wedlock,
I can become a Osaka salesman too.
Am I right?
You are!
This kid is so...
"Determined", you wanted to say?
You don't need to cry.
That's right.
Ikuko's son's foster parents live
at the next station.
I apologize for this late visit. The
train got delayed in the previous station.
Not a problem.
We're glad to see you anytime.
Actually, I came so late to
avoid the attention.
Sorry, the lights are already
out in the house.
Well... is he already asleep?
I'll wake him up.
There's no need to.
I just wanted to make sure he's fine.
Is that so?
Come in, please.
Would you like some tea?
He looks so much like Ikuko.
The more explosions there are,
the angrier people seem to get.
I found some things that
were intact.
Really now?
In the bomb shelter, things
were not damaged at all.
I see.
Fortunately, this warehouse
survived the fire, at least.
My whole body feels numb.
I'd like to lie down right now.
Shall we sleep, Wasuke?
We worked all night.
And I can see you're exhausted too.
Master, should we boil
some rice?
Are you hungry?
I think so.
I'm not sure anymore.
Master, you're alive!
I ran away without even
taking anything.
Your warehouse didn't burn down, master.
I'm so glad.
It was built so well.
I thought you needed something
from the warehouse.
I was afraid that I would not find the shop among
the scorched ruins. Glad that wasn't the case.
I'm glad it survived.
We need to think about the food.
And you two need to rest.
Us two?
Master, it's me.
I'm sorry I took so long.
I was drinking shochu with
an acquaintance of mine...
and looking at the view of
burnt-down Osaka.
It's so nice here.
Master, if you happen to have sake
here, let's have a drink together.
You've had enough already.
Go get some rest, okay?
Yes, thank you.
Have a good night, then.
Excuse me.
Master, things are about to get worse.
What are we going to do?
We won't survive without trade.
Huh? Trade?
Even if we have a small
wooden shop...
we can still continue to do business.
Master, forgive me, but I'm
thinking of leaving Osaka.
But you are indeed the fifth-generation merchant
of the House of Kawachi and I admire your spirit.
Stop flattering me.
I just can't leave everything as it is.
Mum!
Grandma!
Now, it wasn't the best time
to come back here.
Why have you come back?
I heard the warehouse burned down.
I couldn't stop myself from coming.
Get up, everyone!
Come on! Get up!
I have about 100 thousand
left right now.
If we divide this money between the six of us,
each one of you will get about 15 thousand.
It's enough to live comfortably for the rest of
your life. Take the money and go to Tōdai-ji temple.
Why are you doing this?
What are we supposed to do
in that rural temple?
If you stay here, you'll die during
the next bombing raid.
Thank you.
I'll take my share.
Then, I guess it's better to
obey master's orders.
We lost everything.
And you're still spoiling your concubines.
Not only do you treat me and your mother like
cattle, but you've also burned down the shop!
What are you talking about?
Wasuke and I carried water
to put down the fire!
This warehouse is a place meant for men.
We earned what we had with blood and sweat.
And you took advantage of the bombing
raid to destroy everything we built!
Mum, what are you talking about?
And you couldn't even survive a couple of years
on your own. You're always hiding behind me.
Mum, do you agree with
what grandma just said?
Do you also hate me for giving
away the money?
Don't ask me such a thing.
I can't think clearly right now.
I don't know what to do anymore.
Take them to the temple and
ask the priest to take care of them.
Yes, I understand.
You can count on me.
Well, master,
it's time to say goodbye.
Master, please look after Taro.
Oh, that's right!
I completely forgot about Taro.
I'm counting on you.
Farewell!
Help! The old mistress... she...
she fell into the river!
It's my mistake.
I wasn't keeping an eye on her.
I'm so sorry.
Please forgive me.
It was mother's wish to die at Kawachi's
house, that's why she came back.
I think she saw something
in the river.
She bent down her body to get a
closer look and suddenly fell.
I saw it with my own eyes.
She just slipped.
Kikuji, now that grandma is dead,
you're the only one I have left.
The women went to the temple
and didn't know what happened.
I learned about it a year later...
when I decided to secretly
pay them a visit.
The war was over and they
were making plans...
about what to do when they go
back to Osaka.
They could not resign themselves to
remain in that rural wilderness.
I wrote a letter ten months ago,
but there's still no reply.
Could it be that we've lost touch
with him forever?
Or maybe that old hag is intercepting
and destroying our mail.
I'm tired of being in the
middle of nowhere.
I want to go back to Osaka and
start my own business.
You mean horse racing?
My father lost everything on horses.
I want to succeed where he didn't.
If I win, I'll become rich.
And I'm looking for two or three partners
to start my own business.
You want to be a geisha again?
I really like it.
The water is really hot.
Come on, girls!
Join in.
I'm on my way!
Ofuku, what about you?
Well...
The money I got when I left Osaka
is enough for me to live on.
So, I'm planning to enjoy my life.
I'll think about the future later.
Ofuku, you have the most beautiful skin.
Can I touch it?
Ah, it's so pretty!
You girls are so naughty!
So obscene!
Ponta, what is that glistening
in your teeth?
It's a diamond.
A diamond?
They took all my rings during the interrogations,
but didn't notice the diamond in my teeth.
So, what happened to them?
When everybody else was having such a rough time, they
were whooping it up. They were all plump and rosy.
Even when I try to rethink what I was doing with
these women, it was doomed from the beginning.
I saw them only as these fleshy
things called women.
Oh boy, was I ever happy. That was the
end of my life as a prodigal son.
I had never thought I could free myself of
women with such a clean, refreshed feeling.
And what happened to you?
I left the temple after that.
The next day, I asked Wasuke to send
money to settle everything.
All my problems went away with
my grandma and mum too.
So, that's what happened!
It's impossible for money to
solve all the problems...
regarding the women from your
own family.
My sons Taro and Saijiro joined me.
We talked and decided that I would not be
stupid and follow my grandma's rules.
Then, my mother died too, and finally,
I was completely free of women.
I see.
So, that's how your real life started.
And that's when you
could finally rest?
- Finally rest?
- That's right!
I see.
So, whose death anniversary
do we have today?
After the war ended, I married
for a second time.
She was different from all
my other previous women.
She was hard-working.
But she died young.
I see.
So, that's how it was.
Taro has the business acumen.
Saijiro is different, but he was able to
fund his own transport company.
What? Are you still here?
I'm a bit under the weather.
Had to go to the toilet again.
Maybe it was something you ate?
Dad, have you made your decision
about that thing we discussed?
I'm not going to sell the house.
I want to start my own business here.
Business?
Where will you get the funding for that?
I'll think of something.
Are you going to make tabi again?
Making tabi is the only
business I know about.
We had to sell the land where
the shop used to be...
precisely because you're so obsessed
with your precious tabi.
You don't have to worry.
This time, I'll succeed.
There are so many memorial
tablets here.
For all those women I
just told you about.
Are they all dead?
I wonder. I don't know what
happened to all of them.
For me, it's as if they are dead.
So, I wanted to have one day
to remember all of them.
My mother died for real, though.
Cerebral hemorrhage.
Taro, you know...
Give me some money.
We've been sitting for too long,
it's time to go.
Here, take this.
No, no. I can't.
It makes me embarrassed.
Sorry I disturbed you.
Not at all.
Be careful with the cars
on the road!
Auntie Otogi, I'm off too.
Has our guest already left?
And master left too.
I should have seen him off.
It's so hard to negotiate with him.
He refuses to sell this house.
He just can't seem to understand
he can't sell his socks here.
And he keeps telling the same story
to all of his new friends.
Sometimes I wonder
if it's true at all.
Of course it is.
Really?
I guess Auntie Otogi has known my
father for a long time.
Do you also want to stay
in this house?
I'd like to live here until
you find a wife.
Well, women aren't for me!
After hearing dad's stories,
I started to stray away from them.
The old master is a
very kind man.
Auntie Otogi, are you perhaps
in love with father?
It's not like that.
Excuse me, I have to go now.
I'll be waiting.
Even though the old master
comes from a rich family...
he's very strong-willed.
Had he been born under
different circumstances...
he could have become
as kind as his father.
He could have been a good
head of the family.
THE END