Our prophet,
may he rest in peace.
He says:
“Oh, you young people,
those who are lucky to marry
should do so.
Those who accept deserve glory.
Their bond is blessed.”
The two of them know each other
and are now engaged.
Why should I disapprove?
It is God’s will!
May God bless them
and give them peace,
a long life and happiness!
Congratulations!
- Congratulations.
Aren't you Florian Silbereisen?
- Fuck off, shit face!
Let’s fuck him over.
Run after him and take his hand.
Come on, Yara! Come on!
Go, go!
Okay, take her! Now.
Now! Go on!
What d’you want?
- It was all in fun.
All in fun. Let go.
- What d’you want?
Just a prank. They dared me
to hold your hand. That’s all.
A prank?
I swear. Let me go, please
Then get lost.
Hey, schizo! Put that knife away!
What's wrong with that bitch?
- It's ok.
No big deal.
- Let’s get outta here!
No, I gotta go.
- Gotta play Mommy again?
Fuck off!
Just kidding, Yara!
Brush thoroughly.
- Yeah!
I’ll check on you.
- Make som tea for Bab!
Can’t you do it yourself?
- C’mon, I gotta go.
Sure, you gotta work.
Big deals are waiting.
Okay, I’ll do it.
Now off to bed,
you little poopers.
Hey, you should film us!
- Do your own rap, you geeks!
Dude, now we gotta do it again.
There’s that bitch again!
You got the urge?
Should we rough up that slut?
- No, forget it.
Count me in.
- No way. It was our stupid prank.
Where have you been?
Sorry, Dad.
I lost track of time.
It’s your fault I’m late.
This has to stop.
Sorry.
- People have started to talk.
"His kids do as they please."
"He has no idea
what they’re up to."
Take care.
- Good night.
Look at that lovesick jerk.
Forget it, man.
Vallah, she won’t let you near her.
He can’t hear you.
Earth to Bekim! Bekim!
C’mon, kick it in there!
- C’mon! C’mon! Do it!
Just shoot it!
Fuck! Shoot! Shoot!
Shoot! Shoot! Yeah!
Fuckin’ shit!
Every time that slut
works here I lose.
Come here if you got a problem.
- It’s your fault!
That you dick are losing?
- All your fault!
I’ll show you how to lose!
What d’you want from me?
Fuck off!
Let go.
- Cool it.
Just get a new betting form.
- Wanna go back to jail?
He's full of shit!
I want him outta here!
Why don’t you go out with me instead?
- Bekim ...
Just for a drink. And if it’s
uncool, I’ll never, never ...
Hey dude, don’t ride me!
- No, I’m not kiddin’.
Bekim, don’t ride me.
Just forget it.
You can’t just stay home all night.
– Can’t I?
It’s sweet of you to care,
but I’m okay. Thanks.
Hey Bekim, don’t push me.
Forget it.
I told you so, dude!
Ouch! Hey!
So?
What did she say this time?
You keep getting prettier.
Men are gonna start lining up.
With Bakir at the front?
- As if I’d want that ugly weirdo.
Why are your eyes so red?
No idea. Allergy maybe?
Were you smoking pot?
How are you doing?
How are you, Bakir?
I told you we had visitors.
Sorry, you know how it is.
Lots to do.
You don’t even have a job.
- What do you know?
That’s enough!
- Most important: everybody’s fine.
Yeah.
- Look!
She looks like Leyla.
Sorry, Abaz.
Kids say things without thinking.
Okay, good night. C’mon.
Father! – Go find a job.
You sit around doing nothing.
Why can’t we ever talk about her?
Go to sleep.
Can’t you tell me
something about her?
Go to sleep.
Sorry.
- Trouble at home? I gotta go.
It’s okay. I understand.
I have to go. Remember to put
the beverages away. – Sure.
I’m late. See you.
- Bye.
Is she serious?
Shows up late and then takes a break!
Fuck her.
- Hey man!
Here’s Kiki. Did Sunny call?
Don’t freak out!
I just wanted to know where she is.
Well ...
Hey, awesome wheels!
The man, the myth! Bekim!
Have a seat. What’s up?
Hey, what’s up?
- What d’you want?
Shall we go for a drink later?
No way. I’m meeting friends.
Since when d’you have friends?
- Hey Bekim, stop hitting on me!
Okay.
- Hands off! It’s my job.
And the blue Margaux.
Six forty.
The soda is my treat.
You know, that’s kind of our thing.
We film our pranks
and put ‘em online.
Cool.
So you survived the shock?
Your soda!
Wow, deluxe! Awesome wheels!
Best news of the day.
I come and you go.
What d’you want, huh?
What d’you want from me?
Chill out, girl!
- I’ll give you some real girl.
You are so fucked up, man!
What was that about?
- Wanna go for a joyride, Yara?
When my boss sees I closed
the shop... - Kiki.
Hi, Kiki.
Where’s your name from?
- It’s Persian.
It means: the bold one.
- You’re Persian?
No, Albanian.
Okay, bold one. Can you drive?
- No, I’m just seventeen.
Wanna learn?
Hey man!
Your turn!
I’ll catch hell from my brother.
Relax. There’s nobody here.
You were cooler
with a knife at your neck.
Put it on “D” and pull.
One more, one more, okay.
- Yeah, okay.
Now take your foot
off the brake. Just do it.
Take your foot off. Yeah!
Now turn the corner.
Oh my God. Cool. I’m driving!
Now step on the gas
before we start backing up.
Watch out.
Watch out! Stop!
Everything okay with you?
Oh my God!
You look so high. So high!
- But you don’t!
You don’t!
Hey, did you really go to prison?
Why?
- I heard stories.
Okay, I believe what people say.
You can really get
on people's nerves.
Yeah, for a few months.
Breaking and entering ...
... assault and battery.
And how did you get the scar?
A long time ago. I was playing
with my big sister Sunny.
Do you live with her?
No, she lives in France.
Oh la la ... France.
Like with champagne
and the sea and ... blue water?
Exactly.
Someday I’m gonna live there, too.
Cool.
- Yeah.
But damn far away.
I know what you mean.
My sister ran away, too.
She abandoned us.
My sister didn’t abandon me.
Sorry.
- It’s okay.
No, really. I’m sorry.
For real?
Hey, did you get rid of the car?
It was just a kiss, okay?
I’m not a lesbian.
What’s up?
Hey princess!
- Get lost!
Fuck off! Adults only!
Fuck off!
- What’s your problem?
Fuck you!
- C’mon!
Come back here!
Stop! Give it to me!
Stop it! Gimme that!
Ouch!
Stop! Stop! Stop!
Stop it! Stop it!
Hey Yara!
What happened?
- Nothing.
Your dinner’s in the fridge.
Should I warm it up?
Later.
I’m going out a bit, Dad.
- You don’t need to go out.
Where to?
- Just for a second.
Okay, go on.
Hey, come on.
Just a sec.
What’s up?
What do you care?
Yeah, okay.
I won’t be long.
C’mon. Come on!
- Where to?
You’ll see.
Have you been waiting the whole time?
- Maybe.
Terrific.
What’s up?
- Nothing.
C’mon, tell me.
Somehow I can’t stop
thinking about you.
Wow, are you in love with me?
You’re so fucked up.
You know ...
We can’t do this kind of stuff.
- What kind of stuff?
It’s bad enough for us
if we got a boyfriend.
Everybody has the right
to live as they please, right?
Yeah, but ...
- Hey.
I’m just difficult. Sorry.
It’s so fucking complicated.
Calm down.
I don’t think you know
how special you are.
Will you dance for me?
Fuck, fuck, fuck.
What time is it?
I’m in fucking trouble. C’mon.
But it was worth it.
Damn it, Yara!
Answer the phone!
She’s late.
- I told you so.
What did you say?
That we’re crazy? And then?
Not here. What if somebody sees us?
Cool down, lady.
C’mon, get in the car!
- I’m coming.
He’s your brother?
So that’s your date?
You’re a bad influence
for my little sister.
So that’s why you want
to go out with me?
Then stop hitting on me!
Leave her alone,
or I’ll fuck you over! Okay?
We were just kidding.
- Shut up!
Cool it, dude. We’re just friends.
Everything’s okay.
Stop that shit!
Where’d you get that?
Fuck!
Your phone!
What?
- Give me your phone!
No.
You think you can fool me?
I saw everything.
You didn’t see a thing!
- You’ll never see her again!
Do you really
wanna do this to Bab?
What’s wrong with her?
Where were you?
- It’s nothing, Father.
She was out with friends.
Everything’s okay.
You just go to work
and come home. Understand?
Understand?
- Yeah.
That’s too dangerous.
- Just checking if you’re okay.
You gotta get outta here.
- When can I see you again?
Hey, Kiki. Bekim took my phone,
and I’m grounded.
You aren’t asleep?
Why aren’t you asleep yet?
I’m worried, Yara.
You come home so late.
Okay, Babi.
C’mon, go to bed. Good night.
- Good night.
Good night.
Yara?
- I’ll have a look.
What’s wrong?
- Nothing. Just the stupid cat.
Hey, are you nuts?
- Just the stupid cat.
I missed you.
Bekim’s picking me up.
- I want to see you again.
He‘s got his eye on me all day.
I can’t even go to the toilet
without him noticing.
That’s sick.
My father’s totally stressed out.
If Bekim tells him about it ...
That bum thinks
he’s a real big shot.
Like I said, he’s sick.
That’s how it is with us.
I mean, we could talk
about your family, too.
Sorry.
And now?
I do wanna be with you.
Yeah?
- Yeah.
But only in secret?
That can be cool, too.
Where?
I think it’s kind of nice here.
Sure, it might not be France ...
I’ll sneak out somehow, chérie.
Yara?
- Okay, tomorrow. 9 p.m. Schwanenwik.
Put on something fancy.
Babi.
- Bekim told me to pick you up.
Let’s go.
You won’t tell?
- No.
Promise?
- Promise.
Thanks, sweetheart.
Leave the window ajar.
Sleep tight.
It’s much too expensive here.
Did you reserve a table?
What if we didn’t?
- We’re booked up tonight.
Sure.
You think we’re broke or what?
Is that enough?
- Like I said. We’re booked up.
I don’t believe you, asshole.
We aren’t good enough, huh?
- C’mon, let’s go.
No, there’s nobody here.
We’ll just sit down and order.
Don’t raise your voice. Would you
please leave the premises at once.
Hey asshole, you aren’t
gonna kick us out!
We refuse to eat
at a fucking joint like this!
C’mon, Yara!
Your face. Awesome.
Oh my God.
We’re like Bonnie and Clyde.
Yeah, we’re Bonnie and Bonnie.
We’re Bonnie and Bonnie,
and nobody can stop us!
Bonnie and Bonnie
against the rest of the world!
Hey, Yara.
- Hey.
Are you pissed at me?
- No, not at all.
Why don’t you stop by anymore
or answer my messages?
Bekim has my phone, and I’m grounded.
- Fuck
Why?
- No idea. I lost my key.
I looked for it and got home late.
He’s such a bum.
That’s fucking awful.
I was really hoping
you’d be there tonight.
What’re you doing?
- A performance at that art place.
Mike and I had a big fight.
It’s really stupid.
Oh well. Keep cool.
- See ya.
Hey, you know what? I’ll be there.
- Yeah?
Yeah.
Okay, I gotta go. See ya.
- See ya.
I’m off work. Time for
my watchdog to take me home.
10 P.M. GALLERY
BY THE BRIDGE
They’re asleep.
I’m going to bed with Jeta.
Good night.
Sleep tight.
Is everything okay?
Yeah.
Are you sure?
Listen ...
If anything happens,
call this number.
Okay? Yeah?
Don’t forget the bed.
- Yeah.
Yara!
- Hey, that went fast.
Can I go now?
- What’s up?
What’s up, bro?
C’mon, let's go.
What’s that freak doing here?
What’s going on, Yara?
- The freak’s coming with us.
Jamal.
This is Tony, Mikey, Akhi ...
- I’m Abdullah.
He’s Akhi, ‘cause of his beard.
Looks like a terrorist.
Okay, guys, let’s go.
Boy, am I hungry. C’mon!
What’s going on?
- Wait and see.
Let’s get something to drink first.
Want a smoke?
- Hey guys, this way.
This would look real nice
in my poolroom, wouldn’t it?
This crap?
- Yeah.
Dude, I can paint
you that with my dick.
Smoking is not allowed here.
- Of course not.
Didn’t you say you were quitting?
- Yeah, sure.
No touching either.
Dude, what’s wrong with Yara?
No!
Bonnie and Bonnie!
Come to my place.
No.
- C’mon. It’s my birthday.
Seriously? That pick-up works?
This is Yara’s mailbox ...
Where is Yara?
Sweet, you and your sister?
Is that France?
That’s where she lives?
Why no pictures of your parents?
My parents don’t have
any pictures of me either.
Spare your pity. I don’t care.
Sorry, you don’t have to tell me,
if you don’t want to.
There are thousands
of nicer things we could do.
You’re so beautiful.
Who’s that?
Where’s Yara?
- At home!?
Are you kidding me?
She went off with that freak
from the bar. - Kiki?
Yeah, right.
Are you nuts? You ratted on Yara.
She’s in big trouble ‘cause of you.
Me? Are you all whacko?
You are brainless.
C’mon!
Yeah, with everything
and extra cheese.
Okay, thanks.
I dare you to open the door
topless for the pizza man.
No problem.
- Deal.
Deal. But only if you stay with me.
For always?
Just tell me if you’re tired of me.
How about a little trust?
Stop, stop, stop!
Hey, what do I get for it?
Whatever you like.
Yara, what are you doing?
What are you doing?
What are you doing, damn it?
You’re watching a first-class
domestic drama! - Turn that off!
Get off of her!
- Get up, girl!
Put something on.
Put something on!
Don’t, Bekim!
- Get back in there!
Get out!
What d’you want?
What’re you doing here?
You still don’t get it, huh?
I go for pussy!
What’s the deal?
What’s the deal? Huh?
I love Yara, and she loves me.
That’s enough, man!
We’ll solve this another way.
- I can hardly wait!
You won’t change a thing
between us! Not a thing!
Please, don’t.
I curse you.
Turn that off!
ALBANIAN CATCHES SISTER
RED-HANDED WITH LESBIAN!
Get up! What’s this?
Who sent me this?
Tell me! Who sent it?
You’re hurting me, Dad!
- What did you do to me?
You’re grounded!
You’re staying here!
Everyone despises me.
They look away.
You like it? You like it?
- Stop it, Dad!
What do you want? Tell me!
- Look what you’ve done.
You’re a whore just like your sister!
I’ll make up for it ...
Where’s your fucking brother?
My brother did what’s right.
Now everybody knows
your sister is a lesbian slut.
Get outta here. Get outta here.
Where’s Akhi? - Fuck off!
Look after your own family!
What kind of men can’t keep
their women under control?
There are over 20,000 clicks.
Don’t look at it.
I’m so sorry, sweetheart.
I didn’t want it to happen.
I don’t think you’re bad.
They’re coming today
to ask for your hand.
Your mother wore it
on that day, too.
It’s pretty.
I got your number from Isso.
He said you might know
where Sunny is.
Yeah, I’m her sister.
Where is she? C’mon, tell me!
Asshole, stop saying that about
my sister! I don’t believe a word!
Don’t worry, sweetheart.
Oh my God, Kiki.
What are you doing here?
Working.
- Working?
Oh shit, my mistake.
I forgot to tell you
that we got no place
for scum like you.
Sorry.
- What?
You got it right.
My money?
- Money? You got money?
No. You?
- Anybody got any money?
Got money? No?
- Sorry. No money.
What money?
What a bunch of
pathetic motherfuckers.
Hey, you stupid cunt!
How dare you!
Don’t give me that stupid look!
It’s your fault Yara has to marry
that fucking neighbor she hates.
It’s all your fault!
So? What do you think?
That bad?
You look pretty.
You look fantastic.
Turn that off!
Our prophet ...
May he rest in peace.
He says:
“Oh, you young people,
those who are lucky
to marry should do so.
Those who accept deserve glory.
Their bond is blessed.”
The two of them know each
other and are now engaged.
Why should I disapprove?
It is God’s will!
May God bless them
and give them peace,
a long life and happiness!
Congratulations!
- Congratulations.
Excuse me for a minute.
Must be the excitement.
What’s wrong? – I just need
a break. The belt is too tight.
Open up. Open up.
C’mon, open it!
Jeta, open the window.
- No!
I’ll be right there.
Open it, Yara!
Open it!
- Open it, Yara!
Kiki, Kiki, no! No!
Open the door, Yara!
Run, Kiki! Bekim will kill you!
- Come with me!
I just got engaged!
- But I love you!
Open the door, Yara!
No!
Please, don’t go!
Yara, open the door!
Open the door!
Where to, Kiki?
Fuck, Kiki!
- C’mon!
What are we doing here?
- We’re alive!
C’mon, hurry.
Watch out. Let’s go.
40, 20, 90.
Here, take the bag.
Fucking whore!
Bekim, you bastard!
Your fucking sister
took everything in my safe!
Either you take care
of things or I will!
What if I never see
my siblings again?
Baby, I promise.
Everything will be good.
Mohammed’s gonna blame Bekim.
- Yara!
That asshole wanted to marry you off.
– He's still my brother ...
You think he’s gonna kill us?
- Bullshit.
Bekim’s a whacko, but he’s no killer.
Fuck Bekim! Fuck ‘em all.
ALBANIAN GIRL FLEES FROM HER FAMILY
Kiki, we’re famous!
They all want us to make it! Look!
- Yara ...
I want us to make it, okay?
Everything will be fine.
I promise.
Burglary, multiple thefts,
assault and battery, car theft.
That’s quite a list.
- I’m worried about my daughter.
She’s a child.
- That Kiki is crazy.
Do you think Kiki Gerlach
is dangerous?
That lesbian stole my car,
and my sister ran off ...
Don’t tell the whole world!
What did he say?
Why did your daughter
run away with her?
GANGSTER COUPLE ON THE RUN
LESBIAN COUPLE FLEES
ON THE RUN
THE GIRLS JUST WANTED TO ...
BONNIE & BONNIE FLEE FROM THE FAMILY
LIKE IN A MOVIE
Everything okay?
- Ouch, don't!
What is it?
- I think I dislocated my shoulder.
Can you ... can you get out?
Can you get out?
C’mon, hold on tight.
Not there.
We gotta get away, okay?
C’mon, we gotta hide.
Yes?
- Herr Ibrahim?
Your son’s car was found
on Highway B4 outside Uelzen.
A total wreck.
- An accident?
Neither of the girls
were found by the car.
Do you have any idea
where they were going?
Friends? Relatives?
No, nothing.
- If you hear anything, let us know.
France is number 1 in hip hop.
You could be a famous dancer.
You’re really serious, you freak?
I love you.
Did you let Sunny know
that we’re coming?
I don’t have to.
But if you like, I will.
Later, babe, okay?
Bring her back to me.
- You can trust me, Dad.
You promised.
- I’ll explain it to you.
You ran away.
You abandoned us like Leyla.
That isn’t right.
I love you, sweetheart.
I hate you. And Halit
and Krenar hate you, too.
It’s all her fault.
She destroyed our family.
It’s her fault.
I hate both of you.
Dad, my father,
please forgive me.
Now I’ve lost my second daughter.
Babi, no!
You have a temperature.
Your wound is still bleeding.
We can’t go on like this.
You have to go to a hospital.
- And right back to prison?
We’ll go to Leyla. In Uelzen.
She’s a doctor.
- You hate your sister.
Everything is my fault.
Go away.
- I’m not going anywhere.
Hey, did you forget?
The two of us forever!
Are you really giving up?
Kiki!
- Yara, you can still leave now.
I stole the car, and I broke
into the gambling joint.
I don’t want to leave.
You might never see
your siblings again.
I want to go to France with you.
- I don’t want to go with you.
I love you.
- I don’t love you.
Go on, fuck off. Fuck off!
Yara, fuck off, you slut!
Fuck off! Go away!
Go away, fuck off! Go away!
Go away!
We’ll make it!
To all those haters out there:
We are Bonnie and Bonnie.
None of you motherfuckers
will ever tear us apart.
Bekim!
Look in the glove compartment.
Yara, we’ll manage some other way.
My dearest!
I know everything.
The police were here.
Come in. I’ll fix you up first.
There we are.
Your arm will be okay soon.
It will hurt for a while, but
the painkiller will kick in soon.
Thank you.
- Sure.
So you’re lesbian?
No idea. Who cares?
What if I am?
Does that bother you?
Did she talk you
into running away?
Leyla, you know what life
is like in Wilhelmsburg.
It’s no life at all.
Working in that
lousy shop every day.
Then smoking pot with friends,
then putting the kids to bed.
Until I get married, and
the crap starts all over again.
So now you can understand
why I ran away.
I had to take over
all your duties.
Think Babi would have acted
differently if I had stayed?
Kiki is the only person
who cares about what I want.
So you love her?
- Why do you ask?
Because it’s a big step.
We have so many followers
who support us.
What’s wrong, Leyla?
Are you against us now?
No, it’s good
that you’re fighting.
I love my husband.
I paid a high price for my freedom.
Are you coming?
- Just a minute.
Would you do it again?
It’s your life, Yara.
Right.
I’m seventeen.
I’ll decide for myself.
I’m so glad I have you.
We’ll go to France.
Somehow. Tonight.
Because we’re
Bonnie and Bonnie, right?
Right.
You severely injured a man
in a betting shop?
Not severely.
Anyway, the guy’s a dickhead.
And Kiki was previously convicted.
Any other secrets?
Who cares? Whatever I say
you won’t believe us.
What’s your problem?
Is everybody your enemy?
Huh?
- Leyla ...
I’m not going back.
- You’re just making it worse.
You’re ruining your whole life.
What’s going on?
- I’d like you to tell me!
... about northern Germany’s
prettiest crooks: Bonnie and Bonnie.
C’mon, Yara. Let’s go.
You stay here.
- Let me go.
You ratted on us?
- What? No!
Let her go.
The police are coming.
You’re all the same!
Go, take the car key!
I’m driving.
- Here, Yara.
Move it, move it!
Take off!
Move it, Yara! Move it!
What do I do?
- Straight ahead!
Go faster!
- Okay!
Is he behind us?
- No, everything’s fine.
You’re doing great.
Everything’s fine.
What?
- Everything’s fine.
- That guy is there.
What do I do?
- Just keep driving faster.
Straight ahead, straight ahead!
Go faster. Go right.
You gotta turn right.
Where?
Okay now. Turn right.
Fuck, the cops!
Damn it, we’re trapped.
Brake, brake, brake! Brake!
I won’t leave you.
I promise.
Fuck off! All of you! Fuck off!
Fuck off! All of you!
Go away!
- Police! Lower the gun!
Fuck off!
- Drop the gun!
Go away!
- Drop it!
Kiki, drop the gun!
- Drop the gun!
C’mon, drop the gun.
- Stop it!
Kiki, we have so many supporters.
And we have each other.
That’s what counts.
Look at me. Look at me ...
I love you, okay?
Szeretlek.
We can visit your sister later.
– It’ll be okay.
My sister isn’t in France.
She’s in prison.
Listen to your girlfriend.
Put the gun down.
I don’t care. No need to apologize.
It’s no problem.
C’mon, drop the gun.
- Everything will be okay.
We’ll make it.
Stop!
- Fuck off!
EGY ÉVVEL KÉSŐBB