Once upon a time,
there was a very well-behaved girl.
The Buddha appeared
and gave her a magic book.
When you grow up…
The book will give
you the most magical things.
Miss Idol, An!
I want to leave the contest.
THREE MONTHS AGO
This is me.
At this time, my only dream
is to get into Harvard University.
So of course, the only thing
I need to do is to focus on learning.
However, life is not that simple.
JA JA BONG - COOL QUEEN
This is Ja Ja Bong,
the school's queen. As cool as a cucumber.
This is Na Na Duong. Always wear a "No
Makeup" makeup with a sentimental look.
Ja Bong!
Get out! Out! Out!
La La Len Talkative Queen.
Go, Quan!
Go go, Quan!
And that is the group of
the most unattractive girls.
And confronting them,
is "The Great Man's Group".
Diu Tomboy Genuine Gentleman.
Skinny Guitar Skinny, Gaily, and Coolio.
Well-behaved Fatty A Sky full of manners.
We have never messed up with you guys.
Why did you blame us
for our class's bad result?
You did nothing.
But distracting boys. Making
them lose concentration on their study.
I've heard
Ja Ja Bong will be a Dep magazine
bikini model this summer session.
Are you serious?
I'm late every morning because I dream of…
Make the girls just pay
attention to fashion, not lessons.
Bong looks good in anything.
Three scabby sheep can
spoil the whole flock.
What grades do you get?
Your grade is high.
Look. Great grades.
What century are you living in?
The brain is to serve beauty.
Nothing is impossible with our brain.
We get the Miss Idol prize
for our class every year.
Can you?
Just because we don't want to.
- Let's say you want to this time!
- Yes!
If you win, we'll
stand in front of the school…
…screaming out loud
that we are beautiful but stupid.
But if you lose, you have
to tell the whole school that…
Genius club is a piece of junk.
THE AGREEMENT
Let's sign up here.
Hey! Hey there!
You forgot to zip your backpack.
Thank you.
Something wrong!
Is this yours?
My Quan!
Who's that girl?
Jeez! He knows her period.
She's more special than you, Bong.
Do your eyes hurt?
Take these.
We'll get it signed next Monday.
This is our headteacher.
She looks cold but has a big heart.
So weird. Like a freak!
Looks so weird.
- So ugly! Hideous!
- Which planet is she from?
This is the last time I warn you.
You care about everything but your study.
Going to international school
isn't doing anything you want.
In my class,
anyone who can't study well
must repeat a grade.
Don't ever blame me!
An! Introduce yourself!
Gosh! Hurry up,
new friend. We have to study.
Hurry up! Come on!
I'm An.
Oh my!
Why does it take her so long?
Such a role model!
You're wearing uniform to the extra class.
Come on, guys! Don't tease her.
Wow!
I used to go to public school.
My Dad said I would be
more confident in this school.
There's a question you haven't answered.
What's your hobby?
I love reading books.
Wow! Tell us
some interesting stories.
I read about
the butterfly effect, the chaos theory,
the perfection of wisdom,
Greek mythology, Ancient Rome.
Do you love doing anything else?
Something less weird, like
playing instruments, singing, bowling.
Boring.
An, you can sit over there.
- Wow!
- How lucky she is!
- Hi!
- Is it all okay?
Sit next to Quan.
So great to sit near a handsome
guy, although being teased a lot.
How lucky I am!
Why does your hair
have a lot of split ends?
Why are you as fit as a bodybuilder?
Why didn't you eat anything?
What's wrong?
You didn't even touch
the peanut butter made by your Dad.
Why did you use
the whole bottle of medicated oil?
I'm fine, Nanny!
Your Dad dropped by your school,
then he rushed to the airport.
Apply for Miss Idol?
Yup!
You're a potential contestant.
Join our club and be
our entrant for the contest.
I…
- I…
- Don't worry!
Join our club,
okay? This world will be yours.
There are books on economics,
politics, philosophy, and critical theory.
Over here are books on
religions, spirit, theology, literature.
There are also books on applied science.
On economics there is
"The Prize: The Epic Quest for Oil,
Money &amp; Power" by Daniel Yergin.
On psychology there's "The
first and last freedom" by Krishnamurti.
Or "The power of Now" by Eckhart Tolle.
On political philosophy,
"The social contract" by Jean
Jacques Rousseau is also a good one.
You can visit the Tam bookstore
on Nguyen Thi Minh Khai St.
Take a right to 496 Alley.
Then turn to 20th
Street. From there, turn to 20/10/7.
Many good, cheap books.
I gotta go home. Please find someone else.
I'm sorry! Are you okay?
It seems this
is the book my Dad told me about before.
You've just heard the song "Our Memory"
on "Tell Us Your Story on Friday".
From our listener,
Hoai Thuong to her friend, Cong Danh.
May your friendship never die.
Up next is the song "Waiting
for you" from Ms. Lien to Mr. Tho.
Her message says "I've
been looking for you as long as I can.
If you get this message,
please contact me via
my number 0937005123
Miss you forever."
Here you are.
Poor you!
Come here with us!
Sit down!
Here are some Fresh
cookies. So yummy! Try it!
Jeez! I'm trapped.
Why was I so stupid that time?
What have you done, Duong?
I am starving.
An! An!
An! Hold this please.
I'll go get something to clean the table.
Who's that?
Who's up there?
Watch out!
That fat girl is so savage.
Gosh! What's wrong, An?
Come here! Let me help.
Any tissue?
Oops! It's soaking wet.
You should buy a new one.
It's my Dad's
present from his business trip.
It isn't available here.
Daddy's home!
Something seems wrong with you.
I had to cancel the Singapore
meeting tomorrow morning.
I'm fine, Dad. Have you had dinner yet?
Did you remember your stomach meds?
Do you like the new school?
No man is an island.
Even books need to rely on one another.
Don't isolate yourself, my dear.
Hey.
What's that?
My cousin also has a book like yours.
Here's your stomach medicine, Dad.
- Thanks.
- I'm off for school, Dad.
Remember to make more friends, dear.
Do you still want to
go to Harvard University?
I've told you. Your GPA is not
all you need to get into Harvard.
GPA is just a part of it.
They're looking for active students.
If your profile has lots of great
extra-curricular achievements,
you'll have more chance to get in.
Does taking part in Miss Idol count, Dad?
Of course!
As the club president,
on the day An joins our club,
I'd like to ask for
your blessing, Mr. Einstein.
Please bless her
so that she can
contribute to human development
with her knowledge and intelligence.
Namo Amitabha!
I'm sorry. Thank you, Mr. Einstein.
Alright! Let's smell 100 books here
to absorb Mr. Einstein's philosophy, An.
There are four rounds in total.
Round One, Facebook photo.
Round Two, Knowledge.
Round Three, Interview.
And Round Four, Talent.
We first need to choose
an impressive outfit for the first round.
Please don't.
Give me back my shirt.
The game's just
starting but this shirt's dirty.
Okay.
If you take this
I'll take that one home to wash.
Then you keep it again? Come on. Hurry up!
Wait a minute! I'll find
Quan to recharge my energy.
Hi, Mom, it's me.
What's wrong?
How can I help you?
I'm busy, mom.
Thanks.
Ouch!
I explained to Quan. Don't worry.
He wouldn't believe
you threw his shirt away.
Look!
- What?
- What's that?
What? Oh my God!
Oh my God!
Oh dear! Unbelievable!
Can you see it? Can you see it?
I see all white.
Yeah,
two girls in white dresses.
As white as snow.
No. I mean I see a white wall.
Oops, my bad.
They always make
it exaggerated just to take a photo.
I think we should make
an outfit from recycle bottles
to deliver the message
of environmental protection.
And we'll use whatever is available for
makeup. We definitely get tons of likes.
It's strange,
but not beautiful, guys.
An has an oval face,
don't do her eyebrows too straight.
See?
I told you to let me
make you look prettier
but you didn't want to.
Let's come to the photo shoot.
- How beautiful!
You need to have more than
500 likes to pass the first round!
She got hundreds of likes.
Prettier than my girlfriend.
We need 100 more likes.
What should we do?
Mother Nature will
bring you natural beauty.
Come and check out
our make-over tips!
And that transformation
happens thanks to cucumbers, tomatoes
eggs, honey, pure water
and fruit juice. Everyone can do it!
Good news! Good news! The Beauty Club
is sharing beauty tips for you girls!
It's a once-in-a-lifetime
chance! Come on, everyone! Come on!
How rude!
Come on, come on? Are you a fishmonger?
Listen to me.
Ladies and gentlemen!
Come here, beauty takes it all.
How fancy you are!
Beauty doesn't take it all.
Beauty plus intelligence is the best.
Let's buy it.
The taste is also okay.
Buy this.
- One for me.
- It's hot.
Giveaway Vouchers!
Giveaway Vouchers! Vouchers!
Our club will give all of
you a 900-page-long book
on Western Philosophy.
You can read it all year, for sure!
All year long…
A fat pig,
a skinny stork
and a tomboy
- are flattering an ugly duck.
- Are flattering an ugly duck.
BEAUTY SECRETS WITH QUESTIONS
BOOK LOVERS' CLUB
We have no more chance.
Photo voting is till 5 p.m.
Now we have fewer likes than before.
FROM KHANH AN WITH LOVE
How could you have those photos?
It's a long process.
Don't ever tell
La Len I set this mess up, okay?
FROM KHANH AN WITH LOVE
You ugly duck!
Did you do it to get likes for the photo?
What a pity! Your number of
likes fell immediately.
I…
I didn't do anything.
Oh gosh! How dirty! Let's wash her face.
Water can't clean her face.
Stop it.
Hi Dad!
An?
Does the magic book really exist?
What do you mean?
How could you say that to me?
You're just creating people like you.
Strict and conservative.
Teachers like you are no
longer suitable for this modern age.
Do you deserve to be a teacher?
An is super cool.
Gosh.
Only An dares talk like that
to a teacher here. I daren't.
- Yah so do I.
- Look at this.
She's our Miss Idol this year.
How's your contest?
It's okay, Dad. I passed the first round.
Congratulations.
Let's eat.
I had to find an organic
food store to buy the ingredients.
Nowadays many people
sell their consciences for money.
Cheating doesn't bring out any real value.
It can't last, sweetie.
Cheating's like a sweet candy at first.
It seduces you.
Gradually,
you rely on it.
By the time you realize that,
it might be too late.
Hey! Let's dig in.
I'm like a fox
You're like a bunch of green grapes
When you're young and beautiful
I can't get through to you…
Here comes the cake! Have a bite.
What's wrong with you guys?
Do you know who posted that clip?
I trust you.
But is what you said in
the clip really your thoughts?
Actually, An was partially right.
But she expressed
it a bit disrespectfully.
It's fine as long as you're apologetic.
What happened, An?
Do you want to give up?
At least you must try your best.
If trying my best means
hurting other people, does it count?
If it means doing
whatever it takes, does it count?
It does.
What's important is that after making
mistakes you know how to improve yourself.
That's what trying your best means.
If you still don't have any good results,
you can tear this paper apart.
Would you like to have
a ride with me tomorrow?
You love the
yellow outfit, right?
There is a really nice song about yellow.
It's a song about a couple.
But the guy has done something wrong.
And he decided to write her a letter.
In which he said…
If she forgives him,
then on the day he comes back,
he'll tie a yellow ribbon round
the tree in front of their house.
Well, after the exciting first round,
now our 16 beautiful contestants will
move on to the second round - Knowledge.
The fourth session, of
self-study, is canceled today.
Congratulations, Nhu!
Fighting, Nhu! Good job, Nhu!
I'M SORRY. I HAVE TO FLY TO AUSTRALIA FOR
AN URGENT BUSINESS TRIP. GOOD LUCK, DEAR!
Next, please welcome
Ja Ja Bong and Khanh An.
Question One: In Vietnamese Literature,
who can become invisible?
Thuy Kieu?
What?
Although Thuy Kieu is beautiful,
she cannot become invisible.
It's the calligraphy master in the poem
called The Master, by Vu Dinh Lien.
Can you prove it?
"The old man still sits there
Crossing the street nobody sees him"
No-one seeing him although
he's there means he's invisible.
Congratulations, An!
Hurrah!
What phenomenon is used in physics
to help fiber optic cables send data
in telecommunications?
It is…
What's wrong with her?
Reflection.
Time is nearly up!
What happened?
Why did she just shout?
- Answer.
Any other answers, Ja Ja Bong?
No, I don't.
The answer is total internal reflection.
Ja Ja Bong, fighting!
In which country was
the first Euro Cup?
France.
Congrats, Ja Ja Bong!
A free falling object is
deflected to which direction?
It's… it's… it's below.
Ja Ja Bong, please!
It's… it's the East.
Congrats, Ja Bong!
Ja Bong!
How smart she is!
How could you come up with
the idea of putting ants into her clothes?
What a genius!
It makes me laugh thinking
about that nerdy An. Such a silly monkey!
Well, Ja Ja Bong has made history.
What should we say when I beat a member
of the Genius Club in term of knowledge?
Beauty takes it all.
I'm sorry, Dad. Just one last time.
They look pretty high.
You may trip and fall on the stage.
Have you ever?
My new style.
What are you thinking, Linh?
Don't you know Ja Ja Bong's
good at walking on high heels?
Hey, Bong!
If you walk on stage on these high heels,
the judges will definitely let you win.
Hey!
I think cleaning tables with a mop
will suit you more than holding this.
You freak me out.
That's too much.
Who do you think you are?
Didn't you tell me
that you would try your best?
If she finds out
you'll be kicked out of the club.
Let's go.
Based on your excellent academic record,
the judges decided to replace
the student who had an accident with you.
How was Bong?
She's got a sprained ankle.
But it's not Ja Ja Bong.
It's Nhu, Hao Quan's sister.
I've heard Ja Ja Bong
gave Nhu that pair of shoes.
What's this, An?
Pain killer. It hurts a lot, doesn't it?
That's very kind of you.
What have you done to help
people in need around you, Ja Bong?
Here's my answer to the question.
When we grow up
we will realize that we have two hands.
One is to help ourselves.
The other is to help other people.
An is lucky,
she got the chance because Nhu fell over.
That's nothing to be proud of.
But if we consider it carefully
helping others also
means helping ourselves.
Why do I say so?
Think about it.
ARE YOU COMING, DAD?
Once you have a genuine
desire to help others,
you'll have a strong motivation
to live better and more helpfully.
Excellent, Bong!
Did you guys see that?
Or is that an illusion?
Slap me!
- Does it hurt?
Nonsense! Nonsense!
But… do you know
what she's doing in that room?
She is using that book to cheat.
I'm not cheating.
I just want to make things fair.
You guys know I'm scared
of public speaking, okay?
Want to be Ja Bong?
Give it back to me.
Hey you!
Two boys and two girls. What are you doing
in the ladies' restroom? Get out now!
To clarify how I helped the other people,
I'd like to ask Na Na Duong to help.
Duong, could you please give me my bag?
Don't go unless you want to look silly.
You're the one who looks silly.
Tien.
Parents got divorced.
Mom then married a foreigner.
You live with your step mom in a slum.
Your dad rides a bike.
You're at international school
thanks to your mom's money.
Then Ja Ja Bong
helped you join the Beauty Club.
As long as you have
to do everything she asks.
What are you talking about?
Duong!
You think Bong
will keep your secret, okay?
She's waiting for you on stage.
Aren't you one of
the miserable cases that she used to help?
Shut up!
Ja Ja Bong!
You're so evil!
Duong! Duong! Duong!
What? What was that?
Please ask the technician
to open the charity file for me.
I've always been keeping
these things with me.
Because they remind
me to keep helping others.
Thank you, Bong.
You did a really good job.
Khanh An on stage, please.
- Why did he invite Khanh An?
- What is going on?
She is not beautiful.
What you just did
earlier is very beautiful.
Just what we're
looking for in the school environment.
This is the best answer to the question:
What have you done to
help people in need around you?
Do you think both An and Bong
deserve to get into the final round?
Everything I did, I did it for our club.
What a noble act!
But it's all about cheating.
Our club can't take that.
Even when we lose,
we will lose with dignity.
Want to grab something to eat?
Maybe next time.
Ja Bong!
Talk to you later.
Wow. An looks gorgeous today.
Great lipstick.
Yours looks brighter.
- It's nothing compared to yours.
- Yours is the best.
Have you made peace with Na Duong?
Why do I have to do that?
I swear to take back
everything I've given her.
Come on! You guys are friends anyway.
What's going on?
How could La La Len do this to you?
She even put this on
the school Facebook page.
Hey!
La La Len!
Are you okay?
This brand is good. Bong should use this.
Take care of
your skin for the upcoming Final.
Hey!
Even though baking is for women,
you have to be tougher. Nobody judges.
Tough or soft?
As long as it's beautiful.
When cleaning your suitcase this morning,
I found strange men's underwear.
It isn't yours, is it?
You should get married soon so
that An can have both a mom and a dad.
It looks beautiful.
- Hey!
- Quan!
Let's hang out!
We have a test tomorrow
afternoon. Don't you need to study?
But it's tomorrow afternoon.
An, come shopping with us!
Quan, join us!
Let's go! Go!
Go!
Go! Go!
Your mom called me
from the States the other day,
saying they wanted
you to pay them a visit.
And they've chosen you some ladies.
They wanted to set dates up for you there.
Time really flies. I've been
living in Vietnam for 20 years.
Get yourself ready
for a shower of presents.
On your birthdays,
whether you are home or not,
An always makes you a birthday present.
But you always travel around.
You didn't spend much time with her.
Well…
I'm busy running my business.
I just want her to have a better life.
You think money can
solve all kinds of problems?
What she needs is the love of her dad.
She wants you to spend more time with her.
To be honest,
I think An even loves
you more than her own dad.
But you're always busy.
You don't have
time for her. Poor little girl!
An must have
a really big surprise for you.
Dad, with this lunch
box, you will never be hungry.
Thank you dad, for bringing me
up since I was an abandoned baby.
Dad, hurry up! Let's find
someone to take care of you.
No matter who you get married to, I'll
love that person as much as I love you.
Dad, I present you with a lot of time
so that you can be home with me.
Dad, promise me you'll spend
the whole weekend with me on my birthday.
Hey! Let's go to
the cafeteria to welcome Nhu back!
Yeah!
Hurry up! An's waiting for us.
Forget it. If she's there, we won't go.
What's wrong? I thought you guys…
Thanks to An, Nhu can
recover quickly. We must invite her.
Thanks to An?
You're crazy.
You thought
her heels got broken by chance?
An broke her heels so that Nhu had
an accident and she could replace Nhu.
Quan. I just wanted to harm Ja Ja Bong.
Doesn't matter who you want to harm.
I trusted you.
Quan!
Quan, please listen to me!
This is called "Karma".
Joking with me?
You think I don't
know what you're doing behind me?
I can't be seen like this.
The final round is about to come.
And Quan?
Hey!
Time for class. Why are
you still reading books?
- Hello!
- Hello, I'm Khanh An's headteacher.
An missed a crucial test today.
She didn't attend
the class either. Is she okay?
She's fine.
Thank you. I'll talk to her.
Dad, your hair butter is the best.
My hair feels so smooth.
Dad!
Do you want to tell me something?
Did you do anything wrong?
Tell me, An.
I didn't do anything.
I don't know what you're talking about.
Don't you want me to be
more active and beautiful?
I just did what they did.
If they can cheat, then so can I.
Shut up!
The world would be full of bad people
if they all thought like you do.
You think you've become lovely, okay?
In fact,
you just turned out to be a bad one.
I didn't know how to raise you.
This is all my fault.
I'm not capable of being your father.
Dad, I'm wrong. It's my fault. I'm sorry!
Dad! Dad!
Dad! Dad! Dad! Dad!
Dad, don't go.
Dad! Dad!
Dad!
Dad, don't leave me, Dad…
How can my
sweetheart manage to do everything?
There are only two options.
One is to face the pain with discipline.
The other is to confront it with regret.
An is still young,
she won't be able to understand.
Beauty takes…
Takes what? Say it out loud!
Why do you have to mumble?
Beauty takes…
Hold on!
What is that?
The contest hasn't ended
yet. We don't know the winner.
They said they had quit.
The one who signs this form
will be responsible for the contest.
- Does the contest keep going?
- Do they quit?
Hide yourself! Quickly!
I KNOW YOU WON'T LEAVE ME…
LOTS OF MOSQUITOES HERE.
YOU AND NANNY SHOULD TAKE CARE
OF YOURSELF… I'M REALLY SORRY, DAD.
They said, if they forgive each other,
tie a yellow ribbon round the tree.
Thank you, Anh Khue, for
your magnificent performance.
Coming on stage is our candidate
with the most likes and votes.
Please welcome Ja Ja Bong!
Let's welcome
our last performance tonight.
Please give it up for Khanh An!
Woooh look… It's Khanh An.
Time flies quickly, leaving only memories
Dear memories
I will always remember
The voices of my teachers
Dear friends
I will always remember
Those times we argued
So that when we are apart
The longings remain in our hearts
The longings for old friends
And old school
Putting my hand on my lips
To hold back the…
- What happened?
- Oh my God! What happened?
- What's going on?
- The music is off.
- What happened?
Putting my hand on my lips…
Putting my hand on my lips
To hold back the tears
Time flies so quickly…
- Lip sing?
- Get down!
You're lip-syncing!
- You're lip-syncing!
- Get down! Get down!
- Stop singing.
How handsome!
What's that? Who's that?
A new performance?
Yes! An has tried a lot to change.
I knew Ja Bong would do
some tricks with the sound system.
Let's turn the tables on her.
Time flies so quickly
Leaving only memories
Dear memories
I will always remember
The voices of my teachers
Dear friends
I will always remember
Those times we argued
So that when we part ways
The longings remain in our hearts
The longings for old friends
And old school
Putting my hand on my lips
To hold back the tears
Could we stop the flying time?
My heart still regrets the good old days
Dear friends
I can still hear your voices
And laughters echoing somewhere
All of my longings
Who can I send them to now?
If you have a wish for this life
Remember to wish for time to retrace
So that the passions and burning desires
Can stay eternal in our hearts
And so that our love
And dreams will never fade
If you have a wish for this life
Remember to wish for time to retrace
So that we can be together again
Making more memories
So that the smiles can stay forever
In our eyes, on our lips
And in our beautiful memories
Dad, why are you here? I thought
you had a business trip today, right?
I have sold all
the stock of the overseas branch.
Miss Idol, An! Miss Idol, An!
Thanks a lot for trusting
me, my dear teachers and friends.
But I don't think I deserve it.
I'm so sorry.
My Dad taught me to fulfill my
dreams with hard work and real efforts.
But I have cheated to get what I wanted.
That turned me into another person.
I hurt my good friends
and even the people I love the most.
Then I realize the worst thing is
not about failing to achieve my dreams,
but about losing myself.
Thank you everyone for
giving me a chance to make it right.
I'd like to withdraw from the contest.
Why is that?
I still can't believe my eyes.
Hundreds of yellow ribbons are flying.
Let's end the movie with a wide shot!
See? I just quit in
the middle of the contest.
Are you curious about what
I do after this to follow my dream?
If you want to, ask
your friends to watch this movie
so that the producer will have
enough budget for the next sequence.
See you then!