♪ I've found a girl
who'd love me ♪
♪ And make me settle down ♪
♪ She got too fed up of me ♪
♪ So I ran right outta town ♪
♪ I was born reckless ♪
♪ So I shouldn't die ♪
♪ Stay reckless ♪
♪ Till the day I die ♪
♪ Say the way I'm living ♪
♪ My life ain't gonna last ♪
♪ If that two chance I'm given ♪
♪ Gonna keep on living fast ♪
♪ I was born reckless ♪
♪ So I shouldn't die ♪
♪ Stay reckless ♪
♪ Till the day I die ♪
♪ I was born reckless ♪
♪ So I shouldn't die ♪
♪ Stay reckless ♪
♪ Till the day I die ♪
♪ Born reckless ♪
♪ So I shouldn't die ♪
♪ Stay reckless ♪
♪ Till the day I die ♪
- Kelly.
- Hi.
- Hi!
- How's Charlie?
- Oh, he'll live.
- He took a bad spill.
This is not much but..
You're awfully generous, Kelly.
Uh, Charlie might have rode
the limit if that bronc
hadn't been so spooky.
Charlie won't be doing nothing for a while.
Yeah, that's why I figured
you'd be needing this.
You can read a girl's mind
better than that.
Goodnight.
Boy Scout.
Had a tough fight.
First time I ever saw you walk
away from that kind of fight.
Now, gang, let's give a nice hand
to Jackie Adams, a trick rider.
And get her up here to do a song for us.
A real nice hand, how about
a real nice hand there.
Yeah!
- Hey, Jackie. Have a drink.
- Drown.
♪ You can whistle
you can wink ♪
♪ But in spite
of what you think ♪
♪ I'm a good
sweet home type girl ♪
♪ I may not appear naive ♪
♪ But appearances deceive ♪
♪ I'm a good
sweet home type girl ♪
♪ I can't understand
for the life of me ♪
♪ Why no one walks me
down the aisle ♪
♪ Why no one wants
to make a wife of me ♪
♪ Or is my type of girl
out of style ♪
♪ I can sew and I can cook ♪
♪ I deserve a second look ♪
♪ I'm a good
sweet home type girl ♪
♪ Never wander from the farm
never calls a false alarm ♪
♪ I'm a stead home type girl ♪
♪ But my kind of goods
are saleable ♪
♪ Nobody wants to wear
old pearl ♪
♪ But if somebody
should I'm available ♪
♪ I'm a good sweet
home type girl ♪
♪ A good sweet home type girl ♪
♪ My type of goods
are saleable ♪
♪ Nobody wants to wear
old pearl ♪
♪ But if somebody should
I'm available ♪
♪ I'm a good
sweet home type girl ♪
♪ Hah-hah-hah-hah ♪
♪ I'm a good ♪
♪ Sweet home ♪
♪ Type girl ♪♪
Thank you.
You ride, you rope, you sing.
You've got more talent than I thought.
- Anything else?
- Alright, I give up.
You can let go now.
Now, Jackie, that's out of character.
You could win top prize money
with me any time, any place.
And before we get to Panamint
I'd written enough copy
to make you the hottest
rodeo queen in the whole circuit.
That's only the second
thing you have in mind.
What's the matter, baby,
don't you like to see
your name in the newspapers?
You couldn't put it in large
enough print.
Now get your hands off!
Sure.
Ow.
Hey, Charlie!
Five, I get your ten,
he don't rope that girl.
You gotta bet.
No!
Help!
Let me go.
Get off.
Mark Wilson.
Now, son, you shouldn't do that.
Not to a known sports writer.
You loss him up, we can't do
a good job writing about this.
You don't do that.
We don't sell tickets.
We don't get any money
in the kitty proprietary.
We don't get any prizes,
we don't eats well.
Go back, get the wagon.
I'd like to saddle my hands on that
rope spinning trick riding little...
Then you saw me ride today?
Yeah, I saw you ride.
Lady, next time keep sitting in the saddle.
Maybe guys don't get such a good look.
You don't get yourself
in such a tight spot.
I'm sorry, I got you into it.
But thanks for helping me out.
You can drop me off at the nearest bus stop
or something.
I'll be alright.
And Mister.
You'd better keep sitting in the saddle
next time you ride, too.
Maybe you won't get to eat so much dirt.
- Cool Man!
- Eve, honey!
Hi, Eve. How are you doing?
Jackie Adams. Eve Tuttle.
- Hello, Eve.
- Jackie.
- What?
- Oh no, this is strictly co-op.
Everybody on their own.
Well, in that case you take number six
and you two take number 44.
Okay. I'm not sleepy.
Take care of the horses.
- I'm gonna wander.
- Yeah.
- See you in the morning.
- Sure thing.
- Kelly, mind if I wander, too?
- Sure, why not.
Goodnight, see you in the morning.
Goodnight.
- How've things been?
- Sometimes we eat.
Sometimes we think about
the things we ain't got to eat.
Kelly, has he been behaving himself?
Well, you know Kelly.
At least we keep moving.
Or somebody's aim is pretty bad.
Oh now, Eve, you know Kelly
ain't got them kinda bad habit.
Sure.
Well, how's things between you and Kelly?
Well, I guess you'd say we're
just between eating and thinking.
Well, stop thinking and point
Kelly to Little River.
They're having a big
frontier rodeo up there.
Locals.
Kelly oughta walk away with the whole town.
Locals?
I didn't know they held rodeos here.
Yeah, pulled it last season.
Let's sit down.
- Cigarette?
- No, thanks.
Cool Man and I worked just two seasons ago.
We did pretty good.
Eve's husband,
he, uh... didn't do so well.
Fell off a horse and broke his neck.
- You're chilly?
- Hmm-mm.
Thanks.
Like an empty battlefield out there.
Yeah, sometimes you take
a little blood, leave a little.
I saw you ride the other day.
Yeah, I guess I did eat
a mouthful of dirt at that.
For a minute, I didn't think
you'd walk away from that Brahma.
And neither did I.
Seems like... each time
I walk away a little slower.
Why do you, Kelly?
Why do I what?
Stay in it?
Ah, lots of reasons I guess.
Name one that's worth getting buried for?
I'd sort of be unhappy if I got
buried with my pockets empty.
It'd hurt my pride.
It'd hurt your pride a lot more
if they couldn't bury you all in one piece.
Well, to tell the truth
I figure I got three
maybe four more good years left in me.
So, one day I don't walk away
from a bull or a horse.
I end up like Cool Man.
Twisted ribs, broken bones.
A hole big enough to stick your
fist in it from a steer's horn.
When that happens,
I want to have enough put away
so that I can let my aching body to rest
in a nice piece of land
I've got picked out.
Yeah, I got me a real sweet
little piece of land all picked out.
If you live that long.
I'll live that long.
- Name?
- Kelly Cobb.
'Not from around
these parts, huh, friend?'
'Ah, you might say a little bit
from every place.'
Why? What's that got
to do with it?
Oh, now, don't go get
in your horns up at me, friend.
I'm just running this week.
The Mayor here, he makes all of the rules.
'He wants to keep
it a family affair.'
'All the contestants
local from town.'
I don't figure our entry money's
smell is too different.
Exactly what I was thinking.
Weren't you, Mayor?
Isn't that what you were thinking, Mayor?
Hmm-mm. I w-was.
You see, friend, no discrimination.
That'll be 20 dollars.
And there's a special $10 entry
for the big two horse race for the day.
That lets us out.
You're not so local yourself.
Are you?
'It's for the top prize money,
friends.'
Kelly, wait a minute.
Oh, Jackie, I can't take your money.
Forget it, you pay me back.
How would you like to win that?
Yeah, in the roping contest.
'Good afternoon,
ladies and gentlemen.'
'A great big western
welcome to you all.'
'To the Frontier Days rodeo
here in Little River.'
'We've got the top hands from
the surrounding country here'
and they're going to be
competing for top money
on the toughest broncs, bulls
and steers that we could find.
'You're all in for a large size'
'afternoon of thrills,
stills and spills.'
'Now, ladies and gentlemen,
on our afternoon's program'
'it's the cowboys saddle back riding'
'and it looks as if the first
boy is about ready to come out.'
'Yes, he is, and here he comes.'
'Little Dave getting
stumbled up. That's it.'
Now, ladies and gentlemen, we are ready
for our next bronc rider.
It's a new face to you folks.
It's Kelly Cobb.
'He's having a little bit of trouble'
'but he'll be out in a minute
and here he comes.'
'And it's Kelly Cobb.'
Play with him, Kelly.
Hook a head.
- Ride 'em.
- There it is.
- Ya-a-ay.
- 'It's a money ride.'
'For sure,
ladies and gentlemen.'
'Next up is Franky Crawford.'
'Franky is a pretty good boy.'
'Oh, man, oh, man,
that was a real spill.'
Too bad, ladies and gentlemen,
we've got a little
bull docking coming up.
This is the one of the dangerous
events in rodeo
which the cowboy attempts to fist down
a fast running steer after diving
from the back of his horse.
'These steers
can really break.'
'They can break faster than a turkey'
'on a day before Thanksgiving.'
'And Kelly Cobb
isn't pulling one bit.'
'He really nailed that steer
right out of the chute'
'and he's twisting him down.'
'Man, is that Kelly Cobb
like greased lightning.'
'Looks like he's the one
to beat here today.'
'My, my, that doggy there
looks like he ran smack'
'into a butcher's convention.'
'The next dogger out
is Franky Crawford.'
'Got some calf ropin'
coming up next, folks.'
From here it looks like
Ben Preston, the next roper.
Here he comes after those veal chops.
'Oops, Ben's having a little
trouble bring home the bacon.'
'Well, it wasn't
that effective, Frank.'
'Hey, Maestro.
How 'bout a little waltz music"
'Here comes Slim Turner, folks.'
'Slim works in Jenkins' grocery
store here in Little River.'
'He's got a hankerin'
to be a big rodeo star.'
Oops, then, well
keep practicin', boy, keep practicin'.
'Well, that Kelly Cobb's
back again.'
'And folks, if he keeps on goi"
the way he has been today'
'he'll really be totin' home a
sack full of that green stuff.'
'He's got a pair of gats
ropes around the calf's neck.'
'He's down on him now.
He's got him down.'
'He's making his wraps
and tie off.'
'There it is. It's time.'
'And it looks like fast time
in anybody's league.'
And a time of ten-one,
ladies and gentlemen.
Very good time in anyone's league.
'And a hard time
to beat here today.'
'Yes, sir, sure looks like that
man's up to play for keeps.'
'He's got the money
in his pocket right now.'
'And now, ladies and gentlemen,
for the big event'
'of today's rodeo.
It's the Roman riding race'
'Standing race.
Four teams in the race.'
'Eight horses.
The boys are warming up now.'
'Going on down around.'
'They are really going
to give you a big thrill.'
'You want to watch this close.'
'It's the most
difficult thing to do.'
'This is a short closed arena.'
'The boys will be standing one foot'
'on the back of each horse.'
'Very hard, takes tremendous balance'
'and skill to do this job.'
'We've got four
of our men there.'
'We've got Sandy Lawson, Buck Hughes'
'Kelly Cobb and Red Mars.'
'They're about ready now, they're still'
'coming down through.
They're into a gallop now.'
'There's one up.'
'Watch closely, another boy up.
There's the third'
'and then there's the fourth.'
'And they're off.'
'It's the first turn,
it's Sandy Lawson in the lead.'
'Other boys are going wide.'
'Watch it now, there's
a bunch-up on the turn.'
'Watch closely now.
Lawson holding in there.'
'Buck Hughes pressing close
after him.'
'Lawson still going on down
through there.'
Come on.
'All the boys
had to pull wide then.'
'Speeding so fast.'
'It's Sandy Lawson in the lead.'
'Uh-oh, he was in the lead.'
'They're really flying now.'
'It's Buck Hughes,
in the lead now.'
'Watch it, Buck,
they're closing up on you.'
'Going down
the back stretch now.'
There's a bad spill, ladies and gentlemen.
'It's Buck Hughes, he's hung up.
Trying to get loose.'
Yes, he did. He got loose,
ladies and gentlemen.
Buck Hughes is free
and the race is going on.
'They're really moving now.'
'These boys are really
riding hard.'
'Here they come, coming up.'
- 'One lap to go.'
- Yeah!
Yeah, get outta there, Kelly.
Kelly Cobb, now coming in
and taking the lead.
'It's a very short lead.'
'Kelly Cobb is going to win it,
and he's coming down'
'to the wire and it is
Kelly Cobb.'
'Your winner!'
Big brother Spade.
He's gone and the money with him.
Yeah, that's right.
We've been taken.
It's Frontier Day, gentlemen.
And we just got pioneered.
Let's go look up the sheriff.
Good lookin' philly.
Whoa.
Well, here we go again.
Yeah, but in the opposite direction.
That fellow took the money.
He took it alright.
Took it and took all.
I say that we blow out of here
just as quietly and gently as we can.
Well, what's that got to do with us?
I'm the one that sweated out
there for nothing today.
Come on, get with it, Kelly boy.
The law just might get the unfriendly idea
we was in with that feller.
Ringers.
Honest, I swear, I thought
I just heard somebody shot..
Good looking piece of horse flesh.
I bet you got him trained real good.
Have a nice trip, Jafford.
I was just admiring the horse.
Darn it.
- Come on.
- Kelly!
♪ You travel in circles
and that's how it goes ♪
♪ The same dusty places ♪
♪ The same rodeos ♪
♪ Your pockets are empty ♪
♪ Your spirits are high ♪
When are they bringing short and rare?
♪ Or some other guy ♪
♪ There's racing and riding
and ropin' the calf ♪
♪ There's brahmas and broncos
to bust you in half ♪
♪ You get used to losin'
but beggin' your pardon ♪
♪ The bones don't like bruisin'
and the grounds of my parts ♪
♪ You ride for your dinner
you ride for your drink ♪
♪ There's steak for the winner
all juicy and pink ♪
♪ But lose and you find out
the best you can do ♪
♪ Is look for a hand-out
or settle for stew ♪
♪ You travel in circles
and that's how it goes ♪
♪ The same dusty places
the same rodeos ♪
♪ Your pockets are empty
your spirits are high ♪
♪ It's you for the money ♪
♪ Or some other guy ♪♪
- Thank you very much, Tex.
- Alright.
And now, friends, I have a treat for you.
We're gonna have a number by a little lady
who calls herself, Jackie Adams.
'Jackie and her friends
are rodeo performers'
on their way to Panamint.
Broke.
But never let it be said
that the Bill Oakie
ever turned anyone away from here hungry.
So little Jackie
is gonna sing a little song
for her supper.
What do you say we give
her a great big appetite?
How about "I Want Something
To Dream About Tonight"?
I'd love it.
♪ Before I go to sleep tonight ♪
♪ I want something
to dream about ♪
♪ Honey I'd like
to hold you tight ♪
♪ So I'll have something
to dream about ♪
♪ And that's not all
I'd like to do ♪
♪ I want something
to dream about ♪
♪ Honey I want to
kiss you too ♪
♪ So I'll have something
to dream about ♪
♪ I want ♪
♪ Something something ♪
♪ Something ♪
♪ I want ♪
♪ I want something
to dream about tonight ♪
♪ I'm sick and tired of counting
sheep from one to ninety two ♪
Who's thirsty?
Mr. Oakie says
to give you the works.
♪ The time has come
for us to part ♪
♪ I want something
to dream about ♪
♪ Tell me you're mine
with all your heart ♪
♪ So I'll have something
to dream about ♪
♪ I want ♪
♪ Something something ♪
♪ Yes I want ♪
♪ I want something
to dream about tonight ♪
♪ I'm sick and tired of counting
sheep from one to ninety-two ♪
♪ A little bit of love
will make me sleep ♪
♪ And dream
sweet dreams of you ♪
♪ The time has come
for us to part ♪
♪ I want something
to dream about ♪
♪ Tell me you're mine
with all your heart ♪
♪ So I'll have something
to dream about ♪
♪ I want ♪
♪ Something something ♪
♪ Something ♪
♪ I want ♪
♪ Something something
something ♪
♪ I want something
to dream about ♪
♪ Tonight ♪
♪ Yes I want something
to dream about tonight ♪
♪ Dream ♪♪
Thank you.
They liked you.
I like you, too.
Come on, let's talk.
Yeah, she's over 21.
Maybe she wants a career.
Look, I... my friends...
They'll wait.
- Really, I...
- You know, you're pretty good.
How would you like
to work here permanently?
- What do I have to do?
- Sing.
What else?
Now, child
you shouldn't be thinking things like that.
I shouldn't? Father?
'Kelly!
'Kelly!'
You better get the wagon ready.
Go on, get moving.
This is getting to be a habit.
That makes it twice
I had to say, "I'm sorry."
Now, the trouble is you don't
know your own strength.
For a little girl you pack
an awful lot of manpower.
For you too, Kelly?
I gotta check the wagon.
We've got plenty of
night driving to do yet.
Thanks. I'm not very hungry.
You can tell me to shut up
or stop thinking out loud.
But you got a fire burning for Kelly
almost as hot as this one?
'Kelly, he's not like
ordinary people.'
It takes a wild man to ride a wild horse.
He's no different when it comes to women.
I know... like a raising
from a coal.
Just when you think he might
get the peaceful notion
of going the route, it's..
Yeah, when Kelly unseats them,
they hit that ground
harder than any bronc can throw 'em.
And sometimes that kind of hurt
can last a long time.
'Alright, come on, gang,
let's go. We gotta be moving.'
♪ I've always been a lady
in front of company ♪
♪ But like the tree is shady
there's another side of me ♪
♪ I was born reckless
so why shouldn't I ♪
♪ Stay reckless
till the day I die? ♪
♪ I walk right under ladders
where others wouldn't dare ♪
♪ With me it doesn't matter ♪
♪ 'Cause I guess
I just don't care ♪
♪ I was born reckless ♪
♪ So why shouldn't I ♪
♪ Stay reckless
till the day I die? ♪
Papa, Papa.
Uncle Senor Kelly, he is coming.
'Mama, Uncle Senor Kelly,
he is coming.'
Grandfather, grandfather wake up.
'Uncle Senor Kelly,
he is coming.'
Ah, Kelly, come. Amigo!
- A partner, too, huh?
- That's a long story.
Mama, you get more beautiful
every time I see you.
And you are a beautiful liar, Kelly Cobb.
If I were only a little bit younger.
You did not bring the money?
- Dolores, oh!
- Welcome back, Senor Kelly.
Gee, I thought you were gettin'
a little heavier.
Congratulations, Jose.
What do you want this time?
Well, to tell you the truth, Senor Kelly
it's never what I start out wanting.
It's always what Dolores
tells me we're having.
Oh, Jose!
Mama, Papa, I want you to meet..
Oh, Senora Cobb.
Uh, Senorita.
- Oh, then you're not...
- No, we're not.
You are a very foolish boy.
- 'Jackie Adams.'
- How do you do?
Hello, Mama. Hello, Papa.
And this is Lola..
'...and Chiquita.'
'And Manuel.'
- And this is grandfather.
- Grandfather.
Grandfather, he believes in the siesta.
He says it's healthy
and restful for the body.
He takes one siesta a day.
All day long.
Now, can I go back to my siesta?
Come. You will want to wash
after your long ride.
Uh, Papa and me, we got some business
to chew over and then, uh
we'll head into Panamint and sign up.
Sure, sure.
You did not bring the money?
You did not send any money
for the last six months.
Ups and downs, Papa.
I got thrown in Malad City
and I hurt my arm, I couldn't rope.
Couldn't send you what I didn't win.
And before Malad city
when you called me to send you money
you've wrecked then maybe
a woman's heart, hey, amigo?
Ah, that was different.
Oh, no. It is no different.
It is money.
From Red Bluff, you sent me $300.
From Angel's Camp you borrowed back $200.
You win again at Santa Maria
and send more money.
You get into trouble at Pocatello
then you come to Reno.
Ah, Kelly Cobb.
I dreamed that some day
we are able to buy that land out there.
That you and I, we raise
a good-blooded cattle.
Horses, too, maybe.
Like the one you are riding.
But how are we gonna go this?
If you send, you borrow
you send, you borrow?
Hm, pretty soon you're gonna
borrow more than you send.
Then what?
We have nothing.
Um, Papa, I, uh..
- How much?
- Entry fees for tomorrow.
Ay, ay, ay, ay, ay..
Hey, that's it, Tom.
Calf ropin', bareback, bull doggin'
saddle broncs and brahmas.
Hey, going the whole
route, this time, eh, Kelly?
Yeah.
Tell me, what are you planning
to do between events?
- Pray.
- Well.
With some of the bulls we got
around here, ride
that might not be a bad idea.
- Good luck.
- Thank you.
- Number 30.
- See you in the arena.
'He's beautiful.'
What you got against living?
- So, it talks.
- He's a bad one.
'He's got spooks running loose in him'
'from his feet to his brain.'
What's it like to ride him?
To be on his back?
Like you stop living for 10 seconds.
Your head comes off, and you can't think.
Can't breathe.
You go blind until it's all over.
Do you still think he's beautiful?
I know somebody that is.
- What are you selling?
- Les Hunter.
What is that, a name or a new tranquilizer?
I'd hate to think of it
putting you to sleep.
Well, I doubt that.
What do you do?
Rope or... ride?
Rope a little.
In the spectator's manner of speaking.
I see.
Oh, no. No, you don't see.
I've got a winter home here.
My ex-husband was very generous.
So was I.
Well, one good turn deserves another.
This yours, too?
Mm-hm.
I'm having a little party before the rodeo.
Wanna drive me home?
I have to work for a living.
I'll let you.
Kelly!
You, uh, you go ahead
and take care of things.
'I'll see you both back
at the ranch later on.'
Alright, I know.
It takes a wild man to ride a wild horse.
♪ So he's late ♪
♪ But even if he's late ♪
♪ I'll wait ♪
♪ A little longer ♪
♪ Time is dear ♪
♪ But heavens when he's near ♪
♪ I'll wait ♪
♪ A little longer ♪
♪ Here am I ♪
♪ And over me
the sky is blue ♪
♪ The heart of me is too ♪
♪ Finding love as such ♪
♪ That those who want too much ♪
♪ Too soon ♪
♪ Discover love ♪
♪ Is not that way ♪
♪ No matter what they say ♪
♪ It takes ♪
♪ A little longer ♪
♪ When you care
for one who's unaware ♪
♪ It takes ♪
♪ A little longer ♪
♪ On and on ♪
♪ Till one day comes the dawn ♪
♪ It takes a little
longer than it seems ♪
♪ But wait ♪
♪ I will ♪
♪ I'll wait ♪
♪ Until ♪
♪ His arms fulfill ♪
♪ My dreams ♪
♪ When you care
for one who's unaware ♪
♪ It takes ♪
♪ A little longer ♪
♪ On and on till
one day comes the dawn ♪
♪ It takes a little
longer than it seems ♪
♪ But wait ♪
♪ I will ♪
♪ I'll wait ♪
♪ Until ♪
♪ His arms ♪
♪ Fulfill ♪
♪ My ♪
♪ Dreams ♪♪
Alright, kids, everybody go to bed.
You dream the same dream as Kelly, baby.
How do you dream dreams
with your eyes open, Papa?
Well, sometimes it is the best way.
You can see what you want in your dream.
I dream someday all this
belong to Kelly and I.
I save hard to put away my share.
And Kelly?
I know he wants it, too.
But sometimes his eyes are shut too tight.
Not the way he went off
with that little dream today.
His eyes weren't shut.
He will wake up.
You didn't see this dream, Papa.
Right out of a bedtime story.
But not for children.
I don't know, Papa.
With me I get whistles and propositions
from all the wrong characters.
From Kelly, all I get is protection.
What haven't I got
that low-down saddle red wants?
You wait.
Kelly will open his eyes and then...
Then it can be too late.
I don't want the man I marry
in this business.
I know I'm in it.
I'm not on the outside looking in
where all the Kelly's look glamorous.
I've seen too many of 'em
hit the dirt and lay there
and never get up.
- Not Kelly.
- Who says, Papa?
I want Kelly in one piece.
I want him to enjoy
the kind of life I can give him.
I don't want him living it in a wheelchair.
Kelly's indestructible.
One of the iron men.
Like Cool Man?
Maybe after tomorrow
and Kelly wins
maybe we'll come closer to our dreams.
Maybe, Papa.
Maybe.
'Good afternoon,
ladies and gentlemen.'
'It's a big day
here at Panamint.'
'As the Grand Entry Plate
starts off the first day'
'of our two-day rodeo'
'of what promises to be the biggest'
'most exciting rodeo
in the whole rodeo circuit.'
'With contestants
competing for prize stakes'
'that few other
rodeos can match.'
'You name any state in the union'
'and we've got a cowboy'
'representing that state
here today.'
'And they'll be riding the Brahmans'
the barebacks,
the saddle broncs.'
'They'll be doing calf roping
and bulldogging.'
Stop worrying, he'll be here.
Too much prize money for him not to show.
I'm not worried.
Peanuts, peanuts, popcorn.
Peanuts. Peanuts.
'We have assembled here today
some of the finest women riders'
'in the country,
ladies and gentlemen.'
And we present the first event
of the afternoon
Worlds Championship Tele-Pole Trick Riding
'in the women's division.'
- Wish me luck.
- Good luck.
Each Callahan tryin' to outride
these ladies'
'will be giving some
pretty good riding lessons.'
'Yes, siree, folks, these girls
don't take a back saddle'
'to no man.'
'And now, for the first girl
out here is Mara Haynes.'
'There goes little Joan Kirk,
ladies and gentlemen.'
'Little,
but what a big performer.'
'Look at the girl ride.'
'And here's Jackie Adams.'
'And when it comes to trick riding'
'That Jackie sure knows
all the tricks.'
'And now out there in the center
of the field comes Bell Vince.'
'Well, now, you just try that
on your hobby horse.'
'There goes Jackie Adams again,
folks.'
'And Jackie handles that horse
like it was a baby carriage.'
'Looks like this girl's gonna
wrap up all the high points.'
'How'd you like that,
ladies and gentlemen?'
'Wasn't that something?'
A trial riding on four feet,
a horn dynamite today, folks
and there you go.
'And now, friends, we're gonna have'
'the wild and woolly
Brahma bull.'
'Comin' out of the chutes now
is Bert Johnson.'
'Bert's got himself straddled
to Blind Fury and believe me'
'Blind Fury can't see Bert
for dust.'
Tonight, Kelly baby.
Only tonight Liz sees that you behaved.
That you're nice to Liz.
That's for not being nice to Liz.
Just remember.
'And next, comin' out of chute four'
'Chuck Appleton from Calgary.'
'Boy, look at that man go.'
'Well, comin' out of chute number 10'
'I see the last man
up on the Brahmas today'
'is Johnny Morgan
from Stockton, California.'
'Johnny tied the record
for calf ropin' last year.'
'Now, let's see if he can
outride this Brahma.'
That's one event
you can scratch for the day.
Maybe you're lucky at that.
'Folks, these bulls
must be fed on split atoms'
'the way they explode.'
'You just don't take
your life in your hands'
'when you ride these express
trains, you give it away.'
'Well, we've got another one of
those gentle four-legged beasts'
'mounted and ready to go.'
'Next to a Brahma these broncs
are pretty dangerous fellas.'
'They go north, south, east
or west all at the same time.'
Well, we got another one of
these gentle four-legged beasts
mounted and ready to go.
And he's gone.
'Oh-oh, he's got his foot
caught in his stirrup.'
'Good footwork there.'
'Next rider up is Kelly Cobb.'
'Looks like Kelly's ready now
and he's comin' out.'
'I guess Kelly forgot
to do one of his tricks'
'and can that soft ground
can be pretty hard.'
'Well, he's shaky, but we don't
hear any bones rattle.'
'Kelly's up now to try
his luck at calf roping.'
'Guess that rope
just wasn't long enough, huh?'
'Kelly lost.'
'One of the trickiest of all bronc riding'
'is the bareback event.'
'You really don't have too much to sit on'
'and it's a question as to
who can hold on the longest.'
'Well, I guess Kelly decided
to sit this one out.'
'Comin' up now, ladies and gentlemen'
'is a bulldoggin' event.'
'This requires perfect teamwork'
'careful skill and timing
on the part of the cowboy'
'who must stow the steer
to the ground.'
'And the utmost precision'
'and riding on the part
of his hazer.'
That sure got a big hunk of beef
dropped down on him.
'But while the boys are checking over Judd'
'next comin' out is Cool Man Edwardson'
'to saddle the hay
for Kelly Cobb.'
'Kelly seems to be
a little off his stride today.'
'But today isn't over yet.'
Maybe you'd better let that one pass
before you pass out.
You don't wanna haze for me,
just forget it.
Somebody's got to see
that you don't get killed.
'Here they are,
Cool Man and Kelly.'
You alright?
I'm sorry, I missed.
'That was a close one alright'
'but Cool Man is up,
and he's walking away from it.'
'No, sir, you can't keep an old
hound dog like Cool Man down.'
- We're quite a team, alright.
- So I blew today.
You got something to say, say it!
- I gotta be some place.
- Sure, you do.
But don't explain that to me,
explain it to Jackie.
Oh, so that's how it is.
No, it ain't how it is.
So, I'm a louse.
Now, can I go?
I got something important to take care of.
So have I.
You!
I beat my brains out for you.
I picked you up shoveling out stables.
I taught you everything I know.
I wanted you to be even better than I was.
Every time you come out of
a chute, I come out again, too.
Every time you went the ride on
the bull, I rode the limit, too.
Every time you got
your brains scrambled on a bronc
I got a headache.
It was worth it.
I wanted you to be great.
The only thing I couldn't
teach you was how to be human.
- I'll talk to you later.
- I'll talk to you now.
I've seen you fracture lots of hearts.
But every time I see you walkin'
over that kid, the way you have
wavin' that cheap saddle trash
in front of her eyes..
I'm sorry, partner.
Tonight, Kelly baby.
Only tonight Liz sees that you behaved.
That you're really nice to Liz.
That's for not being nice to Liz.
Just remember.
You wanna drink?
Maybe to forget.
Hmm, no, thanks, Papa.
That wouldn't help.
It help me forget.
Ooh, would I ever forget that rodeo today?
That Kelly! Whew!
Yeah, Kelly, you-you can say that again.
You know what he did?
He hit me.
That's what he did.
My friend!
And me, I taught him all he knows.
Every time he rides
I ride again, too.
Every time he wins, I win again, too.
Every time he gets thrown
and crawls in the dirt, I cry.
It's the same thing my friend Kelly does.
But you know what?
There's one thing I can't do through him.
Is make love and break hearts.
Or saddle up a cheap tramp.
Cool Man, where is he?
Where's Kelly now?
Probably out breakin'
all records calf ropin'. Heh.
You saved yourself a lot of tears.
- Just forget Kelly Cobb.
- Yeah, that's right.
Take it from an old man.
Forget.
And you tell me, can you forget him, Papa?
Can you forget your dream?
And you, Cool Man.
Can you forget Kelly? Forget all
the good things about him?
Do you want to?
Papa, let me have the keys
to your pick-up truck.
- Oh, they're in the truck.
- Uh, no, Papa.
Don't let her have 'em.
She can't drive.
- Why not?
- You're sober, that's why.
You don't know how sober.
Thanks, Papa.
My friend, Kelly.
He's a no-good..
...white-bellied, olive-branched
side-windin', snake-eyed baloney bull.
- That's what he is.
- Si.
And that's not all.
He's buzzard bait, that's what he is.
Hittin' me the way he did, my friend.
The dirty sage rat.
Si.
You know what I'm gonna do
the next time I see that vulture?
I'ma gonna wring his neck
so hard till he starts raspin'
like a turkey gobblin' it's spurs
the night before Thanksgiving.
Si. He-he.
And then I'm gonna spin him around
and whop his lump so hard
that it'll make riding a Brahma bull
seem like a hobby horse.
Si. Ha-ha-ha.
Look, I was tossing him down
pretty good last night.
I probably said a lot of things.
Then, I would like to know
if you meant them.
Liz, you're a big girl.
And you've got a big check book.
[chuckles I've got a big taste for life.
I'm trying to tell you, Liz,
I don't go with it.
You and me, we're riding
two different horses.
You talk too much.
Well! Company.
You could say that again, girl.
Out of my way, you!
Jackie, honey, wait a minute.
Let's get this straight.
Hey, what do you think you're doing?
Jackie, baby, I only came here
to say goodbye.
I'll bet you did.
Jackie, please, wait.
- Now look what you've done.
- I haven't started.
What are you gonna do?
Where have I been?
- You make me nervous.
- Do I now?
So, cool off!
Both of you!
Go away!
Now.
- Oh, no.
- Oh, yes.
Oh, no.
Oh, my head. What did
I drink that wine for?
Oh!
Ooh!
Coffee, Mama.
Good and hot.
You're gonna sober up and haze for me today
even if it kills ya.
To be dead would be
such a glorious feeling.
Bite your tongue for saying such a thing.
Oh, even that wouldn't feel better
if I had widen my head.
Drink it.
Where's Jackie?
Uh, she, she did not come back last night.
'So, where is she then?
What happened to her?'
Here, Kelly.
Now it is your turn.
'Well, here we go again,
ladies and gentlemen.'
'About to wind up the big
two-day meet here'
'at Panamint's Annual Rodeo.'
'And friends, this is the day
that some cowboy's'
'gonna walk away
with all the money.'
'And here we go now,
to the calf roping contest.'
'Hey, now. That's mighty
fancy roping and tying'
'in the greased lightning time
of, hold on to your seats'
'nine seconds flat.'
'And I'd say that's gonna be
the time to beat.'
'Hold on, partner.
Ride 'em up.'
'And here, yes, sir.'
'That was Tommy Parks, folks
and he whipped the lemon.'
'And from where I'm sitting,
it looks like Kelly Cobb'
'is back up in the saddle
for little Bronkey.'
Outside.
Ya!
'Man, he's really glued to that saddle
'like it was his own skin.'
'He rode that biggie
right into the ground.'
'Yup, Kelly's back
in pitching today, alright.'
'And there goes Rob Dotson out
on Flying Death.'
'Boy, you just don't sit down for dinner'
'after riding
one of those, fellows.'
'That steer has rolled over
on him. He might be hurt.'
'Nope. Jake's on his feet.'
'He's doggin' that steer
right into the dirt.'
'Good boy, Jake.'
You look like I felt yesterday.
Don't worry about me.
Well, I don't wanna have to
pick you up off the ground.
I can't take the time.
'Well, that's
Georgie Brooks takin' off.'
'And does he ever take off.
Hey, Georgie, where did he go?'
Let's go.
'Anyway, folks'
'if you think doggin' a steer'
'racin' at express train speed'
'is easy'
'just don't try.'
Keep your eye on Kelly Cobb, folks.
Number 30 out there today.
'There they go.'
'Kelly Cobb put that steer down
in the sensational time'
'of four and two-tenth seconds
and comin' out of'
'chute number nine'
'it's Long Whisker
aboard Savage Man.'
'Go do it, Long.'
That's the buzzard to beat.
I saw him steer a guy
with his horns for good
the day we checked in.
You call that spook, Kelly?
You don't know what a nice funeral you had.
Thanks.
'This looks like
a nonstop ride to nowhere.'
'And, man, does that bull
hate people.'
'Too bad, Don.
Try him again sometime.'
And now, out of chute number three
Kelly Cobb is gonna try out
a pair or two on Black Knight.
'This bull, friends,
holds the world's record'
'for throwin' every cowboy
that ever climbed aboard him.'
'He's a killer, folks,
but we got an old saying.'
'That there ain't never a bull
that can't be rode'
'or a cowboy
that can't be thrown.'
Let me know what happened.
Outside.
Ride him, Kelly, ride him!
'Kelly Cobb just did
the impossible, folks.'
'And rode that bull until
it's horns shook loose.'
Hi, Jackie.
You've come just in time.
Our Kelly, he's a new man today.
He's stymieing even the wildest
one into a little kitties.
He better.
Put another dime in the jukebox, Cool Man.
- That bull blows a wicked horn.
- That's no property here.
It's your brain saddlin' back in your head.
You went the limit.
- I did?
- Sure.
Where have you been all night?
Or-or should I ask such a question?
It's alright, Mama.
I stayed with a couple of girls
over at the trailer camp.
Kelly, he worries very bad.
Before I'm through, he'll worry a lot more.
That is good.
♪ You lovable lovable
lovable lovable you ♪
♪ You lovable you ♪
♪ You kissable you ♪
♪ You lovable kissable
lovable dreamable ♪
♪ Dream may come true ♪
♪ You're sweeter than candy ♪
♪ Sugary fine ♪
♪ You huggable kissable
lovable ♪
♪ Will you be mine? ♪
♪ You lovable you ♪
♪ You kissable you ♪
♪ You simply adorable
truly unboreable ♪
♪ Lovable you ♪
♪ Your kisses are dandy ♪
♪ Honest and true ♪
♪ You lovable kissable
lovable kissable you ♪
♪ I ran out of words
describing you ♪
♪ Just when I had lots to say ♪
♪ I sure had
a sweet time bribing you ♪
♪ Sugar and honey to use
at the wedding day ♪
♪ You lovable you ♪
♪ You kissable you ♪
♪ You huggable kissable
lovable dreamable ♪
♪ Dream may come true ♪
♪ Your kisses are candy ♪
♪ Honest and true ♪
♪ You lovable kissable
lovable kissable you ♪
♪ I ran out of words
describing you ♪
♪ Just when I had lots to say ♪
♪ I sure had
a sweet time bribing you ♪
♪ Sugar and honey to use
at the wedding day ♪
♪ You lovable you ♪
♪ You kissable you ♪
♪ You huggable kissable
lovable dreamable ♪
♪ Dream may come true ♪
♪ Your kisses are candy ♪
♪ Honest and true ♪
♪ You lovable kissable
lovable kissable you ♪
lovable kissable you ♪♪
Howdy?
You're the finest looking gal here.
How about a dance?
Why not?
Our little Jackie is growin' up fast.
Yeah.
Come on, gang.
The drinks are on me.
Set 'em up.
How about a drink for poor
dry-little-old me, Champ?
Sure, I'll buy a poor
dry-little-old you a drink.
Champ, you had me squeeze my
heart out for you this afternoon
until it hurt.
It hurt bad.
Looks like her luck might run out
if she gets a live one she can't handle.
Yeah, I tried seeing her after the rodeo.
She wouldn't listen to me say I was sorry.
She kissed me off without a word.
Well, why cry on your beer?
- Kiss off on the rocks.
- Anytime you say, champ.
Maybe she's just trying
to make you over-anxious.
Thanks, father.
Let's grab a table.
Ah, let's drink up.
Now, you got yourself quite a gait.
How would you like to
meander over to my place?
See my new saddle.
That saddle is already broken in.
I'm sure it is.
Excuse me.
Marky, baby.
Oh, no.
Marky, honey.
I'm sorry about what happened.
Really I am.
Sure I know you couldn't be sorrier.
You did say I have more talent
than you thought?
Sure, but that was last week.
Maybe I've got even more talent this week.
Where you going to ride next, champ?
I might just be there.
- Who said we were leaving?
- Kelly, baby.
You read a girl's mind.
You readin' Mark Wilson's mind too?
Settle back.
It's too late this time.
You said you could make me
the hottest rodeo queen
in the circuit.
But you said that was only
the second thing I had in mind.
Maybe I forgot how to... count.
♪ Separate the men
from the boys ♪
♪ Is a job no woman enjoys ♪
♪ She has to take her chances ♪
♪ From the start ♪
♪ And hope she's got a man
and not a boy at heart ♪
♪ Uncertainty
will string her along ♪
♪ Uncertain if she's
right or wrong ♪
♪ To get you to the altar
is the only way ♪
♪ And hope he doesn't falter
on the wedding day ♪
♪ 'Cause nine times out of ten ♪
♪ It's then and only then ♪
♪ You can separate
the men from the boys ♪
♪ To separate
♪ Is a job no woman enjoys ♪
♪ She has to put her foot down ♪
♪ Lay it along ♪
♪ Get off the dime
don't give him time ♪
♪ To him and her ♪
♪ As once he's with
his back to the wall ♪
♪ He'll do his very best ♪
♪ To stall ♪
♪ Yes every man like Custer
makes his final stand ♪
♪ She's got to make him
muster up the wedding band ♪
♪ I'll say it once again ♪
♪ It's then and only then ♪
♪ You can separate
the men from the boys ♪
♪ And always
there's a matter of doubt ♪
♪ No matter
how it all works out ♪
♪ A ring upon her finger ♪
♪ Doesn't mean he'll yield ♪
♪ And every doubt will linger ♪
♪ Till it's signed and sealed ♪
♪ 'Cause nine times out of ten ♪
♪ It's then only then ♪
♪ You can separate
the men from the boys ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ Eliminate the boys
from the men ♪
♪ Separate the men ♪
♪ From the ♪
♪ Boys ♪♪
Tell me, baby. How big
do you want your name in print?
Now, Marky.
Slow down, easy.
Let's not get carried away.
'Let me go.'
'Kelly.'
Well, finally.
You better get the wagon warmed up.
'Kelly.'
- Excuse me.
- But Kelly..
That was a rough one.
When do I ever stop saying I'm sorry.
Pretty quick.
Just as soon as we're married.
'Ole.'
I-I only want to be like you,
Uncle Senor Kelly.
To ride the bull, rope the calf.
Just like you, Uncle Senor Kelly.
Alright. Out you get and off
to bed you go.
- See you, Uncle Senor Kelly.
- Manuel, wait a minute.
Give this to Papa in the morning.
It's for him from us.
Tell him we'll be back.
Tell him that...
Manuel, tell Papa he can dream
his dream for real now.
All our eyes are open.
I'll tell Papa.
And when we do come back, Manuel
we won't be roping calves,
taming broncs, riding bulls
or dogging steers.
We're gonna grow 'em right here.
He's right, Manuel. And we'll
need you and your help.
Si.