25.000
Ripped from DVD.
Excuse me a moment.
When I get myself together,
I'll come with an answer.
Yo, respect,
this is a public service announcement
brought to you
by The Great Singin' Cactus.
If you are affended by words such as
bitch, ass,
dirty slut or even fuck, motherfucker,
tits, pussy,
then you should get your goddam fucking
asses out of here right now.
This ain't going to be a nice movie.
You know,
some people believe
there is an absence of some artistic
creativity of something,
but you know what?
We do not give a fuck,
we like saying shit like this,
just to piss you off...
And now, shut the fuck up and put
the goddam fucking movie on...
I sad, shut the fuck up and put
Are you waiting for christmas or what?
This is goddam wonderful.
I guess we're waiting for christmas.
You know, I got better things to do
than this.
Isn't it weird, how it all happens?
Columbo.
Boys and girls.
Do you know...
...what the internet is?
Well, you could read
some interesting news.
Or you could listen to
a nice song.
But - no no no no no.
No.
The Internet, come closer...
The Internet...
...is about sex,
an infinite electronic complex
full of...
of unexpected turns.
Of course the other things
are also there,
pages of cars and gladiators,
neverending
but there's a way outta there
by a magic click
to another page
and there,
there are those naked chics,
those chics' moms,
or children,
a man shagging a dog or a pig.
Women,
and this is the worst of all,
playing with a horse's dick,
right there.
Well kids...
- Welcome to the internet.
- It's serious you fuckers.
You'll get addicted in no time.
Are you gonna roll
that joint forever?
Why are we drinking vodka,
for christ's sakes?
Why don't we have a pint down
at the pub? Are we in Siberia?
Globalization, man.
Shit.
Hello,
could you help me, please?
- Of course.
- I'm looking for doctor Bates,
the plastic surgeon.
The surgeon?
Plastic surgeon Bates?
Sorry. Down this hallway,
that door over there.
- The last one, right?
- At the very end.
- Thank's.
- You're welcome.
Wanna have a shower?
Man, have you ever wanked
to your class picture?
Not since last Friday.
"Have you seen, Friday 13th?"
Yeah, but my grandad walked in.
The best was Monika, man,
those perky tits,
those nipples...
Jesus and that Jana.
Man o man.
Kiss my ass you wankers.
- Hi.
You know Batman...
...the action hero.
Well we have a lot in common
him and I.
All action, magical,
but pretty lonely right now.
Want me to bring you
a hot dog and soda?
- No thanks.
- Come on.
No, really.
- Here you go.
- Hey!
Great.
You wouldn't believe this freak.
Where?
Him, there!
- Him?
- Some kinda pervert isn't he?
Yeah I guess he is.
It was damn good
the other day, man.
Not sure, but what's the name
of that fucking guy
who buys Bravo,
and jerks off three times
a fuckin' day
fuckin'anywhere man and...
If you didn't have your
sleeping-bag-chic,
you would too.
That was long ago.
Better than robbing banks
in fucking America.
This is a totally
different country.
- I love you, Honey Bunny.
- I love you, Pumpkin.
- You look great today.
- Thanks, good to see you,
I thought you forgot
all about me.
If I knew you were back
from England, I would've called.
You're so nice,
even in England it's rare,
most guys just want to jump
into bed with us.
And that's in the best case.
I'm so happy
we're together again, Petr.
Me too.
I got an idea.
Why don't we get a bottle
of wine and jump in bed?
You're such a pig.
This is a robbery, if any of you
fucking pricks move,
I'll execute every motherfucking
last one of ya'!
An unknown killer knick-named
Bleeding Kaleb
accused of 17 murders,
and two assassinations
of public servants,
he's assumed to be responsible
for another 21 unsolved murders,
the offender usually wears
a black leather coat.
It'll be luscious rose-petal,
straight from the thighs
of little Mulattos.
In skimpy little thongs.
The smell of that half-black
skin does it to me every time.
Shut up and roll.
Guys,
it's the fruit of the gods,
no shit.
T R A S H
Starring
Executive producer
Project manager
Edited by
Sound designer
Director of Photography
Written and directed by
Fuckin' hell. Jason's here...
sportin' a machete.
Horny silicon blond
with a case of beer.
I'm gonna open the door,
for both of 'em.
Look... Cactus.
Oh fuck, it is.
Hello, guys.
Don't get up, please.
I just came to borrow some milk,
going to make pudding.
Wanna drag?
- Strawberry.
- Wanna?
No, no, I'm on my way.
I might be back later.
Thank you, Honza.
Strawberry pudding.
Such a nice boy, thank you.
Shut the fuck up you wankers
and watch the table,
my folks got it as a present
from some friend from Africa
along with that little fucker.
One scratch and they'll have
my balls for book-ends.
I thought it was a Pokemon toy.
I wish you had the same.
Unbelievable,
I couldn't walk for two days.
Reminds me of that guy
I picked up at the disco.
Not much upstairs but
great in bed and he looked
exactly like Rickie.
How 'bout you, Adela?
I quite like Karel.
Leave her alone, you know
they get it on once in a while
and then once a year
she has an orgasm.
Yeah her own little Superhero.
Mr. Great,
the infallible Batman.
Up in the crow's nest
Two young sailors
Smoking havanas
Swinging their legs
The danger won't
Make them cry
While they stare off
Into the sea
I got an idea,
how about we invite
a bit of pussy over.
No hookers in this house, man.
Let's just chill, smoke a joint
and see what happens.
I'd give this one a chance.
These days it's totally common.
You've got a girlfriend,
don't you?
- Where's your morals?
- Don't get your shit in a knot.
A whore is a whore,
you pay you fuck, get it?
No strings attached my love.
What sweethearts!
Relax.
If you feel bad about it,
just get a blow job.
It's like wanking
with your left hand.
If it sucks,
we'll kick her out or kill her.
Once you have this place
to yourself...
Stab her to death.
You fuckers are corrupting me.
That reminds me of how Karel
picked up Adela by accident.
What do you mean, by accident?
He was hitting on Jana here,
but then he was so drunk he
crawled into your sleeping bag.
Must've been a shock.
Wait... didn't you know?
Shake off your crabs,
she's here in half hour.
He really thought
it was me under him.
But the point is, the whole time
he thought he was doing it with me.
But, don't worry about it,
Adela.
You are disgusting.
You're so lame, how can you
be so dumb and bitchy?
Fuck, here she is.
Are you gonna open the door
or what, you prick?
Gentlemen, Ms Nicol.
Cool place,
have your parents left?
No, well,
I live here by myself,
my grandad got hit by a bus last
year. It was all quite ugly.
So what's the plan, boys?
A little strip-tease or do you
just wanna watch me get off?
A wank is cheaper,
so is a blow job.
I'll do it without a condom.
Fuck you,
you fucking low-life
I'm outta here.
Please excuse him.
He's just a bit nervous,
you know?
Turns me on,
I love nervous boys.
Do you have...
Nice. Now, how about money?
I guess we can
trust each other.
So?
Maybe a little strip-tease?
Just to warm up, right?
To relax...
OK, as you please.
- I'll be right back.
- Sure.
God, I thank you
for making me a man.
On Sunday I'll go to church and
pray, I swear.
Fuck, I'm hungry.
There's nothing in the fridge.
- Roll one up.
- Let's order some pizza you wankers.
Something with olives.
Yeah, 1492 Elm Street.
That happens all the time.
- How much?
- Five hundred.
- You mean including delivery?
- No, we have to run out to the airport.
Yeah as if.
Shall we?
Don't stand there, young man,
you'll get sick
and who'll pay then? Who?
Not me!
Good evening, gentlemen,
here you are.
There'd better be olives on it.
But of course,
they're included in the price.
What a mess. Having a party?
A birthday party?
Who's birthday is it?
Well, happy birthday,
I know a song.
Well, what kind of party is it?
I might join in,
maybe have a drink?
Well, let's talk business...
What, 901,50?
- Who said five hundred?
- That's what they told me.
Please let me explain.
- That's my job, isn't it?
- Go on.
Five hundred until 9 p.m.,
and you called before 9.
But your order
got registered at 9:01,
that means a higher rate
and an additional charge,
which is normal
in respectable companies
with a wide range of costumers.
Bla, bla, bla, bullshit,
Crusty the Clown! Little shit!
Little git!
Don't blame me, gentlemen,
I'm just a little Pizza man
in our complex.
By the way the best pizza
complex on this planet.
You won't be much longer.
There's not much left, fuck.
- I told you.
- Well, that's our pizza joint.
- What pizza joint?
- Our pizza joint,
the best in the town.
- What do you mean?
- They make pizza there.
- No, it means you're
the most expensive vehicle
in this fucking world.
But not much longer,
'cause I'm gonna shove
that pizza up your ass.
Fuck, that stupid cow.
You've smoked your brains out.
She's frigid as a fish,
I might as well screw Adela.
- What?
- Nothing, that's what.
She's lying there, right,
so I thought
she's tired after you,
she wants to play,
wanted to help her,
got all naked and...
- You're sleeping with one woman?
- Shut the fuck up.
She's numb, so I wanted
to turn her on,
warm her up and nothing.
For all that money...
You are paying her?
It's a prostitute.
- Do you know that...
- Shut up, fuck you, fuck them
and fuck her,
I'm gonna kick her out.
Well, what a party.
Well, it looks like trouble,
my friends.
Check her pulse, surely,
the pulse is the main thing.
- Go fuck yourself.
Oh no, I've got time.
That bitch, it's borax.
I'm not even breathing
not to mess up that table,
and look at her.
She's dead, man.
She's fucking dead, man.
For fuck's sake, man,
shit I shagged a corpse.
I'm a necrophiliac,
don't even know what it means.
I should've watched Rambo...
Fuck it, man,
no one's gonna know.
What d'ya mean no one?
- I know.
- Keep it to yourself.
Adela's gonna find out
and when we're in bed,
she's gonna say
"Man what's that smell?"
"You shagged a corpse?"
"No honey, I love you."
Fuck.
How about a little help?
I need a new bike
for deliveries or...
Scooter, small one's fine.
How about a punch in the face?
Out of all the fucking beds
in the world,
she has to die in this one.
Should we talk money
or shall I call the cops?
Back off you son of a bitch.
I know some people there,
just to...
Careful, you fuck.
Better get used to it, fucker.
What about this whore?
Let him rot in there,
that little fuck.
The one in the bedroom.
Chop her up and bury her
in the garden?
- We ain't got a garden.
That sucks.
Are ya' kidding?
Fuck me.
Hi, looking for someone?
Sure, I'm lggy,
is my friend still here?
He was, but we paid him
and he's gone.
I mean Nicol, you asshole.
- He's the fucking Cleaner!
- Don't let him in.
Shut up!
You're her boyfriend?
No,
I'm a bouncer and a problem solver,
first let me check this place
out, to make sure there's no cameras
or nothin' and I'm outta here.
- Wassup?
- Come in.
All right.
I know who you are.
Fuck off.
It's Nicol's bouncer.
What d'ya mean, bouncer?
You're Honza, right?
So, to start with,
I'd like a pull on that.
I got a cool job.
So one time I came for Nicol
to one of her tricks
and some painted up weirdo
motherfucker opened the door.
He wouldn't let me in,
kept saying it'll be O.K.
That I can go and have a cigarette.
I didn't trust him.
My dad used to say:
"Never trust friends and
dudes with big cocks."
So I walked in and the place
looked like a fucking dungeon...
Nicol's chained to a table
all covered in rooster's blood
and those mofos jerking off
howling fot Satan.
That one prick
was dressed up like a goat
Cool,
hooves, stuck it down his throat
and then threw him
out some window.
I think you ought
to know something.
Look, this fuckin' sucks,
just tell me where she is.
- Well, something happened.
- Wasn't our fault.
It's like running over snails.
Stop talking shit,
are you on drugs?
Jesus, that's Pizza man!
Man, you know
Nicol's on some shit?
Shit?
What d'ya mean?
Oh, that. Once she took it
and ended up
with those Witnesses...
You mean Jehova's.
Yeah, that's the fucker's name.
He must've been loaded 'cause
people never talk shit about him.
She wore fucking white, talking
God all the fucking time.
Jehova is God's name, man.
I was named after dude from TV,
quite a cool movie,
about mommy who wants
to drown her little boy
and a big mofo croc jumps out
and bites her black head
clean off.
Fuck me.
It was on Mississippi,
Mississippi...
a cruel river...
Damn cruel river.
Well, where's my girl?
Fuck, she's dead.
What happened?
She could manage a whole army,
now I'll have to find another.
- Called the cops yet?
- Not yet.
Cool,
'cause I'd kick your heads in.
Well, we'll leave her
'till tomorrow...
- You mean overnight?
She won't fucking bite.
I'll be back.
Bring gallons of acid, right?
Sure man, the fucking juice,
right, you're a genius?
Now we're fucked.
- Hi.
I saw you walking up.
Great, I didn't.
I was actually peeking,
you couldn't have...
Usually I peek at my door.
Exactly, that's what I meant.
We've got lots in common,
don't you think?
I'm lonely,
so alone in this cruel world.
Shall we put her
in the freezer?
So she won't blow up,
like corpses do.
If that fucker dies,
folks're gonna kill me.
Fuck it,
we'll just get another.
Where? In a supermarket?
From the Chinky market, man,
they have everything.
Let's cover her up...
saw it in a film once, some shit
about respect for the dead.
You do it so you don't have
to look at them.
I knew it'd come handy one day.
Let's have a fucking shot.
Fabio, bro, how's business?
Get fucked, lggy, come on in.
Hey lggy, you look tired.
Any chic problems?
It's just all going wrong,
y'know?
Talking of which,
you owe me some dosh.
Your whores ain't putting out?
They do.
Stop chewing
when you talk to me.
Don't get smart,
whores are the best business,
other than fucking weapons,
of course.
Fabio, I'm in deep shit.
Iggy, you're pissing me off,
no money,
so fuck you.
- Come on, man.
- Fuck you and your problems.
Some guys had a party with Nicol,
she overdosed and woke up dead.
That's none of my business,
man, none of yours either.
- As long as you got your money.
- Well...
You didn't get it?
Who d'ya think we are,
some kinda jokers?
You're gonna bring me that money
tomorrow, as good friends do.
But dad...
Don't you call me Dad at work.
Family!
Gonna be OK, bro,
just get the money,
and have some fun, man.
Stick with us, bro, I tell ya.
Hello.
Shit.
- Wake up, Honza.
- What's the time?
- Dude, it's your grandpa.
- Well, it is...
But he's alive.
Pa, for God's sake, what's up?
Don't swear, boy,
you know I don't like it.
Did you sleep all right?
All right.
That's right.
Good, I wanted to wake you up,
not to miss lunch.
It's no good when it's cold.
Well, introduce us.
Hello, I'm Honza's grandpa.
You're our Honza's girlfriend?
I'm Karel.
Honza's not exactly my type.
Sorry, it's the long hair.
Karel...
The one who takes morph,
morphium?
You should quit,
it's bad for you.
In my times, it was in, too.
We've never been too nosey, but
I hope you're not doing this.
Of course I'm not.
I am Honza's grandpa.
I know, from his dad's side,
I'm Petr.
Hello.
Yes, let's sit down and eat.
Nothing's worse than cold lunch.
Maybe a cold woman.
The young lady won't join us?
Pa, I told you it's Karel.
I mean the one in the bedroom.
Pa, you've seen Nicol?
She's Hungarian?
Good choice, boy, passionate.
Bring her in, be polite.
She's invited, or else
I'll have to tell your parents.
- I promise I won't hit on her.
- Pa...
You two keep talking,
we'll get her.
Good idea.
I don't think so, she gets
grumpy when you wake her up.
It's cool, Honza. Right, man?
Sure.
I'd bet she stinks a bit.
I don't think so.
She hasn't been here long, has she?
No,
but it's that sweet smell, like
in a crematorium, you know?
Grandpa won't smell it.
He's deaf and blind.
I wouldn't take this, y'know,
I mean senses,
one gets worse, another
gets better, know what I mean?
Let's hope it's his touch.
Man, she's gonna be fucking
awful, dunno but...
Hello, I'm Honza's grandpa.
Sorry to wake you up,
but hot lunch will do you good.
Granny made the best gravy,
but she left me
for an older man,
with a younger car...
It might've been
those Fridays of mine...
Close your eyes...
I'm leaving...
Good for you!
Well, I'll have to go,
have a date with an ex-baroness.
She wants opera,
maybe a bottle of wine
will change her mind.
Pa, you're late,
she's waiting. Come on...
Thanks for lunch, 't was great.
Get rat poison,
- I saw some in the cupboard.
- All right
They're spreading diseases.
Both doctors,
and such a filthy place.
But that girl, boy,
she's beautiful.
Good bye, Pa.
Maybe I could invite her
for a drink?
Bye, Pa.
Bye.
Bye and say hello
to your parents.
Grandpa's cool, man.
Glad you're having fun,
you fucks.
It's lggy. Sorry I didn't call
earlier, family stuff.
One forgets.
Were am I?
You wouldn't believe it,
but back to business,
you fucked up,
you have to deal with it.
Fuck it, I'm out.
Man, they're having lunch there,
grandpa thinks she's my girl,
and I'm supposed to be cool.
But she's your whore.
True, but I ain't gonna lose
business for one fucking whore.
I got a good idea,
let's call the cops.
Call the cops and they'll be
scraping you off the walls.
Don't forget
I know where you live.
I'll be back for the money.
Look, Jackie Chan.
Yes, it's him.
That sonofabitch
left us in the shit.
Well, he won't get anything.
Too bad there's no fireplace.
Or a chipper.
Let's put her in the hallway
and call the cops,
and say we found her there.
No fucking way.
They'd know she overdosed,
and that we all shagged her.
They'll know, dude,
'cause of fucking genetics.
Don't tell me
she only shagged just us.
Maybe even Batman.
Her biggest catch was Karel.
There's gotta be a way
to get rid of a damn corpse.
Everybody does it.
We could bury her under the
rose bush, if you had a house.
- Like in the D.I. Y show.
- Everybody knows now, right?
What?
That that guy Jim
buries corpses?
Just take her far away
where no one will
fucking find her.
No one's gonna care,
if they did, that hippie
wouldn't have found her here.
What if she's some
Ukrainian student
and now the mafia's after us?
Yeah, the whole mafia's
studying here
to become lawyers, you asshole.
I got an idea.
Be cool, man,
just chill back.
I don't give a fuck,
I can walk all day.
He's the one with a dead whore
in bedroom, not me.
Fuck that, man, shit,
I'm just looking for a car.
Pardon me, I didn't know.
I got my connection here,
this little dude.
When Skywalker's in trouble,
he'll help,
always wherever he's needed.
- Where d'ya wanna take her to?
Where?
- Where? To the Singing Cactus.
- Fuck that.
Hey, Tony.
Hey, Carlito, how's things?
Cool car.
- Good deal, interested?
- How much?
Eight grand.
You little shit,
two's enough and you know it.
I've got family, Carlito,
mom's sick, sister's pregnant,
kids want to study.
Bullshit, you fuck,
your mom's a whore in Vegas,
your sister is now a brother,
and there's no kids.
Two grand, gentlemen.
Honza...
- Why me again?
- Who else?
Fucking losers.
Keys're in there,
have fun, Carlito.
You too, dude.
Here.
Who the fuck is this?
What d'ya want? Phone number?
Better throw it away.
Nothing's here.
Just go.
Mom...
- What?
- Sir, those boys stole your car.
Could've told me,
I was right there.
Didn't want to disturb you,
thought you were workin'.
Did you do it?
I wanted to stop them
but couldn't.
Next time I might
not take you with me.
Is that some kind of responsibility?
Got something, it might help.
Nothing's for free, though.
I stole it.
One day you'll be something,
at least like me.
Keep trying, nothing's for free.
When do we start? I wanna be
an assassin, just like you.
There's still time.
- Put her in the trunk.
- What?
In the trunk, man.
How, trunk?
For fuck's sake,
can't put her in there,
it's a dead whore,
first cop that looks in,
this isn't fucking Italy.
Don't fucking care where she is,
as long as it's not in mom's bed.
All right then,
put her in here.
Great, let's go...
Fuck.
Fucking awesome...
Iook at those cars.
- Fuck the cars.
So cool, man,
cars moving up and down,
left and right
Yeah, great.
Fuck you.
Shut up and drive.
Karel.
Hear me?
Sure, I might've known.
Who's that whore?
It's her time
of the month again?
Watch out, if you don't
open up, you're in deep shit.
And so are
those fucking assholes.
Start the car, man,
fucking get moving.
Adela, my sweetheart,
wanna ride?
Somewhere...
- What's wrong with'er?
- She's just dead.
We found her like that.
Petr...
Fucking pals, right?
Nice.
Shall I make up my own story?
What if you killed her,
then raped her?
Wouldn't be surprised.
- Are you gonna tell'er?
- What?
You're going to, anyway.
Know what? Fuck that shit.
Calm down, I'm coming.
- Hello.
- Good afternoon.
May I help you?
Are you the land lady?
I own this place.
I also work here,
just to save money.
It's hard to find
a decent person, nowadays...
Do the Bates live here?
Something happened?
You've got a problem.
Me?
Dammit!
Screw this.
What now, Adela?
I'm soaking wet...
Sorry, man.
- Just throw her out.
- Shall I throw'er out?
Look at me.
Fuck off.
Screw you.
Shall I - throw'er out?
Get in and we will go.
So three days, you fucker!
Covered in piss.
Quite a nice place,
do you think they steal,
or even kill?
Who knows,
better stick
to the "NTA" rule.
"NTA" rule?
What's that?
Never Trust Anyone.
NTA, easy.
You little adventurer.
I get so lonely,
if you only knew how sad it is.
Dear wedding guests.
I'm here for my dosh...
you got it?
You're not one of those asses,
are ya?
- Where did they go?
- Don't ask me, I just got here.
You might know better.
Are you waiting here
for'em or what?
Maybe.
So you think you're tough?
The biggest, right?
Hate Italian.
- Got a car?
- You bet.
Sir, why have you
shot my horse?
No it's the two of us, pal,
just like the TV heroes.
You watch TV, don't ya?
Dog and cat.
Is there anything after you die?
Like what?
Don't know...
...like Heaven or Hell.
Fuck no, it's all made up
to scare the shit out of us.
We're still in Matrix.
Once, the fucking Jehovas
came talking about heaven,
where all live
with peace and love.
You mean men and women?
Don't know, they gave me brochures.
I never read'em.
Might be quite cool.
Fuck them,
bunch of stoned hippies.
You've seen "Hair", haven't ya?
- World's a great place, anyway.
- Well...
Dude, turn it off,
let's be fucking enviromental.
It's been a while
since last time, man.
Hope that big-titted
grifter's still here.
I really need to go.
Where?
If only for this day,
life's worth living...
If only for this day...
We'll be there in no time.
No jo, no.
She could come topless, eh?
Fuck me.
Hello, three tequilas, please.
Ok, tres tequilas.
Hombre.
Por favor.
Folklore, man...
- Hey, Meesus, you all alone?
Come along.
We're bigger fish
than those guys, senorita,
and we smell better.
Do ya wanna get
your hooks in us?
Dudes, fuck that. She's done,
I don't think
she'd like to play.
She says she's bored of you.
She's coming with us
and you little farts, you're
getting smacked in the head.
Fuck it.
What? Did you shit your pants?
I kill you with my eyes closed.
Try me.
I'm gonna blow
your fucking guts out,
until you bleed to death.
Man you wanna try my girl, man,
fucking now, man?
Why me?
It sucks to have lame friends.
We could've played
as normal freaks do!
Chickenshits!
Cool, man,
I almost fucking believed you.
Let's get outta here.
This isn't all that cool,
'cause if so,
then who's on first base?
- Fucking cool, eh?
- Shit yeah.
You perverted psycho,
for fuck's sake, gimme the gun.
Stop pointing it at me.
It was cool, man.
You think you live
in a gangsta film,
fucking tough Macho Massimo,
Desperado.
I guess you'd like to kill
and then shag the whole city.
Chill, man, it fuckin' worked.
Now you take his fucking side.
If this dork had a machine gun,
he'd shoot anything that moves.
Where's that bitch?
You're late.
I had to take care
of some old business.
What d'ya mean?
- Don't worry, now we're even.
Stop fucking depressing me, man,
and roll up a joint or what?
Shut up and drive,
for christ's sake.
Hit the road, baby, anyways,
you ain't never gonna forget me.
Not much of a talker, are ya?
It's not my fault
you haven't seen it.
I have a tape,
if you're interested.
Ren and Stimpy.
Cool guys.
Once, Ren had a big long booger.
Stimpy thinks
its a cucumber salad,
What will he do?
Eats it and Stimpy's brain
just falls out of his nostrils.
Weird smell,
it's those fucking cows.
Not much of a talker, are ya?
Why you after them, bro?
Wanna tell me?
I'm no bro of yours.
Sorry, man just call ourselves
blood brothers then.
So yer a tough guy, right? Like
Clint Eastwood and those guys.
They owe you, I owe them.
Life's fucked up.
Cool, Armano.
Give me the money and
we'll call tho whole thing off.
I don't think you'd want that.
Awful smell,
like a rotting fish.
Where's it coming from?
- I figure I stepped in some shit.
- What?
- Might mean good luck.
- Fuck that, man,
you get in this car
with shit on your shoes.
Fuck you,
ya know how much this was?
8 grand just for the rugs,
no shit, man.
D'ya think I'm some kinda a
rock star to buy rugs like that?
But I got'em from some Indian
dude on teleshopping.
Know what?
This is starting to piss me off!
Ya know, I've fucking had it,
get outta my car.
What's up?
You fucked up my rug,
that's what.
Just piss off, will ya?
Damn.
Just chill out and help me.
You must be kidding.
So you won't help me?
Adela, you...?
No.
- He really wants to drown her.
- Fucking asshole.
Got a better idea?
You're really
fucking it up for us.
Shut up!
- Shit, that's not my fault.
- Shit.
Shit, so it's
a fucking full moon.
Low tide.
I should've called the cops
and gone golfing.
- Fuck it, man, I need to piss.
- Can I watch?
- Come on, for fuck's sake.
Shit.
- 300 kms left.
- 500, to be exact.
Cops would at least
give us a ride.
It wasn't such a big fuckup,
was it?
Be glad it's over,
it was actually a nice trip.
We could start hitching.
As if someone's gonna stop
for the four of us.
Look, you fuck.
Cool. Let's go.
Can we get in?
We thought no one'd stop.
Someone stole our car.
This world's a weird place.
- Are those robins?
- Where?
Those are vultures.
Something stinks in here.
Written and directed by
Director of Photography
Wassup now?
Well, well...
We're going to heaven...
It's so romantic, Karel.
So now we're fucking angels,
right?
I wanna be Batman.
This is gonna
cost you a fortune.
Right.
- Who's paying for that pizza?
- You shut up.
When we get there,
I get my dosh, right?
We're gonna help
people in need.
I don't think so,
you're staying indefinitely.
Excuse me, what about my house?
I have stuff to do,
and strawberry pudding.
How long exactly
are we here for?
- Forever.
- That's not fair.
I decide
what's fair.
That wasn't part of the deal.