I hate Punk music.
Hate it.
No, it's a good band. A worthy one.
They're better than I expected.
They're crazy.
They're like a bombed-out ruin left-over
from mass destructions.
My glasses are fogging up.
Shonen Merikensack rocks!
I like Akio.
Jimmy.
Young.
They make me want a Mohawk.
Like I'd be a complete wimp without one.
I'm not sure.
I haven't seen them.
I will now.
Jimmy's vocals. Jimmy's the best.
Akio's cute.
Love and violence.
Exactly.
Too violent.
They're different.
Shonen Merikensack!
I hate them!
Exterminate the human race!
Shonen Merikensack!
The Shonen Merikensack
- Brass Knuckle Kids -
Akio.
Haruo.
Young.
Jimmy.
"Talent Search Division"
They're it!
Boss!
I found a killer band!
What?
This is the real deal!
No! Really?
Yes!
Show me!
We've done this routine for 2 years.
But here's your last.
Yes.
How many "promising" artists have you
and I dug up and buried?
Loads. It was great fun.
Thanks for the memories.
What'll you do?
Help run my father's sushi shop.
Sushi, huh?
Sushi.
Sushi sounds... great.
OK! Show me!
OK!
This is Punk rock.
Is it?
Tell me, Kanna. What's our genre?
Ambient, Okinawan,
club music and guitar pop.
This is?
Punk!
Hardcore punk!
Thanks for everything!
Hold it!
Let's see it.
What're they singing?
Surfin' to pass the time!
What does that mean?
Maybe they like to surf.
Not a chance! What're they called?
Brass Knuckle Kids!
You trying to kill me?
Thanks for everything! Bye!
No way!
This kind of trash...
is what I love!
Most punk these days is too clean,
too healthy.
They sing sappy songs about youth.
So do you like them or what?
I mean,
I did that.
You were in a punk band, boss?
In my youth.
That's how we started this company.
The band failed,
but we've built a major record label.
Where's the rest of them?
One's a fisherman. Another does shiatsu.
You're holding our vocalist.
Telya?
The Great Telya!
The Great Telya's leaving!
Wait, back up.
Forward, turning.
Turning.
Andromeda, is that you?
Don't touch me.
You are.
Andromeda, is that you? From the future.
Andromeda,...
I'm turning.
I bend to pick up litter. Then don't.
Elevator here... not here...
it's here... I get in.
I stop... I turn.
Yes... Good night.
Thank you.
Telya and I left the punk scene.
Now he earns 80% of our revenue.
He kept you from being fired.
Oh... thank you.
Then Punk died.
Except as late night TV intro music.
Crappy "fashion" Punk.
What is "Punk"?
Forget it. Never mind.
No, I won't "forget it."
You don't know what "Punk" is?
Not really. I know "Techno"
and "Hip-Hop"
but not "Punk".
What is it?
It's getting butt naked.
Shock value.
Punk is me.
Come again?
Okay, forget it.
But they're the real deal.
I see.
"You're all idiots!"
They really suck.
That's not important.
It's about power, rage and...
bam!
He's hunky.
That's right. You're a homo.
Kanna!
I want you to contact them immediately.
Does it have to be now?
Damn right!
We spent 2 years digging for this!
My farewell party's at 7!
Don't go.
I'm extending your contract.
Thank you!
In exchange, go make an album.
One album!
Just one?
Anyone can cut multiple albums.
Legends are made with one.
Yes!
One more thing!
I am the boss here.
So don't call me "homo".
Sure, everybody knows.
But I want them to think I don't know.
Life's a bitch.
You're not leaving, then?
Aren't you happy?
I'm happy if you're happy.
Don't you see? If I succeed with this,
I'll earn some clout.
I could get you your big debut!
But you don't like that band?
I hate it.
And yet there's something about them...
something that made me
endure the pain over and over.
What could it be?
Suddenly, I'm jealous of them.
I said I hate them.
You're a hundred times better.
Sakura, sakura, sakura
Sakura la la la
New song?
It's about you.
Actually, I can't write anything
that isn't about you.
Sakura, sakura, sakura
Sakura la la
"Sakura New Town"
Sakura, sakura, sakura
Remember what you promised?
That we'd walk together again
Along this cherry avenue,
hands shaking nervously
F-minus!
Boring song, boring voice,
boring face, probably!
He's a hunk. Look!
Boring!
Tell me about the band!
Fine. I found their official Web site.
An A-plus!
What, no phone number?
Born in 1983 means...?
He's 25, same as me.
Borderline. That's okay.
"Yogurt and Chao Fan"?
Ah, favorite foods.
"Fried rice"?
"Chao Fan", right?
Same thing.
He's baka.
Look, the hunk's number!
Akio! The bass player!
Call him!
I can't!
You have to!
My heart's pounding!
Let's see!
Hey! Don't make me touch your breasts!
Sorry.
They're just amateurs.
Breasts, ugh.
Sorry.
Sign them quickly
and I'll make you director!
Director?
Edokko.
I'm Kurita of Maple Records.
Could you come by the shop?
Kanna!
He's a punk rocker in his prime.
I want you to be on your guard.
Don't get pushed around!
Don't fall for him, either.
And remember...!
One album.
"Edokko"
Excuse me!
I called earlier. I'm Kanna Kurita.
He's no hunk.
Akio... Akio...
Akio!
Akio, you've got a visitor.
Excuse me. Are you Akio's father?
"Akio's father? "
My father is bedridden.
Who're you? A porn queen?
Maple Records Talent Division.
I'm Director Kurita.
I'm here to see Akio of Brass Knuckle Kids.
That's me.
No, the bassist Akio.
Me, me!
No, not you.
Who answered the phone?
You? You can't be him.
You said Akio was here. So where is he?
Right here!
Quiet, you! You in a band?
No.
You're not? What about you?
I am!
You're kidding!
Hold on a second.
Favorite food.
Fried rice!
Gummy bears.
Yeah, that's me.
Very funny. That is not you.
My beard?
No, your age.
How old do you think I am?
Look, it says "1983"!
It says 1983.
You weren't born in 1983!
Do I look that young?
Not at all.
What about this?
That's us! Our final gig!
"Final gig"?
March 23, 1983! Sendai!
What a trip! Where'd you find this?
Hold on.
Brass Knuckle Kids broke up in 1983?
Yeah, but in my heart we're still going.
Thank you for your time.
Your phone's ringing.
Having trouble, director?
Tell "hunky" this.
"Hunky"?
If he signs, we go on tour immediately!
We posted their clip on our site.
The response was incredible!
Boss, Nagoya's a lock!
We've got Nagoya! Let's do Sendai, too!
Wait, wait, no!
We're getting ahead of ourselves.
By the way, how old are you?
Mr. Akio!
How old are you again, Mr. Akio?
No way, no way, no way!
If you can't sign him, your contract's up.
Don't give me that.
This ain't a free ride. I need results!
But boss!
Sign him... or serve sushi.
Think about it.
We'll get back together for you,
Ms. "Major Label".
But I want the original members.
With Haruo on bass.
And me on guitar.
You play guitar?
Akio taught Haruo the guitar.
They're brothers, 2 years apart.
Right, Belle?
A
G
Jimi Hen...
Pinkie on 2nd string, 8th fret.
A
G
Jimi Hen...
Too slow!
Sorry.
Just do the left hand.
A
G
Jimi Hen...
Pinkie!
Pussy!
Sorry!
A
G
Jimi Hen...
Good.
A, G, Jimi Hen...
I let a drunk send me
to the middle of nowhere.
"Sakunami Residence"
You lost?
Mr. Haruo?
Yup. Who're you?
The change is overwhelming.
I'm sorry you came all this way.
That's ancient history to me.
Of course. Why leave a peaceful,
country life for a band in Tokyo?
Yup.
And there's his father?
Whose father?
Your brother says he's bedridden.
You saw my brother?
You asked him before me?
What's that scumbag up to?
Nothing. He's fine.
He's fine, huh?
No, he's drunk all day.
Drunk all day?
He's called the "Sid Vicious of Koenji".
Leave. I ain't playing guitar for
that stinkin' band.
Not guitar... bass.
Your brother will play guitar.
You're on the bass.
Scram!
You tell my brother this.
Our father's... dead.
Haruo! What the hell are you doing?
Just lowering the bridge.
Rad!
Nice move!
When I turn pro, he can be my roadie!
Buzz off!
What? I'm your father!
Beat it!
Screw you!
Roadie, huh?
What a relief.
I did what I could.
Guess I'll return to Tokyo and quit my job.
Then go home and work for dad.
Ugh, my dad.
Welcome.
"Yes! 100,000 hits
on the Brass Knuckle Kids Web site!"
I don't know what to do!
What's wrong, Sweetie?
Help me!
You smell.
Yuck!
I'm quitting! For sure, this time!
I'm quitting!
There, there. I know how you feel.
But if you give up now...
you turn your back on 100,000 fans.
What's the name of that band again?
Brass Knuckle Kids.
You like them, Kanna.
No, I don't.
Sure you do. You wouldn't cry otherwise.
Where's the tough Kanna I know?
I bet everyone in Brass Band Kids...
Knuckle Kids.
They know how you feel.
I'm sure they like you.
I'm sure they don't.
Yes, they do. Everyone loves you, Kanna.
I'm so jealous.
You love me, too, Masaru?
Of course, I do.
And I love you!
There, there.
Kanna.
You've got to make the most of it.
I guess I can give it another shot.
That's my girl!
Stop that.
Haruo has no intention of joining.
And it seems your father has died.
So... how about a new guitarist?
You spilled my drink!
What about a new bassist?
I said original members.
Convincing them is your job.
Easy, Akio. You'll make her cry.
Too late. Look, she's crying.
Maybe if I'd met you 25 years ago,
it'd be easier.
But I sense no potential in you now.
'Cause I'm middle-aged?
No!
'Cause I'm a geezer?
Exactly!
Thanks a lot.
I never had any interest in
going "major", anyway.
Ugly! Ugly cow.
I'm not an ugly cow. It's too late to quit!
Boss still believes
you're a new band like 20-something years old.
In fact, the whole country...
100,000 fans...
can't wait for
Brass Knuckle Kids' national tour.
Get more punk! Punk rock!
The times have finally caught up to us.
Caught up and passed on by, I'd say.
So what next?
You'd better meet my boss, first.
Maybe that'll wake him up.
The tour will be canceled,
the contract nullified.
I'll take responsibility and quit.
I'll go home...
Let's not meet him yet.
Book a studio. I'll get the other two,
but you bring Haruo.
And no cheap garage band studio.
I want the best equipment.
Get up!
Champagne in the dressing rooms.
1st class train car... or limos.
Isn't it a bit soon for a big head?
Not at all. We got 100,000 "heats".
But they all want to see you 25 years ago.
Not if we play better.
That's true but...
can you do it?
We've got to push the lie as far as it will go.
If we put on the show of a lifetime...
it will cease to be a lie...
and become a miracle.
But I have a strange feeling
he could be right.
Let's show them a miracle
that will erase the lie.
Okay.
Sorry but could you hurry it up?
They'll be here soon.
Maybe I could help you?
But they'll be here any minute.
Stop hissing.
This is all wrong.
What're you doing, mister? The drums!
Lookin' good, zipperhead!
Akio!
Young!
Great to see you!
That's the drummer!
You came prepared!
I left my work to my staff.
How old are you now?
"Young" Noodles
He's not named after those noodles.
He's really the youngest.
You die!
He was a glue-sniffing,
head-banging hood from age 13.
He joined the band at what?
17? 18?
I'm 42. Bad luck year.
Yeah, I've been there.
Is Haruo coming?
You call him?
Well... um... I...
Jimmy?
Sorry we're late.
Pain in the butt.
You look so much better!
"Better"?
Jimmy?
You're gonna sing, right?
Here.
I'm sorry. He insisted on showing up.
Sorry, hemorrhoids.
I just had surgery. Can I stand?
Go ahead.
Thanks.
Jimmy?
Yo, Jimmy.
Dear?
Honey!
Miracles.
You have to believe in miracles, Kanna.
I'm not getting any sound here!
What're you drumming?
There's no guitar!
Not bad.
Not bad my ass!
That wouldn't even make it
in a high school talent show!
Lame! Feeble! Out of the question!
It's been 25 years, lady.
And we were never that good.
You can say that again!
100,000 fans are well aware of that!
Stop the video.
How can you sound worse in a
studio than on a low-res PC?
I said stop recording!
With pleasure!
If you can't do it, you should've said so!
The tour's in 2 weeks!
Yo.
Mr. Haruo!
Custom!
Hands off!
What're you doin'?
Shut up and play bass, swine.
Jimmy?
He's standing! Jimmy's standing!
He's not a cripple or anything.
Is that right?
Is this the miracle?
Something's still not right.
Maybe they just suck.
But he's singing.
And she's into it.
This just might work!
If they practice like hell,
this might be possible!
Take this before meals...
this during meals.
And this after meals.
Is that our ride?
Okay, hop in!
My hemorrhoids make sitting hard.
Get in.
No way.
I thought I said limos.
We spent too much on rehearsals.
Just live with it.
Open the window if you're gonna smoke.
This brings back memories. Right, Akio?
Right, Haruo?
You hear me? Open the window!
Taking turns driving.
Akio scoring with the local chicks.
What was that?
There. You happy?
What're you doing?
This is my dad's car.
You're paying for this!
Cow!
Pig!
"Restroom"
Jimmy formed a band with Haruo first.
Was it 30 years ago?
There were no Indie labels.
So they had to try the biggies.
And so...
they became teen idols.
"Boys A La Mode"
Rich girl with the ponytail
Won't you join me on a journey
through space and time
With travel mates Jimmy!
Haru!
Potato!
Cheese!
Murai!
Never mind, don't take it to heart
Hop on Red Riding Hood
Dorky!
We didn't have the word "dorky" back then.
But I thought it.
But they were young
and on television.
They were riding high.
Haru, ready for take off?
Okay!
Launch!
Give them room, please!
But Haruo wasn't happy.
He said it wasn't Rock...
embarrassed to show his brother.
Get in, Jimmy!
I'll squash you!
Make room for the equipment!
Move dammit!
Akio's band was struggling.
So he worked as a roadie.
Akio!
You friends?
That'll make things easy.
Jimmy! Jimmy!
I'll kill you!
It's a pleasure, "Mr. Haruo".
Nostalgic eh, Haruo?
You came here with that crap pop band.
When's the band arriving?
Say what?
They're coming by Bullet Train.
First class.
Okay, staff can go set up first.
Thanks.
Push the lie as far as it will go, right?
Uh-huh.
Easy now. Okay! No sound out of the bass amp.
Wait, never mind.
Hello? Really? Gotcha.
They just passed Hamamatsu.
That's great news!
The line outside is tremendous.
Oh my god.
The crowd's huge.
They've bought up all the merchandise!
Don't get so excited.
I'm not but... is that hair dye?
Nagoya's delinquents are all out there!
Nose rings and all!
Kanna?
What're you doing?
Coming to greet the band.
You can't.
Why not?
Because...
it's dangerous.
They're real edgy right now psyching up.
Their nerves are like razors.
In fact, they have razors.
Where are the band members?
They're slashing themselves for motivation.
If you go in there... you could get hurt.
Wow, I can't wait. Okay,
I'll be in the audience.
This place will be wild tonight.
Know why we're starting the tour in Nagoya?
It's the home of Japanese Punk.
"Star Club", "Genbaku Onanies" and...
Yes!
It's Saturday night! Ready to go crazy!
From Tokyo! Brass Knuckle Kids!
Brass Knuckle Kids!
Boss!
Thanks for everything!
What?
Nothing.
A warm-up band?
What is that?
Evenin'!
With 100,000 Internet "heats"...
we're Brass Knuckle Kids.
Ow!
They're not kids!
Thanks for waiting.
Screw you!
Brass Knuckle Geezers!
Kanna!
Shut up!
Shut the hell up!
You're about to witness a miracle.
Jimmy! Jimmy!
Jimmy!...
Exterminate the human race!
Brass Knuckle Kids!
1 2 3 4
Sorry!
Haruo! Play, Haruo!
What're you doing?
Miss? Miss?
Miss!
Your cell phone's been ringing non-stop.
Sorry.
What a nuisance, huh?
I'm as drunk as Akio.
Hello?
I am so sorry, Boss.
I'm the one who should apologize.
Boss!
Tonight, I saw true Punk Rock.
Punk is a way of life! Right, master?
So the tour is still on?
What do you think?
1st class seats.
I never dreamed you'd show me real Punk.
Boss!
I'm sorry... he wasn't hunky.
Miss? Miss?
Miss!
Your phone's been ringing non-stop.
Stop it.
Move your hands!
Come on... Akio!
Not the hair!
Knock it off!
Did I come all this way to nurse a drunk?
Truth is that footage was from
a concert 25 years ago...
Now you tell me!
I'll pay for repairs, and then it's over.
So the tour is canceled?
Absolutely not. There are cancel fees.
Once the tour's over,
you and the band are through.
It's guys like you who killed Punk Rock.
Did you say something?
That's enough, please.
Think about it!
Why's an old show getting 100,000 "heats"?
"Hits"! The word is "hits"!
It's 'cause today's bands suck!
Say that after you can put on a show.
Forget the past.
What about now? Huh?
Did you play one song right?
Did you please one customer?
Face it.
You're a has-been.
What now?
Continue the tour?
Or shall we go back to Tokyo?
I don't care either way.
What do you mean??
I'm not like them.
I had money and a life.
Shut your trap.
I came 'cause you asked me to.
Lose your job or not,
I'll follow you
What about you?
I don't know. Akio?
What do we do??
I don't know.
Jimmy?
Of course, the band would never last.
Too fake.
They were an ugly band, too.
Wouldn't sell.
That's when Punk arrived in Japan.
I thought here's a fun wave to ride.
Ready, Haru?
No, wait!
Launch!
You call that music?
Your turn.
I incited Young to start a riot.
But I didn't tell the band.
And played dumb.
Take it easy.
And then Young...
hit me with brass knuckles.
Now this is getting fun.
I hate violence!
Play something.
Don't worry. No one's watching you anyway.
Listen up, assholes!
Today, your favorite crappy band
is no more!
Brass Knuckle Kids were born.
It was 1981, I think.
"Brass Knuckle Kids"
Pew!
Who farted? Akio?
Wasn't me.
You fart?
Did you?
You? Did you just fart?
Who cares who did it?
Unbelievable!
Mr. Akio!
That one wasn't me!
"That one"?
Quit stopping the car over a fart!
Well, quit farting! It's gross!
It smells 5 times worse than you all think!
For every fart,
you'll be penalized 500 yen.
Got it?
P.U.
Here's my fine, then.
From the next one!
So you'll be quitting for sure this time?
I'm sorry. It's all my fault.
No, it isn't.
Fried rice.
Chao Fan.
Jumbo dumplings.
Did you hear my new song?
Yeah, I did. It was soothing.
Thanks.
Say, after the tour...
can I meet your father?
I've been thinking about our future.
I'll keep writing songs...
but I don't want to pin everything
on a career that might not happen.
Akio!
Okay, okay!
I'll ask you one more time.
What did I order?
Fried rice.
And what's this?
Chao Fan.
And this?
Fried rice.
Fried rice?
You're saying this is fried rice?