# Mister Lister #
- # Mister Lister #
- Nothing?
- It's okay, honey, just come.
- What?
- It's okay.
- Do you want to get high?
- No, I don't have any.
I'm not calling my mom,
so just come.
Really, it's fine.
Sorry.
Aw.
- Are you bored?
- I mean,
I guess maybe a little.
- Wow, that sucks.
- It doesn't mean anything, D.
I mean, it's just what happens.
- Wow, that sucks.
- It's like, I still love you.
- So what do we do?
- # Nous sommes le nous,
nous sommes le nous #
# Nous sommes le nous #
- Whoo!
Smoke and mirrors!
- This is my blind boyfriend.
He's a mirror.
I'm a cigarette.
- # He is the he #
# She is the she #
# We are the #
# We are the we #
# Nous sommes le nous,
nous sommes le nous #
# We are the we #
# Nous sommes le nous,
nous sommes le nous #
# We are the we #
# Nous sommes le nous,
nous sommes le nous #
# We are the we #
- I feel like we have
to take half the week off,
if we're really going
to do this, you know?
We-we can't half-ass it,
or else what
are we accomplishing?
- Okay, that's fine.
Then let's set it.
But I don't want it
to be random.
- Okay.
Monday, Wednesday, Saturday.
- Are those off or on?
- On.
- Three days?
- And Thursday.
- What about Tuesday?
I want to watch the Idol
with you.
- Oh, fuck, you're right.
- Ready?
- Ready.
- Oh!
- Sucker!
- Go ahead, your pick: days on.
- Tuesday, Saturday
- Wait, wait, one at a time.
- Okay, Saturday.
- What happened to Tuesday?
- Why would I pick it when I
know what you're gonna pick?
I only have two picks.
You pick, go.
- Tuesday, Idol.
- Um, Monday, since we're dark.
- Friiiiii-
Thursday.
- It's Monday, Tuesday,
Thursday, Saturday.
Final answer?
- Final answer.
This is exciting.
- Write your own.
- All right.
Done.
- There are many things
wrong with you.
Would you like me to list them?
- Want me to list them?
- Okay, what do you got?
- Okay.
Being proactive.
- Check.
- Um, really sticking
to our days off.
- No chance in hell.
Check.
- Okay, what do you have?
- Strip clubs.
Trying new things.
- Is that the same as growth?
- I had them separate.
- Okay, um, okay.
No calling on days off.
- Your loss.
- And being independent.
And that is very key, Daryl.
- Listen, you can't use
my Netflix queue.
I know I've got
a big queue, but-
- Very funny, Daryl.
- Also, I like to walk
on the west side of the street,
and we can't be on G-chat
anymore.
- You're always on!
- I'll fix that.
- Fine, I get Whole Foods.
- Overpriced.
I get all city parks.
- Daryl.
- Okay, fine.
I get Madison Square Park
from 2:00 to 4:00.
I'm going to need time to write.
- All right.
Anything we left off?
- I think that's everything.
- Let's get to Kinko's
and laminate.
- Sweet.
Oh, yeah.
- Honey?
- What?
- What do I put on my Facebook?
- Put whatever you want.
Wait, you're on Facebook?
- Yeah.
- What?
When did you put yourself
on Facebook?
- Honey,
MySpace is kind of dead.
- Really?
- Okay, I picked you up
out of the dirt
when you were nothing.
You're not a man.
You're a child,
the epitome of classlessness.
How could you do this to me,
Korny?
- Okay.
- Okay, good, now do it
with conviction this time.
Really own it.
- Okay, I picked you
out of the dirt
when you were fucking nothing,
a piece of shit.
You're not a man.
You're a fucking little boy.
- Easy.
- You're a fucking epitome of-
What is it?
- Olasslessness.
How could you do this
to me, Korny? Korny?
How could you fucking do this
to me, Korny?
- You're fucking fired.
You're fired.
- Okay, here, take that.
- All right, I'll see you later.
Book that commercial.
- Great, thanks.
All right.
Okay, next.
Time for your picture.
Right here.
Excellent.
Nice.
Great, thanks.
- They're four heads above me.
They look at me
like I'm an alien,
like I have fucking leprosy.
I'm gonna call
immigration services.
I'm not kidding.
- Can you get me some numbers?
- They think they're actresses.
They're not fucking actresses.
They're models
with their fucking big books,
their fucking long legs,
talking on
their fancy cell phones.
They got so much money
from all the men
that shower them with gifts,
for what, for what?
For being tall?
Give me a gift for being short.
- I know, honey, it's terrible.
- It's like,
I got a prettier face.
They're dogfaces.
They're dogfaces
with their long legs.
Dogfaces
and fucking giraffe legs.
- Immigrants, yeah, immigrants.
- Minotaurs:
half beast, half woman.
- Try out the copy on me.
- Yeah, Okay.
We had nothing
after the floods came.
- There you are!
- Hi.
Thanks again.
- Yeah, my pleasure.
I'll see you tomorrow.
- Bye.
- Bye-bye.
- Come on.
- What's up?
Sorry I'm late.
Let's go.
- Let's go.
- What's up, boys?
- Oh, snap.
- What are you guys doing here?
- I'm here to fuck your friend.
No, I'm here for the art.
- I'll fuck anybody.
- Oh, my God.
Honey, look at that.
- It's nice.
- There are so many.
- So this is his first
foray into art.
- Oh, yeah?
- You know, I'm taking
my entire kitchen
to the International House
for this performance piece.
- What is that, like a-
like a onesie?
- A onesie?
- See, I told you
it was going to work out.
- Wuzzup.
- What are you doing?
Did you just touch me?
- Um, yeah?
- Don't touch me.
- Okay.
Sorry.
- Oh, that's really nice.
Good guy.
Really classy stuff.
All right, night's over.
- So how's work?
- Fine.
- Anything exciting?
- Daryl, it's dentistry.
I look into people's mouths
for a living.
- Right.
So I think I'm going
to be home more.
- Oh, yeah?
- Yeah, Zoe and me-
- Hey, that's great.
You can help me
with the computer.
- What?
- Yeah,
I can't get the photos-
You know, I can't get the photos
off the digital camera,
so you can help me.
That's terrific.
- That's it, just squat down
and stand.
And then go ahead
and bring your arms up.
We're going to go
into downward dog.
- Zoe?
- Honey, I can't talk
right now, okay?
I'm on my way to rehearsal.
Talk to you later, bye.
- Tolan!
- I can't talk right now.
Okay.
Bye.
Hi.
- Hi, Turner.
- Zoe.
- Nice to meet you.
- Mark out some time
where we can talk about this?
Okay, okay.
Thank you.
Great.
Okay, thanks.
- All right.
Hello, everyone.
So thank you all.
I'm very pleased you're here.
Thank you all.
And I think it's great
we've got the theater today
just to get a feel of it
on the first day,
which I think will be good.
And I thought we'd just start
sort of very easily
by reading through the play
and sort of not doing anything.
- By the time the sun
was setting,
the loneliness was physical.
It had taken on matter
and was musical
like a heartbeat.
Lonely, lonely, lonely.
That's when the phone rang.
That's when I found out-oh.
I'm going to say, "discovered."
Is that okay?
That's when l-
I'm gonna take that back.
That's when the phone rang.
That's when I discovered
what had happened.
The way I felt was numb.
- Oh, my God.
I'm so sorry.
I'm so, so sorry.
- Turn it off.
- Yeah, I really thought
it was off.
- Is it off?
Okay, keep going.
No, just turn it off.
- Um, are you-
okay.
You know,
I'm gonna have to go back.
I'm a little nervous.
That shook me up.
- Want some water?
- Yeah, could you get me-
just have this one
removed too, okay.
Just then, the sun began
going under the horizon.
- Well, maybe he thinks
that you're taken.
Maybe he can smell it on you.
- No, if anything, that makes me
more attractive.
- No, actually, that only works
for men.
- Well, whatever, then he
probably has a girlfriend.
- Maybe.
- Oh, my God.
- Jack and diet
and vodka tonic.
- Thank you.
- I'm fat.
- Whatever, Zo.
He just wants a big tip,
all right?
Plus, you have a boyfriend!
- Snooze!
- Zo, my relationships
last about five minutes.
- Yeah, try sex four years in.
- Oh, good morning, Father.
- Hey.
- Oh, don't you touch that.
Don't you dare.
- Good morning, Mom.
- You know I like my cup
and my spoon just so.
- A little COD, okay.
- Well, if you're going to live
in my house,
you have to deal with my shit.
Good morning, honey.
You want some coffee?
- I got it.
- What are you reading?
- Daryl's article.
- Oh, article?
What?
I'm your spellchecker.
- You're fair.
That's what I like.
They're in jail.
What's my first impression
gonna be?
But some of them even seem nice.
Dangerous nice,
like that guy
who used to be
our old super, Marty.
- Alan,
Marty was a schizophrenic.
Hey, come here.
I want to talk to you.
Come, come, come, come, come.
Hey.
- What?
- I ask you, I beg you.
Let me buy you some shoes,
please, real shoes
like shiny loafers
or hip slip-ons-
- Mom, no.
- Anything but this.
- I love these shoes.
- And these pants.
- What's wrong with my pants?
- Good Lord, Daryl,
they're so tight.
Tell me they're Zoe's.
- They are mine.
- Are you wearing girl pants?
- These are man pants, Mom.
- They look like tiny girl
stripper pants.
- They are my pants, Mom.
- Do you have to lay down
to put them on?
- Okay.
- How much did you pay
for those?
- A lot of money.
They're A.P.O.
- Oh, my God,
more than a hundred?
- I am leaving.
- Oh, my God.
If my grandchildren
come out short and stubby,
we'll know why.
It's those pants.
He paid more than $100
for those girl pants.
I know.
- # Baby, baby, baby, please #
# Baby, baby, I'm on my knees #
# You're hot as hell #
# I'm gonna freeze #
# Baby, baby, baby, please #
# Baby, baby, baby, stay #
- What's up?
What?
Zoe!
What's going on?
- Don't you bring
that thing in here.
- Oh, my God.
Sir, everything's under control.
Please, just don't call PETA.
Thank you.
Oh, my God.
What the hell is going on?
- Look what he did, D.
He shat on my Chanel.
- Oh, my God,
not the Chanel.
- It took me months
to find that van.
I mean, those Chinese
are surprisingly discreet.
- Honey, why the hell
did you buy a dog?
- I don't know.
It was our day off.
I was trying to grow.
What are we gonna do?
Come on, you got to get her
out of the box.
Get her out of the box.
- No, she stays in there,
or I'm leaving.
- What happened
to unconditional love, kitty?
What happened
to unconditional love?
- Mom, it's a dog.
- All right, you have got
to calm down.
- Who's a little boogoo booboo?
- Daryl, I read that piece
you wrote.
It is so good.
You are a really good writer.
- Thank you.
- Have you shown it
to anybody else?
- I'm working for this big-time
journalist now.
- That's good.
What about her?
- Yeah, I would love
to give it to her,
but, you know,
she's busy and stuff.
- So is she smart?
Could she help you?
- She is so smart, yeah.
She is a professor of
public policy and human rights.
- That's heavy.
Good.
- And he wants
to sleep with her.
- What?
I do not.
- You got to start somewhere.
- So we wanted to talk to you.
- All right, go ahead.
I'm all ears.
- Well, obviously,
nothing lasts forever.
Obviously.
And I love Daryl very much.
- And he loves you.
- We are taking days off.
- Okay.
I'm not sure
I know what that means.
- I'm sorry.
Just give me a moment.
I just-
- What?
- Just one minute.
- Okay, okay,
let her deal with it.
- You know,
we talked about this,
taking a few days off.
- You know, I tried to raise
a daughter
who wasn't gonna be afraid
of being alone.
It's tough out there.
I can be with a loser
who doesn't want to be alone
or a loser who deserves to be.
- You're smoking.
- Yeah, why aren't there
more of you?
Way to go, biatch.
- Daryl!
- Coming!
- Hey, welcome to Brooklyn,
you shit-sniffing cocksucker.
- Microdermabrasion!
- Kiddie yoga!
- You have to tell me
if this is too much.
I don't want it
to get all Trump Taj Mahal.
Ooh, pretty.
- I think I should be
in therapy.
- What?
Why?
You know who should be
in therapy?
Your father
should be in therapy.
- Dad?
Why?
- Ooh, he's fat.
Or maybe we could get him
on that program.
How do we get him
on that program?
- What program?
- You know, the program
where you're fat
and then you lose weight,
and they give you money.
Or do you have to be
a celebrity?
Is that celebrity fat people?
- I'm trying to talk to you!
- Well, talk then.
So talk.
Let's talk.
How are you?
How's Zoe?
How are things?
- I don't know,
we're just kind of...
- Tell her you're sorry.
- For what?
- It doesn't matter.
Come on,
I'll make you some tea.
- I don't know.
Is the quinoa really salty?
Last time I had it here
it was really salty.
- No, it's actually...
- You know what?
Oh, God, I don't know.
Nothing looks good.
Never mind,
give me the Dragon Bowl.
I'll love it.
- Okay.
- I'm gonna get that too.
- Great.
- But you know what?
No beans.
- Me too.
- Got it.
- Last thing I need is gas.
- She doesn't take the menus.
- So how's your tummy?
- Why?
- It's always so emotionally
sensitive.
- Oh, yeah.
No, yeah.
It's been--
It's a little funny.
- Yeah, yeah, me too.
So bloated all the time.
Oh, my God,
I look at a piece of fish,
and I want to blow up.
Oh, God, what we do
for our children.
Never mind.
You're beautiful. Who cares?
Moving on.
It's not your fault.
I'm not gonna get into it.
Anyway, how's D?
- I don't know, Mom.
You're out of your mind.
He's fine-
I don't know, he's-
When he's with me,
I want to kill him.
When he's not, I miss him.
I'm, like-
I'm a mess.
- You are a mess.
- Yeah.
- What's going on with you?
- I don't know.
- Boy, you have always been
so codependent, Zoe,
ever since you
were a little child.
- Yeah?
- You were so cute,
always hanging on my leg
every place we went.
Wouldn't let me go in one room.
You would just go, "Mama!"
Funny.
You're not easy, honey.
You are not easy at all.
- What is that supposed to mean?
- It means you're needy,
sweetie.
- Shh, I'm not needy.
- Yes, you are.
You're very needy.
You're not easy at all.
- Yeah, and all
your relationships
have ultimately failed, so...
- You are so fucking judgmental
sometimes.
- Needy, Mom.
- You are so sensitive.
- Honestly?
- I can't even talk to you.
Zoe, come here.
You weren't a burden.
I just want you to be happy.
That's all.
I've lived a lot of mistakes
that you don't have to make.
- Like what?
- Like this manic cycle
of pushing people away
and then needing them,
your fear of independence.
I think a lot of people
would be surprised
to see how really fearful
you are.
- Do you think
I'm pushing him away?
- I don't know, honey.
I think you need to be alone.
- We really shouldn't
be doing this.
- I know.
I'm really sorry, D,
but I just needed to talk.
- Well, it's our day off.
- Do you think that I'm, like,
too needy or that I'm pushing
you away in some way?
- If we don't follow
the rules now,
it's never gonna work.
- Oh, the rules.
All right, D.
You know what?
Fuck you.
Thanks for clarifying.
Fucking asshole.
- Wow, fuck you, huh?
- Frustration rides you well.
- That's a good line.
It must work
on all the insecure actresses.
- Well, working is relative.
You all right?
- Yeah.
Yes.
- All right.
Let's go.
- I mean, it's like she's so
on the outside of this group.
It is a suicide.
- Hi, honey. I'm sorry.
You were right, okay?
So I'm gonna go.
- Who's that in the background?
- Don't worry about it.
- Is that fucking dickface fuck?
- Okay, honey, I'm gonna go.
All right,
so tomorrow's Tuesday.
I'll talk to you then.
- Good job, sweetie.
That's my little man up there.
- He is so cute.
- He is a trip.
- You ever feel like...
- What?
- I don't know, like,
you don't have the words?
- Sure.
- I don't know.
Never mind.
- You have to find out
who you are
outside of who
you wish you were
or who someone else
wants you to be.
Tolan, wait your turn.
Badass.
Oh, God, my neck is killing me.
- Here.
- Mm.
- I can't take this anymore.
Let's go, Luke.
- Emma, can you
give us a minute?
I'll meet you in the car.
You ever see him?
- See him?
- Yeah, I mean, like,
see him in other people.
- Do you?
- Every day.
- Sometimes
I see him in you.
- It's gonna be okay.
- How do you know?
- Hold-
can we hold, please?
No, no, it's really good.
Can we just try it again?
It's good, it's good.
Let's just try it again.
- I don't think the beard
is working.
- No, no,
the beard's good.
The beard's really good.
It just needs a little more-
like you've been waiting for it.
You know what I mean?
And less trepidatious.
- Like, so I'm a little bit
more aggressive.
- A little more gung ho
for it, yeah.
- Okay.
- You know what I mean?
That's good.
And can we try again?
And can we put like a blue
in here or something?
We can see what that does.
It just feels a little warm.
Are you guys good?
- Awesome.
- Yeah.
- All right, let's try it again.
- Hey, Zo.
You smoke?
- No.
You know, cancer.
- Oh, thanks, yeah.
I almost forgot about that.
Hey, you want get a drink,
talk about the show?
- I shouldn't.
I feel like
I'm getting sick.
- No, come on,
it'd be good, really.
We should figure some stuff out.
- I mean, I'm not getting sick.
I neti pot daily,
or at least every other day.
- Actually I'm not asking.
I am taking you out
for a drink.
- Oh.
- Yeah.
- Hey, It's Zoe.
Leave a message,
and I'll get back to you.
- She has to know.
She has to know that
that's what he's saying.
- I think that
deep down she knows,
but that, like, because she is
so controlled,
she doesn't know she knows.
Do you know what I mean?
- That's fine,
but as long as that breaks,
as long as in the moment
he sees that she understands
what he's saying to her
and that she releases to him,
then we're good.
He's not saying, you know,
"You're gonna be okay"
because he's gonna
take care of her
or he's gonna, like,
protect her or whatever.
He's saying,
"You're gonna be okay
"because I am gonna hurt you,
but that's what you need.
And you will survive."
- Okay, yeah, I mean,
I get that.
- So we need submission.
We need you to give yourself
to me,
or we're nowhere.
The moment is-
- I think she does
in the moment.
- Well, I'm not getting it.
- Okay.
- You're gonna be okay.
- How do you know?
- Uh-huh.
Right?
- Yeah.
- Fuck.
That was good.
- Yeah.
That was the scene.
- Could I get a shot
of tequila please?
- Hi, honey.
I'm sorry.
I was just-
I couldn't hear the phone.
So do you want to come over?
I'm just hailing a cab.
- Um, no.
- Why not?
- I'm sorry.
I have nothing to say
to you, Zoe.
- Um, what's your problem?
- Well, let's just say
I'm a little irate.
- Can you be a little irate?
- It's an on day.
You said that we were
gonna hang out.
I've been sitting here
waiting for you.
- I'm sorry.
I was just with the cast.
We were just bonding.
- Okay, well, you could have
invited me.
- Well, we said we were going
to be independent.
- God, dude,
I don't want to hang out
with a lame bunch of actors
anyway!
- Okay, you need to
just calm the fuck down
and talk to me like an adult
in a normal voice.
- Don't fucking tell me
to calm down when you've been
ignoring me all day, okay?
- Honey, you are reading
too much into this.
- Well, you're not giving me
much to work with, Mom.
- What do you want me
to tell you?
We're good people.
We're decent to one another.
That's it.
- Yeah, but that's not it.
There's so much more to it.
It's like, why-
- Okay, Zoe,
did it ever dawn on you
that maybe sometimes
I don't want to talk?
- Good night, Mama.
I love you.
- Will you lock up for me,
honey?
- Yeah.
- Oh, God, I'm a douche bag.
- Why is my stuff
all over the place?
- I don't know.
Were you out with Turner?
- Honey, this isn't healthy,
okay?
Whatever's happening here,
this isn't like-
- I just want to know
what you were doing.
- I don't have to tell you.
It's our day off.
- I know it's our day off,
but I want to know.
- For fuck's sake, Daryl.
- I just want to know
what he gives you
that I don't give you.
- He's not there
all the fucking time!
I was at my mom's.
I just don't understand
how two people
can go from being in a unit
to just being...
alone.
This is why I'll never work
in these things,
'cause I know that they're just
gonna end in disaster.
- That's not true.
- D, whose breakup lasts
as long as the relationship?
- I don't know, ours.
- And lesbians.
- I think I've earned
a nice pastrami on rye.
- Isn't that fatty?
- You don't have to tell her
everything I eat.
- I don't tell Mom everything.
If I drown, don't save me.
- Come on, let's go.
How's Zoe?
- Eh.
- You know we like her.
- Yeah.
- But we like you more.
- Look, I don't want Mom
to know.
Okay, she doesn't get it.
So please don't tell her.
- Then I'm ordering dessert.
- Do you ever see him?
- See him?
- Yeah, I mean, like,
do you ever see him
in other people?
- Do you?
- Every day.
- Sometimes I see him in you.
- It's gonna be okay.
- Oh, my God.
Congratulations!
- Thank you.
- Oh, you were so terrific.
You know that scene,
you made me cry.
Tears were coming down.
It was just so wonderful
of you.
- And then another crazy band
came out to take over for him.
- Who's the crazy band?
- Uh, Capital One I think,
Capital Years?
- But anyway, I'm gonna run,
'cause we have to go to the-
- I'm gonna come
and see it again.
- Oh, you are?
- I really loved it.
I really, really loved it.
I loved it.
- Thank you so much for coming.
- You were just so wonderful.
- Okay, bye.
- Yeah, but I love his music.
You saw him at Warsaw?
- At Warsaw in Brooklyn, yeah.
- Nice.
- I like your style, man.
This is a cool coat.
- Thanks.
- Is it vintage?
- Yeah.
- Yeah!
Me too.
- Hi.
- Hey, guys.
- That's the new Meryl Streep.
Jewish, though.
- Very Jewish.
Okay, should we go to the party?
- Yeah, sure, after you.
And you.
What do you want me to say?
She started talking to me.
We were having a drink.
- I'm sure you two
had a lot to talk about.
She looked really smart.
- Actually, we did.
She knew all about art.
- She knows nothing!
- Okay, you're acting like
a fucking psychopath right now,
and I'm leaving.
- Oh, really?
You're gonna leave now?
All right, go.
Go ahead.
Fucking baby.
And thank you very much.
You ruined my fucking night.
- I ruined your night?
I'm sorry, where does it say
treat your boyfriend
like the cater waiter?
- I'm sorry, where does it say
go talk to the only fucking
long-legged bitch in the room?
- Okay,
what do you want me to do?
Just stand around and not
fucking talk to anybody?
- Yeah.
- I'm socializing.
It doesn't mean anything.
- Oh, bullshit.
You wanted to fuck her.
- You're just projecting.
That's just projection.
- You know what, go ahead,
'cause you and me,
we're done fucking.
- Fine.
Hey, go buy her a sandwich.
I'm sure she's starving.
- Well, it seems you two
are going at it
for every little thing.
- Well, not seeing each other
at all is worse than fighting.
I mean, don't you think?
- Fuck if I know.
These are cute.
- Yeah, get those.
- Mm-hmm.
If you're a mime.
All right.
So how are the folks?
- They're good, you know.
It's not a marriage I'd want,
but I'm not sure I've seen
a marriage that I'd want.
I don't know.
What do you think
about marriage?
Do you think it's an institution
that actually works nowadays?
I feel like-
- Okay, Daryl,
you got a lot of questions.
What do you think about this?
- Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
This is hot.
- Really?
You know, I'm honored, honey,
that you want to talk to me
about marriage.
Do you talk to your own mom
like this?
- Uh, kind of.
I mean, not really.
I don't know.
I mean, something's kind
of changed between us.
I'm afraid she's gonna judge me
or something.
- Oh, honey, we're all afraid
of being judged.
I'll tell you that much.
I don't know.
What do you think?
- That is hot.
You could go to the club
in that.
- Really?
'Cause I think
it looks like I'm nursing.
- I think it's nice.
- Some baby would be very happy.
These are nice jugs.
- Here, try this.
- Okay, I got such a gut.
- What? No, you don't.
Gut's the new black.
- Look at all the fat hanging
out over the underpants.
- Stop it.
Look at your abs.
You got great abs.
- I got to look hot, baby,
hot for my date tonight.
- All right, so tell me,
tell me.
I want some details.
What's his income, build,
star sign?
- I met him at the food co-op.
We were both bagging together,
and he's into woodworking,
and he's married.
- Oh, sounds like a keeper.
- You know what?
There's a lot that
you don't know about.
Ever hear of polyamory?
- What's that, swingers?
- Kinda sorta.
- Oh, I'm gonna turn around
right now.
- Never mind.
Come on.
Come on, baby, we're family.
Yeah, I don't know, honey.
At least he's working.
Here, zip me.
- Okay.
- It's slim pickin's out there.
You know that.
I've only had three hits
this month on JDate.
All of them were octogenarians.
- Oh, come here.
Don't worry.
I know some hot young guys.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
- Like you?
- Like me.
- All right, you know what?
You and Zoe
better stay together.
I really like you.
Fuck her.
What do you think?
- I think you look hot.
- Okay, I look like
Shirley Temple.
- No, you don't.
- I look like
the Goodyear blimp.
I look like Zsa Zsa Gabor
post-stroke.
Take it off.
Unzip me.
Love yourself, love yourself,
love yourself.
- How many wives does that guy
have right there?
- I told you
it's not about polygamy.
It's polyamory.
Okay, It's not about possession.
It's about love and freedom.
- Okay.
- That guy's really cute.
- Let's go talk to some people.
- Okay, just act cool.
Come on, listen and learn.
Hey, how are you?
- How long have you been
polyamorous?
- As long as we've been
together.
- Well, Matt was
in a relationship
when we started
our relationship.
- I mean, we all have
so much baggage,
whether it's, you know,
our personal insecurities
or fear of abandonment.
And then we live in this,
you know,
monogamy-centrist culture
that just reinforces
all that fear mentality.
- Like, haven't you ever wanted
to be with someone else?
- What are you, Jewish?
- Yeah.
Christian?
Nice.
- I like Jewish guys.
- Oh, cool.
- I generally get along better
with Jewish guys.
- I'm a sculptor.
- Sculptor?
- Yeah.
- Do you-what kind of material
do you work with?
- Blood.
- You sculpt blood.
Do you freeze the blood?
- That's absolutely right.
How do you know that?
- Well, I'm educated.
- But you know I mean?
It's like-it's like-
because then otherwise sex
becomes like there's
a primary zone
in which it's morally okay.
And then there's
this other exciting place
where it's exciting
'cause it's not morally okay.
But then that means the person
you're engaging with
you're having
some judgment about,
like it's immoral, you know.
And so you bring your shame
into it.
You know, it's like, why bring
that to somebody else?
- Like, I just rose above
all my human nature
and evolved like just
quantum leap from the cave days.
You know what I mean?
I mean, but what I'm saying is,
that's what it takes.
- Where the hell were you?
- Well, hello to you too, Mom.
- No, really,
where the hell were you?
- Out.
Hi, Dad.
- Hi, Daryl.
- Call Brian.
You know, if you won't answer
your damn cell phone,
what is the point
of paying that bill?
- Brian, dinner.
- I don't know, Mom.
I don't know.
- Wow, what crawled up your ass
and died?
Hey, I want you
to look at something.
These are your bills.
We need you to come back
from la-la land and join us
here in the real world.
This is your student loan.
You've got to help us out.
Oh, and this is
your new insurance card.
Put it in your wallet.
Brian, supper!
- Shit, bitch,
can't a man have a minute?
- Who you calling bitch, bitch?
Snap, snap on you.
Hey, where's Zoe?
Isn't she coming?
- Mom, you need a haircut.
- Yeah, well,
you need to wash your clothes.
Alan, tell him.
He's gonna go to the synagogue
meet and greet
dressed like a homeless.
Honestly.
What's going on?
- Daryl needs a day off
from talking about his days off.
- What?
What's a day off?
- Nothing.
Cops.
- Why can't you be gay
like your brother?
- Mom, please.
He doesn't have the chops.
- Well, all right,
I'm gonna call Zoe.
She'll explain it.
- Joanie, sit down.
- All right,
somebody talk to me.
- Days off, it just means
that Zoe and I
aren't talking to each other
or seeing each other right now.
- What does that mean?
How can you work
on your relationship
if you're not talking or-
are you breaking up?
Did you know about this?
Did everybody
know about this but me?
Okay, fine.
Boys' secrets.
- He won a Pulitzer prize?
- Well, you know,
Daryl's a writer.
- No.
- Oh, yeah. Look out.
- Really?
Nice.
And what's your day job, son?
- Nude model.
- Excuse me. Mort?
- That was nice.
You know there's a back door
in case you meet
any cute Jewish girls.
- Right.
- If you want to move on,
you got to let other people in.
- Well, not necessarily,
because it's not, you know,
in your experience,
nor should it be, necessarily.
But it's interesting.
- I think I'm gonna go
get a drink.
- Oh, okay.
- Do you want anything?
- No, no, thank you.
- Okay.
It was nice talking to you.
- Thank you, you too.
- Bye.
- Hey.
- Hi.
- I think you're the reason
why my parents
made me come here tonight.
- Probably.
- Are you Ethan?
- Oh, Daryl.
Do you want to maybe pretend
to be Ethan for me?
- Sure, you be Leticia.
- Word, Leticia don't
live here no mo'.
- Wow, you really went there.
- Yeah.
- So are you having as much fun
at this thing as I am?
- Actually, I was gonna leave
pretty soon.
I'm meeting some friends
at Esperanto.
Do you maybe want to join?
- I can't.
- Too bad.
I bet you're easy.
You know, couple drinks.
- You have no idea.
- Fuckin' Amores Perros.
Okay, continue.
- I think it's a necessary step.
- Okay, fine.
Are you gonna want
to know details?
- No!
Uh-uh.
- Okay, but I think we should
probably be open.
- No, I don't want to
know that kind of stuff.
I can't handle it.
- Okay, let's do a practice.
- Okay, okay.
- Okay, let's just say
I just went on a date
with my friend Halley,
and it's the next night.
- Okay, wait, wait, wait.
Hold on.
I got to-you know, I got
to figure out my motivation.
Okay, ready.
- I think you should sit down.
- What is it?
- I went on a date
with my friend Halley.
- Wow.
How was it?
- We made out.
How do you feel?
- Um, how do I feel?
I feel upset.
- I'm sorry.
I really like her.
- Like, go on another date,
like her?
- Yeah, she's got a banging ass,
really big tits.
- Okay, stop.
Don't say that.
- What?
- That.
- Are you acting
or are you talking?
- Talking!
Jesus, fuck, don't say that.
"Oh, great ass, tits."
I don't want to hear
that kind of stuff.
- Okay, I'm sorry.
- Do you, though?
- Yeah, I mean we sat
next to each other
in Politics
and the Information Explosion.
She has the cutest handwriting.
Honey, I think
it's a necessary step.
- What's going on?
Any luck?
- I'm not trying too hard.
- What about that guy
right there?
- Who?
- That guy right there.
- Oh, I don't know.
I have to pee.
- What?
Do it at his place.
- No.
- Come on, he's cute.
- You go talk to him
if you think he looks so cute.
- Looks like he had
a good childhood.
He's clean-looking.
- I have to pee.
- Okay, well, I think you...
go talk to him.
That's what I think
you should do.
- I'll go pee on him.
- Yeah, go pee on him.
- We'll get kinky.
- Go ahead.
Go pee on him.
- Wouldn't that make you happy?
- Yeah, it would.
- Fuckin' pervert.
Excuse me.
- Hello.
- And hello.
- Fancy meeting you here.
- I know.
Right here.
- So what do you do?
- I'm an actor.
- Oh, yeah?
I owe that guy over there
ten bucks.
- Damn.
Is that your boyfriend?
- No, mm-mm.
He's gay.
- Oh, yeah, I see that.
- Yeah.
What are you drinking?
- Oran vodka.
- Whoa.
A little bit gay.
- Is this like your A game?
'Cause it's-
- No, no, I'm just riffing.
- Are you?
# Anticipation driving me
out of my mind #
# I've got to hurry #
# 'Cause I know I haven't
got much time #
# To find who you really are #
- Solo.
- # I've got to get closer #
# 'Cause now you feel
so far away from me #
- Whoo!
- Yeah.
- Nice!
- Oh, hey!
- Karaoke!
- Ah, right.
- Very nicely done, man.
- He was in an a capella group
in college.
- Oh, yeah, you can tell.
- All right.
Yeah, you want to sing
another one?
- Yeah.
- You guys want another round?
- Yeah, yeah.
- Yeah?
You good?
- Sure, yeah.
- One more round.
What's wrong, little baby?
Your pussy hurt?
You need a tampon?
- Okay, I feel very
uncomfortable right now.
- Well, you encouraged me, D,
so I don't know
what to tell you.
- I know I encouraged you
earlier,
but now, if you cared-
- No, now?
Now?
No, brother man, no now.
We had a meeting in a kitchen,
and now we're here.
- Well, I'm re-evaluating.
- You can't just, you know,
make these decisions
on your own.
We have to make them together.
We made a decision.
- Okay, I want to fucking
leave now.
- Then leave.
Oh, oh.
- Almost couldn't find you guys.
- Drinks here and here.
- Hey.
- And I think Zoe
is choosing for Daryl.
- Oh, no.
- Ladies choice!
- I'm gonna head out.
- What?
- I got to wake up early.
I got a lot of work to do.
So you guys should stay.
You guys should totally stay.
- We will stay.
- Yeah, we're staying.
- Yeah, man.
- No question.
- d We're gonna get closer d
- Hold on one second, okay?
- Yeah, I got-
I got something for you.
- Look, I don't want to do this
if you're really
not okay with it.
- Yeah, you do.
- Here.
- Thank you.
So did you think my article
was shit?
- Daryl, no.
- I just wanted to impress you.
- You did.
I actually-
I just got an email
from a friend.
An opportunity.
So did we just break the rules?
- Nah, we're supposed to.
- What man wouldn't kill
for that responsibility?
Exactly, and try new things
and be independent.
- It's sweet.
It is.
- So why am I so miserable?
- Look, we all want to believe
in a love that sustains itself.
But it's bullshit.
Believe me.
I've done impeccable research.
- Look, I don't know if it's
the right time or whatever,
but that job?
It's in Vancouver.
- I know.
- There's no treatment
for that, man.
- What's up?
- Oh, what up?
- Okay, listen.
The clap is Chlamydia.
- No, the clap is gonorrhea.
- What the fuck
are you talking about?
- Gonorrhea is the burn.
Gonorrhea burns.
- Yeah.
- What's the drip?
- Yeah, what is the drip?
- I have no idea.
- What's the third main STD?
- Syphilis.
- Hold this.
I'll be right back.
I'm gonna go get something.
- Who the fuck is that?
- Nothing.
- You just made out
with his face.
- I'm not getting close enough
to find out,
but I'm just gonna go
with the clap.
- Why don't you go talk to her?
- Why doesn't Daryl
go talk to her?
- Me?
- Yeah.
- Why doesn't Daryl
go talk to her?
go dance with her?
- You get your head
in the game, son.
- I saw him nine days ago.
And it's like nothing.
It's like-it's just kind of-
he's somewhere.
He's there, but he's not here.
I know that he's in my vicinity.
Do you know what I mean?
I think about him constantly.
- You have dirt on your face.
- What?
Don't touch my face.
- # You can't come #
# Even shadows need to see #
- # Well, don't you say
that you can't come #
# Well, don't you say
# Even shadows need to see #
- Oh...
wow.
I should-
I guess I should probably
get out of here.
- There's like beer
in the fridge and stuff
if you want to have a drink
or something.
- Oh, yeah?
Cool.
Nice.
Thanks.
That was-
Hey, let's not lose that.
All right?
I mean, eight shows a week,
you know?
- Yeah, um-
- I'm out.
- All right, now we're gonna do
some partnering up
for some balancing.
So we're gonna do tuladandasana
and a balancing stick pose.
So I want you to find a partner.
Walk over towards your partner.
Yeah, yeah, find a partner,
and we're gonna do
balancing stick pose.
So one of you is going
to do the posture.
And of you is going to spot
your partner.
All right, arms up over
your head, hands in prayer.
Stretch up, take a big step
forward on your right leg.
Lock your right leg,
point your left toes, and go.
Bring your body down
parallel to the floor.
Point the toes back,
stretching the arms forward,
Keep the legs strong.
- Okay, let's go ahead
and come out of the posture.
- Is everything okay?
- I think she's-
she's crying or something.
- It's not, it's not you.
- I know this is
a really emotional pose.
It's one of the hip openers.
You're really releasing a lot
of emotion and stress,
so it's really normal to have
this kind of reaction.
- Thank you.
- All right, guys, so we're
gonna move into another posture,
so we're gonna move
into tree pose.
All right, so back your mat.
- You're just like
the only person
I want to tell, like,
funny stuff to,
like when I see funny stuff
and stuff,
even if it's on a Wednesday.
- I just think we should talk.
I don't know if we should
be doing this yet.
- No, D, I don't
want to talk it to death.
Okay, and I don't want
to involve our parents.
I just want to be there
for each other.
Don't you?
- Of course.
- So then see?
There's no reason for us
not to be together.
Except Turner Smith
wants to get into your pants.
- No, I think he's gay.
What?
- Are you sure
you want to do this?
- Don't you?
- I just don't know if I
want to lose my days off yet.
- Well, that's okay, honey.
We can just take it slow,
and we can wean ourselves
back on to each other.
Right?
See?
There's no reason
we shouldn't be together.
Right?
- Triple!
So what did she say?
- Huh?
- Zoe?
When you told her
that you were taking the job?
- Oh, she's cool with it.
- Really?
- Yeah.
- 60 points.
Just use the whole board.
- I will.
- So now when I ask you
a question,
you're gonna lie to my face?
- Maybe we can play
something else.
- I'm not lying.
- Go Fish
I could probably handle.
- Do you think
that we can't read you?
- Okay, fine,
I'm not taking the job.
- Jeez.
- It's my life.
It's my decision.
I can do whatever I want.
- I think she just wants to know
that you've thought about it.
- It's in Vancouver.
- You know, it's an opportunity.
I don't see that many
opportunities
just flying towards you.
I mean, you're 23
and babysitting.
- Oh, come on,
end of discussion.
- It's all about her,
and they're not even
really dating.
- That's because
you don't understand.
I don't understand?
That's the reason
you're not dating?
- Okay, I'm not involving you
in this part of my life,
so if you can
just stay out of it.
- I want to hit him in the head
with a shovel.
He's got to get out
of this house.
What did I say?
He won't even talk about it.
Are we stuck with him forever?
- Just leave it alone.
- Forever, though!
- Hey, are we inviting
Zoe and Helaine to the Seder?
I need a head count.
- I don't know.
- Well, we've invited them
the last two years.
I think it might be rude
if we didn't.
- Okay, that's fine.
We can invite them.
- Should we also invite
Zoe's new boyfriend?
- What?
- Boy, you should have seen
the hug he gave her,
very affectionate.
- Who's he?
- That guy in the play with her.
They were outside the theatre.
I saw them.
I tried to get a picture
for you,
but I don't know how that camera
works on the phone.
You need to show me.
- Mom what were you thinking?
- I don't know.
You're staying here for her.
What are you thinking?
- Happy Pesach!
- Oh, Daryl, honey.
My, God, aren't you eating?
- I've been fasting
since Yom Kippur.
Come in, come in.
- When I was 18...
- Yeah.
- There were no jobs.
This was-Herbert Hoover
was the president.
- Yeah.
- It was the Depression.
- Hi, do you need any help?
- No, I need you to go
put on a collared shirt.
That one is ripped,
and it has holes
and schmutz all over it.
- What?
All right, fine.
I'll go put on my jacket
and button down.
- Thank you, trailer trash baby.
Man, when was the last time
you actually showered?
- Mom, go bother Dad.
- I can't.
We're not speaking.
We're having a day off.
- I was going through
Orown Heights,
and it was Purim.
So all those Hasidim,
you know, they give you
these bags of nuts
and other things like that.
We kept them in the car.
We ate some.
We actually ate some,
but I kept most of them
in the car.
- Thank you.
It was really good.
- Hey.
- Oh, hi.
- Hey, oh, my God,
get me a towel.
Oh, it's like a shvitz in here.
Pretty soon we'll all be naked
talking about the old country.
Who's here?
Hey, baby, hi, hi.
- You're rocking
the one earring, huh?
- Oh, shit, I lost one.
Oh, these are my favorites.
- Left is right.
Right is wrong.
- Hello.
- Hey, honey.
- You look beautiful.
- Oh, thank you so much.
You're so adorable.
Can you go to your mom's
and see if she's got
an extra pair of earrings?
Brian says I look gay.
- It's Ellen, not Rosie.
- That's better.
- Yeah, of course.
I think Zoe left a pair
in my room.
I'll go get them.
Just give me one sec.
- Angel.
I mean,
I don't mind looking gay.
- What you did was,
you planted trees,
you cleaned up the place,
you painted the benches green.
- Yeah.
- You know, things that you did
in a park...
- Right.
- For six months.
- I brought these.
- These are nice.
- Zoe left them in my room.
- Gee, can I keep them?
- Yeah.
- All right.
I knew I liked him.
- Hi.
- Oh, everything looks
beautiful.
- You look beautiful.
- Thank you.
I brought you some stuff.
I didn't know what you needed.
- Wow, those are thick.
Are they ortho?
- Orthofeminist.
- How about that?
- Yeah, they're just newly out.
- Great.
- Like myself.
I'm going gay, you know.
- Are you really?
- I'm kidding you.
Anyway, look what I brought,
a little after-dinner treat.
- Helaine, is this real?
- Of course.
I can't get through a Seder
without one.
- Well, you know what?
I'm just gonna put it over here.
- We're gonna party!
Remember where that is now.
- I won't forget.
- Okay, can anybody have this?
- Yeah, sure, it's all yours.
You know, actually,
we're gonna use
the kiddie Haggadahs this year,
'cause we just sort of want
to whip through it.
Not that I don't love
a really good long Seder.
But why don't you take those?
Put them on the table
in case someone gets sexist.
- I only have two of them.
- That's fine.
I think that's all we'll need.
- Cheers, cheers.
- All right, cheers to you.
So glad you're here.
- Oh, my God,
this is a nightmare.
- Okay, everyone, people,
people, people.
Thank you all for coming.
Please take your seats.
Let's begin our Seder.
- These things are gorgeous.
Zoe, where did you get these?
- Everybody get ready to dip
your finger in the wine.
- Bravo, whoo!
- Oh, boy.
Yeah.
- So, Zoe, how is the play?
- Oh, sick of it.
- Really superb.
- And that other boy,
what was his name?
- Turner.
He was adorable.
I want to date him.
- He was very good.
- You two
are so natural together.
- Yeah, he's great to work with.
- Sometimes when the acting
is that good,
it doesn't really seem
like acting.
- Mom.
- Come on, what is going on
with you two?
- Joanie, I don't think
that's very appropriate.
- Oh, please, we're all family.
- I think they should
sort things out by themselves.
- Your father and I
don't take days off.
- Yeah,
maybe that's the problem.
- That's enough.
- I think what they're doing
is mature.
Hear, hear.
- Amen.
- Well, I don't think it makes
sense to be seeing other people.
- Well, that's because
you've only been
with one person your whole life.
- You know absolutely nothing
about what you're talking about.
You're so young.
You're either in a relationship,
or you're not.
- And you make each other
miserable.
- Oh, and you haven't been
Mr. Happy Pants lately.
I would say you're more anxious,
and you're moody,
and you're cruel.
- Joanie.
- All right, I know.
It's none of my business.
But there's a fair way
to do this and there's not.
I want Daryl
to get to go to Vancouver.
- Why?
- I mean, sure, the pay is shit,
but he gets to work
on Max Kleaman's book.
And yes, I don't know
who the fuck that is.
But apparently Daryl adores him.
- Of course.
- So why won't you let him go?
- I won't let him?
- That's not fair.
- Joanie-
- What is she talking about?
- Here's a deal.
You take days off.
Why not take a year off?
He'll be back in the spring.
You can sort out
your little relationship then.
- It's not
a little relationship.
- A real relationship takes more
than four days a week.
- That's enough!
- Zoe.
Zoe, please stay.
- Were you not planning
on telling me about Vancouver?
Did you not think
I'd be excited for you?
- Of course, I wanted to-
- Well, we're supposed
to be communicating.
- And we are.
Look at how well
we're using our time,
how well we've adjusted.
I think we're doing pretty well.
- Those aren't my earrings,
Daryl.
Whose are they?
- Um, I don't know.
Maybe they're my mom's.
- Have you brought girls here?
What do you want me to say?
- Well, if you did,
I'd like you to say yes.
- We were allowed to.
- Like, your parents met them?
- It's their house.
- You introduced them?
You were, like,
dating these girls?
You had some sort
of sustainable-
- I don't think we should
be doing this.
- No, I'm sorry, Daryl.
You brought them home.
Did you tell them
they were beautiful or special?
These girls probably thought
you cared.
Or did you?
I slept with Turner.
- That is so fucking immature.
You're saying that
because you're hurt,
and you want to hurt me back.
Well, what the fuck did you do?
- I didn't like it.
- Well, that's too bad.
'Cause I did.
- Then what are you
still doing here?
I guess this has been
kind of the goal, right?
So this is where
we were headed anyway.
- I'm not gonna do it.
- It's okay.
I'll do it for you.
It's over, okay?
Is everybody clear?
Are we all fucking clear
on that?
- Next year in Jerusalem.
Sorry about that.
I just don't know
what's going on with you,
and it's made me kind of crazy.
- So have you heard from D?
- No.
Why don't you call him?
I hear the girls
are doing it nowadays.
- No.
I don't think I can do this,
Mom.
- Yes, you can.
You'll get used to it.
Then you'll start over.
I'm here for you, Zo,
even when I'm not.
- I think that's everything.
- Okay.
- I put your night guard
in there.
- I need that.
- Yes, no grinding.
- Mom would be mad.
- Mm-hmm.
- Oh.
I want to give you this back.
- It's for my new boyfriend.
- I made copies.
- Hey, remember the time
that we broke up?
- Heyo!
Good one.
- Yeah.
Anyway.
- Here, come here.
- It's hard packing
for yourself.
Makes you appreciate Mom.
- I don't have her superior
spatial relations.
- No.
- Brian got that.
You know she's sorry.
She's told me to do plenty
of things over the years.
- I know.
- And you know what?
99 out of a 100,
she was right.
- Yeah, just ask her.
- Come on, best decisions
I've made were hers.
- Yeah, but Dad,
you're not happy.
- Happy enough.
- Oh, it's a pretty day for it.
Honey, I want you to call us
the minute
that your plane lands.
Thank you.
- Okay.
- I love you.
- I love you, Mom.
- We're proud of you.
- Wait a minute.
- What?
Come on.
Put that away.
- It's important.
Come on.
- Thank you.
- Oh, you're never gonna get
a cab here.
- Just wait a minute.
He'll be all right.
- You think?
Why don't we walk down
to the avenue?
- Okay.
- # I picked a color long ago #
# To suit my tawdry tales
of woe #
# And now it doesn't fit #
# Well, my friend
who's a fan of shades #
# Traveled to the Everglades #
# And asked if I'd come with #
# There's no one
I would rather see #
# She's a special friend to me #
# But I feel
I'd be leaving you behind #
# That's the game
of love and war #
# Choose a side
you're fighting for #
# And see if there's
a white flag to be raised #
# I know it's not
a fair assessment #
# But I can't be asked
to wrestle with the colors #
# Of who you've now become #
# 'Cause you and I,
we're not the same #
# And neither can be
held to blame #
# It's just the way
the story has to end #
# Being here and being there #
# There's no space
for being where #
# I feel I should be #
# Loneliness is like a drink #
# You think you're on the verge
of sinking #
# When you tame the sea #
# Interims are good
for suckers #
# Feeling like they're down
on luck #
# And I'm not gonna drown
in my own tears #
# I can't ask you anymore #
# To be the one that I adore #
# Only when the time
is right for me #
# So let's just be #
- # Baby, baby, baby, please #
# Baby, baby, I'm on my knees #
# You're hot as hell #
# I'm gonna freeze #
# Baby, baby, baby, please #
# Baby, baby, baby, stay #
# Baby, baby, I'm afraid #
# The pillow's cold
where your head used to lay #
# Baby, baby, stay #
Oh, girl.
You know I miss you so much.
I think about you at nighttime
and the morning time too.
I don't know
where you've gone to,
and I don't know
if you're coming back.
I wish I would just
hear from you.
Until then, I just gotta...
I gotta sing.
# Baby, baby, baby girl #
# Baby, baby,
you rock my world #