-  Okay.
Okay.
-  You ready for mine?
-  No growling,
it's gonna freak 'em out.
- Oh come on, a little spook
here and there builds character.
I could barely breathe in this thing.
-  You ready?
- Yeah.
- Okay.
-  What was that?
- I want ice cream for breakfast too.
- Eh, maybe on your birthday.
Ready?
- Happy birthday baby.
- Thank you.
- You sure you got this?
- You go enjoy a relaxing day with Jada.
I'll make sure these mutants
get to where they need to be.
- Right on schedule.
Is she on her way?
- Sure is, boss.
And I've got my two partners here
skipping school to help daddy.
- Jada, it sounds like you're in the car!
- Hey little ladies.
I can't wait to see you guys tonight.
- Hey, you sure you got her
busy until five p.m., mamie?
- Who you think you talking to, papi?
- The car!
- All right, well then
I'll see you tonight, jefe.
Hey, Greecie!
- Don't call me that.
Hi sweeties, you two feeling party ready?
- They sure are.
- I can pick them up after school
in case you need some extra time
to figure out what to do with all this.
- Well, actually Greecie,
the girls are feeling sort of sick.
They've got a case of
I-wanna-plan-mommy's-birthday-itis.
- That's hardly a reason to skip school.
Careful George, in case
they don't get an education
they might turn out like you.
- Well actually, Greece bag, I didn't ask
for your permission now, did I?
But if you want you can check up on them
at around four p.m.
before the big surprise.
- I'm the princess!
- Bye Aunt Greecie.
- Hey, Greece bag, get excited!
This is a party you're
actually invited to.
-  Just rip it open.
-  No way, look at
how pretty the paper is.
- You're giving me anxiety.
I will bring you a whole roll later
if you just put me out of my misery.
- I'm almost done.
Oh I love these!
Thank you so much.
- So how's the book deal coming along?
-  Well, you have to have a book
to have a book deal.
We're gonna have to start buying
the cheaper toilet paper.
- Should I sound the alarm?
- No, I trust him.
He's good at what he does.
I trust his process.
- And George always delivers.
- With a little help from his friends.
- I mean what kind of friend would I be
if I let you wipe your ass
with cheap toilet paper?
Just let me know if you ever need any.
- Thank you.
- Hey, I mean I can't let you have
toilet paper crumble all
on your booty cheeks.
- Oh.
Maybe it's time for me
to try something new.
- Woohoo!
I made it.
Happy birthday, my love.
- Thank you.
Oh whoah.
- Oh my god.
Why do they smell like that?
- Shut up.
- How long have you been
wearing those socks for?
- What was that for?
- A little holy water, disinfectant.
- Wow, woo woo!
Thank you.
Let's do karaoke.
- Yeah right.
You know I can't do that.
My babies are making me dinner.
- Well your biggest baby
should be throwing you a party.
He's had plenty of underemployment time
the last few months.
- Can I just pull the birthday card
and ask you to shut up?
- Yeah, drop it, Griselda.
- Thank you.
- Oh.
Thank ya, Jada.
- My treat.
- All right.
Sweet, thanks.
I start paying student loans next month so
it's going straight in the piggy bank.
- Okay.
- Are you sure you don't wanna come over?
- No.
- I'm having a beer for dinner.
- Well thank you for today, my loves.
- Hey, cheers!
- Yup.
- Oscar-worthy?
- Overkill.
Now, let's go see if George
knows how to throw a party.
- Shh, shh, shh.
Shh, shh ,shh ,shh.
- Baby, baby.
- Hey babe, I'm less than a minute away.
- Less than a minute away?
Oh baby I failed, you're
gonna beat us home.
Just stay out of the kitchen, okay?
The girls worked so hard on dinner,
they'll hate you if you don't wait.
- Okay.
I love you too.
See you soon, bye.
-  Keep walking.
- Okay.
- What you got on you?
- I have my wallet and
my keys and my cellphone.
I don't have any cash,
you can take everything.
- Shh.
-  Bet you got more at home.
- My family will be home any minute.
I have two little girls, please!
- Hurry!
-  Surprise!
- Is there any update?
- No, you know I can't tell you
until you fill out some of
this paperwork first, okay?
You have to have been
registered, we need you to--
- But do we know anything else?
Do we know when she's gonna wake up?
What's happening, is she out of surgery?
- The doctors are doing
the best they can, okay?
There's nothing I can tell you right now
other than we're taking
good care of her, okay?
And I need you to fill this out for me.
- So she's out of surgery.
She did lose quite a lot of blood.
As of right now we have
her in intensive care,
we're watching her very closely.
But as of right now, I'm
afraid she is in a coma.
- And now what?
-  We wait.
I'm very sorry.
-  All right.
Call me if you need anything.
- You sure you don't want me to stay?
- What?
-  Do you want me to stay?
- No, no.
We have to keep a strong
front for the girls.
They need to know that
she's coming right back,
no big deal.
Yeah, but I'll see you all
at the hospital tomorrow.
Yeah, yeah, okay?
Business as usual around here.
All right?
Yeah.
- Hey, you need a ride?
- Yeah, that'd be great, thanks.
Oh my god.
Thanks for the ride.
- Thanks for the company.
- You scared us with the loud music!
-  That's so mean.
- Breakfast time, baby.
We've got a lot to do today.
Today we're gonna go
decorate mom's hospital room.
Yeah, we're gonna grab
everything we can think of
that she would want over there
that would remind her of home.
That way when she wakes up she feels safe
and thinks of us.
Right away, okay?
- Okay!
- Ready, set,
- Go, go, go!
-  Jesus.
What's wrong?
- I can't sleep.
- Why is that?
- 'Cause of what if we
get shot like mommy?
- I'm gonna stay awake
until I'm sure that everyone
in the world is asleep
and no one is awake to
even think about it, okay?
- Will you come sleep with us?
- I'll tell you what.
I still have to vacuum the house
but I'll come check on
you when I'm done, okay?
- Okay.
- All right.
Oh, okay.
Okay.
And if you're still awake
I'll crawl in bed with both of you, okay?
- Okay.
Love you.
- I love you too.
- Okay.
Okay, okay, okay.
- Isabel, why don't you come here
and eat your pancakes at the table, mama.
-  I wanna sit on the couch.
- Okay, well if you get
any syrup on that couch
you're cleaning it.
- Nuh-uh.
- Yes-huh.
And not just the syrupy
spot, the entire couch.
- I can't, it's too big.
- Well I guess you better
find a carwash or something.
- That'll take too long.
- Well I'm not gonna help you.
So I guess you better get down here
and eat your pancakes at the table.
- Well look who arrived to bully my girls
early in the morning.
I'm glad you're here, buddy.
Hey, princess, you wanna
share your pancakes with me?
You can sit on my lap,
that way it doesn't
count as the couch, yeah?
-  You're the worst.
- Oh fuck!
Fuck, fuck, fuck, fuck!
Girls!
Up, up, up, up!
We're late, we're late!
Late, late, late, late!
Come on, come on, come on!
Let's go!
- Ow!
- Dad!
- Matilda!
- I have a test today.
Oh my god, I forgot!
- There we go.
-  It's too tight!
- All right, this one, this
one. Hey, hey, no, no, no, no.
Here we go.
All right.
- This one's too itchy, I hate this one.
- Pick whatever you want.
Perfect, perfect.
Yeah yeah yeah, come on, come on, come on.
All right, let's get out of here.
- I watched movies all day
yesterday like an idiot!
- Hey, don't call
yourself that.
- Oh my god,
I'm gonna fail.
Hey, that's my shirt.
- Daddy said that I could wear it.
- Matty, just this time.
-  Well I didn't, so take it off!
- No!
- Dad!
- Sweetheart, I'll buy you five more
exactly the same, okay?
- I'm not going because
Matilda is a meanie.
-  I don't have
to let you borrow it
if I don't want to.
- I don't have to like
you if I don't want to.
- Enough, yes you do and yes you do!
- You're a meanie.
- Go away.
I'm trying to study.
- And a dummy.
- Girls!
I think it's best that they
stay home with me today.
It's too soon.
We need a little decompressing time.
Yeah.
Thanks, Greecie.
Good breakfast?
- Yeah.
- Isabel, Matilda.
Up up.
Come on, girls, school.
-  Five more minutes.
- Five, okay?
Scoot.
Scoot, sweety.
Oops.
-  Can you give me reggae, Popeye?
- Here.
- Mmm.
Thanks, sweety.
So generous.
-  And who's gonna make me?
- Did you know your mom
hates getting flowers?
Let me tell you a little story.
So one year your mom is playing
Susie Snowflake in our Christmas musical.
Your dad over here, he shows up
with a big beautiful
bouquet of sunflowers.
Your mom sees them
and she is horrified.
But your dad's not a quitter.
So he shows up again on closing night.
But this time,
he has a basket of avocados.
- Avocados?
- Yeah.
- Flowers are prettier.
- Yeah but your mom loved her avocados.
- She takes the avocados
and falls deeply in love with your dad.
- We made beautiful guacamole that night.
- Daddy.
- I bet you did.
- When's mom gonna wake up?
-  Any day now.
- But how do you know?
- I just know.
I can feel it.
-  I miss her.
- I'm gonna go get some napkins.
- I miss her too.
- Dad?
I had fun today.
- Good, baby.
- Is it okay to have fun?
- Baby do you think your
mom would want to hear
that you had a fun day
or that you had a sad day?
- A fun day!
- That's right.
We have to have as much fun as we can
and stay positive
so we have all sorts of good stories
for mommy when she wakes up.
I love you both with all my heart.
- Hello, George, Matilda!
All right, that's perfect.
And, as a final special touch,
a magical butterfly!
There you go.
Perfect, let's see what you look like.
You look so pretty.
All right, you good?
Yeah, let's go.
Ugh, you have any idea how much
high fructose corn syrup
are in these things?
- What's high fructose corn syrup?
- It's something people talk about
to make other people unhappy.
- It's what your dad's
love handles are made of.
- All right babe, you made your point.
You can wake up now.
I'm getting a little mad about this
negative attention-seeking.
All right, then.
Call me when you wake up.
- Good morning!
-  Please, please, please.
Please stay, please.
- Come on.
- Please, pretty pretty pretty,
please.
- Well?
- Well, it's okay with me
if the three of you
wanna have a sleepover.
- Woohoo!
- But I need to get some sleep tonight.
I need to get some work done tomorrow.
- Woo!
- Party, party, party!
-  Party, party!
- Whoah.
Hey.
My goodness, look at you.
- Oh, I was just gonna tell you.
I'm taking the girls to school today.
And if it's okay with you,
I was gonna take them on
an after school girls trip.
- Sure, sure.
All right, well you three have fun.
I'll see you girls later.
Give me kisses.
Hello?
Yes, this is he.
What?
Yeah, yeah.
I'll be there as soon as I can.
That's him.
-  We need you to
fill out some paperwork
before you leave.
- I'm sorry.
- Let's go.
- Dad?
- Jesus.
I didn't think you were home, sweety.
I'm sorry.
- What happened?
- I dropped a glass.
Don't come any closer
with your socks, okay,
you're gonna cut yourself.
- Greece brought us home early
to get a start on dinner.
- Thank you, sweetheart.
- Are you okay?
- I am.
Are you okay?
I'm sorry I scared you Matty.
I know the last thing we
need is being spooked.
- I'm okay.
- Okay.
- Whoops.
For you!
- Oh my little girl!
So you're helping a lot, huh?
I know it might be a surprise to you
but I've been alone with my kids before.
- Okay.
- I appreciate you making dinner.
I know that your heart's
in the right place.
- Can you just swallow your pride
and let me make dinner in peace?
- Pride?
This isn't a pride thing.
Come on, you can barely
take care of yourself.
- She's my sister. I need to
make sure the girls are okay.
- Greece!
I don't want to have
dinner with you, that's it!
Hey, what happened?
Are you okay?
- I killed the bees, I'm a killer.
Mommy would be so mad.
- No, no, no, no she wouldn't.
No she wouldn't, sweetheart.
Come here.
It's a mistake.
It's just a mistake, okay?
It was a mistake.
You didn't do anything wrong.
Lord, may these bees have a home
to arrive to in heaven.
May there be many flowers
surrounding their hive
and may they make honey
if it makes them happy.
- Amen.
- I forget you know all the same stuff,
grew up in the same house
and buried the same roadkill.
- Our mom was a firm believer
that every animal deserved
a death of dignity.
She cried at every burial.
Her words were always so beautiful.
- Well I'm glad you were here.
Thank you.
- You're welcome.
- And, I'm sorry.
- It's okay.
- Hey babe, how you been?
Ah, really, that's great.
You know I really wish you'd
start thinkin' about waking up.
Matilda's smoking meth again.
Isabel's pregnant.
- What, nobody sleeps in on Sundays?
- Good morning, bumeroo.
Can I help you with any homework
after brunch, Matilda?
- Nah, I'll do it tonight.
Dad and I are gonna go play some soccer.
- Yeah.
- Maybe we can save the play
for after we finish your homework.
-  Okay.
- Hey, you don't have to do
what she tells you, sweetheart.
I'm the boss around here.
- It's the last week of school, right?
You can play soccer all summer.
Will it kill you to finish
your homework first now?
- No.
- Yeah, that's right
baby, it won't kill you
so you might as well do it.
But that's an unreasonable
decision making tactic.
You shouldn't do something
because it won't kill you.
- Here he goes.
- If your Aunt Greecie ate dog food
it wouldn't kill her.
- Yeah, that's true.
I mean we all eat your
cooking, we're still alive.
- Well come on girls, come on.
Goal!
- Hey, can I join in?
- Yeah.
- Sure thing, Captain.
- Be on my team, Jada.
- But only if you convince Isabel to play.
Yeah, you baby.
Yeah, come on.
- Come on, Izzy.
Come on Izzy.
Izzy!
We could play your dad three to one.
- All right.
He's running with the ball.
Aw!
Ah, no!
Oh, corazon!
Yeah, woo!
Go, go, score the goal!
-  Score the goal!
- Ah, ah, go, get it, get it, get it!
But you're tiny, you can get that.
What, ah ah ah!
Goal!
Goal, goal, goal, goal, goal.
Ay!
- I'm a fast little girl!
- Over here!
Over here, pass it to me!
Pass it to me before I die.
We scored, right?
Yeah, yeah.
Oh boy.
- Can I help you?
- Go inside.
- Go inside, girls.
George?
- Go inside, go inside.
- Whoah, whoah.
- George?
George!
George, what are you doing?
- Oh shit!
- Wait, what are you doing?!
George, George!
Stop, stop it!
Stop, stop, let him go.
Stop it, George.
You're all right.
It's okay man, chill!
Chill.
It's okay.
Just breathe.
- What do you think my
dad said to those boys?
- Probably just told them to beat it.
- So embarrassing.
- A good dad's job is to be embarrassing.
- Why didn't you play?
- I'm more of a theater kid.
You know, sports were
never really my thing.
- My mom plays.
Hmm, played.
She was coaching me for soccer tryouts
and now I'm not gonna make it to the team.
- I bet Jada can coach
you until she wakes up.
- That's okay.
- Why not?
She's a way better player
than your mom anyway.
- Don't say that.
- Why?
Matty, you know I love
your mom with all my heart.
You know what?
- What?
- She's not a very good player.
She lived on the bench.
We used to go watch her
play when I was younger
just to be sitting on different benches
watching the other kids play.
Matty, you can't put your life on hold
until she wakes up.
You gotta keep doing the best you can
and being the happiest you can be
so you have stories to
tell her later, okay?
- It's just that I'm so
scared she's gonna die.
- Your mom's strong.
I've got all my money on her.
She's not going anywhere, okay?
Come here.
- Thanks.
Thank you for everything.
-  You're losing it, man.
- Yeah I'm fucked.
- No.
- Yeah.
- No, you're not.
- I don't know.
- Look, you're gonna be fine.
And Robin's going to be
here before you know it.
But in the meantime, you
need to control yourself
because she's not here
to bail you out of jail.
- You'll come through.
Huh?
- Yeah, I always do, don't I?
- Must be my charm.
- If anybody can get by on charm alone
it is definitely you.
- No, if I get by, I get by
because I'm Robin's husband.
You take that off the table and
there's not much left.
- Just hang in there, buddy.
She's on the way, I know it.
- Yeah, yeah.
Yeah.
- What's going on out here?
- Well, it's been a pretty full night.
Bedtime for me.
Good night, ladies.
- Actually, do you mind if I stick around
and go through Robin's closet?
I need to borrow something for a dress.
-  Seriously?
- What?
She's not dead, I can borrow something
from my sleeping sister.
-  Whatever.
- Good night.
- Thanks for taking the girls.
- Of course, of course.
- Could have been bad.
- Let's not talk about it.
- That one's one of my favorites.
- I know she loves
Robin and she means well
but I just feel like Robin
wouldn't feel very comfortable
with you and Jada drinking
late at night on her porch.
- You think she'd feel
comfortable with you and I
picking through her closet
together late at night?
It's all circumstances, game-changer.
It wouldn't be happening if she were here.
- Got anything stronger than beer?
- Okay, come on.
-  George.
- Bron?
- Jesus fucking Christ,
Greece, take that off.
- Oh, George, did I really scare you?
Sorry.
- George.
This is the worst thing you
can be doing for yourself.
- Did you sleep in your clothes?
Ew!
- Yeah, ew.
- You slept in your clothes too?
What's wrong with you people?
- All right, one last kiss, princess.
You too, grouchy pants.
I'll spend some time with you later, okay?
- Okay.
- Special date.
-  See you three later.
-  Bye.
- Can one of you go ask Jada
if she's making breakfast.
- Kay.
- Doesn't she look pretty?
- You look very pretty, mommy.
- She can't hear you.
- Hey, we don't know that.
We don't know if she can hear us or not.
We might as well talk to her,
not about her.
Just in case she can, right?
You look very pretty, my love.
Hey why don't you tell mom about the game?
- Dad beat up some kid across the street.
- No, no, no, no, not that part.
No, don't listen to her babe, she's drunk.
- Okay, one more and you're all set.
- Matilda!
Where's your sister?
If you find her before
she steals everything
we'll all get ice cream.
- On it.
What are you doing?
- Nothing, nosy Rosie, go away!
- Isabel.
- Leave it, it's for mommy
for when she's hungry if she wakes up!
She likes them, remember?
- Isabel, I don't think
this is a good idea.
Mommy might not wake up for a long time.
- How long?
- No, don't cry.
Don't cry, I mean like
avocados go bad really fast, right?
Yeah, like in one day.
So if mommy doesn't wake
up till after tomorrow
she's gonna think you
left her a rotten avocado.
- It will rot?
- Yup, really fast.
But I promise, right when she wakes up
we'll bring one for her, okay?
- Okay.
- Hey, dad said we're getting ice cream
on the way home.
- Ice cream!
- Wanna share it?
- Hand holding?
Maybe we'll even get some cookies.
Gimme a kiss.
Ay, cara, get here!
-  Daddy, stop it!
- George, Matilda.
Matilda.
Where are they?
- We made it through another day.
- Don't trip on your way in there.
- Bye, Jada.
- Bye, shorty.
- No, it's fine, it's totally fine.
We will just eat these tomorrow.
I just wish someone would
have called me first, but,
it's totally cool.
- Of course.
Whoah, whoah, whoah.
What are you doing?
-  Hey, what's going on?
- What are you doing, J?
- I've been just
organizing your bookshelf.
- What was wrong with it?
- I just noticed it was a little messy.
- Messy because Robin likes it messy.
She spends hours and hours making it messy
because that's how she fucking likes it.
She likes to stack things differently
and have them sticking out
because that's how she likes it.
- George, I'm sorry, I didn't realize.
I can put it back.
- What were you gonna do, rearrange them
by height and color code them?
Why?
- George, I'm sorry.
- Why?
- I was just trying--
- What are you gonna do,
her closet next?
- Jesus George, I'm sorry.
I was just trying to help.
- What, doesn't anybody call anymore?
Doesn't anybody fucking knock?
Nobody fucking cares about
personal space or alone time?
- Wait, okay.
- No, it's a fucking free for all!
- What the hell are you
talking about?
- My life!
My personal private life!
- Don't talk to me like that.
I was just trying to
help out around here.
- Dammit, it's smothering!
I can't even spend a
fucking second by myself.
I can't even have a fucking moment
with my own goddamn kids!
- Whoah, I love your kids.
And I just don't want
them to feel the imbalance
of Robin being gone.
- But what, do you think that I've
never spent time with them alone?
What, you think that I replace Robin
every time she leaves the house?
No, I'm their fucking dad!
- I didn't know you felt like that.
It's just been nothing but
fun and games around here.
- What are we even fighting about?
The kids aren't even here.
The kids aren't here.
So why don't you just leave?
Look, I get it, I get it that you love 'em
but just fucking leave and
come back when they come back.
Ah, Jada wait, ah fuck,
I'm such a fucking asshole.
I'm sorry.
- Fuck you, George.
I thought you wanted me here.
You don't get to feel sorry
after hurting my feelings.
You're fucking insane, you know that?
- Look, I do, I do want you here.
Just not all the time, okay?
And yeah, yeah I'm not myself.
I'm not thinking straight anymore.
I've lost my mind.
I haven't settled.
- Well, fucking settle.
- I do want you here.
I do want you here.
- George.
-  I do.
I want you here.
- Hey Robbie.
I keep thinking the more often I come
the better chances I have of being here
when you wake up.
The girls are doing good.
We're all hanging in there.
Got you these.
Figured in case we're not here
when you wake up,
you won't have to wake
up to these ugly things.
This really sucks, Robbie.
This really sucks.
-  Dad, let us in, I have to pee.
- Hey.
- Get in there, go, go, go.
-  I've got mac and cheese.
- Mac and cheese.
- Let's drink whiskey.
- Not tonight, Greece.
I really need to read all
the shit that I wrote today,
make sure this book
doesn't sound like I feel.
- Why don't you read to me?
Seriously.
I just spent a 14 hour day with two kids.
I could use some adult time.
And I'm a great listener.
- All right.
But I wanna make it clear
that I don't want your feedback.
You still with me?
That's about as far as I've got
before the story starts skipping around.
You know, a lot of gaps to fill.
- It's great, George.
- Yeah?
Well I'm glad you think so.
It's nice to hear it through your ears
and get a sense of your reactions.
- Martina is an asskicker.
- Ah yeah.
She has a lot of your sister in her.
I have one hell of a muse.
- You sure do.
- Greece, what are you doing?
- What do you mean?
- Look, I think you're
a little drunk right now
and if you want, you can stay the night
but I'm gonna go to bed now.
- What are you talking about?
- This footsy leg thing you're doing.
- Wait, what?
It wasn't sexual, if that's
what you're thinking.
What, you think I'm hitting on you?
- No, Greece, I'm not saying that, okay?
But whatever this, whatever this thing is,
it's not what we've ever been together.
It just doesn't feel right.
- I can't control whatever nasty thoughts
are going on in your head
but you're not gonna pin this on me like
it's something I did.
- What's for lunch?
- PB and Js.
- Ugh, I don't want that.
Daddy, I don't want that!
- Well that's what you're getting ,sweety.
- Why?
- Because I don't have
time to cook, sweetheart.
Dad has to work.
- We can call Jada to come cook for us.
- No.
- Why not?
- Because it's disrespectful to call her
just to come over and cook for us.
And it's Saturday, she has plans.
- How do you know?
What about Aunt Greecie?
- We're not calling Greece or Jada.
We're having PB and Js, that's that.
Am I clear?
- We don't want to stay and eat sammies.
It's boring!
- Why can't they just come pick us up?
- Because I say so!
And because your mother's in the hospital
and this isn't a vacation, okay?
You don't get to party everyday
because your mom's in a coma!
Now have a little respect!
- Sorry, Daddy.
- No, I'm sorry, sweety.
I'm sorry.
What you doing there, Izzy?
- Just dancing.
- Just dancing?
Ah, you know I think I hear it.
- No!
- No.
- No, I know, I know.
Of course it's not that one.
I know it's not that one.
It's this one.
- No.
No.
- I know, I'm sorry.
I'm just trying to confuse you guys.
Hello?
-  Hey.
- Hey, I just put the girls down,
do you think we might be able--
-  I'm outside, George.
- Of course.
Of course you are.
All right, I'll be out in a minute.
Hey.
- I'm sorry.
- It's as much my fault.
I'm not in a good place.
I love her with all my heart
and she's not gone, she's not gone.
- I love her too.
- Come here.
- God, them.
- But I think we're gonna be okay now.
Hey.
You're still my bro, J.
- Well, that's a relief.
I'm gonna give it a few days before
I come pick up the girls.
- Yeah, a little breathing
room would be good, yeah.
- Yeah.
- All right well, see you later, champ.
-  You got it, slugger.
- Hey, what are you doing?
- Why?
- Hey.
- Why?!
Hey, hey.
- Why, why?
Tell me why!
- Hey, hey!
The kids!
What are you, fucking insane?
- Fucking cheater!
- What?
-  You fucked Jada.
- You don't know what
you're talking about.
Jesus, Greece!
-  Dad?
Dad, it's the hospital!
Mom's awake!
- Matilda, get your sister.
-  Get up, Izzie, mom woke up!
-  She's awake, let's go see her!
- Fuck!
Fuck!
- Hold it.
We have to be gentle with mommy.
- It's okay.
Come here, my sweethearts,
I wanna hold you so bad.
Ah, my babies.
My beautiful little girls.
Come here.
- Are you looking at me with
those big eyes of yours?
Isn't she so pretty?
- The prettiest.
- You are the princess.
- Ah, I get to be the princess.
Wow, aren't you sweet.
- Go see mommy.
And be nice to each other
or she'll go back into a coma.
- No she won't, stop lying!
- Hey babies.
- Hi, mommy.
- Hi.
- Hi, how are you?
- I'm breaking a sweat
but I'm happy to be awake.
Hey, you guys wanna see something?
Okay.
-  Mom!
- What?
- Your booty.
-  You saw my little booty?
- All right now girls,
let's remember we have to have fun
a little bit at a time, okay
so we don't tire your mom out too much.
- Ew, mommy!
- Wow, I don't think I've
ever made a noise that loud.
- Do you girls wanna help me
take the bag out to the car?
You wanna help your mom
do that?
- Yeah.
- Yeah, sure.
-  Thank you.
- Hi.
I'm here to see Robin Miller?
- Oh, she'll be out in just a minute.
You can wait for her over there.
- Okay, thanks.
Oh my god.
I love you, I'm so happy you're awake.
- I'm happy I'm okay too.
Happy I was so missed.
Hey, hey, hey, none of that.
- I know, I'm just, I'm so...
- Are you okay?
- Yeah, I'm just so happy you're back.
- Hey.
Car's ready.
Let's get you home.
-  Where's Jada?
- Ah, couldn't make it.
Some kind of work thing.
She said she'd call later.
-  Some sort of
work thing, seriously?
-  Yeah, she'll come over soon.
You okay?
- Yeah.
Oh my god, can we stop and get soft serve?
Chocolate soft serve, I need it.
- You got it, baby.
- Okay.
- Shh.
- Are we ordering pizza?
- Pizza, pizza, pizza!
- Why don't we ask your
mom what she wants to eat
since she's been eating
through a tube for months?
- You monster.
- Pizza, pizza,
pizza, pizza!
- Pizza?
Ooh, I don't know.
I'm sure that there's
something in the fridge
that we could heat up!
- No!
- Jesus Christ there are a
lot of leftovers in here.
Okay.
Oh, no.
Oh, not ready for that yet.
People been bringing you leftovers, baby?
- It was mostly Aunt Greece.
-  Oh was it?
- Yeah, she was unstoppable.
We can throw it all out.
- Hi, I'd like to order
a medium cheese pizza
and a large Hawaiian.
Is it grossing you out?
- Not at all.
You know, when I saw him
he looked like a little boy.
I was expecting a man.
I remembered a man, in fact.
But then I saw him looking so scared
saying bye to his mom.
Just a goddamn kid.
- I never really got to
look at him, I guess.
- Careful.
- Okay.
- I don't feel anything but overwhelmed.
When I think too much it
just makes me wanna puke.
- Hi.
- Look at you.
- Come in, come in.
Oh, careful there.
You got to remember I'm
a delicate flower now.
- Oh, of course.
That was stupid, I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
- It's okay.
Okay, cut it out.
Just get in there and
make me some breakfast.
- How about an omelet?
-  Perfect.
- Oh, sweetheart.
Shit!
- Sorry.
Sorry, I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
Sorry.
- I got it.
- I'm so sorry, what a mess.
- Hey, no big deal.
- Why don't I go buy breakfast?
I'm too much of a klutz
to cook anyway.
- Whatever.
I saw the mountains of
leftovers in my fridge.
I know you know your
way around my kitchen.
- Breakfast sandwiches?
-  Hey, hey, hey relax.
- I'll see you in a little bit.
-  What's with her?
- Not a clue.
- And what's with you?
- Me?
Nothing.
I'm a happy man.
- Maybe if you'd seemed
less upset about the glass
she wouldn't have felt so bad.
- I don't think Greece would get worked up
over broken glass.
- Oh?
Then what is it that my
sister gets worked up over?
Come here.
Give me a kiss.
-  Hey babe.
- Hey.
Oh god, I'm so glad that you picked up.
Why aren't you here, what are you doing?
-  I'm an asshole.
I just had a lot of work things.
I'm so swamped.
- Swamped?
Are you fucking kidding me?
Get your ass over here, I wanna see you.
-  First thing tomorrow, I promise.
- Jada!
-  It's so good to hear your voice.
It sounds different, you know.
Kind of like you haven't been
using it a while or something.
- Are you okay?
Are you crying?
-  Yeah, it's cool.
I'm a mess.
- Can you please come over?
-  Tomorrow, I promise.
-  Mom?
- Two minutes, hon bun.
Oh come here.
Were you two tidying the bookshelf?
- No.
- Was it you?
It might have been Jada.
I don't remember.
- Seems like it was easier to get her here
when I was in a coma than
it is now that I'm awake.
- Can I help you, ma'am?
- Why yes sir, I seem to
have misplaced my sock.
Mm, yes, that's the one.
No!
No, no, no.
No, I'm gonna pee.
Oh, I'm gonna pee, stop!
Okay, oh.
I'm gonna pee.
-  Baby.
- Come in.
I had an accident.
- Guess you did.
Girls are ready.
- Okay.
- God, it's good to have you back.
- Is it?
Say it again.
- Best thing that's ever happened to me.
- It's such a strange feeling knowing
that things have happened
past my last memory.
I mean, everything feels alien and
the furniture has had
more experience than me.
I feel just,
far away, I guess?
- I'm sorry that you're having
an emotional experience
with the furniture.
- It's strange, okay?
I don't know how to explain it.
I don't know who's been in my house
or sat in my chairs or
eaten off my spoons.
I don't even know who's
been holding our kids.
And I don't wanna hear about it,
I just wanna know.
- None of it matters.
It was all awful.
Life without you is no life.
-  Okay.
My neato burrito.
- Oh, scoot over.
This is the happiest I've
ever been in my entire life.
I'm never letting anyone leave this room.
- Well I think we should all go to bed now
and regroup in our happy place tomorrow.
Deal?
- No deal.
I don't wanna wait
because so what if you get shot?
- Hey.
No one's gonna shoot me.
And you should know that I am not scared
of bad guys, okay?
Not even a little bit.
And you shouldn't be either.
Okay?
- Okay.
Good night.
- Good night, baby.
- Good night.
- Maybe we should slow down a bit
and give you a little time
to settle in with family.
- Something doesn't feel right.
-  That's understandable.
- I don't think it is.
- What do you think it is?
- It'll be hard for me to
know that, wouldn't it?
- Hi, mommy.
- Hey baby.
Here for a late night visit.
Did you miss mommy?
- Yeah.
- Yes, good.
Hey baby?
Were Aunt Greece and Jada here a lot
when I was sleeping?
- Yes.
- Okay.
Who was here more?
-  I don't know.
But Aunt Greece was with me and Daddy
and Jada was with Matilda and Daddy.
- Did they spend a lot of time with Daddy?
-  I don't know.
- And did they ever sleep here?
-  Yes, a little bit on the couch
and a little bit with us.
- Okay, okay.
And what about Daddy?
-  He slept too.
- Okay, baby, okay.
Go back to sleep, okay?
- Hey.
Babe.
What's wrong?
You okay?
Hey, talk to me.
Baby, talk to me.
I love you so much, baby, please.
I'm so sorry, I'm so sorry.
Baby, I love you so much.
-  Oh God.
Our family.
- We still are.
We are a family.
It's you, me, our girls.
I was a dead man.
- Fuck.
I wanna leave.
- Yeah, we can leave.
We'll pack up and leave and come back home
when you're ready.
- Okay, can we go now?
-  Now?
It's five in the morning.
The girls are asleep.
You need to get more rest.
- I don't wanna stay
here and be like this.
I wanna leave with my family.
-  Okay, we'll leave now.
- Great.
Oh, shit.
-  There's no one here.
- What?
- No car, no one's in the house.
-  Where'd they go?
Ugh.
-  What are you doing?
-  Did you try calling them?
-  No one picked up.
-  Right.
- May you go with the lord.