They're all gone
Go over there
What's for?
Just go on
What the hell is it to you
if I go to the 'Ladies'?
You dare report me to the old woman
I didn't
I'll beat you up
Stop...
We can stop but from now on
you'll have to pay us 30 cents
protection money
Then we'll not beat you up
nor will anyone else dare, pay up
I have no money
Brother, that gang is bullying
Man Chai again
Let's take a look
What do you think you're doing?
What's up?
You bully him because you are outnumbered
He wanted protection money from me
just now
Kid, not even I have asked you lot
for protection money
and you dare ask him for it?
You must be tired of living
You dare to be a busybody here
I'll beat you up too
Stop, do you know who my father is?
I don't care if he's the governor himself
My father is known as the Uncle Loong
Did you know that?
Nope, although I've eaten
lots of loong ha (Iobsters)
Are you trying to insult my father?
Beat him up
Run, quick
Chase him, stop...
Stop, don't run...
Bastard, you dare hit others
You overturned my stall
You two bastards again
Bastard
If you have the guts look for me
at school tomorrow
Would I be afraid of you?
What's the matter, bluffing?
If you're still here we'll beat you up too
What's the big deal?
You kids fight all day
I'll tell your fathers
Please don't, brother Wang
We dare not next time
Yes we won't dare
Go on quickly
Goodbye
Da De, Xiao De
Are you two alright?
Yep. Would have killed them
if they didn't flee in time
Let's go
Do we have 5 cents, I'd like to eat
sweet beancurd
Where do we get money for it?
You spent the last cent this morning
Let's go
Xiao De
You must be enjoying huh,
we fought for you just now
and you're hiding here now
eating sweet beancurd
I'll treat you, then
What are you doing?
They asked you for 30 cents and now
you treat us to only 5 cents' won'th of
sweet bean curd
That's all I have, eat up
What's there to look at, go away
Pretty girl
Do you want to know the colour
of her panties?
Do you have the guts to ask her?
Never mind, how much do you have on you?
30 cents
Give the money to me
What for?
I'll make you a bet
I'll pull up her skirt for you
to have a look
Give me the money
Alright
Da De, your brother really has guts
Great fun
Sex maniac
You devil, pulling up my skirt
Stop
Are you shameless?
Policeman, he pulled up
my daughter's skirt
Arrest him
What's your name? Where do you live?
I'll report you to your school
What a bad kid!
Little tramp
Stop
Don't run
Xiao De, let's enter the city
You go that way
Stop
You're looking for death
Bastard
Mister, have a seat
I have no time, I have to work
Little brother, what's up?
Where's the policeman?
He doesn't have the guts to come in here
Bullshit. If not for me,
you couldn't have escaped
Go and look for ninth uncle quickly
Strip...
It's said, 'Touch a bra & you get
3 years' bad luck'
you touched the panties,
you'll surely have bad luck
for the rest of your life
Touch wood
Come out...
Please be quiet
I'm not performing this show
This show will be exciting
it features two lovers
Hold on to your tickets if you've got them
if not go and get them quickly
If you're not watching, please go
May I present Leung Shan Pak please
Come out quickly
Please
Your wife refuses to appear up,
speak to her quickly
Go quickly
No way, over my dead body
Not unless I'm dead
No, you're shameless, do it yourself
I'm not doing it...
What's to be afraid of?
I've got payment already
Let's pretend we're doing it at home
I'm not as despicable as you
You have to do it
No way, never
Where are you going?
To get Shing's wife
Forget it, he is way out of line
to force his wife to do such a thing
Forget it, find another one
Where?
Go and look
Friend, have you bought a ticket?
Yes
Go on inside
You two little devils
Ninth uncle
what are you doing here?
To see you
What for?
Have you eaten?
If not, eat with my dad
I have no time now, I'll go later
20 cents each
Thanks
Help, robbery
Robbery?
I have no money
Beat him
Help, robbery, I have no money
Run, quick
Kids...
This way please
A empty seat over there
4 bamboos
Eighty thousand
I win again
Sorry, pay up
You're playing a smooth hand
winning all the time
You've won a lot today
Not a lot, just having fun
Go and play at a bigger table
(bigger stakes)
No need, just having some fun will do
Friend, someone's waiting for you outside
I am winning now
He said it's urgent
Right, go and look
What for?
Don't worry
Ah Chu
Damn
What? Why are you treating customers
like this?
Customer?
You think I'm an amateur?
Why are you beating me?
Do you take me for a swindler?
If you can't explain, I'll make
this publicly known
Be careful
Shut up, we're going to fix you
You have no right to search me, let go
No right? This is our right
Stop
You've come in good time
If you can't find anything, it means
you're bullying me
Can one only lose but not win here?
Brother, we never bully anyone
and no one bullies me
Bastard, do you still deny cheating?
I have not framed you, have I?
You dare to
hold this in your mouth,
not a drop of saliva too
Enough...
Listen, don't ever let me
find you here again
or I'll maim you
Father
Kid, what are you doing here?
Get out
Ah Sing, give him some money
to visit a bone setter
My son
Father
I told you to get out, why are you
still here?
Where's your little brother?
Downstairs
Father, we're so hungry
Go down and wait for me
Xiao Li, I'm going to Mei Wa
to have a meal
look for me if there's anything
I'll wrap it for you
Give me ten cents to buy something to eat
Right, 20 cents would be nice
It's fixed
How smart
Quick enough?
Yes
Arert you afraid father would find out
you're wrapping cocaine for others?
Kids
Father
So quick
What are you all doing here?
Nothing
Hungry?
Yes
Let's go
Uncle Loong
How many times have I told you
not to set up your stall in front of
my entrance
Yes...
If I see you again when I return,
I'll burn it all
Get lost now
Mister, come over here
Kids, did you smell that?
Such a nice aroma
it will tempt even papa
Bastard, if I can't stand firm (tempted)
You're in trouble
Dad, you're joking
Let's go
Uncle Loong, have a seat
What's good to eat?
Naturally we have the good stuff
We've just cut up a small black cur;
plump and smooth
Have a catty
Dad, have two catties instead
Ninth uncle will come in a while
Two catties
Okay
Two more taels of "fox bone" wine
Right, dad?
Smart, coming
Dad, what happened just now?
That fellow wanted to be a cheat
Really?
At my dad's mahjong house?
He must be tired of living
Shut up
You two have finished school for so long
where have you gone?
A friend fell and hurt himself,
so we helped him
Right, brother?
That's right
You want to deceive me?
Have you been fighting?
No, father
Da De, Xiao De
Ninth uncle
Come over here
Make way... it's hot
Ninth uncle...
How's the shop doing?
Still the same
Let me
Dad, is the wine good for the kidneys?
Dad, Ninth uncle
if so then it's won'th a try
we want some too
Right, aunty Wa
No, you're under aged, no wine
I'm not doing it
Let me go
You can't hide forever
I'm not doing it
It's not up to you
Stop beating
None of your business
Beat you to death...
Beat me? Are you out of your mind?
Are you nuts?
You want to kill your own wife?
What a scumbag, only just now
he forced his wife
to host a real show at my place,
he is not human
You've lost everyone because of
your drug habit
Alright, you go back first
No way, never
Where are you going?
What do you want? What else do you want?
Nothing
She's my wife, I can do
whatever I like with her
How could you ask your wife
to do such a thing?
Why not?
If you paid me
I could ask her to sleep with you
Addict Shing
don't ever expect to get cocaine here
again
Let's not waste time on this bastard
a waste of our efforts, let's go
What are you looking at?
Look...
I'll take off my pants for you
to have a look...
Shameless
Damn
Dad, for you
Where did you get it?
You tell me
Quick
We saw a robbery just as
we finished school
and also saw a pack of cigarettes
on the ground
so little brother picked it up
What have I been teaching you?
You can't even look after you kid brother
and let him steal from a robbery
It's not my fault, he picked it up himself
You dare to answer back?
One should not pick things up
from the street
How many times have I told you
I told you not to run around after school
and yet you've come to the
mahjong house to look for me
Come here
Dad, I won't do it again next time
That's what you say each time
It's because I didn't study hard as a kid
that I now have to work in
the mahjong house
If you don't study hard
how could you have a career in society?
Get me my clothes
Wipe away the blood
Thanks, dad
Teach your kid brother to study hard
he's failed in a few subjects
according to his report
Yes
Luckily dad didn't beat me
Easy for you to say
You picked up the cigarettes
but he beat me
you failed and he scolded me
Take out your books and study
I think dad is over doing it
What's the use of studying so much?
Inside Kowloon Walled City
everyone knows my dad is Uncle Loong
When I grow up
I could get a job easily
Shut up and get your books out to study
or dad will beat me up again
when he returns
Alright
You take care the place
Uncle Loong, good morning
Good morning
Good morning, where's the money?
Here
Hurry up, we'll be late again
Look at your books, they're all in my bag
This is yours
There's more
I guess that punk wouldn't dare
beat me again today
He wouldn't dare
Of course
Kids
Father
Dad
Dad...
Don't run...
Don't...
Dead, what to do?
Dead?
What to do?
Father
Father...
Don't die... dad...
Dad, don't die
Get ninth uncle, quick
Get him quickly
Dad, don't die
Don't die
Dad...
Don't cry
Well, not bad, huh?
Xiao De, come on
you're not flying an airplane
if you crash, nothing I do can pay
for the damages
If we crash, you do us a favour to fix it
Don't worry as long as my husband
is driving
My wife knows me well
Good car
Of course, it's a Porsche
What' the big deal?
The car is great, but the people
in it are not
Sit tight
Look... there's a railing in front
How dangerous
Of course, this is mid-night Grand Prix
This I have to see
Come on...
I'm doing it right now
None of your business
Faster...
Look, so many people
Great fun, can't take anymore, speed up
Hope your car crashes!
Damn, I'm finished, this car's
a total loss
Don't be like that, there are people
around
Mr. Cheung, why haven't you
looked me up for so long?
Stop uttering rubbish
Didrt you say you have a new girl for me?
A new girl?
Girls these days don't know how to please
unlike us, who were so gentle
and beautiful
Unfortunately I'm ten years
older than you, or else...
Who's talking about age with you?
We talk about this now
Right...
Are you introducing me to the new comer?
Yes, let me think
Lily is too tall for you
And Mary? She is repugnant
don't get her
Mimi looks good but her figure is not good
Thanks boss
Cheung the great is calling you
What can I do for you?
I am taking all the girls today
except for her and her bunch
Thanks, mister Cheung
What's the big deal?
So lascivious and disgusting
Da De, do we have to start the show
later tonight?
It's about time, start as usual
Officer Cheung is waiting for you
inside the room
Thank you
Where's uncle Biu today?
He's gone to Singapore
and won't be back till next week
Oh man, I've got to hand it to him
He's over sixty and has a few families
how does he do it?
Uncle boasts of his figure
Officer Cheung, sorry
Excuse me
Enjoy yourself, we'll talk later
No problem
He says uncle Biu is good
I say officer Cheung is even better
Obviously
just look at his nose
Let's drink
Coming
Coming immediately...
Ladies, sit over there please
Go over there
Over there, see?
See how they are enjoying themselves
I'll have a little fun with them
Think of a plan
Right... let's release the air
from his tyres
That's childish, not much fun
Let's scratch his car
No meaning
Let's crash his screen
No, if we're caught
we'll be beaten to death
C'mon then, think of a way.
You do claim to be smart
That's because I love to eat
Never mind the bullshit,
think of another way
Damn, it's so frustrating
That guy was so detestable
He wouldn't buy more time with me
yet he wants me to have a late snack
with him
there wouldn't be much benefit if I went
right?
Mine's even worse, he bought two hours
and his hands were all over me
Why didn't you slap him?
I did even better, I touched him too
He would have died for that
What are looking at, bastard?
Don't recognise me?
Even a good man fears an abusive woman
What? You bastard
Have I stepped on your tail?
You have a cur's stinking mouth
You bitches, I'll give you a good beating
What? Would I be scared of you?
Forget it, sit down
Miss, I apologise
If you want to mess around, go home
Please, be quiet, forget it...
You dare mess with me?
Officer...
What's the matter?
There are two suspicious characters
over there
I don't know what they're doing,
please check them out
Where?
Over there
Take me to them
This deal could bring us lots of money
Right
Officer, here they are
Hurry, the police is giving out tickets
I'm sorry, Officer, I'm leaving
immediately
I am sorry
Big Brother
Who did this?
I don't know
Come, come over
Get hold of them
Stop, clear it up before you go
What fun!
That big-mouth bastard can't do anything
that was quite an exciting scene
What a thrill!
What's going to happen to him next?
Maybe he has to pay for the indemnity
or maybe he'll be taken to
the police station
Wait, can they identify us?
Hong Kong is such a big place
how could we be recognized so easily
Even if they did, what could they do?
TRUE
What's there to be afraid of?
Let's find some entertainment
Hurry
Get off...
Hurry...
This is a nice place
What are we doing here?
Barbeque? Tell me early
Barbeque? Screw you, eat them yourself
Ah Ling, let's go over there
We're leaving too
Alright
What about me?
You enjoy yourself
Don't dirty the car, make use of
the tissues in there
The tissues are too coarse,
you must be joking
Xiao De
What?
My period is late for 10 days
No way! You said it was your
safety period that day
Maybe it's because
you are not feeling too well. Right?
No. Don't
Don't
Let go of me
What are you doing?
No
No...
Don't stop
Hurry... Hurry
Hurry
Don't panic, I can't do it in a hurry
The condoms are all used up
What? I just bought you over a dozen
last week
and you've already used them all?
You bastard
You bastard asked me to give myself relief
It's you do it now
I don't want to tonight
But I do
Sorry to interrupt you
You haven't paid your tuition fees
and want to learn?
It's a fair world
Alright, each one will provide relief
for himself today
Damn it
Don't run
You should leave, your brother
is home already
I have to go too, dad will be back soon
Alright
Are you going to meet another woman?
You got it wrong, three a day
I'll take you back
You drink a lot tonight
Didrt expect you to be a strong drinker
You're not bad yourself
I couldn't get you drunk
It's a robbery, officer.
Shouldrt you make an arrest?
Not yet, wait until they've got the money
then we can catch them red-handed
or we can be sued for wrong accusation
Three hundred dollars only?
Give me the pearl necklace
No
It's from my Mom
Give it back to me
Don't move, or I'll shoot
They robbed me
Come over
Drop the knife
Damn, don't move
Officer, it has nothing to do with me
Come over
It has nothing to do with me
Beat you up
Go over there
Handcuff yourself
This is called caught in the spot
Da De, call the station for me
I'll handle the case here
Yes, Sir
Miss, are you alright?
Hot dumplings...
Give me one
Thank you
Hot dumplings...
Brother, you're back
Yes
Brother, have some dumplings
Keep it for yourself
Brother, you've bought one too
Yes
How can I have two?
I'll eat with you
Brother, I'll make some tea for you
Xiao De, how can you go to school
when you stay up late every night?
I've finished my homework at night
so I can sleep a bit more during the day
Brother, it's fun to have a
second-hand car
Do you have a driver's licence?
No, but I can drive
Wait until you get one
Don'tjust keep reading this stuff all day
pay more attention to your study
It's fun
The physics teacher saw you
and you didn't even know
Only you can think of such a thing
You are stupid enough
You should have someone on the lookout
How come you are so stupid?
Goodbye
My dear, you're so early
It's so rare
What is it?
What else? Must be total failure
It's no surprise
What do you want to eat?
Nothing
How about you?
Dear, have you really failed
in all subjects?
Take it out, I'll change them for you
Not this time
Dad will surely kill me
Don't cry, let's think of a way
What else can we do?
Don't be like that
Do you want to let the whole world
know about it?
What am I going to do?
What to do?
Had you listened to me
everything would have been alright
What has that to do with me?
Every time you say it's alright
Lower your voice, please
You've now made a mess
& want to blame it on me
Don't cry
What are you doing? You can shun
the responsibility
Stop shouting
What is it?
Having failed is no big deal,
why scold her?
Shut up, nobody will think you're dumb
He...
What is it?
Nuts
Hey kid
Tastes good huh?
Brother, do you recognize me?
We had a car race the other night
Which night?
Let me refresh your memory
Remember?
A little bit
Yes...
Where's that bastard who drove the car?
I don't know
Don't you know now?
Yes...
Where does he live?
I don't know
Where is he now?
Yes...
Will he be coming?
He...
Is he coming or not?
Speak up
Yes...
When?
Uncle, don't meddle in our affair,
alright?
Stop talking nonsense
Xiao De, run, run
Don't run...
Stand still
Are you blind?
Sorry, Sir
Sorry, Officer Cheung
What happened? You are more fierce
than I am
chasing and beating people in the street
That bastard fooled me
I don't care
Behave yourself
or I'll arrest you
It's not that serious, is it?
Behave yourself, go
Arert you leaving? What are you
standing here for?
What's the big deal?
You are all useless,
you can't even catch that bastard
Find him, or never see me again
No
Abortion is bad for the body
and is dangerous
I won't allow you to do that
Mom, what am I going to do now?
Mom
You dad is back now
clean up your face
I'll find a chance to talk to him
What are you doing?
Preparing dinner
Dad
Ah Ling, don't go back to your room yet
Sit down, let's chat for a while
How come you didn't go out today?
Your eyes are red, have you been crying?
What happened? Have you been bullied?
Tell me
It's nothing
Maybe the contact lenses don't fit
Nothing's wrong
Get a new pair if they don't fit
be careful not to hurt your eyes
Yes
Did the schools give out the
report cards today?
Yes
How did you do?
I'm asking you
Eighteenth
Not bad
Show it to me
Have some tea
Dad
Who's this guy?
A classmate
It's really my classmate
You lied to me
You two are too close to be
ordinary classmates
Speak, who is he?
Dad, no... dad
Are you telling or not?
Speak, who is he?
Why are you hitting her? Calm down
See how you teach your daughter
The poor girl could be cheated
in some days
and you are still kept in the dark
Mom, see for yourself
If he knew, he would surely kill me
Wait until he's calm, I'll think of
some ways
Go in
What are you doing?
Take him out, see how fast he can run
Go
Try to be cool?
Sit down
What are you doing?
Has this bastard committed rape?
No. He's running naked in front of
a girls' school
Officer, that's not true, I've been set up
Don't frame me
What, will the police frame
an innocent person?
We'll find out
Okay. Officer Cheung likes to have fun
with those punks
Alright, he's all yours
Okay
Officer Cheung is here
Stand here
Bring him out later
Officer Cheung, he's yours
Officer
What happened?
This bastard is blatant
Blatant? I'll teach him in his place
in a while
Come over
Officer
Go
What about him?
Bad conduct
This bastard ran naked in front of
a girls' school
Ran naked?
Kid, are you well hung?
No, Sir, I've been set up
Sir, your daughter and I are good friends
if you don't believe me, you can ask her
Kid, don't make some empty claims
What do you want?
Come with me
We are investigating this case
You can bail him out for the time being
Thank you
Ah Sing, is Chan Ka Cheong here yet?
Yes, Officer Cheung has taken him
to his room
Follow me
Alright
Brother
He is your brother?
Look at you. Very soon you could be
beaten to death
He's careless
Officer Cheung, you beat up
every suspect in each case
I just go by the book. You can file
a complaint, though
Never mind...
Make the necessary arrangements
for your brother, go
Wait
Ask your brother never to see
my daughter again
Brother, you have to trust me
Brother, listen to me
Brother, help me
You've to stick your neck out for me
on this one, bro
Stick my neck out?
If I stuck my neck out you will be
beaten to death
It's not my fault, that bastard
stripped me of my clothes and
shoved me on the street
Help me please
Why'd others mess with you
if you don't bother them?
How come no one has bothered to
take off my pants?
A naked Danish hen is hopping
everywhere, so disgusting
Do you agree?
So what?
I'll expose you for peeping at
your sister bathing
Alright, I will not talk
That big-mouth bastard is so arrogant
Ask your big brother to fix him
Nuts
If you want to fix him for
such trivial matters
then many other people would have
to be fixed
So you are letting this go?
Why bother my elder brother,
won't I do just as well?
Anything could be fixed except bullshit
Exactly
The truth is he dares not tell
his elder brother
You have a point
You insult me
You are good at insulting the people only
You bothered him while he was
taking drugs, right?
Go up and think of something
Well, any ideas?
You lot are so useless,
think of something quick
You guys are so frustrating
Let's douse him with urine
Let's make it worse for him
How?
Add some shit to the urine
Where do we find so much shit and urine?
We'll each contribute
Wouldrt that be enough?
No
Xiao De
Xiao De, I have a plan, it must work
Wait
Bring that big-mouth bastard back in a bag
Tie him up and feed him with cocaine
If he won't take, we'll surround
and smoke him with it
so that even by smelling, he'll get hooked
Wouldrt that be revenge for us?
You must be crazy, we will all get hooked
before he does
I grew up among drug addicts
how come I didn't get hooked?
Xiao De
Calling you?
You try to pick up girls like others
yet you create so much trouble, go on...
What is it?
Think
What are we going to do?
Let me think of something
You are procrastinating
Did you know that my mom knows
Your mom... how about your dad?
What difference does it make?
You've never thought about me
Xiao De, I've got an idea
Where's Ah Ling?
Don't bother with her, speak
Dad
Ah Ling, what's going on?
Nothing
Nothing?
You can't hide anything from me
since you were small
Tell me
Has someone molested you?
No, Dad
There must be something wrong, tell me
So, you won't speak, right?
That's fine, I can find out anyway
If I find out that kid has touched you
I'll break his bones
Dad, don't
You're nervous, something must
have happened
Have you been cheated?
By whom? Speak
Speak
No one has cheated me
Who cheated you? Speak
Why have you beaten her again?
It's not her fault
It's useless even if you beat her to death
she's pregnant for 2 months
Do you want to kill the baby too?
Bitch
Mom
Cheung Mei Ling
Who's Cheung Mei Ling?
Here
Go in
Go on
Quick...
Is it done? He's coming
Unless he's diabetic,
otherwise there'll be trouble
Is it working?
Yes
They are here
Have a seat
Brother Ching
The bill?
Here it is
Brother Ching
Coffee again
And you?
No
See if the amount is correct
The money?
Here it is
I don't want to drink this, you go ahead
He's not drinking it, what should we do?
Brother, I'm going first
Okay... let's go
Waiter, plain tea please
I got a idea
What's up?
Nothing, your tea is not hot enough
This would create a big trouble
We can't let him go no matter what
Stop nagging, get prepared quickly
Go on
Tea and milk
Thanks
Coming
Quick
What's the matter?
I can't hold back any longer,
please come out
Excuse me...
Come out quickly
Come out quickly, what are you doing
inside?
Come out quickly
I just came in
He's been in there a long time
Come out quickly
Quick...
Damn it
Come out quickly, someone's waiting
Come on out
You've saved even the room cost
Excuse me
Friend, are you finished?
So many people
I can't take it anymore
Make way
What? Go away
1, 2, 3, 4... 6, 7, 8, 9
The ninth
Done
Burn it shorter
Make a boat
Itjust like an aircraft carrier
Pour the gasoline in
That's enough
That bastard, I want to burn him to death
Too much
The more fire the better
Careful
With this fire we are avenged
That's right
Be careful, use matches
Hurry...
Hurry, be careful
If it's so much pain then stop it
You must be the one who set the fire
Not me
Bright moon shines on ground,
firering shines on ground
You bastards again
Don't run...
Help, a molester
Someone's molesting me
Help...
Make way
He's doing dirty deeds
What have you done?
Why are you doing dirty deeds?
Let go, go away, let me go
What have you to say for yourself?
Go away
Help, molester
Stop, go away...
He molested me
Stop running
Stop, or I'll beat him up
Isn't it fair, bastard?
Go away
There's no point talking to me
I must find my brother before
I can give you a reply
Alright
I am giving you face by talking to you
Listen carefully
If your brother don't apologize to me
by tomorrow
you'll die
Follow me
You have guts
How dare you bargain with my big brother?
Brother
We are specifically here
to apologize to Brother Ching
not to bargain with him
Xiao De
do you know the rules?
You mean...
There's seniority for everything
Be respectful if you're here
specially to apologize
Kneel
Wait
Before he drinks it, I have a condition
Speak up
Hold a feast
for these men of mine
to give them some face
Brother Ching, you have been given
due respect
we are all out here to make a living
let's drink tea and forget our grievances
If I just drink it
that's fine for me but not my men
Alright
If after you have drunk this cup of tea
any brother who is still not pleased
and wants more perks, he can look for
my Ninth uncle
He's your uncle?
Ninth uncle retired a long time ago
He won't want to be bothered by
our matters
We should give him face
Since he's your uncle, I'll drink it
It's hard to believe that the son of
Chan Yuan Loong, previous chief
of the Walled City
is kneeling and apologizing to me
Little brother
Don't mention my father
Don't move, let's talk this out
Xiao De, what else do you want to say?
You have guts
You...
Don't fight
Ninth uncle...
Uncle Jiu...
You guys brought weapons along with you
do you want to kill your uncle?
No...
Ah Ching
What have my nephews done
to incite them to fight each other?
Ninth uncle, he started it
What could I do?
Ninth uncle, he insulted my father
Yi Ching, doesn't matter who's right
or who's wrong
give some face to Uncle Jiu
For any problem hereafter look for
big brother and me
and we'll take care of it for you
Alright, since Ninth uncle is involved,
we'll let it go
Tell you nephew
not to meddle with me again
otherwise don't blame me for not
giving you "face"
Alright
Go
Ninth uncle, we'll be leaving
Ninth uncle, see you
Don't worry, it'll be alright
Ah Jiu, go and have something
to eat with him
Xiao De, you stay
Xiao De, do you realise
what your brother has done for you?
You've got yourself into big trouble
Never mess with them again
otherwise I won't be able to save you
Yes, Ninth uncle
Don't move, police
Officer Cheung, what's the matter?
Turn on the lights
Ask the person in charge to come out
Yes
Look around
Yes, you guys look over that side
Come...
Officer Cheung, what's the matter?
Spot checking
You should know better that
you can't do it here
I've talked to you on the phone
about Xiao De
How's it going?
I talked to his big brotherjust now
Let it go then
Chief, what have you got?
Most of them are juveniles
Please do me a favour
If I do, who's going to do me a favour?
How's it?
Alright
Let's go back
Go...
Havert you cried enough?
You're crying for an hour
Look at you, you look like a dirty cat
Who's going to marry you?
Disgusting
Why are you smoking?
It's been rotten luck these days
My brother doesn't help me
when I'm in trouble
I really wonder
whether we have the same mother
Xiao De
Big Brother, those bastards are up there
I want a leg of Xiao De, get it?
Go
That way
Don't cry...
Run
Don't run
Come out
Let go of me
Come here...
No
Come out
He is not here
Search everywhere
Don't cry, please
Nothing, look over there
Found anything? No
Nothing
That's weird, look over there
It's so dark
Ah Fu
What is it?
Look over here
Alright
I'll have a look
Come up here
Where are you running to?
Go
Don't run
Here
Hurry, run
Big brother
Break his leg
Attack
Xiao De
Xiao De, stop fighting
Run, hurry, run
Hurry
Ah Ling, come here
No, I'm scared
Hurry, they are coming
Help, Xiao De... help me
Hold tight
Help me, Xiao De
Xiao De, hurry and pull me up
Hold tight
Xiao De, help me
Ah Ling
Hurry, go
Ah Ling...
Ah Ling
Bastard
Xiao De, come out here
Xiao De, come out here...
Alright, stay in touch on the phone
Brother
What? Had a fight?
No, Ah Ling fell to her death
Mrs. Cheung
What are you doing here?
I've brought him to Officer Cheung
Let me in
Officer Cheung
Officer Cheung, I'm handing
my brother to you
Officer Cheung, today we are here
to give you an explanation
No more tricks
I must beat him up today
until you ask me to stop
What? Can't do it?
No, stop beating
I'll call the police if you don't
Don't mess with my affairs from now on
Are you alright?
I'll take you to a doctor
Brother Da De...
What happened?
Just now a gang came looking for trouble
even when I mentioned your name
they didn't back down
Brother Da De, we'll go and find them
Right
Da De, where have you been?
You see our club has been messed up
We couldn't even find you
When they came
they said they were here to
teach you a lesson
What was I supposed to do?
Didrt even know who they were?
Before going they said
their big brother was Yi Ching
Uncle Biu, I'm so sorry about the mess
I must leave
Brother Da De
You're suffering, I'll give you a shot
No...
What happened?
I'm asking you
Go away
What if I don't?
Don't move
You two brothers are equally low and mean
I'm charging you for unlawful
possession of weapons
causing injury to others
There's evidence, so you can't deny it
Our affairs should have all been settled
Shut up, this is official business
Da De, someone is here for you
Hurry and go
Ninth Uncle, thank you for visiting me
You asked me to look for Xiao De,
but I can't find him
Don't worry, I'll definitely find him
You've lost your family because of cocaine
If he won't take, we'll surround
& smoke him with it
so that even by smelling, he'll get hooked
I grew up among drug addicts
how come I didn't get hooked?
Still can't find my little brother?
He's nowhere to be found
Ninth uncle, I want to see him,
please help
Get into the car
Da De, don't you want to see your brother?
Get into the car quickly
Officer Cheung, for two?
You're free today?
Over here please
What would you like to drink?
Later
Alright
Where's my brother?
Be patient, we'll talk about it
after this show
What happened to you? Hurry
Hurry...
You think I'm cheap, I'll show you
how cheap I can be
Boss, leaving now? Come again
Who are you looking for?
Where's the one who performed with you?
That drug addict? He's in the washroom
Xiao De
Xiao De... what happened to you?
Why do you do that?
Say whatever you want to say
Xiao De
You can'tjust die like that...
You can't die like that, Xiao De
Xiao De, don't die
Alright, it's done
Don't move
Do you hear me?
Good, take him back
Officer Cheung, after months of
investigation we found
that you abuse your powers
for personal revenge
You tried to get Xiao De hooked
You know the law and you broke it
This is something that cannot be tolerated
I am sorry, I must arrest you now
Please hand over your pistol and badge
So you caused the death of my brother
Be calm
He will be judged
Take him back
Sir, there are dead bodies in the washroom
Call a car, leave two men behind
to finish the job
Yes
Take them away
Go...