More ancient than the earliest
records of Chinese civilization...
are legends.
Legends of great warriors,
of knights and wizards,
and mysterious monks
who could perform wondrous feats.
In these fabulous beings
was embodied the essence
of good and evil.
They had the power to fly
and the strength to defeat whole armies.
These fables thrived
until about 100 years ago,
and then a new legend was born.
According to the Chinese
astrological calendar,
1940 was the year of the dragon.
Bruce Lee was born on the
27th of November of that year.
The place was San Francisco.
His father, Lee Hoi-Chuen,
was a leading comic actor in Hong Kong,
and was appearing in a
touring Cantonese opera troupe,
something like the Chinese equivalent
of a vaudeville show.
His wife, Grace, who was half-German,
was accompanying him.
The tour over, the Lee family
returned to Hong Kong
when Bruce was 3 months old.
A family portrait
in their Nathan road flat
shows Bruce at the center.
Bruce considered his first film role
was in The Beginning of a Boy
which he made when he was six.
Two years later, he played a leading role
inMy Son, Ah Chung.
Much of the material
written about Bruce Lee
states that he never appeared
in films with his father.
These rare scenes from My Son, Ah Chung
prove the opposite.
Interestingly,
this was the first
of their films together
in which Bruce had a more
important role than his father.
The theme of this film was fairly typical
of many of the more than
20 he appeared in
before returning
to San Francisco in 1958.
InAh Chung, Bruce Lee is an orphan,
whose only education is
what he can find on the street.
Hey, you little brat.
Put that down, you!
Uncle.
In what is almost a preview in miniature
of a scene in Enter The Dragon,
Bruce picks up a broomstick and attacks.
Why did you hit me for?
Why did you steal?
It's not your business.
You're a thief.
I'll get you, you pig!
Now then tell me the truth.
Where were you last night?
Are you scheming against me, eh?
You little devil, you!
Are you going to tell me
the truth, are you?
Come along, speak up, I say.
Tell me the truth, you little devil.
You've been nothing but trouble
ever since you came here.
I'll see that you'll get a good fighting.
Oh!
You beat up my brother,
I'll chop off your head!
You devil!
I'll kill you.
How much of his own character
did Bruce bring to these roles?
And how much were his screen characters
beginning to infuse
into his own personality?
As time went on, Bruce would play
more and more of the kind of role
that could be described
as a problem youth.
Many of these reflected themes
of films popular in the
United States at the time,
films like Blackboard Jungle.
One of Bruce's films is
called Boys on the Street.
If we watch him closely
in the many street brawls
with which these films abound,
we can already see the beginnings
of the trademarks
of expression and gesture
which he would later make
so very much his own.
Yes, I got a big mouth,
but I can back it up with my fist.
You want to pick a fight?
You said it, you asked for it.
Hey, stop it.
Paper Tiger, after all.
Stop it, will you?
You kids shouldn't fight here.
This is my place, now get out of here.
Coward, I dare you follow me.
Hey, he took my box.
Get him.
Come on.
Hey, you!
These kids really have guts.
You want some more?
I took your shoeshine box to
get you your first square-off.
Now you know I mean business.
Come on, kids.
Come on, kids, let's go.
Oh, come on, let's go.
Snapshots from
the Lee family's photo album
show Bruce growing to be
a handsome young man,
with a normal interest in girls
and motorbikes.
Although he was bright,
Bruce was not a good student,
at least not in the scholastic sense.
He was more interested
in learning martial arts.
Bruce always maintained
that his first teacher was his father,
who was a devotee of the fighting forms
known as Tai Chi.
But his first real teacher was Yip Man,
a master of the Wing Chun style.
The roots of Wing Chun
reach back to the famed Shaolin Temple.
As this demonstration from
the filmWarriors 2 shows,
it emphasizes lightness and quickness
rather than power and strength.
Stretch out two fingers.
You must try to catch it
when I let it go.
Pick it up.
Do you realize why you can't catch it?
Because when your eyes see it fall,
your brain signals
your hand nerves to react,
but there's a delay.
So we're aiming to minimize that delay.
That's why Wing Chun concentrates
on touch and speed.
Practice, there's no other way.
The wooden man
is a Wing Chun training aid
used to develop quickness
and flexibility in attack.
Your enemy will not stand still.
Your reactions must be
one step ahead of his.
Otherwise you're dead.
Therefore, your fists have got to strike
with the speed of light.
Try again.
But kung fu was not Bruce's only interest
outside movies at that time.
He was quite a snappy dancer,
and in 1958, won a Hong Kong
cha-cha champion.
But somehow, even his achievements
on the dance floor led back to kung fu.
This is Siu Hon Sung,
another of Bruce Lee's kung fu teachers.
He explains how Bruce
negotiated a deal with him.
One day Bruce took me to a coffee shop.
He said, "You're a master
of your styles of gung fu,
and I'm a pretty good cha-cha dancer.
Why don't we do a deal?
You teach me gung fu,
I'll teach you cha-cha."
Now an average person
would take 3 to 4 weeks
to learn my basic moves,
but Bruce took only 3 nights
to master the moves.
So much for my cha-cha lessons.
Bruce didn't even give me time
to learn the basic beat.
The Orphan was the second last film
Bruce would make
before leaving for America.
In it, he played the most extreme
of his delinquent loner roles.
His final film in Hong Kong
was a complete contrast of The Orphan,
and to any role before or after.
The Thunderstorm
is probably the only film
in which he doesn't have
one single fight scene.
Although there are
confrontations in the film,
all the emphasis in The Thunderstorm
is on the character's refusal
to be drawn to fight
under any provocation.
This reluctance, at least initially,
was a character device
that would feature heavily
in all of Bruce's later films.
Mary.
Can I help you,
Mr. Chan?
Mary, mom knows you're leaving us.
It's hard to find jobs these days.
She wants me to give you $100.
Oh, thank her for me, please,
but I just can't take her money.
I'm really sorry about today.
My brother didn't mean it.
He's sorry.
I promise he won't do it again.
That's what he told me to tell you.
Don't apologize,
Mr. Chan.
Well, anyway, I'm not your maid anymore.
Mary, I've never treated you like a maid.
I'm your friend, Mary. Leave her alone!
Mr. Wong.
Sorry about today.
Chan, just leave my sister alone.
David, what's wrong with you?
Mr. Chan was merely
offering to help us out.
We're from a poor family.
My sister will marry
a simple working man.
Yes, cooking meals,
washing clothes, bearing children...
these are what she'll be doing.
Any thoughts of going to school
or marrying a very wealthy man
will just bring her disappointment.
That's only one way of looking at it.
I think... Chan, I'm warning you.
Warning? Yes.
If I see anyone from
your family seeing my sister
or coming to my neighborhood,
I'm gonna kill him.
David!
Are you out of your mind?
Mr. Chan, I think
you better excuse us.
All right.
Mr. Wong, I know
you dislike me very much.
However, I still want to be your friend.
Let's shake hands.
I don't follow foreign habits.
It is quite likely that
Bruce would've returned
to San Francisco anyway,
as he needed to do so
by the time he was 18
to confirm his American citizenship,
but the fact that things were hotting up
in his constant confrontations
with rival street gangs
and that his mother had
to stand guarantor for him
to avoid police prosecution
probably hastened his departure.
Bruce Lee took the next
steamer to the city of his birth.
On the way, he made a little extra money
giving dance lessons.
From San Francisco,
he moved quickly to Seattle.
A Chinese restaurant called Ruby Chows
provided him with accommodation
in return for work.
He served in the restaurant
and lived in the attic.
Once established,
a dramatic change occurred.
He enrolled in high school
and the school dropout
became a diligent student.
He still practiced kung fu passionately,
but not longer on other people.
Graduating from high school,
he went to university
to study philosophy.
His art teacher still treasures
two of the drawings he did at the time.
Bruce was a good student.
And his work with me
was always very ambitious,
and I've no doubt that he was
the same in all his classes.
For the ambitious Bruce Lee,
it was not enough to be
a good martial artist.
He had to be the best.
He taught kung fu
to a group of fellow students,
one of whom was a 19-year-old girl
called Linda Emery.
They were married
and moved into this small
but comfortable house.
The former bully and man about town
became the ideal husband and father
to Brandon and later Shannon.
A kung fu demonstration
at Long Beach in 1964
turned out to be one
of the most important events
in Bruce Lee's life.
It was seen by an acquaintance
of a television producer
who was looking for someone to play
Charlie Chan's number one son
in a proposed series.
A screen test of Bruce was arranged.
Tell us your name,
your age and where you were born.
My last name is Lee.
Bruce Lee.
I was born in San Francisco in 1940.
I'm 24 right now.
And you worked in movies
and pictures in Hong Kong?
Yes, since I was around 6 years old.
And when did you leave Hong Kong?
1959, when I was 18.
I see.
Now look over to me, Bruce, as we talk.
I understand you
just had a baby boy.Yeah.
And you've lost a little
sleep over it, have you?
Three nights.
And tell the crew what time
they shoot the pictures in Hong Kong.
Oh, it's mostly in the morning
because it's kind of noisy in Hong Kong,
you know, around
three million people there.
So every time when they have picture,
it's mostly, say around,
12 a.m. to 5 a.m.
in the morning.
I see.
Look directly into the camera, Bruce.
Directly at it.
And now give me a three-quarter this way.
And hold it.
And give me a profile
that way, all the way.
Good, hold it.
Now come back to a profile
on the other side.
Now hold that.
Give me a three-quarter on that side.
And then give me a right
into the camera again.
All right, now the camera will pull back.
And, Bruce,
first show me the movements
in the classical Chinese theater.
Classical Chinese theater?
Well, you know, what we
talked about in the office.
How they walk and how they start to move.
Well, in a Chinese opera,
they have the warrior
and then the scholar.
The way the warrior walk
will be something like this.
Walking this way,
straight, come out, bend,
straight and then walk out again.
An ordinary scholar,
will be just like a female,
a weakling, 90 pounds...
He'll be just walking,
you know, like a girl, real...
shoulder up and everything.
So by the way they walk,
you can immediately tell who they are.
Right. What character
they represent.
Now show us some gung fu movements.
Well, it's hard to show it alone,
but I will try to do my best.
All right. Maybe one of
the fellows will walk in.
Yeah, it would be...
Go ahead. Go ahead. Go ahead.
Come on, Lee, get in there!
Although accidents
do happen, but, you know...
There are various kinds of strikes.
It depends on where you hit
and what weapon you will be using.
To the eye, you would use fingers.
Don't worry, I won't.
To the eyes or straight at the face,
from the waist everything on.
Hold it, just a minute.
Let's move this gentleman around this way
so you're doing it more into the camera.
Okay, swell.
And then there is bent-arm strike
using the waist again
into a back fist.
Let's have the assistant director
back up this way.
Okay, go ahead.
Continue.
And then, of course,
kung fu is very sneaky.
You know, the Chinese,
they always hit low,
from high go back to the groin.
Now turn around the other
way, would you, Bruce?
Okay. Yeah.
Would you want me to...
These are just natural reactions.
Right, right. That is
a natural reaction.
Right into the camera. Cheat
into the camera a little bit.
Show us again.
All right. Go ahead.
There is a finger jab, there is a punch,
there is the back fist and then low.
Of course, then they use leg,
straight to the groin or come up
or if I can back up a little bit,
they start back from here
and then come back.
All right. He's kind of worried.
For various reasons,
the series was never produced,
but it did lead to the role of Kato
in the series The Green Hornet.
While the show itself was not exactly
an overwhelming success...
it lasted 30 half-hour episodes...
Bruce received favorable reviews
and was probably more
popular than the star.
He had a small part in Marlowe
with James Garner.
And then came Longstreet.
I'll be kicking you.
You ready?
Ready. One and two!
You all right? That guy's fantastic!
Now what is this...
what is this thing you do?
In Cantonese, Jeet Kune Do,
the way of the intercepting fist.
Intercepting fist, huh?
Or foot.
Come on, touch me any way you can.
You see?
To reach me, you must move to me.
Your attack offers me
an opportunity to intercept you.
In this case, I'm using
my longest weapon,
my side kick, against the
nearest target, your kneecap.
This can be compared
to your left jab in boxing,
except it's much more damaging.
I see.
Well, speaking of a left jab...
Oh.
This time I intercept
your emotional tenseness.
By now, Bruce Lee's Jeet Kune Do classes
were so famous
he could charge $275 an hour,
and even then he could pick
and choose his students,
students like Kareem Abdul-Jabbar,
Steve McQueen and James Coburn.
However, Bruce Lee's overriding ambition
was Hollywood.
But Hollywood was not responding.
The movie roles were not forthcoming,
and it was a bitter disappointment
when he was passed up for the lead
in the TV seriesKung Fu.
He returned once again to Hong Kong.
Hong Kong, 1970.
Apart from one brief visit in 1968,
Bruce Lee had been away for 12 years.
Arriving in Hong Kong,
he first approached
what was then Hong Kong's
biggest movie studios.
None of the studio bosses
seemed to recognize
the potential in Bruce.
He was just another actor, they said.
Who could tell?
One who could, it seems,
was Raymond Chow,
the head of a small new
studio, Golden Harvest.
Good morning. Good morning.
The director says
it's his best work so far.
Well, I've seen it once
and I think it's absolutely terrific.
All right, let's roll, then.
Raymond Chow was first
and foremost a filmmaker.
Although now the corporate head
of his new Golden Harvest studio,
his production background
led him to constant contact
with producers, directors and writers.
On the busy Hong Kong grapevine,
Chow had heard
of Shaw's unsuccessful offer
and made sure he saw
a demonstration Bruce gave
on a local TV station
before returning
to the U.S.
The demonstration Bruce gave
on the TV show was very impressive.
He side kicked
five 1-inch pots and broke four.
In addition, he kicked
and broke a 1-inch pot dangling.
Now that takes tremendous
amount of strength
and perfect timing.
But what impressed me more
was when I talked to him
on a long distance call.
He picked the most popular
Hong Kong-made
action picture at that time
and asked a very blunt question.
He asked me whether
that was the best we could do.
I had to say yes.
He then assured me
with sincerity and confidence
that he could do much better.
How could I doubt this man?
Raymond Chow offered Bruce Lee
a two-picture deal with Golden Harvest.
Bruce signed and flew to Thailand
to start work on The Big Boss.
The Big Boss, released asFists of Fury
in the U.S.A.,
was made on a modest budget
under fairly appalling conditions
in the small village
of Pak Chong in Thailand.
For the first time,
Bruce Lee was in his element.
Here was not the aesthetic philosophizing
of Long street.
Here were not the quick
economical knock-downs
of The Green Hornet.
And most certainly,
here was not the hard,
sharp economy of movement
that Bruce Lee had been
teaching his students.
Here suddenly was a whole new style
of martial arts choreography.
Rich, red-blooded, extravagant,
and bursting with power and energy.
And the public loved it!
In Hong Kong, it broke
all previous box office records.
Bruce Lee was a star.
Bruce Lee is incredible.
Well, Bruce Lee didn't
like to waste any time.
He wouldn't beat about the bush.
He got very direct.
Is Bruce Lee your hero?
Yes.
Tell me what you like about him.
He always wins the bad guys
and he is a very quick mover.
A question of body movement,
the choreography, the timing...
in fact, the overcoming
of the limitations of the human body.
I mean, he's not an action man
like Eastwood or Bronson.
I suppose he's more like a Nureyev.
Both Bruce Lee and Raymond Chow
were delighted with the
success of The Big Boss
and set about finalizing
plans for the next film.
WithThe Big Boss a huge success,
Raymond Chow allocated a larger budget
to the next film
and agreed that Bruce would play
a larger role in producing it.
In the meantime,
Linda and the family moved to Hong Kong
and set up house
in suburban Kowloon Tong.
This 11-room, 2-story villa
with its small Japanese-style garden
may not have turned heads in Hollywood,
but for crowded Hong Kong,
it was nothing short of a palace.
There was room for the family
and friends to relax.
Bruce divided his time at home
between his study
and his exercise equipment,
which seemed to be everywhere.
The second film was called
The Chinese Connection
in America, but was released in Hong Kong
and elsewhere asFist Of Fury.
This film took the cinematic expression
of rage and pure
destructive fury to new limits.
It also put weapons in the hands
of Bruce Lee for the first time
in the form of the deadly nunchakus,
two sticks joined by a thong or chain.
Not surprisingly,
Fist Of Fury again
smashed box office records,
including the one Bruce Lee
had so recently set.
Bruce was soon at work again
developing ideas for his next film.
He went location hunting all over Italy
and finally, he decided on Rome.
He brought over Bob Wall,
a top U.S. martial artist
and established champion
who would make a formidable opponent
in his new film Way of the Dragon.
From Korea, he added Tae Kwon Do expert
Hwang In-Shik.
As well as being the star,
Bruce Lee wrote and directed
Way of The Dragon.
The result is another sell-out success
to the extent that in Hong Kong
the showing of the film had to
be suspended at some theaters
while the police worked out ways
to handle the traffic jams
and massive crowds.
Nora Miao, a dynamic
young Hong Kong actress
co-stared with Bruce in all
but the last of Bruce's films.
Here she discusses the recurring themes
of Bruce Lee's films.
When did you first start to know him?
Um, our families have known each other
ever since I was a little kid.
But then at that time,
Bruce went to the States
and he was very young, too.
So I didn't get to meet him
until he came back to Hong Kong
for his first movies for Golden Harvest.
But surprisingly I didn't
meet him in Hong Kong.
Really, where did you meet him?
I actually met him in Thailand,
where we were filming The Big Boss.
I see, talking about his movies,
a lot of people observe that
there are a lot of
autobiographical elements
in Bruce Lee's movies.
Did you experience
or did you find any incidents
that he tried to relate his
experience through his movies?
Did you find any?
In a way, yes.
He always related his films
to his growing up in foreign country.
And he likes to play the part of a man
arriving in a strange land.
InThe Big Boss,
he was alone in a new town
trying to succeed in a new job.
Even the country, Thailand, is strange.
He has no friends and does
not know his potential enemies.
Now this is a good town
and it's very different to back home.
So be careful,
don't get into fights, Chang.
Remember your promise.
You're on your own from now on.
Don't worry, uncle.
InFist of Fury he was
a student returning home
to find everything had changed.
His teacher murdered
and his school and race
insulted by a foreign-led rival school.
InWay of the Dragon,
Bruce is a country boy
from a Hong Kong village who goes to Rome
to help in a Chinese restaurant.
The isolation of Bruce's character
is further underlined
by the barrier of language.
Here, he can't make himself
understood enough
to get something to eat.
Mommy!
Bruce went to the States
when he was very young.
And from what Bruce told me,
he felt that, being a foreigner,
he had to do his best in whatever he did.
And also, perhaps,
he was such a good
martial artist, you know.
In times, people
tend to pick fights with him.
InThe Big Boss, the pendant Bruce wears
is a reminder of a promise
he has made to avoid violence.
In his films, Bruce never went
looking for a fight.
Well, not initially, anyway.
Invariably, his character would resist
intolerable provocation
before violence
was virtually forced on him.
Yeah, we're very thirsty, sweetheart.
We need to cool off, come on.
Leave me alone, you're hurting me.
Come on, we'd like
to have a little bit of fun.
Don't meddle, no fighting.
Remember your promise.
If you don't leave me alone,
I'm going to call the police.
Please.
Then only when he was pushed
beyond his ability to resist
did he become the attacker,
the aggressor.
All right.
Hold it.
Now you get out of here, I'm warning you.
You bastards can't push us around.
You want to fight?
I'll take you on.
Personally I think
Bruce was a great actor,
a very good director
and a very good filmmaker.
And his main ambition in life
is to introduce Chinese kung fu
and Chinese movies to the whole world.
And he wanted to show that the Chinese
could be just as good as anybody else.
In all of Bruce's films,
the enemy were always
foreigners, non-Chinese.
Even when he was pounding
the life out of his compatriots,
it was made abundantly clear
that they were misguided
pawns of a foreign boss.
InThe Big Boss,
he works in an ice factory run by Thais.
The Thai foreman and his gang
bully the Chinese workers into servility.
Get to work!
Inside!
To hell with you, man!
You lousy pig!
Bastard.
It took the brutal and bloody murder
of his Chinese fellow workers
to push Bruce over the edge.
In Fist of Fury, the Japanese
are the enemy.
Delivers an insulting
message to Bruce's school.
The characters read,
"The Chinese are the Sick Man of Asia."
Well, clear a space there.
My friends here promise
to put up a good fight.
Must be someone.
Who's your champion, huh?
Mm, so many here and not
one of you with any courage.
What's the matter with the lot of you?
You afraid of us, huh?
Later in the film, a sign
on a park gate is an insult
that cannot be ignored.
Hey, you.
What do you want?
I will pass.
No, no, not allowed, I'm afraid.
And that?
You're the wrong color, so beat.
Hey, you, come here.
You... you were wanting to get in here?
No, no, no, no.
Tell you what.
There's only one thing you need to do.
Pretend you're a dog
and I'll take you in.
InWay Of The Dragon,
which takes place in Rome,
the underworld is trying to extort money
from the Chinese restaurant
where Bruce is working.
Almost every day, Italian thugs
go to the restaurant
to harass the Chinese,
forcing them to agree
to the payments they demand.
May I help you?
May you help me?
Sure.
Invariably, these foreigners'
assaults on Bruce
and those who he championed
were not just personal or physical,
but strongly racial,
leaving Bruce no other alternative
but to demonstrate the effectiveness
of Chinese martial arts.
Movement number four, dragon seeks path.
Dragon whips his tail.
Bruce's screen personality as a hero
was undeniable and unshakable.
How much of that personality
has been transferred
or injected into his real life?
I would say without a doubt,
the screen image of Bruce
was very much like
the Bruce in real life.
He was so energetic that even
when he was among friends,
his gestures were very physical.
And even when he was relaxing,
he looked very restless.
Left, right, left, right, left.
One, two, left, right.
Hup two, three, four.
Left, right, left...
Hey, what's going on there?
Hup two, three, four.
One, two, three, four.
Left, right, left, right, left, right.
Hup two, three, four.
A-one, two, three, four.
Left, right, left, right,
left, right, left, right.
One, two, three, four.
Bruce didn't drink,
so the parts he played didn't
know how to drink either.
Well, Chang, how about a little drink?
You're quite a drinker.
You put it away like water.
That will make you feel better.
In his movies,
his relationship with women
is usually shy and awkward,
often coy and invariably wholesome.
Mai, you've grown very pretty.
Well, if I was 10 years younger, I'd...
Chang, meet our younger sister, Chow Mai.
This is Chang, our cousin.
How are you?
It's hot.
Chang.
Let me go.
I must go.
I'll see you later.
While there are occasional
hints of romantic feelings,
Bruce's leading ladies
are usually treated more like
one of the boys.
Overt sexuality is only alluded to
when the encounter is with a prostitute,
and then only when
Bruce's lack of sophistication
allows it to happen.
The foreigners here are quite friendly.
You'll see.
When people smile, you smile back.
It's only right.
While you're here,
just don't be so uptight.
In the only bedroom scene
Bruce ever filmed,
a prostitute first gets him drunk,
and even then he goes to sleep.
In his films, Bruce Lee
was at his best as a fighter
rather than a lover.
But he was very concerned
that he would be typecast
as a one-character performer.
InFist of Fury, he used the device
of disguising himself,
perhaps with the object
of demonstrating his dramatic range,
here as a news vendor.
You see what they're doing?
Forcing my hand.
But where can I find him in this place?
Sir, why not try
to get back to Jingwu school,
see if he's turned up there, huh?
Here as a telephone repairman.
Good afternoon there.
I'm from the telephone company.
Oh.
What on earth took you so long?
We haven't got all day, you know.
Just got my orders minutes ago.
These vignettes were more
comedic than convincing.
But later around the time
he was working on Game Of Death,
he was experimenting with a whole range
of new characters.
He makes a very believable
blind swordsman,
his version of a character
called Zatoichi,
who appeared in several Japanese films
popular in Asia at the time.
Tagashira!
Surprisingly, these characters
were all developed
from classical archetypes,
and most were associated
with traditional weaponry,
contrary to his declared philosophy
of the martial arts.
It is not possible to say
how he would've developed
these characters,
but it is interesting to conjecture
what Bruce Lee would have made of roles
like the classic period Chinese swordsman
in films like Duel to the Death.
For some time, actor James Coburn,
writer Stirling Silliphant
and Bruce had been trying to put together
a project to be called Silent Flute.
Finally, 20th Century-Fox
agreed to do it,
but on a tiny budget
and providing it could be shot in India.
Bruce and his colleagues spent weeks
location hunting there and in Nepal.
India, they decided, was a waste of time,
but it was in Nepal
that pagodas like these
gave Bruce an inspiration
for Game of Death.
Bruce never crystallized the plot,
but it went something like this:
there would be a great
martial arts training center
based in a many-storied pagoda.
Each level would be guarded by a master
of a different martial art.
Bruce began to accumulate
the people he wanted to use.
Dan Inosanto...
The Korean seventh-degree Hapkido master
Ji Han Jae.
He began doing screen tests.
This footage of the tests and outtakes
has never been publicly shown before.
In his still-incomplete
concept for Game Of Death,
his ultimate objective would be to get to
whatever was at the top of the pagoda.
In the middle of this,
producer Fred Weintraub
had finally convinced Warner Bros.
To co-produce a project
with the partnership of Raymond Chow
and Bruce Lee.
This was to be Enter The Dragon.
At last, Bruce Lee was to play the lead
in a Hollywood movie.
He applied all his energies
to his performance
and worked closely
with director Robert Clouse
in staging all the martial
arts action in the film.
Bruce Lee first formally
set out his methods
in this early book,
Chinese Kung Fu, published in 1963.
He also illustrated it
with precise drawings
which highlighted
every detail of the text.
The photographs were taken
in the parking lot
next to Ruby Chow's.
Two martial art students demonstrate
how some of these moves work in action.
During his career,
Bruce had never failed
to enlighten his peers
with his in-depth
analysis of martial arts.
Well, gung fu is originated in China.
It is the ancestor of karate and jujitsu.
It's more of a compete system
and it's more fluid.
By that I mean it's more flowing.
There is continuity in movement
instead of one movement,
two movement and then stop.
The best example would be
a glass of water.
Why? Because water is the
softest substance in the world,
but yet it can penetrate
the hardest rock or anything,
granite, you name it.
Water also is insubstantial.
By that I mean
you cannot grasp hold of it.
You cannot punch it and hurt it.
So every gung fu man
is trying to do that,
to be soft like water and flexible
and adapt itself to the opponent.
A karate punch is like an iron bar, wang!
A gung fu punch is like an iron chain
with an iron ball attached to the end,
and it go wang!
And it hurts inside.
Well, gung fu can be practiced
alone or with a partner.
Practicing alone may involve forms.
Some imitate a crane,
a monkey, a praying mantis.
This is a crane form.
Start off.
Many of the moves Bruce used in his films
were designed more for a dramatic effect
than as examples of Jeet Kune Do.
It is also true
that much was an accurate
exposition of his art.
Here he deals with
an attempted grab and throw,
followed unwisely by an
attempt to sneak up behind.
A defense and counter
to a clubbing attack
from the side.
A deadly two-handed knife attack
is foiled with the help of a jacket.
Nunchaku against a sword.
Even Bruce admits that
this a very uneven contest
and would normally be avoided.
And it's not a situation
which many students today
are likely to encounter.
When used effectively,
the wooden staff is an
excellent weapon against knives.
A seemingly impossible situation,
an empty-handed defense against a sword.
Only with incredible speed
and almost psychic anticipation
could anyone survive.
Bruce was absolutely insistent
about physical fitness.
He said, "Training is one of the most
neglected phases of athletics.
Too much time is given
to the development of the skills
and too little to the development
of the individual
for participation."
As I worked with him,
I don't think anyone ever
trained as hard as Bruce did.
I don't think anyone
in the world ever trained
as dedicated a trainer as Bruce was.
It is a popular belief that Bruce Lee
was born with an exceptional physique.
Nothing could be further from the truth.
As a child, he was rather frail.
Reportedly, he never ate well at home,
a habit which seemed to persist
even when he returned
to the United States.
It was only through many
years of constant exercise
and finally reappraising
his dietary habits
that he built himself
into the superb physical specimen
he was to become.
Bruce's emphasis on physical fitness
opened up a new path
for martial art students.
They followed his advice
of applying modern exercising techniques
to the field of martial arts.
They learned to appreciate
Bruce's outlook.
"One may know all the fighting techniques
in the world, but if one is not fit
one does not stand
a chance in a real fight."
His fame and following grew and grew.
Whole magazines were devoted
to one aspect or another
of his life and career.
In the world of martial arts
and action movies,
Bruce Lee was king.
This is noted Taiwanese
actress Betty Ting Pei.
Her undeniable charms had been revealed
to good advantage in numerous film roles,
often as a seductress or femme fatale.
For some three months, her
name had been romantically linked
with that of Bruce Lee,
as had many others in the past.
Whether there is any truth
behind any of the stories
of these liaisons
remains a matter of speculation.
Certainly, though, it could
not have been a disadvantage
for any ambitious young actress
to be linked with Bruce Lee.
On the afternoon of July 20th, 1973,
Bruce Lee went to the
apartment of Betty Ting Pei.
They were to meet Raymond
Chow later for dinner,
an appointment
Bruce Lee was never to keep.
He was rushed to hospital
in an ambulance.
Betty had phoned Raymond
Chow at the restaurant saying
Bruce had laid down with a headache
and she couldn't rouse him.
Chow rushed to Betty's apartment.
Doctors were called,
and finally an ambulance.
Bruce Lee was certified dead on arrival
at Queen Elizabeth Hospital.
Hong Kong was stunned.
And as the word spread,
people read with shock
and disbelief.
The next day, thousands of people
jammed the streets
around the Kowloon Funeral Parlor.
Several hundred
extra police were detailed
to try to control the crowd.
No one could believe
that someone like Bruce Lee,
so young, so fit, could just die.
But Betty Ting Pei would say nothing.
Bruce was my very best friend,
but now he's gone.
Bruce trusted me a lot.
But at that time, I didn't want to
nor do I need to explain anything.
Because of our relationship,
I've been blamed unfairly.
His death came as a shock
and there has been
a lot of pressure on me.
But I'll never let anything
spoil the relationship I had with Bruce.
At the funeral, Linda arrived
with Raymond Chow.
Above a portrait of Bruce
is a banner in Chinese reading,
"A star
sinks in a sea of art."
All around are draped
thousands of tributes.
Relatives and close friends
bow in respect.
Linda and the two children
are draped in the traditional
white robes of mourning.
Members of the funeral party
filed past the open coffin.
Few can hide their grief.
Linda and the children take
a last look as they too leave.
The public controversy
about Bruce Lee's death was still raging,
but it was only at the Hong Kong airport,
about to board a plane
that was carrying
Bruce's body to Seattle,
that Linda finally broke her silence.
It is my wish that the newspapers
and the people of Hong Kong
will stop speculating
on the circumstances
surrounding my husband's death.
Although we do not have
the final autopsy report,
I hold no suspicion of anything
other than natural death.
I myself do not hold any person
or people responsible for his death.
Fate has ways we cannot change.
The only thing of importance is that
Bruce is gone and will not return.
He lives on in our memories
and through his films.
Please remember him
for his genius, his art
and the magic he brought
to every one of us.
For we who knew him very well,
his words and thoughts
will remain with us forever
and influence the rest of our lives.
In Seattle awaits Linda's family
and more bereaved relatives and friends.
And a second funeral.
Beside the coffin was placed
a yin and yang symbol of Jeet Kune Do.
Among the many who came
to pay their respects
were friends and coworkers
like Dan Inosanto,
Jim Kelly, Robert Clouse
and other actors and producers.
Former students James Coburn
and Steve McQueen
silently recalled their
memories of their master.
Bruce's mother said her last goodbyes.
And finally, Linda and the children,
Brandon and Shannon.
Coburn, McQueen and the other pallbearers
throw their white gloves
on the flower-decked casket.
And at last, it was over.
Or was it?
Back in Hong Kong, the inquest started,
and once again the public
began to speculate wildly
on Betty Ting Pei's role
in relation to Bruce's untimely death.
At that time, there was a lot of talk,
scandalous rumors about us.
I was under a lot of pressure,
but I told myself,
silence is the best answer.
I treasured Bruce's friendship very much.
That's why I have put up with the gossip
without saying anything to anyone.
The experts argued over
the results of the autopsy
until the court was satisfied
Bruce Lee had died of cerebral edema,
swelling of the brain
caused by hyper sensitivity
to an ingredient of Equagesic,
the tablet he took
to relieve his headache.
The verdict, death by misadventure.
Bruce has left us.
For movies, it was the fall of a star.
For his fans, they have lost
their most respected idol,
but most important, his family
lost their dearest one.
But for myself, I have lost
a very dear friend.
The coroner's verdict
took some of the pressure
off Betty Ting Pei.
She resumed her film career.
But her subsequent evasive
public statements
about Bruce Lee's death did
nothing to quell persistent
and popular rumors that Bruce had died
while they were making love.
Before long, she became a devout Buddhist
and took to long periods of fasting.
It was not until 10 years after the event
that Betty Ting Pei went
on Hong Kong television
and for the first time denied that
she and Bruce had sexual relations
on the day of his death.
All she had done, she said,
was to let Bruce rest in her bed
and to give him the
painkiller for his headache.
Letters continued to arrive
from Bruce's fans long after his death.
And there were others who saw it
as a great opportunity to be exploited.
Imitators on the screen
appeared by the score.
But there was one last
real Bruce Lee film.
He had shot many thousands
of feet of film
for Game of Death.
After his death, an extensive
worldwide search was done
to find someone who could possibly
double for Bruce in the missing scenes.
Many candidates were flown
to Hong Kong for screen tests.
And from the film footage
of these screen tests,
two look-alikes were finally selected
to enact the missing scenes.
To complete the film,
Raymond Chow brought back Robert Clouse,
the director who had worked
with Bruce on Enter The Dragon.
On the first day of the
recommencement of filming,
the entire cast and crew took
part in a simple ceremony,
offering food and wine
and burning incense
to the spirit of Bruce Lee.
Well, how would you compare
Enter The Dragon with Game Of Death?
Right.
Enter The Dragonwas done about,
I guess, 6 or 7 years ago,
and, um, was, uh,
the, uh, last picture that Bruce made.
And then, of course, now Game Of Death.
It's a very large film.
Production is large.
Most of the leading actors
are from United States.
Hugh O'Brian, Gig Young,
Dean Jagger, Colleen Camp, so on.
It did really very well on the film.
It's interesting
because the film was about a third done
before Bruce died.
There's a good question
in some people's mind
as to whether Bruce did die.
Of course, I've always been
a fan of Bruce Lee's
as millions of people
have throughout the world,
Russell, so I was actually
very thrilled to be in
something which I consider
in many ways not historical,
but to capture the footage
that Bruce Lee had already shot
when he unfortunately died.
A traditional Chinese lion dance
has always been a powerful means
of bringing in good fortune
and dispelling evil spirits.
It's not so surprising
that the reworked plot
of the prophetically titled
Game of Death found room
for a chase scene
through just such a spell.
Not all the action would be kung fu.
Top Hollywood stuntmen
were brought to Hong Kong
for these exciting scenes.
You all right, Billy?
Yeah. All right. Love it.
Is Billy okay?
Nice one, nice one.
There were many who thought
it could never be done,
but in 1978, Game Of Death
was finally completed,
and fans all over the
world could see at last
the final work of Bruce Lee.
How do you like that?
Today, his popularity
has hardly diminished.
He's still a popular feature of movie
and martial arts magazines
of many countries.
The Bruce Lee imitators
have faded into obscurity,
but perhaps a new
young star like Jackie Chan
can rise to the same heights,
a different kind of star
with his own unique style.
Hold it!
Get down!
What's going on?
Look out!
But even a star like Jackie Chan
does not claim to be the new Bruce Lee.
There will never be a new Bruce Lee.
Bruce Lee has gone,
but his spirit lives on.
This is Bruce Lee, the legend.