BUCHAREST NONSTOP
I don't love you anymore.
I never want to see you again.
Fuck off, dirtbag.
Here, boy!
Here!
I'm going to feed the dogs.
Come to mama, boys!
Yes, mother.
Didn't I say I'd come tonight?
Don't make me swear.
OK. I understood...
I can't talk, I'm packing.
Bye now.
I couldn't find cables.
So now what?
I'll take out the battery.
Why not ask the
taxi guy for cables?
You ask.
Come on.
Excuse me.
Do you have cables?
- Are you sure it's the battery?
- I think so.
Turn the key.
Hello!
How are you, sugar?
How's my baby?
Yes, handsome.
I love you too.
Yes, baby.
Tell me...
Yes, baby. I'm coming home.
Tonight!
You'll go to sleep and
find me there in the morning!
I'll wake you up.
Yes, baby!
Sure I got you
something, sugar.
No, baby, it's not a Panda!
Go to sleep now, honey.
Yes, dearest.
I love you too, baby!
Bye!
I'm on my way.
I can't sorry.
OK, just the girdle.
OK, bye!
It's the battery.
I told you.
Can we borrow your cables?
- That's no good.
- Why?
It's the alternator.
Better get a battery.
My client's here.
What are you doing?
Are you moving out?
Weren't you going to work?
A client, right.
Please, give us the cables.
I can't. My client's here!
Maybe it'll work, though.
Come on, Marian, help them.
I know them. You'll get
the cables from Achim.
- Who's Achim?
- The guy at the store.
That's his name?
Hold this.
Leave them with him.
I need them too.
Swear to God.
Thanks so much!
- Thanks so much!
- Cheers!
Who's the hottie?
I don't know. I think
she lives in my building.
In your building, and
you don't know her?
I can't, Jeni.
Call me later.
I'll give you a ride now.
- Then we'll see.
- OK!
- What time's your train?
- 10.
We'll talk.
What was the name of that guy?
To get my cables back...
- Achim?
- Achim.
Achim, right.
Good guy!
- How do you know?
- I know him.
I love you so much...
We'll wake everybody up!
I have to charge the battery.
Right. I'll go get
the cables again.
A guy.
It's my friend's car.
A wreck.
What can I do?
I've got no money.
I said I'd take care of it!
Tomorrow.
I'll do it tomorrow.
Yeah, we'll go. We'll go to the mall
and get you that thing.
I love you too!
Bye now!
I don't know anybody in Bucharest.
But to fuck him...
I was just kidding.
Did you tell Giani?
What's Giani got
to do with me?
You've got nothing
to do with Giani?
I just pay him half, that's all.
Forget about Giani.
The guys I gave my cables.
How do you know them?
I just do.
And? Nothing?
You think everybody's...
Think they've got
money for that?
Those losers?
How do you know them?
I lived in the same
building with one of them.
Lived? Are you moving out?
Aren't you a curious one?
Do you like
what you do?
How's that your business?
Do you like what you do?
- Yes.
- Good. I like it too.
I love it.
He went away,
thought it over
and realized he was wrong.
Yeah, let's have him
do a real comparison.
Let him fuck
the whole block!
Yeah, that irony
really touched me.
Am I going crazy?
He's like an uber-fuck.
Screws anything on legs.
- He cheated on me!
- He admitted it!
So he's half forgiven.
We're interested
in the other half.
And he didn't
admit it, either.
Better it happened now
rather than later.
It's OK...
We're fine.
What a treat.
Not to be missed.
The ice-cream!
It must be soggy by now.
I'll put it in the freezer.
I like it soggy.
My teeth won't hurt.
If it's soggy it goes right
to the abs and thighs.
He didn't even pick up
his phone for a month!
Coward... didn't
even dare tell me.
It's like he's not
right in the head!
Well, you too were supposed to go
to the seaside with him
and went with that jerk to Sinaia!
The poor moron was waiting
to get laid, got
screwed instead.
We weren't even together for real.
I was undecided.
When in need
be undecided.
Virgil was a cool guy.
This is a redneck.
And why go to
the seaside anyway?
Isn't he tanned enough?
I heard you, bitches!
It's not like he's Swedish!
So, are you going
to drive this time?
- I don't think it's OK.
- Why not?
Well, it's in your dad's name.
If anything happens,
I don't want trouble.
And I've never driven
a Dacia before.
- I haven't either!
- You drove the old one!
I'm not driving
this deathtrap.
It's the last time
I'm driving.
Word of honor!
He might have
sold it cheaper.
He would have, if I'd
paid him on the spot.
We would, afterwards.
Just as good.
We're paying as much
as for the other one.
- That one wouldn't even start!
- Like this one did.
It did. He paid 100 to have
the restrictor cleaned.
He could have sold it for scrap iron.
No way! You know why he didn't?
No one's looking for scrap iron.
We paid more than enough.
You just take care.
If you hadn't crashed the last one,
we'd still have it.
Easy. Just enough to bump it,
not to pay for the tow truck.
Why don't you drive,
if you're so smart?
Wasn't last time
supposed to be real?
Didn't I hit my head
without my seatbelt on?
- Don't get so fucking warped.
- Fuck off!
- I'm not driving this piece of shit!
- I'm not, either.
I won't drive it,
you won't drive it.
- So?
- So nothing.
What a douche.
That's why I love you.
We'll be ok.
Hey guys!
Can I have the intercom code?
Where are you going?
My girlfriend Dora,
second floor.
- Family name?
- No family. Just Dora, second floor.
- What are you, a detective?
- The codes 4869.
I'm on third floor,
apartment 32,
so I dial 486932.
Four... eight...
six... nine.
Fucking C!
You'll wait for me, right?
You know it doesn't pay
to keep the engine rolling.
Without that bag,
I could take a client
and come back.
It's in the trunk anyway,
what's it to you?
What if I get an
airport call?
The hell you will! It's gonna be
half an hour tops.
You'll wait, right?
OK, but after half an hour
you pay me double!
Yeah OK, I'll
pay you double.
Hello!
Giani, hi, man!
It's Marian, the taxi guy
who drives Jeni around.
Louder!
Quiet here.
Quiet! Right.
I called because I think...
Jeni is planning to scram.
Which Jeni?
Right, so?
She had a big bag
and asked me
to take her to the station.
What?
Bitch shut your mouth!
Can't you see
I'm on the phone?
And did you drive her there?
No, she's just gone
up to a client.
Well done. Where
are you?
Where uptown?
Be more specific.
Take the baby away.
Give me a reference point.
Near the Italian restaurant,
nearby the park.
What if I get a call...
Do you want that to be
the last call you ever take?
Keep her there.
I'm coming for her.
OK, OK.
Come along.
Not you. You.
Don't tell her
I told you, OK?
I called because you
did me a solid, so...
Nothing to do
with you, chill.
Fucking fuck.
Your problem is being
so subservient.
The moment someone loves you,
you're his bitch.
No wonder they love you.
You're gorgeous. Monica Belluci!
And she is gorgeous
as a petite.
I'm gorgeous
in the slender type.
Is someone throwing
pebbles at our window?
It's the third floor.
It's screwing with my ears.
- It's him.
- Sweet!
He's standing there throwing
pebbles at the window!
They're all pigs.
I'll throw boiling
water at him.
And I'll close the window.
It's him.
- Pick up!
- Don't pick up.
Dorica!
Come here!
Hey, doggie!
Here!
You too, boy.
That's right.
Fuck off!
Ma'am!
Could you please
buzz me in?
Punch the code in.
I forgot it, ma'am.
No code, no getting in.
- Please, ma'am!
- Phone them!
Come on ma'am,
buzz me in.
Fucking hag!
Ma'am, please
buzz me in!
Fuck, I think I gave
him the wrong code.
I just do it by heart.
One, two three, like this.
See you don't run
into him tomorrow!
So? Fuck,
why doesn't he know the code?
He can blow me.
I think he tricked you.
Noticed the way he looked?
How's that?
You gave him the code.
Tomorrow you might come back
to an empty apartment.
That would suck ass.
Why didn't you just
give him the keys?
Save him the trouble of
breaking down the door.
Man. We play
tricks on some,
and others play tricks on us.
I mean, on you.
It's a fucking jungle!
Law of compensation!
So what's he going to take?
My dad's pension?
I don't care.
I'm going away.
Does your dad know
you're leaving?
Sure he does.
Is he OK with it?
The hell he is.
He thinks I should give it up,
that she must have found
someone else there!
- What if she has?
- She hasn't.
- Are you sure?
- Yeah.
I'll get the money and
take her to England.
Where's she staying now?
You said she was looking after
an old hag who died?
She did.
- She's dead, right?
- Right.
She moved in
with a girlfriend.
- A girlfriend with a dick.
- Man, you're a douche.
- Fucking sleazeball.
- Say you love her, man.
Fucking say it.
Yeah, man, I love her.
What if I do?
You and...
Romeo and what's
her name...
What's your mother's name?
Who's there?
It's you...
Why don't you
answer when I call?
Who did you think it'd be?
My mother?
And if you heard
the door close,
didn't you hear the
key in the lock?
Five minutes ago
I told you..
I'd go downstairs
to feed the dogs.
Who do you think it
was?
Why didn't you tell me?
Didn't I?
I told you I was going downstairs
to feed the dogs?
When you don't
want to hear,
you pretend to be
asleep.
You expected a note from me?
Stop yelling.
I heard the key in the lock
and I freaked out.
Who did you think it was?
No one's got the key.
We've got no one!
That's what I'm saying.
We're as lonely as
two broken toys.
If we die...
no one has the key.
They'll break down the
door just to bury us.
We've just had it changed!
That's what you care about.
That they'll break
down the door.
Maybe you'll get an invoice
in heaven, by fax.
You might have
a heart attack
when you see the
cost of a lock!
We'd better take someone in
to look after us,
leave them the house.
Why? Where, in
these two rooms?
I would sleep in the hallway.
Not to live here.
Just to come in and
look after us.
How long will you be
able to get around?
We're all alone here.
We'll starve to death!
You fought with the neighbors
over your stray dogs.
Those that bit the
Japanese tourist.
No one will be here
to feed us.
So what should I do?
Let them kill my dogs?
It's not like they all bit him.
Just one!
How do they know
it was our dog.
and not one from
next door?
And after all what was
the Japanese doing in Romania?
Maybe he had some
business in Romania.
In Bucharest.
Right on our street.
He had an itch to come
here. He deserved it!
Jeez, woman.
That man died!
Does that mean
they should kill all my dogs?
Find the one that bit him,
and kill that one.
What was that?
- What?
- What's that noise?
Nothing.
Don't you hear it?
Outside the window!
I don't hear anything.
They should have a
poll on TV.
Do you think it
was a dog from
entrance A or entrance B?
Now you can hear!
What's that?
- Cheers!
- Hey.
A pack of cigarettes. Superlight.
- Is this OK?
- Yeah.
Anything else?
A pack of gum.
Professional or super-white?
- Which one's cheaper?
- Same price.
Those. Whatever!
Professional.
Got 3 lei in change?
- No.
- Me neither.
Can I get you a cake instead?
Instant coffee?
A condom?
It's OK, thanks.
No problem.
Thanks!
- I need a favor.
- What?
Do you have a
Nokia charger?
What kind?
- Nokia.
- Nokia, but what kind?
What? For a Nokia phone!
There are several kinds.
A thin jack, a thicker one...
- This is the phone.
- This piece of junk?
You need a thick jack!
I haven't got that.
Anything else?
What, are you checking
my phone?
You got me wrong.
I was going to ask you to borrow it.
- Get lost.
- I had a fight with my girl.
Fucking asshole.
My phone battery is dead...
Please...
I forgot the intercom code.
I mean I forgot it...
Why do you think it's gonna be
better near a restaurant?
Listen. There's a
lot of money there.
We might get lucky and come
across a boozed-up moron.
We'll make a ton of money.
First, we'll go
to Di Darius.
If it's a no-go, then Acvatic.
You can't see inside.
Let's do the intersection!
It was OK last time!
And we need to
be both in the car.
Remember how that guy
wanted to beat me up.
What can I do alone?
Are you deaf?
There's more money this way.
Which we split halfway,
but I do all the work.
I drive, I do the work,
thanks for nothing.
There's just more
money this way.
- You don't get it...
- OK... Shut it.
Not even half an hour.
Why do you sit
in the backseat?
I need to change
for the train trip.
This is for you!
It's too much!
The waiting's 20 lei, tops.
- There's no need...
- Take it!
It's OK, keep it.
Best of luck!
This is my lucky day.
Have a drink on
me off-shift.
Take these, too.
What should I do
with them?
I don't know.
Give them to a chick.
Got a chick?
- Do you?
- Yeah, I do.
Give them to her, then.
What are you
looking at?
Come on, Marian...
Haven't you seen
pussy before?
- Haven't you?
- Come on, Jeni!
If I'd known,
I'd give it to you for free.
Jeni!
Come on,
don't be like that.
I'm in a hurry now.
If I weren't...
I'm sorry I'm in a hurry.
Shall we go?
Tell me which way to take.
To the train station.
I don't know.
Train station... OK.
What the...
Fucking shit.
- What's wrong?
- My battery died.
And you made me give
my cables away.
Call me another cab. Marian!
I'm in a hurry!
I'll charge it just a bit.
The hell you are.
Call me a cab!
I'm driving you, OK?
Help us out?
Get real.
Those who take care of you
are in fact looking to
take your house.
They have you sign papers,
then blow up a firecracker
so you'd have a heart attack.
Remember Mrs. Marinescu?
The staircase rattled!
Didn't you say,
if you were
to die before me
there'd be no one to
light a candle for you?
Didn't you say that
every single day?
On and on...
And no one blew
a firecracker on her.
She was nuts.
She threw the Tupperware
at them.
They came everyday
to bring her food,
and she'd keep them
on the doorstep.
The hell they came.
How do you know?
You've been bed-ridden
for four years.
You told me!
You said Mrs. Marinescu
was lucky to have those two kids
bringing her food every day.
They couldn't come
into the building
because of your straydogs.
They were knocking over
their Tupperware.
That was in the beginning.
Mrs. Marinescu told me
after that they'd only
bring her potato stew.
Potato stew until there was no
potato stew anymore.
No wonder the dogs
left them alone.
They couldn't smell the meat.
Meat or no meat,
they came every day.
Do I have meat every day?
Maybe you do, wherever
you go all day long.
I'm as good as alone.
It's been like this since
I was in the army.
Not again!
I won't remind you that
I didn't decide on my own
to have that abortion.
You forced me.
Don't start it again.
We said a million times
we'd never bring it up again.
I'm this close to death and
you've pestered me for
45 years with this!
Did I start this fight?
Today, I didn't say anything...
You told me I should
have left a note
when I went to feed the dogs.
And why didnt I
wake you up?
And why don't we bring
someone to take care for us,
since we're alone.
No wonder we're alone.
You drove me mad
with your jealousy!
And you forced me to
have that abortion
because you weren't sure
it was your baby.
So we're alone.
You were gone for months.
Some officer!
That's why you married me.
I was an officer.
Serving wherever my
country needed me.
And sending you
the paycheck.
No wonder you were bored
and wasted your time
playing rummy
with that dyed-up Mrs. Groza.
That's where you
met that punk, too.
I should have gotten
a divorce then.
I was so ready to
divorce you.
Your mother objected.
"What would the
neighbors say?"
Like I'd married the neighbors.
The neighbors were to envy her
for such a nice
daughter-in-law.
Nice. I was her punching bag.
I shouldn't have agreed
to live with your mother.
She made you think it
wasn't your child.
Just put my SIM card
into your phone.
It costs nothing.
No phone. Get lost,
you're scaring customers away.
What customers?
There's nobody here...
Please! It costs nothing,
I'll use my SIM card!
I'll give you my phone.
Some phone!
Just stand by the door.
Someone's bound to come out.
You think I didn't
try that?
A guy came out and asked
where I was going.
Dora, I said.
- Who?
- Dora.
I don't know her.
Then an old hag came out
to feed the dogs.
I know her. Mrs. Anton,
the building commissioner.
No one comes in without
her knowing.
Fucking douchebag.
What are you doing?
What's the hurry?
What happened?
I think I'm running
out of gas.
Didn't you put some gas?
Just 30 lei's worth. I kept
it running to charge the battery.
Why did you keep it
running 'till now?
What if it stops just when
I'm supposed to leave?
You should have
spent 50 lei on gas.
Why not 50?
I didn't have 50, you moron.
Jerk-off.
You drive and I'll
keep watch, how's that?
Oh, really?
I'll put up a reserve fund so
we don't run out again.
What money?
We spent all of our money.
What did you
spend it all on?
I have no money...
I have problems.
Fuck off!
Please don't talk about
my mother like that.
She wanted the best for us.
How did we come
to her again?
She's been dead 20 years!
God rest her soul.
She cooked for you and
did your laundry,
since you never
had a job in your life.
You were visiting
Mrs. Crazy-Dye all day long.
My mother was
not your servant!
I thought we weren't
talking about her anymore.
What are you talking about?
Now you're singing
her praises!
Didn't I take her
to the doctor?
Here and there
and everywhere?
Let's just finish this.
You'll be dead
and there'll be...
no one to light
a candle for me.
I can't count on you...
in this world...
or the next either.
Enough.
You are wasting
your time here.
- Go home, charge your phone.
- I live in Magurele.
- Near the Physics Institute?
- Where should I go?
I have a cousin working there.
He says there are radiations!
- Radiations?
- Yeah.
Ball out from the court.
Out.
What if she's with
someone else?
Maybe that's why
she won't answer.
Thought about that?
I'd stand by the door just to
see who comes out.
I did that once.
waited all night
and caught her.
I slapped the shit
out of her.
Fucking bitch. She thought
I was at a rock concert.
Where did she live?
- Who?
- The chick you slapped.
A house. Why?
That's easier. You stand
outside and see what
motherfucker comes out,
and bam!
There's hundreds in a building.
I can't ask all of them
where they were.
At least if anyone came out!
You've got a point there.
- Cigarette?
- Thanks.
So what did you do?
Why did you argue?
You must have
done something.
I did.
What's the difference if you
won't let me use your phone?
Have you got an ID on you?
- No.
- No?
No. What's it to you?
You want my name?
It was good collateral.
Are you listening?
The douche is leaving.
- Now?
- Yes, now.
Are you sure?
Yeah, now.
I can't drive if
I'm on the phone.
I'm putting you on speaker!
Make sure you can hear me.
Watch out, OK?
- Go ahead.
- Wait a moment.
Tell me...
A black Audi, I think.
Audi? What color?
Black.
He left.
He's leaving right now.
He's climbing into the car.
Stand by!
- When's he coming?
- In a moment.
Stand by!
I see a car.
What car?
That's not it.
I'll tell you when.
It's coming round
the corner now.
In a few seconds.
He is coming in your direction.
Take care!
I can see him.
When I got there he
didn't even know me.
What's your favorite
sex position?
What are you doing,
Are you blind?
- We've got right of way, dick!
- I've got right of way.
Un-fucking-believable.
- What fucking right of way!
- The fucking right of way!
- I've got right of way!
- You're a fucking idiot, man.
- What are you doing?
- Blood.
- Is the leather stained?
- I've got a concussion.
- My head...
- Let me see.
- No.
You've got paper tissues in there.
Let me.
Unbelievable, what a moron.
Let's go.
It's not stopping.
I'm taking her to
the hospital and
we'll go to the police tomorrow.
- Got insurance?
- It's dad's car. Maybe he does.
I say we go to the police now
so I can have the papers done.
- Are we going already?
- What police? Fuck them.
I'll give you money to fix
this piece of shit.
How much is the wing?
My dad will kill me.
I say we call the cops.
Let's go, please.
Or at least let me sit in the car.
- Patience!
- I'm not feeling well.
Listen.
Let's work it out.
- I'll give you 300 for the wing.
- Not interested.
If there are no casualties,
the cops don't come.
I'm still bleeding.
Let's go to the police.
She's hurt. Why not
go to the police?
I need the paperwork
to fix my car.
It's better all around.
No need. Wait...
Here's another 200
for the car shop.
The mechanic won't fix
my car without the paperwork.
You call the police, I've got
no credit on my phone.
Why won't you call?
Have you been drinking?
I haven't!
- I'm taking a cab.
- Have you been drinking?
Are you DUI?
Take the money.
Please take the money
- I'm not interested.
- Please take it!
It's the third!
I thought you'd quit!
I'm not sure I'm keeping it.
See what he's doing?
Calling me every five minutes.
So why not answer?
You have to talk.
Get me an ashtray.
If I said it's over, it's over!
He went away with her,
he can stay gone.
Good. I never liked him.
Look at people's reaction.
At the baptism party,
they wouldn't let him in
I like him. I think his
bad guy act is sexy.
Didn't you say looks don't
matter if he's a good guy?
No sign of him for a month.
Some good guy.
Now he's calling
you non-stop.
Why can't you pick up?
Why should she?
Is she remote-controlled?
Now you speak, now you don't.
How long did he not
answer his phone?
A month...
And she should pick up
now that he wants to talk.
Fuck the slimebag.
I'm not picking up.
I wish I knew what
he wanted, though.
I don't know who told him that
I cried over him for a month.
- Not me.
- Yeah, I did.
I like him so much I can't
keep secrets from him.
Asshole.
She told him!
Where the fuck did
I tell you to wait?
Jeni! Where are
you going?
I had a client.
I didn't ask you what you had.
I asked where you were going.
I'm going home.
I had a client.
- Do I look stupid?
- No Giani, I just had a client.
Marian, tell him, I had a client.
I'm going home.
Shut the fuck up.
Go take that bag out!
- What bag?
Jeni, get back here!
Don't make me hit
You. Get in!
Fucking shit, get the
bag out already!
Faster! Take the
fucking bag out!
- Mr. Giani, we didn't agree on that.
- What did we agree on?
We agreed you'd wait.
Take out the bag.
Leave the bag in!
I'll punch your face in.
Get in the car!
- If you'd known...
- If you'd known, what?
I'll fucking punch your lights out,
too.
What's wrong with you?
Fucking Teddy Bear...
I got scared, that's
why I asked.
When I used to go
shopping and came back
with my grocery bags
didn't you ask,
"Are you back?"
I was there, you could see.
Still you asked.
What was I to say: "No?"
That's what people say when
they've got nothing to say.
which reminds me...
Could you bring me a pillow
for m back? I'm heating up.
What time does Mrs. Chelba
come for my injection?
Are you listening to me?
Are you asleep?
That's so you.
You start the fight
and want to end it, too.
That's no longer married life.
- Hello!
- Hello.
Can I have...
I'd like.
a sparkling water and cigarettes.
Anything to eat?
Will you ask or not?
If not, we won't do it.
And some special ice-cream.
I got it.
Coming right up.
Take this.
And this, too.
Thanks a lot. How much?
Twenty-five.
Got five lei?
It's ok.
Do you prefer flavored?
No.
Thank you!
Good luck!
Hey you!
Come here.
- Me?
- Yeah. Come here.
What did you say
your name was?
Teddy. Teodor,
but they call me Teddy.
Achim. Nice to
meet you.
Now that we've
met, I'll help you.
Tell me your chick's name
and I'll call her.
- For real?
- For real.
Are you making fun of me?
Enough. Tell me the number.
0766459692...
Wait. 594...
You don't know her number?'
And you say you're in love.
I have it in my phone.
It's not like you know
your numbers by heart.
Tell me your wife's
number let's see.
I don't need to know it by heart.
I got no wife, sucker. Get it?
But I know the numbers
I need to know.
Tell me one that
you know.
Are you dumb?
I can tell you any number
whether I know it by heart or not.
You wouldn't know!
Take my mom's number.
0723456789.
How will you check?
Write it down, and I'll look
it up in your contacts.
Yeah like I'm gonna I've out
my phone to check it.
- Give me a break.
- No, man.
You said 0723456789.
Right?
Now write it down
and we'll see
if it's under "Mommy",
or whatever.
I'm messing with you, man.
456789 is just a joke.
Tell me her real number.
What am I, dumb?
Why do you want my
mama's number?
I don't. I was gonna prove
you don't know it by heart.
If you're afraid, tell
me another number.
Of course I'm afraid.
Look at your face.
What's wrong with my face?
You think I'm gonna
ask your mama out?
Are you picking on my mama?
Enough already.
- I'm not, man!
- And I was going to help you.
I'm not picking on your mama!
I was gonna prove you don't
know your numbers by heart!
Listen...
I don't think you
want to help me.
Motherfucking
douchebag rocker.
You picked on my
mama. Get lost.
I swear on my mother I wasn't
picking on your mother.
Only gypsies swear like that.
Are you a gypsy?
So that's why you're not giving me
your phone, 'cause I'm a gypsy?
Are you?
What if? Have you got
something against them?
No, but...
Are you a xenophobe?
A xenophobe?
You don't know
what that is?
Me, a xenophobe!
Meaning you don't
like gypsies.
Who does?
Dorica!
How can I help you?
Did some guys leave some cables
here? They said they would.
- They did.
- Where are they?
- Gone. They took them again.
- Why?
Their battery is dead. They said
they'd bring them in later.
Man oh man.
Never give away your things.
Give me a coffee. Make it light.
I had three already.
- Instant or filter?
- Filter
Instant gives me heart palpitations.
Take this, I'll make another.
Two lei.
- Excuse me.
- Yes?
One thing. Can I
borrow your phone?
I need to call my girlfriend
here in the building.
We had an argument and
now my battery's dead.
I forgot
the intercom code, too.
Why aren't you
standing by the door?
Go in when someone goes out.
- I tried that.
- You did?
He did. I saw him.
That's not it.
What is it, then?
Why won't you give
him your phone?
How could I?
Look at him!
What about him?
He's tanned. And it's
not from the sun.
What if he's tanned?
Are you scared?
What have you done?
Do you bite?
Me? I didn't do anything.
Come on, please.
I'll pay anything.
Give it to him, man.
You give it to him, if
you've got the guts.
I would but I've got a client.
I called in five minutes.
Vacarescu street, entrance A.
I just came in for the cables.
And coffee.
Dora!
Dorica!
Where can I put this?
Here. At night I take
the container in.
They stole it even
with a chain on.
Give me a pack of cigarettes.
What a thing.
About the container?
About the phone.
Were you afraid
he'd steal it?
The container?
The phone, man.
Light up for me.
Just a sec.
About the phone thing...
I'd have given him the phone,
but did you see his face?
He might be a good boy,
but he's a gypsy.
Gotta watch your wallet.
Even if you know him.
Now that you're here I might
have given it to him.
He was here for an hour.
Is he gone?
A building full of hoes...
You seem to know about it.
Are you married?
Haven't found anyone
worth it. Hoes all over.
I picked up Jeni from
here earlier on.
Jeni from the ground floor?
I know her.
She asked me to give
my cables to those guys.
- I know Jeni.
- A hoe.
A hoe?
What are you talking about?
A fucking hoe. Lucky she's got a guy
looking after her. Giani.
You know what she thought of today?
Do a couple of clients and
leave without paying Giani.
Go where?
I don't know.
She had a fucking big bag.
Fuck the hoe. Going
away without paying.
Wasn't it her money?
It was her ass that got it.
He had her back against thugs.
Giani saved her ass
many times.
- Do you know this girl well?
- He helped her...
Do you know why she
became a prostitute?
Giani used to beat her
She had shades on at night
to hide the blackened eye.
She bought yoghurt
from here.
Couldn't chew because her
jaw was wired up.
Did you know Giani took
her away from Botosani
and now he wants to sell her
to some pimp in Spain?
Do you know what she's
been through?
She kept telling me we
might not meet again.
I thought she was going to Spain,
but she was actually running away.
Fuck, man. Why
didn't she tell me?
I'd have given her a ride to the
station. Did she get beat up bad?
She got beat up
some, for sure.
How do you mow
he beat her up?
- How do I know?
- How do you know?
Tell me, how?
A mate told me.
He drove her and saw.
He radioed me:
do you know Jeni...
See how you're
getting mixed up?
Didn't you say you
picked her up here?
I did, but I drove her
to a client, not to the station.
Something's fishy.
She is a very nice girl.
Why is she a hoe. then?
It's not like she was
aiming for it.
Didn't he grab her by force?
She feared this Giani.
How do you know his
name was Giani?
From the girls. I drive
them around. They told me.
So you know him, right?
Give me his number,
I wanna call him.
I'll run him over,
the fucking sleazebag.
You're shitting your pants over a
guy asking to borrow your phone,
and now you're picking on Giani?
Do you even know who he is?
So you know Giani.
Give me your phone.
He'll fucking punch
your lights out.
Let's see if you've got
his number.
You've got a thing
about phones!
Give me your fucking phone.
I think it was you
who called Giani.
- You fucked up this girl's life.
- I've got a client.
Are you busy?
Did he beat her up badly?
Fucking jerk-off.
Are you scared?
Are you running away?
Get the fuck out of here.
Fuck off, scumbag.
Hi.
Do you have a phone
I could borrow?
I ran out of credit.
Do you have a cigarette?
Aren't you kinda young?
We're over 14.
Give me another pack of cigs. Lights.
Have you smoked them all?
You just bought one.
I gave some away.
And I'm not leaving
until I talk to her.
Even if Im here all night
and you close shop.
It's non-stop, I can't close.
Give me your SIM card.
Are you messing with me?
Give me your card already.
Didn't you go in, though?
Someone came out.
I thought you went in.
- When?
- Just now.
I was at the back to see
if her bedroom light's on.
- What's the pin number?
- 1234.
Cool. Just like my
mom's number.
It's working.
What letter?
Dorica. Under D.
Dan, Danaila...
Wait.
Who's Daniela Baby?
My step sister.
You're shitting me.
Step sister in the gypsy
community. Give me a break.
- Are you calling her?
- Shut up.
Here she is. Dorica!
Elena, Elisabeta...
Who are these?
Cat got your tongue?
Teddy, boy, you
sure love pussy.
Don't you? Are you
calling her or what?
Shut up.
Are you gonna marry her?
What's it to you?
Help me talk to her.
The rest is my business.
If you don't want to marry
her, why do you insist?
I thought it was a serious thing.
I'm only helping young
people to start a family.
Even if they're gypsies.
Is she a gypsy too?
We're not gypsies, man.
Are you calling her or what?
So, say it. Dafto, bulandro!
Give me a break and
call her already.
OK. You wanted Dorica,
we're calling Dorica.
I will ask her to
come down, but after
I will tell her about the
girls in your phone.
- OK, give me my card.
- What's got your goat?
- Give me my card.
- It's ringing. Shut up.
It's ringing.
- Answer that.
- Don't answer.
- Answer him!
She hung up.
Call again and let
me talk to her.
Wait.
- Is it ringing?
- Yes. Shut up.
She's holding strong.
Wait.
- Hello!
- Miss Dora?
No, I'm not Teddy.
How can I explain...
I'm calling from his card.
It's not him.
So you know Teodor,
right? Teddy.
I know him. Why are you calling
from his card? Is he OK?
He's OK. He's next to me,
here at the non-stop.
His battery's dead, and
he asked me to call
and ask you to come downstairs cause
he doesn't remember
the intercom code.
He's asking you to go downstairs
and give him the intercom code.
I never want to see him again.
I don't want to talk to him.
If he forgot the code,
he can't have it.
Tell him I never want
to talk to him again.
If he forgot the code,
he can't have it.
He forgot it tough luck.
She is not giving you
the code. Tough luck.
- Give it here. Let me talk to her.
- Shut up.
Do you want me to shut the window?
Miss? Please come downstairs
and talk to him.
He says you should
go talk to him.
- Should I go?
- Don't go.
Tell him you're not going.
I'm not coming.
- She's not coming.
- Let me talk to her!
What do you want
me to tell her?
Tell her I'm sorry and I
want to apologize tonight.
And she should give
me the code.
Miss, he's sorry.
He apologizes.
And please give him
the code please.
He says he's sorry.
See? He's sorry.
Why should she forgive him?
We decided she wouldn't.
What the fuck?
He did wrong, he
should pay for it.
You don't need his apologies.
Forgiveness is the greatest
virtue. I read that.
So what do I do
if he's sorry?
- Like hell.
- He is sorry.
Hello! Is he sorry
or not?
Let me ask him.
Are you sorry?
Of course I'm sorry.
We should talk about it.
Shut up, moron.
Miss, he says he
wants back in
so you can make up,
and he wants you.
- Just say what I tell you.
- I want to get her back.
Just say what I tell you.
I'm sorry Dora.
He says he wants you
to take him back in.
To make up.
- I'm not ta ling him back.
- We're not taking him back.
I'm taking him back, but
he should convince me.
He should convince us.
Are you nuts? Didn't we decide
we're not having him back?
He should promise.
She says you should promise.
I don't know what, but she's upset.
You made her cry.
Let me talk to her already.
Dora I'm sorry. Dora,
I love you so much.
I can't hear what
she's saying.
Tell her I want to apologize.
Do you want me to
close the window?
- He should admit it.
- Have him admit it.
If he does...
I'll see...
- Do you admit it?
- Admit what?
Miss, please don't cry.
You made her cry.
It's a shame to spill all
your tears over nothing.
What tears?
Tears are not separate,
happy tears in one place and
sad tears someplace else.
- What?
- I can't hear.
Now they'll all be sad tears.
I knocked her over.
You get me?
- A beer, please.
- Inventory.
- Isn't this a non-stop?
- You heard me!
- Can't I...
- Get lost. We're closed.
Hello? I can't
hear him.
I'm asking you, please.
He deserves a chance.
What's she saying?
Look, this guy wants to propose and
you want to cry happy tears right?
What tears, what propo...
I think he's going to propose.
What proposal, what's
all this about tears?
- You're not nuts. Tell him no.
- I do, but not from a non-stop.
I do but not from a non-stop.
Please, miss.
He's here with flowers.
He's got flowers and asking
you to take him back.
I don't want flowers. And I don't
want a proposal from a non-stop.
Go get some flowers, quick.
He hasn't got any flowers.
You can see him from the 2nd floor.
Did he bring snowdrops or what?
I'm not blind. He had
his hands in his pockets.
Give it to me. Let me decide
when and how I propose.
He says he'll decide
when to propose.
- You are not helping me with this.
- What the hell do you want?
That's my business.
Let me talk to her.
I'm closing the window.
He is so nice...
I think it's super-romantic.
I wish it happened to me.
There're five women
for every man on Earth.
Let's not upset them.
I think it's super-romantic.
I wish it happened to me.
If you don't go, I'll
give him the code.
Give him the code
to your house.
- I haven't got a code.
- You haven't got a house.
You're like her.
Collecting losers.
She's not alone.
- Give it to me.
- Cut it out.
Are you messing with us?
Who's there with you?
Mind your own business.
What's your deal here?
You know what?
What do you mean,
what's my deal here?
Am I wasting time
with you here? Fuck this.
I'm trying to help,
and what do I get?
I'm asking you,
please marry this girl.
It's a shame, the way she's
crying for you. Marry her.
- Let me talk to her already.
- Shut up.
Not you, him...
I'll show you I'm a good guy.
I'll put him on, OK?
You're proposing now, OK?
In front of the non-stop.
- He's proposing.
You don't propose
when you want.
You propose when I want.
I am pregnant with you
and you ask if it's yours.
How do I know?
I know.
You're shitting me.
Anyway, shouldn't we break up?
Good. We'll do as you said.
Do you know the pain
I've been through?
I'm taking my hand
off you.
I've cried myself silly the night
you said we should take a break.
So? I just said you should decide
what to do.
I was pregnant with you.
Hello?
I think I ran out of credit.
Fucking...
Talk it over. Like
people in love, right?
It was your fault anyway.
I asked you to be careful,
I had no condoms, and you said
you didn't have any either
just to show me you weren't
seeing any whores.
I asked you to go to the non-stop
for some, why didn't you?
You said they don't sell
condoms at the non-stop.
I asked you to take care.
Man oh man.
I said I'd get pregnant.
You said water and soap were
the best contraceptive.
When I came back, you were
snoring like a drill press.
I said when I was
in the bathroom
that I wanted a girl
who'd look like you.
That I loved you, you moron.
- Redneck.
- The bad boy.
Go quick, someone's
coming out.
I'm not coming.
You can't use me
and throw me away.
And don't come
here, either.
What flowers did you get me?
Hello?
You bastard!
Want a Coke?
Cold?
- Chocolate, too?
- No, I don't.
Yeah you do.
Cheers.
Are you back?
- I came for the cables.
- So you're back.
- Give me a Coke.
- What kind?
Whatever you've got.
And water.
- Still?
- No.
And crackers
And a chocolate.
Several, actually.
Got any kids' candy?
- What kind?
- Whatever.
- Anything to eat?
- No.
Yeah you do.
Give me something to eat.
You've come to your senses?
- Pates ok?
- Yeah.
- Two.
- OK.
Bread?
Did they come along
with my cables?
No.
- How much?
- It's OK.
- Tell me.
- It's OK, I tell you.
- Cheers, man.
- Cheers.
I got you candy
for the kid.
How much to Botosani?
Seven hours or so.
How much, not how long.
A hundred and something.
But I got nothing.
He took everything.
All your stuff?
Everything.
My money, my bag,
my teddy bear.
Forget the teddy bear.
I'll give you a ride.
And I'll give you some money, too.
We'll stop on the way
and get a teddy bear.
Thank you.
Take this, too.
Jeni, I'll talk to the guys.
They'll set him straight.
Be safe! Well done.
What can I get you?
I'd like...
a candle.
I don't understand. What?
A candle...
A candle?
Sorry. Haven't got any.
Sorry. We had scented candles,
but they didn't sell well.
- Jeez, Colonel!
- Yes.
- Sorry. I didn't recognize you.
- Yeah.
You've lost a lot of weight.
Is the power down?
A candle...
Sorry, I really haven't
got any.
How's Mrs. Antonia? OK?
How are the dogs?
- She's...
- Wait maybe I can help.
Colonel...
take this flashlight.
It's old... for free.
- No...
- No charge!
But she's... dead.
It's not dead. Press here.
See? It's on. See?
It's working. You
can use it. Please.
No. Candle.
Haven't got any. Sorry.
You'll do with
the flashlight.
Let me help you.
Cheers, Colonel!
I'll get someone to look
at the electric board, OK?
Oh my God. She's dead!
Fuck.
Colonel, I apologize.
I didn't understand.
I found these candles.
Take them.
What can I say? My condolences.
God rest her soul.
And I apologize once again.
Man, it's a fucking
rattle-bag.
Where are you taking it?
The non-stop here. Or they'll
steal it by tomorrow.
- Steal? This?
- They'll steal the engine.
He can watch it.
- This deathtrap?
- Yeah, this deathtrap.
You were good, I must admit it.
- Take the cables.
- Yes boss!
You left me alone, you dirtbag.
You did well, but I shat my pants
when you didn't take the money.
- Why?
- What if he called the police?
He wanted to give me the lei,
but then I saw the Euros.
And the moron was drunk too.
And the insurance doesn't cover it.
If you're drunk. Get it?
- Still, man.
- What?
What if he called the police?
The money he's got could buy the
cops and the car on top of it.
- The wedding ring, sucker.
- What?
He was married.
He wasn't going to call anyone.
Stop staring at me.
Give him the cables.
- You're smart.
- You can say that again.
I got you the cables.
Good. The man came for them
twice today. He was pretty upset.
We'll work it out.
Give me the money.
Here.
Five hundred for me,
five hundred for you.
How do we split this?
- We'll exchange it tomorrow.
- I need it now.
- Where to exchange it?
- Here.
He hasn't got it.
Don't, man.
Sir, could you exchange five
hundred Euros for us?
Five hundred Euros?
What am I, Carrefour?
I don't make that kind
of money in a week.
Wait. How much did
you owe me?
- Me?
- Yeah.
- Thirteen hundred.
- So. Five hundred?
At a rate of four lei. We'll work out
the difference. Seven, then.
- What difference? What?
- Wait.
Wait, we're getting
confused here.
Four lei is too little.
For how long you put
me off, it's OK.
I'll exchange two hundred,
but not at a rate of four.
Putting me off again?
No, and I'll give you
the rest afterwards.
- Four two OK?
- Four two is OK.
- I don't like it.
- It's OK.
- Let me see if I got the money.
- What are you talking about?
- It's none of your business, man.
- It's my money.
It comes out of my half.
- Where did you get the money?
- What's it to you?
They're fake!
Counterfeit!
Fake, how?
Are you stupid?
Come here. You
seem smarter.
Look here. Do you see
any safety marks here?
This is printer-grade paper, man.
Are you this fucking stupid?
Even my mama could tell.
Fucking shit!
What did you do?
Did you take counterfeit money?
He was giving you lei.
Why didn't you take lei?
You think you're smart?
Un-fucking-believable!
My heart!
What do I do now?
Fucking kill me already.
How do I pay him tonight?
Fuck.
Here, eat these Euros.
You want Euros? Here!
- Fuck.
- Hold it, man.
What are you doing?
Where are you going?
I'm going to look for
a moron like you.
So you're leaving me with
the car all messed up?
Fucking moron!
Where are you going
with the money?
Where did you get the money?
It's a serious crime.
Got money to go to Spain?
I got no money to give you,
much less go to Spain.
It's OK. Have a beer.
Thanks.
Motherfucking life.
Speaking of life.
Do you know Mr. Anton?
The Colonel? Third floor?
No.
Does he need Euros?
He doesn't need anything.
You wouldn't know him, really.
He hasn't gone outside in years.
You know his wife.
Mrs. Anton.
- No.
- You've got to.
The white-haired lady.
Seventy-ish.
- With the stray-dogs?
- That's the one.
- What about her?
- Nothing. She died.
Subtitles ripped by gooz
karagarga, 2018