Good Springs?
I'm just going as far as Searchlight.
What's anybody
wanna go to Good Springs for anyway?
That town has been near deserted ever since
the mine closed and the Gillespies moved
their silver operation over to
Kingman Arizona.
Searchlight is where I turn off.
Thank heaven I come along when I did.
It'll be dark before long.
Rattlers come out to the road
for warmth then.
A person don't stand a chance
way out here with them buggers.
People have been known to just
disappear out here in this desert.
One minute they're there,
and then poof, they're gone.
I'm ahead of schedule today.
Maybe we could... stop and...
stretch somewhere.
I guess Good Springs ain't too
far out of my way.
Thank God I came along wihen I did.
Town's just up ahead.
This looks like a nice quiet spot.
Hey! Hey! God dammit!
Where do you think you're going?
Damn you!
Damn you! Those rattlers are
gonna eat you alive!
I hope they get you and you burn
in hell, you little harlett!
Ow... ow... Jeez.
- Miss.
- Hello.
Something you want?
How can I tell until
I know what you got?
Maybe you're making a mistake.
Maybe you're looking for
somebody else's place.
Not mine.
I'm looking for you.
How do you know?
You ain't seen me before.
You're Jess Tyler.
Who are you?
Just somebody you might like to know.
I don't like people making fun.
Maybe I'm not.
That ain't gonna be cold.
I like it warm.
With foam on it.
You're a Morgan, ain't you?
What makes you think that?
You can tell a Morgan anywhere.
If you know what to look for.
I bet I know what you was
looking for when you was 19.
Bell Morgan was 14.
You musta liked it. You married her.
Maybe.
You didn't like Bell?
Once.
You musta liked her more than
once. You had two kids.
I don't talk about it.
Did other men have something to
do with it?
Maybe.
A man named Moke Blue.
So you put her out.
No.
She left.
With him.
Well, maybe she didn't want to
be stuck out here alone.
Maybe she liked people.
Yeah.
Maybe she liked a lot of things.
Do you ever think about her?
Uh-uh.
Or the children?
Sometimes.
You ever want to see them?
They left when the mine closed.
Ten years ago.
When it was operating, I was in
charge of the small chunks of ore.
You know, the kind that somebody can just reach down,
pick up and stick in their pocket and run off with.
Well, I never did.
Not even a few nuggets?
Just for yourself or Bell?
No.
That's why they give me the job
of guarding it now.
Keeping it away from scavengers.
Well, maybe you shoulda taken some.
- Things may have been different for you and her.
- I doubt it.
That's what I heard.
- Who from?
- Don't you know?
No!
Look who's raring up.
Hey,
don't it get lonely out here?
Or is just milking that
cow good enough for you?
You keep talking like that
something might just happen to you.
Not unless I want it to.
If you were a Morgan, you'd want it to.
That's good because I am a Morgan.
I'm your daughter, Kady.
Hard to say something Jess? You didn't
think I'd still be a little girl, did yah?
No. I didn't think you'd be so
grown up either.
Had to grow up around Bell and that boarding
house she runs for Gillespie miners.
I was ten when I found out that
she was selling more
to the boarders than just
meals and clean sheets.
Jane too, I suppose.
Yeah, it wasn't all bad.
The miners was nice to us.
We reminded them of their own kids.
We called they Daddy Bob, Dadddy George.
It made them feel good, I guess.
Not so lonely.
Jane... used to favor me.
Does she still?
She took over running the place when Bell got
sick but, she wanted to go out and finish school.
Bell's sickness...
all come out of a bottle.
It's pretty bad lung trouble.
The Doctor said she ain't got long.
We tried to get Moke Blue to help out
and that's like trying to get
water to run uphill.
You finish school?
No.
- Why is that?
- Is it ever?
A man?
I got pregnant...
and quit school when I started swelling.
The baby was born about a month ago.
His daddy had even see it.
- Well, I...
- Don't say you're sorry Jess. That's what he said.
I couldn't take it anymore.
Listening to the laughs and whispers.
Walk down the street
with my stomach out and
I hear people say that's
Bell's daughter alright. That's
one kid that listened good to
her parent.
Jane is taking care of the baby.
She really is.
But I had to get away.
You don't have to do that.
Oh, I don't mind. I want to.
I like doing things for a man.
- You will make somebody a good wife.
- Maybe...
but I ain't wanting to get married, righ now.
- What are yo planning on doing?
Keep you from being lonely.
I come to stay with you.
You can't do that Kady.
Sorry, you just can't.
Don't make me go.
Look, get your stuff together
and, I'll run you wherever you
want to go, but
you just can't stay here.
Please.
Jess!
I'm your daughter and I got
no place to go.
Goodnight.
Jess.
Yeah.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Goodnight.
Kady.
It's Sunday. I got to go to church.
Kady!
Kady? Whatcha doing up there?
- Just looking.
- Well, there ain't much to look at.
You ever go in Jess?
Yeah, once in a while.
Make sure there no scavengers
been in there.
How much silver is in there Jess?
Oh, there's a good bit of little stuff.
Chippings mostly.
But...
not enough for Mr. Gillespie to
keep a full crew on.
Keep both me and the mill
working at the same time.
Is that why they closed it down?
Yeah.
Maybe they didn't
stick with it long enough.
Maybe it's still there.
Maybe.
You know Mr. Gillespie is a pretty smart
business man. He knows what he's doing.
Yeah.
It's getting late
and I gotta go to church.
Wanna come?
- Is there enough silver in there to make
one, maybe two people rich?
Yeah.
If they could get to it.
What's to stop them?
- Me. Now, let's go.
No! You're the guard here Jess.
What's to stop
us from getting it out?
Ourselves. Come on.
Is all you want from life is that
miserable shack and a lonely closed down
mine to live with?
Kady, we all come to be what
God put us on this earth to be.
Now, Mr. Gillespie was made to own
this mine and I was made to guard it.
That's just the way things
are and that's just fine.
No it's not Jess.
You got nothing in this job and
living in this place, and
having nothing is being nothing.
Jess, I ain't got anything either.
We could change that
if we had what's in there.
Is that all you came back for?
Silver?
You got more Morgan in you than Tyler.
Maybe so and maybe that ain't all bad.
- Oh, yes it is. Yes it is.
You know, maybe those people in
Kingman were right.
Bad comes from bad.
Maybe you just are just
(?) about his daughter.
No!
Yes! You were bad when got yourself
pregnant without being married!
What I got from it was good!
Little Danny.
Jess, the father of my baby is
Wash Gillespie.
Who's father owns this mine. Yeah.
Oh he enjoyed himself with me pretty good, but he
couldn't stand up to his parents and marry me.
The people who treat you so good Jess.
The good Gillespies...
they talked him out of marrying me
because I'm a Morgan and a Tyler.
I'm not as good as Gillespie.
That don't make stealing their silver right.
- Right? They owe me and my baby!
If I take that silver, that's payment,
and that's right and it's good.
Jess, the first time I ever had a paper
dollar bill in my hand, I was 12 years old.
I let one of the boarders
spend the night with me.
Maybe that was bad,
but the things I bought with that
money was good, and I want more.
For me and for my baby.
I want good things for us, and if
that's bad, then I want to be bad!
I'm taking you to church.
Just remember, you're not
Bell's daughter here.
You're mine.
- Morning John.
- Jess.
- Who's that?
- Ed Lamey.
Some worthless relative of Moke Blue's.
He's a mine scavenger.
Let us all pray.
We thank you Father for allowing us
to gather together again on this day.
Amen.
We don't get many outsiders coming
around here much anymore.
But today, we have Kady Tyler with us.
She has been living with her
mama for some time now.
Well, if our simple way of life ain't too boring
for her, maybe she'll stay around for a while.
Kady Tyler living over there in Kingman coming back this
way, brings to mind the 15th chapter of the book of Luke.
Jesus told a story
about this wealthy man who divided
his goods between his two sons.
One of those sons saved his
portions and stayed home.
The other one took his to a
foreign land
and came in contacts with temptations
that he'd never been faced with before.
He gave into those temptations.
Nefarious living.
Strong wine and the sin of lust and
fornication with the flesh of (?)
- He's talking to me.
- Shhh.
Now, he had nothing left.
So the son went home and faced
his father and he said Father,
I sinned against heaven before thee.
I should no more be called your son.
What did his father do? When his prodigal
son came home with only rags on his back.
- Kicked his butt.
- Kady.
He reached out for him and
hugged him he kissed him.
You should have done that to me Jess.
My son was dead and now he's alive.
He was lost and now he's found and
they all laughed and they rejoiced.
Hallelujah!
Are you the prodigal daughter?
God forgives all sins Kady,
when you come home.
He'll reach down and touch you and
wash all over you with goodness!
And cleanse your heart and soul
when you accept him!
Kady!
Kady! Don't do this. Don't turn away.
What was he trying to do to me?
- Trying to help you Kady.
Then give me some help that I can
hold in my hand and put in my pocket.
- Now let me go!
- Where you going Kady?
Kady!
Reminds me a lot of Bell.
I have been nothing to her for
ten years.
It's hard.
It's been so long a time.
You can only be a daddy to her Jess.
Nothing more.
Come inside.
Talk to the lord some more.
I can't.
Morning Jess.
- Who was that?
- A friend.
- Who was he?
- Oh, don't yell.
Did you lay up with him last night?
If I did would you get your
shotgun and make him marry me?
Where was you last night?
Kady!
I met a girl and
we got to be friends. I stayed
over there when it got too dark.
What was her name?
I forgot.
It was no girl that brought you home.
No.
Who was it then?!
Her brother.
What did you do last night?
Enjoyed ourselves, but I don't
think you like that.
Excuse me Jess.
What are you gonna do?
Women's business.
Kady, can I come in?
- It's hot.
- Thanks.
Kady,
you're welcome to stay
but I just don't want you pulling
anything like you did yesterday.
I've been thinking about it Jess.
I just don't think it will work if I do stay here.
- Look, I don't mind you having fun every now and again.
- No, I...
- I don't even mind if you have
a drink once in a while, but here!
- I want money and I need money.
- Look...
I want to help and I want you to stay here and
I want to be able to figure out what to do
with you and your baby.
- I'm leaving tomorrow...
But I've been thinking about it and
...and find me a job.
No.
You stay here. I'm gonna work the mine.
Silver.
- (?)
- Anything
But we just can't take
a whole lot but...
We can take the small stuff. The chips.
It will be enough to
keep you comfortable.
Yeah!
Ow. Maybe I got feeling too
good last night.
You just needed somebody to
look after you. That's all.
From now on,
you can do whatever you want my dear.
The only thing you'll
miss is the hangover.
Kiss even make it feel better?
Just rest now. Take it easy.
Oh, it's scary in here Jess.
How far back are we going?
Not far. Just to the room where
the main vein petered out.
Are there a lot of rooms?
Yeah, we dug them out
just before the mine closed.
Maybe there is more silver in them.
Let's go further back.
It's too dangerous.
Oh, what's that!
- Probably a rat. It won't bite you.
They're our friends. They can tell even
before God if there's any trouble down here.
They start to run out, we follow them.
This is a good place for chipping.
Look Jess. Gold!
No, that ain't gold. It's copper.
Here. I'll show you.
See... all this right here is copper.
This is zinc.
Now when copper and zinc are together,
that's when you usually find silver.
This is the drill point.
This is a single jack. Like this.
Knock it in there like that and
pry the chips loose.
Silver?
Zinc.
Jess, won't that take too long?
- Well...
Can't we get some dynamite and blast out a big one?
- Dynamite? Are you kidding?
Dynamite would bring the sheriff and
every scavenger from miles around.
- They can't hear us way down here.
- You'd be surprised. Sound carries down here.
You just keep pounding like this.
- OK.
- I'll work this side over here.
Oh...
Kady!
Come on Kady, wake up.
Come on.
- A nice hot bath will help.
- Oh my god.
Here, put this on.
Kady, come on. You can't sleep
dirty like that. Come on.
Come on. You'll feel a lot better.
OK? Some miner you are.
Oh... Ahhh...
That's hot!
Feels good.
Is it going to be like this every day? Hurting
all over and not a thing to show for it?
Well, they didn't close that mine down
because it has a lot of silver in it.
You gotta work for it.
My shoulders feel like
somebody's been mining them.
It'll be like that for a couple days.
- Rub them down for me Jess, please.
Well, you ain't got no liniment around.
Just rub them. Loosen them.
Oh, they hurt.
Harder Jess.
It takes so long this way.
Can there be another main vein
in there?
It's happened. It's rare.
It's happened.
That feels so good Jess.
You got good hands.
- What's wrong?
- It ain't right.
It feels good to me.
Does it to you?
It just ain't right.
It's right if it's good.
But you're my daughter Kady.
I'm a woman too.
Sometimes, I need.
We both do.
- No.
Kady, you got to be careful.
- Ow! Shit! Bitch! Damn!
I told you, you got to be careful!
I'm going to be careful. I'm
gonna be careful getting
that better way of making money.
There is no god damn silver in here.
I'm getting out!
- You got to more gentle, that's all.
You didn't hear me. I'm getting out!
- Kady,
see this. You know what that is?
That's silver.
Look at that.
It's green!
- That's right. Silver is green.
The chippets are. Of course,
if you hit a main vein, it's silver, but
silver ore is all green.
Oh my God! Look Jess. Look at
this. I've been throwing
this stuff away for an hour. Look! Look!
- Silver!
How much is it worth?
- About 90 cents an ounce.
At least a hundred dollars here!
Oh my God, we're rich!
When do we get the money for it?
In a few days, we will take it over
to Colville and sell it over there..
Let's get to work.
Oh we're going to be rich, Jess. Rich!
Stop here Jess!
What for? The office is further down.
- I'm gonna get a new dress.
You get yourself a new suit, a
shave, and a hair cut,
because we're gonna celebrate!
- OK! See you later!
Can I help you sir?
Yes, I'm looking for a girl.
Brown eyes, pretty.
She came in here a little while ago.
- Yes, named Kady.
- That's right.
She said a man would be in to pay for
the dress she bought. That's 8 dollars.
Your friend has very good taste in cloth.
- She's my daughter.
Where did she go?
- She went to the White Horse Cafe. Just across the street.
Kady.
Hey now!
Don't you look good!
You really think so?
- You're the best looking man in the place.
How much did we get?
- 210 dollars.
210 dollars! Let's celebrate!
Sit down and have a drink.
Why don't we just go home and
celebrate?
This is Richard. This is Billy Roy.
That's my daddy.
Richard, get daddy a drink.
- Oh you got it.
Sit down.
What are you drinking?
Um... Coca-Cola.
On Coke Patty.
Is that really your daughter?
I was just asking.
Old man don't look like he's in a
good mood. Let's get out of here.
OK.
You ready to go?
- Have another drink, Jess.
- I wanna be on.
- Where you going?
Billy Roy's got a brand new convertible
car. He's gonna take me for a ride.
Why?
Because sometimes...
people need to be made to feel good.
Kady. No, Kady!
Listen, pops, take it easy
and we won't have any trouble.
I am her daddy and she's staying here with me.
- It's not like she wants to old man,
and right now she wants to go for a ride.
So, that's what we are going to do.
Sit down and have yourself a glass
of prune juice and loosen up.
When we get back
here with her, you can have her.
- But not before.
- Kady.
Don't do this Kady.
Oh, daddy...
You never stopped Bell from doing it.
Don't stop me.
Come home with me.
It'll be different.
Stay down daddy. Stay down.
Kady, get to the truck!
Get to the truck Kady!
Leave Kady!
Get out of here Kady!
Kady! Get out of here Kady!
No!
Get off me! My eyes! My eyes!
- Get off of me!
- Go get the sheriff.
Kady.
- Your honor.
- Oh!?
You got anything to say before...
sentence is passed on you?
The only reason I was in that furniture
store was for the beds.
I didn't take nothing out.
They caught you before you had a chance.
Got any money?
I was only trying to get a good night's rest your honor.
- How much?
Two dollars.
Two dollars is the fine
you are to rest in this community.
I was just passing through.
- Well, you were with us long enough to
catch up with your sleep. Sixteen days.
Next case!
Tyler and Tyler versus White Horse Cafe.
Won't take much to figure that one out.
- Tyler.
- Yes sir.
This is your daughter?
Yes.
Well, now, this court is not about to
make a criminal out of a father defending
the honor of his daughter.
Now, however there are a few
charges that can't be overlooked.
Disturbing the peace,
destruction of private property though
How much a joint like that,
White Horse is worth, I wouldn't know.
I mean considering the kind of
trash it caters to and the transient
no goods that come sailing
through the great state of Nevada.
There's no excuse for you Tyler.
- You're no tourist.
- No sir.
- And you're no transient.
Oh you're part of our own God-fearing community.
How much money you got in your pocket?
Umm. About twelve dollars.
Disorderly conduct, five dollars. Court
costs, five dollars. Two dollars damages.
Pay the clerk or maybe you would
like to work for the county too?
No, I'd rather pay.
As for you, young woman.
How old are you?
Seventeen sir.
Come closer. I didn't hear you.
Come closer.
Closer.
Seventeen eh?
Sixteen.
You been drinking?
- I don't know sir.
- You don't know?
Well sir, I was drinking Coca-cola
but you know how it is.
- You tell me how it is.
- OK.
Sometimes they put a little
something in it, just for fun.
Butchers.
Let me smell your breath.
But today, I don't know if they did or n..
- I want to smell.
You are still not close enough.
Psst. Psst.
Discipline!
A wayward minor. That's a nice
legal word for what you are.
And that's quite enough for me to have
you committed, Do you realize that?
Send you straight up to the reform
school. Isn't that where you belong?
First complaint I hear from him.
You're up for commitment. Understand?
- Yes, your honor.
Discipline!
You're her father man.
Next case.
Discipline!
Discipline! Discipline!
It's a good thing you didn't tell that
judge how much money we really have.
You didn't want me let that judge put you in reform school, haven't you?
- You wouldn't and besides
that he'd like to put me
somewhere else, right.
Don't talk like that.
- You noticed too.
I didn't want to smile too much at him.
I'm afraid you'd start
beating up on him.
Then you'd end up in jail for sure.
- Doesn't it shame you just a little bit to go making up
to every single man you meet?
- What's to be ashamed of?
Well, I guess it's just in the blood.
- I don't want to hear any more of that Morgan stuff.
Well, it's inbred. You got to
be aware of it.
I'm aware of it. Are you?
I am.
- You'd like to have me tonight wouldn't you Jess?
Now Kady now...
Come on Kady, don't do that.
Kady, I got to watch the road.
- It must be lonely plenty.
Let's stop an have another drink somewhere, Jess.
- Oh, no!
How about you going to that reform school?
- Oh yeah.
Jane! Jane!
- Great to see you out here!
- Likewise!
How's Danny?
He's fine. He's in the house.
Jane.
Daddy.
See my baby?
What a pretty baby.
He's your grandson!
OK Danny, come on.
I'll help you Janey.
Hold him for me will you Jess.
He just ate.
Will you burp him for me Jess?
You remember how to do that?
That a boy. Yeah.
Oh, he's a fine boy.
Gonna make a fine man. Aren't yah?
Hey, what's this?
It's a birthmark Jess.
It don't come off.
Oh, he's so sweet.
Yes he is. He is so wonderful.
He's such a sweet boy!
- How'd you like to have a son-in-law, Jess?
What do you mean?
Well, I ran into Wash in Kingman.
We had a good talk and he told
me what happened.
His parents made him leave Kady.
- He's not too strong.
Are you taking his side now?
- But they changed their minds.
Everything is fine now and he
wants to marry her. He always did.
He doesn't sound like
much of a man to me.
Maybe he's not... right now.
He's coming for me tomorrow.
Oh... He's here!
Wash is here!
Kady! Kady!
- Kady!
- Wash! Wash!
Wash Gillespie, I don't give a damn
if this is your property or not.
You turn that big new car around and go right back
to your mama and daddy. Do you understand me?
Heh...
Didn't Janey tell you I was coming?
- Yeah, she told me.
And you thought I'd just be sitting
around here waiting, wide open for you.
Well, I got one baby sucking on me.
I don't need another.
Honey, I'm sorry. I apologize.
I came here to marry you.
Oh, is there something making you
think I wanna marry you?
Heh, yeah. I thought you loved me.
And I thought I was loving a
man, not a mama's boy.
You go on home Wash. When you decide
whose skirt your gonna chase
hers or mine, then you come back
and see if I'm still around.
Kady! Honey!
Honey look, it's you. I want you.
And I mean to have you. I mean
to marry you.
- I ain't heard you ask me.
- I'm asking.
Ask.
Will you marry me?
Yes!
Take it easy. Where'd you learn
how to drive?
Easy! Easy! Use the brakes!
After we're married,
you gotta buy me one of these, Wash.
The color to match my eyes.
This is Wash!
Figures.
- Wash, this is Jess, my daddy.
Sir.
How are you?
This is your son.
Hey Danny, old timer.
I'd like to marry your daughter, sir.
And I'd like your permission
and your blessing.
Well, it's a little late for me to go
on being protective daddy.
Maybe but not for me.
Uh, and I would like to apologize to
everybody for the way that I acted
and tell you that she will never want
for anything as long as she lives.
You got my word on that Jess.
Well...
If you make her happy.
He will.
Come on into my house Wash Gillespie.
I don't want to make
all the arrangements.
We will get married
the day after tomorrow.
There's a hotel in Goldfield where my
parents mommy, daddy and I can stay.
It's a little quick.
I don't want to waste any more time.
Your folks weren't coming up
here tonight, was they Wash?
Uh, no sir.
Only one truck sounds like that.
It's Ed Lamey's.
Jane.
Ain't holding Jess. Ain't holding.
Wouldn't come to your
house if I was holding.
If you was holding Moke Blue
you'd be on your way to hell right now.
Now, turn around and
get off this property.
Now hold on Jess. I come here
on peacable terms.
My golly, it looks like a family
reunion here. Janey, Kady...
I saw you with that boy Jess.
Ain't that a fine boy.
- What are you doing here Moke?
Mr. Gillespie, how do you do?
I brought you something Jess.
Yes sir.
A surprise for you.
Come on Ed,
give me a hand here, will ya,
He keeps the rifle on
the truck if he gets out.
Right!
- Ain't you ready yet?
- Just a minute!
It's Bell, Jess! It's Bell!
You look just fine. Wait a minute!
There you go.
You're alright. You're alright.
Well,
well, hell Jess,
can't you even say hello?
Hello Bell.
Ain't that some surprise?
See, Janey said Kady was over here getting married.
So when I ran over here at the Kingman, I...
said,
hell Bell, why don't we just drive over and
see that? Her whole family is over here.
She was feeling lonesome, so...
- Shut up Moke.
Well, I
did want to see Kady get married.
And, um, I wanted to see
little Danny boy again.
You see Jess holding that boy when
we drove up? Wasn't that a sight?
Get me inside.
The drive over in Ed's
truck damn near killed me.
Must've been harder
on him on Moke though.
Bouncing up and down on their
brains like that.
There's my girls!
Come on over and give your mama a kiss!
Here's the baby! Oh Danny boy!
Sure knows how to keep him in line.
He ain't got much backbone.
Plenty of what makes life good.
Money... huh Jess?
- Money ain't everything Bell.
- No.
But it runs a good second best
to what she caught him with.
You'd better take some lessons
from her honey.
Janey is just like you Jess... stoney.
You know you was born with your
hands between your legs honey.
You ain't took them out since.
I love you.
You just gotta go snap, you know.
Loosen up or you're just gonna
wind up as dried up and barren
as that desert out there!
You know what I mean.
Let's
Bell!
Oh god, she's bleeding again!
Get her on the bed.
Put Danny on the couch.
I'm gonna die.
- Awful sorry Bell.
- Hell, I'm not.
I made a mess of my life.
You lived your life you wanted to.
- I lived it like I liked it.
Like I wanted.
Jess, there's something I gotta
tell you.
I gotta tell you
something... something that
What is it?
Jess...
- Jess...
- What is it Bell?
Is my makeup off?
A little bit.
Get Kady and Jane for me.
Put some on for me OK?
Alright.
Jane, Kady,
Yeah, that Kady has turned into
a real good looking woman.
Must make a man proud, huh Jess?
You're a lucky man Mr. Gillespie.
- Lucky man.
- I think so Mr. Blue.
You got a good-looking woman
a growing heir and silver.
Say Jess, you know that silver
is up to 90 cents an ounce now.
If it goes up just a little bit more
it might be worth your while to open up this
mine again Mr. Gillespie. I mean, maybe
it petered out, but then again, maybe it didn't.
And you could put old Jess there in charge.
Jess knows everything there is to
know about mining, don't you Jess?
Hell Mr. Gillespie, I bet you Jess here
could put a good piece of change in
your pocket just mining the small
bits, and if he didn't another load
It is something worth thinking about, isn't it?
I mean, the price of silver going up and all.
How is that old girl?
- She wants to see you.
- How you feeling Bell?
- Come here Moke.
Come.
What'd you and Jess talk about?
Oh,
we talked about a long time ago.
You talk about us?
I couldn't.
Would you help me get my shoes off?
Sure.
Oh, yesseree
I know these feet. These sweet
little old things.
Damn you!
She tried to kill me.
She was trying to stab me with that damn
big pin in her hat.
The crazy fool stabbed me tried to
chase me. She wanted to kill me.
- Why?
- She wanted me to
go down to hell with her, I guess. I
don't know. The sickness made her crazy.
I don't think killing you would
be called crazy Moke.
Now you get out of this house,
or I will finish for her.
Be good to Mr. Gillespie, you hear me?
You make him a good wife.
Get out!
Damn.
Time's up Moke.
Alright. Now easy Jess, easy. Now don't
get nervous with that thing, will you.
You didn't bring Bell back here to see
the family.
You ain't got that much good in you.
Well, I guess you're right, Jess.
I can't compare
to you when it comes to goodness.
You're so good.
I don't think you got
it in you to shoot me.
That's enought. Leave it alone.
- No, Jess, you can't do it.
I ran off with your
wife you couldn't do it.
So, I sure as hell don't think you're going to shoot
me now for stealing silver that ain't even yours.
Oh yeah, Ed came over and told me that you and Kady
were working the mine. That's why I come here.
Ed saw yah.
So,
you can take me on down to jail if
you wanna share a cell with me.
But I know you ain't got guts
enough to shoot me.
You
What?
That mark.
That's the same mark
on little Danny's belly.
Oh yeah... that mark.
All the boys in the family got
that marking.
You pig! You laid up with my daughter?!
I laid up with
What are you talking about
God, Jess, it's burning.
You will burn in hell... the both of you for
marking up a poor little kid like that!
You're crazy.
I saw it and Bell knew about it too.
That's why she tried to kill you.
- No, hell no.
We got that marking in our family.
Only the men get it.
If the baby's a girl, it skips.
It skips to the next boy.
You see the women are carriers.
Danny ain't your grandson, you
soft singing bastard.
He's mine!
God Jess.
There is stuff coming out of me
and it stinks.
Get me a doctor.
Kady is not my daughter?
Bell and me. We didn't know
it for 17 years... not till
Danny came along and
we seen the marking.
She's not my blood.
You ain't a drop of Tyler
blood in Kady or Danny.
Bell tried to kill me because she
thought I come here to claim him.
Hell, I don't care about them.
I wanted the silver.
Kady.
Get me a doctor Jess, please.
Get me a doctor.
God, what are you doing Jess?
You're crazy!
Jess don't do it! You can't do this!
Jess, you're crazy! Don't
please! Don't do this!
Don't do it! Don't!
Don't! Jess!
Please!
Jess! Come on in!
Well, well, Jess Tyler, How are
you Jess?
It's been a long time... too long.
It's not going to be that way
anymore not after tomorrow.
Listen, you've never
met my wife. Helen! Helen!
Come on out and say hello to Jess Tyler.
- Mrs. Gillespie.
How do you do Mr. Tyler.
I heard my husband mention you often.
Always very highly as a matter of fact.
Jess Tyler was the most honest and upstanding
man I ever knew. I always said that.
I wish all my employees were like that.
Jess!
How about a little drink?
- Oh no thank you. I don't...
Nonsense! This is a celebration.
Joining our families together and
us becoming grandparents to the kids.
To Danny! Did you bring the
bride with you Mr. Tyler?
And the boy? I can't wait to
see my grandson.
No, I didn't bring them.
Jess.
Something wrong?
I just found out something and
Well, I'm afraid I haven't been much of father to her.
- Nonsense! You did what you had to do.
Living in there in that boarding house
and mother working all the time.
I'm afraid she... well, she...
might have picked up some ways.
It was probably inevitable
living under Bell's guidance
that she would mature earlier
than most young ladies Mr. Tyler.
Maybe had I been around,
things would have been different.
But they're not Jess. Now we got to put
things where they belong... in the past.
Now, we are all ready to forget the
circumstances and accept the responsibilities.
Danny is our grandson. Wash's boy.
- No he aint.
- What?
Danny isn't Wash's baby.
He's Moke Blue's.
Who?
That marking on Danny's stomach.
Moke Blue has the exact same
mark in the exact same place.
I'm awful sorry.
Everybody's birth marks.
Dear, a baby and a man have identical
birthmarks.
How could not mean anything?
Not with Moke Blue Jess. He's
old enough to be her father.
Not with him. She couldn't.
Yes she could.
Considering the way that she was raised.
I can't believe it and
I'm going to ask her.
No.
It would only hurt you.
And everybody else.
I think it's best if you just...
don't see her again.
Ever.
Bye.
Hi Jess. How do I look?
Beautiful.
How you gonna like giving me away?
I want you to be happy.
I'm going to get everything I want
and you too Jess. I'll see to it.
Kady! Kady! He's coming!
No, that's not Wash's car.
- Looked like it, I guess.
- But it won't be long.
You'll be Mrs. Gillespie!
Get ready Jess. You don't
want to hold things up!
Sweetheart, how do you feel today?
I feel so good that I feel that
I could go into that Gillespie
mine and take out every piece
of silver in it all by myself.
I just wouldn't have
believed that out of Wash.
Maybe when I go back to clear out
Mama's things, I'll just go see him.
And I'll find out what happened.
- No, Janey, you don't need to do that.
I think the boy showed
us what he's made of.
Jess is right Jane. Let him alone.
I don't want anything from the
Gillespies but what I came here for in
the first place. The silver.
- I'll get it for you.
We'll find it. I promise.
Only we'll go farther back.
But it's dangerous back there.
I know.
But it won't be.
I can fix it.
Come with me and I'll show you.
Now.
Every time I look at those walls, I
know there's gotta be more silver there.
- Enough to make you rich.
- Ow!
Kady, you alright?
Kady.
Jane can came out. Let's go further
back into the mine Jess. Come on!
We just got four more here. You got it?
Yeah.
It's the sheriff.
Let's get those inside.
Morning.
What can I do for you?
- You Jess Tyler?
That's right. I guard this mine.
Sometimes I go through it just to make
sure no scavengers been at it.
Yes sir.
Which one of these girls is
your daughter?
- Both. Why?
- Kady.
I am.
Mr. Tyler, I got a warrant
for your arrest here.
One for Ms. Kady Tyler too.
What for?
Incest.
I loaned my favorite rifle to Moke Blue
a day or two to go hunting with.
He didn't bring it back. I went looking for
it. I thought maybe something might've
happened to it. That's when I seen them.
But they did not observe you?
Oh no sir. I was keeping good
out of sight. I don't wanna
get shot. Everybody knows how
Jess keeps to himself
on the job and don't want people around.
After I see what they doing, I know why.
- Well, just what were they doing?
Mr. Lamey.
- They were hugging and kissing.
Hugging and kissing.
Many fathers and daughters, mothers and sons, show their
affections for each one another by hugging and kissing.
Not like they's doing.
Just where did he touch her
with his hands Lamey?
On her back...
down to her...
her butt.
He put his hands up
under her skirt and rubbed.
Tits too.
How long did this go on?
- Three or four minutes maybe and then
they went on back into the mine.
- Did you follow them then?
No sir, I'd seen enough. After what
they was doing and
I knowed what they was gonna do.
That's all. Step down Mr. Lamey.
Your honor.
The peoples' concern here
is more than just
the question of what point the warmth
of a father's kiss becomes a crime.
It is a weakening of individual
morality
or perhaps simply a slight
misunderstanding
between God and Mr. Tyler,
and yet
there but for the grace of God
goes every man or woman
among us who has ever had an
incestual fantasy.
Fantasizing is not a crime. It
is the act
of incest
that we are dealing with here
today which you must deal with now.
Your honor.
The wickedness of man is great
on the earth.
And every imagination is the thoughts of
its hearts... is only evil continuing.
The acts...
the act to incest...
Is there anyone in this
courtroom who doesn't
know what that means? Sexual relations
between persons too closely
related by blood to be
entitled to marry. That's what it means.
Is there anyone in the whole Christian
world that doesn't know it's a crime?
Stand up, Tyler.
You too young woman.
The crime against nature,
shocking and repulsive
to every basic sense of propriety,
decency, and good citizenship.
If you're guilty Tyler
the sentence for what
you've done is 10 in prison.
What about her?
What about her indeed.
If she went along with you... in this
filthiness, she's just as guilty as you are.
After what I've heard in this
courtroom, Tyler, I'm holding you over
charged with incest and she will stand trial
right along with you, depending of course
on how you plead.
- Suppose I say I'm guilty.
- Are you?
What happens if I say I am?
I take your word for it and
send you to prison.
- There would be no trial.
- No Tyler.
Save the tax payers the money
and me the time, trouble and...
spiritual disgust.
And what happens...
if I say I... forced her?
This is a nation under God.
This is a good Christian community.
If that...
poor child been the object of
your unnatural lust.
She's been punished enough
and we put the criminals behind
bars, not the victims.
Then she'd be free.
- That's what I told you.
Then I'm guilty and I forced her.
Ten years Tyler. Take him to jail.
No! It's not true!
He never forced me to do anything.
Order! Order!
Let's get some order in this court!
You'll find yourselves out in
the street... all of you.
You have any idea...
what you just said.
Yes sir.
He didn't do anything to me
that I didn't want to happen.
Do you solemnly swear this...
swear her in.
He never forced me into anything.
He's the gentlest man I've ever known.
He ain't like any other man who is
grabbing and taking what
they want and taking off.
What we did was bound to happen...
from the first day we met.
And when it did, it was good
for both of us.
He's your...
your father.
And a good man.
Best man I've ever known.
He loves me.
And what you done is against the
law for a father and daughter.
But we wasn't like a
father and daughter.
Not then.
With God... it certainly wasn't.
Did you two... stop to think for a minute if
what would happen if you would have a baby?
We didn't plan to have no babies.
We were just a man and a woman.
He wanted me... I wanted him
and we loved each other.
We don't want people like you walking
the streets with talk like that.
You're going to reform school lady...
and then 10 years in prison
and your child to state's custody to
see that he gets a decent upbringing.
Your honor.
She ain't done nothing wrong.
Me either.
She's not my daughter. - What!
Sit down and shut up!
I had all I can take!
Tyler!
Are you playing games with this court?
No sir.
If you're not this woman's
father... who is?
Moke Blue.
That's a lie!
I've never known you to lie before
Jess, but I don't want to hear that,
even if it is to protect me.
- No Kady, it's true.
Moke Blue... took up with my wife
Kady's mother. - Who is now dead.
Yes sir.
It was about a year before Kady
was born.
It's kind of convenient for you
Tyler that she is dead.
It leaves you free to tell the tale just how you
like it. What about Moke Blue? He sure could
throw some light on this.
Your honor,
- Just a minute Norton. This man
is way out on a limb. I'm
interesting to see just where
he's going to saw it off. Tyler,
approach the bench.
Quiet here! Quiet!
- You aren't the girl's father?
- No sir.
What are you doing here?
If she surely isn't your daughter, then
why did you get yourself into this mess?
All you had to do was tell her.
Why didn't you?
Because she really never had a father.
Not for 10 years.
And she needed that.
And... because
I wanted to be everything I could to you
because I love you.
Your honor, please!
I bet you Mr. Lamey can clear up any
question regarding this girl's parenting.
Stay where you are Lamey.
I don't want anymore lies today.
Yes sir.
What do you know about this
girl's father, whoever he may be?
I know Moke ain't.
How do you know that?
Because he tells me everything.
Moke Blue is my brother.
He's my half brother, really.
We got the mom.
- Same mother?
- Yes sir.
She wasn't married when Moke come
along so he taken the Blue name.
Mama, she never been too proud of what she
done. So, we don't talk about it much.
Your honor.
- Oh can't anybody stay put?
I want you to look at this baby's belly.
Baby's belly?
He's got a red birth mark.
- A butterfly.
- A birthmark?
Will you please listen to me?
It's a marking that only the
boys in that family have.
If Ed Lamey and Moke Blue and her baby are related,
they'll have the same butterfly on his stomach.
Let the court see your stomach, Lamey,
Alright order!
Order! Order! Norton, Norton...
is that a birthmark? Is it a...
- butterfly.
- Is it a butterfly?
It is a butterfly.
Well, I...
Just one more little question.
If Moke Blue is her father,
why the hell didn't he tell her?!
The silver. Silver? Yeah.
Gillespie silver. Moke was sure
that after the wedding, when he
come out and admitted that Kady was his daughter,
that they'd come across with something.
Case is dismissed.
Wash!
I didn't leave you. I'd never
leave you.
Your father told my parents and
he said that I wasn't the father.
He said Moke Blue was the father.
You don't love him.
Not the same way I love you.
But he can give Danny everything
he needs... or wants.
And me
will make it right.
I don't want to lose you.
Jess, you'll never lose me.
You're my daddy.
And you'll always be my daddy.
Always.