I don't suppose we could have the penthouse,
madame?
Did you do the decorating yourselves?
Welcome to the Faroe Islands.
We wish you a pleasant stay.
Rooms are only 300 Dkr per night.
A quick drink?
We're here to have some fun
We could put our pictures in the papers.
No, it's better to show up without warning.
Shit, I forgot to tell dad.
He has no idea where I am.
Hey dad. I bet you don't know
where I am right now.
Not Berlin ...
Not London either.
Actually I'm in ... the Faroes.
The land of your roots, you know.
Dad, are you still there?
But we were supposed to stay away from her!
Now what do I do?
I don't give a shit about your agreement .
You were the one who promised to leave here
alone. Not me.
Don't be so pathetic.
I just want to see her
reaction when she sees me.
Well, you could have come up here some more
with me.
Yes, I know you should have left me with her back
then.
Oh, don't cry, -
- you don't trust me any more.
I've got to go, daddy.
I love you no matter what.
You're the best.
That's all folks.
What if I don't recognize her?
That's her.
Hi, love. Give us a kiss.
How the hell did she make
a Dane come and live up here?
I'll bet he's an islander too.
Let's wait till tomorrow, eh?
So you still want to do it?
This is the first thing I remember from when I was
little.
Have you tried the other way?
Welcome to the Faroes, Barba.
Hey, God.
I'm ready now.
Damn kids.
Aren't you going to tell her?
- Shut up. Let me do this.
It can't be ...
- Why not?
What's happening?
What are a pair of clowns
like you doing here?
Anybody you know?
- We might just be family.
Well, what are you trying to pull?
You'd better stop that.
Thanks for lending me these -
It's 19 years ago today.
I did like them once
a long time ago.
What do you think you're doing?
What's wrong, baby?
Stop that right now.
How long do you think
you'll play mama this time?
"Dearest mama, I want to sleep,
my eyes are heavy"
"Jesus will take care of me."
"Dearest mama, tuck me in..."
What the hell's going on here.?
Have you seen two crazy girls
run past here? ... Thanks.
So you girls are
looking for a ride?
Yes.
I'm going up north.
So are we. We're going to see Rannvá's parents.
Shouldn't we just forget the whole thing?
Well, you can come with me
- if a long detour is OK with you?
Hello love. Don't bother
dressing up in Faroese wool.
You'll always just be a Dane.
I love the zebra, don't you?
Yes, did you do it yourself?
Yes.
What are you going up north for?
Well ... business.
So are we.
Stop. Let me out.
Are you crazy? Don't you know
the air in here is dangerous?
Why the hell did you have to drag me up here?
I have nothing to do here.
I'm not ready yet.
I just thought you missed them. That's all.
I didn't know ...
- What the hell do you know?
No. I just don't understand:
You have a good family here.
It's all right, but not too fast.
I just need some time.
No problem. I've got lots of business to do on the
way.
But let's get out of here before the gnomes think
we live here.
You're not pregnant, are you?
I'd have beaten you up
if you were.
Yes, imagine what healthy and happy kids you'd
have.
This is going to take a while...
Just two points.
I thought moustaches were out up here.
Nice profile.
Did you see him?
Almost too good to be true.
But he probably gets pissed every weekend -
- while his wife's at home with the kids, right?
Rúni, do you also drink
and fuck around every weekend -
- while your wife's at home with the kids? Do you?
Blah blah. Is that all you got out of going abroad for
so long?
Now look.
No, I don't want you
to go over there.
Don't go. I don't want you to.
So you want to fuck with me,
you no good sailor?
Are you so far gone you need two whores?
No friends left?
It's a bit late
to shut up, isn't it?
You had to babble about it
on the radio, didn't you?
You're done with fishing, you .. blabber mouth.
What's that?
Leave my friends alone.
Do your wife's little secrets bother you?
Don't worry. She'll probably wash your bum for you
tonight.
She's in that yellow car.
I can feel it.
Rúni, what was he going on about?
No idea. He's just a confused Dane who's bored up
here.
I need to do something here.
You can go to the village hall.
You should have gone with us tonight, Rúni.
What a waste.
Your dad must be good with the ladies.
Ha. They find him - not the other way around.
Brigitte, 25 years old.
Slept all morning -
Smelling sweetly of sweat.
She gave me chocolate all day,-
- and showed me
the starsigns in the sky.
A man came and took her away, said she was his.
Disappeared.
Joanne, 30, a boozer.
Never slept.
She could make porridge
and sing opera.
Always well dressed -
I borrowed her clothes.
One day she fell ill,
Perhaps from drinking.
Disappeared.
HeIene, 27, very shy.
Smelled like a mother.
Steaks and chocolate pudding every day.
Always cried when she read
sad stories to me.
She said I was good
at consoling her.
Her tears drove my father crazy.
She's in a closed ward now.
Are you never afraid there's a camera
behind the mirror?
I often think people send evil eyes to me
from their windows.
Then I have to wave at them
To get rid of their spell.
When something good happens to me
I hardly dare tell anyone.
That's just Nemesis.
I often imagine that I am
somebody else I'd rather be.
Michelle Pfeiffer,
and then she's me.
But everybody keeps pretending I'm still me.
I'll tell you if you suddenly turn into some screen
bimbo.
There's a phone in the room.
Who says I need to call anybody?
It's written all over you.
What the hell are you up to?
What's in it for you?
Hello, this is Faroese Pool Promoters. Is your
mother in?
Ok.
My little brother says she'll be gone for a few days.
Everybody's got their own thing.
You gutless arseholes!
This is a bloody conspiracy!
Kill all those rich idiots!
All I'm asking for is a chance!
Rúni?
I just told the truth.
You'll never get rid of me!
Rúni, drive down to the village,
I want to talk to somebody.
I've never talked to them before,
I've only seen them from far away
Do you want to come?
Who is it?
Remember: no secrets.
My mother's parents . .
Grandma and grandpa.
Rúni, why don't you go for a little ride around the
village?
Maybe you'll find a pub with some strippers in it?
See you later.
Nobody having anything to do with our former
daughter is welcome.
Your mother was led astray by your sinful father
before getting the Lord's blessing.
And therefore her daughter is unclean.
Excuse me. Do you know what year this is?
Original sin has no age.
Probably not. But we must have got it from you,
grandma.
Close the door please.
It's getting cold inside.
Don't be too sure the pearly gates of Heaven will
open for you.
Here's all the ungodly family.
Sweet dreams to all the things we could have done
together. Bye.
Great Rannvá.
Off you go now.
I think they know by now.
What the hell do you know?
Don't leave us with them.
No, I'd prefer real Hell.
"Thoughts in pride are in my mind,
Falseness, envy, hate I feel."
"Our Father, please, be kind - "
Show me quick how I may heal."
This guy's life is probably already planned for him.
He just doesn't know it yet.
He'll probably never meet
someone like me again.
Do you have to flirt with everybody on the way?
We're here to have fun, remember?
I've never been with a Faroese guy before.
He's a real daddy's boy
on his way into politics.
Probably lived his first years in Denmark -
- and now he talks too much
and thinks too little.
Yeah, real Faroese don't talk much.
First they think long and deep -
- then they do all they can
to keep it all to themselves.
Why are you so boring?
I just want to know what a Faroese guy is like.
Mama would know... though she's with a bloody
Dane now.
What the hell do the Danes have to do with it?
- I hope you'll have it all settled before I come
back.
I just saw someone who owes me a favour.
You're not jealous, are you?
I just want to play with him.
Your father should see you now.
That was fun.
He really believes I'm Lulu from France who's lost
her way.
He's good with compliments.
My knees went all soft.
Why don't people just give each other compliments
all day?
Like: that grim face really becomes you, Rannvá.
- Do you want to talk about it?
- No.
- Rúni, come here.
- Jesus.
Wait, Rúni.
Do you know this guy?
Please, go over there. Well, you asked for it.
Nobody's on board till next week.
Flemish Cap for three months.
Come out here.
So you're the girls dragging poor Rúni all over the
country.
I know all about you girls.
- Surprise, surprise.
The first mate himself.
- Really.
Come on.
Here's to Rúni.
The best, most stubborn and stupidest sailor of all.
He seems to enjoy breaking all the unwritten rules
of this country.
Our dear first mate here is known for his
bullshitting.
It was your big mouth
that said on national TV -
how you and the other small fishermen got drunk -
with the large shipowners who then could make
you sign anything.
And for that,
my beautiful damsels, -
he's been blacklisted all over this pretty little land.
And now look at him: a lonely stubborn man who's
lost everything
Well, he's not totally alone.
We're here.
Now, that's a good one.
A damn good one.
Of course I agree with Rúni in principle -
But it's just not the right way to do it.
- What is the right way then?
Now I think that two such nice girls should have a
drink -
- and sing all night with two real sailors.
"Strong, young boys, guzzling booze, is what we
want .."
Stop that.
Ha. Faroese women.
They get so holy and boring when they've been
abroad too long.
Are you coming, Rúni?
- No.
"Strong, young boys,
killing whales, is what we want.."
I've got to get out.
I can't breathe in here.
Oh Rannvá, what are we doing here?
Open up.
Help me put him to bed.
You've got to get up now anyway.
We ought to take a picture of you and send it to
your dad.
He's always been fighting with his filthy rich father.
''Drunk sailor found in ladies underwear in village
hotel.''
That story will travel fast.
A present from me to his father.
He can't get rid of me that easy.
When he wakes up he'll think he's spent a hot night
with you two.
He'll have a hard-on for days and think how
advanced he is.
- Don't you feel sorry for him?
- No.
Girl on the starboard side.
Damsel in distress.
I'm on my way to the airport.
Nice to meet one of the natives. They always have
so much to tell.
Pretend you don't hear her.
She didn't grow up here.
I'm going to Denmark to get an abortion.
I stole the money from mum and dad.
They think I'm going
to Christian Camp.
''Jesus will take care of everything'', they say.
If you asked that woman
where her husband is -
she'd say he's out watching football -
or at home with a hangover.
Not necessarily.
And one child now doesn't mean you have to get a
whole football team.
You decide that for yourself.
What do you know?
Getting the kids is easy - but giving them a good
home is not.
And I cannot and will not
do that now.
You just have to be careful -
or was the sex too good?
I don't want to give birth to a child -
who will never know its real mother.
This is where our ways part.
Your way looks as crooked and broad as ours.
Thanks for the ride.
It's too easy to get pregnant.
It shouldn't be possible without having the brain
say -
''Ding dong. Now's the perfect time. Get on with it.''
Right?.
I've got some business to do in the village hall.
They don't drink in there -
so there's probably no dancing on the tables.
But they'll find some fun anyway.
He's sweet, isn't he?
A wedding with no drinking?
Is that possible?
My dad took me
to such a party once.
The women had coffee and cake while the men
went in and out.
The men looked happier every time they'd been
out -
- and the women looked more and more sulky.
- Surprise, surprise.
Come here. Have a drink.
What a party.
Look at that. Ladies.
Hello there. What's up.
You're looking cute.
Here have a drink.
Are you girls wearing make-up tonight?
No, we were born like this.
Jesus, I'm sorry to hear that.
Won't you have a drink too?
Listen why don't you
come out of the car a for a while?
Jesus, they're coming out.
Now all of you stand over there and smile.
Is she going to take photos now?
More pictures?
Well I'll be damned.
Hey, what are you going to do with those photos?
We'll send them all around the world.
All around the world? Really?
Hi, I'm the groom.
Are you going to kidnap me?
Mum, now he's also gone
over to those girls.
Tell the others to come out.
Is that you? My old girlfriend?
Why are you here?
You ought to see yourself.
I've bought a new house with my husband and we
have two new cars -
- while you're just fooling around, making a show of
yourself.
It's easier just to run away, isn't it Rannvá?
Why are you so angry? We used to have so much
fun together.
You wanted all the world to see you dance -
and what's happened?
Has he knocked you up
to make you stay?
You cheeky cow.
Rúni.
Hey, we need some good Samaritans here.
Are you deaf or what?
- Take it easy. It's no use.
Let go of me. Let's go.
I've just had an offer I can't refuse -
See you in the next Bed & Breakfast, right?
No need to hurry.
Can't we just go for a ride?
I know somebody here.
See you later, ok?
Try and get some sleep.
I'll see you tomorrow.
Did you really think you could just hide behind all
that make-up?
I know your smell, you know.
Why did you run away?
Did you just use me
for some sort of revenge?
Say something, damn it.
If you knew how much I've been longing for you...
Just once more.
Shut up. Shut up.
Oh no, not her.
Rannvá, what's going on?
- What do you care?
Think of your pretty lover there -
He made a friend of mine pregnant when she was
only 1 7.
For two years he pretended he loved her and the
baby -
- and then he just suddenly ran away.
He broke her heart.
What are you talking about?
What happened just now?
I'm so tired.
- What's wrong with you?
Excuse me.
Now you'll never hear
from Mr Handsome again.
It's not easy to know what's the right or wrong thing
to say here.
How could you know?
You didn't grow up here.
No. but I'm still
a product of this country.
If this country was a little bigger, Dad could've
stayed.
He wouldn't have had to constantly meet my
mother and her boyfriend.
Rúni, why are we always
talking about us?
Yeah, tell us about
all your business?
Will you tell me about that bastard from yesterday?
Oh, that was just somebody who tried to help me
once -
And I thanked him
by hurting him deeply.
Hello Jesus.
Did you send Rúni to us?
Take care further ahead -
it's full of trolls and gnomes.
Hello again. - Yeah, you were good.
-Thanks, I'm not used to people listening to me
here.
Do you really live here?
I spent 20 years abroad-
Trying to make a living out of singing.
Here they've learnt to bear with me.
After all, I'm one of them.
I often wish this country was bigger.
It would be easier to meet someone you get along
with.
The rest of the world is so far away up here.
Look at me: here I am singing the last lines of a
terrible song.
- Why the last lines?
- Who says the song is terrible?
I have a son I never see.
He's a famous singer now.
I miss him so much -
But I taught him myself
not to need me.
All I thought of then was singing-
So he grew up abroad with his foreign father and
family.
I know what to do. I know a great Faroese guy
abroad.
You'd like him.
Have you got a pen?
Well, why not?
Okay, great.
Come. We're leaving now.
Take care.
And don't forget to call him.
Damn it. All I'm asking for is a chance.
He's really pissed today.
You'll never make me hit back.
I don't recognize him any more.
I'm not afraid of you.
I can wait.
Want some?
Now what?
Don't.
Barba, I saw you give her your father's address.
What are you up to?
She's alone. He's alone.
You have to push a little, right?
Perhaps an exciting Faroese woman is all he ever
wanted?
She's not one to sit at home knitting things for your
children.
I'm not going to have any.
I'll manage not to.
How many parents or children are really happy in
this world?
20%? 10%?
Only 2%?
You're such a hypocrite.
You think people just have children -
so they can give them a miserable time and make
them unhappy.
So what?
You don't know what you're saying.
''You just have to be more careful.''
I can't stand it.
Why don't you give your mother a chance for
once?
You've no idea what it's like
to have children -
or you wouldn't be so full of shit.
If you knew so much about children -
- then you wouldn't have treated your parents like
that.
I know more about ...
I could be somewhere abroad now -
- enjoying the heat and the noise -
while admirers waited on me.
This peace is driving me crazy.
It's so typical for me to have a mother -
- in this desolate ... cold ... naked ...
... windy place.
Small islands are not for people: just for birds that
can fly away.
Mama?
She'll probably think
she saw me in a dream -
- or a nightmare.
Do you want her to keep it?
They ... want me at home.
It's probably better
if she thinks I was just a dream.
Why's that better?
Cause ... I don't know what to do.
Cause I'm ashamed.
I don't know if I can face her.
Well, I hope you find out
before she leaves again.
No ... no ...
It looks as if your father's got competition, Barba.
Was she the only one who answered your ad in the
personals?
A used woman. You must be desperate, Rúni.
Well, now you've seen my son -
- and his mother.
7 months ago she just
ran off abroad with the boy.
7 weeks later I got a postcard just saying they were
okay.
I started sailing when I was 14.
I saved up and got my own boat.
Fishing was good
and everything was great -
- but the big guys wouldn't let me keep that.
I was as stupid as everybody else at that fine dinner!
We were going to create one big firm of
shipowners.
We were all drunk when we signed the papers to
secure our future.
We would fish and they would sell it at the best
price.
We thought.
But that night we signed off the right to our own
boats and lives.
And the small fishermen would rather live as slaves
than admit they'd been fooled.
But was it right to say the truth on national TV?
Great attitude, Rannvá.
Typically Faroese.
Shut up, Barba. You still don't know what it's like
here.
No, but people bloody well
create their own lives.
Maybe so, Barba.
But right now we're talking about Rúni.
Can't you show them
you can do without them?
Yeah, show them that there are other things than
cod ...
... money ... and trash fish.
What? Trash fish in the boot?
I just heard of a boat going 5 months to the Barents
Sea.
- So who knows?
Nobody knows.
That's it.
Pull over here, Rúni.
This is where I grew up
with a mother and a father.
Come on, it's not your fault
both your parents wanted you.
So what will it be?
Well, I'm waiting for Rannvá to ask us in for a cup
of tea.
No, I've got one last thing to do.
Well, we'll come along then, all right?
This is my chance.
Here we go.
What's he going to do
with the gun?
Too many American movies?
A man can own a gun, though...
There are so many other things than people to
shoot ...
... hares ... birds ... and ...
Fish. ... Can't you shoot fish?
Oh, no. Look out.
Hey, what happened?
I don't know: here you are -
- well taken care of - and you look really cool
with all that bandage on.
You would have lost if that cod hadn't interfered.
So cods are useful
for something, then?
Daddy could have been one of the people in the
house.
But just when everything was going for him, he lost
interest -
He sold all his ships to be the first and only village
bohemian.
But I don't like having a daughter who plays hide
and seek -
- without saying when the game is over, so we can
find her.
Rumours had it
you'd made your entrance.
You can see it on your father
that you have.
You two were always so close.
Hello darling.
Have you seen who's here?
I know you're my mother. I have lots of pictures of
you.
I think you're so pretty.
- I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry. Suddenly one day she disappeared.
One year later we got a postcard from abroad.
Then we'd start seeing her in the magazines and
the ads.
Ask her what day it is today.
And ask her if she's brought a present for her
daughter.
Rannvá you shit. What's wrong with people?
At least my mother waved goodbye to me when
Dad and I moved abroad.
You know all about me,
and I know nothing about you.
All I know is that I'll never leave her again.
Oh no. That friend of yours...
The one who got pregnant with Mr Handsome ...
I'm so stupid.
Don't.
I'm so embarrassed.
Fuck it all.. I don't care why you left.
But you left us knowing nothing for all this time.
If your lovely daughter and your wonderful father
hadn't been here -
- then ... then ....
Listen, we have to trust her now.
It's always like that:
I do all the boring things - and you get all the hugs.
Mama, I can handle it now.
I want to.
You'll manage. I'll be there.
But what is wrong with this country?
It gave birth to all your ancestors.
Damn it, mama. This must be the only place in the
world -
- where you're seen as a traitor for wanting to live
somewhere else.
Some want to go. Some don't.
And islanders always want to know what is beyond
the horizon.
Ha. I've seen it,
and I'm not tempted by it.
No. That's exactly it.
Do you want me to push you
closer to the window?
No need to.
Barba, how come you didn't find out about
Rannvá?
I found out almost immediately.
Well, dinner's coming up.
We've got to go now.
Well, ... bye.
"Then fare ye well,
your God proclaims - "
"-your life and soul."
"He shelters you
where you may go - "
"- you will be back again."
Perhaps these tiny islands are not just
for birds that can fly away.
Perhaps they're also for people
who don't want to fly away.
Translation: Terkel Skårup