May 18th.
TIHAR JAIL.
Greetings.
What's the matter?
Warden.
Now teII me Ratan.
Home Minister Ravi Menon is tipped
to be the next C.M. of KeraIa.
What? ImpossibIe.
He, the one who uprooted
my cIan and friends.
He, the one who sent me to jaiI.
I'II not spare him aIive.
Never.
Swearing-in ceremony
shouIdn't take pIace.
KiII him.
Don't worry about him.
My friends are going to KeraIa.
They'II kiII him.
Who are they?
Oh God! D.I.G.
Oh My god, cIimbing down the
stairs wiII take time.
Let me sIide through this.
Sir.
Has work on the top over?
- Everything is over.
I can understand that from
the way you're sitting.
HoId him.
TiII the swearing-in ceremony
is over by tomorrow.
Traffic is to be bIocked
on this route.
Chief Minister has said that
pubIic Iife shouIdn't be affected.
He can say Iike that, never mind.
The entire area must be under
the controI of PoIice.
Got it.
If you find any suspicious peopIe,
We'II fire them.- No.
We'II not fire them.- What?
Then what am I to do?
You teII me.
Stupid.
Has the dog squad come?
The dog has come.
What's it?
- What happened?
When I stamped my feet with fuII force.
Shoe naiI pricked me, sir.
Prabhakaran, why're you hesitating
to saIute your senior officer?
I've noticed you're
repeating it often.
Your father-in-Iaw feeIs
embarrassed to saIute you.
Shut up. No famiIy bondage
when I'm on duty.
Otherwise aIso.
Come on, saIute me.
HoId it properIy.
He's barking since
you didn't saIute him.
He's superior to you.
CircIe Inspector.
You saIute him.
Ready for the search?
- Yes sir.
Don't act smart you've the dog.
Get CircIe Inspector.
Dog might've bitten me.
I'm Ieaving him because
my daughter wiII become a widow.
Or eIse, I wouId've kiIIed him
Iong back pIanting a bomb.
Oh God, put me in a fix?
I think it's a bomb.
Hands up.
Oh God!
Don't run...- I'II not. Don't shoot...
Bow to India.
I think your daughter
wiII become a widow.
Oh God!
Mr. Peethambaram, he's mad.
No buIIets have'nt striken!
Catch him.
Me? Today? Monday?
- Catch him.
MAY 19.
I Ravi Menon,
I Ravi Menon, son of Shankar Menon
of Manika MangaIam....
with the duty conscious,
without hypocrisy,
with sincerity and honesty,
I'II withhoId sovereignty
and pride of this country,
As the Chief Minister Of KeraIa,
whatever comes to my knowIedge...
without any partiaIity
I'II treat everyone as equaI.
I swear in the name of god.
Long live Mr. Ravi Menon.
How come there's a hoIe
suddenIy in my cap?
If you ask me genuine questions.
Then I can answer you easiIy.
You were the Home Minister.
Why did you suddenIy
become the Chief Minister.
High command decided
and I obeyed.
Who are the new Ministers?
I wiII announce it Iater.
Since you received threats
twice as a Minister,
it seems Kerala police has arranged
tight security for you.
Is it?
That's our responsibiIity.
Tomorrow they'II go
to the city saying,
a Iong convoy of escort vehicIes
for the Chief Minister.
''Iakhs of money is spent
on his security''.
Hey, this is KeraIa.
As an escort, one jeep wiII do.
Sir, that's...it's our duty.
Are you afraid that
somebody wiII kiII me?
If somebody pIans to kiII me,
Who can rescue me?
Are you repIica of James Bond?
Are you pet of SherIock HoImes?
Are you a fiery jet?
Are you a atom bomb?
Let's meet at the India Gate.
Let's search the internet for HitIer.
Oh god! What's this?
That buIIet is coming on to me.
Let me step aside from it.
When he sees thieves before
him, he'II aim buIIets at them.
Crime Branch wiII beg for him...
CBI, CID's and VIP's in this city,
saIute him secretIy.
When he comes, peopIe shudder.
When he stands,
ashes wiII scatter.
He's the hot wind
bIowing everywhere.
Many songs top the charts.
When peopIe see you,
they start bIowing whistIes.
He's son of god.
Oh God! Shit, it was you.
Pish!
Was it a dream then?
Son, Sahadeva.- Yes mother.
About whom were you taIking now?
Mother...I...father....
Are you a father?
Not that....father
must have come, right?
He's there.
He has started taIking about
accounts from earIy morning.
Rs 2500 to be paid to the shop.
We couId've bought many pints
of Iiquor from that money.
Sugar, rice, saIt,
spices, eggs....
2 tins of power maIt.
Hercuries 5 bottIes. Sorry, horIicks.
This is somebody eIse's account.
No...this is our account onIy.
There's no guarantee I'II get
seIected in the written test,
passing the written test and
get the seIection.
I shouId pass the
physicaI test aIso.
Does it mean you've to
take so many eggs?
Do you've hook worms
in your stomach?
Son, are you eating to Iive,
or Iiving to eat?
No father shouId ever caIcuIate
son's food account.
But the shop keeper is
accounting me for that.
Sahadeva, inspite of
spending so much,
and if you don't pass
the physicaI test.
Just because CoIumbia
has been destroyed,
has America stopped
fIying rockets?
My son, this isn't America.
We're the poor who eat food
from American fIour?
Son, horIicks...
Thanks...- Have you taken it?
No bananas for you today.
No? No vitamins C
for me today.- Yes.
Vikrama, hearing this,
my Vitamin C is scooping out.
Take Vitamin 3x for that.
- Very good.
UntiI you stop drinking,
this famiIy wiII not prosper.
For exampIe, no banana today.
Forget that, do I've a good shirt,
pant or shoes?
Even if you don't have aII these,
You don't Iack means of IiveIihood.
That's okay, my ancestors had...
What?
You're the man
to spoiI my father.
Yesterday, I wasn't responsibIe
for his getting drunk.
He Iost his honour,
drinking continuousIy.
He's not respected at home
as weII as by the peopIe.
That honour is enough for him.
Hereafter don't try to raise it.
I beg you not to ruin our
famiIy befriending him.
My famiIy got ruined because
of your father's friendship.
I'd soId even my wife's auspicious
pendant to give him money.
You know my wife doesn't
aIIow me into the house.
I'm with Chandran's wife now.
I'm carrying the burden of
his 2 fiIthy chiIdren now.
I deserve this.
Brother, I'm Ieaving.
I wiII Ieave.
- Hey, go away man.
I'II Ieave...I'II not step
into this house again.
I'm not responsibIe for his drinking.
Your brother-in-Iaw S.I., ask him.
That idiot wiII not be abIe to bear
if your father doesn't saIute him.
I wiII teII you one thing.
If your bIoody brother-in-Iaw comes.
I'II not mind about your sister.
I'II hit him with cane
and stone him to death.
Who are you going to kiII?
That's...
I'II teII you.
Don't teII him.
An itchy dog is disturbing
my father for a Iong time.
We were teIIing that
we'II kiII it on sight.
Dog with a beIt around it's neck?
No...a Iong beIt
worn around it's waist.
That's about me!
- Yes sir.
Let's not have any
probIem between us.
You aII are famiIy members.
Are they? I'II not step
into their home.
AIong with this big time thief,
there's a smaII time thief, Kochunni.
I've come to take him away.
TempIe festivaI is going
to begin tomorrow.
OnIy if I put them in jaiI.
I can peacefuIIy watch the show.
Aren't you coming home, dear?
I was here onIy for Iong time.
AtIeast get in, pIease.
Is there goId?
She's not your daughter anymore,
but a poIiceman's wife.
She feeIs more proud to enter
that thiefs house than our's.
She can take away
anything from there.
No case wiII be fiIed against her.
- Get Iost you...
Don't tarnish your honour by
taIking to cheap...come...
Kochunni...my son.- Yes dad.
What is it dad?
Don't you know, my study time
is between 7 and 9?
PoIice has come to our threshoId.
- Poor poIice.
What a difficuIty!
So, this year's festivaI coIIection
is ''govinda''Iost).
Are you caIIing your father by name?
- I didn't caII your name.
I meant to say that we've Iost
this year's festivaI coIIection.
Look, they're caIIing,
teII them I'm not here.
Okay, my dear son.
Why did you take so much time
to open the door? - Since it was cIosed.
Trousers? Are you studying in LKG?
- No, this is GuIf.
No, his son robs onIy in
houses of GuIf returned peopIe.
I see.
Come on search.
PIease move.
Oh God! What am I seeing here?
It's Iooks Iike we've entered
duty free shop. - AII are free.
Now you start your duty.
You shouIdn't compIain that
I've not taken you to the shop.
What size Unni? - KochusmaII)Unni.
Where's he? - Not here.
Search the house.
Hubby, Iook at this.
- Take it.
Is it Japanese make?
No Rajappan's, from
southern fieIds.
Then, I'II take this.
Sir, somebody is
in the bathroom.
What a big hoIe!
Why're you barking?
What's your probIem?
That's Iack of stick.
I asked it not to bark.
Oh God! Who pIaced your head here?
Not onIy my head,
my body is aIso there.
I'II rip out your intestines.
Who permitted you to
enter the house?
I didn't enter the house
but inside the bucket.
Hey, get up.
Don't scream. Let poIice go away,
then I'II come out.
We're friends, aren't we?
- Friends?
You beIong to a thiefs famiIy and
I beIong to a poIice famiIy.
Our famiIies don't match.
If there're no thieves,
then no need of poIice.
Don't forget that.
I'II show you whether
there's poIice or not.
Have you caught him?
Can't find him any
where in the fieIds?
I'm sure, he's inside this house.
I'II break your knee if you
step into my house again.
He says this for me
and onIy for me.
Yes. Take him quickIy.
Or eIse I'II go away.
That's why, I don't come to
station when you caII me.
Put him into the jeep.
Hey don't catch me. My shirt is
Ioosening out...I wiII get in.
Brother-in-Iaw.
I respect you for onIy one thing,
when we couIdn't afford
to give any dowry,
and marry off my sister,
you eIoped with her
and married her.
As a brother, I'm gratefuI
to you for that.
Taking that as a chance, if you
try to troubIe my father,
then you'II know the true coIour
of this Sahadevan. Go...
Now, I'm confident that
you'II become S.I.
Go and get my shoes and pant.
No need to count...
Take it and buy.
How's this? - This is okay.
What's this?
What nonsense is this...
inside the shoe.
Where are you Iooking & waIking?
- Somebody had pushed.
Sorry...Iet me remove the shoe.
Where shaII I keep it?
I've seen stones in the rice.
But onIy for the first time.
I see it in the rock.
Has it started to rain stones
ever since I shaved my head?
Hey stop, the one at the top is mine.
Give it to me.
Hey stop! - Go...go...
Oh God! Car...
What is this?
- Nothing, okay sorry...
Are you pIaying hopping game
in the middIe of road?
Don't say anything more.
I've moved. PIease.
What a difficuIty?
I bought a shoe...stiII my
wish hasn't fuIfiIIed.
What wiII I do having this shoe?
How am I to face my father
without shoes?
What is this? Don't go steep.
Hey...shoe...hey, give that
to me and go.
Shoe...stop, I'II come.
PIease.- Go...go fast.
I say go fast.
Nothing to worry.
You'II not have any probIem,
if you get rid of B.P. too.
Better reduce your tension.
Asking the Chief Minister
to reduce his tension?
Now, mother and daughter
wouId have been satisfied.
Come...
Nothing is wrong with me dear.
She gets scared even
if I get a sIight fever,
fearing my death.
I'II die when I'm fated
to die, right doctor?
HeIIo!
I'm Ratan from DeIhi.
Baba is expecting you to convey
the death news of Ravi Menon.
Sure.
Today, we've got a good chance
to execute our pIan.
Good.
We're going to set the bomb.
It'II go off at the right time.
Okay.
Sir, phone...
Oh God! Undavasu toId me that
he wouId caII me.
I gave him this number onIy.
How can the poIiceman
be so irresponsibIe?
HoId it. I'II come now.
HeIIo, Undavasu...sorry
I wiII give it to him.
Sir phone.
Sir, I'm Ramakrishna.
Very nice name.
CaIIed me to teII your name?
We won't be in home for few days.
We're Iocking the doors & Ieaving.
What can I do for that?
We've been asked to inform the station
whiIe Ieaving the home Iocked.
That's why, I've informed.
- Oh is it? Give me your address.
FIat no.12B., - Just a minute,
Iet me note it down.
Sir, you ask I'II note it down.
Yes, fIat no. 12B.
- FIat no 12B.
Sky Iine.- Sky Iine.
MaveIIipuram CoIony.
- MaveIIipuram coIony.
Land mark?- Next to the church.
So, nobody wiII be there for a month.
- A month? Oh My god!
I'II see to it.
Hey idiot, did you take it down?
You don't by heart it...erase it.
I know onIy to write
and not to read.
So sad.
God wiII not gift aII
the taIents to one man.
FooI.
I said I'm a fooI since
I don't know to read.
Sir, festivaI is over...can I go?
You can go...don't waste time.
Then, get me the mobiIe phone Iike
the one, S.I. Peethambaram has.
Why another one Iike that?
- I'II get you his phone.
Let this pen be here itseIf,
or eIse somebody wiII caII me a thief.
Honest thief.
Yes, poIice station.
I'm caIIing you from city hospitaI.
I'm trying to get the Iine
for a Iong time.
Somebody has pIanted a
bomb in the hospitaI.
Bomb?
Yes.- In the city hospitaI.
If you don't come here immediateIy.
Let me inform the controI room first.
Don't...I'II Iose my job,
if it's a hoax caII.
Let me phone up S.I and
ask him to inform.
Let him Iose his job.
Ramakrishna's famiIy has
gone on a tour in 12B.
They've asked to ensure
burgIars don't break in?
Which burgIar can enter when
this S.I. Peethambaram is here?
Do I've to wait?
Car might be insufficient.
There might be many things.
I've caIIed ABT parceI Iorry.
Taxi.
I've to go to the city hospitaI.
Dear, not today some other day.
You'II not Iisten to me when I ask
you not to take sweets.
Now you'II hesitate
to go to the hospitaI.
Come...I say come...
This wiII work out.
This is too much.
Sir....Mr. S.I.
This fooI is deaf too.
Mr.Peethambaran, come down,
there's a bomb.
What?
Mr.Peethambaran bomb...
Yes hubby, somebody has pIanted
a bomb in this buiIding.
Bring our chiIdren.
Oh God! Mixie.
Oh God! What aII the things
I can carry?
Oh God! T.V.
Hubby...- Come here.
What is it?
- I can't carry this.
Oh God! On the verge of death...she's...
Carry our chiId.
I forgot him. Son, get up.
Oh God! My Iight.
Hey wait, I'II come.
Hubby, where has your
haIf moustache vanished?
I'II teII you one thing.
Shave off the entire moustache
and then come down.
Or eIse, I'II be humiIiated.
We're going to reduce you into ashes
and you're taIking about moustache.
Bomb wiII bIast...
Iet's quit the pIace immediateIy.
ChiIdren are there, aren't they?
- What sort of a person he is?
PIease carry.- Why not?
Not me...but my grandpa.
Isn't it enough if we carry
him after death? - Go man.
I needn't go to work for a month.
What's the commotion here?
Is everybody in the
fIats going on a tour?
Do I've to caII the container?
Oh My god!
Why aII of you are running?
Somebody has pIanted a bomb in the fIats.
First Iet me send my Iife down.
If I jump from here,
then my Iife wiII go up.
Idea.
I'II turn the bed into sandwich.
Okay?
Oh My god!
Were you behind me?
What are you eating? I cannot carry you.
A crowd of peopIe are running?
Any competition!
Here, sir's famiIy is aIso coming.
Sir, what happened?
It's time for the bomb to bIast.
Bomb here aIso?
Hey, you had toId me that
there's a bomb here.
It's not here but
in the city hospitaI.
I kicked you
and you're Iaughing.
I'm Iaughing Iooking
at your moustache.
You don't stand here admiring
the beauty of my moustache.
You rush to the hospitaI immediateIy
with a bomb squad & a dog squad.
I'II come Iater with rest of them.
- Hey, you go.
Bringing shame.
How can I take him in this condition?
If bomb goes off,
then we'II Iose our jobs.
Not onIy your jobs,
but aII the peopIe there.
I'm afraid, I'm going to escape.
- Escape?
This is a question of
many peopIe's Iives.
Let's do one thing.
I'II come as dog.
If you do, you can onIy bark.
Can you smeII & trace the bomb?
I meant I'II come on behaIf
of my father with the dog.
Are you a poIiceman?
Nobody can identify me
if I wear the mask.
Who wouId've pIanted the
bomb in hospitaI?
Don't know in which form
is the bomb is now?
You'II get it on next Friday.
Now I've no time.
Is there any necessity
to remove your heImet?
So, we wear heImet to safeguard
ourseIves from getting beaten up.
Attender, why did you
stop the vehicIe?
We've reached the hospitaI.
Where they wouId've pIanted the bomb?
Might be in the mortuary.
Don't know how many innocents
are going to die in the mortuary?
If bomb goes off whiIe
we are waIking,
a shattering sound wiII be heard.
- Then, Iet's crawI and move out.
It's an age of the eviI.
Dog is waIking and
humans are crawIing.
The one who passed just now,
is she a human bomb?
No, she has a worn a
thread around her waist.
Did you find out with the machine?
No...we're Iying down.
We can Iook up & see, I saw.
Hi.
HeIIo, do you recognise me?
I'm...
Big incident is IikeIy to happen here.
Go back home quickIy.
Okay see you.
Even as an infant,
I didn't crawI Iike this.
Bomb must be in this room.
Didn't your hear the sound?
If you're sure, then Iet's go
into some other room.
Be quiet.
Somebody's knocking.
May be god of death?
BIess me grandpa.
Move away.
Oh God!
Don't get afraid!
I heard a ticking sound here.
CIock.
Who are you?
Where are you from?
We're from moon.
Don't teII anybody.
Somebody has pIanted a bomb here.
Oh My god! Bomb here too.
Where is the ambuIance driver?
Let me take this wheeI chair.
Oh My god!
AII are unaware of the bomb.
They might haven't known it.
Coffin makers wiII do
bumper business tomorrow.
Stop! Where are you going?
To downstairs.- I'II heIp you.
May god bIess you.
Where are you taking me to?
Up...- No, down.
Oh God! I may break into pieces.
- Let me see it.
Are you a doctor?- Go away.
Give back my dress.
Don't come here pIease.
Has Arjun gone there?
What's in this?
Who are you?
Leave me.
Arjun, go outside.
AII of you move away.
It's the bomb.
Move away...bomb.
Time piece.
Oh God! It must be a
good company's make.
It's working.
Dog is frightening me.
This is mine.
Dog has taken away aII my things.
Arjun, go fast.
Go...go fast.
AII of us move...bomb...
It's foIIowing me...
divert it's way.
Go...go...
AII of you move.
Arjun, go fast.
Fast...fast...
Go fast.
Arjun, throw...throw...
Arjun, come back.
No...
I want to hear the news
of Ravi Menon's death.
Mustafa's men shouId never faiI.
Baba, there's tight security
to the C.M.
PoIice!
BIoody Government servants.
There was a PoIice Commission
Gowri Shankar in DeIhi.
Now he's the Commissioner here.
He's my man.
Ask our men to meet him.
Okay.
He's briIIiant.
DeadIy
CoId bIooded snake.
Of course I'II heIp him.
You've to accompIish the task
for which he has sent you.
AccompIish it weII.
But that's not easy.
You've to be very carefuI now.
Search is going on.
You aren't safe in that hoteI.
You've to shift from there.
I very weII know how to
divert this case.
SureIy, I'II divert it.
Not MooIam Kuzhi...
But MooIam KuzhiIyiI Sahadevan.
I am sorry,
my MaIayaIam isn't good.
You're trying to become
a poIice officer.
I aIso want to become Iike you.
- Nice body.
I'm taking eggs & miIk to become
a poIice officer...to be more energetic.
Oh God, I haven't come to that stage.
Good.
It's very important for such
peopIe to join our department.
Why did you pIant the bomb
in hospitaI?
Sir, what do you mean?
Did I pIant the bomb?
Don't Iie.
I know you had pIanted it.
It's not justice sir.
TaIking justice to a poIice officer.
Don't hit me, I'm the one
who found the bomb.
Are you poIice to do that?
Sir, I had to do that in a crisis.
So, I couId save many Iives.
Didn't you read in the
papers highIighting,
the smartness of Sahadevan,
man who found the bomb,
and the dog is struggIing
for it's Iife in hospitaI.
It's in aII the news papers.
Did you do it for pubIicity?
I know you had pIanted,
found and defused it.
Sir, are you trying to
put the bIame on me?
RascaI, taIking arrogantIy?
Stop it.
He can reveaI the detaiIs
of the bomb bIast.
No, he's innocent.- No, he's not.
I inquired.
Instead of finding
the reaI cuIprits.
Sir, I can identify them.
I've seen them.
I'II catch them if you want.
- No need, poIice wiII do it.
You know the punishment
for impersonating.
Since your intention is good
and you've S.I. seIection,
a smaII consideration for you.
But don't repeat it.
You can go.
Sir, he's...
Sister, they're very good peopIe.
We've to get onIy such good
peopIe as paying guests.
WiII they pay the rent promptIy?
If they don't then you'II not.
ShaII I caII them inside?
Brothers...come...
PIease come in.- Come.
He's the boss.- Greetings sir.
Sister.- Greetings sister.
Look, no smoking, no Iiquor
and no friends here.
If you want any food,
you've to pay, got it?
Okay?
That's your portion.- That one.
Thank you.
Hey you dog! You wanted me to
saIute you, didn't you?
I put aII my efforts and
got an order to kiII you.
Saw this.
Mercy kiIIing! You deserve it.
This dog had toiIed hard
for your department.
Without even trying to save it,
You're trying to kiII it.
This is too much.
Don't taIk phiIosophy.
Inject it doctor.
No need. I'II inject it.
Don't dare to touch it.
Who are you to say that?
I may be anybody.
Do you know what's this?
- A paper.
Not just a pIain paper.- Then?
An order to stop kiIIing the dog.
And that I can rear it.
This is an order from Maneka Gandhi.
Let me see the order.
Maneka Gandhi's order can't be
shown to fake poIicemen.
Doctor, just a minute.
- You stand there.
Doctor, this isn't
Maneka Gandhi's order.
It's my request.
If you've conscience give the dog
to me without kiIIing it.
I'II take care.
Even I don't have a heart
to kiII it.- Then pIease...
Let me see, come.
Can I go against
Maneka Gandhi's order?
Hand over the dog to him.
- I'II not agree.
This is Maneka Gandhi's order.
If you don't obey,
you'II Iose your job.
What about mercy kiIIing then?
Eat it.
Thank you sir.
What are you going to do with it?
Going to stuff some straw into it?
Take it away and go.
Let's fIatten the top of sparkIes.
Let's Iit the wick of thunder.
Let's tame the fiery wiId horse.
Let's win aII our way.
Let's catch hoId of burning sun
Let's catch hoId of the stormy wind.
Let's break the obstacIes.
Let's reach cIouds and
tame thunder and Iightning.
As god of truth and goodness,
Let's soar towards the sky.
With the hi-tech bIack magic
and atom bomb.
Let's jump into the mirage.
Whether it's underworId,
or action course,
Iet's be sensationaI in attacking.
Whether its Bin Laden or Saddam,
Catch hoId of him
Wish you good Iuck!
O Lord Krishna!
You know about me.
Today is the physicaI test.
PIease make me fit,
don't be stingy.
I don't mean father's drunk fitness.
But this fit.
Okay.
This has become reguIar feature
after getting suspended.
We do the same job in station too.
It'II be very thriIIing to pIay
''fIash'' with the thieves.
Father, I'm Ieaving.
Son...
Son, you'II come up in Iife.
You've to show your smartness,
after you become the S.I.
Hi everybody.
Who's this cIown?
Her brother.
Hey, Iet him not hear it.
He's detective Karamchand.
That's his name now.
How much? - Rs.60.
WiII you accept credit card?- No.
Cheque?- No.
Chain?
Oh That's it!
So you don't have the cash.
You've to wait if you want in cash.
Sister, I bought it in the junction.
Add spices and tamarind
to it and prepare gravy.
This is suit case.
We can prepare onIy in a vesseI.
Is he a fooI?- Thank you.
I didn't shake hands with you.
I asked you to remove the gIoves.
I bought it since I got it free.
You can aIso fry it.
Can aIso prepare gravy
with the rest?
Now my gIoves wiII not stink.
Very inteIIigent.
A detective's weapon is inteIIigence.
Then, how're you managing it.
Poor Indians know
onIy to tease.
UncIe, you haven't changed at aII.
Where are you going?
I've physicaI test today
for poIice seIection.
Why're you unnecessariIy
wasting time?
Become my successor.
No need!
You onIy take up marriage
or siIIy cases in your agency.
Let me take up a case
under government's expenses.
They depend upon other's expenses.
That job is enough for me!
S.I.'s job isn't that easy!
100 peopIe's activities
wiII be on your head!
Nothing on the top of my head!
There's nothing inside aIso!
Your dress is ready!
Wear it and see!
I'm running out of time...
Make it fast.
Wow! You Iook fabuIous!
I didn't expect that
it wouId suit you weII.
Keep it down.- Sorry!
Don't I Iook great?
- If there's nobody eIse...
Can you give me your
goggIes pIease?
I'm bIind!
- Then, why do you wear it?
Oh My goggIes!
Hey, my bag!
Thank god! God sent him
at right time.
Hey my bag.
Excuse me madam.
Don't worry be happy!
Where did it go?
I'm Inspector Sahadevan
from poIice department.
Count 1 2 3.
Count, I say.
1 ,2,3.
Short cut!
RascaI! Did you find onIy that
innocent girI's bag to rob?
Sahadeva, have you reaIIy
become an S.I.?
Didn't you understand even
after getting beaten up?
Inspector Sahadevan
from poIice department.
Hereafter be carefuI.
I'm the onIy man.
I may not find time to attend
aII the pIaces at a time.
So be carefuI!
My dear pubIic,
pubIic nuisance Iike him,
has to be shot on the spot
and fed to dogs.
Do you need to go this extent?
- Yes!
Sir...he...thief...
I know he's the thief!
But which station are you from?
MooIam KuzhiyiI station!
- No such station!
Where did you get
this uniform?
Are you taIking in Chinese?
- From the taiIor's shop.
Oh My god! Then, he's not
a reaI poIiceman.
PIease forgive both of us!
Both of us wiII not pIay
this robbing game ever together.
Together?
- Go ahead!
I'II rob pubIic of it's things,
then he'II come as pubIic
and catch me.
Then both of us wiII
cheat pubIic and escape.
TeII me.
He's Iying! - I beIieved!
Put both of them into the jeep!
I remember our chiIdhood days.
When we pIayed robber & poIice game,
we were together Iike this.
Though we're neighbours,
after a Iong time,
we're in the same ceII.
Since you've become my company...
- Company? Who?
I'm quiet just because
we're in the ceII.
Or eIse I wouId've sent you out!
Oh My god! Can't you do that
after becoming S.I.?
I'II become S.I. and beat you
to puIp.- Hey shut up.
Are you Ieaving me or not?
I've the test!
Are you Sachin TenduIkar
to take up the test?
This is poIice test!
Shut up! I'm on duty there!
I can go there onIy after
fiIing the case on you.
FiIing the case?- Yes!
It's enough if we get same ceII
Iike this in the centraI jaiI.
Get Iost dog!
I may become DSP tomorrow.
- Okay!
If you don't co-operate
with me now,
then I'II transfer you to Attapaadi.
Sahadev, don't transfer me...
- I'II...
Don't...- I'II.
Sure?- Yes!
If you attend the physicaI test onIy,
you can atIeast become S.I.
Yes! I'm not going to Iet
you out for the test.
Brother-in-Iaw!
How is it going to benefit
if you become S.I.?
You join me!
You can mint money!
Get Iost.
Brother-in-Iaw.
Asking me to get Iost?
- Hey caII him 'Sir'.
I'm in a position to caII any beggar,
'Sir' now. -You said this for me.
OnIy about me.
Any doubt?
Hey, I'II not Iet you out today.
Start the jeep!
HeIIo, I'II teII you one thing!
I'II not give you
anymore consideration.
I'II kiII you if I faiI to
attend physicaI test.
I'II kiII you brutaIIy!
I'II behead you and pIace
it on this tabIe,
and surrender myseIf
in the next station.
ReIease him!
Got afraid of his threats, right?
You don't know the vaIue of head.
How'II I drink Iiquor
if he beheads me?
OnIy 10 more minutes Ieft
for the physicaI test.
He'II not be abIe to reach
if he goes aIso.
Don't taIk...reIease me.
ReIease him!
What about me?
FiIe aII the petty cases on him,
and produce him in the court!
Just petty cases!
OnIy 2 months! I thought 420!
SmiIe wherever you see me.
- Get Iost!
Run...poIice...
Uniform! Let nobody know it!
What's this?
Everyone becomes poIice
onIy after the test.
Have you become before
the test itseIf?
Sorry sir...fancy dress
...time is over!
PIease no sir...
- Meet him if you want!
Excuse me sir.
Good morning sir!
For the physicaI test...
What's the time now?- 10.65.
What? - No...1 1 .05.
I'm 5 minutes Iate, sorry sir.
You know that you've
to report before 1 1 .
You're Iate, cIear out from here.
Sir, pIease...- No.
Sir, I'II faII at your feet...
- Don't you understand me rascaI! Get out!
What's it?
No sir, he's Iate!
Sir, they're sending me out
since I'm 5 minutes Iate.
This job is my dream!
My ambition!
I say get out.
- Leave him inside.
Who's punctuaI here?
- Thank you sir!
Thank you...
thank you very much sir!
94...move...
MuscIes wiII go.
Measure it fast.
I'II take his measurement!
He's going to transfer
me to Attapaadi.
ShaII I take your measurements?
Don't ditch me.
Brother-in-Iaw! My chest is 90 - 95.
60 - 65!
No sir, it's 90 - 95.
Are you teIIing the vehicIe no.?
- What's it Peethambaran?
He's unfit sir.
He's disquaIified!
Oh God sir, he's taking
revenge on me!
Is it so?
Do one thing!
Ask him to cIimb the post and
test it, okay?- Thank you sir.
My chest 90-95.
Post is ready!
Oh God!
I've poured 5 Iitres of
oiI on the post.
What?- 1/2 Iitre!
Sorry, you're unfit.
- Sir, pIease.
You're totaIIy unfit for
this poIice job. CIear out.
Are they fit sir?
- Yes, they are fit.
Can't you see from their bodies?
- They're strong!
PoIice job wiII not suit oId
fashioned guys Iike you.
The criminaIs who're brave and
have muscuIar bodies Iike them.
Do you've the strength
to fight with them?
Now, am I fit sir?
Are you hitting the poIiceman, rascaI?
Why're the poIice so
angry on my son?
WouId anybody spare him
if he hits a poIiceman?
Son, have this.
I don't want this.
It'II not get digested anymore.
I'm dejected.
UnnecessariIy I had to spend
IavishIy my father's money...
For whom I'm earning aII this.
I just bIabber something when
I'm drunk.- No father.
I'm disrespected and
mocked wherever I go.
Mother, what if I try for
some other job?
Son...
You're getting dejected
for a siIIy thing first,
and were you trying to
become a poIice officer?
FaiIures are stepping
stones to success.
The disrespect and mocking,
are support for your desires.
You've to achieve your
aim utiIizing them.
I'm sure you'II achieve.
FaiIing to find the cuIprits
behind the bomb bIast,
is a shame to the
entire department.
Sir, the investigation
has been intensified.
But since criminaI's
attempt had faiIed,
I doubt that they wouId've
Ieft from our country.
No, their aim is to expIode and
spoiI the peace of our country.
So, I expect a series
of expIosions.
We've to be more carefuI.
Sir, our dog squad
is very weak.
We don't have an efficient dog
in our department now.
Arjun, hurt in the bIast and
struggIing for Iife. He's very smart.
Then re-induct the dog
back to the department.
It's impossibIe.
We had ordered for mercy kiIIing.
A man had taken it by the order
of Maneka Gandhi to rear it.
He's very arrogant.
- He's his brother-in-Iaw sir.
I've no such reIations.
He's my enemy.
Don't try to escape.
You've to bring back the dog again.
Sir...- No, it's an order.
PoIiceman is hacked to death.
It must be poIiceman had
hacked him to death.
Where's the dog?
- It's before me.
That means....- Our sir.
Where's the barking dog?
- It's barking before me.
I'm asking you about Arjun.
You've to ask Krishnan about it.
Are you fooIing me?
Is there any necessity
to make you one?
Where's your dog named Arjun?
Don't caII my ''dog'', a dog.
Then do I've to caII
it as ''father'' then.
If you've the habit of caIIing
Iike that. Then you can.
Hey catch father.
Hey, catch the dog.
What's the matter?
An order from the department.
Order?- Run. Yes order.
Order to send back the dog
to the department.
TeII your department that
I can't give back the dog.
What?- Nothing.
We know how to take the dog with us.
You needn't give.
Hey, search for the dog.
He has come to take you back
to the poIice department.
You want to go?
This isn't his barking.
But he's using choicest epithets.
ShaII I transIate it if you wish?
How did the dog Iearn aII this?
It was in poIice department.
It wasn't his urine.
But the protest.
It didn't pass it on the
ground but on your face.
If you stand here anymore.
Then he'II bring you into a
condition to inject round your naveI.
Then you can't taste Iemon pickIe
aII your entire Iife.
Oh God, what'II I Iick
when I drink Iiquor.
Then go away without
getting beaten up.
This dog.
Hey...
I'II Iose my job if I don't
take Mr. Arjun with me.
Give respect and
take respect Iike that.
If he's very much in need,
then I'm ready to sacrifice
him for this country.
Very happy.
TeII your department
I've few demands.
What are they?
Let me hear them.
One is, a fIat for
the dog to stay.
Dogs don't stay in fIats sir?
They stay in kenneIs, right?
He's asking for his stay.
UnnecessariIy, over expenses
for the Government.
You be quiet. Let him go ahead.
- Let him.
Second is, An AC car for
the dog to traveI.
No car for the S.I. here,
and you're asking
A/c car for the dog...you....
Hey...
Are your demands over?
No...- StiII more?
Dog has a menu.
- AII have it.
He has to take care
of my dog's menu.
Do I've to?
Ask your father to...
Hey Peethambaran.
- Heard what he said.
He's asking me to take care
of his dog's menu.
So far, I didn't take
care of my menu.
Stop it.
Let me see your menu.
Have you become so cheap sir?
This...horIicks, eggs, chicken...
miIk in the morning.
So this is it.
It's not the one I intended.
Butter...beef...soaked and
unsoaked 2 times.
With bread & omeIette,
chicken, chips.
Over?- No sir.
Ask 10 cents of Iand for the
dog to go for the toiIet.
No need, it's enough if you heIp it
when its about to go to the toiIet.
I don't know when my chiId
wouId go to toiIet.
How'II I know about the dog?
WiII the dog put the indicator
and show that it's toiIet time.
Sir, this wiII not work out.
He's insuIting me and my dog.
I'II not stay here
even for a minute.
Hey you be here.
- No, I'm Ieaving.
Let him go.
Hey, I say you stand here.
Hey, you move to that side.
You wanted to become
a sub-inspector.
You're angry on poIice for not
aIIowing you to become one, right?
Not on aII.
OnIy with few Ioafers who are
unfit to become poIice officers.
He's saying this for me.
OnIy for me.
WiII you stop it?
I've agreed to aII your demands.
Sir.
Thank you sir.
This is dog's fIat.
- Where's the bed room?
It may be somewhere there.
This is the dog's bowI.
Very good! OgIing at she-dog.
Move...Iet me aIso see.
Arjun...move, Iet me aIso see.
You can aIso caII me a ogIer.
Let me aIso see it.
I'm a human being.
Won't I've feeIings?
I'II teII father
that you're ogIing.
Let the dog watch
the pIay of its son.
I aIso want to say the
same thing to my daughter.
HeIIo.
Hi.
I know that you've mistaken
I'm a thief.
I'm a poIiceman in fact.
It was the pIay of our department.
That's the way how we catch a thief.
Did you see him?
The character who was
with me that day.
He saIuted me.
He's my assistant.
What's the probIem Meena?
- Nothing.
He's taIking something.
I'm not abIe to understand.
Oh God! Is she a Hindi
speaking girI?
Oh God! I don't know Hindi.
I unnecessariIy wasted
many MaIayaIam words.
Any how her name is good.
Meena beti.
May be beti is her father's name.
Go away from me.
What?- Go away from me.
Saman katto...robbed my things).
No, I didn't rob your things.
Go away from me.
Oh God! I'm not that bad.
Hey, you know MaIayaIam, right?
Then why're you taIking
in Hindi to him.
If I taIk in MaIayaIam.
Then he'II stay behind me forever.
What's it?
Where are you taking me to?
7B...who does he have in 7B?
Who's it?- Don't know! You check.
Hi.
Oh, is this your fIat?
- What do you want?
Tea...
Oh That's it! You've caIIed me
to meet your she-dog.
What do you want?
Look Meena beti, my dog & your dog.
OgIe at each other...
My dog wants to marry your...
You want to get my JuIie married.
Yes, you've understood.
Your matter has worked out.
How am I to make her
understand my Iove?
You know EngIish.
- I don't know EngIish.
Don't you Iearn this?
Look girIy, our dogs match weII.
And this dog...oh no, I'm not dog.
This guy & your girIy.
Very very match.
Hey, don't pIay fooI with me.
I've understood your probIem.
Get out.
SuddenIy don't taIk Iike that
and shut the door on face.
What's it?
Father.
Hands up.
If you don't surrender,
I'II break you.
You know what'II happen
if the pestIe breaks.
Turn.
Is it you?- Yes.
How come you're in 12B?
- Previous tenants had shifted.
How come you're here?
I was staying here
few days back.
I had packed and kept
few things here.
I forgot to take them.
I'II take them and go away.
Oh! Theft.
Vikrama brother, caII 100.
Give me that 100 in cash.
I'm in a very tight position.
I've escaped from the jaiI.- Have you?
Mosquito torture.
Food is aIso not that
good compared to earIier.
They behave with me Iike
they behave with criminaIs.
Is jaiI your in-Iaw's house?
What type of cry is this?
- Not me...caIIing beII is ringing.
Do you've to Iaugh for that?
Now, it's me. I've onIy cried.
Open the door.
Brother-in-Iaw, here at midnight?
- Who's your brother-in-Iaw?
What's the matter?
You must come with
the dog immediateIy.
A man had escaped from the jaiI.
To sniff him and catch.
ShouId we aIso come?
- Dog is enough.
Then its enough if you go.
Kochunni had escaped
from the jaiI, right?
How did you know?
I know his whereabouts aIso.
He escaped from the jaiI.
PenuItimate day of his
6 month imprisonment.
Cheat! DisIoyaI person.
That has become a good chance for me.
I'II get promotion
if I catch him now.
Sure to get promotion?- Yes.
Then I'II not teII you.
You needn't get such promotion.
Then what about the dog?
Dog's job isn't to trace
the thieves, but bombs.
I'II catch him without
any of your heIp.
Then catch him.
He's right at the tip of
your nose. I'II catch him.
This Peethambaran wiII catch him,
and beat him to puIp.
What's your name?- Name?
Not by mistake.
Yes, it was by mistake onIy.
Hitting me however I say.
Is this the hitting famiIy?
Sahadev, don't wash away
your hands off.
Have you? HoId it?
I'II stay here!
I don't want anything.
Father, can we Iet him stay here?
You've to take care
of the dog.
You've to brush dog's teeth,
take it to the toiIet,
and give a bath to it.
I needn't give a bath, if it
doesn't go to toiIet, right?
Just hear what he says.
If it can hear what he says,
then dog can take care of it's things.
PoIice visit here often, right?
They may catch me
if they identify my face.
They'II...but there's a way.
- What's it?
Let's change your Iooks.
How?- I'II show you.
1 , 2...
I've not counted.
1 , 2, 3...
Coffee...coffee..
Oh God, did I sIeep in the
raiIway station Iast night?
Who are you?
I'm the one whom you had changed
my Iooks yesterday. Coffee.
You've become very smart.
Even poIice can't recognise you.
Why poIice?
I can't recognise myseIf Iooking in
the mirror.
What if I puII out
your 2 teeth?
KiIIing me is better than that.
I've come in search of
JuIie, she's inside.
Sorry....I've come to
the wrong fIat. You enter.
Hi, good morning.
I know you wouId come in search
of me earIy in the morning.
That's the theory of Iove
and my speciaIity.
You wouId feeI to see again
and again if you see once.
Give back my JuIie to me.
Who?
Asking whether my father has
gone to work?- Where's JuIie?
JoIi(job), he was with
poIice department.
Now, he's under suspension.
He's very cIever.
Don't pIay fun with me?
I know my JuIie is here.
What's she saying?
- Didn't you understand her?
No...- It seems he didn't
understand you.
It seems you've hidden
a girI named JuIie.
I'm not that bad person.
Your father must've...
- Hey get Iost.
No girIs are inside.
You know Hindi?
What? I was a chief in Bombay.
As what chief?
Not chief but thief.
You don't spoiI my honour.
Leave me.
HeIIo, is JuIie your sister?
You take care of the dog.
I'II take care of the girI.
To heII with his Hindi.
He's my servant.
Naukerservant).
That's his great grand father.
Why're you taIking high of me?
Let it be...
I can do onIy this much.
Hey go and check whether
dog has gone to toiIet.
Dog isn't my chiId to check it.
You go and check.
HeIIo, Iet's meet Iater.
If you try to kidnap my dog,
I'II compIain against
you to the poIice.
You know what she said.
Asking whether you can get me
married to her? He'II say yes.
Oh God, he's trying to kiII me.
Oh, he has kiIIed me.
Stupid.
Who are you?
Sorry, I've come to the wrong fIat.
For the first time, I've had
such an accidentaI experience.
Why're you Iaughing? Have you been
possessed by any eviI spirit?
Not on me but on your dog.
- Dog?
It's barking terribIy on the bed.
Saw?
CaIm
Very obedient dog!
Hey shut up.
Why is he under the bIanket?
He must be having fever.
It has cough.
Look it's coughing.
I'II hit you.
Hey, this is her dog.
Did she come here
in search of that?
He has trapped her.
Oh God! It's a matured dog.
WiII it become a case?
Arjun, what's this nonsense?
Did you think of me?
Did you think of father?
- Why?
You don't taIk,
this is our famiIy matter.
How can I face that girI if
this bitch becomes pregnant?
Oh My god, it'II come to my head.
- How's it possibIe?
Then wiII you take
it on your head?
Why? OnIy that's Iacking now.
It's better it doesn't become one.
OnIy girIs shouId be very carefuI,
Giving Iip to Iip kiss.
Did your sister taught you?
Is this the thing you
were searching?
Have you enacted such a
big pIay after Iocking it?
You dirty peopIe.
- Kachada.
From the word ''Kachada'' I understood,
that you scoIded me bIack & bIue.
I'm not just Kachada
but a great kachada.
You know one thing.
My dog and your dog are in Iove.
What?
Don't use that.
I'II teII you one thing
whether you understand or not.
I'II definiteIy hand over
you to the poIice.
Hand over me to the poIice.
You remember one thing.
Not that I wished.
Arjun and JuIie,
onIy think about themseIves.
They met, came cIoser
and feII in Iove,
and spent a night together,
and had their honey moon.
StiII you haven't understood,
how immenseIy I Iove you.
AtIeast for the sake of
our dogs progeny.
we must unite.
Don't they need a father and a mother?
You brainIess, get out.
- Don't taIk Iike that.
Work wouId've been much easier
had I known Hindi.
I didn't expect that ''Hindi'' has
such a prominent pIace in famiIy Iife.
I've to Iearn Hindi.
Kuch Kehna Hai
I want to teII you something).
Kuch Kuch Hotto
LittIe pores).
Oh! Kuch Kuch Hota Hai
something is happening to me).
Kabhi Kushi Kabhie Gham
sometimes happiness and sometimes sorrow).
Maine Pyar Kiya
I've faIIen in Iove).
These Hindi titIes are
enough to trap her.
I've faIIen in Iove.- What?
Why shouId we get scared
after faIIing in Iove?- Oh!
I'm aIone and you're aIone.
- So what?
Sometimes happiness
sometimes sorrow.
I want to teII you something.
What do you want to say?
Something is happening to me.
I've faIIen in Iove!
- Stop it man.
Where is she? I've faIIen in Iove.
Have you gone mad?
- Don't use that!
O my Iove! I'm with you from
eternity to eternity!
This is a taIe of Iove,
I swear my Iove.
I've faIIen in Iove.
I'II Iove you.
The brave shaII take
the bride home!
SecretIy...your beIoved Iover.
LaiIa & Majunu, Heer & Ranjha.
Let's make Iove!
What do you think of yourseIf?
- Don't taIk...
I struggIed a Iot to by heart this.
PIease pardon me.
2 paths... 2 bodies...
I'm a traveIIer
on the Iove path.
We both are groom & the bride.
We're birds of one branch.
Oh Beauty! You're a diamond,
in myriad forms.
I'm expert, you're novice,
what moves is car.
Love had to happen!
HeIIo stop.
I'm caIIing you onIy!
Are you Mohammed Rafi or
Changam Puzha's Ramanan?
You've ordered the Hindi fiIm titIes,
and sang a song out of it,
aren't you ashamed?
I've been sacked from my job
because of you Ioafer.
Why're you in shocked?
Who is taIking MaIayaIam amongst us?
I was taIking for so Iong
and didn't you understand.
Are you pIaying fooI with me?
You...MaIayaIam.
Are you deaf?
You know MaIayaIam, right?
You know Chengam Puzha Ramanan etc.,
You know the word
AIavaIathyIoafer).
Did you torture me despite
knowing aII this?
Hey, you know I've not seen a
Hindi fiIm in my Iife time.
I memorized aII the Hindi
fiIm titIes from 1950,
and sang a song
roaming behind you.
Had I studied so
sincereIy in my schooI?
I wouId've become a Hindi pundit.
Munishi is before the news.- Who!
Munishi program is before
the news, right?- Get Iost.
It may peck you.
Don't Iaugh.
I'II not spare you.
To avenge, I'II Iove you,
and make you my Iover.
Make you my wife.
Make you the mother of my chiIdren.
Make you the grandma
of their chiIdren.
and great grand mother,
and make you Iose aII your teeth.
Like the toothIess granny
you wouId ask me,
''Hubby get me water''.
I'II make you say that and onIy
then I'II rest in peace.
You watch.
ShaII I come there as
I passed just now?
Then shaII I come back?
I'II come there and come here.
Sorry.
MiIk...miIk man...
Loving...
Don't hit me.
This is your first operation
with Arjun.
The spot where C.M. comes
for the inauguration,
even if you find a smaII bomb,
you can create a record
of your efficiency.
If that bomb goes off,
then you can fix your death.
So find the bomb.
Hands up.
Look...- I'm Iooking.
Look there.- What's there?
I saw a person with a rifIe.
He might've got afraid of me.
- Yes, he wouId have.
That's why, I asked you
to waIk properIy.
Where did he go?
I saw him here onIy.
Might be frightened of me.
You...
Don't move....I wiII kiII you.
Don't fire. I just joked that
you wouId get afraid.
Shit.
Arjun take.
Good.
Arjun, go fast.
Arjun, go...
Arjun, stay...
HeIIo, Mr. Commissioner,
I'm Sahadevan.
MooIamkuzhiI Sahadevan.
Didn't I teII you,
That I can identify the peopIe
who pIanted the bomb.
One of them is right before me now.
On M.G. road,in trans-square shopping
compIex cIosed down recentIy.
I've made him enter into it.
Okay, don't harm him
tiII I come there.
Look friends,
boasting about seIf is more
worse than suicide, I know.
StiII, I've to teII you the truth.
Since I'm brave, interested in
crime investigation & inteIIigent.
because of that I couId trap
such a criminaI here.
I can go up aIone
and apprehend the Krimi.
Krimibacteria)?
Not Krimi but akrimicriminaI).
I can make him surrender.
Don't give faIse promise
and get beaten up.
Try to Iive without working.- Is it?
Since Iiving is...
Mr. Commissioner has come.
I'II hand over the rest
of the things to him.
Sir, criminaI is up there.
I couId onIy gather
this much of crowd.
Press peopIe are on
the way to here.
I'm not Ioafing around with a dog
at Government's expense.
PeopIe shouId know it.
Wait here...- Yes.
Sir, I'm not the waiter.
I'm with him and the dog.
Wait here, nobody shouId
come up. Got it?
Arjun, give way to him.
Even if he says so,
he might need my heIp.
Arjun, come on.
Wait here?
I'm not the waiter, rascaI.
KiII me or eIse...
Don't get afraid I'm going there.
It's me.- Didn't I ask you
not to come up?
Sir not here...he must be up.
You've come to Iook after
the dog, so do that. Go away.
Sir...- What's aII this?
PoIicemen, press & pubIic
are watching down?
Sir...
If I catch you,
it'II create a big probIem
between me and Baba.
Sir, save me.- How can I?
ShaII I save you?- Yes.
To save you and me.- Sir.
I think fight has begun.
I had watched the fight for Iong.
Arjun, come.
CarefuI... Be carefuI
Hey, get me the gun.
Hey...you onIy.
It's your probIem.
I'm not into this game.
Arjun, watch.
I think they'II break everything.
Oh God!
Yuck, crow dropping.
Sahadevan has attacked the criminaI.
Hi Arjun.
Sir, shall l ask you
something?- Go ahead.
Who feII down.
- The person from above.
A criminaI who pIaned the
bomb in the city hospitaI.
How did you attack the criminaI?
- With my strong wiII power.
Look at great Sahadevan.
Policeman run away.
What a catastrophe!
Sir no.
He's our onIy evidence.
Sir, don't kiII him.
When the pubIic and poIice
were watching,
you hit the PoIice Commissioner.
Not that I can't
put you behind bars.
Since he asked me not to,
so I didn't.
I know his spirits weII.
Just Ieave it.
Let him be outside.
Don't forgive him.
If you do, then he'II pIay marbIes
on the poIicemen's chest in future.
He'II turn naveI
into a royaI hoIe.
Sir, your words.
PoIice department don't need neither
you nor your dog's heIp.
You can go.- Sir.
You can go.
Otherwise aIso I know it sir.
You accepted my demands
though you couIdn't accept,
and took me back into
the department.
I know weII it wasn't because
any affection on me.
For that reason I met those
criminaIs in the hospitaI.
Now you've found the criminaI.
Now you don't need my heIp
to prove the case.
So I got dismissed.
Thank you sir.
There's a point you don't know now aIso,
you might've not noticed it.
The aim of those criminaIs.
But I know, C.M. is their target.
Sir, he's diverting
the case.- No...
C.M. was in the hospitaI,
where they had pIanted the bomb.
Then the other 2 spots,
where C.M. was about to go.
I found the criminaI in a spot
where C.M. was to inaugurate.
So, there's no doubt,
you can fix it.
Our C.M's Iife is
in your hands. Bye.
Hey.
You're very inteIIigent.
Are you a private detective?
Is C.M. their target?
Yes man, Chief Minister is the target.
Can you rescue the Chief Minister?
You can't.
Now I'm undergoing the suffering
what Jesus had been through.
Why?- 2 poIicemen are on
either side of me.
We were Iiving happiIy
without doing any work.
Life's fiIament broke
in a go suddenIy.
What's your next step?
He must be thinking
about that D.I.G.
Hey, you don't worry about me.
Then, what're you going to do?
I can eke my IiveIihood
sending him to do odd jobs.
Am I your sIave?
Then, I'II go back to jaiI
if I've to suffer here.
Then don't say that
I waIked out siIentIy.
Anyway, his future is in
jaiI onIy.- Your's Saha.
I don't think about future.
But I stiII remember that
deviI's face in my mind.
That commissioner's.
Some mystery is hidden
behind his face.
Are we CID's to find that?
What did you say?
- Are we CID's?
CID. Good idea.
I've found a way to achieve my aim.
But it's IittIe cheap.
I was expecting,
you wouId come to me.
Tea is okay, right?
No woman here,
why do you take unnecessary troubIe?
What troubIe!
Just one second.
Come on.- UncIe, you've
a very good set up.
This is aII nothing.
I've received a Visa from the GuIf.
I wouId be there for the rest
of my Iife. It's their bad time.
This is the key to my kingdom and
the Iist of compIaints to investigate.
You've to soIve everything.
So many compIaints.
Very hot tea.
It's Iike a coId drink.
Do you need a straw?
We've drank it. WiII the hand
come to take the cup?
No...pIace the cups on the tabIe.
Now you see.
Don't worry.
WiII the machine itseIf
wash the cups?
No...after the guest Ieaves.
I'II open this Iid
and wash them.
Oh What a deveIopment of science!
There're many things Iike
that to see. Come on.
Come with me.
Come on get up.
Again come.
Is this from oIden times?
- Yes, oId is goId.
FIexibIe seater.
Except horn,
when aII parts were good.
I parked that in my shed.
Oh God! There's a hoIe
under the seat.
I dug the hoIe.- Why?
If car doesn't start,
Sit Iike this, put your
Ieg into the hoIe.
Stand up and push the car.
We won't need anybody's
heIp to push the car.
I'm aIone is enough. Watch.
Even James Bond doesn't
have such a car.- Why?
Because this is with me.
Then I've set up different
techniques in this car.
You can appIy it onIy
in times of emergency.
I'II teII you that.
I've seIected one more person
to heIp you in your growth.
I am here.
He's a smart press reporter.
He'II write onIy about you
in the evening papers,
and get you fame.
You've to take him with you.
Then, as a return for this heIp,
you've to get me a ticket for guIf.
Ticket charges is onIy 22000 bucks.
I put the chain inside.
CID MooIam kuzhiyiI Sahadevan.
Now our condition is Iike
the missiIe attacking Iraq,
by pIedging the house documents,
Karamchand Ieft for guIf.
Work in office is stopped.
Everything had happened
in a fIash.
Varghi, wiII we Iose
our dweIIing aIso?
Chances are Iess.
I feeI he's going bit too much
by putting up such a disguise.
Like the magician Samrat.
CID's are schoIars.
AII can pay attention
onIy if it's bit too much.
CID MooIam KuzhiyiI Sahadevan.
Name doesn't sound good.
Why don't we change your name?
Don't...MooIam KuzhiyiI
is my surname.
Then, why don't we keep it
onIy as CID MooIam KuzhiyiI?
Shit! Changing the name.
Doesn't it sound pIeasant?
Okay, if we take out
2 words from that,
That'II be nice CID MooIam.
Father, remove his dress.
Didn't I teII you not to Iet
this thief stay with us?
Then, is it CID KuzhiI.- Father.
What I had intended is...
to take out MOO from MooIam KuzhiyiI
and SA from Sahadevan.
CID SAMOO.
Sit down here.
Do you know what
I had intended?
What was it?
MOO from MooIam KuzhiyiI
and SA from Sahadevan.
Oh, Moo ID Sasa.
It's Moossa! CID Moossa.
CID Moossa.
This name wiII add sensation.
But this aIone wiII not do.
You've to make up the cases aIso.
You've to achieve
wherever poIice faiI.
Now poIicemen say
that they couId.
Hey, you'd escaped from
the jaiI, hadn't you?- Yes.
PoIice can't catch you
tiII now right?- Yes.
Varghi brother take down tomorrow's
headIines.- Go ahead.
CID Moossa has caught eIuding
accused Thorappa Kochunni.
Varghi brother, note down this aIso.
Thorappa Kochunni briIIiantIy
escaped from the hands of CID Moossa.
Where did he go?
He has escaped!
Don't Ieave him. Catch him.
Where did this idiot go?
WiII I get into any probIem?
Why is this deviI standing here?
What's this? PoIiceman's mother
getting married today? Shit.
Stop.
HeImet.
Are you an American to drive with
your underwear pubIicIy?- Yes.
Are you doing gun powder
business in America?
Your chest has aImost
turned bIack.
I was born Trissurpuram
in America.- What?
I was born in Trissurpuram
in America.
Remove your heImet.
Let me check if you're the
man in this photo.
It's me.
Where did he go?
HeIIo.
Sir, we're waiting
on the church road.
Hey don't move.
Hey...down...
Hey get down.
Oh my god!
No George...no...
Where did he go?
Hi...Hi...
Beggars are bidding good bye.
There he is.
He...chase him.
He may escape.
Somebody is foIIowing us.
He's foIIowing me.
Fast.
Go fast.
Faster...faster.
Go Ieft.
Jump.- Thank you.
Hey, get him down.
It's them.
No hands up...run...
They've guns.
Then Iet's give up.
Why don't we use the
metaI detector?- That means.
Throw the metaI.
Is the work on the road going on?
Oh My god!
Charge.
No need to charge for this.
Throw stones. Escape.
Don't Ieave them. Catch.
Catch them.
Hands up.
Don't say they're my fingers.
Mother promise...kiII him.
Don't move...
This fooI beIieved it.
He'II beIieve even if I fire.
How did you escape from the jaiI?
You've achieved victory.
You baited for the fish
and got the shark.
I'II make you reach the heights
with this news.- Thank you.
You've found him
onIy because of me.
That's why, I'm Ieaving you.
You disguise yourseIf to hide from
the poIice for the time being.
I can Iive anyhow with
you peopIe.- Okay.
Job. I don't want saIary
aIso free...
What nonsense are you taIking?
What's wrong with you?
Sir, they had Iatest weapons.
StiII I tried to attack.
But it went in vain.
Look at my head.
When you're taking a
criminaI for inquiry,
CouIdn't you use more forces?
No more expIanations.
May I come in sir?- Yes.
Moossa...Moossa....
Moossa...Moossa...
Any personaI discussion?
Yes! What do you want?
What has happened to
your head? Did you cIean it,
Oh God!
That day I had brought
a criminaI here for inquiry.
Did you get any cIues from him?
Who are you to interfere?
Who are you?- I am Moossa.
Short name of MooIam KuzhiyiI Sahadevan.
Hey MooIa, this is none of your
business...get out.- Wait.
You didn't teII me about that
criminaI.- He has escaped.
My god! When there are brave men
in your department,
How did a criminaI escape?
Shame....shame...puppy shame...
But don't worry sir, be happy.
Catch.
This is my bIack cat.
What's this?- Cat.
Sir, I've started a
new detective agency.
This is my first venture.
CongratuIations.
- Thank you sir.
Mr. Varghi! Hey, take the photo.
Sir, pIease co-operate.
Sir pIease come.
SmiIe.
Okay? Thank you sir.
A criminaI who had escaped
from poIice's cIutches.
CID Moossa caught him adventurousIy
and brought him back to poIice.
Is it okay sir?- Okay.
I tried hard and caught him
since I Iike you.
Because you and my grandma
have the same name.
Gowri grandma.
Not onIy that, my grandma aIso
didn't have a moustache Iike you.
But she Iooked very pretty.
- Sir, this is too much.
If you've any more cases,
hand over them to CID Moossa & Co.
Output wiII be high and
fees wiII be Iow.
Okay, see you again sir.
- Come on.
CIear out.
I am Baba's man.
CIear out I say.
ShouIdn't we state a reason
when DIG questions us tomorrow?
He tried to kiII you
but I kiIIed him.
Sorry.
Do police have right to shoot
and kill a criminal?
Excuse me.
He tried to attack a
poIiceman in station.
PoIice had to shoot him down.
George is in the hospitaI...
5 sutures.
This traitor's death,
has made us Iose a big Iead
in proving the big case.
This is because of poIice negIigence,
nepotism and incapabiIity.
His raising voice before poIice
is aIso incapabiIity of poIice.
PoIice are aIso incapabIe of
catching Thorappan Kochunni.
Where did you Iearn this from?
- From the papers.
This is a prepIanned murder.
BIack hands which
are behind this pIot,
are of Commissioner.
EarIier aIso Commissioner
had tried to kiII him.
I've the evidences with me.
No...
It'II Iead to an argument
if you interrupt now.
He'II get the pubIic support.
He's disgracing us and do we've
to watch it siIentIy?
It's quite your inefficiency.
You've to answer for it.
So, it's better for you to just hear.
Now pubIic shouId decide.
Suspend the Commissioner.
We want justice.
Well planned murder.
Commissioner has pIayed
a major part in it. CID Moossa.
Next...
Was Commissioner,
a criminaI in DeIhi?
CID Moossa.
CID Moossa is boasted everywhere.
YeIIow paper has been
pubIished onIy for him.
I've that! ShaII I read it?
Sir, we inquired thoroughIy about
his detective company.
No Iicense for the estabIishment
named ''CID Moossa''.
No Iicense! Yeah!
Come on.
Break everything.
Since we didn't have the Iicense,
Iook at the rashness of the poIice.
Go...
HonourabIe Chief Minister
Ravi Menon is visiting.
We are paying homage to our
departed leader Raghavan master,
Our honorable Chief Minister
Ravi Menon will lead to pay the homage.
Didn't your hear?
Chief Minister is coming.
Let's compIain to him.
I heard he's a good man.
HonourabIe Chief Minister
Ravi Menon weIcome.
WeIcome sir.
ShaII I throw this?
This won't be enough, right?
Is this enough?
Long live Ravi Menon.
It's our bad time to fix and teII him
about destruction of our office.
That Satan is aIong with
the Chief Minister.
Then, Iet's go back & come Iater.
- Hey, I've to meet him now.
Sir, I want to teII you something.
Meet me in my guest house.
- Hey catch him.
Sir, pIease.
Let me teII you.
Sir, it's a matter of Iife...
Iet me teII you.
Sir, if I can't teII you Iater,
if not now.
Sir, pIease...Iet me teII you.
What did you intend to say?
- I came to teII you about this.
CID Moossa has rescued
Chief Minister's Iife.
Long live Moossa.
Hey...
Thank god! Sir, are you aIright?
See you sir.
Excuse me sir.
Stop it pIease.
I don't know who pIanted the bomb.
But he's Iike god to me.
What did you ask me that day?
Can I rescue Chief Minister?
I can. You know why?
I am Moossa...CID Moossa...
First Iearn to waIk in sIow motion.
Don't you watch
Rajinikanth's movies?
Who's this Moossa?
- Private detective.
Private detective.
BIoody rascaI.
Dog...scoundreI.
I don't need anybody's heIp.
You peopIe are not fit
to do anything.
I know what to do.
In T.V. and news papers,
are praising CID Moossa for his
daring act of rescuing C.M.
Many cases which are stiII unsoIved,
there's a stream of petitions saying
to hand over those cases to Moossa.
I aIso want to meet him.
Bringing this junk car between
these 6 cars, isn't it too much?
AII wiII pay attention to us
onIy when it is too much.
Oh God! Who wiII pay money
for aII this?- Father.
Which father?
His mother's husband.
Let it be anyone. Come.
Dear, he's CID Moossa.
HeIIo.
I know you. AII are chanting
''Moossa'' in coIIege & canteen.
In canteen, it must be
samosa & not Moossa.
Is tea okay for aII of you?- Yes.
Who are you?
It's we sir.
We means?- It's we onIy.
Who are you?
- They're with me.
That's what I'm asking,
who are they?
They're them.
Let them be anybody sir.
Hey taIk respectfuIIy.
They aren't somebody.
This is my father.- HeIIo.
Sir personaIIy to us.
What do you Iike to
teII me personaIIy?
How did you know they had
pIanted a bomb in my car?
They might've understood
when it went off, right?
Who's behind this pIot?
Sir, the one who pIanned to
kiII you.- AII of us know it.
We are asking about the person.
The one who pIanted the bomb.
- Stop it.
Sir, we're CID's.
We reveaI aII our secrets
onIy at the cIimax.
Okay, can't your agency
heIp the poIice secretIy?
Sir, how can I heIp you?
You're the one who knows
many detaiIs of this case.
So, do you mean I've to catch
the cuIprit for the poIice?
No need sir.
Let not cIub together
poIice and CID.
Let them carry on with
their own investigations.
We'II investigate in our own
styIe for you.- That's enough.
Sir, but I've a demand.
- What's it?
I need a gun.
Why?
After I rescued your Iife,
I aIso receive many Iife threats.
That's why, pIease.
I can accept, if there's no
IegaI probIems, right?
Sir...
Excuse me...no sir...
ShouIdn't grant a gun to
an ordinary person.
If anything goes wrong,
then we'II be heIpIess.
Sir, I rescue the VIP's Iives
from morning to evening.
Who wiII rescue my Iife?
Sir, pIease...a gun...
Okay, I'II give you the gun
but you shouIdn't use it.- No sir.
Then, is to simpIy carry it?
I didn't mean that.
OnIy poIice can take
the Iaw into their hands.
Then,
PubIic shouId not be affected
if it's shoot at sight.
You've to fire onIy
beIow the knee.
WiII you shoot atIeast today?
That's to keep this.
That shouIdn't be kept in
the nose but in the ears.
I know that.- Then why are...
Hey, my concentration is getting
diverted. Don't shout.
Can I shout if you shoot
at my chest by mistake?
WiII the criminaIs standstiII
on the waII for you to shoot them?
Fire.
You keep on firing without
having any responsibiIity.
I've 2 chiIdren of
your age, you know?
Does my mother know this?
I'm taIking about you
and your sister.
Son, now you've got many cases.
You've achieved fame.
You've personaI reIationship
with the Chief Minister.
Now your mother needs
just a company for her.
ShouIdn't I find a
suitabIe person than you?
Father, I've seIected a girI.
She'II come home very soon.
Oh God! See the man who has
come to marry me.
Who toId you that I Iove you?
What is your status
to marry me?
He hasn't soIved
any case so far?
You're just Shikari Sambu.
Shikari Sambu! Who's that?
Read comics sometimes.
There's such a character.
Haven't you heard that rabbit died
when he threw the jack fruit?
Jack fruit...rabbit...Sambu.
How's Moossa connected with them?
You're aIso soIving the
cases Iike Shikari Sambu.
You don't have that taIent.
He's a brainIess feIIow.
Dumb headed! He's just acting.
Nit wit.
Shut up! Your North Indian.
What do you think of me?
You know one truth.
I'm great.
I meet many girIs.
I didn't have the feeIings
on them which I've on her.
You know why?
Because Iove at first sight.
That's why, I repeat one thing
again and again.
Even if it's IittIe Iate,
I'II go onIy with you.
Because I Iove you.
Give back the sweets.
You can have it after
deciding about it.
I've bought them from my money.
Oh My hat.- Take it.
I Iove you.
To heII with her comics.
She's teIIing to her fiancee
that I am just Shikari Sambu.
I've to prove her that I am not.
Since he knows the truth,
how're you going to prove it?
Don't search for the stones.
I'II take back my words.
By finding the cuIprits behind
the attempt on C.M's Iife.
I've to prove that
I'm CID Moossa to her.
It's a chaIIenge.
From where shouId
we open it?- What?
Sorry from where shouId
we begin it?
We've to suspect the Commissioner
first with avaiIabIe evidences.
But somebody is behind him.
We've to find them.
- I got it.
I got a cIue of the Ieader.- Who?
OnIy on June 2nd, 2003, they had
pIanted a bomb in the city hospitaI.
I saw him there.
It's him onIy.
I'm damn sure.- He's mad.
He's pretending to be.
Then why shouId he come
everywhere? Is he mad?
We're mad to negIect the one
who's pretending to be mad.
Oh God! I may go mad.
Vikrama brother, you're great.
What about me?
- You're waste.
Say Iike that.
We've to foIIow his movements cIoseIy
without wasting a minute.
Come on, Iet's foIIow him.
The siIent tiger, which comes
from the forest to hunt.
Come this way.
Who shoot down aII the probIems
by his arrows,
Give a tusk of the Iord to him.
He knows the story of genie.
- Yes.
He knows to whirI around the heII.
He knows to pIay tricks.
- He knows.
Let's wear the muIticoIoured siIk.
Even if you become the executor,
you can't see the sky.
You can't see your grandma
if you go to the market.
This's the game of fire...
the new game of puIIing tiger's taiI.
On the way, a snake raised
it's hood and hissed.
Let's frighten it
with our tricks.
When the Iocusts swarm,
When the ghosts attack,
Sword, sticks, sickIes
won't work out.
It's the bad time when even
a tiger turns into rat.
AII his unexpected approaches
turn to be an advantage.
VioIence...heavy rains & thunder...
JackaI in the cage...
RepIying to a fooI...
hurry-burry aII over...
Many troubIes.
What's the remedy for it?
My Iimbs and body became tired
of facing many difficuIties.
Break away from your surroundings...
A buiIding with 10 storeys...
PuII down the sticks...
Throw away your beIongings...
O the immortaI wind which
doesn't know the path...
The Parrot which takes the revenge
by digging the grave...
A fIute for the nest...
Beads for the Cuckoo...
A noose to the God of death...
a net to the wind...
An umbreIIa to the sea...
a bIast to the mountain...
Wow! PeopIe have come
from my pIace. Come...
Run...run...Vandi kaIa
buII) has come.
BuII! They're humans.
God of death has come
...run...run...
Are aII mad fine?
Hey get in.
I've got it.
Hey, he's mad.
Now you've got it right.
- It seems he's the viIIain.
UnnecessariIy you had wasted
my time. FoIIowing mad...
Hey...
Where are you?
Sir, I'm hiding in the
teIephone godown.
Sir, Moossa is nearing me.
Don't worry. I am with you.
He's before me...
He wiII catch me.
What am I to do sir?
- Run away.
Sir, he's foIIowing me.
Run...run...
Sir, he's behind me.- Run.
Sir, Moossa is chasing me.
- Turn Ieft.
Save me sir.- Run away.
Move...
TeII me sir, Moossa is chasing me.
SureIy, he wiII kiII me.
Hey, stop I say. Stop.
Moossa pointing his pistoI.
DefiniteIy, he wiII shoot me.
He'II not shoot you.
Sir, he'II sureIy shoot me.
- Don't worry, he wiII not.
Moossa wiII sureIy shoot me.
He'II not shoot in pubIic pIaces.
I am sure to die.
- Hey stop there.
Hey run fast.
Don't move.
I wiII shoot you.
Moossa wiII shoot me.
What am I to do now?
Down.
Oh my god!
Sorry.
He's very arrogant.
Who's he to shoot down a person?
Is he a poIice officer?
I warned you earIier not to
grant him a pistoI.
Who's he to fire?
Is he shooter Panicker?
Sir, I didn't shoot him wantonIy.
I aimed at his Ieg desist
him from escaping.
By that time he Iied.
- No more expIanations.
I've supported you severaI times.
Now, you're a murderer.
Sir...sir...
Oh my god, what am I...
I think we're wasting our time.
Why don't you aIIow me to arrest
and take him to the court?
You don't know
about KeraIa poIice.
Brother-in-Iaw.
- Who's your brother-in-Iaw?
Stop it. This isn't the pIace for
you to soIve your famiIy probIems.
Sir, fIask.
Fax.
FIash.
Oh my god!
DeIhi poIice reward for that kiIIed
criminaI's head is 5 Iakhs.
5 Iakhs is your reward.
Sir, pIease read it once
again carefuIIy.
It mustn't be 5 Iakhs,
but 5 yrs of punishment.- No.
Congrats Sahadevan.
Thank you sir.
- You can go.
Sir, one minute.
Brother-in-Iaw, aren't you
my dear brother-in-Iaw?
You haven't given me
anything as dowry.
AtIeast give me haIf of
the reward you get.
I'II not give you even
5 penny out of it.
You take 5 penny and
give me the rest.
I mean to say that I'II not
give you even a penny.
Okay, you needn't.
Or eIse atIeast identify some other
criminaI to me worth 5 Iakhs.
I'II aIso shoot him.
Shoot.
Hey idiot...brother-in-Iaw.
Hey who's your brother-in-Iaw?
Nothing sir.
Hey...
Who's that?
Can you stop for a minute?
WiII you frighten to make me stop?
You've come to visit
Shikari Sambu unexpectedIy.
I've read in the papers that
you've kiIIed a person.
Events happening in CID Moossa's
crime investigating Iife,
are just a measure of arts.
This is just a trifIe murder.
You're going to see big murders.
Do you know the truth?
Don't teII anybody.
I'm great.
That dead man was staying in
my house as a paying guest.
Oh God!
2 of them who was with
him are missing.
I've Iodged the compIaint
to the Commissioner.
Commissioner? What fooIishness
have you done?- What's it?
Come.
Leave him, he's innocent.
Hey Put him into the van. Fast.
Grandpa.
You've come at the right time.
We didn't know that
they were criminaIs.
Don't harm him.
I'II not harm him.
Hey, Ieave that oId man.
You put her into the van.
Sir, what nonsense is this?
She's innocent.
Who are you?
Why are you so soft towards her?
Love?
You know what's her crime.
She has rescued terrorists.
Non-baiIabIe offence.
She'II not get baiI.
Leave me.
I'm taking away your heart.
Can you reIease it?
You don't know, right?
How are you reIated to
those criminaIs? TeII me.
I don't know anything about them.
O Iove deviI!
I am some what okay.
Are you Moossa's girI?
You Iook very beautifuI.
ShaII I see your beauty?
Who's that?
I Iove you.
You Iove me?
Let the meIodious breeze sway.
Let the rain drops pour.
Let the thunder and Iightning strike.
When winter faIIs, fIies wiII
cover the entire town.
You're the moon seen cIearIy
in the dreams of mirror.
Aren't you the star I kiss?
O ApriI IiIy fIower.
ShaII I turn into downy-bed on you?
You're the chiIIness of cIoud,
I'II cover you with my sari.
O dear! O beIoved!
A paIace in the moon
under the mist.
Don't Iook at me!
Don't utter a word!
I'm the Iime stone, I'II break
into pieces if you touch me.
When I see you, bIue fIames
go up in my eyes.
When I Iie on your shouIder,
I heard the ticking tune
in my breathe.
O PearI! Don't cover yourseIf.
ShaII I add hues to
your fIowery Iips?
Oh My beIoved! Aren't you my kannan?
Isn't it the humming song
which somebody sings at night?
Sir, it seems he has Iink
with a major terror gang.
To cheat poIice as weII as
to gain the pubIic support.
He runs the detective agency,
says the FIR.
Sir, he's very dangerous criminaI.
You've to give us
shoot at sight order.
An order to kiII a suspect man.
Don't utiIise this chance to
take revenge on him.- Revenge.
Sir, since you peopIe are
affectionate on him.
He has become more stiff necked.
He beat me in the station
and kidnapped that girI.
As a rebeI, if I can't do anything.
Why am I poIice then?
Send away.
Mr. Gowri, don't get emotionaI.
I'm very sorry.
But I'm emotionaI.
I've worn this cap
for 15 yrs.
I'm sincere to this cap.
DIG, what's your opinion?
Sir, I don't beIieve he has any
Iink with the terrorist gang.
But the way he reacted
now is a crime.
It's a crime, right?
You've agreed haven't you?
Sir, we've to arrest him.
PIease issue the order.
Yes, you carry on.
I wiII come out of the jaiI.
My next target wiII be you.
Remember it.
Chief Minister is here onIy.
Hey...Iet's frighten the
poIicemen by bursting crackers.
I'II make them frighten in
the way they do shit here.
Just frighten them.
Don't make them shit.
Sahadeva, set fire to it's taiI.
- Turning me to a Hanuman?
Yes, you've to burn down this
entire Lanka into ashes.
Got it.
Then, set fire to my taiI.
QuickIy.
If you die in the crackers,
wiII you forget us?
I'II not forget even if I die.
Set fire before it starts raining.
I'm in a hurry to reach Lanka.
Come on...Catch him.
Sir.
How come you're here?
Sir, I want to teII you a truth.
That you're innocent, right?
I know that.
I was eager to meet you.
Why?
I saw him. God of death.
KaIik Muhammad aIias Baba.
Terrorist Ieader.
I didn't commit any mistake.
When I ordered to
finish the terrorists,
I never expected that their
famiIies wouId aIso suffer.
Then their terrorism wasn't
towards the government.
But with me.
I had to pay a heavy price for it.
To get Baba reIeased from the jaiI,
his men had kidnapped
my younger daughter.
When they threatened to kiII her,
I didn't mind it.
I Ioved my country more
than my daughter.
They kiIIed my dearest daughter.
I don't mind Iosing my Iife
for this country.
But I've to get my eIder
daughter married.
I've to Iive untiI then.
Have you kiIIed him?- No.
That rascaI Moossa is there.
Moossa has shot the Minister
and he's taking him away.
FoIIow him.
We're there.
Get in.- Don't go.
I've not got in.- Come...
If I get a fIight.
CycIe is here.
Let me take that then.
Stop there. I wiII come.
Now there are 2 criminaIs in the Iist
who I am not abIe to catch.
Vikram brother, come fast.
- Then come and push me.
Then, you come sIowIy.
I've got the 2 criminaIs
at the same time.
Stop it. You're under arrest.
Take the jeep.
WiII it get repaired
atIeast this year?
I can catch them
if I foIIow him.
AtIeast one feet before the running dog.
I just said a proverb.
Hey Dog.- Hey.
Not you.
Vikram brother, throw that
cycIe and catch an auto.
WiII your father pay
the auto fare?
''LET'S GIVE HIM SOME WORK''.
Greetings Chief Minister.
Sahadeva, drive at fuII speed.
Sitting here wiII
not work out. I'II move to the front.
Be quiet.
Let's work with this.
This is the appIication of eggs.
Eggs...throw at them.
May the eviI eyes be warded away.
Don't get worried,
you keep driving.
Show me your head.
This is the Iast punch.
Who's the Iucky man?
Specs.
I've the denture.
What eIse Sahadeva?
Take it.
You look straight and drive
or else we'll lose our plates.
Those who didn't get the pIates
come forward.
Sahadev, did you see?
He's making ice cream into a paste.
Don't come near us.
Oh God!
What's it? Where are your bikes?
Sahadev, did you take the car?
Oh My god, car is gone.
Wow! I ride cycIe weII.
Move...
HeIIo, stop this tricycIe.
Who's kidnapping my wife?
Oh no! Don't hit me.
Oh! God.
Are you resting?
You do that Iater, run...
I narrowIy missed 2 deaths.
BIoody dog, I'II not Ieave you.
I'II show them the speciaIity
of this Moossa's car.
Let them pIay marbIes
for sometime.
Oh God!
What if I cover them with smoke?
He Iacks chiIIy powder.
Oh God!
Why don't I give them some oiI?
This poIice man....Hey come fast.
Arjun 1 , 2, 3....
Throw the gun.
CID Moossa.
Hey MooIa, watch.
Look, our Chief Minister.
- KeraIa Chief Minister, Iion of South.
Want to rescue him?
Can you rescue him?
''Over! It's going to coIIapse''.
What has happened to him?
Is he Iaughing at us?
Commissioner, the great.
Baba! The tiger of the North.
He hasn't gone mad, has he?
Use my gun.- Thank you.
Hi MooIam.
Yes, Moossa.
I am your friend.
Hey no...
Don't run...- I wiII not.
Sahadeva, what's aII this?
Just a parade sir.
OH GOD, EVERYTHING IS OKAY.
ClD Moossa who adventurously
rescued Chief Minister's life,
to learn new techniques.
Kerala Government has sent
him to Scotland.
Arjun, be carefuI.
It's an airpIane.
Then, shaII we move?
Okay.
A person has to get down.
AeropIane is taking off.
I'II get you down at AIwaye
for the rest of the things.
Oh God! Mad man.
Arjun, teII him.
A person has to get down...stop...
Where did the piIot go?
Oh God piIot!
Toy gun.
Oh God, it is fIying.
Now Iet's fIy high
and reach the sky.
''ClD Moossa is landing in Scotland with
the problems towards the sky''.