Subtitles by explosiveskull
www.OpenSubtitles.org
Anderson's coming
out fast and furious.
And he's just landed a blow on
the forehead of Reiss Gibbons.
He's opened up a cut.
That cut
looks deep, Bobby.
It sure does, Jimmy.
Will the Cinderella story
of Reiss Gibbons continue?
Can he defend his Legends
Light Heavyweight title
for a fifth straight time?
Or will Anderson
dash his hopes?
Reiss pushes Anderson
to the center of the cage.
Anderson is so quick and
so smooth with his kicks.
Come on, Reiss.
These two men are
putting on one hell of a fight.
This has been one of the
most exciting title fights
in Legends history.
Max Black has to be pleased
with the way her champion is
performing tonight.
Everybody is on hand
to see this fight.
It's always an event
when he steps into the cage.
Come on!
Finish him!
Anderson is so quick to
firing up those kicks, Bobby.
Yeah, they're
really starting to open
up the cut above Reiss's eye.
He's knocked him down!
Anderson's
right back up.
Reiss is relentless.
He stalks Anderson.
He's raining down elbows.
He's got him up
against the cage.
Wait a minute.
Showtime Kick!
Reiss counters with a right hand!
What a fight!
Reiss knocked him out!
He knocked him out!
- Beautiful right hand.
- Incredible!
Ladies and gentlemen, you
are looking at the number
one fighter on the planet...
The five-time Legends
Light Heavyweight
Champion of the World.
Come on!
Reiss, that's five title
defenses in a row now. How are you feeling?
I feel amazing, lad.
Unstoppable.
Anderson opened up that
cut in the beginning of the round.
How bad did he hurt you?
You know, he
definitely left his mark.
Thank you, Stephanie.
What's next
for the five-time champ?
Uh, I'm gonna be a dad.
Have you got any tips?
We want to stay in the
Reiss Gibbons business.
Five-time champ has a
real nice ring to it.
Okay, it's Alien meets Prison
Break set in a space jail.
Who would I be playing?
The most dangerous
cop on earth wrongly
accused and sent
to space jail.
It's a bit cliche, isn't it?
We want to continue protecting
those pearly whites of yours.
That's molded perfectly
to your mouth.
How's that feel?
What'd he say?
It feels great.
Check this out.
Your own shoe.
There aren't very many athletes
with their very own shoe.
Baby Swap.
You're a dangerous cop who
swaps bodies with an infant.
Hard and Wet.
It's Fast and Furious
on a cruise ship.
The speed is low, but the
stakes are crazy high.
You into this?
Try the gun.
When you step out
onto the red carpet,
you're going to have the
best smile in show biz.
Hey, babe.
She's done it again.
I told you, you've got to
put the nappy on straightaway.
Oh, shit.
She's got a tiny
bladder, baby.
I think she's
doing it on purpose.
Of course she's not.
Are you?
Every time I pick her
up, she pisses on me.
I thought footwork
was your thing, big guy.
Well, I'm not quick
enough for this one.
Silly lump.
That's Marcus.
Where's Daddy going?
Is Daddy going to go to work?
I love you both.
Bye.
Say bye to Daddy.
Hm?
We've been working on that.
Come on!
Nice throw.
Offense, Reiss.
Offense.
Love it.
All right.
Line up, everyone.
Come on, line up.
All right, before everyone goes
home, Reiss, come up here.
Been together a long time.
You drive me crazy,
but I'm very proud of you. Love you, man.
I love you too, Marcus.
All right.
Let's welcome back the
five-time Light Heavyweight
World Champion, Reiss Gibbons.
Tomorrow you've got the 10:00
AM with Stevenson's manager.
Yep.
I need to make him understand why Domingus
has to be his first title defense.
He's really stubborn, Max.
Oh, man, he doesn't
know stubborn.
At 12:00 you need
to be in Birmingham
to meet with Anderson
to renew his contract.
Good, good.
Then you fly
straight out to Vegas
to sit down with The Nightmare
who's just become a free agent.
He hasn't become
a free agent, Fred.
He's become the free agent.
The guy's a monster.
I gotta sign him.
Oh, boy.
So how we looking here?
20,000 capacity.
Yeah?
You think we could fill it?
With a solid
headliner, we can.
Speaking of which.
Give me a second.
Yep.
There he is!
How you doing, man?
I'm good, Max.
How you doing?
Nice to see you.
Good to see you.
Looking good.
Thank you.
You too.
How Reiss doing?
Yeah, he's great.
In phenomenal shape as always.
Of course.
So I got a proposition
for you boys.
Go on.
All right.
So now you defended
the title five times.
Now, Reiss has basically
cleaned out the division.
I think the fans
deserve something
really special for the
sixth title defense.
Well, what have you got in mind?
What are you thinking?
Randy Stone.
Who?
Randy Stone, man.
Oh, come on.
He's the current
pro wrestling champ.
Max, that's fake
fighting, isn't it?
It's an opportunity for us
to tap in to their audience.
So Reiss can do what, jump
off tables and smash people
over the head with chairs?
No, so he can fight
in the Legends cage.
Max, look, Reiss went through a murderer's
row to become champ, and you know that.
Yeah.
And now you want
to offer a title shot
to this random wrestler who's never
even set foot in a cage before.
How does that work?
What's Reiss got to lose?
His dignity, his pride,
his self-respect, his fans.
I mean, this guy, what, does
he wear tights for a living?
Come on.
Reggie, think about this.
We do this fight, all of Randy
Stone's fans tune into it.
Reiss beats the fucking
shit out of him,
and whammo, all of a sudden
Stone's fans are Reiss's fans.
Ta-da!
Come on.
Think about Conor McGregor,
right, when he fought Mayweather.
Do you know how much money that
guy is making in endorsements?
Oh, yeah.
They are... Millions are
coming out of that guy's ass,
and he didn't even win.
Huh?
I mean, come on.
Look at that.
Reiss, Reiss, Reiss...
he would freak
out all these people, right?
He would love it.
I'll see.
I'll let you know, Max. Yeah?
All right.
I'll do my research.
Be smart.
Take it easy, Max.
All right, I'll give you a call.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Fucking managers.
How'd that go?
Yeah, great.
Let's go.
Nobody in this sport seems
to have any guts anymore.
Nobody in this organization
seems to have any guts anymore.
I love this guy.
He's funny, man.
Want a drink?
Yeah, I need one
after seeing this shit.
You haven't seen danger yet.
They want to call me dangerous,
you haven't seen nothing yet.
They want to
call me violent...
You're trying... you're trying to
tell me I have to fight this guy?
Yeah.
Buffalo Bad Boy, trust
me when I tell you...
This guy is amazing.
What? how is he amazing?
He's amazing.
He'll make you look great as well.
Look. He's bare
chested, he's committed.
This is going
to be a hard pass.
I'm not fighting him.
Well, I'll have to hard
sell it to you, then.
His pecs... are you
scared of his pecs?
Oh, definitely. Is that what this is?
Because he's topless?
Petrified.
You can be topless, too.
I've seen it.
Look at it as more of
an exhibition match.
His fans are gonna tune in.
He's got these
crazy wrestling fans
who love watching him get hit
over the head with a steel chair.
He's not going to
have a steel chair.
He's gonna have no weapons.
He's gonna have to fight you.
And these so-called tough
guys are going get knocked
out easily, emphatic fashion.
I want a highlight
reel knockout.
Can you give me that?
I want someone like Jake Carver.
Three-fight win streak.
Yeah, look...
That's who I want.
Look how entertaining
this guy is.
Right?
Bare chest?
He's entertaining
as a comedian.
Looks like he just stepped out of
some sort of an '80s tribute band.
Look.
...when I get that son of a
bitch inside a steel cage and I
get my fingernails
underneath his eyelids
and I pull on his flesh...
Come on, you gotta
give this guy a shot.
Give this guy a shot.
He should be a comedian.
I'm not going to lie.
He is making me laugh.
He is a comedian.
Look, he's got a
massive fan base
in the wrestling world, yeah?
They're going to come over.
They're going to give us those
pay-per-view numbers, man.
Okay?
Boss lady asked for this, yeah?
It's what Max wants.
Yeah, so when you
knock him out, like
I said, in devastating
fashion, you can have you
whatever you want after that.
Anything you say.
You deserve this.
Ooh!
You deserve it.
All right.
Think about it, yeah?
Easy money?
Easy money.
Easy money, man.
Easy money. All right.
Can we toast to this?
We can toast to this. To you.
To knocking out Big Mouth.
Give me the contract.
I'll give you the contract.
And let's clean out this clown.
Easy money.
This episode
of The MMA Show
is brought to you by Lex.
Lex, providing capital
to fuel growth in energy,
tech, and real estate.
And right now we're joined in
studio by none other than Max
Black, promoter of Legends.
And apparently you have
a pretty big announcement
for our listeners today, huh?
That's right, Stephen.
We are putting together
the biggest fight
in the history of Legends.
All right, you ready for this?
Mm-hmm.
You sure?
Yeah.
All right, here we go.
Reiss Gibbons, five-time
light heavyweight champion,
will be fighting Randy Stone.
From pro wrestling?
That's right.
Max, come on.
I mean, no offense
to pro wrestling,
but you're not talking about
a real fight here, are you?
I mean, you're talking MMA
you're talking pro wrestling...
apples, oranges.
Stephen, come on, man.
Use your imagination.
You put four-ounce
gloves on anyone,
and in MMA, anything
could happen.
That's why people love it.
That's what's so
beautiful about it.
You can't possibly look
me in the eyes right now
and tell me that you
believe that Randy
Stone has any chance,
has a chance in hell,
of beating Reiss Gibbons.
He's got a shot.
How is it that
this guy just walks
in from pro wrestling
into MMA and off the bat
he gets a title shot?
It's unheard of.
It's absurd.
The purists are going
to go crazy here.
Honestly, I saw
this guy train.
I mean, he's knocking
out his sparring partners
left and right.
And did I mention,
Danny Thicket is training him right now.
He's a legend, of course.
Legendary trainer.
And he wouldn't be
wasting his time on anyone
unless he believed in him.
Randy Stone is also huge.
Big guy.
The guy is as strong as an ox.
Max, Max, are you just trying
to take a turd here, polish
it up, and call it a diamond?
Or... Come on.
I'm telling you, I
think this is going
to be a really exciting fight.
There you have it.
So one month from today.
Yep.
Reiss Gibbons.
Randy Stone.
Yep.
For the Light Heavyweight
Championship. Uh-huh.
And that's me.
It's going to be a fight you're
never going to forget about.
I know, but you see
what I'm doing right now?
You're tapping out.
I'm tapping out.
I'm tapping out on The MMA Show for today.
That's all I got.
I can't believe it, man.
Believe it.
Oh.
Man.
Beautiful thing, man.
You did it. That's you up there,
your face, for everyone to see.
Everyone?
Walk past and see it.
Kids will see that.
They look up to you anyway
because you're tall.
Most people anyway.
Most people.
But now they
really see it, man.
Walking past this, remember?
I remember, man.
As a kid
a broke down billboard.
With the paper hanging up?
With the paper hanging up.
Now look at us, man.
Yeah, man.
It's beautiful.
Man, are you crying?
Huh?
There might be a
slight tear, bro.
It might be a bit of glazing.
Oh, come here.
Come on.
Yeah, yeah. I'm crying.
It's okay, it's okay.
I can see a little something.
The Legends cage
is reserved for the very
best fighters on the planet.
And Reiss Gibbons is
the best of the best.
The five-time champion
has faced all challenges
and cleared out his division.
Now, with all his endorsement
deals and new movie deals,
Reiss Gibbons is on
top of the world.
But it wasn't always
like this for Reiss.
Reiss comes from
humble beginnings.
He is the oldest
of three children,
and his parents,
Amanda and Dante,
passed away when he
was just 15 years old.
Reiss was left to
fend for himself.
When my parents passed
away, it was really tough.
I felt lost, and...
you know, until I met Marcus.
He kind of took
me under his wing.
And, you know, he showed me
how to throw my first punch.
I didn't know how
to express myself,
and he showed me how to put that and turn
it around and make it positive, you know.
That's all right.
Let him work.
Let him work there.
Nice.
Yeah, Marcus has taught
me, as a man and a fighter,
to be humble in victory or
defeat, to look after your own.
And that's exactly why my
family is so important.
That's exactly why strength
is so important to me,
because I gotta look
after my people, you know.
Do you know, people
recognizing you on the street,
it's a bit weird at the start.
But you kind of
get used to it.
And again, I don't
want to turn them down.
I want to show them
that I do care.
If they want a picture,
it takes two seconds out of my day.
Who am I to say no to that?
I love coming back
and coming to the gyms
and seeing their little
faces beam when I walk in.
Yeah, I do think I can
inspire them, for sure.
You know, seeing someone from
their own area coming up,
having a rough childhood,
losing people that they love,
you know, and I still
am on the right track.
I would love to
inspire all of them.
If I didn't have fighting
to fall back on, who knows?
I would have been either in a
cell or in a box, six foot deep.
That's how most people
I know have ended up.
So it's not no joke.
It's serious.
But his
sixth title defense
presents a new challenge...
wrestling champion
Randy Stone.
Randy is one of
the best wrestlers
the world has ever seen.
And he's gonna shake up the
world of Mixed Martial Arts.
I am on a pilgrimage to
scorch the earth of AEW one
broken neck at a time, until
I am the last man standing.
Well, hands down,
Randy Stone is the most powerful fighter
that I've ever worked with.
He's one of the strongest
human beings I've ever seen.
For a world champion,
I don't think he's
ever been hit by
a guy like me.
It's going to be like
getting hit by a truck.
He thinks that's
some kind of joke.
It ain't going to be funny.
Well, he knocks out
all his training partners.
So I've been having
a hard time keeping
people in the ring with him.
He's so intense and he's
so powerful that he's
been knocking them out clean.
It's actually getting to
be a bit of a problem.
Randy's the
most divisive figure
to ever step foot
in the Legends cage,
splitting the world of MMA and
professional wrestling right
down the middle.
I've been in
the ring with Randy Stone.
And I know this
is the MMA world.
And I am sure
Gibbons thinks he's
going to have a night
off because wrestling
is fake, right?
But you can't fake toughness.
And you can't fake strength.
And Randy Stone
has both of those.
I think both Gibbons
and the MMA world
are going to be in for
a shock.
He truly is hardcore.
He is extreme.
And everyone's talking
about this match.
When Reiss hits Randy Stone and
he realizes he can't hurt Randy
Stone, the life and soul
will get totally sucked
out of Reiss Gibbons.
I'm picking Randy all the way.
Randy, as an
opponent, he's a clown.
It's a joke.
That's why I keep laughing.
How can I keep a straight face
when we talk about this guy?
I feel like I'm
going to walk through
him like I walk through
my Sunday dinners at home.
I want to stick a fork
in him because he's done.
We've seen this all before.
He's funny.
People want to come over to our
sport, especially from more
an acting sort of
background, fake wrestling.
This is real life.
This is real sport.
And I think you have
more chance of seeing
Elvis Presley crash a UFO on
top of the Loch Ness Monster
than him winning.
Randy Stone coming in
to fight Reiss Gibbons.
What do I think?
Not much.
I don't think it's going
to have anything to offer.
I think Reiss puts him
away in the first round.
I find it incredibly
disrespectful when
so-called experts
talk about how pro
wrestlers aren't
real athletes.
I'm telling you, Randy Stone is
going to this guy up.
Randy Stone is not going
to beat Reiss Gibbons.
Reiss Gibbons is going to
beat him the first round
by knockout or submission.
I know Randy Stone
quite well, actually.
And he wouldn't be
doing anything that he
doesn't think he can win.
And I know the performance
side is one thing,
but there's a lot of
overlap in the training.
And I think people are
going to be surprised.
And watching Randy train, he's
got some heavy hands, man.
He's got some real
pop in those hands.
I think he's going to
surprise a lot of critics.
He's going to shut
a lot of mouths,
people that doubt professional
wrestlers in MMA fights.
All eyes
will be on this fight.
And one thing is for sure.
The world of professional wrestling
and the world of MMA will collide.
And we're joined
by Randy Stone.
Randy, thanks for taking the
time to talk with us today.
Oh, you're welcome.
Now, many pro wrestlers
have attempted to cross over
into MMA and do what you're
about to do right now
and haven't quite found the...
to put it politely, the
success they were hoping for.
What makes you any different?
I don't think about it.
I didn't come here to talk
about some other losers.
about somebody else's failures.
I didn't come here to
talk about the past.
I came here to talk
about the future,
and the future is, I'm
gonna knock Reiss Gibbons'
head off of his shoulders.
These are bricks.
These are Mack trucks.
I'm gonna knock him out.
I've been telling
everybody for weeks.
I'm telling the whole world.
I'm gonna knock him out.
And you all think it's a joke.
You're talking to me...
I'm here on this bush
league level show.
Randy, we can appreciate that
you have your game face on
and you're in the zone,
but we're the biggest
MMA show in the world, so...
Everybody thinks this is going
to be some big embarrassment.
Everybody thinks I'm going to
go out there and get my pants
pulled down and show the crack
of my ass in front of the whole
world, like I'm gonna...
I'm gonna be the one
that's embarrassed.
There's a lot of gum chewing
going on there as well.
You know, people do that
when they're nervous.
There's a reason I'm the
biggest superstar in the world.
There's a reason he needs
me to sell a pay-per-view.
That's the irony.
Well, you're not
lacking confidence.
But let me ask you, this is
your first pro MMA fight,
your first training camp.
And how's that going for you?
It's going, dude.
I'm in the best
shape of my life.
I'm stronger than him.
I'm bigger than him.
I'm faster than him.
I'm tougher than him.
I'm smarter than him.
I'm better looking than him.
I have no respect for him.
But you have to realize
that the pundits, the experts,
have Reiss as a 10-to-1
favorite to retain
his title against you.
And if you're
keeping score, those
are the worst odds for
any challenger competing
inside of a Legends cage.
How are you feeling?
Odds makers, betting
lines, people playing games.
No, this ain't...
This ain't a game, dude.
This is absurd.
Where's he going?
This isn't scripted like the
other place you came from.
Come on.
I don't know what he
was expecting here.
I mean, we ask the tough questions
on The Stephen Drake Show.
We're going to take a little break.
We're going to pay the bills.
We're going to come
back, and we're
going to talk to the Nightmare,
the hottest free agent in MMA.
He should be here
in a minute anyway.
Oh, there he is.
Look,
he brought his cheerleaders.
He's a lot bigger in person.
He ain't that big.
Should we go say hello?
Sure, come on.
Yo, Randy, I thought
I'd introduce myself.
I'm Reiss.
I'm not going to
shake your fucking hand.
What?
After all that shit you talked?
Man, that's just promotion.
I thought you of all people
would understand that.
Yeah.
You don't know shit
about promotion.
You don't think I belong
in a cage with you?
I don't. But let's
keep it professional.
I'm going to make
you a lot of money.
Oh, no, no, no.
Let's get this straight.
I don't need you.
You need me.
I'm going to make
you a lot of money.
You should show some respect.
Save it for the fight.
I want Randy.
All right.
Welcome, everyone.
Welcome to "Legends:
Worlds Collide."
Man, we are so excited
about this fight.
When my father died and I
took over Legends, many of you
people in this very room...
I know who you are,
I don't forget...
thought I was going to run
Legends into the ground.
And now here we are, on the
cusp of the biggest fight
in our history.
And we are trending
at this moment,
looking around, over 2
million buys on pay-per-view.
So definitely at
the right place.
All right.
So why don't we open it up to
questions, let these guys talk.
Randy, what's your mental state right now?
Are you excited?
Are you feeling confident?
Brother, there
ain't a word for what
my mental state is right now.
Confidence is not the word.
Complete self-assurance.
Like I know the sun's going
to come up tomorrow morning,
I know I'm going to take
this man's head off.
I'm feeling homicidal.
Reiss is feeling suicidal.
I'm going to kill this man.
Man, you've got to stop acting, Randy.
You know that, right?
This is real.
When we step in there...
When we step in there,
I ain't gonna throw you through no
table, jump off a turnbuckle, huh?
Yeah, it's gonna be real.
This is real. Yeah, it's real.
It's going to be real.
You laugh. It's real.
You think it's a joke.
You're all laughing.
You, with your stupid little
vlog, you think I'm a joke.
Nobody listens to your stupid
fucking podcast, by the way.
Everybody thinks
this is some kind
of Max Black big
publicity stunt, put Randy
Stone in a cage,
real big joke.
It's not going to be
funny when they're pulling
Reiss's teeth out of
the back of his ass
when I knock his head off.
All right, all right.
How about we have
another question?
Reiss, Reiss!
Hey, Reiss...
Have you looked
at any of the wrestling greats
for, you know, a new gimmick?
Someone like Roddy Piper
or Macho Man Randy Savage.
Hey, fuck you over
there, all right?
This isn't a joke.
I'm going to beat this man
within an inch of his life.
I'm going to walk away with
that championship belt.
I'm the toughest
man in the world.
I'm the biggest name in combat sports.
I'm going to prove that.
Let's see.
Let's see when you're
standing in front of 20,000
strong Londoners, yeah?
Let's see.
You're going to be quaking in
your little leather boots, man.
You're going to
get lobotomized.
You're not going to be
able to form sentences
after I knock you out.
I just hope you'll be able to get
your dick hard after the fight.
All right, all
right, guys, hey?
If not, honey, you
know where to find me.
I'll be in the biggest
suite in London.
I won't even make you
sleep on the couch.
Okay, okay, okay, okay.
And here we
are at last, the fight
the world has been
waiting for.
Reiss Gibbons versus Randy
Stone, Worlds Collide.
These guys
have been trash
talking each other for weeks.
There's real bad blood
between these two fighters.
The live gate
sold out within an hour.
If we look at the
tale of the tape,
the big thing that jumps
out are their records.
Reiss Gibbons, undefeated with
a perfect record of 19 and 0,
versus Randy Stone's 0 and 0.
This is Randy Stone's
first ever professional fight.
This has gotten big fight
bill written all over it.
You are
absolutely right, Jimmy.
Knee.
Hook.
Hook right hand.
Knee.
Come on.
Yeah, looking good, huh?
How are you? How's it going?
Good, good, good.
Yeah, you feel good?
I feel good.
I'm gonna whoop this clown's
ass, Max. Yeah?
You ready to kill him?
Committed to kill him.
Just do me a favor.
Try not to make it
too quick so I can
squeeze in a couple of spots.
I'll try, I'll try.
But I know, easy
money for me, right?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Just take it easy.
Have a good time.
You need anything?
Bottle of champagne for my win.
All right.
Afterward it'll be waiting for you.
Dom Perignon, yeah?
All right. You got it, man.
All right.
Have a good time. 2, 3.
2, 3.
The internet has
literally been exploding
in the build-up to this fight.
I don't think I've ever seen
this level of hostility.
Absolutely, Bobby.
And there are so many question
marks surrounding Stone.
While Randy is
known as a wrestler,
a little known
fact is he actually
started out boxing
as a teenager when he
was growing up in Cincinnati.
He has described those years
as some of the most rewarding,
and that is the itch that
got him into the cage.
You got this.
Okay, gentlemen.
We already went over the
rules in the locker room.
Any questions from
the challenger?
the champion?
Okay, you can touch
gloves if you want.
And there's the
theatrics from pro wrestling.
I guess Randy
Stone doesn't touch hands.
Fight.
Randy Stone comes
out with a flying knee.
He's not wasting
any time in there.
Randy's throwing
hooks with bad intentions,
but he's lacking a lot of
finesse in his technique.
He's really sloppy in there.
He's just
hurling his punches.
I would like to see
Reiss keep his hands up, though.
Get in there, Randy.
Take this serious. Come on.
Keep your hands up.
Quit showboating.
Let's go.
He really does look
like an amateur in there
with a professional.
Reiss is so smooth
with his striking,
so technical, whereas Randy
telegraphs his punches.
This looks like
it's going to get ugly real
quick for Randy Stone.
At least he's starting to do some
real damage against the cage.
He's turning it up.
Yes, he is, Bobby.
Reiss picking him
apart, and he's just
landed a spinning back kick.
Reiss tosses Randy Stone to
the ground like a rag doll.
Well, Randy
rushes in like a bull.
He presses Reiss up
against the cage.
Reiss is just so
hard to take down, though.
He's grabbing the fence!
Randy's
grabbing the fence.
There's no five second
rule like in pro wrestling.
Off the cage.
Circle out.
Randy's doing a really
good job of applying pressure.
I'm surprised Reiss hasn't
managed to escape by now.
And Randy Stone
has landed a takedown.
That is only the second
time in Reiss's career
he has been taken down.
I'm stunned, Bobby.
Taking down Reiss
Gibbons is no small feat.
This is
signature Danny Thicket,
working up against the
cage, dirty boxing,
making it a dogfight.
And Randy's landed
a second takedown.
I'm really surprised at how much Reiss
is struggling with Randy's size and power.
Back it.
Back up.
Stay on him.
No mercy.
Come on, move!
Well, this is what Danny
Thicket has been talking about.
There's one thing you can't
fake, and that's strength.
And Randy's just hit
a slick judo throw.
Get off the bottom.
Work your way up.
Get out of there.
Reiss is back
up, and he's just
landed a nice elbow,
opening up a cut in Randy Stone's head.
Combinations, just
like we practiced.
Randy hits
another takedown.
That's the fourth of
this fight.
I can't believe it.
And now he's mounted Reiss.
Reiss is launching haymakers.
Randy is
clearly demonstrating
his strength advantage.
Reiss is really struggling.
Nice.
Nice work.
Go to work.
Let's work.
Reiss is on
shaky legs out there.
He really looks
unsure of himself.
Come on, Reiss.
Keep your hands up.
Come on, do some hand fighting.
Do some hand fighting, Randy.
Reiss lands a nice jab.
Combinations, just
like we practiced.
Another.
Reiss looks like he's
getting back into his groove.
He's creating some distance.
He's got to keep Stone
away from him, though.
He needs to keep
those hands up.
Randy lands a hook.
Finish him.
Yeah!
- Reiss is out!
- Oh, my God.
I can't believe it.
Reiss is knocked out.
He is out.
That's one of the
most dynamic punches
I've ever seen in this cage.
Oh, my God.
He's wrestling down
the referee right now.
Reiss doesn't even
know where he is.
TJ Steele is talking to Reiss,
and Reiss is still coming to.
It's over.
You're knocked out.
What started out as a
joke has turned into a travesty
for Reiss Gibbons
and his team.
This is the
most shocking night
in the history of Legends,
perhaps in the history
of Mixed Martial Arts.
I don't think a single person
in this arena saw this coming.
I told you all!
And look at him...
Shouting to the crowd.
The antics... He's loving it.
Randy Stone is loving it.
Welcome to
the Randy Stone era.
Wow!
Ladies and gentlemen, winning
the fight in the first round
by knockout, and new Light
Heavyweight Legends Champion
of the World, Randy Stone!
I told you!
I told all you.
You thought I was a joke.
Who's the joke now?
Reiss Gibbons is a joke.
I'm the champion
of the world now.
Who's laughing now?
Laugh it up!
We're gonna party in London
tonight, you motherfuckers.
It's 3:00 in the morning.
I've been turned into a meme.
"When your mom says quit
crying before she gives
"you something to cry about."
"When you lose your mom
in the grocery store."
People suck.
Come back to bed.
I'm good, baby.
Reiss,
thanks for coming on the show tonight.
How are you feeling?
Well, losing is no fun.
Yeah, I can imagine.
The doctors, what do they say?
What kind of time frame
are you looking at here?
When are you getting
back in the cage?
Well, I wasn't
knocked out, so anytime.
You...
You kind of were, Reiss.
I took no damage.
I can get back in there
as soon as possible.
Look, I respect you.
The whole MMA
community respects you.
But there were some questions
about your cage etiquette.
They're saying you didn't
take this fight seriously,
and you didn't take
Randy Stone seriously.
And you paid for it.
Take it easy,
Steve, all right?
Look, if I was showboating
and I got the knockout,
no one would be talking,
right?
But I was having fun in there,
I got clipped, that's that.
Lucky shot.
Is this the biggest upset
in the history of MMA?
Well, that's for you to
decide, Steve, all right?
Well, do you get
the immediate rematch?
Do you want the
immediate rematch?
Well, yeah.
You know, I've held the belt
longer than anyone, you know.
But... That's
after this tiny little movie
from Jake Thorn.
Reiss, are you...
Are you not on social media?
Yeah, I just
turned my phone off.
I'm not trying
to pile on here.
One of your castmates tweeted
out about a half hour ago...
And I don't mean to be the
bearer of bad news here,
but apparently
you've been replaced.
They recast the role.
What?
It's on Twitter.
You should turn your phone on.
Prostitutes we
can pay off, yeah?
Women claiming that
you've got kids
through them that
you're not paying for,
we can pay them off, too.
But you get busted for
steroids, injecting
needles into your left
butt cheek five times...
And you tell me
it's an accident.
Is it an accident?
What was you doing? Was you in
Vegas again with the snow bunnies?
Yeah?
Sniffing cocaine
off their fake tits
and playing darts with them, and the
darts happened to contain steroids?
And then you happened to land
on them accidentally five times?
You're right.
Picograms, man.
It's a real thing.
It's a real thing,
and it happens.
Yeah?
Now, what you're going to do, you're
going to go home and see your family.
By the way, your wife's been calling
me every single morning, yeah?
Why doesn't she call you?
Do you know why she can't call you?
'Cause your phone's always off.
Why is it always off?
You got a 10-bedroom
mansion back there.
You can afford a charger.
So what you're gonna do,
you're gonna go home,
and you're gonna get a
phone call from me, yeah?
And when you get
that phone call,
it's going to be me talking about the
press conference. Yeah? Stephen Drake.
He's going to get
the exclusive.
You're gonna talk
about your life.
You're gonna talk about
the fact that fighting
is the only thing that's
kept you sane, all right?
And that's going
to secure things.
You're gonna have to deal
with a two-year suspension.
When you come back,
you're gonna come back stronger than ever.
Yeah, look at me...
Stronger than ever.
You're going to be
the champion.
Have another kid in
the meantime, yeah?
And don't drive home yourself, yeah?
Get a cab.
We don't need you running over
any pregnant women again, yeah?
That was a difficult situation to solve,
wasn't it, yeah? All right. Wicked.
Come on.
You got this, yeah?
Stay out of trouble till then, yeah?
Thank you, Carlos.
And Carlos, please don't
end up in Dubai again, yeah?
All right.
Magic man.
I deserve this.
Yo, I'm cut from
Jake Thorn's movie.
I just found out.
How does Stephen fucking
Drake find out before I do?
And you're supposed to
be the first to know.
Reiss, I was going
to call you as soon as.
So what happened?
That role was about
you being the strongest
soldier in the whole world.
It just doesn't work if
you're not the champ.
That was only my first loss.
I know.
I know, Reiss.
It's not the fact
that you lost.
It's the way you lost.
The crying thing,
the wrestling the ref to the canvas.
The media just got hold of it.
And you know
better than anyone.
You're only as good
as your last fight.
People have got a real
short-term memory these days.
Then get me the rematch.
It's too soon.
We need to run it back.
Get me the rematch, Reggie.
Are you sure?
Get me the rematch now.
Laila Ali
has a plus one.
Yeah, definitely.
Front row.
Great.
Idris Elba wants 10.
10?
10 comps?
Guy's lucky he's so hot.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, sure.
Front row?
That's great.
Peter Andre?
No.
No, no, no.
- Hard no.
- Hey, Max.
Reggie!
You got a minute?
Of course.
For you, I got a minute and a half.
- Lovely.
- Yeah.
You look great, too.
Look at you.
Hi, Fred.
What's poppin', Reg?
Not bad.
All good. Right.
You're in a good mood.
Yeah, are you kidding me?
I got sponsors coming out
of my ears, my eyes, my ass.
It's great.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
Hey, team effort, man.
So we getting that rematch?
Yeah, of course you are.
We can't wait to
agree to that bout.
Now, Reiss is
ready to sign ASAP.
He wants to redeem himself
and prove to the world
that it was just a fluke.
Yeah.
Well, yeah.
I mean, he'll get it.
You know.
But?
The truth is this.
Stone had a hard time
making the cut at 205.
So he's moving up
to heavyweight,
and he's going to
challenge Ferguson.
Right?
I mean, the whole
champ-champ thing...
You know, you can't blame him.
Everyone wants to
do that right now.
But I want Reiss
to fight Nightmare.
Nightmare?
Yeah.
We just signed him.
But Max, we want Randy Stone.
Yeah, but I'm not
offering you Stone.
Max, we've always
stepped out for you, right?
Mm-hmm.
You've needed us to fight on
three weeks' notice. We've done it.
Two weeks' notice.
We've done it.
Yep. You guys are the best.
Up in weight, we've done it.
Down in
weight, we've done it.
Yep.
Right?
- Reiss has always been a company man.
- Yep.
- Held onto the strap for
nearly five years. - Yes.
He deserves a rematch.
Reggie, you and I
both know the money
fight is Stone-Ferguson.
The money fight...
But this is about the
right fight, though, Max.
Right fight?
What is this, Mr.
Rogers' playhouse?
What are we in
kindergarten, Reggie?
Grow the fuck up.
Okay.
So what if we lose?
Wow.
You got that much
faith in him, huh?
Max, it's not about faith.
I'm being realistic.
Look, Nightmare is
a dangerous fight.
If we lose that fight,
that's two losses in a row.
You know that.
It's a bad fight for us.
Look, if Randy Stone is
too heavy for the division,
then strip him.
I'm not gonna strip him.
Create an interim title, then.
I'm not going to do that.
Max, who's running this
fucking company, you know?
You or Randy Stone?
Where are your fucking balls at?
I've done a pretty
good job without balls,
wouldn't you say, Reggie?
I don't know.
I think that the
Max Black I know
would have told him
to go fuck himself.
Yeah.
Well, you're lucky the Max
Black is in a good mood today,
or else I might tell
you to go fuck yourself.
Listen, man, we go
way back, right?
I know you're just
trying to do your job.
Well, give me a fucking break.
That's what I'm
trying to do here.
I'm just trying to do my job.
And the truth is, the
Stone-Ferguson thing
is set already.
So basically, you
got two choices.
If you believe Reiss could win,
you have him fight Nightmare.
What's the second
choice, then?
Or you sit on the shelf.
All right, Max.
Thank you.
All right?
Yeah.
- We cool?
- We're good.
All right, man.
Take it easy.
- Fred, see ya later.
- Give Reiss my love.
I'll give you a call.
Yeah.
Peace.
Who else we got?
Okay.
Drake.
Are you kidding me?
Which side?
Whoever's side we're going to put him
on, they're going to hate us.
Pivot couple of Ryans.
Are they coming?
Yeah, both Ryans.
Well, fucking put
Ryan in the front row.
Okay, Ryans.
Put Ryan Gosling near me.
Yeah, I'm on it.
No fucking way.
No way.
Marcus, it's the only fight Max is
willing to offer. Yo, Reggie, tell him.
It's true, Marcus.
Then you wait.
It could be a whole year.
Then he spends some
time with this kid.
Stone and Ferguson fight,
we start talking trash,
we get our rematch.
I'm not waiting a year.
We're not taking
the Nightmare fight.
Why not?
He's less popular.
He's more dangerous.
Quite frankly, it's
a bad match for you.
If I was the champ, I'd
have to fight him anyway.
So what's the difference?
If you're champ, the
juice is worth the squeeze.
Yeah, we're talking back end
points on pay-per-view, bigger
show money,
and more PR, Reiss.
You know, I'm
not afraid of him.
He's hungry.
He's dangerous.
Oh, yeah.
His last fight, he
broke a guy's orbital.
He's retired now.
Reiss, can't you see
what Max is trying to do?
She's trying to use you to
build her young fighter.
You deserve better than that.
She's throwing
you to the wolves.
I'm a wolf.
You're not listening.
We're not taking the fight.
That's final.
Yeah, I had a
feeling you'd say that.
I'm going to LA.
I'm going to do this
camp with Tony Gunn.
LA?
Reiss, you don't
need to go to LA.
Are you serious?
Reiss!
Makes me a little nervous.
Hard leg kick again.
Oh, that's a knockout.
That's it.
A hard, hard punch.
Not gonna hold up.
14 more.
Sorry.
I must have carried some
extra weight on the flight.
Come on, that's no excuse.
You're a professional.
Let's go.
Come on.
Back on the bike.
Come on, let's go.
Three more.
- Tony.
- I'm not calling it.
We're calling it.
No.
Reiss, it's not worth it.
We're not calling it, Ellie.
Come on.
Let's get going.
Got anything left in you?
Can you cut these last two?
Tony, he's finished.
Let him answer.
Reiss.
My body won't sweat anymore.
I'm done, Tony.
You do realize you'll be
giving up 20% of your purse.
Yeah.
Fine.
My fee stays the same.
What's up?
I'm not used to
sharing a locker room.
That's what you get
when you're not the champ.
A roomful of dicks and ass.
Looking good out there, Corey.
All right, next time, man.
Dude.
MCL?
Doc said eight weeks.
I'd give it 10,
just to be safe.
Definitely, Max.
Owie.
That sucks.
Oh, man, you fought
your ass off.
Those judges were bullshit.
We'll run it back.
All right?
Good fighting.
A little something for you.
Hey, Tony.
How you doing?
Good to see you, Max.
Sorry about the weight.
What happened?
It's just a really tough cut.
I'm sorry.
Do we need to
move you to heavy?
Hell, no.
Those guys are monsters.
Big boys.
All right. Well,
this can't happen again, Reiss.
I know.
Marcus, what are you doing here?
I got added.
Fight on the prelims.
Oh, no way.
That's amazing.
Yeah.
First pro fight.
How'd you get on?
Won by split decision.
Man, that adrenaline dump.
Yeah, you'll get
used to it, man.
I'm proud of you.
Marcus.
Tony.
Do your thing, brother.
Congrats.
That's Marcus, huh?
Yeah.
Pretty serious with
those chops he's got.
Reiss is getting
absolutely pummeled.
Nightmare is just hammering
him against the cage.
Reiss, you gotta go.
Come on.
Reiss opted
to fly out to LA
and do this camp with Tony
Gunn, one of the rising
stars in the world
of coaching.
Tony is not looking
pleased right now.
Hey, who's the joke now?
Randy Stone is
in attendance tonight.
Randy of course has his big
pay-per-view heavyweight title
fight coming up with Ferguson.
You're running around
this cage like a clown.
Oh, shut up, man.
Changing your camp
is going to throw off...
Hey, use your distance.
Calm down.
Breathe.
...right
now, before taking
on Nightmare, the scariest human
being in Legends promotion.
Get the fuck out
of there, Reiss.
What are you doing?
Reiss missed weight
for this fight, the first time
in his career he's
missed weight.
Nightmare, of course,
was kind enough to make
this fight a catchweight.
I wouldn't
call that kind, Bobby.
Look at the size
of him in there.
He's huge.
Is this even a fight?
Reiss is on the mat.
He's trying to get
Nightmare to do jujitsu.
Come on.
Reiss, no one's
here for that shit.
What are you doing?
Boo!
It's shocking.
He's not even doing anything.
Come on!
Let's go.
Nightmare is
actually taunting Reiss.
And the referee has stepped
in and is standing Reiss up.
They're forcing the fight
back to the stand-up.
The crowd is clearly
unhappy with this display.
Punish him!
Come on.
Reiss, come on.
Out of the corner.
Out of the corner, man.
Reiss really looks like he
doesn't want to be in there right now.
He's even moving stiff.
It just looks like something's
not right with him.
And Nightmare's
throwing his hands up...
We came here to fight!
...shouting to the crowd.
He's taunting Reiss right now.
Get in there.
Let's go.
Hey, who's the joke now?
Randy Stone is up,
out of his seat, and shouting at him.
The crowd is screaming for
Reiss Gibbons to engage.
Come on, get
your head in the game.
Look at him.
He's embarrassing you.
Get in there!
Come on!
Come on, Reiss!
Reiss, come on!
Reiss fires
alternative jab.
Nightmare follows up
with a fast counter.
This is starting to
get embarrassing.
Hey, Reiss, would you fight?
Look at your boy!
Knockout!
I'm here with the former
Light Heavyweight Legends
Champion, Reiss Gibbons.
I hate asking questions right
after a knockout, Reiss.
But if you can, how are
you feeling right now?
I've been around a long time.
And, you know, I've fought
the best of the best.
I think it's the
last time you're
going to see me in the cage.
What,
are you saying you're
ready to retire right now?
I never started this
sport to be average.
I wanted to be the best,
and I no longer am the best.
So I want to say thank you to my
coach for this camp, Tony Gunn.
Where's my coach?
It's been an
honor to announce your fights
all these years, Reiss.
Sorry to see you
go out like this.
We wish you nothing
but the best.
Reiss Gibbons,
ladies and gentlemen.
Where the fuck did you go?
I'm not sticking
around for that shit.
What do you mean?
What do I mean?
It's nice to be the last fucking
person in the entire arena
who knows you're retiring.
A waste of my fucking time.
And what the fuck were
you doing out there?
Everything we worked on,
everything we trained...
You did nothing.
Nothing.
Where the fuck were you?
I'm out of here.
Good luck to you.
You're a
million miles away.
I don't think I
got anymore, Ellie.
What happens next?
Whatever we want.
We could get that farm
we've always dreamed of, hm?
I could get a horse.
What the hell are we
going to do with a horse?
I've always wanted a horse.
Reiss, what's up, bro?
I know you always get
mad when I do this, Roy,
but I want to pull
some of my money out.
Reiss, when was
the last time you
took a look at your finances?
I don't know.
I don't deal with
that side of things.
You're in the red.
That can't be right.
I'm afraid it is.
What about the account I
put aside for when I get old?
You kept dipping into it.
That Swiss account?
Take a look.
You were supposed
to take care of me.
I'm not your dad, bruv.
I'm here to advise you.
Then where was the advice?
You had one job, one
fucking job, Reggie.
Take care of my money.
Where is that now?
Reiss, you don't listen.
Look, can you sit down?
Reiss, sit down, bruv.
Now, listen.
Your outgoings were too high.
Sponsorship deals,
they're finned.
Pay-per-view back end,
that went out the window when you lost
the belt. Bruv, flying
your whole family to LA
for that extravagant
purchase, first class,
for this Nightmare training
camp you didn't even need.
Look, eventually the
money is going to run out
when it's no longer coming in.
It's that simple.
And the poor
investments you made...
The CBD oil, the high-tech
start-up companies.
Bruv, they all went
bust within a year.
And I told you not to do that.
I'm never going back
to that life, Reggie.
I know.
Ellie is going to freak out.
What do I do?
You gotta tell her the truth.
She's going to find out.
This is definitely authentic?
Can't get that
label anywhere else.
How come you're selling them?
Are you okay to do
a bank transfer?
Yeah.
Thanks.
Well, thank you.
Nice to meet you, man.
Big fan.
Massive fan, man.
Nice, man.
My nephew, you're
his favorite fighter.
His name's Kyle.
What's your name, bro?
Jerome, man.
Jerome.
I'm Darryl, man.
I'm Darryl.
Yeah, the fight with Anderson
was his favorite, yeah?
Yo.
Kyle, guess who I'm with.
Say something to
the camera, man.
Yo, Kyle, stay in school, man.
Be good, okay?
Yeah, yeah.
Yo, man.
I appreciate it, man.
Stick in there, man.
You mean the world to us, man.
Five-time champ, man.
Five times!
Pleasure.
Yes!
Reiss.
Go back to sleep, baby.
Reiss, get dressed.
Bruv, it's 6:30
in the morning.
Yeah, I know.
And Ferguson's out of the
Randy Stone fight. What?
I know. Look, Reiss,
this is our chance.
You can get a rematch.
I'm retired.
Retirement?
Reiss, stop talking nonsense.
Look, I've been calling Max all morning.
What did she say?
Well, she hasn't
returned my calls yet,
but that's 'cause
she needs convincing.
The fight's in a few weeks.
Reiss, you've taken a fight
on a week's notice before.
Come on.
Get your head in the game.
My head's not in it, man.
Oh, Reiss.
Come on.
Look, this is yours.
This is your opportunity.
I can't.
What do you mean you can't?
What's... Reiss, this isn't you, man.
Talk to me.
I'm sorry, Reggie.
See yourself out.
Reiss, stop. Stop.
Look, this isn't you, yeah?
Alpha, man.
Look, stop all the weakness.
We'll sit down, we'll have a coffee,
and we'll talk about it, yeah?
Reggie, see yourself out.
Are you sure this is
what you want to do?
Yes.
Why are you turning this down?
Ellie.
I don't want to fight anymore.
Why?
I'm afraid.
Good.
Finally you got
that out of the way.
I have poured everything
I've got into this, into us.
I've sacrificed everything.
I've put my whole life
on hold.
Do you know why?
Because I believe in you,
Reiss.
I can't believe you have
the nerve to follow me here.
Look, Max...
No.
You haven't even
heard my question yet.
I don't need to hear
your question, Reggie.
The answer is no.
Listen, Max, that's our fight.
Oh, man.
You know, you got a
lot of balls, right?
First you lose the first two,
and then you officially retire?
Fuck you.
Look... Listen, Max.
It's a mistake, okay?
It's Nightmare's fight. Sorry.
I'm announcing it right now.
Max, just listen.
Max.
No.
It's a mistake.
You know what? Reggie, you're really
bugging the shit out of me right now.
Just give me one minute.
No. No.
Just I'll explain...
Do you want me to call security?
You wouldn't do that.
Yeah, I will.
We've got 100 missed calls.
I could arrest you
for stalking.
Well, if you
returned my calls,
you wouldn't have so many
calls in the first place.
Listen, I gave Reiss every
fucking chance there was.
It broke my heart when
he lost that fight.
I love the guy.
But at a certain point, you
gotta draw the line, okay?
It's just business, Reggie.
Max.
Max, please!
Sorry. Are you fucking crazy?
I'm sorry.
But just hear me out, Max.
Okay.
Okay, listen.
You got 30 fucking seconds.
Thank you. Look, Max.
Look, you said it yourself.
You love an underdog
story, right?
Well, this is the
biggest underdog story
in the history of Legends,
maybe in the history of MMA, all right.
The first time they
fought, Reiss was the king,
and he went through a
murderer's row to get there,
went through so
much hell and back.
And you've been there. You've seen it.
You know this, right?
This time, the roles are
completely reversed, right?
He's the one who's got to
go through the trenches
and he's got to
dig deep and he's
got to win this time, right?
The odds are
stacked against him,
and there's only one fighter on
that roster that can sell out
that arena within three weeks
lead up time that you've got left.
And that's Reiss, right?
And Max, just like you, I'm just trying
to do my job, just like you are, right?
That's all we can do, right?
So what do you say?
Your 30 seconds are up.
Hey, man.
How you doing?
Nice to see you, too.
Pleasure, as always.
Hey, thanks
for having me on.
Yeah.
Thanks for making the time.
Sure.
So, Max, it's always
interesting to say the least
when you come in the studio.
Tell me, what's the
latest with Ferguson.
He's injured. He's out of the fight.
What's going on?
Yeah, well, it's a drag.
It's too bad, but the
MRI results came back.
And, I mean, Ferguson's...
He's out.
He's out of the fight completely, huh?
Yeah, there's no way.
I mean, it's going to be at least
nine months till he could fight again.
He dropped this bombshell.
Your main event is now off.
Yeah.
What does this mean
for the rest of the card?
Well, I mean, come on.
You know this business.
The show must go on, right?
Right, right.
So you have an opponent in
mind for Randy Stone, then?
Uh, yeah.
Yes.
Yes. Yes.
Yes, I do.
In just three weeks' time,
Randy Stone will be fighting...
Come on.
Randy Stone is going to
be fighting Reiss Gibbons.
Are you
fucking shitting me?
I just cost myself
advertising revenue.
Shit.
Woo!
Fuck.
I need to stop talking here.
That's big fucking news.
First, you drop
that Reiss is coming
out of retirement,
moving to heavyweight,
and now I'm speechless.
Your spee...
Well, that is a first.
What are you doing
here, Hollywood?
Yeah, I deserve that.
I've been offered the
Randy Stone rematch.
Yeah, I heard.
Everyone's counting
me out against him.
Everyone.
What do you think?
Now you care what I think?
I think you shouldn't have
taken the Nightmare fight.
I know.
I hated watching that fight.
You broke my heart, Reiss.
I know I did, Marcus.
But I need to know.
Do you think I can take him?
You cut one corner, pull
one Hollywood bullshit move,
I'll kick your ass myself.
You understand that?
You can beat him
on the ground.
He hasn't been tested there.
You need to take him
into deep waters.
If you want to win
this fight, Reiss,
you need to make it
a technical fight.
I'm feeling
good about myself.
I'm feeling good about
this charitable thing
I'm doing, giving this
broke son of a bitch
another chance at glory.
You can talk about
your being charitable,
but that's just talk.
That's all you have
for this fight.
I can grapple, I can strike,
I can take you to the ground.
I'll beat you at
everything, all right?
I'll beat you on the ground.
I'll beat you on the feet.
I'll beat you in wrestling.
I'll beat you in jujitsu.
I'll beat you in
chess, checkers,
a fucking spelling bee.
I'm better than you, Reiss.
No more flukes.
No more jokes.
I'm stepping in there serious.
I'm ready to throw down.
I'm going to bring
that whole toolbox,
and I'm gonna use it on you.
Come fight night, I'm going to
show you, man, the real Reiss.
You know, I know what
I did wrong last time.
This time I'm gonna go in
there, and I'm gonna make
sure I execute my game plan.
I'm gonna finish it, man.
Technically I knocked
your dick in the dirt.
Technically I'm
the champion now.
I'm the baddest man
in the world now.
This will be the
ugliest fight of your life.
He's stronger than you.
He's meaner than you.
But you have a bigger heart.
You're a martial artist.
Remember the Mitchell fight?
Yeah.
You knocked him out.
Yeah, eventually.
First time we fought
it didn't go so well.
I underestimated him,
overlooked him, kind
of similar to what you did.
Not quite as bad.
Hell, came back, looked at
the films, took it serious.
Like you do this time.
You're better than him,
been doing it longer.
Got more heart.
Show all that out there,
and he can't beat you.
So... You got it, man.
You got this.
And here
we go, the rematch
we've all been waiting for.
Randy Stone, Reiss Gibbons 2.
Only a short time ago,
Reiss he announced
his retirement after that
devastating loss to Nightmare.
But here he is with
another opportunity
to climb the mountain
again and redeem himself.
Everybody is
counting Reiss Gibbons out.
He's coming into this fight
as the clear underdog.
Do you think he can do it?
We'll soon find out, Bobby.
5, 4, 3, 2, 1.
Reiss!
Bouncing back from a
knockout is so tough.
Can Reiss overcome the mental
demons he had to endure when he
got knocked out
by Randy Stone?
This was his
first ever knockout.
He had movie deals.
He had sneaker deals.
He had his own mouth guard.
And in one night, one punch,
one man took it all away... Randy Stone.
I can't imagine what it
feels like to be Reiss Gibbons
right now as Randy
makes his walk.
Reiss's heart must be
beating out of his chest.
And of course, despite
being a heavyweight,
Randy Stone doesn't have
to worry about making 205.
He can come in at
his natural weight...
Stronger, meaner,
and more ferocious.
What Reiss has gone
through in the past year
is a roller coaster ride.
And the big question,
can he battle back
and reclaim his spot?
We're moments away.
Let's take it to our emcee.
Ladies and gentlemen,
it is now time for our main event.
The moment you've
all been waiting for,
live from London, England!
And brought to you by Lex.
Are you ready
for a new legend?
This fight is scheduled
for five five-minute rounds
for the vacant Heavyweight
Legends Champion of the World.
Introducing first, he
hails from London, England,
weighing in at 217
pounds, Reiss Gibbons.
His opponent comes to
us via Cincinnati, Ohio.
Weighing in at 235
pounds, the reigning,
the defending Light
Heavyweight Legends Champion
of the World, Randy Stone.
Here we go.
No more waiting.
I cannot believe the
moment has finally arrived.
The bad blood, the trash talk, the tension
so thick you can cut it with a knife...
Okay, gentlemen.
We went over the rules
in the locker room.
Any questions from
the challenger?
Champion, any questions?
Touch gloves if you want.
Back to your corners.
Come on, show him!
Come on, Reiss.
We are ready for war.
Fight.
And Reiss springs at
him and immediately presses
Randy Stone against the cage.
He's a man
on a mission.
What, are you gonna
hump my leg all night?
Reiss is wasting
no time in there.
We just don't know if we'll
see the champion from the past.
Reiss is firing off
some great punches.
Reiss is
really moving well.
He's displaying
great head movement.
He's looking really confident.
And Reiss lands
a vicious takedown.
There you go.
And immediately
passes to side control.
Randy is so strong.
He gets up right away.
That's it, Reiss.
Come on!
Reiss is showing a much
improved arsenal of strikes.
But Randy counters with a great Superman
punch, forcing Reiss to back up.
Get off the cage!
And Randy tosses
Reiss to the ground.
He's just so powerful.
Randy's
raining down punches.
Reiss is throwing up
one submission attempt
after another,
but to no avail.
Reiss, come on!
Randy shrugs them
off like they were nothing.
Signature
Danny Thicket.
Fight mean, and make them pay.
Well, that's the
way it's looking right now.
It may not be an issue if
he has to conserve himself.
Come on.
Cover up.
Reiss!
Reiss looks hurt.
Randy looks like he may
have torn something when
he opened up Reiss's guard.
Randy just won't stop.
He smells blood, and he's
going after him, Bobby.
Come on.
Get off the bottom.
Don't stay down there.
No mercy.
And Randy Stone is the
last guy you want on top of you
when you're not feeling well.
It looks like something went
really wrong when Reiss tried
to lock in
that triangle choke.
We worked on this.
Randy has such
vicious knees and elbows.
Come on, Reiss.
Get off of there.
You gotta get off there.
And Reiss just looks
completely manhandled.
Reiss tries to escape.
Randy locks him into
a guillotine choke.
It looks tight.
It looks really tight.
Hold on.
This might
end the first round.
And he's reaching for
a different position.
He transitions to
a bulldog choke.
I don't think he
can do anything.
20 seconds left.
Come on.
Randy is pressing
down on the back of his neck.
That's 235 pounds on the
back of Reiss's neck.
With the right amount of
pressure, he could snap his neck.
Don't tap.
Don't you tap.
Reiss is holding
on for dear life.
I don't know how he's not
unconscious right now.
TJ Steele is peering in.
It looks like he's
trying to end this fight.
Reiss is in
a lot of trouble.
He does not look like he's
gonna get out of this.
TJ Steele might
end this fight right now.
Reiss is about to
go unconscious.
I can't believe
he's still holding on.
And saved by the horn.
I can't believe he
survived that round.
Look at him. Reiss is
clearly shaken by that.
He's not even sure
what corner to go to.
He doesn't even
know where he's at.
He is completely out of it.
And look at
the way he's walking.
Something is clearly
wrong with Reiss' leg.
Randy is basically
mocking him.
Take a deep breath.
Deep breaths, buddy. Talk to me.
What's going on?
Fuck, Marcus, man.
I've torn my groin.
Can you fight?
Should I stop it?
No, don't fucking stop it.
All right.
Forget about your groin
and start thinking
how you're gonna
beat this guy.
See him go to
the wrong quarter?
He went to the wrong
fucking corner.
The guy is lost.
The guy has already lost.
You keep those take-downs clean.
Use your weight.
John,
you got anything for him?
Those strikes,
they're nice and clean.
Keep working those
combinations like we worked on.
Finish this round right,
we'll be drinking margaritas in an hour.
Deep breath.
Deep breath. Calm down.
Come on.
You've done this a long...
You've done this a long time.
You can do this.
Here we go.
Round two.
Reiss is limping
off the stall.
You can just see
by the look on his face
that he's in agony.
He's trying his best not to
show it, but Reiss is in pain.
And Stone knows it.
Stone is a natural finisher,
and I guarantee you,
he's going to look to end
this fight in this round.
Reiss has just opened
a cut over Randy's eye.
There is no
quit in Reiss Gibbons.
Pain or no pain,
he's here to fight.
Come on.
Move.
Reiss, come on.
And Randy lifts Reiss up
as if he was a bag of feathers.
Look at the power of Randy!
He's beating him
into submission.
This is that famous
mean streak that he was known
for in the world of wrestling.
Get out of this, Reiss.
Reiss, get out of it. Reiss, get out of it.
Get off the cage!
He's throwing elbows.
He's throwing punches and knees.
And Randy has just
headbutted Reiss.
Oh, that is so disappointing.
It looks like
he just got a little
too overzealous in there with all
the adrenaline and excitement.
Have some class.
He will definitely get
a point deducted for that.
As he should, Jimmy.
And the doctor has come
in to inspect Reiss's eye.
It does not look good.
You can see
I'm fighting.
- Straight ahead.
- I'm fighting.
I can fight.
Okay.
I don't know if you can continue.
I can.
I don't know...
Your left eye is
nearly completely shut.
I can see.
This is not looking good.
Okay, how many fingers?
Three.
Yeah, see, you hesitated.
No, I'm fine.
Please, please.
Please, I can continue.
- I really don't know.
- Please.
Please.
Yeah, yeah.
I'm okay.
Don't stop it.
I can fight.
Ref. REISS: Please,
I'm begging you.
Let me continue.
I can.
Okay.
Well, they're
letting him fight.
This is a
little surprising.
I know Reiss has a huge heart,
but I've never seen an eye
that badly swollen.
Surely his vision is going
to be impaired right now.
Reiss looks
out of breath.
I'm sure
he'll struggle to see.
I'm assuming the
doctors and the ref
will be keeping a
close eye on him
as he goes to continue
into the round.
Come on, bitch.
You motherfucker.
Cover!
Cover up!
And Randy comes
out with heavy hands.
He wants to end this fight.
Reiss is sitting there
like a punching bag right now.
Reiss is holding
on for dear life.
Come on.
He's got him
against the cage,
and he's hitting
him over and over.
I have never seen one
man take such a beating.
Randy is just so
mean with his strikes.
And the horn.
What a fight, Jimmy.
What a fight.
I need a finish.
His groin is ripped.
His eye is blind.
Take him down.
Finish him.
Count him out.
It's time to
send this guy home.
I'm gonna take his head off.
I'm still not free of him.
We're gonna have
to stop it, bro.
No.
No, don't stop it, man.
I can't put you
out there blind.
You got nothing left to prove.
Please.
Yeah?
All right.
He's the one in the
middle, all right?
Third round.
And this is shaping up to be
the fight of the century, easily
the most exciting fight to have
ever taken place in the Legends
cage with two of
its biggest stars,
Reiss Gibbons and Randy Stone.
I can
guarantee you this.
No matter how this fight
goes, these two men
will never be the same.
Show me something, Reiss.
Come on.
You gotta move, Reiss.
Get out of there.
Trip him up.
Look at the blood
on both their faces.
Randy is
taunting Reiss in there,
bouncing around, using feints.
He knows that Reiss's vision
is bound to be affected.
You got this, Reiss.
Send him home.
Reiss is just
flailing, throwing
his arms up with little
success, just grabbing air.
This is
just getting messy.
Reiss looks like
he's out on his feet.
It's clear he
can't see in there.
They need to stop this fight.
If you don't show me something,
I gotta throw in the towel.
Amazing how Reiss
is still hanging on.
It looks like Reiss
is trying to draw him in.
Reiss has just locked
in a guillotine choke.
It looks tight, Bobby.
Get him, Reiss.
Randy's trying to get
out, but it's really tight.
Come on, Randy.
Let's go. Let's go.
Work the head.
Danny Thicket is
shouting instructions.
He's trying to get out, but
Reiss is locking him in.
This is the
first time we have ever
seen Randy Stone in trouble.
And Randy lifts Reiss
up and above his head.
Just look at the power!
What Randy Stone
needs to do is put Reiss down
and then roll out in order
to get out of this position.
There you go, Reiss.
Randy rolls out.
But Reiss transitions
to a rear naked choke.
That's it.
He's got it locked in.
And Reiss is
squeezing for dear life.
Come on!
You gotta tap!
Hold him tight. Come on.
Squeeze harder.
Some room!
Make some room, Randy.
Come on.
You can do this!
Go, go, go, go, go, go!
Don't tap out, Randy.
Reiss is squeezing,
and Randy Stone is really
struggling to fight the hands.
He's going.
He's out. He's out.
I can't believe it!
Yes!
What you have
just seen is greatness,
and his name is Reiss Gibbons.
Reiss has come back to
win the heavyweight title!
Unbelievable, Bobby!
Of Legends!
I can't believe it!
It's never
been done before.
This is the most amazing fight
in the history of Legends,
probably in the history
of Mixed Martial Arts.
Coming back from the
depths of despair,
from two devastating
losses in a row,
coming back from retirement,
coming back from the lowest
point in his career to rise up
and claim the most prestigious
prize in our sport against
arguably the toughest
man on this planet.
It's a fairy tale, Jimmy.
I cannot believe
what I've just seen.
You did it!
I'm so proud of you.
I'm so proud of you, brother.
Congratulations,
Reiss Gibbons.
It's been a pleasure and an
honor to call your fight.
Ladies and
gentlemen, our referee
TJ Steele has stopped this
fight in the third round,
declaring the winner by rear
naked choke, your winner
and new Heavyweight Legends
Champion of the World, the one,
the only, Reiss Gibbons!
I thought you were
going to give up.
Not this time.
You're a tough son
of a bitch after all.
You owe me a
rematch and a drink.
I made your ass famous.
All right.
Let's do it.
Make it two drinks.
I've got you.
Three drinks.
All right.
Marcus, that's a hell of a fighter
you built. No quit in that boy.
Congratulations.
Thank you, man.
Your boy is good.
Thank you.
We have work to do.
The biggest... The
biggest event ever.
I mean, the live
gate was ridiculous.
Over 30,000 people.
We had to turn people away.
Pay-per-view is out of this...
I mean, it's off the charts.
It's off the charts.
I mean, this was the most exciting
fight I've ever seen in my life.
The fans were going crazy.
I mean, it didn't look so
good for Reiss for a while,
but, I mean, you
gotta hand it to him.
He's a champ.
That guy is a
champ, coming back.
Oh, the eye is going to
be fine.
I mean, yeah, it's bad.
Did you see the fight?
The fight was insane.
But you know, Reiss...
I have to say, Reiss bounces
back like nobody you've
ever seen in this business.
I mean, he'll probably
end up getting,
you know, eye patch
sponsors from this thing.
That's all we know.
Don't worry about Reiss.
He's a six-time
champ now, right?
I mean, he's our guy.
We started Legends with him.
I'm so proud of him.
I was nervous.
I'll be honest, I was
nervous for a little bit.
It wasn't looking good.
But, you know, Reiss
has got so much heart.
And he's a beautiful spirit.
He's the sort of fighter...
He loves to fight,
but of all a
sudden, you know, he
could turn around and go become
a professor or something.
I don't know.
He could do something else.
I mean, the one who's
off the chart is Randy.
I mean, that guy...
I mean, that guy is
in an animal, right?
I mean, he could do no wrong.
You have no idea the
sponsors this guy is getting.
I mean, we're
talking book deals.
We're talking
restaurant deals.
speaking engagements.
I mean, he's now the star...
We just found out tonight.
Am I allowed to say?
All right.
I'm allowed to say this.
He's gonna be the
new Ax Man, right?
From the guys who brought
you the Chainsaw trilogy,
he's the new
Ax Man coming out.
Amazing.
He's opening up... He
just got this gig today.
I mean, it doesn't matter.
It doesn't matter
if this guy loses.
He's now going to
be the spokesman
of the Cult of Raw Aggression.
I don't know if
you've heard about it.
It's this big... You know,
big motivational speaker.
And now we're going to
tie it...
Legends, we're going to tie this
into his new restaurant, Raw.
You know, I think before
when he was a pro wrestler,
he had that restaurant, Meat,
when he was a huge meat eater,
and it was raw meat,
any kind of meat.
But now I don't know.
He's got this new
whole thing going on.
He's gone vegan,
and that's where
he says a lot of
his stuff's coming...
So now Raw is featuring,
like, vegan sausages
and anything raw.
And he gets his power.
So we're going to tie that
in the Raw Aggression
into the Raw restaurants,
the Legends thing.
We're packaging it.
You can get it in the stores.
You can get it anywhere.
It's pretty awesome.
And what it
specializes in beets...
Like, beet juice,
so you could eat it,
and it looks like blood.
And Randy sells
the shit out of it.
Oh, man.
He's got everything...
Diapers, diaper sponsors.
You know, you can
never be too strong.
People love this guy.
It doesn't matter if he wins or loses.
He's an animal.
They love him.
Oh, yeah.
I mean, of all people,
Randy...
I mean, listen.
He just got this
huge book deal also.
It's going to be a big thing.
It's those
motivational things.
He's really big on that
chain, but he's wrestling
with your inner aggro.
He talks, and people
write it down.
He's got pictures.
I mean, he's a lot different.
He's kind of a
sensitive guy, really.
I mean, you would
never believe it,
but I think the whole raw
thing has shifted him.
Subtitles by explosiveskull
www.OpenSubtitles.org