BETA FILM presents
In 972, the Fatimids founded Al-Azhar,
to make it a center for Islamic knowledge.
The Great Imam
is the highest authority in Sunni Islam.
For centuries the rulers of Egypt
have tried to control Al-Azhar.
So far they have not succeeded.
Oh God...
Come on, wake up!
Good day!
It's for you.
Open it.
You have been accepted
to Al-Azhar University.
Congratulations!
Come on!
God has blessed you with a gift.
You used to come here every day to read
by yourself.
Al-Azhar is the greatest
Islamic institution in the world.
And they chose you.
Come on!
Yes, father?
Let me feel your hand.
You smell like tobacco.
All three of you, put your hands up!
What are you doing?
Hush, you're going to wake up dad.
What is this?
I received a scholarship.
- Are you kidding?
For Cairo?
-Yes.
What will you say to dad?
I don't know.
You know what he is like.
He will find out.
What do you want? Go to sleep!
God gave you a brain
that thinks more than necessary.
You are like your mother.
She was always curious, peace be upon her.
She sent you to school
so that you don't become
a fisherman like me!
I had your brother read the letter to me.
If God wants you to go to Cairo,
no one should stand in the way
of His plans.
Not even your father.
Have a good trip!
Thank you.
I will miss you.
Take care of yourself, Adam.
Will you take care of dad?
Do you promise?
Look at me.
You know how much I love you.
Yes, father.
Don't forget where you came from.
- No, Dad.
Good bye.
Goodbye, father.
Oh! Al-Azhar!
This is the elite!
May God bless you with knowledge!
What is your name?
- Adam, sir.
My God, what a nice name!
If God wills, after your studies,
you will become Sheikh Adam!
Here you are.
Goodbye.
tUp to The third floor, the corridor
on the right, the district office.
Thank you.
- Good luck!
Excuse me.
Hello.
Isn't this my place?
No, this is mine.
Is that so?
Is there anyone here?
Do you snore?
- No.
Are you sure?
- Yes.
Then it is free.
Are you new here?
Yes, I just arrived.
Welcome.
Can you please turn off the light?
This life is just a game
fun
competition for material wealth.
Like the rain
making the grass happy to grow,
Then it fades
it will finally turn yellow
and it will turn to dust and rubbish.
The afterlife is eternal. And there
Only God's forgiveness matters.
What are you doing?
I am creating a new brand of cigarettes.
My own brand.
Listen, Adam.
It doesn't matter who you are,
but who you want to be.
We're running late.
Calm down, Sardine.
God has rewarded you with a sure hand.
You don't tremble.
In the name of the merciful God,
Al-Azhar is the guiding light
of the Islamic world.
And on the day
when you will leave Al-Azhar
and you will return to your villages,
and you will become bearers
of this knowledge.
Are you all right, Sheikh?
Out of the way!
We need a doctor!
The Grand Imam is in a critical condition.
What does he say?
Let's pray for him.
We wish him a speedy recovery!
Good day. I have a meeting
with Your Excellency
Okay, sir. You may go there.
Open the barrier.
Who will manage the situation?
Colonel Ibrahim, sir.
Please.
As you know
the Great Imam died yesterday.
May he rest in peace.
Now we need
the best possible new Imam.
Of course, sir.
Who are our insiders?
We have eyes and ears,
but it's very delicate.
Really difficult.
Those idiots changed the constitution.
From now on the grand imam is appointed for life.
It is not a matter of issuing
some religious recommendations.
The choice of the next Great Imam
is a matter of national security.
No one should hold a post for life,
except our president!
We don't want that!
It won't be good to have two pharaoh's
in the country
Sheikh Durrani is close
to the Muslim Brotherhood.
He supports terrorists!
Sheikh Negm, the blind,
one of the most popular
imams in Egypt.
Is not connected to any group.
The President
wants Beblavi.
His views coincide with
those of the president.
Make sure he is chosen.
Consider the task accomplished.
Do you have a prayer rug?
Ahmed, bring the general a prayer rug!
Stay away until they choose
the new grand imam.
Until they choose you.
Please!
Don't get involved.
Who does the council want?
The majority wants the Blind Sheikh.
We want another.
I was exposed. You must let me go.
Do you know what the sentence
is for traitors?
Death.
Find me new "angel".
An unattached Freshman.
Don't worry.
Close your eyes
to see the truth.
Need is blind
until she becomes conscious.
And freedom is a a condition
of the conscience.
Do you know who said this?
A communist Jewish philosopher
called Marx.
He also said that religion
is proof of the limitation of man
in the face of what he cannot understand.
Life is not a game.
Hello
Where are you from?
From Manzala.
Fisherman?
I am Sheikh Negm's assistant.
If you need help...
Thank you.
Tell me which doctrine does
Sheikh Negm follow?
The truth.
Which truth?
The truth of Sheikh Negm.
Do you want to pray?
Have you been to the town yet?
I will go tonight.
Do you want to come with me?
Why not.
This is halal.
Drink!
What is the matter?
Come.
Your soul is still pure.
What?
But every single moment in this
place will corrupt it.
Wait for me here.
This morning
One of our students was found dead.
Colonel Ibrahim is here,
to find out what happened.
May God help him.
To discover the truth.
Excuse me for intruding on such
a delicate moment.
Maybe we can pause our investigation
until a new Grand Imam is elected.
Can you tell me when this
will take place?
The question is purely technical.
We have our procedures and we follow them.
May God give you the strength.
Who was his supervisor?
He was an assistant in my department.
What else can you tell me about him?
Nothing you don't already know.
Why is State Security investigating this?
The deceased has foreign citizenship.
President Nasser tried to turn Al-Azhar
into a state institution.
Sadat tried to corrupt it.
And Mrs. Suzanne Mubarak tried
to change the laws of God,
to please the Americans
and the women around her.
So tell us, Colonel,
What are your instructions?
I just want to know why the boy is dead.
Osama.
Where are you from?
From Alexandria.
Ahmed of Giza.
Your name?
Adam Taha.
Where are you from Adam?
- From Manzala.
A fisherman?
- Yes.
You are free to go there.
You forgot the feet.
After sunset, go out through
the exit that Zizo showed you.
Then take a minibus to the center.
Get off at Mohandessin
The Arab League road.
There is an American cafe there.
I'll meet you there.
Order something
and sit at a table next to me.
Take out your phone
like you're talking to someone.
Did you order something?
I'm not hungry, sir.
If you don't order, they'll kick you out.
I have no money.
Order a cinnamon latte and
a brownies with cream.
Latte with cinnamon
and a brownie with cream.
Keep the money for the next time.
Don't you have relatives in Cairo?
I don't have any.
Tell me what happened?
On the way back from the mosque
they were waiting for us.
Who?
Men with knives.
Officially, your friend died
in an accident.
But as you saw, he was killed.
We will find out who did it.
And they will pay for it.
We want you to help us.
Sir, all I know...
Listen, Adam
I only ask you to attend the dawn prayer.
What shall I pray?
Praying and observing who else is praying.
Remember their faces, learn their names.
Adam? - Yes it's me.
Someone asked me to do something.
I am not sure if this
is acceptable or a sin.
A right is a right, a sin is a sin.
God will guide you.
Prayer is better than sleep.
God is great. There is no other God.
Straight line, upright posture.
No distance between you.
We will all die, my children.
Who complains
of life's accidents and fate,
he will weaken his faith.
Now go.
Please pray for your brother
and pray to God to have mercy on him
and forgive his sins.
Do you have the names?
- No.
Your father has gallstones.
That's why he suffers.
If left untreated, he will die.
We have a hospital in Dakhleya.
I will arrange the operation.
He won't know you helped him.
We do not forget those who work for us.
But I have to ask you one thing.
Don't call your village imam anymore.
And I want you to know who prays
at dawn in the mosque.
Sharia is not Islamic law.
It is rather a divine right.
Fiqh is the human interpretation
of this right.
There are five principles in Sharia:
care for religion, life, material goods
generation and reason.
Recite!
Bro...
I have a study group for those who wish
to improve their recitation.
You are welcome.
Aslam.
Asfur.
Harun.
Nazim.
God bless you!
Bravo.
For you, brother.
He sings, Sheikh!
Leave it.
He is new here.
He doesn't know that we don't sing here.
It is forbidden to sing in the Koran.
STATE SECURITY
Come in!
Honorable Sheikh!
Come in, sir
I'm listening.
I have come to confess.
Confession?
I killed him.
I can't believe it what you say.
Sit down, please.
- Why?
Because I'm blind?
No, but you have a high position.
Do you have another suspect?
No, but we are still
investigating the accident.
We? Who are "we"?
Us, the State Security.
Who do you work for?
For the president?
Correct.
My president is Almighty God.
Very good, Sheikh.
How could you be so reckless?
Recruiting a foreign informant?
And what's more, the assistant
of the Blind Sheikh!
Are you out of your mind?
I never planned for him to die, sir.
Don't worry about me!
I know, every morning in front
of the mirror you say to yourself
Why am I not the boss?
You are older than me.
You've worked here much longer.
Do you know why they didn't promote you?
- No, sir.
But I have a feeling that you know
and are getting ready to tell me.
I swear on my m others grave
if it blows up in our face,
It's your head, not mine!
Clear?
- Yes.
Listen.
You leave me no choice.
Arrest him!
Good day.
Aslam Aslan, Nazim bin Saïd...
Nazim bin Saïd?
Sounds like a foreign name.
He is from Algeria.
I hear your father's surgery went well.
I am very grateful to you.
You don't need to thank me, Adam.
Your work is important to us.
I will tell you a secret.
We believe that the Muslim Brotherhood
infiltrated Al-Azhar.
And they murdered your friend.
Do you know this book?
This is a guide to modern jihad.
But it is forbidden, sir.
Let Nazim see you with it.
Don't be afraid.
How are you?
- Okay.
The infidels who are in power
They treat true Muslims as terrorists.
We invite you to tea with us.
Thank you.
Do you like to read forbidden books?
Adam, we are like family here.
You can trust us.
Not the books condemned by God
or idolatrous books.
But the books that scare tyrants
and the kings.
It is time for every Muslim
to make a choice.
Our children are being killed in Palestine.
In Syria and Iraq, the infidels rape our women.
China built concentration camps
for extermination of the Muslims.
Yet our leaders turn a blind eye
and take their money.
In Burma they kill us.
And what does the so-called
"civilized" world say?
They give the Nobel Peace Prize
to the leader of the criminal gangs
that kill us.
There is no need to look further.
Al-Azhar!
The guiding ray of Islam in the world.
What does Al-Azhar say about all this?
Nothing.
And speaking of that,
Do you know what happened
to the Blind Sheikh?
It seems he is sick.
State security arrested him.
They will keep him until the Grand Imam
they want is elected.
They think they can scare the Council
and for him to choose
their puppet candidate.
But they will fail.
The corrupt leaders
of this country
try to prevent God's will.
And they have put snakes
to penetrate among us.
Your friend Zizo.
Some say I killed him.
Is that possible?
Can you believe that, my brothers?
Do you know what I think?
He was killed by State Security.
Brother.
Want to do more than just lectures?
- Yes.
Soliman thinks you have arrested
the Blind Sheikh,
to force the Council to select
your candidate.
And what about it?
He says you will fail, sir.
Am I going to fail?
That's what he said, sir.
You said it, Adam.
No, he said it, not me.
He doesn't trust you. He's using you
as a courier.
You have to earn his trust.
- How?
Do you share his views?
I'm taking that as a yes
Does it matter what I believe, sir?
It changes everything. For him.
Like Satan
penetrating pious minds?
Welcome to the dark side.
Shut up.
"The establishment of the kingdom of God
on earth, the destruction of human,
the struggle with the power of the usurpers
and its return to God,
the supremacy of divine law alone,
the abolition of human laws
and to all those who do not follow
the instructions..."
Raed, Raed, I beg you!
Milestones on the Road to Islam
by Sayyid Qutb.
What are you looking at?
Why are you hanging around
Souleyman and his gang?
This is a study group.
- A group of which he is the leader.
You know they hate me, right?
You have no idea!
Not a word about the book!
- I will say nothing.
Will you take part in the recitation
competition on Friday?
Against your new friends.
Are you confident?
- Yes always.
Don't come crying to me
when you lose on Friday.
Come on, let's go.
Why don't you like Souleyman?
It's not that, but I....
Because of how he behaves with
your friend Raed?
He is not my friend, sir.
Is that so?
- No.
Does he suspect you?
Don't worry.
I'll shut him up.
- No.
Why are you afraid of him?
He's not your friend, is he?
Tariq Ibn Ziyad burned his boats
when he arrived in Spain.
He said to his men: "The sea is behind us,
the enemy is before us."
Do I have to burn your father's
boat to motivate you?
Non.
Gain Souleyman's trust.
How is dad?
Has anyone visited the house?
Nobody?
Sorry, I can't talk anymore.
I miss you.
Stop.
Stop it, Asfur.
Forget "they persisted."
They persevered and looked proud.
And now the two finalists remain!
The winner is Raed Abdelmajid!
Congratulations, son!
What do you want?
Dirty balance!
- What have I done?
Is it because I won?
What is this?
They are not mine, I swear.
Traitor!
Adam...
What mess have you gotten yourself into?
You did the right thing, brother.
God punishes the unbelievers.
God bless you.
Bravo.
Adam...
Who gave you "Milestones on the Road to Islam"?
You know this book is forbidden.
- Yes.
Who gave you your copy?
- My uncle.
He sells books.
Seriously?
- Yes.
He sells books, God bless him.
Call hin.
Right away ?
Yes, right away.
Alright.
I have no credit.
Please.
Put it on speaker.
Hello?
Hello uncle, how are you?
Hi Adam, how are you?
We miss you.
I'm fine, thank God.
I just wanted....
to thank you.
About the book you gave me.
What? I do not understand.
The book I took from you.
The book that...
Don't you remember?
I really don't understand Adam.
Is there a problem?
No, uncle.
S.O.S
Who are you writing to?
Give me your phone.
Watch him.
Get out!
Who do you work for?
I don't understand.
Damn stairs!
Listen, Adam.
How many meters doy ou think  it is
to the ground?
Twelve.... Maybe 13.
Your body will be unrecognizable.
Who do you take orders from, boy?
Sheikh Durrani, Sir!
Are you sure you want to play
this game with me?
I carry out orders that I receive
over the phone.
You are resigning today.
And you will tell Sheikh Durrani
that Adam will replace you.
Then you tell the university that you
want to pursue something else.
Tourism, for example.
I hear he's picking up speed again.
The sphinx smiles again.
Yes, as you wish sir.
Coffee.
Can you make coffee?
Today my assistant resigned.
He was like the son I never had.
He recommended you as my deputy.
I told you not to worry.
Go to the pharmacy.
Get me paracetamol for children.
And a tooth brush for babies.
It's for the child.
- Of course.
Congratulations.
It's for my son's son, idiot!
I'm a grandfather.
Congratulations on your new job.
How are you?
Do you already have a girlfriend?
Was there anything else, sir?
Are you being smart?
Answer me!
No, sir.
Youthink you are better than the others?
Do you think you have a gift or so?
Is that why you got this scholarship?
You are nothing!
Have you ever wondered why we are
looking for people like you?
We helped you so you could help us.
Maybe your friend.
The village imam helped us find you.
No, you are not better than others.
I took a big risk to save your skin.
Give me something.
Whatever.
Today he asked me to buy baby things
for the son of his son.
And then ?
He has no son.
I want you to go downtown tonight.
I want McDonald's.
Everyone says the meat in their
burgers is halal.
Get me two Big Macs
with fries and lots of ketchup.
If someone sees you, say they are for you.
He just wants me to buy him McDonald's.
I will drive you.
Let's go.
We just passed McDonald's.
Sir...
Good evening. Colonel
Ibrahim, I called you.
Get in, Colonel.
Please.
Welcome. Come in.
Come to the living room.
Welcome.
Um Reem is Sheikh Durrani's housekeeper.
Sit down.
May God protect him, he is a man of God,
he gives us everything we need.
What can I get you?
We will not rest.
- Hibiscus or Pepsi?
It won't be long.
- Good.
Here, sir.
There, sir.
How are you, Rim?
My name is Ibrahim.
Can I hold it?
His diapers need to be changed.
You are very cute!
God bless him!
What a beautiful baby!
We need to talk to your daughter.
I am going to do the laundry.
God bless you.
Who is the father, Rim?
Please don't ask me that!
Don't be afraid.
Nobody will hurt you.
Sheikh Durrani is a great man.
He is like a father to me,
I have everything.
It's my fault.
Will they take it from me?
Listen, Rim.
If you keep quiet,
no one will take it.
Do you understand?
Let's go.
Goodbye, Rim.
What's up?
It's not possible, what she said.
How can she be sure that Durrani
is the father?
He took her virginity.
How can you be sure?
Thanks to you.
You discovered his secret.
After seeing you, I did some research.
I found you were right.
Sheikh Durrani has no son.
That's right, there are only girls.
He has secretly married Rim.
He bought her an apartment.
Do you think he did it out of kindness?
Why are you telling me all this?
You make sure Durrani doesn't become
the next Grand Imam.
Just a moment.
This world is in decline.
The signs of the Last Judgment are visible.
Ignorance of religion has spread,
the denial of religious precepts
and attacks on the Prophet's way of life.
The spread of obscenity among us,
wear and tear and bank interest
alcohol consumption and entertainment...
The House of Islam has caught
fire and is burning!
The Muslim brotherhood
Salafists...
ISIS...
They all aim to burn the home
of Islam to the ground.
And women appear
purely naked on the streets.
And the people have more trust
in the hypocrites than
in the true believers,
who are accused of lying
and criticism of customs!
Good night.
- You too.
Come in!
Good evening, respected Sheikh.
Aren't you Sheikh Durrani's
new assistant?
I have information that would interest you.
I don't like gossip, boy.
He got a girl pregnant.
A girl the age of his children,
in sin.
The next Great Imam - father
of an illegitimate child?
If what you say is true,
this will destroy Al-Azhar's reputation.
I refuse to accuse Sheikh Durrani.
I will do the accusation, sir.
You?
But who are you? Who will listen to you?
He would listen to me.
Who do you work for?
For Sheikh Durrani, sir.
Sheikh Durrani.
Good evening.
Damn it!
What is this mess ? I had you
told not to be smart.
Zizo was your informant, wasn't he?
That's why he's dead.
He had him killed.
Did you kill him?
Tariq Ibn Ziyad never burned boats.
This is a myth propagated by his enemies.
Actually, he had no boats.
He borrowed them from
a Spanish nobleman.
His men could not have won
if they were afraid.
They fought because they
believed in victory.
I want guarantees.
Of course.
I guarantee that if you fail,
You'll wish what happened
to Zizo happens to you.
Honorable Sheikh.
You are next in line for the post
of grand imam.
Some don't want that to happen.
Why are you taking the blame
for the accident?
Your president..
The President of the Republic
he would announce himself as the next
Great Imam if he could.
Zizo was your informant, wasn't he?
It wasn't an accident.
On Judgment Day
the killer will carry his victim
on his back forever.
19TH INTERNATIONAL ISLAMIC FORUM
We follow the procedure.
We are not in a hurry.
Can you tell us if Sheikh Negm
is still alive?
Internet rumors claim that
State Security arrested him,
to prevent him from becoming elected
as the next Great Imam.
Only rumours!
This is a religious conference.
Religious conference!
Rumors have no place here.
What is your question?
I have a question about secret marriage.
Ask your question.
Suppose a young woman
let's say she is called Rim
has a child from a married man
with an impeccable reputation
my question is, can we have trust
in a man who has a secret marriage
and also a child
that his legal family doesn't know about?
What will be the legal judgement
for such a person?
Excellent question.
Who on the Council wants to answer him?
Sheikh Durrani?
Do you want to answer?
Okay.
Sheikh Abdel Kader
has written extensively
on the clandestine marriage.
Thank you, Sheikh.
It depends on the circumstances.
First of all:
Did the girl's guardian approve
of the marriage?
Secondly:
Does the man have the resources
to get married
in some other way than seceretely?
Third:
did they get married
before or after
the conception of the child?
Some people
in the parliament they want..
Sheikh Omar Al-Beblawi.
Blessed be the newly elected.
Thank God!
In reality it's not really about me.
This goes much further.
The main thing is that religion
and the state work side by side.
What concerns Al-Azhar
concerns the state.
And vice versa.
Holy water from Zamzam. May we drink
it together in Mecca.
I see a very bright future for you.
Come in.
Put the box on the floor.
Greet Major General Sobhi, head
of State Security.
Adam is a model of the ideal student.
I do my best, sir.
Honorable Sheikh, I will unpack
the books after your meeting.
No, no, no.
Yet, you don't unpack the books.
Another student will do it.
You will stand behind me
at the prayer next Friday.
OK?
Yes, thanks.
Adam, have we met before?
God created 40 d oublesof everyone, sir.
At the moment
anywhere on the Internet
there are calls for demonstrations
against the government
for greater freedom.
My take on this is,
that the civil war
is something more serious than murder.
Please, sir.
There is no need.
Congratulations sir, congratulations.Greetings, sir.
The president is very pleased.
- Thank God.
What is this?
- The report, sir.
No, it won't work like that, Ibrahim.
The blind sheikh cannot be the murderer.
He is blind!
- But he insisted to admit.
What is he looking for?
- I don't know.
And if we notify general Al Sakran?
No, not worth the trouble.
Is there anything else?
-Yes.
Your "angel".
We don't need him anymore.
Get rid of him.
Sir, that's a bit too much.
Too much?
You know very well
that we don't like to leave traces.
Get him to admit that he killed Zizo.
Then we will hang him.
Bring him to me.
Where is your mother?
- Sleeping.
Did you do your homework?
What are we going to eat when she sleeps?
You accomplished your mission perfectly.
I have come to arrest you.
Will I see my family again?
I don't think so.
We do not decide our destiny.
God chose you.
You chose me.
Leave the university.
Only 3 weeks of classes left.
Go home.
And forget you ever met me.
Major General Sobhi?
Sorry to bother you so late.
My young informant disappeared.
Yes, I assure you.
I only know his first name: Raed.
I know it's unbelievable
but that is how it happened, sir.
Of course, sir.
Very good. Goodbye.
'Sardine, can we meet? Raed"
good evening.
Till tomorrow.
Don't be afraid.
Let's not complicate this.
You killed Zizo.
Understood?
Some think
That they will not talk.
When we pull out their nails.
They still don't talk.
Do you know when they talk?
When we bring their fathers...
to watch the torture.
An ugly sight!
Open it
Is your father at home?
Father!
What's up?
Someone wants to talk to you.
Who?
- I do not know.
Get inside
What do you want, Osman?
- You must come with us.
At this hour?
Okay, enter.
Should I bring food?
No, there is no need.
I found him.
Your "angel".
Calm down.
If only a hair falls from his head,
I will kill you!
He is still alive.
Damn you!
Lord, forgive me.
Damn you, Sobhi!
My brother, I don't understand.
Why do you care about him?
We still need him.
For what?
Is nothing.
You sent your men to kill Zizo!
Why?
He was compromised. There should be
no connection between us.
Why wasn't I notified?
For your own good, fool!
The Blind Sheikh knows that Zizo
was my informant!
He also knows that we killed him!
He confessed to the crime to
Denounce us in public.
We must kill him too.
The Blind Sheikh?
Are you crazy?
You need permission from the
general Al Sakran.
What the hell am I doing here?
Sir, we killed Zizo Albizri.
I told him...
- Enough! Shut up!
Sir, I know this is a politically
sensitive decision.
But the Blind Sheikh forced
us to arrest him
for the murder of Zizo.
Did he force us?
And where is he now?
He is here, sir.
In the building?
May God have mercy on us all!
What if he's gone? Forever!
You want me to become an accomplice
to murder
of one of the country's greatest
religious leaders?
No, sir.
Sir...
The boy helped us choose the Great Imam.
He could convince the Blind Sheikh
to withdraw his confession.
And we will close the investigation
and write it as an accident.
Please let us.
Sit down.
Do you know that the Blind Sheikh
confessed to the murder
of the foreign student?
It wasn't him, sir.
State security killed him, sir.
He Worked for them,
but he wanted to leave.
But why the Blind Sheikh
to confess to a crime he did not commit?
To tell the truth to the whole world
during his trial
He would have turned to the media.
But he knows who controls the media.
Well, could the son of a fisherman
make him change his mind?
Could try sir.
Why would he do it?
Al-Azhar and the state should
never be in conflict.
This could be a civil war.
I need your advice Sheikh.
They forced me to confess to killing Zizo.
And I will be hanged for it.
A true believer is not afraid of death.
I know that.
I am a believer.
But I'm afraid.
I'm afraid for my father.
He will lose his son.
My brothers will lose their brother
like we lost my mother.
If your faith is strong
and your heart is pure, one day
you will meet her in heaven.
And if you confess to a murder
you didn't commit?
Are you going to heaven?
If the intention is to reveal the truth,
the intention is good.
I thought that God created us
to fulfill his wishes.
Not to change them.
I run from the will of
God to fulfill his wishes.
When Omar Ibn Al Khattab was told
that the Prophet Muhammad had died,
he drew his sword.
Whoever will say that Mohammad
is dead, I cut off his nec!
But Abu Bakr replied:
Whoever loves Muhammad
knows that Muhammad is dead.
He who worships God knows
that God is immortal.
Who exactly are you?
I am your student.
You are no longer a student.
You don't need anyone to teach you
your religion.
Tell the people outside
that I withdraw my confession.
Power is a double-edged sword.
He can easily cut your hand.
Welcome home.
- How are you?
I'm fine. What's new?
Hello, Dad.
- Welcome home, son.
If only your mother was here to see you!
You're back!
Congratulations.
Welcome home.
Glory be to God.
Glory be to God..
What did you learn?