Is the dreamer dreaming the dream?
Or is the dream dreaming the dreamer?
Next message.
Hello.
I would like to advertise an ad in your newspaper.
How much does it cost?
We have a few options.
The price depends on the size and location.
A big ad, small, medium, color or black and white.
I see,
I want it to appear for one week starting this friday.
A small black and white ad at the bottom left corner.
I got it.
What's the content of the ad?
Call for Dreams.
Ok.
Anything else?
Yes yes.
Please write,
Looking for dreams,
I might get back to you,
Send me your description of a dream and contact,
Privacy guaranteed.
Not for sexual purposes.
That's all.
Fine.
It will cost 85'000 yen
and it will be ready by tomorrow evening.
All the best.
Thanks.
Call for Dreams.
Please leave your contact and message,
and maybe I'll get back to you.
You have one new message.
I dream of shooting,
Someone.
Four bullets.
Hi. Long time no see.
Come in.
Is it raining?
Yes, its a little rainy.
I'm just making ozoni soup,
Want to eat together? Ill help you.
Rice cake?
Tasty.
Yes.
So,
whats going on with you lately?
Nothing special,
I don't have much work now.
How's health?
Health is good.
You loved to read books once, are you reading now?
I don't have too much time for that now.
I see
Look at the rice cake.
Yes.
Is it true that some people choke to death from it?
Especially old people.
Strange food.
You eat fast.
It still hurts a little.
I could feel when it went off.
You have one new message.
Im walking with my twin sister,
in an airport.
We slowly approach an aircraft.
Someone pushes me.
I fall next to a lady I don't know.
Our skins touch, it makes me shiver.
I keep quiet,
and look at her legs.
Orange nail polish,
and a skull tattoo.
A stewardess starts demonstrating safety instructions.
The plane fills with fog.
My number,
Address,
Akihabara.
5-26
Please come today if possible.
Dream number 972.
Relieved a little bit.
I found interesting facts about the rain.
Feeling nausea and revolt.
Woke up at 5am again.
In the dark silky rain
calling birds but they're not coming.
Darkness makes me nervous.
Looking at my arms, bleeding
bright blood, almost white.
Feeling powerless.
My sight narrows gradually.
I close my eyes.
Ladies and gentlemen I’m your flight attendant today, my name is Eko.
To release your seat belt, press the buckle.
Your seat belt must remain tight in case of tremors.
There are 4 emergency exits,
in the front and back,
and two in the middle.
Pull the life vest from under your seat
pull down the strap,
and blow air through the hose.
In case of lack of oxygen, air masks will drop down.
Stay seated and pull the masks towards you.
Cover your nose and mouth and breath normally.
In order to keep air clean and fresh,
this is a non smoking flight.
Good evening, welcome, how are you?
A little tired.
I was a stewardess today.
Look.
Where do you have Pachinko from? (luck machines)
Oh, from Youtube.
You probably want the small dish.
You're the only one that orders it.
Always been this way?
Yes.
Thanks for waiting, please.
When I was your age,
life was much simpler.
There were only four channels on TV.
Yes.
Today things are not what they seem.
What's that, are you recording?
The tape recorder is like a confession machine.
Every act of recording,
transforms the present into a memory.
I see.
Every copy,
by copying,
the present dissolves into the past.
People want to re-invent themselves differently.
To remember events, not necessarily in the way they happened.
A recording is an opportunity for change.
When will you find something real to do?
There is no ׳real׳ anymore.
You choose to act in a reality of your choice.
It looks empty today.
Yes, a lot of spare time.
Maybe tomorrow will be better.
Have you ever thought what dictates our notion of time?
It's the rhythm of our breath, undoubtedly.
In which dimension could this rhythm disappear?
Which dimension would be revealed?
Excuse me?
Is anyone here?
Call for Dreams.
Please leave your contact and message.
Maybe I'll get back to you.
Call for Dreams.
Please leave your contact and message.
Maybe I'll get back to you.
Call for Dreams.
Please leave your contact and message.
Maybe I'll get back to you.
Call for Dreams.
Please leave your contact and message.
Maybe I'll get back to you.
Call for Dreams.
Please leave your contact and message.
and maybe I'll get back to you.
Call for Dreams.
Please leave your contact and message.
and maybe I'll get back to you.
Call for Dreams.
Please leave your contact and message.
and maybe I'll get back to you.
One new message.
I have two dreams that are somehow connected.
Im in an office arguing with a Japanese lady.
Suddenly I shoot her.
Ill tell you the second dream after you dance.
Ladies and gentlemen my name is..
Excuse me.
Where the boys are,
someone waits for me
A smiling face
a warm embrace
two arms to hold me tenderly
Where the boys are
my true love will be
He's walkin' down some street in town
and I know he's lookin' there for me
In the crowd of a million people I'll find my valentine
And then I'll climb to the highest steeple
and tell the world he's mine
Till he holds me I'll wait impatiently
Where the boys are, where the boys are
Where the boys are, someone waits for me
Till he holds me
I'll wait impatiently
Where the boys are, where the boys are
Where the boys are, someone waits for me
The second dream starts with balconies.
Different types of balconies.
I'm standing on a balcony.
My face is black.
I'm changing faces.
My car strolls into a deserted hotel.
On a summer day.
The song ׳Where The Boys Are׳ by Connie Francis is playing on the radio.
My daughter keeps on hiding from me.
Changing faces.
Her name was Eko.
She was found dead in that deserted hotel.
Just lying there in a ruined game arcade.
I can remember every detail.
What I don't understand,
is why she resembles the Japanese lady from the first dream.
I'm also spreading on the dirty floor.
Wounded.
Time passes like a burning car.
I'm useless.
I can only move an ear.
Do you believe in parallel worlds?
Can such a thing exist?
A reality parallel to this one.
As if we have a copy,
existing in parallel in another world.
Every page has four corners,
every sheet of paper can rip and rejoin differently.
The first sentences that you think of,
will be the ones that define you.
After you write, you rip the paper
and pass it over to me, one by one in separate.
You come and sit down.
A waitress will come to you,
and offer different cocktails.
You will ask for a "White Russian".
It's very important that you ask just for that.
Then make one phone call to this number.
Wait for a red light to blink in my ear.
At 22:22, the location:
The Pink Fish club in Shibuya.
And bring this tape recording.
Next message.
The Pink Fish Club
Its me.
I know.
I invited "Call For Dreams" here,
and got the disk with your video files from the security cam,
Like you wanted.
The Pink Fish Club
Welcome.
Do you want to order something?
What do you recommend?
This is a cocktail bar,
there are many choices, our recommendation,
Earthquake,
Corpse Reviver,
Red Lotus,
Black Russian.
Do you have a White Russian?
Yes we do.
So yes please.
With pleasure.
Nothing seemed to matter anymore.
But then again, everything did.
The moment you look at something, it changes.
You will wake up now and remember nothing.
You can keep the briefcase.
This is what I call sweet dreams.
Floor 44.
I have no idea what you’re up to,
But what you asked for is here.
Inside this briefcase.
Give him.
Are you coming?
Goodbye.
Entry is not allowed here.
How did you get in?
Wait a moment please.
One to four,
Stop.
There is a trespasser.
Tunnel 8 section 3.
Dispatch security urgently.
I'm extremely terrified,
but I've never felt calmer.
People with armor are chasing me.
Lurking in the shadows.
I lay down on the grass,
watching them find me.
And I walk through a huge condensed urban forest,
with swarms of birds,
and a big orange full moon.
There is snow everywhere.
Snow is falling from the night sky.
But its summertime.
Police shalom. Some of the calls are recorded.
If you have an extension number, press it now.
What's up?
Ok, where are you?
On the way, why?
If no one told you,
We've taken the Tokyo guy for more questioning.
What's up?
Ok.
Look,
all he is saying is that he was deported from Tokyo
and that he doesn’t know whats in the briefcase.
He has no prior records or finger prints anywhere.
A ghost.
Keep an eye.
Sit.
Do you know why you're here?
I have no idea.
You don't have an idea ha?
No one explained to you?
Look,
we have nothing on you.
In the briefcase that was with you when you were arrested,
we found a newspaper from 3 days ago in Japanese,
a cassette,
a pepper shredder,
and a disk with video files, where you appear.
Lets start with you telling me your name.
I understand.
Look.
You can play dumb and be silent,
but it won't help you.
So you have two options.
Cooperate with me and we finish quickly and leave.
At least I will.
Or we can have the long and exhausting version.
What's this?
I have no idea.
Then I'll tell you.
Allenbi street in Tel Aviv.
Sunday night.
So?
So where were you last sunday night for example?
Not in Allenbi.
Are you sure?
Do you have witnesses?
We sharpened this frame.
I would be worried if I were you.
Maybe you'll sharpen your memories?
It's not possible, thats the truth.
And I don't have anyway to prove it to you,
only fragments.
Fragments are good.
Hello.
Listen, they called from the lab about the shreds of paper
from the pepper grinder found in his briefcase.
It seems the shreds are from a few notes,
in a woman's handwriting.
Im sending the result to your mobile soon.
Good.
How much longer will this take?
As long as needed.
You will wake up now and remember nothing.
This might sound strange to you,
but this video you are showing me,
where I supposedly shoot a girl,
I dreamed about it.
Yesterday.
Is anyone here?
You don't have a name.
You don't have an ID.
You're nothing.
As far as I'm concerned you don't exist.
And I'm not talking to you.
How can I be talking to someone who doesn't exist?
Right?
You have one new message.
Is the dreamer dreaming the dream?
Or is the dream dreaming the dreamer?
What's the matter?