[pulsing electronic percussion]
[whirring electronic tones]
- I woke up to her
talking to my boyfriend
at, like, three in
the morning, um,
and it was, because
I had called him,
and I, I just, I don't even know
how I dialed his phone
number 'cause I was asleep,
or I was in this state.
And I, he, he doesn't
know what I said to him.
I just started talking
in, in tongues,
and, uh, after I woke up, I
didn't realize what I had done.
[skittering and jangling
electronic effects]
- [Woman On Recording] Why
do you wanna hurt me so much?
Are you sick?
You, you're really strange.
[whirring electronic effects
over ominous ambient music]
I was like, it's like this
is some kind of addiction
that I've gotta break
away from and, uh,
he encouraged it and he
shoulda just left me alone
'cause I don't really
think he cares about me.
[crackling electronic effects
over unsettling ambient music]
And I don't think
he'll ever understand
why I'm the way I, I am,
'cause sometimes I don't
understand it myself.
[muffled sigh]
[eerie and unsettling
ambient electronic music]
I don't even know, I, I
don't think he ever loved me.
I don't think he
meant it at all.
I wish he did.
[beeping electronic tones
over shuddering ambient music]
I just wanna know.
[eerie and unsettling ambient
music with shuddering rhythm]
[unsettling melodic tones
over whirring ambient music]
- [Reporter] US military has
issued four million dollars
in grants to
university researchers
to study ways to read
people's thoughts,
but critics say such
mind reading technology
could be used during
interrogations.
The project's a corroboration
among researchers
at the University of California.
[jangling bell tones]
- [Voice On PA] Now arriving
Vermont/Santa Monica Station.
Exit here for Los
Angeles City College.
[eerie ambient music with
unsettling electronic tones]
- [Woman] You haven't
boarded already?
[eerie ambient music
with shuddering rhythm]
Why don't you stick, we
stick with Purple Line?
- Right, yeah.
You're not makin' it easy.
- [sighs] Do you know where
this is that we're at [grunts],
where the station is?
- [Onlooker] Uh--
- [Tristan] I need
to get to Palmdale.
- No, uh, you're far
from that, buddy.
[Tristan screeching
nonsensically]
Are you OK?
- [Woman On Recording]
You're sadistic and sick,
and I hate your guts.
[Tristan groans over
phone cracking to ground]
- Buddy, what's your
fucking problem?
- It burns!
- Fucking asshole!
- It's not me.
- [Woman On Recording]
You've got some kind of need
to play weird games,
and his games are
gettin' really dangerous.
[woman shrieks]
- Will someone help me?
Hey, buddy, give
that back to me!
Shit!
[Tristan groaning]
- [Woman On Recording] I just
think I should pull myself,
I'm wasted like hell, you're
makin' me fuckin' sick!
- Hey, hey what's your problem?
- [Woman On Recording] I
wanna punch your balls off!
[eerie ambient music
with shuddering rhythm]
- [Onlooker] Call the police.
Hey, he's--
[eerie ambient music
with shuddering rhythm]
[Tristan shouts desperately]
- [Man] The first
law of thermodynamics
[shuddering percussion]
energy cannot be
created or destroyed,
only changed into other forms.
It's one of the first things
they teach you in science class,
but sometimes, we have to
learn things the hard way.
[eerie and pulsing
electronic music]
[controller buzzing]
[static crackling over
beeping electronic tones]
- [Woman On recording]
Yeah, I know
you've got enough evidence,
and it doesn't matter
about these calls anymore
because I'm already in
way over my head anyway,
so I can just tell
you what I think.
If you're trying to
set me up to hurt me,
you can do it, so go ahead
and do it, get it over with.
I don't care anymore, you know,
'cause then I'll know for sure
that I could never
trust you anyway.
[electronics buzzing]
[whirring ambient tones]
[muffled radio chatter over
throbbing electronic music]
[radio beeps]
- [Officer On Radio] Cruiser 10,
I need a medical crew and guide.
I've got one victim of interest.
- [Dispatch] Copy.
Units responding
to the shooting,
be sure to remain on channel
two, channel function normal.
[static crackling over
rhythmic electronic music]
[engines rumbling over
[car horns honking]
[rhythmic and tense
electronic music]
[transmission crunching]
[briefcase rattling]
[doors rattling over
tense electronic music]
[static crackles]
[footsteps thudding over
tense electronic music]
[door rattling]
[gun clacking on desk]
[briefcase rattling]
[chair clanging on floor]
[briefcase clacking]
[eerie and tense
electronic music]
[hard drive clacking
into computer]
- I don't know how much
longer I have, man.
[sighs] A lot of the time,
I just sound like
I'm fucking crazy.
They make you sound like
you're fucking crazy, arright?
You know what I'm
fucking talking about!
This is a warning, man,
you need to save it,
and you need to put
it somewhere safe, OK?
Look, my time has
come, your time is now,
because then your
time will come,
and it's time for
you to stand up,
and it's time for you to
make precautions, all right?
This isn't a fuckin'
diatribe, it's a eulogy,
and understand this is the
last image you're gonna see
and understand what
you need to do.
Upload everything you
have and preserve it, man.
Upload and run, upload
and run, run, run!
Upload and run!
[keyboard clacking]
- This is the part we
need to to back up.
I'm uploading offsite.
It, it's not safe here anymore!
[electronic buzzing]
[eerie ambient music]
- Hello, I am here to guide you
through the specialized
study program.
You will be developing
new technologies
for the study of the mind.
I hope you do well in
all your assignments.
- Yeah, it's, uh,
actually pretty cool.
You get to participate
in an independent study
and still, at the end of it all,
you get a masters degree
in psychopathology.
- [Miles] I've just
always wanted to be part
of something groundbreaking,
and I think this could be it.
- Miles?
- Yes?
- Follow me, please.
- Thanks, man, see ya.
[ominous ambient music]
[phone ringing]
[eerie strings over
ominous ambient music]
[door creaking]
[footsteps clacking]
What's with all the
heavy screening?
- It's nothing to
stress out about.
Everyone has to go through
the same screening process
in order to be accepted
into the program.
It's a small, exclusive class.
[whirring and buzzing
electronic effects]
OK, let me just get the system
dialed in to your reactions.
[whirring electronic effects
over ominous ambient music]
Currently in LA, there
are approximately 800
open murder cases
of young girls.
- God!
- Many of them were abused.
Our work here is to
prevent psychopathologies
that lead to suffering and
often to violent death.
Sometimes, we lose
people from the program
because it's just too
much for them to handle.
Are you prepared to become
involved in difficult situations
which could test
you emotionally?
- I'm on my way to becoming
a doctor, obviously.
Emotionally detach
myself from patients.
- I hope to be
able to help people
with mental handicaps
that have been cast aside.
- There's nothing more
in the world I wanna do
than dedicate my
life to this program.
- Anything I can do to help.
- Whatever you ask
me, I'll do it.
This is all I want.
- OK, Room 107
tomorrow at one p.m.
You'll be meeting with
our head of admissions.
- OK.
[computer buzzing over
eerie ambient music]
[whirring electronic tones]
- [Man In Mask] I'm a
conscious dreamer myself.
I can set myself
and go somewhere,
and when I go there,
then I see everything.
I can fly around, I can
see papers on desks.
In top security places, they
put everything on tape now
'cause you can't
really go get a tape
and put in on a
machine and play it,
but you can look at a
desk with papers on it
and read those papers.
- I mean, these people
are a fucking cult!
I mean, do you understand
that they're using you?
I mean, everything
has gone haywire!
Tell me you understand that.
They took me in and made me
feel like I was somebody.
They understood me,
treated me like a family.
My mother died when I was five,
and my father doesn't
even know that I existed.
You're a bastard, an orphan.
Hey, save it for brunch!
Family week, that
guys an asshole!
He doesn't give
a fuck about you!
He used you, man!
Are you gonna let me talk?
He used you, don't
you understand that?
What I'm tryin' to say is--
[lighter snapping]
What can I do to
make you understand?
What can you do to understand
that you grabbed onto
this fucking cult?
I'm--
I'm so drained right
now, I can barely move.
- [Mysterious Woman]
Depending on how well
they take on that frequency,
that person may
direct that frequency,
and they could
start hallucinating,
it could start, um,
changing their, their,
their waveforms, they could
start fighting with themselves.
Then they'd have a
split personality,
then that just goes into a
whole nother snowball effect
of insanity to themselves, and
then they're uncontrollable.
[ominous ambient music with
buzzing electronic tones]
[door rattling]
- Miles, right?
- [Miles] Yes.
- Thank you so much for coming.
- [Miles] Thanks for seeing me.
- No problem, find the place OK?
- [Miles] Yeah, yeah.
- Well, you weren't
waitin' long?
- [Miles] No, no.
- Good, good, good, good.
Before we get started,
there's something
you've gotta understand.
If you become part
of this program,
you cannot talk about
this with anybody, Miles.
- I understand.
- They'll just get confused.
You just can't talk about it,
so I've got your word
as a fellow scientist?
- You have my word.
- Good, so, I ask
this to everybody.
Why, why are you interested
in psychopathology?
- Growing up, I was exposed
to a lot of violence
at a very young age.
I was, uh, raised in a home.
- Orphanage?
- [Miles] Yeah.
- I lost my parents
when I was young.
- Growing up, I
wanted to be a part
of something that
made a difference,
and I think the research you're
doing here is incredible.
- There's nothing usual
about this program.
There's nothing like it on
this campus or anyplace else.
Everybody works at their
own pace, independently,
and Miles, I don't
see an end to this.
[eerie, buzzing ambient music]
It's limitless.
The only limit to this
program is one's imagination.
You know?
I can count on you,
there's a lot of people
who aren't gonna
understand what we do here,
out of ignorance, fear, but--
[eerie ambient music]
- I wanna be a part
of it, I wanna help.
- You've got an old soul.
See it in your eyes.
[ominous and eerie
ambient music]
I can't remember the
last time I said this,
but I got a good
feeling about you,
I really do.
[ominous ambient music]
I want you to take
this home, OK?
Look at it, your
first assignment.
[ominous and eerie
ambient music]
- I wanna do a great job.
- Thanks, Miles.
[ominous and eerie
ambient music]
[door rattling]
You're gonna have to.
[eerie electronic music]
[traffic whooshing]
[plastic crinkling]
[eerie electronic music]
[phone buzzing]
- Hello, I am Adam Whitney,
the director of this program.
Dale, you'll be
working to different
miniature camera technologies
to use for the study of
human behavior patterns.
Miles, you will be
creating sensors
to measure fluctuations in
the body's energy field.
Tristan, I want you to study
the relation between
bioplasma and the human DNA.
Noah, I want you to study
these images carefully
so that you will
remember the information
whenever I test you.
[distorted groaning over
eerie ambient music]
- [Woman] Stop it, stop, stop!
[distorted voices over
eerie ambient music]
[phone buzzing]
[eerie and ominous
ambient music]
[Noah sighs]
[briefcase rattling]
[traffic whooshing]
[button clacking]
[eerie humming ambiance]
- [Woman On Recording]
I suppose you think
just 'cause I have an
illness, a mental illness,
that you can treat me like
I'm some kind of guinea pig.
I am a human being,
and you don't have
any right to treat me this way.
I don't know who you people are
or what you're doing this
for, I don't really care.
I never met such sick
human beings in my life.
You know what, your whole
fuckin' profession sucks.
[muffled rattling]
[eerie ambient music]
[traffic whooshing over
ominous electronic music]
- [Mysterious Woman]
All information
is on different
levels of energy.
There's already a
frequency up here
and it's coming off of
every television set,
computer system, telephone.
They're just
constantly coming out,
you can't get away from it.
They could just stimulate
your thoughts and feelings.
Make you love,
depressed, fear, hate,
move any part of your body.
They could have you
jump off an airplane.
crash the airplane.
You may be struggling
with it the whole time,
but you would inevitably,
would have to surrender to it.
[ominous ambient music]
[machinery whirring]
[muffled chatter]
- [Noah] You don't happen to
have any acetaminophen, do you?
- [Miles] No, not on me.
- So, uh, what-what, what do
you think of these assignments?
- I think they're pretty
amazing, actually,
but we're not
supposed to be talking
about our specific assignments.
It's an independent
study, remember?
- I'm having a
difficult time, uh,
digesting these case studies.
[eerie electronic music]
They're kind of fucked
up to be honest with you.
- Come on, these
people need our help.
Just give yourself a
little bit of time, Noah,
you're just letting
it get to you.
Hey, do you know a
guy named Dale Wilton?
Wasn't he a friend of
yours from high school?
So I heard he enrolled
in the program, too.
- Unless he got in, I saw him
at the, uh, reunion, fucker!
Last got in touch with
each other years back.
We had this horrible fight.
- [Miles] Ah, bury the hatchet.
- Yeah, a friend is a friend.
[vaguely ominous
electronic music]
[ominous, rumbling ambiance]
[traffic whooshing]
[doors rattling]
[elevator whirring]
- [Man] I put cameras
everywhere, everywhere!
[eerie and tense
electronic music]
It was a sick game, it
kept getting sicker.
We were like fresh
blood transfusions
for a parasitic dictator who
was addicted to immortality.
[muffled chatter over eerie
and tense electronic music]
- [Bouncer] ID?
- Come on, drink up,
man, you all right?
- Yeah.
I'm OK.
- Forget about the program,
it's the end of the week.
Time to get out.
- All right, I'm good, I'm just,
you know, a little
tired, that's all.
- Yeah, you look tired [scoffs].
- [scoffs] Life is
standing upright,
spinning around on
bullshit, here, cheers.
[glasses clink]
- Can I get a shot of something
real strong, uh, whiskey?
- Yeah, my favorite one, too.
[eerie and tense
electronic music]
- I'm gonna be in a very
awkward situation in a second.
But thank you, wow!
- [Miles] No, wait, here
he comes, here he comes.
- Really?
[tense, eerie ambient music]
This is way too
fucking confusing--
- Miles, Noah, hey.
- What's goin' on?
- I just wanted to
know if you fuckers
have put the past behind us.
- Well, why would
I hold resentment?
That's been such
a long time ago.
- You know that
bullshit that went down,
it's, like, I apologize,
and I'm sorry.
- Saw you and Bernice Hall.
Figured you'd become
a psych student.
- It's, uh, it's the only
thing that's inspired me.
- Obviously something, right?
- Don't hate me, man.
[tense electronic music]
It's good to see you guys.
- Well, it's, uh,
good to see you.
[tense electro rock music]
- That guy over there ordered
you guys a couple of drinks.
- [Miles] What guy?
- Your friend, Dale.
Two black devils.
- [Miles] I am not
fuckin' drinkin' this.
- He's not being nice anyway.
Fuck that guy.
[muffled chatter over
tense electro rock music]
[traffic whooshing]
- [Cheryl] I'm
writin' a letter here,
and I'm gonna get this off
my chest once and for all.
The letter is to the dean,
and I'm really sorry [sighs],
but you ruined my
life, you know that?
I had a nervous breakdown, you
ruined my fuckin' life, man,
and you did it on purpose,
and, uh, you enjoyed it.
And you deserve for
me to turn you in,
I should've turned you
in a long time ago,
'cause what you did
to me was wrong.
You were sexually
harassing me, I'm sorry,
that's exactly what it was.
Regardless of whether
I went with it
or how I felt about you.
That's exactly what is was, OK,
but don't rub my nose in it,
because I covered up for
you, you fuckin' prick.
[ominous and tense
electronic music]
[traffic humming]
[phone buzzing over eerie
and ominous ambient music]
- [Woman On Phone] Yeah, I think
the whole thing was a setup
'cause he's got some kind
of need to play weird games,
and his games would get
really dangerous, you know?
He'd better watch out.
I don't need this shit,
I need a normal person.
I may be schizophrenic or
whatever the hell I've got,
but I'm more normal
than you'll ever be.
[ominous ambient music]
[muffled rattling]
- [Man On Phone]
They're, they're,
they're doin' studies
for the government.
Th-that's the, the reason
they're getting the funding
for all of this.
They wanna have weapons
that are undetectable
unless you know what
you're looking for.
Unless you know how to
interlace the waveforms,
break down the
synapses of the brain.
They know they can't kill
me because if they do,
I've clouded that
information somewhere
and someone will find it,
and unless they can get me
to tell them where that's at,
they may actually come out here.
[ominous and eerie
ambient music]
[tense and unsettling
- Oh, Noah, come on in,
Adam Whitney.
- Very nice to finally meet you.
- Sit down, please.
Sit down, you ought
to get off your feet.
- Well, thank you.
- How's your work, going along?
- Going well, I guess.
- I have a lot of
confidence in you, Noah.
Over the years, I have developed
a certain sensitivity
in reading people.
I know you will do well here.
Genesis 9:17,
God said to Noah, "This is
the token of the covenant
"which I have
established between me
"and all the flesh
upon this earth."
I know you will do
well here, Noah.
- Thanks.
- Very good.
[ominous and eerie
ambient music]
[traffic whooshing over
eerie ambient music]
[electronics buzzing]
- I don't know who
you people are,
and I don't really care.
I've never met such sick
human beings in my life.
You know what, your whole
fuckin' profession sucks!
[phone line beeping]
[ominous and eerie
ambient music]
[motorcycle engine rumbling]
[ominous and eerie
ambient music]
[train horn blaring]
[electronics buzzing]
- [Man With Mask] Yeah,
yeah, you rolling?
- [Camera Operator] Mm-hmm.
- [Man With Mask]
Right, so I was at USC,
and I was, I was a psych major.
I had a little job measuring
lie detector results.
My teacher had there in
the psych department,
he got me quote
"employed" out there,
actually, I was just,
like, the guinea pig
for early mind
control experiments,
but the government
were to cover that up
so the ones that were
whistleblowing, like myself,
we were under threat because
we were telling the truth
and exposing these
people, but, uh,
these people didn't
like to be exposed,
so we got threatened
as a result.
[door creaking]
[door thuds]
[car whooshing over
tense electronic music]
- Pleasure, sir.
- My pleasure, too.
- [Miles] I'm a big
fan of your work.
- Huh, thank you.
This is a small
follow-through meeting
to find out how you are doing.
Is everything all right?
- Absolutely, I feel
like I'm finally
beginning to understand
how the neurotransmitters
of the brain actually work.
- If we could develop the tools
to map the psyche of
disturbed individuals,
I believe we could free
them from pain forever.
- [Miles] That's
almost overwhelming.
- [Adam] Are there questions?
- Not specifically.
- [Adam] OK, then,
see you in two weeks.
- [scoffs] OK, thank you.
- By the way,
your friend, Noah,
missed his meeting.
You heard something?
You know something about that?
- I don't really know.
[tense ambient music]
He stopped returning my
calls and emails days ago.
[scoffs] It's like
he just disappeared.
- Well, I'm sorry to hear that.
However, you are still here.
Miles, you have a great future.
- [scoffs] Thank you, sir.
- Call me Adam.
[eerie ambient music]
[traffic whooshing over
eerie ambient music]
[phone buzzing and whirring]
[static crackling]
- [Cheryl] Is it that you
just wanted to hurt me,
or are you just
the kind of person
that likes to hurt people?
You can always go work
at my web training,
I hear they like to sexually
harass their students, too.
[train whistle howling over
tense electronic music]
[muffled shouting over
buzzing electronic effects]
[electronics buzzing]
[traffic whooshing]
- Most of our work is
done sitting at computers,
but the most challenging
is in the field.
- That's the part I
really wanna get into.
- Sexuality, Miles,
is the direct link
to the primal scream.
Orgasm is a little death.
It's only when we
are close to death
that our minds can be pure,
and we need that purity
for our experiments.
- [Miles] I can see that.
- [Adam] I believe you are
ready for the next level.
Make sure you follow
all the instructions
to the last detail.
[ominous electronic music]
[footsteps clacking over
ominous electronic music]
- [Miles] Hey.
- Hey.
- [Miles] Haven't I
seen you around before?
What's your name?
- Gemini.
- Gemini,
please, come in.
[door crunching]
So, Gemini, is that
your real name?
- We don't wanna talk about
our real names, now, do we?
- Of course not.
[engine rumbling]
[computer buzzing over ominous
and eerie electronic music]
[static crackling]
[traffic whooshing]
[rhythmic, vaguely ominous
and eerie electronic music]
[pills rattling]
[rhythmic, vaguely ominous
and eerie electronic music]
What are the pills for?
- You don't need to worry
about that right now.
[rhythmic, vaguely ominous
and eerie electronic music]
- [Miles] Give me just a second
to get this thing set up.
[switches clacking]
[sighs] Do you ever get
nervous when you're doin' this?
- [Gemini] That's
another question,
you ask so many questions!
- [Miles] Let's
just get to work.
- You'll do fine.
[ominous and unsettling
electronic music]
[switches clicking]
[muffled shouting]
No, no, stop, stop [gasps]!
[eerie electronic music]
[echoed shouting]
[Gemini gasps]
[tense and unsettling
electronic music]
[computer beeping]
- [sighs] The fuck?
Hello?
- Dale, it's me,
you've gotta come out
and meet me right away.
You remember the spot
where we used to hang out?
[sighs] You've got to come out
right away [sighs], please.
- Fuck, man, it's
four in the morning!
- I need you to do me
this one last favor
if you were ever my fucking
friend, do you understand?
Please!
- This better be serious.
- There's no time
for explanations!
- All right, give
me half an hour.
[keyboard clacking]
[buzzing and bubbling
electronic effects]
[tense and ominous
ambient music]
Noah!
[footsteps crunching]
[tense and ominous
ambient music]
What's goin' on with you,
why'd you wanna meet
all the way out here?
- Copper wiring in the walls.
The transmission
can't be traced here.
This entire place
is a dead zone.
Don't you remember from class?
- Why don't you come back,
finish, get your degree?
- Why?
So I can grow up
and be like you?
- So what have you been doing?
- Been collecting things.
Transmissions,
people's testimony,
people who've been damaged.
- So what's so urgent, hmm?
- I intercepted this one
from the Victims Channel.
- What's that?
[tape snapping]
- It's a closed
circuit video blog.
Victims of psychological
torture use it
to communicate with each other.
People who have been
psychologically raped
are on that tape, Dale.
Do you understand how
important that is?
[tense electronic music]
Thank you for coming.
[tense and ominous
electronic music]
[keyboard clacking]
- I could hear his voice.
It was almost like
about five to 10
people or something like that.
All of them kept telling me
a whole bunch of different
things, like how does it feel
to get fucked all the
way through your brains.
I didn't know whether I was
asleep with my eyes closed
and, and everybody
was talking to me,
but they were able to, like,
receive this information
and take it out
and they were also, I
felt like they were trying
to put in, uh, different,
uh, data inside of me
that would make
me destroy myself.
- I would have these
weird aura feelings,
like this real, really weird,
like warm, warmth come over me.
It would start with
the fingertips,
and it would, and
also I could feel it
go up through my veins all
the way up into my head
into the back of my eye.
I know there is something being
completely stolen from me.
- Our enemy is a blur.
[tense electronic music]
I mean [sighs], assignments,
I don't trust anybody, really.
[traffic whooshing]
- Science is unpredictable,
but you're the one
who pushed it too far.
- You didn't tell me
she could die from it!
- She had AIDS.
Her time was limited.
I'm sorry about
what has happened,
but we have to take risks.
- No, I'm sorry [sighs].
I don't really feel
like I can be a part
of this project anymore.
- But you agreed.
- You can't prove that.
- Let me tell you something.
I have slept with
many of my students
with no risk of being
reported, no risk at all,
because I record the
girl telling me how
much she wants me.
So I have her
consent on the tape,
like I have yours
concerning our project.
Our future on this
planet is precarious,
and yet we have
to evolve somehow.
To capture the essence of
the human being, his mind,
his personality, come on, Miles!
You worked on the project, you
know what I'm talking about!
I can make this
situation go away.
[tense electronic music]
But you have to help me.
Someone is making threats.
It's a former student of
mine who had some problems,
but I think I have a good
idea how to find her.
- There's one student,
she disappeared,
but we're gonna find her
using technology
we've developed here,
and trust me, we're
all fully committed.
[tense electronic music]
[electronics buzzing
and whirring]
- [Mysterious Woman] But
once, in the olden days,
they used to, um, cut one
arm and then cut one hand,
and then they could travel
and they could speak
to each other by
touching that wound.
When we actually
tested this again,
we took our college, uh, student
and we took some of his blood,
and we had him take a log,
what girlfriend,
what did he eat,
how did he feel, what
type of tests did he take,
what time did he go to sleep,
and for three months,
his blood reacted
to exactly what was going
on with him, exactly.
So in the same ways as blood
holds electricity and waveforms,
they could do the same
thing with another person.
[tense, vaguely eerie
ambient electronic music]
- [Mysterious Man] I knew for
me it was a new beginning.
I felt this power
that was nothing
like I'd ever felt before.
There was nothing that
I couldn't accomplish.
I could do anything.
It filled a hole, a void inside
that I had since I was a child,
but I still knew that I had to
do whatever was asked of me.
I was going to find Cheryl,
otherwise, who knows
what would happen.
- [Dale] Another part
of the facility, huh?
- The way that you
see everything.
- Yeah, it's cool.
- Cameras everywhere.
- Yeah.
- So tell me, how's
your work, tell us.
- Yeah, they're very
good, I'm excited.
I think I'm breaking
through some barriers.
- Good.
Now, do you know what is
the meaning of theater?
- Uh, live theater, like plays?
- [Adam] Yes.
- Entertainment?
- With theater
was born the mask.
It hides the face
of whoever wears it,
his identity, and
at the same time,
the vibration of the brain,
suddenly, this mask
reflects their power.
As a next assignment, Dale,
I want you to wear it.
Meet the divine.
- [Dale] Uh, thank you, I'm, uh,
I'm lookin' forward to this.
- Good.
- [Dale] All right,
yeah, thank you.
[traffic whooshing over
tense electronic music]
[rhythmic electronic music]
[phone whoops]
- Oh my God, he's on his way.
[bird fluttering]
[snickers] He looks
really cute, I'm excited.
I get tired of
talkin' to pigeons
all the time, you know, guys?
As cool as you are, no offense.
[rhythmic electronic music]
[Jeanie chuckles]
Be good, OK, watch the fort.
Bye, babies.
[traffic humming over quietly
tense electronic music]
Hey, Dale?
Jeanie.
- Hi, thanks for coming out.
- You're even better
looking in person.
- So are you, so, you
wanna go somewhere?
- [Jeanie] Yeah, totally,
where do you wanna go?
- Um, oh, I figured
I'm just kind of a,
I'm stressed out, I'm
a, I'm a psych student.
I've been doin' a lot
of studying, you know,
so I'm just, uh, a
little overwhelmed.
- Yeah, man,
school's killing me.
I'm doing internet marketing.
- [Dale] Wow, that sounds heavy.
- Yeah, it's a lotta
work, a lotta work.
- [Dale] So you understand
what I'm sayin'?
- Totally, hey, do have
anything to get high?
- [scoffs] Uh, depends on
what you get high with.
- Uh, well, I'm feelin'
like a, a downer,
like, um, vikes or oxies
or somethin', you know?
Somethin' to just chill,
chill me out [chuckles].
- Yeah, I've got
a bad back, so I,
I think I've got 30
milligram oxycodone.
- [Jeanie] What?
- I do.
- Oh, man.
- 30 milli, that's awesome, yes!
- It's better than 10.
- [chuckles] Yeah, it is!
Wow, they look real.
- They're real.
- Eh, I don't like
to take stuff that's,
you know, bad for me.
- [Dale] Yeah, no, I understand.
- [Jeanie] This is
cool, this'll just--
- [Dale] Be careful
drinking, you know?
- Eh, gimme a minute.
- There you go.
[rhythmic electronic music]
So, do you like cam sex?
- [scoffs] Sometimes, yeah.
- Sometimes, I like
masks, you know?
Plays out your
subconscious, your id.
- [Jeanie] Your id?
- Desire for love and sex,
controlled by your libido,
and then the desire for
death and aggression.
These two competing
instincts, you know,
build up in the id
causing tension,
and you gotta
release that tension.
- [Jeanie] Wow!
- You feel me?
- [chuckles] I'm all about
releasing tension right now.
- [Dale] Yeah, absolutely.
[engine rumbling]
The journey begins.
- [Jeanie] I'm excited.
So ready, I could fuckin'
use a cool change.
- [Dale] Oh, it's gonna be cool.
[Jeanie laughs]
All right, Jeanie, I have
something to ask you.
- Ask me.
- [Dale] How would you feel
if you I wanted you
to be blindfolded?
- Uh--
- [Dale] Would
that freak you out?
- No, man, that's kinda
kinky, I'm into it.
- You up for it.
- All right, I, I feel
like I gotta trust you.
You seem, like, you know, kinky.
[traffic whooshing]
[moans passionately] Yeah, yeah!
Oh, yeah [laughs]!
[unsettling electronic music]
Yeah [moans], yeah!
[Jeanie moaning passionately
over eerie electronic music]
[Jeanie laughs]
[Jeanie gasps and moans]
[Jeanie chuckles]
[Jeanie gasping over
eerie electronic music]
Yeah [gasps], yeah, oh yeah!
[Jeanie gasping and shrieking
over eerie electronic music]
[eerie ambient tones]
[Dale grunting aggressively]
[Dale gasping]
[eerie and unsettling
electronic music]
[machinery whirring]
[Tristan sighs]
[Tristan grunts]
[ominous ambient music]
[Tristan sighs]
[zipper crunching]
[doors crunching shut]
[ominous ambient music]
[engine rumbling]
[ominous and eerie
ambient music]
- Dale!
- I saw that tape,
it made me sick, man.
- C'mere.
Look at my eye.
Here, right by the pupil, look.
- There's nothing in your eye.
- I know.
- [Dale] Just, what
are talking about?
- Shh, shh!
- All right.
- Just look, right there.
- [Dale] All right,
listen, listen.
- Just look!
- Listen, you've
been awake too long.
Look, there's
nothing in your eye!
I promise you, there's
nothing in your eye.
[tense and ominous
ambient music]
- I am getting, like, tension,
tension headaches in the
frontal part of my lobe [sighs].
Shh, swelling pressure.
[tense ambient music]
Yeah, yeah, uh [sighs],
[sighs] I found him.
- Hey, look, let me see
what I can find out, OK?
You're fine, all right?
[Noah sighs]
It's all in your head.
[ominous and tense
ambient music]
- Thanks.
[footsteps clacking]
[switch clacking]
[eerie and unsettling
ambient electronic music]
[keyboard clacking]
- [clears throat] They're
constantly making new things
to make the
cellphone invaluable,
that you can't do
anything without it.
I remember I was bleeding
from under my nails,
so I electrocuted myself.
I'd been on the phone a lot,
and I started thinking
these crazy thoughts
like is it, is it the phone
I've been holding to
this side of my head,
and is it doing
something to me, like.
[ominous and eerie
ambient electronic music]
- You're a victim.
You were his victim,
he's sick, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry for my sicknesses.
[eerie and ominous
ambient electronic music]
- [Computerized Voice] Preview
and identification completed.
[door rattling]
[electronics buzzing over
ominous ambient music]
- Go on, keep working.
- [Tristan] OK.
[keyboard clacking]
- [Adam] You found anything?
- No, there's been
a lotta action,
just, uh, none that you
might be looking for [sighs].
- Well, then work harder.
I'll come check
with you tomorrow.
- Listen, you don't have
to obsess so hard, sir.
I've got the data,
and I'm analyzing it with,
with all the records we have.
I mean, if I find a
match, I'll tell you.
- I don't like to repeat myself.
[electronics buzzing over
ominous and tense ambient music]
Good night, Tristan.
[electronics buzzing over
unsettling ambient music]
- Fuck!
[ominous and unsettling
rumbling ambient tones]
- You've got the sensitivities
to psychological disorders.
It creates an obscenity
in electromagnetic
radiation, the EMR.
[whirring electronic
music over muffled dialog]
Concentrated exposure can, can
lead to heart irregularities
and cancer, brain
tumors, just look.
It can actually alter
your, your, your DNA.
I mean restructure,
essentially, uh, rewire
the human genome.
This information was to be
made available at any cost.
[lighter snapping]
- These people are
like a family to me!
Don't you understand that,
don't you understand that?
They were like a family to me!
You know how important that is,
that's all I ever wanted!
Maybe you don't care,
maybe you don't,
but that's all I ever wanted!
Can't you guys
both respect that?
Shut up, shut up,
you pussy!
You'd be suckin' dick
if it wasn't for me,
wouldn't you, wouldn't you?
If it were up to you,
we'd be serial killers?
That's not the
point, you understand
what type of position
we're in right now, right?
Fuck you!
What, do you wanna hit me,
do you want me to hit you?
Don't touch him,
leave him alone.
Fuckin' put your finger on my
face, put me up one more time!
[gun clicking]
Stop it, just calm down.
Leave him alone, just calm down!
OK, do you agree that I'm
the voice of reason here?
I'm trying, didn't
I just try, right?
We have got an open
mind, all of us.
We've gotta listen to each other
and understand where
each one is coming from.
Everyone here is
trying to make sense.
If you just would listen to
him, I will listen to you,
and you listen to
me, we have a chance!
Help me out, man!
I understand, I respect you,
just help me out, man, please!
The funny thing is
I'm talkin' to nobody!
[eerie and ominous
ambient music]
- [Tristan] Whitney
keeps classified files
of the students who've
been part of the program,
and the files go back for years.
He, he keeps old
cellphones around.
I mean, why would
he keep this old,
outdated technology
around, is, is,
I, I think it might
have something to do
with the frequency of the
phone, can't be duplicated
'cause it's a crystal and every
phone crystal is different.
[drawer snaps]
[electronics buzzing]
[low throbbing ambient tones]
- You find something?
- Not yet, nope.
I don't [sighs],
I don't know what it is.
- And did you do
everything I told you?
- I injected them with the dye,
and then I did everything
the way you showed me.
- Well, then, I'll have to
come back again tomorrow.
Oh, by the way, did
you get the order?
- Oh, yeah, came
in this morning.
[box rattling]
1000 pills of ketamine.
Enough to stop a herd
of elephants there.
[box rattling over
buzzing electronics]
- I'll see you tomorrow.
- Oh, hey, I was,
I was thinking,
could, could I maybe, could
I maybe get one of those?
[box rattling]
[pills rattling]
- Accomplishment.
- Thanks.
[bottle thwacks]
[electronics buzzing over
low rumbling ambient tones]
I got you.
[phone buzzing]
[keypad thwacking]
[camera snaps]
- That was a very intense
conversation in class.
I didn't wanna leave,
I wanted to stay.
[eerie and tense ambient music]
- How can you swallow the shit
that they're
feeding us in there?
- What do you mean?
I think you've got it all wrong.
[eerie and tense ambient music]
- I'm outta here,
for good.
- You can't leave.
- Yeah, right?
- [Dale] Hey, Kamal!
- I'm out, you got
it under control.
[ominous and eerie
ambient electronic music]
[muffled chatter over eerie,
unsettling ambient music]
[phone chirping]
Hello?
[modem buzzing and whirring]
[static crackling]
[unsettling throbbing
ambient tones]
[Tristan sighs]
[unsettling throbbing
ambient tones]
[gloves thwacking]
[Tristan sighs]
[phone clacking]
[eerie ambient music]
[door alarm dinging]
[engine rumbling]
[echoing rock guitar over
jangling electronic tones]
[rhythmic electro rock music]
[eerie and unsettling
electronic accent]
- Hey, you people
just have this need
to manipulate and
control other people.
That's really sick.
Yeah, only you're
not any healthier
than anybody else, none of you.
I think you're all really
sicker than most human beings .
You're really sick people.
[buzzing and whirring
electronic tones]
[low, throbbing ambient tones]
[ominous and eerie
electronic tones]
[bell clanging]
[swell of ominous and
unsettling electronic music]
[Tristan gags]
[ominous and unsettling
electronic music]
[Tristan coughing and gagging]
[Tristan gasping and coughing]
[Tristan groaning over
rattling ignition]
- [Tristan] [gasps] Fuck!
[Tristan coughing]
[Tristan gasping and grunting
over tense ambient music]
[Tristan gasping for breath]
[Tristan grunting over
rattling ignition]
Dammit!
[Tristan gasping and grunting]
[train whistle wailing]
[train whirring on tracks
over dinging alarm bell]
- I got into a car accident,
and some people helped me
before the ambulance got there.
I don't know, they were, like,
some other kind of ambulance,
and once I, at the hospital,
I don't know exactly when,
what happened to me, I mean,
they say that they stick
their finger up your, uh,
anus to, for reflex, um,
but I don't know,
sometimes I wonder if maybe
they did stick
something, um, in there.
Some kind of, uh,
chip or something,
'cause after the car accident,
I felt like I had
to be reborn again.
- [scoffs] This is the
only place that's safe.
There's no wires
that are above me
that are not
grounded to the dirt.
The dirt keeps, keeps the arc
from coming off of
their power lines
and shooting through, I mean,
I've seen, I've seen the
television completely off.
[mimics electrical buzz] Go
right, right out and turn white.
It, it doesn't matter,
it doesn't even have
to be plugged in.
They can, they can,
they can make a,
a cellphone explode
next to your head.
[unsettling guitar accents]
If you're listening to this,
you know that I need your help.
They're trying to fucking kill
me with invisible waveforms.
Get all of the incriminating
data from the tests
and the people
who've been tested on
and the ones that
are still out there.
I have it all back
up into the cloud,
but if I were to die,
which is very likely,
I have it all encapsulated,
uh, titanium flash drive.
[eerie and unsettling
ambient music]
[door rattling]
[gun clicks]
[lock clacking]
- [Cheryl] You don't understand
anything about me, I mean,
[sniveling] you don't
understand how much you hurt me.
I know you don't want [sighs]--
[hatch thuds]
[lock clacking]
[low rumbling ambient tones]
[eerie and unsettling
ambient music]
[footsteps clacking over
eerie ambient music]
[switches snapping]
[eerie pulsing ambient tones]
- Genesis 9:17.
God said unto Noah,
"This is the token
of the covenant
"which I have
established between me
"and all the flesh that
is upon the earth."
[unsettling ambient music]
[woman gasps]
[woman shrieks]
[woman thuds to the ground]
- [Woman] No, please [gasps]!
[strikes thudding]
[strikes cracking]
[woman coughing and gagging]
[switches snapping]
[distant dogs barking
over eerie ambient tones]
- Fuck, [muttering]!
Fuck!
It's not my, fuck [gasps]!
[eerie and unsettling
ambient music]
[low rumbling ambient tones]
[traffic humming]
[eerie and unsettling
ambient music]
- What's that on your head?
[strap snapping]
- Protects me from
the transmissions.
They're coming for me.
[gasping] They're coming
for me, aren't they?
- I haven't heard
anything like that.
- No.
The great and glorious science,
are you proud of what
you've accomplished?
- What do you mean?
Somebody's gotta infiltrate,
see what's going on.
You're certainly
not doin' it, Noah.
Somebody's gotta
be on the inside.
- On the inside, they
are on the inside of you.
- What the fuck are
you talking about,
they're on the inside of me?
Let me ask you something.
Do you think you can take
them on on your own, huh?
You need me as
much as I need you.
- Did you find
out what it's like
when they're done using you?
They'll tell you what to do,
because there's no getting away.
Not in this pathetic life.
You gotta trust somebody.
[buzzing electronic tones
over unsettling ambient music]
If anything happens
to me, anything,
I'm gonna put a special
package for you right here.
- [Dale] What are you
talking about, Noah?
- This is everything I've
collected so far, do you get it?
This is all the tapes, my
tapes, the victims' tapes,
this is my life, and
I am giving it to you.
- [Dale] If something
happens to me,
what do you want me to do?
[tense, pulsing
electronic music]
- If that time ever comes,
[scoffs] look inside
the briefcase.
You're gonna find
some information.
Follow the instructions exactly
then destroy any extra
copies to make sure
that the feds don't get them,
do you understand me, Dale?
- Yeah, if that time comes,
you can trust in me.
- How long have we
known each other?
- [Dale] Long time, why?
- Remember I was so
idealistic that I,
now you're working
on secret patents
and I'm doing, well, this shit.
[eerie electronic music]
We're still friends, right?
- Yeah, of course we're friends.
We'll always be close.
- All right.
[slaps thwacking over
eerie ambient music]
Just remember this spot, OK?
- Of course.
[tense and eerie ambient music]
[crickets chirping over
rumbling ambient tones]
[door rattling]
[eerie, unsettling
ambient music]
[skittering electronic accent]
[woman gasps]
[skittering and screeching
electronic tones]
[punches thwacking]
[skittering and screeching
electronic tones]
[whooshing electronic effects]
[Noah gasps]
[switches clicking]
[Dale coughing and retching]
[toilet flushing]
[Dale gasps]
[metal clanging]
I'm scared.
I didn't realize that
Whitney was manipulating us.
I just want to stay
in control [gasps].
[gun cocking]
[Dale gasping]
I'm sorry, I'm so sorry.
I can't take it back now.
[Dale sniveling]
[distant traffic humming]
[insects chirping over
rumbling ambient tones]
- [Tristan] Who's out there?
Show your fucking self!
- [Hooded Man] I can't
show you who I am!
- I'm gonna fry your fucking
brain with waveforms!
Let me see your face!
- [Hooded Man] I'm
an administrator
for the Victims Channel.
I can't show you my face,
I have to be anonymous.
- Blog dude from the,
from the Victims Channel?
Show me that you're unarmed.
[ominous ambient music]
Turn your fucking
camera on all of this.
You, you need to
process all of this!
This is where, this is where
they test it on the victims,
[grunting] all the tapes,
everything comes from here!
You gotta be quick,
though, we gotta hurry!
[insects chirping over
ominous ambient music]
Are you ready to hear this?
- [Victims Channel Rep]
Just tell your story.
- The test started off
with whenever we get a
person who came into the
psychiatric part of the school.
We would, um, first
inject them with this dye,
I thought it was a
dye, which later on,
I come to find out is a, some
kind of nanotechnology liquid
that's not even classified
to use on people,
but it makes it so we can see
how the synapses
of the brain are,
are communicating with that
part of the body at that moment.
The ultimate goal is
to create a weapon
that doesn't even
kill people but,
it can wipe out
massive amounts of,
of, of brain frequency
and basically turn
people into sheep.
[rhythmic and eerie
electronic music]
[eerie and ominous
ambient music]
[swell of tense
electronic music]
- [Cheryl] The day I
met you in the library.
I, I really did like you.
Wow.
- Adam Whitney, I
wrote this book.
- Cheryl.
I was so stupid to think
you were a nice person.
You know, I thought
we could get along,
but if you didn't want me,
you should've just let me go.
[button clicks]
- They've tapped into
the, the whole grid
where if she comes within
any of those cameras, and
we, we get glimpses of her,
and we can pick up on her
waveform, but then she's gone.
If somehow they're able
to, uh, find her frequency
or whatever it is that's
leaving the messages,
then more people are gonna die.
I mean, there's no evidence
the, that the woman is real.
She could just be some cloud
just drifting through the
wires, through the fiberoptics,
and, and, and theoretically,
she could be implanted
into someone else's mind,
and I think that that's what
he's the most afraid of.
If, if, if this doesn't get out,
more people will be
missing, you know?
More tests'll be done, but
people don't know that.
That's the--
[muffled rustling]
- [Victims Channel
Rep] Who is that?
- Come on!
[tense electronic music]
[tense electronic music with
unsettling buzzing tones]
[rhythmic and tense
electronic music]
[footsteps thudding]
[rhythmic and tense
electronic music]
[muffled rattling]
[rhythmic and tense
electronic music]
[footsteps thudding over
tense electronic music]
[muffled rattling]
[footsteps and rattling
over tense electronic music]
[glass shattering]
[tense electronic music with
unsettling buzzing tones]
[ominous and tense
electronic music]
C'mon, c'mon, down here, down!
Get in here!
[ominous and tense
electronic music]
- Fuck!
[ominous electronic music]
[object thwacking on trailer]
Son of a bitch!
[rhythmic and tense
electronic music]
[engine rumbling over
tense electronic music]
[men gasping over
[rhythmic and tense
electronic music]
[echoing shouts over
tense electronic music]
[van creaking]
[men grunting]
[Tristan sighs]
- [Victims Channel Rep] Come on!
[ignition rattling]
- I'm gonna take you to
the medical facility.
It's, it's close to here.
[engine rumbling]
God!
[engine rumbling over
tense ambient music]
I'm gonna give you something.
During admissions, everyone
that was admitted to the school
signed a waiver
releasing their lives.
I cannot give this chip to you
without seeing your face,
I have to see your face!
I have to know who, who's,
who's hands these
peoples' lives are in.
[tense electronic music]
Take it, their DNA
code, everything!
Their lives are on that.
[ominous and tense
electronic music]
See the light up there
on the third floor?
Up above this bridge?
- [Victims Channel Rep] Yeah.
- You're gonna go
to the third floor.
Whitney's retina
scan is on that chip.
It'll give you complete access
to anywhere in the system.
- [Victims Channel Rep] All
right, I'll get what I can.
- Use the code that I gave you.
[engine rumbling over
eerie ambient music]
[door crunching]
[engine rumbling]
[eerie ambient music]
There's somehow,
let everybody know
that there's machines
that are controlling, uh,
all of the synapses
in, in our minds.
Everything we do,
they know we're gonna
do it before we do it.
It's like he's waitin' behind
you at the gas station,
but what is he doin'?
He's not buying
anything, you know?
Heh, and then you go
and wait behind him.
He looks at you like you're
fuckin' crazy, but you're not!
[engine rumbling over eerie
and ominous ambient music]
[door creaking]
[door crunching]
[traffic whooshing over eerie
and ominous ambient music]
[ominous and menacing
ambient electronic music]
[train screeching over
ominous ambient music]
[alarm dings]
[muffled PA chatter over
ominous ambient music]
[eerie and ominous
ambient music]
[doors rattling]
[eerie ambient music]
[buzzing electronic tones
over eerie ambient music]
[Tristan groaning over
buzzing electronic tones]
[eerie and ominous
electronic music]
[buzzing electronic tones]
[train whirring]
- [PA Announcer] Now arriving
Vermont/Santa Monica Station.
Exit here for Los
Angeles City College.
[rumbling ambient tones]
Stand clear, the
doors are closing.
[footsteps clacking]
[ominous rumbling ambient tones]
[eerie and ominous
ambient music]
- I read this thing
recently about the dinosaurs
becoming extinct is because
they found this iridium
that was along the, it
was all along the fossils,
that it's not found,
like, on Earth.
It's, like, they find
it in outer space, yeah,
so they found that,
like, the earth,
there must've been these
meteorites or something
coming from outer
space that made the,
that eradicated the dinosaurs.
- Yeah, that's their
life, you know that.
- So, I really like this part
here that she has to say.
This chapter about how
to make experiments
with biological
transmutation successful.
Like, that's really interesting,
it's, like,
one-of-a-kind research.
- You know, it's just research.
Two plus two equals four.
- It's kind of cold in here.
Do you maybe wanna
get out of here,
maybe go to my
place for a drink?
- Very sweet, but
I can't, I can't.
I have to go back
to the project.
It takes all of my free time.
- Maybe I could come with you?
I'd really like to see what
you've been working on.
- [Adam] You sure?
[rhythmic electro rock music]
- [Cheryl] Yeah, I'm totally
sure, I'd really like to go.
- OK, let's pick up my car.
- [Cheryl] Mm-hmm.
[rhythmic electro rock music]
[traffic whooshing]
[eerie and ominous
ambient music]
- [Computerized Voice] Preview
and identification completed.
- [Cheryl] Wow, this
place is amazing!
- My lab, and I'm proud of it.
- So, Adam, do you
have any children?
- I always dream
of having a family,
but you know how it is
once you get married.
50 percent of your
time for the wife,
time for the kids,
another 50 percent for
the career, what's left?
So I focus on my work,
and in some ways,
my students are my children.
[door rattling over
ominous ambient music]
What you are about to see I
shouldn't really show to nobody.
You understand that?
- Yeah, you make
me feel special.
- Here, here we see the cutting
edge of mind technology.
Nobody's authorized
to do this but me.
Everything here, all the labs,
the whole project is being
financed by the government.
There are special
parts of this program
that I have to do
separate from the school
so that there is
no interference.
- What is this place?
- It's OK, I'm the
only one to use it.
To tell you the truth,
I really need your help.
- What do you mean?
- I have to record
a human waveform.
- You mean the bioplasma?
- Yes, exactly!
And I need someone
as dedicated as I am
to be able to analyze
it completely.
- What do you need me to do?
[ominous ambient music]
- [lips smacking] Trust me.
[eerie and ominous
ambient music]
[buttons snapping]
[buzzing electrical hum]
[eerie and ominous
electronic music]
[Cheryl gasps]
[tense electronic music with
unsettling gurgling accents]
[computer buzzing over
eerie pulsing ambient music]
[static crackling]
- If this gets in the wrong
people's hands, we're fucked!
Do you get it, fucked!
Chill out.
It's getting people's
mind, their souls!
Am I the only one here
who wants to live, guys?
I wanna live!
Come on, I know, we had
no father, I get it!
Where's all this
hate coming from?
We had nothing!
Where did this come from?
Talk to him!
Will you please let me talk?
I'm gonna end up killing myself,
can you please help
me out, Dale, please?
You're everything that I
never wanted to be, OK?
He fucking used you man!
Ask him when we talk.
That's the whole reason that
we're even in this mess!
Does anyone here understand me?
It's not about pers, Dale,
it's not about personal issues!
Can't you understand that?
What the hell is wrong with you?
We all need each
other, you need me,
you need me, we need
each other, Dale!
Do you guys understand
right now, single-handedly,
we're the most powerful
group of people in the world,
and if you guys were with me,
we could be unstoppable!
OK, what do you want me to do?
Do you want me to be
somebody that I'm not?
What do you want me to do?
I want you to get every message,
every testimonial, every
bit of data, every CD,
every incriminating evidence
that we possible could have
and destroy it, now!
[objects thwacking on counter]
[eerie, vaguely
unsettling ambient music]
[plastic snapping over
quietly tense ambient music]
[CD cracking]
[eerie electronic music
over rhythmic percussion]
[plastic rattling]
[eerie electronic music
over rhythmic percussion]
[eerie, gurgling ambient
music with jangling guitar]
[phone thwacking]
[eerie and ominous
ambient music]
- [Adam] I believe you are
ready for the next level.
- I'm so glad I could help you.
- I thank you, darling.
[footsteps clacking over
eerie ambient music]
[electronics buzzing
and whirring]
[eerie throbbing
electronic tones]
[Cheryl gasping and groaning
over unsettling ambiance]
[throbbing and pulsing
electronic tones]
[pulsing and whirring
[eerie and ominous
ambient music]
Fuck!
[eerie and ominous
ambient music]
- [Mysterious Man]
For all the women
that Whitney had abused,
she was the anomaly.
[shuddering percussion accent]
The second law of thermodynamics
says that entropy,
the random disorder of energy
and matter in a system,
always increases with time.
It's as if whenever she
goes through the wires,
her waveform is amplified,
and then could show up
anywhere at anytime.
[muffled rattling]
[eerie buzzing electronic tones]
[footsteps thudding]
[eerie pulsing electronic music]
[electronics buzzing
and whirring]
[buttons snapping]
[eerie pulsing and
whirring electronic music]
[pulsing electronic tones
over unsettling ambient music]
- Seem to think because
you're a psychologist
that you know more about
how to live life than I do,
but I don't play these kinds
of sick, psychotic games
with other people's heads, do I?
No, see, you people just
have this need to manipulate
and control other people,
that's really sick.
You know, and you're not any
healthier than anybody else.
None of you, I think you're all
really sicker than
most human beings.
You're really sick people.
[static crackling]
[pulsing electronic tones
over rumbling ambiance]
[ominous and eerie
ambient music]
I call, suppose I
call the police,
and you deserve for
me to turn you in.
I shoulda turned you
in a long time ago
'cause what you did
to me was wrong.
You were sexually
harassing me, I'm sorry,
that's exactly what it was.
Regardless of whether
I went with it
or how I felt about you,
that's exactly what it was,
OK, but don't rub my nose in it,
'cause I covered up for
you, you fuckin' prick!
[eerie screeching
electronic music]
[muffled shrieking and gasping]
- [Cheryl] [sobs] No [gasping]!
[Cheryl whimpering]
- You're coming with me.
[eerie and ominous
ambient music]
- [Man With Mask]
Adopted children
and children in placements
are, uh, prime targets.
You can get a child
out of a placement,
mind control it, and
then bring it back.
Nobody knows the difference,
so later on in life, when they
need to fast-track somebody,
they use these people that
they've mind controlled
earlier in their life
when they were young.
- Do you guys realize
that if we get caught,
we're going to prison forever!
I'd rather be dead.
Fuckin' A, man, we gotta
pull this together!
I'd definitely
rather you be dead!
This should've been decided
an hour ago, am I right?
Listen, you listen,
everybody in the world,
every person is different.
Everybody has a
different purpose,
everyone has a different reason.
I'm already dead, guys!
OK, guys, let's come together!
You, you, let's come
together, look at me!
Look at me, look at me,
let's pull it together, OK?
Are you with me, huh?
We can do it, you
can do it, come on!
Yeah, it's the best idea
I've ever heard, let's go.
Right now, let's fuckin' do it!
[metal creaking]
[computer buzzing over
eerie pulsing ambient music]
[muffled rattling]
[buzzing alarm tones]
[static crackling]
[insects chirping over eerie
and ominous ambient music]
[gun rattling]
- Look at who I
am, look at me now!
- Neither of us knew
what could happen.
- You were always the expert!
You knew this
could happen to me!
[gunshots cracking]
[insects chirping]
[static buzzing]
You didn't kill me,
'cause I'm already dead!
[gun rattling]
[tense ambient electronic music]
- [Miles] You like
to torture people!
- [Adam] What?
- You like to study pain!
- [Adam] Hey, hey,
hey, I-I-I didn't,
I don't want to hurt nobody!
Stop, stop, stop it, stop it.
Come on, come on!
- And neither did I.
[engine rumbling over tense
ambient electronic music]
[gun cocking]
[car door crunching]
[gate clanging]
[tense ambient music]
- Look, look, you
don't understand.
I was just trying to
purify their souls
for our experiment,
you know that!
I am not a bad person.
- Maybe I'm a bad person.
[gunshot cracking]
It's only when we're close
to death that our minds are--
- Please, please, please
don't, don't shoot!
I-I'm, please, no-no, please!
- Don't, don't what?
[gunshot cracking]
- No, no, no, no!
[Adam groans]
[gasping] Wait [gasps], wait!
Wait [gasps], you
did it [gasping].
Cheryl did, it
worked, it worked!
[gun clicking]
They're gonna come after us,
they're gonna find out
everything about us!
They're gonna find
out everything!
- I burned all my files, Dale.
I suggest you do the same.
[gun rattling]
[distant siren blaring]
- [Dale] What's the
matter with you?
What's the matter with you!
- See ya around.
[Dale gasping over eerie
and ominous ambient music]
[tense pulsing electronic music]
[keyboard clacking]
[electronic buzzing]
[tense pulsing electronic music]
- I was embarrassed in
front of a bunch of people.
I looked like a goddamn fool,
and I don't know why because
I didn't do anything to you.
Maybe you're just sadistic.
You ruined my life.
[buzzing electronic tones]
[buzzing and skittering
electronic tones]
[buzzing electronic tones
over clattering percussion]
- Preserve it, man,
preserve it for us!
Preserve for it for
the fucking guinea pigs
who've been psychologically
raped, day in, day out.
[gasps] My frequency's
unknown, man.
Please.
- [Mysterious Woman]
There is a theory
that there is an entity
that created all
electroneurologic
field of information.
It could actually
create holograms,
become entities in
front of your face.
Call you up on the telephone,
replicate any voice pattern,
whether they be your
friends or parents.
They can have complete
control of all your computers.
You can't get away from it.
[ominous ambient music]
[footsteps clacking over
ominous ambient music]
[ominous and eerie
ambient music]
[traffic humming over
eerie ambient music]
[Tristan coughing]
[traffic whooshing]
[traffic whooshing over
tense electronic music]
- [Tristan] Gotta
listen now, everybody!
They're stalking
us, Victims Channel!
[wheelchair rattling]
[groans] Shit [groans]!
[Tristan gasping]
I gotta get back up, OK.
It's not too late,
gotta listen to me!
Listen to me!
[traffic humming over
ominous ambient music]
[ominous ambient music]
- [Cheryl] My phone
is disconnected.
Did you want to see me, you
know where I am, goodbye.
[Cheryl laughing over
ominous ambient music]
[phone line crunching]
[ominous and eerie
ambient electronic music]
[rhythmic and unsettling
electronic music
with murky bass]