By the end of the Eighties,
one out of every three youth in Chile
were what you could call, marginal...
Candy or spice
CHOLICA I
CHOLICA II CALLING...
CHOLICA I, PLEASE ANSWER.
CHOLICA I,
CHOLICA II HERE
CHOLICA I, PLEASE ANSWER.
I remember the day I felt on this planet,
I was only two megamikes from the goal.
Alone, with no destiny
I decided to proceed with my mission,
On first contact with the natives
learned that they divided time into days,
This I never figured out,
Since all days were the same.
They would always just lie there
As it forsaken...
I decided to give them my message
anyway.
Are you coming or not?
No way Niki
Hey kid! Treat the customer well.
Don't forget that!
You got a bonus!!
Grandpa, is it true you've been here for 30
years?
36! When I started cars were for real.
Solids not like now.
So always the same trip.
You never got bored?
Listen kid, time will teach you
every day has its little things...
You know? Sometimes I got funny ideas,
I scare myself; the world seems so crazy...
Want some advice? Don't waste your
youth.
It's the best part of life.
OK, Let's bet.
OK, lets see now.
A tie!
A tie! That's safe enough
Union Española v/s Everton Is it Everton?
O'Higgins Sucker
Catolica v/s Huachipato
Local!
Union Española v/s Cobreloa
A tie
Visitor
A tie,
O'Higgins v/s Everton
Visitor
Hand me that joint, loco
Here...
Strong, right?
How long are we staying here?
Nothing is happening.
Negra, try to score a cigarette at least.
Shit, only girls get in for free...
Really? Did you score something?
So lets pitch in and buy booze.
You got money or what?
I ain't got one, Bro.
Nothing is happening.
You jerks are all crazy...
What do you mean nothing doing?
With the guy back there it was all
happening.
Go back then...
What's wrong bitch?
What do we do guys?
Santiago is boring tonight.
Let's go to your neighbourhood
Nah! That shit is really boring...
More boring than shit cruising with you
assholes.
Listen to the bitch!
Fuck you assholes!
Got lost bitch! See you in heaven. Got lost!
You don't have the balls to get laid.
Lady D! Hand me your skirt to blow my
nose.
Get lost! Get lost assholes!
Don't get eaten by a shark!
Let's play a game.
It's three pills. So catch one... gets three
wishes.
Baby I'll take one wish
So you can have five wishes.
A little present.
These pills are good shit!
Totally!
The opium of the masses.
Takes away your hunger...
And makes you a bit more stupid.
I'm already getting wired...
Cheek it out guy! It's Negra!
Look at that fucking car!
Bro. Follow Her!
This is wonderful!
Girl, you are trembling!
Are you frightened?
I don't know you.
I'm a little scared.
Fear? You've got to defeat fear.
Otherwise there's no growth.
Look. If I'd been scared,
I would've never crossed the Andes.
Understand?
You could work with me, you know?
Really?
Let's play a game.
A game?
Listen, you give me a present.
And I give you... another present...
OK!
Take off your jacket.
Aaah, now I got it!
I give you a present...
And you give me another present.
Easy!!
Check his pockets!
Don't move asshole!
Shit a car!
A car full of Cops!
Shut up, Motherfucker!
How come you never talk to me?
Do you think I'll spend the rest of my life
screwing in stolen cars?
And where would you like to get laid?
I'm fed up!
Always the same shit.
What are we going to do?
Let's fuck, Negrita...
You know I hate this shit...
I told you, I don't want to screw in this car!
Bye then.
Niki, we've been through a lot
together. Haven't we?
Do you think we might break up one day?
Don't know Negrita. Bye now...
AND THE NAMES OF THE DAYS WERE
MONDAY, TUESDAY, WEDNESDAY,
WITH THEIR GLUE SNIFFING MOONS...
CHOLICA I, LOVER AND OUT.
Didn't I tell you there was no one here?
And the old Lady?
She's out; they took her to the beach...
What's that noise?
The old Lady's ghost...
Don't move!!
Hands up!!
She saw us!
Waste her! Waste her!
Everyday has its little things...
Hey loco, what time is it?
Maybe around five?
Maybe you have something to do?
The chick from Ap.34 should be arriving
soon...
No doubt, the best thing around.
That chick likes money...
But love is much stronger, Bro.
What's up?
Here, cloudy turning to cloudy...
And
You nervous
Listen guy, work I do... all under control.
Go check what's going on around the
corner.
Nasty shit is going on there.
Go on!
What's going on?
Go! Hey, behind there.
And... what beach?
All of them! On the bike, Hmm?
We'll ask the boy's for little present.
Fucker!
Asshole, you gonna hit me again, jerk of f!
So you are going to hit me again,
motherfucker!
You going out with a fucking snoop! Bitch!
You're jealous? Asshole!
You faggot! Go, go with your buddies,
motherfucker!
I'm staying here. I'm leaving this shit!
Leave by yourself, stupid bitch.
Jerk!
Listen Bro. The world is full of chicks...
Don't worry, pretty soon...
Oh? The darling is home!
Hey! That crying is driving me crazy! Do
something!
OK now! Let me do my work.
Sweetheart go work things out with your
husband.
We each have our room.
Don't start with me!
Oh, I shouldn't. You are sick or something!
You just hang out all day!
What do you mean! It's me that hassle
around.
What's going on with you! Stop already
So, You are staying.
Come here this minute!
Well then, will something happen?
Nothing doing, loco...
And with Garganta?
Check it out! Totally far out.
When I was in the joint I had hope.
Getting out, finding something new...
To be free.
Cut that out. At least here the room is
bigger.
And if you fuck up. In you go!
It makes me wonder.
Change that tape. Change the tape!
Shit! What a crybaby.
Hey guy. It's rough. No big deal.
In the joint people have a different
mentality.
They are all winners.
Out here there's no room for you.
Here we are the ones that trickle down.
Those who snatch, and those waiting for
the trickle.
Got it?
Man, we are privileged, chit, privileged!
We haven't got anything to loose, Bro.
I want to be a birdie. I want to be a bird.
Fuck it, we are under fire! Attacked!
It's mass acclaim! Bro!
OK. OK fucker, let's make a pit stop.
I need to take a leak mate.
Partner, hey Bro! Don't leave me!
Motherfucker!
Shit! 2500 watts!
Fuck! Light for everyone.
Thanks Mr. Mayor.
What solid shit!
Solid man! Like you and me!
Hey man Bro! Shit's got future is pure light!
Hey guy, where are you going?
Hey! Hey Loco! Asshole! This fucker!
Are you going crazy?
OK kid, sober up and you are out.
And next time leave the bike at home.
Sleep tight, sweeties.
Guy, Do you have a cigarette?
OK! Time to get up!!
Listen kids, we need you to give us a hand.
We need you for a line up. We need faces.
Behave and you are out first thing in the
morning.
And us boss?
You are too fucking ugly.
Here, stop up, next spot.
Show us your numbers. Get up there.
Look up!
This way lady. Take your time.
I think this is him. It could be
numbers 4 or 5...
I didn't have my glasses. I'm not sure.
OK. And the bicycle
I told you it's my brother in law!
What do you mean I told you, fucker.
What's his name?
The cat
Cat... Cat who?
Orrego. Felipe
Where does he live?
In my apartment. I gave you the address.
Was it with him that you robbed the old
Lady?
But I told you I haven't robbed anything.
I have a job. I'm a mechanic. Ask if you
want.
Why should I steal?
That's what I'd like to know.
Why did you do it?
But I haven't stolen anything.
I was home that day.
Leave home at dawn, or I lose my job.
I support my whole family.
Sure, and your mother is unemployed.
And your baby is sick, Hmm?
It's my sister's baby, and my mother is the
sick one.
Hello? Yes.
Listen kid, my patience is running out.
We'll give you one more chance...
Are we going to be friends?
Better tell us everything.
There's evidence against you.
Wanna talk to you friends? We've got him.
So you can work on your story.
It wasn't me.
Poor guy.
The lady is half blind, and gaga to boot
So what do we do?
Does he have a record?
No, he doesn't
Let's let him go.
OK. Kid, We'll let you go this time.
But, if you've lied. You'll deal with me!
It's over, see. You are all day in a daze.
The police was here asking about you.
It's been very difficult putting all of this
together.
I don't need trouble. Let' s leave it at that.
OK, you go...
haven't told you my story, and I'm already
fired.
Just leave if you don't want to end up in
jail.
You ungrateful bastard!
Drugs are the worst you guys.
They are putting up grass!
They'll plant a lawn.
There, a row of trees, a playground here.
They used to bring the police squad.
Now they bring recreation squad. How
about it?
Democracy Bro. Democracy is here!
Hi! What are you young men up to?
Us? We're just waiting for the grass to
grow.
We want to know what young people think.
We're putting in some green areas,
some playgrounds... etc.
Nice can you imagine? All green.
All you can do here is get bored.
Sometimes we attempt to amuse
ourselves... foolishly.
Drink some beers, take some speed.
And end up pretty fucked up. Right?
Would you have another question?
Listen guy! I smoked some grass too in my
day.
We all have problems. We must work them
out.
We've been forgotten all this time and now
ah?
City Hall has an excellent disposition.
Want you to know you have a friend there.
OK! Good afternoon.
You had so much time and now, you
remember the crazies.
Now that we've gone crazy...
I thought you were coming tomorrow...
can leave if you want...
What have you been up to?
Being good... as always.
It shows. You look good.
I'm changing everything.
I want a total revolution.
Here, a little present.
What a beast!
Let's go...
Come in.
One hour, Bro.
Come in,
Try this on.
It's a bit big. Try another. A tighter one.
Are you getting hairier or what?
Nah... as always.
Well, It's been quite a while since I saw
you...
No, no, no! Let's stop this game
The last time...
Hey you! Going out again? Where are you
going?
Remember it's you sister's birthday
tomorrow.
Yes? How many?
I don't know, 27 or 28.I can't remember.
Don't give me that angelic look... You could
almost fool me.
I heard the number you and friends pulled
the other day.
I've told you. If someone comes offering
stuff...
We say: "Yes" you hear?
If they offer grass. Then it's grass we
want...
Bicycles? Lt' bicycles we want...
Yugoss? It's Yugos we want...
We don't have to be stupid...
How long are you going to be begging?
It's better than nothing,
You don't get it, do you?
We could count blocks...
Let's count blocks all night long...
I no longer sleep.
And this is... a "pelusa"...
OK champ, catch me.
I spoke and we were stuck.
I've got you!
And, the dwarfs!
The dwarfs are going to got us...
And Me?
And you.
Be serious! Loco.
I have a toothache. Loco!
Hey! I've got you!
Me, five hundred and twelve...
You, four hundred and six...
Something is loose. You're dumber than
usual...
My tooth is bursting loco. My tooth Loco!
What did you do with the money I gave you
asshole?
Drugs are the worst! The worst!
And now the fucker complains...
I've got a mission here...
There she is. The same star she tells me.
I've got a mission to fulfill in this world.
The future is ours guy.
What future guy?
The other day this gypsy looked at my
hand...
She looked at me and she started laughing
like crazy.
Must've been your filthy hands...
So, everything is clear.
Can I count on you?
You know we never fail.
That's what we are here for. Right?
So it's the same deal. If you are caught,
I'll claim you stole my car, OK?
If we fuck up... we are fucked.
Nobody loves me!
The world is so cruel!
I'm so ugly!
Cut it out! Feto.
We are almost there!!
Hey! What if the police stops us?
Are you crazy? They don't stop this kind of
car...
To think we've got 4000 Km. Of shoreline
The whole sea.
Right here bro... Here every day! Shit!
And we, stuck in the world's driest spot...
It's just not right...
I'd rather be bored here
than going crazy in that dump.
Hello!
So. What do you want?
Don't remember me?
Oh... Yes. Mr. Gustavito sends you...
Here it is. Tell Mr. Gustavito its grade A,
Last night, we went wild...
It's a present for Mr. Gustavito
Please take him these avocados.
In your name, Lady.
OK. My friend, have a good trip.
Take it easy.
Not bad? Don Pedro seems to like us. Well
done!
Take some if you want.
Check Nacho out! It's ok. It's ok.
Good work!
You can stay if you want to.
We can smoke something, drink
something... OK?
Sure thing!
Manuela.
What a beautiful fish!
So it's a fish!
Nice.
Please stand there. Ah!
You look so beautiful!
Don't you remember me?
Sorry, what's going on?
What's this? A good luck charm?
This is a tool
Can I tell you a secret?
If you want to.
I know you. I've known you for a long time.
Yes? That's nice.
Don't you remember those dawns by the
river?
Where you and I would bathe,
among those gray hippies
You are quite crazy... ah?
But it wasn't in this lifetime. It was
thousands of years ago.
I was a princess and you a fisherman.
I would stare at you as you sailed through
the river.
One day you looked at me.
And we promised ourselves eternal love.
Do you remember now?
Cheers! Mom.
What's going on?
I brought some pisco for us to drink.
What time is it?
I bet you never thought I was once
a great lover.
Lover? Marijuana lover maybe.
I can smell it.
This is nice
Really nice.
Well now I had such a strange dream...
a nice dream.
There was this guy,
I think he was coming for me.
Yes, he was coming for me.
He told me so.
And he started kissing me.
I didn't know what to do.
But I liked it.
He told me we'd meet in another lifetime
we'd meet in another lifetime
and he was coming for me...
I don't know where, but he was taking me.
And?
Then you arrived, and fucked
my dream up!
Is your hair wet?
I was swimming.
You were swimming...
Here, buy yourself a present.
What did you do?
Don't make any questions lady.
You didn't mug anybody.
It was just grass, joints.
Well OK. If it's only joints.
I'm talking, a big party.
On this side, booze! I mean BOOZE Bro.
On this other side: Chicks man.
And there we were. Fooling around.
The girls were kind of stoned,
So we talked to them and shit...
We made plans to get together.
They wanted to know how we scored
the grass...
All of sudden... in the middle of this...
I see fucking Niki having a ball
The fucker goes out to the terrace
And there's this huge pool.
The motherfucker has this
incredible chick with him.
What a chick!
This is good.
Make it roll!
I need guys that can handle it.
That's what we are here for.
This trip is north
This shit is heavy.
You mean it's dangerous?
What's with you mate?
There's nothing for free in life.
Or do people give you things?
Why don't you uncurl you hair jerk!
You can't imagine the amount money you'll
make.
Hi!
What happened the other night
was beautiful!
Yes, it was nice.
A trip. Sometimes I go crazy.
Let's talk another time
I haven't slept a wink.
So, a crazy trip!
Such is life; each one is into his own trip...
You better go...
You knew? I hate to be
played around with...
Bitch!
Get lost!
Asshole!
Onyx, Duot, Tritium, Quatrix,, Fivcola,
Soxtot, Soptrium.
Fucking A!
Everything ok?
Sure!
Let's stop this shit Bro.
We are totally wired!
Niki! Rorro is looking for you.
And what are you up to. So neat...
You would think you bathed.
We are leaving.
What do you mean?
We are going north.
But they are fixing the place up...
There'll be plenty to do.
I hope so.
It seems we'll be there. W e want to have
him up north...
Right, Rorro?
Sure,
Clean slate.
Hey! Don't spend it all... Leave some for the
north OK?
Listen I'm in the business to make money.
Not to front money. Dig?
Some kind of businessman.
Guy... To make money, you've got to front
money.
It's the market economy.
You mean in the country or sharks,
the sharks win...
And what do you want wimps to win?
Hey you! I told you Rorro
was looking for you.
Tell him I'm coming.
What are you two up to?
You seem so edgy.
Nothing, what are you doing in my room?
Why don't split. It's my room after all.
You know what, I'm going to tell on you
I'll turn you in.
What's the big deal? After all I'm the
moneymaker.
You want money?
Here. Take some.
Buy some lunch.
The first rule in this is.
Be clean and know nothing.
I'll say it again. This is big stuff.
Any mess up and we are all fucked.
When you've got to go, you go.
And when are we leaving?
Yesterday!
Front up some money, not like last time.
How old are you?
23 and what are you up to?
Up to here in dust, man.
So that's it, hum...
That's it.
And you want out?
Sure thing.
So...
The north awaits you kid.
Life or death.
We're talking big money Bro.
Fucking red alert, no fuck-ups.
I at least will grab the money,
grab the old lady and split.
We'll give the guys some plant,
a huge lawn...
Shit, a fucking swimming pool
With our name on a plate
so they wont forget us.
Candy or spice?
Candy.
Life or death?
Life, always life.
A voice of alert, arms in the evening...
Arms at night. Nothing to fear...
Candy or spice
Spice!
Heaven or Earth?
Earth!
Life or death?
Hey, what's your game?
Walking blindly by the abyss.
Quickly obeying a destiny.
It's that crazy chick again.
I have already forgiven you...
Walking blindly by the abyss.
Quickly obeying a destiny.
Your move.
You've got me.
Again...
Let's play one more.
Pilot approaching runaway.
Centaury space ship ready to take of f.
Over Cholica I...
Game over shit head.
Hey! Be cool.
I'll show you jerk!
Come, asshole!
Catch him!
Don't move man, you may die.
Nacho, Bro!
Nacho...
Niki!
I would've liked to be a sailor.
Well now I sail the desert.
My God! We are all alone in the desert,
no one to save us.
Poor things, no one to save us...
Liqui Molly, Sweetheart!
Occasionally she got moody...
What brings you here?
We are studying the ozone layer...
In the desert...
It's all fate.
You got a cigarette?
What's up?
Witch way is it?
Candy or spice?
Or you want to go back?
Playing cards on the wall fuckers...
Lockers to the right...
This is it!
What's going on?
What are you doing there?
Nothing, be cool!
What are you doing? Answer!
This kid has got to learn.
In this desert we're the bosses!
Are you ok?
He's ok.
You've got what you wanted;
now you can go.
And?
There was no answer.
What's today?
Thursday.
He told me to call today at this time.
Who is it?
Delivery,
to uncle.
One moment.
So, no problems, everything ok?
No problem, beautiful trip.
Let's see the package.
The money first, it's five bills.
What do you mean five bills?
The deal was with you and Nacho.
He's out
So it's half.
Same deal. Five bills.
Check out this asshole. Shit!
OK! So go get the stuff.
The money first.
Shit!
Let's make it now.
Let's go!
Hold it! Don't move!
Take cover!
Let's go!
Stop, stop asshole! Stop!
Wake up son of a bitch!
Wake up you creeps!
Niki is here!
Here you creeps,
Nacho sends you this shit!
Let's go! Everything's ok.
Walking blindly by the abyss...
Where ever you might be... If you
remember us...
And they called there days,
Monday, Tuesday,
Wednesday...
They say the street will take care of you...
But they'll crack your skull every time.
So everybody has a blade.
CHOLICA I, THE PLANET CALLING...
CHOLICA I, HERE WE ARE...
GREETINGS.