From 2013 to 2015, civil war
tore the Central African Republic apart.
Seleka and Anti-Balaka militias clashed,
pitting Muslims and Christians against each other.
Thousands of people were killed,
a million were displaced.
Camille Lepage covered the conflict
from October 2013 to May 2014.
Central African Republic – May 12, 2014
Blue Unit, Blue Unit!
Blue listening.
There's a convoy advancing in our direction.
A truck and a dozen motorcycles.
David, can you see if they're armed?
Affirmative. They're armed. I see AKs...
They're armed. It's a group of Anti-Balaka.
What do we do?
I repeat. Anti-Balaka approaching.
Prepare to establish contact. Take no risks.
Ok, preparing to establish contact.
David, stay above.
In position.
Stefan, to the left. Galiano, to the right.
Calm down! I can't hear what you're saying.
Turn off the engines.
Lower your weapon.
Can we come forward?
What's going on?
Lower your weapon.
Calm down.
Does anyone speak French here?
Everyone, calm down.
What's going on?
Look.
What's underneath?
Blue Unit, there are five bodies in the vehicle.
Four Central Africans and one white woman.
Perpignan – September 7, 2013
Festival of Photojournalism "Visa pour l'image"
Pardon.
Thanks.
Got it all? – Yeah.
Don't take any risks.
I promise.
You promise?
You said that last time and took some anyway.
Be careful.
The Central African Republic (CAR).
Since their coup in March 2013,
Seleka rebels have sowed terror.
On November 16, they assassinate a judge.
Bangui – November 22, 2013
You're all students? – All of us.
What are you studying? – Us three, Economy.
At the university over there?
You're a journalist? – Yeah.
You work for? – I'm a photographer.
You have to talk about us and our situation.
That's why I'm here. – Tell the world.
We're sick of it! We want the truth.
We're suffering.
Is this the campus?
Yeah!
You have class here? – We live here.
Leïla, are you Muslim? – No, I'm Christian.
But isn't your name...
My father's Muslim.
Keep your shoes on.
I'm not the President! It says "no exceptions."
You're our guest. We don't mind.
So whose room is this?
The boys' room.
Just boys? – Yes, four of us.
This is my bed.
And that's your guitar? – Yep.
Everyone, get together for a group photo.
Smile!
No running water?
No, we go downstairs to get it.
Since when?
Over ten years.
Decades.
Did the coup change things? – A lot.
Like what? – Lots of robbing, killing.
Lots of violence. – Like during the mutinies.
No, no...
Before the Muslims, things were good.
Why accuse the Muslims? – It's true.
Muslims aren't all Seleka. Look at Abdou.
We're the first victims.
My cousin was robbed and tortured.
Our entire neighborhood was pillaged.
You're talking about one cousin.
I don't agree.
It's different. – Muslims brought the Seleka.
Don't lump them all together.
It's the Muslims!
You support the Seleka, don't you? – Idiot.
I'm gonna engage you. – You should!
What does "engage" mean?
I'm gonna smack him! He's a thug!
I'm 25 years old. – 25?
You're not scared coming to a country in crisis?
Am I too old or too young?
Too young!
You're not afraid of the shooting?
I'm interested. – Really?
Interested in what?
What good does it do us?
Your pictures. – What do we get out of it?
When you protest,
what do you get?
We do it for the country.
It's the same for me.
If I wanted to become rich, I wouldn't be here.
I'm here because...
I want to show what's happening.
I want to support your country,
and incite people to come help.
Are you married?
You always talk about money!
We can talk about other things.
Are you married?
No.
Any children? – No.
Are your parents worried? – Yes.
Aren't they afraid?
Yes, but they let me come.
And you're not afraid?
I'm interested in telling your story.
You're interested, ok,
but aren't you afraid of the Seleka?
No.
It's 150. Don't pay him more.
We'll see you tomorrow. – See you then!
Chicken shawarma with garlic sauce.
And cabbage.
How's your family?
How's your family? – Fine, thank you. You?
Give me 500 francs. – I did this morning!
Give 500!
We're hungry.
Here.
Share it.
Share it! That's all I have.
Early December 2013.
The capital is calm, but war wages in the North.
The Seleka are pillaging and burning villages.
The population forms self-defense militias:
the Anti-Balaka.
Rodrigue, come here. Prepare table 7.
What do you want? – A beer.
What about some sauerkraut? – No.
Excuse me, are you journalists?
Yes. What gave us away?
My name is Camille. I'm a photographer.
I'm François, journalist.
François Quessemand from Le Monde. – Exactly.
I'm Camille Lepage.
I sent you some pictures via email.
Ok. I didn't reply?
No. – I'll do it soon.
I wanted to know if by chance
you needed a photographer.
I'm accompanied by this ravishing creature.
Hi. – Michaël Zumstein.
Pleased to meet you.
Mathias Fincher.
Your pictures of Gaza in the New York Times
were simply...
They were amazing. – Thank you.
So, what are your plans here?
We hope to go north tomorrow.
Toward Bossangoa?
You're interested in the Anti-Balaka?
I heard they might attack Bangui.
That's the rumor.
With machetes...
Can I come in the car with you?
Frankly, alone it's hard financially.
We would've been happy to, but...
It's not possible.
At least, not this time.
Sorry.
Another time?
Ok, fine. Enjoy your meal.
Let's call it!
Call the gozo!
Do you know any Anti-Balaka?
Yes, lots of people from my neighborhood.
Friends, too.
So you know lots of people there?
Even my cousin is there.
How long has he been there?
Last month. The Seleka came for him.
But he escaped.
Near Bossangoa?
Yeah, near Paoua, Bossangoa.
Are they still there?
Yes.
And if I wanted to meet them?
It's tricky.
It'll be complicated.
Djotodia, resign!
The Seleka just killed again!
Take pictures! The world has to know!
Djotodia, resign!
A journalist!
Leave her alone!
Look! I work here often.
I'm here all the time. It's ok.
It's Camille.
Come in.
What's going on?
The Seleka came last night.
Why didn't you call me?
They were everywhere.
What were they looking for?
Cyril. They must've spotted him at the protest.
Because of his rap.
All I did was sing. – Against the Seleka!
Someone snitched.
You think they were looking for you?
I'm absolutely sure of it.
They were everywhere in the building.
They'll come back.
That's what scares me.
We all hid on the roof yesterday.
Do you have a place to go? – His sister's.
But they're everywhere!
They won't look for you there.
Staying here is too dangerous.
Call if anything happens. – Ok.
Wait...
Here. Take it.
Did you want to go with him?
No.
Cyril's your boyfriend!
What?
Tell me!
Come on, you can tell me!
Tell you what? – That he's your boyfriend.
Is it Abdou?
With his crazy eyes!
Want another? – Yes, thanks.
Rodrigue?
Can we have another round, please?
For my generation, it was Bosnia, Sarajevo.
It was insane.
And I continued...
Iraq, Afghanistan...
I feel like I've had several lives, like a spy.
You never felt like staying put?
Not really.
Strange thing, going from country to country.
No... – Isn't it frustrating?
No, it's exciting.
Even without getting to know the people?
Getting to know the people? – Yeah.
Are you kidding?
You can't from opposite sides of the camera.
What can you build? You're going back to France.
You don't get to know people.
You can't imagine what they're going through.
You're screwed if you do that. Be careful!
Well, I don't know...
How about you? Get anything published?
In South Sudan, I worked for AFP.
Then I had some photos published.
Right now, it's pretty rough.
If France intervenes, you'll have work.
Did you contact Libération?
Wrote to the photo department. Nothing.
Doesn't surprise me. Call Maria.
Maria Malagardis. On my behalf.
Ok. What does she do?
She's in charge of Africa.
Ok.
Thanks a lot.
It's nothing.
Thursday, December 5, 2013
Not now, not now. Tomorrow.
Easy!
Go home! – It's fine!
You're nuts walking here. – I had to leave!
Are the Anti-Balaka attacking?
They were repelled.
The north of town is being hit: PK10, Boy-Rabe.
You can't stay over there.
We'll find you a room here.
I'll pay three times that.
However much you want.
Where is this van?
Find a car?
Hey.
No one can bring it?
Out of 3,500 guys, no one can bring a van?
I don't give a shit. I'm paying!
Fuck me! The only vehicle in Bangui.
I know. – No driver?
Nope. Know why? They're all afraid.
I found 2 grenades in the glove compartment.
I sent him home with twice the pay
and kept the vehicle.
Mathias! We have to get going.
Bringing your chick? – Shut up.
Have a problem with chicks?
Thanks all the same.
She's funny. – Yeah, hilarious.
It's deserted.
Hello, François Quessemand,
from Le Monde.
Any update on the French intervention?
Are they deploying today?
Hello? I was...
Ask where.
He hung up on me.
We're going to the hospital.
Then to PK5 on the Muslim side.
Stop! – What the hell is that?
Holy shit.
12:40 pm, Community Hospital morgue
The stench...
See the ones that just arrived?
There are some outside, too. Go see.
Gimme a sec.
Fuck! You never listen!
Don't talk to me like that!
You keep getting in the way!
She's always in front!
We keep telling you. – Ballbreaker!
Go fuck yourself!
The CAR is holding its breath.
Since last March, chaos has been complete.
The French Army may intervene in coming days.
They're awaiting the UN's green light
and a resolution in coming hours.
The French have to come, for fuck's sake!
They're waiting for the UN's mandate.
It's a bloodbath. They just need to come!
We've intervened without a mandate too many times.
That's what you don't get.
Mandate, my ass! It won't change a thing.
We're out front.
Yes, in front of the shop.
The Seleka went door to door,
they killed my neighbor and came to my place.
Where were you? – I hid behind the fridge.
The others, under the bed.
Luckily, they didn't find us.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the situation in the CAR has become alarming
and frightening.
Massacres are still going on
as I speak.
In the face of such chaos,
the Security Council
unanimously adopted a resolution
to provide security,
restore stability
and protect the population.
France will support this operation.
Shut up.
...we owe assistance and solidarity...
Work's on its way.
I give them 10 min to call.
"Small country!" It's bigger than France.
"A country that is our friend."
Yes, speaking.
It's Libération!
Can I send them tonight?
What else? Show me.
C'mon, agree already! – Not that one.
Not that one? – This one and the other one.
Hit send.
Here's to your publication.
To Camille!
To France!
December 8, 2013
Arrival of French troops in the CAR
Walk!
We're pillaging the Muslims.
December 10, 2013 – Fouh Mosque
...several armored troop vehicles.
Boali Camp command
says the imminent French reinforcement
coming from Cameroun and Gabon
already has a dissuasive effect.
But witnesses speak of pillaging and violence
in certain neighborhoods.
The torrential rain
may calm Christian and Muslim armed gangs.
Many casualties yesterday.
80 bodies, some burnt, inside a mosque,
many cadavers along the roads,
and 50 bodies were brought to the local morgue.
The wounded need treatment in a climate of fear.
The streets are clear of traffic. A supermarket...
During Seleka disarmament,
the Anti-Balaka went on the offensive
hunting down the last Muslims in poorer districts.
France watched, helpless,
the rising tide of violence.
Keep driving.
Keep going.
Don't stop.
We're the press!
Calm down!
Accelerate.
Journalist!
We're the press! Calm down!
Easy!
We're through.
It's over.
That's too much.
5,000 is too expensive.
And for pay-on-arrival?
Just a minute.
You have enough?
I'll pay half now, half on arrival.
I can give you the money.
No, it's ok. – I can lend you money.
My brother will pay the other half.
You have enough for the trip and 3 days of food?
I'm good, thanks.
It's fine.
Take care of yourself. – Thanks.
Call when you reach Cameroun.
I'll stay in touch.
I need your number there.
I'll call you once I get there.
He's pay-on-arrival.
2,500 now.
Take care of yourself.
Goodbye.
We stay in touch?
We stay in touch.
Come in.
What are you doing here?
I was looking for you. – How are you?
It's been days since you disappeared.
I'm sorry. I've been so busy with work.
Don't drop friends like that!
I thought you might've left.
I'm sorry. How are you?
It's heated in your neighborhood.
People are fleeing because they're scared.
They're taking shelter at the airport.
Have you fled too?
No, I'm not scared.
We're waiting to see how things evolve.
We will die here!
Obey the soldiers! Move back!
Shit, it's gory.
You were there all day? – Yeah.
They're cutting his dick off.
Did you photograph that too?
Her baptism by fire. – What a baptism...
Ok, I'm sending it.
You can't send that!
Would you rather we took pictures of the sunset?
Imagine if the victim's family sees these photos.
Bullshit argument.
In France, you'd think differently.
This isn't France. People are getting macheted!
Where's these photos' journalistic value?
It's gratuitous. – Gratuitous?
They tell the story of what's happening here!
Gratuitous, my ass.
They tell that Africans are savages?
Are you fucking nuts?
We're not inventing the violence!
Ever wonder if it's not for our benefit?
"Take pictures!" They're putting on a show.
I was a friend of Leïla's.
We met at the university.
She told me about you. You're Camille?
Thank you. – I was very fond of her.
That's kind of you.
Thank you.
My condolences.
The Seleka forced an elder out of this house
and Leïla tried to intervene.
They called her a slut!
She said, "My name is Leïla."
A Muslim name.
"How dare you say that!" And they killed her.
We'll never have peace with the Muslims here.
Cyril is right!
We must clean the country.
But it's their country, too! They were born here.
They're all the same!
We take them in and look what they do!
It won't go unpunished. – Meaning what?
That's your answer? Use your head!
You're lecturing me? That's the problem with you!
You think this is your country.
This isn't your home, ok?
Colonization is over! – What's your point?
You destroy all our leaders.
You killed Boganda, ousted David Dacko.
And Bokassa, too!
And Patassé! – You wreak havoc!
Who is "you"? Me?
You think you're different?
You're the same. All you want is your photos!
You come, you take, and you leave!
You're a great photographer.
You are.
And you know it.
You need to protect yourself.
It's time to think about you.
I mean it.
It's important.
It's important, darling.
Otherwise, you won't be able to continue.
You need to take a step back, have some fun.
Let's go for a walk.
Ok?
Come on.
Put your shoes on!
I don't feel like it.
Come on, Camille.
It'll be good for you.
I'm so tired.
No, wait! She's cheating!
You used both hands!
Angers – December 25, 2013
You'd never stooped so low!
She's been my cross to carry for years!
For 5 years, she was covered in pimples!
No! You're so mean!
You can't make fun of that!
She kept whining,
"I'm ugly, I'm fat, no one loves me!"
Only I could stand her.
You loved me.
Yes, I loved you.
Then, she bloomed into a photographer!
Have you heard?
She decided to save Africa!
She said, "All those poor little black people!
It's not fair!
I will speak out for those who suffer!
Cursed countries don't exist! I'm going!
Mom, can you help me out for a few months?
I mean a few years!"
"I won't do an internship, Mom. Don't insist.
No, I won't work in France!
I have important battles to fight."
Wait, hello?
The New York Times?
Yes, yes...
It's the New York Times!
Yes, it's Camille Lepage.
Camille 'The Page'."
Loser alert! – Thanks a lot.
Then one day, I was at the dentist's
and I read a magazine in the waiting room.
What do I see? Camille’s 5-page photo spread.
Fuck! That's my sister!
Hey guys! You, with the cavity, look at this!
My sister took these!
I was so proud.
Look what she's achieved.
All that to say,
little sis', I wasn't very supportive,
because I had doubts.
It seemed impossible to me.
But...
you did it.
What you've done is amazing.
I'm so proud of you. – We all are.
There's no reason to be.
You crazy or what?
If France intervened, it's because of you.
But what will it change for them?
I don't know what to tell you.
Boys?
Zero in that department.
Zero?
Not even one.
When's the last time you had sex, girl?
Please don't start!
What happened?
It's complicated.
Not even a flirt with a student?
No.
You met people, didn't you?
Of course.
But being white over there sucks.
You meet people, but ultimately...
The star is back? – How are you?
When'd you get back? – A few days ago.
You going back? – Not sure yet.
How was it over there?
Cheers!
Was it hard, Camille? – What?
All the violence.
The horrible images. Did you see all that?
What? – Did you see that?
Yep. – It's nuts.
Yep, totally.
Another one, please.
Pleased to meet you. We can kiss hello.
Shall we go to my office?
Coffee? – No, thank you.
Jill, this is Camille.
She took the CAR pictures for us.
Nice to meet you. Great job.
Thomas, this is Camille Lepage.
You did a great job. – Thank you.
Excuse me.
None of it interests you?
I'm proposing totally different things.
We've already talked about the CAR.
We're done.
Unless something new happens.
Things are happening!
Hundreds of thousands of refugees.
People are dying! What more do you want?
I know.
What about Ukraine?
What do you say? How about going to Ukraine?
I don't understand.
Jan Andersen is going for us.
What do you think?
Me going to Ukraine?
I'm talking about the CAR.
You're not going to become a specialist of CAR.
Think about Ukraine.
Easy, easy.
I'm here to see Cyril.
He's a student.
You want a cigarette?
Yeah. Give me a cigarette.
Do you know him? He's tall and thin.
No? He didn't come here?
Give me three. – No.
I'm giving you one.
What's your name? – Death Defier.
And you? – Five Minutes.
Five Minutes? And you're Two Minutes?
Who's One Minute?
I'm Yanguiré. Who are you?
Camille.
Why're you here? – I'm looking for my friend.
You're a spy.
I'm just looking for Cyril.
He's not here? Ok, I'm going then.
You're pretty.
Thanks. – I love you.
You love me?
That was fast!
Don't touch my bag.
Stop.
Easy! Calm down!
Get back to your posts!
Why are you here?
I was looking for my friend Cyril.
Who is Cyril?
A friend. He's not here. I'll go.
Do I look stupid?
No, I didn't mean... – Give me that!
To the office!
I don't need to go to the office. Wait!
Give me my phone.
Forget the office.
My taxi is waiting. Easy!
I'm going. – Move!
Back off!
Good day to you, sir. – At ease.
Hello.
Speak out loud!
Yes, that's me.
Why did you come in secret?
I didn't. I have an authorization.
I don't understand what you're saying.
I'm not with RFI radio. – You're a spy!
A spy? – Yes!
Calm down!
I don't... – We're not criminals!
You don't know what's going on here.
You say what suits you.
I've been here a long time.
I was here when Judge Bria was killed.
Were you?
I was with Tanguy Rézidou's family
when they pulled out the body. I was here.
And when Fleury Doumana was killed, I was here.
On December 5, I went to Boy-Rabe.
You've been here since December?
Do you like it here?
It's my new home.
You have a gun. Does that mean you're a chief?
They trust me.
They are young. My age.
We can laugh together, make jokes...
Do they realize the violence they commit?
Do they realize how horrific their actions are?
When someone has killed,
can you see it in their eyes?
You sure you want to come with us?
I'm sure!
Thank you!
Did you get some sleep? – Yeah.
Can I take your picture?
Yes.
What does that mean?
I don't understand.
He says, you're tiring with your pictures.
I don't speak French.
My pictures tire you out?
No.
It bothers you? – Yes.
It's not a problem.
So many photos. Too many.
What did he say?
The Chief must come...
quickly, so we can attack in Bambari.
The Seleka have already caused a lot of trouble.
Understand?
You're in a hurry to go?
Yes.
You're not afraid of dying?
No.
I'm fighting for my country.
If I die...
that's a good thing.
Because I'm fighting for my country.
If I die, my little boy will...
He'll be sad?
Yes.
My French isn't good.
You're doing a good job. I understand you.
Fire!
I don't understand.
That's bath water?
A little.
I'll take this off.
The Seleka killed her husband
and her son.
My aunt spent two months in the bush.
Living on roots and leaves.
The Seleka killed a lot of people here.
You understand the hell we live in?
You've killed too.
What's the idea? An eye for an eye?
If everyone thinks like that, nothing will change.
You hunt down the Fulani, too. You never let up.
And you wonder why they rebel?
Don't talk to me like that.
I didn't bring you here to get lectured.
If you're not happy,
go back to Bangui.
Here.
Eat.
You're not eating with us?
You're her guest. You have to eat. Eat.
You're getting better at that.
Thank you.
I told her how you helped me pay for the taxi
when the Seleka came for me.
She thinks you saved my life.
No, thank you for your kindness.
What do you think about what Cyril does?
What do you think about the Anti-Balaka?
She wants you to take me to France
for a better life.
But if everyone leaves for France...
This is where things need to change.
The country needs to be re-built.
I love your country.
See, I'm here, not in France.
I don't live in France.
Here.
All good? – Thank you.
Have everything you need?
Sometimes I wake up wondering what I'm doing here.
Alone in the middle of this war that's not mine.
What would I be doing in France?
I'd have a job somewhere.
We'd go for drinks and dance all night.
Narcisse?
Why do I feel so good here?
I'll always be a foreigner to them.
A white woman.
And yet,
I feel more at home here than anywhere else.
I've always wanted to be here.
Alive like never before.
With my brothers.
My human brothers.
How are you?
Good.
Hey! – How are you, Camille?
And you? – Good.
On May 12, 2014,
Camille Lepage was caught in an ambush
with the Anti-Balaka she was accompanying.
Camille, the chief and three fighters
were killed instantly.
This film is based on true events.
It is dedicated to all the victims
of the Central African Republic crisis.