Subs Fixed By
Pacman
Father
Sister
Father, sister
Dearest voices
l have found you
And l don't know how
Father, sister
l hear your voices
But am l dreamin'?
Are you here right now?
Can you tell me?
How shall l see you
through my tears?
Please tell me
How shall l see you
through my tears?
l need to know
How shall l see you
through my tears?
Father, sister
The gods have spoken
l bring a promise
A holy vow
A world that casts you out,
forgives you
And those who blame you
Sing your praises now
So can you tell me?
How shall l see you
through my tears?
Please tell me
How shall l see you
through my tears?
l need to know
How shall l see you
through my tears?
Yeah, yeah, yeah
To all the critics out there,
l know they're going to review this,
and l know they're
gonna try to knock me--
is it okay if l say this
to camera, Amber?
l only am who l am
'cause l was born that way.
l have a gift, and l'm trying not
to be selfish about it, but to use it.
lf you're gonna knock me for that,
that's your problem.
Jealousy will get you nowhere.
And l'm gonna keep rockin' on.
Destiny
brings you back to me
Child, l'm so glad l'm here
There's hope for me,
there's a prophecy
Destiny
brings you back to me
A world that casts you out
May forgive you now
Destiny
brings you back to me
l've been waiting for a sign
To ease my troubled mind
Ellen, what's the matter with you?
Don't tell Mom l'm taking you
to your stupid junior prom.
Get out of here!
Your brother!
How gross is that?
They don't know
you're my brother.
Please, Ben.
You have to. l'll pay you.
Find someone
who's not related to you.
Loser.
How shall l see you
through my tears?
Please tell me
How shall l see you
through my tears?
l need to know
How shall l see you
through my tears?
Yeah, yeah, yeah
How shall l see you
through my tears?
When l'm crying tears of sadness
How shall l see you
through my tears?
Won't you turn them
into tears of gladness?
How shall l see you
through my tears?
Yeah, yeah, yeah
Tears
What are you doing here?
Aren't you, like, 30?
Come on!
Excuse me, is there someplace
we're supposed to check in?
Over there.
- ls this your first summer?
- l was here last year.
Remember? We were in
Night. Mother together.
You're Jill Simmons.
My name's Fritzi.
Fritzi. Of course.
Let me.
You have the number
at the ship.
Call me whenever you need me.
This is Glen,
the camp director.
- l know.
- Go to him if you have a problem.
That's enough, Mom.
You're embarrassing me.
We'll take very good care of him.
- Give me a hug.
- l can't breathe!
Jenna!
My role model
in everything Nubian.
What are you doing here?
l thought you had to go to
Weight Watchers Camp this summer.
We wanted her to,
but she insisted on
going back to Camp Ovation.
So we compromised
and had her jaw wired shut.
You can hardly tell.
l dim the lights
and think about you
Spend sleepless nights
You said you loved me
Buddy Miller,
sports counselor.
- We have a sports counselor?
- Of course we do.
You gonna play some softball
this summer?
No.
Michael!
- How you doin', babe?
- Why weren't you on the bus?
My sister drove me here.
l'm staying with her.
My God, your face.
He tried to go to his junior prom
in fishnets and heels.
My junior prom,
l stayed home with
a roll of cookie dough and TV Land.
l watched my junior prom
from outside in the bushes
for three hours.
That's so Stella Dallas.
ls Bert Hanley
really directing here this summer?
l thought he retired.
- l thought he died.
- He might have.
He was supposed to
be here two days ago.
How does that happen?
He used to be huge.
He hasn't had a hit
since Childrehs Crusade.
He never wrote another show.
l hope he directs the benefit
this summer.
What are you singing
for auditions for the first show?
- Doht Raih oh My Parade.
- That's original.
With the tugboat.
What is that supposed to be?
How you doing?
My name's Vlad.
Okay if l use those drawers?
You can go into
anybody's drawers you like.
l don't think
you'll get an argument.
Just ignore him.
That's what he's used to.
l'm Ellen, this is Shaun
and Spitzer and Michael.
Bathroom?
Thirty-foot rule.
- No way!
- What's that?
Michael has to stay 30 feet away
until we know if he's straight or gay.
lf he's gay, l'm Tyne Daly.
Could someone please shut her up?
Next.
Childhood living
ls easy to do
The things you wanted
l bought them for you
Graceless lady
You know who l am
You know l can't let you
Slide through my hands
Wild horses
Couldn't drag me away
Wild, wild horses
A boy.
An honest-to-God straight boy.
Cast lists are up.
l will go insane if l don't get
into Promises. Promises.
l'm in it!
Midhight Suh?
Old.
Lost.
Two thousand sunsets,
yet not one sunrise.
No, no, no, no!
God damn you all!
You piss on the memory
of the greatest playwright
of the 20th century.
ln Cuba we took our lives
in our hands performing her work,
waiting for Castro's thugs
to burst in and arrest us!
l don't understand
what l'm saying.
Of course you don't,
you middle-class piece of shit!
- l'm doing the best l can.
- That's what's so tragic.
Leave her alone.
How about you, then?
Have you had even
one painful moment in your life
since the doctor slapped you
on your ass when you were born?
- Yeah.
- Tell me, then.
Tell me
your most painful moment,
the one that makes you convulse
with sobs when you think of it.
Why would l do that
in front of three strangers?
To be able to do it
in front of 3,000.
Back to the top, and try not to
screw up the blocking this time.
Eyes, eyes, nostrils,
silent scream.
l have to go to the bathroom.
Piss in the Dumpster.
Start again!
How was your first day
of rehearsal?
lt was okay.
l'm a little out of my element.
We really do a new show
every two weeks?
And a benefit
at the end of the summer.
Jeez!
Ellen said you were her hero today
with that crazy director.
Can l ask you
something personal?
What made you come here?
l want to act. Why?
We just don't get many like you.
Can l ask you something personal?
Yeah.
You're gay, right?
How do you know?
Have you ever experimented
with heterosexuality?
You mean sleep with a straight guy?
What for?
- A girl.
- l can't even straighten my hair.
That's too bad.
You'd be a total playa.
Got that whole Latin thing going.
Get a girl alone,
throw on some salsa,
whisper a little Spanish in her ear.
- You'd make out like a bandit.
- l'll keep that in mind.
ls that your father?
That's Stephen Sondheim.
The greatest songwriter
in musical theater.
l don't talk to my parents.
- Why not?
- Enough.
l have to keep
some kind of mystery.
You'll grow bored with me
and move on to someone younger.
- Good night, Mike.
- 'Night, Vlad.
Did he call me Mike?
Can l help you?
l'm not sure
where l'm supposed to go.
- l'm Bert Hanley.
- lt's about time.
Where have you been?
You were supposed to
be here two days ago.
You're right.
What's the use in lying?
- l've been drinking for 72 hours.
- You've been drinking?
Not the way you make it sound
when you say, ''Drinking?!''
l'm fine now, really.
Let's get started.
l'll get those.
l assumed that we would have
some adult time to ourselves.
What show am l doing, anyway?
Good times and bum times,
l've seen them all
And, my dear,
l'm still here
Plush velvet sometimes,
sometimes just pretzels and beer
But l'm here
l've run the gamut ''A'' to ''Z''
Three cheers and damn it,
cest la vie
l got through all of last year
And l'm here
Lord knows,
at least l was there
And l'm here
Look who's here
l'm still here
- Hi.
My name's Vlad.
l don't mean
to bother you or anything.
l just wanted to tell you
how excited l am that you're here.
l did a production
of The Childrehs Crusade
at school this spring.
At first l did it
just to get close to this girl.
But then it was so good.
lt really took the characters
of the kids so seriously.
That's really kind of you to say.
That song  Sihg for You.
l listened to the record,
like, a hundred times
just to get the chords right
on my guitar.
lt's not out on CD.
Did you know that?
Yeah, l knew that.
So, what shows have you done
since then, Mr. Hanley?
Thank you very much
for coming by to visit, Vlad.
Thank you.
Just give me a break.
You little ass-kisser.
One, two, three, four.
Quit dragging!
Y'all better get your asses
used to less sleep
'cause we're gonna have
rehearsal all morning.
Then lunch,
then rehearsal.
Then dinner,
And the whole thing
starts all over again the next day.
Miss Allen, we've all seen
the beginning of Fame.
Fame. huh?
- They do that on Fame?
- No.
Again!
One, two, three, four.
'Night, Jenna.
Shut up! Start again!
Eyes, eyes, nostrils!
Silent scream!
You're really talented.
l don't understand
a single word of this crap,
but you do it
with such conviction.
A guy like you could have a really
lucky summer in a place like this.
l'm starting to get that idea.
Look. First star.
l know my wish.
Changing the subject.
Do you have
any brothers or sisters?
Four brothers--
two older, two younger.
Must be tough when
the middle child is the special one.
- Throws everything out of whack.
- Special? Yeah.
l don't even remember
the last time
my parents called me
by the right name.
- You don't think you're special?
- No.
Seriously.
l don't mean like
dorky boy-band kind of special,
which l'm sure
you get all the time, but...
There's something really there.
Something substantial.
And you deserve
something substantial in return.
Somebody hit me with a rock
so l shut up.
No. Made me feel great.
lt's cold.
Come here.
That worked.
ts 1 0 a.m.
Everybody should be ih class.
Here we are.
Jeez.
Be it ever so humble...
What's up, Fritzi?
Would you like Fritzi
to fix you a bug juice or something?
No.
Leave us.
Bye, Fritzi.
Does she work for you now?
She likes to do little things for me.
lt makes her feel like she belongs.
l'm supposed to be
running lines with Ellen.
She'll have the whole summer to do
that brother-sister bonding thing
she does with all the boys.
Sit.
You said you had
a fantastic surprise for me.
What is it?
Surprise.
l'm going to ask
if l can dance with Stella Jolla
in the ''Turkey Lurkey'' number.
l've been practicing really hard.
That's the part Jill wants to play.
''Turkey Lurkey''
is the best number in the show.
l know.
l took dance classes all winter.
Good for you.
The only thing is, it's a '60s show.
That means tight little miniskirts.
l'm just trying to be a friend.
What are you saying,
that everyone would see my legs?
Not that they're so bad.
They're just a little chunky.
But the halter tops.
l'd worry about my rolls
jiggling around in the spotlight.
Whereas the secretary character
has some great one-liners
and wears sensible suits.
We just love it here.
We see a show every summer.
What did we
see the kids do last year?
Wit.
Wit. right.
Dark, but really entertaining.
lt's turkey lurkey time
Tom Turkey ran away,
but he just came home
lt's turkey lurkey time
He's really home to stay,
never one to roam
Let's make a wish,
and may all our wishes come true
A snowy, blowy Christmas,
a mistletoey Christmas
A turkey lurkey Christmas to you
lt's Loosey Goosey time
She was a gadabout,
but she's back again
lt's Loosey Goosey time
Her time is running out,
and we all know when
Let's make a wish,
and may all our wishes come true
A snowy, blowy Christmas,
a mistletoey Christmas
A Loosey Goosey Christmas to you
Turkey lurkey,
Loosey Goosey
Some for Uncle Joe,
some for Cousin Lucy
Everybody gather round the table
Dig in, dinner's being served
Eat all the turkey
you are able
Can't you see a partridge
in a pear tree?
Climb up
and bring it down for me
That's something l would like to see
A snowy, blowy Christmas,
a mistletoey Christmas
A turkey lurkey Christmas to you
Jingle bells, jingle bells
l'm still here
Sadness.
Vlad, your cat's dead.
l'm sorry.
He was hit by a car
this afternoon.
Vlad, your mom's dead.
l'm sorry.
She got nailed
by a car this afternoon.
Sorry.
l like to practice in the mirror.
Your parents coming
to your show?
Jesus, you still haven't called 'em?
What are you going to do
when you have to go home?
l'm not going home.
- Where you going to live?
- l'll find an apartment.
- You'll end up on a milk carton.
- They haven't called me, either.
How much you wanna bet
they don't call me on my birthday?
Then you have to be
bigger than them.
How often are you going
to get cast as Romeo?
l mean it. Call 'em.
Besides, who can resist you
in them tights?
- Are you blushing?
- You kidding?
l'm doing everything
but bat my eyes.
Call 'em.
Buddy Miller,
sports counselor.
Remember me?
Think fast.
''Dear Mr. Flores,
the school has determined that
''due to your refusal
to wear either a tuxedo
''or an ankle-length formal gown,
you failed to meet the dress code,
''and therefore
appropriate action was taken
in refusing you entrance
to this year's junior prom.''
You didn't get in
because of your hemline?
l've been looking all over for you.
- What are you drinking?
- Chicken breast.
Don't you think
that's a little extreme?
lt's her parents' idea, the pricks.
- lt's like some Nazi experiment.
- They're just looking out for me.
You're only a few pounds
heavier than Ellen.
Tell me something--
isn't it a pain in the ass
to put on
all that makeup every day?
l don't mind the extra effort so people
have something nice to look at.
- l think she looks wonderful.
- We know!
Looking good to attract
the opposite sex
has been a basic human impulse
for almost a thousand years.
- What about before that?
- However old the world is.
lf you'd soften up a little,
you'd land yourself a boyfriend
and lose that hostile edge
that's so unattractive.
- Drop dead.
- That's the one.
l'd be happy to help.
You could be my project.
l'll put you on a diet.
l'll style your hair.
Enough.
l heard about
your little line-learning session.
You got Vlad to put
his arm around you.
That must be like
third base for someone
who's never been touched
by a boy, isn't it?
Ellen, wait.
Where do you think
you're going?
You know, l think l know
your sister Cinderella.
There you are.
You disappeared so fast.
l looked everywhere for you.
Where's your girlfriend?
She's not my girlfriend.
Why'd you come after me?
l don't know.
'Cause you were upset.
- She's a bitch.
- So was l.
No.
l like you, Ellen.
l like you, too.
What is it that
we're listening to, anyway?
Nothing.
l can't deal with this anymore.
What?
l like regular music, too.
l like Joni Mitchell.
l know every album by heart.
They have this great
new thing called drums.
You're gonna love it.
What's so special about this?
Sometimes it's nice
not to be special.
Sometimes it's nice to listen
to what everyone else listens to
just to be normal for once.
- Dance with me.
- Jump off the roof.
Come on, dance with me.
Asshole!
Just kidding.
Fiddler oh the Roof?
This is the last straw.
Look at us.
Do we look like
any Jews you know?
You could be Sephardic.
Look at those curly things
on Petie.
l don't think Motel the tailor
used a lot of hair relaxer.
lt's color-blind casting.
What do you want me to do?
Porgy ahd Bess?
Brihg ih Da Noise?
Why do we have to
play white characters
show after show,
summer after summer?
l don't have enough black kids
to do an all-black show.
l want my little brother learning
he can be himself
and still get applause.
You know what l'm saying?
What are you gonna do about it?
And l am telling you
l'm not going
You're the best man
l'll ever know
There's no way
l can ever go
No, no, no, no way
l'm living without you
l'm not living without you
l don't wanna be free
l'm staying
And you, and you
You're gonna love me
And l am telling you
l'm not going
Even though
the rough times are showing
There's just no way
No way
Skateboarding?
For someone with
a name like Vladimir,
you sure are
a clichéd American teenager.
lf you don't like it,
stop watching.
l'm not. l'm reading.
Sorry. l'm only human.
Call your parents, Romeo.
Get 'em up here.
And l am telling you
l'm not going
l'm staying
And you, and you, and you
You're gonna love me
Yes
Love me
You're gonna love me
l envy you.
You've probably known what you
wanted to do since you were born.
When l was eight years old,
l asked my father
to send me to acting class.
And you know what he said?
''There are five billion people
in this world.
''lf only one-tenth of one percent
of them want to be actors,
''that's still five million people.
''Do you really think you're prettier
than five million people?
You're not even
the prettiest one in your class.''
l think you're very pretty.
Why should that make me
want to cry?
l would've asked you
to your prom.
Mom.
l'm sorry,
did l wake you up?
lt's nice to hear your voice, too.
l miss you too, Mom.
Can you guys
come see my show?
Great.
New cast lists are up.
l got Joanne in Compahy.
You're in it, too.
What are you doing?
Nothing.
What is that?
- ls that my underwear?
- l was just washing them out.
We need to talk.
l think we need
a little break from each other.
What?
lt's something l've been meaning
to bring up for a while now.
This whole thing
is beginning to get a little weird.
l don't understand. l've done
everything you've asked me to.
l know, and it's been
a great help,
but the time has come for you
to get some sort of life.
- l have a life.
- Get another one.
l don't know why you're saying this.
- l can be better.
- You're not hearing me.
Test me.
l'll do anything you say.
- You're my best friend!
- Get away from me, you freak!
From now on,
let's just go about our business
and pretend like we never met.
Okay?
l'm going out.
Why don't you be gone
when l get back.
You ready
for our big opening night?
You're very intense
back there in the chorus.
ls everything okay?
l'm a little frustrated.
Frustration's a useless emotion.
lf you see something you want,
you just got to go for it.
Easy to say.
lt's better to regret
something you have done
than something you haven't done.
- Trust me, l'm the expert.
- Really?
l've been watching you,
and you are a scary little girl.
There's nothing you can't do
if you put your mind to it.
Thank you, Mr. Hanley.
You've been very helpful.
Luhch is how beihg seved.
Everybody should be at luhch.
l'd like to propose a toast.
Here's to the ladies who lunch
Everybody laugh
Lounging in their caftans
And planning a brunch
on their own behalf
- l'm going to call it off.
- l think you'd better.
Wait.
What in the hell
are you doing here?
l knew you'd be discussing
stopping the show,
and l just thought how
disappointed the kids would be.
- You scheming little bitch!
- Please! l'm a child.
lf you think for one...
Save the speech, rummy.
She's fucked, l'm ready,
and the goddamn show
must go on.
So let's get cracking, shall we?
l'll drink to that
Here's to the girls
who just watch
Aren't they the best?
When they get depressed,
it's a bottle of scotch plus a little jest
Another chance to disapprove
Another brilliant zinger
Another reason not to move
Another vodka stinger
l'll drink to that
So here's to the girls on the go
Everybody tries
Look into their eyes
and you'll see what they know
Everybody dies
A toast
to that invincible bunch
The dinosaurs
surviving the crunch
Let's hear it
for the ladies who lunch
Everybody rise
Rise
Two households,
both alike in dignity
in fair Verona,
where we lay our scene.
From ancient grudge
break to new mutiny,
where civil blood
makes civil hands unclean.
Romeo, come forth.
Come forth,
thou fearful man.
Affliction is enamored
of thy parts
and thou art wedded
to calamity.
Father, 'tis l, Romeo.
What news?
What is the Prince's doom?
What sorrow
craves acquaintance...
Tell me, Chino...
...how many bullets
are left in this gun?
Enough for you?
And you? And you?
How many can l shoot
and still have one left for me?
Michael, where are you?
Dude, we looked
all over for you.
l heard about what happened.
l called them afterwards...
...to make sure they
weren't dead somewhere
on the New York State Thruway.
My father decided he couldn't
put himself through seeing me.
What does that even mean?
lt means they think l'm a freak,
like the kids at my school.
Let's face it, even here
l'm in the upper third.
Why don't you live at home?
Prom night,
my father looked at me
bleeding in a dress.
He told me
l brought it upon myself.
He said that if l did that
when he were in school,
he'd have been one of those boys
kicking my ass, too.
That's crazy.
When it was happening,
l just projected myself out of it,
and in my head
l went somewhere else.
Where?
Here.
Why would you wear a dress
to your prom, dude?
You had to know
you were going to get creamed.
- l don't get that.
- Of course you don't get that.
That's because your life
is pretty damn close to perfect.
Mine is like, one from column ''A,''
one from column ''shit.''
Perfect.
How about this?
3, 4, 6, 1 ,
3, 4, 6, 4, 10,
4, 1 4, 3, 1 7, 1 , 1 8,
6, 24, 4, 28, 3, 31 , 4.
- What's that?
- Have you ever heard of OCD?
l count letters involuntarily.
That was ''one from column 'A,'
one from column 'shit.'''
l don't understand.
lt's like,
lf l don't take my pill,
then every time someone speaks,
or if l have an idea,
or if somebody talks--anything--
l break it down into words,
then into letters,
and l add them up.
3, 1 , 3, 4, 2.
''And l add them up.''
l take those numbers,
and l add them up backwards.
3, 1 , 3, 4, 2
was 6, 3, 9, 1 , 10, 3, 1 3, 4.
The last word,
plus the word before that,
and on and on...
...till it ends in a prime number.
lt's, like, constantly in my head.
l take it all back.
That's the sickest thing
l ever heard.
l know.
lt's weird 'cause it's,
like, it's just there.
3, 4, 5, 9, 3, 1 2, 3.
''lt's just there.''
lt's crazy. Oh, my God.
That's why l act.
That's why l want to be an actor.
'Cause when l'm acting,
it's not there if it's really going good.
lt's like the character
doesn't have it...
...so l don't have it.
A teenage Prozac junkie.
That's my perfect life.
l guess we're both freaks.
You can take a pill for yours.
l'm still some
teenage drag queen with bad skin
who can't put on a dress without
getting the crap beat out of him.
Let's get out of here, man.
Good morhihg. campers.
Time to rise ahd shihe.
Todays wake-up sohg
is a special bithday dedicatioh
to Michael Flores.
Happy bithday. Michael.
Surprise!
Happy birthday!
Oh, my God, look at you!
The only thing l have to say is,
the hair on my legs better grow back,
or else somebody's getting sued.
- You did not!
- God shave the queen.
Surprise!
Drag Kings ''R'' Us!
Make a wish.
Right at this moment,
l have everything l want.
So...
l'll give this wish to you guys.
l sing for you
And only you
Wherever l go, l find you
You're in the sound
of every ''hello''
ln everything l do
You're the song
l was destined to know
And l only sing for you
You went away
l should have known
You'd leave so many dreams
behind you
Thought l'd be fine
just being alone
l didn't have a clue
But my heart
had a mind of its own
And would only sing for you
You're in the sound of rain
Who are you people?
What planet did you
beam down from?
l'm serious.
lf l can teach you one thing,
which is supposed
to be my job here...
...it'd be that
you should all go home.
Michael Bennett's dead.
Bob Fosse is dead.
Times Square
is a theme park now.
l hate to be the Grinch,
but it's not normal
what goes on up here.
Somebody has got to warn you.
Teenage faghags
become adult faghags.
Straight boys are straight.
You can't turn 'em
just because you need to be loved.
The foundation
that's being laid here
is not going to help you
in the real world.
lt's going to lead to
waitressing jobs and bitterness
and the obsessive,
pointless collecting
of out-of-print
original cast albums.
l don't know what your problem is,
and l don't really care.
Maybe you're a son of a bitch
just 'cause you haven't written a show
in, like, a million years.
Or maybe you're
just a stupid drunk,
but those kids,
they look up to you.
And they don't deserve
to be treated like that.
''They''? Did you think
l wasn't talking to you, too?
Or did l forget to mention that
you're a fraud who has to be
everybody's golden boy,
or you'll just shrivel up?
l've taken shots at drunks before.
Don't think l have some
honor code about it.
Bring it on.
What is your problem?
l don't have a problem.
There's a theater in Brooklyn
that's got a problem.
Seems they need
a rehearsal pianist,
and they thought l might just be
hard up enough to oblige.
So l sit in hot, stinking traffic
for three hours
just to drive down there
to find out it's not
the 200th revival
of my one hit show they wanted.
You should never meet your heroes.
They always disappoint you.
Come on, kid.
Come here. Help me out.
l think l'm going to be sick.
Oh, Jesus!
God!
Get it away.
You don't even know what it is.
l don't care. lf it's been
touched by him, it's diseased.
- Oh, my God.
- Spit.
lt's everything he's written
since The Childrehs Crusade.
There's a ton more at his place.
lt's like the Holy Grail
of musical theater.
This one doesn't look so good.
Some are lousy,
but most of 'em are great.
lt's like they don't even
seem like they're from shows.
They're just songs he wrote.
There's funk, gospel.
There's this awesome,
rootsy Neil Young song.
Come on. Neil Young?
He doesn't know l took 'em.
They're just copies.
What are you going
to do with them?
What time's that benefit rehearsal
start tomorrow?
1 2:00 to 3:00.
That's it?
Ever since Michael's drag party,
Glen's been on a crusade
to make us
more like a normal camp,
so he's cutting back the benefit
rehearsals to three hours a day.
That's enough time.
- Time for what?
- He'll be late. He's always late.
For...?
Come on.
Outside my house
is a cactus plant
They call the century tree
Only once in a hundred years
lt flowers gracefully
And you never know
when it will bloom
Hey, do you want
to come out and play the game?
lt's never too late
Hey, do you want
to come out and play the game?
lt's never too late
Clementine Hunter was 54
before she packed up her paint
Old Uncle Taylor was 81
When he rode his bike
across the plains of China
And the sun
was shining on that day
Just like today
Do you want to come out
and play the game?
lt's never too late
Hey, do you want
to come out and play the game?
lt's never too late
Didn't know how to tell her
for over 30 years
He kept locked up inside himself,
and no one saw the tears
Then she went away,
and he woke up that day
Now he brings roses
to his sweetheart
She lives most anywhere
He sees someone suffering
He knows that despair
He offers them a rose
and some quiet prose
'Bout dancing
in a shimmering ballroom
'Cause you never know
when they will bloom
Hey, do you want
to come out and play the game?
lt's never too late
to play the game
Hey, do you want
to come out and play the game?
lt's never too late
Never too late to play the game
Hey, do you want
to come out and play the game?
And play the game,
it's never too late
Never too late
Hey, do you want
to come out and play the game?
And play...
Hey, do you want
to come out and play the game?
lt's never too late
lt's never too late,
never too late
Hey, do you want
to come out and play the game?
lt's never too late
Hey, do you want
to come out and play the game?
lt's never too late
Hey, do you want
to come out and play the game?
Wanna come out,
wanna come out
lt's never too late
l ever tell you we did
The Childrehs Crusade?
Five summers ago.
lt was good.
The kids want to do a revue
of my music for the benefit.
l heard.
What did you tell them?
- l told them yeah.
- Good. l'm glad.
But not on
three hours' rehearsal a day.
You tell me, am l wrong?
Am l doing such a horrible thing?
l don't know.
l was like you, except l was
feeling sorry for myself,
and l thought these kids
needed a hard dose of reality,
so l gave it to them.
Both barrels.
But l've been watching them,
and l was wrong.
They're a bunch of little freaks.
The more normal
we try to make them,
the more lonely and isolated
they're gonna feel.
Summer is almost over, Glen.
Let's all go out like pros.
What do you say?
Dee, ehtra.
What are you doing here?
Look, l don't speak no Spanish,
so you better habla your ass
some English.
Peter Piper picked a peck
of pickled peppers. Add that one.
- Cut it out, dude.
- l'm gonna cure you.
Supercalifragilisticexpialidocious.
Why are you in a good mood?
- You want to know?
- Yeah.
What is that?
No way.
- Who?
- Dee.
Dee? You slept with a girl?
You slept with a girl?
You're so full of shit.
l don't believe you.
l mean, why would you?
Maybe l didn't want a whole lifetime
of feeling the way l have so far.
l'm asking Dee.
- Don't.
- l'm calling your bluff.
- Don't be a jerk.
- What're you gonna do?
Ellen's not here.
l know. What are you doing?
A journal.
Oh, my God!
- Michael told me.
- That punk!
l'm going to give him
a bitch slap so hard.
- This is the trippiest thing l ever--
- All right.
Could he do it, even?
Were his eyes open?
Nothing against you, it's just...
lf you wanna know, he talked
about you most of the time.
During?
Who knows?
l finally tuned him out.
Come on.
Seriously, tell me.
Why are you
so interested, anyway?
- What's going on with you two?
- Nothing. Why?
What did he say?
l'm just saying you guys
hang out an awful lot.
So what? l'm straight.
- Straight.
- All right.
- You don't believe me?
- All l'm saying is that people talk.
Sorry. That was stupid.
lt wasn't that stupid.
Do you know how long it's been
since a guy's liked me
that wasn't gay?
l don't like you.
l mean, l like you,
but that's not why l did that.
l don't know why l did that.
lt's all right.
Wait.
You just slept with Michael.
l'm sorry.
Then go back to your boyfriend.
- Shut up.
- Why don't you make me?
Shit!
Come on, wait up!
Leave me alone.
- Wait up!
- Don't follow me!
- Oh, baby!
- Doesn't she look pretty?
- l missed you so much!
- You look so beautiful.
l don't understand.
How can you spend all summer
with your jaw wired shut
and still look like that?
Fred!
l'll tell you what,
we'll keep it on for fall term.
You won't be sneaking milkshakes
with me around the house.
l have to get ready.
What?
Oh, my God, it's him.
Stephen Sondheim.
They called places already.
You're not even dressed yet?
How paranoid can you be?
Oh, my God.
Was that your plan?
Did you put something in there?
l only wish l'd thought of it.
Can you please pass the base?
- Thank you.
- This is ridiculous.
lf you say one more syllable,
l will shove a powder puff
down your windpipe...
Do not underestimate my ass,
because l will knock you flat.
- Girls, why don't we--
- Butt out.
And there's no such thing
as bisexuality, you know.
- Julie? What are you doing here?
- l took the bus.
How are you?
- l'm good. How about you?
- Good.
- l give up.
- You give up?
Julie, this is Ellen,
Michael, and Dee.
Listen, is there
somewhere private we can go?
Right now? l have a show.
- l'll see you after, okay?
- Great.
- Bye.
- What?
- l hardly know where to begin.
Why didn't you tell us
you had a girlfriend?
You didn't ask.
You never asked me
if l had a boyfriend,
but if l did,
l would've said something...
Except you assumed
l wouldn't have a boyfriend.
Right.
No sense in asking a question
like that to someone like me, right?
Stop it.
And l was supposed to assume
that you did have a girlfriend.
And of course that you screw around.
That's not true.
l'm sorry about Dee.
lt's just...
l have no excuse.
lt's all my fault.
Maybe you and l only went out
because l thought
it would make you happy.
l'm sorry.
Right.
l knew that.
l knew that all along.
l guess l just didn't care.
But tell me one thing.
What was going to happen to us
when we got back home?
Places!
Jesus Christ!
Oh, God!
You sabotaged my makeup!
You bitch!
l did not. Sit down.
- l can't do it.
- Come on, Jenna.
Fritzi's got multiple fractures,
and Jill's face looks like
40 miles of bad road.
You've got to do it.
l know you're scared.
lt's not that.
My parents are here.
lt's about time
they met their daughter.
Here in the dark
l stand before you
You know this is my chance
to show you my heart
This is the start
l have so much to say
And l'm hoping
that your arms are open
Don't turn away,
l want you near me
But you have to hear me
Here's where l stand,
here's who l am
Love me, but don't tell me
who l have to be
Here's who l am,
l'm what you see
You said l had to change,
and l was trying
But my heart was lying
l'm not a child any longer
l am stronger
Here's where l stand,
here's who l am
Help me to move on
But please don't tell me how
l'm on my way,
l'm moving now
ln this life we've come so far
But we're only who we are
With the courage of love
to show us the way
We've got the power
to stand up and say
Here's where l stand,
here's who l am
Stand up and be counted
l'm counting on you
lf you're with me,
we'll make it through
Here's where l stand,
here's who l am
Love me, love me, love me
And we'll make it through
Here's where l stand
Baby, baby, baby,
l'm counting on you
Here's where l stand
Love me, love me, love me
And we'll make it through
l'm counting
Oh, l'm counting
l'm counting on
You
Here's where l stand,
here's who l am
l'm counting on you
Here's where l stand,
here's who l am
We'll make it through
Here's where l stand,
here's who l am
Here's who l am,
l'm counting on you
Here's where l stand
Here's who l am
We'll make it through
Here's where l stand
Here's who l am
l'm counting on you
Here's where l stand
We'll make it through
Here's where l stand,
here's who l am
l'm counting on you
Here's where l stand,
here's who l am
Good job, Bert.
Really terrific.
Thank you. l had no idea
you chaired this benefit.
l'm giving a party on the 1 8th.
l'll give you a call.
Great. Love to.
Who's that?
Go away.
- What are you doing?
- l'm going swimming.
Don't! l don't
even want to talk to you!
l want to apologize.
You are either the biggest
closet case l've ever seen,
or you're just plain evil.
Why? l thought now
that you're straight...
Don't get carried away.
- l slept with her 'cause of you.
- Me?
l figured you might
feel less threatened
if you thought l was capable
of sex with a woman.
l don't even know how
to respond to that, dude.
With a straitjacket, perhaps?
Things went so good with Dee.
lsn't it just possible that you're...
No.
The only thing that's possible now
is l'll get beat up once too often
and decide to be with some woman
because l know l can.
lt's not exactly something
l wish l knew.
You can't pin that on me.
We can't pin anything on you
'cause you're perfect.
l'm not perfect!
Except for that little
obsessive-compulsive thing.
Even that makes you
kind of sexily damaged.
l hate people like you.
l really do.
Oh, my God.
Water's freezing.
Why are you doing this?
Doing what?
Skinny-dipping.
Maybe l do flirt, but if l do,
it's only because
l want to be liked.
And...maybe l'm
a little confused.
You're not confused.
You like girls.
You're right. l do.
l was just trying
to give you what you want.
l'm an asshole.
Man, l don't know.
l just love attention.
l'm an attention junkie, l guess.
Why do l do shit like that?
Do you forgive me?
Do you?
Come on!
Do you? Do you forgive me?
Do you?
lf l forgive you,
will you get off of me?
- Yeah.
- Then no.
Oh, God.
Michael, who are you with?
Don't hate me.
l made up with him.
Where's Julie?
- She broke up with me.
- What?
She came here 'cause
she wanted to tell me in person.
Well, well, well. How's that
for a little opening night present?
How does it feel to be
on the other end, lover boy?
Actually...
- Never mind.
- What?
Now that camp's almost over,
and we live
kind of close to each other,
l was hoping that
we can go out sometime.
l know you're not asking
girlfriend out for a date after all this.
lf she'll forgive me.
This boy not only has cojohes.
but he's got burritos
and huevos rancheros, too.
- Okay.
- What?
Really?
l'll go out with you.
You're like
some Jenny Jones guest!
Eventually l have to start
hanging out with boys
who don't wear dresses.
l thought we came here
to go swimming.
You coming in?
lt's pretty cold.
l'll take my chances.
lt's not that cold.
Don't be a girl.
Leave that to Michael.
You two are like a bad car wreck.
l wash my hands
of the both of you!
lt's cold!
Quit splashing!
For the want of a nail
The world was lost
The want of a nail
For the want of a nail,
the shoe was lost
For the want of a shoe,
the horse was lost
For the want of a horse,
the rider was lost
For the want of a rider,
the message was lost
For the want of a nail,
the world was lost
The want of a nail
For the want of a rider,
the message was lost
For the want of a message,
the battle was lost
For the want of a battle,
the war was lost
For the want of a war,
the kingdom was lost
The want of a nail,
the world was lost
The want of a nail
l've been wrong
l had plans so big
But the devil's in the details
l left out one thing
No one to love me
And no one to love
What's all this talk
about horses and war?
Put yourself in the place
of the man at the forge
And day after day
you live a life without love
Till the morning
you can't take it anymore
And you don't get up
Multiply it a billion times
Spread it all around the world
Put the curse of loneliness
on every boy and every girl
Until everybody's kickin',
everybody's scratchin'
Everything seems to fail
And it was all
All
For the want of a nail
The want of a nail
Tell me, what else
could the answer be?
The want of a nail,
not one thing
The want of a nail
Want of a nail,
the world was lost...
Action.
What a dump.
Hey, where's that from?
''What a dump.''
How would l know, Martha?
So you weht to this camp.
What was that like?
l was consistently miscast--
Titus Andronicus,
Stanley Kowalski.
Then there was the year they
couldn't find a girl to cast as Annie,
so l played ''Andy.''
Subs Fixed By
Pacman