In the year 1807...
... a small ship of the Royal Navy set sail
from England for a secret destination.
With five million French
and Spanish soldiers...
... poised on the continent
under Napoleon...
... nothing could save England from invasion
except her 300 ships.
HMS Lydia was soon far beyond
battle-charged Europe.
Under the most secret of sealed orders,
she sailed deep into southern waters...
... fought her way around the Horn...
... headed north again, into the Pacific.
For seven months,
she stayed out of sight of land.
Becalmed finally...
... her weary crew toiled at the oars
in the vain hope of towing her into a wind.
They thirsted and hungered
and wondered where she was going...
... what she would do
when she got there, if she got there.
These were things
known only to one man aboard.
Heave!
Heave.
- Heave.
- Heave!
Heave!
Five years hard labor,
the judge says to me...
...or honorable service
in His Majesty's Navy.
What did I pick? Hornblower.
What are we doing in the Pacific, anyway?
I tell you, he's got us lost.
There's islands there
where we could have a picnic.
Brown-skinned girls, bread growing
on trees, where the Bounty went.
Why don't you ask Hornblower
to take us there?
What's wrong with our cargo
doing the asking?
Muskets and ammunition.
Who for? Why not for us?
Come on, get on with your work.
Get on with it.
- You've had your water ration, Carter.
- Me throat's closing up on me.
I can't help that. One-half cup a day.
Officers and crew the same. Even him.
Hornblower? He ain't human.
- Mr. Bush.
- Thank you.
How much do you suppose
he's paced the deck since Plymouth, sir?
Well, an hour a day at three knots,
and we're 201 days out.
I'd say the distance
between Plymouth and Aberdeen.
I'd like to know what he's thinking.
What would you think about? A rotting ship
and 10,000 miles from a friendly port.
- Good morning, gentlemen.
- Good morning, sir.
Mr. Bush, would you have the hands
piped aft to witness punishment?
- Aye, aye, sir.
- What about the towing crews, sir?
- That won't be necessary.
- Very good, sir.
Hands lay aft to witness punishment!
Shoulder arms!
Bosun's mate, do your duty.
Do you know why I'm having
Hommel flogged, Mr. Gerard?
I reported him for fighting, sir.
I'm not having him flogged
for fighting, Mr. Gerard.
I'm having him flogged because you said
in front of the men that you'd flog him.
This is a ship of war.
As its captain, I must uphold
my lieutenant's authority.
I understand, sir.
Flogging only makes a bad man worse,
Mr. Gerard.
And it can break a good man's spirit.
Is Hommel a bad man?
Aside from his temper, sir,
he's a good sailor.
A good sailor, ill-fed and thirsty.
Watch the cat as it cuts his back to pieces,
Mr. Gerard.
And in future, perhaps you'll think twice
before you threaten anyone with a flogging.
Dismiss the hands.
- Dismiss the hands.
- Hands dismissed!
Come in.
Yes, doctor?
I'm here to make a representation.
Since the lime juice ran out, the men
are dropping with scurvy every hour.
There's 39 sick and off duty,
49 just sick.
And eight dead. I know the figures.
Nine dead. Hazlitt, a minute ago.
Hazlitt...
He was a good topman.
You'll lose more than Hazlitt if you
don't put ashore for fresh food and water.
Dig into your medical kit
and get me a breath of fresh wind.
There's land to the east.
Have us towed there.
The Lydia will not come within sight of land
until we reach our destination.
Unless you'd have us fail our mission.
I don't know what our mission is
or why we're in the Pacific.
All I know is, three more days...
...and I won't answer for the life
of anyone on this ship.
We continue as before.
- Captain Hornblower.
- You may go, doctor.
Scurvy visits the quarterdeck
as well as the fo'c's'le, sir.
And I know how you've been
driving yourself.
I said you may go.
Deck there!
Now.
- Sixty-five, thirty.
- Mr. Crystal, would you tell the cooper...
...to scald his water casks for filling?
- Very good, sir.
Are we...? Are we towing ashore, sir?
There's no need to stammer, Mr. Gerard.
No, we are not towing ashore.
I expect the wind before morning...
...and we're within a hundred miles
of our destination.
Did you say something, Mr. Crystal?
What with chronometers that haven't
been checked for seven months...
...and Spanish charts
that aren't to be trusted...
...we can be 300 miles
out of our reckoning.
That means five days without food, sir.
Gentlemen, we will raise our destination
within two days.
It will be identified by a fortress on a hill
overlooking a large bay.
A fortress and a wind before morning.
Heat's gone to his head.
Well, I think he knows
more than he's saying.
- Care to take a wage on it, Mr. Bush?
- How much can you afford?
I've got five shillings that says no wind...
...and 10 shillings
that we don't sight any fortress.
Done.
Heave!
- Course north by west.
- North by west. As if it mattered.
Look at that candle.
Straighter than Hornblower's backbone.
Heave! Heave! Heave!
Heave!
The wind!
Call the watch!
Call the starboard watch!
Come on, there!
- Hands aloft to secure!
- Come on, get aloft there!
Watch the clew lines there!
Fo'c's'le party, take in the towing cable!
Haul in those tow lines!
Secure the guns!
Make these guns fast!
Away with the yards!
- Keep her into the wind.
- Aye, aye, sir.
Away with the stays!
Watch it there, Mr. Longley.
- Up the shrouds.
- Yes, sir.
That's five shillings, Mr. Crystal.
There's still 10 shillings
riding on that fortress.
You were right, sir.
Blowing nice and steady.
Aye. Nice and steady.
- Everything secure aloft?
- Aye, aye, sir.
Starboard your helm.
Let the wind take her.
- I'll have my lunch now, Polwheal.
- Aye, sir.
- You sent for me, sir?
- This ship is getting slack, Mr. Gerard.
It's taking you longer every day
to clear for action.
- The hands are weak, sir, and...
- And what?
Restless, sir. After all, sir,
seven months without sighting land.
That's no excuse.
You ought to control them.
Land ho! Off the starboard bow!
An officer who cannot control his men
is not reliable.
Yes, sir. Excuse me, sir,
that was "land ho."
- I have ears, Mr. Gerard.
- Thought you'd be interested, sir.
It took you 11 minutes and 20 seconds
to clear for action yesterday.
- I want it done in 10. Now.
- Now, sir?
You seem to have your mind
on something else.
- I said now.
- Aye, aye, sir.
- Land, sir!
- I said I'd have my lunch now, Polwheal.
Aye, aye, sir.
Fortress off the larboard bow!
A fortress, by Gad.
- He's made it.
- That's 10 more shillings, Mr. Crystal.
And may my liver rot if any other man
in the whole navy could've done it.
Including Lord Hood.
Mr. Longley, my respects to the captain.
- Tell him a fortress off the larboard bow.
- Aye, aye, sir.
If I hadn't been here to see that...
...if any man had told me,
I'd have called him a liar.
Hit it right on the nose,
after 10,000 miles at sea.
Mr. Bush's respects, sir.
Fortress off the larboard bow!
May his liver rot if anyone else
in the ruddy navy could've done it.
Including Lord Hood.
I don't think that Mr. Bush
intended you...
...to convey the last part
of that message, Mr. Longley.
My compliments to Mr. Bush.
Tell him to hold the course.
- I'll be on deck presently.
- Aye, aye, sir.
- Mr. Longley.
- Yes, sir?
- Not so much noise on the companion wing.
- Aye, aye, sir.
- Mr. Longley.
- Yes, sir?
The next time, would you knock
before you enter the captain's cabin?
Aye, aye, sir.
- Water casks ready for filling?
- Water casks ready for filling, sir.
- The ship cleared for action?
- Cleared for action, sir.
- Ten minutes and two seconds, sir.
- Very good, Mr. Gerard.
- We'll have the guns loaded and run out.
- Aye, aye, sir.
- Bring her into the wind.
- Aye, sir.
Starboard battery load!
- Ease your helm.
- Aye, aye, sir.
- Let go the anchor, Mr. Bush.
Let go the anchor!
Deck there!
Mr. Bush.
Rum-looking lot, eh, sir?
They're His Majesty's allies, Mr. Bush.
Allies, sir?
I thought that this part of the world
belonged to Spain.
Don Julian Alvarado,
a prince of this country...
...has been persuaded by England
to revolt against Spain.
Then our cargo of arms is for him.
If Don Julian
can conquer Central America...
...Spain will have to take ships
and soldiers from Napoleon...
...to preserve her colonies.
- Man the side, Mr. Bush.
- Aye, aye, sir.
Man the side!
Captain Hornblower?
I am Don Jose Hernandez,
admiral in the service of El Supremo.
El Supremo? That means the almighty.
El Supremo was formerly known to men
as Don Julian Alvarado.
And where is this Don Julian Alvarado?
El Supremo is in his fortress.
You will come with me now.
Mr. Bush...
...here are the keys to my dispatch box
containing the Admiralty's orders.
If I'm not back aboard by midnight...
...you assume command.
- Not back aboard, sir?
But you said they were on our side.
War breeds strange allies, Mr. Bush.
Captain Horatio Hornblower,
at your service.
King George of England charges me
with messages of his friendship.
I am not interested
in the words of a mere king.
Have you brought me the guns and powder
for my conquest of the Americas?
A thousand muskets,
a million rounds of ammunition...
...and cannon for your fort, senor.
- Human beings do not address me as senor!
Make arrangements with Admiral Hernandez
for landing your cargo.
I can hand over nothing
until my ship is reprovisioned.
I have given you an order!
Perhaps outside you saw various criminals
suffering punishment.
They, too, disobeyed me.
If I am not back aboard the Lydia
within one hour...
...she'll train her guns upon your fort
and reduce it to rubble.
- With you in it, captain?
- That is my order.
Such earthly matters are beneath me.
We are allies, are we not?
Make known your needs
to Admiral Hernandez.
Aside from water,
I shall need 200 bullocks...
...500 pigs, 100 quintals of salt...
...40 tons of flour, 10 tons of sugar,
five tons of tobacco, one ton of coffee...
...the juice of 40,000 limes...
...and are there any wines
to be had here? Spirits?
We drink a spirit distilled from molasses
which you probably do not know.
We call it rum. Would that do?
Well, if there's nothing better,
that will have to do.
- One hundred barrels.
- Start now.
When you have landed my weapons,
I intend to move on El Salvador and burn it.
- Perhaps you'll accompany me?
- No, my orders are to blockade Panama.
It is your loss.
A burning town is a magnificent sight.
You are in luck, captain.
This scum, who enters without knocking,
brings news of a visitor from Panama.
- An ally?
- I hardly think so.
Three months ago the Spanish viceroy
sent a diplomat...
...who warned me to curb
my political ambitions.
In answer, I sent part of him
back to Panama.
His head, to be precise.
Then the Spanish already know
of your plan?
This visitor comes armed
to destroy my city.
She is a Spanish warship of 60 guns,
the Natividad.
A Spanish ship of the line in these waters?
When does she arrive?
According to this wretch, before dawn.
I must take measures to prepare my ship.
See that my provisions
are sent out immediately.
Captain! You will not destroy
the Natividad.
You will capture her
and turn her over to me.
If I capture the Natividad,
she will be a prize belonging to my king.
Your king would not wish you
to offend me.
You were charged
with a mission, captain:
To aid me in my conquest
of the Americas.
If I fail, England fails.
I cannot surrender a British prize ship
without authority from the Admiralty.
Think, captain! With two ships,
we could crush all Spanish America.
There are 10,000 troops in Panama
whom you could blockade...
...while I destroyed El Salvador,
Honduras and Costa Rica.
You would be helping
your country's cause.
Before I can turn the Natividad over to you,
senor, I must first capture her.
Now, you must excuse me.
Prepare the boats for storing ship.
There are enough provisions coming
to make us independent for six months.
- Our cargo goes ashore.
- Aye, aye, sir.
Oh, and, Mr. Bush, there's a Spanish ship
of 60 guns due here before dawn.
Send your best lookout
to the top of that hill...
...to warn us of the enemy's approach.
- Aye, aye, sir.
A 60-gunner.
What do you suppose he's up to?
If we don't clear the bay,
I'll wager we're all dead by morning.
- How much can you afford this time?
- Twenty shillings.
Done. Where shall I send the money
if you win?
- Mr. Harrison, get the boats out.
- Aye, aye, sir.
Clear away the boats!
I hear the Natividad's
a 100-gun ship of the line.
We'd better up-anchor
and get out of here.
- Not till we get this grub aboard.
- Look!
- What's it read, Mr. Longley?
- "Ship's royals horizon, southeast."
Lookout station reports
Natividad sighted, sir.
- Thank you. We'll have the lights out.
- All lights out!
Shall I stop the loading, sir?
- No, we've a few hours yet.
- Aren't we gonna run for open water, sir?
We'll remain at anchor here
under the lee of this point.
- Aye, aye, sir.
- Oh, Mr. Bush.
Would you and Mr. Gerard
and Mr. Longley give me the pleasure...
...of your company at supper tonight?
- Thank you, sir.
Tonight, sir?
Our young midshipman may be risking
his life before dawn, Mr. Bush.
His stomach might feel better
with a meal in it.
What if the Spanish attack
while we're at anchor, sir?
The Lydia'd be blown to bits.
And I'd lose 20 shillings.
- Gentlemen, the king.
- The king.
Thank you, sir.
Signal from the point.
Natividad's gone about.
One more tack,
and she'll be at the harbor mouth.
Very good, Mr. Crystal.
Well, gentlemen...
...that leaves us time
for a rubber at whist.
Will you cut for deal, Mr. Longley?
Lookout reports
Natividad's anchored, sir.
- Snugged down for the night, eh?
- Yes, sir.
That's the Spanish for you.
I've been gambling that
they would do exactly that.
Now, gentlemen...
...here's what I plan to do.
What a prize she'll make.
We'll all be stinking rich.
Dead, more likely.
Don't hurry, Mr. Longley.
It has a bad effect on the men.
- Set them an example. Take your time.
- Aye, aye, sir.
- Good luck, sir.
- Thank you, Mr. Crystal.
Wake them up, Mr. Longley.
You may retain your sword, captain.
Mr. Bush, will you remove these officers
to the Lydia and put them in irons?
But we have surrendered.
There are rules of war.
Believe me, if Don Julian as much
as sees you during the coming day...
...he'll have you all killed.
Those are his rules of war.
That was wonderful swordplay, sir.
Mr. Longley, when I was a midshipman...
...I was at the bottom of my class
in swordsmanship.
This is the first occasion
I've had to use one of these since.
I hope it's the last.
She's a beauty, sir.
Purser reckons she's worth
120,000 guineas.
That gives every man jack aboard Lydia
50 guineas prize money.
Natividad is not a prize ship, Mr. Bush.
- I beg your pardon, sir.
- She's to be used by our ally, Don Julian.
You're giving her away, sir?
But your own share'd be worth 10,000.
I asked for no figures.
But, sir, you yourself
said that Don Julian was mad.
- Can you trust him?
- Rest easy, Mr. Bush.
I alone will have to answer
to the Admiralty for this decision.
Deck there!
- An 11 -gun salute, Mr. Bush.
- Aye, aye, sir.
Fire!
You'll remember in the future, captain,
that the correct signal for El Supremo...
...is 23 guns.
Our king himself receives only 21.
That is why I always have 23.
I have noticed before, captain,
that you have shown a little disrespect.
But I have been mild enough to attribute it
to your foreign breeding.
You did not kill many.
No, I didn't want to deprive you
of your crew, Supremo.
I shall kill the officers, then, and replace
them with my own. Where are they?
I greatly regret that I threw them
overboard this morning...
...with their hands and feet tied.
- That is a pity.
I was looking forward
to making an example of them...
...in case any of these wretches
hesitated to serve me.
But there are other ways.
We sail tonight.
You will proceed south to blockade Panama.
- I shall take care of the north.
- Mr. Bush, we're returning to the Lydia.
I'd like to know why Hornblower
gave that monkey-face our ship.
What happened to our prize money?
I ask you, what happened to it?
Loose and make all plain sail.
Loose and make all plain sail!
Sail off the larboard bow!
Keep an eye on her, Mr. Crystal.
She's a Spaniard.
Ease your helm down.
She's hove to
and preparing to lower her boat.
A white flag. I don't like it.
- What is she, Mr. Bush?
- Spanish lugger, sir. Flying a white flag.
That'll mean a parley.
- Run out a gun.
- Aye, aye, sir.
- Why do the enemy want to speak to us?
- We'll soon know.
- Stand by the carronade, Mr. Gerard.
- Stand by the carronade.
There are women aboard.
What are these Spaniards up to?
Women?
You're right, by George.
Better get the sling ready.
Mr. Bush, have you ever seen our captain
talking to a lady?
No, but I'm willing to wager
what his first words will be.
- The exact words?
- Aye.
- How much?
- A guinea.
- Done.
- What are they?
Estobar Entenza, capitan
in his most Catholic Majesty's Navy.
Capitan Hornblower?
Oh, thank heaven
we have found you in time.
You might have fallen afoul
of our warship Natividad...
...before I could bring you
the wonderful news.
- News?
- Captain Hornblower...
...I welcome you
as the new ally of Spain.
That's done it.
For a month, your country and mine have
been brothers-in-arms against Napoleon.
Together, with God's help,
we shall destroy him.
Oh, perhaps you think
it is too good to be true.
Here is a letter from your Admiralty.
Thank you.
Excuse me. Mr. Bush.
- Bring the prisoners here.
- Aye, aye, sir.
Last month,
Napoleon kidnapped our king...
...and put his own brother
on the throne of Spain.
Our government in exile
immediately concluded...
...an alliance with His Britannic Majesty.
You understand now my fear that you
might have encountered the Natividad.
Her capitan also is ignorant
of the new alliance.
It happened, sir...
...that last week
we did encounter the Natividad.
You were wise to show your heels, capitan.
She is twice your strength.
Imagine what would have happened.
We captured the Natividad, senor.
Impossible!
Captain, you are... You are joking.
I've never been more serious in my life.
- Where is the captain?
- Over there.
Captain Hornblower?
My name is Wellesley,
Lady Barbara Wellesley.
Wellesley?
You're not related
to the Duke of Wellington?
- He's my brother.
- Oh, but...
- A Spanish lugger?
- There's yellow fever in Panama.
And when Capt. Entenza set out
in search of you, he was good enough to...
- What the devil is that, Mr. Longley?
- I'm not quite sure, sir.
Forgive me, captain,
but I was about to tell you...
...that I require passage to England
for myself and my maid.
Not in the Lydia?
What other British ship
is in these waters, sir?
Do you suggest that we swim home?
I suggest that Your Ladyship
cross the Isthmus of Panama...
...and embark on a ship which has frills
and fancies enough for women passengers.
A thousand people died
in Panama this week.
May I ask why you were in Panama
in the first place?
Because, sir,
the British packet I was sailing in...
...was captured months ago
by the Spaniards.
I was their prisoner until the alliance.
I must say, I was treated
by the enemy with more courtesy...
...than I've received so far from
the captain of His Majesty's ship Lydia.
- Exactly.
- Oh, capitan, capitan, it cannot be true.
You gave the Natividad
to the rebel Don Julian?
But a week ago
you were already our ally.
Santa Maria, do you realize
what you have done?
We have no ship in the Pacific!
They'll burn our ports, sack all our cities!
I am well aware of the situation.
This removes any possibility
of Your Ladyship's remaining aboard.
Indeed.
We're on our way to fight
a ship twice our strength.
If we're defeated, you'll be in the hands
of a butchering maniac.
If I return to Panama,
I'll probably die of the fever.
And since there's a good chance of death
in either case...
...I must insist
upon making the choice myself.
Longley! If I am to overtake Natividad,
I must ask you to leave at once. Adios.
Mr. Bush, see these gentlemen
over the side.
Mr. Longley, Lady Wellesley
will be moving into my cabin.
Be a little crowded, sir.
Clear my things into Mr. Bush's cabin.
Move his into the wardroom.
If Your Ladyship
will accompany Mr. Longley...
...perhaps you'll come
to regret your insistence.
Get that boat underway! Man the braces!
I hope I'm not disturbing the ship's routine,
Mr. Longley.
Oh, no. Not in the least, ma'am.
I'm afraid Captain Hornblower
thinks otherwise.
He's got a lot of his mind, ma'am.
If he doesn't retake the Natividad,
he's in for serious trouble.
Surely it isn't his fault
that Spain changed sides in the war.
I'm afraid the Admiralty
won't stop to consider that.
- You're fond of the captain, aren't you?
- Fond, ma'am?
He's the best officer in the service.
He's a better sailor than Mr. Bush,
a better gunner than Mr. Gerard.
When it comes to navigation,
Mr. Crystal doesn't hold a candle to him.
That's not all. He's as gentle
and warm-hearted as any man...
...who's ever sailed for the king.
- Mr. Longley!
Gentle and warm-hearted?
I see what you mean.
- Polwheal!
- Excuse me, ma'am.
Mr. Bush, I'll have you remind everyone
that this is still a ship of war!
- Clear away!
- Aye, aye, sir.
You are so big and so strong.
- Yes, surely. Feel that.
- Here.
- Oh, you got nothing there.
- Just get ahold of that now.
- Now, let's see what you got.
- No!
Come out of there! I'll eat you alive!
Mr. Bush!
Mr. Bush, we are not
on a pleasure cruise.
Our lives and our passengers' lives depend
upon this ship being properly handled.
The men seem to have their minds
on other things.
You will inform Her Ladyship
that she and her maid will remain below.
Aye, aye, sir.
May I wish you the best of fortune
in what lies ahead.
- Thank you.
- It is the captain's wish, Your Ladyship...
...that from now on,
you and your maid remain below.
Can two women really be so distracting,
captain?
May I remind you, ma'am, that my men...
...have been continually at sea
for eight months?
Oh, captain.
And how long have you been at sea?
Sail! Off the larboard bow!
Mr. Longley, conduct Lady Barbara
and her maid to the cable tier.
- They'll remain there until the action is over.
- Aye, aye, sir.
Captain's ordered you
to the cable tier, ma'am.
The cable tier? And what if I refuse?
I shall have to carry you, ma'am.
Orders, ma'am.
You'd get me shot if you didn't.
I shouldn't want to do that, Mr. Longley.
Man the braces there!
Port your helm. Keep her as close
near the wind as she'll lie.
Aye, aye, sir.
Mr. Bush, beat to quarters
and clear for action!
He'll have quite a shock, sir...
...when he gets his 23-gun
salute broadside.
I'm afraid not, Mr. Bush.
It looks as though Don Julian
has heard the news too.
Our chance to surprise him is gone.
She's got twice our guns
and twice our men.
We can't stand off and pound her
and we can't go in and board her.
All we can do is outsail her
and hit when she can't hit back.
I'm not worried.
Not with Captain Hornblower.
He's crowded on every rag she'll carry.
Look at her heel, sir.
- Her gun ports are under water.
- That's what we've been waiting for.
- Starboard battery, ready!
Helm the weather!
- Fire as your guns bear!
Ease your helm!
Mr. Harrison, the helm's a lee!
Head and foresheets, let go!
- I thought we were going across her bow!
- So do they.
Hornblower fooled them and me too.
- Check your foresheets!
- Starboard battery, reload!
Port battery, fire as your guns bear!
- Port battery, reload.
- Well done.
That's one in the beezer, one in the belly
and nothing back from him.
Hornblower's amazing.
Two broadsides into her
without a round back.
Now we've a chance
in a pounding match.
But there'll be no fooling her a third time,
I'm thinking. Here she comes.
For what we are about to receive,
may we all be truly thankful.
Stand by on the quarterdeck!
- Two starboard guns out of action.
- Report to Mr. Gerard.
Aye, aye, sir.
Two starboard guns out of action.
- Where?
- The fo'c's'le.
Quist, look out!
Do you hear that?
He knew my name. He knew my name.
Chop that rigging away.
I'm all right, sir.
Of course you are, sonny.
Of course you are.
Quist, take him below.
Run up a new set of colors!
- Blast her as she goes by, Mr. Gerard.
- Aye, aye, sir. Port battery, ready!
Fire!
Get those guns back into action!
Get these wounded below!
Clear this wreckage away!
That's it, men,
get that wreckage overboard.
Fire!
Give me a hand here, men.
Get this stuff off of him.
McCrea, over here, the captain.
- Are you all right, sir?
- See to your duties, Mr. Bush. I'm all right.
- What are you doing on deck?
- The surgeon's been killed, sir.
- Who's with the wounded?
- Her Ladyship.
- What?
- She insisted on helping, sir.
- There's so many, sir.
- She's down there?
No stopping her. Put on a bosun's jacket
and went to work.
- Well, go below, man, and help her.
- Aye, aye, sir.
Stand by to go about. Have every gun
ready to fire when we cross her.
Aye, aye, sir. Stand by to go about!
- Hard alee!
- Aye, aye, sir.
Port battery, ready!
We're in range. Ready!
Steady there! A keg of rum
if you get the foremast!
- Hard astarboard.
- Shift over the headsheets!
Cease fire!
Our mission in the Pacific is finished,
gentlemen.
Thank you for the way
you've all carried out your duties.
Your conduct today will be brought
to the attention of the Admiralty.
- What course shall I set, sir?
- Course?
- South, Mr. Crystal.
- Very good, sir.
Mr. Gerard, I told you to clear the decks
for action in 10 minutes.
You did it in eight.
Bosun, double ration of rum all around.
- Aye, aye, sir.
- Well done, well done.
- Well, Quist, there goes your prize money.
- It's all right, sir.
You'll find us another one.
It's a big ocean.
I came back to you, Mother, didn't I?
I promised you I'd come back.
Yes, dear, you've come back to me.
Did you miss me?
Oh, yes. Yes, my own.
Kiss me the way you used to, Mother...
...when I was very little.
Couldn't you?
Just once?
If I only knew how.
On his eyes and on his mouth,
Your Ladyship.
That's right, Mother.
Good night.
How did you know?
It was the way she said goodbye to him
at Plymouth.
As though she was kissing him
good night.
And she was.
- Good afternoon, ma'am.
- Good afternoon, captain.
I haven't had an opportunity yet...
...to thank you for everything
you did for the men.
- Have you a chill, Your Ladyship?
- It's just the strain of the past two weeks.
Well, I don't wonder. What you saw
was never meant for woman's eyes.
But I did see, captain.
And I know there's not another officer
in the king's service...
...who could've done
what you've done on this voyage.
I'm glad you think so, Your Ladyship.
- All England will think so.
- Thank you, ma'am.
Your Ladyship.
Mr. Bush. Mr. Gerard.
Her Ladyship is ill. Give me a hand.
- It is the fever! The fever!
- Make sense, girl.
Milady, she has the yellow fever
from Panama.
We will all die.
Oh, I have seen
how it strikes down whole cities.
Sentry, keep her quiet. Allow nobody
aft of her without my orders.
And our surgeon dead.
Bring me the medical books
from the sick bay.
And some more blankets.
Just put them inside the door.
Don't come in.
If it's yellow fever,
this cabin will be quarantined.
- I thought you might feel the need of this.
- Oh, thank you, Mr. Bush.
- The books tell you anything, sir?
- Well, enough to give me some hope.
Swamp fever and yellow fever
have the same symptoms in the beginning.
- When will you know?
- In 72 hours.
If it's swamp fever,
her temperature will break.
If it's yellow fever...
Hebe.
Hebe?
- Will you fetch Lady Barbara's maid, please?
- Aye, sir.
Oh, Hebe, you may go in
to Lady Barbara now.
No, it's all right. The fever's broken.
Go in quickly.
I'm sure everybody'll be happy
about Lady Barbara's recovery, sir.
Myself included. It would've been
a black mark against this ship...
...if anything had happened
to the Duke of Wellington's sister.
It wouldn't have set so well
with Mucho Pomposo either.
- Mucho Pomposo?
- Oh, a slip of the tongue.
I meant Admiral Leighton.
Sir Rodney Leighton,
the man she's going to marry.
As soon as she gets back to England,
according to Her Ladyship's servant.
Will that be all, sir?
Oh, yes, that's all.
Thank you, Polwheal.
Good night, sir.
Dear Hebe.
And to think I nearly left you in Panama.
What would have happened
to me if I had?
Oh, milady, I did not help you.
I was afraid of the fever.
The whole time, only one was here.
The capitan was the only one.
- How long was I ill, Hebe?
- Three day and three night, milady.
He was the only one?
- Good morning, captain.
- Good morning.
I'm glad to see that you're better.
It's my good fortune that you're not
only a captain, but a doctor as well.
I did no more than read a medical book,
Your Ladyship.
And go 72 hours without sleep.
That's not unusual for a sailor,
Your Ladyship.
I do wish you'd call me Lady Barbara
instead of Your Ladyship.
Oh, certainly, Your Lady...
Lady Barbara.
Of course, if Lady Barbara
doesn't come easily to you...
...and you wish to attract my attention,
you can always say:
You see, captain,
I'm well enough to be rude.
Please forgive me.
You're very observant.
No one's ever noticed that before.
Oh, I'm sure of that, captain.
Won't you sit down?
Well, thank you, but I must
make an inspection of the ship.
We've a difficult voyage ahead.
- When should we reach England, Captain?
- In the spring, Lady Barbara.
It should take as long as that?
With fair winds
and all the canvas we can carry...
...I think I can promise you that
we'll have you home before the first robin.
Now you must excuse me,
Your Ladyship.
I mean, Lady Barbara.
How beautiful the stars are tonight.
It's as though we were sailing
the heavens instead of the sea.
Well, in a way, we are. We steer from
star to star rather than from land to land.
You never forget you're the captain
of a ship, do you?
No, the ship's captain
cannot afford to forget.
On a night like this,
I can forget everything.
Who I am, where I come from,
where I'm going.
I only knew the Lydia's
sailing on and on in space.
There is no other world
and this voyage will never end.
- How much?
- Five and a half, sir.
Five and a half knots.
We're making a quick passage.
Is that what you really want,
a quick passage?
Well, every captain wants that,
Lady Barbara.
Well, it's getting late.
There'll be a chill in the air.
These tropical nights are deceptive.
I don't want a quick passage.
I don't want this voyage to end.
- Barbara...
- How much longer are we going to pretend?
You must know I love you.
Why do you fight against it?
I'm married, Lady Barbara.
Forgive me.
I've made a terrible mistake.
I'm deeply ashamed.
No, please. Stay here
and speed your ship homeward.
Mr. Bush, we'll have more sail on her.
Reset your t'gallants.
But the wind is increasing.
I was about to reduce sail.
- I gave you an order, Mr. Bush.
- Aye, aye, sir.
Away aloft! Set the t'gallants!
And I thought I knew all his moods.
I've never seen him drive the ship so hard.
It's as if he wished
the Lydia would fly home.
Now.
Thirty-one.
Are we near land, Mr. Bush?
See those sea gulls, ma'am?
They sleep in England.
With any luck, we'll sight
Land's End tonight, ma'am.
And if the weather holds,
Plymouth by morning.
You've been at sea a long time, ma'am.
A lifetime, Mr. Bush.
- Oh, my love.
- Barbara. Barbara.
- I have no longing for the land.
- Nor I.
I've known from the first, I think,
when you tried to make me leave the ship.
All captain and no heart, I thought.
Now every mile closer to England
is agony for me.
Oh, my dear. My sweet.
Land ho!
What are we to do?
Do?
We are lovers and the world is ours.
- But...
- Hebe is safe.
She wouldn't be indiscreet.
But we're not free...
...either of us.
You really believe it can end here?
In this one moment?
I see.
It isn't easy for me to say.
Please try to understand.
Admiral's barge heading our way.
Hoist the storm warnings.
- It's Mucho Pomposo himself.
- Who?
Sir Rodney Leighton, Knight of the Bath,
Knight of the Tower and Sword of Portugal.
For some extraordinary reason,
a rear admiral in His Majesty's Navy.
Come to claim his lady.
Pipe the side!
Captain Hornblower at your service, sir.
Lady Barbara Wellesley is aboard,
is she not?
She's been informed of your arrival, sir.
Your exploits at sea, captain,
have made you quite famous.
When you make your report
to the Admiralty you'll probably find...
...that you've something better
to command than this 38-gunner.
I did little to deserve it.
It's my belief
that you were very fortunate...
...to sink the Natividad,
having first given her away as you did.
- On your own initiative.
- It seemed the best thing to do at the time.
The captain of a frigate
doesn't normally decide Admiralty policy.
There was no way of consulting
the Admiralty, or I'd have done so.
But, really, Hornblower, giving away
a 60-gun prize to a madman.
I stood ready to answer
for my action, sir.
Had you been serving under me,
you'd have answered for it.
A court martial might have considered
your action irresponsible.
It caused you to risk the life
of the Duke of Wellington's sister.
I apologize for that, sir.
It would have gone very hard with you
had anything happened to her.
I, too, value Lady Barbara highly.
We're to be married.
Yes, so Lady Barbara has told me, sir.
I suppose a ship of this size
is rather confining...
...and confidences are likely to be freer
than under normal circumstances.
Here you are, at last, my dear.
You've no idea how concerned I've been
for your welfare.
That was sweet of you.
Shall we go? Your family waits
impatiently in London.
And after that, my family in Ireland.
Goodbye, Captain Hornblower.
Thank you for your kindness.
Goodbye, Lady Barbara.
- Gentlemen.
- Goodbye, ma'am.
Maria?
Maria.
Oh, sir. It's you at last.
Mrs. McPhee. Where's my wife?
If only you could've come home sooner,
captain, to be here in time.
- What's happened?
- She's dead, sir.
Died in childbed, giving you a son.
She so wanted to live, sir,
at least until you returned.
She left this for you, sir.
It was on her deathbed she wrote it.
- Where is the child?
- In here, sir.
He's a strong lad,
with a lusty voice when he's awake.
Fine boy.
My husband:
Not knowing where you are,
I cannot send these last words to you...
... but I pray you will come back
to read them.
Do not forget me completely, Horatio,
when I'm gone.
Though we've been married
for 15 years...
... in all that time we were together
for only 15 months...
... one Christmas, two birthdays.
But I am not sorry for the years.
I know you have not loved me deeply,
Horatio.
But I have loved you more
for never betraying it to me.
I know it was because
you are sorry for me.
And because a sailor
needed someone to come home to.
And I pray now
you will come home to our son.
Your loving wife, Maria.
You shouldn't be here in the dark
like this, sir.
And I'm beginning to think you don't like
my cooking as much as ship's food.
Two weeks now, and you've done
no more than nibble at it.
This'll cheer you up.
It's about the lady you brought...
...from the other side of the world.
A bonnie wedding it must've been.
By special messenger, sir,
from the Admiralty.
I hope it's not to be the sea again, sir.
- I'll be leaving for London in the morning.
- You've had so little time with the lad.
Dashed if that report of yours didn't read
like a novel. Couldn't put it down.
- Thank you.
- You know everyone?
Leighton, Elliott, Bolton, Macartney.
You know enough of them.
It's a pleasure to see you again, sir.
You've changed since you were
one of my midshipmen.
- Quite a fellow with the girls, eh?
- I beg your pardon, sir?
Come, come. Six months at sea
with a flower of the English nobility.
Don't tell me it wasn't a trifle gay, what?
What? What?
Well, Hornblower, after that cruise,
you may not find it so exciting...
...commanding a ship of the line.
- A ship of the line?
We're giving you a 74. A Frenchman
we captured, renamed the Sutherland.
- The Lydia's crew will be transferred to her.
- I'm extremely grateful.
You'll be attached
to Leighton's squadron.
And now, gentlemen,
the confounded war.
I think Napoleon has bitten off more
than he can chew in the Spanish peninsula.
The Duke of Wellington
has a chance to defeat him...
...and bring victory to England,
if we can maintain our naval blockade.
But not a single French ship must sail.
That's up to you.
Now, if you look at this map,
Macartney'll be here...
Captain Hornblower.
Barbara.
I hoped we would meet.
I wanted to tell you how sorry I was
about the news you had at home.
Well, thank you.
I would have written, but I only heard
upon my return from Ireland.
- After the ceremony.
- Yes, of course, Lady Barbara.
I hear you have a son.
Yes. He's a boy to be proud of.
I'm sure he is.
Well, I must take my leave now.
I wish you every happiness.
Thank you.
Goodbye, Horatio.
Goodbye, Barbara.
Signal from the flagship, sir.
All captains come aboard.
Oh, very good, Mr. Bush.
Acknowledge, and clear away the gig.
Acknowledge!
Clear away the captain's gig!
Clear away the yard and stay tackles!
Brace around the foremain yard!
Well, gentlemen,
now that we are finally all assembled...
...l've some fairly startling news
that has been sent to me by cutter.
The French have broken
Macartney's blockade at Brest.
The old boy supposedly had Napoleon's
ships completely bottled up in here.
A pea-soup fog settled in for 48 hours.
- When it lifted, four ships had slipped away.
- Any idea what course they took?
The only place they could go
is to the Mediterranean.
So if we proceed from our position here,
stand well out into the bay...
...we'll intercept them about here.
Four against four, the outcome's obvious.
You don't seem to agree,
Captain Hornblower.
Where else would they go
except the Mediterranean?
- I submit, sir, here.
- North of Spain?
Nonsense. Why should they?
Napoleon's army has already
been pushed deep into Spain...
...by the Duke of Wellington.
If I were Napoleon,
I'd consider it a good idea...
...to thrust from the northeast,
behind the duke.
And supply them by sea?
Better than hauling over
the Pyrenees, I'd say.
The French wouldn't risk four ships
on such a gamble.
What does Napoleon care about ships...
...except to help him
in his military operations?
I submit most urgently
that instead of standing out to sea...
...we move north along the French coast.
Be the devil to pay with the Admiralty
if they got to the Mediterranean.
Be the devil to pay with the duke
otherwise.
Perhaps we could take care of both
possibilities with a wide deployment.
Three of us fanning out from here,
and one ship inshore.
Good idea, Sylvester. You see,
I've no objection to a practical suggestion.
I welcome it, in fact.
We've a war to win.
Very well then, who goes inshore?
Which of our ships
has the shallowest draught?
The Sutherland, sir. French built.
Oh, I see now what was influencing you,
Hornblower.
The prospect of picking up
a prize or two, eh?
- Not at all, sir.
- Well, I'll make sure of that.
I know how you enjoy
acting on your own initiative.
I'm ordering you not to risk your ship
in any way for any reason.
I want nothing crackbrained.
If you sight the enemy,
bring me the news...
...and we'll destroy them together,
is that clear?
Perfectly clear, sir.
Just the same, put it in writing, Rogers.
Sail off the larboard bow!
That's queer, sir. It's a French brig,
but she's not running away.
- Standby guns crew.
- Standby guns crew!
She can't have see our flag yet.
She's signaling.
M.V.
We can't blame her for thinking
we're French. We're French built.
M.V. Is not in the code, sir.
She'll start running fast enough
if we can't give her a conventional signal.
- Port your helm!
- Aye, aye, sir.
You're right, sir, there she goes.
- Put one across her bow, Mr. Gerard.
- Aye, aye, sir.
Muzzle right point. Steady.
Fire!
Good shot, Mr. Gerard.
Any closer, and you'd have sunk her.
- She's lowering her flag, sir.
- Take your boat and board her, Mr. Bush.
Bring her in.
I'd like a word with her captain.
- Aye, aye, sir.
- Bring her into the wind!
- Make the boat ready!
Not another British ship in sight.
That means, we'll have to take
all the prize money.
Off with the cap, Alfonse.
Merchant brig Marie Louise, sir.
Captain doesn't comprend English.
He doesn't seem to understand
French either, Mr. Bush.
Shall I flog it out of him, sir?
No, I don't consort brutality, Mr. Bush.
Just take him up on deck,
chop off his head...
...and give his body to the cook.
No, no, capitan, no. I am only a poor man.
I care not about Napoleon.
- I'll tell you what you want to know.
- That's better.
Now that we've overcome
the barrier of language...
...once again,
what does this signal M.V. Mean?
- It is French recognition signal, capitan.
- Thank you.
That may be very useful, Mr. Bush.
Put the captain in the cable tier.
Tell off a prize crew
to sail the brig to England.
Brig and cargo ought to be worth
2000 pounds, sir.
Come along, Alfonse.
Just a minute, Mr. Bush.
What is the cargo?
Forty tons of powder, 100 casks of beef
and 1000 bushels of oats, sir.
A thousand bushels...?
- Do you know what that means?
- A lot of horses, I'd say.
Correct. And horses mean cavalry,
and cavalry means a land engagement.
Where were you bound for?
Come on, man, or I'll guillotine you
here and now.
- Where were you bound for?
- La Teste, captain.
La Teste.
There's no army near La Teste,
is there?
You were transferring your cargo
to four French ships of the line?
The ones that escaped from Brest?
For an attack on Wellington and Spain.
I knew it. Sentry, take this man
down to the cable tier.
Mr. Bush, cram on all sail
and set a course for La Teste.
You're going
without advising the admiral?
We've no time. I'd rather be court-martialed
than let those ships get away.
Send the French brig
to look for Leighton.
- Aye, aye, sir.
- Oh, and Mr. Bush...
...pass the word to the sailmaker
to make me a French flag.
Aye, aye, sir.
- Let's hope that fools them, sir.
- We'll know soon enough, Mr. Bush.
Clear for action, but keep
the gun ports shut and crew out of sight.
- Aye, aye, sir. Beat to quarters.
- Beat to quarters!
Stand by on the quarterdeck!
Mr. Bush.
There is a magnificent sight.
Mr. Gerard, we'll load with chain shot.
I want those four Frenchmen dismasted.
Aye, aye, sir.
Hoist M.V.
That fooled them, sir.
I really believe they're pleased to see us.
Might be somewhat different
on the way back.
Especially with the wind dropping away.
We'll close to point-blank range
and take them in succession, Mr. Bush.
Aye, aye, sir.
Now, strike that French flag
and send up our own!
At her rigging. Fire as you bear!
Fire as your guns bear!
Fire!
- Fire to starboard. Wear ship!
- Aye, aye, sir.
We'll give her another broadside.
For luck, lads!
- Port, you helm.
- Aye, aye, sir.
Bring up the spinnaker.
- Bring her as close as she'll take.
- Aye, aye, sir.
Fire when ready, Mr. Bush!
Fire when ready!
Broadside, fire!
Get this gun back into action.
Get the wounded below.
Fire as your guns bear!
Keep firing, men. Keep at it!
Get back to your guns, men.
Another broadside!
Let them have another broadside!
Fire!
Come on, get this off, you devils.
Get it off. Get it off.
- Carter, bring me a length of line here.
- Aye, aye, sir.
Well, we left them cold meat
for Leighton, sir.
Six feet of water in the well, sir.
We're sinking.
Then we'll sink her where it'll do
some good, in the main channel.
Draper, Saunders, Derrick,
bring the wounded up from the cockpit.
Tie them to anything that will float!
Men, give a hand here with Mr. Bush.
Lash him well to a grating.
Quist, give a hand here with this gun.
Men, clear the deck. Pull it in.
Scoot around forward.
Quickly, men. We'll her sink here right here,
with a shot through her hull.
That's right. Chuck it up.
- Lf you don't mind, Mr. Quist.
- Aye, aye, sir.
Stand by now.
Over the side! Abandon ship!
Over you go!
Fellas, give a hand!
Come on, or you'll go down with her.
Come along, boys. Overboard.
- Over the side, Quist.
- Aye, aye, sir.
Look at the Sutherland, sir.
They'll never get past her now.
They're like ships in a bottle.
So it would seem, Quist.
Men.
Our squadron should be here
before nightfall. That means you'll be free.
Mr. Bush, you and I are to be taken to Paris
and tried as pirates.
Well, I expected to lose my leg, sir,
but not all the way up to the neck.
Pardon, sir, but Mr. Bush
didn't ought to travel far without care...
...not with that leg of his.
I'd like to look after him, if you don't
mind putting up with an old jailbird.
Oh, I can't allow you to do that, Quist.
The wind is getting stronger every second.
You'll be on your way home
with the rest of them.
I respectfully submit,
you won't hardly find a way of stopping me.
Thank you, Quist.
Well, I'll say goodbye to you now, men,
for myself and Mr. Bush.
It's not likely
that we'll ever see you again.
You know the England
that you fought for.
You know that you never need lose faith
in her final victory.
I want to thank you all...
...for the honor that you've bestowed on me
by fighting at my side.
What's all that yelling mean, sir?
They've just sighted our squadron.
Good for Leighton!
Captain Hornblower,
you're leaving for Paris immediately.
Inside, or you shall find your grave here.
You're about to lose your ships, colonel,
and the fort.
That is hardly likely
to endear you to the emperor.
How is it now, Bush?
It's not my leg that's worrying me, sir.
It's knowing that you won't even try
to make a break as long as I'm here.
- I'm afraid he's delirious, Quist.
- He's not, sir. He's talking sense.
If you get a chance, why don't you
have a go, sir? I'll stick with Mr. Bush.
It's all or none of us.
- I'm afraid I dozed off. What was wrong?
- Something with the wheel.
They didn't wanna get
their delicate hands dirty.
You all right, Bush?
I feel better than I have for days, sir.
I had a good sleep.
Just the same, sir, I think we ought
to keep a tight hold on him for a bit.
I made a terrible job of fixing that wheel,
sir. Ought to be flogged for it.
- What's he say, sir?
- The horses are loose.
He sent three of the men after them.
Now's your chance, sir.
You two. Get out of the coach.
Go. Pick up that wheel.
No. I'll slow you down, sir.
You get on without me.
- It'll be quicker this way, sir.
- Out this way.
- Does it hurt, Bush?
- Less every day, sir.
We'd stand a better chance
if we looked like the others.
So I borrowed these.
Quist, you ought to get a medal.
A medal, sir?
I got the jail for that in Hampshire.
Now, don't tell me
you stopped to cook these.
A poacher I may have been, sir,
but a cook, never.
Those birds just sort of flew
out of the kitchen into me hands, sir.
Where would you say we are, sir?
Oh, this is probably a tributary
of the river Loire.
If we continue on, we should each
the port of Nantes, God willing.
- And after that, sir?
- Beyond Nantes is the sea.
And beyond that, England.
Oh, sink me, Portsmouth.
All in good time, gentlemen.
Meanwhile, remember, you're French.
- Look over at that dock.
- Why, it's the old Witch of Endor, sir.
She went aground on the French coast
during the october gales.
She looks seaworthy enough now,
though.
It'd take about 20 men to handle her,
I'm afraid.
Aye. This is one time I wish
we was octopuses.
Steady. Uniforms.
Why, they're not Frenchmen.
They're Hollanders.
Dutch, sir.
They're still Napoleon's allies, though.
Right, Mr. Bush.
And as such,
they have access to all shipping.
Set a course for that rowboat, Quist.
We won't be French much longer, Quist.
What's all that about, sir?
Big Dutchman's giving a birthday party.
Let's join in.
Only an anchor watch aboard, sir.
Two hands and a master's mate.
- What are they, sir?
- Convict labor.
Fair riles me to see human beings treated
that way, even if they are Napoleon's men.
I'd like to brain that sergeant
and throw him in the sea.
They're English prisoners, sir.
Let's go aboard.
I'll send the other two down here.
See that they're entertained.
Aye, aye, sir.
Looks like fair weather, Mr. Bush.
What's up now, Alf?
Seems that the Dutchman wants us
to move the Witch downstream.
Might be the chance
of throwing the sergeant overboard.
You said you'd brain him
and throw him in the sea.
- What are you waiting for?
- Come on, lads, let's go.
Over the side with him. Over the side.
Put me down, you fools!
I'm from Hampshire.
Let go of me!
No, no, no. Not them.
Cast off, Mr. Bush. Take the wheel,
Quist. Make sail, men.
We're on our way to England.
All right, lads. Come on, now.
Heave! Heave!
- Heave! Heave!
- Drop the topsail!
Heave! Heave!
- Let the wind take her!
- Aye, aye, sir.
The Witch of Endor?
Captain Horatio Hornblower?
If your eyesight's good and I'm sober...
...there's a dead man approaching
in a lost ship.
Answer back the Flying Dutchman just
got in ahead of him. And sign it St. Peter.
It's the truth. It's the Witch.
I'd know that girl's beakhead anywhere.
Here, let's send a telegraph.
Witch of Endor? Hornblower?
- Is everyone in Plymouth drunk, Woodford?
- It's the Witch, sir.
And they've confirmed Hornblower
in private code.
Well, why are you standing about, man?
Meet him where he lands. Bring him here.
The news has gone around.
All Plymouth's wild with excitement.
Plymouth? If it really is Hornblower,
all England will go wild.
Prize crew.
Goodbye, Quist.
- I hope we sail together again.
- Thank you kindly, sir.
Perhaps you'll come
and take a glass of ale...
...in the pub I'll buy with my prize money.
I'll call it the Hornblower Arms.
I'd be honored, Quist.
Goodbye, sir. God bless you both.
- Goodbye, men.
- Goodbye!
Gad, Hornblower, the only pleasure
I seem to get from life these days...
...is when you come home
from one of your adventures.
Thank you. May I call your attention
to the gallant behavior...
...of my first lieutenant, Mr. Bush?
- Indeed you may.
Mr. Bush, the greatest pleasure
of an admiral is to reward good conduct.
I'm promoting you to captain.
If Leighton knew you were alive...
...l'm sure he'd have recommended it
in his last report.
- His last report, sir?
- Of course, you couldn't have known.
He was killed at La Teste. Great loss.
We need all our admirals
if we're ever to finish this confounded war.
- Yes, my lord.
- Oh, yes. Nearly forgot.
Hornblower,
you're to leave for London at once.
- Oh, I'm afraid I can't, sir.
- Can't?
Wouldn't be surprised
if there was a knighthood in it for you.
Thank you, my lord.
But I'd like to see my son first.
In that case, you'd better be off.
Thank you, my lord.
[ENGLISH]