Parou~
Morning!
Time for lunch!
Eat your food.
Cat cafe
Translated, timed and subbed by Rjgman56.
People with a ton of different tastes and hobbies have gathered around.
Akihabara is a city in Japan where you can enjoy food and all kinds of hobbies.
In this city there are customers who like to be consoled and surrounded by cats.
There is a cat cafe that will hopefully improve their mood and put a smile on their face.
The name of that cafe is Mocha!
People who are burdened with worries can be consoled here.
It is a warm place.
This person is Yamagoto-san.
He's a master at cat play.
He wears a military outfit all the time and is the store manager of a neighborhood store.
This is Yumi-san.
Because Akihabara is on the way to work...
She comes here to have fun and play around.
Her job is...
A secret!
The older cats are always doing things at their own pace.
It seems like cats who act like this are popular.
He is in his twenties but a manager of a company.
He is an elite businessman named Aizawa-san.
And the store manager of this new cafe is me.
Sakuragi Sakura.
It's a little bit different than the job I wanted to do since I was a kid but...
This place right now is my special place.
Being surrounded by a lot of unique customers and cats..
Makes everyday so fulfilling.
It seems like we are going to have a new encounter again today.
I'm interested in that cat.
Is this your first time?
Yes!
Is there any cat you're interested in?
No..well...not yet...
Even if the cats are a similar color...
They all have very different personalities depending on which one you pick.
Is that right?
Yes!
For example!
This cat is a British shorthair named Puri-chan!
She's our store's number one cat!
Puri?
It's a cute name.
That's right!
It's hard to tell the difference when she wants to do something or she doesn't want to.
She's a total Tsundere but she's such a sweetie that she has a ton of fans.
You have a lot of fans?
Are you okay?
Sorry about that!
But...I have to go now..
I'll come again.
Okay!
Please come again.
I'll be waiting for you!
Is something wrong?
Well..
That girl...
An idol?
I don't know too much about them but..
If I'm not mistaken, I believe she is from the idol girl group called Hoshikuzu Shoujo.
It's just that she's not a very popular member from the group.
There's always been rumors that she's going to retire.
Thank you so much!
Thanks as always!
Thank you!
I think it would be better if you smiled a little bit more.
Yes, thank you.
Really? That makes me happy!!
Then come again tomorrow! Thanks!
Thanks!
Is that right? You dyed it red?
Then shall we dye it red together?
It looks really good on you!
Is it okay for you not to be over there?
Well..it's fine for today.
Sometimes we want to be your fans too.
Thanks.
Besides...you know?
Well..you see Shiho-chan...
How do I say this?
She talks to us from there with a smile on her face but..
She's not really that good at starting conversations.
It's kinda like...every time we go over there she can't really think of anything to talk about.
Is that right?
But I'm glad that you came.
Come again okay?
Thanks!
Thanks! Bye! Bye!
Later!
Thanks!
It seems like the underground idol Shiho Namiki-sama skipped on cleaning duties again today~
Seriously? She can't help sell so she should just quit already.
She's already being punished by staying in the group. LOL.
Just quit!
I've seen a live video before but there weren't that many people there. LOL.
I think I saw that video too. Namiki wasn't really popular at all.
I'm home!
Welcome home.
Where's your friend?
She went to go get Shouta.
Oh, is that right?
What about dinner?
It's okay. I already ate.
Are you dancing and jumping around like always?
There's a lot of idols these days aren't there?
Pretty much.
What are you going to do after you graduate high school?
Is that really going to supply you money?
I don't know.
You don't know? This is about you.
It's fine to chase after your dreams but...
Wouldn't it be better to think about something more realistic?
One, two, three, four!
Should we try out another pose?
Ready..set...
One, two, three, four..
Just like that!
One more time.
Five, six, seven, eight!
Shiho!
Are you doing a proper job?
Your fans that came over to me won't always do that!
Sorry...
I don't want you to apologize.
During our handshakes with fans...
Don't just stand there but show our fans a good time!
Are you even giving it any thought?
That's enough!
Shiho is doing her best...
Doing her best? She's just causing fans to leave!
Yui!
I want to make Hoshikuzu Shoujo more popular!
In order to do that...
Everyone feels the same way!
That's why we're pushing ourselves...
When has she ever pushed herself?
How is Shiho going to grow if she just stands there and does nothing?
Yui!
It's fine! Just leave her alone.
But...
What the heck?
Now then, we have the last song coming right up!
Umm...
What is it?
I have a little announcement to make.
Umm...
I..Namiki Shiho...
I'll retire as an idol this month.
What's the meaning of this?
I've already made up my mind.
Are you being serious?
Aren't you being a little too hard on yourself?
I'm not popular anyways!
It will be the same if I'm not there.
Wakana.
Is it okay for you not to pick that up?
Yes...
I'm a little tired.
There's days like that too huh?
It must be nice to be popular...
But this cat is actually a very hard worker.
Well...maybe it's a black cat...
Translator note: Kuronin means hardworker and Kuro means black. It's a wordplay.
A black cat?
When this cat first came here it became popular very quickly but...
All of the other cats were jealous of her.
They were jealous?
That happens too?
It does.
It happens.
In the cat world as well.
They get a little outcasted from their comrades.
They get outcasted?
But Puri is strong!
And she never lost herself!
After that she started to gain friends slowly but surely.
I'm not strong like that.
I'm sorry! Did I do something to...
It's me!
Just quit! Unpopular idol.
I think I'm worthless.
I shouldn't be a partner to those girls..
But...
Whether it's in my house or at my company...
It doesn't matter where. I don't have anyone on my side...
There are times when I can't endure that.
There's not a single person I can tell this too.
Thanks for telling me this.
Do you feel relieved?
Puri?
What's wrong?
She's saying "You're not alone!"
She's helping you cheer me up.
Thanks Puri.
If you're with me then everything is okay huh?
Puri.
Thank you for today.
Not at all. I didn't do anything.
I felt like you were pushing me forward.
I'm glad.
First, I'm going to tell the other members my true feelings.
That's right.
Yeah!
Sensei!
Sakura sensei!
I'll see you again sensei!
I'm sorry!
Do you really want to quit?
Then why?
Show me your smartphone.
Just do it!
You're always looking at your smartphone with a scared look.
I thought that it might be this.
Yui...
Shiho!
There's no need for you to be in the same room as the people who throw stones at you!
Umm...at the last live I made a retirement announcement but...
Please let me take it back!
I want to continue being an idol with these members!
Please take care of me!
Now then...let us all get fired up together!
Please listen to...
"Sun! Sun! Sun!"
The sky that you can see...
Has no limits to it's height.
We used to look at the blue sky all the time in the past.
Under the hot sunshine..
We had our backs pressed together underneath the sunshine.
We couldn't handle this hot summer day.
We don't want these days to stop.
We don't want this excitement to stop.
We have no choice but to jump.
Boom! Boom! Boom!
Just like a gun..
Up! Up! Up!
Shoot for the sky!
We have a smile on our faces.
Our dreams will for sure come true in the future.
We aren't going to stop!
Sun! Sun! Sun!
Our high expectations.
Someone will come and be the light in our life.
It's all going to start from here.
We are connected to our future right now...
Just like a bird in the sky.
Puri!
Thanks for the other day.
She's hard to catch.
This one is cute too.
You're right...
So cute!
He's a cutie right?
So cute...
Everyone may not cheer you on.
There are times where you worry or stop in a standstill.
But if you change your perspective a little bit then there should be people who are there to support you.
And the person who ends up supporting you is your biggest fan.
Sometimes I get very curious on how the cat's memory works.
How much do they remember me and the guests?
I'm always observing them but I don't see too much.
They are unable to speak.
How is the fish?
Is it yummy?
It's yummy isn't it?
The cat who carries memories.
Sayo-san.
Are you off work?
Yes!
I haven't seen you around lately and so I got worried.
I'm sorry.
I've been a little bit busy.
Is that right?
Please don't push yourself too much.
When you're not around, Goumon gets lonely.
Thanks.
Day service Chiyoda.
That will be 2000 yen.
I'm sorry. I'll come again!
Yes!
I'm sorry...
She suddenly called someone a thief while she was going on a walk..
And then she started swinging her cane at them.
I'm sorry for causing trouble...
Thank goodness that the person who was walking didn't get hurt but...
If she gets too violent we won't be able to care for her anymore.
Sayo! Are you there?
I'm coming right now so wait right there!
That's how it is.
Thank you!
Sayo!
Are you there?
Hurry up and take off my shoes!
My feet are so sore!
Very very very sore!
I'll massage them afterwards.
I'm very sorry to say this but your Mother's Alzheimer's is very advanced.
At this stage she will have plenty of delusions and mood disorders.
It is very important for her family to be kind to her and take proper care of her.
Please don't confuse her, get mad at her, or blame her.
This is no good!
I'm telling you to get away from me!
Hey, come on..what are you doing?
Stop it!
Be quiet!
Hey Mom..it's time for your bath!
Mom!
Stop it!
Open up!
Mom!
That's not the place where we are living!
Hey!
Who are you?
Is Sayo-san okay?
Hey Goumon..
Do you remember your parents?
He's so cute when he looks over here!
Mi! He's looking everywhere.
He's getting so big.
Mi! Mi-chan!
In the past...
I was always thinking about if I was reborn in a different household.
What don't you like?
What is causing you to do this?
Everyone in the daytime are a lot nicer than you!
Then why don't you just get out of this house?
I'm home!
Have you eaten dinner yet Mom?
Mom?
Mom!
Sayo-san?
What's wrong?
I said something awful to her after all.
With cats, even if they get into fights...
They will get along again and sleep together in 10 minutes.
I want to be able to get over things as fast as they do.
That sounds like something you would say.
Even if you got into a fight with your Mom...
I hope that she will be able to forget about it soon.
I wonder if I can be as kind as you are?
I don't understand my Mom anymore.
Mi?
I remembered something.
Mi? Where are you?
My father used to have a really cute cat called Mi.
But after my father's funeral, he suddenly left the house.
And then when I was looking for Mi, I ended up getting lost.
Mi-chan was probably lonely huh?
After your dad passed away.
I wonder if your Mom left the house in the night with the same feelings as Mi-chan?
Is she looking for my father?
Mom? Are you there?
Mom!
Mom?
Mom...
Is this place...
Sayo!
Mom...
Mi!
Saiyo-chan.
Don't cry.
Look, I found Mi-chan.
Okay? Let's go back.
She wasn't looking for your father?
Were you looking for him this entire time for me?
Mom...
I'm sorry...
I was scared.
I was scared you would forget everything.
I was afraid you might forget me and Dad...
What are you looking at?
The sky?
He's looking at the sky!
There's clouds.
Can you see the sakura trees?
Mi...
Thanks...
Sayo-san!
Sakura-san!
Yukie-san.
Good afternoon.
We had a wonderful meal again today didn't we?
Yes, yes.
You always eat wonderful food.
She's not this calm everyday though.
From now on...when things get tough then tell me please.
Thanks.
Please bring Yukie-san with you the next time we go out shopping.
Sure!
Shall we go?
There are times when we remember things that we have forgotten about.
That is proof that we have lived.
The fun memories...
The sad memories...
I think that life is very abundant with both of these kinds of memories.
And I'm sure that what happened today will become a good memory for me.
There is a cat cafe in Akihabara called Mocha.
Regardless of someone's gender, nationality, age or occupation...
There are a ton of people who come here daily.
They come with various feelings to see these cats.
Most of them are cat lovers but..
Sometimes they aren't.
A spoiled kitty with blue eyes.
What's up with that guy?
He's just been sighing a lot...
He's a customer who has come here a lot though...
He kinda gives off some bad vibes...
I wonder if he knows that he is being a nuisance?
Is that how it is?
Then why is he here?
Recruiting people in their 30's and 40's.
This is Yoko. How are you? The other day you made a promise with Miku. I want you to decide on a day to fulfill that promise.
President Otegawa. 5th anniversary. Congratulations. From the company.
Yoko...
I finally found you.
Leave all the lawyer stuff to me.
That's right.
I don't want you to be bothered by all that stuff.
That's not a problem.
Later!
Hey...
Are you eating properly?
I'm not going to die. I'll make it work somehow.
You know what?
Miku is looking forward to seeing you.
You can set aside some time right?
I'm sorry.
Why are you sorry?
I don't plan on seeing Miku.
Umm!
How about we wear this together?
What the heck is that?
Ah! These are cat ears that you put on your head...
I can tell by looking at it!
Why do I have to wear something so stupid like that?
Because...you're always making such a scary face!
If you're having a hard time with the cats...
Then you need to make yourself look like a cat as well!
Stop spewing all of that nonsense!
That scared the hell out of me!
What the hell is wrong with you dumbass!?
Hey!
What's up with that attitude?
What's up with you?
I should be asking you that!
Why are you coming to a cat cafe and then abusing the cats?
Hold on! I apologize for that!
Like I said...What's up with you?
Umm..sir..how can I say this?
You are going to scare the cats with your behavior and attitude.
Cats are very sensitive creatures!
Voices and sounds that might not be a big deal to humans will scare the cats!
Are you saying that it's my fault?
Well...yes...
Aren't you pampering them too much?
All these kinds of sounds happen all the time!
If they are scared by something like this...
Then aren't you and the cats all sensitive weaklings?
That's not true...
Whatever!
What's up with that guy?
Umm...
It's you...
Here you go!
Did something happen?
What is this place?
This used to be my castle.
Half a year ago.
I divorced my wife.
I don't plan on seeing my daughter anymore.
I don't want to bother them or put any burdens on them.
Umm...can I ask you a question?
You're always looking at your smartphone aren't you?
What are you looking at?
Don't tell me...is voyeurism your hobby?
There's no way that's that true!
Then please prove your innocence!
So cute!
How old is she?
She's seven and a half years old.
Her name is Miku.
Miku-chan huh?
Miku seems to be obsessed with that cat.
She made a promise with me to go and see her one last time.
I plan on declining somehow.
I can't see my daughter for the last time and show her that I'm scared of cats...
Is that really all?
You don't want her to see your unsightly side?
Come with me!
What is it?
Hey..hey...what's going on?
You made a promise didn't you?
Yeah...
Then you need to keep it!
Not seeing her is going to make you look way more lame!
This kitty is called Hokomato.
It's the same kind of cat that Miku-chan has.
It is a ragdoll breed.
Ragdoll?
When people pick them up they are very relaxed or go limp.
They look just like stuffed animals so that's why they're called Ragdolls.
It's okay!
When I was a kid I got scratched by a cat...
It's not going to scratch you!
Here!
I'm going to wear this?
Yes!
In order to understand the feelings of a cat...you have to act like one.
You're making a scary face!
You need to be calmer. Take a deep breath, take a deep breath.
Okay!
Here...
Come here!
He's licking it! He's licking it!
Your voice is too loud!
You're going to scare him away again!
Take a deep breath, take a deep breath.
Yes, just like that....
It's okay if you do it normally.
Normally huh? Normally...Normally...
Hey...
You can make a wonderful face like that too can't you?
This cat is pretty spoiled isn't he?
Both of you seem pretty spoiled to me.
Shut up...
Normally huh?
He's acting like himself.
He's eating a lot!
A lot! Amazing!
The other one came!
So cute!
I saw a little bit of their sweet side.
I think that's important.
Umm...
Thank you...
I was able to learn a lot of different things from you.
You..the cats...and everyone here are pros after all huh?
Yes!
Papa!
Hurry up! Hurry up!
Okay! Okay!
Here you go Dad!
Alright..
I'll show you what I'm made of.
So cute!
Look Papa!
The feelings that you aren't able to say very clearly...
Sometimes you can start to become more honest about them bit by bit.
It might seem easy but it is actually pretty difficult.
But the most important thing is the smiles of the people who are important to you after you do so.
I'm sure...it can be done!
The words "Looking back" may be used in a slightly negative sense.
But the people who can look back are actually strong people.
And then, are the people who are able to make a step forward stronger?
I think that they do become stronger.
The other side of farewell.
I'm sorry to everyone who was affected by this tragedy.
I'll see you again sensei!
Nothing is abnormal.
Is that right?
Baron has been sick since yesterday.
Is he drinking water?
Yes. He's drinking a little too much.
Is that right?
Maybe it's stress?
Stress?
Has he been touched by a lot of different customers recently?
Not particularly...
And another thing...have you been stressed out?
Me?
Cats can feel when humans are stressed out and sometimes they get stressed out as well. So watch out for that.
Okay...
Is this theme good?
That looks nice.
Sakura-san.
Baron has had enough.
Sorry!
Are you okay?
Did something happen?
No, I'm totally okay!
Hana-chan?
You're late sensei.
It seems like Baron has calmed down already.
I see...
Thank goodness.
Sensei...
Why didn't you realize this?
Sorry...
I'm really sorry...
I had to keep holding him down.
Hana-chan...
Sensei...
You're too late.
Hana-chan...
Sakura-san.
Are you okay?
Yeah..
I'm okay...
Your face is looking pale.
It's time to give them some snacks.
Sakura-san!
Are you okay?
Sakura-san?
She bought a cat didn't she?
That's what it seems like.
A cat tower with no cat...feels pretty lonely.
She used to be my student.
I'm sorry!
It's okay!
You need to rest!
What about the store?
Yamamoto-kun is taking care of it.
Before I met you guys....I used to be a teacher.
Is that right?
I had a student called Hana-chan.
I found the cat that she was hiding behind the back of the school.
Sensei! How about we raise it together?
Well...but you know...
His name is Puchi!
It's a cute name isn't it?
You can't keep it at your house?
No way! My Dad can't stand cats.
In that case...
Where are you going to keep him?
Please sensei!
Okay..
I understand.
Then...let's take care of him together.
Sensei!
But this has to be a secret okay?
Yeah! Thanks!
That's good for you Puchi!
I did raise the kitty for some time but...
That girl died...
It was a suicide.
I was told that she was bullied.
I didn't notice it...
Sakura-san...
After that I quit from the school right away.
And I raised Puchi here.
Sorry about this.
It's a pretty depressing story.
That kind of thing happened huh?
Sakura-san.
You're always talking about other people.
But you never really talk about yourself.
That's right.
I'm not good at talking about myself...
Take a little break from the store.
About that...
You have a fever too.
Besides...you're going to this aren't you?
No...
I didn't go to the ceremony.
Even if I go now...
I don't know how to face her parents.
I think it would be better if you went.
Isn't the reason why Baron is stressed out because you have all of these worries?
Are you stressed out Sakura-san?
Me?
Cats can tell when a human is stressed out and they can become stressed too.
Be careful okay?
If that's the case...
Then for the sake of Baron and the other cats...
You need to go to Hana-chan's third year anniversary and sort out your feelings.
Sakura-san...
You need to rest some more!
It's okay.
My fever has already went down.
Sorry...this is my fault.
Alright! It's time for me to go back to my store.
Thanks.
You're a lifesaver.
If anything happens then call me right away.
Please don't push yourself too much.
Later!
Baron...
Is that okay?
Today is special.
I need to spoil him sometimes.
Are you feeling better?
It's a snack for cats after all.
Good for you Baron!
He's eating a lot.
I'm glad you're doing better.
Eat up.
Good for you Puchi!
I wonder if I can ever take care of him?
That's true.
After you graduate, won't you be living on your own?
That would be great!
I want to be with you forever!
Right?
Good for you Puchi!
Sakura-san?
Are you okay?
Sakura-san...
Hana-chan...really wanted to live.
I should have been more...
Yes?
Nice to meet you.
My name is Sakuragi Sakura.
Come in!
The food should be ready in a little bit.
Okay!
Thanks for coming here.
No problem.
Umm...
I need to apologize to you two.
Apologize?
Yes.
I was very close to Hana-san as her teacher.
That's why...
If I would have noticed this...
Then I could have done something and...
Everyone is saying the same thing.
Her teachers, her childhood friends and her other friends.
Everyone...
But you know what?
When we hear those words...It's super painful because we are the ones who think that the most.
We are her parents.
Why didn't we the family notice this?
When other people use those words...
We feel like we are being blamed...
That wasn't my intention!
I'm sorry!
It's fine! It's fine!
We didn't want to talk about that today.
You know what?
The other day...we finally organized Hana's room.
When we did, we found her diary.
To be honest...we were afraid to see it.
Today me and Sakura sensei feed Puchi some homemade fish snacks.
Puchi finished my meal. I'm only 18. I feel like it will be a little bit longer.
Lately Puchi hasn't had an appetite.
Sakura sensei has been researching a way on how to make pet food.
She's a god!
I took a lot of time in sewing toys for Puchi but it was a big failure!
Sakura sensei was laughing so hard she cried!
I'll get my revenge next time!
I'm really grateful that Sakura sensei was able to meet Puchi!
I'll look forward to seeing them tomorrow!
She didn't write anything about her getting bullied.
She wrote a ton of things about the fun times she had with you and us...
Thanks for being with Hana until the very end!
I was also so happy being together with Hana-san!
Puri! Puri!
Puri!
Welcome!
Are you by yourself?
Yes...
Sorry to keep you waiting!
There are some things in the past that I can't change and that I worry about.
But...even then...
I still want to do my best here!
There are people who are important to me and that cherish me.
And there are cats here who give me something irreplaceable.
In this place.
Thanks for watching! Please like my Facebook page at Rjgman56 Japanese drama subs fanpage for updates!