Florence, 1518
- This one?
- Yes.
- What are you doing here?
Can't you see?
Hiding?
I'm working.
He is working!
What a good fellow.
Drawing naked men for the monks.
I'm going to teach you to respect your masters.
I have no masters.
No?
Then what are you doing in that workshop?
Working gold for them.
And they throw you out?
- I left them!
They were stealing money from my wages!
And what were you stealing?
You lying slug!
You are jealous of my hands,
God guide my hands to work gold!
You'll never work gold again!
Come on!
Well, come on... come on.
I kill you all, bastards!
CELLINI
A VIOLENT LIFE
Who are you?
Porzia.
You are beautiful, Porzia...
Too beautiful to be out by yourself.
Come with me.
Who can resist an invitation like that?
But there is something you should know: I can't pay you.
Perhaps you can.
I believe you did this.
Where did you get it?
That is no business of yours.
You're Benvenuto Cellini, aren't you?
How do you know my name?
Who told you that I was in Rome?
Come with me and you'll find out.
Porzia.
This is a man.
And a very handsome man, too.
Would you like to spend the
night with the great lady?
Shut up, whore.
You are Benvenuto Cellini?
Answer me.
This is your idea of a joke?
Did you draw this snake?
- I just told you.
I've never seen you before.
Huh?.. I understand.
No, you don't.
But no matter.
They tell me you're a goldsmith?
Perhaps.
What is it to you?
You think diamonds could be mounted better?
If I mount them, yes.
Show me how you do it.
You draw far too well for a goldsmith.
And you understand drawing far too well for a woman.
Why did you pretend not to know who I was?
Because I only know what my eyes tell me.
And what your eyes tell you now?
That you are vain and ambitious.
Why start with my virtues?
What else?
That you are poor.
Isn't that why I am here?
Isn't a poor goldsmith just what you need?
Take it and bring it back melted your way.
Are you sure you'll see these diamonds again?
No, but I'm sure I'll see you again...one way or another.
Get out of my way.
Hey you, someone wants to see you.
Who?
Porzia.
Why such a strange face, signor Cellini?
You look so you've never see me before.
What are these games?
Where exactly am I?
Porzia?
You are in the house of Sigismundo Chigi, the Pope's banker.
A banker?
You just met his wife Sulpizia.
That is you.
- No, Sulpizia is Sulpizia and I...
Porzia.
- You enjoy making fun of me, don't you?
Enormously.
What's the point of this farce?
It's about time we had a farce.
All the dramas in this palace, it's so gloomy.
Money, power, treachery, blood.
I can only play my own part in life.
Wouldn't you like to play a part with me?
I will bid you goodbye, my lady.
What a fool you are.
Perhaps.
It's just a game.
Doesn't it excite you?
Two women who are really one... or vice versa.
Didn't you know that all women have two souls?
I don't see the souls, just the bodies.
What does it matter to you whether is Porzia or Sulpizia?
Isn't the life only the shadow of a dream, and we are only shadows?
When you kiss a woman, it could be her or someone else..
... it depends on how you kiss her.
You don't love me enough yet.
I'm not taking anymore bets.
There will be two more.
I bet three ducats on that.
Have you got them?
I'll have them, soon I will be the richest man in town.
It's true, so they say.
- What do they say?
- That you find a rich woman.
Come on, run, unfortunate one!
I won, I won!
I won.
Thank you, my beauty.
...today with you...
It's your fault, I am ruined!
Leave him alone!
Who the devil are you?
Someone who doesn't like seeing a child being beaten.
This is my son, I beat him when I want.
- How much not to beat your son?
- Never again?
Never again.
Is it enough?
Who are you, sir?
Who am I?
Someone who wants everything
and then discover..
... it means nothing to him, like these three ducats.
Are you a dreamer?
A great artist,..
who can take a hand of earth like this...
... and turn it into a beautiful living thing for all eternity.
So, raise... Come on.
Raising... Gently, carefully.
- Want a rosary?
- No thanks.
Beautiful... How much is it?
Are you sure the lady will like it?
- Do you?
-Not a bit
it's just like a..
You have great talent.
What's the matter?
Don't you want to be paid?
I didn't work for money.
I worked for you.
Don't you know the proverb?
When the poor give to the rich, the devil laughs.
Well, let him laugh.
What is that you really want?
An introduction to the Pope.
I won't introduce you to the Pope,..
... but I will send him your jewels.
And what's more
I'll give you money to make your workshop worthy of you.
And in return, you will give me a fifth if the price
... of every piece you sell.
Only a fifth?
Why not half?
Yes, you're right, you will give me half.
I never divided anything with anyone.
You will with me.
And if I don't accept?
Why should I?
Because I know that gold jewels' bussiness.
And?
And your hands are good bussiness.
Teach me, I pray you.
- What would you know?
How to become a courtyard.
Can you swear, are you a gambler, do you mock your neighbour.?
Are you a heretic, a slanderer, a scandal monger?
Are you an agent and a patient?
- Wait, what is an agent and a patient?
- Well, husband and wife.
But women no longer frequent the court.
This is because is forbidden to take a wife.
One takes a husband.
Is he a new player or do my eyes deceive me?
No, Your Holliness, your eyes have not deceived you.
Do I know him?
- I say so.
How do you become a heretic?
When someone tells you that at court, goodness, discretion
love and integrity, try to say: "I don't believe it".
I don't believe it.
- What is your name, my son?
- Benvenuto Cellini...
I am a Florentine.
Cellini.. Cellini?
The son of Master Giovanni... engineer to the house of Medici.
He served Your Holliness well,
when you were cardinal in Florence.
Haven't you a soul?
Of course I have, if I hadn't to be sladed.
My friend, seek for it your breast.
Here...
..it is.
What do you think, Benvenuto, whose soul are they talking about?
About mine.
But now it is no longer mine, it belongs to Your Holiness.
Your flattery is about as good as your play.
Why did you come here?
My father - may he rest in peace - told me to.
He came to me in a dream.
He was crying and said:..
... if you don't play for Pope,
you won't have my blessing.
What scoundrels are these Florentines,
even dead ones.
- How do you become an envious?
Hate other people's good fortune.
- How do you mock your neighbor? - Telling stories.
- How to spew poison? - telling the truth.
My father told me that I could serve
your holliness even better with my own art.
I am a goldsmith and sculptor.The best that is
Holy father, holy father, I know who this man is.
The Florentine authorities notifies his presence in Rome
to the Most reverend inquisitor.
Go on.
He had already been condamned for brawling, violence and lechery.
- It's true? - I was just a boy.
When he was brought before the Florentine court ...
... for the attempting murder of a young jeweler ...
- I had to defend my honor. -...and sentenced to death.
He must be send over to the Florentines
but they can hang him.
Look at this, fine example of people's splendor.
Why don't you make me a silver bowl where I can throw the bones.
Let me tell you how it should be.
A spout, you will make me a spout,
must be in the shape of a faun, you understand?
He will be suported but two naked nymphs with slightly bent legs.
Better, on second thoughts,
make them almost naked...almost.
Which is it to be today - are you Porzia, who came for love, ..
... or Sulpizia for money?
Who did you corrupt to go to the Pope?
A cardinal? .. A swiss guard?
A musician.
What did you pay him with?
A smile.
I am the one to get you work.
You'd be a fool to try on your own.
You'll never understand the way is Pope, cardinals and nobles.
You are an earthly creature ...
... they belong to heaven.
They think they do.
Our agreement was that I bought you, and only I will sell you.
Want some? ... Beans.
Who is the boy?
My apprentice ... Why?
Get rid of him.
If I knew what moves your heart, my lady , perhaps I'll do it ..
... but since I don't understand, the boy stays with me.
Paolino ... leave  me alone with the lady.
Are you in love with him?
What are you doing?
You are crazy.
No, but I will find out. - Porzia, Sulpizia? ..
- Game is over, understand?
No.
I'll have you murdered.
I swear, they'll find your body in the Tiber.
Benvenuto?
Benvenuto, where are you?
It's me, Porzia.
Porzia.
You are in danger, Benvenuto.
You must get away.
Look behind you.
Careful, you break my neck.
This is the left one, idiot.
What is this man doing here?
Your Holiness, you called me.
Did I? .. I dont remember.
Ah, yes.
I 've heard you've been behaved badly, licentious,
quarrelsome, arogant
I received a complaint from the Bishop of Salamanca.
He says you made him a silver vase ...
... and demanded payment on delivery.
- Is that true? - Absolutely true.
Good ... I'can't stand the bishop of Salamanca.
You may come closer.
What really happened with a certain lady?
Simply this.
I told her I was born a free man
and I wanted to live as a free man.
I wanted to belong to myself and not to others.
If anyone wanted me they should ask me.
Leave us alone.
My dear Benvenuto, do you think such words are appropriate in here?
I can't make up my mind whether I have to throw you out or ...
... or to envy you.
When they made me Pope, I also thought that I would be free.
But free to do what?
I seem to have everything, but there is one final temptation.
Do you know what the ultimate temptation is, Benvenuto ... for the Pope?
Sainthood.
I believe I shall be damned for wanting it.
But who knows, perhaps I served the Lord ..... exactly as I am.
Or perhaps He has no better material to work with
I don't like the word "freedom" coming from a mouth of a  Florentine.
It reminds me of when my family when thrown out of Florence - ..
... sedition, desorder, republicanism.
And you ...you annoy me.
You want to make too much noise in the world,
you are greedy for something.
What is it?
- Your money, Holliness. - What did you say?
Let me show you.
Here is a coin made by your predecessor's careless engravers.
Does Is seem worthy of the great Pope?
Appoint me Master of engravers of the Mint
... and I will make you the most beautiful coins in the world.
With your face on them.And your name
You will endure for all eternity.
I wasn't quite what I had in mind- to be remembered because of a penny.
Not just a penny, Holliness, a penny made by Benvenuto Cellini.
The plague is send by God?
- Who told you that?
The barber.
-On account of our sins? - In account of your sins, master.
Don't open it.
- Open up, Benvenuto. - It's Rosso.
Open the door, you scoundrel ... I heard you.
- You are alone? - Of course I'm alone.
- Go, Paolino. Are you locking out the oldest friends?
Come on, open up!
Rosso(Red).
- Benvenuto, ...you're broke.
You liar!
I brought Faustina with me.
Haven't you heard of Faustina? .. Half of Italy knows her.
The intimate friend of noblemen, cardinals...
Come on, you're exaggerating. - And the village priests too.
Look at her,
She's like Michelangelo's "Sibyl" ..
who's falling from the ceiling of the Sistine Chapel.
Flesh, as only he knew how to paint it.
Actually, if you looked at her naked,
you would understand what I mean
She ... she bought this for me.
I was down begging outside churches
- Where are they from? - From Venice.
From Venice? .. Get out of here all of you.
- What's the matter with you?
There is a plague in Venice, they'll carry us.
On the contrary, looking at you I'd say you had it.
not to mention scabies, frenchpox(syphilis)
colics, otitis media ... and  diarrhea.
- Who's she? - She is my darling daughter ...
You wouldn't think so, would you?
She's so thin and ugly.
Pantasilea!
Has it this beggar shag has the place they call a convenience
... where a lady can relieve herself decently?
I'm dying for a piss.
Faustina, read my hand.
And how much will you give me?
I will paint your portrait dressed up like a princess.
No, ... do it naked, I prefere that.
... I always feel better that way.
Your master did this?
How is he like? - He is wonderful.
- Is that what he says? - He really is.
Men are all alike.
No, he is not like anyone.
The others beat you or they want what they want.
No, sometimes he does tell lies
but I've find out why he does.
Sometimes he invent things ... stories.
- And people believe them? - He believes them.
You will have a lot of money, but not now.
Not yet.
So much money.
But you have a long, long way.
That's enough.
What's the matter?
What else have you seen?
Faustina, I want to know.
Sickness.
Here.
He is already sick, he has a tapeworm inside.
Listen, Rosso, why don't you read Faustina's hand ..
so we can find out with who she's gonna sleep tonight.
What do we do now?
What would you like to do?
One guess.
Rosso is asleep.
You're the one I want.
I know.
But there is only one bed.
You live like a peasant, and spend like a lord.
This will double your pleasure.
It's not for me, it's for him.
Rosso is a great painter, but is shy.
I wouldn't say so.
He has no luck with women.
Go to bed, Faustina, but afterwards..
tell him you did it for love.
Are you just good or are you ...
Is it the boy?
Have you got to sleep down there?
I'm just good.
It's not very wise to leave your door open ...
... when the man with the scythe walks.
But I closed it myself.
Then the devil must have opened it
to take you with him to his golden kingdom of darkness.
Can't defy me.
I can save you.
Who are you?
I am the doctor of the damned.
Benvenuto, are you talking to yourself?
What's the matter with you?
He's gone!
- Rosso, have you seen him? See him?
He is raving.
It was the devil himself.
He's ill.
He is ill.
How do you know?
He was up there with you, wasn't he?
Well, well, well, my girl lost her virginity.
You slept with him, didn't you, you little slut!
No wonder he's raving.
Just look at him!
This man has the plague!
The plague?
Get away from me ... Don't touch, don't touch me!
Rosso...
- Don't.
Rosso, stay with me!
Don't touch him, come here at once!
No, I'm staying with him.
You think the plague spare little whores like you?
Come on.
Don't leave me, I'm afraid!
Go away, don't touch me.
What are you doing here, goldsmith?
I need your help.
You ask for help from someone who tried to kill you?
I am sick.
You're just dreaming.
I've got the plague.
We all got the plague.
Please.
Say: my love.
Say it.
Please, ...
... my love.
Yes, you finally found your Porzia again.
She was my sister, the other side of my soul.
If we'd been one you might have loved us both.
Now get out.
No..
let me stay with her.
I want to die with her.
Go and die among your own kind.
Master, master, master!
Paolino, where am I?
You are here in the workshop, with me!
Fetch a doctor...
... the one who was here last night - the devil.
The devil?
I send for the barber.
It's him.
Tell me, Master Cellini, have you slept with anyone recently?
Yes, yes.
When?
Last night.
That's bad.
Don't you know it could be fatal during the plague?
What kind of creature?
A young girl.
How young?
Just a child.
Then perhaps there is still hope.
He has to drink to be purified ..
... if we can manage to disolve the humours.
Fetch some water, boy.
He's drowning!
Better to drown than die of the plague.
Is this what you call a plague?
I dont know what to call it.
I don't understand the meaning of such wondrous event.
I do.
Since time doesn't produce the same circumstances
the fortune always remains the same.
It is now certain ..
... that the Emperor Charles wanted to start a war king of Naples.
descending for this purpose from the Alps.
It would be a sin to give such a beautiful coin in the hands of the venturous ..
... usurers, gamblers,.
At least they know their value, your Holiness.
As a result, Your Holiness may find himself crushed, ..
between the mortar and the pestle.
Does he think I'm a clove of garlic?
Who wrote this?
Your legate in Germany at the court of the Holy Emperor Charles.
Tell him that His Holiness knows the designs of
providence without his assistance.
Not to mention those of the most cristian, I wonder, emperor.
You convinced me, you can have the mint.
Six silver scud a month, as wages.
Not including the cost of the material, naturally.
Clement, Clement, repent before it's too late.
Expiate your sins because your Rome is a New Babylon.
Is a nest of vices, corruption and death.
Everything will be destroyed by the flame
of the Antichrist, marching down from the Alps.
Listen.
Expiation
Anathema.
Forgive me, Holiness, I didn't know what I was saying.
Someone spoke for me ... Sorry.
Forgive me.
You may retire.
Recite a "Miserere"
And one for me too.
I should have him hung.
No, they are too many.
Rome is full of madmen preaching death ...
... it's all one hears
Are you? Are you afraid of death, Benvenuto?
When I was a boy, I saw a salamander in a fire.
She fought and twisted, but it didn't burn and didn't die.
It was an omen.My omen
I  shall never die.
More anguished you whores!
Use some feeling into it.
There is nothing to laugh about that, Faustina,
they just killed your son, for Goodnes sake
Show us some grief.
That's better.
Now try to weep.
And you three, up on the cross.
- The son of God is dead!- But we are still alive!
Benvenuto.
My God, who is this beautiful love treat?
She's called Pomona.
Why?
Pomona, this is Rosso Fiorentino, a great painter,
and once a great friend of mine.
Once?
Before you ran off and left me to die.
But there is nothing wrong with you ..
... and you manage to land with this beautiful creature!
Come, Pomona.
I want you to meet Giulio Romano, ..
and Gianfrancesco Penni.
Wonderful painters.
Both of them.
Great friends of mine!
I wish you have died,
so I could have forget all about you.
You have changed.
How changed?
Into a whore, you mean?
Thanks to you.
- Where are you going? - To move my bowels.
Do I need permission?
Or hers?
I love this shade of yellow.
There is a lot of it.
And this carmine too.
Especially a wood
Gorgeous.
When I was in the convent...
You, liar..
The only place you were ever in was a whorehouse.
even before you had hair between your legs.
Come away.
- What about you, Pomona? - I was never in a convent.
- Three ducats. - No.
- Five. - No.
Up to now you've cost me nothing.
I said no,
I didn't say I wanted your money.
Have  you forgotten?
I'll beat you!
I'm marrying  a tinker
For God sake, why?
So I don't have to sleep in different bed every night
and end up with bastards like you.
So why are you crying?
Because I won't see you anymore
... and I won't be a saint in your paintings.
I loved that.
You are a bunch of Godless sinners, ..
... but you do lovely saints
Yes, saints.
Naked men, naked women,
animals, billy goats, monsters, Gods!
This whore was so rich and her house was so fancy
then one day when the Spanish ambassador needed to spit, ..
...  he did it straight in the face of one of her servants
so as not to dirty the carpet.
See, grief is distorting their bodies.
What's the matter, aren't you feeling well?
No, not very.
Don't tell me you're pregnant.
Pregnant?
This always happens sooner or later.
- Let's see.
- No... no.
- Come on.
No, please.
Show Mother Faustina.
Look, it should be done like this.
- Well, show me. - No no.
No no no.
She is a man.
No.
Benvenuto told me it was just a joke.
Pomona is a man.
You have to decide who you prefere - boys or girls?
What a pity, I almost fell in love with her already.
Beauty.
Beauty isn't a natural condition, it's artificial.
Beauty has to be invented
... like your horses, Julio,
like my golden lilies, ..
Rosso's colors.
Glassmaker colors....and vulgars.
Figures as flat as pancakes
And you call yourself a Raphael's disciple?
Raphael is been dead only for 9 years.
You're right Penni, Raphael is dead.
I wonder what have you
done with his colors,
his skies, his methods of depicting
light and shadow, his flesh tones?
We shit on them, isn't that right friends?
You're disgusting.
You dirt his name.
Whose? Raphael?
The one who smacked his lips on the Pope's ass?
Raphael.
You heard what he said, Benvenuto, he insulted Raphael.
Yes, but why are you so excited?
Rosso says nasty things about everyone, even about God.
Do you remember how the abbot of the monastery of the Holy Trinity ...
...comisioned your first painting?
He run out of Florence when he saw it.
Shouting that he had never seen so many devils in a place before.
And you used to steal your mother's tin spoons
to make false coins.
Benvenuto, you saved my life this afternoon.
Yes, I did, although you don't deserve it.
Can you lend me a few thousands ducats?
A woman?
No, I'm leaving.
I'm frightened, Benvenuto.
The troops of the empire
are coming this way-
Mercenaries-30 thousand of them.
They are heading for Naples.
Rome is a golden cow, they 'll rip her belly along the way.
This is not my calf, someone will do something
Hear that?
They toll for Giovanni delle Bande Nere....
he was killed in Gadagnola a week ago., ..
... he was the last real soldier, ...
...which is coming to an end.
And I saw a woman sitting on a bright red beast ..
Having 7 heads and 10 horns.
She was covered in gold and precious stones and pearls
having a golden cup in her hand, ..
full of abomination and filthiness and fornication.
And I saw the woman drunken with the blood of the saints,
and with the blood of the martyrs of Jesus
... and she was that great city, Rome!
All the men report to the gates!
Do you think that prayers will save you?
And in one day should come to her the wrath of God,
they will all burn with fire.
To the gates!
And the whole city will be engulfed in flames, God will make his judgment.
Did you  hear me? .. To arms!
- Where is the river? - Over there.
Let's go back.
What? .. It was your idea.
I know,  but now I'm afraid. So am I.
-Well, then. Let's go back. - No.
We've seen enough.
No, that we're here we must behave like men.
I'm not a big man... a little man.
Little man.
Listen, Paolino, you go back home now.
- No, not alone. - Yes, alone.
Go back yo the house, shut yourself in , keep a close eye on things.
At a time like this, the city is full of robbers.
If I don't come back, it's all yours.
Do what I say!
Yes, master.
Holy Father, I've been looking for you everywhere.
You must come with me.
Let me die here.
Save yourself.
Help, pull me up.
The Pope!
You're facing a catastrophy, Your Holiness.
Camillo Orsini, who defended the Tarioni gate, has been overcome.
Captain Giulio de Ferrara was killed.
Rome is at the mercy of Germans, Spaniards, Bohemians  and Italians  as well
There are 30 thousand imperial soldiers in the city.
These are not soldiers, Holy father, just a bunch of thieves and murderers.
Fool!
You're responsible for all this.
The imperial generals asked him twice to negociate.
All they requested, your Holliness, was money, provisions
and free passage to Naples ...
And twice he refused them...
I told him to.
If only the romans have forces.
They did.
More then a thousand died at the gates.
All is not lost.
Within three days the Duke of Urbino will be here with his Venetian troupes.
The duke will never arrive... and nor anyone else.
We can't wait any longer.
I have already send Marc Antonio Altieri to the imperial camp...
... with an offer of surrender to the Constable of Bourbon.
The constable of Bourbon is dead.
How would you know? - I killed him.
Let me pass, let me show the Pope..
... what a German Antichrist wants to do with his church.
Take care of your eyes, brothers.
This unhappy man was Cardinal Christopher Nomalo.
Was, brothers, was.
The Lord gave up his altar and cursed his sanctuary ...
for the sins of his prophets and the inequity of his priests..
The Lord has thrown down and has no pity.
The Lutheran Antichrist came to Rome, ..
... to hang the Pope with a golden cord.
Forgive me, brothers ... This is my fault.
I'm alone to blame.
I thought in my heart that neither gold nor steel
was needed to save us..
... only my sacred presence  .
I was the one who was blind.
I confess it before this poor suffering creature.
Mea culpa ... Mea culpa.
Mea massima culpa.
Mea culpa.
Come on, get it here.
Like this.
Reload.
Fire.
Get back cannon position.
Why is no one here.
What are you doing here, you bastards?
I cut you to pieces!
No, my wife is down there.
Yes, being raped and disemboweled by those savages.
If I shoot you, then you will have hope to save your families from being killed ..
... and if you don't shoot, I'll kill you.
Give me that.
I hit it, hit it.
Go to the east side.
Where is the core.
Are you having a good time, Benvenuto?
Wonderful, much better than my art.
Come on, for the glory of God!
We are not afraid of you.
It's me, Holy Father, Benvenuto.
I want to confess.
The Venetians have abandoned us,
the troops are looting the palaces...
are killed.
Pier Luigi Fornese is filling his castle, ..
... the son of the cardinal is filling his castle
with treasures stolen from the churches of Rome.
And you?
Want to confess?
Yes, for all my kilings.
A lot of them, Benvenuto?
How many, tell me?
I can't say, Holy Father, but many...so many!
Did you hear that, most eminent Cardinals?
There is a man who is actually killing our enemies ..
... there is a man who is trying to save our beloved city.
Come forward, come and listen to him.
Well, Benvenuto, give us some details.
Yesterday ... I saw a Spanish prince down there, in the fields.
having some trenches repaired.
Go on.
But far away, about three kilometers.
So I took my firing piece (shell) and loaded it with the finest gunpowder.
I calculated the trajectory and distance, and fired.
Out of vanity this prince carried a big sword,
and he was holding it in front of him like this.
My cannonball struck him directly ...
... and I swear to you, the sword himself cut him in half.
In half?
In half, Holy Father.
Amazing.
A terrible sight.
No no.
Yes, that's why I need to confess.
You already confessed.
Give me absolution.
"Ego te absolvo a peccatis tuis"
For all the crimes ..
... which I did for the Roman Apostolic Church.
Ego te absolvo
And for the ones that I'll have yet to commit.
You always ask a great deal, don't you, Benvenuto?
"Ego te absolvo a peccatis tuis"
In the name of the Father the Son and the Holy spirit.
What are you doing here?
Conditions for the surrender of the castle known as Sant Angelo ...
signed on June 5, 1527 from the birth of Christ ...
... by the imperial captains: ..
... Prince Filibert D'Orange, count of Foerberg, ..
... Giovanni d' Urbino, Andrea Mendoz and myself - Gian Bartolomeo Dekinara.
His Holiness Clement VII entrust himself to the mercy ...
...of most Catholic Emperor Charles V pledging himself ...
... to conceal gold and valuables for the sum of 400,000 gold ducats.
In guarantee of which sum, which can be paid in three installments, ..
... the castles  ...and Ostia, ..
... Civitavecchia, Modena, Parma and Piacenza,
are to be handed over
... together with the most eminent cardinals Salviati, ...
... Ridolfi ...
... and Ricasoli.
Why me?
I am not responsible for what His Holiness has done.
They will be imprisoned.
And in case of defaulted payment, put to death.
Pope Clement will remain a prisoner
in the castle until the payment is consigned.
He will be granted 10 bronze scudos a day.
Dear Master Cellini.
When did I became dear to you, master Cavalgino?
His Holiness wishes to ask you for a favor.
One that is highly secret and of a great importance to the church.
Benvenuto, I ask you to do for me, for the church, ..
... what no Pope had dared to ask for a thousand years.
I do not understand, Holiness.
Use your head, idiot.
How do you think we're going to pay the ransom of 400,000 ducats?
From St. Peter's gold.
Start with this cross.
Start what?
We want you to separate gold from the other metals.
Melt it down and recast it into 5 pound lingots.
- No. - You're the goldsmith.
But not a fool.
Why me?
Everything will be forgiven to you, Holiness.
But who knows the questions a poor devil like me will have to answer one day..
Why were you there, Benvenuto?
What profit did you make out from it?
It was sacrilege, Benvenuto.
I forgive you in advance.
In any case, the matter is already decided.
Master Cellini has agree to do this favour for the church.
Watch him day and night ..
... don't let him out of your sight for a moment.
Chalice with decoration, ..
... weight one quarter of a pound.
Primitive but beautiful.
I'm not an artist.
You don't have to be an artist, just a man.
I wonder where she came from.
Somewhere on the other side of the world.
Her gold may have come from stealing, usury, blood, ..
and yet she may be worth of miracles.
Pull out the eyes out before you melt it down.