What are you doing there?
Give coffee and tea for the guests!
You do this work
- Shall I bring the bride?
- Yes -Ok
- Sit down!
- Move aside!
Put it there!
Auspicious time is coming
Bring the groom quickly! -Ok
- I'll bring the sacred rice
- Ok!
Chakram, auspicious time is running out!
- Is he inside? -Yes madam!
- Then why doesn't he open the door?
- Chakram brother!-What happened?
- He is not responding!
- What happened?-Nothing Mom!
- Oh dear! -Nothing -Oh god!
- Dear! -Be quiet
- He is not opening the door!
Dear!
- Brother, Open the door!
- Open the door
- Break the door!
- Break it!
- Brother!
Hit with force!
Don't be late!
Dear!
Dear! Chakram is not there
I don't like this marriage
Don't search for me! Chakram
- In law!
- Doesn't he like this marriage?
- Sister!
- Au nty!
- Lakshmi, check her
- Aunty, get up!
Go! He wouldn't go a long way!
- Wherever he is, catch him!
- Ok sir!
Search!
Go
Go away!
- Brother!
- Come on!
He is going there!
Come on
Chennai!I don't mind if you lose your life
I want him (Chakram)!
She is not your daughter but mine!
It may be my son, who did
injustice to my daughter...
I'll slash him!
Die! I'll die!
This problem will not be solved
until I die!
This is the problem from the day
I married you!
You are complaining about my Mom
and I am complaining about you
That's why for the last one week
I am roaming and sleeping in the auto
But you're making calls
to me. Don't shout!
I'll die! -Brother, auto..
- I'll not come!
You won't prosper until I die!
I'll die in the Hussain Sagar(River)
or any railway track!
- Brother, please! - I told you
that I won't come. Go
Collect my body at the evening
from Gandhi Hospital!
- Don't shout!
- Brother
I told you that I won't come
Go
Do you want me to explain?
That's what I am telling
You are killing me like this!
You, idiot!
- Please brother
Do you think this is your Dad's auto?
- I want to go back to the mosque brother!
Oh god!
Water!
Where is the water bottle?
- Water!
- Take it
Don't be afraid
I will die within few days
Blood will come out sometimes
- Don't mistake me
I want to tell you something -Tell me
Death only will come without inviting
and without doing any hard work
If a person like me cannot live
even if he wants to live
Is it a curse to you?
You have a golden life
All problems will be solved if you talk
with your wife and mom
Why are you going to die for this?
You should live
You should fight
But, don't say I'll die!
Thanks for giving water. Sorry for
speaking nonsense! I take leave!
I'll drop you
Where do you want to go?
Where do I want to go?
Sahara ironing.com
I want a two bedroom flat!
Keep the phone down!
When did this wastrel come? Has your
yesterday's stupor not yet come down?
It is not yesterday's stupor
coming down, brother in law!
The stupor that I boozed today
is not mounting up!
- Stop your trumpery!
- When did I do that, brother in law?
You have lost colony's security job
because of over boozing!
Your wife...
Your wife working as a maid but you are
boozing and roaming with that money
Am I roaming? I am not
getting the stupor when I booze!
I am a big man, how can I roam?
It is wrong to speak with you
Then give some money to play cards!
Take it!
- This is Sahara Colony!
- Has we reached so quickly?
I'll bring it!
Where is your flat?
Here or there or somewhere!
But, it is somewhere in this colony!
- I'll search for it! -I don't want money
from you! -Take it!
- I hit you without knowing about you
- I don't want your money!
- No.
- Take it!
What is this?
It seems like blood
until it is in our mouth!
That means.
- That's it!
Wait!
What wrong I did to you?
You made me a fool early in the morning!
- Give my money!
- How much?
Rs.50 for auto charge and Rs.200
for making me a fool! Give me!
Don't get blessings!
- Take your money!
- Is this money?
How dare you give a paper to me?
Hyderabad auto drivers are like
atom bomb! Give money
- Why are you getting angry?
It is money! -Money!
It is Rs.1000
Do you asked me Rs.250?
Keep all the money
Avarice leads to immense loss!
What I want is Rs.1000 Note!
It is original!
Don't forget to speak
with your wife and mom!
Bye !
Sahara ironing.com
This is the only house I have
Capturing, it is injustice!
Do you love this house so much?
You will live only for an year. Then you'll
die! Why do you want this house?
I told you that I'll give money!
I'll pay for it!
I have seen a lot of money like that!
Money doesn't have a long life!
Are you telling dialogues?
Don't you do what I said?
- I'll kill you!
- Sir please sir!
- I beg you!
Come this side!
Please sir!
Why should we fight with a rogue!
- Who are you? -He is my grandpa.
I am his grandson!
I am his grandson
He is my grandpa!
Because he is old, he is behaving like this
He doesn't know about you
We'll not fight with you!
Leave him for my sake!
- I am like your brother! Please sir!
- Shut up! What is your problem?
Give me some time
I am here only! I'll manage it!
It's ok sir! I came here to bring him
from here to my town!
Give me one week time
Please sir!
One week!
- Ten days sir! 10 days -After
10 days. -It's your wish!
You can do whatever you want
Please sir
Thank you brother!
Visit my town once!
Sorry old man! I lied to that rowdy
that I am your grandson...
...because I couldn't bear
you getting blows...
Aren't you film actor Padma Rao?
- My life got liberated after
seeing you! -What is this?
I am your fan sir! Oh gosh!
Paathaala Bhairavi, Potti(Short) Pleader!
Deasodhaarakudu. Devatha(Goddess)
Oh god! I've watched all
the films in the Television!
What is this sir! I thought you would be
at Jubli hills in a bungalow with cars!
Why are you in this house?
What is the quarrel?
Those were long time back!
I have lost all money because of
luxurious life, habits and donations!
In the end my own children...
...bluffed and looted my money!
Great man N.T.R, I don't know
in which world he is in now,
After he became Chief Minister,
he searched for me and give this house to me
My desire is to give this house
to orphans like me..
...The persons who do not have shelters
Orphanage! But, while seeing the situation..
..L am scared that I'll lose the house!
You don't be afraid grandpa!
I am from Rayalaseema!
We can play cricket with bombs!
They are just kids to me!
Until this problem comes to an end,
I'll stay here and I'll see their end!
Shall I stay here, grandpa?
Are you trying to stay here permanently
with the name of relationship?
How can I do comedy with you, grandpa?
The actual matter is...
I came here to become a
comedian in cinema field!
If I stay here, I can learn some dialogues,
I'll do some service to you...
...and also I can see the
end of those rowdies!
I'll pay rent grandpa!
Shall I keep my bag in that room?
Ok, Do it!
Actually, what is your name?
Chakram, grandpa!
What? Wasn't he found in Chennai,
Salem and some other places?
Make merry!
My name is Chakram! Are you
the washer man in this colony?
Do you want money?
ls Rs.1000 enough to you?
We don't have the time to love!
East! It'll go!
- What is this fire?
- Goddess got angry!
Not like that! I think you
could not do it properly!
Once in a day only!
Has your desire went in ruin?
You hit him well!
What will you become Padmarao?
- I am his grandson!
Why did you interfere in that quarrel?
Why can't you explain to him!
- That Yadav is very dangerous guy!
- He has done 2 or 3 murders!
Why are you talking like this?
Millions of people laughed at our grandpa!
Now he is in distress! It is your
fortune to have a man like him!
Will you leave if anyone is in distress?
You've a lot of people in a big colony!
What can that rowdy do
if you are together?
Excessive stupor is not good for health!
Do you have these type of
ideas about this colony?
Then, listen...
Buchi Babu who is living on that flat!
Well talk about the MP post
of Vijayawada Rajasekar!
- Do you know who is elected as a
candidate for that post? -For whom?
For me! I don't like politics
So I canvassed for him and he won
- Anyway he is my childhood friend!
- Oh gosh!
- Vijayakumar!
- What about Vijayakumar?
He asked IG promotion from DIG.
I did that with my influence!
- Do you know Shankaramoorthy?
- Who is he? -Don't you read newspapers?
He is Rajasthan's Chief Minister!
He asked transfer to AP!
I did that also
He is giving money on interest with
his dowry and he'll do unnecessary chats
He is like a dialogue king!
Hyderbad rowdies do not bother
about other's words! -Really
They are not scared about court,
case and police!
I am asking frankly! Why did that old
man haveing great affection with that house?
We don't know that
he'll die today or tomorrow!
I'll do the settlement with a good rate!
Tell him to give them!
Why are you fighting with rowdies?
Now No. 2
Mr. and Mrs. Basavaraju!
Is this really a dish?
Can you only break this?
Can't I break it?
- Leave me! -I'll kill you!
Don't you have the respect
about your hubby! -I'll hit you!
Made for each other!
What are you saying?
Are you telling us to fight with those
rowdies for that old man who'll die soon?
Do you have sense?
Now, No.3
Nadipudi Narahari!
Not like that!
If it is a department, they would've some
percentage from the top to bottom!
- Yes! - Is it new? That is rule! It was
introduced from the day we got independence!
- Rs.60 Million contract! -Yes
- I am asking 10 percent commission!
You send Rs.0.5 million...
Send Rs.1 million! -Ok
- What do you say!
- Ok! -Bye!
What will you give if I visit your house,
what'll you bring if you visit mine?
What service can that old man provide
with that Old Age Palace? Tell me!
That house is looking like
a mark of evil eye!
Why are you fighting with rowdies!
It is nonsense!
At least you explain him!
They are not kids!
They are like thunders!
I don't want this education!
- I don't want this
- Don't play! Be quiet!
- Eat it!
We don't know when and whom
they will attack at anytime!
They can change this Hi-Tech city
as Jurassic Park!
“Oh gosh!
- Stop!
Then No.5
I am looking to launch a pub
with discothéque near Panjagutta
We'll get minimum Rs.50,000 per day!
I won't do other than that brother in law!
- I want Rs.3 million!
- Rs.30 Million?
Then, do you think we can go
to America with Rs.30?
What do you think?
Earning money is not very easy!
Don't talk nonsense dad!
If a cow grazes on the field,
can it calf graze out of the field?
They don't know what they are doing!
They are like apes!
- Our grandpa...
- Can't you understand it once?
- Do you think, fighting with Yadav
is like a comedy! -Not like that...
I think this petrol pipe is leaking!
Who is Lakshmi?
- That means... -Her father is like
Shoban Babu in old films...
...and Jagapathy Babu in new films!
He has two wives (Aayanaki lddharu)
- He'll drink brandy and whisky
in a same glass! -That means?
I can't understand your behavior, son!
- Having a daughter at marriageable age,
you're roaming with a concubine -Mom!
She is not a concubine!
Mind your words!
It's your wish
We won't speak anything!
But, we are finding hard
to control our Lakshmi!
- She discontinued her
education in medicine! -Why?
- Why did she stop her education in between?
- Don't know!
In this house all are
behaving as per their wish!
Mom! Keep quiet!
Take money for this month's expenses
and also her education expenses!
Come dear!
Why did you discontinue your college?
It's your ambition to become a doctor!
Three years are completed.
How many days do you left to finish it?
Listen to me
Who want your money?
Don't you have shame to roam
with a concubine at this age?
Are you trying to cleanse
your sins with money?
Do you think nobody is
here to question you?
Have you got self regard?
Is this concubine your wife?
ls my Mom your concubine?
- Shut up!
- Beldamel You shut up!
Stop!
All are watching us!
Let them watch!
All of them know about this fuss!
If you have responsibilities as a Dad,
leave her and stay with us!
Otherwise, it is disgusting
for you to visit...
...and give money monthly once
Don't you get any person
other than my dad?
- Wait! -I'll hit with slipper!
Get down from the car -Stop Lakshmi!
Get down!
- Is he your Dad?
- Disgusting!
Who is this sister?
Is she your Mom?
Then, who is this sister
Is she dummy for your Mummy?
That means,
does your dad have two wives?
All the men are like this only!
We should not believe them!
He won't prosper
He'll go to ruins
Do you know how raged you are?
It'll get a shock if I touch you!
That's great!
- Yamini, one time...
- Disgusting! -Once please..
- Get lost! -Only once!
- Why are you falling on like that? Go
- Get lost
- Don't you like me?
An actor must have
responsibility and dignity!
Lot of the people would feel happy
while seeing us on the stage and screen!
They'll laugh, cry, think and follow us!
That's why we should have respect
and responsibility about the society!
This whole world is like our family!
Whole world is my family!
But I lead a solitary life!
The familial life is mine
I am ecstatic and void too!
It is superb, Grandpa!
- Teach this song completely to me!
- Sure, I'll teach you completely!
Dear! I am feeling sleepy!
Don't you? Sleep early dear!
I don't have time to sleep!
Whole world is my family!
But I lead a solitary life
- You got it right
- I am learning it!
Oh Lord Krishna and Vaasudeva!
She is not keeping water in the bedroom!
Oh gosh! Who are you?
Oh god!
Oh gosh!
Thief!
Thieves!
Have thieves entered into this colony
last night? In which house?
Illegal earnings (Nadamantrapu siri)
He lost(Hari) it!
It's pity!
Is it Narahari sir?
To discuss about that,
colony persons have arranged meeting!
They are going to arrange
a new security guard!
Dear brother and sisters!
Thieves have entered
into our colony for the third time!
We arranged this meeting to appoint
a new security guard because...
...our old security guard
has not done his duty properly!
He got that money thorough
illegal means. How can it live long?
It'll go in the way it came!
I knew this before!
Mind your words! You are doing
interest business with wife's dowry...
...Are you giving advice to others?
Why are you scolding my hubby!
My parents have the money,
so we are getting it!
- We are not poor! -We are also
not begging! By hard work, we are living
We don't know to earn money
in an illegal way!
Don't talk like this!
I know whom you are telling this!
- You be quiet! -Wait
- Go -shut up!
Here, this is not to discuss
about how we earn!
We'll appoint a new security guard
if our Buchi Babu...
...releases the fund
entrusted with him!
How can you appoint? Don't you read
the news what happened in Banjara Hills?
Thieves have killed the security guard
and we paid the compensation for it!
I don't accept that! Why for that!
They are roaming without a job
like rogues! Tell them to do that security!
Is it ok if thieves kill us?
Do you think what we studied is
for doing security job in this colony?
We won't do that! We are going to launch
a pub soon in Panjagutta cantre!
- What? Did you give money to him?
- I did not give!
Look...Discussions have been finished
in a friendly atmosphere!
Sunday the Goddess will not do it!
Is Narahari wounded severely?
- Yes, he is hit by thieves!
Is Deepavali (Festival) coming soon?
Not Deepavali but crackers are blowing!
- Who is firing it now?
Someone is going to get hurt
by our colony children!
Don't know who it would be!
- Snake!
That's great!
Oh god! Great!
Volga
My name is wheel(Chakram)!
Earth wheel, Lord Vishnu's wheel,
Lord Sudharshan's wheel!
Bus wheel, car wheel, bicycle wheel!
Time wheel!
I know about past, present and future!
Don't talk too much!
What do you know?
Your real name is Bunny!
His real name is Chinny!
Your puppy name is Snoopy!
You have one rupee in pocket!
You like Tom and Jerry!
Your like cherry fruit!
You have braces on your teeth!
You have not zipped up!
- What else you know?
- I know a lot!
You will drench your bed during nights!
You will loot your friends pencils!
You will damage
sofa seats with knife!
On stomach pain pretext,
you would skip school!
How do you say all these?
These are all face reading!
Volga
One whose hair is combed to front is Pandu!
Your Hindi marks are two!
One whose hair is combed to back is Venu!
Who has hit you is Srinu!
These are all crop reading!
Did you fall from the cycle?
All the time you keep
a finger in mouth! -Yes
These are all dress reading!
Face reading, crop reading,
and dress reading are over! -Oh gosh!
Now, future reading!
You will become a
Chiranjeevi in the time to come
You will dance like Chiranjeevi!
You will have lot of fans!
Volga
You will replace Sachin in Indian Team!
You will score billions of runs!
You are an Air force!
You are a Military force!
You are a junior Tata!
You are a junior Gates(Bill Gates)!
You will be adorned with Padmashri
Doctorates, Gnanapeeta and Bharatha Rathna
What should we do for that?
Do pranks!
Don't disturb others!
Always smile
Don't make others laugh at you!
Dream yourself and don't
forget to make your dreams real
Prosper, but don't forget
the land from where you took off!
Don't forget Motherland and Mother India
Volga
I'll do some good magic
other than this in the evening!
You have sent that innocent
mischievous children to school with magic!
I don't know anything else than drinks!
What will you give me?
Big Mountain (Penu konda),
Golkonda, Anaconda!
Rattle snake!
- Is goddess angry? -You are
having some bad thoughts in your mind!
Other than boozing, I don't have
any other bad thought in my mind!
That is bad!
- Shall I try it once again?
- No, once in a day! I know that!
Sometimes we can try it twice!
Mad fellow!
Twice!
He has interfered in a quarrel of
Padmarao's house on that day!
Today he is becoming famous
among children! Who is he?
- I have doubts!
- I also have a doubt (Anumaanam)
Why did you put meeting, uncle?
Was it about me?
Naturally you will fight between your!
Because it is someone else's
issue, is it interesting?
You are wondering who am I?
Actually I am from.
Cudappah!
- I am trying to act in films!
- Is he a factionist?
- Idiot! -Sisters!
- Oh gosh!
It was very hard to send
these little devils to the school!
You have showed a good magic
to the children!
You are singing well!
Don't praise me heavily,
sisters! I'll ruin!
Sholay (Fire)
- You are doing magic greatly!
- It's my childhood hahit!
- Visit our houses often, then
we can chat over a cup of coffee!
Shall I visit tonight? Disgusting!
I said it for dinner!
- You eyes will ruin!
- Naughty boy!
- Is Lakshmi in the house? -No!
- What has she done again?
Sir came in the morning. He gave this money
to give you without her knowledge!
- He is a good man!
- Don't introduce him to us!
Why are you staying there
like a newly married groom?
He is Chakram!
Padmarao's grandson!
- He is very energetic!
- What energetic? Idiot!
I little bit over acted
to stop Lakshmi while quarreling!
It is wrong
I apologise!
Don't take my mistake to
your heart but to your stomach
Impossible!
- You are a grown up! How can I
hide you in my stomach! -Granny!
You are also being comical!
- I'll say sorry to you, sister!
- It's ok!
You remind me of my brother!
Actually my husband is not like that!
There must be a strong reason behind it!
My worry is about my daughter Lakshmi!
She had quit her doctorate studies!
She is really very angry!
She doesn't speak to anyone!
Because of this, this colony people are
speaking according to their imagination!
I think it's our bad time!
You don't worry sister!
You've called me as a brother!
Leave it to me!
I'll take care of that gossips!
My amount is Rs.1000
Why did Lakshmi fight with her father?
Not like that! Rajeshwari was
the main background of that incident!
She doesn't respect her husband!
My aunt's daughter saw Rajeshwari
with another person in Shanthi theatre!
My amount is Rs.6,500
- Write it!
- If a girl is ready to do wrongs,
all will happen like this! -Sisters!
- You? -Are you talking about Rajeshwari?
- I'll tell you -Do you know about that?
- Careful! I know about
Rajeshwari's illegal contact!
- Who? -A person called Prabhakar,
working in a cinema field!
- He'll roam with suitcases!
- Is it! -Yes!
- Doesn't our colony have a charming ladies?
- Who said like that?
- I did not say like that! -Then who?
- Next colony women!
- They are talking about cheaply
about our colony ladies! -How?
A lady called Kanthan
hits her husband rashly!
A lady called Saroja has
killed her mother in law with poison!
A lady called Rathnam,
has a good friendship with guys!
- Oh Lord Ram!
- They are idiots (Surpanagai)
- They don't have another work!
- That's all gossips!
Damn them!
Why are you getting angry?
ls there anyone like that here?
Oh gosh! It's ridiculous!
It is like that sister!
If we gossip about others,
others will do the same about us!
- If your husbands know about this...
- Oh god! -Oh god!
- She is not studying well!
- Shut up!
That's why she is going to special classes!
My daughter is working hard!
Be careful
Take it
- Go!
- Why are you shouting?
My collection is Rs.500 today!
What about your collection?
- My Dad advised before giving this Rs.200
- And your Dad?
- He acted smart but
did not give any money! -Wait!
- If we get Rs.1 lakh, we'll run away
from home and we'll enjoy
- Yes
- Is it you?
- Are you waiting for the bus?
Or are you going to movie today?
- No aunty! We felt boring!
We are thinking what to do!
Will you come to my house?
Let's go to a film after having coffee!
- Oh gosh!
It sounds good!
Are you staying alone in this house?
- You have a lot of lip-sticks!
- These are good! -Take it!
Take this as a gift of mine!
I have a lot like this!
- I have bought this in London!
- You are so lucky!
You are visiting foreign countries a lot!
These girls will be match for your taste
Don't be in a hurry!
Only now they are coming my way!
Waiting moments will be pleasant!
First send Rs.50,000 advance!
Tomorrow we are going to celebrate
Goddess Varalakshmi feast at my home!
- You must attend that feast!
- Are you inviting us to your home?
- We won't come there!
- Granny!
- Don't think about the past!
- Yes, Granny!
We are young people!
Without our knowledge, we'll do mistakes!
You are elders! You should forgive us
instead of punishing! Tell her!
Nothing will happen like that in future!
We'll stay together from today onwards!
Is it ok to you, Granny?
What do you say Raji?
Not about minding! I am very happy
because you visited my house!
I never thought that
we would unite like this!
Let's unite...Come!(Kalisundham Raa!)
- Is this your play, Chap!
- It's because of your blessings, Granny!
- Nice guy!
- I feel happy!
Oh gosh!
Rowdy has arrived!
- We'll take leave!
- Goddess Varalakshmi.
- Get lost! -Come quickly
You must attend the feast!
Where were you roaming
like a guy until now?
Why are you not answering
when mother in law questions you?
After quitting the education...
Oh gosh!
Shut up!
- What is your problem?
- Problem?
You are thinking like you only
have problems in this world...
..all of them laughing about you,
they are commenting you on your back etc
Because of this you are
behaving like psycho!
Who are you? After all a girl in
World's total population of 6000 millions!
Do you think they don't have
another work other than your issue?
You are not that famous!
You are not a kid!
Do you know one thing?
Yesterday is not ours!
It's gone!
Tomorrow is not for us!
We don't know what will happen
Today is in our hands!
Be happy and live happy!
That is not very hard!
Do you know another thing?
A smile can reverse hundreds of worries!
It will unite thousands of people!
For instance, smile once in front of mirror!
You can see the difference!
It is very easy to give a lecture!
Go and play with kids...
- It's me! Move aside!
- Why did he come this side?
Can factionists make girls to laugh?
How can factionists do comedy!
This was taught by Osama brother
in Afghanistan lairs!
- Osama Bin Laden?
- Yes!
Do you know from where the bombs
were supplied for that plane crash?
I have supplied it!
I was also tried to crash a flight!
- Because of my stomach pain!
- Stomach Pain!
- It's for me!
- Dawood brother! It is Ibrahim!
Oh God!
Lakshmi Smiled!
My stupor has come down!
Oh gosh!
It is Lakshmi!
Switch it off!
- We are very happy when
you smile! -Yes
You have talked to us
like this a year before!
- I tried a lot to say sorry!
But you never gave a chance! -Leave it!
- Anyway we are so lucky!
- For what?
- Today, Srinu's last birthday!
Why? Does he have AIDS?
No, he is going to America within a month!
That's why we've arranged for a
birthday party in a discotheque!
- You must attend it!
- Me to disco? No way!
- You should come! -Wait!
I will not cut the cake if you won't attend!
You may leave after he cuts the cake!
It's just a coke!
Nothing will happen. Drink!
- Wait Lakshmi!
- What happened?
- Leave aside! What happened
Lakshmi? -I'll go home!
Come I'll take drop you!
- Who are you to take her!
I'll drop you! -Wait!
I'll take her!
Come on!
- Who are you? -Wait. Come with me!
- Be quiet! -Leave her!
From Narsi town district, In Kottha koota
family, a boy belonging to nomads..
..Who came now is a doctor
His name is Ganga Raju!
Ganga Raju speaks a lot!
Ganga Raju told about mirror bungalow!
Ganga Raju said there is a well
in the middle of the house!
Ganga Raju says that hair is like a rope!
Ganga Raju said nobody can stop me!
- How dare you hit me!
- Where is Lakshmi?
You remind of my dad!
Really!
My dad likes me a lot!
I also like my dad very much!
Guys will get temptation
while seeing charming girls like you!
They will try to impress you!
Before chide them,
don't you have sense?
Do you drink whatever
they give? Mad girl!
Meaning of smile is friendship!
It's not a meaning of innocent!
Your father is sending money for
your house expenses without your knowledge
Are you getting angry?
It's correct!
Then, how is your home running?
Food, clothes, rent... How?
Our angry will not feed food
for us and our people!
If you have a self-respect,
take care of them! Do any work!
You may ask what job will I get
from my discontinued doctor degree!
Do you know, there may be small
people in this world not the small jobs?
Volga
Little hot and little warmth!
Little tough and little loving!
Let me offer you the nectar of my lips!
Let your hug arrest the time!
Become a whirlwind and embrace me!
You spread like snow
Turn into a fire to melt me!
Volga
If I close the door
will my thoughts bout you stop?
If you are in my mind,
how can I continue bathing?
Your toxin has passed into my veins!
I can't control my emotions!
Even it is an allegation
it gives me pleasure!
Let me explain my feelings to you!
Volga
You reminded me that I am a girl!
but learnt the secrets buried in mind!
When your ravishing air
explained me your deeds
I could hear the startled sound
and get the cupid's letter
At a time when youth is salacious
Volga
Like this!
Oh gosh!
What? Is it a fighting scene?
Just a minute!
I'll do solo fight!
Monkey fight!
Rooster fight!
What is he doing? Does he have an
experience in fighting?
I don't know all these!
Don't worry
I am with you!
- Don't push me!
- Wait guys!
It is Yadav brother!
It's wrong dear!
Don't say like that!
You must study!
You should go college!
- Do you want a bike? I'll buy you
from Bombay -Please sir!
I wanted to talk to you!
Show pity to him! Give 10 days time!
We'll discuss about it!
10 days sir, please!
Brother, don't!
Please!
I'll talk to him brother!
Don't do it!
- Don't brother!
- Get lost!
Please brother, I'll talk to Yadav brother!
Leave it for once!
I said don't! Can't you understand?
I said no!
I am begging you!
Leave him!
I am telling for your sake!
Otherwise you'll get into trouble!
Brother, leave me!
Don't hit
Don't hit brother!
Is you age around at 45 to 50?
You would have diseases like
blood pressure and diabetes!
Because of smoke from your childhood,
your levers would've been damaged
Even an heart attack might
come today or tomorrow
You may have started boozing
from the age of 10 years!
Because of that your kidney
also would've been damaged
Eating health hazard foods in boozing,
your stomach will burst!
Throat cancer due to consumption
of chewing products in large amount...
You may live at least
for 5 to 10 years with diseases
Why all these trouble?
What will you earn
by torturing these people?
Will you enjoy with
this kind of money?
You will say it's for your son
Without knowing how you earned
this money your son...
..will addict to bad habits and will take
the drugs throughout the night...
..while enjoying the disco with boozing
In a hurry of coming to home...
..in the bike which you bought for him...
..he'll drive in an inebriated condition
at top speed in between 100 and 200..
..And will ram to a lorry in any road
No, no
It's enough
Don't tell me more!
- You have doubts about me,
isn't it? - Yes
Don't reveal to anyone
In fact, I am a brother in the jungle!
You mean you are a Naxalite?
To mingle with the purpose
of public service...
Brothers thought this colony is the
right place and have sent me here
Hail the red flag!
Service For Public
There may be small people
in this world not the small jobs
One friend had told me
I didn't think you will
take control of your life so fast
Each and every day
my liking over you is growing!
I don't like girls who are scared
and worried for trivial issues
They should be like you
like a firebrand, daring, independent
That's why I like Indira Gandhi,
Kiran Bedi, Mother Teresa...
..and Sahara colony Lakshmi
I like you very much
You are running out of time
for Pizza Delivery. Go
- Come inside
- Who is that?
Lakshmi come inside
Pizza has been ordered for this address
Do you work in the Pizza store?
Why do you work?
Am I not there to take care?
Will you take the Pizza
and pay the bill or not?
Let's not talk outside, come inside
Will you take the Pizza or not?
We didn't order
Are you scared?
Will you take the Pizza
and pay the bill or not?
I ordered the Pizza for this address
- Is it you?
- Yes
What is the problem
you had with your father?
Because he is living with
some other person, isn't it?
Your father looked after you
very well until yesterday...
Hae you ever thought under
what circumstances he lives there?
After bearing all your humiliations..
Why does he come
to see you repeatedly?
Why is he doing this?...
Because he didn't
forget the duty of a father
He could have covered up his
relationship if he had desired
But he didn't
There is no use in pinpointing
the mistakes to anyone
Everyone will lose the peace
Look, Life is not easy
for anyone at anytime
We should adjust to each and every place!
We can't avoid that
After 10 years, there is no use in you
and your mom parting from your father
Because it will be too late!
If you want to solve your problem...
Take the right decision at the right time
I know how it feels
by separating from the father
I just wanted to say my opinion
Then it's your wish and their fortune
Prises went high for all!
Father please
I am sorry father
Mother is waiting
Shall we go to home?
I made them to search entire Tamil Nadu
and Bangalore! But, Chakram was not found!
Remaining is Hyderabad only!
Bribe! It is wrong dear!
You should say it as percentage!
I have to oblige
everybody in the department
Listen! First you send the advance
I will take care of everything
Brothers have started a battle
against corrupt officers!
Brothers has cut down
an officer's left leg and right hand...
while doing corruption
near agency office
Brothers has cut down a throat
of a corrupt forest officer...
..and hanged him into a
banyan tree in front of public! -Oh gosh!
Brothers are showing interest in
Hyderabad's corrupt officers...
...Name and details of it!
- What did you say your
name is? -I forgot it!
I remember it!
Red flag Hail!
Percentage? It may be a percentage
or bribe, it is wrong!
Government is giving salary
for doing our duty!
You apply the tender in a legal way
Right person will get
the tender as per the rule!
Don't call me now onwards
with this reason! Bye!
- I'll snip this Nuptial thread!
- You need not to do that, I'll do it myself!
- Aren't you scared about the husband?
- Don't you respect your wife?
I feel very hungry!
I didn't eat last night!
I came here because
your cooking is good!
A couple are fighting
from the day they get married!
There!
Brothers have warned them twice!
But they disobeyed that!
They made a call to me
from the forest at midnight!
They told me to cut down their hands!
I have done it!
Do you have Sambar (Indian sauce)?
If couple of hearts gets together,
If couple of lives gets together!
If anybody give accompany,
that is a fortune and a Paradise!
Oh rainbow!
Oh gosh! I can also compose
some good numbers!
What is your problem?
Last night Police has arrested
our Team Commander in an operation!
I knew that last night!
Home minister made a call and told me!
- Now, what is your situation?
- I am scared!
I wan it! Do you know IG
DIG, Chief Justice?
That's why we planned to
kidnap your daughter.
...In an exchange scheme
of our Team Commander's release!
Damn your plan! Who told them
to kidnap my daughter?
- It's me!
- Why?
You only said to me! You know
IG, DIG and Chief Justice!
Make a call to them urgently!
How can I know them?
I don't know anyone!
You said that you knew them!
It's a lie!
Because of my bad time,
I have created a fib in this colony!
Your daughter's life is in danger
because of your fibs!
She is an innocent girl!
Tell them not to harm her!
- You should not speak lie at anytime,
anywhere, any place! - I should not!
Really!
What is this?
- I'll say! This is a newly released five,
...ten rupees coin! -No
I'll say! It is the pigment
in cheek of a bride!
- I also! It is a small hole
in my Dad's head -No -Stupid!
- It is a button of Narahari
sir's Pant! -No
- It is a shit of a crow on
the beach! -Shut up!
- I'll say correctly.
- Tell!
It is a planet of Mars
which came near the earth! -No
- It's like my nuptial thread!
- No -I'll tell you
- It is the hip of Aishwarya Roy!
- I'll kill you -Me!
- It is a hole in ozone
- No
I'll tell you. It is a mole
of Simran's high lip!
- I'll say correctly! Is it a
last zero of Rs.100 note? -No
- I'll say
- What will you say?
It is a last drop (Chukka) of a drink!
- Your stupor(Kicka) went high!
Catch him!
He is out!
Can't anyone see this as a white paper?
All are watching the dot in this but
no one is watching it as a white paper!
If we consider as a human's character,
then the dot is like a little bit of bad!
We are watching the dot, but we are not
seeing the whiteness around the paper!
We can also having the qualities
what we don't like from others!
We can see if we think ourselﬂ
No one is perfect!
We are unable to unite because
we are watching the bad things on others!
You are all living a
lonely life in this colony!
You should all unite and live
with affection and friendship!
That's why we are celebrating
a festival day in our colony!
Let's celebrate all the festival of union!
Diwali, Bhogi, Sankranthi, Holi
(Indians Festivals)
Oh Lord Krishna!
Oh Lord Rama!
Volga
From young ones to older ones...
Should celebrate this festival!
Whether sweet or sour
Should share with everyone
Volga
Rangoli and Holi are a joyous celebrations!
Wherever you are, it would be there!
Colourful crackers means Diwali (A Festival)
Whenever we invite it should come!
Has festivals ever claimed
to follow the almanacs only?
Is there any auspicious time
to spend time happily?
Volga
On Ugadi(new year) day
bitter dishes are consumed!
If you habituate as a daily routine
Life would become pleasant
Those doing Ganapthy worship and not
..immersing the idol in ocean
would lead a prosperous life
An auspicious time to
solve the miseries of devotees ..
..and keeping eyes awake like
a lamp is the Shivarathri festival
Should there be a
specific day for visitors?
There are so many relatives around us
Are they not happy?
Volga
Like a mothers lullaby
and a folk song to shepherds ..
..and to human beings like
giving good counsels is Krshna Jayathi
Sree Rama navami
propounds humane approach ..
..of providing tent to those in hot sun!
The victorious moment of coming together ..
..and learning about the
good in you is Dusserah
The hot air coming from
our breath has turned Bogil
The designs drawn within
mind is called Sankranthi
Beat the rhythm
If you count from one progressively ..
Number nine would not cross the threshold!
If you keep on adding numerals to it
it would become infinite!
If you and me want to remain unchanged ..
We can be one among the millions!
If you and me consider both as 'us' ..
we would become
a populace of the humanity!
Don't shout! I can't understand
whether is it going on left or right!
I'll beg plead!
Don't shout!
Why are you shouting with kids?
The car looks good!
I want to drive this car
with my mom...
...and wife until I die,
without meter charge!
That girl also looking beautiful!
It will be good, if anybody say
like if you wins a lottery,
..the girl is free with lottery money!
Wait Chakram!
Chakram, wait!
Is Chakram in Hyderabad?
I am Pedda Reddy speaking!
I need your Hyderabad guest house urgently!
- Where? -Father in law! I have seen
Chakram in an auto. This is the Number
He ran away on seeing me.
He didn't even pay heed to my call!
Some kids and a girl were with him!
He didn't stop even when I called him!
Has he given a noon show tickets when
you had gone to a matinee show movie?
Wait!
You are buying a sari for her
and she is buying a sari for you!
I am losing my money!
It would be better
if you are not together!
I promising!
I'm not coming!
You are preparing mutton,
she is preparing chicken!
I am unable to eat...
I am not coming
My belly is increasing
It is disturbing when I drive the auto!
No, listen to me!
My money is exhausting!
I said I won't come!
Nothing, I am talking with customer
Give me the phone!
Where is Chakram (Wheel)?
One wheel in the front and two wheels
in the back! Which wheel do you want!
Hyderabad autos are like atom bomb!
Don't play with us!
Give me the phone!
I have waited for you near the greens field!
I have waited until the rooster noise!
You fool!
Where are you going?
- I am going to my farm house!
- For what?
- For a party!
- With boy friends or girl friends?
My friends!
It means, two girl friends among them!
I want to go Mumbai!
Will you drop me?
- Yes I'll do!
- Do you have petrol in your car?
I have a petrol card!
- Then, for your expenses?
I am have a credit card!
- Then start the car!
If I...
We are coming!
Oh gosh! You're
looking so beautiful!
Even the film stars
can't shine in front of you!
Let's go!
This is your life's turning point!
Your can make your dreams come true!
We are getting scared!
We'll go to our home!
Why are you getting scared?
It'll be very fun!
He is a rich man! It's enough to give
company for one hour!
He'll give ten thousand each!
All for you!
You can buy whatever you want!
Is it ok?
He has a five star hotel in Singapore!
I am going next week!
You are also welcome!
Will you come?
Do you know what happened?
Cry for it!
You may be in a brothel house
had I not visited at the right time!
There are a lot more valuable than money!
Like values, Standards..
We can't buy that with money!
We should not lose it for money!
We ourselves are a great asset!
Study well!
Get good marks!
If you are ready to work hard today,
you will have lot of opportunities!
Here and at abroad also! We can
achieve anything. We can earn more!!
Don't repeat this wrong again!
Study well!
Brother! Run!
- Don't come! Run away!
- What happened?-Don't come
Lot of people are coming for you!
Run away!
- Wait!
- Let's call the police!
- Which area is this?
- It's Banjara Hills!
- Get down
- Don't make noise! Come
Just a minute!
Tell them it is Banjara hills...
Leave me!
That is...
Dad!
What is this?
I am asking you!
Is it fair to walk out
without informing us?
I feel my head has cut down!
What wrong did we do?
You doesn't love your Dad!
It's ok!
But, do you remember
at least your Mom?
She is crying because of you?
I am scared that she may die!
Let's go home!
Are you trying to do marriage
with the name of mother?
I won't come!
I don't like this marriage!
Don't you like this marriage?
Come!
Answer to her!
Why did you cheat her?
Tell that to her
You made her believe, loved her,
promised to marry her...
...don't you feel ashamed to run off
at the marriage hour
You are not bothered about your parents
You need not reply to us
But, you should answer to her
Tell
- I don't like this marriage -That's what
I am asking, why? -Wait for a minute!
Ask him!
Did I make any mistake?
- You did not made any mistake
- Then, why?
Then, why have you go away?
I hate you!
You said I love you at that time!
Why do you hate now?
Suddenly, what happened?
On the time I said I love you,
did you ask why? No
Because you liked it!
But, now you are asking why
when I say I hate you!
Because you doesn't like it!
Is it all your wish?
Love and hatred are feelings!
There will be no reasons for feelings!
I don't like you
Turn this side and tell that you hate me!
Ok. I am telling this by watching you!
I don't like you!
Is it enough?
Wait!
Leave me
Catch him!
Be calm! I'll speak with him!
Leave me!
What is this nuisance?
Because you have kidnapped Chakram!
That is.. you've brought him here
Are you mad?
Do you know who I am?
- Do you know the relation
between us? -Inspector sir!
No one has kidnapped me!
I am safe. Watch it!
He is well know to me!
I came on my own because of some work!
It looks my people have
troubled you unnecessarily!
Leave the way
Nothing has happened
I am fine. I am ok!
Don't be scared
- What happened
- Nothing has happened to me!
Who told you...
Are you.
He is well know person to me
I came here to speak with him
Will you call police for that?
ls there any meaning for it?
Let's go! Granny, Is it you?
For everything. Go
Who is that girl? What is
all these? Tell me
Who is that girl?
Volga
Just one word!
A mute word is hidden in mind!
Just one word that
would even surfeit the lips!
My name is your love!
Hugging you is my way!
My glance is your smiles
You are my soul!
I want to tell you this!
Volga
If it is not me
what will you do?
Will you not believe me
and say smilingly, stop it?
I stay in your mind as your desire!
lam the feel in your lips!
I compare myself to
your bewitching charm!
Leaning on your heart I will hear my name!
Volga
My feet said walking over your
foot marks is a pleasant journey
My life said, parting from you is death!
I don't remember my life,
before you arrived!
I will not forget the
moment I saw you first!
I spend every moment as a birth!
You are glorious
Do you know that?
Volga
We came here because
it is a better place than India!
We've finished MBBS, MD, MS degrees!
We are working in one of the
best hospital in the world!
We are earning a lot!
Next..
Both our Dads will conduct our marriage
Next, we'll beget kids
May be we'll make them as good doctors
Then, we'll do marriage for them
Then, we will get retirement
Then, a good farm house,
lake view, with 10 workers.
Then, we'll die!
Will life end like that?
I want something more
Our money, education and our
knowledge should be useful to others
For us, our well wishers,
our state and our nation!
I want to build a big
super specialty hospital in India!
We'll import the best equipments
for that hospital!
We'll ask our friends and
world's best doctors..
...To do service for one
or two months in a year!
We'll give a best medical service
for all in our area!
After five years,
there would be no one like patient!
Will you come with me?
- Uncle
- Son in law
Are you fine?
- Are you fine?
- Fine
Dad!
Mother!
I was expecting a call since yesterday!
But you never called!
There won't be phone in the night
- Why, don't you have a cell phone?
Don't go away from me any more
I can't live without you
Ok don't cry, I won't go
Where is dad?
Oh gosh!
Expected dawn...
If it encountered today..
Hadn't father changed yet?
While hidden heart jumps...
Why the dawn is not coming?
Why the mist is not going out?
Oh my gold!
I will tell you in Telugu, father
What is this all aunty?
- Isn't it only a monkey
will born to a monkey? - Aunty!
You have to live with
this monkey from tomorrow
You have shied enough
Let's go
Your towel had dropped
- Oh gosh!
It's cheating
Leave him, he may die
Both of you're doing nuisance!
English for the aunty!
Oh Gajuvaaka girl!
Are we not bangles seller?
Don't you have the shame
While having a young son -For me
- Baby
- For me
There is no hurry for my son's marriage!
I will again marry
two or three times and...
Isn't it enough killing me?
Will you still kill 2 or 3 persons?
Why do you talk like that?
- What? -Uncle, I am going
out of the house..
..Including my daughter
Come
What happened?
- What happened brother?
Your husband is mad about
cinema now he is influencing it on him
Even I may get infected
Not like that uncle,
Won't you get them married?
Uncle it's me who is going to marry
If you want me to marry your daughter...
- I need dowry
- Dowry!
It is ours, for us,
for our people
Our people no need to search and
worry for the treatment..
..And for money, foreign treatment
everything will be here
Totally free
I and Lakshmi have decided
We are not going to take a step back!
Our education, experience should
benefit our people and our nation
We have to spend more for this hospital
Both father and uncle...
Should give all their properties
That's the dowry I need
If you agree for this
we will get marry
You are like gold!
- Greetings Minister -Greetings!
Come -Be quiet man!
- Come
- Are you fine?
Chakram, are you an American Doctor?
She is Lakshmi
Are you fine?
- She is my daughter
- Let's go
The groom will reach
at the auspicious time
Oh gosh!
Dad, is this marriage
for you or me?
- Mother -Not like that
Oh god! What is this crazy work?
I am groom's assistant!
- What assistant? Tell him
- Does it look good?
- Everybody is laughing
- Laughing!
Mr.Chowdary!You get ready!
Come Oh, today is my marriage!
Haven't you got ready yet?
This side
Oh god! I don't know
to wear groom's dress!
Bring the groom soon
He is not opening the door
Chakram open the door
Son is not there
I don't like this marriage
don't try to search for me
Sahara colony?
Why have they come for Chakram?
What is the connection between
Chakram and them? I need all the details
Is it Sahara colony?
What is all this?
- Who are they?
- Grand father they are...
Who are that villains blew me like this?
- They are not villains!
- Why did they tried to kidnap you?
- Why did they hit you
What happened inside?
What did they do to you?
Who is that lady and why is she crying?
Why did you prevent them
from being questioned by the police?
What is your relationship with them?
Oh gosh! So many questions?
I will answer it all one by one
- Then who is he?
- Kandhula Pedha Reddy!
Cuddapah, 200 crore properties
A big factionist!
- He is my father
- Your father!
I am his only son
Is he your father?
Then why did he kidnap you?
It is because of movie craze!
To become a big comedian,
I have told you know...
He doesn't like movies!
Want to do the fashion
lfl did the fashion...
There will be awards,
cutouts, whistles, autographs
Flower pouring, milk pouring, isn't it?
That's why I escaped from the house
But he came here too
It's my fate!
Then who is that girl?
You won't give up that,
she is my uncle's daughter
Sister in law!
She is troubling me to marry her
lfl get married my female fans
will get upset that's why I escaped
- That's it!
- Then what
Do you think I will enact a comedy
like Samara Simha Reddy and Indra?
You are all spoiled by watching
the cinema, go and mind your business
I feel asleep
Come let's go
- Oh gosh! -Get treated
by the doctor -It's ok
Forgive me grand father
I am leaving without completing
the work of your orphanage, again
escape!
Thief, thief!
- Thief, thief!
Who are they?
Hey stop!
Hit him!
How can you escape from here?
Someone call the police
- Stop!
Let us first see their face
removing the mask before hitting
He said correct! Remove it!
Are you the thieves?
- Scoundrel! You told me
about America. Is this your work?
- How dare you?
- Wastrels - Stop!
Why do you hit them?
Mistake is yours
This age is very dangerous
They quickly get attracted
even it may good or bad
That's why your parents should take
the responsibility for your children!
You should guide them or else
they will end up like this
Don't bow your heads
Die by committing suicide
Is this life?
Our parents dream about
our future with expectations
They feel anxious about
our future when we grow
We shouldn't make them
feel agonized for giving us birth
People should not pinpoint
on us but salute us
Life is beautiful
Don't make it ugly
Try to know it's value!
Forgive me
Not for me for your parents
- Forgive me
- Get up!
We did a mistake
It's too late now, good night
Go home. Good night
uncle -Let's go
Good night
Go! Go!
Go dear!
You have solved so many people's problems
- Why don't you solve my
problem too? -What you want?
- I need money -What for?
- For liquor
Don't you have the
concern other than liquor?
I use it for liquor for
whatever purpose you give
Liquor king!, Liquor gold! There it is!
You gave the bottle
I thought you'll give the money
- Just a minute -What? Do you
know what is being prepared?
- Do you know?- I know
Then tell me soon
Grapes, Orange, Apple,
little bit of fruit peels!
By mixing all these..
They keep everything in the underground
in a pot until it become rot..
After we keep, flies, mosquitoes,
worms will jump on to this...
After they finish their daily activities.
It comes into a decay position after
they will do bath and family and die!
You mean in this- Yes
Then they take it out and put in the
bottle like this, to make money
If we drink it before it become rot,
it is Juice and it is good for health!
If you drink after it becomes rot,
your body will also go rot! Now you drink
Was I drinking this rot
all these days?
I won't drink it in my life any more
Everybody in our colony
admire you as a good security guard
Only if you were perfect there
won't be theft in our colony
Think it once
Are you escaping again?
Where?
- Father -Why?
Tell me
Deserting me, your mother and Lakshmi
I am unable to understand
- Swear on me and Mom...
- Father!
Swear on me and Mom's life!
Tell me the truth
I will die
Father I will die
Listen to me carefully
I have done blood test because your blood
wasn't clotted on the day you got scratch!
It is an advance stage!
You can live a maximum
for 2 to 3 months
Open the door
I didn't know how to tell this
And hesitated how you might take it
I was scared what would happen to
mom and Lakshmi if they hear it...
...That's why I escaped
I am escaping
Dad!
You were healthy!
Don't be scared
We'll go to America
I will save you
by selling all my properties
There are big doctors, isn't there?
I am also a doctor
There is no medicine for this
Your hundred crore rupees
can't save me even for a ten minutes.
Father!
Father don't cry
Your cry prompting me also to cry
Oh gosh!
That's why
That's why I escaped without telling
Everybody will die
You will also die but
lam going little earlier
After I escaped from the marriage...
I am living in this colony
Everyone here are good people
They are making hell
out of the small issues
Death is the biggest problem in the world
That is not a problem at all
when compared to death
I feel like laughing
I wanted to treat all the patients after
launching Super Specialty Hospital...
But I don't have that much time
They also have the sickness,
but it is psychological
That's why I started the treatment
I will make at least
some people smile before I die
Only you gave me
this smile, this is yours
Why are you crying?
This doesn't suit you
I am not going anywhere
I will be born to you again and again
I won't leave you
Be courageous
You should look after
mother and Lakshmi
Lakshmi should forget me
She should get marry again
You should conduct her
marriage by supervising yourself
Lakshmi shouldn't know
about my death ever
You came to know everything, right?
What happened uncle?
Volga
Sony cell phone pizza!
To your heart, give me a visa!
I saw sonic ﬂights speed in you!
Focus on me, like a love virus!
Shall I embrace you like a golden wire?
Oh Mona Lisa!
I'll slit your heart with my smile!
Oh Oasis! I'll hijack your heart!
Volga
Your Paris style charm
spreads on me like a virus
...My dreams will go
nonstop like a Qualis car
My youth frothed like champagne
My mind became stormy!
My heart played rhythms to welcome you!
Shall I come like a rocket?
Once I become like Venus planet.
Oh living platinum!
Will you give me a kiss?
I'll become an ATM to give kisses!
- Wiil you give me a kiss?
- When I become one!
Will you give me a kiss?
Volga
Your bod glitters like Melbouen
joine me like a Kohinoor Diamond,
I'll battle outwith your charm
like Bin Laden!
When your acid glances touch me
It's very sweet like a fruit salad!
Kill me with love!
Your hip is a nylon swing!
If you swing, it'll fire me!
I'll come like a dream on your eyes!
I'll make all the dreams come true!
- I'll come like a dream!
- I'll will make it true!
I'll come like a dream!
Volga
Father
Pay obeisance to him
Get up
You have created problems
for the marriage, right?
She is the girl
whom I am going to marry
Where is Lakshmi?
I just wanted to show her
Make arrangements for the marriage
Oh Lakshmi! My old darling
Her name is also Lakshmi
My new darling
I like her very much
I will marry her
Does she look good?
Oh gosh! I am scared
She might kill in the rage
O
I had once loved you
out of stupidity and innocence
Now I give up
I too feel sad
Let's do one thing
I like this girl very much
I will marry her
But I won't be unfair to you
Weekly once
-ls Sunday ok
- Ok
I will keep you
As a concubine!
I can understand your position
You won't get anyone other than me
You are unable to keep
anyone other than me
I am not bothered if you roam with her
I am not bothered if you marry her
I feel ashamed to have loved...
..a person like you
I need some forty lakh rupees
To construct an old age home for grandpa!
That is the only work I've to finish
Lakshmi, You only...
Are you going to London?
Yes uncle
I don't like to stay here
I will go
Because of Chakram right?
Forget him
He is a Scoundrel
I will take care of you
I will look for a better man
than him... - No uncle
It's enough
Don't stop me
I will go
O
RAJ IV GANDHI AIRPORT
This is your passport
Forget the past
Take care of yourself
Call me if you need any help
I am sorry dear!
I can't understand what I do
It seems I am infected to bad deeds
I can't live without you
Don't desert me
Please dear!
Did you expected
me to crawl like this?
I was thinking in the night
I felt sorry for you
I felt it was unfair
That's why a festival
fresh offer for you
Not two days in a week Friday
Saturday, Sunday three days for you
Uncle I will keep her in
a separate house after the marriage
I've made Lakshmi agree to this
Is it ok for you?
I did love you once
Weekly 3 days, is it ok?
Please don't lower yourself any more
I didn't think that
you are such a rogue
Did you think that I won't
get anyone else other than you?
Within ten days...
A boy handsome than you
More rich than you
More educated than you
a better boy than you
And who is ready to die for me
I will show you by marrying such a boy
Stay here
Don't run away once again like a coward
Be here if you have the courage
I will show you who am I
Do it to prove it
I will be here only
Come father
You will not prosper!
I will pray to the God brother in law...
..Because I stayed with you
like a dog...
...You've given me a good gift
- Come father
You gave me a very good gift!
Come
- Did you reveal it
to her? - No
Mother
Are you fine?
Nobody informed me
Even your father didn't
phone me that you are here
Your uncle left from here
without saying anything
I got scared!
My limbs were unmoved after hearing
That's why I went immediately
Are you fine my dear?
Mother, I regained my breath
only after seeing you
Where have you been
all these days?-Mother I feel hungry
Oh I am a fool! I forgot it. I've prepared
your favorite dishes. Come let's eat
One of my close friends
He has blood cancer!
It comes to one in every crore people
I have marriage here but received
an urgent phone call for me to be there
If I tell you will stop me
that's why I ran away
Marriage can wait
but not the life, isn't it mother?
Poor fellow! How is that boy now?
He is fine but he can't live longer
Oh gosh! What an agony it will be
for the parents to lose a young son
Unfortunate ones
God has cheated them, what can we do?
Why is he like that?
What happened?
Both of you have started it again!
If Lakshmi was here...
Ok where is Lakshmi and brother?
What can I say about her?
When we both met I had just teased
her that I will marry another girl
She felt it bad and went to London
without informing. Mad girl!
You do all this funny things
What to do now?
I am going to London. I will bring
her here after apologizing to her
Isn't it father?-That's all
- Is it? Then let's go
Where are you coming?
You make arrangement for the marriage
I will bring her back
Yes, there are lot of works I informed it
to your brother! Make al the arrangements!
I will come with him. Give him the rice
Why are you chatting?
Rice - Open the mouth
You go and look after the marriage
works, I will bring back Lakshmi
Will you come surely?
won't you escape again?
How can I escape again?
I will just go like this and come back
If you won't come
It's like I am dead
Are you gone crazy?
won't you believe me?
I am swearing on me
- Son!- Then what!
Have both of you gone crazy?
Why do you talk about the death?
Come this side, You go
Get in - Is it he?
He did an accident yesterday!
Why him? You go! His can drive nicely
I will comeback quickly!
I don't want Dad here! Take him also
No -Don't speak!
- Marriage works is there, know?
I will stay with you
Tell him mother
Father doesn't listen to me
I will stay with you
Take care of mother
- Go safely and bring back Lakshmi
- Ok, take care of father
I will look forward for you
Volga
Whole world is my family!
But I lead a solitary life!
The familial life is mine
I am ecstatic and void too!
Volga
As a poet, poem, wife and husband ..
In the jasmine ﬂowers strewn path
in the snow showering desert
Is it a victory song with tears!
Or is it a deluge of tears?
I enjoyed it myself with amazement!
I am dreaming alone!
Dreams, stories, dialogues
lyrics, colors and rainbows!
Epic heroines and girls!
Volga
I am sky's eye and
also the fire in the eyes!
I am the cool moon to eyes
But I'll remain the source of light to moon
I will turn as sun,
moon, sky and directions
Volga
Sun beams, rainbows, music, its tempo ..
..It's goal, time taken to
reach and Indra 's magic
Volga
To where?
World is a family, only one life
Don't you know I don't
have much time?
I want to make everyone
laugh till my death
To make everyone happy
Are you crying?
I am not going anywhere?
I will be with you in your memory
I will be in your eyes while seeing you
If you cry ever I will
fall down as your tear drops
You should always live with a smile
If you smile ever I will also
smile while looking from there
Come sit down
Come
Father!
- I will not stop you at all
Go wherever you want
make people smile howsoever
I want to be with you
- I mean
- Chakram
I am very proud to give birth to you!
You are not my son
You are my father
My father should not die like an orphan
I will be with you
Think me like your bag!
I don't have anybody other than you
I want to live for some more days
Who is that? Is he
asking scooter for festival?
How can I buy scooter for him?
Tell it won't be possible
Am I stealing the banks for buying whatever
he asks? It may be our daughter!
He is asking scooter today. He may ask
Howra mail tomorrow. How can I?
Keep the phone
I am dying because of son in laws!
We don't have
- We don't have
Are you kidding?
How can you say 'no ticket'?
One shouldn't travel without ticket
We are not traveling
- Then who are traveling?
- It's the train
- Then what are you doing?
- We are sitting
- Sitting?
- You too sit
Look mister!
One who travel in the train.
Whoever sits in the train
should buy the tickets.-Tell me once more
Whoever sits in the
train should buy the tickets
Did you buy?
You are sitting right?
Whoever in the train...
Sit down
Everyone in the train should buy ticket
- Did you buy? -Why should I buy?
- You are also in the train- I am TC
So what if you are a TC
- So what is your intention?
You mean everyone in the train
TC, driver, guards, should buy the tickets
According to you everyone
in the train should buy, right?
- We are working here
- But you are rewarded for working
Why are you talking like this?
We are public servants
Who is public?
- It's us
- We are public
- We are the owners
Can the owners buy the ticket?
Wait
What did he said?
Isn't he accepting it?
Do one thing, Kill him
and you too die after that
Don't worry about me
Couple of members are here, they'll kill me!
I will also die
Oh my god!
As a poet, poem, wife and husband ..
In the jasmine ﬂowers strewn path
in the snow showering desert
Is it a victory song with tears!
Or is it a deluge of tears?
I enjoyed it myself with amazement!
I am dreaming alone!
Dreams, stories, dialogues
lyrics, colors and rainbows!
Epic heroines and girls!
Whole world is my family!
But I lead a solitary life!
He got caught like that!
Oh gosh! I am getting a stomach pain!
I'll die if I stay with you for sometime!
I can't smile! Stop it, sir
I don't remember when did I smile last!
This is the first time after 20 years
I am laughing in this job
You have told the value of the laughter
My son had taught this
Did your son teach you?
Where is he now?
See here
Why are you stunned?
Everyone will die
You will also die, I will also die
But my boy went early
We should live smiling till our life ends
We should make others smile
We should laugh until we know its value
This is also taught by my son
Train has come, let's go
He is looking from there
A baby is ready to leave in an
air palanquin, went like a procession!
Despite closing the voice entrance
with silence, the heart hums it!
My heart is my loneliness
My heart is the mother of my songs
My heart is like my wife
It is a film journey from my heart!