Deuk Gu Kim, managed by Hyun Chi Kim
who was a world class fighter in his time,
and trained by yet another Kim Yoon Gu.
I'm told by Irving Rada
top rank promotions director.
Not all of the Kim's are not the same Kim's.
In fact, Kim is a very
common name in Korea.
I will tell you something, this particular
Kim looks to be in great shape.
I agree. He's ready to fight
Here in Las Vegas.
There is the Champion, Boom Boom Mancini!
Making his way into the Coly outdoor ring.
The noise in this arena seems
to be is getting louder and louder,
as the audience anticipates
the boxers' entrance.
Deuk Gu Kim is not intimidated by Mancini.
He has very good punch to counterattack.
Kim also has a great
reputation of good combinations.
Good Afternoon, Ladies and Gentlemen.
Today's main event.
Top rank and Round one
It's a 15 round match for the WBA world title.
In the blue corner, weighing in at
134.75 lbs, from Seoul,
South Korea & ranked number one
in the world WBA. Deuk Gu Kim!!
And in the red corner, weighing at
134.25 lbs, from Youngstown, Ohio
and currently the world WBA champion
Ray Boom Boom Mancini!
Ray Boom Boom Mancini's father
Lenny Mancini attended at Ringside today.
I'm sure he's very proud of his son,
the world Champion.
We'll be here to witness as he defends
his title against a very strong opponent.
Okay, gentlemen
no blows below the waist.
If I pull on you,
I want you to pull back.
If either of you gets knocked down on the canvas
three times in a row, the fight is over.
Now the best of luck to both of you.
These two fighters have
very similar physical stats.
Both 5 feet 6 inches tall.
Each weighting 134 pounds.
This means, this match is
a great opportunity to test their skills.
Champion
Yoo, Oh-seong
Chae, Min-seo
Where are you heading to?
Can you give me a ride?
Where are you going?
To the terminal
Do you have any money?
No.
Hop on!
7 years later....
No way!
Hey..
What's the matter?
No.
Alright.
Ah, what the hell is this?
Next.
2700..
2800..
2900..
3000.
Next.
It should be 100 won,
Just give me 50.
Can it be washed in a second?
Yup, just in a second.
Hey, I'm busy.
Hey, Miss.
Laughter brings you luck
It not only brings you luck but also beauty.
Usually when girls laugh..
- Why don't you try laughing?
- Pardon me?
Laugh, you son of a bitch!
It will bring you luck!
Hey, why you crackin' up?
You son of a bitch.
Who the hell do you think you are?
Get your ass over here.
What you looking at?
Let's see what you've got with your luck.
Laugh, you idiot!
Then you shall be lucky.
Are you nuts?
Watch where you're going.
Man,
What's that smell? lt smells like shit.
You know..
Gummy bears doesn't have bears in it..
Hey.. about the other day..
How am I supposed to know..
A Boxing Match
Between Korea and Thailand.
Attention!
Salute to the master.
You!
Are you here to learn boxing?
Yes, sir.
I'm here to box and
I will someday become a champion,
and honor the nation.
What about you?
Yes.
I'm here to learn from the great master
and to train my body and mind..
and strengthen power and..
Cut the bullshit.
So.. You are here to become a champion
and become a millionaire
and have fame and all that?
Is that so?
Yes..
I have two things
for you to keep in mind.
No matter where you go.
Don't you ever curse
and talk like trash.
Yes, sir.
It's okay for normal people,
But for boxers
they will criticize you no matter what.
And..
Even if you become a dump scooper,
Be good at it.
It doesn't matter what you do
as long as you are good at it!
Even if you end up with
a bucket filled with shit in your hand..
If you are the best man at it
then you are the champion.
You know what I mean?
Yes, sir.
Enough for today.
Yes.
Hello!
Kim, Duk-koo!
Yes, sir.
Do you want to spar with me?
Don't let it in!
If you let in..
Pull up your guard.
Switch the sparring partner.
Enough, Duk-koo.
You get down and Pil-seung, you're up.
Why is it so complicated?
Hey, Kim, Duk-koo
It's almost curfew.
If your home's too far
won't you just sleep in the gym?
If we always get beat up
everyday, we'll become crippled.
You know what?
What?
I could have gotten
that major punch right at the..
Why didn't you?
I was about to..
But you know that kid was master's puppy.
Do you want to go for it?
Me? Why?
So I can get beat up like hell?
Hey.. boxing is the fairest thing in the world.
What is?
Have you seen a boxer with three arms?
You got two arms to fight with
and same goes with your opponent.
If the guy connect 10 punches.
You go with 15
or 20 if you wish.
You know how much you make
if you become a champion?
How much?
I would say over 10 million won.
The blue corner, 68 Kg, WBK.
Dong-a Gymnasium picnic party
The Asian Champion
Hwang, Joon-seok.
The Red Corner, 63 Kg
WBK World Champion, Lee, Sang-bong.
The winner will be
prized with 20 fried chickens!
1978 MBC
A rookie king selective match.
The new kids are always full of passion.
Open burrow is more
common than stomache burrow.
He turned his back with his eyes closed.
Here it comes again.
Right hook.
He's down.
Hey,
what's the matter?
I had peach juice after the weight check.
I've been suffering from
diarrhea since then..
You shouldn't have
drank anything without eating.
Next will be a semi-final match for light weight
fighters Jong-shil Lee from Gookdong Gymnasium
and Duk-koo Kim from
Dong-a Gymnasium will also be fighting.
That fighter is quick but weak.
Push him until 30 seconds are left and
When I say go, then start attacking him.
Understood?
First round.
The match has begun.
Stand up, you idiot.
How many light weights
do we have in this gym?
If you've got picked for
one of the two tickets.
At least you should have tried your best.
I'm so sorry.
Next!
Park, Jong-pal, you are up!
From now on, you don't
have to show up anymore.
You are on your own.
And you, you're the winner today
and this is for the winner.
Understood?
Yes, sir..
There it goes again.
Other coaches walk loudly
while players are asleep.
But our master walks silently
when he comes into the gym
not to wake us up.
Even if it's lower
than all the other voices.
Our boss was watching like this, I stepped
backward and the boss shouted "Here it comes."
And that's when I gave
him a punch. Then he fell over.
Hey,
what are you doing?
I want to go to middle school.
Can you support me?
My father's money goes here.
So we are dead broke.
Ask my step mother?
Now..
you mean my dad..
So?
My dad is like a..
He locked me in the attick,
and fed me like a bird.
To hide my existence
to the woman he lives with.
And there..
I made a pact to myself.
I don't have a father.
My father is dead.
I have lived that way since then.
What am I?
You?
Duk-koo, the dog.
How you know it was my nickname?
Wow..
You are a genius!
You only went up to grammar school.
Where'd you learn your English?
Anyway, you were wrong.
Why am I Duk-koo the dog
and not Kim, Duk-koo?
l almost became
a Baek Duk-koo.. never mind.
I was never born.
Anyways,
I was originally Lee, Duk-koo,
But..
My dad passed away
and my mom got married again,
and as long as I could remember
My last name has
changed two or three times.
Anyway.. Later on
people called me Kim, Duk-koo.
So.
So I.. Well, what the hell..
Remember? Master told us not to curse
So.. just call me Duk-koo
the dog.. I could care less..
Alright.. I like Duk-koo the dog.
See? That's why..
Got it. Sang-bong the dog?
From now on, anyone with
no father will have the dog at the end of their name.
Really? then we are brothers
since we both end with "the dog."
Right on!
Cheers, brother!
You be the older brother!
It's a new begining...
Women are like blocks of my life...
Asian-Pacific Championship Title Match.
Usually, I don't ask this kind of favors
But it's my friend's birthday...
No way, there might not be
people wanting illegal tickets.
Then give me some more.
Well my friends from
hometown will be visiting.
No, there are rules you know..
OK, then you can pay me 20% next time.
Alright, then 10%!
You don't have to pay me next Time.
When's the next match?
I don't know.
You take 8,000 won and l take 10,000 won.
What round you got?
4th round.
How about me? What round do I get?
Kim, Duk-koo is squinting his face
Here we have
the fourth round of bloody battle.
The refree is headed towards Kim, Duk-koo.
Duk-koo
Kim, Duk-koo is the winner.
- He's got the victory on decision.
- He made a victorious comeback.
Kim, Duk-koo looks stunned, indeed.
And he cheers for the opponent
What a gentleman with great manners.
It sure was a bloody battle.
He's got to check if the opponent is alright.
Yes, the fourth round was a vicious round.
Here, take it.
You earned this by being beaten up.
You know what I mean.
Try hard. Do well in the 6th round next Time.
Yes.
Waitress, here!
Give us 2 more portions.
The same one?
Yes.
How come I'm still not full?
There must be a beggar
family living in my stomach.
My mother says when you're hungry
you will feel better to eat grinded
perilla japonica with sesame oil.
I already tried.. but it doesn't help..
Water is good for hunger.
It's easy to get.. It's embarrassing to
get food for free but for water it's not.
Can you afford it?
Don't worry.
I sure can let you eat as much meat
as you want on your birthday.
And I got the check.
20,000 won?
Don't worry, I also have some more money.
What are you staring at? Start eating.
Why aren't you eating?
It's not roasted yet.
1981 . 4
Win vs Lim.
1981 . 8
Win vs Runeaskal.
1981 . 9
Win vs Blashmeo.
OPBF Championship Title Match.
1981 . 12
Win Ohkwubo Kashiro
We've just moved in to the 4th floor.
Uh, really?
We work for Korea Multi-business..
Nice to meet you..
Yes..
What's wrong?
What's Korea Multi-business?
Don't know.
Yes..
Hi!
I'm Duk-koo Kim
national Champion for light weight.
Has our accounting clerk lady come up yet?
No, not yet.
OK, I get it. See you.
Have you seen Jong-pal Park
the Oriental Champion?
I don't know.. I didn't see anybody.
Can you tell him that
I'm looking for him if you see him?
I don't know whom you're talking about.
Women are like blocks of my life.
Duk-koo Kim? What is he?
Rush! Rush, Robot
Fly to the sky, Taekwon V.
Brave heart and justice is the name
With courage and spirit.
Dashing through the sky with open arms.
Great! Awesome!
Taekwon V is the killer.
Who could dare to put up with him?
Rush! Rush, Robot.
Fly to the sky, Taekwon V.
You are born to fight for justice.
Who could dare to put up with him?
May I have a cup of
tea with you after work?
Anyone seen my Levi's?
I'm not so into boxing.
Then what are you into?
Picture searching games.
What year were you born?
Shall I make a guess?
Do you believe in such things?
I'm also into physiognomy.
l go to church and my boyfriend's
a steward at the church.
If so, I should go to church too.
And pray that you would break up
with your boyfriend in the near future.
Can I ask you something?
what?
Why do you have to work out
in suits with your name on it?
It prevents you
from being lazy all the time.
People notice my name
and that's why I try to do my best.
Can I ask one?
Sure.
How long have you been
going out with your boyfriend?
I can walk alone from here.
My boyfriend waits for me
in front of the house.
Dad
How come you are so late?
Why are you out here in the cold weather?
Something's wrong?
Are you nuts?
What's the matter with you?
I think I can do it.
I can't hear the spirit.
I'm all about the big match.
If we beat Han, Seung-hee
then we are No. 1 in Korea.
Keep it up!
Everybody, attention!
Next month, there shall be
a third Oriental Champion.
Kwang-min Kim will
be fighting with Duk-koo.
Help each other so that Duk-koo
can win. Work hard for the victory.