- John Coltrane, he could
get in his spaceship
and it could take him
anywhere he wanted to go.
- Just to say the name John Coltrane,
it makes me shake, tremble.
It's like talking' about
Beethoven, Shakespeare.
You're talking' about an artistic genius
and a spiritual giant.
- Trane had a sound that was heavenly,
it was like, oh my God.
- Coltrane's strength of character
is in his journey through music.
He sacrificed.
And he had the insight
and the consciousness
to touch that thing that's
inside of all of us.
- Right now, we're gonna take you down
to a favorite little spot of ours
here in New York, Cafe Bohemia.
Down there at the present time
is a young man whose name is Miles Davis.
I'm sure you know who he is,
he's a real cool
stylist, Miles Davis is.
- 1957, John Coltrane is part of one
of the ground-breaking groups of the day,
the Miles Davis Quintet.
Miles Davis is looked
upon as the harbinger
of everything new.
He is on the cutting edge.
Everyone is looking at him
for the promise of what is to come.
- Are you really asking
me a question like that?
How good was that band?
- Well, I think it was probably one
of the greatest jazz bands
that was ever formed.
- Everybody in the band
had their own voice
and John was really, really
special in that regard,
in that you could hear that
he was going somewhere,
and I think that Miles heard
that he was going somewhere.
- Being with Miles Davis
was huge for Coltrane,
absolutely huge.
It catapulted him from being somebody
that only really serious
record collectors knew about
to being somebody that everybody knew.
- John Coltrane's experiences
in Miles Davis' Quintet was sort of
like going up to the high
diving board every night;
allowing himself to be scared,
allowing himself to not know
exactly what was gonna be ahead of him.
- It's of a high, high caliber to be able
to play on the level which is exceptional.
You've got to be touched by
the supreme whatever to be
able to play like Miles played
and like Coltrane played.
- At this time, Coltrane
is a relative newlywed.
With the entire Miles
Davis Band as best men,
Coltrane marries Naima Austin,
a woman he'd met in Philadelphia.
Naima has a child, Antonia.
- This is a man who gets
his first experience
as fatherhood with me,
and I was a handful, little bit.
I was a handful.
I was remembering one time,
John had this gig, it was a bad night,
snowy, he did the gig.
I needed some shoes.
He walked back from that gig home
so he wouldn't spend any of the money
so that I could get
the shoes the next day.
You know, you make that sacrifice,
you work all night and then you walk home
so that I can get a pair of shoes?
That's father.
- John Coltrane is working consistently
to support the wife
and daughter he adores.
Life is good, but there's a problem.
- We are playing in nightclubs
where the pimps and hustlers are around
and you go for the hype,
that hey man, you take some of this
and you'll feel up and
good, you'll feel good.
And you go for it and then you're stuck.
- Hard drugs is an addiction.
Charlie Parker, the great
prophet before Coltrane,
Charlie Parker, he was on drugs.
He wanted to get off,
he didn't quite make it.
- There was the misguided notion
that artistic ability was
enhanced with hard drugs.
Charlie Parker is the example.
- You're gonna turn from
somebody that can't play
to a Charlie Parker by doing this?
It doesn't happen, it's a myth.
Geez, and some of my friends, I mean,
they died following that trail.
- Before Coltrane was really aware of it,
he was using the needle and he
was really heavily addicted.
He had become a heroin addict,
and it's not generally known that he
was also drinking to excess.
The funny thing about him though
is that everybody loved him.
I'd spoke to over 250
people when I did my book
and I couldn't find anybody that said
oh, when he was drunk, he was a terror.
They all said oh, I didn't
even know when he was drunk
because he was always so sweet.
He was that kind of a person,
but he was unreliable.
Miles Davis famously wrote
in his autobiography,
he would come to the gig in clothes
that looked like he'd slept in them.
So this was not making a great
impression on Miles Davis.
- John Coltrane's fired.
He's never been higher in his career,
and so the drop down is long and hard,
and he realizes that he can
go the way of Charlie Parker,
and just continue on a
self-destructive path
or really, is he gonna find
a way of dedicating himself
to a clean spiritual existence
that brings together everything
that has inspired him
from the time he was a child.
And so here's John Coltrane
at a pivotal point of his life.
He's gotta make a decision.
- I was born in a small town called Hamlet
in North Carolina in 1926.
My family moved from there
when I was a few months old to High Point.
I was an only child.
I was brought up Methodist.
It wasn't too strict, but it was there.
In my early years when I was
going to church every Sunday,
I was under the influence
of my grandfather.
He was the dominating cat in the family.
Both of my grandfathers were ministers.
I grew up in that and I
guess I just accepted it.
- To understand John Coltrane's beginnings
is to understand that he
comes from the American south
and the racial realities
that he grew up with,
the idea that the black church
was the primary force that
held his family together
and also it was the source point
for his first musical experiences,
and the fact that music and
the spirituality were there
as one at the very beginning
is to really get at the DNA
of what John Coltrane's all about.
- The Jim Crow South was
basically a reference
to what the south was like
after the Civil War, after reconstruction,
where segregation had been reimposed.
It was a place ready-made for the blues,
ready-made for jazz, ready-made for people
using their pain to catapult their art.
- The Jim Crow South
where Coltrane grew up
proceeded from slavery, and under slavery
it was against the law
for us to read or write.
How will our humanity be expressed?
Creatively, courageously.
It was against the law for black people
to worship God without white supervision.
So what do you do?
You steal away at night.
Near the creek.
Hold hands in the rain
shower and lift your voice.
Lift your voice.
Vocals create community,
camaraderie and so forth.
Black music was the black response
to being terrorized and traumatized.
We gonna share and spread
some soothing sweetness
against the backdrop
of a dark catastrophe.
That's black music.
- John grew up in an extended family.
He was living in the same house
with his mother and father,
his grandfather and grandmother,
and aunt and uncle and cousin.
And then, within a period of two years
his father died, his uncle died,
his grandfather died, and eventually
so did his grandmother.
It was a devastating few
years for the family.
- He's only 12 years old.
Can you imagine what that
does for any human being?
How you gonna respond?
- And the one thing that happens
just at that point in
John Coltrane's life is
that he started to take up music.
He's gone from playing clarinet
to alto saxophone.
And it's almost like he
hangs on to the music
like a life preserver.
He finds, in music, a way of dealing
with these harsh, harsh realities
that are suddenly thrust
upon the Coltrane family.
- Their standard of living
was all of a sudden totally changed.
All the men are gone,
and Coltrane's mother just had to leave
and go north to find work.
- When I finished high school
I moved to be with my
mother in Philadelphia.
This was 1943.
I worked for a year in a signal depot.
We had a war, you know.
Then I decided to study music again.
My mother made many sacrifices
to enable me to study music.
And I was able to take lessons
from a private saxophone instructor.
- I was 16.
I'd been playing saxophone for two years.
When one of the kids
came home from school,
he said, "There's a new guy
that moved into the projects,
"and he plays alto, and he
sounds just like Johnny Hodges."
I said, "Really?
"Do you think you can bring
him by the house tomorrow?"
He said, "I think so."
About four o'clock the doorbell rang
and there was this country
bumpkin' looking' guy
standing on the street.
And he stood in the
doorway with this horn,
just stood there.
I didn't know what to say.
The only thing I could think to say
was, "Play something."
And that's what he was waiting for.
Now, John and I became very close
and he joined our little coterie there.
He was quiet.
I had to talk all the time.
He never talked until he put
that saxophone is his mouth.
Ya.
- June 5, 1945, first time
Coltrane sees Charlie Parker.
Blows his mind.
What kind of person is he?
This brother got so
much creativity in him.
Willing to cut against the grain,
courageous to the core.
You can just see Coltrane,
just, his mind was blown.
- John and I was screaming, screaming.
It's no wonder we didn't
fall over the balcony.
We had never heard anything
like that in our life.
We'd never heard double-time.
It's impossible.
- The first time I heard Charlie Parker,
I knew that was the thing for me.
Charlie Parker did all the
things I would like to do
and more.
He really had a genius.
- Coltrane was in the Navy in 1945 to '46
and stationed at Pearl Harbor.
- The very first John Coltrane recordings
quote, unquote come from 1946
when he's a part of a Navy band
and they do this recording in Hawaii
and they're playing big Bird tunes.
And you can hear this
very young John Coltrane
playing and imitating the style
of Charlie Parker, his hero.
- When you hear that recording
from when he's in the Navy,
he doesn't play that well.
It's not possible to even
believe it's Coltrane.
- Some people blossom very early.
For Coltrane, that was not the case.
I don't think you could listen to that
and say, "Great things ahead."
- And just that he could
go from that way of playing
to what he became, man,
that's all you need to know about him.
- After a year in the Navy,
I came back to Philadelphia
and then went on the road.
I accepted work with all kinds of groups,
even if I didn't agree
with their musical tenets
because I could learn something
while I was making a living.
They were, in comparison to baseball,
like the minor leagues.
I then went with Dizzy
Gillespie from 1949 to 1951.
I wanted to find my own
way but I wasn't ready.
There was so much to learn yet.
- For John Coltrane to be playing
with someone of Dizzy's stature had to be
like waking up to all of
your Christmases at one time.
- Dizzy was wonderful.
In every way you can imagine.
His sense of humor was incredible.
That's how he got the name Dizzy.
But he was a genius.
- So Dizz was hearing something
in Coltrane's playing as being promising,
as being filled with possibilities,
and that this guy needed nurturing.
- When we finally got with Dizzy's band,
John would be practicing in the hotels.
And invariably, somebody would holler,
"Hey, tell that guy to stop all that noise
"up there with that horn!"
And Trane would stop practicing
and just finger the horn for an hour;
just practice fingering'.
I never seen anybody do that.
- He was such a, just
like compulsive practicer.
He just wanted to practice all the time.
I looked up to him so much,
I was like okay, that's what I have to do.
When you start doing' that
you kinda get a connection
with the instrument.
I understand why he did that
because there's a deeper
connection you get
when you spend that much time with it.
It starts to kinda feel like
an extension of yourself.
- He always had that horn
and he played all day long.
And when he went to work,
during the intermission
he was in the men's room playing his horn.
I mean, this is spartan practice.
You know, not everybody was into that.
I wasn't into that.
But it was like he was
trying to best himself.
- Dizzy had a very strict
rule about drug use
and that December of 1950,
he caught Coltrane and
Jimmy Heath shooting up.
- We were getting high
down in the basement.
And Dizzy came down at
intermission and he caught us,
and he fired us.
But Trane begged his way back in
and I, I didn't.
- Coltrane begged.
"No, please, I won't do it again.
"Let me stay.
"I really love playing with you,"
so forth and so on.
And it worked, Dizzy let him stay.
But it only lasted a few more months.
By April of '51, Coltrane was out again.
- I stayed in obscurity for a long time
because I was happy to play
what was expected of me
without trying to add anything.
All this time musically,
I was progressing very
little in the way I wanted.
I had not reached the point
when I could take active steps by myself.
In fact, I don't think
I reached that point
until after I got with Miles.
It was Miles who made me wanna be
a much better musician.
In 1955 I joined Miles on a regular basis
and worked with him
till the middle of 1957.
Why he picked me, I don't know.
Maybe he saw something in my playing
that he hoped would grow.
I had this desire, which
I think we all have,
to be as original as I could be,
but there was so many musical conclusions
I hadn't arrived at
that I felt inadequate.
- In the spring of 1957,
Miles Davis hit a breaking point
with John Coltrane in his group.
John Coltrane's drug habit
is getting in the way of the music.
For Miles, there's no
way getting past that.
- Getting fired by Miles
was really the shock of his life
and there was no other gig
like a Miles Davis gig.
That was the top of the field, number one.
And number two is that he was
kinda counting on this gig
for his security and stability,
and building a home, and
having a married life.
- John Coltrane was by no
means the only great musician
who had drug problems.
Killed Charlie Parker at an early age
and many other were afflicted.
When he looked into the abyss,
he decided that he
couldn't stay where he was.
He was either gonna go down and die
or go up and become even greater.
- He quit what they call cold-turkey,
which means he didn't go to an institution
and he didn't have any
kind of medical support.
During the days he would just stay home
and keep the doors closed.
- Only one time did it ever
become difficult for me
and that was when he was withdrawing.
And I could hear him.
I could see mommy taking'
him to the bathroom
because he was always regurgitating.
He was doing the cold-turkey.
One night it was really, really bad
and I became really afraid.
And I remember praying, saying to myself,
"Please, God, don't
"don't take my father."
And each night he seemed to
not be as sick.
- And we thank God, you know, that He
allowed John Coltrane to get past,
you know, the gates of hell.
- He just decided to do it.
And by strength of will
and faith, he did.
- So he cleaned up.
And when he cleaned up,
things began to unfold.
- During the year 1957
I experienced, by the grace of God,
a spiritual awakening which was to lead me
to a richer, fuller, more productive life.
At that time, in gratitude,
I humbly asked to be given
the means and privilege
to make others happy through music.
- John Coltrane returns to New York
after he gets himself clean,
and he's very much like
a man on a mission.
- After going cold-turkey
and not using drugs,
his energy level went up a notch.
He smiled more.
You know, that gorilla off your back.
Ya, I think he was really happy.
- When I stopped drinking
and all that other stuff,
it helped me in all kinds of ways.
I was able to play better
right then, you know?
I could play better and think better.
Everything.
- Very significantly,
that's also the time period
that he started playing
with Thelonious Monk on an informal basis,
and then joined his band in July of '57.
- If you say Thelonious
Monk's name to any musician,
I'd say to Miles, "Thelonious Monk,"
he'd say, "Oh, Monk Monk Monk."
Dizzy, "Oh, whoa, whoa,
whoa, Monk Monk Monk."
First, his musicianship was supreme;
just his knowledge, his ability to play,
his harmonic sophistication,
the structures of his songs,
and it's Coltrane learning from Monk.
Trane would come in the morning
and they would just practice all day.
- You spending' time in Monk's house
and he's going through,
that level of genius taking time
to help nurture your genius.
- After working with Thelonious Monk,
Coltrane is fully on his feet.
- He's got the confidence now.
And it is in 1957
that he records his
first album as a leader.
- The cover says Coltrane.
You know, it's like once you're known
just by your last name, you
know you're already getting big.
And then it said up in the corner,
it said the NEW, in capital letters,
tenor saxophone star.
And the other thing is
that he had an opportunity
to do some of his own original music.
- His music just sounded different.
It was like there was new blood in it;
his playing, there was
new blood in his playing.
There was a certain kind
of almost recklessness.
He's pushing forward,
such that he may not even know
what he's pushing forward to.
- After my late teens,
I questioned a lot of what
I had found in religion,
but I never did anything about it.
I was too busy doing other things.
Recently I started looking into
what people were thinking
when I saw there were so many religions
and kind of opposed somewhat
to the next and so forth.
It screwed up my head.
I just couldn't believe
that one guy could be right,
because if he's right, somebody
else has gotta be wrong.
- The three of us, we didn't
go to church every Sunday.
But I knew that my
parents believed in God.
They had a strong belief in God.
We had bibles.
We had the Koran.
My father was looking at
different eastern religion;
Buddhism, Shinto.
- He never set out specifically to say
I'm a Christian or I'm a Muslim
or I'm a Hindu or a Buddhist.
I think he studied all of these religions
and understood that there is
something higher than that.
There's something that all these religions
are basically saying that's universal.
- I like to describe
it as a little picture,
which is our world, and the big picture.
John was about the big picture.
John was very celestial.
Celestial meant spiritual.
He had a deep understanding,
a deep feeling for
higher worlds than this world.
- Coltrane was definitely someone
who was inspired by the
concept of the infinite,
and imagining how science
and music and math
all worked together, and
that there was some kind
of universal truth.
And so for Coltrane to be inspired
by Albert Einstein, who is a deep thinker,
not just about space
travel and time and energy,
but the biggest of the big questions.
Why are we here?
What are we supposed to be doing?
And where are we supposed
to take ourselves?
Coltrane was absolutely on that same road.
- At the end of 1957, Coltrane
came back into Miles' band.
The difference though, the
second stint with Miles,
is that now Coltrane kinda
had a sense of who he was.
One of the reasons that being with Miles
was so productive for Coltrane
is that Miles gave him tons of space.
Miles let him solo at length
and he really didn't try to edit Coltrane.
He didn't say, you know,
when you're playing with me
you gotta play shorter solos than I do.
Almost invariably, Coltrane
played longer solos.
There is a famous story
about Miles making a joke to Coltrane
in saying why do you play so long
and Coltrane saying well, I
can't find a good place to stop.
And Miles saying well,
you could just take the
horn out of your mouth.
- Miles is a strange guy.
He doesn't talk a lot and
he rarely discusses music.
You always have the impression
that he's in a bad mood
and that he's not interested in
or affected by what
other people are doing.
It's very hard in a situation like that
to know exactly what you should do.
And maybe it's because of that
that I just started to do what I wanted.
- Here we go.
- Wait.
- Okay.
- Trane and I'll play one,
you know, together, out.
You know what I mean?
Can you hear me?
- Ya.
- Let's go.
- Oh, Kind of Blue was one
of the greatest records ever made.
It's just got a great feel.
You can never grow tired of that album.
And it crosses all boundaries.
People who don't understand jazz get it.
- Kind of Blue is so key to understanding
where John Coltrane would go in the 1960s.
That really is sort of the fuse
to the Coltrane explosion later.
It's very interesting.
You've got the first session
from Kind of Blue in early '59.
A little while later,
about a month and a half,
you've got the second session.
In between, John Coltrane's
doing Giant Steps.
- It was unprecedented.
It was something that forced all of us
to call into question
what we had been hearing
as that which was innovative.
- Every tune on Giant Steps
was composed by Coltrane.
So, that album was huge for him
because it showed something
that I don't think people yet knew,
which is that he was
as brilliant a composer
as we was a saxophonist.
- Writing has always been
a secondary thing for me,
but I find that lately
I'm spending more and more time at it.
I'm trying to tune myself,
to look to myself and to nature
and to other sounds in music,
and interpret things I feel there.
- So Miles' band was a great environment
for Coltrane to grow, and he grew so much
that he grew too big for the band.
I mean, he grew out of it.
He couldn't exist in it anymore.
- He was actually saying to me
he was going to leave Miles Davis,
"I'm gonna leave Miles
"because what I'm playing with that group
"sounds incorrect, sounds wrong."
It's like he took off a suit of clothes
that he doesn't wanna wear anymore.
- And from the time we
started out in my living room,
we knew nothing that was going to happen.
It just happened when it happened.
But when it did happen, I
said it should've happened
because he was really ready.
He had his stuff together there.
Yes, this should be.
- John Coltrane is one
of my favorite creators
because he was very soulful,
and stories being told through his music
without even words;
stories through experience.
We know somebody went up and down
and then came back up again.
We celebrate them and we relate to them
because we all have our ups and downs.
- You know, some people play jazz,
some people play reggae,
some people play blues.
He played life.
- You can't describe music with words.
We can say oh, ya, this guy was doing
a lot of technical stuff.
Wow, when we analyze it,
and wow, look at this.
Look at these changes and these harmonics.
But it's not about that,
it's about hearing it.
- His sound, you know,
it makes people cry.
Like oh, damn, what is this tears?
Why am I crying?
What's going on?
Your body's doing something
that your mind don't want to do.
- His sound is stunning.
It ranges through the
different emotions people have
in a way that very few people can do.
And as I said, he did it
partly from his own inner spirit,
but he also was intellectually brilliant,
that is he wrote brilliant music
and he could take a standard
and play it in a way
that made you think you were
hearing it for the first time.
- Within a year of leaving
Miles Davis for good,
John Coltrane has an incredible radio hit
with his tune that is
from The Sound of Music.
- So here's this Broadway melody,
oh, and he just transforms
it into this gorgeous thing.
- My Favorite Things was a record
that I actually played for my friends
because I felt like they would like it.
The reason that music touches everybody
is that was Coltrane's intention.
And he put a lot of everybody's
music in that music.
You know, in that soprano saxophone,
that kind of nasal sound is really popular
all over the world.
Coltrane had worked on
that his entire life.
How can I bring people together
and how can I bring these cultures
and how can I bring this music together.
And what allowed him to bring it together
was a spiritual consciousness.
- He is creating this new approach,
this new sound that many people
would not even expect to hear from jazz,
an Eastern sound if you will,
a much more spiritual sound.
It is so fresh and yet wonderfully
popular at the same time.
- I've got to keep experimenting.
I feel that I'm just beginning.
I have a part of what I'm
looking for in my grasp,
but not all.
I like Eastern music.
Africa, Spain or Scotland, India or China.
It's that universal side of music
which interests and draws me.
And that's where I wanna go.
- For Coltrane, I think
there was a pattern
of doing something that is unexpected
when you look at what came before it.
So he would do something that
would sort of trip himself up
so he could figure out what to do next.
And that sense of struggle
and thinking through the
next problem propelled him
and made him keep getting better
and stronger and more
interesting and challenging.
- He was never satisfied.
Insatiable.
If he got from here to there,
he wanted to go there.
And if he got there, he
wanted to go over there.
- There's an intensity that
I've never heard anything like it,
before him or after him.
I always liken it to looking at the sun.
Hearing John Coltrane, it's like
the brightest light you can hear.
- I mean, his tone is so unique.
I mean, it's so striking.
I mean, no one had that tone on the horn.
During that time it became the standard.
- It's not the car, it's the driver.
So his sound, it sounds like it's coming
from some deep part of himself.
Even though you hear
him on different horns,
you hear him on different mouth pieces,
you can see him playing different setups.
Still, it doesn't matter.
It's coming from that soul.
- His grandfather was a preacher.
And I can hear that,
they said there's a
wailing, sometimes wailing.
I can hear Trane's appreciation
for what his grandfather's mission was.
- The evolution of John Coltrane's bands,
till he develops what we now
call the classic quartet,
is typical Coltrane experimentation.
It's him trying out new ideas,
new players, new things.
- He went through a lot of
tryouts with different people,
and finally he got the
group that he wanted.
And he was able to fly
like he wanted to do.
- I'm very lucky.
I work with very fine musicians.
They are very inventive.
I don't have to tell anybody what to do.
We have a great confidence in one another,
that's essential.
They're with me in always wanting
the band to move into new areas.
We don't believe in standing still.
- And just to have Elvin,
the level of intelligence,
the seriousness that he was on,
and Jimmy the type of heart he had,
and McCoy who was young, was a kid.
They are originals.
They sent music in another direction,
gave us another way to perceive
the universe through music.
People who heard them, their
lives were transformed.
- When I was 17 I was a jazz buff.
I was well aware of rock 'n roll,
but I considered jazz the higher art form.
I had heard that Coltrane was coming
to Shelly's Manne-Hole in Hollywood.
Saw them, oh, I don't
know, five or six times.
Unbelievable.
I didn't know that Coltrane
would be such an icon,
but I sensed that I was witnessing magic.
It would be just like Coltrane
would be saying something
on his tenor or soprano,
Elvin would answer
and then it would get all intertwined.
It was free, ooh.
I mean, they still would come back
to the tune and the chord changes,
but they'd go out on the
edge as far as they could.
They were inspiring.
The bathroom at Shelly's Manne-Hole
was behind the stage,
next to the dressing room.
I went to the bathroom a lot.
And I didn't really have to go,
but I was near my heroes.
One time I came out of the bathroom door
and Coltrane was just
standing there looking at me.
And I shunned eye contact and
then he went to the stage.
He had this quiet
spirituality about himself.
Everybody kinda parted like the Red Sea.
And then right behind him was Elvin Jones.
Elvin Jones gave me my
hands, which he did.
I copied all his style.
And then I found my own.
I think it gave me the courage to maybe...
A drummer's job is to keep the beat,
but then, if you can be expressive,
have a conversation with the singer
or the soloist, you can push 'em.
And I witnessed that
with Elvin and Coltrane,
and I pushed Jim Morrison
because of those guys.
The greatest quartet
in the history of jazz.
Miraculous.
- We were like brothers.
And we were there for a reason,
which was to create beautiful music.
You know, I use the word beautiful
because I couldn't think of a better word.
But,
we were committed.
We thought that what we were doing,
the gift came from the Almighty.
Not that we were walking around,
I'm this, I'm that...
you know, I'm this, I'm that.
It's not ego at all.
It's what you were put here for,
what's your reason for being here.
- Birmingham is a symbol
of hard-core resistance to integration.
It is probably the most
thoroughly segregated city
in the United States, and the injustices
inflicted upon Negroes are
the notorious realities.
- Growing up in the south, of course,
I know he wanted things to be better.
But he didn't talk about it.
I think he put that in his music.
- Coltrane did talk politics in his music.
It was only a few months after
that horrible bombing of a church,
and he wrote a piece called Alabama.
- And it shows the creativity
and depth of Coltrane.
A beautiful elegy screaming with pain,
under-girded by love.
I mean, it was just, it's
a masterful piece really.
- These children,
unoffending innocent and beautiful,
were the victims of
one of the most vicious
and tragic crimes ever
perpetrated against humanity.
- Coltrane himself told McCoy
Tyner, his piano player,
that he developed the
melody out of the speech
that Martin Luther King gave.
- And today, as I stand over
the remains of these
beautiful, darling girls,
I paraphrase the words of Shakespeare.
Goodnight sweet princesses.
Goodnight those who symbolize a new day.
May the flight of angels take thee
to thy eternal rest.
- Martin Luther King Jr. John
Coltrane go hand-in-hand.
Hand-in-hand.
Why?
Because they're love warriors.
They represent the best,
not just of black people,
not just for America.
They represent the best
of the human spirit.
- That song has a soul
that lets you know that
it was a lot of pain going on there,
but it's something that's
inspirational about that song.
When you hear Alabama, you
feel all that struggle,
from those times, the times
of the civil rights days,
but you all feel the progress.
- John Coltrane was ahead of his time.
I don't think that his
music is a thermometer.
It's a thermostat.
See, a thermometer just
reflects the climate.
A thermostat shapes the climate.
So when you hear Alabama,
it's not just his deep love
of the precious four girls
who were killed by
cowardly white supremacists
in 16th Street Baptist Church.
It's not just a re-figuration musically
of certain speech patterns
of Martin Luther King Jr.
He's looking at black people
all the way down the road.
He's already telling us
you gonna need courage,
vision, and most importantly love
at the center of it.
- As black people, we've been
through a lot in this country,
and we stay hopeful.
And that's what I feel in Alabama,
is the pain we went through
but the hope that we have.
- It was at night when all of the sudden
the voices got louder
and louder and louder and
I'm like, uh oh, oh dear.
What is going on?
- It's hard to know
specifically what was happening
in John Coltrane's personal
life in the early '60s,
but certainly there's indications
that he was not that happy
with his marriage to Naima.
- They didn't know I was sitting
around the bend of the stairway,
but I could hear everything.
Neither one of my parents were arguers.
So when that argument erupted,
I knew something was
really, really, really bad.
And
that was the day he left.
But he came back and he talked to me.
He said there were things
going on I can't explain.
I love you very much.
You're my daughter.
I'll always take care of you.
And that was it.
- My mother, Alice McLeod at the time,
was playing with a
vibraphonist named Terry Gibbs
and they were doing a double bill
with John Coltrane's Quartet
at the original Birdland on
52nd Street in New York City.
- They noticed each other
and it was a little bit
like, you know, there's a young lady here,
and oh, she's a pianist.
John definitely stuck
around to hear a little bit
of her playing and admired that.
- Something in the sound of
his tenor caught her ear.
At one point, in between
the breaks of the band,
my father started to follow my mother
around the club with his horn.
So he was serenading her through the club,
and I guess at that point they began
to sit and have conversations.
- They spoke.
They had a lot of things
in common when they spoke.
- I just remember my mother saying
that he's just a very
kind, gracious person,
very decent man, and they
hit it off very well.
- She was interested in the harp
and he bought her a concert size harp.
Beautiful.
It's painted in gold, you know,
like an orchestra would have.
I think that's true love
when someone buys you a harp.
They're both gentle people,
I think perfectly paired by the universe.
- John Coltrane used
to leave little notes,
little poems, expressing
his love for Alice
around the home.
He would leave for the gig.
You know, she would come back to the house
and she would find these little messages.
And I don't think the romance
ever left John and Alice's relationship.
- He was married before,
and for whatever reasons
did not have any children with Naima.
Clearly, when he met my mom,
they didn't waste much time.
In a very short span three sons were born.
He was an only child and his father
was an only child as well.
So I think maybe it was something
that he wanted to do in his
lifetime, to father children,
and I think it made him extremely happy.
- John Coltrane has set aside some time
and he secludes himself
above the garage in his house
at Dix Hills, Long Island
to put together what he sees as a suite.
He doesn't know how it's gonna go.
He has some loose melodies, some ideas.
Mrs. Coltrane tells the story
about him coming down
and grabbing little bits
of food now and again,
and then disappearing for a whole day.
This is just after John Jr. is born.
So she's got her four year old daughter
and an infant and a disappeared husband.
- And she said he was upstairs.
This was like two weeks he was up there.
And she always related these stories to us
in a happy way, that what he was doing
was significant and important
and she understood that;
as if he was on a mission and she
was there to support it.
- A few days later he
comes down the stairs,
and as Mrs. Coltrane put it,
"it was like Moses coming
down from the mountain."
And for once, the guy who really thought
and rethought about music,
seemed very satisfied
with where he was with this project,
and his words to Mrs. Coltrane were,
"it's the first time I
have everything ready.
"I've completed the project on paper.
"I know exactly what I'm
gonna do in the studio."
- All praise to God.
This album is a humble offering to Him,
an attempt to say thank you God,
through our work, even as
we do through our hearts,
and with our tongues.
May He help and strengthen all men
in every good endeavor.
- It's the individual expression of a
musical titan who wants
to give a certain message
to the world, in light of
his own relationship to God.
- A Love Supreme is something
I think every great musician aspires to,
which is finding that one moment
or that one song or that one recording,
that one album which
really kind of encapsulates
everything that they are,
what their message is.
- The thing about A Love Supreme,
all of Trane's mysticism is in it.
The totality of his consciousness
expresses itself most
fully on that record.
I don't even think he knew why.
Sometimes in the life of artists
or people who search
and practice and study
and work on stuff, they find things
and it's in there.
And it was in there.
- The second piece on there
is the one that touches me.
That's the one that
touches me, that melody.
- Where does it take you?
- It takes me to heaven,
where I wanna be when I leave here.
That's it, isn't it?
- And the audacity that someone
would absolutely speak to the
heavens using a jazz group,
it speaks to the singularity
of John Coltrane's vision.
- I think I played that album
more than I play any
other album in my life.
When somebody's music is that uplifting,
there's something angelic about it,
just something that just
touches you in your spirit
where you're like I know this
is coming from another place.
- I just thought oh my god,
you know, this guy,
his mind,
and his heart is so,
they're in a place that
everybody ought to reach for.
- May we never forget
that in the sunshine of our lives,
through the storm and after the rain,
it is all with God.
In all ways and forever.
All praise to God.
- It was '67 and I was
with a friend of mine
who was a conga player.
He'd just came into the band.
His name was Marcus
The Magnificent Malone.
He took me to his house,
he says here man, and
he put a joint in there,
and he put John Coltrane,
he put it on, loud.
A Love Supreme.
* A love supreme a love supreme
I remember it, that it was like,
like a vortex of a whole new
* A love supreme
* A love supreme experience.
Different than Jimi Hendrix,
different than Otis Redding,
different than BB King or
Tito Puente or Olatunji.
It was a vortex of
possibilities.
I play A Love Supreme a lot.
And I play it in every hotel that I go to.
As soon as I walk in, I
put on a little sound,
put out some incense,
and I have no doubt
that that room is clean
from negative, harmful spirits.
That's why he is so important
because it doesn't matter what religion
or what ideology you believe,
his sound is the sound of light
and the sound of love.
And I'm happy to tell you
that I'm very grateful
that my eyes, my heart, and my ears
will always be open to John Coltrane.
- John was a genius.
Beethoven survives.
Bach survives.
I don't think we should be afraid
to put John on their level at least.
Anything John plays, anything John writes
is beyond,
unquestionably beyond.
- Coltrane gave another dimension
to American music in the 20th century.
His music was deeply rooted
in the Afro-American experience
and in the American experience,
and with Coltrane, because of his studies
and his seriousness, the human experience.
- This music is connected
to an awful lot of stuff,
and it's connected to the past,
and it's connected to the future,
and it's connected to you, you know,
almost whoever you are
because of its humanity.
- I, myself, don't
recognize the word jazz.
I mean, we're sold under this name,
but to me, the word doesn't exist.
I just feel that I play John Coltrane.
I think the main thing a
musician would like to do
is give a picture to the listener
of the many wonderful things he knows of
and senses in the universe.
That's what music is to me.
It's just another way of saying
this is a big, beautiful
universe we live in
that's been given to us,
and here's an example
of just how magnificent
and encompassing it is.
- John Coltrane, he was outward bound
the way he was playing.
He could get in his
spaceship, metaphorically,
and it could take him
anywhere he wanted to go.
That's the way he was.
- One of the most incredible chapters
in John Coltrane's life is 1965,
'cause he has achieved a level of success
that includes Grammy nominations;
he's been inducted into
the downbeat Hall of Fame,
one of the very first
living jazz musicians
to be afforded that honor;
he has an outstanding best-selling
album in A Love Supreme.
There is an awareness that is starting
to creep into all levels of music fandom
and he starts to dismantle that
because he is now gonna
try new musical ideas.
Musical ideas that are not popular,
musical ideas that challenge most ears,
musical ideas that, in effect,
will take apart his classic quartet.
By the end of 1965 he
will lose Elvin Jones
and McCoy Tyner because of this new path
that he is going along.
And he will replace them
with a very young drummer
named Rashied Ali from Philadelphia,
and his wife, Alice Coltrane, on piano.
And he'll expand the band
and bring in a second
horn with Pharaoh Sanders.
- Here's the thing, John
Coltrane went from bebop
to Miles Davis Quintet, modern cool,
to his own quartet.
He went the whole transition.
So he could play standards.
He had the right to go out
as far as he wanted.
- John Coltrane's sound
rearranges molecular structure.
People are like what.
- Some said that he's taking
jazz in the wrong direction
which is of course a lie.
He's taking it forward.
And the reason you're not aware of it,
because you've never heard it before.
- Coltrane was definitely
one of the scientists
of the saxophone, someone who was pushing
the instrument to its limit.
Kinda of what Jimi Hendrix would later do
with the electric guitar.
- I don't care what the critics say.
If you like it, you like it.
If you don't, you don't.
He may have been reaching
for something else
spiritually, that they don't understand.
- He was brave enough and had the courage
to never doubt himself.
What was more of a concern for him
was he has to be as authentic
as he could possibly be.
- Would you want him to tiptoe
to where he's trying to get?
You know, John Coltrane,
you know, he's mean.
- Ya, I do understand it.
I'm open to it.
I try to embrace it.
I try to follow it.
I just proceed on the premise
that I'm not prepared to fully grasp
all the creativity that's taking place.
If it's Coltrane, I already
have a certain trust,
but it's not the kind of music
I would just sit there and
listen to all the time.
I got to really, gotta zero in
and I still don't fully
grasp what's going on.
- Coltrane thought it was
cleansing and uplifting,
but that's not what people heard.
What they heard was shrieking.
- Later when I saw him play,
I would say half the audience
left before it was over.
They just didn't know.
They were witnessing
something ahead of its time,
something spiritual but cathartic,
and tumultuous, and I just ate it up.
He could go to Mars, I'm with him.
- I have no fear about my
music being too way out.
My goals remain the same
and that is to uplift
people as much as I can,
to inspire them to realize more and more
of their capacities for
living meaningful lives,
because there certainly
is meaning to life.
- I was a first year student
in junior high school when it happened.
The explosion took place
at precisely 11:02 a.m.
50 meters up in the air.
I saw the flash and gazed
at the center of that overpowering light.
And at that time, a powerful force hit me,
lifting my body up and
flinging it across the room.
The earth was shaking.
The heat was intense.
Much of Nagasaki vanished.
Perhaps as many as 75,000
people died instantly
and another 75,000 were wounded
and exposed to massive radiation
and an uncertain future.
- I dislike war, period.
So therefore, as far as I'm concerned,
it should stop.
- It was July 14, 1966
when I went to pick up John Coltrane
and his musicians at the train station.
Everyone came out except Coltrane.
I looked all over for him
and found him in a car
of the express train playing the flute.
I was so surprised.
Then, he looked at me and grinned.
I asked him a question.
"Why were you playing the flute?"
He said that he was searching
for the sound of Nagasaki.
I was extremely moved by this.
I asked him if he wanted
to go straight to his hotel
and he said no.
He said he wanted to go to
the atomic bomb hypo-center.
For me, that place is sacred.
It's the same as a grave site.
He took a wreath of flowers
and put it down in front of the pillar.
And then he stood up and he prayed.
He was praying and looking up at the sky.
He just kept staring up above the pillar
for a considerable amount of time.
I asked him why and he replied
that he was imagining the sounds,
the plane, the bomb, the suffering
of the Japanese people.
I think that Coltrane has studied
about all of these things,
and for that reason,
he chose to come to Nagasaki
on his Japanese tour.
- My name is Yasuhiro
Fujioka, but known as Fuji
because of very long and
difficult name for foreigners.
So, everybody calls me
Fuji, like Mt. Fuji.
I'm a journalist, a lecturer,
a businessman, and chef.
I'm also the author of four
books on John Coltrane.
I admit it, I am obsessed
by John Coltrane.
I am the number one collector
of memorabilia of John Coltrane.
I was in high school
when I heard John Coltrane on the radio.
This music blew my mind.
The next day I rushed to the record shop,
the smallest in the world.
More than 40 years later I still go there.
That day I buy my first
John Coltrane record.
This is the album.
This is John Coltrane's Ole.
So within maybe five, six, seven years
I became a complete
collector of John Coltrane.
Then I decide to travel
all over the world.
So now, almost four months a
year or five months a year,
I'm abroad, still chasing Trane.
Ooh!
Wow!
I have a special passion for photographs,
posters, books, and tapes and vinyls,
anything John Coltrane
that catches my eye.
My collection is so large
that I had to build John
Coltrane house in Osaka
to store it all.
I want to listen to the music
of John Coltrane every day.
Every day and every evening, every night.
Every moment.
Surrounding Coltrane music and surrounding
by the photographs and the memorabilia.
Makes me happy.
When John Coltrane came to Japan
it was not an easy flight
from America in those days.
And his schedule was so tight,
16 shows in 17 days in
cities all over the country.
He was giving his life
to the people of Japan,
spending so much energy.
That was his last tour.
- Coltrane's concert in
Nagasaki was something special.
I was the announcer that night.
The second song was Peace On Earth.
He must have wanted to
perform that here in Nagasaki.
The whole concert hall was
totally caught up in Coltrane.
It was an amazing atmosphere.
- Why John Coltrane is so special for me
is he came to Japan, he
played Peace On Earth.
At that time we were still so struggling
from the atomic bombing,
and many people are still struggling,
and Coltrane was so kind to play for us.
Coltrane composed the song Peace On Earth
almost as requiem for
victim of the atomic bomb,
as well as his wish to stop all war.
That made me so,
I don't know how to say,
more,
I can't say enough.
I have no words.
His passion was peace and love
for the universe.
- You know, the last time I
talked to John on the phone,
his voice sounded,
it sounded...
- There were indications
by the end of 1966
and into '67 that Coltrane
wasn't doing well.
His side men later would report
that he was holding his
side like he was in pain.
And sure enough, he was later
diagnosed with liver cancer.
- At first when Coltrane died,
I think it was just shock.
I mean, he was only 40
and he hadn't been ill for a long time.
- My mother did speak of
John's death in this way,
which it was, this just floored me,
she said,
"it was beautiful.
"It was warm and the
breath went out of him.
"He was not in any pain."
She said at the very, this
is the moment of transition,
she used the word beautiful.
That's how she revealed it to me.
- All the things flashed through my mind
that we had done together.
And I went into my apartment,
I shut the door, and cried.
Boy...
It was rough.
Phew.
That really got me.
And you can see it's getting me now.
I'm sorry.
- I was at the funeral.
They wanted me to be a pallbearer,
but man, I could not do it.
I looked at him
in the casket,
and the way he was embalmed and all that.
Only thing I recognized was his hands.
He had fingers that went kinda strange,
'cause I been looking' at his hands,
we'd been practicing together,
and that's the only thing
that reminded me of Trane.
So that wasn't him.
He had passed on to the next place.
His spirit was gone.
- John was my best friend.
It wasn't like 99% of other people.
He existed in the real world.
I mean, he had a family, he had kids,
but that's not where he was at.
He was not in the real world.
He was someplace else.
So he's cool.
He's cool.
He was cool when he was here
and he's cool in the big picture.
He's cool.
- Since Trane passed away,
his music has transcended,
and it's more and more known, people...
That type of artistic
achievement stays around.
It's mythic because of
the sacrifice involved,
and it will remain mythic.
- If you go to any kind of
comprehensive retrospective
of Picasso's art, it's
breathtaking what he did,
how he went from being a
very good traditional painter
to the Blue period, his abstract,
and then his cubist work.
If you think about what John Coltrane did,
moving through his various
phases of musical creativity,
he basically did everything Picasso did
in about 50 years less time.
And I just think that
if you've got any kind of love for music
and regard for the craft,
you hear three or four notes and say
this man owns his horn, owns his music,
and at least when he's playing,
is the master of his soul.
- His spirit is still very much alive
and he's saying, "I'm gonna use music
"to try to convince you to grasp in time
"a love supreme so you that don't remain
"just a prisoner of time.
"You will be a maker, a creator
"of a better world."
That is a Coltrane version
of what he learned in Sunday school,
was he was taught that the kingdom of God
is within you and everywhere you go,
you oughta leave a little heaven behind.
And he left some heaven behind.
- To be a musician is really something.
It goes very, very deep.
My music is the spiritual
expression of what I am,
my faith, my knowledge, my being.
I know that there are bad forces.
I know that there are forces out here
that bring suffering to others
and misery to the world,
but I wanna be the opposite force.
I want to be the force
which is truly for good.