KLARA
FOR CHIARA FRUGONI
- When will we get there?
- It's almost there, Pacifica.
You said so earlier.
I'm beat and hungry as a wolf.
- What was it?
- How do I know?
- Wolf?
- You about that wolf again!
- What if...
- What?
If it's the devil?
The clothing bites me.
Pacifica, do you have any doubts?
- Do you want to go home?
- Don't.
I'm with you.
Francis.
We are ready.
I, Clare, vow to observe
the gospel of our Lord Jesus Christ
And live in obedience,
poverty and chastity.
I, Pacifica, vow to observe
the gospel of our Lord Jesus Christ
And live in obedience,
poverty and chastity.
As our Lord said to the apostles:
don't take anything on the road.
Neither cane nor bag.
Neither sandals nor money.
Promise to follow
Christ's example.
Who said
to the seeker of perfection:
"If you want to be perfect,
sell what you own
And distribute to the poor.
And follow me."
We promise.
Today was a holiday and there was a whole hen!
Delicious!
Did you know that we have a name in common?
What?
I'm Pacifica and you're Pacifica.
Pass the bread.
Take bread.
Take.
We will eat together.
You can't stay here.
Why?
Because your relatives will come
And they will take you home.
And what are we going to do?
There's nothing we can do.
- We cut our hair.
- That's not enough.
- Only the monastery will protect you.
- Go to St. Paul's.
- I don't want to.
- They will make servants of us.
This is how they treat those without a dowry.
Just for a few days.
Then we will take you to St. Damian.
You will be with your sisters from the service.
You have to minister,
since you don't have dowries.
The kitchen needs to be taken care of,
Clean it from dirt and dust,
As well as clean the entire house.
We are servants of the Lord,
We have peaceful souls.
Probably.
Put sandals on your feet.
I don't want dirt in my convention.
There was one thing,
that Father Benedict wanted,
and which he was not given the opportunity to receive.
He had a sister named Scholastica....
This is a story about Scholastica,
sister of our patron saint
St. Benedict.
- Do you understand Latin?
- Yes.
I was taught by a grammar master.
I am a widow without a dowry,
I came here with my sister.
We are servants, but nobles.
- I even have an adult son.
- Do you?
But he left me.
He is traveling the world.
Sister Bentevenga fell asleep.
Francis should teach
In our language,
bring the Bible closer to those unfamiliar with Latin.
Francis is right.
But the Bible must not be translated
into our language. That would be a sin.
Listen to how beautiful it is.
Benedict visits Scholastica.
She asks him to stay the night,
because she doesn't want to be alone,
But Benedict can't.
She must return to the convent.
Scholastica cries.
She cries so much,
That her tears cause torrential rain.
And Benedict and his confreres
are not allowed to go outside.
Divine goodness.
...raised her head from the table
And a thunderstorm broke loose,
Accompanied by heavy rain.
And the saintly Benedict
and the confreres who are with him
They could not even foot
step outside...
Klara!
Get out!
Favarone's daughter!
Get out, woman!
Come out and show them your head.
They can't do anything to you.
Favarone's daughter!
Woman of shamelessness!
You have to go home,
Under the authority of his father.
Your hair?
- What did you do?
- I cut them down.
Now what?
Would you like to be on duty with these nuns?
Why?
No, father.
I want to be with Francis and his brothers.
I want to live in poverty.
And when they look at me
This they look at and say
That I am too bold
However, I cannot tear my eyes away
and stop staring
Because when you look at me,
I'm already waiting to be with you
So that you believe in me and love me wholeheartedly
But I see someone else
May the fires of hell consume him
Because I think to myself,
That he is jealous of me
But I don't want to be sad
He must not look at me
He is wasting his time and I will get away from him
You are pulling the thread....
you press the pedal...
And then the shy...
- And it's falling down.
- Can we too?
- Yes.
- Cristina, start, I'll watch.
- I rewind the thread.
- Yes.
And I'm dragging...
- Did you find them?
- We can keep them.
Take a look at these.
Small.
They are big and small. For every foot.
Elijah...
Footwear.
Destroyed, but can be repaired.
We'll try it on.
Our brothers go barefoot.
We will put them on, going to the lepers.
We go barefoot in the monastery.
Francis agrees.
These are nice.
Ms. Klara?
Yes, sister?
Through the love of
Our Lord Jesus Christ
heal my child.
I am not a medic.
He has been in a fever for three days.
Help me, please.
- I think it's better with him.
- Heat is the best medicine.
What will we do when you start healing?
There will be no room for newcomers.
We will open a hospice
For those in need.
- We have enough room to sleep.
- For now.
And how will the new sisters arrive?
Really? Do you think they will be different?
I think so.
For me, the brothers of the forest are like knights.
Those from King Arthur's Round Table.
Now you also have sisters.
Faithful and courageous.
But you have to talk
with the Holy Father, as we did.
Otherwise, it will be difficult.
Yes.
I will write to the Pope.
Come, I'll show you.
- Here will be a vegetable garden?
- Yes.
We will plant garlic, onions, turnips
and other similar plants.
- Onions and turnips are good.
- They are.
Leave room for flowers.
You won't eat flowers.
But they are beautiful.
Agnes, what have you done?
I want to be a nun like you.
- Did anyone see you?
- I came with a servant, but he went home.
Did you tell him to keep quiet?
Don't count on protection,
if your father comes here to get you.
What?
Our father died.
How so?
Was he sick?
Didn't you know?
Now Monaldo's uncle...
Monaldo's uncle forcibly
wants to marry me to Mr. Alfredo,
Ignazia's father. He is a widower.
But Mr. Alfredo is 70 years old!
Agnes?
Did our father suffer a lot?
Yes.
And he kept asking about you.
Until the last minute.
Uncle!
- Let go!
- Let go of my sister!
Don't hurt her!
Let her go!
Your father was too good.
I would have killed you!
It hurts!
Let go!
Francis!
- No, let me go!
- Let her go!
And what to put her on a horse!
Heavy as lead. Not to be moved.
Satanic demon!
- I will kill, not leave here!
- No!
On the horses!
Let's go!
What happened?
You saw for yourself.
You have seen.
How did you do it?
Klara...
I admit that I am amazed.
Never before has the Holy Father been asked
to grant the female order
the privilege of poverty.
But so be it,
In the name of God Almighty.
Thus.
KNOWLEDGE...
That the hand of the heavenly bridegroom
rests under your head.
He who feeds the birds in the sky
And clothes the lilies of the field,
will not spare you
Neither food nor clothing.
And also in eternal life
will provide you with the same.
So how did you bring ...
proposal
to maintain strict poverty
We support with apostolic grace.
So that no one forces you to own
any property.
"When the eighth day came
And it was necessary to circumcise Him,
He was given the name Jesus...
With which the angel called them,
Before it was conceived in the womb."
Let the words of the gospel
take away our sins.
After eight days had passed
Jesus was circumcised.
Think that today Jesus Christ begins to
shed his holy blood for us.
One who has never committed sin,
and even was the enemy of sin
and overcame all sin....
begins today
suffering for our sins.
So cry with him.
With compassion.
Because he was crying uproariously today.
On this festive day
we should rejoice
of our salvation.
But we should also show compassion
Jesus Christ's suffering.
His body so noble and delicate....
Was cut by His mother.
The baby Jesus cried.
And His mother also wept,
Mary the ever Virgin.
She certainly cried!
When my Tommaso died,
I was heartbroken.
Mother and son are one body.
She cried, and as the boy
was resting on her bosom,
is when he saw her crying,
he put his hand over her mouth....
And begged her by gesturing....
So that she doesn't cry.
They say that Brother Francis
stayed with the great sultan.
They talked a lot.
The Sultan listened attentively to his teachings.
Great.
The Lord told us to preach to all
salvation and poverty.
We want to go there, too.
- Along with my brothers.
- I will go with you.
- We will talk when Francis returns.
- For you, the journey is dangerous.
It is necessary to know their languages and Latin.
It's true.
If people do not understand
The preached Word,
They will take you for heretics.
I know Latin and some folk languages.
It's time for a meal.
I return to my duties.
Pacific, when you go
collect alms, look for oil.
I will put the empty jug there, on the bench.
Be that as it may.
- Have you eaten?
- Some bread.
It's too dangerous.
- What's that cough, Balvino?
- Nothing like that, don't worry.
- We listened to beautiful words today.
- They are.
The joys and sorrows of our Lord
Associated with His birth.
As he lay in the manger,
He had a stone under his head.
I saw this stone in Bethlehem.
You really made a pilgrimage
To Bethlehem?
Yes, with my nanny I joined a monastery.
I would go there, too.
First to Morocco, where they martyred
our brothers. Then to Bethlehem.
Balvino,
didn't you meet wolves in Bethlehem?
Wolves?
The moon was full, we were asleep,
when we heard a howl.
One woman stood up,
because her child had to go to the need.
We had a stick to scare away the wolves.
With your bare hands you can't.
Wolves inspire fear.
- And they ran away?
- Yes, we scared them away.
Wolves are like dogs. They are afraid of the stick.
Today you are not fasting, Klara,
For you are wearing yourself out.
Francis already told you that.
If you don't eat
Mondays, Wednesdays and Fridays,
then chew some bread
and sip a little water.
I eat some bread.
Don't worry about me.
Give some flour.
Who filled the jug?
Nobody. I was just about to take it.
- Did you fill it?
- How?
The jug was not full, but empty.
Pacifica found a full jug.
Did you put it there?
It is full.
Right.
Well!
You've never eaten like this.
It is a gift from God.
Every meal is a gift from God.
Francis says.
Our Francis likes to eat!
I wonder what he eats in the East.
There they eat porridge
with almond milk and cinnamon.
For eating pork
Is threatened with cursing.
How can they live without pork?
- And what do they eat in Morocco?
- They eat bread. Like we do.
But this bread is like a sponge.
They pack inside
meat, herbs, pour oil.
Spongy bread?
Mother of God! My stomach swells from that!
Hello, Klara.
The Holy Father greets you.
- Much is being said about you in Rome.
- God be thanked.
And glory to Him forever.
A woman cannot live in poverty.
The Holy Father has given his consent,
But it cannot last.
The sisters live off the property.
They can't travel like brothers.
But we have an agreement.
Together we live in poverty.
But if you don't own anything,
you don't have protection either.
As a prioress
you must protect your sisters.
You call me a prioress
according to the rule of Benedict.
But we are not Benedictines.
I am the sister of my sisters.
We live and hike together.
Only servants can leave the cloister,
nuns cannot.
- You go all out.
- None of us is a servant.
There are no servants here.
We go all out, if necessary.
To carry the tablecloths to the altar.
To comfort the souls and bodies of the sick.
To work and ask for alms.
We go out to set an example for everyone,
How to live according to the gospel.
- Like Francis' brothers.
- But you are not brothers.
You are women.
No woman can be an example.
We are children of God
and angels of His gospel.
The risen Christ
revealed himself first to women.
Yes, but remember Saint Paul,
Who said,
That a woman should remain silent.
And according to the Book of Kohelet....
woman is the cause of sin.
And through the fault of women we all die.
And the Church Fathers?
They say that no apostle allowed
a woman to tower over a man.
Yes, but...
A woman is tempted to sin with her body.
Today, thousands of young women...
wants to create a poor order,
such as yours.
They are women who go barefoot.
And they call themselves "lesser sisters."
They stain the name of the lesser brothers.
And the true vow of poverty
Brother Francis.
You guys won't be able to do what the brothers did.
A woman always
sets an example with modesty
And a monastic cloister.
So I can't travel?
Travel?
And where to?
Dogs! Scoundrels!
Your tongues only pave my heart!
I wanted to live in love,
To serve our Lord, our brothers!
But no!
No!
They want us to wither
like the fig tree from the gospel!
We will not go
Morocco or the Holy Land.
Ugolino said they would imprison us,
will close the doors of the monastery,
if we move.
I think she is blazing a trail of hatred towards us.
May God support us.
They gave us bread and mushrooms
In exchange for tablecloths for the altars.
Light a fire and clean the mushrooms.
Coming.
Fly my song
Ask the nightingale in the forest
Will he greetings from me
This pale fair-haired beauty
Say I love her truly
But I dare not say her name
Klara!
Help!
Pick it up!
Klara?
I'm fine.
Nothing happened.
The door was as light as a coat.
Did I perform another miracle?
The trip to the East taught me a lot.
We are the same people as others.
And being among the disbelievers,
we should not get into disputes.
Because we are Christians.
Brothers of all creation.
God reveals himself in our actions.
And the gospel brings peace to people.
He does not offend anyone.
This is the example we are to set:
Treat everyone as brothers.
But Brother Francis...
example alone...
We will not convert the infidels.
We are not called to convert.
We are witnesses to the Word.
And others can see that.
Cost these sweets.
They come with honey and almonds.
Jacopa de' Settesoli
gave them to us in Rome.
Jacopa is a woman, but she is like a brother.
Elijah?
Who is this Jacopa?
Francis is founding a new order?
Don't.
Leon said that in the Portiuncula
terrible things were happening.
Which ones?
While we were away,
The brothers occupied the brick houses.
When Francis saw this, he went crazy.
He climbed onto the roof and scattered everything.
- Tiles, bricks...
- Well done.
But the houses do not belong to the brothers,
but to the authorities of Assisi.
So we kept them.
Now the brothers are sleeping in them,
even if Francis doesn't let them.
And we should sleep in huts.
It's always been that way.
Help yourself to sweets.
When you guys are away,
there's always something going on.
Even Philip asked the Pope
for protection for us.
- On our behalf!
- Do you want to? - No!
He had no bad intentions.
He did it for you.
We don't need anything.
Ugolino wants to impose a clause,
to protect us.
We don't want to live in confinement.
This is how we are comfortable.
Klara?
Let me tell you a dream.
What kind of dream?
I dreamt that I was a hen....
small and black.
I wanted to hide the chickens under my wings,
But I couldn't.
- Chickens are brothers.
- Who have grown up.
- I can't control them anymore.
- Are they still chickens?
And the Knights of the Round Table
Where are they now?
I cannot torment my own brothers.
- As the mighty do.
- No, Francis.
But you have to defend your work.
- Our work.
- How?
By force?
Should I become a ruler?
I will not be him.
It's not for me.
How's that? Good?
He looks happy.
But he is sick.
His eyes are failing.
If you don't rest,
you will not recover.
How does it feel?
Her throat hurts.
It's better for her to sleep now.
- I dreamt that she regained her speech.
- Another dream!
Scrofula cannot be cured.
You stop talking, then you die.
My dream was beautiful.
It seemed real.
Ms. Klara should not wash my feet.
I just came here.
I am a newcomer.
She always does it.
We wash each other's feet.
But it's a priori.
If Clare hears you...
We are minor sisters.
There is no prioress here.
Yes.
Mrs. Klara ... don't wash my feet.
I walked all day.
They stink, they're dirty....
It's okay now. Be calm.
I don't like between my fingers!
Enough is enough.
Well...
Enough!
God!
Klara!
- Does it hurt?
- Sorry!
- It's not a big deal.
The blood... is still flowing...
It's nothing.
Bull of Pope Honorius III
Regarding the Rule of the Friars Minor.
Chapter Eleven.
I firmly command all brothers,
so that they don't have
suspicious conversations with women
and that they should not enter the homes of nuns.
And that they should not be godfathers of
of men and women.
So that it does not lead to mischief
Among the brethren or in matters pertaining to them.
You! You said,
That you don't want to write down the rule!
That you are God's last madman!
He had to do it that way.
- The first rule was not approved.
- Of course.
And this one?
Who wrote it for you?
- Ugolino himself?
- Klara!
I'm here to talk!
New rule makes no mention of poverty
Nor about revolt against the mighty.
There is nothing left of your
First proposal. Our proposal.
You are angry because I wrote,
That the sisters and we are to live separately.
Separately?
- We started together.
- I couldn't have done otherwise.
You could.
We have a new rule
and thanks to it we are still lasting.
You should write a rule for the sisters.
So that what we have already done,
Has not been in vain.
Write a rule,
Which will be approved by the pope.
Why are you telling me what to do?
Sisters do not have to listen to brothers.
- You said.
- Do what you want to do.
Don't come to St. Damian anymore.
Follow your rule.
Stay away from women.
Everyone.
Are you afraid?
Are we dangerous?
So stay here.
You are no longer welcome with us.
Balvina dies.
Her time has come.
Our prayers were of no avail.
Walk away.
Down!
Pacifica,
boil an egg and bring it here.
Go.
Did she die?
Don't.
Give her water.
When she speaks again,
bring her to me.
Go...
tell Clara that I am healthy.
She recovered.
Balvina has recovered.
Francis wrote a new rule.
It has been approved.
And what's in it?
Brothers should not approach women.
They are not allowed to walk
the same roads.
Neither eat together.
Brothers are not allowed to take
From women vows of obedience.
And Francis did that with us.
We vowed to obey him.
Now what?
We were left alone.
But we are together.
Let us sing together with joy
With a loud voice, let us sing with joy
Let's sing joyful hallelujahs loudly
With a heart devoted to God
let us sing alleluia
Ms. Klara ...
We are from Spoleto, my son is sick.
What happened?
- Does it hurt?
- Yes.
- How long does it take?
- One week.
Come.
Benvenuta, bring water,
jug and a small tool.
Did you put something up your nose?
It was a stone.
- Dill broth and cloth!
- It's a miracle!
With the sign of the cross on the forehead
Healed my son!
- A miracle!
- Quiet. It's no miracle.
A miracle!
- What kind of miracle?
- A miracle!
Enough! You're stupid!
I just took the stone out of his nose!
When the stench starts to bother you,
cover your nose.
It stinks less in winter than in summer.
If we cover our noses,
these people won't be sorry?
A stink is a stink.
We know it and they know it too.
The mouth must be covered.
Otherwise the plague will attack.
I will bandage you up.
And already.
You are young.
You don't remember these forests.
We used to go there with our mothers
pick wild strawberries....
wild apples.
Then they cut down the trees.
And now there are fields there.
Well cared for... plowed...
I would like to see those forests again.
To her I gave a maiden.
And you want a rooster? Take it.
And do you want a dog or a sheep?
A dog is nice.
A sheep? Then take the sheep.
I made them for little Tommas.
He never parted with one dog.
Then he grew up and didn't play anymore.
Do you want it?
Take.
Don't you want to?
They are afraid of you.
Are they afraid?
Why?
Because you are holy and do miracles.
Is that not true?
Francis...
"Don't take anything on the road.
Neither a staff nor a bag," says our Lord.
And now I'm constantly walking with a stick.
Pacific said,
That you have found a new medic.
- Ugolino sought him out in Rieti.
- In Rieti?
So why did you come here?
You're overextending yourself.
To see your face.
Perhaps for the last time.
And you?
Didn't you want to see all of me?
Do you know what they will do when I die?
They will cut me
And sell the pieces to the churches.
Let's pray together.
Let's recite a psalm praising the
Creator's love.
Now that my eyes can't see,
shows me the beauty of the world.
Let Clare read, because she knows Latin.
- Hallelujah.
Klara!
In our language, because the sisters do not understand.
Praise the Lord from the heavens.
Praise Him on high.
Praise Him, all His angels.
Praise Him, sun and moon.
Praise Him,
All the shining stars.
It's like the smile of the universe,
our earthly paradise.
We should pray in the language of the people.
How we preach.
But it is not allowed to translate the Bible
into our language.
Today we did it, but that's not the way to do it.
That's why I wrote my own prayer.
In our language.
Which we all understand.
Educated and simple people.
Women and children.
Then we will understand,
what we are praying for.
Refuse it.
I'm not done yet.
Writing tires my eyes.
I will work on it at night.
Klara!
Francis is feeling unwell.
He asks you to come.
I'm blind!
Rats!
I am blind...
I'm blind, Klara.
I turned off the light.
Together we are blind.
Don't cry.
I'm not crying.
But you don't cry either.
Sleep.
Sleep, Francis.
Sickness and suffering
Is your way to eternal life.
Supreme, almighty, good Lord,
Yours is the fame, glory and honor,
And all blessings.
Only to You, the Most High, do they befit,
And no man is worthy
To name you.
Praised be, O Lord,
With all thy creations,
First of all, with brother sun,
Which the day creates,
And you shine through them.
And it is beautiful and radiant
In great splendor.
Yours, the Most High,
is the image.
Praised be, Lord,
By brother moon and stars.
Thou hast formed them in heaven
bright, precious and beautiful,
Praised be, Lord,
By brother wind and air,
And cloudy and cheerful time, and all kinds of time,
and through which
you give creatures sustenance.
Praised be, Lord,
By sister water.
What useful is great, and humble,
And precious, and pure.
Praised be, O Lord, by the brother fire
With which you light the night.
And he is beautiful and joyful,
And strong, and powerful.
Praised be, O Lord,
By our sister mother earth,
Which nourishes and hides us.
And it bears various fruits
With colorful flowers and herbs.
Praised be, O Lord, by those,
Who forgive for the sake of your love
And endure weakness and affliction.
Blessed are,
Who persevere in peace,
For through You, Most High,
they shall be crowned.
Praised be, Lord,
Through our sister, bodily death,
Which no man alive
can't outrun.
Woe to those who will die
In mortal sins.
Blessed are,
Who find themselves in Your will,
For the second death
evil shall not do unto them.
Praise and bless the Lord
And do thanks to Him,
And serve Him with great humility.
Won't you say goodbye to me!
I just wanted to be with people.
I didn't want to scare them.
I didn't want them to call me a saint.
Human affairs are difficult for us.
But you are strong.
Stronger than your brother Francis.
We go to the village.
Maybe we can find flour.
Your food,
Balvino sister, is good.
- Did you guys do it?
- Yes, Your Holiness.
This is the duty of a servant of our Lord.
These dishes are delicious and flavorful.
Worthy not of a servant, but of a lady.
I want to write our rule.
- There are no rules written by women.
- Ours will be the first.
We will only approve the cloister rule.
You know it, Klara.
Just a clause.
Yes, Clause.
But according to our rule.
Some sisters
work outside the convent.
And we must preserve the privilege of poverty.
Now I am the Pope.
I can free you from the vow of poverty.
Holy Father, I do not desire at all
exemption from this vow.
So did my sisters.
Just watch!
You are leading into temptation
The poor sinner.
You were not such a generous hostess....
When I was a cardinal.
With our rule, we do not want
have a vicar and superiors.
We are lesser sisters.
Like brothers. Those of Francis.
Brothers...
Francis has been dead for two years.
And everything has changed.
Your Holiness...
With holy patience and wisdom
anything can be done.
Are you not eating, Ms. Klara?
You know that in the world...
many conventions are emerging,
Where sisters live like you?
Even in Bohemia, the emperor's daughter...
Yes, I exchange letters
With Agnes Czech.
Holy patience!
Klara...
Be temperate in your judgment of
of these important women.
For the sake of yourself and your sisters.
Write.
And I'll look at your rule.
Balvino.
What do we have to eat?
Almost nothing.
Just a bit of bread.
Let's cut the bread.
There are 50 of us, into 50 pieces.
Not enough.
Slice. Enough.
KLARA
Polish version commissioned by HBO
HIVENTY POLAND
"Song of the Sun" by St. Francis
translated by Leopold Staff
Text: Grzegorz Janiak