There was a time
when some gutter folk
would give you shit.
Think he's a big man,.
Then he gets this funny little half smile
when you shove a gun in his mouth
and tell him, "That's funny,
let's hear another one."
It got his attention and everything else
he's got around your finger.
And you don't hear shit no
more when you come collecting.
I don't hold a gun no more.
Not like that.
Yo!
I pack and I wax my Tommy,
but it don't get no use.
It's not the same.
A used gun and something there to remind
you of what's gone.
I felt this city's winter
on my knuckles for 65 years.
Makes you wonder what else is out there.
- Just a minute!
Hang on!
- You're here for your tribute I presume?
- Did you talk to the guy?
- He thought I was a
different Lou or something,
I don't know.
It's been 15 years,
I didn't know he retired.
Bad heart.
He gave me his sons card.
He said he'll take care of it.
They're not gonna suspend your license,
but they're not gonna give it back to you
until you see a judge.
- What am I supposed to do until then?
- Why don't you try slowing down?
- What, like I'm out enjoying myself?
I can't depend on the boss and cabs.
It's just not the best month.
Joey's not paying for shit.
I'm working nights, I
don't know what to do.
- How much I owe ya for the food?
I need a grand.
- You and me both sweetheart.
So how's Michael?
- A handful.
Can't find anyone to
watch him after school
since I started this second shift.
Ma's in Florida.
Latchkey kids are good for nothing.
- So why don't you ask me?
- You want me to ask you?
- I don't know, why don't you ask me?
- I don't know.
Wednesday, a couple of
hours in the afternoon?
You all right with that?
- Yeah, I'm all right with that.
Aren't you gonna stay for the turkey?
I wish, I can't.
- Okay.
- Thanks for calling the guy.
- Okay honey.
Bye.
- See you Wednesday.
- Okay.
My little girl.
She spends all my money then breaks my
freaking balls for not having any.
She's divorced to some jack-off
two-bit half a wiseguy out of Cicero.
I wonder about those clowns
from the Cicero crew.
Yeah, but she talks to me again.
You get two families in this line of work.
Before too long, your family
become your other family.
And then your other
family becomes your life.
And then, it's not even yours anymore.
- Hey.
How's war counselor?
How's everything on the outside today?
Mild with
a cold front on the way.
- Good.
This is for the Chinese
- Yes and no Mr. D'Agnostino.
The city's rather vocal
clean sweep initiative
is in full swing now
and plus the indictments
handed out tomorrow.
These are federal regarding tax fraud and
one's going to your
friend in construction.
The labor leader.
Concerned about the thing from '91.
- We took care of that in '91.
- If the feds can procure testimony,
it'll make their racketeering case and
there's way of knowing
what our friend might say.
With him as a turncoat witness,
you could be looking at 25.
- 20...
25?
Do I look like I got 25 in me?
- You can still sign on the dotted line.
Keep it in the single
digits and end this now.
A plea bargain is still an option...
- You know how many fucking
times I gotta tell you?
I don't cut no fucking deals.
I stand trial, like my old man.
Have you had a good meal recently?
'Cause here's what I recommend.
You go to our club and you
talk to our friend there,
let him know we spoke.
You make sure he realizes
every little thing
is gonna be taken care of.
What, do you think I'm gonna sit here now?
I'm gonna agree to stand trial?
I see before me here the table's clear.
I'll never sign.
- I understand.
- And Angelo,
every fucking one of 'em.
Stefano's gone inside.
Used to be it was blood or
number two got the bump up.
Now it's the big talk and bigger ideas.
No respect or history, no nothing.
There was a time it
was me, Sammy, Stefano,
and Frankie knocking over
the collection plate.
Now, Sammy's number two
and I'm eating his shit every fucking day.
Look who decided to show up.
- Nothing I could do.
Construction.
Bumper to bumper for two freaking hours.
- Only two seasons in this fucking city,
winter and construction.
- If there are any issues,
now would be the time Mr. Galante.
- One guy, sure.
But three all-stars for 80 large,
I mean, come on, you're giving
me gangbanger prices here.
And believe me when I tell you my friend,
this ain't a job for no
fucking Mullen Johns.
- I trust 80,000 and
Stefano's graces will suffice?
- Understood.
I just don't have anyone working
these prices right now.
- We hear anything from Cicero yet?
- I tell you anything from Cicero yet?
When I know, you'll know.
- Somebody's gotta straighten him out.
This is family shit
we're talking about here.
Fuck the politics.
Who's Lorenzo looking out for anyway?
- I'm only gonna tell you this once,
watch your fucking mouth
You wanna talk shit, be smart about it.
Now don't make me bring this up again.
Bunch of nagging fucks.
No wonder all you
Marazano's are divorced?
- Guys, let's go.
All right.
Listen up here, all of ya.
Big month guys.
We got ourselves a contract
bigger than Asian cock.
We're all gonna have to
suck it just a little bit.
Old man goes on trial soon,
you can bet he's gonna want a clean house,
let's keep him very very happy, okay?
All right, now get the fuck out of here.
Let me count my money.
You got it boss.
- Enz, you got a minute?
- Sure, why not?
- That work you were talking
about with our friend?
- You think you wanna give it to me?
I got some shit I gotta take care of,
I could use the extra cash.
- Lou,
this here's a younger man's job
and it don't pay shit.
Besides, you ain't done a hit since 1986.
It's just not smart.
Don't worry, I'll find ya something.
I think we're done here.
Most of these punks
don't know their history.
Not Enzo.
Can't forget the shit we
used to put him through.
Big man, still bitter after 10s of years.
Wanna get in?
You wanna get your cut?
You get put through the
wringer every fucking day
until you accept that's the system
it used to be and it worked.
- Frankies getting out again.
I guess it's gonna be a party
- Frank Salerno's had
more welcome back parties
than fucking birthdays.
Don't let it bother you Lou.
You don't want it.
- Why not somebody a little more seasoned?
I don't even mean me.
If Stefano were giving out the interest...
- But he ain't.
Everything changes Lou.
And fuck you for thinking otherwise.
When the old man starts
giving out the good stuff,
Lorenzo knows where to send it
- Lorenzo eats alone.
- We're closed pal.
Yeah?
Well if you wanna be open tomorrow,
I think we should talk.
It's a very dangerous
neighborhood you know?
We all gotta look out for each other.
Insurance.
In case anything should
ever happen, you know?
- You're not gonna squeeze me.
And your gramps, he ain't scary anymore.
- You don't pay your street
tax, you get fucked up.
You hear me guy?
- Yeah.
Tiger cage, three o'clock sharp.
- Is there a problem?
- Look at that one there.
- What's the deal Sammy?
I got this shit on my TV.
- Lorenzo's giving you the bit.
- Yeah?
- It's yours.
But I gotta ask, why you
wanna do this all the sudden?
- I don't know, I just,
I figured I'd get away.
Start up somewhere new.
Maybe Vegas.
- Vegas?
It's fucking like 120
degrees in the summer there.
- But it's dry heat.
- Yeah, so is a fucking oven
but I don't see you climbing inside one.
- Thought you old-timers
retire to Florida?
- Fuck Florida.
- Here.
The old man wants 'em done one at a time.
First one's by Wednesday.
Enzo wants you to send 'em on vacation.
Some place warm.
You ready to get your hands dirty?
- Never clean in the first place.
I don't have any delusions of status.
Things go wrong, hey, you cheated.
I take the fall, I go away.
I stay forgotten.
I need a fucking drink.
I need the money.
- Hello, you guys ready?
- Yeah, she'll take the filet.
Miss?
- Yeah.
Yeah I'm sorry.
Could you repeat that please?
- Seen here, a local 397 representative
and suspected Chicago
Outfit member Joe Barbone
was brought in for questioning on
federal charges of income tax evasion
and misuse of union pension funds
back through the early 90s.
- I just wanna get this
confusion cleaned up
so that I can get back to work
as Labor Leader for
Chicago's union workers.
As follows,
the District Attorney's...
- Hey.
- Still need?
- I've been called worse.
- Got a light?
- Not since 98.
- That's pretty committed.
- I still get shaky from time to time.
- Need a new wick or
you just out of fluid?
- You're still a ball buster Lorraine.
Gotta ease up.
- What brings you around Lou?
Down on your luck a little?
Thought maybe you'd come by at close,
take me home with you?
- What are you doing Wednesday
night at eight o'clock?
- You're looking at it.
What do you have planned?
- Still working on it.
You still over there near
the side of the river?
- Yup.
- How's parking over there?
Am I gonna have a problem finding a spot?
- Things really don't change, do they?
You know,
I read the person you are at 30,
is the person you are for
the rest of your life.
- You didn't know me at 30.
- I could imagine.
- Hey, what are you doing?
What are you doing?
Get down.
Come on.
That's dangerous.
- I just wanna hold it.
Does that look like something
your mother would let you hold?
She's gonna be here soon.
15 minutes ago.
- She's always late.
I hate her.
- Michael, don't ever let me hear you
disrespect your mother again.
You understand me?
Otherwise, you're gonna get a slap
like you never had before.
Now just sit down and be a good boy.
You know what this is?
This is a Chicago Typewriter.
The whole city was written down
with this thing right here.
This is respect.
- Can I hold it?
- You think you can lift it?
Okay, you can lift it.
- Does it work?
- No, it's an antique.
- What, do you think you're dangerous now?
Not a fucking word about this.
Go ahead.
You forgot where I lived.
- Red line's a disaster.
- Okay pal.
Let's see ya.
Be good.
- Thanks again Lou.
- Bye Annie.
Be careful.
- Okay.
They can't stop
the flood of memories
when it starts to rain.
You either fight to get dry
or you let it pour all over you.
You let your hands idle enough
and you start to notice how much
blood's built up over the years.
And nothing's gonna wash
them off but a fresh start.
- Next thing I knew,
I put you all over the south side,
pulling that crackers
tooth out of my glove.
That's a good one Eddie.
What happened to him, I forget?
- Who gives a fuck what happened to him?
I'm staring at a ghost here.
- You miss me?
- New plates, new paint.
You'll be driving good
in this for a while.
- I need a piece too.
Nothing that's gonna jam.
What?
- I'm not worrying
about the piece jamming.
Man, what are you thinking?
Crazy and stupid's a
young punks line of work.
You trying to get back a
piece of the glory days Lou?
Well, you may as well forget about it
'cause believe me, the
glory days are over.
- I got two grand here,
you want it or you don't?
It's all right?
- Yeah, it's all right.
Give me a hand here.
This fat fuck weighs a ton.
Flush his ashes down the toilet.
- I give him first taste of hell.
The beauty of Chinatown,
body never found.
Secrets never heard.
And that's how I know the
evening went off without a hitch.
So it's back to the
day I wasn't there for,
and the piece of pavement
outside Lorraine's apartment
that I call an alibi.
I should start appreciating her more.
Maybe some flowers.
- Can't see shit.
Rough morning hey?
- You start with me this early,
you're gonna see a rough
morning you wouldn't believe.
What are we looking at?
- We got another one of these guys.
Crime lab's here, body has been removed.
As far as I know, this alley is clean.
- We got a nine millimeter
slug in the wall over here.
No splatter.
Based on the trajectory,
I'd place the shooter
at 5'8, 5'9.
Looks like the victim was urinating.
We're getting the dirt below checked out.
Don't step in it Ralph.
Shooter fires again.
Judging from the splatter, I'd say that it
was a jugular shot and I place the victim
height at 5'10, six foot.
Shooter drags the victim out
of the alley, into the street.
We got a male boot print
size 10 over there.
Then puts him in the trunk and backs out.
We have tire tracks and the blood.
The lab's already on it.
- How long on the blood?
- Without a body to match DNA,
it's only gonna tell us who it's not.
Either way it's gonna take a better part
of a week for analysis.
- So the shooter hits
him on the second ya?
Maybe we got a witness out there.
- Have Streets and Sand come through
and clean all this up when you're
done playing crime scene.
So how'd our date go?
- It was all right.
You were late.
The roast wasn't done yet
but I still gave you shit all night.
Dinner was delicious, you
didn't shut up about it.
We drank wine and we
talked until the morning.
- Sounds nice.
- I thought so.
- Come on, I'm all shaved.
- And what if I'm not?
- I'll grab a beer and I'll wait.
- You are all charm, you know that?
I'd like to see that
quality on a real date.
I don't think I have.
So it would be quite the evening.
- You remember that time...
- Yeah.
- Give me a minute, I'll remember.
- Yeah, but I won't.
And besides, I'm not in the habit
of putting out two nights in a row.
- Really?
You left that part out.
- Well it's not something that works
its way into a conversation.
Especially the way we did it.
Now go to your boys.
- Good morning ma'am.
Is there a Dolores M.
Russo that lives here?
- Who the fuck wants to know?
- We recovered a black Lexus
at a crime scene this morning ma'am.
The vehicle was registered
to Dolores Russo...
- What makes you think it's hers?
Come back when you got a warrant
you sons of bitches.
- It's registered to Dolores
Russo at this address.
Now you mind if we come in?
- Joe's got all that
shit in my mothers name.
She's upstairs if you want,
but she doesn't remember much these days.
- When's the last time you saw Joe?
- A few nights ago, why?
- So your husband's been
in the papers lately,
you think of any enemies
Joe might have had.
Anything involving his
recent legal issues?
- Joe doesn't tell me anything.
I knew he must be in some kind of shit.
He sent me flowers, the asshole.
He never sends me flowers.
- I guess the card would
be asking too much.
Never sends you flowers?
- No.
He never sends me flowers.
Are we done?
- It's been a pleasure ma'am.
Joey Barbone.
10 will get you 20 we never find him.
Take me up, I could use the money.
Think about it.
He's under federal investigation,
he got it up the ass so hard
- You got a stop sign.
he got a concussion.
- D'Agnostino's facing trial next month.
It's time to clean house.
It's Flower Man shit.
- It's what?
- What year were you born?
60?
- No, 1972.
- I'm not even gonna tell you what
I got in my house older than you.
You never heard of the Flower Man?
- No.
- The late 80s saw lawyers putting
the heat on trash like D'Agnostino.
Weird shit.
Bodies turning up everywhere.
Then there's the Flower Man.
The shit written about this guy.
We knew he was from a 31st street crew.
- So what did you do?
- For about a year, year and a half
we had this string of squeaky
clean gangland murders
tighter than a Korean snatch.
And corresponding
statements from the widows
that day that their husbands
had sent 'em flowers.
Flowers, all of 'em.
One's a coincidence, two's a crisis,
16 is a fucking pandemic.
- So you think he's back now?
Today?
With all due respect Ralph,
it just seems like a
little bit of a stretch.
- I didn't say I thought he was back.
We're looking at a copycat,
intentional or not.
I wanna know who sent those flowers.
Trace that delivery.
- Is that what you did back then?
That work out for you pretty good?
- No.
Hey, look at this guy over here!
- Hey, Frank Frontera.
Salud.
Hey,.
Welcome back my friend.
- I can't believe my eyes.
Look at you.
I was hoping you'd look a little bit more
fucking old or something.
How's life on the outside?
- As long as my young friends
keep buying me drinks,
no complaints.
I'm looking at young
copies of old friends.
When did everybody up
and die and get replaced?
- I don't know.
It's strange.
- Excuse me.
- Lou, to what do I owe the pleasure?
Have a seat.
- I can stand.
We got words.
- We do?
- I'll be quick.
- What's up Lou?
Usually, you need something
disposable for that.
Like a tissue.
Me?
I get Lou Marazano.
- That's pretty fucking funny.
You need to take care of your family.
Always late on your payments.
I'm fucking disgusted with you.
You gotta get out and throw your stick
around for a couple of dogs, fine.
Just remember where your blood is.
He's a good kid, he needs his father.
- You're right.
- That's right.
- Who was your father Lou?
Paint me a picture.
- Hey.
Is this really the night for that?
- Fucking hands off me.
- Lou!
Come over here.
- Now I'm gonna let that go.
- Lou Marazano.
Lou here, he kills this fat union fuck,
now he thinks he can instigate
whenever he wants, with whomever he wants.
So you tell me Lou,
you taking over Cicero now?
- It's not the way it is Enz.
This is strictly family shit.
- Except it's not.
And you need to know that by now.
If things go with Cicero,
it's never strictly
anything with you two again.
And don't you forget it.
Here's to Frank Salerno.
Welcome back my friend.
What the fuck is pension rift?
"His primary known contact
is a man named" what?
Ray Berkowski.
Ray.
Still into late
nights and early mornings?
- What do you say tiger?
Is this for me?
- Half of it.
- I'll take what I can get.
- So I hear you can place Joe Barbone
at the Franklin crime scene.
- We got his Lexus 10 yards away,
a witness in the bar around
the corner puts him there.
His wife hadn't seen him since.
- How much you wanna bet the feds aren't
gonna be very happy?
They're gonna be barking
around here pretty soon.
- We got flowers Harry.
- No Ralph.
- What?
- How old would he have to be?
Don't go jump starting senility.
You've always been a few years
from a blubbering old man.
- What the fuck did I say?
I just said we got flowers.
Hey, this ain't your home no more.
Get out of my ass, you're
worse than my ulcers.
- Yeah, that's me doing that.
What's your gut say?
- It says after 20 years of nothing,
we got flowers.
34 East Shiller.
East Shiller with an S.
- Shiller, delivery, address,
I know you know these words.
- All right.
- Give me that.
Shiller.
- Shiller?
- Yes, Shiller.
What does he look like?
Skinny?
Fat?
Largo?
- A boy.
13,.
- 13, boy, red hood.
I don't know, you know,
maybe it's me Ralph, but 13's a little
young for you and your car.
- You're staying here.
I'll catch back up with you later.
- I don't understand this
lead we're working on here.
- Start by shaking up
every 13-year-old Latino
who goes by that flower shop.
A red hood would be nice.
Our lead is the boy.
Find the boy.
- Hello.
We gotta meet.
I'll pick you up.
- Michael, come say
goodbye to your grandpa!
- I'll see you pal.
Be a good boy.
- Alderman in there's putting wood
to his secretary late nights.
One of Bobby's Russians got family ties
to the cleaning crew.
That's your best bet.
Administration says gotta
be done by Thursday.
Gotta be clean.
How you feeling?
- Having the time of my life.
Why?
- You know, you wanna sit this one out?
Nobody's gonna judge.
- Fixing that up for the kid?
- Fixing it up for myself.
I gotta keep busy.
How ya doing Ralph.
- How are ya brother?
- So when are you gonna cash in
and get yourself a gold watch?
- When my cellphone dies.
Who needs a gold watch these days?
I need something to show for it first.
- Yeah, guys like us weren't
meant for this kind of job.
We should have been firefighters.
You wanna beer?
- Yeah, sure.
Why not?
So tell me about Pension Rift.
- It started back when the
state redid the expressways
with 60 year cement.
It wasn't until '91 union bean counters
finally noticed that million of dollars
got siphoned off the pension funds.
I got called in to stretch Barbone
for some felony assaults that were
linked to the investigation.
I mean, the whole thing was mobbed up.
- You're kidding me?
How'd something like that get tucked away?
- Well, I was only working
on it for a few weeks
before they called me off
and moved up the ranks.
But things were very sloppy.
You know how it is.
Alderman Rossi was suspected
of laundering money
through charity
organizations from his ward.
It's amazing who gets
elected today and who stays.
I strongly suggest you do
what you can while you can.
- Amen to that brother.
This is what
happens when you use people.
They make it too easy.
What I never got was,
I know she was using me too.
But for why and for what?
Really, for what?
- What have you seen?
- 20 suspects an hour.
- And?
- I'm going up to every one of 'em
who walks by that flower shop
and not one red hood.
I mean this is ridiculous.
- In '88, me and Harry staked
out 68th and Blackstone
after a body washed up in the river.
We lived off of peanuts
and pissed in pop bottles,
slept with our eyes open.
Neither one of us left the car for a week.
'Cause we knew that when it went down,
the both of us had to be there.
We knew that doing your fucking job means
doing your fucking job.
I've known Harry since we
were both wearing blue shirts.
He's an honest fucking
cop, among very few.
Better or worse, that
shit don't go unnoticed.
Shut up would ya?
I got a hangover.
- You in the red, police.
Stop!
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Hey, all right.
All right, easy, easy, easy.
Speedy turn around.
You understand these words?
Stop.
Police, it doesn't mean anything to you?
Come on, I'm not gonna find any drugs
or weapons in here am I?
What do we got here?
What's that?
Where'd you
get the cash, Rodrigo?
- My mother.
I was gonna buy shoes.
- Your mother gave you $70 to buy shoes?
Let's go.
I wanna ask her in person.
- Wait, wait, wait, okay.
I did a favor for this
guy, running errands.
- What kind of errands?
- Flowers?
Was it flowers?
Look, somebody died kid.
Somebody sent flowers
to a guy who got killed.
That's a very bad thing
to get wrapped up in.
Now you tell me, and you be very careful
how you answer me.
What did he look like?
- He looked like you.
- Like me?
- Yeah.
You know, old and shit.
All right, let's go.
- Come on.
This way junior.
Fight, fight, fight, fight!
- Hey!
What are you doing?
Come on.
You're not hungry?
- I don't like onions.
- That's a Chicago Dog,
it's like a sandwich.
It's got tomatoes, relish, pickles,
mustard, onions.
And I'm gonna sit right
here until you eat it.
Otherwise, you're gonna
walk yourself home.
Is that such a problem?
You like it?
- No.
I said that too.
My father did the same thing.
He caught me tuning up a couple of kids
when I was your age.
He gave me a smack,
like I'll never forget.
And then we ate dogs, right here.
Not exactly here, but
a place just like this.
He said to me "Lou, you're a Marazano.
"The blood that pumps through your heart,
"that keeps you alive day after day
"is the same blood that built this city."
They tuft it out so I could have it good.
Now you've got it better.
What the hell are you doing
working over a kid like that?
Was it for money?
- No.
He doesn't have any?
- Then what's the point?
- I don't know.
- You don't know.
That's pretty stupid.
I mean, when I was a kid
we did some stupid things,
but never for nothing.
If you get caught, what
do ya got to show for it?
You do this a lot?
- I don't know.
- Listen to me, I don't wanna hear
another I don't know out of your mouth.
Question, answer.
You be straight with people,
they'll be straight with you.
If you don't know your answer,
then that's the trouble.
Your father teach you this stuff?
Finish your dog.
It's gonna be a talk.
It's gonna be a good talk.
It's gonna make a difference.
It's gonna make a family.
This right here's a situation gonna go
one of two ways.
And the first one is the way it's gonna go
because if I think about the
second way it's gonna happen,
I'm gonna really start to like the idea.
You should be
doing more fucking work
instead of fucking with
Johnny the Puerto Rican.
Fucking coconut monkey.
- We gotta have a talk.
- We've been having a few of those lately.
You a whiskey man, ain't you Lou?
Sharon, two old fashions.
She makes a beauty of a drink.
Now listen, I'm fine sitting down,
getting shit right between us.
But, I gotta ask,
you running juice for Angela now?
What about Lorenzo?
How many points she giving ya?
- I'm not fucking around here Joey.
You and Angela are adults,
that's between you two.
I'm here on behalf of Michael.
He's a good kid.
- I know he's a good kid.
He's my fucking son.
- He's been getting in fights,
beating up kids for nothing.
- Like you didn't do
the same thing, come on.
- I had an old man to straighten me out.
He needs his father.
- He has a father.
- You're not fucking listening to me Joey.
You're all yipped up on snow.
- You got a lot of balls saying that.
I mean, who the fuck do you think you are?
Parent of the year?
- This is not about me.
This is about Michael.
- Not anymore it's not.
You fucked that up.
Just like the great fucking job
you did on your daughter.
You ought to be apologizing to me
you geriatric mother fucker.
You know, she's got a hard
on for pieces of shit.
Gee, I wonder where she got that from?
- Sit down.
You interrupted a family conference.
If I have to come back here one more time,
you're fucking dead.
You hear me?
Take care of yours and be
grateful for the privilege.
Try me you fucking jack off!
- Lonely in your office?
Corner view don't make for good company?
- Hey, do me a favor,
don't.
No sense in reopening this case.
Nothing to be gained.
Some bitch got misty,
sent his wife flowers.
- We got a 13-year-old kid
in Pilsen says otherwise.
Really, well that's something.
Yeah, I'll give you that.
Gotta ask though, says otherwise to what?
13-year-old Mexican
punk looky-loo testimony
ain't worth a taco shit and you know it.
- Good thing I got friends
in high places right?
Jesus Ralph, why
don't you just retire?
Who'd of thought?
Most optimistic stewed
potato on the force.
You report to me and that's a courtesy.
Until you get something,
not a word of this spills.
We don't need your bullshit
leaking to the press
or the feds.
I'll humor you under one condition.
- What's that?
- A shower.
Just once, I'm dying to see what happens.
If you start washing down the drain
I'll light a candle.
Freeman.
It's Maloney, how's
your view of the Alderman?
- Occasionally entertaining.
He's got a
campaign event at two.
Tail him.
Yeah.
Our friends got some added heat.
It ain't right.
When's it ever?
- I'm just telling you what I'm seeing.
It ain't up to you
to determine what's right.
You said it was you, so it's you.
This motherfuckers done
the dawn after next.
I'll do the favor of
forgetting this conversation.
Lorraine!
- We have nothing to
say to each other Lou.
- Listen, I'm sorry!
Just give me a chance!
- Yeah, I've given you
20 years of chances.
And now it's become a boring rerun!
- Stuff came up with my son-in-law,
it needed sorting out.
All right?
Just let me come in and explain.
- Yeah, is that what you call it now?
Is that what we do, explaining?
You come over, you fuck
me after you get done
with God knows what terrible thing
you're out there doing?
I get to go over my lines
just in case you get caught!
You are a selfish prick!
- Come on Lorraine,
it wasn't like that last night.
- "It wasn't like that last night."
Right, you know what Lou?
I don't want a commitment.
I just wanted dinner that's not a
figment of my imagination.
Now go fuck yourself!
Lorraine, why don't you stop!
Lorraine!
First time Frankie went away,
was on account of something dumb.
Next time was on account
of something personal.
Keeping everyone around me at a distance
made me a cold son of a bitch.
But it kept me alive.
Tonight, that's exactly
what I'm trying to be.
A cold son of a bitch.
- Here ya go chief.
Lock up when you're done fellas.
Cute little number.
That's our show for the night.
What next chief?
- We wait.
- Police have added union representative
Joseph Barbone to the missing persons list
after his car was found at the scene
of a shooting late last week.
The 600 block of Bert Franklin
was ruled a crime scene
after a bloody trail
and several nine millimeter encasements
were found on the sidewalk
in a nearby alley.
Regarding false testimony in conjunction
with previous indictments.
Fuck.
- Police are asking the
community for any information
leading to the whereabouts of Joe Barbone.
- Mirelli.
It's me, Phil Rossi.
Come on, pick up.
Listen, I'm...
- You all right?
Here we go!
- In progress, 10 block
perimeter on Madison.
Request assistance.
- Excuse me!
You all right?
- No, he's not breathing.
- We got a white male,
possible asphyxiation,
request EMT.
- Tell them to pick up a fucking priest.
Dispatch, homicide suspect.
- Good evening officer.
- I noticed you were limping.
Is there a problem, are you hurt?
- Just a little arthritis,
nothing serious.
I'm out for a walk, it
keeps the joints loose.
- Where ya headed to tonight?
- Headed back to the old lady's place.
Walking keeps my blood flowing.
Helps me keep a hard on.
- Well shit head, you got any ID's on you?
- I got ID back at my old lady's place.
I'm parked out front.
- Well it's your lucky night,
'cause you're gonna get a lift.
Grab the hood.
- What's new Lou?
You ever get that?
I bet you do Lou.
Know any good flower shop in Pilsen?
Is that gold?
A gold watch.
We all get one of them sooner or later.
It's important to know
when it's your time.
I heard you gotta go for a jog
before you get a hard on.
Well that's a sad state
of affairs there pal.
Don't get me wrong, my
prostates like Thunderdome,
think you can't even get a hard on.
That is old my friend.
I mean, no disrespect, but look at you.
Something went wrong.
Let's drop the bullshit.
You're scum.
You have been for half
a century, maybe longer.
That's just sad.
Never made captain.
Never even came close.
- What's your excuse?
- I've been meaning to ask
you something for a long time.
What kind of a man sends flowers
to the widow of a man he's killed?
What kind of a man is that?
- I give up.
I'm not very good at knock knock jokes.
- No, no.
I'm serious.
I mean, at first,
I thought it was just some bullshit
wop respect deal.
You people got a lot of that bullshit.
Then I thought, he's a psycho.
Can't separate himself
from what his mother
told him he was.
And then I thought,
well he's just a faggot.
But now, I just kinda
think he's chicken shit.
Chicken shit in the eyes of God.
Can't face up to his own evil.
You little fucking pussy.
So tell me Lou,
which is it?
Chicken shit, or is he just a faggot?
- I don't know what the
fuck you're talking about!
- I think you do Lou.
Step forward number two.
- If you see him, shout it out.
- None of these are the guy.
- You sure?
Take another look at 'em.
Number one?
Number two?
Are you sure?
- Yeah.
I'm sure.
Step back number two.
- So was Mr.
Marazano with you earlier?
- Yeah.
Came over around six.
- Can ya fill me in on your evening?
- Nothing special.
Watched Jeopardy, the Wheel.
My oven wasn't working so
I made some TV dinners.
He had a fucking fit.
My niece called, that took a while.
He went for a walk and now he's in
a room with indigestion
and I'm sitting here enjoying the pleasure
of your company without my face on.
- I just wanna make sure you realize,
honey you're lying to
me and I'm gonna charge
you as an accessory.
You already know that right?
- You listen to me,
I've been with Lou Marazano for 20 years.
You do not sit there with that smirk
on your face and tell me
that I can be an accessory.
- Can you verify that Lou was with you
last Wednesday evening 10:30 p.m.?
It is a fucking no go.
Stories corroborate.
- What do you mean?
She said he left at 8:25.
Coroners have Rossi dying at what?
8:30.
No way he could've gotten there on time.
- What about last Wednesday?
- Neighbor gave a statement saying
they saw his Caddy parked
out all night long, Ralph.
We gotta let him go.
What's the news counselor?
The cleaning crew
was taken in last night.
- What are you telling me for?
You know what to do.
I understand
the protocol Stefano.
I thought you'd appreciate
consultation on this one.
I'll tell
you what, history or no,
messes are not to be tolerated.
Not now and not ever.
Now you clean it the fuck up!
- You watch your fucking
tone there counselor!
You know, I should have said fuck it!
Let the old fuck rot in jail!
I was just doing a favor!
And don't you forget it!
Lou.
He got pinched last night.
Lou's never ratted out nobody.
I seen him do his time like a man.
- Guys his age can't do time.
They ain't got enough time left.
First he leaves his bad blood in Cicero
and then...
- Wait, wait, wait.
What are you saying Enzo?
It starts with a call,
then it's a drive,
and then it's a friend.
I been on every angle
this situation before.
I've made the call, I've seen the drive,
and I've been the friend.
Every angle but the one I'm in right now.
- How's your weekend?
- A little rough around the edges.
You?
- Is there any other kind?
We don't do things like we used to.
- I don't get invited Sammy.
- Yeah.
Things kinda change Lou.
You started treading water
a little too long there
It was a lot more fun when you were
totally fucking nuts
Remember that shit?
You kind of fell off
after your wife left ya.
You know that?
- Maybe I should talk to someone.
Let it all out.
I could use a smoke Sam.
- Sure thing pal.
Fuck!
God damn it!
Boss, go, go, go, go, go!
- Don't shoot!
- Fucked up my hand pretty good Lou!
I'll be honest!
I'm a little pissed at ya!
- Why don't you go and fuck yourself!
- Listen to me Lou,
you had a nice chance
here and you blew it!
Simple as that!
You wanna do something for your family?
Drop your gun and come out!
The only thing you got to offer them now
is your dead body!
You make a run for it,
and they'll be the ones to pay!
Come on out!
I promise you an open casket!
Lou!
- Fuck that, I'm going to Vegas!
This is the angle of the situation
I know pretty well.
We're like brothers to each other.
Difference is, I never wanted
a brother in the first place.
- Maloney, what's up?
- Forget it pal.
Do you think you're leaving?
It appears so.
So where do we stand?
- It's been a pleasure Elliot.
- All the feds care about is
sending D'Agnostino down state.
They're not even looking, they don't care,
they don't give a shit
about all the people
that Marazano killed!
What about the Pension Rift file?
Last time I checked that was yours.
You started it, so what
are you gonna do about it?
What now?
- Keep it quiet pal.
There's no beating them.
- Maloney's a good cop.
And it can be very frustrating
only being a good cop.
We gotta a revolving door of good cops
between the academy and dives.
You get me?
- Yeah I do, sir,
and that's what I wanted
to talk to you about.
- I apologize.
I got a pretty full plate right now
and I'm headed to a conference.
- Let me take over the case.
Look, Maloney was onto something.
Yeah, it was big and it
needs follow-through.
I mean, a victory like this sir,
is exactly what the department needs.
- Tell me what you got son.
- Pension Rift.
- Not familiar.
- It was this scandal in '91.
Barbone and Rossi were involved.
Some names were blacked
out on a case file.
Maloney thought that's what this
whole thing was about all along.
But we could use some help.
I want this legal,
but I also want it done quickly.
- The eternal struggle son.
This department is covered in red tape.
A good cop respects that.
A great cop respects it too much
not to know what's behind.
You get me?
- What time they gonna be there?
- Is that Sammy?
- Geez Sammy, turn them off.
Fuck.
- Lou!
- Lou.
- Gloves are off Enz.
- You better think this through Lou.
You better think about your daughter,
your grandson
You want them winding
up in Chinatown?
It's a bad life Lou and even worse dead.
You hear me?
- Sammy said the same thing,
only he had a nicer tone.
- I don't do nicer tone.
Put away the gun Lou.
You fucked up pretty bad in Cicero.
And I don't know what the
score is yet right now,
but I'm willing to overlook this thing
if you just put away the fucking gun.
- We got flowers.
Flowers.
Think about that.
What kind of a man almost goes to pieces,
let's everything fall apart
because of flowers?
What kind of man is that?
- Jesus Christ Maloney, you've
been gone, for what, a day?
You look like shit.
- Hey, I took some me time.
- All right, follow me.
We got a four-bagger.
Listen, there was a shootout between the
warehouse district yesterday.
Sammy Delano, a few of
Lorenzo's guys got turned
into Swiss cheese.
- So, this yours?
You got a lead on this?
- Yeah, it's mine.
You got a problem with that?
- No I don't.
- Good.
'Cause you're a liability my friend,
but you're a resource and
I need ya on this one.
I need you to make me look good.
That's a solid fucking
witness you got there.
Sir, excuse me...
- He doesn't speak English.
He doesn't understand English.
- He doesn't speak English?
Not at all.
- Hey.
Grab that thing, submit it as evidence.
- Sir, I need to know
where you got this watch.
Suspects apartment is on the
second floor, number two.
Right there!
I want someone around back
now in case of escape.
You guys better put on some slack,
suspect is considered armed and dangerous.
- All this for a 60-year-old?
- We've got him linked to nine homicides
over the past three days.
- You like those odds?
Room clear!
Clear!
- Jesus.
Search the building, the boiler room,
the fucking janitor's closet!
Someone go door to door
and check each apartment.
I've been
expecting you Mr. Marazano.
- Easy.
- Yes sir.
The problem still remains that
one of three informants
has not been silenced.
The young detective will lead you to him.
Make sure it gets done.
Keep your hands
where I can see them.
- Something you'd like to say?
- Open the door.
- What, you gonna hit me too?
We don't have anything to say!
- Angela, open the door.
I need you to open the door now!
- You make things worse with Joey
and that takes some kind of talent!
He's calling here talking crazy!
No, get that out of here Lou.
- It's clean.
I swear, I earned it.
- Yeah?
How?
- It's an investment for a better life
for you and Michael.
Just please take it and go away, leave.
- I can't just do that.
- What's here for you?
Go see your mother, go anywhere.
You're never gonna get a
chance like this again Angela.
- Am I gonna see you again?
- Yeah, you're gonna see me again baby.
I'll go talk to Michael.
You mind if I sit down?
Why don't you come and sit by me.
How ya doing, okay?
Listen, grandpa's going on vacation.
- How long are you gonna be?
Just a while.
I just thought I'd come and talk to you.
I wanted you to know that
I shouldn't have hit ya
and I'm sorry.
But you shouldn't have told your mother
about me hitting ya or the gun.
- I didn't tell her about the gun.
- Good.
Proud of you.
But I want you to remember something.
To be brave,
to be smart.
And I wanna see the person
that you're gonna be.
And there's no room for I don't knows.
But most of all, don't ever tell
your mother that I let you hold that gun.
Okay?
In fact, don't ever pick up
a gun in your whole life.
You promise me that?
- Promise.
Good.
You be a good boy.
Take care of your mother.
You make me proud okay.
Grandpa loves you pal.
You just be careful.
And you get out of here
as soon as possible.
- Yeah, you too pop.
- You ask yourself, did you
do enough for you and yours?
Bye.
Nah.
Not even close.
- We checked all the public
areas in the building,
we'll have a blue shirt stick around
in case he comes back.
- He wasn't dumb enough to get caught here
in the first place.
He's not coming back.
- Walsh.
It's Harry.
Pension Rift's deeper than you think.
Meet me at the La Salle garage
after everybody clears out.
- Good, I got it.
Be on the lookout.
Suspect drives an '89 Cadillac Fleetwood.
What's he doing here?
- Listen, we got Marazano's watch.
I take the latte on the side.
That is nine murders
that we can link him to.
Why couldn't you just let it go?
- Civil servant, man of the people.
- It's a big picture thing Ralphy,
but we've had some fun.
Let's keep it at that.
Get on the ground!
Stop or I'll shoot!
Drop the gun!
- Looks like I'll make
Captain before you Flower Man.
- What about your partner?
- Drop your piece and turn around.
Nice and slow for me Flower Man.
You shot my partner.
- You sure about that?
- I'm sure you killed 16 in '86
and you're having a pretty
good comeback, killer.
You've had quite the day
here fucking Flower Man.
- Yeah.
How'd you do today?
- I did pretty good.
Brought in a fucking mass murderer.
- I'll believe it when I see it.
You gonna arrest me
or just plead til you drown my boots?
- Maybe I'll just pull the trigger.
How's that!
- You can't see a god damn thing!
- Shut the fuck up jackoff!
Now you answer me.
Which is it?
Chicken shit or faggot?
Chicken shit or faggot!
- You tell me.
I'll miss the rain.
The world smells better during and after.
But especially before,
because you know it's coming.
Better get the fuck out of my way.