WELCOME TO GATLIN
Joshua!
Jack ... This evening you will come to regret.
I'll get you ...!
Eli?
- He is approaching. He is full, right? - He will beat me again.
Not if I can determine.
We run away! I will not leave you!
Boy!
I am the only one who can handle him.
Well, please hurry.
Why, Dad? Why would you do my brother mischief?
The family is holy father. I would never hurt you.
- Not even for it here. - It was you who took it!
Brat...!
Vogt has it here that you watched over me.
Eli, you would jo skynde you.
Where is he? Come, now, we go. He can do what he wants with me ...
- But you he shall not make mischief. - We will stick together. Does not?
The boys placed with you for adoption is in order.
It may take time for them to get used to the new environment.
- The boys have not before ... ... seen the city.
- You're nervous, but I know ... - They're here now.
I'll get them. Conditions you in peace.
- You are lovely. - Thanks.
And you're too young to have a teenage son.
- William and Amanda, your new boys. - Hey, Eli. Josh.
Welcome to Chicago.
DOOMSDAY IS NEAR
We live here.
- Home, lovely home. - Are you ready?
Fine. Slightly larger than our camper. They have many fine things, mrs. Porter.
Now we go up, I'll show you the room.
Children in the house.
This is our room. Need anything, so we just nearby.
Knock before you go in.
Joshua! Put it down again. It is very, very expensive.
- They have a beautiful home, mr. Porter. - Thanks.
It is also your home. You do not say mr. and mrs. Porter.
Josh, you may well not take it up.
Bill, it's just glass.
Come, now we eat.
- New, Japanese invention: Pizza. - Thanks. Sit down.
- Should I help cut it? - Amanda! It takes a while ...
... folds it and puts it in his mouth.
- grace. - Pardon.
Would you say it?
May He who walks behind the rows, protect our crops and provide front
- to the disbelief forever be tormented in hell fire.
Amen.
- It was a hefty grace. - Pizza?
This is your new farm. "Amanda's garden".
- She really green fingers. - Social worker said ...
... that cultivated corn here. - Did she? No, no corn.
Now I know. I sell corn on the stock exchange.
- What's on the other side? - It is an old, disused factory.
But you and Joshua do not play over there.
Where is your brother?
- She can not take it from me. - Malcolm?
And so here he scores points ...!
- Hi! I moved in with a neighbor. - What is this clothing?
- Is that the new Amish fashion? - Why do you cap vice versa?
Joshua?
- Come home now. Came. - Thanks.
It was supposed to be a surprise.
- Do not go to strangers ... - William?
- There were insects in the trunk. - What?
Insects, Amanda?
I would take something from home.
It's fine corn.
- I do not think it feels nice. - We should probably just get used to it.
Calm. It here arranges himself. Eli is a gem, and Joshua ...
... must learn a little more discipline. But you may also.
You do not do anything until we saw the boys again, right?
Quietly.
You have probably slept in the same bed for life. We leave them now.
I've ruined everything. He was angry with me because I ...
... lost glass thing, and afterwards because I was talking with strangers.
- We have in any case apart. - Yes.
Good night.
I offer it here for him, going behind the rows!
David, I deserve the new job. I have two mouths more to feed.
- Is that why you wanted to adopt? - Who got Agritect-order? I...
- It deserves appreciation. - William, you're too impatient.
Relax, enjoy your new family. The market will not disappear.
No, but I do maybe. Remember it.
I must think about it.
The here fits just fine. And what about this? Good color.
I'll get a pair of scissors.
Now...?
Eli, you forgot your suitcase in ...
- I could therefore not like the clothes? - Modest clothing is the best.
It's probably not all children in the school who can afford the kind of clothes.
Why should we make them feel inadequate?
- Where's the principal's office? - At the bottom left.
- Mrs. Porter?
- Amanda Porter.
Father Frank Nolan. I am headmaster here.
- It must be your boys. Joshua? - Close. Eli.
Lovely shirt. I...
I will show you the classroom. This way.
Good morning, class.
Joshua, you'll go over in rum 101. That's my class. And Eli ...
- Room 112. - Will you separate us?
- In going well in different classes. - Father, home ...
- I'm used to being together ... - No!
- Do we go out for a moment? - Of course.
Excuse us. Remove yourselves from them.
Hey!
- I would not put myself there. - Why not?
Because I think you will try to suck my dick.
Have you kolort ears?
- Do you feel this? - Your fool. What do you want to do?
- Want to cut in an Amish-young? -, I can cut you, you whore!
She's my sister. I bitches you if you talk like that to her.
- Move! - What's wrong with you?
Nolan will.
Eli, I'm sorry. In can meet in the intervals.
- Why are you leaving yourself up? - Should not it?
You really are from the country ... Are you waiting for your brother?
What you did this morning was cool, but stupid.
- Put you out with T-Loc. - He should not fall out with Eli.
Do you play well?
- "The Mummy"! Let Amish guy to be with. - Why?
Because I say so!
- No, Malcolm. He can not play. - Let him be with.
- Can you play? - A little.
Little...?
We shake hands when you do something good.
- Beautiful. - Good fit.
I must go.
First you will leave me, and then play with them.
- I chose not to leave you. - We were never separated, you said.
- We should not. - So do not play with them.
I beg you.
The wilderness will rejoice, and the desert will bloom.
He who walks behind the rows, and we all His children ... are selected.
We will bloom on the ground, at home, in klasseværelsernes times ...
... and on the playgrounds. For the unbelievers marks our victory over them.
We are the seeds, and now our time has come to grow.
If the unbelievers goes over us ...
... they will be destroyed.
Bless my upcoming fall.
What the heck...?
What's going on?
My goodness ...!
Hallelujah!
- Why do not you listen for? - I will not argue about little corn.
If you do not cut them away, so I do.
It's his hobby!
This is idiotic. Well.
I look at it tomorrow.
My goodness ...!
Hello?
Boh!
- There frightened I tell you what? - Yes, you did.
- Should you reap? - No, but it might well do.
- Will you taste? - Yes please.
It smells sweet.
- Eli, where does it come here from? - My father. May he rest in peace.
He began to cultivate them, and I helped him.
Those here are the only copies. I train with them from Gatlin ...
... that look, they can grow here. - They grow really.
It's not even season. Earth is terribly bad.
No stains, no pests.
You have grown here in a month.
Do you have any idea what this might be worth?
My father always said, "You reap what you sow."
It smells good.
Goodbye.
Why are your brother never with us?
Excuse me.
Why did you say that?
- Eli, come and sit with us. - You can sit here.
Or would you rather eat with ... that?
"Who" is a friend. It does not hurt to get a little friends.
I will maybe also.
My sermon today is taken from Genesis 37th
Joseph dreamed a dream, and he told it to his brothers.
They hated him for it. They sold their brother as a slave ...
... and said to his father that he was dead.
- Joseph had seen a true vision ... - Joshua? You were right.
... will meet with resistance from the ignorant and evil.
- I need to get me friends. - Eli Porter!
- Bored my sermon you? - Yes, Father.
You might want to come forward and share your thoughts with us?
Thank you, Father.
- Who was Joseph? - Who the hell cares ...?
I do. It should ye do. For he was a child, as we are.
A child with a huge worldview. Joseph loved World-
- who gave us food in our stomachs, a roof over our heads ...
... and gave us sea and air. But he predicted the group-
- that profane Mother Earth. They poison our food ...
... and traps our forest. - Eli?
The plague our air and pollutes our water.
Who was this group?
His brothers. His adult brothers.
Joseph would not let it happen. And you should not either!
Enough is enough!
Enough is enough.
Go into my office. Now!
When you want to ask forgiveness, then I'm in the classroom.
- Could you not like my sermon? - Your words do not interest me.
It is the kind you can take ...!
- You did not tell your brother was a priest. - He gets it from his father, he says.
- Your father, you mean? - Nej. His...
Pardon. He's adopted.
Mrs. Porter, it's Samantha Gordon. I found an article-
- from Gatlinburg, and this concern really Eli. Will you call me?
Hello?
Damn! Here you pay tax to electricity ...
Aw, shucks. Where did it go?
Are you looking for this?
They speak with the Chicago police. Wait here...
... so will the infidels quickly be destroyed.
- Have a good day. - Goodbye.
- Do not I get a kys? - Yeah.
Bye mom.
- Mr. Porter, your wife is on the setter. - I'm in a meeting.
- She says it is important. - Tell her I'm out.
Feel sometime. Almost like substance. It is not at all porous.
The shit ...!
So I suppose I must do it yourself.
Good news. Some of you will be brought up.
Not you, Jenkins. Thee I pulled in for some years.
You did not even know the name of America's longest river.
- Where did it come from? - Charles, you know better than that.
Immune against pests and pesticides. Man cultivates the four uger-
- regardless of how the soil looks.
You hold a fortune in his hands, Charles.
- Why do you want me with this? - Why mix my company into it?
- Ethically, you are bound to ... - To hell with ethics!
William, this is the first time I hear you curse.
There are only two major mountain ranges in the United States ...
For the heck ...!
William!
I need an investor, but there are others that I can go to.
Do I get a meeting with your board?
Pardon...
- Yes, Eli? - Do I drink some water?
Yes go ahead.
Tak, Frank.
- What a tragedy! - Call if you need anything.
Good God.
AUTUMN IS OVER OS
Good morning.
Hello, James.
Hi Jonathan. Danielle.
Gary...
Good morning.
I told Monsignor, that I was glad the English program.
... and let them burn in hell eternal fire.
These deceivers and traitors, they know who they are ...
Excuse me.
Eli up leads it on and a little strange, but I've heard of him ...
- And he says very sensible. - No, Maria.
Stay away from him. You do not know what he is capable.
Josh, what are you talking about? You ... what's wrong?
See it here.
I found it under his bed this morning.
My goodness!
He's your brother, but you should not show it to anyone?
- You can show it to Father Nolan. - No.
Why not?
- Because we are brothers. - He's adopted.
Eli and I have gone through a lot. We have always looked at each other.
You feel safe with Malcolm, right?
And with me?
- What is it? - I've never done this before.
It's straightforward.
First base.
Second base.
- How to make a homerun? - You do not.
Malcolm, Maria and I are just friends.
She's my sister. Understood? Let me put it like this ...
She should not interfere with a family like yours.
- Especially not your crazy brother. - Eli? How regards this him?
Do not be silly! Look around. Here should be a lot of people.
Let me ask you something. Who do you think they stay with?
With age comes blindness. But we who are young persons
- have a vision of purity. A gift from Him that goes behind the rows.
We must obey Him and rid the world of evil. Our main harvest.
Autumn is here, your clown.
- Halløjsa. - Stop it there bullshit.
I am here to her Dee.
- I can not do without him. - What do you want to do?
- Ecclesiastes me to death. - You can of course try.
Come back, you little shit.
You need to get a decent game beatings.
Where are you, you little fool?
- You are here with me now. - No. You are here ... with me.
Before hell! Now you die ...!
Take it away ... take it away!
Help me!
I can help you. But the question is whether you will help me.
Yes Yes. Take it away ...!
Let us pray.
I saw an angel come down from heaven, with the key ...
... to the bottomless pit and a great chain in his hand.
This ends my sermon on Revelation.
Is there anyone who has questions ?!
Frank, this is just my opinion. The last weeks we have not had-
- smoking in the toilets, fights, drugs, knives. You must realize the facts.
- Finally, we are seeing results. - In terms of what?
Are you blind, Frank?
Noah did not let the world reborn. Had it not been for his children-
- who should fill up all his desires, they had never seen earth decay.
- Hello. - Hi.
- Josh ... I ask forgiveness. - It is not required.
Whatever you are, then you definitely ... not him.
I'm just curious, but what happened to his parents?
- He said they disappeared. - Just like your father, right?
They are like weeds and must be removed.
Joshua, you should be in your bed. As late you will not go ...
- Hi. - Hi. You are up late.
- Do you work hard? - I'll make some notes for tomorrow.
Idle hands are the Devil's tools.
It helps me not to think about Amanda.
- Should I talk about my corn in the morning? - Yeah. We can export the ...
... to people throughout the world. - Also for children?
Especially for children.
- Now go to bed. - Good night.
What happened to his parents?
He said they disappeared.
Just like your father, right?
What happened to my father? What did you do to him in Gatlinburg?
I made sure that he could never hurt you.
Face it, brother! I'm the only family you have.
Enough is enough!
I agree with that.
Letter to Amanda Porter.
- She's not here. - Will you sign for her?
So.
Malcolm! Wake up.
- What the hell is that? - Let me in.
Josh, if it is not any good murder thee.
It is not good. Take clothes. Come on!
I need your help now to put an end to the madness ...
... and evil. Do not fail me now.
When I was 14, moved father and I to Gatlinburg. The city was berygtet-
- so it was cheap to buy land. Malcolm, listen for!
Land was cheap. Dad had to spend much of its corn experiments.
And it woke me of?
Lord, give me strength to fight this devil ...
... with a child's face. He haunts my the dream
- and at school I feel his presence everywhere.
Hey, Frank!
1964? No, it can not be him.
Yes, I can recognize his face. Look at this.
Social Office will check on their orphans.
All rednecks know when it is harvest moon. Have you seen one?
- No. - We have such a one to watch in the night.
Now we must go to Father Nolan.
- Who the hell are you? - You know as well, not, Father?
- Why are we going to Nolan? - I think he understands it.
You knew from the beginning who I was. It knew my foster mother too.
Some people know the kind Frank. I do not know why.
To stop you!
Of course, Frank. You might want to try ad.
Sorry.
- Who are you?! - Let us pray.
- Pray to me, Frank. - No ...!
- Pray to me. - No!
Well...
What do you do?!
You will not get away with it here.
- Father? He is not here. - We look after the chapel.
Dear Frank. Thank you lived long enough to-
- to see your work destroyed. Your pupils turned against you.
- I want ... - What? If you want to destroy me?
With this? Your Bible can not do against mine.
- Show it to me, then you should get to see. - Frank, Frank, Frank ...
Do you think I am so stupid that I have it with me?
Why should it be so stupid?
Come ...
Is that where your vulnerability lies?
- I do not have time for this. - That is it...
You can not hide from God!
Fader Nolan!
Father Nolan, are you hurt?
Fader?
Good God!
- Father, what happened? - What the hell is happening?
- Bible ... - What is he saying?
Destroy it.
- What is he talking about ?! - Eli's bible. Back home in Gatlinburg!
Josh?
Hello Maria.
The partnership with Germany is in order. Congratulations.
- We take a drink. - Good idea.
Now we eat dinner.
Your parents are waiting for us.
- This is my home. - That?
Home, lovely home.
I think he laid it at the foot of the scarecrow.
- What Scarecrow? - You go to the right, I left.
Delicious, Eli. It was thoughtful of you to take food with.
- It's my way of saying thank you. - For what?
Maria has not told? Tell, Maria.
- I shall be first. - The first...?
Val, what is it?
A good start.
Do not even thought ...!
Josh, this is green!
You're fired.
Oh God!
Far?
Goddamn...!
Did it? Did you?
Where the hell is the scarecrow? Josh, I slip.
Josh? Nej...!
Do you remember where we put the car? Damn ... the Bible!
I'll get it.
Josh!
Malcolm? What the hell is happening?
This is harvest moon night where the children have to leave their home
- and their worldly property to unite signal
- with Him that goes behind the rows. Tonight we must cleanse the old ...
... cleanse the earth and to harvest clean.
This cross unites you with Him that goes behind the rows.
Thanks for liftet. I'll see you tomorrow.
Eli?
Let us thank Him that goes behind the rows ...
... for the gifts He has bestowed upon us. Let us ask for strength
- to complete his vision to put an end to all the corrupt.
For us children are the country's purity ...
... and the creatures over 19 years ...
Beast!
Time of change has come. For now, the Beast killed ...
... for the rescue paralyzed.
Eli?
Oh ... Dad came home.
- Sheep. - Eli, what are you doing there?
Who are your friends?
- Eli, what does all of this? - Went meeting well?
- Yes, the meeting went ... - Good. You worked hard.
Thanks to you, our seed spread, our churches will grow ...
... and our harvest will be rich. - Yes Yes.
- Dad, now you need to rest. - No, the night is young ...!
Eli...!
Let our harvests begin.
- I knew you would come, brother. - I'm not your brother!
- I have your weakness, your creeps. - Then destroy it.
I must put an end to you and your Bible simultaneously.
- Then come and get me. - If the Bible was so important ...
Why did you leave it so? I have realized that you are like a worm.
To kill one half, then the other live on.
The Bible is your other half, Eli. Now I will crush you completely.
- Give it to me! - Go to hell!
This part of the worm does not like to be harmed, what?
Come on, Eli! Come on, brother. Want your Bible?
I have it here. Come and take it!
Give it to me, brother. Give me the book!
Maria ... He killed Malcolm.
- Now...! - Do you really want it?
Here you go.
Maria?
It's over now.
Help me!
Maria!
No!
We must cut the root of.
- You all right? - Yes.
This is only the beginning. Soon we will sell to the world.