Councilman.
Good morning.
Councilman, the pig dog ass.
What did you call me?
No, what did you call her?
I called her pig dog because
cunt bitch whore takes too long.
Let the record show that 91% of AIDS
babies are black or Latino.
You blocked the health care measures.
What's up with that?
Let the record show people of color
die faster and in disproportionate numbers.
You block treatment to the people.
There's death in the street
and blood on your hands.
We want AIDS hospice and
health to this district now.
We're dying and you're doing nothing.
Call my office...
We want needle exchange for drug users.
We die, you do nothing.
You're deadlier than the virus.
We are black faggots
with a political agenda.
We your worst nightmare.
Who do you think you're talking to?
A murderer!
And we gonna fight you to the death.
♪ Party time ♪
Boo!
Ah!
La la la la la.
Mmm.
Some folks got AIDS and some folks
got Magic Johnson disease.
Folks with Magic Johnson
disease is innocent victims.
Well, I ain't got Magic Johnson disease
and I ain't got Ryan White's disease.
I got AIDS, dammit and I
got it by sucking dick,
getting fucked and
sticking needles in my arm
and the government doesn't give a shit.
I am not innocent.
I was never innocent, but I am strong.
Just picture it.
If I was a weak woman, I'd be
out killing mother fuckers.
No, that's where you're wrong.
This goes far beyond freedom of protest.
This goes far beyond freedom of expression.
This goes far beyond even
simple assault and battery.
This is attempted murder
and while I appreciate
the expressions of sympathy that have been
conveyed by the mayor and
the police commissioner,
I will not be satisfied until these people
are found and brought to justice.
You'll have to excuse
me, we're running late.
Thank you all very much.
Repeating our top story.
Councilman Melvin Freeman
was attacked by faggots
outside his Greenwich
Village home this morning
making it the third attack in as many weeks
by this gang of self-proclaimed
raging, atheist,
meat-eating, HIV positive,
colored terrorists.
So I had him up in the bed
and that juicy Latin
dick was just a swinging.
So I unzipped it and girl,
the meat just fell out.
So when you woke up what happened?
It's true.
Believe it.
I put my teeth marks on him.
Dear, can't you just
spray like the other animals?
Oh, please, just 'cause you never
actually got the knack
of classic dick sucking...
Oh, hooker I will suck a dick 'til the head
caves in and the balls scream mercy.
And you know I'll cut your
heart out to get to some dick.
I know you won't.
You know I will.
I bet you should.
You know I could.
I bet you did.
Oh, please.
Girl, for someone so gorgeous, you sure
don't know how to work it.
You'd look so stunning in girl drag.
I just can't think what
I'd do with you, though.
Max, did you think about what I said?
Said what?
What he say?
You so cute!
Come on, it could work.
He trusts me implicitly.
We could sneak in his office.
We could drug him.
I even bought chloroform.
Wait a minute, you want
us to kidnap a politician?
I want us to kidnap Melvin Freeman.
You're such a rotten child.
When I was giving birth to you,
I should have crossed my legs and inhaled!
Lucy, you know you just wanna get Freeman
so you can work some trade.
like the rest of us.
We're talking about the
real AIDS acquisition files.
Look out, Dan, a flows in a tizzy.
I'm the one who works there.
I'm the one who knows what's going on.
Yes, but you're not the one who knows
what's going on in the real world, Sam.
Let's get real.
Trade, all he wants is trade.
I know this'll work.
I know if you'll only trust me.
No!
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Brava!
No.
That was awful what you just did.
Look, that's all I got to say
on the subject, okay?
Will you just think...
Washroom trade.
Central palm trade.
Prospect for trade.
Washington Square Park trade.
I know this'll...
Grand Central Station trade.
He only trusts me.
The World Trade Center.
bathroom trade.
Honey, to the death, to the death.
Just call it what it is.
It's dick, honey.
Hey!
Hello, sweetheart.
Say hello to your worst
technical nightmare.
I know you missed me.
Wanna take away some more of my rights?
Give me a kiss.
Show me you love me.
Who here is HIV positive?
Come on.
Don't disappoint me.
Well, I've got news for you.
What?
We are all HIV positive.
Tell 'em, girl.
You and you and you and you
and your brothers and your sisters
and your mothers and all your chillens.
AIDS is number one on the charts
as the number one killer of black women.
I am Jamela and HIV positive.
Positively dangerous when
I'm pissed so don't try it.
Move, Silas, I don't want to hear that.
We are going to church this Sunday.
Boy, don't you be talking to me like that.
Don't be rolling your eyes at me like that.
Boy, what is wrong with you?
This is Sunday and every Sunday
I have to go through this.
I don't want to hear it
no more, you hear me?
We are going to church
and I don't wanna know
anything about it.
Larry, hmmm.
We are going to church.
Now, if you wanna come
along, you can go upstairs
and get yourself a tie and come on,
otherwise, keep your cocksucking ass here.
You call yourself a church lady and talking
about cocksuckers, you should be...
Well, that is what they do with it.
You old woman.
Who are you calling old, honey?
You!
Who am I standing in front of?
Honey, I do not wanna hear...
A big old sinner, that's what you are!
You ain't nothing but a sinner.
But you can't even...
You big sissy, you.
You can call me whatever you want to.
Big old sinner.
Sinner, sinner, sinner,
that's what you are.
The biggest sinner in Harlem.
I will see you Thanksgiving.
Fine, I'll bring the turkey.
Step up.
Maybe we should carry him.
Another step, step up high, higher.
Yeah, it's kinda rocky, be careful now.
Keep walking forward, forward.
Step up.
But you did beat us, Dada.
It's...
No, sir.
Yes, you did.
I remember very well.
Poor little Max.
I must have been what, about nine years old
and you used to chase me 'round and 'round
the kitchen table beating
me with the frozen dinners.
Dinners, that's right.
You used to chase me up
that tree in the back yard.
I used to have to wait there for hours
for you to cool off Dada.
Don't you remember that?
No, sir, I don't remember that.
Of course you don't remember that.
Three dresses, one for the kitchen,
one for church and one for bed.
That's all Mama could have.
Now how could a woman
live in three dresses?
Not so.
Could you live...
Oh, yes it was so, Dada.
How could a woman live
in three dresses her whole,
and you were making so much money, Dada.
Hand over fist.
Really, me and Jamela saw your paystubs
on the bureau.
Jamela, Jamela, where is your baby?
Don't bring the baby to see me.
I thought I told you.
She's staying with Aunt Flo.
With Aunt Flo?
Yeah, she's been there...
You don't love your baby.
Of course I love my baby.
I just had some things to take care of.
I had some things to attend to.
There's nothing more important for a mother
to attend to than to suckle her child...
Shut, up let me handle this.
You don't know what is more important
for a mother to do for her baby.
I had to leave her with Aunt Flo because
it was the best thing for her.
She is healthy.
She is well-loved.
And I care about her.
Day when there would be war over baby.
A little child shall lead them.
There you go off again, please.
I'm going to pray for you.
I'm going to pray that God
will show you the way...
Yeah, well...
And I will pray for you too, Maxwell
so that when you have your children,
God will show you the
right way not to leave
your children with other people
and not to take care of them...
Oh Lord, I pray and I pray that I'm so glad
my children are healthy and good...
Dada, Dada, Dada, Dada, Dada.
I think that's enough praying.
In a related story, 23 gay and lesbian
activists were arrested
during a city hall sit-in
accusing the government
of secretly compiling
comprehensive lists of
all HIV positive people
in the Tri-State area.
Councilman Hardigan denied the existence
of the so-called AIDS acquisition files
and criticized public
demonstrations as anti-American.
Hello, Mr. Mayor.
Good to hear from you.
Just let me kiss you.
I want to kiss you.
Yeah, Paul.
Great, send him in.
Hey, Mel.
How was Maine?
Oh, Maine is Maine.
How the hell are you?
I hear the faggots been
knocking the hell out of you.
Let me see your noggin'.
It's just a scratch, really.
I'm gonna milk it for all it's worth.
I'm gonna show these
little pieces of dog shit
they don't know who they're fucking with
when they're fucking with me.
I'll break their fucking legs.
These little faggots are really getting
way out of control, you know.
Thank you, Sam.
Something has to be done about it.
I want you to know I saw
Hardigan the other day.
Ho, ho, ho, let me tell ya.
He looks terrible.
He was right out in the
street when they got him.
Bam, bam.
Yeah, but fucking Hardigan deserves that.
You got a point, there.
Listen, if we're gonna
get this bill through,
we've got to take care...
Thank you, Sam.
Women's coalition.
I have a few ideas about what
to do about the coalition,
however, I need your help.
I'm your man.
Spare any change?
Can you spare any change, a dollar?
Spent 27% of New York City's hospital AIDS.
No money, no beds, no staff, no treatment.
You shit.
Oh, you'll go to hell, that's right.
I'm a black faggot, that's right,
a fat, black faggot who's
gonna kick your fucking ass.
Come on, come on with it.
I'm gonna kick your fucking ass right now.
You come on, come on.
Get the fuck out of our neighborhood.
Oh, you think that shit was scary?
I'm Larvetta Larvon Lavicomtess Delarva.
Mortals may address me as Larva
and I'm the only infected
person in the history of AIDS
who hasn't lost weight.
You better be scared.
Oh hi.
Hey.
What?
Look at you.
Call me.
It's a little early for that, Max.
Oh come on, but it makes me feel better.
Well, you look great.
Thank you.
You see what he does to me?
Great.
Max, you gotta take better
care of yourself, Max.
Max, you take better care of yourself, oh!
Can you be serious for one minute, Max?
Max.
What?
What's this money for?
Oh, for my jewelries.
Jewelries, no.
Yes, no, 'cause I have no stones.
Max.
Okay, no.
We gotta get more vodka.
No, no, no, Max.
Okay, okay, okay.
It's for rent and utilities.
Rent and utilities, that's right.
Now promise.
I promise, I swear...
I'll give it to Jamela next time.
I swear to Goddesses
I will pay it tomorrow.
Okay.
Ow.
See? See?
You do feel bad.
What can I do?
Kiss me.
Kiss you?
Mmm hmm.
Is that better?
No.
No?
Now?
Now.
Girl.
You still got it.
I don't know where you put it,
but you still got it.
Saw this woman today.
She was laying on the street
bleeding from her mouth.
I wanted to help her.
She wouldn't let me.
I know she didn't try.
I gave him the money.
She didn't try.
'Cause I'm fab.
Go, girl.
Oh Jesus Christ.
Why don't you go somewhere else with that?
You're making me sick already!
Hey, hey, hey, hey!
Kiss my ass!
What's the matter, Miss Dumb Pussy?
That trifling husband of yours
ain't slamming you right, lately?
Oh, yeah?
And well maybe if you
kept your head on his dick
instead of outta that window you wouldn't
be so worried about
what's going on up here!
What do you know about my husband?
Here's a battery.
Go get that vibrator of yours and stick it
in your stale pussy and rotate
the fuck out of my business!
Oh, yeah?
Well, fuck you!
Oh, Miss Thing.
Oh, you oughta read
Dear Abby, she's fierce.
I mean Erma Bombeck.
This mother fucker gets back.
I'll be out in a minute, y'all.
I'm just using the.
Come on outta there now, child please.
Yeah, that's right.
your ass.
Yes!
my ass.
New York City remains both fascinated
and outraged by the bizarre gay terrorists
who are ultimately
described by their victims
as ugly black women,
overdressed homos or freaks.
This morning the police detained several
leaders of local gay activist groups
and although all denied
knowledge and responsibility
for the attacks, many pledged support
of the gay gang's activities.
Later, the mayor issued a city-wide alert
for the immediate apprehension of quote,
"This bunch of colored fags".
♪ You can move on outta here ♪
Oh, come on baby, what's the problem, huh?
What's the matter with you?
Come on, come on, come on.
This is supposed to be a celebration.
I know.
Look, I got this great idea, you know?
I realize die and go on and our
ashes scattered over the
waters on Christopher Street.
You gonna be the next leader
of the Max Mo-Freak gang.
Come on, what's the problem?
This is the problem here, Max.
Oh come on, this is my problem, not yours.
Max.
This is good chicken.
Chicken, y'all had chicken?
Yeah well, Max made some quiche.
Oh, please.
You know I got an idea.
When we go back tonight, I'm
gonna send them for pizza
and they can stay out all night,
and we'll have our own
private celebration, okay?
Okay, just me and you, like it used to be.
Max.
That time he made apple quiche
and had the nerve to tell us he made it.
He had the nerve to fix
his face talking about
he made pork and bean quiche, oh please.
I don't wanna talk
about death anymore, Max.
I wanna talk about life.
Life, and...
Max.
What's, what's...
They're doing great things
with research now, Max.
You don't have to die.
Oh, well wait a minute.
Stop the presses.
Walk me cross the water.
You're gonna step down from
your pedestal of 21 years
to tell me that they're
doing research to save my...
I hate it when you
talk to me that way, Max.
No, no, they're doing
research to save my tired life?
What, have you been talking
to your friends in college?
Look at the way you talk to people.
That's the only way I get things done, Sam.
How many times do I have
to tell that to you?
You're wrong, you're wrong!
You've seen what's going on.
They're not doing anything for me
or your friends at college.
All the sudden it's about research.
No, no, not my friends...
And oh, they're gonna do
something for Marmalade,
any of us down here.
Oh, Sam come on.
Y'all want some barbecue?
In the house?
You're brighter than that.
Max, I'm tired of it.
I don't wanna do this anymore.
Look, I'm tired of this conversation.
Max!
Max, I'm sick of you.
I'm sick of the way you do things.
I'm sick of the...
No, no, no, I'm sick.
And I'm healthy.
I'm healthy.
♪ A lot of boys make me cry ♪
♪ Someone answer to my call ♪
♪ This bitter ♪
♪ May not be so bitter ♪
♪ After all ♪
♪ Ooh ♪
Oh stop.
Do you like them?
Sure.
I like them.
Do you like them, or
do you really like them?
I really like them.
Do you want some more?
Yes.
Six o'clock.
There.
I'll get you some more.
Six o'clock.
Thank you.
You seem to be a bit uncomfortable.
No.
I hope I'm not making you afraid of me.
I like to think that we
have a lot in common.
Okay.
I want you to be
completely at ease with me.
I'm sorry.
Don't apologize.
Aren't you afraid?
I mean, to be seen in public with me?
I'd be proud to be seen anywhere with you.
That's the stupidest
thing that I've ever heard.
It is pretty stupid, Sam.
Yeah.
Okay, now it's your turn.
You get to say something stupid to me.
I can't think of anything.
I'm so bored with city council.
You know I've been on city
council for ten years now?
I was elected when I was 25 years old.
There's nothing left for me now.
I have my sights set on bigger things.
President?
No one wants to be President, Sam.
Presidents don't make enough
money for what they do.
No, I'm running for Congress.
Yeah, the mayor, party, the owe me a lot.
I've done a lot for
them the past few years.
I'm gonna call in a few chits.
I really think that I'm ready for it
and I have all the
contacts to make it work.
I think so, too.
When I get down to Washington,
I'd like to have you there with me.
I think we could find a place for you.
Really?
Yeah.
Doing what?
Doesn't matter, really.
I'd just like to have you around.
That's really corny.
That's two corny things from me.
You get to say one.
You can tell me one corny thing.
Your eyes like two huge...
Okay, okay, you're excused.
We believe the government is acquiring
names and numbers of
all HIV positive people
in New York City.
We can't prove it yet...
The AIDS acquisition
files, you heard of them?
Uh huh.
So, you want the government
knowing who you are,
and where you are and who you
fucking, when you fucking,
what your HIV status is even before you do?
Hell no.
To the death.
What's this?
The AIDS crisis is not over.
The discrimination impact
let the record show.
For legislative AIDS trials against
children of color and
children without color.
Councilman Eddie Hicks.
Guilty.
University Hospital
President T. Warden Cropp.
Guilty.
Sister Mary Clarence.
Commissioner what's his name?
Guilty.
Councilman Melvin Freeman.
Fight to the death, my
children, to the death.
Ghetto.
Before we start, I want to ask something.
Last week I pushed very hard to organize
a nice political reception for us
with pizza and performances and such
and I got the go ahead
to do the groundwork,
then come to find out you
ordered the idea to be killed.
Now, what I wanna know is why should I
spend time at these
meetings giving all this
creative input when you go ahead and do
whatever the hell you feel like?
I have better things to do with my time.
I could have been sucking dick.
Don't y'all know who I am?
I am Larvetta Larvon Lavicomtess Delarva
and I will be heard.
Shut it down, shut it down.
And I'm sick of having
to work in an opium den.
I'm trying to bring you
people up to a new level.
Will you just relax?
Maybe you're right.
Maybe I better just take
my aristocratic black ass
back to my chateau to be
served flawlessly by my...
Ta ta ta ta.
Maybe you'd better.
Next.
Bitch.
Ghetto.
Answer the fucking question.
Are you in or out?
Use your brain, it's not hard.
I'm in.
I just don't wanna go to jail.
I'm a songstress.
She's out.
I'm not out.
In fact, I was in long before
you even showed up, Foxy Brown.
Watch it.
Cleopatra Jones.
Watch what?
Who are we supposed to watch?
And who's watching the watchers?
Joan, please.
I just don't wanna go to jail.
Are you on?
Fuck you.
No, are you on?
It's a simple question.
Are you on?
I don't gotta put up with this shit.
I'm a woman of substance.
I ain't judging you.
I just wanna know.
Are you on?
Well?
Marmalade is a warrior.
Marmalade is fearless.
Marmalade is an addict.
So are a lot of people.
We all got issues, Miss Shenequa
and you can't lay them all out on me.
I am an addict, baby,
but I am not the problem.
Besides, I have nowhere to go.
Addict.
Ghetto.
Come on guys.
Freeman is big in the
AIDS acquisition scam,
I can just feel it.
You can just feel it?
If we kidnap him and bring him here,
we could force information
or blackmail him.
With what?
I don't wanna get shot.
You have no proof.
I do nothing without proof, Sam.
Freeman really trusts me now.
Trusts you'd go right to jail.
I don't wanna get jail.
Not if we do it right.
Why are we still talking about this?
You can flap your wings
all you want, honey.
It ain't gonna fly.
What are we talking about?
We're not big medical doctors
with psychological degrees.
We limited queens who can
barely finish a manicure.
Speak for yourself.
What the fuck are we gonna do with Freeman?
Freeman has different sides.
I've seen it.
Different sides.
Oh, yeah?
Well, what if he resists?
We'd have to beat him up.
Oh, don't worry.
Sam can just monologue him to death.
You've all got no respect.
No respect for me as a gay Asian militant.
When we first met you, you were
a closeted apolitical Oriental.
So big deal about my life.
You've still got no respect.
What have you been doing in that office?
Have you blown it?
No.
Well, what have you done?
Nothing.
Yes you have.
You've done something.
Stop it.
You too young to be scheming up shit.
I'm young?
Yes.
Now, if you refuse to
present evidence and refuse
to cite sources...
Max!
I refuse to address the issue any further.
So that's it?
We're not even gonna try?
I thought you guys were badasses.
To the death.
Yes, but not a silly death, Sammy.
I really don't need your help, you know.
Dorothy, please.
I've got my own shit.
Bull fagga jones shit.
And I'm cool with it.
Well, sister, if you got your own shit
and you're cool with it, that just means
you have cool shit, now don't it?
Next!
Da da!
Ooh, she's so funny.
Gorgeous, but funny.
Ghetto.
I'm sorry.
I thought we were a self-proclaimed
queer terrorist group
dedicated to queer terrorism.
We are.
So why should I expend energy on some
abortion clinic dealing with tired fish
pollyannas who wanna kill their kid?
No, see but I have the
right to control my body.
So control your body by not fucking.
What?
I said control your body by not fucking
and face the consequences of your actions.
Pregnancy is a consequence?
Yep.
Is rape a consequence?
Is AIDS a consequence?
AIDS is not comparable to baby making.
If a woman gets herself pregnant.
I wanna know how a woman
gets herself pregnant.
If she opens up her legs then that's
what's gonna happen.
She gonna get herself
pregnant now ain't it?
LaLarva.
La victim.
Abort all the babies you
want, just call it murder.
Call it murder!
Step off, Betty, step the fuck off.
Are you ever here?
Ever?
Here, on this planet with us?
Divide and conquer.
That's how it always falls.
You are why every revolution has failed.
Me? I...
Yes, you.
I am the cause?
You.
For why every single revolution...
Yes, you...
Has failed?
Big house momma, sitting
up here trying not to...
Look, come and get your bitch, okay?
No, you come for me.
You come for me, okay?
I'm ready.
Would y'all please shut up!
Jesus fucking H Chri...
I swear I hate every last one of you.
You, you, you, you, you, you.
You, ya big cocoon mother fucker.
And you, twist your wig and maybe
you can think straight, okay?
And would you stop writing
all this goddamn shit down?
And Sam fix your piercing and get a clone.
Jesus fucking Christ.
Uh oh, out of liquor.
Hey, hey Pedro.
Jose!
Get your friends and come on up.
We having a party.
Ooh, look at that one.
Shut the fuck up.
looking for him.
Ooh, which one?
The one with the dick swinging in the wind.
He was what?
He was sucking that man's dick yesterday.
Stop.
Oh, yes.
I love me a less giving it man.
Oh worship that.
In the name of the father,
the son, that holy thing.
You better stop here with me.
Come on baby.
Stop it right now.
Oh!
Oh please, holy Mary mother of dick.
Oh please, the only
reason I hang out with you
is light-skinning it.
You didn't go there.
Oh, yes I did.
You shouldn't.
But you know I did.
You better never do it again.
Oh, what you gonna do?
Yeah, y'all come waaa!
He's the devil.
Larva is the devil.
He's lonely.
He's angry, he's hurting.
He's obviously lonely.
No, Sam, Larva is the devil.
Look at him.
He's deeply disturbed.
Look what he's doing to Max.
He's disruptive.
Have you noticed we don't
have one plan for next week?
I'm not gonna spend another
day in his presence.
They are just too old for me, anyway.
I like my men young, light-skinned
and so dumb they can even spell commitment.
Isn't it a little late in the day
to be so goddamn color struck?
Why?
To uplift the race.
Oh child please.
The race'll do fine without me.
My preferences are a part of who I am
and I will not apologize.
Now I loves my black people.
But I loves me, ooh, a light-skinned man.
Don't go there.
Why don't you just let the child
make up his own mind already?
Come on, Sam.
Oh, Fernando.
Better yell a little harder.
Fernando.
Larva.
Samuel.
Will you marry me?
Where's the ring?
I lost it.
You can't marry the Larva without a ring.
But I won't tell Max.
Marriage ha!
The last time I heard
that it was from Raoul.
He was the one that infected me.
Gangster bitch mother fucker Raoul.
I know you did it.
I know.
How can you be sure?
I'm sure.
Besides, Raoul was too
smitten by your vicomtess.
Too smitten as it should be.
Oh, he was dumb, dumb!
Couldn't write, couldn't read.
Couldn't spell dick.
But he sure did know how to work one.
Lord have mercy.
He could say ooh.
Then he would just pull his teeth
out of his mouth.
Oh.
Now who's gonna marry a
fat, ugly, disease-ridden
bag like myself?
Fame, fortune and a title to boot.
But I fear your vicomtess
will die waiting for the vicomdale.
I know, I know.
Just what?
Oh, you kiss my mother fuck...
Fuck you Sam.
♪ I wanna see you ♪
♪ When I'm leaving ♪
♪ 'Cause I'm leaving ♪
You alright?
You know, Sam, I got this brilliant idea.
Let's go away.
Let's get the fuck outta
here, just me and you.
I don't want them around.
We'll go to Jamaica.
You know, I know this, there's this beach.
It's a villa, I don't know where it is
but we can find it, you know?
And it's got sand, like
snow in August it's so white
and blue water and oh, man, me and you
could be on the beach, just me and you,
like we used to be.
I just want to be honest, I
just want to suck your dick.
Max.
Boo!
Who the fuck you think
you blowing off, huh?
I'm Max Mo-Freak.
You little fucking geisha
girl Suzy Wong bitch.
Why don't you take your ass
back on the fucking boat
to them damn rice fields?
I been doing more shit than when
you were little with your
little tiny fucking feet bound.
You don't know who you're fucking with.
Shit.
Not with that nigger.
Not in there.
I'm trying to save her life, goddammit.
Save my life, mind your goddamn business.
What, oh now that you can't get no ass
you gotta find someone else to shoot up?
Break it up, break it up.
What's your problem?
Don't you push me.
I'm so tired.
Get off of me, Sam.
You tired?
I'm so tired of this.
I'm so tired of you wasting
your life away with this...
What the fuck is wrong with dreaming?
This dream of yours.
Oh, oh.
And you're doing it all wrong.
Look at you.
You coming down off your pedestal
of your self-righteousness
to say we doing it wrong.
You wasting your time?
Is that it?
Yeah, I'm wasting my time.
I don't have that much time.
Max, you know I don't have that much time.
I know to the death, to the death, huh?
So, what to the death when it's convenient?
Huh?
I don't wanna kill myself, though.
going away?
I don't wanna watch you kill yourself!
How can you stand here and watch...
Don't sit here and preach to me!
Don't sit here and preach to me.
How can you...
You're wasting your time, huh?
Is that what you're telling me?
Y'all are a lost cause.
Revolution's over, huh?
That what you telling me?
You done, huh?
All the marching, all them women out there
with their babies, huh?
With their babies, that's over, right?
'Cause you wasting your time
and we ain't doing what
you want us to do, huh?
'Cause everything ain't right.
Everything ain't Jamela's way?
Max, no, it's not like that!
I just can't watch you kill yourself.
Then, you know what then?
Hey, hey, Jamela, hey, fuck off.
Fuck off, okay?
Is that the way you want it?
Yeah.
I won't waste your time.
I don't wanna do anything
that's gonna inconvenience you.
You know, we ain't perfect.
'Cause that's the way you want it.
Jamela, fuck off.
Fuck off!
I been taking care of
you for 30 years, Max.
I don't need no preaching.
Don't need no preaching.
Fuck off.
Hmm?
Max, now that that's over
can we go get my shit now?
Max.
Gonna go get it now?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
We're gonna go get your shit.
We're gonna go, alright?
Gonna get it now?
Yeah, let me think.
Alright, alright.
Where that bottle of
vodka I left around here?
I drank it.
Okay.
It's me.
I know.
I'm one of them.
You've gotta go now.
They're on their way.
You've gotta go.
Don't make me go.
Stop that.
I don't want you to get hurt.
Let me stay.
Can you?
I love you.
Yeah?
Oh, I ain't done.
I guess I could sing
for you mother fuckers.
I mean, people, now.
Oh, I got a little ditty.
You get that, ditty?
Fuck you.
I'm gonna give you a little ditty
that my mama taught me right on her knee.
Picture that.
♪ Give the piano player a drink ♪
♪ Because he's bringing me down ♪
♪ He's got a rhythm yeah ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ So me of mercy ♪
♪ Give me a pickfoot ♪
♪ Doo doo doo doo hey ♪
♪ And a bottle of beer ♪
♪ Yes yes yes ooh ♪
Hoo, thank you, thank
you, thank you so much.
Don't everybody clap at once.
Y'all ain't getting no
more outta me tonight.
I'm tired.
And the band gotta go pee.
Oh, how y'all doing?
The little people.
Hi.
Who's that big bitch there?
Alright wait a minute, wait, wait.
Wait a minute.
Oh, help me up.
Oh what you got baby?
stomach, I got stuff.
cheap, got a little cheap.
Okay.
You got the words.
Ooh, we gonna go have ourselves some fun.
I'll be back to sing.
She'll be right back, okay?
Be right back.
Trying to steal my thunder?
Let's go, alright?
Okay, we gonna be back in a minute.
Just like a lady.
Max...
Hey.
Shh.
Get off of me.
How can you think of that?
We're in serious trouble.
I thought these were your friends.
I know but they're nuts.
Capable of anything, gotta think.
Don't let me stop you.
This is for your sake.
Thank you.
Hey, is the bald one your boyfriend?
He is your boyfriend.
Shut up.
I thought you said you
were so pure and innocent.
Shh shh, please stop it.
This could be the end of
your political career.
Not with you on the case.
Oh God.
Hey Sam.
What?
Do you love me?
Brunch is served.
Why is he still blindfolded?
So he can't see where we are.
Actually, we took a cab here,
so I know where we are.
I think I should speak.
Melvin here, he's not quite the person
we thought he was.
He's actually a very special person.
He's forced to do things he hates.
I mean, that whole AIDS hospice...
See, my thoughts on the
AIDS hospice is simply this:
why should we allow them to force another
AIDS hospice on this community?
We're not the only place
in the city that has AIDS.
They have AIDS on the upper east side.
Nobody's trying to force an
AIDS hospice down their throat.
They have AIDS down in Battery Park City.
Nobody's trying to give
them an AIDS hospice.
You see, the more we allow them to turn
this community into a AIDS ghetto,
a dumping ground for people with AIDS,
it takes away from our ability to serve
other people in other ways.
I mean, what about day care
and housing, senior citizens?
And there are other ways
to serve people with AIDS.
You know, we didn't cause this disease.
Why should we have to bear the brunt of it?
Melvin's gonna help us get
the AIDS acquisition files.
But you have to trust him.
You have to trust me.
Max?
Max, what do you say, Max?
Suck my dick mother fucker.
Suck my dick.
Yeah, yeah.
You're a sick person, Max.
You're a sick person.
Oh damn.
You should be a doctor.
You have this fucking
fantastic diagnostic ability.
Let me get this player.
Come on, Freddie, give me a player.
Come on, let's go.
I want to hear, I'm all ears.
I'm all ears mother fucker.
All ears.
Max, please.
Bitch, it's left goddammit, left.
I know when I'm right,
Lawrence and it's right.
Don't you dare go there.
How dare you speak to your
vicomtess like that?
It's left, you bitch.
And where's your glasses?
You can't see worth a damn.
When was the last time
you were up in Harlem,
Miss I'm Wearing My Knockoff
Donna Karan sunglasses.
Don't you dare go there.
It's left, goddammit, left.
Where are we?
Max.
Please.
Would you shut the fuck up?
What?
Where are we?
Oh.
You were right, I'm sorry.
Sorry?
Well, how sorry do you want me to be?
Didn't you call me bitch?
I'm sorry.
Well, it's just that your "I'm sorry"
is so much less emphatic than your "bitch".
Where is my chiffon scarf?
No, Kappa girls are alright.
It's those Gammas you gotta watch out for.
Wait, wasn't it a Kappa who wrote
an article in Essence magazine about
black women having to share black men?
What?
No, seriously.
Apparently there's this
shortage of black men
so us black women have
to start doubling up.
Oh, that's ridiculous.
It is girl.
There is no biblical
reference for such nonsense.
You girls can find all the
good black men you need
and you don't gotta
downgrade yourselves, either.
All you gotta do is go to prison.
That's not downgrading yourself?
No, I'm serious.
Prison is the only place where...
Maxwell, Larry.
It's been a while.
My stoop isn't used to such a gathering
but find yourselves a seat.
So, Maxwell, what brings you
and your friends up this way?
One guess.
Oh come on, now.
Can't you be civil to your Aunt Flo?
This is between Jamela
and me, okay, that's it.
Oh no, oh no, that's not it at all.
Why'd you have to bring your entourage?
No, you've always relied on
Jamela to be your strength.
Well, now you gotta learn by yourself.
Well look, if you could
just keep your dime store
philosophy to yourself, okay?
Max, respect.
I'm sorry, I just wish it
wasn't Wednesday, you know?
It's just that in African traditions,
you know Wednesday's a bad
day to make any decisions.
Has something to do with the energies
and the moon and the chakras.
It's just always better to
make a decision on Thursdays.
Max, you know my answer.
I'm your brother.
And I'm your sister.
I don't have time or patience.
If I get cancer, if it
moves into my cervix,
it's different for a man.
It's just that Jamela needs some time
to be with herself and Zalea.
You can understand that.
I mean, come on.
You oughta be able to.
You're always tripping off
into some fantasy land,
dragging Jamela down with you.
You probably could use some rest yourself.
Look, look, there is
no time for rest, okay?
You're always finding some cause to fight,
but really the only cause
you're fighting is yourself.
Max it's time to come home.
It's time for home.
Yeah, right.
It's been a pleasure to meet you.
You did the right thing, girl.
How could you let him leave?
How could I let myself stay?
To feel like I feel.
Nina, Nina, where is she?
Right or wrong.
Nina, where is she?
You know I don't have time...
I just see you.
Nina.
'Cause you made me love you.
Hey, hey, mother fucker.
Get the fuck off.
Nigger, who the fuck you think you are?
That's my bitch, nigger.
That your bitch, that's your bitch, nigger?
Fuck out of my face mother fucker.
No baby, you gotta pay.
This here's a capitalist society.
Come on, come on.
Pull yourself up, come on.
Ooh, I feel so good.
Ooh, so good.
Yeah, yeah honey.
Look, relax yourself.
Relax?
Relax yourself.
Why should I relax?
You relax, you relax mother fucker.
You relax.
What are we gonna do about her?
Liz, don't worry about it, shit.
I just want to kill me somebody.
You hear me, girl?
Tell 'em, girl.
Shoot, I'm strong.
Tell me who.
Who?
You, you, you mother fucker.
You, you, him.
No, it's not gonna work no more.
Please, I need some shit.
You gotta help me out.
Careful Nina.
Get the fuck off.
Max, wait.
Everything is fucked and me most of all.
God burns in heaven and
the devil freezes in hell
and what difference does it make, huh?
You know?
What difference does it make?
Maybe after all is said and done,
maybe when all this shit is over,
there'll be a little
bit of love left for me.
And I will know just what to do with it.
Get out of my way.
It's day two in the
mysterious disappearance
of Councilman Melvin Freeman.
His secretary reports
Mr. Freeman left work
for a dinner engagement Tuesday night
and has not been heard from since.
You'll remember the councilman had recently
been victim of two faggot attacks
by the notorious drag queen gang
that has been rampaging the
city and still remains at large.
Mel.
Douglas.
Thanks for coming.
I really appreciate it.
Blink, mother fucker
and you die in the dark.
I heard you got my name on your list.
Well now, I got yours.
Alright, everybody drop your tools.
Get them hands in the air.
Good work, Al.
And you trusted him?
That's enough out of you.
You alright, Councilman?
Everybody freeze!
You lyin' son of a...
Max, no, Max!
Move.
Move!
Marmalade.
Hurry.
Let's go, let's go, run!
Run, hurry!
Max, come on!
That's who framed us!
That one.
Ma, Ma?
Where's your mother?
He's shot.
Oh my God, Samuel!
What are you doing to me?
Gotta help him.
Are you going to medical school?
Look at this.
Oh my God, oh my God.
Alright, alright, dear,
get a bottle of whiskey.
On the table, on the table.
Lay him down gently.
Gently, gently.
Oh!
Give him the whiskey.
Not on the wound, not on the wound.
Give it to him.
It's an anesthesia.
Careful, careful.
No, don't stir the wound.
Alright, alright, alright.
Lemme just see.
Need a band-aid.
Come on Max.
Pour it in his mouth.
He's got AIDS?
Alright, alright.
Let's be careful, alright.
Put the antiseptic on the gauze.
Larva.
It'll sting, it'll sting.
Don't move.
Ow!
Shit.
Goddammit.
I'm sorry.
Hold him down.
Hold him...
I don't like that.
Marmalade, tell 'em.
You know what a scalpel is?
Get me the scalpel from in there.
Yes.
Ma.
Careful, careful.
You alright?
Okay, it's gonna hurt.
I ain't bitch.
It's gonna hurt.
Everybody hold him.
Gonna hurt.
Ouch!
Alright, alright, alright.
I see the bullet.
Alright, I see it.
Calm him down.
Goddamn, get this bitch off of me!
Get her off.
It's okay.
Damn.
I see it.
I see it, I see it.
Alright, get me the,
alright, hold him down, hold him down.
It's good, he's alive.
Alright, alright, hold him down.
Ow, ow, ow!
It's alright, it's okay.
Now come on, you can take it.
You can take it, bitch.
Shit!
Oh, there it is.
There it is.
It's out.
You did very well.
Oh goddammit.
Give him some whiskey.
give up the bottle.
Okay, you did just fine.
He'll be fine.
We got the acquisition files.
He did just fine.
Get that damn bitch away from me.
Get away.
Are you...
HIV positive too?
No.
Why didn't you tell me all of this before?
You never asked.
I'm asking.
This is Max.
He's my lover.
I'm gay.
We help people.
This is Max?
This, he's my lover, we're freaks,
you help people and that's it?
What happened to medical school?
I hated it.
I gave the money to Max.
To him?
Oh, Sam you, oh Sam.
I've worked so hard to
send you to medical school.
Now, what happened?
What happened?
Sam, you were such a wonderful baby.
Everything you did was wonderful.
Everything you touched turned to gold...
I still am, Ma, I still am.
I know you still are, dear,
and the best thing for you to do
is just to get away from these people
and go back to medical school, alright?
If you don't like the school,
if you don't like the
school you're going to...
No, Ma, I want...
You can go to any other school.
You want to go to Europe?
I'll send you to Europe, alright?
Alright?
Just get away from these people.
Ma, Ma...
They're a bad influence on you.
I want to go to Manila.
Manila!
Are you crazy?
Manil...
God!
Sam, I tried to get out
of there and we're here.
We're fine now, alright?
I don't want you to go to Manila, alright.
Ma!
No, the thing to do is to get away
from these people, I want
these people out of here...
Ma, I love you.
And you go to school.
I love you too, and that's not the point.
Alright, alright all you
people, come back in here.
Pick him up and take him out of here.
I want you freaks out of here.
You people turned my son into a faggot!
He's not a fag!
Alright, just get out of here!
I want you out of here right now.
Pick up all your dirty things
and get out of here and don't come back!
Sam, I don't want you
seeing these people anymore,
alright, don't you see these people
and don't call him.
Put your arm around him.
I guess your date never did show up, huh?
Get out.
Come on, Larva.
Let's just go.
Get out and don't come back.
Thank you, Miss Yien.
We ain't coming back.
I just forgot something for a minute.
I'll see you later Sam, okay?
You have a lovely home.
Thank you.
♪ Not to worry ♪
♪ Nevermind ♪
♪ Life will fix it ♪
♪ Every time ♪
♪ Give a balance ♪
♪ Fill a need ♪
♪ Bring a flower from a seed ♪
♪ Hold your head up ♪
♪ Raise your chin ♪
♪ It wasn't you ♪
♪ Invented sin ♪
So what you going to get tonight?
They offered me some hot toys.
I love them hot toy.
That hot toy.
Well, that's a different kind baby.
Give me some orgies.
Wait, lookie, look!
Larry, Larry.
Ah!
Oh God, Sammy.
I missed you.
Oh, precious, I missed you too.
How've you been?
I been fine.
Ooh, you look bigger, yes you do.
It's the shirt.
Oh, it ain't no shirt.
Cute!
Isn't he great?
Ooh, Sam.
This is Claude.
Claude's my husband.
We got married.
Oh, it's been a long time.
So, how've you been?
Good.
Well, you know what I want you to do?
I want you to stay for
dinner, 'cause we have
some hot dogs, some macaroni and cheese,
some pinto beans, some lima beans,
some kidney beans, some green beans.
And don't forget...
He cooks, cleans, is artistic and fucks
me like a horse in heat.
And he's so dark skinned.
I know.
Ooh.
Ooh I know.
I know.
How many times you gonna know?
Oh shut up.
Old fool.
Sammy is smoking.
You better go ahead.
Trying to quit, actually.
Oh, oh really?
So.
You stopped writing.
So you don't know what's happened.
You don't know.
What's happened?
You should have written.
I wrote.
Unknown address or return
to sender but still I wrote.
Dammit, Larry.
I don't need this.
You know why I went away.
I'm not gonna apologize, I'm not.
Just tell me what you have to.
Jamela's dead.
February 21st.
Nina Simone's birthday.
Oh, a cunt to the end.
She kept lecturing me on and on and on
and sending me to the store for candy.
Can you image the vicomtess
going to the store for candy?
Oh, but she was okay.
She had her family around to see her off,
and Flo's got her baby.
Did she get my letter?
I don't know.
But she wished you well.
She did.
Lady Marmalade was killed, too.
When they found her in the hotel room,
strangled under the bed, the only thing
holding her head to her shoulders was skin.
Creole Lady Marmalade.
Dear God.
And your boyfriend is now Congressman.
But you outed him.
Ha!
That was a happy day for her.
Oh, sister denied nothing and lept all over
the liberal middle road gate ticket
and really tear the roof off a sucker.
Mmm, we never got fingered
for the crimes, though.
I give her that.
So you're telling me
Melvin Freeman's a gay hero?
Heroine, darling, heroine.
Oh, please.
She still votes fascist.
But nationally renowned now as
the first gay congressman of color.
I'll give her that.
And there you go.
There you go.
Mmm.
Larry?
Yeah, sweetie.
Sammy.
It's not good.
What do you expect?
He got shot.
He's got pneumonia.
He's got night sweats.
He's got shingles.
He's coughing up blood.
Does he hate me?
Let's find out.
♪ How can I follow ♪
♪ Any one else ♪
♪ Hoo hoo ♪
♪ I got to find it ♪
♪ For myself ♪
♪ Hoo hoo ♪
♪ I am ♪
Peace.
Beautiful.
You're beautiful.
I love you, Max.
I love you, too.
Goddammit.
♪ Sunshine woke me up this morning ♪
♪ Came creeping 'round my door ♪
♪ I said could this be a dawning ♪
♪ Or something less or something more ♪
♪ Open my eyes as I lay sleeping ♪
♪ Said girl you should be aware ♪
♪ But the hours you spend dreaming ♪
♪ You could move on outta here ♪
♪ Oh sunshine ♪
♪ Paint the day ♪
♪ Sunshine ♪
♪ Open up a way ♪
♪ For me to say ♪
♪ I'm so glad ♪
♪ I'm alive to say ♪
♪ I could live my life all over ♪
♪ I wouldn't change the stall I chose ♪
♪ Because the rain falls on everybody ♪
♪ Whether you're in or out of doors ♪
♪ Sunshine woke me up this morning ♪
♪ Oh it got me up ♪
♪ Oh it came creeping 'round my door ♪
♪
♪ I said could this be a dawning ♪
♪ Of something less or something more ♪
♪ Oh sunshine ♪
♪ It came today ♪
♪ Sunshine ♪
♪ Open up the way ♪
♪ For me to say ♪
♪ I'm so glad ♪
♪ I'm alive today ♪
♪ Oh day ♪
♪ Day ♪
♪ yeah ♪