The undefeated
favorites... team
doesn't seem to playing
their usual game.
With less than a
minute left, they're
still trailing by five points.
We gotta double right.
36 slam on...
read.
Break!
Gonna win this
game and make it score.
They have the ball deep
in their own territory.
Quarterback Pat...
number ten is calling the play.
He almost drops the ball,
but he makes the hand off
to star running back
number 45, John Carluccio.
All right.
That was good now.
That was good.
Here's what we're going to do.
We're going to run a slot
left, passed 69, double in.
What's the matter, John?
John?
Hey, ref!
Ref!
Need a time.
There's a time out on the field.
The quarterback is
motioning to the refs.
John Carluccio, number
45, the driving force
behind this amazing team
is leaving the field.
Lane?
Lance, where are you?
Right here.
All right.
Another $150 bucks.
I should have bought
stock in the company.
36...
Go ahead.
...backup running back
is coming into the game.
What's the matter?
You all right?
Come on, come on.
Will you hurry up?
...it's all right?
...batteries went dead.
Thank god.
You all right now?
Can you hear?
All right.
Come here.
Now get back in there.
John Carluccio comes running back
on the field and his replacement
number 31 Lance...
disappointedly leaves the field.
Guess you don't get
much playing time
serving backup to John Carluccio.
Lance must be a pretty frustrated
young man about this time.
Hut!
The clock ticking
away, quarterback Pat
...fades back
and throws a...
pass to number 45, John Carluccio.
Carluccio makes it down to the...
one yard line.
First down... high!
Hey, how about that pass, huh?
What do you mean pass?
It was a great catch.
He's making Pat look good.
All right, well, they're a
pretty good combination, huh?
Here's the play.
The quarterback...
is taking them all around him
himself.
He's got the whole
team out in front,
...Carluccio
does a great run.
Touchdown!
...does it again!
Winning another game...
keeping their undefeated
record intact.
Looks like for the first time ever,
...is gonna
have a winning team!
Way to go, guys!
We'll see you at the
championship game.
You can bet on it, Gary, if
I have anything to do with it.
Fat chance!
Christ?
Hey, bro, who won the game?
High.
What is this?
Another set of wheels?
You know my old lady, man.
She married some rich
old dude in Houston.
This is my wedding gift.
Hey, say hello to...
Hi.
Chris, where have you been?
Haven't seen you too much lately.
Vacationing.
Where?
Take a guess.
Alcatraz.
It's close.
State Country Club for Boys.
Well, that figures.
Yeah, I finally make the big time.
If you need me, I'm back.
He's a real clown.
Wasn't that Jimmy's boy?
Yeah.
His father's serving time.
Yes.
Chris is all right.
Eh, just don't turn
your back on him.
Bravo... bravo.
...what do you
say we gt something to eat?
Well, son, you still
play like an amateur.
But you eat like a pro.
You just quit, do you?
Quit?
Why quit?
Well, at least your
grandson plays like Virtuoso.
No thanks to you.
Pat, two minutes, man!
Mom?
Dad?
Bye.
Hey, kid?
Pat's waiting, dad.
...terrific.
Maybe you oughtta try
putting on some pants.
Thank you.
Have a good day.
May I help you?
Two.
Oh.
That's $4.45 with tax.
Don't bother wrapping them.
You know, Rose, it warms the heart
to see kids taking precautions.
...that's, uh, better.
Susie...
Well, if I am...
You do?
...come...
didn't get...?
I don't know.
Well, you gotta come by.
At least to the locker
room and say hello.
OK.
Wanna come next week?
I mean, can you blame
a guy for seeking
a out a more mature relationship.
Honest, I really like you, Susie.
You're gonna make me puke.
...I just met you five
minutes ago and you're all over
me like an octopus.
Susan?
What?
I wanna talk to you.
Not now.
Come on.
Laura!
I wanna tell you
something in the kitchen.
...would you get off?
God, you jocks are all the
same, groping sex maniacs.
Laura, what do you want?
I don't know what to do.
Word came directly
from Ron, I swear.
Ron?
Ron is the biggest
BS artist in school.
Do you like him?
I guess so.
I mean, do you like him?
Yeah.
OK.
Well, do you wanna do it?
All right.
What do you want from me?
Blind dates, it's always
a shot in the dark.
You know that.
Pat, I thought we
were passed this stage.
Ron, he set us up.
What are you complaining about?
Look who's making the sacrifices.
Shh.
I gave up the beauty
of the beast, didn't I?
What beauty?
If you're so unhappy, let's trade.
No way.
Where'd you put them?
What?
You know.
Under the pillow.
What?
Mom, some friends just
came in for a quickie visit.
Come on.
Outta here, you rotten
kids! Now
get out of here.
- You have no right to be...
- hi there. Come on,
come on.
It's time to go.
Out of here, you rotten kids!
At last, an improvement.
But don't let it go to your heads.
You're still quite a
ways from performing
with the Vienna Philharmonica.
And I would like you kids to
continue working from letter D.
And now scram.
Hi, John.
Oh hi, Corri.
I, uh, heard about your
big score Saturday night.
Oh, well you know how it is.
Yeah, that's not what Suzie said.
Oh, by the way, you forgot
these balloons under the pillow.
See you later.
Hi, sis.
Hi, pat.
Pat, look what your
sister just laid on me.
I knew she was growing
faster, but not this fast.
Come on.
Coach Rizzo will
really cheer us up.
Johnny, come here.
Pat, excuse us, eh?
Don't be late for practice.
Yes, grandpa?
Johnny, you missed a
couple of rehearsals
because of football practice.
And while I tried to
understand as your grandfather,
as your teacher, I
find it unacceptable.
Grandpa.
You're talented, gifted.
Don't waste it on barbarism.
Grandpa, give me a break, will you?
I've spoken to Mr. Hoit
of the Youth Symphony.
Now, he said he would accept you
because of my recommendation.
Now how many boys get an
opportunity like that?
You've got to get serious.
Forget football.
You need more rehearsals.
Grandpa, I just turned 17.
And all that's really important to me
right now is what I'm
doing on Saturday night.
You know what I mean?
Oh, yes.
But if you're old enough to mate,
you're old enough to make up
your own mind about your life.
You were my age.
All the brothers in
Naples had to keep
iron locks on their doors.
Well, my boy, I guess there's just
no way of getting
through to you, is there?
Coming?
How about that, huh?
- Come on, man.
- We're late.
We gotta get out of here.
We gotta get...
Rizzo's gonna kill us.
I will see you out there.
Wait, Pat.
I have something to show you.
What?
Come here.
Ouch!
Boy, isn't he a handsome guy?
That's pretty funny.
Come here.
25 laps.
How many miles is that?
Six or seven.
Oh.
No more hot idea.
No more...
Let's get something to drink.
Yeah.
- How was the olympic?
- Huh?
What's up, coach?
This way.
Sure, coach.
I want to to know.
What is it?
You're disqualified.
I'm, I'm what?
I had nothing to do
with it, honest to god.
It's the new district
medical examiner, Dr. Bowers.
Dr. Bowers?
He says you can't play
with a hearing handicap.
Handicap?
He's never even examined me.
It's in the records, John.
I'm sorry.
What is this?
A union meeting or something?
Come on, break it up.
Is that all then?
I gotta stick by the rules.
I'm sorry.
Without John, we're
not a championship team.
That's what we got.
You got the word.
John's disqualified.
I've been shooting my mouth off
with the doctor for over an hour.
And all he comes up with
is the same answer, no.
N-O.
Are you the coach or not?
As far as the doc's concerned,
coaches are canned jellyfish.
Did I tell you they
gave me a new secretary?
No.
Oh, yeah.
A beauty.
Well, she must be because
obviously she can't type.
You know what?
What?
I forgot to ask.
No monkey business.
Mm.
Oh,
You know it's 11:30
and John's not home yet.
Well, he's a growing boy.
You're gonna have
to get used to it.
Not on week days.
Huh, come on.
Let him have a little fun.
John, are you all right?
Yeah, just fabulous.
Why didn't you call me?
I didn't get a chance to.
What the hell was all that?
I don't know.
John?
That was quite
an entrance down there.
Don't like you talking that
way to your mother...
Come on, John.
You wanna tell me or not?
I'd love to you about it, dad.
I can't play on the team any more.
I'm disqualified.
What are you talking about?
Something about my handicap.
But you never said
I was handicapped.
They're telling me I'm handicap..
Now wait a minute.
Somebody's flipped
their rocker here.
You're perfectly normal.
Well, not according
to Dr. Bowers I'm not.
Bowers?
He's, he's a has been.
Thee guy that replaced
Dr. Silver after he
suffered from a stroke.
Dad, if they don't let me
play, I'm quitting school.
Hold it, hold it now.
Playing football is important, but
your education's still number one.
We always agreed on that.
I wanna bust the place up!
All right.
Now we'll fight
him, but we'll do it
through the proper channels
and without losing our head.
Am I handicapped?
Huh?
Answer me, am I handicapped?
Am I?
No.
Huh?
Come on now, I said no.
Come on John.
I'm gonna back you up.
Huh?
Can I handle that?
All right then, come on.
It's all right.
I love you, dad.
By a majority vote of five to one,
the board has approved funds
converting all hand towel
dispensers in the toilet areas
to electric drying machines.
And now to the next
order of business.
Uh, Mr. Carluccio, uh, I have
your letter here requesting
a consideration of your son's case.
...you have
the floor...
Thank you, Mr. Henderson.
Um, I'm here seeking to overturn
a decision passed by Dr. Bowers
prohibiting my son
from playing football.
The directive is arbitrary
and discriminatory.
Discrimination is a
very strong accusation.
I'll prove it to you.
All right.
How?
By demonstrating that my son can
hear normally with
his hearing aid on.
John, would you step up here.
Now Mr. Carluccio,
um, would you
have your son remove
his hearing aid?
Why?
I've just proved he can hear
me even when my back is turned.
Well, you did.
But can he hear you
without his hearing aid?
Excuse me.
Um, Mr. Henderson,
but would you be
able to read without
your glasses, sir?
All right.
I remove my glasses.
I can still see, but can you
hear without your hearing aid?
Mr. Henderson, may I
say something, please?
Go ahead, Coach Rizzo.
Well, uh, I just want to say
that John Carluccio is about
the best player I've ever coached.
Why, I'd play him if he were
cock-eyed and horse-tailed.
Thank you.
Can we proceed now?
The board should immediately
reverse Dr. Bowers decision.
Now just a moment.
There are six members on this board
and we are trying objectively
and democratically
to examine both sides
of the question.
I don't think we can take a vote
until we've consulted with Dr.
Bowers, the legally
appointed medical examiner
of this district.
I will submit a written
report to the board.
There.
We'll convene again in two weeks.
Meeting adjourned.
...stop horsing
around and get out in the field!
Hey guys, I think
that is the first time
I have ever seen
Lance in the shower.
I hope it shrunk his head though.
Hey, John.
Can I help, coach?
Yeah, sure, John.
How does that feel?
Feels real good, coach.
Thanks.
Oh, let's see.
How'd you like to take
out the ball bag, huh?
Sure.
OK, come on.
Everybody finish dressing outside.
Come on...
Let's go.
Move it.
Come on, outside, everybody.
...take it easy, man.
Dr. Bowers?
Your father is very insistent
that I speak with you.
So, uh, pull up a chair.
That'll do.
Just there.
Thank you.
Can you hear me?
Yes, sir.
What did I say precisely?
Can you hear me.
Well, according to your
records you lost the hearing
in one ear and 50 percent in
the other at the age of eight.
Yeah, that's right.
A swimming accident.
And you've played football
since the age of seven.
Um, Dr. Bowers
does it say anything
in your records about
the fact that I've
played violin since
the age of three?
Oh, yes, yes.
Extraordinary.
Now, remove your
hearing aid, please.
I don't see the point.
I must have your cooperation.
Count from one to ten.
Count from one to ten, please.
What?
Oh, that's all right, son.
I've been asking you to
count from one to ten.
It, it's all right.
Remove the hearing aid, please.
Why are you doing this to me?
Please understand me.
My only and primary
interest is the preservation
of whatever little
hearing you may have left.
It's only a minor disability.
You don't read lips.
Can you do sing language?
Hell no.
Why, should I?
Well, I wish it were
only a minor disability,
but I'm afraid it's
much more than that.
The way I see it, you
endanger not only yourself
by playing, but
also your teammates.
We haven't had an
injury in two years.
And I have proven my abilities.
At best I say you've
been lucky to get
away with it as long as you have.
You're turning me into
some kind of freak.
That's preposterous.
I'm acting in accordance
of my best judgement.
What'd he say?
Nothing.
There's nothing
wrong with you, man.
Yeah, they oughtta
bring doc Silver back.
I don't know.
Maybe that doctor's
got a point, you know?
That's rotten coming
from you, Lance.
You've got asthma.
What makes you so
different from me, huh?
What makes you different from me?
Come on, man.
I'm sorry.
No, no, no.
Drop it, please, like this.
Dah, dah, dah.
Pick up to three.
Trumpets only, huh?
All right now.
One, two, three, four.
Wait, no, no, no, no, no.
You see, it all begins with scales.
You must practice
your scales every day.
They are your voices.
The maestro Pablo Casals said,
scales were his teachers.
They liberated him.
Trumpets, again.
One, two, three, four.
One... John?
John!
Lisa, take over.
John?
Don't jeopardize the good things
you have going for yourself.
Like what?
Dah, dah, dah?
Yes, absolutely, dah, dah, dah.
Take what's happening
as an opportunity
to concentrate on what
is really important.
Get off your high
horse, will you grandpa?
You know what's important?
What's important is that I
don't feel like playing today.
That's what's important.
And it's my own decision.
My own damn decision.
So go dah dah yourself.
It had better be worth it.
I don't find this one bit amusing.
It's not meant to be.
All right, come on.
Let's circle up, let's go.
Doctor.
Let's go.
Come on.
Let's go, come on.
All right.
All right, ready, let's go.
17...
17.
Come on!
I can't.
Why not?
I don't wanna hurt the guy.
- You know.
- Come on.
Come on.
This is John's chance
to prove himself.
Come on.
I said break it up!
Shut up!
Shut up...!
I'm surprised at you.
I stick out and this is
the way you repay me, huh?
He asked for it!
I don't care who asked for it!
You know my rules!
No fighting!
Well, I'm sorry.
That's not good enough!
Now go on, take you uniform off.
You're through.
Go on.
Beat it.
Get out of here.
Get out.
And you, you creep.
You're suspended.
What about tomorrow's game, coach?
I said you're
suspended till tomorrow.
Now shut up!
Hey, Pops.
Hi, Johnny.
Hey, You're a little
early, ain't you?
I didn't have any practice today.
Is there like a soda or something.
Oh, yeah.
Chris is here, huh?
Yeah, he's here.
Wish to heck he wasn't.
He's as welcome as a
skunk at a church social.
Now don't you go getting
into no trouble, you hear?
I won't.
See you.
It's nice.
Think I'm gonna
call it, "Heart Sick.
Teenage Bourbon Alcohol Blues."
Well, I'm always
open to suggestions.
OK, well, take it from the hook.
OK.
...country love.
Country love.
Nice compromise.
It's a deal.
It's a song.
Well, why don't you, um, why
don't you come on Saturday
and bring your axe and...?
Well, I had a blast last
session, so I'd love to.
OK.
See you.
OK, Saturday.
All right.
Election time...
All right, bro.
One for you.
Hey, John.
Hi, how you doing?
Good.
You haven't lost your touch.
I keep in practice, you know.
I got a couple of, uh,
buddies I want you to meet.
You've got, uh,
Herman here and Jess.
Hey, hey, what's you say?
How you going?
Come on over to our table and
meet a couple of foxy ladies.
US bred and prime beef.
Here we got, we got
Samantha and Linda.
This is John Tiger Carluccio,
Mr. Grid Iron itself.
Pops...
Hey, how's your dad?
He's doing pretty well.
He just got promoted to district
sales manager at Metro Life.
Metro Life?
Yeah.
That's kinda like my old man.
He got promoted from... to Sing Sing.
I hear you ain't on a team anymore.
Yeah, some quack doctor
barred from all contact sports.
Want my boys to squeeze
his nose a little?
Na.
John?
You don't any coach on your
back to worry about now.
Welcome to the adult world.
Hello?
Yes?
What?
No, we weren't aware that
he was absent from school.
Um, expulsion?
Mr. Martin, he's been going
through an awful lot lately.
Yes.
Of course we'll do
what's necessary.
OK.
John?
Give me a beer.
I don't believe it.
Ah.
I think the boys might want a beer.
Go on, give them one.
How about two?
Why not?
Hey boys, how about a
little Gatorade, huh?
Vitamin C enriched.
Cheers.
You trying to get kicked
out of school or what?
Come on, who cares, huh?
Where's your P-R-I-D-E?
What is this?
A spelling bee?
No.
It means pride.
I don't see anybody
asking your opinion.
All right.
Coach Rizzo sees this, you'll
never get on the team again.
Never.
Let's see if you
can spell this out.
You tell coach Rizzo to
take it and...
What's with you?
Split.
No way.
I don't blame you
for feeling bitter.
Hey, look it.
There's a lot of things
you can do to fight back.
But hanging out with...?
That sure isn't the way.
Are you gonna start preaching?
Look it, you do whatever you want.
Just let me say this first.
A skunk don't stink all the time,
but if you don't watch
out, it'll spray you.
Why don't you lay off Christ?
It'll spray you?
Jeez.
If you don't
watch out, it'll spray you.
I don't know..
Why don't you share some of
the stuff you've been smoking?
If you don't
watch out it'll spray you.
Hey listen, forget
those creeps, man.
I mean, you're still one of us.
Nothing's changed.
It's all in your mind.
The guys need you.
You mean that?
Yeah, sure.
Who's more psyched
up than you, anyway?
Come on.
Let's go down...
Sure.
Dynamite chick.
Oh.
That's just dying to meet you.
What?
Another one of your
hack blind dates?
No thanks.
Ah, yeah.
Let's go...
Ah, looking good, right!
Right!
Get them up, get them up,
get them up!
Hey coach, why don't
you let me gear up
and get in there are run
a couple of plays just
to keep my timing sharp, huh?
I can't.
Where you going?
I busted my chin strap.
Well, hurry it up.
All right, all right.
Let's go.
Huddle up, huddle up.
Quiet.
All right, quiet down though.
That was good.
That was very good.
How's it going, John?
Hey, hey, hey, all right.
That's good, that's good...
All right!
OK, come on.
Come on.
Let's huddle up, huddle up.
All right, let's go, lads.
Let's go.
Lousy, Bob.
How about yourself?
We miss your play, man.
That's good.
That's good!
Hey, I'll be seeing
you around, John, huh?
All right, let's
go, let's go, let's go!
...first down,
you know they play.
Let's go.
Let's go, let's go.
Come on, make it look good now.
Make any money today, Pop?
- Eh, broke even.
- Eh, boy.
You need a lift?
Ah, no, not tonight.
I think I'm gonna bike it home.
Take it easy.
All right.
Uh, Johnny, come here.
Now look, kid, Just
a word of advice.
Life is funny.
Sometimes you're the
bug and sometimes you're
the windshield.
Sometimes I'm the what?
You know what I mean.
I know you've had it rough,
but this ain't the answer.
Now you've got a real good future
if you'll just stick to your
music and your school books.
This ain't for you.
You just give some
darn serious thoughts
to what I've said to you.
Can I come in?
Yeah, sure.
I'm finished anyway.
You know, one day they'll
stand in line to see you.
Sure, selling
hamburgers at McDonald's.
Hey, come here.
Listen, I know things seem
a little dim right now.
Like my old coach
always used to say,
every adversity, every
headache, carries with it
the seed of an equivalent
or greater benefit.
Words suck, dad.
Listen, John.
Um, did you ever
think perhaps, there
might be some truth in
what the doctors say?
First the doctor,
then coach, now you.
Come on, take it easy.
I'm just questioning it.
What the hell is there to question?
Risk of injury.
Injury?
Injury.
You know, that's I've been
hearing lately, injury.
You really just don't
understand, do you?
Well, you think I don't know?
I was headed for college
sophomore of the years honors.
Just because you got hurt doesn't
mean I'm gonna get hurt.
Right.
All right.
But do you think that's going
to you where you're headed?
Big deal.
So I smoke a little.
The point is, John,
you're breaking the rules!
Now if you want to win,
you do with some discipline
and now falling.
Come on, hit me again, big shot.
What difference does it make?
How about a hand for
the man who helped me
write this song, John Carluccio.
...outlaws.
We'll be back in a few minutes.
Hi.
I didn't know you could
play the country...
...with Jimmy O. Now.
Did I see you come
in here with Chris?
Yeah, it's no big deal.
Besides, I thought
he was your friend.
He is.
But I've known him
since kindergarten.
Well, I'm here with Sam.
Sam?
Samantha.
The blonde.
Oh.
She's my cousin.
Anyway, she asked me to tag along.
Who are you here with?
An old friend.
You're loosing your touch, John.
You're not kidding.
Lately I'm batting a big fat zero.
I know someone that can
end that batting slump.
You're serious, aren't you?
Mhmm.
I mean, you're like a
little kid sister to me.
Maybe not that little
any more, but... besides,
your brother Pat would murder
me if I ever laid a hand on you.
Who said I'd let you?
Do you wanna dance?
Hi, guys.
What's going on?
Hey, John.
John, we got a little surprise...
Why don't you try a little?
No, Chris.
Come on, it'll make you feel good.
Come on.
Go.
Yeah.
Huh?
Come on, two toots
are better than one.
John.
Hurry up.
You got it on your nose.
Wipe your nose.
John, please take me home.
Come on, pretty mama.
Fun's just beginning.
Hey, cousin Corri, Chris
says he has a surprise.
Come on.
Chris is right.
...OK?
What is going on here?
Chris... what is this?
Another car?
...get in.
We go... come on!
Hello, Cadillac.
I've had my eyes on
you for a long time.
Wow, a limousine.
You know what to do?
Yeah.
Give me 30.
30?
You got it.
One, two, three...
Five six, seven,
eight, nine, ten, 11,
16,
21, 22, 23,
He did it.
...come on!
I can't believe...
Shh, shh.
Oh, John, I don't wanna go.
I can't believe...
Come on, man.
You chicken?
I don't wanna go.
Yee haw!
Please let me out!
Chris, stop the car.
Let me out!
Sure, go ahead.
Chris, stop the car.
Let go!
I'm trying to drive, jerk!
Watch it!
Now where the hell have you been?
Morning.
Juice?
No, mom.
Dad?
Nobody's perfect.
I'm learning that.
It won't happen again.
John, we trust you.
Don't hang us up.
All right?
All right.
No more questions.
I'll get your breakfast.
Thanks, mom.
Here, read the comics.
John, Corri wants to talk to you.
Corri?
Wow.
The police got Herman.
That's too bad.
You can thank Chris for that.
Chris blames you.
He told Sam that he
lost control of the limo
because you bugged him.
That guy is definitely a psycho.
I don't want anything
to do with him any more.
So pretty here.
Yeah, sometimes I come
down here and I play my violin.
There's something very magical
about nature and music.
You love your music, don't you?
Yeah.
I can remember my grandfather
putting a violin in my hands
when I was three.
He'd like to think I'd
become another...
You never know
if you really studied.
Well, I don't know.
Now, my dad, he was supposed
to become another...
But he wrote poetry
and played football
until he hurt his knees.
Did he ever
publish any of his poems?
Na.
I think he sent some out once.
But they got rejected.
He lost heart and that's when
he got into selling insurance.
I'll bet your
grandfather went wild.
Poor dad.
Some day, when I become a somebody,
I'm gonna publish his poetry.
Without even reading it.
You know, you're a
hard one to figure out.
I mean, you play violin.
You're willing to go out
on the football field
and roll in the mud
with a bunch of animals.
Bash your head in.
It's, it's a contradiction.
Weird.
You're a menace to my ego.
Be serious, John.
Are you playing football
to prove something?
I mean, is it because
of your dad or, or is it
your hearing problem?
What are you trying to prove?
You some kind of
shrink or something?
Someday I will be.
Oh, no.
A weirdo.
Forget about practicing
with me, Corri.
John?
John!
I roll in the mud!
In the past, when I
used to look at you,
Go on.
Don't stop.
A light used to kind of go
off in my brain, you know?
Incest, incest.
Only yesterday, you were...
Skinny little sister.
I remember you as the
fattest kid on the block.
I'm not trying to prove anything.
The only thing I really
can't do is hear in stereo.
Why don't you try
stacking up the speakers?
The next item on
this evening's agenda
will be the decision on
the John Carluccio matter.
May I have the Dr. Bowers file?
Thank you.
Dr. Bowers' report was read
to members of the board
and by a vote of four to two, they
decided to uphold the
doctor's decision.
Now we will.
The board can have my resignation
effective immediately.
Mr...?
You mean that's it?
There's no more discussion?
Mr. Carluccio,
the matter has been resolved.
What do you mean
it's been resolved?
- What's the word?
- Pride!
What's the word?
Pride!
We want John!
I would like to know the
meaning of this intrusion.
John Carluccio won this
for the best Little League
catcher five years
ago, batting 424.
Very impressive.
And this for...
Valley's most valuable
football player, John Carluccio.
How many more do you have?
I am truly sorry, but...
Oh, don't apologize.
I just want you all to know that I
think this is a gutless decision.
Mr. Carluccio, we have
a very long agenda.
Mr. Henderson?
Yes, John?
Ever since I've
been taken off the team,
there's been a lot
of talk, feelings.
From my dad, my mom, my
friends, school board,
it's like whether I play
or not is a big deal.
And people are asking why, why do I
wanna play, what am
I trying to prove.
I'd like to play football, just
like I like to play the violin.
One really isn't more
important than the other one.
Now a doctor says that
I can't play football.
And it seems pretty simple to me.
Why, I don't like being
told I can't do something
I know that I'm capable of doing.
I don't want be told that.
And I'm not going to
accept being told that.
Well said, John!
My hands are tied.
That's it.
One more now.
Now let me have your attention.
Let me have your attention.
By this time tomorrow, we'll be
in the playoffs, which should
put us in the championship game.
Now we've beat these
guys before on our field
and we can do it again.
Now, I want you guys to
concentrate and execute.
But you're gonna have
to want it bad enough.
Do you want it bad enough?
Yeah!
I'm proud of you guys.
Don't disappoint me.
We've come this far.
Disappoint me, I'm
gonna cut your ears
off and hang them on my belt!
And get to bed early!
No partying, OK, let's go!
John?
Go, go, go, go, go!
Get him!
Pick him up!
...huh?
Get him up.
Get him up!
John?
Chris.
Hey Jess, where's Herman?
He's on a forced vacation.
Why?
Because of him.
Can you hear that?
Chris.
You.
And you?
How about you?
Are you OK now?
You were very troubled when
you came to see me last week.
Yes, especially since
we started classes.
Good.
Because when learn sign
language, and especially
lip reading, then
you don't have to be
afraid of not
communicating with anyone.
That's what scared me...
When Chris took my aid, I
was, I was, I don't know.
It made me realize
that dad's not always
going to be around
with a spare one.
Would it be reassuring
to know that sign
language isn't hard to learn?
You know, I feel like I'm, I'm
a person finding his roots.
Beginning to know
what I'm all about.
Let's go...
Let's start.
OK, come on!
OK, who wants first honor?
I do.
Come on, man.
Let's go!
Man, you're too small.
What are you talking about?
Hey, you guys think you're tough?
Come on, fair fight!
I'll take all you
apes on one by one.
Just like you did
with Carluccio, right?
Come on, man!
He's all right.
From here on out, I'm
gonna call you...
We're approaching the end
of first half of this
championship game.
High will kick
off down by touchdown.
And the ball goes to number 33.
Oscar...
He's gotta wedge up the middle.
...he's out the opening,
going down the field... touchdown!
High now trails by two touchdowns.
They seem to have
run out of miracles.
They sorely miss the player,
their star running back,
John Carluccio, disqualified.
Earlier this season
because of a hearing handicap.
High is desperately
in need of a scoring drive.
Here comes the kickoff.
...first and ten
on their own 27 yard line.
Quarterback...
had the ball.
He's fading back to pass.
Oh!
Oh, boy did he get hit.
He was sacked for a loss.
Right now it looks pretty dismal
for... high fans.
There's the snap.
It's headed off to number
31, Lance...
He's tackled for no gain.
There's...
It's a pitch out to Lance...
...running
around...
Pounded to the turf!
Oh, he's not getting up.
It looks like he may be injured.
Time out on the field.
If... is injured,
...chances for victory
would seem to be
slipping further away.
...do I
have your permission
to put John in the game?
What?
I want your permission
to let him play.
You got it.
Hurry up and suit up!
Get your ugly face in that game!
You know you're committing suicide.
Can you think of
a better way to go?
Rizzo!
Hey, what do you want from me?
I got a game to win!
After the
punt... High
has the ball first down
on their 29 yard line.
Now.
Wait a minute, folks.
This is incredible!
John Carluccio, number
45, is I uniform
and he's coming into the game!