I've always believed
in the hope of Christmas.
No matter how hard
life is...
No matter how much
we've messed up...
What time is it mama?
9:30.
Or how broken our lives have become.
At Christmas...
Good things can happen.
He'll be here baby.
Mason.
Wha-
Oh brother.
Good morning,
smoky mountains
and happy December.
That's 600 hours...
3,600 minutes...
Or 25 days until Christmas.
And the highs today are gonna
be in the mid 30's,
so hey, put on your Grandmama's
sweater...
Break out your aunt Edna's
fruitcake...
And pour yourself another cup
of that eggnog latte.
Whatever you do,
button up tight
as you start your day today.
Hi, I'm Dj Baley and we are
WMTN 93.7
and this is your Tennessee
mountain Christmas station.
Up next, we've got a new
Christmas song from Mason Wyatt
to kick off our commercial free
Christmas marathon.
It's Mason Wyatt, with
"o come all ye faithful."
It's
crooked.
o come all ye faithful
joyful and triumphant
o come ye, o come ye
to Bethlehem
come and behold him
born the king of angels
o come, let us adore him
Christ the lord
Orders are
ready!
Pies are on the
table, hun.
BlackBerry crumb?Three in the bottom.
That smells good.Mm-hmm.
come and behold him
born the king of angels
o come, let us adore him
Christ the lord
Oh!
Who died?
Jimmy Wade
Haygood.
You look nice, shug.
Thank you.
And try not to
burn this place down
while I'm gone.
No promises.
Good luck, dear.
Thank you...
Mama.
You're welcome!
That's right,
Trish Greene.
It's Mason Wyatt day
down in pine valley.
Why don't you remind our
listeners,
why today is so special?
Well, our very own
country music superstar,
Mason Wyatt will be dancin'
live on TV
to raise money for
the Nashville children's home.
Ah, does it get any better
than that, people?
That's right, Trish.
Now hey, he'll be dancing on
the hit show "dancin' country,"
so come on out everybody for a
local viewing
at the Holly theater, to
support our local legend.
The one, the only...
Mason Wyatt!
Oh, I cannot wait
to see this.
We'll have gifts,
prizes and lots of fun, folks.
So come on out everybody and
support Mason Wyatt.
People, trust me, you
don't want to miss this.
Ha-ha.
Shelby Haygood,
how's life?
I am doing good,
mayor.
How are you?
I'm alive,
so I'm smiling.
BlackBerry
crumb.
Hmm, I think we'll
put this one
under the counter.
So uh, you comin' tonight?
Well...
50/50.
50/50?
Okay.
Thank you.Mm-hmm.
This is for you.Thank you.
All right,
merry December.
Ha!
Merry December.
Your little fella
is falling asleep
over there.
Come on, fella,
it's Christmas.
You got to stand on
your own two feet.
Better!
Miss Shelby!
Shh.
Okay,
now you can't tell
anyone, all right?
Look what I brought.
You don't like pie,
do you?
No, I do.
You do, I know you do.
It's our secret, okay?Okay.
Okay.
M'm, what kind of pie
do you like?
Cherry.
It's your lucky day.
High-five.
This is my favorite
time of the year all.
The cocoa, the lights,
the trees, all the presents.
But let's not forget why
we celebrate
this wonderful season.
"And she brought forth her
first born son;
and wrapped him
in swaddling clothes,
and laid him in a manger,
because there was no room
for them in the inn.
And there were
in the same country,
Shepherds abiding in the field,
keeping watch over their flock
by night.
And lo, the angel of the lord
came upon them,
and the glory of the lord shone
round about them,
and they were sore afraid.
And the angel said unto them,
'fear not, for behold I bring
you good tidings of great joy
which shall be to all people.
For unto you is born this day
in the city of David,
a savior, which is Christ
the lord.
And this shall be a sign
unto you...
Ye shall find the babe wrapped
in swaddling clothes
lying in a manger.'
and suddenly, there was with
the angel
a multitude of the heavenly
host
praising god and saying 'glory
to god in the highest,
and on earth peace, good will
toward men.'"
So... what do you think?
Stink, stank, stunk.
Just...
That's how it goes.
So this would
really allow us
to do some things,
you know?
Create twice
the inventory,
generate some revenue.
Maybe create some jobs.
Okay your silence
is killing me,
Mr. Robertson.
I don't know what
to say, Shelby.
Well say "yes."
That'll make us both
feel better.
I thought this meeting
was in reference
to a letter you received
about bringing your
accounts current, not...
Buying more land.
Now loaning you additional
money at this point...
Would be impossible.
Look, I know we're not
breaking the bank lately.
But that letter,
we thought it
was a notice,
just like all the others.
You have always worked
with us in the past.
I'm sorry...
But no.
We've been generous
in the past,
but with the takeover our
policies have changed.
That farm has been
in my family
for 40 years.
Longer than this bank
has been here.
I understand.
But now may be
the time for you
to try to find a way
to make sure that
your house and land
avoids foreclosure.
Hold on.
Certain interests are doing
everything they can
to convince the county
commission to allow
unprecedented development
in that area.
Now your property,
and the adjoining land,
would finally make
that happen.
Ralph Baxter.
He has been trying to build
that tourist trap
for years.
It's not gonna happen.
The town's not gonna
go for it.
It would change
who we are.
Look outside.
A lot has changed
over the years.
Well I'm not
agreeing to it.
It's our land,
it's our crop.
And it's certainly not his.
For now...
Until the bank has
to foreclose on you
for non-payment.
Then it goes to
the highest bidder.
And we both know
who that is.
All right,
all right folks.
Everybody settle down just a
little bit, if you would.
Again, I'm Dj Baley,
I'm your host tonight.
Please, listen to my radio show
on WMTN, that's 93.7.
#1 on the dial,
#1 in your hearts,
if you would.
Thank you for
your support.
But look a here.
I have got the grand prize
right here in my hand...
The big one.
This is a Mason Wyatt
autographed CD
and two tickets
to see him over
in Knoxville,
at the Knoxville center
for the arts.
Gonna be a live concert,
get to see the boy
in person.
Are we ready?
Get your tickets out.
Who wants some of this
right here, huh?
Yeah, yeah!
All right.
Here we go.
I'm gonna stir it
up good,
make sure it's fair.
Fair for everybody.
And there it is
right there.
Ready?
Excited?
Here it is.
1-5-3-4-2-7.
Got it!
Oh, miss Donna,
Donna Clark.
Come on up, Donna.
Come on up, Donna
and get your prize.
Hey.hey...
Didn't expect on seeing
your face here tonight.
Yeah, well, that makes
two of us.
I heard you
on the radio.
Oh, I sound like
Minnie Pearl.
I did.
It's so bad.
Are you nervous?
I am not the one
dancing.
All right,
everyone,
if you would please
take your places;
the show's about
to start.
All right now, let's hear it
for "dancin' country,"
the number one show in America!
It's time for
"dancin' country",
a one night
only special
to benefit children
around the world.
Tonight, your favorite country
music celebrities
will dance the night away.
And all for a good cause.
Tonight's show features
Charlie Wilkins, Mabel rimes,
Mason Wyatt and Shelly hunter.
Let's hear a little from our
first dancer, Mason Wyatt.
Come on.
I'm not perfect,
you know.
I don't claim to be.
Uh, but I do hope
my mistakes
don't define me.
I hope people give me
another chance, you know?
Can you give me
a sec?
Um, I'm doing this
because I want to show
people that I haven't
forgotten
where I came from.
I feel like I’m
misunderstood, you know?
More than anything.
I don't think
the bad boy thing,
that's not me.
I'm a good man.
I'm ready to go.
Let's dance
our faces off.
Oh my gosh.
You know, small town boy,
small town values.
I'm here to work.
Where's Mason? I work hard.
You know, that's
what I do.
Always.
I don't do anything
halfway.
Again, seriously?I'm excited.
It'll be fun;
I hope.
Are we done?
Up first, we have
Mason Wyatt and Lana Parker,
dancing for the Nashville
children's home.
Where's she going?
I don't know.
What is that?
A chicken dances
better than that.
He looks like
an idiot.
You used to date
him.
It's awful.
No, no, no, not
the Macarena!
This couldn't get
any worse.
It just did.
Oh, this is bad.
This is so bad.
Oh wow, don't do
that to Travolta.
Oh my word.
Is that
the cabbage patch?
I think it's
the tootsie roll.
I believe the young
folks call that
the Dougie.
Huh.oh.
We have that there...
Not to mention that.
Good evening
ladies.
It's too late
for coffee, daddy.
Oh, it's never
too late for coffee.
Unlike your mama,
I can always go to sleep
and wake up whenever
I need to.
What are y'all
working on?
We're in trouble,
daddy.
Eh, we've been there before.But not like this.
We might lose
the house.
We been there
before too.
It's winter;
I don't know
what to do.
Take a look at that.
As far as I know...
A child was born
in that manger.
Everything's gonna
be all right.
You're a strong woman,
Shelby belle.
We raised you that way.
But there's some things,
strong just don't fix.
You need a good dose
of hope.
And you're not gonna
get that
rooting through
them papers
in the middle
of the night.
Now the sun will
come up tomorrow,
I promise you,
just like it always does.
But what you need
tonight...
Is a good night's sleep.
Good night honey.
You too.
I'm gonna start mine
right now.
He's right.
We're fighters,
we'll make it.
Howdy brother bud.
Nine letter word
for a popular
Christmas dessert.
Fruitcake.no, no.
Doesn't fit,
tried it.
Mm.
Mincemeat.
Huh.
That'll be.
Mason Wyatt?
In the flesh,
Mr. Haygood.
Good morning, sir.
I thought my eyesight
was failing me,
but my ears were
shooting 20/20.
It seems like
they are.
It's good to see you, son.Good to see you.
Um, you watched
it then, I guess.
Watched what?
You didn't see it?
See what?
Eight letter word
for a seventies icon.
Travolta.
Bam.
Ha ha!
That'll work.
You didn't see it,
huh?
Thanks for that.
Oh yeah, we saw it.
We all saw it.
I wasn't me.
Well it sure looked
like you,
sounded like you,
strutted like a rooster
like you.
I don't know what
I was thinking.
Did the interview rounds
this morning...
Went looking
for somewhere
to Bury my head
in the sand.
Pine valley seemed like
the place, so...
Um...
Oh, go ahead, ask me;
Get it over with.
You saw me coming
from a mile away.
Oh, before you ever
came around the corner.
How is she?
Oh, she's Shelby.
Still got that fire?
Any chance she hates
me any less
after all these years?
Well, like I said,
she's still Shelby.
I can't blame her
if she does I guess.
She'll talk to you.
I doubt it's what you
want to hear,
but she's got some things
she wants to say to you.
You know, I tried
to reach out
to that girl
like 100 times
over the years
and nothing.
That first year...
Burning all those
photographs
sure did keep
the house warm.
Great.
Lord, we thank you
for this food,
for the nourishment
of our bodies
and for your provision
for us.
And please lord,
make sure we
take the time
to think of you
and your life,
during this
holiday season.
In Jesus' name
we pray, amen.
Amen to that.
I'll get it.
Is the gun case locked?
Always, why?Oh, no reason.
Hey, Shelby belle,
it's good to see you.
Hey!
Don't call
me that.
Um...
Let the man in...
Will ya?
He's gonna freeze
to death out there.
Daddy, will you
explain to me why
you're not surprised
that Mason Wyatt
is at our front door?
Because I asked him
to dinner.
Hey! Stop that!
Shelby, the world is
gonna keep spinning around.
Let the man in before
he freezes to death.
Thank y'all again for
inviting me tonight.
It's been a long time
since I sat down
for a home cooked meal.
Everything looks
incredible ma'am,
thank you.You're welcome.
I ran into Mason
over at bud's.
I figured well,
it wouldn't be a bad idea
for us to catch up over
some sweet tea.
Yes sir, yes sir.
I was just
running around
just getting
some stuff together.
It's good
to see you.
Well for your sake,
I hope you run better
than you dance.
I kind of teed that
one up for you, huh?
This is delicious.
I'm glad
you like it.
How long you gonna be
hanging around town, son?
You know, I’m
not really sure.
Yeah, Mason why
are you here?
I mean, I'm sure
there's some
selfish reason.
But I for one, would
really like to know
why Mason Wyatt
has decided to grace
our little town with
his presence.
And while you're at it,
you can stop with all
the sappy Okie dokie,
yes sirs and yes ma'am's.
Oh, did you want me
to give you an answer
or you just gonna
keep taking shots at me?
I was telling your dad
earlier I lost touch...
And I know that.
And I was thinking,
I was hoping that
spending some time
here back in town
would help jar my
memory.
Maybe even help me
write some new songs.
That would show
who I really am.
So, you're
right, Shelby.
I'm back in town
for selfish reasons.
And I told him we
had plenty of
room out here.
Daddy!
Hey, what do you
keep doing that for?
Not in my house.
You want honesty,
Mason, do you?
Well honestly,
we are about to
lose everything.
This house, the farm,
everything that we have
spent decades working for.
Do you know
how that feels?
You build something
with your hands and
have somebody come in
and take it from you?
We need money and
we need it quick,
so yeah you
can stay here
for a price.
I'm thinking
$4,000 a month.
But it's Christmas so...
I'm gonna charge you five.
Cat got your tongue?
I can do that.
Cash.
In advance.
Fine.great,
you can sleep in the barn.
If you'll excuse me.
Well, that went about
how I thought it would.
There's usually some method
to your daddy's madness.
I know mama.
It's gonna be some
Christmas for sure.
Daddy I
want to see Santa!
Okay honey, right after
we get our tree.
What's wrong
with you?
You really
haven't heard?
Heard what?
Mason is back
in town.
Mason?mason.
Ma'am...
Mason Wyatt?Mason Wyatt.
So have you seen him?Daddy, daddy...
Yeah, you could say that.
He slept in our
barn last night.
Ma'am...
Girl, you better stop
that lying to me.
I wish I was.
He sat down
for dinner
and everything.
To be a fly
on that wall.
I want to
see Santa!
How'd he look?
I didn't notice.
Oh please.
Ma'am.
Alright ladies, look at
this one, this is all yours.
Yay!
It's my best one.
Bye ladies,
merry Christmas!
Bye, merry Christmas!
Oh...
You
didn't notice?
I don't believe
that any longer
than it look you
to say it.
Because Mason Wyatt's
a lot of things, but
Hard to look at
ain't one of 'em.
Oh... your head
must be a mess.
It already was.
And Mason limping back
into town is the last
thing I need.
It's December 3rd,
and a brisk morning
out there.
22 more sleeps
until Christmas.
In honor of that, let's
give away 22 Christmas
sprinkle donuts from
JoJo's donut factory.
That's just two shy of two
dozen folks
and tell you what I'll do,
the first caller who can call
in and tell me the name of
Rudolph's girlfriend is going
to win themselves some donuts.
Caller #1, you're on the air.
Is it Clarice?
It looks like we've
got ourselves a Rudolph fan.
You just won darlin'.
Yee haw!
That's right,
that's right.
You get 22 Christmas
sprinkle donuts...
Cows.what?
The cows.
Probably blocking
the road up ahead.
I mean, you know
it happened just
last week.
You know I got
to say, this has...
This has got to
be my lucky day.
I mean running
into you way out
here like this.
How's that?
Well, it's funny
you should ask.
You see I got
this personal
matter I'd like
to discuss with you.
I mean, if you
got a minute.
Well, apparently I do.
Well that's
just great.
Here, let
me help you.
Alrighty.
You see...
I heard about
your problems.
And it's a
terrible shame.
Such beautiful
property.
Have you heard that
my company is purchasing
all the nearby
land around you?
Yup.
Well, I'd like to
help you out as well.
The Haygood farm deed,
I'd like to make an offer.
Yeah?mm-hmm.
You want to become
a farmer, do ya?
No, no, heck no.
I just want the land.
You wanna
develop it?
Yes, as a matter
of fact I do.
I think it'd help
out the town a lot.
It's not for sale.
Not yet.
You have a
nice day.
Knock knock.
Don't worry I
come in peace.
With cash.
Your dad told me
all about
the bank stuff
and times are
a little tight
for me too but...
I hope this helps.
I'll count it later.
I'm sure you will.
You won't even
know I'm here.
That ship has
sailed, Mason.
Okay, good talk.
Okay, you had
the strawberry,
there you go.
Thank you so much.
Have a good day.
Mm.right?
Satisfied.
I'm a buyer,
for Harrison's.
Supermarket?
Exactly.
We come
up here every year
to grab our tree
and on our way
to grab breakfast we
ran into this place.
Well great, we are
here every Saturday.
That's what I heard.
So I'm guessing
today is my lucky day.
More, okay.
Um, look, I'd love to take
several of these back
to the home office just to
see what the response is.
I mean we're always
looking for good product.
Okay, all right,
well that's great.
Just so you know
these are fresh
baked every morning.
Really?
Wonderful.
Well give me like...
Two of each.
Okay, thank you.
Ready for this?Yeah, thank you.
Here you go sir.
Got it, thank you.
You know what, let me
give you a brochure too,
you can check
out our farm.
We'll be in
touch, really.
Thank you.
Nice meeting
you, take care.
You always work
this early?
You always
sleep this late?
Sometimes.
Sometimes?
Sometimes you always
sleep this late?
You know
what I mean.
You've expanded.
What?
Not... not you,
the farm.
You've expanded
You look good, you
look great, Shelby.
Give me a tour?
Sure.
This is our farm.
Over here is where
we grow the blackberries.
The blueberries.
And then up there
is the strawberries.
Then in that house
up there is where we
make all our jams, and our
jellies, and our pies,
and it's also a place
where a scared,
17 year old
version of me
cried herself to sleep
on Christmas Eve
and every other night
for about 6 months
waiting for
her boyfriend to call,
or come home, or write
like he promised...
And I would try to
explain that to you Mason,
I really would...
But I just don't think
that dog will hunt.
So finally, at the end
of our property, out there,
that is where
I'm about to go.
Hey Mason...
That over there...
That's the barn.
That's where all
the animals sleep.
Baxter...
By unanimous consent
the commission
has approved a plan
to limit left turns
on Wilson road
between the hours of
7 A.M. and 9 A.M.
So that the crossing
guards may do their job.
All right.
Last order of business,
the town will hear
from Mr. Ralph Baxter.
Good afternoon.
Uh, just a little
clarification Mr. Baxter,
nothing you're
presenting here today
has officially
been submitted
beyond here, correct?
That is correct.
All right,
let's hear it.
Thank you.
Now most, if not
all of you know
about our plan
to build
a visitor center,
restaurant,
and business park on
highway 49, near
the Haygood farm.
The benefits will be many,
and they have been
detailed in the plan
that I have submitted
through the proper channels.
However, I think it's
important to know
that we may only get
the one opportunity
to take our case
to the people who
that can make
things happen.
So I cannot stress to
you enough,
the importance
of having
the full support of
this great town.
I think... I think
that we can all agree,
that revenue sharing
on this property...
I don't.
Excuse me?
I'm sorry but I don't
agree with Mr. Baxter,
not one little bit.
Shelby I don't think
we're ready to discuss
this from the floor.
Well, I can't
sit here and
listen to this.
No, no, Mr. Mayor,
I welcome miss Haygood's
constructive criticism.
After all, our goal
is to provide a service
to this town so
you go right ahead,
little lady,
go right ahead.
All right, Shelby.
Whatcha got?
We have always
preserved our
way of life.
Our mountains.
Developing that
kind of land,
bringing in these
kind of stores,
it's gonna change
who we are.
And there's something
so special about
living off the
beaten path.
About a simple life.
Well said.
But, let me just say,
you may refuse
to evolve Ms. Haygood...
But that doesn't
mean the rest of us
have to grow
stagnant with you.
I think everybody here knows
that the significant
portion of your
business is...
Down the mountain.
While the rest of us live
and work here in this town.
And this plan
provides more revenue.
More jobs.
And that is something
this town sorely needs.
That farm...
That is the only
home I have ever
known and I am
not going to sit
quietly and let
him take it.
So that's what this
is all about, huh?
Hm?
That's what
this is about.
She doesn't care
about the well-being
of the people
of this town.
She only cares about
what's best
for the Haygood family.
No, no, I care more
about this town
and these people
than you could
ever pretend to.
I'm sure.
Of course you do.
Mr. Mayor if I may,
I'd like to submit
the full proposal.
And with the town's
support of this proposal,
I will then
be submitting
it to the
proper authorities.
The town accepts the
submission of
Mr. Baxter's proposal.
And we'll plan to put it
to a vote as soon as those
who wish to...
Have had a chance
to review the materials.
Thank you Mr. Mayor.
We are not
quitting.
Merry Christmas.
Can you wear that
turtleneck tonight,
the red one?
How much?!
How much
do we owe?
Is someone with you?
Sorry, Darla, this'll
only take a minute.
Shelby?
Is that you?
Yes.
Darla, honey, I’m
gonna have to call
you back.
Oh Shelby
darling please, please
erase this from
your memory.
I will.
Thanks.
Merry Christmas.
And
Glenn honey, you better
call me when
Shelby leaves.
$41,501 to bring your
line of credit current.
$22,148 to bring your
second mortgage current.
That is...
$63,649 and...
Both are due in 60 days.
"About half
past ten the cracked bell
at the small
church began to ring.
And presently the
people began
to gather for
the morning sermon.
The Sunday school children
distributed themselves about
the house and occupied
pews with their parents,
so as to be
under supervision.
Aunt Polly came,and Tom,
and sid and Mary
sat with her.
Tom being placed
next to the aisle
in order that he
might be
as far away from
the open window
and the seductive
outside summer
scenes as possible."
Hey hun.
Well... I told the
bank we're keeping
the land.
That sounds about right.
You think so?
Yup.
Now we just gotta
figure out a way
to do that.
And we will.
He's not here.
That's good,
I don't care.
You keep saying
it and you might
get an echo.
Mm-hm.
Can I ask you
a question?
After all these years
the hate that you feel
for that fella hadn't
even abated
a little bit?
He made a mistake
years ago,
and he's been
trying to make up
for it off and
on ever since.
But would you tell me...
What has this hate
gotten you?
You know...
It ain't baggage if
you don't carry it around.
I remember seeing the
two of you together,
and I don't think I've
ever seen you happier.
We just want
you to be happy.
I'm happy.
This farm
makes me happy.
This way
of life.
I'm happy.
Where were we?
Well, Tom was sittin' on the
aisle away from the window...
I'm sorry was
that too loud?
No.
Sounds nice.
You hurt her once
when you left.
And I didn't know if
she would get over it.
Now you're back...
And I know she won't,
if it happens again.
I'm asking you not
to do that.I...
No please, just
hear my words.
You have my word.
Okay.
Good.
go and tell it
on the mountain
over the hills
and everywhere
go and tell it
on the mountain
that Jesus Christ
is born
Go tell it on the mountain
Well I don't
understand
because this
says that we're
Pre-approved.
Yes, yes sir.
Mm-hm.
So we're Pre-qualified,
but not Pre-approved.
I understand completely,
you can stop talking now.
Yes, yes ma'am, I know
what debt to income ratio is.
Thank you for
your time.
Thank you,
okay, I understand.
Thank you.
Thank you, thank you
for your time.
Morning sir.
Mornin' son.
Sleep well?
Yeah, short.
Rooster.
Yup.
The older I get
the more I dislike
that creature.
I do miss these mountains
though.
Mm-hm.
How long's it
been since your
folks passed?
12 years
for daddy and...
9 for mama.
Yeah, I think
that's the last
time we saw you.
Had a girl on
each arm as
I remember.
Yes sir.
I expect that
picture has burned
into Shelby's mind.
Your folks were
good people, Mason.
They were proud
of you.
Proud of your success.
Maybe.
You want
some help?
Always.
Step right up.
All right, thank you.
It's been awhile.
So, don't judge
me on this alone.
A little out of
practice, aren't you?
Go and set it up again.
Best decision
I ever made.
Overhead is higher,
but profits have
nearly doubled.
I tell ya, pick
your own is
the way to go.
We got a petting
zoo over there,
goats, sheep, rabbits,
horseback riding
all day long.
Chuck wagon rides
in the evening.
Year round store
for the produce.
I tell you it's been great.
Why don't you go
find your mom.
But uh...
You obviously
didn't come here
to talk about that.
Well, no sir.
You know the 50 acres
we have out back?
Sure. It's
good land.
Yeah, we think so.
It's always produced
great crop for us.
I was wondering
if you thought
about expanding?
We could lease it to
you for a season or two.
Well, I haven't really
considered a sublease.
You said yourself,
it's good land.
You won't have to put
much time into it.
Be a lot more
inventory for
your store.
Tell you what...
You bring me a proposal,
I'll think about
it and give you
a quick decision.
All right.
Thank you sir.Sure.
It's a start.
Yup, I feel good.
It's peaceful here.
Just what I need
to recalibrate actually.
Ready go back out...
Soon as you find some gigs.
Great.
All right well,
make some calls,
I want to start
as soon as possible.
Thanks man.
Mornin'.
Morning.
This place looks good
on you Shelby belle.
Shelby.
Mm-hm.
I missed it here.
Missed the people.
Missed the culture.
Yeah, well that's
kind of funny because
you've been here what?
5 days?
A week?
Spent your whole time
on this farm
licking your wounds,
gettin' in my way.
Haven't been out in town,
being a man of the people.
But you always were,
"all hat and no cattle",
Mason so
whatever flips
your pancake.
Okay.
Listen I saw the note
inside from the bank.
About how much y'all owe.
I can't do much but I
thought maybe at least
I could make a
few phone calls.
No.
No?no.
Suit yourself.
Wow.
Oh yup, I called Joe son's
corner in mount olive,
biggest order
in years.
Good job.
That's
Mason Wyatt.
It's him,
it's really him!
How ya doing?
Hi.
How many?
Just the one.
Hey Mason!
Come here, we're
just telling
lies and chewing
the fat.
Good to see
everybody.
Now you know
mayor bud there.
Of course,
the puzzle man.
And this is
coach bullet,
the meanest man in town
and also tight
as dick's hat there.
Coach I had you
for gym
in junior high
actually.
Yeah I remember.
You never could
climb the rope.
Yeah, I still can't
You remember Baley?
He's on the radio
as we speak.
17 minute
commercial free.
And as a matter
of fact,
Perry Como has
two minutes and
28 seconds
left boys.
I've enjoyed it.
Gotta go.
Good to see you.
Hey, I'd love
to have you
on the radio
sometime son,
come and see me,
all right.
We'll do it.
All right Baley.
And this is
cousin Larry
over here.
We call him chipper
because he's such
a big fan
of the braves.
Oh yeah, me too.
I got to sing
the national anthem
at Turner field
one time.
Oh yeah?
Any slip ups?
No, but I wrote
the lyrics on
my hand so...
Well grab a seat
and get some
grub in you.
Yup, it's him all right.
Wow...
Okay, well um...
Let me get you
a menu.
No, no, that's
all right.
What's good?
Oh, we're stuck
with the oatmeal
and fruit cup,
but uh...
If I was you I’d just
live a little.
I'd go for the
smoky mountain breakfast
with a side of pancakes,
you can't lose.
All right,
smoky mountain breakfast
with a side
of pancakes please.
Um, any fruit
on the pancakes?
We can do
blueberries...
Blackberries...
Peaches...
Strawberries...
Raspberries...
Elderberries...
Boysenberries...
You name it.
Um, blueberries.
And how would you
like your eggs?
Fried.
Medium, so that
the yolk is running
and nothing else.
Got it.
Ham, bacon,
or sausage?
Bring him a little
of all three
so we can
all have a whiff.
Biscuits and gravy
or grits?
Grits.
Oh, that's fancy.
Thank you.
Um, could I also get
some black coffee,
if you don't mind.
Yes sir, yes.
I think you made
her day.
No more like
her year.
I don't think
I've ever made
that many decisions
about food
in my entire life.
My mama says you dance
like a chicken.
But I think
you did real good.
Thank you.
Sweet girl...
Blind as a bat,
but a sweet girl.
I'll see you fellas
on Friday.
Alrighty, Wade.
Got your guitar
with you?Always.
Good, let's go.
Where we goin'?
I need your help
on a little something
that Shelby cooks up
every Christmas.
All right.
There is a rumor...
There is?Mmm-hmm,
mmm-hmm.
What is it?
There is a rumor
that Santa
is on his way here.
He is?!He is!
Wait, wait,
I think I hear...
Did you hear that?I do, I heard it too.
Did you guys hear?
I think I heard
his reindeer.
Ho, ho, ho!
Santa!
Merry Christmas!
Ho, ho, ho!
Santa Claus,
and we got Mrs. Claus.
Merry Christmas!
Well has everyone been a
good little boy or girl?
Dashing through the snow
in a one horse open sleigh
o'er the fields we go
laughing all the way
ha, ha, ha!
Bells on Bob tails ring
making spirits bright...
You know this is one of my
favorite days of the year.
Yeah?
Seeing all the smiles
on these kids' faces.
Jingle bells, jingle bells
jingle all the way...
You know you still got it.What?
That.
That little sparkle
in your eye
every time you
look at him.
Same as you
always have.
Yeah well that spark
burned me once.
I'm not gonna let it
burn me again.
Yes ma'am.
Are you Mason Wyatt?
I am Mason Wyatt,
yeah.
Miss Shelby says
you sing really pretty
but you dance...
I know she says I dance
like a chicken.
Nope, she says
you dance
like a one
legged goat.
Yeah well.
She also says
you're kinda cute.
Ooooh!
Really?
Well I'll tell
you what.
Can you tell miss Shelby
that the one legged goat
says thank you.
Okay, I will.
Okay.
You guys wanna sing
some more?
Yes!Are you ready?
Yes!
I need you to clap.
Can you clap?
Here we go.
Dashing through the snow
in a one horse open sleigh
o'er the hills we go
laughing all the way
ha ha ha
bells on Bob-tails ring...
What?
Oh no.
Morning.
Shelby.
Where- where
is everybody?
I had to lay 'em
all off 'til spring.
The bank called
in my line yesterday,
and it took all
the cash we had
just to keep this place
from foreclosure.
I just hope we can
start back up
when the new season begins.
Listen, I'm sorry.
We won't be in any position
to expand anytime soon.
I understand.
Yes sir,
the reports
are generating now.
I'll have them to you
by end of business.
Okay.
Yes sir, okay.
Sorry, uh.
How can I help you,
Shelby?
I just left
the Miller farm.
Is it true
that y'all
called in
their note?
I'm not at Liberty
to discuss that.
But we have had
to make
some tough decisions
this quarter.
What about us?
I'm sorry.
You should be receiving
your letter today.
What does that mean?
If you can't bring
your account current,
we'll have to begin
foreclosure proceedings.
By when?January 2nd.
I'm sorry, Shelby.
I just want to
let you know
that pine valley
savings and loan
appreciates
your business.
Been a pleasure working
with you over the years.
You know if you're gonna
do business with him,
you're gonna want to
keep both hands
on your wallet.
Ha.
That's nothing.
Uh, like I said,
we appreciate
your business.
We'll get that
paperwork out-
Less than three weeks.
What are we gonna do?
You talk to
the grocery woman?
Mm-hmm.
She said she can't
do anything
until after
the holidays.
Hm.
I've got an idea.
What?
Mason.
Mason?
No, he doesn't have
that kind of money.
And if he did,
we wouldn't take
it from him.
No, no, no!
I'm not talking
about that.
I've got another
idea.
It'll work Shelby.
Daddy, I can't, no! It's a good idea.
Absolutely not, no.
No! Ugh.
Everything okay?
We got the final notice
on the house.
We have until
January 2.
Okay.
My father has some...
Hair brained idea.
All right,
let's hear it.
He thinks that we
should have a concert.
Benefit concert here
on Christmas Eve.
And I mean,
I cannot believe
I'm getting ready
to ask you this.
Mason...
Would you play here
on Christmas Eve?
That's it?
Please?
No, I mean is that
all you need?
Yeah.
Of course.
Shelby, I'd be
happy to help.
All right.
So this is
a business deal,
and we'll split
the proceeds.
Okay, what about
merchandise?
I don't know,
what about it?
How do we
split that?
Whatever's
standard.
Okay, standardly
I get to
keep it all.
Oh, well okay.
I'm just messing
with you.
Whatever you want,
Shelby.
Honestly, I’m-
I really am
happy to help.
Great.
So we got a deal?
You bet.
Pleasure doing
business with you.
This place hasn't
changed much.
No.
How old were you
when you first
came through here?
16.
No.yeah,
I had just played my
first show at Harper's.
July 4th.
Okay guys,
here we go in 3, 2...
Okay, that was David bowie
and bing Crosby
with "little drummer boy,"
one of my favorites.
Mine too.Really?
Yeah, I love the mix
of the old and the new
with David bowie
and bing Crosby.
Yeah, good, good.
Hey, if some of you
listeners out there
think you might
recognize that voice
then you are
probably correct.
Joining us today in studio
is our special guest...
Mr. Mason Wyatt.
Welcome.good to be here.
Oh, it's good
to have you.
Good to have you.
And joining him as well,
is miss Shelby Haygood,
a local business owner.
Good to have you.
Oh, uh hey-
hey y'all.
I know you all have
come up today
to talk about
an exciting event
that's about
to take place.
But I can't resist
talking a little
music first,
if that's okay.
That sounds good.
We just found out,
of course,
that you're a
bing Crosby fan.
What about some
of your other
Christmas songs
you like?
I love all
Christmas music
to be honest
with you.
I'm a big fan
in general.
But Johnny Mathis.
Yeah.
Perry Como,
Andy Williams.
Uh, Dolly Parton.
Amen.
Darlene love, "please come
home for Christmas."
There you go.
John Lennon,
"happy Christmas."
Uh, John Mellencamp,
"I saw mama kissing
Santa Claus."
Yeah.
John Denver
and the muppets.
Oh, man yeah.That's the best.
Uh yeah, the boss
of course,
"Santa Claus is
coming to town."
Oh, preach it
brother, yeah.
But still my favorite
to this day
is Nat King Cole singing,
"o holy night."
Really?
Yeah, yeah.
My mom used to put that
on every Christmas Eve.
She would break out the vinyl
and put that record on.
And I still...
Can't listen to that song
without breaking down,
to be honest.
Which is why I’m
so excited that
we're doing this concert,
to honor Christmas,
which my mom loved
so much.
Well I'm glad you
brought that up, Mason.
Why don't we let
our listeners in
on what's going on
with you guys?
So what's cooking?
Shelby,
what's cooking?
Uh, well uh, um...
On December 24th
we're having
a concert
at the farm.
You remember when we
used to do those downtown,
we would put on those
Christmas concerts
and those cantatas?
Yeah, yeah...
Chet Adkins came
to one of those.
Doc Watson as well.
Exactly, right.
Well I love those,
I miss those.
I think a lot of you
guys do too,
and so I wanted to do
'em again.
And just kind of wanted
to bring things back
to the way they used
to be.
With that in mind,
I thought
one of the best things
we could do
is to help out
one of our own
who's in need
this Christmas.
And so, we're putting
on a benefit concert
for the classic
Haygood farm,
where things have
stayed simple.
And we want to keep
it that way.
So the event
starts early.
You guys will still be
able to go to church
later on that
night.
And hang the stocking
the way
it's supposed
to be hung.
I think we open
the doors at 10 am,
and you've got all kinds
of craziness planned.
Why don't you tell
them about that?
Uh, yeah,
we've got hayrides,
a petting zoo.
Uh...
Food for everyone.
Santa's gonna be
there.
And Mason's going on
in the afternoon.
And it's a very fair
price too, I may say.
Am I right?
Oh, we think so.
It's $15 a person,
and kids under five
are free.
We think it's
a great way
to spend a very
important day
with the people
that you care about.
I agree,
I agree.
Let's give our
listeners a chance
to win some
tickets now,
if you'll be our
ninth caller
and can tell us
one of your
favorite
Christmas songs,
then we will get you
some tickets.
And we're gonna
talk Mason
into doing a live number
for us now,
if you don't mind.
What are you gonna
do for us?
I'm gonna do "o come all
ye faithful".
Good.
O come all ye faithful
joyful and triumphant
o come ye, o come ye
to Bethlehem
come and behold him
born the king of angels
o come let us adore him
o come, let us adore him
Christ the lord
You positive?
You can get those flights?
So it's official?
All right, give me
10 minutes,
I'll call you back.
Good morning, son.
Morning
everybody.
Good morning.
We were just recounting
that church picnic
we took down by
Robert's creek.
Do you remember that?
Oh I remember.
Oh, you know,
please tell me
you are not going around
still telling that lie.
No, it's the truth,
but I do
tell the story
every time I get
a chance, yeah.
Okay, maybe it
wasn't a lie,
but it's a drastic
exaggeration.
My favorite kind.
I tell it like
I saw it.
Well you need to get
your eyes checked then.
Oh yeah, I didn't
see you
running out
of the forest
like some bear
was chasing you.
It was a brisk walk,
I will give you that.
Oh you come bustin'
outta there full throttle.
Run over that
blanket that's
loaded down
with tater salad.
Daddy!
And I forget um,
Shelby,
was that a bear?
Stop, now you know
it wasn't.
So stop.
What was it now,
can you help me?
It was the biggest bunny
rabbit I've ever seen.
You were runnin'
for your life
from a bunny, Shelby.
Well listen,
I saw eyes and ears
and it was
coming at me
and if I had to do it
again I would.
It was a very
big bunny,
I will give you that.
All right, y'all need
to stop okay?
Just stop.
Hey can I talk to you out
front for a second?
Yes please, gladly.
They look cute together,
don't they?
You all right?Yeah.
What's up?
Uh...
I have an offer.
You have an offer.
Yeah, I have an offer
to play in Seattle
tomorrow night.
It's a big deal.
Uh, so you're
leaving?
You're not gonna
be here?
I'll be here, it's...
One of the headliners
broke his leg skiing
or something
and the promoters
want me to come out
and play tomorrow night
and then pick it back up
on the 27th.
So, I'd fly out
a few hours,
play the show
and then come back
first thing the morning
of the 24th.
At the latest.At the latest,
yeah.
I do this all
the time,
all right?
This is a good offer,Shelby.
The one I've been
waiting for.
You know I need
the money
and I need
the fresh start.
Mason, just stop.
You know, we've been
here before.
You leaving, promising
to come back.
This is different.
How's it different?
This place means
everything to me
and you know that
and you're still choosing
to leave.
I mean this is it,
this was our
last hope.
I'll be back.
You have said that
to me before.
I promise,
I'll be here.
So stupid.
I'm stupid,
you know.
Stupid for believing
in you,
stupid for thinking
that you've changed.
You know what, Mason?
You do what you always do,
which is whatever is best
for Mason Wyatt
and I'll do what I do.
Which is expect nothing
from you.
Imagining that's my head?
I turned them down.
Shelby I...
Never should've
left you
in the first
place.
I don't know why
I didn't come back.
Why I waited so long
to write.
Call.
So many decisions
that I've made,
things that I've
done...
Honestly I don't know
why I've done them.
I wish to god I could
take them back.
But I can't.
I'm here to stay.
I can do this
on my own, Mason.
I don't need you.
Yeah, I know.
I need you.
Always have.
Always will.
Uh, so...
Now I'm gonna go slink
back to my room...
'Cause I have a concert
to get ready for.
Good morning
smoky mountains
and merry Christmas Eve.
It's a beautiful day
in these mountains
and it's a beautiful day
to be alive folks.
Only one more day until
Christmas morning
and the big guy
hops down the chimney.
We are live here today
at the Haygood farm
for a Christmas Eve
to remember.
We have quite
the turn out today,
people have come from...
Well all up and down
these smoky mountains
to help one of their own.
Today is truly a miracle
that can only happen
on Christmas Eve.
You can truly feel
the spirit of Christmas
out here folks and we've even
got a Christmas raffle
with a prize you don't
want to miss.
Now if you aren't here then uh
you're really missing out
so come on over
and give us a visit.
All the proceeds will go to
saving the Haygood farm
and all those wonderful pies
that you all love so much.
So, what do you think about
all this miss Shelby?
Uh... it's amazing.
It is amazing,
isn't it?
It is, I mean
I just...
It means
so much to me
and to my family.
I love this town.
And I love
these people.
Yeah.
And we love Christmas.We do love Christmas.
We do.
So no matter what happens
here today,
you know this is going
to be a day
that we won't
ever forget.
So thank you.
Oh you're welcome honey,
you're very welcome,
no problem.
Thank all of you.
And now ladies and
gentlemen,
Mr. Mason Wyatt!
Thank you guys so much.
It's good to be back
where it all began.
I want you guys
to remember something.
There's always hope.
You can always come home.
So with that in mind,
I thought we'd start off
with a little seasonal music,
is that all right?
joy to the world
the lord is come
let earth receive her king
let every heart
prepare him room
and heaven and nature sing
and heaven, and heaven and
nature sing
I'm sorry darlin'.
It's okay.
Well?
Nope.
Thank you
for everything.
It's the Harrison woman!
What?the grocery lady.
She's right here.
Hello?
Uh...
Yes ma'am.
Yes, we can do that.
Yeah we could do that.
Thank you.
O... okay.
Yes...
We can have an order out
that soon, absolutely.
Thank you.
Yes, merry Christmas
to you, too.
What, what?
She... she saw one
of our flyers
and then heard the concert
on the radio.
And, and?
And she loves our story,
and Harrison's loves
our story!
She wants to help,
she's gonna put us
in all her stores,
she's gonna turn
in a v.O.,
we're gonna get the money
the day after tomorrow.
That's wonderful.
Oh thank you lord.
Let's go celebrate inside,
it's cold out here!
I wanna change
my Facebook status.
Amen to that.
Tag that banker
fella in it.
Shelby, um, I was
wonderin'.
Uh oh.
No, I was wonderin'
if you would dance
with me.
I think dancin' with you
would be hazardous
to my health.
Fair enough,
I just...
Mason.
I'm kidding.
I'd love to.
Ready?
Always.
No matter how hard life is,
no matter how much
we've messed up...
Or how broken our lives
have become...
At Christmas...
Good things can happen.
So when it comes to it...
I believe a baby was born
in that manger.
Merry Christmas
Shelby belle.
Merry Christmas.
I believe in Christmas.
I believe in hope.
silent night
holy night
all is calm
all is bright
round yon virgin
mother and child
holy infant
so tender and mild
sleep in heavenly
peace
O come all ye faithful
joyful and triumphant
o come ye, o come ye
to Bethlehem
come and behold him
born the king of angels
o come let us adore him
Christ the lord
Come and behold him
born the king of angels
o come let us adore him
Christ the lord