Thanks.
Tickets, please.
Here.
Thanks.
Your ticket, please.
Are you a student?
- Not yet.
- Your chin has deceived me.
- It's beautiful embroidered like a student.
- A habit before the baccalaureate.
I see she writes something on her.
"Per aspera ad astra".
School Decision.
Young... in the adjacent compartment is
an archbishop, in the flesh and bone!
Have you seen him?
Then do not waste time, young man!
- Here's how nice it is!
- Yes.
He doesn't see us.
- That's how it starts.
- What will happen?
I'm coming back here all the more often.
Night...
- Sometimes even the day.
- Soon I will go to the world.
- I know everything...
- And what's waiting for me in my life?
Maybe I know that too, but
I can't say anything.
It's better not to know.
I'm coming back...
I forgot my chin in the compartment.
One embroidered?
You will not lose it, nor will
you change it with another.
Wicio!
- Come here.
- Mama, what the hell are you?
Come on, boy, come here.
- You're beautiful.
- Yes, Mama...
- You are the most beautiful.
- You make me leave...
Here's a birthday present, son.
Mama, and if I can't
get to the bitch?
- Can't you?
- Everything is possible.
- You must always be first.
- Don't talk nonsense, Mom.
You will be a great doctor,
a great professor.
You will care for us and heal
all, the poor and the rich...
Kings and beggars, you will care for...
- Speaking brings bad luck.
- Only the weak are scared.
Jadzia, my little girl...
What do you think, how
long will this agony last?
It will not last long, believe
me, the sky is merciful.
If that's what you say!
If that were the case!
But what's up, boy?
- A student cap.
- So Wicio is at the university?
- Nobody tells me anything?
- Not yet, Dad.
Now he's just getting the baccalaureate.
- He's in medicine in autumn.
- At Autumn?
Thank God!
I will not live until then.
Hello.
Please go to Colonel
Nalecz with a telegram.
In the Military District.
I can not leave home.
He's arrived recently.
But he's tired, he's just dropped.
Tired ? Dear neighbour, all
the city envies for you.
Take my bike, and see
to sign the receipt.
I forgot the iron.
I have to go. Thank you.
Go, Wicio.
Maybe you can give people a joy.
A good news.
- Come to us?
- I have a telegram.
Come in, please.
- Who's Zosia?
- Someone from the mail with a telegram.
Where is it?
Mama, Dad comes!
Mammy, tomorrow dad comes!
I had a feeling.
I dreamed of a train running
on the ground, without rails.
Signs receipt.
Pass, please, and the exact
time of your receipt.
- Let's give him something.
- Give him 50 thick ones.
But here he writes "arrive", not "arrive".
I haven't noticed the joy.
- Let's give him a zloty.
- Too bad people.
- Mother...
- I'll be 50.
- I'm going...
- Yeah, I get it.
Ladies, thank you and I
wish you a good night.
Thanks for the junk, I
hope to enrich myself.
Excuse me!
Did you see what happened?
Maybe I'm gonna fuck
you, how about?
Maybe it will be an unhappy love
that will bring death to me.
- Wicio, come tell me something.
- All right, what are you doing here?
- We're making it easy.
- And something else?
- We're doing a Japanese theatre, come on.
- I'm not in the mood.
Come on, come and even
ask me to bring you.
Mr. Wicio!
It's been a while since we haven't seen each other.
The mother sends you to the country
so you don't mess up the girls here.
We wouldn't give
up such a knight.
Don't forget I'm your fiancé.
Lowa, these are just empty words.
- What do I have of that?
- What do you mean?
Body Pleasure...
emancipation...
Stop, shameless!
Stop it!
Do we play or not play?
Take a look, it's jealous!
According to Wicio...
Once again, please
put that plate...
Not a little fucked up!
Seduce students...
Mama, don't be yours.
Better go to bed.
God... what a sad sad!
What a misfortune!
What a terrible year!
It is said to be war.
Every year this is said.
Did not you even
create a friend?
- Why me and not you?
- I have one.
- You? Who are you stupid?
- I know I do.
- Show me her picture.
- Now, at night?
- What are you watching?
- These old people are over 30,
They're not even young, but
they're still in love, right?
- Yeah, like any of us.
- Do you know anything?
I have so much energy in me
that I feel I'm bursting.
- Bring him back to Kiezun's bike.
- Yeah, I'm going.
Excuse me, I didn't know you were here.
Please, it's a free place.
You can sit down.
Thank you, but I go down to the first halt.
- You'll cool down.
- How come I haven't seen you before?
What if you ride this train?
- One and a half years.
- Impossible!
I haven't seen you before.
- Yesterday I saw you first.
- All you can.
In this winter, you were beaten with snow
and thumped me down the aisle, though.
I don't think so, I would
have remembered you.
And yet it is, but it does nothing.
Don't say that, it's not true.
- Do not do anything?
- No, I didn't notice you
Here we go down!
Colonia Halt!
Goodbye.
So, you've waited for them.
I have been watching you.
- Whichever ? Alina?
- I do not know if I like something or someone.
- Medicine, maybe...
- Are we?
- On what ?
- That you conquered yourself.
- Who?
- Alina.
What name...
- You'll like your name...
- What do you want from me?
- Are you jealous?
- Maybe... Well, are we betting?
- On what ?
- I do not know, if I win I'll ask you something.
Lowka, I think you crazed her.
- You just met her...
- He's been here for over a year?
- Possibly. Well, do we bet?
- What can I get from you?
What I'd like to gain from you.
Let's hit the palm!
What will be, will be.
It's done.
What is it, don't you recognize me again?
Come with me, let me spend the
night at your mistress...
Let me in at least...
- What a luck, daddy!
- All right, little girl.
What a good thing!
Yes, tomorrow we'll get up early.
Let's have some tea, though.
- Let's have some tea, though.
- Yes.
Just leave me inside,
don't make me hurt.
Either you eat me or I get away.
I know it's ugly what I do, but I
swear it's the first and last time.
What the hell is he doing?
It's all for nothing...
In vain everything.
Light up again!
You have nothing to lose!
You hear me?
I command you all my strength!
First and Last Time...
Goodbye, buddy!
Rex! Come here, Rex!
Cunning them in the garden?
You mess up with me, haianao!
- Who's there ?
- Excuse me, I lost myself...
Where?
We were looking for the road to the cemetery.
No, sir, this leads to
the military district.
My mother died on a foreign
land, but he wanted it
to rest in the cemetery on the edge
of the forest next to the church.
But there is no church there.
Exact.
And no cemetery.
But it will be after the war.
Mr. Wicio, are you accompanying me a little?
I hear a radio.
You, don't you?
How do you know me?
I met you, but I don't
remember how well.
Please accompany me a little, if you are kind.
Today I'm crazy and I'm cured.
Yes, I know...
You will love yourself with dissipation, until...
- Until ?
- You'll see for yourself, it's not much.
- How do you know?
- From what I remember...
How many brains are there!
Soon to get bored.
Who are you?
Witek, I have been looking for you all night.
- What do you want ?
- Greta is very sick.
- Why don't you call a doctor?
- At this time?
- He's got a fever.
- I don't know.
But do not you learn all day ?!
- Are you crazy?
- You've healed Lowka.
- He was just constipated!
- Don't you help me?
- I can't.
- It's lazy!
If you want, I can consult
it, but what use.
Are you asleep?
- Wicio came to see you.
- But I have nothing.
I have been drinking some teas.
Until tomorrow I'll pass.
Come on, sit well.
- Say...
- Bring it. Give me a secondary watch.
Do you want to chew tomorrow?
Give me your hand.
No temperature.
It couldn't, it was like a stove.
She wanted to call you.
I didn't want it!
How is it!
Raise your shirt, immortal!
- I don't want !
- Come on, come on, Berlin!
"Are you just listening, or are you ashamed?"
Come on, fuck it!
I cannot hear anything.
But something else?
- Anything else, leave me cold.
- What you said ?
- Ninic, I think he has nothing.
- Doesn't he have anything?
- Is that healthy?
- So it seems.
- You just knew.
- Then why did you want a doctor?
You're a fool.
It's okay with your head!
- Pay attention !
- I don't care what you are!
Aren't you ashamed?
Dare to make me a German?
How scary!
Look what my eyes are.
I just have to change
this idiot name.
What's wrong, son?
- Hell!
- What you said ?
- I don't understand!
You better stop, prusacule!
It's been so many years and you
haven't taught this language yet!
What do you want me to tell you?
Wladislaw Drewnowski?
Wladislaw Drewnowski, is not it?
- Do you know anything?
- No.
- You're doing well.
- I'm fine?
- Yes, you!
- You going crazy, Engel?
Not Engel, Wladek!
What did you mean by that?
What this means?
- Fuck you!
- What's up with you?
Listen to me!
Hear my commandments!
I'm a mean, cold, lover of love.
But if I still courage,
you have to listen to me
Listen to me, you must
come to me immediately.
I have been ticking today for you.
Number up to ten.
One, two, three, four, five, six...
Seven, seven and a half,
eight, eight and a quarter...
I order you for the
last time to come here.
If you do not do what I say, you'll
be spending your whole life.
Either... it means I do
not have to command you.
Please, then, I beg you with all
my heart, listen to me and come.
"And if not, I will curse
you, you will see!"
Hello.
- You kissed me, and I came.
- But I didn't want to...
How, I just felt the fluid...
- And then I was gone.
- That... that's a mistake.
- I know, but I brought you the book.
- What book?
- "Notions of Chemistry". Don't you recognise her?
- No...
- No... I don't know.
- But it's yours.
Maybe he doesn't remember.
Anyway, thank you.
I had the impression that
you were waiting for me.
Ced I dreamed you last night.
On the word!
I don't know how exactly, but
I have dreamed you exactly.
It's an error...
You said that again.
But I am a very good environment.
It's strange, isn't it?
I was sick and I left
the last two hours.
- It's the first time I come here.
- And for the first time.
You see?
It's a weird thing,
Yeah, it's very weird.
- Can I stay a little longer? I'm tired.
- Sure you do.
- You haven't even seen me before?
- I'm a busy man, I work a lot.
- I want to study medicine.
- And my father is a doctor.
Your cousin studying?
- Right, but he broke his studies.
- Has he interrupted his studies?
An unfortunate love story...
- I'm an egocentric.
- Here?
Nothing... sin.
Not at all, I'm a real monster...
a selfish one.
- Like me.
- Impossible.
Then we're going to bother each other.
Yeah... do you think so?
- Where did you lose your book?
- Where did you find it?
Don't we go down to town?
- We can get rid of the unseen.
- I'm lucky.
- So good.
- It's good and bad.
- Why is it bad?
- Because luck is being paid.
And how do you plan to pay?
Once, with a high price.
I'm going to die young.
- It's up to you now to want to die young.
- And you?
And I, but I can't, I
still have some problems.
To show you a great place.
Really... it's nice here.
I'm not breathing anymore.
God, how beautiful she is!
- Did you know I like the ice cream?
- Not me.
Take yours too.
Don't ruin my pleasure.
- Nothing can convince me.
- I throw it on you.
So, life is not the worst thing...
May...
I often change my opinions.
I'll think about it.
- What are you thinking about now?
- To you, of course.
It's not worth it.
I apologise...
Don't do anything. It's late.
I have to go back. You?
I have to stay, but I still
have little to do with it.
- I think I was terrible.
- Don't do anything.
It's typical of cold-hearted.
- So you want to leave?
- I don't want it, but I have to.
- Goodbye.
He has to turn his head.
Like a good sign.
Attention!
Either the plains of the spring
And the green mountains and the valleys
Shadows or shady dumbbells
And the springs and streams
in the eternal movement.
Mr Witek!
Witek!
- Where are you going ?
- See who's calling me.
- We both know who.
- Mom, you must!
I tell her you're not home.
- Mom, I'm no longer a child.
- Yes, you are.
Wicio, I have a bad feeling.
- Mammy, I know what I'm doing.
- That's not a company for you.
Wicio!
Hello.
Are we disturbing you?
- Not at all, I just finished learning.
- My cousin, Silwek... Mr. Wicio.
- Pleasant.
- That's what we see.
Don't ignore what he says.
How long will that fence support?
Mr. Wicio, come with us to the river?
I'd come, but I don't have a bicycle.
- It's okay, I'm on the frame.
- Let's try.
- Rex, come here.
- I would prefer it further.
- Not so fast!
- I can even slow down.
- Are you mad at me?
- From where to where ?
- Do you want to study medicine?
- Yeah, I'm getting ready for medicine.
Do you want to treat the rich?
The rich, but
especially the poor.
Start with the poor and
end up with the rich.
- We're trying our powers?
- If that's what you want...
- Only if you have courage.
- I like to risk.
I trust the grievous, young.
- Fight for Alina.
- I can't!
- Leave us! Going here?
- Yes, it works.
I don't support these silly turns!
Mr. Witek, be wise.
Mr. Witek, come here right
away, or you'll regret it!
- Let's have a tutorial. Are you ready?
- I'm ready.
What a power it has!
Broke my bones!
- Of course he broke them!
- I am sorry.
You won, you belong.
- Has anyone asked me?
- Be quiet.
- Not for fighting.
- But for whom?
For nobody...
For absolutely nothing,
Now I'll fall asleep.
- And I'll sleep...
- That's a nice day.
But anyway, I will not fall asleep anyway.
And I'm gonna hurt myself until morning.
I don't have air, it's cold,
I'm thinking too many,
thoughtless thoughts,
dreams and hopelessness...
that make my heart beat.
And it suddenly envelops me.
But you have the pills.
I got you a bottle today.
- I wish you didn't make misconceptions.
- I did not.
- I really did not have an idea.
- But you're weird about me.
I could just take all
the pills and sleep...
By the end of the world.
- Suicide is a great sin.
- What a shame?
It is greater sin to thrive you to
live if you do not want it any more.
I don't know what to say.
When we do not know anything, we
have to take an example from nature.
That is, fear, the fear
of living, to face life.
Who knows, once and for all,
people will be able to...
Some motivated requests to
obtain the right to death.
- Are you going bad?
- That's not what I said.
Get your hands off me, mucus!
I did it for pure affection, grasunico.
Mouth, or I'm moving your fingers!
I have had enough !
Have you ever said a
beautiful word to a woman?
That you love her, you want her...
Are you crazy after her?
I can say that any time.
- Go ahead !
- Can you tell you?
- Why not ?
- But they will all hear.
And why not hear?
I love you.
He wanted it!
No shame!
- I should feel offended.
- Teach you.
Another day to keep
your dignity, Lowka!
I feel like I'm going crazy, I
think someday I'll explode.
How do I see a skirt, how do I go crazy.
When the wind blows in the girls'
hair, when I see an empty foot...
I feel like I'm suffocating.
The worst, however, is the night
- It will pass...
- And I'm still dead on that I'm gonna think.
- What a disaster!
- We all go through this.
- And you?
- And I, but they do not hurt me.
But if I stay so long, I die.
- Did Engel tell you?
- He did not say anything to me.
Dad wants to send me to
Germany when school finishes.
- What happened ?
- Still nothing.
- She's afraid of a fool.
- There will be no war!
That's what has always been said.
Who to fight? Who?
Me and Engel? Engel with me?
Engel, are we going to fight each other?
We will live long and well to death.
We're going to get back to 2,000.
Don't you think?
What a wonderful night...
Weird...
A huge mass of birds floats
the park above the city.
Are you there yet?
- All right, all at bedtime.
- What's the matter with you?
Where are my pills?
- The park was here.
- How will I sleep without them?
They were here on the table.
Did any of you take the pills?
For what ?
We sleep with and without them,
We'll buy some more tomorrow.
- We're going over this night.
- Nonsense!
- I'm equal if I sleep or not.
- Then why are you crying?
I don't know... it came to me.
- Every year, the same.
- We're in 1939.
I can't even believe how time goes by...
Good night, ladies.
Good night.
- Leaves !
- You have no shame!
- Witek, you sleeping without pills?
- Yes.
I, without my pills,
can't sleep.
Good night.
Ready!
I love you!
Are you, Rex?
Are you spying on me?
Why?
Grandpa, can you hear me?
I fell in love.
Yes, it was something like that...
Why would you drag?
But I can not remember
it well, son.
I'm in love, Grandpa.
Okay, it's fine...
Nobody died of it yet.
Maybe I will be the first to die.
- Why are you torturing me like that?
- Do I bother you?
You torture yourself.
- Can I drive you to the train?
- If you want...
Don't you see anything?
Don't you see what a stab wound?
I broke my head because
of you and you.
You talk stupid things and you
lose your sense of humour.
- I can afford, we do not have witnesses.
- You're ridiculous.
- That's how you'll always be.
- How are you?
- You know.
- How do I know?
You noticed me in secret.
You drive me only to the corner of the street.
Only there!
Do you know there will be war?
Why aren't you saying anything ?
Now, thank you...
And goodbye.
Allow me... can you let me
drive you to the garage?
- So you don't want to ?
- I don't want.
- Goodbye.
We have to meet again.
- For the last time, it's very important.
- We just broke up.
I have to talk to you.
I expect you six in front of your house.
- In front of the house?
- Yes, I beg you. For the last time.
- How do you want...
- Does that mean yes?
God, in fact, nothing happened.
I will go crazy !
So here it was hidden!
I caught you, you were gone. Recognise!
Don't you want to admit it?
Rcunosc.
And what if?
- And our bet?
- What bet?
- Stop doing the innocent!
- Are you stupid?
- Where have you been all day ?
- What's up with you, it's my job.
I got his hand!
Witek, you know she's sick.
They did X-ray.
- He's got a big heart.
- Many live well with the big heart.
- Do you have anything with her?
- What are you up to? I have nothing with her.
- Then it's good, no one to hurt her.
- Who's hurt her?
Witek, do you hear?
Yes, I hear.
- I wanted to apologise.
- For what ?
- For everything.
- Okay, but you don't have it for what.
You treat me like a child.
Engel does everything in my account always.
- Greta, but it's not a big deal.
- For me it is.
Why did you bring me here?
I don't know, that's how it was.
What do you want to tell me ?
I'm curious.
I can't tell you that all of a sudden.
Then we wait a little longer.
- Who did you rust for?
- Did I bother?
- For me, or for your cousin?
- For me.
Show me your hands...
- You still have a long way to live.
- No!
My road stops here.
See? Next to this milling.
Alina!
Alina, what happened?
Wait for me!
Alina, wait for me!
Here he must have fallen.
If I find my coin, everything
will be good again
Only here could I lose her.
I'll look for her until I find her.
- And if you don't find her?
- Are you spying on me?
Possible.
Fr, you lost your bet.
- This isn't something to bet.
- What's with you?
- You lost and you have to pay.
- How do you know?
- The whole city talks to you and Alina.
- How do I pay for you?
I'll give you three legs in the ass.
- Lowka, jokes!
- I just bet, have you forgot?
- You're not going to tell anyone?
- I have my honour too.
Then go ahead.
Lowka, leave the jokes!
Leo Tigerovich, get up!
You want to scare me?
What...
What happened?
God!
My tooth is shaking.
- Who are you?
- I'm Lowka.
Wait a minute...
Thank God!
Come with me?
Where?
To the Baum sisters.
What did you forget?
It's just waiting for you.
Come on, I can't go alone.
- Come, I brought something...
- What?
Have...
I have... harsh grasses.
- Today I decided to go to action.
- What do you want to do?
I looked for him and I found him.
I brought you the wrong owl.
- So only can the force be brought?
- No questions.
- You were there?
He prayed on his knees under a tree.
Come to drink from the elixir of forgetfulness.
Come, don't be stubborn.
It's not nice to
refuse an older lady.
Drink it to the bottom and it
will open your third eye...
- You'll see better.
- I like it too.
Bea, Wicio!
- Maybe we will not see each other again.
- Why don't we see each other again?
You know why.
And I drink for the first time.
Then, in the beauty of
the beautiful ladies!
- Which one?
- All... And mine.
I have begun to see
with my third eye.
And I started to feel...
a slight nausea.
But it is a delight.
Nonsense...
Dance with me?
I wanted...
I wanted to break my bad luck.
Then you had to throw him harder.
I didn't know.
And now what will happen?
You will definitely be happy.
- How do you know?
- I think we'll all be happy.
The next month I'm leaving.
- What idea !
- Dad's afraid of a war.
Engelbarth, my dear...
It's already very late.
Father, let me stay
for an hour, please.
You know, I'm a...
a bad, gruff, but in fact...
I am no longer German and
I will not be any more.
I don't understand you any more.
A wise old man drinks so
much wine and generally...
Generally, what?
In general, so many...
Look at Engel as he looks...
Does he look like a young man how should he?
He is no longer German, but
neither Polish will be.
Greta... I think I'm sorry.
I see everything on the pieces.
And I'm sorry.
Let's get out of the air.
- I can't do this anymore !
- I have been drinking for the first time in my life.
- Why is everything rotating with me?
- I thought it was different.
- What are you saying?
- I'm thinking about my life.
- Just now ?
- Maybe we'll die from this wine.
- Maybe it was poisoned.
- I wouldn't allow that!
First I would die!
Kiss Me !
- Not that...
- I am sorry.
He's very nice.
Not worse than others.
She has exactly the same breasts...
exactly the same body...
exactly the same hips...
exact...
So what happens to me?
What happens?
Monthly Sinister...
What is it?
Do you hear my heart beating?
What are you looking for?
It's not good at all.
It hurts me very badly,
but I don't know why.
- What are you looking for in the drawer?
- The Father's Acts.
- Whose father?
- Yours.
There's a decoration
he got in the war
for acts of bravery and heroism,
era and a sheet of paper...
imprinted with the black
letters of the front desk
bearing the energetic signature
of General Szeptycki.
- He was over here.
- There are a lot of old papers and pictures here.
Yes, but I can't find
the old German documents.
Workbook, identity card...
- The partisan card.
- That's something I didn't see.
You are right...
These are no longer.
- But the pictures?
- I don't know...
There is a passport photo here.
But the others?
Maybe they destroyed your mother, afraid.
- Here's a picture of Dad.
- See?
An absolutely common face like
anyone else on the street.
I can't remember it anymore.
Does it express meekness, pride?
Was he sympathetic?
What did she think, what did she want?
Who did he really love?
- Do you know?
- I didn't think about that.
- Will you still miss it?
- Why did you come here?
Don't inspire fear, do you?
Maybe I'm a spirit that
just feels terrible,
is struggling...
Trying to make sense of the absurd?
But what do I want to say...
It is that I can't change your fate.
I'm not interested in my future.
Is Renia the one
having a long, black,
or Niusia, hit by a bomb?
No, I think he did not
die, he went to Stockholm.
- Then he never heard of her.
- My name is Alina.
- Is that so bad?
- It's for the first time in my life.
- I'm taking my picture with me.
- Take it.
Let me be lucky.
Though I don't
need luck in fact.
Are you?
Do you come home this time?
No, I woke up from my sleep.
I was awakened.
What are you doing?
What you say?
He took it there, among the trees.
Mama, look at it! There!
There's nobody there.
Soon it's day.
You haunt day and night you don't sleep.
- I have seen it before.
- And you say that, simple?
- It's not terrifying.
- What ghosts were in my time!
And that's true, but he does
not want anything from us.
You drank?
God, he's started!
- Did you take my 50 pockets out of my pocket?
- What were they looking for?
- Next to a talisman?
- Good luck.
- I know well...
- Give it to me!
- Shall I give it to you? I threw her into the river.
- You're superstitious.
Wicio, it's for your sake.
You have to be strong,
you can't crash.
Mom, my life belongs to me.
They talk and walk
all night and night.
I'm doing something, and
I only know nothing.
Only nobody tells me anything.
- Are you, Wicio?
- Yeah, I can't sleep.
Did you open the window?
- My mom has a snake skin under my bed.
- Nonsense!
Every day he prays, he boils
all kinds of herbs...
- Hang on the price.
- Did you hear the nightingale?
I hear everything.
Now I'm just a big, dying ear.
- Don't you sleep, Grandpa?
- I stay awake...
I'm awake, son.
And if I die before you?
What do you say there ?
Scuzaþi me...
Hello, Zuza.
- Here you go.
- No, thank you.
I'd like to tell you
something between four eyes.
- What ?
- I want to ask you what's wrong with Alina.
- With Alina?
- I gave him a book I need now.
Go to it.
He's in bed, he's cold.
That was... I did not know...
Yeah, I'll go over to her.
- That's a lot easier.
- I'm not the man of simple solutions.
But I'm afraid yours
will not enjoy too much.
- But she ?
- That's what you know better.
- Now it's too late.
- Why is it late?
Now it's all.
- What is it ?
- A telegram for the lady.
I sign.
- I have to hand it to her personally.
- I said I signed up!
- No, Miss Alina!
- Stay in your room!
- I sign the receipt.
- No, I cant!
- Give it to me!
- Give it back to me!
- Give me the receipt to sign it.
- Give it to me!
- Don't you need a receipt?
- No, it's a telegram for Alina!
- I'll show you, mucus!
- I'll slash your ass with salt!
- What's up?
What you said ?
Donkey!
What are you doing ? Are you crazy?
What did you get?
- Go too far!
- He always comes with fake telegrams!
I'm losing it with salt!
- There's no point in coming.
- Did she send you?
No, but I know everything.
- Why doesn't he want it any more?
- He is not allowed.
- After the baccalaureate goes abroad.
- In a few days...
- Yes...
- And what am l going to do?
- It's going to be a war.
- I don't care.
If I don't see it, I'm going crazy!
- She may think it's just a crap.
- And if not?
Maybe that's what you say,
but maybe she doesn't.
Mr. Witold! Mr. Witold!
I think she suffers a lot.
Alina!
God help me!
What are you doing ?
Are you still alive?
- What are you up to?
- I know he bloated you with salt.
Listen to me, spit on
this place and go home.
Your mama is waiting for you.
Their bourgeois don't make two money.
- Do you know an obese girl?
- No.
You have no pride if you
stand here begging.
Better take a bottle of
gas and fire everything.
- Why does that impress you?
- But then, why are you with them?
Take a look at what a gerlos is!
Okay, I got a message for you.
Alina waits for you at midday at the river.
- Aren't you happy ?
- You want to get rid of me ?
Do you see it at the window?
What are you sneaking
around this house, son?
I know what I do.
Everything will be alright.
Let's go.
I dreamed a big fire.
Everything burns...
- The house, the city, the whole world.
- No, I'm staying here.
- I'm going to get it until they all get up.
- I know, mama,
But stay here and don't force me,
otherwise something terrible will happen.
Swear to come back.
Jur.
I brought your coat.
Okay, leave him, but now
go, leave me alone.
- What are you doing, what have you been up to?
- You should have left me alone!
Did I start everything?
You were the one.
- Now it's too late.
- Why is it too late?
You know too well.
Right after the baccalaureate
we get married.
You're crazy.
My guy will not let me.
Now it's too late.
- What do you look for?
- Who?
- Cousin! But tell me the truth.
- What are they looking for?
Rex!
Where did you get a bitch?
Maybe he cherished me.
And don't forget that... to me!
Now it's too late.
Cucumber, tell me how much I'll live.
How long will we live?
See?
We will not live too much.
Number of years!
Five... six... seven...
- 42, 43, 44...
- It's enough, I don't want more.
We don't need prophecy.
I wish you, I conquered you.
Now it's too late.
The cuckoo says we have
many years ahead of us.
- Where have you been to meet you?
- But you?
It's from too much sun.
Stay so...
I'll make you shade.
- Mor!
- No!
You're just getting up to life.
Where have we been before?
How do I know everything?
- When did we last that?
- No...
Wait yet, not yet, please.
My heart struggles.
Where have we been, so long?
- Do we run together?
- Somewhere in a university city.
- You'll be the biggest doctor.
- And you, his wife.
- Is that love?
- It's impossible not to love me.
- We are the best.
- And Silvek?
- Silvek? It's some kind of surgeon.
- Why?
He used to meditate
and so he cherished
but a high school
girl was Jewish.
- When will there be no differences?
- There will always be differences.
- What are we doing now ?
- We're darting, or our dad kills us.
We meet here the day the
results are displayed.
- Good-bye, my husband.
- Goodbye, my wife.
Don't follow me, I
have to go back alone.
He has to turn around.
It will be a good sign.
You came back ?
This is good.
I know, everything will be fine again.
I know.
- Drink tea before bedtime.
- You think he's helping?
You have to keep up before
the baccalaureate exam.
Grandpa is better.
Today he ate a plate full of soup.
And he listened to the nightingale singing.
- Mama, does life really have a purpose?
- If you do that, it's good.
- It would be faster than the week.
- Sleep...
One week you missed exams.
And where will I be then?
Witek, what's going on with you?
Why aren't you saying anything?
No, you can't.
You fell?
Say something !
Did you fall to the baccalaureate?
Look what the mask I got from my dad.
A real gas mask.
- What's going to happen now?
- I don't know.
- You're lucky.
- I don't even know what to say.
- You can try again next year.
- I will not be in the year.
- It's my fault ?
- Neither you nor mine.
Do you love me?
Why was I the one you
stopped suddenly then?
- You regret it?
- No, I'm ready for anything.
- What do you mean ?
- Everything.
Someone is waiting for us.
E Rex.
Come here, next to us.
Let's get poisoned!
I bother you and you, me.
- Don't you scare eternity?
- Along with you, no.
- It's better to die out of love.
- Yeah, it's better.
- I'm coming tomorrow, here in a white dress.
- Why white?
- Until the last moment...
- Until the beginning of eternity.
Witek!
Witold!
I was looking for you.
Do you want to marry yourself?
Leave him alone.
He also has his problems.
Witold, Witold...
What are you doing?
- He's leaving and who knows when he's coming back.
- Greta, is that it?
You forgot ?
What's going on with you?
- Do you hear the hammer?
- I will not say anything.
You'll see, I'll get drunk
with beer or beer...
I will be scandalous...
- And finally they're gonna blow me at the hospice.
- What did you say, pigeon?
It's our last day together
Because today we will be separated
Because today...
- And she packed.
- Who?
Alina!
The ordinance handed out the whole day of luggage.
- When it leaves ?
- At night.
Goes to Krakow.
Better said in Lvov.
God!
You're crazy, pigeon!
Come on!
Get up!
Faster !
What have you filled these suitcases with?
They are so heavy!
With black feelings and
five fears of fear.
This is...
I have been hooked up with these suitcases.
- Goodbye.
- Get back fast, I'll wait for you.
After the war we will
find a knight to honour.
Don't fuck!
Who wants war? There will be no war.
It's just a little bang.
Turn around, white goose.
- Stop it!
- He went crazy!
I have succeeded.
A good sign.
But what does he use to me?
Perhaps others, those who remain.
Did I just look... or did I
really see the archbishop?
I don't even know...
- Hello.
- Good day, sweetheart.
- Today is my birthday. What do you want me to do?
- What can I wish for you?
Stay here next to me.
- You dirty the dress.
- I will never have to.
Come...
Kiss Me...
---------
- Are you ready?
- Yes.
- We can do it differently.
- Let's go.
Anyway, soon death will begin.
Let's go to the river...
We'll need water.
- I put it in a piece of paper.
- I... in a hurry.
- We say goodbye first.
- We'll have plenty of time.
- Who starts?
- I can start it.
No, leave me.
I'm the man... yet...
Good.
- I want to give it to you.
- I'd prefer to take it myself.
If it's a sin I want to
be responsible for it.
You have to get it out
of my hand, my husband.
First Brakes...
Did you know I like it?
I thought it better
to bring them myself.
Let's go to shore.
Let's leave the river without sin.
Farewell...
I think now...
Goodbye, my lover.
Thanks for everything.
Thanks for death.
And I thank you.
You know how I love you...
How I loved you...
- With all.
- For all.
- Can you hear me?
- Very far.
Soon we will know everything.
- If there's anything to know.
- It doesn't matter any more.
- Sleep, lover...
- You sleep in peace, sweetheart...
There is no world of my childhood.
She lives only in
me and with me.
It will turn into ash and disappear
somewhere in nothingness.