Here, stop right here!
Thank you.
- See you on Tuesday. Bye.
- Bye.
Oh, God!
Please close the door.
Idiots!
Where is he?
Nitin...
My darling Miku.
Has nobody fed you?
Eat... eat.
The power is on...
Water?
Sir... no sign of a forced entry.
Excuse me.
Cuts are precise and perfect,
like a surgeon's work.
Except this. Not so perfect.
Maybe the nurse did it...
Cellophane paper, sir.
Thin but very strong.
We're checking for fingerprints.
Was he sliced from bottom to top
or top to bottom?
Er... the autopsy report
will tell us, sir.
First the neck was cut.
Then these 'designer' cuts
were made at leisure.
Had he been alive,
he would have struggled,
the cuts would not have been so smooth.
Nitin... what?
Nitin Srivastav, a film critic.
He wrote film reviews for firstview.com.
Film critic!
Any CCTV footage from the building?
This is an old building, sir.
The security guard is the CCTV here.
He says that Srivastav had not
stepped out today
and he had no visitors.
- According to forensics, the murder was...
- What is this?
Triangle, sir.
Draw it.
A triangle would look like that.
Why is this inverted?
- Good morning, Danny.
- Good morning.
Bye, Danny.
Let's go!
Shit! There's just one egg.
Forgot to buy them again?
You should have reminded me.
I forgot too.
Kaleem bhai, here we come?
'...incident took place
in Jogeshwari, Mumbai.'
'The victim Nitin Srivastav
was alone at home
when he was murdered.'
- 'The police don't have any leads yet.'
- Wait a minute.
- I want more bread.
- Get to work.
Sorry, Danny.
When there's no cricket match
there's murder! Damn TV.
What's going on, Kaleem bhai?
Some film...
- What do you call them?
- Critic.
Yes. He was brutally murdered.
I've always said
Oshiwara and Jogeshwari
are extremely dangerous areas.
Why isn't it so tasty at home?
We don't add sweat and grime
at home.
Sir, post mortem report says,
two weapons were used.
One on the neck and another
on the body.
But how did the killer enter the house?
Besides the husband and wife,
nobody had the house keys.
No lock tampering.
Srivastav didn't open the door,
he was in the toilet.
Srivastav opened the door!
- But...
- The bell rang.
Srivastav opened the door.
The killer entered.
Srivastav was found on the pot
doesn't mean,
he was on the pot.
Any motive?
Nothing in the phone records.
They were a happy couple. No children.
No property issues. No enemies.
At the website he worked for
he hardly interacted
with other journalists.
He'd watch films,
email reviews from home.
Give me the photograph
of the cellophane paper.
Looks like gift-wrapping paper, sir.
No fingerprints.
Mrs. Srivastav confirmed
she hasn't seen it before.
This pattern looks very familiar...
I still can't believe it.
Wonderful man. A senior critic
but no ego.
He called me last week
after reading my review.
The building had no security cameras.
Crazy!
Poor Mrs. Srivastav.
Can't imagine what she's going through.
Don't feel like writing a review now.
There is a screening at 6 p.m.
Screening? Isn't the press-show tomorrow?
Ajay (movie star) didn't call you?
Kartik sir, am I late?
Just catch your breath, Nila. It's okay.
- I'll... just go pay my respects.
- Sure.
Entertainment reporter...
joined recently.
Loves cinema.
Stop. Stop.
Mom's been chewing my head...
flowers, flowers...
found them finally.
Danny's Flowers... so nice.
Everything in Bandra is nice,
except the rent!
No one in the shop.
Good... no one pestering,
'buy this, buy that'.
Hey, pink and white lilies.
Mom wanted something more exotic.
Sunflowers or orchids?
What were those flowers
in that 'Silsila' film song?
Tulips, tulips...
Won't get tulips here.
Have to go to Amsterdam for them.
Tulips.
♪ Who knows what you said? ♪
♪ Who knows what I heard? ♪
♪ Something stirred in my heart ♪
♪ Who knows what you said? ♪
Excuse me.
I forgot to pay.
- It's okay.
- Please, I insist.
No, no... it's okay.
- It's not okay.
- The card machine is not working.
Next time?
Thank you.
♪ My lowered eyes looked up again ♪
♪ My faltering feet are steady now ♪
Stop dreaming. Stop!
She's just like us.
So? You'll give away flowers for free?
Tulips in Bandra! Cool!
Very cool... flowers and the florist.
Yes, Srini.
Sir, according to the lab reports,
the cellophane paper is
at least ten years old.
This pattern is not available
anywhere, sir.
We've checked all the gift shops.
In fact, none of the manufacturers
have seen this pattern, sir.
I've also checked with
a few old manufacturers.
First check who is at your door.
Yes, sir?
When Mrs. Srivastav rang the doorbell...
it rang, right?
Yes, sir.
She opened the door...
it was dark inside,
the fuse was off...
then how did the doorbell ring?
Shit!
Of course, sir.
After the doorbell rang
and before Mrs. Srivastav
entered the house,
somebody turned off the power,
which means--
The killer was inside the house
when she entered.
Let's go. Finish this at home.
No, Richa,
I really have to send this interview
otherwise they'll kill me. I'm sorry.
- Bye.
- Hey, did you know Nitin Srivastav?
Why?
You attended his prayer meeting...
I didn't know him personally, but
we've always had like
a strange connection.
I've been following his reviews
since my college days.
The films he gave
a one or two star rating to,
like this 'Paani Paani Re'...
I would love those films.
I loved 'Paani Paani Re'!
And when he gave a four star rating,
I knew...
I wouldn't like the film.
Our opinions were different
but, so what?
At least he was honest about
the kind of cinema he liked.
This is India...
Shetty's films work here,
not Scorcese's!
And if Nitin rated a film four stars,
it's a sure hit.
Hit means a good film?
I don't agree.
Bye, guys.
- Bye, sir.
- Bye.
You know, I like Kartik sir's reviews.
He knows cinema.
One day... One day.
- Okay, bye.
- Bye.
Shit!
When does Nature's Basket close?
Yellow lentils... I'm getting it.
Orange lentils... calm down.
Got it.
Turmeric powder...
Patience, I'm looking for it.
Cow ghee...
Why is cow ghee so expensive?
Let's just get a cow.
Sugar-free chocolate?
Since when are you diabetic?
Okay, you're the boss.
Don't forget the eggs!
Admiring natural beauty
in Nature's Basket?
I can't help it,
it's nature's conspiracy.
Bangalore was better,
at least you ate on time.
I haven't come to Mumbai to eat.
Everything is so expensive here...
makes sense to eat less.
I never knew tulips smell so nice.
It feels so romantic.
The flowers are not creating the feeling,
Amit Trivedi's song is.
They should never make films
without songs.
Nice to live next to a film studio.
Flowers and songs...
Will I get a role in a film?
Will I get some pickle?
What will you do if I find a real lover?
I'll move the furniture around...
you'll keep tripping and falling.
Go ahead.
How else can I fall into somebody's arms?
Get out.
Who would kill a film critic?
- Sir, maybe some underworld connection?
- Don't waste your time.
They would have shot husband,
wife and the cat and left.
Somebody has spent time
and enjoyed this.
Tell me, what sort of a relationship does
the film industry have with critics?
Film guys and media
have a love-hate relationship, sir.
Once, this actor called up a journalist...
Film critics and the film industry
have just one connection...
Reviews!
Sir, that's it.
That's it!
'Paani Paani Re' was Nitin Srivastav's
last film review. One star!
You kill the critic because
you don't like the review of your film?
Sir, we must question them.
Whom?
The makers of 'Paani Paani', sir.
Why just them?
Nitin Srivastav must have criticised
many films in his life.
But... the murder took place after
this review.
It's very sad.
I just returned from Ajmer this morning.
Ajmer?
Mr. Arvind, since 1992,
I go to Ajmer Sharif to pray the day
before the release of any of my films.
You haven't read the reviews of your film?
Reviews? I haven't read a single review
of any of my films till date.
And reviews don't make a film work.
It's all about word of mouth.
The audience didn't like the film,
so it flopped.
Good reviews wouldn't
have made any difference.
Mr. Himani, what are these leaves
on the posters?
Earlier, they were only
on international film posters.
Now it's become fashionable here too.
My gut feeling,
we're on the right track, sir.
Let us meet the director.
This is an intelligent film,
not a potboiler.
It really needed the critics' support.
The reviews have really depressed me.
How depressed were you?
On a scale of one to five...
how much did the reviews affect you?
Sir, I haven't stepped out since Friday.
Even avoiding my lead actor's calls...
I am quite upset.
I was quite close to Mr. Nitin.
He was a dear friend.
Dear friend? But he trashed your film...
Hadn't you lashed out at critics
in an interview?
Give me a second.
It's an old story, sir.
There was a lady
who said something like -
'A tree would be more expressive
than Purab.'
I also said some things.
Anyway, I've forgotten about it.
Done and dusted.
He won't even be able to play
the role of a killer... anybody else?
The light man? Catering man?
The case is not so straightforward.
Go away.
Checked flower shops?
You don't use any plastic?
Isn't it banned?
Okay, let's go.
Hi.
All okay?
They're raiding plastic users.
Good... you know how dangerous plastic is?
But I only use plastic!
Money first then flowers.
It's okay, really.
No, it's not okay.
I'll want flowers regularly.
If you keep giving it for free,
you'll have to shut shop soon.
As long as flowers bloom,
this shop will be open.
What do you think?
I think he is flirting.
Yeah, you're the expert.
I'm just getting the vibes.
You're not getting anything.
No I am serious. Don't do this.
Richa, I'll talk to you later.
Five minutes. I'll call you back.
Yeah. Okay, bye.
So expensive?
'She's just like us!'
You should've looked at her ears
before staring into her eyes.
How could I know she was on the phone?
Found one thing in common
and fell in love?
Film critic.
Filmy cellophane paper.
Why is it inverted?
This... is a triangle.
'Two critics have been killed
in two weeks.'
'Last night, famous film critic
Irshad Ali's body was discovered
on the railway tracks
between Nallasopara and Virar.'
'Half the mangled body
was found on the railway track.'
'The rest of the body was crushed
by a speeding train.'
'This incident has terrorized
the media and the film industry.'
Both murders have been committed
by the same person.
Same cellophane paper. Same star.
Kills and signs off with a star.
Arvind, what star?
On Nitin Srivastav...
It was half done,
the bell rang, the killer had to flee.
Else, there'd be a star carved
on Nitin Srivastav's forehead too.
Sir, we have got a new kind
of a serial killer...
who is giving stars to people
who give star ratings!
A critic's critic!
I will get off here.
It'll be faster to walk.
Here.
- Wow, are these candles?
- Yes, madam.
- Want a husband candle, madam?
- Husband candle?
Want a husband, take a husband candle.
If you have a husband,
take a baby candle.
If you have both,
take a school, car or airplane.
Only 500 rupees.
500 rupees? Isn't that a lot
for a husband?
I'll give you a family pack,
husband and baby for 700 rupees.
It's nature's conspiracy.
Meet her. What's the problem?
It's good she isn't like us.
Four voices, won't know
who is talking to who.
♪ Who knows what you said? ♪
Stop it.
♪ Who knows what I heard? ♪
Stop!
- This one.
- Doggy candle? 300 rupees.
200.
How can you not like a dog lover?
Fine, 250. Last price.
These are prayer candles, madam.
Be generous...
Okay, give.
No, please. It's okay.
I had overcharged you that day.
So... refund?
How does one light these?
You don't like dogs?
I love dogs... more than people at times.
- Then how can you burn a puppy?
- Are you mad?
I mean it's a candle,
so I was just asking.
I wouldn't set Waxy on fire.
I'll take care of him,
feed him, toilet train him.
So cute. My Waxy.
Thank you.
- Return the change.
- Yes, sir.
You don't light these candles.
They are offered to Mother Mary.
You go to church regularly?
When my mother was alive,
she'd force me to.
Now, I force myself to go.
I'm so sorry.
Dad?
- Does your mother like flowers?
- Yes, tulips.
She only likes tulips now.
Can't help it... single mom, fully spoilt.
Waxy, you're going to meet my single,
spoilt mom.
Say thanks to Danny.
What?
Danny's Flowers means you're Danny, no?
Why? I could be Flowers too, Nila.
How do you know my name?
Debit card.
Ah, when you were looting me...
First entice customers with
free flowers and then fleece them.
Good strategy.
Next time, give me a
'frequent flower discount'.
That... depends on the frequency.
Where do you get tulips from?
I grow them...
in my garden.
Tulips grow in Mumbai?
With a little love, patience and water,
anything can be grown anywhere.
- Bye.
Why are you grinning like a pig?
Right... a little more to the right.
Wrong! Wrong!
- Good evening, Amit ji.
- Good evening, ma'am.
Okay. Ready? Let's roll.
Your film releases tomorrow.
The film has a name, madam
- 'Third Umpire'...
just like the third umpire in cricket.
But it's not a cricket film,
it's just a metaphor.
Third Umpire.
One who sees what nobody else can.
After all these years... do you still
feel nervous before a film's release?
I get even more nervous today...
Social media is very quick
to declare the result...
I get nervous when the phone beeps.
Actually, it's the critics
who are more nervous these days.
Yeah.
It is very sad.
Two of our finest critics
of the industry, you know,
we've lost them.
I had deep respect for them.
I have read all their reviews of my films
and learnt a lot from them.
Are reviews important to you
or only box office matters?
See, ma'am... box office matters.
If films don't work,
who will give me work?
Not just me...
all the workers in this industry.
But you know, reviews are important.
We need critics.
Critiquing is a must for society,
for progress in any field.
Everyone likes to hear praises
but true learning happens
when we are made aware
of our shortcomings...
when somebody shows us
the way to become better.
Cinema needs critics for growth.
Cinema needs fearless,
unbiased voices for its evolution.
Careful, sir.
Body parts are scattered
all over the field.
Found 11 till now.
Sir, liver.
Come on, put on the damn lights.
- The same cellophane paper, sir.
- A star on the forehead?
No, this time...
one and a half stars.
The victim is Parikshit Prabhu,
senior film critic, Mumbai Republic.
He gave a one and a half star rating
to the film 'Third Umpire'.
Impossible.
Possible.
She likes dogs, not you.
If she liked dogs,
she would've kept a real one.
She likes craftsmanship, fool.
According to Juhu police,
the CCTV footage of Marriott Hotel shows
Prabhu leaving alone in a car at 11 p.m.
Prabhu may not have driven
to this place alone.
This seat is pushed forward...
maybe the killer was hiding behind it
with a weapon.
Toilet. Railway track.
And now a cricket ground.
Sir, the film is called 'Third Umpire'
so... cricket ground?
'Third Umpire'... one and a half stars.
'A picture whose heart
is in the right place
but whose other organs
are all over the place'.
He has scattered the organs
all over the ground,
except the heart!
He has been killed according
to what he has written.
Give me the other reviews.
Look at this.
'Lots of loo breaks in this boring,
long film
that should have been cut ruthlessly
in many places'.
Nitin was ruthlessly cut inside a loo.
How didn't we get this?
Irshad Ali - 'First half not bad.
The film is on track'... railway track.
'Second half is a bloody mess'.
Bloody hell!
Danny...
Danny!
It's a holiday for the flowers...
but not for the florist.
Our investigation clearly shows that
the murders that have taken place
in the last three weeks
have been committed by a serial killer.
One who is clearly targeting film critics.
I assure you that our best officers
are working on this case.
The public shouldn't panic--
Sir, we hear that the bodies
had a star symbol on them.
Why aren't the police sharing
the full information with the media, sir?
The victims are all from media.
The channels are ripping us apart.
The Home Minister and the Chief Minister
are pressurizing me.
Do you have any clues
apart from the reviews and stars?
Er, sir... the manner of these murders...
There could be another next week.
How are we going to stop it?
We have no fingerprints,
no CCTV footage...
- not one suspect!
- We may not have a suspect
but the targets are all clear.
Friends...
In the light of the shocking
events of the past few weeks,
Mr. Arvind Mathur,
Head of Crime Branch, Mumbai,
would like to address our film critics.
Thank you, all the producers
and directors present.
Sir, the entire film industry is with you.
- Over to you.
- Thank you, sir.
Let me get to the point straightaway...
we need your help.
♪ Happy birthday ♪
What do you mean by 'write carefully'?
Should we praise all films?
Sir, we're dealing with a psychopath,
who is committing a murder every week
affected by negative reviews.
Till we catch him, we have to make sure
that you are safe...
that is why I'm requesting you.
The police are not doing their job
and stopping us from doing ours.
Sir, I am not stopping you
from doing your job.
If you want us to be safe,
give us security.
Our reviews can be positive or negative,
it is your duty to ensure our security.
- Perfect.
- He is right.
There are at least 300 critics
in Mumbai.
How do we ensure their security 24x7?
You can provide security
to 543 politicians,
but not to 300 critics?
♪ Happy birthday ♪
We will give you
the personal phone numbers
of our officers...
for your security.
Let's stop this reviewing of films.
What's the problem?
Why don't you stop making films?
Sir, it is only film industry people
who have issues with critics.
Hello... what nonsense...
If we stop making films
how will you survive?
- Look at what he's saying.
- These producers are big bullies...
Once a producer had even chased a critic
with a knife.
You must be secretly thrilled.
Danny's Flowers.
Danny... Danny... where are you?
Who do you want to meet?
Nila Menon. Is she at home?
It is a surprise.
Birthday.
What are these?
Couldn't you find any roses?
Roses are... common.
Please close the door.
You?
It's a week since you visited the shop.
I just passed by your shop.
You closed early today?
And how did you find out where I live?
- You came to the shop?
- Yes.
Thought you must be bored
of fresh flowers.
Wow! Did you...
So beautiful.
So I shouldn't come to the shop anymore?
Apart from the flowers,
is there no other reason
to come to the shop?
Oh, the fragrance of newsprint!
You know I work for a newspaper?
Which one?
If I had known, I would've used that.
Okay, bye.
No okay bye.
Come in.
Mom!
Come here.
Danny, Mr. Tulips.
- Hello.
What are these?
Are the flowers on a strike?
Mom, it's so gorgeous.
Are you a florist or an artist?
Can't a man be both?
A man can be anything he wants, darling...
but paper can't be a flower.
Aunty, tomorrow I'll get tulips--
'Aunty'?
Nila, is he blind?
Sit. Please sit.
Hey, you'll have idli?
Mom makes the best idlis.
I'm fine.
No, you'll have idli.
Waxy? He's sleeping.
Hey, why aren't you on social media?
Because I'm in front of you.
Nila.
He is a flower-seller.
Yeah, so?
Have some thundering-hot idlis
with chutney.
Thank you.
Ma'am...
Sit down.
Won't you eat?
Who are you to invite me
to eat in my own house?
Ignore her.
She's like this every time
she sees a guy.
Just focus on your idlis.
Are all delivery guys served idlis,
in this house?
Yes. And the food delivery guy
is served biryani.
The booze delivery guy
has a few pegs before leaving.
Mom, can we have some privacy please?
Sure.
So tell me, have you always been
fond of flowers?
No. Mom loved flowers.
Dead or alive?
Flowers or Mom?
You are my type.
I love Moms.
I am trying.
So tell me, your Mom...
She was a florist.
I'm just keeping her shop
and her passion alive.
You are also very passionate about it.
I have become, over time...
flowers, gardening, no social media.
It's almost meditative.
Hm, I should also meditate.
It's only been four months in Mumbai,
and I am already fed up...
what movie stars drink, eat, wear...
who's having an affair with who!
This can actually kill
your love for movies.
You love movies?
Love?
No films means 'the end' for her!
That's why this house is
right next to a film studio.
House? Look at this hole!
We need cinema to feel alive.
Life is so dead, flat, boring, ugly...
Light never falls perfectly on the face.
Look at the moon,
it looks gorgeous only on screen,
with music.
Where? Where is the music?
The background score of our lives...
incessant honking...
The sound of violins
have to be imagined at funerals,
to feel the sorrow.
I mean, even falling in love...
You know when I think
I'll really fall in love?
When?
When someone actually walks towards me
in slow motion...
You should make a film.
No way.
I can watch 500 films in the time
it takes to make one.
What joy...
It's the best job ever...
earning a living doing
what you love most...
just watch movies!
That's why my dream is to be a critic.
Are you okay?
Hearing 'critic' made you choke?
I understand.
What's happening is so crazy.
- Three critics, one after the other...
- Yeah, crazy.
Excuse me.
Vaishnavi, Richa, Nila, Rohit,
you all should be embarrassed.
Tomorrow is Guru Dutt's
94th birth anniversary,
you should be ashamed you didn't know.
I want an 800 word article.
You guys figure it out between
yourselves who is going to do it.
I want it by 2 a.m. tonight!
Shit!
It is Guru Dutt's birth anniversary.
What a filmmaker!
I want to write this.
I really want to write this.
Anyway, thank you for the thundering idlis
and no rain, yet... I'll go.
But why?
Because this is real life
and you need to work.
If it were a film, I would've
been reading your article by now.
Bye, ma'am. Thank you.
See you soon.
What's going on?
What?
He may be cute but... a flower-seller?
If a mother has expensive taste,
a daughter has to do such things.
You're so ungrateful.
Also...
a person who spends
all his life with flowers,
has a fragrance that's unmatched.
Make sure your life doesn't end up without
fragrance like these 'Kaagaz Ke Phool' (Paper Flowers).
On Guru Dutt's birthday...
'Kaagaz Ke Phool' (Paper Flowers)
♪ Life inflicts... ♪
♪ ...such sweet pain ♪
♪ You are no longer you ♪
♪ I am no longer me ♪
Great piece, Nila.
Can't believe someone so young can
write so passionately about Guru Dutt.
- Thank you, sir.
- Beautiful.
Thank you, thank you.
He liked it.
- Hello, sir.
- Hi. Nice piece.
Thank you.
Lucky you. You got to write
on Guru Dutt.
I have to write about
'Kalinga - the war is not over'.
- Have you watched it?
- The press show is this evening.
But I do not feel like going.
- Why?
- What's the point?
'No negative comments... be careful...'
The police should write these reviews.
Right.
It's not about the film anymore.
Thank your stars
you're not a film critic at this time.
Do the police have any clue
about the killer?
I wouldn't know.
Our investigative journalists
must be facing this everyday, right?
They cover political scandals,
business scams, underworld exposés...
so many psychos must be after
their blood.
I wonder how they carry on writing.
Four and a half stars - Mallika Bhonsle.
Five stars - Ashwin Banerjee.
'The film is so good... Wow!'
'Great songs, action, performance,
direction... four awards guaranteed.'
'A director who doesn't just make
grand historical films
but creates history.'
'Every frame of the film
is like a painting.'
- 'Four stars.'
- 'Five stars.'
'I'm going with five stars.'
'Pandey's View gives 'Kalinga'
four and a half stars!'
One and a half stars.
One and a half? Who?
Shit!
- Secure the whole area.
- Let's move.
I am going to Dehradun with the kids.
- Reshma...
- Kartik, I cannot live like this anymore.
Like a terrorist attack
is about to happen!
The whole building is terrified.
I'll just...
Such a critical situation...
and he has given
one and a half stars!
This fellow has made our lives hell.
Everyone is giving four and five stars...
What's his problem? As if there'll be
a shortage of stars in the sky.
Sorry, sir.
I love journalism and I love cinema.
I'd be betraying both
if I lied about the film.
I'll never be able
to face myself again, sir.
- Because of me, the police--
- Do you watch all films?
Yes, sir. As many as I can.
How do you do it?
I don't have the patience.
Have you watched all psychopath films?
You think this is inspired by some film?
You know, like a copycat killer. Right?
Yes... but to the best of my knowledge,
there is no such film.
Because of me, the police are...
I am really sorry.
No, no.
Your ethics may actually help us here.
At least the target is clear...
- Yes, Nila?
- Hats off to you, sir.
The film is rubbish.
You were absolutely bang on.
Which building? What's that parcel?
That building is on the other side.
♪ If your head reels ♪
♪ Or heart sinks ♪
♪ Come, my friend ♪
♪ Come to me ♪
♪ Why worry? ♪
Four and a half stars.
You thought you'll get away?
Govind Pandey - 'Pandey's View'.
Want to know my view?
What's good is good,
what's bad is bad!
Simple.
You will get a chance.
You talk so much every week.
Let others talk for once.
Where was I?
You read the review
and went to watch the film.
After reading your review,
I went to see the film.
I saw the film. What did you see?
Horses?
Jewellery?
Songs?
Let's discuss this.
This is a very special film.
It requires a special talent
to waste so much money
and make such a fool of the audience.
It's the worst film I've seen in years.
You liked it?
Don't lie.
You never give less than four stars
to any of this producer's films.
What did he give you?
A gold watch?
Or a designer bag for your wife?
Or a 3-day 4-night holiday in Thailand?
Huh?
The film is a hit?
The audience likes the film?
Then let the audience speak.
Why are you needed?
If the audience wants to be fooled,
it's their choice.
Why are you helping them to be fools?
Open the eyes of the audience.
Upgrade their tastes.
Improve the quality of entertainment.
It's your bloody job!
'Kalinga is a brilliant film.'
'Every frame of the film
is like a painting.'
Pandey...
this is what is called
a beautiful painting.
I give it four and a half stars.
Who is the artist?
Touch my feet.
Cut!
It's the fourth murder...
Sir...
The fire forced the guard
to turn off the main switch.
Automatically, the alarms, cameras and
the security system got deactivated.
We have just three weeks, Arvind.
The CBI will take over the case
after that.
It's the Home Minister's decision.
I can't do much about it.
The media is on a protest.
'Outside the Crime Branch building
a peaceful candle march
is being held by the critics.'
'The Critics Guild of India has decided,
till the police assures them of security,
no critic will write film reviews
for any newspaper, website or channel.'
- I can't believe this!
- What a useless protest!
Millions of people post their reviews
after every film.
What difference will it make if these
'official' critics write or don't write.
It does make a difference.
Official makes a difference.
It has the stamp of credibility.
A professional movie expert
who knows cinema.
That's why people wait
for these reviews...
and trust these 'official critics'.
I write a review after watching every film,
but don't post it...
because even my 72 followers
won't see it as an 'official' review.
'In this film studio,
many films have been made...
are being made and will be made.'
'But this studio has not changed
nor has its ambience.'
'Everything is the same...
only the film changes
and the filmmakers change.'
♪ I have seen a world full of friends ♪
♪ They all part, one by one ♪
''Kaagaz Ke Phool' is an
utterly undistinguished picture.'
'An incoherent slow tale, boringly told.'
''Kaagaz Ke Phool'
is a negative picture...'
'...weak script'
'...weak performances'
'...scrappy editing.'
The genius maker of 'Paper Flowers'
was silenced by the mediocre critics.
Stop... right here.
Hello.
Hello...
Sorry. I was in the washroom.
You okay?
- No.
- What's wrong?
If you desperately want to do something
but don't get a chance...
and the ones who've got the chance
are wasting it...
what would you do?
I'd say 'thank you'.
'Thank you'?
When somebody makes you
want to be like them
beware!
Our originality dies.
When somebody makes you
not want to be like them,
we should thank them.
We become original only
when we learn what not to be.
- What profound advice!
- Huh?
Sorry. But what is this chance
that you wouldn't waste?
What are you?
I mean, apart from being
a crazy Guru Dutt fan?
Guru Dutt?
What Guru Dutt?
Why are you pretending?
What do you mean? I'm confused.
Didn't you make those paper flowers
specially for Guru Dutt's birthday?
Like a tribute?
I made them for you.
You told me that it was
some Guru Dutt's birthday.
And what is the connection
between that and paper flowers?
'Paper flowers'?
'Kaagaz Ke Phool (Paper Flowers)'
was Guru Dutt's last film.
Don't know?
Wow! You've made a simple coincidence
seem so profound.
Almost like a film scene.
You really do love cinema.
Are you sure?
You're not pulling my leg?
Guru Dutt...
'Kaagaz Ke Phool'...
not watched it?
No, no...
Forget reality.
Reality is boring.
I am a Guru Dutt fan.
I am a Guru Dutt fan!
A fan that makes paper flowers.
You feel better now?
Do you like me better?
Is the lighting okay?
I hate tube lights.
- You are mad!
- Mad is fine.
As long as I'm not flat and ugly.
Should I play some music?
♪ Who knows what you said? ♪
♪ Who knows what I heard? ♪
♪ Something stirred in my heart ♪
♪ I trembled with joy ♪
♪ I quivered with excitement ♪
♪ My dreams reawakened ♪
♪ Something stirred in my heart ♪
Sir, the forensic report is ready.
Do you like sports?
Er... yes, sir.
Which sport do you play?
Cricket.
And?
Football.
Er... bad--badminton.
And?
Sir... I play tennis too, sometimes.
I play just one sport...
and I've never lost a game.
What do they think?
The CBI will play on my ground
while I watch from the sidelines?
We're doing something wrong.
Strategy is wrong.
Sir, don't...
Sir... Please, sir. Don't...
It's loaded!
The gun, sir.
To catch a psychopath
think like one.
- Hello?
- Rosy's mother passed away.
Many people came to the funeral,
to offer their condolences.
Rosy noticed a handsome man there...
it was love at first sight.
He offered his condolences and left.
Rosy asked everyone
but nobody knew the man.
Rosy searched for him... everywhere.
But she didn't find him.
One day, Rosy killed her sister...
Why?
Rosy felt that the man would return,
to offer condolences.
After all these years, why are you
asking me such stupid questions?
Just explaining what thinking
like a psychopath means.
Sir, meet Dr. Zenobia Shroff.
- Pleasure.
Criminal psychologist
and a leading member
of the Psychopath Society.
Not the Psychopath Society,
the Society of Scientific
Study of Psychopathy - SSSP.
Basically, she understands
how the minds of serial killers work.
I gave her a call.
Surprise... she was on vacation,
in Pune... on a spiritual holiday!
Please have a seat.
Thank you for saving me.
Too much silence. I was going quite mad.
I'm a Bollywood buff.
A psychopath in Bollywood...
can't be more tempting.
- So the killer is taking a break?
- Looks like it.
No reviews, no murder.
That is exactly what he wants.
He must be jumping with joy.
At least you said, it's a 'he'.
We have no proof of even that.
That's my job.
To prove something without any proof.
83% serial killers are men.
That doesn't mean this person
isn't from the 17%.
It could be a big-built, strong woman
who can carry a man on her shoulders
and fling him on a railway track.
But look at Nitin Srivastav.
I mean, can you even
look at Nitin Srivastav?
Don't mean to be insensitive,
nor do I mean to body shame...
But even the most disturbed woman...
will not enjoy making designer cuts
on such an attractive nude body...
she would at least cover the paunch
with a towel!
So in my expert opinion,
only a man would not be disgusted.
Caught you!
Let's catch him.
When our 'Guru' is so sad,
why are you smiling?
Tell me.
Stop. Stop it.
Stop it. Stop!
Stop. Stop!
He has taught us
not to be like him.
He is a true teacher,
he taught us to be original.
Why hasn't anyone made
a biopic on him yet?
Biopic! Let's make a biopic.
Not his, ours.
Another one?
Not one... a series.
A web series that goes on
season after season.
I'm serious. See this.
The storyboard is also ready.
Episode 1...
Please close the door.
A film is a director's baby.
How can you molest someone's child?
Bloody paedophile.
One star?
'General audience will not understand.
Will not work.'
I am the general audience...
I go around on a cycle.
I really liked the film.
Did you review the film or my cycle?
Will it run, will it not?
The business a film does
is not your business.
Your business is to feel the film,
make people aware of its layers,
lovingly examine its beauty and flaws.
Someone's life is in your hands.
You write such long reviews but...
'Film should have been cut ruthlessly'?
How's the edit?
It's the first cut!
One star...
First half on track.
Mr. Irshad, what problem
did you have with the second half?
If the film kept going
on a predictable track,
everyone would know, after Vasai station
comes Nallasopara then Virar.
But imagine,
after Nallasopara if suddenly
Churchgate station appeared?
Isn't that interesting?
There's time.
When a filmmaker is trying
to change the track of cinema
why are you waving the red flag?
To create something new,
we must destroy the old.
In a web series, how will you say
first half and second half?
- Why were only these four targeted?
- Excuse me?
The four critics were killed
according to their reviews, right?
Why were only these four targeted?
Why did he choose these reviews?
What do you mean?
Prabhu had given the film
one and a half stars,
but three other critics had given
the same film one star.
Why weren't they targeted?
Pandey had given the film
four and a half stars
but four others had given five stars.
And look at this!
Not just Nitin, two other critics
had given the film one star.
They weren't harmed. Why?
Because all the other reviews were dull!
They were boring.
Only these four gave him
an interesting script in their reviews.
Script?
Heart is in the right place.
Your heart will be in place.
Don't worry.
But all other organs
are all over the place.
What a scene you can picture
reading the lines!
What a killer script!
Liver - forward short leg.
No. Silly point.
Kidneys - first slip, second slip.
Small intestine - gully.
Large intestine - cover.
Pancreas - mid-off.
At fine leg....
What are the organs of a film?
What a meaningless review
of such a meaningful film.
Mr. Bachchan is doing so many
experimental films these days...
what if he gets depressed and retires?
How will cinema progress
without Mr. Bachchan?
Once upon a time,
there was a film director
who is again searching
for a good script...
to direct murders!
For the best movie experience
mobile phones and some critics
should be silent.
This is crazy.
Critics must have finished his career
years ago and--
But this just doesn't make sense.
If his film was criticised
many years ago,
why is he killing now
for other films?
Is this psychopath expecting an award?
Serial killers can be broadly classified
into four categories -
this type is the 'mission-oriented killer'.
To justify their violence,
they come up with a 'noble mission'
in their heads...
a cause.
Sometimes it takes years for this
trauma to become a 'mission'.
I hope you're right, Dr. Shroff.
I know I'm right, sir.
Their logic is very twisted.
They don't think
they are killers or villains.
They think they're heroes.
Pandey is the clue.
Have you watched 'Kalinga'?
Pandey gave the film four and a half stars
that's why he killed him.
Because he believes,
false praise also harms cinema...
Just like 'Save the Girl Child',
'Save Cows',
'Save Power',
this psychopath's mission is
'Save Cinema'.
What are you doing?
Chopping.
Who?
Chopping my hair.
How can you be so cruel?
Poor things...
They are alive. They grow!
Don't cut.
I think you look very cool
with long hair.
Stop. Stop.
They are alive,
how can you chop them off?
- I want to meet you now.
- Who's stopping you?
I have these bloody deadlines today.
What are you doing tomorrow?
Nothing. I'm free.
♪ I have lost my heart ♪
♪ Tell me how this happened ♪
♪ Slowly and steadily ♪
♪ I have been slayed by your eyes ♪
♪ You breath has grazed and wounded me ♪
♪ How will I ever heal? ♪
♪ Every drop of blood that
drips from my wounds ♪
♪ thanks you ♪
♪ You have wounded my heart ♪
♪ My heart, my life, my soul ♪
♪ My cruel love,
The balm you apply to heal me ♪
♪ Is my very own blood ♪
Hey, this is the art gallery
where the murder happened.
- What murder?
- You didn't see it on the news?
The critic's... painting...
It was gruesome.
Nila means?
I'm talking about murders
and you're asking me about the moon?
Nila means moon, in Tamil.
Mom is Tamil.
Oh, I thought it was Neela...
like 'blue' in Hindi.
Neela?
Blue?
♪ Your lips are like daggers ♪
♪ Your cruel words are like poison ♪
♪ Piercing through me like a sword ♪
♪ It hurts and injures me ♪
♪ Wounding me like a weapon ♪
♪ Flailing and floundering ♪
♪ I have lost my heart and surrendered ♪
♪ It's bliss to lose myself ♪
The loo is inside?
Again?
This was the Intermission. Second half?
We need a list
of all the filmmakers whose last film
was trashed by the critics.
There must be thousands of them.
This cellophane paper is ten years old.
So something has happened ten years ago.
Let's start with the last 10-12 years.
I think I know somebody who can help us.
Let's try.
It's funny...
here I am writing a book
'One Hit wonders of Bollywood'.
About actors who disappeared
after one hit film.
And you want to know about directors
who disappeared after directing a flop film.
Not just flop,
but whose last film
was also heavily criticised.
The first name that comes to mind
is Guru Dutt.
But I understand you want names
from the last 12 years.
- Guru Dutt?
- Yes.
'Kaagaz Ke Phool'.
His best and most personal film
was trashed by critics.
He didn't make films after that.
He died a few years later...
a broken and depressed man.
Today the same film is considered
a masterpiece.
A film truly ahead of its time.
Damn! You critics are killers.
But, ma'am, I'm just curious...
depression in artists
leads to alcohol, drugs
and even suicide...
I can understand but--
Depression doesn't always
lead to self-harm.
External violence is also a manifestation
of deep inner turmoil and disturbance.
Your seniors were very lucky
that Guru Dutt harmed only himself.
I guess I have a lot of research to do.
Kartik,
is there someone who can assist you?
Someone who has the
knowledge of films like you.
We don't have much time.
Are you a florist or Pablo Escobar?
You grow marijuana, right?
Such a big house in posh Bandra... how?
Advantage of being born into
a Catholic family in Bandra.
70 years ago, my grandfather
got it cheap because he was Catholic.
Now I struggle to pay the electricity bill
by selling flowers.
One minute, I have something for you.
You're thinking about my mother now?
For you.
Thank you.
Look at that, what a lovely scene.
Father watching a film.
Hey, was it your father or grandfather?
Someone in your family
was a filmmaker, right?
Shit!
You saw those film cans!
That was supposed to be a surprise.
What surprise?
If I tell you, how will it be a surprise.
Idiot! Idiot!
Why did you let her come inside?
She saw the film cans.
Yes, she did.
What to do? I handled it.
Rubbish, you handled it.
We can't take a chance.
She can turn up any time.
Shift all the cans down.
And cut!
Was it okay?
I'm proud of you.
Where are the leaves on the poster?
What leaves, Mom?
The ones that are like brackets.
'Best Film of the Year.'
'Winner of 10 Oscars.'
Medals are awarded
after you win a race.
You should put them now.
Best! Best! Best!
Print the leaves.
'A dismal debut.'
'A slow, depressing film.'
'A headache-inducing story.'
'Where is the film in this film?'
Your film is the best film.
You are the best director.
You are the best.
The best.
Coming soon.
How? Everyone has shut up.
For how long?
We have found 216 directors so far.
Whatever reviews we could find are here.
This is the first time I'm hearing
of some of these films.
Many Wikipedia pages and photos
are missing.
I've even checked with
the Directors Association,
half these people are
not even registered.
It's as if they never even existed.
- Hi, I'm Nila.
- Zenobia.
It will be tough to find
and interrogate 216 people.
Yeah, but it's not impossible.
Arushi Kanakia, Akash Gulati...
what about Sebastian Gomes?
Rajesh Batra...
Whose birthday?
It's Moushumi Aunty's anniversary today.
I'm going to give her this cake
and wish her.
Hold on.
Where did you get this?
I baked it.
Not the cake.
This cellophane paper.
I don't know.
It was lying around at home.
It must have come from somewhere...
I think... yes!
The day of Govind Pandey's murder,
after you left,
a bouquet arrived.
It was left at the door.
There was a 'Thank you' note,
without a name.
This bouquet was sent to you
by the killer!
I want the footage from that day.
This is Kinu, Malhotra's son.
Apartment number D-45.
He was wearing dark glasses
and a hoodie.
This bouquet was sent to you
by the killer!
You know how dangerous plastic is?
On Guru Dutt's birthday... paper flowers?
Guru Dutt?
What Guru Dutt?
Hearing 'critic' made you choke?
Oh, poisoning her own husband?
- Tired?
- Yes, good night.
Your boyfriend was here.
Danny came here?
He's Catholic, maybe I should say Romeo.
When? Why?
Why are you panicking?
He came to take me out on a date.
I said,
'Waste of time...
the entire city looks the same to me.'
Heartbroken,
he left you the gift
that he had actually got for me...
Surprise!
I grew flowers in a film can
hoping the florist appears
in your film like dream.
What happened?
Mom, I'm so stupid.
How could I be so stupid?
Bought the cans from a junk shop,
got the idea from the internet.
The poem is original.
It's... so beautiful.
I tried growing them in many cans,
only one was a success.
What are you doing?
I'm waiting for Blue - part two.
Thursday. I have my periods.
Sir, I know I have just one week.
There are suspects...
216 suspects, sir.
I need time, try and understand--
Sorry, sir.
Okay, sir.
I feel like killing somebody.
Criticism is turning everyone
into killers.
God save the world!
Will the threat of CBI taking over the case
make the killer give himself up?
Quiet, Arvind.
I am hunting for clues in the reviews
Kartik has compiled.
We will all be reviewed in a week.
Let's see if we have any stars left.
Star!
Zenobia, stars!
'We' should be giving stars!
'We' should write reviews not read.
It's just a film review.
It's just a-just a...
Yeah, listen, there's nothing to...
Nonsense!
Not one critic is ready.
Everyone is scared.
Sorry, Nikhil. I can't do this.
I promised Reshma,
I can't do this to her.
I can't put my family
through another trauma.
Sorry, Arvind sir.
I'm done with this.
Please excuse me.
I'm... I'm sorry, sir.
What if we use a fake name?
A fake name won't work.
You are damn yum!
And?
And damn hot.
And damn cool.
And?
And I'm in the office!
Rest on Thursday night.
And?
If you're lucky,
then Friday morning too!
Nila?
Oh! I'll call you back. Okay bye.
Hi, sir. You are here?
You know her?
Do you need some other help, sir?
Yeah.
I need a critic.
Mom...
Mom, wake up.
What happened?
I was seeing such a nice dream.
What's wrong, huh?
Mom...
Where are you going?
You were 11...
Your school had taken you
to watch 'Lion King'.
You came home and wrote
your first review.
And I saw the film
as you read it to me.
The light is on. Read it...
Read.
I knew then...
you will be a great critic.
I said 'yes' bravely.
Thought I'm getting a chance
to make a difference...
But now I'm a little...
This police order...
I can't talk to anyone and it's just...
I wish I could speak to Danny.
He would have sorted out my head.
To be a lion in life,
you need to have more courage
than a sheep.
What kind of a mother are you?
So willing to sacrifice
your daughter, huh?
If anything happens to me,
will you manage on your own?
I am proud of you, Nila.
Proud of you.
How are you, Danny?
Long time...
Danny's special scrambled eggs,
two portions.
The joy of breaking a fast.
Why shout? I'm right here.
Sir, after the Mumbai Post article,
everyone wants to publish
reviews on Friday.
Media war.
Scared that Mumbai Post
will grab their audience.
It'll look real if everyone reviews.
Security for everyone?
Not everyone... just four.
Tell the others to write
at their own risk.
They will be too scared to write.
Our 'filmmaker' should not find
a good script in any of the reviews,
except one.
I'm getting nervous, Arvind.
Ever thought we'd watch a film
under such pressure?
I'm scared to even rate cab drivers
these days.
All this will make us think about
every word we write.
What to 'think' in a film
like 'Ding Dong'?
The poster itself is telling us
not to use our brains.
Who's that girl?
Just look at her.
She's so young.
This just doesn't seem right.
If she was old, would it be right?
She's a brave girl.
She wants to be a brave girl.
She knows the danger...
but the foolish idealism of youth!
And you and me...
we're taking advantage of that.
'Foolish idealism of youth'?
If not for this 'foolish idealism',
no one would be in the army
or the police.
- All set, sir.
- Yeah, let's go.
Let's go.
Rest on Thursday night.
If you're lucky,
then Friday morning too!
- Did you like the film?
- It was great fun.
It was not stupid at all...
very smart slapstick.
It's been so long
since I've laughed so hard.
Everyone enjoyed it.
Good. Rate it one star.
But why? I loved it.
You loved, I loved it...
the killer will also like it.
So kill it.
No.
Look, Nila, if you don't want
to take the risk, I get it.
Let's just call this off.
But...
this is my first review.
This has been my dream.
The dream of becoming a critic
will come true
when the nightmare of being a critic ends.
What about ethics?
This could harm the film.
Ethics is about doing the right thing.
Now wrong is right!
Do you want to give it five stars?
Not five, but at least...
One!
Something's wrong...
Something's wrong.
Yeah, she dumped you.
Don't be so desperate. Wait.
She disconnected the call.
You called her 16 times
and she disconnects after 3 rings?
For security reasons,
we have to shift your mother from here.
Just for a few days.
We had a date today.
I want to know why she didn't come.
The date is tomorrow.
Our date.
Mom, come here.
I just finished the review of 'Ding Dong'.
Two tickets.
The security should remain invisible.
Our 'guest' shouldn't suspect a thing.
Ding-dong, the first review is out!
Nila?
'Something really urgent came up.
I'm so sorry I missed your calls.'
'Where are you? I need you.'
Where were you?
You'll have to wait, Nila.
'Ding Dong is a good entertaining film.'
What the hell is happening?
Why wasn't our review online first?
We announced first.
We had to be the first!
'...and I am going with three stars.'
'Good entertaining film!'
Give me something for
my entertainment, madam.
Upload. Next.
''Ding Dong' is a breezy film.'
'It's not a brilliant masterpiece...
three and a half stars.'
Come on, give it four stars.
What are you saving half a star for?
Okay, go. Next.
'Ding Dong... very wrong!'
One star?
Who's the critic?
Nila!
Blah blah...
'Writing is bad, jokes are cheap.'
'My head is splitting
into a thousand pieces.'
'Ding Dong is pure torture,
guaranteed to cause brain damage.'
'My advice - save your money
and your brain.
Stay at home.'
Love you, Nila.
I love you.
I'm coming home!
Are you okay?
No.
Don't feel guilty.
The film is a hit.
Negative or positive reviews
don't make a difference.
I don't give a damn about the film.
I'm just really missing my mother.
I don't need your phone to speak to her.
Stop it, please.
It's just for a few days,
she's comfortable and safe...
I can't take this anymore.
I can't, please...
What am I doing?
I don't want to die.
We are all here,
no one can touch you.
You have been a brave girl.
I've not been brave,
I've just been stupid!
Just chill now. Relax.
Chill? Chill?
Are you insane?
It's just hitting me now,
I'm waiting here for someone
to smash my head,
because of your stupid script...
into a thousand pieces.
And you're telling me to chill?
I'm so dumb!
- Try and understand, Nila...
- No, I can't!
Please, please,
I just want to go meet my Mom.
Sorry, I can't do this.
Please, please...
I want to go talk to my Mom, please.
Let me go, Arvind sir.
I'm sorry. Please...
Yeah?
Do you know Danny?
Yes! Please, ask him to come up.
I love him. I want to see him.
If he really loves you,
he will understand...
- tell him she's sleeping.
- No, please!
Give him the phone.
Danny, I want to see you.
Please come up. I am really scared.
Take me away from here.
Please...
- What's wrong with you?
- Please... I want to see Danny! Please!
Please!
Okay, five minutes.
Yes, sir?
Okay, sir.
Are you new here?
- Danny.
- Just hold on.
You cannot stay here for too long.
This is madness.
I'm not going to leave.
That's not your decision.
Please...
I think she's stressed out.
If she rests a bit she'll be fine.
How can you do this?
Do what?
I'm not leaving Nila alone.
Alone?
Can't you see me?
It's the job of the police
to protect us from danger
but you're inviting danger home.
I see you, not the police.
Don't cops have a heart?
I love Nila.
I can give my life for her.
Let me be here, please.
I love my job...
I can take a life for it.
If I listen to my heart,
I will lose focus.
Danny... don't leave me.
I'm here. I'm here.
It was just a bad dream.
Thank you.
I think you should leave now.
Who the fuck are you to tell me to go?
Make sure that he leaves the building.
Perfect throw... fell on the mark!
Sorry, the budget is tight.
It's all I could manage.
Hurry up man, the shot is ready!
Lights!
Camera!
Action!
You know when I think
I'll really fall in love?
When someone actually
walks towards me in slow motion...
Have you fallen in love now?
How will she reply?
Sound-proof studio, Nila.
When did I say my name was Danny?
His name is Sebastian Gomes.
Danny...
was the name of our dog.
Wherever he peed in the garden,
flowers grew.
So... Danny's flowers!
My mother's husband...
unfortunately my father...
killed him.
Why?
Shut up!
I'm talking, why are you interrupting?
Why?
Shall I tell her?
♪ Who knows what you said? ♪
You said,
'I wish I'd used my brain
and stayed at home'.
♪ Who knows what I heard? ♪
We need cinema to feel alive.
♪ Something stirred in my heart ♪
Something stirred in my heart.
Nila lives in cinema.
Welcome to your dream home, Nila.
Wonder how many homes
have been made here...
are being made here...
and will be made here.
Feeling alive?
Whose cycle is that?
Sir, this is Danny's.
Get his phone number
and tell him to take his cycle.
♪ I trembled with joy ♪
...seeing one star.
♪ I quivered with excitement ♪
...seeing your name.
♪ My dreams reawakened ♪
at last...
A good critic.
'Head is splitting into a thousand pieces'?
If you write a wrong review,
won't my head split too?
Why, Nila?
Why?
You were my cinema...
beautiful,
magical...
Reality is...
ugly, flat, boring.
Why did you have to become real
and ruin my film?
'Pyaasa' (Thirsty)?
He is not answering his phone.
But we found the name of his shop
- 'Danny's Flowers'.
I loved you, Danny.
Sebastian Gomes.
I am not a critic, Danny.
The police told me to...
I know why you rated it one star.
What would you rate it,
if it was up to you?
Four stars.
What a joke!
You would have given it four stars?
Four stars?
It's a copy of a Mongolian film.
Every frame is a copy.
Not official. A stolen copy!
Mongolia makes some
very good films you know.
Haven't watched them?
That's the problem...
ignorant critics.
If you celebrate a thief,
everyone will think stealing is right!
Who will try to think out of the box?
Cinema is art,
not a damn photocopy machine!
If you had given it one star
and said it was a copy,
I would have fallen at your feet.
I would have been ecstatic...
and my cinema would be alive.
I thought we had something
in common, Nila.
You turned out too real!
Now I have to give you four little stars.
Bastard!
If the head splits
into a thousand pieces,
where will we carve the stars?
You should've thought of this!
A review is one person's opinion.
Everyone has a different opinion.
Tell me one film everyone
had the same opinion about.
'Chup (Shut Up)'
written and directed
by Sebastian Gomes.
The one film everyone
had the same opinion about.
You didn't like your film too?
You also didn't like your film?
Then kill yourself first.
Criticism really hurts when the artist
is not sure of his own work.
Did you also give your film 'one star'?
Tell me.
Why are you silent?
? The world... ?
? This world of palaces,
of thrones, of crowns ?
? This enemy of man,
this divided world ?
? A world hungry for wealth
and full of traditions ?
? Would it matter if such a world
were mine? ?
? Wounded bodies, thirsty souls ?
? Confused eyes, unhappy hearts ?
? Is this a world or a nightmare? ?
? Would it matter if such a world
were mine? ?
Should we run away?
If we go, who'll look after Ma?
Look after Ma...
or cineMa?
? Here a man's life is a toy ?
? Here live worshippers of the dead ?
? Here death is cheaper than life ?
? Would it matter if such a world
were mine? ?
? Youth lose their way ?
As long as the real dog is alive,
chill.
? Here love is just another trade ?
? Would it matter if such a world
were mine? ?
This is the story of his life.
He made his own biopic.
If this was his life,
I'm not surprised
that he turned out like this.
No.
It was this life that made him
an artist.
Pain is the most powerful fuel
for an artist.
If his film had been appreciated
by the world,
the story would have been different.
But unfortunately, the critics...
they didn't just criticise his film,
they criticised his life.
They gave his pain a 'one star' rating...
If someone ridicules your pain...
it can really damage you.
Critics finished what his father
just started.
He was in the wrong profession.
He should've been in politics.
There are so many critics here...
Danny's special scrambled eggs,
two portions.
Sukethu Varma,
film critic
dies of Covid.
Shut up!
He is mad, be sensitive.
♪ Burn it, blow this world away ♪
♪ Burn it, burn it ♪
♪ Take this world away from my sight ♪
♪ It's your world, you can keep it ♪
♪ Would it matter if such a world
were mine? ♪