The beacon fires on the border
The iron cavalry rides a thousand miles
Seeking joy, finding peace
in the mountains and rivers
The fragrance of wine in the
phoenix pavilion and dragon tower
Ambition arises from sorrow
The mournful cry of geese
spreads across the northern land
Brave warriors embark on their journey
To join the army and serve the country with joy
To kill the enemy and fill them with fear
Toast together upon returning from battle
Please sing it again
I say, change to a more pleasant one
Don't trouble the singer
Then I've to trouble you
Who are you?
I'm going to join army under General Zhang
to fight the enemy
Oh, an unknown soldier
Do you know who our master is?
If you recognize him, you'll be stunned
Must be a subject of Song Dynasty
Our master is the son of the prime minister!
He's one of the corrupt Song Dynasty
Kill him!
Murder!
My lady, please...
You should not...
You still want revenge!
But I don't know martial arts
What can I use for revenge?
Miss, you can't do this
With your status, you can gather people to help
revenge for the country
You're not thinking about the Song Dynasty
You should also seek revenge for your parents
Mother...
We've arrived
Uncle, this is General Wang
The honorable general
This is our General's daughter
The daughter of General
Zhang and everyone
We all warmly welcome you
Have you heard that the border
has been breached by the Jin army?
General Zhang served the country faithfully
General Zhang is an extraordinary loyal minister
Everyone is here, what can I do?
Just give your orders
Excuse us for coming abruptly
Please consider that we are all common people
Besides asking for your shelter
There are a few more things to discuss
I'm expecting your instruction
Tell everyone in the village
No one is allowed to mention
that the miss is staying here
Understood
we need to set up headquarters here
Gather heroes from all directions to seek revenge
Reclaim our lost territory
Just a moment!
You're here to audition, not to fight for your life
What do you do?
I...
Are we comparing fists or weapons?
You're not good enough.
How about that guy over there.
At your service
Alright, another lesson.
Please...
Take care
Ta Kuan!
Just another big mouth
Big Fatty, Second Fatty, both can try
Please forgive me for
not recognising your ability
Don't be too polite
I don't care for niceties.
May I ask your name?
Just a prisoner
Could I test you?
Please give me a blade
You are really the man we need
to drive out the invaders
killing the Jin people...
I might be interested.
But now I have a condition
If you serve the country
We will reward you
You tell me, any conditions
I just want to see your lady
Our lady?
She is not here!
You are not a honest man.
I came here just for her
Since she's not here, I'll leave
Please stay, sir
Which lady are you talking about
General Zhang's daughter
I heard Zhang Zhe has a daughter,
I didn't expect her to be so beautiful
It seems fortune favours me!
Don't be imprudent
Uncle Wang, who is he?
Why do you bring him to see me?
We've tried to recruit for days
He is the only one with
real martial arts skills
He wants to see you
Since you are a knight,
please take a seat
This seat is vacant
You must know the purpose
of our recruitment,
to expel the Jin and recover the territory
On the other hand,
it is also to avenge father
Simply put,
you need a group of fearless people
To fight the Jin soldiers to the death
Are you willing to take on
this heavy responsibility?
It depends on the conditions you offer me
Don't push your luck
Why are there more conditions?
I don't want to risk my life for you for no reason
If you don't want to, then get lost
You're not a citizen of the Song Dynasty
Don't be disrespectful
We are also people who have lost their homes
and haven’t much money with us
We have no authority to offer you
a high rank position.
I don't care about high positions or wealth.
What I want is you
What did you say?
I've been wandering for many years
But I still haven't found a wife
What I wish is to marry you
Damn madman
Don't be impolite
This girl is quick and ruthless.
Eight darts in a throw
There's one more here.
Bravo!
Nothing special
But I can still compete with the Jin soldiers.
Sister, marriage is a big deal.
It's not a joke.
I promise to marry you.
But I have conditions too.
Let's hear it.
I want the head of General Wan Yan.
To be offered before my deceased father's spirit.
Only then can we get married.
I came to seek revenge on you.
I didn't expect to avenge you!
Ha...
What's your name?
Jin Shan-Kuo
Miss, don't worry.
No matter what,
you won't marry that barbarian.
As long as he can bring back Wan Yan's head
to avenge my father
Chun Mei, is his martial arts great?
High martial arts skill, low character.
Who?
It's me, Wang Fuon
Uncle Wang, is there something?
Miss, please forgive me.
I'm afraid I've erred.
Jin Shan-Kuo is a fugitive.
What grudge does he have with my father?
He killed the Premier's son
He was sentenced to death by General Zhang,
but he escaped.
I don't know how he ended up here.
It doesn't matter.
What do you think of his martial arts skills?
Rarely seen in a hundred years.
Then let's make good use of him.
But he wants to marry the miss.
Having avenged my father
I have no attachment to the world.
He won't marry a dead person.
Lady...
Our miss is the General's daughter.
What are you?
A murderer and fugitive.
You're not even worthy to speak with her
You actually want to marry her?
You're really a shameless guy
Have you eaten a lot?
Are you done cursing?
If you're done, please leave.
If there's no more nonsense, continue.
I'm going to sleep.
Have you finished?
Tolerable
It's this guy, annoying and troublesome.
I want to discuss something with you.
How can we obtain Wan Yan's head?
That's my business, don't worry about it.
I can give you some information
Wan Yan has four Generals
Known as the Four Heavenly Kings,
each with strong martial arts.
The first one is Fan Tong.
He is cunning and ruthless,
with excellent lightness skills.
He is a famous assassin under Wan Yan's command.
General Fan.
I think I'll send you to investigate
Zhang En-Zhu's whereabouts.
That's your specialty.
We must capture her.
I heard that girl is quite good-looking.
The second one is Hung Tu.
He has immense strength and is fearless.
But he lacks intelligence.
General Hung, take some soldiers
Go to the Four Villages to
search for gold and jewels.
If you can find beautiful women,
that would be even better.
What if there are neither
girls nor treasures there?
What's the point of that village then?
Alright, then I will burn it down
The third one is Har Cha.
He is Kuan Yan's right-hand
man and never leaves his side.
To kill Kuan Yan, we must first eliminate him.
General, what mission do you assign me!
Your duty is to guard me
The fourth one is Na Sha.
He has a skill called Blood Sand Palm,
which can strike through walls.
Quickly
Master Jia, the General has something to say.
Tell him to wait.
Didn't you see me practicing?
The General said there's an important matter.
Get out of here!
General...
Out, all of you!
Master, please take a seat
How is your Blood Sand Palm training going?
It's about 90% complete
Very good, now don't you think
we should continue to advance
But there are still a few things to take care of
Zhang Zhe is dead
His daughter's whereabouts
are unknown, it's a concern
What should we do?
Jin Shan-Kuo
I'm talking to you, why are you falling asleep?
Someone like him will be a
problem sooner or later
It's better to get rid of him early
You are not a decent men
You want to plot against me while I'm asleep
I will go before I get killed here
Can you just leave like that?
If I want to leave, who can stop me?
Wait ten days
If I don't die, I will bring
back the head of Shu Wanyan
Will, you go alone?
My wife is my business alone
If I don't come back in ten days
It means the Four Great Kings are stronger than me
Tell your Miss to marry someone else
There are no beauties, so why keep this house?
Why not set it on fire?
Yes
Quick! Quick!
Hurry! Go! Let's go!
Go! Let's go!
Let's go!
The girls are not beautiful,
and there are not many jewels
Why don't we burn it down?
Come up!
Go away, you are all useless
What are you doing here? Get away
Messenger
I am the messenger.
Are you Hung Tu?
You are Hung Tu, right?
General Hung, for whom is the message?
You don't look like Hung Tu.
Come here.
General Hung.
Back off, I'm looking for the
General who carries a big iron rod.
I am General Hung, what's the matter?
There are many jewels and
beautiful women over there.
Where?
In the woods over there.
Wait for me here.
Messenger
I am here
Where is the treasure?
Under the ground
Dig a bigger hole. You have a big body.
Dig more
You'll see them when you're about die
Who are you?
A messenger
Who sent you?
The King of Hell sent me.
What's over there?
I'm right here.
Hung Tu!
They say you have unlimited strength.
I see you! You're just a dumb brute.
Hung Tu! Why don't you leave the trees alone?
That is the man we want
Waiter! I need a room
What?
A guest room?
Yes, a guest room
I think you should go somewhere else.
What?
Innkeeper, don't be afraid.
I'm an old friend of General Hung.
Sorry to bother you, is it okay?
Good wine
How does it taste?
Anyone who dares to come will lose their life.
Take the staff back to your boss.
A messenger is waiting here for him
Don't forget, give it to Har Cha.
Where is the messenger?
He has gone to sleep
Had dinner and went to sleep.
Which room is he staying in?
The first one, just up the stair
Sir, sir
Come on.
What are you doing?
Go and see if General Har has returned.
He hasn't come back yet.
Who are you?
A messenger
You're the one who killed General Hung.
It'll be your turn soon
I'm here to borrow something from you.
I want to marry without a dowry.
You... What do you want?
Let's talk.
They asked for... your head.
General Wan Yan,
please cooperate.
Lend me your head.
Hold!
Na sha!
It's me!
Look here!
Thank you, Master
After him!
He's hurt.
He can't run far.
Dad, please bless us in heaven
Uncle Wang, how many days has Jin Shan-Kuo been gone?
Today is the seventh day.
Why is there no news at all?
Did he escape?
I'm more anxious than you.
I've sent someone to town for news.
My lady, Mr. Jin...
- What happened?
- He, he was killed by that Na Sha.
Did someone see it with their own eyes?
Is it true?
The news came from Jin's army camp.
Jin Shan-Kuo killed Hung Tu on the way.
Then a person broke into Wan Yan's tent late at night.
He was almost successful
But he was hit in the vital
point by the Blood Sand Palm.
He is indeed a brave warrior.
It happened last night.
He might have died on the way back.
Dad, tell me.
Who else can I ask?
Let's not give up,
there is still a glimmer of hope.
I heard that Lu Ba is
causing trouble at Wuli Peak.
I'll call on him
Many knights have gone solo,
We should make contact with them
Since he is an old hero, please let him in.
Certainly.
Miss Zhang, you don't know me.
I've been looking for you for a long time.
May I ask for the name of the heroic guest?
Under General Wan Yan,
there are four great generals.
I am Ghost Shadow Fan Tong.
Kill him
Anyone dares to make a move,
I won't spare her.
My lady, tell them stand aside
Who are you? Tell him to let me through.
I'm a messenger.
Attack!
Has he still fever?
No.
Hasn't he woken up yet?
It's not too hot, you can feed him.
He's is sweating a lot,
he probably won't die.
It's not that I can't die,
it's that I don't want to die.
You're awake!
I can't bear to die.
You almost couldn't marry your wife.
You've been unconscious
for three days and three nights.
I will have words with Wang Feng.
He did not warn me that
Na sha has Blood Sand Palm technique.
Well, where is Wang Feng?
General Wang has arrived.
Wang Feng, did the wind blow you here?
General Wang
General Pang
Don't call me General Pang
I'm the Mountain King now.
Just call me Pang Ba.
What about it, do you want to join us?
General Pang
I told you not to call me General Pang.
In my mind, you will always be a
general of the Great Song Dynasty.
Although you are a defeated general.
You should not forget
where you came from.
Don't talk about that.
It is just upsetting.
What exactly are you here for?
I want to ask you to join us
Raise the banner of the people again,
let's fight side by side.
You only have one arm left.
What's the point of talking
about fighting or not fighting?
They can cut me to pieces,
I'll never give up
The General's daughter is
gathering people at Lu Zhuang.
Preparing to fight the Jin army.
General Pang, for Song Dynasty
Lead your troops down the mountain.
You ask them, who will go with you
Gentlemen,
Are you happy to become bandits
and be despised for thousands of years?
General Pang
Who called me General?
Don't come here to sow discord.
If you're willing to stay,
we'll take you in.
If not, get out of here right now.
Pang Ba, it's not shameful to be defeated.
What's shameful is that you've
become scared of the Jin army.
Wang Feng,
if you talk like that again...
I shall take your other arm!
Hurry up and put on your
clothes, don't catch a cold.
Is the lady sleeping?
You're always thinking about her.
Jin Shan-Yao, don't dream the impossible.
You must know you're no match.
But she personally promised me.
Why do you have to marry her?
Is it just for revenge?
You have to admit
Your lady is beautiful
But she doesn't like you at all.
I don't care, I want her.
Choosing a wife is a lifelong matter.
You should marry a girl who is your match.
The most important thing is that she likes you.
I've always been disliked by people.
No one has ever liked me.
At first, I disliked you greatly.
But slowly, I stopped disliking you.
It seems like you never look at me directly.
Take a closer look.
I have a bad habit.
I'm not sure to like someone who likes me,
but I must like someone who doesn't like me.
You'll never be able to have her in your life.
Why didn't that Na Sha kill you
Don’t' go yet.
I need your help with something.
I asked you to look at me before.
Why are you staring at me now?
This is my bad habit.
You're here again.
We are doomed to meet each other.
How's your nose? Is it better?
Can you go to another place?
Look, my business is ruined.
No problem, only if someone trouble me
Even if it's a little,
it's still business, right?
Come on, give me two jugs of wine
He didn't die?
That's right.
Did you see it with your own eyes?
I saw him with my own eyes.
He's drinking in the restaurant.
This time, I'll make sure he dies.
Master, should I report to the General?
Get some more men to go with you
Unnecessary.
They'll only make trouble.
We've been here for a while,
shouldn't they be here by now?
Master, I've missed you these days.
I was just about to visit you.
Leave.
Please have a seat.
Probably haven't been close
to a woman in your whole life.
But you can always have a little wine!
Trivial tricks, don't show off in front of me.
I've been wanting to test you,
go ahead and do your best.
I dare not,
I've come to learn your Blood Sand Palm.
No wonder you've recovered so quickly.
Your internal strength is not bad.
Sit down, I have something to tell you.
Then talk right now
I've never encountered a
worthy opponent in my life.
Being able to spar with you today,
I feel it's worth it.
However, don't plan on leaving here alive.
I came here with no intention of staying alive.
Show me your palm.
I'll let you die without any regrets.
Kill him!
Your turn, girl.
You don't touch women,
but I'm getting married.
Na Sha
We have eliminated three
of the Four Heavenly Kings.
But there are still thousands of
people under Wan Yan Zheng.
With just us, we can't risk launching an attack.
How many people are there under Pang?
From what I know, there are about a hundred people.
Most of them tend toward us except Pang.
Uncle Wang, I want to meet General Pang.
My lady
Even if I go, I might not be able to persuade him.
But everyone is shedding blood and sweat.
I may not have martial arts skills,
but I should contribute my part.
Is Wuli Peak ahead?
Probably!
Hey, you're guarding the lady,
I'll go ahead to scout.
No point riding into a volley of arrows.
Would you like to take a rest?
How should I address you?
Call me whatever you want
I've wanted to thank you for a long time
Regardless of your intentions
or what your purpose is
I'm very grateful to you
You're not marrying me just to
get revenge on my father, are you?
If that's the case,
you'll live your life in hatred
I hope you won't.
I'm willing to repay you for the rest of my life
This mountain is mine
Those trees were planted by me
This mountain doesn't concern you
Those trees were not planted by you
General Gan, do you know me?
Lady
Surprising to see you here, lady
But I can't go back
I have no face to go back
General Pang, we need you
I know I know, I understand
The Jin army is trying to capture me,
they want my head.
Song regards me as a rebel.
Even if I go back, what then?
You can redeem yourself
through your achievements
Drive the Jin army out of the border
You will be a hero of the country
I'm not brave enough.
How many soldiers do you have?
I only have about a hundred people here
Can you take on thousands
of Jin soldiers in battle?
You!
Wang Feng is right about your being scared.
You...!
So this a great general of the Song Dynasty?
Shan-Kuo!
Enemies roam freely in our land,
and I can do nothing.
I can only do what heroes do.
Offer my head to the enemy.
Take the opportunity to kill Wang Yan.
For our country's sake,
to avenge General Zhang.
Even if I, Pang Ba, die, I have no regrets.
Pang Ba's final words.
An extraordinary general, a great hero.
Sure! It's Pang Pa
Still not ready to die, Chang?
I killed him with my own hands,
so there's no mistake.
You finally know what's good for you.
Thanks to master's blessings,
I hope I can secure a good position.
You won't be disappointed.
If all the people of the Song Dynasty were like you,
we would already rule your country.
Is Miss Zhang at Lu Zhuang?
If the master doesn't believe it,
I can show you the way.
How many are there?
There are probably about twenty men and women.
Is there a man called...
Well, what's his name?
The messenger.
Right, the one called messenger?
I never heard of any messenger
Lu Da Kang is the strongest one there.
Pang Ba, you, who else is left?
What's so special about Lu Dagang?
Don't let them slip away.
Let's go now.
Wang Feng, you lead the way.
It seems like there's no one in this village.
Burn it when we come back.
Climb to the tower.
General, they're hiding in this temple.
General, this is the person you're looking for.
Yes, yes, yes, it's her.
Look, she's more beautiful than a painting.
Wang Feng...
Little lady, take this.
Fight!
Beauty.
Beautiful.
Beautiful, beautiful...
Prettier than a painting
Dad!
General Wang, where is Jin Shan-Kuo
My lady...
Miss, Jin Shan-Kuo...
Lady...
Jin Shan-Kuo wants you to take care.
Where is he?
He is gone!