"GREY CITY"
SÃO PAULO, DECEMBER 2008
This city was not
made for the people.
It's made for cars, for the
robots, you know?
Who have a routine of going and
coming back from work,
doing everyday
the very same thing.
And once a year they decide
to do something different.
Once a year or maybe twice...
But why is that?
São Paulo has no beach, man!
If you're stressed, you go
to the sea, you surf a little,
you feel great.
But São Paulo is a concrete
jungle buildings, buildings
and more buildings... The more you
build, the less you have trees
and parks... And more
and more buildings...
As if you're building a wall
around you, you know?
So you have to escape, any how you
have to runaway from all these.
Or be apart of it.
That's the history
of graffiti, you know?
Of "picho"... you belong to it!
And the youth is talking.
It's not only graffiti,
it's "picho" as well.
A lot of people manifesting,
talking...
The guy is there cause he needs
to express himself.
Some stuff, you know?
But I think graffiti and "picho"
are the only movements nowadays,
in which the young
people talk, for real.
Cause nowadays they are very
settled, very quiet, you know?
- These people are talking.
- They are occupying buildings.
They are occupying the city.
In away or another, they are
expressing themselves,
questioning something...
The guy is beating the system
and doing what he wants.
The city suffocates you
and you need to talk,
you need to put your
name on it. And you do it.
The guy has the energy to go there
and do it. And fuck it, I did it.
I think, since the very first guy
who took a spray and scribbled,
I don't know,
anything, on street.
He was already
questioning this, right?
How the city could be used...
Not only to... not only
to display a product,
to sell a car or
something like that...
But also to make art, right?
It's not an art that only
one person owns.
In São Paulo is
pretty easy to paint.
You just don't paint if
you don't want to.
Like, people have other
things to worry about,
look at the traffic jam!
Everybody is trying to get
somewhere, do you really think
they're going to worry that
someone is painting the wall?
They want to arrive at their
house, or to their job...
This is Babylon,
man, this is chaos.
A chaotic city deserves
chaos, you know?
I don't wanna drive
by with my car here
and see that wall
painted grey.
I don't wanna see grey, I want to
see color, so I'm gonna change it.
I'll put some color over there
and put my name on it.
I wanna see my name on the city.
São Paulo being the way it is...
Giving us the freedom
to paint during the day.
With or without permission.
Allowed us to do our
job, to create it.
Everything we learned was here,
in São Paulo, in the streets.
And it's the same for many
other graffiti artists.
And this work was valued
abroad, you know?
The work we took abroad
was created here.
QOSGEMEQOS - PORTUGAL
OSGEMEQOS - USA
NUNCA - ITALY
NUNCA - CANADA
NINA - INDIA
I think being on the
streets gives you the power
to talk to all the people.
Regardless of social class or
cultural life a person has or not.
And you can talk either positive
or negative things.
It's a very strong weapon,
because it works with image.
And image is a direct language,
you don't need to stop
to read it or listen to it.
You see it and it's in your
mind already, unconsciously.
Like a subliminal message.
I think image on street
is powerful!
If we think the city
as a support.
And graffiti as one
manifestation of it.
Graffiti is one of the most
interesting things São Paulo
produces and considering
a chaotic city like São Paulo,
graffiti helps composing
the chaos itself.
When [ first left Brazil,
I thought this chaos was a
negative thing, but on coming back
I realized chaos is the best
thing we have.
Because that's what makes
us more creative.
That our "Brazilian way"
has not only a vicious side of
improvising all the time.
But that there's a side of
creativity and generosity,
and I think and
graffiti is part of it.
What got my attention regarding
painting on the streets
back in those days...
someone I've never met could
see my work, you know?
From the moment I draw
something on the streets,
it's not mine anymore,
it becomes a public good.
It feels that the wall
is a dirty support,
but you don't touch the
wall, the paint does.
Crazy enough, you don't
make contact to the wall,
the paint does it;
it's quite magic!
Comes from your mind,
passes through the veins
and through your instrument,
this is an instrument.
The ink then leaves
the spray towards the wall;
we don't touch the wall.
It's magic, you don't
touch the dirt;
you transform it on
something nice.
It's a subliminal magic, you don't
realize it's happening, but it is.
Spray does it.
It's different from picking up
a brush and painting the wall.
Spray is sort of magic,
what it offers you, what it can do.
If you hold a spray can,
you'll feel like writing
your name or doing anything.
To anyone you give a spray can,
they will press "tsss tsss"
and look for a place to write,
you know? It's automatic.
Well, there is the magic.
And when this is part of you,
there's nothing you can do,
but do it. Just move
on and let it out.
I believe this is the most direct
way of treating each person
who passes by as human being.
Cause we don't see
each car as a gear.
Each car that passes
by has a story,
the guy who argued with his
wife, a girl who fell in love.
Everyone has a story,
everyone is a human being.
I think graffiti as a way of
talking to people.
And then there's a break through.
One day the guy sees
the wall all grey
and in the following
day it's colorful!
That's what's nice about it.
We're driving by when
we saw they had erased it.
I think they finished erasing
right before we saw it.
It's shocking because you
get used to it, right?
So we thought, "Ok,
is it war you want?
Is that how it's gonna
be from now on?"
When you see they've
erased a graffiti you did down
there and another on the other
side of the city or avenue, ok...
But when they erase
a work like this,
this big! You feel you're
being persecuted.
You understand
this is serious stuff.
Where you see grey paint,
that's us.
He said: Just erase it!
I think this one is awful'
We erased it.
- Do you know the schedule already?
- Fuck no!
Look, I'll erase all this,
you see?
A nice graffiti like
that one I'll leave be.
The guys are improving
their jobs...
Not blurring anymore.
They're using more art, right?
After our combat,
they're using more art.
We're going to work
here all day and night
to be able to finish it
by tomorrow.
To deliver our work to the
population no later than tomorrow.
You pass by a place
for seven years
and see the same painting.
And suddenly one day you
see that one side of it is grey.
It's like they'd taken off
apart your life.
The guys spent more than
a month to do the panel,
they spent more than six
months looking
for sponsorship to make it happen.
And due to an internal
bureaucracy,
a legal act, somebody
erased it, you know?
Man, we already lack
culture to keep erasing
the culture in the streets.
I'm not talking about erasing
a letter, my name,
or somebody else's name.
We're talking about erasing
work of artists, you know?
Every district has
a truck like this.
Butanta have it,
Pinheiros have it...
If they painted like this one,
which looks nice,
and not those black stuff.
This is very ugly,
don't you think? Look at it!
It's awful!
Awful. All smudged.
All messed up.
But there might have
some art in there;
maybe for an art curator,
this is beauty!
"MUNICIPALITY ACTS WITH RIGOR
DUETO THE CLEAN CITY ACT
AGAINST VISUAL POLLUTION"
Look, I think it's a good thing!
It was unbearable to see bigger
and bigger billboards in the city
and live with all the excess of
logos and publicity.
I particularly like
the advertising displays,
because they give some information
about the moment they were
conceived, you know?
Even though it's advertising.
But now they have to
think how they're going to allow
certain manifestations
to happen, such as graffiti;
because São Paulo is internationally
known by its graffiti.
A lot of kids lost their graffiti
there, you know? With this act.
Look how nice, you see?
That's a beautiful work.
I won't touch it.
It's a work of culture, right?
Yeah.
How often do you do this job?
Everyday, Monday to Friday.
Everyday there's
something to be done.
Do you think this is art?
That ain't art.
He didn't have the
right to cover in grey
only because there's an act...
Man, go ask the people what
they want first!
That was a mistake, for sure!
A work for which the artists
dedicated months to prepare...
and it was great to the city!
I think 80% maybe 90%
of the population
approved that graffiti.
The vast majority would definitely
approve to keep it there.
What kind of criteria
they're using in order
to erase a work of
700 square meters?
It's pretty. Some are pretty
and we don't erase it.
We just erase the ugly ones.
The ugly ones we erase, right?
They hire an outsourced
company to cover the paintings,
which evaluates and says
"erase here, erase there",
but the guys themselves don't
know what they re doing.
If the criteria are complex,
I think it's possible to
rethink these criteria.
Whoever is doing this job will
have a subjective standard.
If you chose to erase one
painting and leave another,
you're using a subjective
standard.
Even if it were the league
of graffiti super heroes,
it would be a subjective
choice.
Man's best friend, while it
doesn't know money, if it does...
Have you ever made any story
about dog pounds, man?
Nope.
If you go to "Zoonose" you will
see how the dog catchers work...
That is cruel! Yeah,
I worked there for 8 years.
Which one are you going
to cover?
We're going to cover this one
and leave this other as it is;
this is no work of art...
it's useless.
That one is out. Only
the one in the middle stays.
Only this one stays.
This one I can't leave.
We're keeping only this one.
You think this is graffiti?
Do you find it pretty?
What do you think about
this? Tell me the truth,
do you think this is nice?
If you don't offer
people what to see,
do not prevent them of what
they can see, you know?
They paint more often
during the weekends.
Next week... Monday is a bank
holiday, so Tuesday... on Wednesday,
you'll go out there and
it's all painted back.
And we cover again.
They should take this money
they re spending in grey paint
and use it to clean the rivers
or the culvert.
LUIS - We're going to defeat them
by fatigue, right?
They do graffiti and I'll go
there and cover it again.
They won't endure.
At one time they'll give up...
They'll have to spend
money on it.
Cause they have to buy
spray cans and stuff, right?
They'll paint and
we'll cover it...
That's it.
I was pissed off because
they had erased the wall
and in the following day
a reporter called me up.
We don't know what happened,
but the graffiti is gone...
The Mayor will have
to apologize publicly.
So, after a week
or two in which the media
couldn't stop talking about it,
the City Hall called us.
Maybe after a month.
Mayor Kassab himself called us,
and then the Secretary of Culture...
The City Hall called the
artists and will let the wall
to be covered in graffiti again.
"FOLHA DE S.PAULO"
CITY HALL ERASES ARTISTS
WALL BY MISTAKE®
I don't believe there's such
thing as a 700 m2 mistake!
That doesn't exist.
I kept thinking about it,
you know?
I even thought for a moment:
"Damn, maybe they just missed
it and erased the wall, right?"
But damn, that's a huge mistake.
Beyond huge,
just impossible to happen.
We realized the
importance of that work
to the city. A lot of people
called us non conformist
about the deletion...
Everybody was talking about it...
Now that the work is back,
you see people's reaction
when they pass by. "Great
that you're doing it again!"
"Congrats" or "Thanks" and
you see how important that is.
It means it already
belongs to the city.
One drawing completes
the other;
the wall hasn't been finished,
but the drawings will unite...
see, the water in the background
goes till the end
and suddenly a mountain appears...
everything is a single thing.
There are yet things to be drawn,
I'll draw something over
Nunca's and Osgemeos
will do the same...
CITY HALL AUTHORIZED THE
PAINTING OF THE NEW WALL,
BUT DECLINED TO AFFORD IT.
THE COMMERCIAL
ASSOCIATION OF SÃO PAULO
SPONSORED THE WORK.
THE GRAFFITI ARTISTS HAD
15 DAYS TO COMPLETE THE JOB.
Have you got any black?
- Yeap, but I'll use it.
- You'll use it?
I think it's great they
get the opportunity
to show their work in a
bigger scale, you know?
For the first time they're
doing a work this big.
It's good for their work,
you know?
To break down some barriers that
might yet exist; such as how to fit
their drawing in a particular
theme that we'd like;
how to fit in with Nunca's
or Nina's ideas, you know?
You see, nowadays they're
the guys who do more graffiti
in São Paulo.
They're every where.
We invited them to
be part of this work,
because they have
a very good style.
It's a new generation and they
worry about defending a style,
you know? They have they're
own style.
They are the new generation
and they're absorbing what's
been happening nowadays. ..
It's nice to be together,
develop the work together,
get to know how each one of us
develop the whole thing, you know?
Where all these references
come from. It's nice.
Now, this will take long...
"Treas" (trees).
Graffiti has its own culture,
of joining people,
the gang painting
together, you know?
We've known each
other for many years,
we like each other and we
always want to paint together.
If you are an artist that
comes from this environment,
you're different from an artist
that learned about art
in the university and
knows all about art history.
Graffiti has its own university,
that has no tuition
and anyone can do.
Being on the streets all the time,
let you more prepared
and less spoilt.
Today is gone, the rain will
stop at 8 o'clock at night.
Annoying not to have beige
to finish it all there.
Do that small part over
there, man!
Then you come back here.
Fuck, man! Hard life, man!
And you know what? There's
no power here, bro.
The battery?
Yeah, the battery is dead.
No, man! They should have
switched off down there.
Figo! (FINOK)
Bro, the battery is gone.
No, it doesn't, is switched off.
Pull the yellow button.
The red one...
Yeah, this one, now turn it on.
The machine is off.
The battery is dead!
No, it's not! The machine is
off, that's all.
Turn the machine on...
It's off, I told you.
That's it, the battery is dead.
Wow, wow! How stupid
can you be?! You Jerk!
You eat shit!
I can't believe it.
Just lower us down, sorry.
Really?
Take all the paint from here.
Watch your head!
Tell the guys to take the
cars away.
Hey Claudio (ISE)! Move your car!
Hey Gustavo! Gustavo,
take the car away.
This is mine.
Fuck it.
The man who is jealous of
Osgemeos has just arrived.
I don't need this,
cause Osgemeos is weak.
He copies all Osgemeos' ideas.
Osgemeos is weak;
Osgemeos envy Nunca!
Be careful there, man!
Osgemeos made a letter to Nunca...
down there.
Made to Nunca because
Osgemeos copies Nunca.
Go finish it for once!
I've got to know
that a guy named Pepeu,
sings a rap much better than
I do... talking about combat,
let's battle, I'm just waiting
for you to come up.
Bro, I think that was
the first rap song
I've ever heard in my life.
I'm Otavio, from Osgemeos,
we started attending
"São Bento" around 85, 86,
we're just kids...
And I believe it represented
to us what we are today.
The hip hop movement
unites four cultures,
in music: rap; in dance,
breakdance; in pickups: DJ.
And, the writers: graffiti.
Indeed, every thing
that we've learned
so far about hip hop,
we learned there.
There was a guy
from the north who had an info
that a guy from the South didn't
have, but who would bring
another info;
so everyone exchanged infos.
Thaide, DJ Hum, all this
generation... even Racionais,
KLJ... KLJ used
to breakdance.
All that generation came from
there, where everything started.
We also breakdanced a bit, but
then we decided to go for graffiti.
I was the one
who used to take
them to breakdance at
"São Bento".
But I never joined them while
they're painting trains.
Train wagons, or unauthorized
walls. I never did it...
And I used to tell them:
"Take care,
cause if the police catches
you, this is your problem."
Oh, yes, I warned them.
In 86, 87 we would paint exactly
what the Americans painted...
The ideal style and
competing for the best style
is the key to all
forms of rocking.
For the rap MC it's
rocking the mic.
For the b-boys it's rocking
your body and breakdancing.
Or for writers, rocking the city
with your name on the train.
What we wanted to do?
Leave from it.
We have to respect it,
right?
Where we were born, how we
were born, the old school,
but we have to keep
moving forward.
Everything that was to be
made related to graffiti,
related to the NY style,
the European style,
was already done.
And in Brazil, it seems we have
another life experience, right?
To have national and
cultural references.
I actually think that
graffiti for us wasn't
from the São Bento times.
We learnt to draw there,
get in touch with the
culture and all...
We began to really paint graffiti
in the late 80's, early 90's.
When we started to go
out to the streets,
when we wanted to occupy
the streets...
Quit drawing in t-shirts
and paper stuff
and face the street
as a support.
To really discover São Paulo
through graffiti.
Then we really got to know São
Paulo, how's to walk in São Paulo,
how's to paint in São Paulo, how's
to hustle the police in São Paulo.
Graffiti artists are
arrested in São Paulo
and will be sued.
GRAFFITI ARTISTS WANT TO RECOVER
THE RAP PREHENDED GEAR.
CITY HALL IS REPRESSING
GRAFFITI ARTISTS AGAIN.
It was at that time
we met Binho and Speto,
who already did
graffiti back then.
It was a crew who did,
unwillingly,
actually ignoring its
results...
Vitche.
You know, we were doing
it for the love!
Speto is a guy that
always helped us,
meaning we always exchanged
lots of references.
He was one of the guys who
developed his style prematurely.
In 84/85, he already
had his style.
Damn! How this guy has got style?
It helped us develop ours.
In 99, when we began to travel,
we already had our style,
and that's what we took abroad,
what we built here...
And that's where people got to
know us. "Wow, that's nice!"
came to us and asked:
"Man, that's not graffiti...
What is it that you're doing?"
And we said "We come from a
place that has always been very
We knew really few about it.
The first time we saw
an American Fat Cap.
I think it was when Barry
came here and brought it.
Man, when we saw it, we said
"Damn! That's how you do it!"
Like, there's a cap that makes
a thick line and you make
a hair stroke, you know?
I remember that Osgemeos
used to sell some caps that were...
They were so bad...
Deodorant cap,
or something like that...
That made a thick line,
you know?
The guys invented
the Brazilian Fat Cap.
That's it, I bought
it once from them,
didn't like it and threw
it away, you know?
Due to the high
cost of spray paint,
we had to develop some
other way to paint,
using latex first, as background,
then outline with spray,
to make it cheaper.
I remember the guys saying: "Man,
you use latex to paint graffiti?
What do you mean?"
I remember we going there
in the first years...
we entered in a hip hop shop,
a graffiti shop,
and there was a huge wall
filled with spray cans.
All colors, all brands,
all caps...
Wow! Amazing, right?
They asked me what I wanted,
and I said: "One color and
a can of latex, and that's it!"
So it made Brazil, São Paulo,
which is the cradle of graffiti,
to have it's own identity,
and this identity made all
the difference abroad.
BRAZILIANS MODIFY TATE MODERN
I believe that all these
artists have a certain intimacy
with this wild environment
of the street, you know?
For me, do this work at Tate is
like they had invited a cannibal
to have a cup of tea, you know?
I think it's what
each one think it is.
We did what we had in our minds,
which was our project.
A naked masked character,
holding a lot of cameras...
Each one interprets the
way they feel like it.
You know, it was really
a mind opening experience
to me to come to São Paulo and just
see what there are in the streets.
I loved, I mean, what I was doing
when I was there in São Paulo,
everyday, every
morning I'd wake up...
I had lots of meetings
I was very busy,
but every morning I'd
wake up seven o'clock,
and I'd just go for
really long walks.
Walk around the city, walk around
this... underneath the car motorways,
take a lot of photographs...
It was like heaven, it was amazing.
It was really to show me that
this art can be so important
and really inspiring.
And I just thought "We have
to bring this to London".
And, you know, luckily I had
the opportunity to do that.
It's not graffiti anymore,
but at the same time,
the essence is from graffiti,
so it's hard to say
"you aren't graffiti
artists anymore." What is it?
Is this art? You can consider
it as contemporary art,
but do you take
graffiti out o fit?
So I see this way, there's all
this graffiti essence,
but they are somewhere
else, beyond...
But it's hard to dissociate,
it's practically impossible,
this is graffiti, this
is in the streets, man.
Very well, you're not...
Look out! Mobile Court of...
-Justice.
- Justice.
You're caught painting;
they put you in there,
judge you and take
you straight to jail.
Yeah, the thing is...
- All very fast.
- Mobility.
Because the law in Brazil
works out fine.
U-hu!
- Take out the car.
-What for?
Sol can put the cart
there, bro.
Weren't you
painting here?
- No,
- cause the battery is dead.
This cart is a piece of shit.
I started painting because
I liked to paint and
I keep up
because I like it.
I never thought of it "wow, this
will be my profession", you know?
But it was something I believed
that could make me happy,
while I was doing it.
Like my mom, she always told me:
"l want you to be a doctor,
a lawyer" to develop a
standardized work.
With time I made her
understand this,
and I think now she understands
a bit more like it.
You can have an almost
self-sufficient work
without needing to work at a
company or firm and be a corporate
guy, you know?
To feel complete, to be happy.
And today I live almost
exclusively from it,
from selling the
paintings I do.
But when I cease to feel happy
with it, I'll do something else.
Or keep doing it and go
sell pizza, whatever.
That's not what
I wanna do, though.
- You finished?
-No...
I need the cart so I can
paint the character up there.
Will you do another one?
There's no red, right?
The big one.
What for?
Don't you need it to cut
it there, on the hand?
I'll see if I find it.
Hold on.
Do you need more?
Do you need more color?
Just that?
Bro, the small cans they're
using to out line
only come with this cap.
He doesn't think. He takes
one can, then goes up in the cart,
and then it runs out. Then
he comes down to get one more.
Why doesn't he take all at once?
You're getting bold, huh?
Till recently you wouldn't
climb up a stool to get cookies
in the closet. Now you're
hanging from the crane.
You need to use a
ladder there, right?
There's noway to get
down from here,
not even if I was Kiko's size.
Motherfucker! I'll fall
because of you!
Should I erase it, Figo? Just
leave the yellow rays, right?
To shorten it, right?
Ready! Here you are.
It's fucking great. All your
drawings look like letters.
Look at this bird's beak, bro.
Coyo! Let's go
do one over there?
What was that? Do one
there? I'm going too.
You're painting, man.
You can't.
- Where's 2&?
-Who? Zefix?
Wow! Go figure.
We've fucking painted there
already... lots of times.
Down there?
Ah, there... damn, it's true!
Shall we go there?
- Let's? Everybody doing a throw.
- A throw! Hey nigga!
I'll be right back.
Aren't you going?
No, I'll keep looking
the stuff that...
So lend me the...
that cap, then.
The American fat cap?
Here you are.
- No, no, no, the...
-Claudio has it.
- Do you have it?
-No.
Fuck off! C'mon now. Oh, you'll
give me the bad one, bro?
This one is good!
Then you use it...
let me use the other one.
Ok.
Where is it? Down here?
Just around the corner.
It's a cool spot.
But will it stay?
Ah, we've painted that wall
about 600 times.
- One more...
- One more, one less...
What's your limit?
Here? Up to where?
Wow, motherfucker! Doing it
in fluorescent green.
Look at the color he's painting.
When you do a
throw up like this,
it's like when you press
the fuck off key, you know?
When you're with your friends,
one support search other,
you know?
Like "Yeah, right! People
don't like it, but fuck off!
I'm here with my friends and
we like to do it and that's it!"
And we do it.
When you go out just to do it,
your vibe is different, you know?
You don't mind the consequences,
you just wanna do it.
Like beginning, middle
and end, you know?
You just wanna finish
what you started.
Throw up for those who
don't like it, it's ugly.
It's my favorite.
The moment you're there, painting,
you're there, painting.
You're thinking about nothing.
It's really thinking
about nothing, you know?
It's your therapy moment.
But that's very personal.
That's how it works for us.
I may be going down a hill,
whatever.
The paint goes out the can
and reaches the wall,
that's it. It's automatic,
you know?
Here, I've got black.
The best thing bout graffiti
is that it drives
you from hate to
love very quickly.
You start painting smoothly,
you know?
Suddenly you feel hate and start
panting fast, and then you feel ok,
cause it just relaxed you,
and you paints lowly.
There's nothing like
graffiti for those who like
graffiti, only sex. It's the only
thing that resembles it, you know?
Imagine you having a
10-minute orgasm.
It's the same. It's
the same feeling.
You're painting a 700m2 wall,
but from 3 to 3 hours
I see you guys crazy to paint
something under the bridge.
Explain to me. Doesn't
this satisfy you?
I don't know, maybe not,
right? I don't think so.
There's always this will to
reach a different place,
anew place, you know?
To really tag it, you know?
And these are completely
different things.
This is a sponsored wall,
everyone is earning some money,
and you have time to think.
You scribble, come back,
look at it, approach,
and scribble again, you know?
I think that if you grab some cans
and go out to the streets
to "pichar" or do whatever.
It's another dynamic,
it's other... it's something else.
The difference is the following.
These is permitted, those are not.
But what's the limit, you know?
For us it is!
We're part of the city.
And this is graffiti, right?
The fact that you write down your
name, "it's my name over there!"
Messes a lot with people's ego.
"You went there and wrote
Osgemeos, so what?"
We sure did! That's our name.
You'll pass by and will read
"Gemeos". One more, you know?
You wrote your name or drew
something that people
recognize as your work.
What's the difference? Both
interfere in a place you don't own.
And if you don't own it,
it's self-promotion.
Both are self-promotion, the
only difference is the technique.
I think that every
time a guy goes out
to paint someone's wall he
says "never" to a private place.
He starts breaking a rule.
I don't think São Paulo
deserves graffiti's best.
You'll have to do it
and fuck off.
I think every
big city is like this.
The stuff these guys do,
a wall like this,
São Paulo do not deserve it.
It's too pretty to
São Paulo, you know?
The city don't give
you back such quality.
The guys offer a fucking great
job, and the city wastes it,
you know? People erase it.
Then they only order to remake it
because the news brought it up,
you know?
Nobody cares spontaneously.
People only care if there's some
trouble behind it, you know?
This one I need a permission,
cause it belongs
to the construction site,
you know what I mean?
We can't erase that one,
right, man?
- No, this one is gone.
-This one?
- Yeah.
- Not that one, right?
Just the one on the top.
Only the "Gemeos"
over there, written "Gemeos".
Not the character.
The character is creative.
It's pretty! Nice, man!
I won't touch the
character, you see?
Only that one
on the top and this one here.
These guys want to leave
their names, right?
But I'll erase the name.
It's not necessary to put
the name. Is it? It isn't.
There it is, it's pretty already.
Leave your brand.
If I was a "graffiti" writer
and only wrote my only name,
I'd take a ride with this
character.
I"d start putting my name from
here to there, see?
Like if I had done it.
Meaning that you did the
character.
Of course!
In my personal opinion
it's a culture.
If I was a pichador, I would
also do a character, like,
since there's a female,
I'd do a male.
Asking for the spray can.
A mind, right?
I think their names
should be used only
as a signature down there,
like they were...
They'd even get more famous due to
their names, their phone number...
If some store, or firm, whatever,
needed their paintings
to do an image for an ad,
they'd profit with it.
Not putting their names in
pichagao.
Cause the guy should me, but you
saw, I already covered the feet.
I paint it all!
I erase everything,
so I don't waste my time.
Have you ever
touched a spray can?
Yeah, I painted
when I was younger.
I've painted a lot. I climbed
up buildings to paint.
How many times the police
caught me with a spray can
and painted my hair,
all my body...
they made fun of
us and everything.
All police units that catch a
pichador do it. Paint them all.
I've already heard of this
Osgemeos guys, they're from Lapa.
But I have no contact with them.
Cause in the past,
Osgemeos was the name of a crew,
not because the guys are twins,
it was the name of a team.
From then on,
the guys grew older, so other
people came on their place.
Check this out. I erase it.
My aim today is to erase it all.
Back in those days I was a brat
and didn't care bout anything.
I got high and had fun.
You'll have to apply
two layers.
Two to three layers to
cover this stuff.
Damn, I don't know
if they're being so smart
or so naive, for real.
Damn, how are you gonna stop I
don't know how many million kids
from painting somewhere.
If you gather all graffiti artists
and picho writers from São Paulo,
I wouldn't say millions,
but a few thousand.
They worked at a bank,
and they told me:
"Mom, were quitting work, because
we'll live out of drawing."
I almost freaked out, because
I always supported them,
I thought everything
they did was fine.
It's a symbiosis, right,
man? Their work is so crazy...
Gustavo started to draw,
then stopped and left.
Otéavio came and resumed drawing.
Like he was Gustavo there...
no, no Gustavo... Gustavo!
They never communicated orally.
They always communicated
by telepathy.
No need to speak, they
understood each other.
It's very... Wow,
check out that nice car!
Awesome, huh?
They're 2, but they've got
an entity,
but of course, the entity
Osgemeos,
it seems you're talking to one
person that discusses
their own ideas, cause
they discuss between them,
but actually they re discussing
Osgemeos' ideas.
Damn, where did you
take that from?
People who never heard of
Brazil, really, you know?
Is there graffiti in Brazil?
São Paulo? Where's São Paulo?
In Argentina? You know?
- We heard those questions.
-That's crazy.
Buenos Aires...
Yeah, it's so ridiculous.
But it was nice, because we gave
the opportunity to people know
what happened, you know?
Down there.
People thought they
were delinquents.
Cause graffiti was always
considered something de classed,
you know? From delinquent people...
So they were never considered
artists, and it took very long,
only when they started
to travel abroad.
It comes from (Secretary)
Andrea Matarazzo.
From the Mayor, Clean City Act,
put an end to "picho"
and "graffiti" in São Paulo.
They want it to be done right, you
know? But it's a complicated issue.
It's a brown wrapper,
but we need to keep going.
They paint, we cover,
they paint we cover.
"LOOK! THEY ARE BACK AGAIN!"
"YOUR MONEY SPENT IN GREY PAINT!"
"THE POLITICIANS ARE FOOLING YOW!
You agree 100% with
your boss' criteria?
Look, I think City
Hall's work is nice, ok?
I think it's a well-done job.
I agree 100% with
the City Hall in this work.
I'd agree 89,99%.
Here you still see
things like this wall,
erased for no reason.
People in Germany were horrified
when they heard something
this size was erased.
So here it is still difficult
to consider this as art.
Because they come to see it,
but keep chasing for drug addicts,
or if the boys don't get inspired
by snorting something.
People ask: "But don't
you... nothing?" None.
They don't drink, don't
smoke, nothing.
They always say:
"My drug is to paint."
That's it. To snort
paint non-stop.
The issue of
international recognition
as a necessity to validate
things in Brazil
happens in everything, right?
It's not a phenomenon
confined to contemporary art.
It took us almost 20
years since we began to like
graffiti until we could get
to travel and meet
other graffiti artists
and other cultures.
And in this period
we've stayed there,
sometimes with very
few information,
we ended up creating
another language of painting,
and we brought it
with us when came here.
I think it happens in all
other cultural fields,
due to a colonial mentality
of consuming imported things.
Then the culture from abroad
ends up bringing
back Brazilian culture.
I think it's alack of
self confidence, you know?
To say "Damn, this is good!" We
don't need a stamp from outside.
You see, I just paint
authorized by dweller.
Check that out. You think that
stuff is pretty?
That's just awful.
Let's stop by this wall and
ask if the guy authorizes.
If he does, I'll
cover it. Hold on.
I need permission
to paint that wall,
and need to talk to the person
in charge.
We're from the City Hall,
no cost. City Hall.
It's that color over there,
the grey color.
It'll look much prettier.
I see. But I can't authorize,
because it doesn't
belong to us.
Where is the entrance?
Good morning.
It's the City Hall.
I"d like to speak to the
person in charge.
The wall around the block
is yours, right?
Can I paint it? Thanks!
I pass by everyday,
and I find it pretty,
but then it was being erased.
I find it a great pity.
But I believe that's
the more discussion.
To wonder what is art
and what isn't.
This is an important
issue now a days.
Ok.
People look this way,
it's a matter of taste, right?
A matter of taste.
You heard what she said, right?
She thinks this is not good.
She doesn't like it.
Each one has an opinion, right?
She doesn't like it either,
just like us. She thinks it's ugly
graffiti. What she said?
What?
She said it's ugly
graffiti, right?
- That's right.
- Was that or not?
No. She said she
liked the painting, right?
But it's a matter of...
It was authorized.
What's going on now is
the following:
There will be an official
graffiti,
which is where the City Hall
allow site,
and there'll still be
the unofficial, the always...
These guys started like this,
actually. Doing it.
Because graffiti wasn't
allowed!
Thus, you can't intervene
anywhere in the city.
City Hall is now permitting
interventions and is studying
to allow it in certain places.
All right. Is that official?
Yes. We'll have the official
graffiti artists, but look,
street art was born as
a transgression.
So those who really want to do
graffiti and "picho"
will just keep doing it.
We were up there and
Gustavo asked me:
"Do donkeys have hair?"
What did he mean?
He's drawing
a donkey over there.
He asked while he was doing it.
That's crazy.
What did you tell him?
I said: "A jackass does!"
I think he asked to the
right person.
Yeah, when I started at the City
Hall, I had hair.
But now... I'd like
you to film my pay slip.
It would be nice to take a
picture in front of the politician
over there, the... A lot of
people passed by and asked:
"ls it Kassab over there?"
"ls it the Mayor?"
And I'm like: "No, it ain't."
But he's got bright eyes, huh?
Just like the Mayor (Kassab).
It's coincidence.
It" wasn't intentional.
They're worried with
something they shouldn't, right?
It's not a problem to the city,
but a solution.
It's sad because it's not just
with this work.
There are thousands
of other works,
from other artists, right?
They suffer from it as well.
Not just us, not just our crew,
but also everyone in São Paulo.
The guy leaves the periphery to
paint in the city, or whatever,
he comes from the countryside
and he suffers from it.
He saves some money, buys his
cans, do a nice piece of work
somewhere and suddenly he has no
time to take a picture of it.
It's like pruning the guy's dream.
That's why we need to
struggle to keep it.
We can't lose it. It's
São Paulo's main feature.
The graffiti on the streets.
People like graffiti.
If we stop painting every where
and just paint where it's allowed,
that's it, we'll
lose it, you know?
We must fight to paint everywhere,
to avoid losing something
so São Paulo like.
Paint everywhere.
WALL INAUGURATION DAY
1212112008
This is the deal: The Mayor has to
come inaugurate the wall, right?
We're in his city, right? Somehow
he take care of all this.
Before he became Mayor,
the wall was already here.
And that was authorized and
sponsored as well.
But that's it. He does
his part we do ours.
Not just here, but all
around the city.
We hope it stays now, right?
That this put an end.
We believe it will end.
That's what we felt, you know?
This experience with the City
Hall, you know?
I think if they had criteria to
take the billboards from a 1920
building's, I think this deserves
to be considered as well.
I mean, this is even more explicit.
Yeah, if a castle in
Scotland recognizes our work,
why won't they do it here, right?
So I think this was an alert,
a start, you know?
"Wait a minute, let me pay
attention to this." You know?
How'd that happen?
I was playing football.
That's nice, cool.
It is very beautiful.
The City Hall authorized it,
and this wall will be declared
as a historical landmark.
So he told me while he was
putting the plaster:
"Now that I painted the wall, I'll
be famous, my name will be known,
because I painted with the top
of the graffiti artists.
I think the Mayor will come
over to see what we've painted.
Actually he'll apologize
publicly, right?
He'll apologize in front
of everybody.
Nice, huh? Noble act.
-It's the least.
-The least.
- The Mayor is coming!
- It seems he actually arrived!
He arrived, so we'll see him
and I talk to you later.
- Looks pretty, huh?
- Looks pretty.
Looks really pretty,
right? It's beautiful!
This is the group of artists...
- Hey!
- Good morning! Thank you.
- How is it going?
- Hello.
How're you doing?
Delivered back to town,
right?
That's right.
With the Mayor,
the city will be clean
and pretty.
Clean and beautiful.
- We appreciate.
- And with more graffiti!
That's it. More graffiti.
Everywhere there's...
It was nice to bring it back.
The city is to be congratulated
it has changed.
It's getting better and better.
Really,
it's a God's blessing.
You are a blessing.
It's amazing to see the reaction
of the people when they pass by.
Is it?
Please guys look at me
down here.
Just for the records,
this is a symbolic act,
because we wanted to do it here
so it's with the presence of the
media, the Commercial Association,
the Mayor, Dom Fernando...
We didn't call the population
to avoid disturbance,
it is even dangerous, and
there could be an accident.
The media will reverberate
so the society can acknowledge
this inauguration, from
the symbolic point of view.
So we want to ask for a blessing
to those who worked here...
we know that the art always
involves harmony,
integrity and unity.
Hence, if we take something
or put something,
it's not possible,
because it's a work of art.
A work of art, in an important
place... a work that is...
was erased by mistake
several months ago.
But the Commercial Association
understood the relevance
of this artist's work for
São Paulo, and gave an important
step toward such recognition, and
this present to São Paulo.
It's a big city, a city that
need to live with culture,
with art, generate jobs.
There's no more risk of
erasing it again, right, Mayor?
I hope not.
It's obvious that after
all the media coverage over it,
the Mayor went there and
recognized the mistake and:
"C'mon, let's undo the mistake."
But what about the other paintings
from the other guys, man?
What about all the history
that was erased?
The graffiti artists themselves
are here, right? Behind you,
they know that this action
isn't normal in São Paulo.
On the contrary. The graffiti
works have been very well
respected and admired in
the city of São Paulo,
and mainly because of our
management.
And we intend to keep it this way.
Mr. Mayor, you mentioned
that erasing the wall
was a mistake. Isn't a 700m2
mistake as this wall deletion
quite curious?
The investigation procedures
are being coordinated
by the Districts Office,
that will have all the available
information for you.
- They have no schedule!
- They travel the whole year!
They scheduled to this week
because they had no other time.
Japan, Scotland...
At Milu Vilela's house
there's a wall painted by them.
Yeah.
We did it, right?
I think those works with
colorful letters are also graffiti.
It can't be erased, so, I think we
need to... because our work,
like this one, it is respected
now, but what about the others
that are... Thousands of
other artists in town, right?
I didn't know!
That I didn't know!
You didn't know, right?
Matarazzo! We are leaving.
I wore the best clothes
and sent the kids
Everyone showered up and
combed, just to please
Mr. Mayor, the authority
and the priest to bless
Today we'll eat grey paint
brought by the VW, van
Just take this Picture,
Instagram it to denounce
I'll put a tag in your forehead,
and a hashtag along with it
A bomb and a throw up from
the other side of the bridge
Fight against this grey paint
brought by the VW, van
Neither minister, nor president
with the scene will agree
Enough to be embarrassed
for the others
I wore the best clothes
and sent the kids
Don'tlet me eat grey paint
brought by the VW, van
AFTER 150 HOURS OF SPRAY, THE
COLORS ARE BACK ON THE WALL.
When one of the twins questioned
about the whole
He got bounced, but the
can will retaliate
Today we won't eat grey paint
brought by the VW, van
DESPITE THE REPERCUSSION KASSAB'S
MANAGEMENT CONTINUED
PAINTING GRAY GRAFFITIS THROUGH
OUT THE CITY.
UNTIL THE RELEASE OF THIS
FILM, THE NEW MAYOR,
FERNANDO HADDAD, KEPT
THE SAME POLICY.
GILBERTO KASSAB - LEFT THE
CITY HALL WITH LOW APPROVAL RATES.
FOUNDED ANEW PARTY THAT HAS
BECOME ONE OF THE MAIN
POLITICAL FORCES IN BRAZIL.
NINA - CAME TO BE REPRESENTED
BY AN IMPORTANT ART GALLERY
AND PUBLISHED A BOOK WITH
AN OVERVIEW OF HER WORK.
CURRENTLY DEDICATES HERSELF MORETO
PAINTING ON CANVAS THAN GRAFFITI.
NUNCA - HIS EXHIBITION
"PAU BRASIL IS OVER"
WAS A BIG COMMERCIAL SUCCESS.
HE'S CURRENTLY DEVELOPING A NEW
GRAFFITI PROJECT IN SÃO PAULO.
OSGEMEOS - THE EXHIBITION "VERTIGEM"
HAD RECORD AUDIENCES IN BRAZIL.
"THE GUARDIAN" NOMINATED
2 OF THEIR GRAFFITI PAINTINGS
AS THE 10 BEST STREET
ART WORKS IN THE WORLD.
FINOK - IN 2008 HE WAS A PROMISE,
TODAY HE'S ONE OF THE MAIN ARTISTS
OF SCENE.
ZEFIX - HE WALKED AWAY FROM
THE CREW AND BESIDES GRAFFITI,
HE NOW DEDICATES HIMSELF TO
THE STUDIES OF ESOTERICISM.
ISE - REMAINS ONE OF THE MOST
IMPORTANT NAMES
ON THE STREETS OF SÃO PAULO.
HE OWNS ONE OF THE MAIN
GRAFFITI SHOPS IN TOWN.