No one ever sees this part
of an astronomer's life.
People imagine that we show up
and just look around
and we're all famous.
Everything is perfect
and it all works out just fine.
But sometimes you get here,
and there's nothing
but clouds and more clouds.
I don't think it will clear up.
It's depressing.
And minutes go by
but it doesn't clear.
Should we switch on a light
and do a calibration?
So we can see a spectrum.
I'm curious about this.
I'm missing those two.
No, they're there.
See? Here and here.
And those little ones
in between.
Those two?
I think it's like this.
I thought we'd lost the star
for a second there!
Those of us who are physicists
have so much in our minds,
we are overwhelmed
by nature per se.
We think about it
all the time.
Maybe you think about it
all the time!
I don't spend my whole life
thinking about it.
But it's striking.
You don't even need the sky
to understand
how big nature is.
How wise it is.
How much information
we fail to notice.
An atom, everything
is a universe in itself.
Your work is to constantly
be watching the sky.
It must be extraordinary.
I think that
if you watch the sky...
I mean, from the moment
that you look at it
with profundity and tranquility,
you realize that
the sky is there.
My God, so many things
are up there!
I believe that this realization
happens to everyone
who really looks at the sky.
It hits them the very first time
they look at the sky.
I can't fathom
that a human being can look up
and not be genuinely amazed.
-Does this happen to you?
-Yes.
Does it happen
every time you look at the sky?
-I think so.
-Or only when...
Every time
I look at the sky here,
I don't know how to express it.
The silence.
The beauty.
In Chile, it's like
we can touch the sky.
And the stars...
I´m inspired by these mountains
to take care of the earth.
They remind me of images
I have seen of Mars,
which is all desert.
They say that there could have
been life there,
but there's no life now.
For an astronomer,
I am very earth-centred.
I like physics,
but I am not a spiritual person.
I don't look at the stars
and have profound thoughts.
I look at the stars
and I always think
about the earth.
Look, we have wars.
People are hungry.
People are homeless.
People can't find work
to support their families.
And look how insignificant
we are.
We are absolutely nothing.
We are so tiny in the immensity
of the universe.
Why do we have to live
like this?
Instead of living in harmony
and helping each other.
Trying to further
the progress of humanity
in a positive way,
to make things better.
Not just to kill each other.
I always think
of this amusing analogy.
Human beings
are the equivalent
of ants living in an ant's nest.
The ants go to find food
to bring back to the nest.
And when an ant comes up
and looks around,
I wonder what is it thinking?
I mean, I don't believe
an ant thinks,
but what does an ant see?
For us,
as observers of the universe,
it's kind of the same.
We are ants
looking through a telescope.
But is the universe really
what we happen to see?
Or is it just
what we are capable of seeing?
An ant could never fathom
that it lives on a planet
that is round,
or that has mountains, etcetera.
And we are kind of the same.
Like the ants, we look
and see what we can see,
but we can't grasp
the immensity of the universe.
When I speak with people
who have an explanation
for everything,
and who think
they know everything,
I just think
that's an impossibility.
Because we aren't looking down
from above,
we are looking upward
from below.
Hey you, don´t be so nosy!
Nosy little buggers!
Go outside!
Out!
This one is so stubborn.
Right, you´re pouring
some gasoline over it.
You know what?
Let's add those plastic bags.
Now I want the shiny knife.
You should cut it in half.
Not destroy it.
I´ve already destroyed it.
I'm taking it out
on the chicken.
I have to take it out
on something!
How is the wine?
Is it off?
No, it tastes...
It´s not bad.
Not bad at all.
The factory makes crappy wine.
Sure, it´s not a bottle
of San Pedro.
It's fine for making vinegar!
No use to you
because it´s a bit sweet, right?
Yes, a bit sweet.
-You find it sweet?
-A bit sweet and acidic.
What do the people see
in the sky here?
You can see shooting stars
around here.
You see them sneaking in
and then they disappear.
I don't know,
maybe they fall into the sea.
People call them shooting stars.
You see them a lot.
Mostly in the summer,
because the sky is clear,
so you can see them falling.
In Mexico,
where you are from...
From Canada.
In your country,
you look at the sky, don't you?
But I live in the city.
With all the lights and buildings,
you can't see anything.
Of course,
you don't appreciate it.
If there are too many lights,
you don't see anything.
The sky is hidden.
We spend so much time
looking down.
When I arrived in this desert
and watched the sky,
it was as if I was seeing it
for the first time.
I had never seen a sky
so alive,
so profound.
It seems as if we watch the sky
less and less.
Is it the same here?
I remember in the old days,
my grandparents,
who have since passed away,
they loved looking up
at the night sky.
Every single night
they'd go outside,
sit on their bench
and watch the sky.
That was in the countryside.
They have been dead
for ages.
But they loved watching
what was happening in the night sky.
The elders gave names
to all of the stars.
The Three Marías, the Bright Star.
We have names
for almost all the stars.
One night in the desert,
I lay on the ground
watching the stars.
I felt like...
I felt like it was moving.
Have you ever felt that?
You mean how it moves?
Yes, that´s right.
I think the earth moves.
I don't believe the sky is moving.
No. I'm telling you,
the Earth has two movements,
rotation and revolution.
Revolution follows
the line of the equator,
and rotation is
around the magnetic poles.
It has to turn and move that way,
or else we would fall.
No sweetie!
You're just like Columbus
who believed
that the earth was flat.
But there must be some way
that we hold ourselves upright
in the night.
If not, we'd fall off.
No, you don't understand!
Right now,
it's daytime for us,
and in the part below,
it's nighttime.
And when night falls here,
it's day in the other part
and night here for us.
Right now,
we are belly up!
We are upside down,
the others are not.
But then how do we
hold ourselves upright?
It's because of the...
What is it called?
Gravity!
That's why there's gravity!
The way I feel...
I arrived here
when I was very young.
Once every two or three months,
we travelled to Vallenar
to buy supplies.
We just went for a short time
and came back.
And I thought...
When night fell,
the cars turned on their headlights.
But I didn't know
what headlights were!
I thought that the stars
had come down.
I think it must be the same
for someone
who's used to city lights
and who sees natural light,
like a star.
It must seem different to them,
and strange at the same time.
There's something amazing
about the desert here.
It's as though everything
is alive, right?
Yes, I've had experiences,
when I was young and even now,
working at night.
There are apparitions.
I've seen people
who don't actually exist.
But something more intimate
happened when I was young.
A young girl appeared
out of nowhere.
She accompanied me
until I was older.
And then I didn't see her again.
We did not speak,
we just gestured.
When I was feeling bad,
I would feel better
when she was around.
But we never communicated
like you and I are doing right now.
Was it like a spirit?
Yes, but more than a spirit,
an angel I believe.
An angel from the sky?
That would be beautiful.
The sky will never stop
being beautiful.
At least the sky here
is different than in other places,
even though it is the same.
I am afraid of not being able
to see the sky one day.
And I wonder,
are there beings out there
like us, or who think like us?
I have always believed
that we aren't the only ones.
When I was a child,
I would go out with my flashlight
and shine it upwards
to see if they would respond.
What would happen
if someone replied?
What would we do?
Maybe we would run away.
The sky is always interesting.
Always.
-What is that?
-A UFO.
I see four.
I'm not sure how
the lights are divided.
Sometimes they spin.
They spin like propellers,
but slowly.
I can't tell what this might be.
It looks like a red spot.
I don't know if it's a UFO or what.
There are two small objects.
Can't make out what it is.
There are two of them.
There are beings and spirits.
I'll tell you how it happened.
Once I was with Negro Fernando
and Ricardo and another guy.
There was something big and tall
in that area and it stopped there.
We all said,
"Look at that!"
All of a sudden, it disappeared.
-Was it spinning?
-No, it was still.
It's like at night,
when you can see lights and flashes.
It shined beautifully
and all of us stayed there
watching it for quite a while.
Then it disappeared.
And Negro said,
"What was that?"
Some people say they exist,
but do you believe...
-In Martians?
-Yes.
They say that extraterrestrials
live up there on other planets,
and they can come down,
fall in love and have a child.
And the children
would be demigods.
And these planets
are superior to ours?
I believe that
we're more evil than them.
That's probably why
they don't show up,
because they know we're evil.
I slept so well!
Let's light the campfire, okay?
Did it go out? I was sleeping.
The scientists, they say
we are the dust of stars
And their offspring
treading in their footsteps
Yet I've only seen dust
deep beneath the ground
Toiling in the mine
in air heavy like stone
Sometimes I want to go above
to stare at my wide-eyed star
She shines from far away
over the desolate land
My search for gold is fruitless
I search but I get no answer
But I think
there's a true-hearted star
Singing to me in the sky
That pretty pale blue light
no one can hide
An impossible dream
shaped by time into a star
She shines brighter than gold
and remains sleepless by my side
I want you always near
Star of mine, Isabela
This music feels right
for that planet.
What's the name of your planet?
The planet is not mine.
A Swiss group discovered it.
It's called WASP 4.
But we have our own name for it.
We call it the Golem.
What are sunsets like there?
Apparently, considering the clouds
that we see now,
sunrise and sunset on this planet
must be white.
If you were on that planet,
you would not notice a change.
Maybe you wouldn't even know
if it was day or night.
Let's go to WASP 50.
We are watching the star
all the time.
What will happen is a planet
will cross in front of it.
So the brightness of the star,
which should be fairly constant,
will suddenly diminish.
We will see an eclipse now,
when the planet eclipses its star.
So this decrease in light
will bring us all the information
about the planet's atmosphere.
And the light of the star,
how does it travel
all the way to us?
Each ray of light is created
in the centre of the star.
This is very chaotic.
Protons colliding with protons,
generating new elements.
From all this chaos,
a ray of light escapes.
Now, that ray of light
leaving the centre of the star
takes millions
or hundreds of thousands of years
to exit the star,
and then reaches the atmosphere.
It must be crazy,
with storms circling around.
It goes through
the planet's atmosphere,
it leaves,
and easily travels
for hundreds of years through space,
until it meets this pale blue dot
that is the Earth.
The light continues to travel
until it reaches the telescope.
It goes inside, bouncing around
the entire optical system.
That light is transformed
into current.
That's what goes into the computer.
It's what we analyze.
I find it magical.
We observe the light as it arrives
and passes through the telescope.
We analyze it right away.
We see the eclipse right away.
It's incredible.
In my imagination,
I can see the eclipse directly.
I imagine exactly
what is happening,
or rather, what happened
in this case.
It must be hundreds or thousands
of light-years away,
so all of this happened
hundreds or thousands of years ago.
But we are seeing it now.
We are seeing this information
reach us in real time,
as the planet
passes in front of the star.
I think I'm flying among the stars.
Because I see a beautiful moon.
It seems as though
the earth is far away.
In those days,
animals could speak.
Fox was walking over the hill.
And Fox met Condor,
who was carrying his guitar.
Condor said to Fox,
"We are invited
to a party in the sky."
"Let's go!"
And Fox says, "How can I get there
if I can't fly?"
So Condor says,
"You can get on here."
Condor, the guitar player,
slung the instrument
over his chest.
And Fox went on Condor's back,
until they arrived in the sky.
When they arrived,
they saw some guests,
and the party seemed just so-so.
They were the main artists,
because
everyone in the Universe knew
that Condor played the guitar
beautifully
and that Fox danced very well,
especially when he wore
his silver spurs.
So the party kicked off in the sky,
and the next day,
the hosts said, "We have to pay Fox
"because Fox made everyone happy,
everyone danced all night."
So they started bringing
small bags full of seeds.
And the seeds that Fox
carried heavily on his back
were hurled to the four corners
of the earth.
That's how all the trees, herbs
and shrubs that we see nowadays
came to be.
I remember my grandmother
was tall and skinny.
She used to wear thin skirts
that stuck to her body.
I was the only grandchild,
the only child in the valley!
I was the only one!
She said to me,
when people look at the sky
and see what we call
shooting stars,
they should spit three times.
If not,
the star will steal your memory.
That is what my grandmother said.
The star will steal your memory.
I don't know what a star
has to do with your memory.
Also in the sky
is what we call,
what people today call
the Magellanic clouds,
those patches of cloud
in the night sky.
The old people called them
guanaco's mudholes.
The guanacos
in the mountains around here,
they have specific places
they go to roll around.
They give themselves a dust bath.
They wallow around,
covering their bodies in dust.
They say that what we see
in the sky from Earth
are the mudholes of guanacos.
Did your grandmother talk
about the Milky Way?
I heard that the ancestors
saw animals
in the dark patches of the sky.
Llamas, birds and foxes.
What we call the Milky Way
is a river.
There must be something to it,
since she would always say
that it's a river.
When someone died,
we had to kill a dog for them.
This dog would help its owner
swim across the river in the sky.
So people would kill
the dead person's favourite dog
and the dog would join his master
so they could cross the river,
on their way to the sky.
The ancestors were keen observers.
They made astronomical
observations.
It's been said that
the Southern Cross or Chakana
was a very important symbol
for ancient native cultures.
That's why we can see it
in rock art
and petroglyphs.
In the Southern Cross, you see
the duality between man and woman,
winter and summer,
day and night.
Life and death.
Man is pure dust
Among so many tracks
Needn´t go to the sky
To reach the stars
The constellation that I like
and that always
brings back memories
is the constellation
they call Orion,
where the Three Marías are.
It always makes me think
of my daughter, who died.
Before she died,
she used to say,
"That star is me."
"I am that star."
I always remember this.
The sky is like...
How can I say it?
It's like family.
It's like seeing your brother,
your cousins there.
There's my mother, my daughter,
my cousins.
And they are visiting me.
They are watching me from up there.
My daughter is up there,
she's watching me from her star.
And others as well,
they are watching us.
One metre of surplus!
One metre extra below!
COCKTAIL OK
-Okay, cheers!
-Cheers!
-Yes, we had first light.
-Out of focus, however.
He was happy
because the camera was working.
Everyone have a seat.
Just a moment, please.
I'd like to make a toast.
As scientists, you know
that there are always questions.
One question leads to another.
There's an infinity of questions.
It won't surprise you that tonight,
I have yet another question.
What is your true connection
with the sky?
One at a time!
First things first.
To the sky!
Which nourishes us
and quenches our thirst.
That's the wisdom of the earth.
-He didn't get it.
-What does that mean?
-That the sky nourishes us?
-Yes.
Well...
So you're an exoplanet hunter?
But what does that really mean?
It's like science fiction.
And why do you chase planets?
Why does this matter to us?
Planet hunting resonates
with the public
because it raises fundamental
questions about our origins,
about why we are here.
And these questions are connected
to our habitat, our earth,
but also to the existence
of other similar worlds elsewhere
and maybe of life elsewhere.
So when we explain to people
that we are looking for planets
and for life elsewhere,
obviously it resonates profoundly.
These are age-old questions
that everyone has wondered about
at some point or another.
And often, we think about them
when we look up at the sky.
And that's how it's connected
to our understanding of the sky.
We feel renewed because
when we watch the sky,
we forget everything we've learned.
We see the immensity in front of us,
and not just in terms of distance.
Of course, people have trouble
understanding such huge distances.
But there's also an immensity
of possibilities.
In the sky, our imagination
takes flight
and everything is possible.
Everything that opens our minds
is important
and is a catalyst for our growth.
Historically,
the sky is the first level.
And then understanding the sky,
and what's behind the sky,
that's the second level.
For me,
that's what astrophysics is.
It's the scientific explanation
for the wanderings
of our imagination
beyond the screen of the sky.
If we want to go to a planet
that we discover,
which might be
a hundred light years away,
it will take us 10,000 years
to get there.
10,000 years to get there.
So we either put people to sleep
and wake them when they arrive,
and here we're starting
to get into science fiction,
which I've always loved,
and I still love.
Or else we create
something like Noah's ark.
We send out families
and a future generation will arrive.
Subtitles T&S COOP
(Copyright) 2017