- You two, come out.
- Stand up.
Come here. You too.
Hurry up. Come on.
You piece of scum!
What exactly have you done?
Sorry, sir.
We doubled the dosage this time.
I think he might have overdosed.
Please forgive us!
You are good for nothing.
To win this war,
we have to turn those captives
into our warriors.
The experiment has to be successful!
Yes!
During World War II,
the day before Japan's surrender,
Japan's biochemical laboratory
was destroyed by the British Army.
Since then,
it has been left buried underground...
Thunderbolt Circus
Ladies and gentlemen.
Tonight, the Thunderbolt Circus show
officially begins!
First, please welcome...
Goodness. I forgot.
Right.
First, please welcome our gorgeous Yao Li
and handsome He Jun
for their amazing
Nine-Section Whip performance!
Ladies and gentlemen.
Here comes
the most exciting part of the show.
He is the renowned King of Flying Daggers.
He is going to show you
his breathtaking flying dagger technique!
I suggest you don't blink.
Because his flying daggers are so fast
that they can hardly be seen.
Ladies and gentlemen,
please welcome
the King of Flying Daggers.
It's me, Twin-dagger Sunny.
Mr. Tak, Sunny is messing around again.
Ladies and gentlemen.
I'm the world-renowned, invincible,
and one and only master of flying daggers,
the descendant of Swordsman Li.
I'm the Merciless Flying Dagger
who never misses his target,
Twin-dagger Sunny.
Are you all very excited?
- We're in trouble. He's gone crazy again.
- Come on, let the show begin.
Hold this apple.
Don't worry.
I will pay you after the show.
Don't be scared, hold it.
Get a little bit closer. Don't panic.
You won't get hurt.
- I can't watch this.
- Ladies and gentlemen.
Call an ambulance.
Once the flying dagger is out,
no one can compare to it!
Great! Yes!
Cool!
Brilliant!
- Nice!
- Amazing!
Give me a chance.
Just once.
Stand over there.
What the heck!
You jerk! Are you creating trouble again?
You don't know what's good for you!
I'll pay you shortly.
This is ridiculous! All right!
Come on, show me how good you are!
You're in trouble. You're dead meat.
You really pissed me off.
I'll deal with you backstage.
Come on, go ahead!
Ladies and gentlemen,
this is the real King of Flying Daggers,
Cheung Tai-chu!
Excuse me. Move!
This is urgent!
Come, have a seat.
Don't be mad, I brought you two new girls.
Mr. Tak.
I really don't understand
why you have to keep this kid.
He's out of his mind.
He will get you into big trouble.
Besides, his dad died many years ago.
Thousand Flying Daggers?
Screw that!
Tai-chu, I wasn't pranking you.
I just wanted to perform
the flying daggers.
Silly kid.
If you fool around again, I'll kill you
with my daggers sooner or later.
Don't be mad. Enjoy yourselves.
- Just go and have fun.
- Let's go.
Enjoy!
Let me down.
I can't take it anymore.
I'll treat you to dinner.
Hey!
Why are you still standing there?
Chu hides a dagger behind his smile.
Stay away from him.
He'll kill you sooner or later.
Don't stay here.
You should go back to Hong Kong.
I'm not leaving.
I only want to perform the flying daggers,
but you never let me.
So I can only find a chance to try it.
Do you want to try it?
Do you want to learn it?
I watched you grow up.
How can I not know what you're capable of?
I keep telling you
that you have no talent for it.
Stop thinking
about the flying daggers, okay?
You screw up every time.
I've put up with that.
I continued letting you
work here as a clown.
If your late parents
didn't ask me to take care of you,
I would have kicked you out
a long time ago!
Please give me one more chance.
Stop it. It's out of the question.
I really can do it.
No way.
I really can't do it.
- I can.
- What can you do?
You can't do anything!
You can't perform the flying daggers,
be a good man, or do any work.
You fail at everything!
Feel with your heart.
Aim with your eyes.
Throw with your force.
Combine your force with the wind.
You have to befriend the wind.
Let the wind carry your flying dagger.
My son, you can surely do it.
Do I really lack the talent
to perform the flying dagger?
Someone is digging for gold on that hill.
Let's check it out.
Really?
Yes, I'm not lying! Let's take a look!
- Hurry!
- Let's go!
Warning: Restricted military area
Those three over there.
They were talking big at the bar.
They said they bought the treasure map
with all they had
and that the Japanese
left gold bars during the war.
We are going to be rich.
Honey, if we get the gold bars,
we can leave the circus for good.
Honey, I'll hire ten maids to serve you
and travel around the world with you.
Do you want ten maids to watch me
so that you can fool around?
Honey, how would I dare to do that?
What wouldn't you dare to do?
Hurry! We are never going to worry
about money anymore!
Don't panic.
Let's go inside.
How embarrassing!
I knew it was not steep enough here.
Good thing no one saw me.
It looks steeper over there.
I'll go and check that side.
Hey!
Tai-chu!
Are you all having a campfire party?
It must be very fun, right?
Did everyone get drunk so quickly?
I was practicing my backflip there.
I'm almost done. I already feel dizzy.
It seems like I can't see anything.
Since you followed us here,
this is our fate.
All right, I'll give you a chance.
Let's share the good times, okay?
Come on.
It's so dark in this big cave.
Could there be ghosts here?
A monster!
What monster? Those are just human bones.
Human bones?
Does a human have such a long spine?
Look at the skull,
it's as big as a rice cooker.
It has claws too.
Could it be that we've discovered aliens?
No matter what it is,
it's already dead.
That's obvious.
Come here.
Find out if there's anything ahead.
- Go.
- Is there a path ahead?
- I see it.
- Get going!
No way!
Amitabha.
Tai-chu.
It seems that many people died here.
Let's go.
Shut up!
Don't you ever shut up?
You'll die right here if you keep talking!
Do not open
Honey, what are these?
There are so many of them.
I don't know either.
Open it.
I told you to open it.
Goodness. I sprained my hand earlier.
I can't exert force. What should I do?
Kan, you're the strongest. You do it.
He told you to open it, do it!
Did you hear that?
There was a click, I've recovered.
It's okay now.
- It's okay? Are you sure?
- Yes.
- It's fine? Open it!
All right.
How can I open it?
God bless me.
Gold bars.
Honey, they are gold bars!
Really?
Am I dreaming?
It's true! They are really gold bars.
Tai-chu, we are rich!
Kan, take Sunny
to keep watch over there.
- Keep watch?
- Go!
We are really rich.
We can really travel around the world.
Check if there is more.
Kan, actually,
there is no one here.
Why should we keep watch?
- Honey.
- Honey, let's go!
Run!
My brother!
Tai-chu, run!
Fish Market
- Then...
- Okay.
What is wrong with you?
Didn't you know someone was on board?
Hey, look at him. He looks horrible.
It seems like he's sick.
Could it be contagious?
What should we do?
We can't let others know about our stuff.
Let's just throw him overboard!
Life is just like a flying dagger,
you must have a target.
My son, focus on your target
and persevere in it.
Don't give up easily.
What happened?
Help.
I'm starving.
Is anyone here?
Hey! Is anybody here?
Hey!
Is anyone here?
Is anybody here?
I'm starving.
Salted fish? This will do fine.
I'll eat it first.
It's delicious.
Hey! What are you doing?
Are you stealing?
People, come and help! There's a thief!
Help! You fatso, don't go!
I'm not a thief. I'm just hungry!
I'm not a thief!
I'm just hungry.
- Sorry.
- Fatso! Don't ever come back!
We'll beat you up
if we ever see you here again!
Please. Stop the car!
Please help me! Stop!
Sir, please. I have a flat tire.
Can you help me?
Okay.
Hey, did you jump into the sea?
No.
Did you get robbed then?
So why are you alone and completely wet
so late at night?
I just went night swimming.
Night swimming?
With clothes on?
Do you have an identity card?
If you don't, I have to take you
to the police station.
No.
Don't report me to the police.
I have an identity card.
My name is Li Fei.
I'm the Merciless Flying Dagger
who never misses his target,
Twin-dagger Sunny.
Do you have such an exalted title?
Yes.
I'm from the Thunderbolt Circus.
I'm a flying dagger performer.
Should I take you to the hospital?
There is no need for that.
I don't understand
how I got so fat suddenly.
Perhaps you'd better take me home.
By the way, you are so nice.
What is your name?
My name is Angel.
The name really suits you.
Actually, I know you.
I've seen you on television.
You are the muse of the news.
The cookies were delicious.
Thank you, Ms. Angel.
Angel.
Actually...
Actually, I'm not this fat.
I'm quite slim.
The next time you jump into the sea,
no one will give you a ride anymore.
Thank you so much.
You're welcome.
Bye.
Uncle Tak!
Why aren't they back yet?
What is that?
It's a robbery!
Good evening, everyone.
Here are the news headlines,
I'm Angel Chan.
Around midnight yesterday,
an armored car was robbed
at Wang Tai Road in Kowloon Bay.
Over five million dollars were taken.
On the same night,
at Wan Hoi St. in Hung Hom,
a jewelry factory was robbed as well.
Many gunshots were heard at the scene.
There were no gunshot wounds
on the injured police officer though.
It is suspected that
he was hit with a hard object.
For this jewelry shop robbery,
the criminals purportedly
didn't fire any shots at all.
Yet they managed to steal jewelry
with an estimated value of 30 million.
According to witnesses,
the robbers were three men and one woman
with terrifying and strange appearances.
This is similar to previous robbery cases.
For the sake of confidentiality,
the police refuse to divulge
further details to the public.
This is already the eighth robbery case
within the week.
Strangely, in the crime scenes,
they found...
Non-human, bizarre palm print,
four robbers, incompetent police
- What weapons did they use?
- They had no weapons.
What happened
to this bulletproof glass then?
They said the security guard hit the wall
after a robber punched him.
Then the glass shattered.
Really?
Mr. Tong.
This is Mr. Yu Sam, a professor
from the Biochemical Research Center.
And the two people behind us are
the experts we hired from the Mainland,
Suen Ho and Ching Shau-wah.
They have arrested criminals
with supernatural powers before.
Just leave it up to them.
Suen Ho, we are counting on you.
Once the case is closed,
I will pay you double, okay?
What do you think?
These are more powerful than the last one.
So what?
Old Man, look at this diamond ring.
It's much bigger than what we ordered.
Take it then.
After all, they've been robbed.
The police wouldn't notice
if one more goes missing.
We are getting married in a month.
Do you want to marry me in jail?
I don't need a month. Give me 20 days.
I'll surely catch them.
I will marry you right after that.
Hello!
Why didn't you call me before coming here?
According to James's circular,
I'll be a paparazzi next week.
Why is that?
Mr. Lam lodged a complaint.
He said you defamed him
in your interview last time.
He sent us a legal letter.
The boss needs to find a scapegoat.
He is complaining after two years?
Come on.
Listen to me first.
Actually, you are already lucky
for not being fired.
We can't do anything
if these rich people want to mess around.
Right?
KK, don't lie to me.
Tell me the truth.
Do you want the truth?
Okay.
The company wants to use new talent,
so you should take a break.
That's it.
Use new talent?
YoYo?
Yes.
There's nothing I can do to help you.
It's strictly business.
You've been a newcomer once.
When you got promoted,
you kicked someone out too.
The company only prioritizes
the biggest returns.
She has only been working here
for two months.
Yes.
She's inexperienced.
She can't even speak clearly.
But...
Don't get mad if I'm frank, okay?
She's younger than you
and has a cuter smile.
Viewers like her better.
I'm very satisfied with that.
You are even more satisfied
with sleeping with her, right?
Even if that is true, so what?
Angel, you are outdated.
Actually, isn't it better
if you leave now?
At least some viewers will remember you
as the muse of CSS News.
Besides,
I also want you to know
that love
really can't be controlled sometimes.
First, I'm dumping you.
Second, I quit.
Don't ever come to me again.
Honey.
Why didn't you call me before coming here?
I surely won't let you look down on me.
So painful.
Uncle Tak!
Hello?
Uncle Tak, this is Sunny.
I'm back in Hong Kong.
Why aren't you guys back here yet?
You jerk, what did you do?
You guys are wanted
by the Malaysian police.
They detained all of our stuff.
I don't even have any spare underwear.
I had nothing to do with that.
It was Tai-chu and his squad.
I already told you
not to hang out with them.
Uncle Tak.
I'm so scared.
I think something is wrong with me.
I'm so slim.
You have always been slim.
No, I was very fat last night.
What the heck are you talking about?
And I see a mosquito staring at me
and flying so slowly.
Are you nuts?
Either go to the police station
or a mental hospital.
No, the police will arrest me.
Go. You didn't do anything.
Why should you be afraid?
Go to the police and get it settled.
Okay.
Bye.
Do you want to bite me?
Why was that so easy?
Go!
It's very dangerous here, sir!
- Go!
- Me?
Stand over there first.
Sir, what's going on?
I want to report a case.
The station is in trouble.
Do you want to report a case?
Go somewhere else. Go.
There's a limit to my patience!
- You're going to be in trouble!
- Yes.
Someone is holding a policewoman hostage.
One, two. Two are down on the floor.
No way! How can you see that
from so far away?
I can see it very clearly.
Sir, we can't shoot.
His gun is aimed at the hostage.
If we shoot him, the hostage is at risk.
Do you want me to kill her?
Snipers ready,
open fire when you have a chance.
Useless police! Get out of here!
Get out!
What is going on?
Angel, something happened!
A criminal took an officer's gun
and is holding someone hostage.
- Who are you?
- We're from CSS News. Thank you.
- We are together.
- Okay, go in.
- Angel!
- Yes.
Don't you recognize me?
I'm Sunny Lee!
Sunny?
Twin-dagger Sunny!
I'm the fat guy from last night.
The very slim one.
Why isn't the car I want here yet?
Hey, stop bugging me. Someone is dead.
She's still alive. Don't worry.
That policewoman
seems to be out of breath.
You can see that?
That criminal is holding a gun
to the policewoman's head.
Her neck is strapped with tape.
She can't breathe.
She's dying.
- Freeze!
Who made the shot?
Sir, we didn't shoot.
It looks to be a bamboo stick.
- What's your name, sir?
- Yes. Look here. Excuse me.
- Look here. Thank you. Right side.
- Excuse me.
Follow me!
- Excuse me!
- James, pass me the camera.
- Catch it!
Angel, go! I'll stop them. Come back soon!
Do you recognize me now?
Everyone recognizes you now.
Can you do me a favor?
Sure. What is it?
Please do an exclusive interview with me.
You have a rare genetic mutation.
Your cells divide so much faster
than an ordinary person's cells
and they keep changing.
Your cartilage tissues
keep proliferating too.
Stop this nonsense.
I just want to know
when I will go back to normal.
Tai-chu, you said
you and your friends
were infected with a biochemical toxin.
I think I have to know
the composition of the toxin
before I can answer you.
Actually, I don't know how to cure you.
Please let me go.
My wife and kids are waiting for me.
Please spare me.
Hey, come and have a look.
A hostage situation occurred
at a police station this morning.
The hostage was already released
from the hospital after treatment.
The criminal suffered an arm injury
and is facing police charges.
The nameless hero captured on camera
rescued the hostage with a bamboo stick.
His identity has yet to be determined.
I can't believe he is still alive.
Tell me!
He was infected just like us.
But how is he doing just fine?
Why didn't his appearance change?
Different people
may react to the toxin in different ways.
Maybe he has certain defensive antibodies.
You killed my little brother.
Not only are you alive,
but your appearance didn't even change.
Spectacular Thunderbolt Circus
Hello, everybody. I'm Angel Chan.
In this period of frequent robberies,
a nameless hero
has finally stepped forward.
He used a bamboo stick
to resolve a hostage-taking incident
and rescued a policewoman's life.
He is now right next to me.
Let him introduce himself.
Hi.
Hello, everybody.
I'm Li Fei.
My English name is Sunny Lee.
My nickname is Twin-dagger Sunny.
Twin-dagger Sunny.
- Yes.
- Based on the nickname,
it's obvious that what you did
didn't happen by chance.
Based on your skill
and the environment here,
is your job related to martial arts?
This place isn't related to martial arts.
This is the training area of a circus.
I travel with this circus
to perform all around the world.
Who taught you your flying dagger skill?
My dad taught me that.
My dad was the 26th descendent
of the Thousand Flying Daggers.
The Merciless Flying Dagger
who never misses his target.
Where is your dad now?
He has already passed away.
But it's okay.
As my dad told me,
"Life is like a flying dagger."
Once the flying dagger is released,
it must hit its target.
Why don't you show
your flying dagger skills to our viewers?
Act natural. Just think of it
as your performance on stage.
All right, I'll show you.
I'd like to see
your flying dagger skills too!
Tai-chu!
Angel?
Hello, Angel.
I'm a fan of yours.
Can we be friends?
Let me settle my affairs first.
Sunny.
Why do you look the same?
Tai-chu, you...
Your appearance didn't change much either.
You look quite handsome.
What medicine did you take?
I ate salted fish.
Some cookies.
I got fat. Then I became slim again.
I vomited and got diarrhea.
Then I was fine.
Isn't that amazing?
All right.
Be good
and come with me.
I'm not going with you.
Come with me!
- Hey!
- Go!
He's so fast.
Help!
Angel!
Sunny.
I dreamed of my brother again last night.
He told me that he died miserably.
He slipped and fell to his death.
Tai-chu.
It was really not my fault.
I saw you kill my brother!
I think
God wouldn't be that unfair.
He granted us power
but turned us into freaks.
And he only favors you!
Old Man, they are evolving so fast.
They are already in phase two now.
So what?
Fortunately,
fate arranged for you
to make us perfect.
Your blood
will be our antidote.
Tai-chu, don't act recklessly.
Are you going to drink my blood?
Let me tell you a secret concoction.
Listen.
Four taels of astragalus root.
Ten grams of Chinese yam.
Half a catty of each fritillaria.
Bellflower root and loquat.
If you like it sweet,
add two candied dates.
Fine, no candied dates.
The most important thing
is the cooking method!
Help!
You are still so incredible
even after getting anesthetized.
Old Man!
Hit his acupuncture point!
Cheung Tai-chu!
Don't force me!
Sunny.
Sunny!
Old Man.
I don't think Sunny is with them.
He is not a bad guy.
So what?
They are of the same kind anyway.
We must make him tell us
where the other freaks are.
Do slow-motion here.
Yes, okay.
Shoot until there.
- Yes, make an end shot here.
- Okay.
I'm making it clear to the public
that there are no mutants.
Please don't make any random guesses
to avoid public anxiety.
Then how do you explain
the pictures and clips that we took?
I repeat, there are no mutants.
We will do our best to get the suspects.
Are you capable of dealing with them?
Officer Hong, look.
Where did you get this?
Sunny's case is very peculiar.
I've never seen it before.
His blood contains
a strong biochemical toxin indeed,
but it didn't affect his cell tissues.
In fact, it made him many times
more powerful than ordinary people.
I think his own antibodies
neutralized the toxin.
I compared Sunny's preliminary report
with He Jun's, the suspect who got killed.
I found that there's no obvious mutation
in Sunny's muscle and joint tissues.
We can say
that he is a rare and extraordinary guy.
But Sunny is a mutant after all.
He poses a threat to the public
to a certain extent.
I suggest detaining him indefinitely
for further observation.
Until when?
That is not the solution.
He is in every headline now.
The public would think
that Sunny Lee is a hero
who punishes criminals and beats mutants.
How can we explain why a hero is detained?
Ms. Angel Chan
just proposed a good suggestion.
Listen to her first.
I think that
since we can't hide our hero Sunny,
why don't we follow the public opinion
and make him an embodiment of justice
or a savior?
Give him shows, ads, and endorsements.
I'm very experienced in media.
I can be his agent.
This would be advantageous
to the police, to Sunny,
and even in rebuilding the public's trust.
I think
it would be most advantageous to her.
I personally agree
with Ms. Chan's suggestion.
We must strike while the iron is hot.
That's why I already hired Ms. Chan
as a special consultant.
Sir, I think it's quite a good idea.
The experts we hire
cannot seem to help us
capture those mutants anyway.
From now on,
you two should just do your best
to assist and protect Sunny.
Who do you think you are
to give us orders?
Old Man.
Let's go. We quit.
Okay.
We'll do our best
to cooperate with your operation.
The merciless razor
will never miss its target!
It will root out
all its opponents!
The hairs are stuck.
Cut! One more time!
Mutant?
Gosh!
As a superhero, I have to attend
networking parties so often.
I keep running around.
How can I have time to take a break?
Luckily, I have the Diarrhea Killer.
Without it, what should I do
if my stomach aches
while fighting mutants?
Diarrhea Killer, so cool!
Mutant.
Stop!
- Nice!
- How did I do? Is it okay?
You were great.
- I think so.
- But we are in a hurry, let's go.
Hold it first.
- Sunny!
Twin-dagger Sunny, God's Favored One
Twin-dagger Sunny, Flying Dagger Hero
Crime-busting Ambassador,
Flying Dagger Hero, Twin-dagger Sunny
Twin-dagger nasal decongestant.
- Sugar, egg. Yes.
- Right.
After pouring in everything...
Yes, just stir it thoroughly.
That's incredible!
Twin-dagger Sunny,
Flying Dagger Hero Sunny
Wake up. You can do it! Go!
- Go!
- Sunny!
- Nice!
Crime-busting Pioneer
Thank you.
What Sunny means is,
he will work harder and do his best
after getting this award.
He'll always be your Twin-dagger Sunny!
Old Man, inform Officer Tong.
They might be getting ready
to make a move.
There's no need.
I've been waiting for them.
You've been swallowing
your anger these days
because you want to use Sunny as bait?
You finally got it.
But...
Tai!
You don't need to use
a flying dagger to kill pests.
Use Super Mutant Killer.
Just spray it all over, so fragrant.
All the pests and even mutants
will get killed instantly.
Super Mutant Killer.
Kill!
Hi!
Get the flying dagger, yo, yo, yo!
This event was very successful.
It's so-so.
Do you want some wine?
I don't drink when I'm working.
So professional.
Are you used to living here?
Actually...
We are here to catch mutants
like Cheung Tai-chu.
But I realize that
turning into a monster on the outside
isn't the scariest thing.
What do you mean?
Sometimes, people can easily lose
their direction in life.
They'll even lose themselves.
While striving for fame and gain,
we unconsciously change.
It's so quiet, Old Man.
It hasn't been this peaceful
for a long time.
Haven't you always said
you wanted to buy a house by the sea
and live a peaceful life?
All right.
Let's buy one when we capture the mutants.
Do you remember what day it is tomorrow?
It's supposed to be our wedding date,
we missed it again.
Tai.
I'm really confident this time.
We have already found their weakness.
I believe we can finish this soon.
We have never dealt
with such tough mutants before.
Old Man.
Let's get some help.
Help?
Who can help us?
Sunny.
They are all monsters anyway.
If we ask this little monster for help,
wouldn't it be much easier?
Don't you trust me anymore?
You think I can't handle this, right?
Old Man.
You know that's not what I meant.
Also, that day,
you placed Sunny
in a really dangerous situation.
You saw the mutant,
but you didn't inform the police.
Don't you think
you were too selfish to do that?
I'm selfish?
Consider me selfish then.
I won't feel at peace
until I am recognized for my success.
Even if we buy a house by the sea,
do you think
I would really feel happy and at peace?
Are you feeling exhausted?
Are you not feeling well?
Tell me.
Once the flying dagger is out,
no one can compare to it.
I can help you out.
Do you think I am a bad person?
No.
Don't you think I'm too selfish
to use you this way?
As long as you're happy, that's fine.
Angel.
You're the one
who made my dreams come true.
Just like my dad,
I can finally perform flying daggers
on stage.
No matter what,
I have to thank you.
Idiot.
Monster, don't move. All right.
Attack him!
Okay. Monster, move a bit.
Together, look to the left.
Yes.
Time to eat.
After working the whole night,
these are so yummy.
Flying-dagger hero?
I told you, I'll be back.
Without you,
my life is worthless.
Tai-chu.
My blood may not be able to save you.
You'd better surrender.
I don't care!
I still want your blood.
The number you dialed
cannot be reached at the moment.
Please try again later.
Your life is mine!
Also,
Angel belongs to me too.
Do not hurt Angel!
You evil monster, you still don't get it!
Is there something wrong with your brain?
I won't let you off
until you die!
Come with me.
It's you again.
You are finally here.
All right.
Today, I'll offer your blood
as a sacrifice to my husband.
Your four major acupuncture points
in Qimen are now blocked.
Do you feel paralyzed?
Do you want to escape?
You are mine!
You can't escape!
Open the door!
What? The studio is on fire!
- This is unbelievable!
- Open the door!
I heard voices inside.
I think someone is trapped inside!
Call the police!
Go!
Hurry!
I will take you
as a contribution to science later.
You can't move anyway.
Just quietly wait
to become a mutant specimen.
It didn't work.
Why?
I've waited for you for so long.
Old Man, run!
Tai, I'm going to fulfill my promise soon.
Our wedding date remains unchanged.
Old Man, you can't win against him.
Run!
Do you think I can't win?
I just dealt with one out there.
Look at him.
Tai, it's showtime.
Old Man!
Stop!
You're useless!
Old Man, run!
So you are still evolving.
Tai, are you all right?
Is anyone hurt?
What in the world?
I didn't expect
the monster to evolve so quickly.
Silver needles and acupuncture points
didn't work!
Good thing I killed one
or they would assume
that I'm easy to deal with.
Tai.
Let's use a steel mill instead
and double the anesthetics.
We'll definitely get that monster
next time.
Tai!
Shau-wah...
Shau-wah.
Don't joke around with me.
This is not funny.
I'm not going to play along!
Old Man.
I like that you call me Tai.
You gave me this name.
Tai.
Be good.
You will be fine.
Don't sleep.
We are going to the hospital now
and you will be fine.
There's no need.
Old Man.
Sorry.
Carry on by yourself in the future.
Don't say that.
I don't want that.
Without you,
how could I carry on?
Don't leave me.
Old Man.
Remember.
No matter what happens,
don't lose yourself.
Old Man.
Tai.
It's okay. Don't be afraid.
No matter where you are,
I will always be with you.
You will never get lost.
Old Man.
It's so beautiful here.
So peaceful.
Tai!
I was wrong. Come back.
Come back, okay?
I won't fight them anymore.
Thank you for saving me.
Just like you,
I was befuddled for half my life.
From now on,
this is none of my business anymore.
The right things, the wrong things,
I have done them all.
It's time to leave.
I have been the people's hero
for a period of time.
Being the Twin-dagger Hero
changed my life.
I thought that it could bring me
happiness and success.
But actually, I have been lying to myself.
You would even risk your life
to achieve recognition in the past.
How can you give up so easily now?
Suen Ho,
please help me.
Tai once said
a little monster like you
would be able to tackle them.
Let me teach you
how to control your power.
This was Tai's last request
from me.
You imbibed too much poisonous gas,
and luckily, excreted all of them.
You can only be considered a half-mutant.
You can only use your power
when you are in danger.
But you can't control it.
And you can't throw
flying daggers accurately.
I'm now going to train you
to improve your concentration.
Don't think of anything else,
other than your target.
I will tell you
about Cheung Tai-chu's weakness.
News headlines.
The series of mutant attacks
has caused heavy casualties.
Experts have yet to come up
with a way to deal with mutants.
The mutants kidnapped six scientists
studying biochemical toxins.
This series of murders and arsons
have caused panic,
resulting in a citywide evacuation.
Ms. Chan, you better take a rest.
You haven't slept for two days.
If we have any news about Sunny,
we'll definitely let you know.
Can you help me?
My name is Angel.
- Angel!
- Yes.
Wake up. You can do it! Go!
- Go!
Hello? Sunny?
Angel.
It's me.
Cheung Tai-chu.
I sent Sunny to heaven,
but I am in hell.
Angel.
Where are you?
I am so lonely.
I just realized
that what God gave me isn't power,
but a form of punishment.
I am becoming more and more powerful,
but I have never felt lonelier.
You deserve the worst punishment!
Angel.
You are the only one I want to see now.
Stop hiding.
No matter where you are, I will find you.
We have to remind you
that what you want to do
is very dangerous.
Even if you can lure Cheung Tai-chu out,
we can't guarantee that we can catch him.
I have already decided.
Forget that I haven't found
a treatment method.
Even if I did,
I won't help you!
God gave you power,
but your vicious mind is from yourself!
There is no cure for it.
Just wait for your demise!
Angel, if you still don't come out,
I will kill so many people.
You don't have to find me anymore.
I have finally figured it out.
Actually, you and I are both bad.
We are the same type of person.
I am lonely too.
Tomorrow is my birthday.
Kowloon Bay Building, 131.
Bravo One, clear.
Roger out.
Bravo Two, clear.
Command Center,
there's nothing suspicious here.
Monitoring continued.
Roger out.
Snipers, keep a close watch.
Once the target appears, kill him.
Roger.
The target is here! Watch out!
The target is going down!
Brave Two, follow!
He's too fast, I can't shoot him!
Attention, all teams.
Take strict containment!
Brave One, roger out.
Brave Two, roger out.
Ms. Angel, the mutant is coming down.
Leave through the backdoor as planned.
Ms. Angel, it will be very dangerous
if you stay.
We can't protect you.
Take her away!
Ms. Angel, let's go!
Bravo Two, our line of sight is blocked.
Our comrade might be behind the door.
All units, hold your fire!
Angel.
Happy birthday.
Cheer up.
From now on,
we will be friends forever.
Actually, I would prefer
that we be lovers.
And we will be together forever.
Lovers?
Why do you love me so much?
Whenever I think about you,
I feel very happy.
Do you know what love is?
It's a kind of feeling.
Your minds are in sync,
you miss each other,
you laugh and cry together,
and he is the only one in your heart.
That is love.
You are just a pitiful person.
I don't care!
Come with me.
I will give you whatever you want.
I want you to die!
It's useless!
Come with me!
Hold your fire!
Angel just pushed Cheung Tai-chu
out the window. We can't take aim!
Angel.
Sunny.
Sunny, you're not dead?
Stop this!
Hold your fire!
It's the Flying-dagger Hero!
Sunny!
What was that?
Let me deal with you!
Tai is waiting for you in the Netherworld.
Go and accompany her.
Angel!
Sunny!
It's okay.
After I kill that idiot, you will be mine.
Sunny.
I feel strange seeing you alive.
It seems like I feel less lonely.
But you came back to die.
Even if you can't change how you look,
you can change your ways.
Stop this.
I don't want to be human!
I want to be God!
He gave me power,
so I can have everything I want,
including love.
You're so pathetic.
Shut up.
You can't even save yourself.
How can you be the Flying-dagger Hero?
Come on.
Release your flying daggers!
Help!
- Help!
I can't open it!
Angel!
Angel.
Go!
Why?
You laughed and cried together.
You even sacrificed your life for him.
Angel.
Angel!
I can't believe this.
Angel.
If you still won't take me
to the hospital,
I will really die.
Feel with your heart.
Aim with your eyes.
Throw with your force.
Combine your force with the wind.
You have to befriend the wind.
Let the wind carry your flying dagger.
My son, you surely can do it.
- Fly!
- That was so close, my son!
- Gosh!
My son.
Do you know? You're the 28th descendant
of Thousand Flying Daggers.
You can't fail.
You must hit it, understand?
Listen, life is like a flying dagger.
Once the flying dagger is released,
it must hit its target.
Dear, if you are the target,
he might hit it accurately.
In that case,
if my sacrifice can make him good at this,
I'm willing to do it!