The one who created this world
with his omnipotent power,
who gave life to all creatures
and mankind,
has granted us mortals this world
full of endless colors.
Every ruler derives power from him,
and is imprinted in his likeness.
O, God, the one…
You have conferred the form
of every creature.
Defend me.
Give me strength to trample upon Satan.
Give me the love of a lover
longing for death.
Lighten the burden of the sins
I must bear beyond the grave.
Are you hiding? We're not putting the
fuses in yet. Why are you so scared?
I hope you get fucked by a male wolf,
you chicken!
- These are full of water.
- That's why I told you not to touch them.
- But I've still got to bring the grease.
- Yes, grease it.
Are you blowing it up yet?
I have a plastic bag.
- Don't blow it up without me.
- Why would I do that?
Pull it back.
Pull back and let go slowly.
Slowly!
One last time! OK! Do it slowly! Good!
Finish!
Follow her!
Work till the end!
The finish line!
Finish!
Faster!
More! Till the end!
Till the end!
Christ was born on the 25th of December
- It's hard.
- It's hard, but interesting to learn.
- Should we expect the girls soon?
- Yes, very soon.
It's almost 11:00.
It's almost 11:30 already.
I'm going to complain to the authorities
about this.
Be thankful we didn't complain when you
missed several lectures, dear teacher.
- You better be quiet.
- I will still complain.
…and three and four.
C-major. Three and four.
We move to F major on "dilav."
Let's start it from the beginning.
One, two, three, four.
Dilav, dilav, ranina…
What's wrong, Malvina?
Keep the same tempo.
I want to say a toast
to the memory of one manly man.
It's been three years… No, 30 years,
since the passing of Manana's husband.
On the 3rd of October,
no 3rd of November.
I'm going to stand up in his honor.
He was a real man!
Even in 100 years he will be like that.
Let's remember him, Manana.
When my brother said a toast yesterday,
he said a toast for Yuza.
He said that it was his 30th anniversary.
We drank to his 30th anniversary.
I said that you wanted
to organize an event
and he named eight or nine friends
who are still alive.
Mr. Zurab, I was Manana's bridesmaid,
and my husband was the best man
at the wedding of that great man.
30 years have passed, but he is not dead.
When family and friends remember you,
you're never dead. Let's drink for Yuza.
Are you still here?
You swine. Filthy unbeliever!
Archil, why are you dicking around?
The power went out! The relay broke.
The boys don't have air.
I'll take them outside.
- Where are my tools…
- Get to work quickly!
This is good. I don't understand…
The train is sliding!
Put something under the wheels.
Did they turn off the power
from the outside?
No!
The power is out in our section!
- What's going on?
- I can't feel my fucking legs!
The power relay is leaking.
- So?
- There is no air being pumped.
Achiko is trying to fix it now.
I am exhausted.
- Want a cigarette?
- I quit.
- Are you going too?
- Yes, I'll give him a hand.
I took the guys outside.
- Did you have a big load?
- Just a little bit.
You have to find the broken relay.
- Good morning, gentlemen.
- Good morning.
Good morning!
Hello!
How are you?
Hello.
I won't be home tonight.
Rehearsal in the morning.
Leave the light on.
I'll have to stay here today again,
tomorrow I will come home.
How are the kids?
OK.
Have you heard?
Mikha is back.
People!
Women are afraid to leave their house
because of this maniac.
This is unacceptable!
You talk too much!
Let's beat him senseless!
Oh motherland…
The beautiful…
There is nothing
Like you anywhere
Oh motherland…
The beautiful…
There is nothing
Like you anywhere
Sit down children. Everyone.
Leave it alone.
I am deeply sorry, children,
that I sometimes run late. Sometimes.
Merab, leave me alone,
I don't have time. I'm in class.
I have a class! I will call you after.
I know about the wedding.
I will meet with Peter later about that.
OK, it's not going to be a problem.
OK, thank you. That would be great.
I will call you later.
Let's start, Bana!
Pass me the instrument.
What's going on here?
Did you get it? What did you get?
What did you get?
You nod like you got it,
so what did you get?
Boys, follow the girl's example…
First, second, third, fourth,
fifth, sixth, seventh…
How can girls be better,
aren't you ashamed?
B-flat major, children.
We've been studying for a month and a half
and there is no result.
It won't work like this.
I want you to be praised.
When you're praised,
I'll be praised in return.
We can't work like this.
Which school do you go to?
Public school #2.
Who is his classmate?
- I am. He's in my class.
- Does he study at all in school?
- So-so.
- What?
So-so.
B-flat major, children.
Who knows "B-flat major"?
You will drive me nuts.
B-flat major!
What is it?
Third string in first tonality, first and
second string in second tonality.
- B-flat major, Diana.
- Yes.
Tell me B-flat major.
First and third strings in first tonality.
Very well.
Kids, do you see now what's going on?
Come inside the building,
since you're here.
Just come inside, for God's sake.
Our guests today are Irina Pkhaladze,
Mari Pkhaladze and Ms. Tsitso Bokoveli.
Mari is 13 years old and
has already won 13 gold medals in running.
I have been training
athletes for 25 years,
our city has never had
such a successful athlete.
We are very proud.
I don't push them to their limit.
They don't get enough calories,
so I'm afraid to push them.
The city feeds them
once a day at the soup kitchen.
Eating once a day is not enough.
If they could eat three times a day,
I'd push them all the way.
This is a huge problem.
If we can find someone
who can sponsor their meals
so that the kids
can receive enough calories,
we can aim for a world championship.
Hello, how is it going?
They stole the metal again.
I have no idea.
Common.
What do you mean "don't worry"?
Should I not worry?
What should I do about the bank loan?
No. I came over and everything was gone.
I will kill them if I find them.
I'll break those iron rods
over their heads.
I came by to work
and everything was gone.
I was just collecting the metal
for the client
to pay down my loan a bit.
I'm going to get evicted.
I can't do this anymore.
I can't guard it 24 hours a day.
- You're blocking me.
- Move.
It's beginning to rain.
One, two, three, four. One, two…
Three… four…
It's OK.
Three, four…
I follow you like a mountain mist
I want to make you lost
You seemed like a quail with a broken wing
But you fled so quickly
Where did you get lost
Continue!
Coming up.
Achiko.
Guladi.
Sit down.
Turn it over or you will get dirty.
Koba, this sausage is yours.
One of you has to eat it.
Even if you don't feel like it.
I ate my share.
Are you a company CEO?
Who cares about "shares"?
I don't want to eat anymore.
I'm forcing myself to eat.
- Have some more…
- Is it from your "share"?
Kind of smells like chocolate.
Is it good?
Let me throw it out.
Don't leave the bread uneaten.
- What's your dog's name?
- Mickey.
The tiny one, right?
Really tiny one…
Yeah.
Finish the food, please.
Let's clean up here.
You are force-feeding me.
- I can't eat it anymore.
- We can leave it here then.
Take it to Mickey.
Do we have a bag?
Put it there.
I'd like to drink a toast
to all our brothers
who died in the mines.
On behalf of our late friend Koba,
let's drink to those who put
their uniforms on by themselves,
but couldn't take them off again.
May God bless them.
There are many others who passed away.
Our brother,
Giorgi died in the mines recently.
To all. It's impossible to count.
May God bless them.
The day before yesterday
another young man died.
To the memory of all those
who died working in the mines.
Out of three glasses,
one goes out to them.
Let's never forget them.
Oh motherland, the beautiful
Adorned with roses and flowers
You are a gem
You, my sweet homeland
My heart beats for you
You are my sigh
and my joy
As your leaf
Shining in the sun rolling in the winds
Has flown from you
To the land so far from here
So my heart is open
For all the others to share
How I long for you, how I long for you
My Magnolia
So my heart goes out to others
I would probably not remember you,
my Magnolia
I could not…
I couldn't hear you.
OK. I will call you back.
- It's really dishonest.
- I did not fall behind.
This is all due to our genes speaking out…
Sometimes we want to dance,
sometimes we want to sing,
but in the end,
none of this has any meaning.
My dears, none of us here
can dance Swan Lake.
You are wrong! We have done it.
We have done it.
Show me!
Show me you can dance Swan Lake.
Play the music!
First ask these three…
I don't want them to perform.
I want you to perform Swan Lake.
You will be the first swan.
- Who's the second swan?
- You.
The love of bright sunshine
And wild seas we bear
I don't think southern winds
Will leave and disappear
But her heart is open
For all the others to share
I don't know why, do you know what for
My Magnolia?
So my heart goes out to others
I don't know why, do you know what for
My Magnolia?
Have you ever had such a moment
Forever gone?
It will come back, it will come back
Don't you think?
The love of beautiful seas
And mountains we bear
I long for you, I long for you
My Magnolia
I wrote the lyrics
and music for this song.
I'll sing it for you for the first time.
You are the source of my dreams
I can't take my eyes off of you
You are the icon I pray to
Your candle illuminates my night
Call me, where are you
Let me look at you
For a while at least
Do you need my help?
Open it.
Watch the wagon.
Leave it alone.
Put it over there, please.
Can you do it alone?
I can do anything.
Niko!
To the gray world…
gray century…
gray town…
Amen.
Subtitle translation by: Michael Evans