[suspenseful music]
[wind whistling]
[waves crashing]
- She still alive?
- Not for long.
Come here.
- Too bad, she's so pretty.
- Nah.
- Oh, come on, she was pretty.
- She's all right.
[hand thudding]
The car is pretty.
[van door slams]
[truck slams]
[car engine roars]
[waves crashing]
[engine revving]
- There's somebody over there.
- That's them, maybe.
[engine revving]
Let's take a look.
[bumpers thud]
[intense music]
[engine revving]
[van thudding]
[explosion thunders]
- That's them!
- Hands up!
[car door slams]
[suspenseful music]
[guns firing]
[man groans]
[car engine roars]
[guns firing]
[tires screeching]
[officer groans]
[suspenseful music]
[engine roars]
[tires screeching]
[fire crackling]
[tense music]
[light thuds]
[radio beeping]
[fingers tapping]
- B14 to headquarters.
[buttons clicking]
This is Al Romero. Come in.
- [Dispatcher] Read you, over.
- North on Route 21, 11
mile mark, officer down.
It's my partner, Carlos Rivas,
badly wounded out
at Muller's Point.
And one perpetrator
also wounded.
But you must show
at Muller Crossing
- [Dispatcher] Units
B34 and C5 in the area
of related interchange, they're
waiting for instructions,
should I put them through?
- No, wait a second,
I'll call you back.
- North on Route 21, 11
mile mark, officer down.
It's my partner, Carlos Rivas,
badly wounded out
at Muller's Point.
Get me that [indistinct].
- [Dispatcher] Who
the hell's that?
- Captain Badal.
- This is Badal.
- Officer Carlos
Rivas badly wounded,
and one suspect also wounded.
Set up a roadblock.
We got him.
- [Badal] Description
of the car?
- It's a Jag, a gray Jaguar.
I got the plate.
It's W1723EO.
That's W1723EO.
- [Dispatcher] Got it,
okay, over and out.
[suspenseful music]
[car engine roars]
- You got it?
- [Woman] It's so
funny, I was just going
to call you back, my hand
was right on the phone.
Are you running in diplomatic
circles now, inspector?
- Okay, who's car is it?
- [Woman] It's registered
to a Mr. Thomas Radeck,
Columbian Consul.
[suspenseful music continues]
[car engine roars]
- Got your ass now, prick.
[tires screeching]
[radio buttons clicking]
B14 to headquarters.
- [Badal] Badal here.
- Nobody at the
intersection, what happened?
- [Badal] Wouldn't [indistinct]
- Yeah, all right, don't worry.
I've got this son of a bitch.
- [Badal] Let him go.
- What? I got him!
I said, got him!
- [Badal] Let him go, Romero.
- What can I do back there?
I got the guy who did it.
Let me put him away.
- [Badal] Romero,
you have your orders.
Get back and take care of
the corpse and your partner.
[tires screeching]
[handbrake rasps]
[handbrake clicks]
[car engine roars]
[indistinct radio chatter]
- He's gone, I'm sorry.
- Shit!
Did you tell Maria?
- Not yet.
- So long, man.
I'll do it.
- You'll do what?
- I'll talk to Maria.
You know where she is?
- She's working on the
missing American girls sting,
with the Anti-Drug Force.
Luis Barbosa, that's another
scumbag who was in drugs.
- She's got needle
marks all over,
in her goddamn neck.
Poor kid.
[knocking on door]
- Captain, there's someone
waiting to see you.
- Let him wait, I'm busy!
I'd like to speak to Don Thomas.
Look, Badal calling.
[phone rings]
- Hello.
No, this is his personal
assistant, Chucho.
Don Thomas is in a
meeting right now,
he can't be disturbed.
- This is Inspector Badal.
Please tell Don Thomas
that one of your men
is leaving Consul [indistinct].
He's driving a car which
belongs to Don Thomas.
[gentle piano music]
We checked it from
the license plate.
Tell Don Thomas that
I have done my best.
That that is kind of
mistake can't happen again,
I'm not the chief of police,
nor the Minister
of the Interior.
And this kind of thing-
- [Chucho] All right, all
right, you have my word,
this won't happen again.
- And I must clean up-
- [Chucho] I will. Goodbye.
- He's as oily as a snake.
What did he want
anyway, essentially?
- It's Flores, he must've
gotten rid of a girl,
and he offed a cop.
And he let them see the
plates on one of our cars.
- I never want to
hear from him again.
Never.
All right?
- Okay.
[soft piano music continues]
- [Chief of police] Well,
we've been waiting for you.
- I'm sorry for
the interruption,
but it seems that
one of my employees,
at the consolute had
a little car trouble.
- Nothing serious, I hope.
- I hope not.
May I have a review
with the bidding please?
- His Honor opened two diamonds,
two spades, Juno trumps.
- [Thomas] Fine.
- Four spades.
[sirens wailing]
[car doors slamming]
- Excuse me.
- Wait a minute.
- All right, I'm sorry.
- No, I know, I know, I know!
We-
- I had him!
He's one of those
assholes dealing drugs
to little girls, pimps them,
and then kills them off
when they get outta line!
He killed my partner!
And I had the son of a bitch!
- Easy!
There was no time.
We didn't have a
car anywhere around.
- Then why'd you call me off?
I had him.
[hand slams]
- Because I lost one of
my best guys tonight,
that's enough for me.
I didn't want to lose you too.
- What about the car?
- Stolen.
Registered to an
ambassador or something.
He reported the
theft a few days ago.
[Al scoffs]
- Want one?
- I'm on the wagon.
One second, I'll
be right with you.
Is officer Maria
Mendoza back yet?
Thanks.
She already knows about Carlos.
- Who told her?
- Who knows. Some
diplomat, maybe.
Would you like a cup of coffee?
- No. Thank you.
- You still haven't
heard from your wife?
- No.
- Come with me.
- If Maria calls,
I'm in the cooler.
- [Vinny] Roger.
- You already saw
her, didn't you?
- Yeah, but I'd like
you to show this man
both of the girls
they brought in today.
- [Coroner] There were three.
- It's cold in here.
- You're right.
[tense music]
- OD's?
All three?
- [Coroner] It looks that way.
[Paul belches]
- Excuse me.
- The entertainment's not
so great in this place.
- You think my wife
will end up like that?
- Maybe not.
Maybe she's just getting it on
with some guy who's
better looking than you.
- What?
- No, nothing.
I'm sorry, had a bad day.
- I'd thank God.
- Hmm?
- If that's where she's gone,
if that's what she's doing,
I'd get done on my
knees and thank God
that she's alive,
and that's all.
- You're sure she was a user?
And it's been two weeks
since she disappeared?
- 15 days.
- Why don't you go home,
I'll let you know when
we find something.
- Go home. Yeah.
I've just been away.
[lighter rasps]
We got married six months ago.
I didn't know she used drugs.
She thought that our love would
help her get her straight.
- How old did you say she was?
- 20.
[Paul coughing]
I don't smoke.
- Come up to the office,
we'll get a cup of coffee.
- Hi, Flores.
- Chucho, You scared
the hell outta me.
What the hell's wrong with you?
Turn the headlights
off, you're blinding me.
- You had a little
accident tonight.
- You say that like
I shit in my pants.
[Flores scoffs]
I had to get rid of
a girl, that's all.
It was crazy.
He jumped out in front of
my car and yelled "stop".
Chucho, did you think
I was gonna pull over
and show 'em my license?
- But you left your
business card, man.
[fingers snap]
- Shit, the damn cover came off.
So, you come to chew me out
because the old man got mad?
Turn those lights off, will you?
- They make you nervous?
- Come on, stop playing around.
I get the message, I fucked up.
Don't worry about it.
Chucho, you remember when
we got caught stealing
that car when we was kids.
- I remember.
- Boy, did we ever
fuck up that time, hey?
It was worth it, though.
Remember that car?
It was a pretty car.
[guns firing]
[Flores groans]
[knees thud]
- Pretty car.
[gun fires]
- It was a fucking
Chevy, Flores.
- Thanks for everything.
- Don't mention it.
I'll call you as soon
as we get a lead.
- In any case, if
you don't mind,
I'll come back to
see how you're doing,
I don't have much else to do.
- Sure.
Maria.
[lips smacking]
- You feeling better?
- Hi.
- Paul. Paul Boles.
- What's going on?
- They told you, right?
- I came soon as I could.
You need me for
the identification.
- Yes.
- Okay.
Hi.
- Hi.
- This one too?
- Yeah.
[tense music]
- Carlos! [Maria sobs]
- We were at Muller's Point,
they opened fire at us.
- You son of a bitch!
You let him die,
you son of a bitch.
How could you do it?
You son of a bitch!
You let him die! [crying]
[eerie music]
[people chattering]
- They just tell
me you were here.
I'm sorry.
- Maria, come with me.
- Captain, we've got
a possible homicide
at the harbor, and a car that
[indistinct] description.
- [hand slams] Get them there!
Um, you can stay here
and see to Maria.
- I'm going down, I wanna see
if it's the car I was chasing.
Can you wait for her?
- I got nothing else to do.
[sirens wailing]
[upbeat jazz music]
- Good evening, detective.
I saw the whole thing.
- Are you the one who called?
- He was too drunk
to see the numbers,
I had to dial.
- I was coming out
of the Barking Dog,
I was having a glass of milk.
- Milk, my arse.
- Will you please shut up,
I'm telling you a story.
- That's him. He's the
one that killed Carlos.
- [Drunk man] Guns
rang out like thunder.
I hid among the bushes.
And did I mention
that I am a pacifist?
And then the cars came
rolling up like butterflies.
- [Sailor] Rolling
up like butterflies?
- Butterflies flutter,
they don't roll.
- Will you, please.
If I'm saying the
butterflies roll,
they damn well gonna roll.
Like I was saying, the
two cars come fluttering,
and two guys come up and dump
that poor bastard in the fish.
Then they leave so quick they
forgot one of their cars.
- Search him.
If you find a ring, arrest him.
- You cut off his damn
finger, you stupid old drunk.
- He wasn't using it.
- Take them both in.
[commentating in
foreign language]
- Good night.
- I'll ask you to take you home.
That is if you don't mind.
- That is nice of
you, but I'll manage.
[Maria sighs]
It wouldn't be too much trouble?
Where you from?
- California, San Francisco.
- It's cold.
You a friend of Al Romeros'?
- Not exactly.
- He's a nice guy, he's...
He was my husband's best friend.
That's the one, the brick.
- You wouldn't wanna
have a cup of coffee?
- No thanks.
- Sorry, I understand.
- What's your name?
- Paul. Paul Boles.
- Bye, Paul.
Your scarf.
- It's Allyson's scarf.
I hope she'll be
able to wear it.
- Why do you say that?
- She's been missing
for two weeks.
- Drugs?
I think I'll have
that cup of coffee,
I can't face going home.
[elegant piano music]
- [Paul] Maria, make
yourself at home.
- Is that her?
She's very pretty.
[leaves rustling]
[wind howling]
- Maria!
[elegant piano music continues]
- Have you been married long?
- No long, no.
- I was married six years.
We were planning to
have a baby next year.
We had waited.
We were both very busy working.
- Allyson was...
I hope to God she
still is pregnant.
- [Maria] How'd you meet her?
- We met in New Orleans.
I was doing a session,
and she comes in while
I'm doing a solo.
- When'd she get into drugs?
- I didn't know
anything about that.
You know, you see things.
How money disappears.
But I thought that
was all over long ago.
She said she wanted
to make a new start.
She said if I was strong
enough I could help her.
I guess I wasn't strong enough.
A couple of months
ago I had to go back
to the States to
see this guy I know
about doing the
music for a movie,
I was only gone
a couple of days,
but when I got back
it was different.
She'd met somebody.
- Do you mean another guy?
- Yeah. I mean, no.
Another girl.
They went everywhere together.
Got to the point where
we hardly saw each other.
So I asked her, "What
the hell was going on?"
She told me, nothing.
For a few weeks
it was fine again.
Like it used to be.
Then, after a while, she
started going out again.
Late at night, no explanation.
So one night I found some works
on the floor in the bathroom.
I was gonna scream at her,
tell her she was throwing
everything away for nothing.
I waited up all night long,
but she never came home.
She still hasn't come home.
- Paul, can I tell
you something?
I work for the antidrug unit
in the police department.
So did Al Romero and Carlos,
until they got transferred.
The thing is, we were working
on identifying the
high-level dealers.
Only, we had a lot of
trouble getting evidence.
Then came the transfers.
You see what I'm getting at?
- You mean the police
are in on this?
- Yeah. In on it or bought off.
- But the antidrug is a part
of the police, isn't it?
- Well, it's supposed
to be independent, but.
[Paul sighs]
- You can't trust anybody.
- Myself, Al, maybe one
or two others beyond that.
Can I make a phone call?
- Sure.
[phone dial whirring]
- Maria Mendoza speaking.
Yes.
Okay, thanks.
Fine.
I've got a few days off.
If there's anything
I can do for you,
please let me know.
- All right.
Can I take you home?
- Thanks, I'm really
feeling much better,
I'd like to walk a bit.
- All right.
- Maria, what can I do?
- Go to the U.S. Embassy,
bang on the table until
they do something.
- I already did.
They swear they're
doing all they can.
- Why don't you try
finding the girl?
- You mean Melissa?
- Yeah.
- But she wasn't
seeing her anymore.
- Are you sure?
[wind howling]
[downbeat saxophone music]
[moves to upbeat jazz music]
[moves to downbeat jazz music]
[horn honking]
[dogs barking]
[soft music]
- Aren't you ashamed
to be seen like that?
- Why should I be?
You are the first man
who ever saw me naked.
- I don't remember.
- How could you forget,
it was my birthday.
- Ah, but that's
not the same thing.
You we're fat, pink, ugly,
and you were screaming.
- [Lupita] Can I
have the sports car?
- You have the will? No.
- Why not?
- I made inquires.
No money, no education,
common family.
- Yeah, but it's a Valenti.
[hand slaps]
- Mind your mouth, young lady.
[soft music continues]
- Dad! Okay?
- Take the car, but be careful,
don't let that dummy
near the wheel.
- That nosy cop is
here to see you.
- I told you I didn't
want to see him.
- I spoke to the inspector,
it's just about the
report on the stolen car.
- Oh. I'll talk to him.
But it seems like you can't
live in this country anymore
without the government poking
its nose into your business.
[soft music continues]
- You're gonna take that
little jerk out for a spin?
- What is it to you, pussface?
- Officer.
- Early Mason, very
nice, very expensive.
- You're an art connoisseur?
- Actually, I don't
have much of a chance
to move in those circles.
- Police work must
be very difficult?
- [Al] You should see
some of the characters
we have to talk to.
- My assistant tells me
you're here on business.
- That's right, just routine.
It appears there'd
been some mistake
on your report,
on the stolen car.
- My secretary takes care
of this sort of thing.
What kind of a mistake?
- Your car was stolen
on February 3rd.
Is that right?
- I suppose so.
- No.
- Here you are getting
out of the stolen car
to go to the OMS party.
Do you remember that?
- I think so.
- The OMS party was
on February 4th.
- Quite right,
officer, there appears
to be an error in the date.
- Of course.
- My secretary will go to
bed without his supper.
- I'll release the car for you.
- Fine. Will that be all?
- One more thing.
[plastic rustling]
This.
No.
Is this yours?
- I don't believe so.
- Sure it is, sure.
See..
Here's the bill on the jewelers.
Expensive.
It will probably cost
more than the painting
- Of course, I
remember this ring now.
- Of course you will.
If you'll just sign
the receipt for it.
Read it. The description is-
- I trust our police department.
- You are very trustworthy.
Don't you wanna know
how we found it?
- Naturally.
- We found it,
reported by a drunk
who have cut a
finger off a corpse
with a jackknife to get it.
- Gruesome.
You do move in
different stories.
- You know whose?
- Who's what?
- Whose corpse?
It was a certain Flores Fuentes.
Did you know him?
- The name means nothing to me.
- Of course not.
You wouldn't know
anybody like that.
He was a cheap
gangster, a murder,
and a car thief, not your type.
- That's an interesting story.
Will that be all now?
- For the moment.
- Thank you very much for
all you've done, officer.
I'll send a check to the
Police Benevolent Association.
- You're a real nice guy, Don.
[soft music continues]
- How the hell did Flores
get his hands on this ring?
- Maybe you ought to ask Lupita.
- What would she know
about that creep?
[sighs] Encourageable little...
She reminds me of her mother.
- B14 to headquarters.
[radio hisses]
B14 to headquarters.
Let me speak to Badal.
[radio hisses]
- [Badal] Badal.
- I just saw him.
He's a nice guy, just like
you said, he was very polite.
He's even going to send
a check to the PBA,
isn't that great?
- [Badal] I told
you, he's a nice boy.
- He's one of the nicest
pricks I ever met.
[car engine roars]
[metal clanging]
[buttons clicking]
[fist thudding]
Is this the Marine Life
Conservation Group?
I like to speak to
Mr. Steve Brevin.
I'm calling long distance.
[phone rings]
- Brevin here.
- This is amigo.
Your were right.
- [Steve] Then you can help us?
- Carlos can't do much.
- Sorry.
Okay, I'll be down
in about three days,
in the meantime you
can get things rolling
with Operation Marine Life.
Got everything you need?
- I hope so.
- See you soon, amigo.
- [Al] See you later.
[phone thuds]
[knocking on door]
- Come in.
- Jeff.
- [Jeff] What's up, Steve?
- You got a minute?
- Yeah. Come on in.
- What's up, Steve?
- Well, I'm ready to
put Operation Marine
Life into action.
- Didn't you just lose an amigo?
- Yeah, unfortunately,
but now his partner
is ready to step in.
And that's the guy I
was telling you about.
- [Jeff] Oh, why don't you
give it a few days, Steve?
- A few days?
For God sakes, Jeff.
I mean, we're averaging
six OD's a day,
every day, in this
country alone.
- Steve, all I'm saying to you,
that if you'd like to-
- We're talkin'
about human lives.
And we can't just sit on
our butts and do nothin'.
And we gotta at least
try and put a stop to it.
- But, Steve, all I am saying-
- What's the matter, Jeff,
did you get another
phone call from upstairs?
I thought you were gonna
make those DA big shots
put up or shut up, back
'em up against the wall.
Always had a lot of
bureaucratic bullshit.
- Now listen, Steve, calm down.
Here.
- What's that?
- Take it.
- You're gonna need some
expenses, aren't you?
- Well it's a start, but uh,
[smirks] it won't be enough.
- [chuckles] It never is.
- You won't regret
it, Jeff. Thanks.
- And Steve, you'll remember,
I want Thomas
brought here alive.
I want to take a look
at this son of a bitch.
- You'll see him,
Jeff, warts and all.
[suspenseful music]
[chain clinking]
[suspenseful music continues]
- Melissa?
Melissa!
Anybody home?
[birds flutter]
Melissa!
- Get out of here
or I burn your face
off, you bastard!
- Excuse me, miss, I'm
looking for Melissa.
- Are you a friend of her?
- [Paul] Are you her mother?
- Grandmother!
- I'm a friend of
your granddaughter.
- Let you call yourself
a friend, you bastard!
You and the rest,
what have you done
with my granddaughter?
- Please, let me explain.
I'm looking for my wife,
and she was very
friendly with Melissa.
I thought she could
help me find her.
- You know?
You know what she did to me?
She hit to me, that's what.
Her own grandmother,
an old woman.
That's not her.
That's not my Melissa.
- Do you know where
I can find her?
- If she ever comes
back here, I kill her.
But she's too chicken,
they made her like that.
She wasn't chicken before.
- Who made her like that?
What are their names?
- The junkies of the
cemetery, that's who.
- Cemetery? What's
this cemetery?
- It's where they
bury dead people.
It's where the kids are.
And it's called The Cemetery.
- You want me to
tell her something?
- Yes.
Tell her I said,
"Go fuck yourself!"
[suspenseful music]
- Nice car, cop.
Nice car, cop.
- Look, I'm not a cop.
I'm looking for Melissa.
[kid with white hat speaking
in foreign language]
- He don't understand.
- [Paul] No.
Look, at least-
- Do we smiley to him?
- Give the a smiley to him!
- I just-
Come on, man, I just wanna
talk to Melissa, okay?
- Cops aren't welcome
here this often.
We got sort of an understanding.
- We got sort of
an understanding.
- Look, I told
you, I'm not a cop.
- You guys, you
don't understand.
He's just looking
for a little action.
- I just want to talk
to Melissa, that's all.
- He's no cop.
- Thank you.
- Cop or no cop, I think
we'll take you down.
- Take him down.
[kids chuckling]
- Go! Go there.
- No.
Come on, please, come on.
[kids chattering]
[growling]
- Let him go, he's
a friend of mine.
You two, fuck off.
- You're gonna give this
cop a freebie, Melissa?
- A freebie, Melissa.
- Come with me.
- Do you know where Alison is?
- Where she is?
- [Paul] She's been
missing for 17 days.
- I haven't seen her.
I thought she went straight.
I thought that
she went with you.
- When did you see her last?
- About three weeks ago.
She was with a guy,
her dealer, I think.
I was high, I don't remember.
- You're dying, Melissa.
- All our lives we're dying.
- Eh! Take it easy.
Who the hell do
you think you are?
- [Junkie] I'm right here,
cop, don't get smart.
[knocking on window]
Don't get smart, cop.
- You're right, you
don't understand.
[suspenseful music]
Do you know why we
call this The Dead Bus?
Because, one day, it was
driving some little kids
to school, no traffic, no rain,
and just like that,
for no reason,
it ran over into this turnover,
and all the little
kids go to heaven.
You know what they found out?
The driver didn't stop.
He was high, the
motherfucker. [sobbing]
And one of those little
kids was my own son.
The man was high, see?
[Melissa sighs]
[Melissa sobbing]
Come on, I take you
to Allyson place.
- [Paul] What do you
mean, Allyson's place?
- [Melissa] We
all have a coffin.
- [Paul] A coffin?
- A car.
It wasn't like her to show us.
Maybe she left something.
It's the best car.
Allyson has expensive taste.
[paper rustling]
- "At the night's end,
that's when my dreams become
too much [indistinct]."
[pole clanging]
[tense music]
Ugh!
Ugh! Allyson!
[Junkie barking]
[Paul retching]
- His name!
The dealer!
- No.
- Melissa, he killed her!
- Okay, I take you there.
[junkie barking]
- Hey.
Melissa!
You are fucking
crazy! Come back!
- You fucking better come back.
- Did you see what
they did to Allyson?
- She was fucking around!
- Fucking around!
[Junkie] Melissa,
you're fucking crazy.
Come back here.
[suspenseful music]
[engine roars]
[truck clanking]
- Uh, yes, uh, chief.
Yes, uh.
No, ballistics was very firm.
Seven shots, three
different guns.
I said three. Right.
It seem unlikely, it was
two guys who found the body.
Three guns, and only two guys.
- You mean one of
them had two guns
and found them both
at the same time.
Excuse me, chief, this was
a drunk and an old sailor.
- We have motive for theft.
One of the guns.
The knife they actually
used to cut off the finger.
We got opportunity.
They were with the body.
As for the guns, maybe there
was a third accomplice.
- [Badal] I suppose
it's possible.
- The evidence is
all there, Badal.
Now let the courts
do their duty.
- [Badal] But I can't consent.
- Detective, your consent
doesn't come in to it,
anymore than it did when you
committed statutory rape.
Now, I have done
all I can to keep
that quiet for
you, because I hate
to see a man's career
go down the drain
over some silly
misunderstanding.
But if you can't put
away two suspects
with all this evidence,
I'm wondering,
what could your career-
- Yeah, chief.
All right, I understand.
I stay in line.
- Badal, I can sympathize
with your attraction
for school girls, but you
don't have to act like one.
Look, I tell you what, why
don't we just forget about it?
Goodbye.
- Wait, don't hang up.
I think I see your logic.
I'll do the necessary.
- We got a tough job
ahead of us, Badal.
I know I can count on you
to help restore confidence,
to handle all the
attacks of the press,
even from their own minister.
We have all the hard problems.
Drugs, murder, rape.
- They have brought it
for you [indistinct]
- Drugs
- That's nice, you don't
have to worry about me.
[lips smacking]
- You want the car, or money?
- Yes.
- Both.
- [chuckles] I always
said I'm smart, daddy.
- Where are you going?
- Out with friends.
- What happened to
what's his name?
- What's his name was a jerk.
[car keys jingling]
[Lupita giggles]
- Ah, Lupita.
- Yes?
- May I talk to you
about something?
- Sure.
- You don't ever fool
around with drugs, do you?
- Drugs users are stupid little
people with no imagination.
- I'm relieved to hear you say.
- How can I do
something so stupid
when I have everything I want?
And a father who
loves me so much.
[people chattering]
[phone slams]
[sirens wailing]
- Nobody here?
- I'm here.
- I mean, no one else?
- Disturbances.
- Huh?
- At the demonstration.
I'm holding down the fort.
- Ah.
- I just sort of spoke
with the chief of police.
- I know.
- You know?
- You left the door open.
- You heard everything?
- [Al] Everything.
- Are you going to report me?
- To who? The chief of police?
- I'm ashamed of this, Al.
- Good for you.
- Say what you're thinking.
I'm correct, it's allowed.
- That's what I used to think.
Now I just think
you're an asshole.
- They got me by the balls.
- Everybody knows
about the girl, Badal.
And everyone knows
who raped who.
- She was a minor.
- She was a whore.
- Everyone knows.
- You're an idiot.
You're so busy trying
to save your arse,
you don't even notice when
they cut off your balls.
- I have got a wife.
Two kids.
- And what do the kids
think of their dad?
- What can I do?
- One, you don't
frame those guys
for a murder they didn't do.
And two, show up
tomorrow morning at
Maria Mendoza's house.
- What time?
[phone dial whirring]
- Maria. How are you holding up?
Our friend arrives tomorrow.
Can we meet at your house?
Okay. See you then.
10 o'clock.
I'll just be a minute.
Please take this.
[people chattering]
Please.
Please!
Mr. Paul Boles, please.
- Mr. Paul Boles has
just left, officer.
- Did he get my messages?
- If you left him a message,
I'm sure he would
have received it,
or we'll receive
it and carry it on.
- What kind of
crappy hotel is this?
- Please, officer.
He just came in a
few minutes ago,
but he went out
again right away.
He had a lady waiting
for him in the car.
I told him I had messages,
but he evidently didn't
want to keep her waiting.
- Did you get a
look at the lady?
- She was rather rough looking.
Bold hair, hot pants,
uh, like a tiger.
- Okay. Thanks.
- Patty, Patty, Patty something!
[upbeat jazz music]
[truck thuds]
- That's him.
- Are you sure?
- Of course.
Every night he's
whoring, fucking around
and marketing his shit in clubs.
Now he's going to
the Tobacco Garden.
They call him "The Cowboy."
- But you're sure?
- He's other name is Ilrosso.
I'm sure, I introduced
him to Allyson.
[upbeat music]
[Paul breathing heavily]
What are you doing with that?
- [breathing heavily]
What do you think?
- Paul! Wait!
What are you doing? Wait!
[car door slams]
[feelgood music]
[people chattering]
[feelgood music continues]
- Hey! Who are you?
- [inhales] I'm
Allyson's husband.
- Allyson who?
[knife thuds]
[drug dealer groans]
[people screaming]
[feelgood music continues]
[indistinct chattering]
[people screaming]
- He killed Cowboy
- Paul!
- [Male voice] Get him. Quick.
Get away.
[shoes stomping]
- Ugh!
- Take that, you fucker.
[fists thudding]
[shoes thudding]
- You motherfucker.
- Get him, bitch.
[indistinct chattering]
- [Male voice] Take that, bitch.
- Get him.
- Asshole.
- B14 to headquarters.
I need help in
Tobacco Gardens area.
[car engine roars]
- [Male voice] Leave my
brother alone, motherfucker.
[shoes thudding]
[indistinct chattering]
[junkies whistling]
- [Male voice] Come on.
[car engine roars]
[indistinct chattering]
- Police, got to move.
[gun fires]
- Melissa!
Melissa, what the fuck
is wrong with you?
- We all knew you.
- [indistinct].
Bitch!
- [Male voice] He
killed [indistinct].
- He killed The
Cowboy, I saw him.
- If he killed someone
I'll take car of it.
[engines roar]
[sirens wailing]
[handcuffs snap]
[feelgood music]
[sirens wailing]
[police speaking in
foreign language]
[tires screeching]
[police speaking in
foreign language]
[anxious music]
[engine revving]
- Melissa!
[indistinct shouting]
Stupid bitch, come back here.
Melissa!
Stop, fucking stop.
[indistinct shouting]
[bike engine revving]
Melissa! Come back!
[bike engine roars]
[Melissa screams]
[glass shattering]
- A couple of more
minutes with those guys,
I'd be scraping you
off the sidewalk.
- I might have been better off.
What are the prisons
like in this country?
- Hell.
They're like hell.
- Guess I'll know soon enough.
[keys jingle]
I don't understand.
- You will.
[handcuffs clinking]
- I Think that's him.
[door clicks]
- Come in.
I'm Maria Mendoza.
- Maria, pleasure.
- Hello, amigo.
- Hi, Al, good to see you.
- This is Paul Boles,
I told you about him.
- Ah.
Paul, how are you?
I understand to got yourself
a little scrape last night.
- I found the dead
body of my wife
in the trunk of a car.
I tracked down the drug
deal who killed her.
Slash his throat.
And got beat practically
to death by his goons
when they caught up with me.
- Uh, would anyone
want some coffee?
- Oh, yes. Thanks, Maria.
- Sit down.
- Is Inspector
Badal gonna join us?
- I hope so.
- It takes a lotta
guts to go through
with a decision like that.
We'd better start without him.
- [Al] He's basically a good-
- Al, we'll go without him.
Now, as you know, the
idea is to concentrate
on the three main targets.
I don't want anybody distracted
by some nickel
and dime bag type,
even though we have very
good personal reasons
to go after them.
Understood?
- So, there's Don Thomas,
the chief of the police,
and the bank guy,
what's his name?
- Luis Betancourt, president
of The Central Bank.
They call him Bleach, because
he leaves grimy drug money
smelling clean and fresh.
- You know, once we put
this plan into action,
there's no turnin' back.
I wanna be sure that you're
all in this to the end.
Have you got any doubts,
anybody wants out,
now's the time.
Maria?
- I'm in.
- Al?
- You know how I feel about it.
- Paul?
- I'll do whatever
you tell me, and
I'll die trying.
- Now, we've gotta act fast.
Romero and this Betancourt,
they're no problem.
But as to Don Thomas, he's mine.
I plan on taking him back alive.
- To the States?
[scoffs] You can just walk in
and take him out alive.
I mean, this guy's got more cops
and bodyguards than
President Bush.
- Yeah, I know.
But he's also got a daughter
he loves more than money.
A daughter I
understand that runs
around a lot without bodyguards.
Okay.
[door bell buzzes]
[gun snaps]
- I'm sorry I'm late.
I had something to take care of.
[gentle guitar music]
[female vocalizing]
[water sploshing]
- Wanna take a walk?
- If you want to.
[gentle guitar music continues]
[tense music]
My father didn't want me
to take the convertible,
I was pissed off.
But you know, it's nice.
In private.
[tense music continues]
- [Guy in car] What?
[pistol thuds]
[guy in car groans]
- One sound and I'll
blow your brains out.
[tense music continues]
[car door slams]
[car engine roars]
[gentle guitar music]
- There's a girl who
knows what she wants.
- What about you?
You know what you want?
- No!
[suspenseful music]
[phone rings]
- [sighs] What is it?
- [Chucho] I'm sorry
to disturb you,
but there's an urgent call.
- Are you crazy, it's
the middle of the night.
- [Chucho] It's
from your daughter.
[suspenseful music continues]
- She's not back yet?
- [Chucho] No, sir.
- Put the call through.
- [Male voice] Don Thomas?
- Yes.
- [Male voice] Lupita was
driving the sedan tonight.
- Who is this?
- [Male voice] If you
want to see her again,
you'll follow our orders.
- What orders?
- Calling back at noon.
Call the police if you like,
it won't make any difference.
[phone clicks]
- Chucho!
Chucho!
- May I help you, sir?
- Get Chucho in here now!
[ball clanging]
[elegant music]
[tape ripping]
- Did you wanna say something?
- Why don't you untie my hands,
I can do incredible
things with my hands.
- And what about your mouth?
- Yes, that too.
I can show you a good
time while we're waiting.
- That sounds very
exciting, Lupita.
- Ah, come on, untie my hands.
Anyway, my father won't let
me stay here too much longer.
- You know what, Lupita?
- What?
- Save it for someone
who appreciate you.
- Bastard!
- No, your father's the bastard.
That's why you're here.
But if you have to
go to the bathroom,
just bang your head against
the wall three times.
[elegant music continues]
[knocking on glass]
- It's time to call.
[ball whirrs]
- Thomas Radeck, please.
If you would like to see
your daughter alive again,
be at the opera house
tonight at 10 o'clock,
you'll receive
further instructions.
- Shoot.
[phone slams]
- It was too short,
I couldn't trace it.
- Fuck me.
Who could it be,
what do they want?
- We'll get them, we've
got the whole police force.
- Well, whoever they are,
they certainly knew
how to get to me.
- We have to see
the chief of police,
it's an emergency.
[people chattering]
- Sir.
- Captain Badal.
The police chief box.
- Box number three.
[dramatic music]
[singing in foreign language]
- What the hell
are you doing here,
I told you to watch the hall.
- Come on, go in the hall!
- Okay, sir.
[lighter clicking]
[dramatic music continues]
[singing in foreign language]
[fist thuds]
[dramatic music continues]
[singing in foreign language]
[hand smacks]
[people gasping]
[police chief screams]
[body thuds]
[people screaming]
[gun fires]
- Run for it!
[people screaming]
- Don't go out.
- I want to know
what's happening!
- Don Thomas.
They killed the chief of police.
He's knifed.
[paper rustling]
[tense music]
- "We weren't kidding.
We don't want
money, we want you.
Follow instructions you
will receive at dawn
or your daughter
comes back in pieces."
[tense music]
- [Paul] It's a little
strange, isn't it?
We're gonna kill someone
who we don't even know.
- Did you know The Cowboy?
- I don't know.
He reminds me of somebody.
- Look, this guy kills people
he doesn't know everyday.
Kids.
Without him all this drug
money would just be paper.
- My friend. They
killed my friend.
[indistinct mumbling]
He was such a nice guy.
- Come on.
- They killed my friend.
They killed my friend.
My friend. My friend.
My friend. What?
We are being followed.
- It's a police car.
- Hi, thanks for seeing us home.
- Don't mention it.
[guns firing]
[Betancourt groans]
[dog barking]
- Mendoza to headquarters.
Shot fired on Truhilio Avenue.
[gun fires]
[Betancourt groans]
[suspenseful jazz music]
- I never felt so powerless.
- We'll get them.
- We don't even
know who they are.
They competition?
Politics, maybe.
- [Chucho] We'll
know soon enough.
- Will you stop
talking like that!
My daughter's life is at stake.
If it's me they want,
it's me they'll get.
- You can't do that.
- You watch me.
[car engine roars]
[body thuds]
[tires screeching]
[suspenseful music continues]
- Another envelope.
[paper rustling]
- "We weren't kidding.
We have killed two
of your friends.
We want you.
Go to the phone
booth at Royan Square
with one man, no more.
Otherwise you daughter
gets an envelope."
- They're crazy, you
can't go through with it.
- Would you like
to come with me?
[birds chirping]
- Go peacefully.
[buttons clicking]
- Hello?
Yes.
I'd like to speak with
officer Al Romero, please.
Yes, it's Paul Boles calling.
[typewriter clicking]
- Al, there's a Mr.
Boles on line two.
- Again, Panchito.
Thanks, Vinny.
This is Al Romero.
How are you feeling, Mr. Boles?
- No, there's nothing new.
We're doing the best we can.
Okay. 10 o'clock would be best.
See you. Bye.
It was what's his name? Boles.
The guy with the
wife by the junkyard.
- Ah.
Yes, chief, yes.
We're doing everything
by the book.
What on earth do you want?
[suspenseful music]
- Without him we're finished,
we can't let him
go through with it.
Keep it safe, when the
car stops get ready.
The tracking signal's already
planted under the dashboard.
- Let's go.
What were you doing?
- [Chucho] My girlfriend.
- I didn't know you
had a girlfriend.
- I try to keep business
separate from my personal life.
- Intelligent.
- Okay, let's go.
[hands clap]
Now you all know
what we have to do.
[curtain thuds]
There are the weapons.
And I hope you don't
have to use 'em all.
- I hope we do need
all this stuff.
- Phone was ready?
- [Al] Ready.
- Okay, get her in, come on.
- [Mendoza] Is that
how you're planning
to get Don Thomas
back to the States?
- At least as far as
the Mexican border.
- What are the prisons
like in the States?
- Not too pleasant.
With any kinda luck at all,
he'll spend the rest
of his life in prison.
- Yeah, with any luck at all.
[suspenseful music continues]
- Lock it up.
- You all right?
- I was just thinking.
- About Carlos?
I was just thinking
about Allyson.
[suspenseful music continues]
- Let me go instead of you.
- No, Chucho, it wouldn't work.
- What could they want?
- I suppose they
want to kill me.
- They won't.
- Don't do anything foolish.
I could mean Lupita's life.
- Yeah, what about your life?
- Haven't you ever loved anyone?
What if it were your girlfriend?
What if it were her?
- Right.
[phone ringing]
- Yes.
- [Male voice] Take the small
radio receiver above the door.
[phone pings]
- [Lupita] Daddy. Daddy.
- [Male voice] Drive
to the Sierra Bridge.
You have two minutes.
[switch clicks]
[car engine roars]
- The Sierra Bridge.
[tense music]
- [Lupita] Daddy!
- Don Thomas.
You and your man
will leave the car
and walk slowly to the
middle of the bridge.
That's where the
exchange will take place.
Don't try anything foolish.
There's a rifle trained
on your daughter.
- Throw down your gun.
[tense music continues]
[gun thuds]
The little one too.
Do as they say.
[Chucho sighs]
[gun thuds]
- Oh come on.
[door clicks]
You sure you wanna
do this, inspector?
- It's a chance to see
an old friend of mine.
- Go ahead.
[tense music continues]
- I love you more than
I've ever loved anything.
- How much is that?
- I believe we've already met.
- I used to be you puppet.
- When I yell, start
running zigzag.
Now! Lupita!
[suspenseful music]
[Badal groans]
[gun fires]
[helicopter whirring]
[guns firing]
- Ow, shit!
- Come on.
[guns firing]
[seagulls squawking]
[suspenseful music continues]
[van door slams]
[car engine roars]
[grenade snaps]
[guns firing]
[rifle snaps]
[explosion thunders]
- Got him!
- God no! God! [sobbing]
[crying] I don't wanna die!
No, no, I don't wanna die!
- Thank you, Chucho.
I owe you my life.
[Lupita sobs]
- What do we do now?
- We start over.
Figure out a new plan.
- How? We got nothing.
- Let's try to take him now.
We got nothing to lose.
We've got guns, and
they have a harder time
to get things back in order.
- He's right.
- We got a plan with nothing?
- With our balls.
- Yeah, with our balls.
- What do we got to lose?
It just might work.
Let's go, come on.
[suspenseful music]
[van engine roars]
[dog barking]
- [Guard 1] Hey, what's
that truck doing over there?
- [Guard 2] Get outta here.
- [Guard 1] You can't stay here.
- [Guard 2] What's going on?
[dog barking]
Get outta here.
[explosion thunders]
[guns firing]
[dog barking]
[explosion thunders]
[guns firing]
- Stop!
[suspenseful music continues]
- Don Thomas!
You're under arrest.
I'm taking you back
to the United States,
where you'll stand trail before
the American Court of Justice.
[suspenseful music continues]
[handcuffs snap]
- Move.
[gun fires]
- [Lupita] No!
[somber music]
[body thuds]
- This is our justice.
[somber music continues]
[downbeat jazz music]
[Lupita sobbing]