I was just in the neighborhood.
I thought I'd drop off your trousers.
They're ready.
Here.
Just a moment.
Come in.
Straight on.
Perfect.
For the length, perhaps I need...
a different pair of sandals.
I always wear my trousers with a belt.
Then they fit better.
I'll be right back. - Okay.
CLOUD 9
Werner?
How much, a lot or a little? - In between.
The speech wasn't great, was it?
I can't understand a word.
It wasn't a very good speech.
He was just a cemetery orator.
Yes.
And now I'm the last of the old staff.
But we still have each other.
Dance with me into the morning,
Dance as our happiness grows,
Here in your arms just a-dreaming,
Sweet music dispels our sorrows.
May I ask for this tango tonight, my dear,
Said a gentleman later to her.
He was quicker and took her away from here.
Hi. - Hello.
I'd like to speak to Mrs. Lindner.
I have a jacket too. It might need some altering.
Inge, it's for you.
Yes?
Good afternoon.
Hello.
I have this jacket. It needs a small alteration.
I don't do alterations any more. - It can't be very much work.
No, it's not possible. It's not possible.
I can understand if it's an inconvenient moment.
Could I come back later?
No.
I'm afraid not.
Goodbye.
What was the problem.
Nothing.
Why?
Since when don't you do alterations?
It's all a bit much at the moment.
If you're sending people away, you should take down that notice.
I'm going to read for a bit.
Yes.
What?
Yes, but...
Sunday...
I've got the grandchildren.
I'm telling you right now, I'm not coming.
No, I don't want this any more.
Sunday at 10. Yes, I heard you.
If you want to wait,
that's your problem.
I'm not...
No, I don't want to.
Not at all. I've got to go now. Bye.
The balls aren't very good.
They look fine. You've done a fine job.
Do you think so?
"Steep incline" means it's going up a mountain.
You can hear it working.
Shall I show you my favorite engine?
This one. - Yes, that's a fine engine.
Have you ever heard one like this?
No? - That's this one? - Yes.
Thanks, Momma.
Take care.
Bye, Werner. Have a nice evening. - You too.
Bye, and thanks a lot.
See you the day after tomorrow?
Okay, get moving.
Let's go.
Bye, my darlings.
Front helper engine 02-0201
and engine 01-2204, pulling a special train
of the GDR Model Rail Association.
through Ottendorf station.
Engine 02...
If I ever end up like my father, you can shoot me in the woods.
Sure you don't want to come?
He's your son.
See you tomorrow. Bye.
Have a nice trip. – Enjoy your Sunday.
Say hello to the sea for me.
Oh, you lovely rose garden,
Oh, you lovely laurel bouquet,
Ever are you within my heart
Never will you get away.
Father, mother won't bear our love.
Yes, my dear, you know it's true.
Tell me the appointed hour,
When I ought to come to you.
I have stayed with you so often,
Lost in wonder, half the night,
All sleep forgotten, in love...
Here.
Your tea.
My, you're sweating.
God, what on earth have you caught?
Huh, little dear? - Thanks.
I've got two hours.
My beauty.
It doesn't matter.
I'm sorry. - No.
Don't worry.
Actually...
Do you know how80-year-olds screw?
What?
She stands on her head,
and he lowers it in from above.
That's a good one.
Funny.
For the future.
How old are you anyway? - Me?
Seventy-six.
We've still got four years.
Thanks.
Enjoy it. Bon appetit. - Thanks.
I'll wait a bit. It's still hot.
Do you know how 80-year-olds screw?
She stands on her head, and he lowers it in.
Is that the kind of thing you tell each other in the choir?
The choir?
Incredible.
I wanted to tell you that I love you very much.
Karl,
I can't talk longer.
Good night.
See you soon.
Everything okay?
I can't stop thinking of Werner.
What are you doing tomorrow?
At rain ride.
Where to?
I don't know. Werner always decides.
He loves train rides.
Just for fun?
With no destination?
Yes, it's nice.
Sitting by the window,
with the countryside flying by.
It's lovely.
I prefer bike rides.
Through nature. Or I walk.
I have to...
to touch and smell everything.
That's my thing.
But train rides are nice too.
Just look at this guy.
No living creature can become as large and as old
as a tree.
The countryside along the train lines.
is much prettier than along the freeways.
But now we're here.
Together. - Yes.
For you this isn't a problem.
For me this is no problem at all.
...the soldiers can die during their overseas deployment.
One feels for them, and has a sense of responsibility
for the political decision taken.
And so, I may say...
You dropped all your ash in the pretzel sticks.
That's disgusting.
...in 2004 you were asked
how you would console a woman whose husband had died in service.
Eighteen soldiers have already died in Afghanistan.
And you replied: "It's no consolation,
but he died a meaningful death."
Do you still think this? - Yes, I'm convinced of it.
Well, I don't think there should be soldiers any more.
If a man wants to be a soldier,
he should have to ask his mother to sign her permission.
And if she doesn't,
the man shouldn't be allowed to become a soldier.
Globally.
...but I'm still convinced it's right for us to intervene.
We are still defending Germany, even in the Hindu Kush.
Look at the trees.
The countryside by the train lines.
is much prettier than by the freeways.
What's the matter.
It's so pretty.
Really?
Yes. - Seriously?
Yes.
Really.
Good grief, this is...
This is news.
I told myself it just couldn't be happening.
Momma! - I was immediately...
I had these instant butterflies in my stomach.
But that's just...
I mean...
Momma. - I'm always...
I long for him constantly.
I can't do this, not like this.
Why not? - It's wonderful, but I can't...
I can't be in the apartment
as if nothing had happened.
What year are you living in?
No, I can't just pretend... - Yes, you can.
You can see him.
But you have to...
Nobody except us...
...should know? - No way.
Momma, this is wonderful.
Enjoy it. Just enjoy it.
We won't tell anyone.
Thanks.
With nice puckered lips.
Perfect. Now mezzo forte.
Right!
Now back.
Hold, hold.
Hold.
And down.
Oh, man. - Up.
Down.
Say that again.
Yes, it's true.
I'm sorry.
Have you lost your marbles?
How long has it been going on?
A few weeks.
I'm really sorry, I tell you.
Stop your blubbering!
I don't want to cry, but it's so sad.
It isn't as if I don't care for you any more.
But it just... It just happened.
I didn't want it.
I hoped it would pass.
Stop moaning.
I'm so sorry.
Get lost!
If only I hadn't told you.
This isn't solving anything.
So what do you think I should do?
Congratulate you?
Got yourself a younger guy, huh?
He fucks better than me, or what?
I don't think it's right to say...
I helped to raise your kids. "Now you can get lost."
What's going on in your mind?
If you want to leave, I understand. - Oh, you want me to leave you.
Who "fell in love," me or you?
Me, but... - But?
There must be a reason.
Of course there is.
You live for the moment.
I always thought you were so wonderfully naive.
What's that supposed to mean?
You don't think about things.
You just live for the moment.
Really? - Yes.
So that's how you see me. - Yes.
You're not acting very intelligently.
That's interesting. - Yes.
You're being stupid.
It's for you to decide.
Not me.
That's what I'm doing. -Well, do it.
After living together for so long
we should be able to talk to each other
if something like this happens.
I'm going to the garden.
Have fun.
Are you staying home today? - I don't know.
Will you come over later? - No!
Come on, listen. - Get lost!
Listen...
Just leave me alone.
I really am sorry.
Please go.
I said go.
Leave me alone.
Bye.
Normally, I ought to be happy now.
You can always come to me.
If you want to.
Perhaps I'm already too old for this sort of thing.
I always hoped I'd fall in love again properly.
But I stopped expecting it.
Perhaps we should go away somewhere.
Where?
Some place you like.
Where have you been?
That's my business.
Were you with your guy?
Do you intend to make this place your second home?
What's wrong with you? -What's wrong with me?
Are you drunk? - I'm not drunk.
It sure looks like it.
I want to know where you were.
It doesn't concern you. It's my business.
Your business.
You fuck him all day and all evening,
and then come back here to rest.
You're behaving like a child. Have you gone senile, or what?
Don't touch me, stop.
Are you crazy?
If anyone's crazy here it's you. - Let me go.
Stop hitting me.
I'm not hitting you. But I want to know what's going on.
What's going on? I told you.
Aren't you ashamed, at your age?
Inge, I don't have much time left.
Neither do l. Just because I'm over sixty,
I have to sit here in the dumps for twenty years?
What's my age got to do with it?
It doesn't matter if I'm 16 or 60... or 80.
It does matter.
Perhaps, but at the moment that's the way I feel.
I wish this hadn't happened to me.
But it has, so what should I do?
And me?
Should I sit on my chair with my legs crossed?
Watching you carrying on?
That's so mean, what you're saying.
I'm not "carrying on."
It's an awful situation for me.
We've been together for 30 years.
What do you think you're doing?
You've got to decide for once.
You've got to think about what you're doing.
Stop being such a silly brat.
That's just so mean.
Why accuse me of being a silly brat
just because I feel something different?
That's no argument.
Perhaps not.
But you're only thinking about yourself.
That's not true at all.
Do you think this isn't painful for me?
But I can't change the fact that it's happening.
And all you can do is lay into me.
What's the point of that?
Werner, tell me.
If one of us can change what's happening, it's you not me.
I feel...
Let's get some sleep and talk about it again tomorrow.
We'll just go round in circles.
How can you make such a mess?
I can't help you.
But let's not be nasty to one another.
I'm so sorry.
Werner?
Hi.
Morning, it's Momma.
I just wanted to ask if Werner called you?
No, I just wanted...
I'll ring you again later.
No, get the kids ready first.
I'll call you later.
Talk to you later.
Was it necessary, Momma?
Yes.
My God, poor Werner.
What were you thinking?
What do you mean, "poor Werner"?
You wanted to keep it to yourself.
That's what we agreed.
I want to tell the truth, so I can look Werner in the eye.
It wasn't possible any more. What do you think I should do?
Be with another man, arrange to see him,
And lie through my teeth to Werner? – Exactly that.
At least that way you wouldn't cause so much pain.
You're putting the family in jeopardy.
I'm sorry, I can't.
You're like a stranger.
Sorry, but...
You're so hard.
Yes, it's strange when someone puts herself first suddenly.
I can see that. It was never an issue.
Whether I had any personal dreams, desires or whatever.
That was never an issue.
But you could fall on your face. -Yes, I know.
But still... I'm coming in five minutes.
Five more minutes. Go and play out back.
Sorry.
Surely I can have a chat with Grandma for five minutes.
Think it over, Momma. Please.
You just can't do this to Werner.
We're in a fine mess now.
This is just what I wanted to avoid.
What a mess.
Let's get some coffee.
Yes.
Scoff at worldly destiny.
Three things they have shown me today:
How from this life to gain insight,
How to smoke, sleep, waste it away,
How to give it threefold spite,
How to give it threefold spite.
The gypsies lingered in my gaze,
As I traveled on my ways.
Wardrobe.
I've already cleared out my stuff.
And the writing desk can hold a lot.
This has got to go.
It doesn't belong here.
You sleep there,
and I'll get set up in here.
So you can gather your wits.
I've made something to eat.
Join me? - Yes.
As a welcome.
Are you happy?
Yes.
I'm seventy-six.
At my age, you don't know how long you've got left.
Why are you doing this?
It's only worth it for the things you never had.
She's my daughter.
I don't suppose you expect anything but contempt from me.
...but as of Wednesday there is another number:
The child-protection hotline...
...unstable, with heavy rain...
Three, two, one, zero!
We're sailing over the lake.
We're sailing over the...
With a big wooden root stick.
With a big wooden root stick, and no oar.
Could you take off my watch?
Thanks.
We can even still sing together.
When did we do that for the first time?
My God!
Petra was still very little.
Yes.
The same age as Laura now. - Right.
Do you remember carrying her through the sunflower field?
Yes.
She was so small. She couldn't see over the tops.
She was crying, and you put her on your shoulders,
piggy-back.
She was thrilled.
At that moment you won her heart. That's when you became her dad.
I'll be off.
What were you thinking of exactly,
bringing my trousers round to the apartment?
I wanted to see you again.
I liked you.
You did?
The first time you came to our place
with your trousers, for a fitting,
you kept giving me the eye.
Well, you were certainly taking the measure of... things.
I thought:
He seems to fancy you.
What, you noticed?
Do you always do that?
A woman knocks at your door, and you throw her onto the carpet.
Always.
I love sleeping with you.
And I love sleeping with you.
Whoever has been fortunate
to find a friend indeed,
He who has won a lovely maid,
Join our cheering company.
Yes, he who just one soul can call
his own, his own upon the earth.
But he who never could at all,
weeping from our throng go forth.
Werner, I think it's better if we separate.
I'll look for my own place at first.
I'm just fetching a few things.
What we do with the furniture...
We can discuss that later.
Would you like a drink?
I'll open a bottle of wine.
I was often surprised these last few weeks.
You sometimes looked like a young girl.
Now I know why.
I didn't want this.
It just happened.
What did I do wrong?
You didn't do anything wrong.
Otherwise we couldn't have lived together for 30 years.
Perhaps everything has its time.
I would never have thought
this could still happen to us.
Perhaps you'll forgive me some day.
Danneberg.
Yes, I'm Karl.
Yes.
Hold on.
Just a moment.
Inge,
it's your daughter.
Petra?
Hello.
Yes, what?
What's wrong?
Is it...?
What?
No, it can't be true.
Sorry.
What?
No.
Inge.
Werner, he's...
I didn't want this.
It can't be true.
It's my fault.
Come on, Momma.
Subtitles: alias film & sprach transfer Berlin