My grandmother Kaku used to tell me
me stories again and again,
handed down by our ancestors about
the Chindi,
which is a Navajo word for spirit.
But in contrast to Casper, the
the Chindi was one that could not be tamed,
all-consuming evil power that exacted revenge
for the injustice done to our people.
Well, cheers then.
Serves them right.
First they seize
the land under their nails,
and then they don't even give anything away.
Only a dead Injun is a
a good Injun, right?
Cheers!
How the hell would you know that?
You weren't out there with us.
What?
What we did,
was not completely housebroken.
It's a shame that the elders weren't
were with us from the beginning
and saw the boy.
He was really something.
But what's done is done.
Amen, Captain. Well said.
Who is that?
What...
I don't know what you are,
but you haven't seen
seen the last of me.
CLOWN MOTEL
WELCOME TO THE WORLD FAMOUS CLOWN MOTEL
OFFICE
Feet.
Yes,.
You know, Ana, I
admire your small church community.
Somehow you manage to
to stay alive again and again.
We have to, Mr. Wilson.
We were here before you came
and are still here,
when you are gone again.
First of all
I have no intention of leaving.
You cannot
imagine how many offers
I have already received for this motel.
I knocked them all out.
Why didn't your people
did not make an offer
when I wanted to buy the store?
We were not considered white enough
to be allowed to make an offer.
Well.
That's the way it is.
But I can promise you one thing.
If I ever sell the motel
sell the motel, I will make sure,
that the person who buys it also knows
which staff belong to it
and how valuable you people are.
Are you implying something?
that you would not let us
would let us make you an offer?
No, nothing like that.
I just can't imagine
that your bell bag is big enough,
to buy this property.
What do you know about the size of
of our bell bag, Mr. Wilson!
Ana, take it easy.
You don't want to attack
attack your boss on the same day
and be fired,
the day your visitor arrives, right?
Alma is here?
I didn't even know
that you had children, Ana.
You never asked for it
asked for it, Mr. Wilson.
I had been away for far too long.
I had to go back to where
where I had grown up and do,
what I could to expose the
uncover the atrocities,
committed against my Greasewood ancestors
were committed.
Bloody hell!
Now I finally know what the
Clown Motel challenge is all about.
And it looks that way,
I won't get much sleep tonight
not get much sleep tonight.
Hey! Hey Joe!
Well, good to see,
that the members of Kaku's
sect have aged quite well.
Joe Bamford,
grumpy as ever,
and the clothes should
and the clothes could be washed again.
Alma,
since your childhood
nothing has changed.
Well, maybe apart from the job.
But the clowns,
they are still here.
It's new.
A remarkable collection.
Yes,
only much bigger,
since I was a child.
That was probably a long time
before I bought the motel.
The last time I was here, I was eight
I was eight, around fifteen years ago.
I have a few minutes now,
if you want to have the conversation,
that you have asked me for.
Yes.
Good.
The house looks smaller.
In fifteen years, they have probably
have also grown quite a bit.
I can't remember the wall
there. And the door, is it new?
You have a good eye, Miss Perez.
A few years ago we
a few years ago.
Behind the wall we have
we laid some pipes
and put a small extension there.
So you're here to do research for a
research for a college paper, yes?
Yes, exactly.
Is it something economic?
It's for my final thesis.
Cultural Anthropology.
My final thesis
in cultural anthropology
deals with the
Greasewood Indians.
The Greasewood Indians.
Is that a North American
Indian tribe?
A tribe of North American
Native Americans, yes.
You have never heard of
heard of the Greasewoods?
No, but I don't know
history either.
Well, that seems pretty obvious.
Do you know what this
this is, Mr. Wilson?
A creepy clown skull.
This stone carving is
not a creepy clown skull,
but a death totem.
It is said to ward off evil spirits.
For my studies they are
extremely difficult to find,
and you have several
of them in your collection.
Wow.
Are they perhaps even valuable?
Mr. Wilson,
Surely you think you know
know everything about your motel.
But these horror stories
you tell in your brochures
and your website,
are surely on the one
or another way, right?
Yes,
There are eyewitnesses.
Tragic deaths have
have occurred in these rooms.
And all the time
an evil clown lurks somewhere nearby.
What I would like to know from you is,
what was on this site before
the Clown Motel was built.
Sure.
I'll tell you what I know.
- Coffee?
- No, thank you very much.
I see that you are marketing the cemetery
and mining facilities on your website
as tourist destinations and write,
that in the 1900s
miners lived here.
Yes, that's right.
They actually did.
But if you know more, I am
I am very interested, because I am
always on the lookout for new
ghost stories for my website.
Horror sells.
I'm talking about what was here in
Tonapa was in the 1800s.
Back then it was still called Butler City.
There was this massacre.
And the Greasewoods were built
to build the railroad here,
killed or driven away.
There is no railroad nearby.
That's exactly how it is.
And that's why I'm trying
to bring light into the darkness.
Okay. I'm all ears.
The reason why no
railroad was built...
Sit down.
...is that those who
committed the massacre,
were massacred themselves.
Right here.
My research has revealed
that this place used to be called Butler City.
Founded by Wyatt Earp,
who passed through here.
Wyatt Earp?
What do you say?
Do you have proof of this?
Only legends and legends that are
passed down through generations.
But I'm looking for evidence,
for documents, articles, for
artifacts and records.
And this is where you can help me.
There is a cellar
under this building.
I often played in it as a child.
And I remember that there was a box down there
box with all these documents.
Do you know anything about
about this box, Mr. Wilson?
No, because the cellar was
already sealed at the time
when I bought the motel.
The building authorities claimed that
it was structurally unstable
and would not comply with
building regulations, and well...
Well, if I could get access to that box with
the documents inside,
that would be a great enrichment
for my research work.
And if these documents
have historical significance,
can I notify the Historical Registrar
and notify this place
into a Greasewood memorial
into a Greasewood memorial.
But what happens to my motel then?
Well, I suppose the government
would make you an offer
and reclaim the land.
Reclaim the land.
It's a very good thing that you
you're not studying economics, Miss Perez,
because that was the worst
business meeting,
I was ever allowed to lead to
access to my cellar.
What possible
reason I should have,
To let them go into my cellar,
if I would lose my
would lose my country?
Well, possibly,
because it is the only right thing to do.
Regardless of this, the
anyone, no matter who,
into the cellar.
It is simply unsafe,
because it is in danger of collapsing.
They could shut me down,
if I break the rules.
I'm really sorry.
So that was it, the cellar,
what you wanted to talk to me about?
If yes,
we have probably ticked off the topic.
I wish I could
help you, but I can't.
I don't know if you're planning
to go over to the cemetery,
to make a few sketches or something.
The gravestones there
are quite remarkable.
I'm not sure if this
this meets archaeological standards
corresponds to the university,
but the kids like to use it,
when they go there.
So,
I have to get back to work now
get back to work.
Here come a few executives
of the biggest bank in the area
to a stag party,
in about 15 minutes or so.
That sounds like fat profiteers from the
of the land that was stolen from my people.
I cannot and will not
not contradict it.
Here, please take this.
I would like to give it to you,
because it means
much more to you than it does to me.
You also know, Alma, that the work you do here is important,
that the work you do here is important.
Do not let obstacles
obstacles.
There will be many more of these in your
many more in your life.
Very good advice, Mr.
Wilson. Accepted with thanks.
Yes!
- What the hell...
- Stay calm.
- Holy shit!
- Well?
I know that may not look
may not look like much,
But that's the whole point.
We give Louis a
a fitting farewell,
and this is the perfect place to
to bury a few secrets.
- Isn't that right, Mr. Arturo?
- That's right.
But you can say that out loud.
Well, there are certainly
a lot of things to bury.
And knowing Sloan,
he buries his entire
last bonus at the gaming table.
- No, not this time.
- You say that now.
Well, me and Brooke are going to
dry out every bar in the area.
- You said it, baby.
- What about Louis here?
After all, his wedding is coming up.
Sometimes his head is stuck
between the tits of a stripper.
As befits a banker.
Yes, we are good bankers. That's why
we deserve a good time.
Yes.
Are you sure that
it's safe here?
He booked the trip through a
church congregation.
So as far as I'm concerned,
we are blessed.
Nobody gets into difficulties today,
that they can't overcome. Is that clear?
So then, first we check in
divide the rooms between us,
grab something to eat and then
we'll turn this place upside down.
- This is how we do it.
- I'll take a room with Carrie.
Mike, you're with Sloan,
and Louis gets a room
for you alone, just in case,
that he might have
should have company tonight.
Yeah!
That's not going to happen.
I am faithful. Nothing will happen.
What are you doing here?
So you've already been here at the motel.
Are you spying on me, Kaku?
Please, Toko, the book
was lying there when I came in.
Of course.
This is a forgotten popular belief.
I didn't know that the
book was still in print.
It won't. It belonged to mom.
Correct.
Why do you torture yourself with
all these myths?
The Chindi spirits.
Your whole sect is
named after a Chindi.
That was long before my time.
I don't like it any more than you do.
But it is history.
And history is
dark and depressing,
unless you are white.
Mr. Wilson told me
why you're here.
It was very unpleasant for him
to find out.
It was also very depressing for me.
I'm doing this for us, Kaku.
For your sect,
for our family, for our people.
For all of us,
that are still left.
When your mother left with you
I stayed here.
Our church is here.
This is still our home, and
you have no right to take it away from us.
Do you really think they would
build a memorial in this motel
and leave us our place?
We are dealing with the US government.
They don't build memorials for us.
They build them for themselves.
That's cynical, Kaku
Cynical is the word of a young
for older and wiser, Toko.
You should write a book about our people
or a documentary.
Or put us on a TV show,
that would make me very proud.
But this memorial idea?
This is a hopeless endeavor.
Kaku is afraid of change.
This is due to the insularity of a
religious fringe group like theirs.
Kaku believes she is leading the group,
and no one can dissuade them.
Our church community has
tried to stop the vengeful Chindi
from his murderous retribution
on this city.
Only we, the Greasewood descendants,
can put an end to the killing.
This sabre is the last
part that we have to carry out
of the sacred ritual in order to
banish the Chindi for good.
It must be done.
Evil must disappear.
Kaku, I need to talk to you.
Please don't make a scene.
What have you got yourself into now?
Have I lost my way?
What have you gotten yourself into with
your sect got yourself into?
Into your room. Now.
Kaku, how could you?
How could I what, Toko?
Your sect has made the booking
for the bankers,
who took the piss out of you.
Watch your tongue.
That's how I earn my money.
We wanted our money back, and that
was the only way to get it.
Our agency books the rooms, and
Mr. Wilson gives us a commission.
It's as simple as that.
There are other possibilities
in the world than just this motel.
I don't understand you, Kaku.
And I don't understand you. You are
just as stubborn as your mother.
I am punished with a
daughter who doesn't listen,
and a granddaughter,
who is following in her footsteps.
Yes.
Because she wanted justice.
True, lasting
Justice for our ancestors.
You can help me with that. I just want
I just want you to let me into the cellar.
Absolutely not.
Then at least let me
in Clem Wilson's office.
Maybe I can find something there.
What you need to find,
Alma, is the way to the church.
Drop the matter, and I
will do what your mother failed to do.
I will teach you our
history
and introduce you to Chindi.
Do you actually listen to yourself?
You are employed by a completely
unscrupulous man,
who takes you like a
Christmas goose.
Why are you protecting this motel,
if you can make this place a
a consecrated place?
We are the last of the Greasewood.
The name of this motel may
belong to someone else,
but the land and its
spirit have always belonged to us.
Let it go.
It would be the best thing,
when you've checked out,
before I come back tomorrow.
Even better,
you are already leaving today.
BALD WIEDER DA
The old trick still works.
The Clown Motel seems to be
to be quite popular.
What do you say?
WELCOME
Shit.
You only dance with me.
I have finally
into the cellar.
Compared to the past
nothing has changed here.
I'm surprised Clem Wilson
hasn't made his way down here yet,
to find a few exhibits
for his website.
But
everything is still there,
after all these years.
Just as I remember it.
"The doctors said I had
typhoid. But what do they know?
I know it was because of the Greasewood.
So I can in my right mind
confess to the crime,
that I have committed, in the hope
that the elders will forgive me,
although they have every right
to condemn me
and send me into the fires
of hell.
Our deceptive maneuver was simple.
We lured the two tribal elders
of the Greasewood tribe into the saloon,
to negotiate their land for the construction
of the railroad.
Captain Cranston, who had set up a unit similar to the Pinkertons
unit similar to the Pinkertons,
was hired to secure the
acquisition of the land."
"A financial settlement should be
compensation should be negotiated,
and the elders came in good faith.
I was just there as a distraction,
while Cranston's men
murdered the entire tribe,
including the two elders,
when they returned."
"I found out that the
younger of the two eldest,
who was killed was not the one
was the one who came into the saloon later.
He moved like a shadow
and slaughtered the men
in the most cruel way."
"At the end
he went after the captain."
"Unfortunately, I wanted to
the dignity of the captain
and pulled the sabre away."
"Its hideous mouth spat fire
fire, and it had the appearance of it,
as if it wanted to devour me."
"I pointed Cranston's gun at him,
and he just laughed maniacally.
Before he supernaturally
disappeared,
he kept repeating the words:
Bai ja pei, Bai ja pei,
Bai ja pei, Bai ja pei."
Hey, she's down in the basement.
I'm coming as fast as I can.
The sabre is ready.
It's happening tonight.
And ready?
Beauty takes time.
Then we'll be sitting here
here all night.
This is the stuff
that nightmares are made of.
Let's go! The ladies are waiting.
Perfect!
Let's go!
Feet!
Hey boss.
Just don't think I don't know about
your little conspiracy.
- Conspiracy?
- Yes.
You always take the bookings for
these bachelor parties,
when I'm working the night shift here.
- Are you going to church?
- Yes, sir.
For the bell bag.
- Thanks, boss.
- Okay, no thanks.
Do not worry.
I won't. Good night, Joe.
Good night.
Hello?
Johnson, do you ever sleep?
I told you, I'm not selling.
I'm not interested in whether
he has Chinese backers.
If I don't sell,
then I don't sell.
So, please uncover.
He's out, and...
Full on the twelve.
Mike Hardy, ladies and gentlemen,
remember the name.
- So here you go.
- Thank you beauty.
- With pleasure.
- And this one is for you.
Thank you, that is really
very thoughtful of you.
- Gladly.
- And the inserts.
And one for mom,
one for dad.
Oh yes.
All set, yes? Map?
Yes.
Split.
Not bad.
Lucky guy.
And over.
Yes!
Downright disgusting.
How you try to buy a good time with your
buy a good time with your dirty money.
Excuse me?
I don't apologize for anything.
These cut-throat
of bankers. All the same.
Give me a break.
We just want to have fun here.
Keep your mouth shut before
something slips in.
Just like my fist.
Keep your mouth shut before
something I have slips into yours.
- Could you please repeat that.
- What problem do you have?
- Leave it alone. Sit down again.
- Come on, baby, it's no use.
Because of you bankers
lost my business partner.
Granted him loans,
even though you knew
that he cannot repay them.
And then, as expected, when he defaulted
you fell all over him
and have not only ruined his
his business,
but also his
private property.
In the end, he died on the
from heart failure.
That is my problem.
That's enough. Get out of here!
Brooke, sit down, it's no good.
And you, sir, stand back.
What I think
you don't have to tell me!
Hey, take it easy!
Taking someone to the grave and
then dance around on his grave,
that still turns you on, doesn't it?
Very nice, away with
him. Well done. Bye!
I'll look after your chips.
What an asshole, man.
I'm very sorry.
That was totally out of character for me.
I don't know whether it's nerves
or I'm just getting cold feet.
It's funny because, as you can
as you can see, I love my girl.
You know, she knows that I love her,
and you know that I love her too.
So, to cut a long story short, we met
met a year ago.
Online, okay. Now it feels
feels like we're rushing it.
An example: I like ice cream, but
I don't know what her favorite ice cream is.
I'm sorry that I was so
I threw up on you so awkwardly,
but it just had to come out.
Besides, I've already had
five of these drinks.
I think it's very sweet.
It is very sexy when a man
is willing to commit to a woman.
Enjoy your drink.
And how I will enjoy it.
It's what she wanted.
That's where it's going, my friend.
Silence!
Oh boy, am I tired.
The party goes on, folks.
I've just dusted off a round of
of coke from the bartender.
Oh no, man, I haven't done that shit
I haven't done since,
since I started
I've been cramming for my exams.
But then it's high time
time. To you or to us?
I'd rather see you,
Mike doesn't seem to be in a good mood.
That and coke don't mix well
don't mix well, as I know.
Yes.
Fucking city, damn it!
Come on, big guy.
I'll show you what your
future wife doesn't show you.
That's what I should do.
Forgive me.
Shit.
What the...
"Out of the corner of my eye, I kept seeing
shadows moving again and again.
They instilled fear in me and
I couldn't do anything about it.
As if that could have protected me,
I pointed Cranston's guns at him,
to keep him in check.
I kept the captain's sabre and
pistol and also his protective totem."
This is Joe's box.
That doesn't exist.
It has begun.
Carrie, why have you been
all this time?
You know that, my darling.
Men.
Oh, really? Men are like mice.
Afraid of a woman's body.
Carrie?
Guys, this isn't fun anymore.
Unlock the damn door, okay?
Carrie?
Carrie!
Sloan.
Say something, boys!
What the hell!
And who are you supposed to be?
Oh, now I understand.
You're part of that whole
Clown Motel bla bla bla stuff, right?
Well, you should really
do something for your hair.
Fuck off! Fuck you.
You can do this.
Damn it, you can do it!
Nicky, I didn't wake you up, did I?
It's already past midnight.
Why are you calling me so late?
Oh, come on,
It's not that late after all.
When did you get so old?
Since I have children,
Michael. What do you want?
I'm here on a
men's evening in Tonapa.
Louis celebrates his
fucking bachelor party.
Our Louis is finally getting married.
You know who he is, don't you?
Mike, I have to interrupt you here.
I know what it's all about,
and you can't expect anything from me.
That's not the point.
And even if that were the case
I wouldn't need much.
And if at all,
maybe only two grand.
I don't have them.
So don't ask any more questions.
I'm not asking you to.
You know very well,
that I'm good for two grand.
Look, you give me two, and
and I'll give you two and a half in return.
You're about to wake Jen up, so...
No, you can't just
like that. Don't leave me in the lurch.
Nicky, just a small transfer,
just to keep me flush.
I've got nothing, Mike.
And even if I did, Jen would kill me
if I gave it to you.
And I can't even blame her for that.
Your fucking bank screwed me.
Or have you already forgotten that?
- I'm hanging up now. Good night.
- No, Nicky! Nicky, don't hang up!
Shit!
Stay calm.
Carrie can give you some
money, or Brooke.
Yes, it will work out.
Oh man, I'm going to tell them a
story about the horse
and pick up every hundred.
Except for Louis, well.
Yes. Three hundred.
Three hundred should be enough.
What do you think, handsome?
What the hell is that?
No, no, no.
No, no!
Do you know what
will happen next?
Honestly, I have no idea,
what will happen next.
I'm only used to one woman
and have never been in a situation like this.
Oh my God, I'll probably
I'll probably end up in hell next.
How can you be so sexy?
I've never had vanilla before.
- No?
- No.
Then enjoy it.
Oh boy.
You know, if you add
a little something on top,
I'll let you believe in all the
superpowers I have.
I don't doubt that for a moment.
Hey!
You don't have
a fucking heart attack?
Our Chindi
has taken care of our problems.
Who remains now,
is the one who deceived us,
for his shameless selfishness.
Who is trying to claim our heritage.
But the Chindi takes care of it.
Betrayal of our own bloodline.
Theft from our own clan.
Until the end of the night,
Yes, until the end of the night,
this motel will have a new
new owner.
What are you doing here?
Count the totems.
Nothing has changed.
Then the Chindi is still hunting.
I wonder if the murder took place there?
Where all the blood spatter is?
I don't believe it.
What do you think, Chief?
Doesn't look good at all.
- Let's take a closer look.
- Let's do it.
So all of this makes
no goddamn sense to me.
Oh really? Don't you have such
cases in Long Island?
I thought you had already
seen pretty much everything there.
We have too. But this
here is something completely different.
It happens here every few years.
The craziest deaths,
you can imagine.
Maybe there is
some kind of ghost is up to mischief,
On the other hand, it could also be
that the drinking water here is contaminated.
I've been doing this job
for around twelve years now,
and the most unusual
crimes always happen here.
There must be a logical
explanation for this.
Logical? The guy on the bed
was slashed from back to front.
His ribs were split open,
as if it were hunting season.
Not to mention
of the fact that the mattress,
on which he was lying is completely undamaged
apart from the bloodstains.
Maybe he cut himself with
cut himself with his razor.
The victim is said to have accomplished the superhuman
feat,
to fillet your own body with
with a razor?
Before or after
he scalped himself?
That's nonsense.
Apart from that, what about the
other three bodies we found,
one of whom looked
as if her face had been boiled?
I won't be able to sleep tonight
not be able to sleep tonight.
What about the owner of the motel?
Has anyone spoken to him yet?
Yes, he is being looked after.
These deaths are too
cruel, bizarre and too fast.
This will be another one of those
unsolved trap, like all the others.
That doesn't make your work
not pleasant either.
The same applies to everyone else here.
It's called the curse of the Clown Motel.
- That's simply unbelievable.
- Yes, I know.
I've never heard of anything like it.
Everything is so strange, I can't even
even describe one of the cases exactly.
- It is absolutely incomprehensible to me.
- Do I understand correctly that...
Mr. Wilson?
Mr. Wilson,
Was there any reason to believe
that one of the men was violent?
No, they were just bankers.
They seemed quite normal to me.
On the other hand, you never know,
when an angel mutates into a devil.
I don't know what got into them.
We saw a parked
parked car outside.
A dark station wagon built in 2014.
We have checked it out.
It belongs to an Alma Perez.
Is this a relative
of your employee Ana Perez?
Ana is
Miss Perez's grandmother.
Ana was at an event last night
event organized by her church,
and Alma is somehow
disappeared.
Disappeared?
I haven't the faintest idea,
where. If I knew, I would say so.
I'm sure there are a lot of things
that you need to take care of now.
We will now leave you in peace.
All the best.
Johnson?
Clem Wilson.
Do you still have the guy
who wants to buy the motel?
Tell him it's his.
One dollar.
No, I'm not taking the piss.
Draw up the contract.
Our people and our tribal area
deserve so much more
than this run-down motel.
Our people deserve
justice towards them,
who took advantage of us
then and now.
That is why the Chindi
must never be stopped.
Someone must continue the fight
for our ancestors.
Perhaps something
stopped him. Is that possible?
How are you supposed to stop a
Chindi, Ana? How?
Out!
Toko?