Anna,
this isn't the first time
I've addressed you this way.
In 2014,
I told you
about a film I wanted to make,
as brief and clear as a gesture.
I made it,
but, in the end,
it was long and complicated.
The film was dedicated to you.
I know you haven't seen it.
That doesn't matter.
You turned 18 this year,
more or less the age of the characters.
A year that we spent in lockdown,
on hold, forced to reflect on our lives.
The present has come to a halt,
leaving us the past and the future.
We think once more
about all our experiences
and all we have been through.
What we have built,
our successes and failures.
What we have acquired
and what we have lost.
About those we have lost.
Those who have died
and those who are missing.
Our vanished loves.
The felling of loss is dreadful
because it is incomprehensible.
Yet, at the same time,
it is magnificent in its depth.
In this lockdown,
silence would have been nice.
Everyone has something to say,
but what can we really do?
A gesture, probably.
The strongest,
the craziest,
the most violent, the most beautiful.
Like love.
But we can't always
imagine this gesture.
So we start dreaming of films again.
That makes you think about time,
about the perception
of things over time.
Take your time.
Do nut surrender to the current mood.
That will be your liberty.
And I repeat to you, as seven years ago,
that even if winter is long and harsh,
spring always returns.
And that's why we keep going.
Because there's always a rebirth.
NOCTURAMA, which was dedicated to you,
may have seemed full of despair,
but it too
carried this rebirth within it.
This new film
is my own little gesture today.
A gesture towards you, my love.
This will be my sorrow
and I must bear it alone.
I hug you in my
Hello and welcome to my channel,
Patricia Coma's channel.
A channel to help you live better.
Living better means living longer.
Living longer means
a better chance of understanding things.
As the Romanian philosopher Cioran said:
"It's no use killing oneself
As one always does it too late."
Music, please.
The weather with Patricia Coma
I don't know where you live,
but you do.
Look at the map behind me.
Find your home
and you'll know the weather tomorrow.
If you live in northern France,
it will be about 48°C in the afternoon.
If you live in Nice, like me,
it will be 61°C.
You can't go out anyway,
so never mind.
Hi, Tess, I'm busy now.
Can I call you later?
OK, bye.
(Gilles Deleuze)
The dream that people have
is always a devouring dream
that threatens to engulf us.
The fact that others dream
is very dangerous.
A dream is an overwhelming desire
for power.
And each one of us is more or less
the victim of others' dreaming,
even the most graceful young girl's.
The most graceful young girl can
be a voracious ghoul.
Not through her soul,
but through her dreams.
Beware of other's dreaming
because if you're caught in it,
you're finished.
Never get caught in another's dream.
I need to be honest
and tell you something.
Tell me what?
It's hard to say this.
I don't know how.
It's about Scott.
He had and accident?
No, he's fine, but you won't like it.
I don't understand. What is this?
I'm sorry to have to tell you.
Stop, you're worrying me.
What's wrong?
The other evening,
I saw him kiss another woman.
What?
No.
It's true.
Who was it?
It doesn't matter.
We don't care who she was, ok.
He's cheating on you.
I find it hard to believe,
coming from you.
Sharon, I'd never have made up
such a thing.
No, but it suits you.
You come here accusing him,
Yet won't say who she is.
I saw them, I didn't imagine it.
He cheated on you. I came to tell you
because I worry about you.
I weighed the pros and cons all night.
But I felt you had a right to the truth.
Is knowing the truth a good thing?
Frankly, I'm not so sure.
It can be better to suffer one hour
than every hour.
I don't know.
What would you do in my shoes?
Hello and welcome to my channel.
Patricia Coma's channel,
A channel to help you live better.
I'll talk now about something
I especially cherish:
the Revelator.
It's a small square device
with four luminous pads.
One red, one blue, one green
and one yellow.
It's a game.
The rules are simple:
Just repeat the colour sequence
that appears and vanishes
by pressing
the pads that have just lit up.
Most people find it useful
as it exercises the memory.
And it can be played alone,
an advantage today.
As it's easy at first,
that encourages you to continue.
Win.
On continuing, you realize
even if you're distracted,
even if you're not sure,
You're never mistaken.
Win.
You can't be caught out.
You feel almost invincible.
You self-confidence is boundless.
Then you'll wonder
what is really happening.
You can't get it wrong
even if you want to.
How is that possible?
To prove you aren't winning by chance,
you try to force a mistake.
But it can't be done.
You always press the right colour.
At that point, you begin to have doubts.
Not in yourself, as you keep winning,
but in the fact that the Revelator
is simply showing
you don't control your choices
and free will doesn't exist.
Don't be afraid.
Look.
I'm not afraid,
with a thousand reasons to be,
a thousand decisions to make.
What will I do about Scott?
Leaving him terrifies me.
So I force myself not to be afraid.
I try my hardest.
I control myself
What are you going to do?
What are you going do?
I don't know.
I love Scott.
Maybe I should turn a blind eye.
And suffer in silence?
I could never leave him.
It would be too painful.
A world collapsing.
Do you think he's really in love
or is it just a fling?
-I don't know.
I can't leave him.
I think he would kill me.
Even telling him seems impossible.
It can be better to suffer one hour
than every hour.
I don't know.
What would you do in my shoes?
The Revelator is simply proving to you
you don't control your choices
and free will doesn't exist.
How's it going?
I'm fine.
-I had a really weird dream.
-Shit, so did I.
-What was it?
-You first.
-No, go on.
I was in the wood, I was walking...
Never get caught in another's dream.
I know I'm here for you German class,
but I got swamped.
I've taken on too many things,
but I don't want to give any up.
But I have one quality.
I can do two things at once:
Answer my fans' questions
and give you a German lesson.
Daphné from Toulouse asks me,
"How can we reach limbo?"
The first way to reach limbo
is to pile up enough levels,
to sink deeper into the spirit,
in order to attain a state
where only the raw subconscious remains,
disconnected from reality.
Patrcia,
I have an important question for you.
But it's a personal one.
Could you possibly answer me in private?
I am currently
full of doubt and anxiety, and
-Ready?
-Yes.
Go on.
Win.
-You see.
-Try it again.
Win.
You're the devil.
I've thought it over.
I'll talk to Scott.
-You'll leave him?
Winning's sole interest
lies in losing.
You want to lose, at least once.
But you can't
First, you feel disappointment.
Playing isn't fun.
Then anxiety.You want to stop playing.
Then emptiness.
You want nothing anymore
The only question that interests you is:
"How is it possible?"
The first possibility,
if you win each time,
is simply that the colour combination
offered by the Revelator
matches your thought pattern
as you play.
Each sequence
is a phototherapeutic transcription
of your association of ideas.
You simply follow your thoughts
and so win,
as they're yours.
The second possibility is that,
without realizing,
you're under hypnosis.
Hypnosis is a way to attain limbo,
to allow your brain to reach a level
that you cannot control.
You're able to do things
you could not do normally.
Patricia?
-Are you lost?
-Yes.
Let's go that way.
It's dangerous here.
What's your name?
What are you doing here?
I don't know.
What do you usually do?
I pass the time doing nothing much.
Do you have friends?
Yes, but we rarely see each other.
How do you feel?
I'm a bit scared.
Then again, there are reasons to be,
with terrorism,
ecology, the economy.
The future is scary.
Obviously, but I've always known that.
You live with it.
That's true.
What did you want to ask in private?
I wanted to know...
I don't know...
It's something personal... about love...
But I don't dare ask.
Ask me when you feel ready.
-Bought a Revelator?
-Yes.
Don't be afraid.
Bought from my channel?
I dunno.
No one but me sells them.
Know how it works?
Yes.
This is the one place it won't work.
The only one.
It's a bit like...
a place out of time.
We call it the Free Zone.
But you can play anywhere else.
But what's the games goal?
Patricia?
Win.
Be it
a thought transcription or hypnosis,
you are not free to choose.
Most people who buy a Revelator
stop choosing.
Some of them even come down
With catatonia.
They gaze at what happens,
but aren't part of the world.
They can be,
but don't want to be..
I'd like a romance
that no one judges.
That no one talks about,
that no one sees.
Other people's gaze is so toxic.
Yeah, I understand,
but it may not be possible.
I need a romance that no one judges
Not even me.
Revelator, barely used.
Set a starting price
and let bidders compete.
A hot soup
with vegetables that stay raw.
That may seem odd or absurd,
Unfeasible, inconsequential, futile...
However,
it's not odd, it's a life skill.
Nor absurd as it's meaningful.
Nor inconsequential
as I preserves vitamins,
And surely not futile.
as we touch the vegetable's heart.
The Crudimix exists,
here it is.
It heats raw food
with its power and its beauty.
It produces hot soups
with vegetables that stay raw.
We shall talk about production
in a coming tutorial.
However, no one can tell if the Crudimix
could grind up a human hand.
For a hand cannot fit
through the Crudimix's top.
Next week, the deeper meaning
of Michael Jackson's songs.
What we took for paedophilia
is in fact philanthropy.
As his song says:
"We are the world,
we are the children.
We are the ones to make a brighter day,
so let's start giving."
Scott, where were you?
-I was at the office.
-This late?
What are you imagining, Sharon?
I don't lie. You know I love you.
I'm sure there's another woman
in your life.
Sharon, you're the only one.
I saw you look at Barbara.
Don't lie.
I'm not lying.
In fact, I was thinking,
Robert Pattinson
should ditch Kristen Stewart.
She'll cheat on him again.
He can find better.
A doll cannot lose heart.
Only a conscious being can.
I could lose heart, not her.
We could say that deciding
to stop choosing
Shows we can still do so.
But it's not true.
Every form of behaviour
is compatible with determinism.
Why and how do things occur?
That's the profound question
that we spend our lives
trying to answer.
And we shall soon talk about production.
For now, we'll listen
To a Neapolitan singer,
born in Piedmont.
Even if he has a moustache, long hair
and resembles a soccer player,
he is able to sing
definitive things like:
"You are a woman, I am a man
You loved me,
You loved me."
I'll say it again:
every form of behaviour
is compatible with determinism.
(Andrea Laszlo De Simone)
-A volte
Perdo parti di me
Rimango cosi solo
In stati di abbandono
E a volte
(La mente è debole)
Io non sono in me
(E a volte forte come alberi)
Perdo la lucidità
(Dà frutti l'anima)
E non so più chi sono
(E il corpo muore per mangiarti)
Sono solo un uomo
Robert Pattinson
should ditch Kristen Stewart,
She'll cheat on him again.
He can find better.
-Scott, where were you?
I've gone from tycoon to TV star
to US president on my first run.
I'm not just smart, I'm a genius
a very stable genius.
This late?
You're hiding something, Scott.
Kim Jong-un called me old,
but I never called him short and fat.
I want to be his friend,
And perhaps will be.
I'm sure there's another woman
in your life.
Kim Jong-un says the nuclear button
is on his desk.
Can someone in his feeble regime
tell him
my button is bigger, more powerful
and works?
Io non sono in me
(Che cadono come niente)
Perdo la lucidità
(L'istinto è un vento forte)
E non so più chi sono
(Un lupo combattente)
Sono solo
I saw you look at Barbara.
Don't lie.
The Chinese invented global warming
to make American labour uncompetitive.
It's cold and snowy in New York,
we need global warming.
Ma sono solo un uomo
Sorry, losers, my IQ is record-breaking
and you know it.
Don't beat yourself up.
It's not your fault.
I'm going to eat your soul.
Puke it up and eat it again.
I don't understand.
I'm going to eat your soul.
Puke it up and eat it again.
(Bonnie Banane)
-Such osmosis
Such harmony
Such symbiosis
Such irony
Such osmosis
Such harmony
Such mise en scène
Eternal mise en abyme
I watch the scene
I immerse myself in it
I observe this cascade of hair
As it's being combed
Who are the servants?
Who holds the reins?
Will some disturb
Our bodies as they bathe?
Such Osmosis
Such Harmony
Such mise en scène
Eternal mise en abyme
Add a little of this oil...
-Is that you?
-Yeah.
-It's brilliant.
-You said it.
I never know how I get here.
How I leave.
No one does.
It's as if there were trapped souls
that can't find the door..
While others move freely.
Here you can do so much.
You can produce so much.
But me...
What can I produce?
I don't know. You'll see
what you can bring.
(L'osmose)
What is the reason for it?
What is the cause of it?
(L'osmose)
A whole load of things
Production, what is it?
In Latin,
productio means to extend or bring forth,
But if you present evidence
at a trial,
you produce it.
It's also the act of engendering,
of giving birth.
It's a phenomenon found in nature
and also in society.
Karl Marx founds
his understanding of man on it.
Perhaps love is also
an extension of production
by other means.
A business deal above all.
A masterpiece of industrial influence
over romantic life and reproduction
to create prototypes:
your children.
Lives born of French fiction.
Today production in the noble sense
has a poor reputation.
Look at Jeff Bezos.
They say he sold his soul
to the devil,
but he just invents things.
Starting from a garage,
look where he is now.
His latest challenge: becoming immortal.
Immortality is a fine project.
Thanks to my channel,
you many not become immortal,
but you will live better.
For me, this world is evil,
and the evil within me comes from that.
I was born with the devil in me.
I was obliged to kill,
just as a poet is obliged to write.
Satan stood next to my crib
and has been with me since.
I was born to be possessed by demons.
How does it work specifically?
Specifically?
It's always the same,
and always different.
If I think of the last one...
She hitched a ride,
we talked a little in the car...
I looked at her.
And, the thing is,
that girl didn't even look human.
All I could see her as
was a store dummy.
She looked like an Apple phone.
She kept saying words that weren't hers.
Words that everyone says.
As if she were begging
to be looked at or heard.
So I pulled out a knife.
Then she was begging to live.
To go on living.
I got sick of listening to her,
so I stabbed her.
How did that feel?
I'd like some water.
Thank you.
You look into their eyes.
You feel the breath leave their body.
And, right then, believe me
you're God.
And after?
After, I went home.
I felt pretty good.
Good enough to eat pears, for instance.
Are you gonna hurt me?
-No.
-But you've often lied, right?
That's true.
You're totally indifferent.
Even psychopaths have emotions.
Well, maybe not.
Satan dwells in each one of us.
I reject
the hypocritical and moralistic dogma
of this so-called civilized society.
I don't need to hear those views.
I've heard them enough.
They make me sick.
Maybe you're just very paranoid.
-May I ask you something?
-Of course.
-It's a real question.
-I'm listening.
If I'm beheaded,
do you think I could hear,
even briefly,
the blood gushing from my neck?
The ultimate pleasure
to end all pleasure.
I don't know.
Maybe.
But very briefly.
That's something.
-I don't understand.
-Even psychopaths have emotions.
Well, maybe not.
Maybe you don't understand me
or simply can't.
-Scott...
-If I'm beheaded,
could I hear, even briefly,
the blood gushing from my neck?
The ultimate pleasure
to end all pleasure.
I don't understand!
I'm going to eat your soul.
Puke it up and eat it again.
Puke it up and eat it again!
Ted Bundy.
Charles Manson's out.
He never Killed.
-Edmund Kemper.
-Kemper's not bad.
-I like the cannibal.
-The Jap?
No, the German one.
The one with a 4-year-old girl
cut up in his fridge.
There were bits in the fridge,
a hand cooking in a pan
and even intestines jammed in the bin.
I don't know him. Gross.
I forget his name.
For me. Donald Harvey is the best
I find his story so touching.
No, it's Ted Bunny, hands down.
Plus he's a hunk.
Ok, but Donald Harvey killed
to ease his victims' pain.
That's beautiful, he said once,
"I'm the angel of death.",
That's beautiful.
The angel of death is Charles Cullen.
- There can be two.
- I'm sure.
-You're sure?
-I heard a story
about a woman
whose arm really hurt
because of injuries from burns
or something...
She was begging for someone to kill her.
So he killed her.
It's really beautiful.
Edmund Kemper's last victim
was his mother.
He beheaded her, put her head
on a shelf and used it as a dartboard
- Respect
- That's horrible.
Plus he was exceptionally gifted
with an IQ of 250.
-250?
-150, 150!
Chill.
Ted Bundy, returned to crime scenes
to bang his victims as long as he could.
Until animals ate them.
-Horrible.
-I think he said:
"I'm the coldest son of a bitch
you ever met."
-Ouh yeah!
You're all fans of the stars.
I think I'm touched more
by serial killers who stay unknown.
- True.
- They remain unknown.
They touch me the most.
- You don't seem touched.
- Looking at me?
With Zoom, no one knows
who's watching who.
It's wild. Looking at me, Tess?
Yes, I'm looking at you.
-Tess, I'm looking.
-Who am I looking at?
Ok, cut it out now.
Tess? The book?
I have the book.
Awesome.
No.
"How to be top dog
without being a bitch?"
It's a handbook?
-How to show character?
-I guess so.
Like how to be self-confident,
Bold and all that without...
-Without getting an attitude.
What's being a bitch?
I don't want to be vulgar...
It means what it says.
...
"A girl's superficial
relationships result from her
inner superficiality."
If your relationships are superficial,
you're superficial inside.
It's how you are.
Superficial relations don't make
you superficial. It's meaningless.
Why are we obliged to be superficial?
Start by asking that.
"A girl is superficial..."
Nice.
"Seduction never ends for a girl,
the girl ends with seduction."
-That's really sad.
-It's depressing.
-She lives for seduction?
-Horrible.
Who's this girl anyway?
It's us.
I didn't under it as a girl,
I though it meant
a citizen in society.
Why say girl if they don't mean a girl?
The citizen ends when their seduction...
-It's Greek to me.
-Who's behind you, Tess?
-No one.
-Are you sure?
Who sees someone being me?
The stress...
"A girl isn't meant
To understand you.
Understand us?
Understand what?
As the girl,
we can't understand ourselves?
Our parents?
So we never understand ourselves.
We don't know ourselves.
We don't understand ourselves
or others.
"The girl is a viewpoint on passing
time, but a viewpoint incarnated...
-Euh...
What happened?
Tess?
-Has she gone?
-Tess?
Act as if your decisions mattered.
Never mind reality.
Our survival
depends on our capacity
for lying to ourselves.
Any news of Tess?
None at all.
-Spooky.
-Spooky, yeah.
-Totally spooky.
The curfew...
Shit, I'm sick of this lockdown.
I'll go mad. I wanna kill someone,
blow stuff up.
Chill. Chill, babe.
We're in it together, we'll make it.
We're sure to.
Sharon seems suspicious.
I can't go on much longer.
But I'm not sure
What I feel for Barbara.
Do I love one,
the other or both.
I think I'm lost, Ashley.
Sorry I can't focus
On what you're saying.
I have problems too.
The curfew...
Shit, I'm sick of this lockdown.
I'll go mad.
I wanna kill someone,
Blow stuff up.
Chill, Ashley.
We're all in the same shit.
Screw others.
I have to do something.
Something has to happen.
I beg you, Scott. Fuck me.
-Shit, I'm your brother.
-Screw that.
I need to do something
That feels good.
Please, fuck me.
Ok, but even if winter
Is long and harsh,
spring always returns.
Screw that. This is winter.
I know what I say will not change
your behavior or your decisions.
But I'll say it anyway.
Maybe because I have no choice either.
But perhaps I do it too
to feel less lonely.
I can't see you.
I don't know you.
But I know you're there.
Even if there aren't
many subscribers yet.
Maybe there isn't even one for now.
But I know it will increase.
That it will work.
Shit, Scott,
you'll make me cum.
Why is your climate today?
My climate?
Yes, your internal weather.
The shock is too great
for me to figure out how I feel.
I can't think,
I feel anaesthetized,
I'm like a zombie
Maybe you could decide
to do differently?
Yes, but now I know it's no use.
A draw will determine
access to a vaccine.
Only 15% of the world's population
can be vaccinated.
Go on.
The draw will eliminate countries
rather than people.
With 7.8 billion people
it would be unmanageable.
But 197 countries are manageable.
I can't think clearly about my life.
I'd like to find the words, but I can't
I feel divided.
You know, a break-up
is a paroxysm of false phrases.
Phrases established before the break-up.
Our relationship
is a power struggle now.
-That's good. It's good
-I don't know...
I can't think clearly about my life.
I could never say anything conclusive.
There's no subject of dispute,
There are just desires for dispute.
Australia has been eliminated.
But it's not much use
as the population is only 25 million.
I don't know.
I can't think clearly about my life.
I could never say anything conclusive.
Confusion is a luxury only the very
young can afford.
And you're not so young.
Brazil is eliminated.
With 210 million, that's better.
I can't think clearly about my life.
Maturity isn't a matter of age
but of working on..
Africa is eliminated,
That's good as the population
is 1.216 billion.
We're progressing.
Ah.
France has just been eliminated.
I could never say anything conclusive.
Sometimes, girls rewrite history
to avoid feeling shame,
depriving themselves of depth.
-I don't understand.
-Think of yourself.
Solely of yourself.
-But...
Others?
You pay me, not others.
-What can I do?
-Be selfish
Later, confront what you've done.
Face it.
Yes, but it's painful and hard
Facing things.
It takes time from life's pleasures.
Sharon...
Yes?
The transference is working.
-I don't know.
-It is.
I'm doing a transference onto you.
I see you as my daughter.
Are you sure that's a good thing?
Yes. It's a very good thing,
believe me.
Now, imagine you're in a forest,
alone, at night,
and tell me what you feel.
Patricia?
Patricia, are you there?
Patricia, I'm going this way, ok?
Tess?
Shit, it's good to see you.
I'm really pleased.
Me too. I was worried
We all were.
It was horrific.
-What was? What happened?
-It was horrific.
Tell me.
Why are you in the Free Zone?
What's that?
Here. It's a place. I don't really know.
I can't get out of this fucking place.
How did you get here?
-I don't know,
I come in and out somehow.
What happened on Zoom?
A guy got into my place.
He came into my room.
Yeah, I know. We all saw him.
I didn't.
He was behind me.
He grabbed me by my neck.
I couldn't move or cry out.
He tried to strip me.
I kept hitting him,
so he began beating me.
He started tearing my clothes,
hitting me harder and harder.
He tried to rape me.
I hit him,
but he held my neck and my arms.
At one point, I kicked the wardrobe
and we fell back.
He let go of my neck,
and, staggering back
I fell six floors from the window.
That's how I died.
By falling six floors.
What are you doing here, Tess?
You should ask yourself
what you're doing here.
Tell me what's wrong, Sharon, please.
It can't be because of what I said.
I wasn't myself.
I spoke those words,
But it wasn't me saying them.
I don't give a damn about Barbara.
It's true. Believe me.
It's not that.
I don't give a damn
about that slut Barbara.
-So What's wrong?
-Scott...
I had a horrible dream.
And I think it was real.
That everything in the dream is true.
What did you dream?
I was alone in a forest at night.
Totally lost.
I didn't know where to go.
It got darker and darker.
As I went it deeper,
I began to meet people.
People I knew.
Well, people I had known.
Because they were all dead.
I met everyone who had died around me.
My father...
My brother...
I met them all in that forest.
-You spoke to them?
-Yes.
What did you say?
I asked questions, mainly to my brother.
Did he answer?
He said he was always watching me.
That he had seen me crying,
Limping and living in the belief
that injury should guide us.
He told me to stop seeing his death
as a mystery I had to solve.
It was a dream, Scott, but a true dream.
The forest exists. I was really there.
I'm sorry, Sharon. So sorry for you.
Did that scare you?
No, it enlightened me.
Good.
You know, one day, men will look back
and say I gave birth
to the 21st century.
No, the 21st century is mine.
You can't steal it.
So how did it enlighten you?
About what to do. I'm leaving.
We aren't fee to choose here,
it's scientifically proven.
-Where will you go?
Somewhere free will exists
Even if I confront my fears.
I'll confront them and it'll be fine.
Do you feel you're renouncing
something by doing that?
I know I'll hurt people,
They won't understand
and blame themselves,
say it's their fault.
I hope they 'll understand.
I won't be dead, just everywhere.
You're probably right.
Tutta
La volontà
D'un tratto se ne va
Di fronte all'ovvietà
Tutto questo
E immensità
E lavorare per 10 ore
Compiere sempre scelte di cuore
Chiedere scusa
I understand her so well.
If only I could leave too.
I'm not brave enough.
Sometimes, it can be braver to stay.
I miss her.
I have nothing special to say today.
Nothing to teach you
or to share with you.
Some days are like that
You have to accept them.
I don't know who I am anymore!
Screw this soap opera after 40 years!
Three people have played me!
Sharon, did you really buy a Revelator?
Am I played by Heidi Stone,
Monica Roberts,
or Sharon Potter?
Is it a sign that a Sharon
was the last to play Sharon Williams?
A sign I'm really her?
Tell me. I'm losing my mind!
And I'm accused of murder too,
accused of Jess' murder!
Do you realize?
Maybe it'll all work out.
I want to go away, Scott.
I want to leave you.
You want us to split up?
I gave you my most beautiful years.
Have you had other years?
Forgive me.
I hope the scars I leave you
won't make you forget
the power of my feelings for you.
Have you had other dreams?
You really want to know?
Yes.
Eagles don't fly with pigeons.
I know what you'll say.
What can you expect of my modernity
when all that awaits your is survival?
I simply say: take what you can.
I give you all I can.
I promise.
I give you all I...
The weather with Patricia Coma
We have to regain trust.
I feel better today
and I hope you do too.
So, the weather.
I don't know where you live,
but you do.
Look at the map behind me,
find your home
and you'll know the weather tomorrow.
If you're in northern France,
it will be around 57°C
In the afternoon.
If you live in Nice, like me,
It'll be 71°C.
You can't go out anyway,
so never mind.
Hello and welcome to my channel,
Patricia Coma's channel.
A channel that will teach you
to live better.
Coma comes from the Greek, kōma,
which means "deep sleep".
In Latin caumare,
which means "to rest in great heat"
And chômage, "unemployment".
Dad?
Dad, is that you?
Hello, dear.
-Patricia.
-It's good to see you.
Do you have your Revelator?
No, I left it.
-It doesn't work here, right?
-No, it doesn't.
But can I do what I want here?
Yes. Here, you can be yourself.
No one will judge you.
-It's really scary.
-Yes, that's true.
Why sell things and go to a place
where they don't work?
I'm like everyone else.
I have to make a living
and I need somewhere to be free.
Why doesn't it work here?
Because here isn't like in real life.
It's a sort of...
halfway station.
Like an intermediary state.
A hazy state.
-But you...
Are you still alive?
Do you know what "limbo" means?
Anna,
there's no world before
and no world after,
as we have so often heard.
But there's you in the world
and that's what matters.
We need to think that our sacrifices
will be rewarded
by access to another reality.
That the negative
will be purifying in a way.
That the worst thing would be
that it's all no use.
We are passing through a period
that is between life and death,
between day and night.
A sort of day for night effect,
but without a director.
"If you pass through hell, do not stop."
Limbo,
is not just between two worlds,
between dream and reality.
It comes from limbus,
meaning "the margin",
a blank space waiting to be filled.
In the centre, there is no space.
It is in limbo that you'll see
things impossible to see elsewhere.
That others will not see.
In this time of darkest night
in which we are sinking
ever more deeply,
there can be clarity
as vast as the obscurity.
One is so alone there,
one becomes oneself.
And that is the moment
when one attains poetry,
that which we shall need
when a new day dawns.
Because a new day will soon dawn.
A new day will soon dawn, my love,
and you will emerge from limbo
with a strength that you cannot imagine.
And I shall be near you,
or rather behind you,
watching you unleash it.
That will be the start of another story.
A story that belongs only to you.