Hi Pete.
- Hello Ben.
Well, you're right on time.
- You bet.
That's the boy.
Eve, here is your Times and Tribune.
- Thanks, Ben. Put them there.
Here is them theater
magazines you ordered.
Oh swell. I've been waiting for those.
I don't know why.
You ain't never sold any.
I know. I read them.
I can't make head nor
tail of that magazine.
Why don't they put it in English?
We in the theatre have a language
all our own. We understand.
It's just what your mother used to say.
- Yeah?
Yep. You know, Eve ..
She used to come in here
after that .. carnival troop ..
She'd read that paper
from cover to cover.
Then she'd talk about how she's
going to be on Broadway next year.
With her name in big electric lights.
But somehow ..
- Yeah. I know.
Somehow she never made the grade.
Well, you can't blame her for trying.
Yeah, that's right.
Hi Willis.
- Hello, Eve.
Hey, Mr Harvey.
What's all the excitement about?
Somebody important passing through?
Yes, Eve. John Banks the
actor from New York.
He's taken a cottage at Sulphur Springs.
Banks?
He couldn't be coming to Burnsdale?
We'll soon find out.
Mr Banks?
- Yes.
Right this way.
Will you hold it please.
Thank you.
- Oh, Mr Banks.
I'm Harvey, editor
of the Burnsdale Star.
We're mighty pleased
about this visit of yours.
And hope you enjoy every minute ..
- Thank you.
Greetings and salutations to you all.
Oh, Mr Banks.
We're just giving a little play
tomorrow night over at the hotel.
We would certainly like to
have you come to see it.
Mr Adams, your autograph please.
How long you figuring on
staying with us, Mr Banks?
That, dear chap is entirely
in the hands of ..
Oh, Mr Banks. This is Eve Appleton.
She's our leading lady.
How do you do, sir.
All ready to go, sir.
- Come on, driver.
Hello .. Bill.
Hello, Evie.
Bill, did you see him?
- See who? What?
That was John Banks
that just got off the train.
John Banks, the actor.
Good heavens, Bill.
Everybody knows him. He's famous.
That's fine, Evie.
Walter.
- Yeah?
Finish this tire for me, will you?
Sixty cents.
The driver is at the Busy Bee diner.
- Okay, Bill.
That fellow Banks sure gave you
the once-over, Miss Appleton.
I thought he knew
you there for a minute.
Better close up the news stand,
Evie. It's almost suppertime.
Lem will take care of that. Come on.
Say .. do you think he'll come
to the play tomorrow night?
I don't know.
Look Evie. Don't say
much about it before Ma.
You know how she feels about
play acting, anyway.
What did I say?
- Nothing, darling.
Only I don't want an argument like
we had the last time. That's all.
Now, let me see.
I think with a new paint job
and with new tires all round ..
We could let you have that
blue roadster for $250.
How is that, Miss Appleton? Okay?
Okay.
There you are, sweet.
Thanks, Bill.
How's my big girl?
Come on. Put your bib on.
My, the kitchen's hot.
I almost fainted this morning.
I'll put a fan in there for you,
mum. I meant to do it before.
I asked you a dozen times to let me
get a colored girl Mother Appleton.
I'll pay for her wages myself.
We don't need any colored girl.
This is your house, Eve.
And your family.
Please. Let's not go into that again.
Sitting down in that depot
all day reading magazines ..
And running out to play-act every night.
I should think you'd be old enough to
throw those ideas out of your head.
Hey, mum. Eve said they had a lot of
excitement at the depot this morning.
Who was it you said came in, honey?
- John Banks.
He's that famous actor from New York.
- Actor?
He's staying at Sulphur Springs.
Willis asked him to see
our play tomorrow night.
Yeah?
If he comes, I can't forget my lines.
Eve, you're forgetting
to feed your daughter.
There you are, sweetheart.
Oh, I'm warm. Open a window.
They are all open, sir.
- Well, close them.
The room is full of bugs.
- Bugs, sir?
Yes, bugs.
I quite agree, sir.
[ Clapping noises ]
What's that?
Who is applauding who?
A play, sir. Don't you remember?
They asked us to come.
There was a young lady
at the station, sir.
Yes, a lady. Emerson, quick.
Get my coat.
Yes, yes. I remember. Right you are.
The lady.
- Here it is, sir.
It sounds to me as if the
performance is just about over, sir.
Really?
That's perfect, Emerson.
Perfect.
Good timing for my actions.
You were simply magnificent.
You should be on Broadway, Eve.
Thanks, Willis. Say, did John
Banks see our show tonight?
I don't think so.
No-one saw him come in.
Oh, mother, how thrilling.
John Banks the famous actor
is on his way backstage.
He must have seen the
performance tonight.
Are you sure?
- Of course I'm sure.
Is that him over there now?
My dear, dear girl.
I tell you I've never seen
anything like it in my life.
You were superb. But simply superb.
I was swept away. Completely swept away.
And by the other performers.
And you think it really
measured up to standard?
Oh certainly.
But you .. you my dear girl.
You .. are ..
Oh, many a flower is
born to blush unseen ..
And waste its sweetness
on the desert air.
That's awfully kind of you, Mr Banks.
I .. we thought that you hadn't come.
I hadn't come? Why, of course I came.
I sat at the back. I always do.
It frames the illusion more.
I learnt that from Belasco.
- David?
Yes of course, David.
Excellent show. Excellent.
I saw Viola Allen in the
part years ago in New York.
There isn't .. that .. to
choose between you.
Really?
- Absolutely.
To hear him talk, you'd think there
was nobody else in the show.
Wouldn't you.
In the theater you know ..
Success is largely a matter of luck,
influence and the right connections.
I can do a great deal
for you if you let me.
I've an awful lot to learn.
Oh, it wouldn't take long, you know.
A word here, a word there on Broadway.
That's all you need.
Really?
- Certainly. Won't you sit down?
Thank you. Oh, Bill.
Bill, won't you come here.
Excuse me a minute, please.
Bill, I want you to meet Mr Banks.
This is my husband, Mr Appleton.
How do you do.
Glad to know you, Mr Banks.
Congratulations.
Your wife is a splendid artist.
Who, Eve?
Well, Mr Banks is going to let
me meet his manager tonight.
You don't mind waiting a few
minutes more do you, Bill.
No, but it's kinda late, Eve.
I think we'd better go home.
Yes, it is a bit late tonight,
but tomorrow say?
Anytime. I'd be most happy
to do whatever I can.
I offered to improve
your wife's technique.
Well .. well, goodnight, Mr Banks.
Thanks a lot for everything.
- Au revoir. The pleasure was mine.
Goodnight.
What did he mean,
'improve your technique'?
Going out somewhere?
Oh yes.
Yes, I told Sue Miller that
I'd meet her at the movies.
Don't wait up for me.
- Alright.
I'll be back in time
for the baby's bottle.
Got your key?
- Uhuh.
Where did she say she was going?
- To a picture show.
Hmm.
Pretty much dressed
up for that, wasn't she?
Oh, I didn't notice.
There are lots of things
you don't notice, my son.
What? What are you talking about, mum?
I get things, even if you don't.
Everyone in town is talking about what
a fool she made of herself last night ..
With that play actor from New York.
That big windbag?
Eve didn't talk to him for five minutes.
How do you know that she didn't
go out to see him just now?
What?
She didn't dress up like that
to go anywhere with Sue Miller.
I know that much.
- Look here, mum.
I'll not let you talk
that way about Eve.
If she said she went to
a picture show, she did.
Well.
It's very easy to find out, my son.
Hello, Bill.
Hello, Helen.
Just one?
I don't know. I'm looking for Eve.
How long has she been inside?
- Eve hasn't been here tonight, Bill.
She hasn't?
Why no. Did she say she was coming?
No, I'm just looking.
Of course, I'm delighted you came.
In fact, I'm very flattered
you remembered.
I couldn't forget you.
Thank you.
Nice here, isn't it.
A poor place.
An unworthy thing but .. I know.
Well.
You told me that you were leaving soon
and I wanted to meet your manager.
My manager?
- Yes.
Oh, of course.
Won't you sit down?
Thank you.
And I thought you came to see me.
Oh, I didn't mean that.
- No, of course not.
But you are quite right. Business
before pleasure even in the theater.
Won't you indulge in a little ..?
- No thank you.
You know, you don't
look very comfortable.
I'm quite comfortable, thank you.
Would you like to take off your hat?
Katharine Cornell never wears a hat.
After dark.
I say, Emerson.
Come out here a minute, will you.
We've just had a most lovely caller.
I want you to meet Mrs ..
Appleton.
This is Mr Emerson, my manager.
Mrs Appleton. It's a great pleasure.
Pleased to meet you, Mr Emerson.
Have a really good look
at her, my dear chap.
Isn't she everything I said she was?
Hasn't she definite possibilities?
Oh, decidedly.
Decidedly. But definite possibilities.
Do you really think so?
My dear young lady, if you can
act, New York is at your feet.
Max should see her.
He must see her.
I'll tell you what. Go to the hotel
and send a telegram to Max.
Tell him to take the first train
to Burnsdale. Simply say ..
'We have found another
Catherine Cornell. Stop'.
But I don't know enough yet.
Never mind, just leave that to me.
Hurry, hurry. Before the office closes.
Righto. Excuse me.
Which cottage has John Banks got?
John Banks?
- Yes. Banks.
Cottage five, down by the lake.
Maybe I'd better announce you. I think
he's got company. You know how it is.
Posture, my dear. Posture.
It's the foundation of a good actress.
Now.
Stomach in.
Chin up.
Splendid.
You know you have a perfect face.
Wide, liquid eyes.
Maturity.
You have everything .. but experience.
Eve, walk to the car.
This little scene seems
vaguely familiar.
Even for an amateur performance.
Walk to the car, Eve.
Yes, Bill.
I resent this intrusion.
- You shut up or I'll ..
Listen you clod. I don't care what you
tell your wife but you apologise to me.
Miss Sherman.
Do you recognise the
defendant, Bill Appleton?
Yes, I do.
Now then, Miss Sherman.
Will you kindly tell the
jury in your own words.
Exactly what transpired that night
when the defendant, Bill Appleton ..
Came to your theater and enquired from
you as to the whereabouts of his wife.
Well, it was around eight thirty.
And when he came up to me at the theater
and asked if his wife was inside ..
I told him, no. And he looked surprised.
Then he rushed off,
sort of mad and excited.
Well ..
He came in the hotel kind of wild-like.
And he asked me where John
Banks' cottage was and I told him.
And then he ran off in that direction.
His eyes blazing.
There was no sign of death by drowning
as no water found in the lungs.
In my opinion, John Banks died
of a concussion of the brain.
Caused by a sudden and
severe blow on the left temple.
You don't deny that you were
alone with the deceased?
In his apartment that night
when your husband came in?
We were alone, but he was talking ..
- Never mind. Just answer my question.
Your husband was jealous and angry
when he came in. Wasn't he?
He was upset.
He was angry and threatening, wasn't he?
Well, yes.
No .. no!
And lastly, ladies and
gentlemen of the jury.
A motive of jealousy has been
established by the prosecution ..
On the un-contradicted
testimony of three witnesses.
Whether that jealousy was justified
or not is no concern of yours.
What you are called upon to decide ..
Is whether the defendant,
William Appleton ..
Believed in wife's guilt sufficiently to
cause him to premeditate murder.
Should you decide that
question in the affirmative.
Then your verdict must read:
Guilty of murder in the first degree.
That is all.
Your Honor.
- Yes?
Your Honor will grant me an exception
to the last portion of your charge?
Exception noted.
The jury will retire.
Do they always take this long?
In homicide cases, yes.
Now come on, Eve. Sit down.
You're getting yourself all worked up.
They're liable to be out
there for hours yet.
If I only knew what
they were going to do.
I know.
You know what?
What the jury is going to do.
What do you mean?
They are going to find Bill guilty
of murder in the first degree.
Joe.
I never felt any other way.
I did my best of course.
If you'd have had more money and
a famous Lawyer like Darrell.
You might have beaten them.
But the name of John Banks
was too big a name.
All that publicity had us
licked before we started.
How can you say that now?
Because it's true.
Bill Appleton, an innocent man, is going
to pay for the murder of John Banks.
And do you want to know who
is really guilty of the crime?
You.
I am?
You lied, Eve.
Calmly and deliberately
you lied to Bill.
That lie killed John Banks.
Bill loves you.
It's a kind of love I don't
think you understand.
Dumb, patient, trusting. Like a dog.
Of course no-one can blame you
about having dreams of things ..
Away from this drab town.
On the stage or Broadway or
whatever is on your mind.
We all have our dreams tucked away.
But when you wed Bill ..
You should have put that dream far
away in a private corner of your heart.
You didn't do it.
Instead, as time went on ..
You allowed that dream to become more
important than your husband or baby.
No Eve, you didn't give
Bill an even break.
If you had, this would
never have happened.
Alright Joe, the jury is coming in.
- Thanks, Pete.
Come on, Eve.
Ladies and gentlemen of the jury,
have you agreed upon a verdict?
We have.
Do you find the defendant William
Appleton guilty or not guilty?
Guilty of murder in the first degree.
William Appleton.
The court, considering your reputation
for industry and honest living ..
Will not impose the death penalty.
But does sentence you to imprisonment
for the rest of your natural life.
Alright Ed. Open up.
Bill.
Just a minute, please.
Okay.
Don't worry about me,
Evie. I'll be alright.
It's you I'm worried about.
You and the baby.
Look, Bill.
I want to kiss you goodbye.
Then I'll tell you something,
and then I'm going away.
And you aren't to say
a word. Understand?
Sure, Evie. Anything you say.
Now listen, Bill.
And listen carefully.
I haven't been the best wife in the
world. No. Please Bill, you promised.
I haven't done a lot of
things I should have.
I didn't see that before, but I do now.
Today, after I leave here.
Jackie and I are going
away from Burnsdale.
I'll write you every week.
And I'll always be in touch with Joe.
But I might not see you again until ..
Until after my job is done.
And my job is to get you out of here.
From now on, everything
I do is part of that job.
And .. when my work is done.
And you are freed.
Then I swear that I'll
come back as your wife.
And I'll try to make
you as happy as I can.
Goodbye, Bill.
Goodbye, boy. I'll be seeing you.
Come on, Appleton.
Don't know where you'll put her.
Well, I got to find some place.
Porter. Make up Number 6, will you.
Yes, sir.
You kids get to bed. You got
an early call in the morning.
Say, what is this anyway?
Grand Central waiting room?
I'm sorry, Tim.
There is a new girl joining the show at
Wichita and we're pulling in there now.
I got to get her some place to sleep.
Well, why can't she join in the daytime?
Three shows a day.
A sleeper jump each night but no sleep.
What do you think I am,
an outboard motor?
Alright, alright.
You got a couple of hours.
You might as well knock 'em off.
Oh, what's the use.
You got a cigarette?
Here. A couple of drags for you.
Thanks.
What's this new girl like?
Do I know her?
'Wilson' is the name. Her agent
shipped her on. I guess she's alright.
Say, is that her?
Yes.
And a baby.
That's all this troupe needed.
Carriage 4, Miss.
- This way, Miss Wilson.
Are you Mr Haines?
Yes, I'm the manager. Here's your bunk.
Let me take your bag.
You can park the kid there
while he's fixing the berth.
Hey, porter. Will you make it up.
This is Miss Adams, our
prima-donna, Miss Wilson.
Pleased to meet you.
- How do you do.
See you in the morning.
Porter, make it snappy.
- Yes, sir.
Your kid?
- Sure.
Kinda sleepy, isn't she?
- Ah, no.
She gets a little upset sometimes.
When she wakes up sudden like.
Yeah, who wouldn't.
A fine life for a baby.
- She doesn't seem to mind.
Putting on weight all the time.
- Bet that's more than you're doing.
Been in burlesque long?
- This is my first show.
Where are you from?
I was in a carnival four months.
- A carnival?
Ha. Twenty shows a day?
Say, after that you ought
to like burlesque.
It will be better for her, too.
All ready ma'am.
- Thank you.
There is my good little girl.
Yes.
Almost in bed, darling.
Can I help you, Miss?
- I guess I can make it.
No, no. You take the lower.
I'll sleep up there.
I don't want to put you out.
- I'm used to it.
I'm getting close to forty and
I've been a sucker all my life.
Go on, get the kid in there
and get her to sleep.
She is kinda tired.
You can't blame her much.
Come on, sweetheart.
I tell you some women aren't
even fit to be mothers.
Jamie, hang a new set of
lines on here in the morning.
Why don't you go home?
He hasn't got any home.
Say, don't you get enough of
that with four shows a day?
Can I help it if I'm conscientious?
Who are you waiting for?
- Eve Wilson.
Why?
- Why not leave her alone?
What do you mean?
We're breaking in an act together.
Yeah, I saw you rehearsing that stale
routine. That won't get you anywhere.
No? What would you say if I told
you we already got bookings?
I'd say you were a liar.
Yeah, well look. There's a telegram
from my agent. Take a gander at that.
What did you do? Send it to yourself?
Ha. Vaudeville.
Work one week and lay off three.
If you're lucky.
The girl is doing alright where she is.
She's happy and the kid is happy.
So, a cheap honky-tonk piano player like
you comes and puts ideas in her head.
Why don't you mind your own business?
Why don't you mind yours?
- Ah, you give me a pain in the neck.
Eve. Evie.
- What is it, Tommy?
It's here. A cinch.
- You hear from the agent?
Look. We open in Duluth in two weeks.
Gee, Tommy. That's swell.
If we make good in Duluth, we're a cinch
for 40 weeks of darned good vaudeville.
That means more money, too?
- And how.
Of course, Duluth is not
Broadway, but don't worry.
Brogan and Wilson will get there too.
- You bet we will.
It's kind of cold this time
of year up in Duluth.
I must get some warm things for Jackie.
- Oh, Jackie. Oh yes.
That's one thing I wanted
to talk to you about too.
Now, look. Understand, I like kids.
I'm crazy about them.
But when you hop around the
country making one-night stands.
Getting in and out of Pullmans.
If you've got kids, no dice.
I don't get you, Tommy.
You got an aunt or uncle someplace where
we can park the kid until we get going?
Oh, Jackie wouldn't be in the way.
She's such a little, small baby.
Big or small, on the road
a kid is a nuisance.
They're always catching whooping
cough or measles or something.
Why, the first thing you know they'll
be a packed house out there, waiting.
While we're in quarantine.
When Jackie has measles
I want to have them too.
So will you when you get to know her.
- I'll tell you what I'll do.
You park the kid someplace and
I'll make it 'Wilson and Brogan'.
And where would you suggest I park her?
Well, if you folks can't
see this your way ..
There is always those children's homes.
Now look, don't take it that way.
Some pretty big people have
come out of those homes.
Yeah, but big people
didn't put them in there.
I guess you'd better do a single, Tommy.
I can't. I need you, Eve.
I can't get along without you.
And neither can Jackie.
But Eve.
- Count me out.
Goodnight, Tommy.
There's a good girl.
Yes, darling. It isn't so bad, is it.
No, you're going to be alright.
You're going to wake
everybody up, darling.
Say, what is this anyway?
Feeding time at the zoo?
Why can't you keep that child quiet?
- She doesn't do it all the time.
No, she sort of does
it ever night, that's all.
And she keeps everybody awake.
What's the matter with her, anyhow?
What's wrong with her?
Oh I know, she wants her doggy.
Where is it? Get out the way, you don't
know about taking care of children.
Come on darling, look. It's your old
auntie Tim that's with you now.
Here it is. Here's your doggy.
Rin-Tin-Tin. The winner
of all the bright medals.
Now you're going to sleep, aren't you.
Just peaceful and quiet.
Sure you are.
She kinda likes you, doesn't she.
Don't give me that.
I know what you're up to.
What are you talking about?
I hear you're going into vaudeville.
- So what?
I've seen ambitious
dames like you before.
You know, you can't get far in show
business with a kid on your hands.
What's it to you?
Ah, don't be cute. You know you're
just dying to palm her off on to me.
So that's what you think.
Sure.
You've got me all figured out.
I'm getting close to forty.
I'm thinking of quitting this racket.
I've saved money all along.
I'd make a pretty good touch as
a second-hand mama, wouldn't I?
If you've finished patting yourself
on the back you can do me a favor.
Yeah?
- Yeah.
Get out and stay out.
What's the matter?
Annoyed because I told you the truth?
- It wasn't the truth.
Sure, I've got ambitions,
but Jackie goes with them.
And I don't think of giving
her up to you or anyone else.
Ah, why don't you stop
telling yourself jokes.
I know more about you
than you think I do.
In what way?
- The hard way.
Ha.
Just because I'm getting near forty does
not mean my eyes and ears aren't good.
You're young. You're in burlesque.
You never talk about your past.
The kid's father is just a bad memory
to you. Probably the town's Casanova.
You're paying him off and
are tickled to death to do it.
Well. So you've been reading my mail.
As long as you know that much,
you might as well know all of it.
Jackie's father is in jail for life.
And everything I do and every
move I make is to help him.
Gee kid, I guess I got you
all wrong. I didn't think ..
You know about the letters I
get from my lawyer, don't you.
Here's one that came tonight. Read it.
Eve, I can't ..
- Go ahead. Read it.
And that's about all I'll hear
from you tonight, wise lady.
If you just leave me alone
now, I'd appreciate it.
Alright.
Gee .. I'm sorry I ..
Go on. Leave me alone.
Okay, okay.
But remember, I'm still
not taking the kid.
I didn't come to apologise. I just came
back to return your file. I thought ..
Are you sleeping, darling?
The idea of leaving you
in a draught like this.
The nerve of her.
Not for one million bucks.
How do you like that.
The oriental number is the finale.
Yeah. Say, I just happened to think.
Don't they have any men in a real harem?
- Yeah. In a way.
Say look. You're passing a big chance.
You don't get one like this every day.
No use, Tommy. It wouldn't work out.
Oh, sure it would. You're making
something big out of nothing.
In no time, we'll be out there
and knocking them dead.
You got to think it over.
- I've got to think of Jackie.
And I can't do it.
Come on, Mary. On stage there. Hurry up.
- Okay.
Well, ain't women something.
Hey, Brogan. Wait a minute.
- What do you want?
That was a fine act you and Eve Wilson
put on for my benefit just now.
Tell her from me she's wasting her time.
What the matter? Nutty or something?
- She just turned down vaudeville, eh?
Yeah.
- She won't leave her kid.
And she got you to talk about
it in front of me, didn't she?
Didn't she?
- Yeah .. no.
What is it? Tell me, what is
it you're trying to drive at?
Just this.
You know I'm quitting the show tomorrow
night. And I'm going home to Boston.
And you both got it figured out that it
will be swell to palm the kid off on me.
So you two could do a
double in vaudeville, see.
But it ain't going to work.
Just because I'm getting close to forty
doesn't mean I'm that soft brained.
You ain't got much idea of it.
Ah, what's the use.
Listen sister, let me
tell you something.
If I should decide to take Jackie
home with me and take care of her.
I could make a swell job of it.
And you could go into
vaudeville with the Brogan boy.
What kind of a woman do you think I am?
Deep down, fairly sensible.
And smart enough to know
that many a good mother ..
Has left has left her child in somebody
else's care when it was necessary.
Ah, there is no use
fooling myself any longer.
I'm daffy about the kid.
I've been nuts about her
from the first time I saw her.
Go on, laugh.
Hey, Tim.
No encores on the dance
tonight so watch your cue.
Okay, okay.
I've got plenty of money, I tell you.
Not that I want to support
Jackie all her life.
Later on, you can take care
of both of us if you want.
After you've made good.
Wait a minute, Tim.
Will you answer a question honestly?
If I can.
What are you doing all this for?
A tough question, a tough answer.
I had a kid once. Years ago.
A pretty little monkey.
Just like Jackie.
She was fine one morning.
She was dead that night.
Well.
Upon my soul, here comes
Mrs Asterbilt herself.
In the flesh.
How do you do, Madame?
I have never seen you look so gorgeous.
Oh dear, dear, dear. Mr Binkeltwist.
Such flattery coming from you.
Utterly, you overwhelm me.
Up to here, no less.
No. I never bother with politics.
Tim.
What?
If you really want to do it.
It's okay with me.
I had a baby.
You're leaving the show Sunday night?
Yeah.
Do you mind leaving tonight?
Tonight?
Yeah.
Right after the show.
Go home.
Take Jackie.
I won't get there until
after you've gone.
You mean, you're not even
going to tell the kid goodbye?
If I did, I'd never let you have her.
Eve.
I rather like the way they've
designed this banquet hall.
You will make your entrance through
the double-doors in the center.
The light comes from the candles on
the table. Effective, don't you think?
Grand, Bert. Grand.
- Glad you like it.
You know, I can hardly wait
for rehearsals to start.
Well, it won't be long now. We've
only got to get that one part set.
How many girls were interviewed today?
- A million.
Well, there can't be many more left.
How many left, Miss McDermott?
About eight, and one of them
seems to be fairly intelligent.
Ha. I can hardly believe it.
Are you too tired to
see another one, dear?
Why not. We might as well
hear the bright one.
Send her in, Miss McDermott.
- Right.
It's swell of you, Janet. Giving up
time to help me cast a new play.
Not many stars would do it.
- Oh yes they would.
If they were as much in love as I am.
This is Miss Wilson, Mr Ballin.
How do you do, Miss Wilson.
Please sit down.
Thank you.
- Miss Eaton.
She'll read with you.
Tell me, do I know your work?
- I doubt it. I've not worked Broadway.
Well, go from the second act.
Miss Winifred's entrance.
Go on, dear.
Jane, I'm surprised at you.
Why did you tell me last night
that my husband hadn't been home?
Forgive me, Mrs Widdecombe.
But I can't answer that question.
You can't? Why not?
- Because it wouldn't be fair.
Please don't ask me anymore. Please.
But I must ask you.
Why you deliberately lied to me.
Yes, I know I did.
But I lied because I wanted
to save your happiness.
That's enough, Miss Wilson.
You read very well.
- Yes, she does.
You're very kind.
Tell me, you have no
Broadway experience?
No, I haven't.
It just hasn't happened so far.
- Where are you from?
Well, I .. I was with a
carnival show first.
And after that, burlesque.
Then I was a year or so
in vaudeville, and now ..
Well I've been around Broadway
for the last few months.
Hoping for bigger and better things.
You haven't picked an
easy game you know.
How well, I know.
I like the way you talk.
I'm sure Miss Eaton does too.
How would you like to work and work
very hard for at least a year or so?
Oh, yes.
Small parts in the beginning.
- I won't mind that.
And not so much money.
You'd have to get by on very little.
If I made good quickly, I could
make more money couldn't I?
Perhaps.
All I want is a chance.
Well, the chance is yours.
You will work for me.
Come tomorrow and
we'll discuss a contract.
Your part will be the one you just read
I wish you all the luck in the world.
Thank you.
You've both been so good .. goodbye.
Rehearsals start Wednesday
morning at ten o'clock.
I'll be there.
You know Janet, I've got a hunch
that girl has got something.
Yes. I was watching you.
I got it.
Do you realize this play opens on Monday
and you still don't know the third act?
We've gone over it and over, rehearsed
it and rehearsed it, and still nothing.
Now, you really must
put a little heart into it.
With the exception of Miss Wilson, you
all read your lines like wooden Indians.
We've been rehearsing
this play for ten days ..
And Miss Wilson is the only cast member
who has caught the spirit of the play.
And that goes for everybody.
Now come on, let's do the third act.
Keep the first scene. Start
at Winifred's entrance.
And don't forget she must
not slam the door ..
Because she knows the person is
not in the other corner of the room.
No, I mean it sincerely.
You're doing a grand job.
I'm glad I gave you an important part.
- Thanks, Bert.
You've made it a beautiful play.
- You ought to read the next.
You've already given me an idea for it.
- I have?
What is it?
- It's a love story.
Well, that's a new idea.
Ha. Something different.
Hadn't we better be getting back?
- Yep.
Going to start with the third act?
- Yes.
I want to hear you read the long speech.
- I don't think I know it yet.
As one wooden Indian to another,
I hope you have a good, long contract.
No, I think I'll change all this.
I'd rather you didn't say anything.
As long as you sit there looking at
him intently while he reads the letter.
Of course you're in love with him, so ..
Say, what's the matter?
Hello Janet. What's on your mind?
I thought I might find you alone.
Well, Miss Wilson and I
were going out to dinner.
I'll wait outside.
- No. Wait a minute.
In that case, you might as well
stay and here what I've got to say.
I don't want this girl in my company.
But Janet, you agreed.
- I've changed my mind.
Why?
It's a privilege we stars enjoy.
Now look here, Janet.
You'd like to argue about it, Bert?
No. Not right now.
Tell Gibson to give her two weeks'
salary and go and let her go.
The star, Miss Eaton, must approve
her cast. It's in her contract.
You never did this to me before, Janet.
- No. I've never had the occasion.
This is all a joke, isn't it?
You're just fooling.
Trying me out.
Not at all. Your try-out
is over, Miss Wilson.
I see.
A good sport, wasn't it.
Swell fun.
Tossing a heart into the clouds and
watching it bounce back into the cellar.
Say, now listen.
No, you listen.
Why you've done this
to me, I don't know.
All I know it that I've always
dreamed of getting a fair chance.
It meant much more to me than ..
Than just ambition and success.
More than either one
of you will ever know.
Wait a minute. I'm the star around here.
If there are any scenes to
be played, I'll play them.
I'm not playing a scene, Miss Eaton.
I'm just telling you.
You don't know what it means.
Eve.
Eve, please.
I don't know what got into Eaton.
- I think I know, Bert.
It wasn't your fault.
But you'll still work for me.
I want you back here tomorrow.
What?
- There'll be other parts.
I'll put you on a personal contract.
We'll have a play ready in a month.
No, Bert.
But Eve, it's a great chance for you.
It's what you've been living for.
You were born for the stage.
This is only a break in the game.
You are honest, genuine .. real.
We'll do great things together.
Oh Eve, it's more than that.
I ..
No, Bert.
No.
- Eve.
Did you say a pretty goodbye?
That was the rottenest trick
I've ever seen pulled.
For a woman in love, Bert?
I've been watching you with that
girl. That's why I threw her out.
And that's why she's going to stay out.
Got a match?
- Sure.
You've been watching me? Well,
do you know what I've just seen?
What?
I've seen a fine exhibition
of meanness and pettiness.
I see nothing but unhappiness
for both of us if this keeps up.
But it's not going to keep up.
Now, you're just a name
on the program to me.
Bert.
And whether you like it or not
that's the way it's going to stay.
You sure there's been no slip-up?
- Perfectly sure.
She hasn't been here or phoned?
- No, sir.
You found out where she lives?
- Yes, we have.
What? Where is it?
- She moved this morning.
Moved?
- Yes.
But she left no forwarding address.
Alright. Well, keep looking for her.
- Yes, sir.
Let me know when you hear something.
That play ran for over a year in London.
In the next production
she featured alone.
She's surely changed.
I'd not have known her.
Four years can change a lot of things.
With the next plays she wasn't so lucky.
Now she's up again.
Here is the playbill.
She's starring in one of the
biggest hits in London.
Isn't that fine.
When do you sail?
- Tuesday.
Looking forward to the trip?
- Oh no.
Six days bouncing around on a boat is no
thrill for a woman who's approaching 40.
No. Well, I hope you enjoy it anyway.
Mummy .. mummy.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Jackie, this is Mr Grant.
- How do you do, Jackie.
I knew you when you were just a baby.
- Anything you want, dear?
Will I need my long
underwear in England?
Yes, you will.
We are not going to take any chances.
Now hurry, darling. We've a lot to do.
Goodbye, Jackie. And I hope
you have a very nice trip.
Thank you, and goodbye now.
- Goodbye, dear.
Well, she's certainly like her mother.
If you mean she's stage-struck, right.
Like living with a pint-sized Garbo.
Didn't she call you 'mummy'?
Well, you see we haven't told her yet.
Oh I see, because I hope
she'll see her father soon.
What?
That's the reason I came to Boston as
soon as I heard you were joining Eve.
See, there are things I want
you tell her, Miss Adams.
Things I cannot put in a letter.
- Yes?
An account of what I've spent to date.
She's to read them and burn the records.
And you are to tell her this.
After seven years of work I'm now in
a position to free Bill Appleton.
Free?
It must be done in the next ten months,
while the governor is still in office.
Of course, it will take money.
How much?
Well roughly, about
ten thousand dollars.
Ten thousand?
- Yes.
You see, while Eve has always sent me
money, she's never sent me very much.
Just enough to make the routine
appeals to the parole board ..
And get a few comforts for Bill in jail.
- And?
Well, setting him free is
something else entirely.
I've got to employ powerful
attorneys and important men ..
That are politically
close to the governor.
They come high.
A lot of money and get it fast, huh?
- I'm afraid so.
Otherwise, if I miss this chance Bill
and Eve may never be together again.
So what?
I beg your pardon? What did you say?
Oh nothing, Mr Grant. Nothing.
Eve.
Jackie.
Tim, darling.
- Eve.
Jackie.
Take it easy, kid. I'll explain later.
Jackie, this is Eve Wilson.
How do you do, Miss Wilson.
Mummy's told me a lot about you.
Mummy?
Oh, she has?
Oh yes. I have your picture in my room.
You're in the family, almost.
Stop prattling so much
and keep your head up.
You look grand, Eve.
Customs inspection is
over this way, ma'am.
Come on, darling.
Mummy, wait for me.
Train for Bristol? Platform 6.
- Thank you.
Mummy .. oh, mummy.
Yes, dear?
Do you mind if I have some gum, please?
No, darling. Here.
Thank you, mummy.
Six years I've been waiting to see her.
And what do I get?
'How do you, Miss Wilson'?
Why doesn't she know I'm her mother?
Why didn't you ever tell her? Why?
Okay, lady. Here it is.
Jackie grew up just taking it
for granted I was her mother.
Go on.
Coming over on the boat, I
tried awfully hard to tell her.
Words kept sticking in my
throat until I got a sore spot.
I couldn't do it.
She's too close to me, Eve.
I just couldn't.
In all my letters I sent
messages to Jackie.
Didn't she ..?
- I meant to tell her every year.
But I couldn't tell her part of the
story and not tell her the rest.
How could I tell her that
her father was in prison?
And why.
You don't know Jackie like I do, Eve.
She's not ready for that. Not yet.
When the time does come.
I thought you should
be the one to tell her.
Yes. I guess I should.
Thanks, Tim.
Thanks for everything.
Gee, Eve.
She is going to be wild about you.
Just wait and see.
Then everything will be so much easier.
I'll wait.
In the meantime we'll share
her as long as we can.
Don't worry about that.
I've had some awfully swell years.
Mummy.
- Yes, darling?
I think I'm going to like Eve.
- I hope so.
I know you will, dear.
Mummy says we're going to live with you.
Are we?
Yes, darling.
And you and I are going to be pals.
Will you teach me to be an actress?
An actress?
Well, if you really want to.
That's the only thing
the child dreams about.
When I grow up, I'm going
to be a star just like you.
Only bigger. Much, much bigger.
Oh, do you think so?
I'm sure.
Oh.
Say, do you mind if
I sit over here by you?
That make up smells awfully good.
Tim.
Did Joe Grant say anything else?
No. After he mentioned ten thousand
dollars we both stopped talking.
Have you got it?
- Of course not.
Between the money I've sent to you and
Joe, my income tax, expenses over here.
I've only saved a couple of thousand.
And you've got to keep
up appearances too.
How are you going to raise
the rest of the money?
I'll get it somehow.
I've got to.
It's the first time that Joe
has given me any actual hope.
Eve.
Are you still in love
with Jackie's father?
In love with him?
He's been in jail for
seven years, hasn't he.
For why?
Because he was guilty? Uhuh.
Because I didn't have money enough
to pay for lawyers to get him off.
It isn't a matter of if I love him.
It's a matter of justice.
Does that answer your question?
I think so.
Hey, you're early.
They're still applauding.
It's him. I saw him.
- Who?
In the audience. Staring at me.
Well, who?
- Bert Ballin.
Say, isn't he that New York producer?
- I don't want to see him.
Tell him I'm that I've left.
Tell him anything.
Sure. But wait until he gets here.
Say.
What does this guy mean to you anyway?
I haven't seen him for four years, Tim.
If you must know, he's the
reason I left New York.
Oh.
And?
That's just as hard to explain
as it is to understand.
I rehearsed a play for
ten days with Bert Ballin.
It was my first New York job.
Gee, he was wonderful to me.
I knew if I saw any more of him ..
Or let him anywhere near me, that ..
That I'd forget the one thing
I'd sworn to remember.
Don't let them tell you
it can't happen, Tim.
I know it can.
[ Buzzer ]
I'm not in.
Will you ask Miss Wilson
if she will see me, please.
Yes. She'll see you, Come in.
Make yourself at home.
I'll tell Miss Wilson you're here.
Thanks.
Eve .. Mr Ballin is here to see you.
Hello there.
Hello again. After all this time.
I saw the show tonight.
You are a great artist.
Thank you.
No, no. I mean it sincerely.
I'm proud to think I
guessed it so long ago.
Praise from you would
make any actress happy.
You didn't think so then, did you.
- Oh yes I did.
Then why did you run away?
I owe you an apology for that.
And why didn't you answer my letters?
I never meant to be unkind. Believe me.
I just felt that ..
That I must make my way alone.
Without you.
- Well, you've done it brilliantly.
I come to you as a humble
playwright to a great star.
Will you read a play of mine?
Of course.
If you like it, I'll do the play with
you in New York as soon as it's ready.
It's not as easy as all that.
- You know ..
Deep down, I think I wrote
the play for you, Eve.
Really?
- Yes.
At least, you were seldom out of
my mind when I was working on it.
Bert.
I want to ask you something.
What?
If I gambled on your play,
would you gamble on me?
How do you mean?
I'm going to need a large sum
of money, ten thousand dollars.
If I open in your play,
and it is successful ..
Would you advance me that
much to use against my contract?
I don't see why not.
Thank you.
When can I have the play?
- I'll send it to you in the morning.
Alright.
I'll read it and let you know
afterwards. Goodnight, Bert.
Eve.
Goodnight. Thanks.
What are you hopping about so for?
Mummy, does this remind you of tonight?
Oh, I love to be in a London park.
The fog.
Yes, the fog.
It simply smothers me.
But I love it so.
You're going to love to go to
bed in about five minutes, too.
Mummy, I think I'll be a
music hall comedy star.
Tragedy annoys me sometimes.
That's too bad.
But music.
Ah, music has a lullaby all of its own.
Some lullaby.
I don't know.
Tragedy suits my personality better.
Why doesn't he come?
- Get up.
Oh, that's right.
It is he, my loved one.
He has a gun.
Don't shoot. Don't shoot.
Wonderful, darling.
- Bravo. Bravo.
Did you really like it?
- You bet we did.
There's one thing, Jackie,
if you must be a great actress.
What's that?
- You must learn to keep your head up.
You too?
Great, kid.
Really swell. The finest opening
night performance I've ever seen.
Thanks, Tim. You're sweet.
Congratulations, Bert.
It was a grand job all the way around.
- Thanks, Tim.
Why didn't you come backstage?
I was afraid there would
be too many people.
Jackie and I stopped and got a hot
chocolate and now we're going to bed.
Come on, Jackie.
Eve.
I think you're swell.
Thanks, darling.
I'd rather hear you say that
than anyone else in the world.
Hey, you.
Psst.
Ah, gee.
Sometimes, I don't think mummy
understands my artistic temper.
Goodnight, Eve.
- Goodnight, sweetheart.
Goodnight, Mr Ballin.
- Goodnight.
And that's my cue also.
Goodnight, you two.
I'm still so excited.
Do you mind if I walk up and down for
a bit? I just can't seem to sit still.
Go on, keep travelling.
On the night of my first Broadway hit I
walked from 42nd Street to Bronx Zoo.
I'm liable to cover
the same mileage here.
You know, Mr Ballin.
You look very handsome tonight.
That's just part of the excitement.
I'll look normal again in the morning.
Are you hungry?
- Too nervous to eat.
How about some wine?
- No, I don't need it.
The way I feel, I could out-bubble
champagne, two to one.
Come here, you.
I've got to let lose some
of this excess energy.
Say.
I didn't hit you too hard, did I?
Yes, you did.
It was years ago, too.
And I still feel the punch.
Bert, that audience tonight.
They weren't fooling us, were they?
No, we're successful alright.
I know the symptoms.
We're good for a year on Broadway.
Then we can clean up on the road.
Oh, Bert.
Bert, I'm so happy I could weep.
No crying tonight, young lady.
I have something that will change that.
- Do you know why I feel this way?
Because I know that life will never
hold so much for me again.
It will be so beautiful.
Oh.
Here is the advance you asked for.
Advance?
- Yes.
Why, what's the matter?
You look as though you've seen a ghost.
Yes.
I have.
That's a fine thing to say to a fellow
who's going to ask you to marry him.
Bert.
A very simple wedding.
Just the three old 'R's.
Ring, rice and the Reverend.
Bert, there's something I've got
to tell you about this check.
I ask a girl to marry me and she tries
to tell me the history of a check.
But you mustn't. Not until you've heard.
I don't doubt you've got a lot to tell
me about your past but .. look at me.
I've robbed banks, poisoned wells,
pulled little children's noses.
You can't match that.
There is only one thing
I want to know from you.
Do you love me?
- Please.
The first day we met
you knew I loved you.
You knew it in London.
You know it now.
Do you know how much I love you?
Did you see tonight's program?
Your name is printed
twice as big as mine.
Greater love hath no playwright.
Hmm?
Will you just lie perfectly
still and let me talk?
Must you?
Alright. Go ahead.
You know that check you gave me?
That was to get a man out of jail.
He's in for murder.
Murder?
Yes .. a life sentence.
He had a wife and baby too.
That was eight years ago.
And in time.
The wife knew that she was
guiltier than he was.
And she made a pledge.
To set him free.
She swore that when he was freed.
She'd go back to him with her child.
Tell me.
This girl.
Does she still love her husband?
No.
I don't think she ever
loved him .. this way.
That makes it all very
simple, doesn't it.
Simple.
She sets her husband free and
goes back to the man she loves.
Isn't that the only thing for her to do?
Answer me, Eve.
Isn't it?
No, Bert.
Do you mean you want to go back to him?
Of course I don't want to.
But after I've worked out your
advance of ten thousand dollars.
That's what I have to do.
But you never loved him. You said that.
Even so.
But why .. why?
This was all years ago.
Eve, you've changed.
You're not the same person.
He can't expect you to
keep a promise like that.
Eight years in prison.
What do you think that does to a man?
Do you think He could come here to this?
He doesn't know about this.
Suppose he did know?
He won't find out.
They'll never find out.
Eve, you don't know what you're saying.
This whole thing doesn't make sense.
It's not right.
Listen, darling.
I love you for what
you want to do but ..
What do you think you can give
another man as long as you love me?
Every hour, every minute you lived
with him you'd be lying to him.
Would he want that?
Is he selfish enough? Bitter enough?
To crucify you and Jackie for
a promise made so long ago?
Now man worth that
sacrifice would want it.
Your happiness would
come first, not his.
But is it right to ..?
- The right thing is the kind thing.
And there is only one kind,
one honest thing for you to do.
Go to him and tell him the truth.
About yourself and about us.
Then you'll both be free.
Free from lies and heartache and
deception for the rest of your lives.
It's going to be hard, Eve.
Terribly hard.
But it's right.
You see that now?
You know it's right, don't you.
Just have a seat, Mrs Appleton.
He'll be right in.
Thank you.
Evie.
Bill.
How are you?
I knew it.
You're just the same.
You look just like I knew you would.
I'm a little older, Bill.
No, no .. just the same.
You didn't bring Jackie.
Well ..
Jackie is in school.
She's a big girl now.
Gee, I can hardly wait to see her.
Eve .. tell me quick. Is it true?
What?
What Joe Grant was telling me.
About me being free again.
Maybe.
It isn't 'maybe' anymore, Bill.
We're almost positive now.
In a few months, you're
going to be out of here.
Out of here?
Oh, Evie.
Has it been so bad?
No, no .. not too bad.
You got used to things you know.
They said you were sick.
Are you well again?
Sure, sure.
It's them prison doctors.
They had me in the hospital
ward a couple of times.
Saying there was something wrong
with my heart. What do they know.
They ought to be listening
to it now with you here.
It's beating perfect.
Bill.
There is ..
There is something I want to tell you.
- You don't have to tell me. I know.
About everything.
No.
- Joe Grant told me.
You're living in New York.
Being a nursemaid for rich kids.
Supporting Jackie and helping my
case with money out of your pay.
There ain't many wives
would have done that.
I'm glad it's almost over.
It's my turn to take care of you.
I didn't mean that, Bill.
I meant .. I meant about us.
You and I ..
Why? What about us?
Things can happen to people.
They can change.
Inside, I mean.
Me .. change my feelings about you?
No, I'd never do that, Eve.
But ..
You see.
There ain't much for a fellow
to do here except think.
And all I ever dream about.
All I ever prayed for was ..
Being with you and Jackie
again in the same little house.
And running the same little garage.
All you ever dreamed about.
All you ever prayed for.
Of course there was a time when I ..
Wasn't quite sure.
I'd say to myself.
She is so far away.
Meeting different people and ..
She's so pretty.
What makes you think she'll
ever come back to you.
Then all of a sudden I remember
what you said eight years ago.
I'd see you standing there in front
of me with your eyes burning.
And then I'd know that everything
was coming out alright for me.
And everything is, Bill.
Everything is coming out fine for you.
Deep down in my heart
I never doubted it.
Never once in all those years.
Well, I guess that's the last
performance for a while, Sam.
Yep. I guess you're right there.
- Goodnight.
Goodnight there.
No, Eve. No.
I don't want to go away.
I want to stay here.
Don't you want to see your father?
No, I don't know him.
But you will.
And you'll love him.
He loves you.
I don't care. I want to
stay here with mummy.
Please Eve, please, please.
Oh, Jackie.
But you aren't Eve anymore.
Are you.
You are my mummy.
Tim isn't my mummy.
She is just something else.
Oh, I'm all mixed up.
Please, Eve.
I want to stay here. Please.
I know, dear.
But sometimes we have to do
things we don't want to do.
Why? Why do we?
It's not sure, baby.
The part we have to play.
The hardest part in both our lives.
There is no script.
There are no lines to follow.
We can't make one mistake.
No, not even one.
What would I have to do?
You would have to play
the part of a little girl.
Who's been very poor.
And your mother was a nursemaid.
And your father had been away.
Sick.
And you've come back to him.
And you are going to be so kind to him.
And not he, nor anyone else.
Must ever know about mummy Tim.
Or about London or the theater.
Or anything else that's ever happened.
You will have to be
a great little actress.
A great little actress, Jackie.
One of the finest that ever lived.
But we'd do it together, wouldn't we.
I bet I'd make an awful mess of it.
No you won't, darling.
We'll do our best.
No matter how hard it is.
Our level best.
Eve.
Bert.
I couldn't let you go
without seeing you again.
I hoped you wouldn't.
Eve .. it doesn't come easy to say this.
But I realize now that you
were right and I was wrong.
There can be something
greater than love.
Something a great deal less selfish.
I couldn't see it that night because ..
Well, I guess I wasn't
big enough, but ..
You are doing this because
that's the kind of person you are.
I love you even more
for it if that's possible.
Bert.
I want to go with you as far
as that prison, wherever it is.
And Eve.
If you ever need me.
If you ever want me.
- I know that, dear.
You've made it a lot easier.
That's what I hoped.
And remember, if it will
make the rest of it easier.
I'll always be waiting.
I'll never give up hope.
Never.
Taxi. Taxi. Taxi.
Cab.
Taxi, lady?
Do you know 52nd Street?
- Yes, ma'am.
Do you know each little caf
on both sides of the street?
Yes, ma'am.
Well take me there and
drop me off at each one.
Are you celebrating something?
Yeah.
I'm celebrating my birthday.
I just passed forty.
Hello, Joe.
- Hello Matt.
Waiting for somebody?
- No. Just looking around.
Okay.
Well, hello.
- Hello, Joe.
And Jackie, do you remember me?
- Hello, Mr Grant.
Joe, this is Mr Ballin.
He's been awfully kind to us.
I'm glad to meet you.
- How do you do.
They're releasing him at noon.
Do you want me to go with you?
No, I .. I think we'd better go alone.
Well, you've just about got time.
Thanks.
Goodbye, Bert.
Goodbye.
Come on, Jackie.
Mummy.
What?
What did you say?
I said 'mummy'.
Yes. Yes darling, what is it?
Keep your head up, mummy.
..s-d..