- Oi.
I'll be back in a month.
The usual thing, feed the fish.
Lots of love, Jodi.
- Not too shabby, huh?
- Okay, bye.
- Reckon she'll like these?
- Yeah, look how cute they are.
- I still
can't believe it.
- Do we have to have
this discussion again?
- I know, I know,
I've said it before.
- Change-of-life baby.
Some woman have
children into their 50s.
- Yeah.
I'm just bloody
glad it wasn't us.
- Yeah, you've said
that before too.
Hey, what's this?
- Don't know.
Maybe the giraffe and
hippo are breeding.
- My wallet's not in here.
Did I give it to you?
- No.
- Sure?
Can you go and get the
ticket to the airline?
- Yeah, sure.
- In that little thing...
- Yeah, I know.
Drop the gun, dead
beat, or I'll blow
your testicles to kingdom come.
Who says dead beat?
Sounds shit.
- I don't suppose
you've had another
look for my wallet?
- Oh.
No, I'm just learning
my lines, babe.
- Don't worry about it.
Hello?
Yeah.
Yep.
Ah, that's awesome.
Bye.
- Who was it?
- Hello?
- Sis, it's me.
Are you alone?
- Yeah, what's wrong?
- Sorry for disturbing you.
Jodi left a second set of keys.
- Oh, thanks for that.
- That's cute.
- Oh, did you hear that?
She thinks you're cute.
Think you'd better have him.
- Aww.
Sure?
What do you say?
- Thank you.
- Catch you later.
Sallie?
Hey, Bill.
You haven't seen
Sallie around, have ya?
- No, is everything all right?
- Yeah, she's probably
just gone for a wander.
It's a little bit strange
but I'm sure it'll
be okay, Irene.
- Well, you've
got me worried now.
- Well, don't be.
Honestly, I'm sure she'll
wander in any second.
I'll call you as soon
as I know anything.
Bye-bye.
Look, the reason I'm calling is
I'm just wondering,
have you seen Sallie
at all or have
you spoken to her?
- No, I haven't.
- Hmm.
- Is something wrong?
- Oh no, it's just,
she's just not about.
Well, if she shows up
can you give us a call?
Uh-huh.
Thank you, Jacky.
If someone is admitted
under that name
can you please get them
to call me immediately?
Have you heard from her?
- No.
Have you?
Called the police?
- Yeah.
- It'll be fine.
- Look, is there
something I can do?
I could, I could stay with you.
- Look, the police
are on their way.
They'll probably
be here any minute.
- Has she disappeared before?
- No.
- Was she on medication?
Isn't the first 48 hours,
they're really crucial, yeah?
- They are, Mr.
Raven, but there are
some questions we
need to ask, okay?
- Of course.
- The two of you
getting along okay?
Any relationship troubles?
- No.
- Did she or
you have any money problems?
- No.
- Did she take her passport
or credit cards with her?
- Actually, her passport's
here but her wallet was stolen.
- Stolen?
- Yeah.
Somewhere between
the airport and here.
- Any reason that
you can think of
for her to leave so suddenly?
- No.
- Anything
at all you'd like to add?
- Yeah, it's strange.
I think we were followed.
- Where?
- In the park, on the way
back from the airport.
- Did you get a
look at the person?
- No, I didn't see him at all.
- Was there
anyone that might have
had a grudge against
you or your girlfriend?
- We've been away six years.
No.
- The end of the world party?
- Yeah, it's like, even if
we invite everyone at once,
we just invite everyone.
Maybe, like--
- Uh, sorry.
Mitch, get rid of
the cigarette, mate.
And stick it where
the sun don't shine.
You boys have a good
holiday, stay out of trouble.
Look, I'll see you
guys next term.
And remember astrology
assignment's due first week back.
What's a constellation
and who named them.
- Yes, sir, we know.
- What's the ecliptic?
Did you have a fight?
You said someone followed you?
- Yeah, I think so.
- Any idea why?
Is there anything else you
can think of that might help?
- No.
- Surely there has to be
something out of the ordinary.
- I don't have it.
- She swapped it.
- Who did you swap it with?
- Susie Faletti.
- These gentlemen need
to find the elephant.
There's not a school
friend of yours
that would know her address?
- Okay, I'll try.
- Good girl.
I'll text you the address.
You look like you
could do with a rest.
- What are we looking for?
- Anything.
Oi!
Fagan.
What's that say?
- The Signatures Club.
Fagan.
You know him?
- No.
- Yo.
You boys looking to play?
- Yeah.
Mate, we're actually looking
for Fagan, is he about?
- All right, I'll tell you what.
Take a seat.
It's $20 bucks to play,
$35 if you win your match
we take five for the house.
- Check.
- You boys
looking to find Fagan?
- Yeah, is he around?
- Nah, Fagan ain't been
around here for ages.
- Can you help us out?
- Yeah.
Yeah, I'll see you boys at
that door after your game, huh.
- I'll take your horse
thingy, and the black square.
- Check.
- You're gone, mate.
He just moved your queen--
- Hey, we're here to
find Fagan, remember?
- Mate.
- Have you seen her?
- No, no, what are, what
are you playing at, man?
You fucking with us?
No, I haven't seen her.
I can't help.
I fucking can't help, all right?
Oh fuck!
Wait, wait, wait.
You boys had a deal
with Fagan, yeah?
I know what you're
after, yeah, yeah.
Yeah, okay, you
better not be cops.
- Mate, we're not cops.
- Okay cool, just
wait one minute.
Yeah.
Woo!
There you go, boys.
$1,200, yeah?
Includes ammo.
You won't do better, let's go.
You got the cash, huh?
- Um.
No, I think we'll
find Fagan, mate.
- Hey, hey, mate, Fagan
ain't doing guns no more.
She's going straight.
Yeah, let's go, okay.
Are we on or what?
Huh?
Okay, okay, now what's up, boys?
Let's go.
Um, a grand, that's it.
- Look mate, I think, really,
I think we'll pass, okay?
- You'll pass?
Mate, mate this thing
will smash anything
within 100 meters.
What's the problem, huh?
- No, we just need to think
about this, all right?
- You need to think about it?
What's your game, man?
Are you undercovers?
Just look at this guy, man.
- Hey, we're not.
Relax.
- Relax?
How about I just take it--
- Hey.
- Keep your gun, maybe
that's a fair deal.
- Of course I want
it, I want it, yeah.
Mate, you've got to understand.
Chill, please.
Please?
- Chill it,
huh?
- Okay, I came here to find
Fagan, do you understand?
So you've got to throw
in Fagan's address.
$750 is all I got, though.
Deal?
- Get rid of it.
Mate, hey.
- Yeah, okay.
Keep a look out, will you?
- I can't believe
we bought a gun.
- I know.
But if I hadn't, he might
have put a bullet in us.
Plus I got the address.
Did you see how
wired he was, man?
- Yes, it was a very
uncomfortable situation.
- Hello!
Can you keep a look out?
- For what?
- I'm about to break in.
- Mate, no.
- Just keep a look out.
Just hang back, all right?
Hello?
Is anybody here?
- Hurry up.
- Hang back.
- Sallie's?
Hey, hide.
Hide!
- Don't fuckin' move.
Get down.
Stay there.
Where is it?
Where is the address?
- On the table.
- Jodi, 88 Shephard
Street, this is it?
This is the address?
- Yeah, yeah.
- Did you have to do that?
- Let's just get out of here.
- Okay, okay, I'll
call the cops.
- Wait, wait, wait,
wait, wait, wait.
Let's just take a minute
to think about this.
- Mate, I'm leaving
right now, come on.
- Just wait.
- Mate, we've got to go.
Come on!
- Fagan?
- Oh, shit!
Oh, shit!
What the fuck?
- Fagan?
- Down, get down!
Get down!
- Hey, hey!
Get down, down, down, down.
- Don't kill me, don't
kill me, please, please!
Take whatever you want,
keep the elephant.
- I don't want the elephant.
I want my girlfriend.
- I don't know where she is.
- What are you doing here?
- Why did you kill Fagan?
- We didn't.
What are you going to
do, fry him to death?
Right, now you're going to
tell us what's going on.
- I'm not telling you shit.
- Uh-huh.
- Come on boys, come on.
What are you going to do?
Don't kill me, please.
- You're going to tell
me where the fuck Sallie is.
- You either tell
us or tell the police, mate.
Because that's where
we're going now.
- No, I don't think so.
Because I'm sure they'd
love to hear how we met.
As I remember it, you
were standing over
Fagan Smallman's dead body
with a gun in your hand.
I reckon that'll interest them
more than your missing
girlfriend's purse.
Oh yeah, and if I
remember correctly
I saw you put a bullet in her.
No, no, no!
I'll talk to the cops!
Please, let me out!
- Do you think
he's okay in there?
- Let me out of here!
- Max
Raven recalls Sallie
on the phone before
she disappeared.
- Yeah, we talked
about catching up.
Her seeing Mum and Dad,
nothing that would
be of any help.
- You realize you were the
last person to talk to her
before she went missing?
- No, I hadn't.
- Did she
mention who she talked to
on the other call?
- No.
- You're positive?
- Yeah.
- Was there a reason
you called her?
- She's my sister.
She'd just got in,
I wanted to say hi.
I haven't seen
her for six years.
- What are we doing here?
- Ah, audition.
Audition.
- Great.
Where do we go next,
drop him off at yoga?
You can let go of me.
I'm not going anywhere.
- Sure.
- Listen, I don't have a choice.
I just want to get the elephant,
get my money, and
get out of here.
You help me do
that, it's all good.
- Hey, and what
about Sallie, huh?
- What about Fagan?
- So where are we driving to?
- His place.
- What?
Why?
There's nothing there.
Oh, shit!
- Shit.
What do we do?
- I've got the address.
G'day, mate.
- What do you want?
- I don't know how to
tell you this but, um,
I believe your daughter
Susie has an elephant
which belongs to me, and
I really need it back.
- She traded that at school.
- Look, I really
have to have it back.
- Sorry mate, there's no way
I'm going to break my
little angel's heart.
- What about for a--
- Susie?
- At least I've never
made a little kid cry.
- You're a drug runner, right?
- Fuck you, arsehole.
- You're the arsehole.
- Hey, oh, Max.
- Hey!
You tell me right now.
Why did Fagan have
Sallie's purse, why?
- Okay, okay!
- Why?
- Let go, let go.
I would have told you
anyway, like I fucking care.
- Good.
- It was the first time
I'd ever smuggled anything.
I didn't know what it was.
I didn't want to know.
When we landed in Sydney,
everything went wrong.
I started feeling real sick.
I didn't know if it
was me freaking out,
or the bloody airplane food.
I just didn't think I could
hold it together enough
to get through
customs, you know.
So I gave the purse to Fagan
so she could get the elephant.
I just couldn't do it.
- Pull over.
- Hey, hey, hey,
what are you doing?
Just leave it.
Don't open them.
- Hey, hey.
- Chill.
- Are
you bloody serious?
- All right, they're
mine, they're mine!
- Hey, hey, hey!
- Hey!
You can have them when
I get Sallie back.
- Mate, I have to
hand them over.
I'm not fucking
around, I need them!
- You can have them
back when we get Sallie.
I don't want the
diamonds, you understand?
- I don't think you understand.
- Do you know much
about diamonds?
- No, that's why I'm here.
- This is a rough diamond, and,
you don't have a Kimberly
Process Certificate?
- Mate, I'm just
after some help.
If you can't point me
in the right direction,
that's, that's cool.
- No, no, that's fine.
Just hang on a second.
No, he doesn't know a
thing about diamonds.
- Look, I really feel it's time
we got the police involved.
We got the diamonds.
Why not just give
them to the cops?
- No, hold on to these.
Keep them well hidden, okay?
Oi, oi.
You even think about
stealing those diamonds,
I'll make it my life's
mission to find you
and kill you.
You understand?
- Yeah, whatever.
- Max, I don't feel
good about this.
What's the plan, mate?
- Well,
if anything comes up
will you let us know?
- Yeah.
- No matter how small.
- Sorry, Max, the
front door was open.
- That's okay, mate.
- Any clues to what happened?
- Yeah, look, I, um,
I'm not coping so well with
Sallie's disappearance.
I got a bit upset.
- Do you mind if we--
- No, of course.
- You
ever heard of a woman
called Fagan Smallman?
- Doesn't ring any bells.
- She was found dead
recently in her apartment.
- Right, is that related
to Sallie's disappearance?
- She was a member of
a local chess club.
- Yeah, how does
that concern me?
- Apparently
you made a visit
to this chess club.
- So I had a game of chess.
- Have you ever heard
of conflict diamonds?
- Yeah, sure.
- There have been a lot
of deaths over them.
Civil wars, Mr. Raven.
- That's not something I
want to get involved in.
- Yeah, well I reckon
you are involved.
I think you're out
there playing detective.
- Mate, I've just come
back to this country
for a couple auditions.
- Do you think we're idiots?
- Of course I'm
looking for Sallie!
- Just calm down.
- Do you understand,
is that okay?
- Is there anything
you want to tell us?
- No.
- That's it, then.
- I hope you know what
you're doing, Mr. Raven.
- It's okay, mate.
- I'm gonna have to go.
- The food's almost ready.
- Yeah I know.
Look, it's to do with Sallie
I can't really talk about it.
- No?
It's okay.
- So, after, after D5
there's a knight exchange
and then black will have
to retreat, say, to E7.
And as the white
tries to exploit the,
the pole weakness
on the queen's side
black will counter play
on the king's side.
Too fast?
- Yeah, just a little
mate, just a little.
- Sorry, I'm not good at this.
I'm not good at this teaching.
- Well, you're
passionate about it.
That's all you need
really, to be a teacher.
A good teacher.
- You teach?
- Ahh, yep, yep, science.
11 years.
- 11 years?
- Yeah.
- That would do my head in.
- Actually, it is good to
have a bit of time off.
- You call this a holiday?
- You ever tried
to explain the laws
of the universe to kids
with behavioral problems?
- Good at science and such
a shitty chess player,
how does that work?
- On the ground!
On the ground, both of you.
On the ground and
don't fuckin' move.
Check the house, mate.
Now stay down and shut up!
- Hey!
Now drop the gun.
- Don't be stupid, mate.
- I've got the diamonds.
- Then just hand them over
and let's end this now.
- You think
I'd keep them here?
- What do you want?
- I want my girlfriend.
You bring her and I'll give
you your fucking diamonds.
- Where?
- Hawthorne Canal,
under the West Link.
Two hours.
- The diamonds.
- Where's Sallie?
- Where are the stones?
I'm not fucking around here.
- I just want to
see Sallie's okay.
- The diamonds are
all that concerns me.
- Okay, you've got your
diamonds, where's Sallie?
- Hey, hey, where's my money?
I never got paid.
- Where's Sallie?
- Wait!
- I just want--
- Wait a minute!
- Have you got her or what?
Hey!
- Fuck!
- I can't believe
you didn't use it.
At least when they were
in the car driving off
you could've blown out
a window or something.
- Hey, hey mate, this
is all new to us, okay?
We don't normally go
around blowing out windows.
- He's right, I
should have used it.
- Ah, I'm so fucked.
You boys have completely
fucked this up.
They have the diamonds, your
girlfriend, and my money.
And what do we have?
Nothing.
- Shut up!
- I'm not scared of you.
Especially after how
you just handled that.
I mean, if Sallie's found dead
you can blame yourself
after that balls-up.
- Hey, hey, hey, leave
him Max, leave him.
- You're an idiot.
- Leave him!
Hey, we don't need this!
- You thought you could
handle these blokes?
What are you,
James fucking Bond?
You're a bloody actor,
probably a lousy one.
There are people I owe
money to, impatient people.
You gonna protect me from them?
Damn right.
I should be busting your
ass for fucking this up.
- Hey, hey, hey, hey!
Jesus!
- I'm a dead man!
- Fucking stay there.
- What, that's it, not a word?
- What do you want
us to say, Perry?
Eh, eh?
- You want us to ask why
or how you're a dead man?
Because I can tell you at this
moment, I don't care, mate.
- Well, fuck you too.
And your mate.
- Hey, hey, hey,
where are you going?
- Let him go.
- Perry!
Where you going?
We're behaving like
people I don't know
and I don't want to know.
Guns, mate.
Kidnap.
Murder.
Conflict diamonds,
drug smuggling.
You know the most exciting
thing that happened to me
before this was getting
my wisdom teeth out.
Mate, can we just stop
and have a real hard think
about what we're doing here?
- I'm sorry, man.
I need a place to stay.
What?
- I can't.
- Why not?
- I just can't, Max.
- Hey.
Any news?
- Not really.
- I'm worried, Max.
- I'm gonna find her.
If it's the last thing I
do, I'm gonna find her.
- Yeah, I know.
- Okay.
Listen, I need to
ask you something.
- Okay, what?
- I need a place to stay.
Hello?
- Hey, look.
I'm worried about Perry.
I think he's gonna
get killed, mate.
- What's that got to do with us?
- Max, I don't want
blood on our hands, okay?
I'm calling the police now.
If there's anything
you need to do, right,
to protect yourself--
- You can't call
the police, okay?
We put a bullet.
- What, Fagan?
Mate, she was already dead.
- Cops don't know that.
It ain't gonna make
any difference to them.
- What if Perry is
telling the truth, okay?
Then these guys
are gonna kill him.
- Perry?
You in there, Perry?
- Hey, Perry!
Oi!
- You can wait here a minute.
- Oh.
- Jesus!
I'll get the cops.
- Oh, shit!
Sh--
- Hey, don't touch anything.
- We're not action heroes, mate.
School teacher, actor, mate.
That's it.
- Fuck, let's go.
- The police
haven't told us much.
- No, me neither.
- Well, it's nice to see
you after such a long time.
Manners, look, this is Max.
- Hi, Max.
- Hello, you must be Violet.
Sallie's told me
a lot about you.
- So you
can't sleep, huh?
Would you like me
to read you a story?
Okay, say goodnight.
- Goodnight.
- 'Night.
Look, Joe, I, uh,
I want you to know
I'm doing everything I
can to find your daughter.
- Oh, thanks, Max.
But I think we'll leave
it all to the police.
- Oh, hi, Sallie.
It's Bill here,
Jodie's neighbor.
Umm, I've just got a me--
- Hi, Sal, it's Jacky.
Um, I really need to
speak to you so I'll try--
- Hi,
Sal, it's Victoria.
You guys have probably landed.
I can't wait to see you.
Hope you had a good trip.
Give me a call, lots of love.
- She told you everything, yeah?
Was she involved in anything?
Anything I didn't know about?
- What do you mean?
- You just start to wonder
whether you really
knew somebody.
- Of course you did.
- What about the
last phone call?
Was there anything that she
said out of the ordinary?
Anything stuck in your mind?
- Well, she was still upset.
- Yeah.
- It must have been
hard on both of you.
She wanted to keep
the baby, Max.
I mean, she knew you didn't,
she understood that, but,
it was really tough for her.
And she said she wishes
she hadn't chosen a name.
Anais?
- Yeah.
- You, you okay?
- Yep.
- Can I get you another?
- Yeah, maybe one more.
- Hey, Max.
I have to talk to you.
We need to meet up.
- How long is it since
you've spoken to them?
- It's been a while.
- Even your little sister?
- Yeah.
You know, I never thought
that you and Sallie
would stay together.
- Well, we did.
Come on, I went all the way to
South Africa to be with her.
- Maybe she's left
you for someone else?
- No.
I love your sister.
- It's a possibility, Max.
- No, it's not.
- It is.
- Yeah, well look I don't
want to hear it anymore.
I won't listen anymore.
- It's just a possibility.
- Later.
- Where are they?
Where are they?
- What?
- We're only talking
about diamonds.
- Where's Sallie?
- Sallie?
Who the fuck's Sallie?
- Violet?
Violet?
Oh, my god.
- Look, I don't have them.
if had 'em, I would
give them to you.
All I want is Sallie, that's it.
Nothing else.
- What about
that mate of his?
The one who had the
diamonds under the bridge.
- Hey, he wouldn't
take them, all right?
- Yeah, hey, what's his address?
What's his address?
- All right, he's got a
fuckin' family, all right,
he'd never do it.
- Ahh, he got a family.
And you want your girl back.
You want your girl back?
- Yeah.
- Oh, Jesus Christ.
- Okay, now who has
the fuckin' diamonds?
Huh?
Come on.
I'm going to start putting
a hole into this fucker
until someone's dead.
- Not peeping?
Ready,
and pop!
Open.
Do you love that?
- Yeah.
- Okay, you can have that.
What are you gonna call her?
- Isabella.
- Isabella, lovely.
Now, look at this.
Do you think that's pretty?
- Yeah.
- It's this way.
- Fuckin' better be.
- Jacky, where are they?
- What?
- Where are they?
- I don't know what
you're on about.
- I stuck a bag of
diamonds in your toilet.
With packets of diamonds in 'em.
Now one of the
packets is missing.
I ain't fucking
around, where are they?
Where are they?
- I sold them.
- What?
Sold them?
- Yeah, I did.
- You sold them?
- Well, it's your fucking fault
for hiding them in my toilet.
- My fucking fault?
- I've got this shitty crappy
life and I come across them.
What the fuck did you
expect me to do with them?
- You're insane.
You're insane!
- What are you involved in?
What?
Fuck that, right?
Where's the money,
have you got the money?
- I spent it.
- You spent it?
- Yeah on my
shitty, crappy life.
- On your shitty, crappy life.
- To make it a bit better.
- Great.
That's fucking great.
- What were you
doing hiding diamonds here?
- My place isn't safe.
- Well, I sold them.
- Great.
Well, we need to get 'em back.
Where are they?
- Pawn shop.
- Pawn shop, right.
Get your things together.
We're going there now.
- I was just getting
my life back on track.
And then you
started to came back
and started to fuck it up again.
- Sallie and Richard's life
are in danger right
now, all right?
So you're gonna get
your shit together
and we're leaving now.
Now!
- Max, please, stop.
I can't, I can't do it.
He's not gonna give them back.
What do you mean he's not
going to give them back?
I'm going to put
a gun to his face.
- Oh, fuck!
This is...
I'm just gonna go, okay?
Please.
- Look, they're
conflict diamonds.
He has bought conflict diamonds.
He's not gonna call the cops.
- I can't, Max, okay?
Please.
- Don't worry about Richard,
don't worry about your sister.
Give me your car keys.
Good on ya.
- Sweetie.
It's okay, darling.
Oh, shhh!
Shhh, it's okay.
Are you all right, darling?
Ohh.
Shhh.
- Yes, Jacky.
- Don't you fucking move.
- Max.
- Richard about?
- Um, yeah, you might
find him down there.
- No, he's not in the car.
Is he not home?
- He hasn't set foot
inside this house
for over three months, Max.
- Really?
- There's a lot of
things Richard hasn't told you.
- Mummy?
- Is Felix okay?
- He's fine.
- Okay, um.
Do you mind if I hang
about and wait for him?
- Sure.
- Thank you.
- And when you see him, tell
him to move his bloody car.
It's embarrassing.
- I want Sallie and Richard.
I'm not fucking around!
- Neither are we!
- The diamonds, mate.
- Hey!
Richard, Sallie, no tricks.
I want my girlfriend.
- I told you so
many fucking times!
We do not have her.
- Police!
Police, don't move!
- Gun shots being fired.
Suspects heading
north on Sutton Ave.
- What do you want, mate?
- Look, I'm really
sorry I left you, mate.
- Take some time.
- Are you okay?
- I'll survive.
- You and Monica?
- Divorced.
- You didn't want to tell me?
- You didn't ask.
- And what, you don't have
anywhere else to live?
- No, not really.
At least I get to see
Felix this way, eh?
- You really are
fucked up, aren't you?
- What?
- I'm leaving.
- Yeah right, mate, okay.
Hey!
- I'm leaving.
- What the fuck's
wrong with your head?
- I don't know.
- Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey.
I should be pissed at you.
You put my life in danger.
- I know man, I'm fucked!
Sallie knew it, everyone
fucking knows it.
- Don't, don't do
the Poor Max routine.
- I'm not, mate, I'm not.
- Giving me shit, mate.
- I'm not.
I'm just telling you to
get out of my life, man.
- You know, mate, I realize
what you're really good at.
Weak as piss,
mate, weak as piss.
- Is this yours?
- Yeah.
A friend gave it to me.
- This friend of yours,
is he in the photo?
- That bloke.
- Good friends, are you?
- More acquaintances.
Oi.
- What'd you do to Fagan, man?
- Sorry?
- Is there something you want?
- Look, I've lost his details
and I desperately need
to get in touch with him.
Can you help me?
- Well, why don't
you give me yours
and if I see him
I'll let him know.
- Look, I gave you
an address and a gun
and next thing I know she
got her brains blown out.
Don't take a super sleuth to
see a connection now, huh?
- You know, I really
wanted to surprise him.
- He really
doesn't like surprises.
- I didn't kill her.
- Look, what do you
want from us, man?
Why are you pressin' us?
- The blokes who did kill
Fagan, I need to find 'em.
- Are you gonna give
me your details?
Because if you're not,
there's nothing more
I can do for you.
- I thought I told
you to piss off.
- Well, my
hearing's going, I reckon.
- You want me to
say it out louder?
- Mate, I've known
you since I was seven.
You reckon you're going to
get rid of me that easily, eh?
- Ricky...
Go back to Monica.
- She doesn't want me.
- Neither do I.
- I'm sorry I've been
such a shit to you.
You okay?
- I don't know what to do.
- It'll be okay.
- Just go, okay?
I don't want you here, I
don't want you in my life.
Okay.
If anything happens
to you, not my fault.
Hey!
- So that's how it's
going to be, is it?
- Just need to know
if you have my woman.
- What's with this chick?
You're a dumb fuck.
I don't have your bitch.
- Calm down, calm down!
Hey Max--
- Stay there.
You stay there.
- You don't know
what you're doing.
You're fuckin' in
over your head.
So why don't you leave it
and piss off before you
get yourself killed?
- Don't come any closer.
You tell me what's
happened to Sallie.
- You're weak as piss.
Give us the fucking gun, eh?
- No!
Fuck you!
- We gotta go.
This is bad, mate, really bad.
All right, I'll get
the car, you stay here.
Just help me.
- I don't know if
this is a good idea.
- Are you kidding, mate?
You were holding him
when he was shot.
Do you know how easy it
is to link him to us?
Not fucking around
mate, let's go!
- I don't
think anyone saw us.
- Mate, have you
fucking watched TV?
Shit, they're gonna trace
to us like fucking CSI.
- Let's just get this
fucking body out of the boot.
- Yeah.
- Oh!
I think you're gonna win.
Your go.
- I want number six.
- Number six.
Yes!
One, two, three,
you can jump four.
- I wanna see Mummy.
- Aren't we having fun?
- But I still miss Mummy.
- Violet, listen to me, darling.
Please sweetie,
sweetheart, stop.
I need you to listen.
Mummy's not your real mummy.
I am.
Do you understand, sweetie?
I know it's confusing, darling.
Hey?
- I wanna go home.
- Don't you want to
spend some more time with me?
- You won't go on your own
because you know I'm right.
- She gave her to me.
- You took her away.
- She couldn't have
looked after her.
- She just wants to
start caring for her child.
- Well, she didn't
care at the time.
- She didn't know
what she wanted.
We need to pull together.
- This family has
never been together.
- You know I'm leaving?
- Yeah.
- I can't stay.
- Jacky,
what's happening?
You're using again, huh?
- No.
Just a few times.
It's been fucking tough, okay?
- Yeah.
It's been tough.
- Max, we could be together.
- I'm going, Jacky.
- Wait.
Max, please.
Look, please.
- I made my decision
back then, okay?
- I'm leaving
tomorrow with Violet.
- Is Violet your daughter?
- No.
She's ours.
- Hello?
- I'm keeping her.
- I'll call the police.
- Do it.
She's my child.
- She's mine legally.
- You took
advantage of me.
- Advantage?
You gave birth to her
on the bathroom floor.
We've all lived
through your drugs.
I'm not allowing Violet
to go through it too.
- I have been clean for a year.
I've got a job and a unit.
I'm ready to look after her.
- Have you told her anything?
- I will.
- Sallie is missing.
Why are you doing this now?
- Darling, stay away from that.
Sweetie, get away.
- Is she okay?
Let me speak to her.
- She's fine.
I need your signature
to get Violet a visa.
- What?
Never, I'll never sign it.
- You will, or you'll
never see her again.
- Jacky, please.
Please just bring her home.
- I just,
I just want my daughter.
- Well, I'm not
letting you take her.
- Sweetie, get away.
- Hello.
Whoa!
What's going on?
Darling, are you okay?
Can you wait outside?
Are you okay?
- Yeah.
- Just wait there, okay?
Jacky?
Jacky.
Ohh.
Oh, shit.
- Max.
Max!
We need to talk.
- We think we may
have found Sallie.
- A body washed up at Bondi.
We think it's her.
- I didn't do enough.
- We did
everything we could, mate.
- I could've done more.
- There was nothing else
we could have done, Max.
- I just,
I'm gonna...
I just really, really
wanna hurt him.
- I'm leaving now.
- What, where?
- Just help me.
- Jacky, I'm kinda
busy right now.
- You have my car and you
are bringing it here now
to get me and your daughter.
- Jacky?
Jacky, we know you're in there!
Jacky!
Violet!
- Mummy!
- Darling, please!
- Just go.
- Here we go.
- I've been followed.
- Move.
- Hey, it's all right.
Listen, are you okay?
- Yes.
- Yeah?
- Yes, yes.
- Let's get the
fuck out of this.
- Yes, yes.
- Let's go.
- Don't try and stop me.
- Jacky, what about Violet?
Does the name Anais
mean anything to you?
- I really want you
out of my life, Max.
- Did you know Sallie
had an abortion?
Jacky, did Sallie
know Violet was ours?
Did you tell her?
Did you, Jacky?
- It's me.
Are you alone?
- Yeah, what's wrong?
- Come on, I need to know!
- You know what?
I think I'm gonna take
you home to Irene.
- Can't we stay
a little longer please?
- That's a
good idea actually.
We'll just stay a
little bit longer.