They say things happen for a reason.
That everything is part of some grand plan.
The truth is there are actions,
and there are consequences.
We live and die by them.
And somewhere in this mess
{ calf "the fife"...
it just clicked.
The perfect plan.
Such a plan.
God knows [ never meant to hurt anyone.
Made a match on the Moreling case?
Yeah.
I was able to rebuild his jaw here,
and the bite mark...
South America again?
Getting out a week from Friday,
lest you forget.
You're wasting your talents here.
You let me do my thing...
and the dead patients don't sue.
I find that gratifying.
I know a lot of places
they'd kill for a brilliant oral surgeon.
Places that wouldn't give
a shit about your past.
Or the fact that some supermodel got lucky
in court and ruined your career.
She's publishing a book now
about her ordeal.
Got a reporter stirring
up all that crap again.
- You'd think, after four years...
- Yeah, you got a raw deal.
Don't ever think I take for granted
what you did for me.
You've been a real friend.
I mean that.
Nothing. Just sort of misplaced a body...
maybe.
One of these days,
I want a ride in your plane.
You better make it soon.
My wife's threatened to liquidate that, too.
Know what the most valuable thing
in this world is?
Your good name. Your reputation.
You dirty your name,
you can never wash it clean.
It's the only part of you that lives forever.
Dr. Tyler?
Hi. Maury Newman.
We talked on the phone. I'm writing
the book about Ashley Commerford.
Oh, yeah.
It's going to print in five days.
You could still be the final chapter.
She lied and ruined my life.
What else do you want to know?
I don't get it.
Why wouldn't you want to tell
your side of the story?
- What's the story you're looking for?
- "Justice isn't blind to beauty."
If she hadn't been a top model,
none of this would have happened to you.
Come on, Doctor! Think about it.
This isn't exactly your old BMW, is it?
I don't need my old BMW.
I need to go to the store
without people whispering behind me.
Or sticking cameras
where they don't belong.
Do you understand?
She's in every magazine,
on every daytime show.
The infection was foreseeable.
You should tell your side of the story.
You can't take the high road.
You did nothing wrong. We'll appeal.
What happened to her face is a tragedy.
He explicitly warned Miss Commerford
not to travel to Thailand.
Evening, Kye.
Got another foreclosure notice today.
Did that reporter get hold of you?
Yeah, he ambushed me
right outside the office.
Wants me on some rancid TV show.
- Nothing fucking works in this house.
- Play the part of some helpless victim.
- We can't eat pride, Max.
- Then spend less.
That wasn't the deal.
I married a doctor, not a mortician.
I'm just getting a little more respect
these days from the dead.
- What are you gonna do?
- Sell the plane.
Then we'll have some cash.
Honey, at your pace...
we're not gonna have any cash.
As it is, you're living on bounced checks.
So what is this?
Another 80-proof night in the town?
I still haven't given up on my life.
Everyone always said my brother
was the good one.
A heart so big,
you could pour an ocean into it.
Could have made a fortune,
never broke a sweat.
All that made him happy was putting a smile
on some hungry kid's face.
I remember the day his boat exploded
in Guatemala.
That's the day I stopped believing in God.
Stop it. Go home, Romeo.
Sit down, Dr. Tyler.
- Have you chosen your PIN number?
- Yes.
- What's the matter?
- God, not here.
Where, then?
Come on.
The trust account's in your name now.
I'm the executive on the account.
You're the only one
who can use that PIN code.
Not even your lawyer can use that.
My wife, Kye, can't freeze anything now?
No.
You gotta write her out.
You don't give her anything.
She doesn't get shit.
She's a lazy bitch.
I'm gonna come.
You better relax.
Wendy, I'd like to see you
in my office, please.
If something comes up,
you got $3,000 in the box downstairs.
Fuck, we're really gonna do this.
After four years of hard labor, honey,
I sure hope so.
Hi, Wendy.
- What the hell was that?
- Professional jealousy.
- Thank you for choosing New Union.
- Thank you.
The service here is outstanding.
Roger, Delta One.
We have received your distress call.
Can we have your coordinates, please?
Delta One, do you copy?
Delta One, come in.
My brother was about to live again.
Man...
you wouldn't find this place on any map.
Mr. Salent?
You're ready?
It's not a real burn.
The prints will grow back in a month or two.
The face...
May I see the face?
{ wondered,
“ "Would anyone really miss Dr. Max Tyler?"”
At least Maury Newman would have
a perfect closing chapter to his story.
Yeah, it's Max. No doubt.
He's got a lot of life insurance.
Any signs of foul play?
That's it, then.
Insurance company will take it from here.
Sorry about your friend.
Cut the legal horseshit.
Here's the deal.
Of the three insurance notes, $3 million
is to be paid into a charitable trust...
to be managed by Eva Cruz.
You will receive the house
and all other assets...
including a Meissen mantel clock,
an original Pekkari print...
and a '92 Chevy Tahoe...
I spent the last four years in hell, and if
this tramp thinks she's gonna get a cent...
- Listen, you never even cared for him...
- It's my money, you whore!
Hold on!
- I'll fucking kill you!
- Ladies, stop it!
Checkmate.
What did you find unique
about your brother?
I think my brother had a compassion.
He had a compassion for people that I don't.
They used to say he had the heart...
I had the brains.
I envied that son of a bitch.
Brother, would you relax?
What are you so scared of, Max?
I'll never let nothing bad happen to you.
My man! Yeah. Give me five!
Relax.
It's just Captain Cordillo.
Give me those cigarettes.
Just bribe him with a few cigarettes...
he lets me help the people.
Only the good die young?
Guatemala, back in '92.
He was a human rights activist.
"Hand in hand,
all headlong hurl ourselves..."
"And on the ragged stones,
beat forth our brains..."
"To make a mutual closure of our house."
- Mister, have a cigar?
- All right.
- Two cigars?
- You take every last dollar I have, okay?
Thank you.
- Ball for sale, sir.
- No, thank you.
Hi, you've reached Eva Cruz, please leave...
Mr. Tyler.
When did you lose your passport?
That's why I'm here.
I haven't the faintest recollection.
Mr. Tyler, are you aware
that you've been missing for eight years?
The world had pretty much written you off...
as deceased.
If that's the consensus,
I'm just gonna say the world's wrong.
Where have you been, Mr. Tyler?
As I said, I was in the south.
I was with the Indians.
And had you been held against your will
or anything like that?
No, I was in Guatemala.
I was traveling up the Machaquila River.
Evidently, there was a fire
in the engine room...
and subsequently an explosion.
So you don't remember?
When they fished me out,
I was suffering from a concussion.
- A prolonged amnesia can be serious.
- Quite frankly, it's been hell.
But I'm feeling fine now.
In fact, I feel good.
Just wanna get my passport back.
Repatriation requires certain protocols,
and should everything check out...
then you should be home
in a couple of days.
Jeffrey, if you could process Mr. Tyler
for repatriation, please?
Since we can't use your prints...
it's gonna take an extra day
summoning your dental records.
Please enter your account code now.
Your balance is $3 million.
For any other services, please press 1.
No, that's good, that's real good.
Yes, sirree bob.
Yeah?
Is something wrong?
{ just ran up the stairs. You okay?
Where have you been?
Running around, getting stuff ready.
They screwed up our plane tickets.
How is the Kye situation?
{ think we're home free.
God, I can't wait to see what you look like.
I look good, I look real good.
Things are gonna be a lot more fun
being him than it was being me.
Hurry. I want you to hurry.
I'm gonna fill up the tub with champagne.
Eva, listen to me.
I love you.
I'm gonna call you as soon as I land.
All right?
Okay. { love you, foo. Bye.
Mr. Tyler?
I'm afraid I've got some bad news for you.
Pay your parking tickets.
Private.
- Good luck, sir.
- Thank you, sir.
- Welcome home, Mr. Tyler.
- Thank you.
Welcome to New Union Bank.
For account information,
please press 1 now.
For account balance,
please enter your account number...
followed by the pound key.
Please enter your PIN code now.
Thank you. Your account balance is zero.
For other services, please press 1.
I'll stay calm when you tell me
how six hours ago I had $3 million...
and now I'm sitting with fuck-all?
There was a wire transfer authorized
this afternoon.
I did not authorize a wire transfer!
You need a fucking PIN code
to authorize a wire transfer!
Your PIN authorization
is on the transfer, sir.
Good morning.
That's a nice silk scarf you're wearing.
It complements your eyes.
- Thank you.
- Maybe you could help me.
I just got off a plane. I'm so damned tired.
I'm conducting an inquiry.
Actually, it's a case of fraud.
I'm working for an insurance firm.
Let me get this straight for you.
You got a...
You had an employee by the name of Eva.
Eva Cruz.
If she would have left
a forwarding address...
that would certainly serve our purposes.
- You're an investigator?
- Yes, ma'am.
I knew there was something off about her.
Some loser died
and left her in charge of a chunk of money.
She sailed out of here like royalty.
I bet she gets a big kick out of us having
to serve her as a prime client now.
All her settlement is still in this bank?
She's transferring the money
to a bank in the Caymans.
But I'm having it held.
She had someone cut corners trying
to move the money out of the trust it was in.
So I'm making her come in to sign a waiver.
She's coming here?
When is she coming in here?
Now.
Oh, my God.
Max?
- How did you find us?
- Look at your face.
You!
Get the fuck off!
What did you do?
What the fuck is this?
Stop it, Max!
Stop it!
Where the fuck is it?
Now we know where we all stand.
Look at you, Max.
Look at yourself.
Never give your trust to anyone.
It's the cardinal rule of hustling, right?
Shut the fuck up.
You know, Kye and I, we go way back.
Back to the old days.
As soon as she found out
what you were up to, she called me.
The rest was easy.
Will you fucking shut up?
Should have kept her in the money, Max.
You stop that transfer.
You withdraw everything. You hear me?
The reality of a divorce
is that you split things evenly.
The way I see it,
there are three of us standing here.
We split it three ways.
I ain't splitting shit.
You got different destinations here?
Are you two splitting up?
That's too bad.
You make a hell of a good-looking couple.
I'm not negotiating, girls.
- Fuck you.
Fuck you. I'd rather turn us in.
Go ahead.
Hi, yes, I'd like to report an emergency.
I'm at the Plaza Hotel. Room 508.
Hang up.
Yes, I'd like to report gross insurance fraud
and other shit that doesn't have a name.
No, it is an emergency.
It's life and death.
My name?
My name is Eva...
I'm fucking out of here!
Go ahead.
No!
The women didn't check out.
They had fake IDs.
Torn-up plane tickets in different names.
He's delirious. Lower the dosage.
How'd you do it, Sam?
How'd you survive the boat?
You never got on that boat.
You bought up the hit?
You remember Cortez?
Nobody forgets a bloodbath like that.
You tell me what I want to know,
or I'll handle this the way you would have...
and believe me, you don't want that.
Where the hell am I?
Why do you stroll into a consulate
and break a perfect cover?
The consulate.
My passport.
Were you trying to send a message?
Network still active?
I don't know.
Hey, Doc, you got something for amnesia?
I don't know what you're talking about.
Get me out of this!
Get the fuck away from me!
Was your younger brother working for you?
What's his name?
Max, the doctor.
All those trips
to South America in his plane.
What was he doing? Acting as your courier?
Then Max goes and dies.
Now you got a problem.
Because he's your go-between,
your link to the old world.
Business is on hold...
so you go to the consulate to try and get
a message to someone who can help.
Someone from the old days. Is that it?
Give me something so I can help you, Sam.
I'm not Sam.
I'm his brother.
It's gonna be a long night.
No!
Mr. Crawley's on the line.
He wants an update on the situation.
Right, better think about talking, Sam...
'cause if Crawley has to come down here,
he won't be as nice to you as I've been.
Sam, do we need the girl?
Sam, what did they do to you?
Open up. Swallow.
Swallow.
Who is she?
Met her in Belize.
Belize? That's where you've been hiding?
I don't recall.
What?
Sam, it's me. You can drop the damn act.
You do remember me, right, Sam?
You remember me, right?
Yes.
Four years, I've been living like a roach.
I've been eating people's shit.
Show me the money, Sam.
Sam, it's my payday.
I'm gonna get you something to eat.
Get you some clothes.
Don't go outside. All our friends are dead.
Don't worry about this,
we're gonna figure this out.
We're gonna put it back together,
piece by piece.
Just like Humpty Dumpty.
Just like him.
I'm out of here.
You know what's out there?
- Let's get the money and get out of here.
- You're going nowhere.
Not with my money.
No, baby, that's our money.
I worked just as hard as you for that money.
That is our money, Max.
- Get over it.
- Get over what?
You tried to play Kye,
and she played you first.
Have you any shame?
Or hasn't it dawned on you
those people killed Kye?
Now you got two things left in the world.
You have him and me.
You're not going anywhere...
till I find out whatever the hell it is
my brother got himself mixed up in.
Who the fuck that is, I don't know.
And I don't know what it is
these people want from me.
I don't know what the hell is going on here,
but until we do...
if he leads, we follow.
You understand?
This is Pope. Get me Crawley on the line.
- You're gonna play some tennis today?
- Yeah, the weather looks good.
- And you, boys?
- Maybe later. After swimming.
Yeah, this is Crawley.
I'm afraid I got some bad news, Mr. Crawley.
Hold on.
What happened?
Sam got away. He had help.
It has to be someone from the old days.
This is not how I planned my retirement.
You've got to find them
before they disappear again.
The information they have
could destroy us all. Do you understand?
Very well.
How you doing, sir?
I think you'll find that
to your satisfaction.
How're we doing today? You okay?
Good. You all right?
Good, that's it.
What do you think, bro?
Move down here, do some good?
Time to wake up.
Brought you a shirt and a jacket here.
- I'm all right.
- Come on, try it on.
Come on, put it on.
Where the hell have you been, man?
Man, it's good to see you.
This is for you.
Come on, take it.
Okay, { remember.
I remember I was attached...
to UNICEF as an attaché.
Yeah, that was your specialty,
hiding in plain sight.
Damn, that was a beautiful cover.
What do you mean, "cover"?
To train and supply the rebels
in Central America.
Sam, you were D.C.0O.
Deep Cover Operative, CIA.
Man, what you lost in here
can bring down some high people.
What's your real name?
John Wolfe.
What happened to my exchange program?
The program I developed for those kids?
Sam, we were using them kids as mules.
I think you'll find that
to your satisfaction.
How're we doing today? Good?
You all good? Good.
You built your own little network
inside the CIA.
It was a fantastic operation.
It was all profit. No overhead.
We were moving coca for the Colombians
using the CIA resources.
It was fantastic.
Then a cease-and-desist order
came from upstairs.
You blackmailed the company.
That was the beginning of the end.
They got everyone but me.
And you.
The last thing you did...
before getting on that boat
was hide the money.
Our money, Sam.
- Where's the money?
- We'll find it.
How much is there?
How many zeroes are there?
About $3 million.
$3 million? Sam, we had $250 million.
We had a quarter billion.
Where's the money?
All right, it's a start.
- Where are we going to find it?
- We'll go to San Diego.
It's in the bank.
Who the hell is this Crawley character?
- You don't remember Crawley?
- No.
They mentioned him.
He was the big boy at the CIA.
He's enemy number one, man.
He's the one who made you.
They mentioned something about
some place called Cortez.
Some things about you
that are better off forgotten.
What the hell?
I might as well know everything.
They cleared an airfield near this village.
We'd land our 727s out of Cali there.
It was going great...
till the federales seized the shipment.
You get the snitch,
and killed everyone involved.
Then you went after their families.
Young, old...
didn't matter.
Just left them rotting in the sun.
The only ones who were happy
were the dogs.
Do you remember this man?
Yeah, he came in a couple of days ago.
He was asking me some questions
about one of our clients.
I see.
Couple of days ago, you said?
Can't even really listen to what he says,
you know?
Doesn't even make any sense.
Remember, it was your brother
who did those things, not you.
About tomorrow...
I still have a friend at the bank, Susan.
Maybe she can help us.
We're still gonna need about an hour
together, alone in there.
Why haven't...
We can take care of our problem,
right here and now.
He's gonna kill us, sooner or later.
Self-defense.
I'm a doctor.
Hey, kids, look what daddy brought home.
So I'm thinking about tomorrow and...
Are there any side exits to that bank?
- No.
- What about the cameras?
Pretty much everywhere.
I think I'm gonna wait on the street then,
with the artillery.
So how much money
are we gonna get in cash?
Depends on how much is in the reserve.
Probably no more than $200,000 or $300,000.
So it's a one-stop shop.
So we're gonna have to transfer the balance
to my little account.
So, you know,
this $3 million we're picking up...
it's part of our little contingency funds.
We had a few of them laying around.
But the big money, I mean,
the really big money...
is locked away in Sam's head.
If you want, you know,
we can head down south...
and visit some of the old neighborhood.
See if we can't wake his memory up.
And he trusts you. That's important.
Imagine that payoff.
I'm trying.
$3 million buys you a little time.
$200 million plus...
now, that's freedom.
I'm a bad drunk.
Soam.
You know, you can tell a lot about a man
by his hands.
Is that right?
Strong, shrewd...
capable...
unafraid...
lonely...
I'm not your plaything.
I told you, I was a bad drunk.
You got the account number, right?
Sam, in and out real quick, right?
Just like old times.
Pretty, listen,
I'm gonna be on the phone with my bankers.
Look smart.
Have fun.
So, what's the plan?
Just stay out of my way,
and let me do the talking.
We'll be out of here with the money
before that asshole realizes what happened.
What brings you in?
Remember when I had you
transfer that money to the Caymans?
I need you to reverse it,
and I need to cash it out.
No way there's that much in reserve.
You get us out of here within an hour...
you got $10,000.
Shit.
I'll try.
I need a moneytransfer request.
You have reached the Zurich National Bank.
Please hold for the next available agent.
Hold. Ja, there is a transfer request now.
I'll hold till it goes through.
Yes.
What the hell are you doing?
You see what time it is?
- I know.
- It's been over an hour.
- It'll be here soon.
- He's gonna pick us up now.
- You look familiar.
- Yeah, I get that a lot.
The money's here. Let's go.
Hi, this is Wendy Hall at New Union Bank.
I was told to call this number...
if I had any information
on the man who showed up here.
The transfer is coming now
in the amount of $1.
This is right, $1 U.S., Mr. Deere?
Are you there, Mr. Deere?
I don't know what you're playing.
We got friends.
- Where're you going?
- Come on.
- You told Wolfe that was the only access.
- Why don't you just trust me?
Shit, we gotta go out the front.
There.
Move! Get out of the way!
Going somewhere?
- Now!
- Get down!
What the fuck?
We got him now.
That's all, folks!
Yes, Mr. Crawley.
So what was that mess
at the bank this afternoon?
I wasn't there, but I've got every available
agent down there looking for him.
In other words, it's back to square one.
Reed came across something,
I'm checking into it now.
A couple of months ago...
someone requested
Sam Tyler's dental records.
I don't want play-by-play.
I want results.
Prick.
Why did this coroner's office...
request Sam Tyler's dental records
from 19792.
I don't know.
Come on, get to work!
Sam, you'd never double-cross me, right?
No way in hell you'd double-cross me.
Not after all we've been through, right?
Sam, I'm talking to you.
Get down. Run.
Run!
You don't wanna miss this.
Losers.
Partner, cheated death,
like the old days, right?
We're partners, Sam?
You remember, we're partners?
Damn, that feels good.
Double-crossing bastard, Sam.
After all we've been through,
you're gonna double-cross me?
Today's a good day to die, Sam.
Sam is dead.
- What?
- Sam is dead.
That's right, Sam is dead.
Ease up, he's telling you the truth.
I'm his brother.
Stop it, it's the truth!
I'm a surgeon.
I live in San Diego.
You ever fucking heard of plastic surgery?
Look at him, look at the scars!
- Whose money is in the bag, then?
- It's my settlement.
What settlement?
My insurance.
You're the dentist?
No way! You're the dentist from San Diego?
Sam, man, he always talked about you.
He said you were the smart one.
You wanted to start a new life as Sam Tyler?
You're so stupid.
Damn, I hate dentists.
Stop it!
He's worth more to us alive.
Welcome back to the land of the living, man.
You're my new tradable commodity, brother.
You've been reincarnated now.
You're my cow.
Leave him alone.
Forget about him.
- I knew you had your eyes on me.
- You got me good.
You're a cold-hearted bitch.
I like that.
- That's it.
- We're gonna have a good time.
You got me.
Come on, shoot.
Pussy.
You can't shoot, can you?
Max Tyler, right? Big killer.
You really think I was gonna give you
a loaded gun?
You think I'm that stupid?
You really think I gave you a loaded gun?
What is it?
Nothing.
Just wanna hang around bodegas somehow.
Keep it together.
In an hour,
we're gonna be across the border.
We're gonna keep heading south
on that bus, just like we planned.
We're gonna make it.
Come on.
Let's get out of here.
This way.
Buenas noches, ma'am.
- Two cups of coffee.
- Thank you, ma'am.
Enjoying the show?
I'd probably enjoy it a lot more
if I could trust you.
Max, what we had was...
What did we have?
For the most part, it was real.
It still is.
As long as I'm holding cash.
You tell me that it never crossed
your mind to take the money and split.
You tell me that.
Never.
Everything we've been through...
Come on.
Look how far we've come.
This is me.
I don't know who you are.
Right here, this is me.
Come on, baby, it's right there.
I can't do this.
- I'm not doing it.
- What?
I'm not running no more.
- Running is better than dying.
- Fuck it, we'll cut a deal.
Cut a deal?
I can't cut a deal at this point.
We've got information
for Christ's sake. Let's use it.
Exposure is what they're afraid of.
If Crawley wants to negotiate,
fuck it, let's talk!
I can't do that.
What the hell have you got to lose?
Just come with me on the bus.
Please, just you and me.
This is what we've been waiting for,
a chance to just get the money and go.
Come on.
Okay, here.
You take it.
You keep it.
I'm sorry.
You just be careful.
- I'm sorry for everything.
- Yeah, I know.
- You be careful.
- Yeah, okay.
Just keep walking.
There's a hotel in Guadalajara.
La Pacifica.
I'll be there for a week.
Like last time.
Wait!
{ left a package for you in
a convenience-store bathroom down here...
and you're gonna know where
in about three days.
How do I know
this isn't some kind of bullshit?
"This isn't exactly your old BUW, Mr. Tyler."
Do you remember telling me that?
Max?
Max Tyler?
Hello? Shit.
Judy, can you trace a call for me?
And your name?
Same as it was the last time
I was transferred, honey.
You tell Mr. Crawley...
his former associate, Mr. Sam Tyler,
is on the phone.
Maybe he could avail himself here.
- Just a moment.
- Thank you.
Dr. Max Tyler.
I hope you had a lot of fun
playing your brother.
You're in a lot of trouble.
How would you like me
to respond to that, sir?
I'd like for us to meet,
maybe straighten things out.
Are you gonna bring your household tools?
No need for that now.
Is the man who broke you out
of the factory with you?
Are you referring to John Wolfe?
Yes, I'm referring to John Wolfe.
He's not with me right now.
I assume you'd want something in return
for his whereabouts.
Yes, I would.
I would like a new and a functional identity.
Is that clear?
Where is the woman?
I've got enough evidence
on "Tropic of Cancer"...
for Congress to cancel their lunch break.
Is this beginning to make sense now?
Nobody has that much knowledge,
then there's the burden of proof.
I'd say it's enough to be accused
these days, wouldn't you?
Where are you, Max?
What?
Can I call you Max?
You there?
Are you there, Max?
Max, are you there?
I'll tell you what.
Everything I've got here is on paper.
In about three days,
I'm gonna toss it to the vultures.
You're gonna be on every laptop
from San Diego to Sri Lanka.
You want me to give you
a toll-free number to Career Blazers?
There is no need for that.
Where do I send a car?
You know a little border town
called El Centro?
- It's the old diner off the 8.
- Okay.
Why're we coming all the way out here?
Less to worry about.
Sorry about the Frankenstein routine.
No hard feelings?
Crawley is this way.
Wait here.
Pope, he wants to see you alone.
So where's Crawley?
Rough night we're having.
So where are Agent Jones and Philips?
Where the fuck are they?
Boss is gonna be pissed if...
Crawley?
No, Crawley's dead.
It's just you and me now, Max.
Look at you.
Jesus Christ.
What did they do to you?
Mommy and Daddy are dead.
I know. I was there.
Do you know how much
they believed in you?
You think so?
I think I was a walking time bomb.
- You're just about every belief they had.
- Do you know how much we looked for you?
What did you come down here for?
Why you got these spooks
digging up my bones?
You doing me a favor?
You flush out Crawley,
I got to settle all my debts.
I could never say
we're cut from the same cloth.
Shit, we're both sitting here now, ain't we?
If you recall me as a boy, brother,
I was a believer.
You were there.
I was champion to these tribes
down here once, wasn't 1?
I was champion to the indigenous people
of South Vietnam.
I was into civil rights.
You were nothing
but a dope-smoking bigot...
if you recall.
Yeah, I was a kid once, too.
I was a kid when I got out of that war.
You know what I had on my back?
My uniform.
You know what I did with that uniform?
I wore it. You know why?
Because it's all I had.
So you're right.
You don't ever say
we're cut from the same cloth.
You choose to love a queen...
and she turns out to be a whore,
you just make adjustments.
By the way, your girl's up top.
I'm pressed for time now.
Catch that dinghy.
Don't look back.
You're a fanatic.
Fanatic?
Fanatics run this world, brother.
I've got nothing to do with that.
I hope one day God understands you, Sam.
- Understands me?
- You took the lives of innocents.
Innocents?
"Innocence" is a matter of semantics.
Every day, some 15-year-old boy
in some far away land does what I did.
You understand him.
Next time you choose a new life,
make one up.
It's safer.
We had a quarter billion.
Where's the money?
We split it three ways.
Look at yourself. Look at your face.
Writing a book about Ashley Commerford.
You could still be the final chapter.
Straighten things out.
Why wouldn't you want to tell
your side of the story?
I hope you had a lot of fun
playing your brother.
Wait! The money!
Eva!
Purgatory.
That's what { call this place.
I don't travel much now.
{ think I understand now
what money was to Eva.
It's not the glitter it buys.
It's the security.
The most valuable thing we own
is our good name.
Our reputation.
That's the only part of
us that lives forever.