a TAKEONE STUDIO production
storywiz and TAKEONE STUDIO presents
original story THE CONTORTED HOUSE
written by JEON Gun-woo
SEO Young-hee
KIM Min-jae KIM Bo-min
directed by KANG Dong-hun
With the change of circumstances
when we move there,
things could get better for you too,
don't you think?
You make it sound like
we're moving because of me.
I really don't want to move.
What else can we do?
We can't afford not to.
I'm doing this for all of us
to live a better life.
But you...
What did you do?
Can't you see how much I am struggling
to keep afloat right now?
Hold on.
Ji-woo, I'm fine.
Go back to bed, sweetie.
Let's talk this through before you go.
No, let's talk later.
Is someone's funeral that important to you?
I said later.
Take the kids with you if you're going.
Myeong-hye
The person you're trying to reach
isn't available.
Mom...
Hee-woo.
Oh, Uncle...
Didn't you miss me?
You didn't even call.
I'd want for nothing else in this world
if I had a daughter like you.
When did you get here?
Here.
Oh...
I'll be going now.
- Okay, see you later.
- See you.
What happen to the CEO
wasn't your fault.
- I'll call you.
- Good luck with the move.
Okay.
Let's go.
Hee-woo, I'll visit you
at your new home sometime.
I have to go in now,
so hurry and follow your dad.
You saw them, didn't you?
What?
Things like them can hurt
you and your family.
If you ever need help later, call me.
Savior Kim
Okay?
CONTORTED
You're awake.
We're almost done here,
so get some more rest.
Hey, Ji-woo.
I have a headache right now.
Hee-woo.
Choi Hee-woo!
Go play with your sister on the swing.
Oh, hey.
Look at all this. Wow.
The people who lived here before
left all these nice things behind.
Isn't it great?
Why would you accept used things?
I mean...
If you go around this way,
it's the master bedroom.
If you have a headache,
go in there and rest for a bit.
Not that way,
go around that way.
Let me know if you need anything.
Ji-woo, what's wrong?
What happened?
Did you fall?
Are you alright? Okay?
Where's your sister?
Where's your sister, Ji-woo?
Hee-woo!
Ji-woo, are you alright?
Hee-woo?
I don't see her.
Let me take a look at you.
Didn't you get hurt?
My poor baby.
How could you leave your sister alone here?
The shed is a bit strange.
What?
It feels like there's someone in there.
You two go back inside.
I'll go check.
What the...
Why did this fall off?
Huh?
There are strange noises
coming from the shed.
What?
There must be something in there.
Noises from the shed?
- I'll go check it out.
- Okay.
Don't worry.
Whatever.
This is the first day in our new home,
so be patient with us, okay?
Your mom will make
something really good tomorrow.
I'll cook.
- Dong-woo, where are you going?
- Thanks for dinner.
Dong-woo,
don't be on your phone for too long.
- Did you hear that?
- What?
There was a strange noise.
Did you hear that?
- Did you?
- Dong-woo.
Please walk with care.
Mom says it was too loud.
I told you to go see what's in the shed.
What's wrong with you?
Kids are getting anxious.
Please stop.
I couldn't find the key to the shed.
I'll ask the realtor about it,
so just wait a bit till then.
What if something happens?
Like what?
It's locked so tight that
not even a ghost or monster could get out.
What if it ends up coming out
when we open the door?
Just kidding.
Finish your food. I'll protect you,
so don't worry and eat.
Let's stop sighing and
just enjoy our dinner.
Hee-woo!
What's wrong?
Did something happen?
No.
It's okay.
Did you have a nightmare?
I asked if you had a nightmare!
Why won't you answer me?
I ended up like this because of you!
Just why won't you call me Mom?
Why?
I keep hearing strange noises
from the shed.
And my nightmares are getting worse.
I know I shouldn't,
but I blame everything on Hee-woo.
Whenever I look into her eyes,
I feel like she can read my mind.
We brought her home in the first place
because of her beautiful eyes,
but I'm afraid of how I might change.
Hee-woo,
you remember Sister Veronica, right?
She's going to be your mother
from now on.
Now say hello.
Shall we go camping and barbecue
in the front yard?
Yes?
What are you so happy about?
Oh, I was telling them
that we should go camping in our front yard.
Do something about the shed.
What about it?
I heard a strange sound again last night.
What sound?
I didn't hear anything.
Of course you didn't.
Dong-woo.
- Where are you going?
- Put your dishes in the sink.
It's okay, I'll do it later.
Hee-woo, did you hear anything
from the shed last night?
You really didn't hear it?
When I head out,
I'll stop by the real estate
and ask about the shed key.
Hee-woo.
You didn't hear it either, right?
Is there anything you need?
No.
You always say that.
It's okay to tell me
if you need something.
- I'm really fine.
- Really?
Alright. I'll be back.
See you later.
Okay.
Ultrasound Room
Let's go.
Goodbye.
Yes, it's me.
I just got tested.
Yes.
Let's talk at home.
Hee-woo,
should we get some ice cream on the way back?
Yes.
Okay.
Mom...
Can we play hide-and-seek?
You can't go outside, okay?
Go hide.
One...
Two...
Three...
Four...
Five...
Six...
Seven...
Eight...
Nine...
Ten...
Here I come.
Hurry and run.
Hide and seek.
Where could you be?
I can smell Ji-woo here.
Is she here?
Got you!
Ji-woo!
It's me.
Where's Ji-woo?
Weren't you just talking to someone?
Stay with Ji-woo.
You must've just moved in.
Yes, we moved in yesterday.
Which house do you live in?
Over there.
I was close to the previous tenants.
What were they like?
Well...
They were just ordinary neighbors...
And nice...
At first.
But they just disappeared one day.
Isn't that strange?
I was actually in the middle of something.
It's upsetting to find out.
- What's up?
- Why?
I just thought you'd be bored.
Boo!
Go play your games.
They said
this house is a bit contorted,
not standing straight up.
That's why when the wind blows,
creak, creak...
It makes noises.
Hee-woo!
Hee-woo.
Wake up, Hee-woo!
Mom, will she be okay?
Yes, she'll be fine.
Oh no.
The person you're trying to reach
isn't available.
Hello, ma'am.
I called to ask if I could visit you
at your office today.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I'm not at my office right now.
I don't think I'll get back by today.
Oh, I see.
How unfortunate.
I'll see you some other time.
By the way, ma'am,
you know the publishing job
you talked about last time?
I was wondering how that's going.
Oh, right. You see...
Regardless of conditions,
I can definitely do the job.
You see, about that...
Don't get me wrong.
Because of that plagiarism claim issue...
Of course, I believe you 100%.
But the publisher seems to be under pressure...
You know, on this situation.
Even the CEO died in such a way.
Ma'am, I did not plagiarize.
I know that, of course.
I'm in the middle of a meeting right now,
so I'll call you later.
Okay then.
I'll talk to you later.
Gosh, what a headache.
Such an embarrassed.
Who was it?
No one important.
Hee-woo...
I’m sorry, but is there
a patient named Choi Hee-woo...
Never mind, I found it.
Sorry I'm late.
Is Hee-woo okay?
Why didn't you pick up the phone?
I had it on vibrate,
so I didn't know you called. I'm sorry.
What is wrong with you?
Why do you make things so difficult?
Okay, I'm sorry.
I feel like I'm losing my mind.
Look at what happened
as soon as we moved.
I'm doing my best here.
I said I'm sorry.
This is the best you can do?
What did they say about Hee-woo?
Uh...
Yes?
Could I have some water?
Water?
Are you alright?
Yes.
I'm sorry.
What?
You don't want me to go?
Don't open that door.
What?
The shed.
Are you okay?
Yes.
Oh.
This must be my lucky day.
What do you think you're doing?
I have bad depression.
And this helps with that.
You understand, right?
You can't smoke in someone's car.
Life without a husband or kids
would've been so much better.
Don't you think so?
Misfortune isn't something
that humans can fix.
Isn't it hard trying to act
like a good person?
What are you talking about?
Acting like you care for her
but resenting her on the inside.
That's bad.
Put out that cigarette now.
That's what's tormenting you.
Put it out!
What is all this?
Choi Dong-woo!
Come down here and
clean this mess up.
I can't stand this!
I'm so sick of this!
I hate this!
Hush, little baby
Don't say a word
Mama's gonna buy you
A mockingbird
The virus attacks the weakest part
of a living organism and infects it.
It infiltrates the cellular tissue
of the infected organism
and grows and propagates by plundering it.
Direct treatment is impossible in reality.
This is driving me nuts.
After the virus proliferates,
it comes out of the cell
and attacks another cell.
Hee-woo, don't be scared.
We're your friends.
She's trying to go in the shed.
Hurry and wake your father up.
Tell him to stop her.
It's too late.
I told you it's bad
to act like you don't resent her.
It's troubling and shameful,
isn't it?
Put the mask on.
Hide in there and be at ease.
No matter how cruel and corrupt you are,
you can hide it.
There's no need to act like a good person.
Just hide in there
and live in peace like me.
Have some of this too.
Should I tell Mom to come today?
No, it's okay.
Hee-woo.
You know Mom is a bit sick.
Never mind.
Do you want to know a secret?
Mom...
Hold on, I have to take this.
Yes, sir.
Oh, right.
I was actually going to call you.
When the money comes in,
I'll be sure to repay you first.
I'm sorry.
Yes, I'll let you know.
Yes, talk to you soon.
Hey, Dong-woo.
Dad, Mom won't wake up again.
I have to go to school today.
Okay, I will be there soon.
Thank you.
Dong-woo.
Dong-woo...
Where's Mom?
Get your backpack. Let's go.
Come on, Dong-woo.
Let's go.
Mom, you look pretty.
I look pretty?
Yes, very, very pretty.
Hee-woo.
I need to go the real estate.
Stay here and play with this.
Okay.
Hello, ma'am.
Oh, hello.
How did the move go?
What brings you here today?
I'd like the key to the shed, please.
- Shed?
- Yes.
Yes, there's a shed behind our house.
I'd like the key to that.
There was a key?
I am not sure I have one.
Hold on for a second.
I looked for it at home,
but it wasn't there.
Where could it be?
You know that
we kind of moved in a hurry.
But...
why was this house so cheap?
Well, you see...
There really is no key. Nothing.
I'll look into it and get back to you.
There aren't any other issues, right?
Well...
Actually, my wife
keeps saying she can hear
strange noises from the shed.
I'm sorry, but
I have to go out right now.
I'll give you a call after I look into it.
This isn't an urgent matter, is it?
But the key...
I mean, it is not that urgent. Right?
I'll look into it and let you know.
Give me a call, then.
Yes, of course. Goodbye.
- Please call me.
- Okay.
What were you doing?
Hello, Mr. Jang.
- How have you been, Mr. Choi?
- Good.
This publishing company I know
is looking for an author illustrator.
Oh, really?
So I called you right away.
Oh, thank you so much.
I've been so off the grid lately.
Thank you so much for calling me.
Okay. I'll get back to you
as soon as I get an answer from them.
Okay, thank you.
Goodbye. Thank you.
Dong-woo.
Dong-woo!
Don't you wanna say hi?
Hi.
Are you alright?
Yes.
Why are you just standing here?
Where's Dong-woo?
He went up to his room.
You're home.
Yeah. What's going on?
What makes you so happy?
What? You don't like it?
Of course I like it.
It's just that it's been a while.
You were right about moving here.
I feel much refreshed,
and have no headache.
Really? That's a relief.
Shall we?
Hurry over.
Let's enjoy the meal.
Here you go.
Hee-woo, eat up.
Dong-woo, come on down.
- Go ahead.
- Okay, thanks.
How is it?
Uh... it's... good...
Eat up.
Choi Hee-woo!
Hee-woo.
I think...
we need to make more effort
to understand your mom.
She may get better while staying here.
And about your school?
You can go when you get better.
- Okay.
And can I ask you about one more thing?
When you were alone in the car
this afternoon,
you seemed to be talking.
It looked like
you were talking to someone.
What was that about?
I was practicing speaking to friends.
Really?
Yes.
You want to sleep?
Let me know if you need anything.
Is that so?
Are you so happy with that?
I should try it too?
Then of course.
Well...
I'll do it soon.
They say this house is contorted.
I said this house is contorted.
Can an incompetent and indecisive
coward like you
take care of our children?
Just keep on sleeping.
It suits you.
I'm going out.
What?
Are you alright?
I'm doing great.
Mom.
Mommy.
Happy Real Estate
Hey, Yeong-gyu,
it's me.
Could you look into something for me?
You know the place we moved into?
Could you look into that house for me?
I'll tell you more when we meet.
Yes. I'll text you the address.
Please get on it as fast as you can.
Yeah. Sorry about that.
The house was built six years ago
by a guy named Park Sang-ho.
As soon as he completed the house,
he suddenly died from Gramoxone.
His eldest and third kids also died from it.
His wife is also mentioned in there.
Something was strange about his wife.
She took out multiple insurances
on her husband and kids.
And this may be unrelated,
but the kids were all adopted.
Anyway, they started an investigation,
but there was no proof of crime.
So the cops were about to wrap it up
when the middle child suddenly
called the police, asking for help.
So the cops were dispatched to the house,
but no one was there.
That's strange.
Did somebody do that on purpose?
A young couple with two kids
moved in there last year.
They killed their kids
and committed suicide together.
Their kids were also adopted.
This was just before you moved in.
You didn't hear anything about it?
I didn't hear anything about that
when we moved in.
I have a bad feeling about it.
Why don't you just move out of that house?
I don't have the money right now.
I wish I could help. I'm sorry.
No, why are you sorry?
I'm the one who's sorry.
Thanks for looking into it.
Hee-woo.
Where's your mom?
She went out.
The person you're trying to reach
isn't available.
Dong-woo, Hee-woo.
Hee-woo, it's time for dinner.
I'm coming in.
Hee-woo.
Choi Hee-woo!
What is all this?
I got dinner for us.
Stop feeding the kids instant food like this.
I got something delicious,
so wait just a minute.
Hee-woo, if you don't want to eat this,
you don't have to.
Okay?
You can just eat the rice.
It's an insurance policy.
She's just like the woman who killed us.
Run away. She'll kill you too.
After killing you...
Dong-woo,
I brought something delicious.
Why aren't you eating?
This is so good.
Open wide.
Come on.
Myeong-hye, stop it.
It's okay.
I'll eat it.
Open wide.
Open.
What is this?
The kids could get hurt.
Since we're so pressed for money,
we must prepare ahead.
Yes, we're pressed for money,
and you think we can afford that?
Who knows what'll happen?
We have to think of Ji-woo and
Dong-woo too.
You're incompetent.
Myeong-hye.
What's wrong with you?
What do you mean?
You are not okay right now.
Are you off your meds?
Myeong-hye's getting strange again.
Where did it all go wrong?
I really don't know
what to do anymore.
You scared me!
Did you do something wrong?
It's late, I thought you are sleeping.
So that's where this book was.
Ji-woo was looking for it all day.
Ji-woo?
Did you not take your meds again?
You know how much
Ji-woo loves this book.
You should've asked before taking it.
Myeong-hye, look at me.
Please get a hold of yourself.
Ji-woo...
Huh?
Let's be honest here.
Didn't that insurance policy
get you excited?
The publishing company CEO
committed suicide
because of your plagiarism.
You did great. Good job.
Savior Kim
Hello?
Sir, please help me.
I can't hear you. Who is this?
We met at the funeral home.
You gave me your business card.
What are you doing?
Who is this?
What were you doing?
Did you call the sister at the orphanage?
It's nothing.
What do you mean, it's nothing?
Hee-woo,
you must be hungry.
Let's eat.
Honey, Hee-woo says she's hungry.
Gramoxone
Here you go.
Eat up, Hee-woo.
You must eat and get strong.
What?
I'm not hungry.
Really?
Then we should wake Dong-woo and Ji-woo
so they can eat this.
You're such a good girl, Hee-woo.
Eat up.
Eat so you won't get sick again.
Eat it.
Eat it!
Choi Hee-woo!
Hee-woo, can you call me Dad?
Say Dad.
Please don't kill me.
Call me Dad!
Don't kill her.
I'm going to finish her off.
Hey, guys.
Ji-woo, Dong-woo,
let's go upstairs.
Hee-woo did something wrong,
so she must be punished.
Mom, what's wrong with you?
Go upstairs.
Now!
She was the one who threw and
killed Ji-woo.
Do you know how much trouble
you put me through all this time?
Huh? Do you?
Choi Hee-woo.
Come here.
Come over here.
Don't kill me.
Answer me.
Get over here, Choi Hee-woo!
Hee-woo!
Dong-woo!
Come here.
Choi Hee-woo! Stop there!
Choi Hee-woo!
Open the door, Dong-woo.
Dong-woo!
Stop right there!
What's wrong with you, Mom?
Don't do that to Hee-woo.
Go play with Ji-woo.
Reporter Kang Yeong-gyu
Hyun-min
The person you're trying to reach
isn't available.
Uncle, it's Hee-woo.
Mom and Dad are acting strange.
Please help me.
Hyun-min
Reporter Kang Yeong-gyu
Hee-woo.
Choi Hee-woo.
Mommy, save me.
Please save me.
Mom!
Mom.
Please...
Mom?
Save me...
Go play with your sister on the swing.
Please save me!
You can't go outside, okay?
Go hide.
Mom!
Yes, she'll be fine.
No!
I'll kill you all!
Let go of me!
Mom, please stop.
You're just tired from taking care of us.
You're sick because of trying so hard.
You love us.
You want to do more for us,
but you can't, so you're upset.
Mom, I love you.
Please come back.
Mom. No!
Mom!
Mom...
Gramoxone
Mom.
Mom. No!
No!
Mom...
Dong-woo.
Dong-woo, are you alright?
I'm okay.
What about Hee-woo?
Where is she?
I don't know.
Dong-woo,
get in my car and stay there.
Hee-woo!
Hee-woo, are you okay?
Where's your mom?
Where's your dad?
Hee-woo, it's okay.
Everything will be okay.
It's okay.