[ music playing ]
[Boy]  I fly solo.
Trust me.
I am not a team player.
I am not an athlete.
I don't even know
how to swim,
which is
just one of the sources
of ridicule I've gotten
since freshman year
and the one
that the golden boys
of Saint Raymond's
swimming team are
enjoying today.
That's Matt Prylek,
our school's best swimmer
and my worst nightmare.
And that's me, Tommy Dolen,
the one supplying
all their laughs.
My dad tried to teach me
to swim once
with the same warmth
that's going on here,
but that didn't work out
so well either.
Welcome back
to a new school year.
Now, if anyone had told me
in this moment
that, in less than a month,
I would develop
the most unlikely friendship,
I would have said they
swallowed way too much water.
♪ Above the noise
is where I'll be ♪.
♪ I hear a voice
in my head ♪
♪ It's telling me
to slow it down ♪
♪ I'm thinking that I might
just take the clue ♪
♪ My thoughts are flying
out of bounds ♪
♪ I'm hoping that
the miracle is true ♪
[Tommy V.O.]
Look, I know a lot of people
are worse off than me,
even if you couldn't
tell it by looking at them,
like this kid who's
been bumming coinage here
the last few days.
He told me his parents
lost their jobs.
♪ And I want to know ♪
♪ Why I wake up
every morning
searching for ♪
[ laughter ]
♪ Something that
I can't find ♪
Abby!
Your boss ready
for me yet?
[ laughter ]
♪ Seasons change ♪
♪ And the clouds don't lie ♪
♪ And I will try to know ♪
♪ How it feels to fly ♪
[ laughing ]
♪ The other night ♪
♪ I felt lonely ♪
[ entry bell rings ]
Are you kidding?
They'll kill me.
I don't mean your teachers
or your principal.
I'll talk to the boys.
Maybe they just want
to pal around.
They didn't know
you can't swim.
[ laughs ] Of course
they knew, all right?
Today was the worst,
but it's not just today.
It's every day.
The names, texts,
online humiliation,
taking shots,
stealing lunches.
Why didn't you tell me?
I was afraid you'd
invite them over
for Sunday dinner.
I could make braciole.
They'd like that.
Table seven needs
their check.
Listen. Just think.
If you all
just got together
and talked...
[ TV Announcer ] This week,
we're announcing the final ists
for our Teenage
Cooking Contest
right here on
Mealtime Network,
where the winner
will walk off
with her or his
own TV show,
plus a special
grand prize
I'll be revealing
a little later.
I already told you,
all right?
I'm not joining
any contest.
It's past
the deadline.
Should have.
Could have won.
Well, it's too late now,
all right,
and that's
just what I want,
give them more excuses.
[ entry bell rings ]
I'll finish up here.
Go wait
on the new customer.
Prylek!
I'm still
hoping to hear
you get
life imprisonment
one day,
but I think this'd
do for a start.
Her family just
moved here from Kansas.
She goes to your school.
She's a blogger,
and she explained to me
what that was.
I'll take care
of tables two and four.
Here.
You take this to Sarah.
When are you gonna learn
you don't have to do
everything alone?
Just talk to her
for just a minute.
[ TV Announcer ]
Our special added
prize
will be $50,000,
and today we're
announcing our
third contestant,
and this one's
a local boy,
Saint Raymond's own
Tommy Dolen!
[ plates clatter ]
[ gasps ]
Thanks, Rip. Only
three more contestants
left to be announced.
Then tune in
next week...
[ Tommy V.O. ] I'm sorry.
when all 16 square off
to compete...
[ Tommy V.O. ]
I-I'm sorry.
I'm really, really sorry.
...and $50,000.
[ telephone line ringing ]
[ Matt V.O. ] You told Abby
about the job.
You helped her
move up here.
She'll talk
to her boss.
MAN: Think so?
She still
isn't picking up.
I'll fix this
in the morning.
Mangia, bello!
I know I should
have told you
I was taking
your pizzelles down
to the TV station
and entering you
in that contest.
I can't talk on TV,
all right?
Can you please
just call them
and tell them that
I can't do it, all right?
I'm sorry. I have to go
to Ned's before school.
Yeah, but I think--
I can't.
I just can't, all right,
Gran? [ kiss ]
I love you. Bye.
Bye.
Matty! Matty!
Your alarm clock
broken?
Five minutes,
dressed and out.
[Tommy V.O.] Once a month,
I go to pay rent
to the landlord
of the pizzeria, Ned Foley.
Hey, Dolen!
You brain-dead?
[Tommy V.O.] Like I was saying,
every month
I go to Ned Foley's,
the landlord
of Gran's pizzeria,
to pay the rent,
but who knew today's visit
would trigger something
completely unexpected?
[ telephone line ringing ]
I'll see her
when she shows up.
[ Ned laughs ]
Sold it all, and I want you
to level the entire block.
Now, the one problem is
gonna be
the old lady that runs
the pizza place.
She's been there
since the War of 1812,
and she doesn't get
that the chain places
are killing her.
My grandfather
put this stupid clause
in her lease.
I really hope
she doesn't remember it,
Not that it'll help,
though.
Don't think her and
her goofy grandson
have a dime
to their names.
Look, if she's
gonna be a problem,
I may need you to help
me out around this,
all right?
Just like you did
with the pub.
Then not only will
I give the demolition
job to you,
I will also
recommend you
to the buyer
to build
his brand-new--
[ rattles ]
Oh.
Hold on a second.
Yeah,
no problem.
Did you withdraw me
from the contest yet?
Okay, good.
Don't, all right?
I'll see you later.
[Tommy V.O.] I usually try
to stay under the radar,
but I gotta do this
for Gran, you know,
even if it makes things
worse at school.
When I was curled up
on that pool deck
choking up water,
Matt Prylek was bragging
to all his buddies
about how his brother helped
his ex-girlfriend Abby
score a job as the Assistant
Principal's new secretary.
Prylek was
dangerous enough before.
Now he's got a skeleton key
to the school.
As per our new
zero-tolerance policy,
effective immediately,
you are suspended
from all
extracurricular
activities.
What?
That's total...
[Woman] And any infraction
of any school rules
could result
in expulsion
and home schooling
until June.
Uh, Ms. Sykes,
it's Matty's
senior year.
All the assistant coaches
from--from the colleges
he wants to get into can
finally come see him, so...
Mr. Prylek,
I'm aware of Matthew's--
Kyle, please.
Swimming is
Matty's whole life.
[ knock on door ]
Come in, please.
Oh, sorry.
I didn't realize
you were still
in the meeting.
Uh, Coach Nadley called,
and I reconfirmed
your anti-bullying
campaign meeting with
the board for 11:00.
Sorry to bother you.
No.
Thanks, Abby.
Uh-huh.
Matthew...
I'll reduce
your suspension...
to a one-month
period if you'll--
One month?
Are you out--
What do I
have to do?
People
look up to you.
Stop all
the bullying
immediately.
If you become
an anti-bullying
role model
within 30 days,
I will restore
all your
extracurricular
activities.
You mean like--
like doing what?
I mean like
for the next month,
go out of your way
to be kind to the kids
who are bullied
at this school,
starting
with Tommy Dolen.
Done.
Okay.
Go. Be nice.
Be kind. Get out.
[ laughing ]
Okay, you got that one.
[ boys laughing ]
Dolen! My mom says
you're gonna be
a big TV star.
Bad enough
this place pumped
money into Home Ec
which should have
gone to athletics--
Yeah. Now you're gonna
make us all look like--
Joe! Knock it off!
But you were the one
who planted the seed
in her head.
How about
an espresso?
Kyle, I thought
I said I need to--
Come on.
It's just coffee.
A cooking show, Dolen?
Isn't that the kid
whose grandma runs
the pizza joint?
Uh, yeah.
He's just been picked
to be on a TV
cooking contest.
The teachers were
talking about it.
If he wins,
he gets his own show
and $50,000.
[Kyle V.O.] We're a team.
Think about it.
You volunteer
to do this,
and Sykes may lift
your suspension
sooner than the end
of the month.
Not having
the brains
to see a whole new
security system
is what
got you nailed.
So now I gotta help him
win 50 grand?
No! You just--
You just have to appear
to be helping.
Once he says yes,
then we'll work
on sabotaging
this whole thing.
So I can get expelled?
We'll do it in a way
that it won't
stick to you.
You'll see.
It'll be fine.
How?
Just leave that to me.
Once we're in--
Wait.
He should pay for all
the trouble he's caused me,
but what's
in this for you?
The biggest job
I ever had
and helping out
my bro.
I don't think there's
this many rules
to pick a Pope.
What?
[Gran V.O.]
No, it makes sense to me.
You can't do this
on your own.
You have to have a team.
A team? I don't need
a team, all right?
I cook alone.
Besides, where am I
gonna find two--
Friends?
I'm sorry, bello,
but, uh, I don't qualify
as one of your peers.
You know, I'm not
gonna be around forever.
Maybe this is a good chance
for you to branch out.
Who wants to?
If I didn't have to--
[ doorbell rings ]
[ knocking on door ]
This contest
sounds awesome,
and I know I was
totally out of line
and wrong but--
about the pool and today.
Sorry, man.
I know I may have
hassled you a little, but--
Yeah, only three years.
So when's this whole
contest thing over?
F-Four weeks, but--
That's perfect.
You need a bodyguard
so, that way, no one--
Yeah, so no one
drowns me or tries
to beat my face in?
With me around, no one will
even give you any trouble.
Why? Do you want
exclusive dibs?
Look, I don't know what
you're up to, Prylek,
but this is my house,
all right?
This is the only place
where I can come
to be without people
like you--
Ciao, ragazzo.
I'm Tommy's grandmother.
You like pizzelles?
I would love one.
Wow.
Hi. I'm Matt.
Oh, you're Matt.
Yeah.
Come on in the kitchen.
Thank you.
Mmm, these are
really good.
Tommy made them.
Oh, yeah?
Family recipe.
Interesting.
♪ Take me
off the sidelines ♪
♪ Blow sand
beneath my feet ♪
♪ Oh, break me out
this gilded cage ♪
♪ That holds me ♪
♪ Come fill my veins
with sunlight ♪
♪ Send a postcard
from my lungs ♪
♪ I want to taste
salvation-- ♪
Great dinner
last night, T!
Sheesh, man,
you can cook!
And that Gran of yours,
she's off the hook.
I wouldn't take
any bets on that.
Anybody
bother you today?
Not till 10 seconds ago.
Have you been
thinking about
what we were
talking about?
Yeah, I don't--
don't want a bodyguard.
Not that.
You've already got one.
I was talking
about having me join
your posse.
Your Gran told me
how you need
a cooking crew,
and I have made
some pretty mean
barbecue--
Yo, Julia Childish!
What's up?
Told you
to back off, Joe.
Let's roll, T.
Off the team? Why?
Well, well,
the diving instructor,
he--he said that
I need to take a month
off of swimming, so--
You know, 'cause
I sprained my hand.
It has to do with
the force of how you
hit the water.
You just got--
Diving and swimming,
you gotta protect
the hand, you know.
♪ It's all right ♪
♪ It's okay ♪
♪ You can't
hold us at bay ♪
♪ And you know
that it's time ♪
♪ That we're gonna
push that line ♪
[Matt V.O.]
Those two right there.
That's our crew.
They c--They can't
even turn up a flame.
You want to bet?
I know these two guys.
They're just
not here yet.
They're the only ones close
to being in my league.
Where was
this side of you
out in the hallway?
I know my way
around the kitchen.
When I'm
done with you,
there won't be
a room in the house
you've missed.
[ laughs ]
That's one.
He's really good,
but he's quiet,
you know, shy,
keeps to himself.
Haven't heard a word
from him all last year.
Up until yesterday,
I could have said
the same thing
about somebody else
around here.
Maybe he can't talk.
Okay, I got this.
Ahem!
Hi. My name is Matt,
and I don't sign.
[ girl laughs ]
Do you have
a pen and paper?
I can write a note.
Oh. Oh, uh,
let's go outside
into the hallway
so we can talk--
talk--talking.
[ Australian accent ]
No worries.
You're starting to...
embarrass yourself, mate.
[ giggles ]
And then we win
the contest.
So, uh,
are you on board?
I don't...
know about...
being on TV.
What if...
I have...
to speak?
All the...
guys in
my old school...
always
made fun of--
Anyone tries bullying you,
and they're gonna
get..
But, hey, girls
must love the accent.
Am I right? [ laughs ]
Yeah.
The fact that I'm...
cute as a cloud...
doesn't hurt
either, but--
And that's what's
so great about this, too.
I mean, we get to make
all these amazing dishes,
and we don't have to talk
or deal with anybody else.
There's the other one,
Bobby Butler.
We have to go
into class, though.
Bobby Butler,
Matt Prylek.
You're
on our squad now.
My boys and I are
gonna make you a TV star.
Now don't
be late for class.
Meet you all back here
after eighth period!
♪ I'm sailing away ♪
♪ To a land of opportunity ♪
♪ The sun will shine ♪
♪ And birds will sing
there every day ♪
♪ I'm sailing away ♪
♪ And I hope
that you remember me ♪
♪ It was fun,
we had our run ♪
♪ Hip-hip-hooray ♪
♪ I'm running away ♪
♪ To a place where
you won't bother me ♪
♪ We won't talk
for a while ♪
♪ We'll be okay ♪
♪ And I'm changing my name ♪
♪ To a word
that's really hard to say ♪
♪ It's no one's fault ♪
♪ I'm just too young ♪
♪ And you're insane ♪
This isn't
the swimming pool,
okay, Prylek?
You're
in my kitchen now.
We don't just
push people around.
And what
a great bodyguard
you've been so far.
You're fired.
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Come on. Come on.
Tommy, Dolen,
stop, look.
Bro, I-I'm trying
to be different,
and that's not
gonna happen overnight,
but I am trying.
Can't you give me
a chance?
[ chuckles ]
See you guys later.
[TV Announcer]
Now here's your host...
Rip Barker.
Our contestants
span the country,
but our next team
is homegrown.
Please say hello
to Team Tommy!
[ drumroll ]
[ applause ]
And from Detroit
by way of the Ukraine,
the Bartosh cousins!
[ applause ]
[ drumroll ]
[ cheering ]
And finally,
from Connecticut,
Team Dennis!
[ drumroll ]
[ applause ]
Yeah! Thanks, Rip!
I just want to say
how fortunate I am
to be working
with my two talented
underprivileged
teammates
whom I discovered
on the Interne--
Yeah, we'll have
plenty of time
to talk later,
but right now,
let's get the first round
of our contest under way.
Here's how it'll work.
Our distinguished judges
will eliminate
one team each show
until we pick
our big winner...
Shh!
on the grand finale night.
Wait.
[ Announcer ] Thanks,
Rip. And every team captain
is a wonderful chef,
so it's anyone's game.
The winner of "Teen Chef"
will go on
to host their
very own TV show.
To be a TV show host
for the Mealtime Network,
one must be
highly self-disciplined.
♪ Feeling the world
go round... ♪
Every team has received
the contest rules
and must follow
each one of them precisely.
Failure to do so could
result in a team forfeiture.
♪ I'm not giving up ♪
♪ Got you
under my skin ♪
♪ And I don't care
if I sin ♪
♪ I really want it ♪
♪ I really want it
right now ♪
And now back to Rip Barker
and our team elimination
for week one.
[ applause ]
Thanks for being with us.
And the highest scores
of tonight's show,
Team Tommy!
[ fanfare plays ]
[ applause ]
[Rip V.O.] Congrats.
Tune in next week,
when we'll lead off
with each team captain
telling America
how they discovered
their signature dishes.
Until next Friday,
good night.
[ Director V.O.] Cut!
That's a wrap.
Hey, how would you
like to take over
that assignment
for me next week?
I believe
the competition rules
state that there
shall be no delegation
of a captain's duties.
I got you covered.
Can't wait.
[ knocking on door ]
Eye contact.
You need
to make eye contact
with your audience.
Find a friendly face,
and stare them down.
At least you didn't
tell me Gran's advice
to picture them
all naked.
♪ There's a boy
in the back seat ♪
I like that. Come on.
♪ Singing to the song ♪
What?
♪ Playing on the radio ♪
♪ Knowing he's
the one singing ♪
♪ "I-I-I ♪
♪ I just want to be
a rock star" ♪
[Tommy V.O.]
And even though my parents had--
uh, weren't here any more,
our house
still felt the same
with my Gran baking
pizzelles in the kitchen.
[ applause ]
♪ ♪
[ cheering ]
[Crowd cheering]
Tommy! Tommy! Tommy! Tommy!
Tommy! Tommy!
Tommy! Tommy! Tommy!
Looks like I really
will need your help.
It turns out that grandson
of old mozzarella mama
is on some
TV show.
Already on it.
Got my brother
on the inside.
Well, I hope
he works fast.
There's only three shows
left in the next two weeks.
♪ I was born
to be a rock star ♪
♪ Singing, "I-I-I ♪
♪ I just want
to be a rock star" ♪
♪ Singing, "I-I-I..." ♪
Prylek
gets suspended,
and then we lose
our fans to these--
To these lunch ladies!
♪ If there's a meaning. Can
you show me a sign? ♪
♪ The more I look, it just
gets harder to find ♪
♪ The world is spinning,
and I want to know why ♪
Hey, bro! Bro.
Whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa. Hey.
Didn't--
Didn't you hear me?
I heard you when you said
you sprained your hand
and were off the team,
but now I just heard
your buddies say you
were suspended, so...
Well, no, I really
wanted to help you
on the contest,
and I thought
if--if you knew that
I'd been suspended
for harassing you,
you might--
might think...
I might think what?
That I wasn't
being real
I got that spice thing
you wanted.
Saffron.
I said saffron,
saffron
from a spice shop.
This is--This is paprika
from a warehouse.
Well, well...
they're both red.
Why are you really
doing all this?
I feel horrible
about the pool
and assembly
and last year.
I was hoping
that we could work
on the contest
together and then...
maybe the school's
anti-bullying project?
Hey, Sarah.
What are you--
What are you
doing here?
Respectfully whispering.
It's just some research
for a blog I'm writing.
In the cooking area?
It's a hot topic
all over town.
Where are all
your adoring fans?
I, uh--I--
You know,
couldn't...
find the one
I was looking for,
so, uh, I came here,
and it worked.
She found me.
Well, she doesn't have time
to bask in the glow
of your spotlight.
Too busy, uh, reporting
on pop culture, huh?
Well, it doesn't come
with a TV show,
but someone
should hold a mirror
to the narcissism
of society.
You know,
feeding people isn't
such a selfish thing.
And feeding
your ego publicly isn't
such a selfless one.
[Tommy's thoughts]
Eye contact.
Are you okay?
Um, oh, yeah, yeah.
You know--
You know,
but people--
people do things
for all kind
of reasons, right?
You know,
reasons other people
may not even
know about, so...
Right.
And even if I was
doing this for me,
I don't get
much props
from others
around here
anyway, so...
[ scoffs ]
Could you say
three sentences in a row
without "I"
or "me" in them?
Uh, would that make you
want to spend more
than 30 seconds with me?
[ laughs ]
There you go again.
No. I--
Nah, I was just--
I was just wondering
if you want to--
Shh!
[ sighs ]
Chicks.
[Kyle V.O.]
You spent what on saffron?
[Matt V.O.]
Do you want him
to think I'm sincere?
That's a whole day,
both jobs.
I'd better get
my money's worth.
This Friday night's
the one...
when you
blow the contest.
He must totally
trust you by now.
I wouldn't say totally.
Besides, the coach
just left me a message.
He wants to see me
in the morning.
This might
already be over.
Do you have a world map
that shows the picture
of you in the center?
You made a commitment,
so make sure Dolen
trusts you by Friday.
Again, how am I
supposed to pull this off
without getting caught?
Well, what do you guys
have planned
for Friday night's
competition?
Each team is doing
a different culture's food,
and Tommy hasn't
picked out our culture yet.
Well, the minute
he does, let me know,
and I'll tell you
how to screw it up.
I'm pretty sure I can
figure that out on my own.
[ laughs ]
Yeah, because you've
done so well thinking
for yourself so far.
Let me do the thinking
for the both of us,
all right,
boy brainless?
[Coach V.O.]
Two top teams?
U of Texas and UC.
Which one?
Well, you're gonna
have to guess, boy.
But, I--
And then I had
to tell 'em that
you were suspended,
and he decided
to pass
on a potential
disciplinary risk.
You're batting
.500, Matt.
You better figure out
a way to get reinstated.
Matt. Matt.
Matt.
Man,
thanks for the--
Thanks for
the saff--
[ running footsteps ]
All right,
diversion excursion.
It's time
to take care of Matt
and put Dolen
out of commission
at the same time.
Me? No, no, no, no.
I have to deal with
the Booster Club.
There were
other witnesses.
[ sighs ]
I'm confident that
you'll handle it
appropriately.
♪ What to do now ♪
Anything else?
♪ Yeah, it's no doubt ♪
♪ That you been
bringing me down ♪
♪ And I don't
want to drown ♪
♪ So keep the weight off ♪
♪ Off my shoulders ♪
He told her
he startled you
and your reaction
was just a reflex.
Tommy, I'll make
it up to you by--
[ gasping ] Ow.
[Tommy V.O.]
Bobby, Bobby, Bobby.
Don't try to move.
[Philip V.O.]
Who would...
leave spilled
olive oil?
You okay?
Ow.
[ shower running ]
What's wrong with you?
You trying to get me
out of here?
I'm trying to help you!
It wasn't meant
for that runt.
It was for Dolen.
And how is that
supposed to help?
He'd be out
of the contest.
Your alibi is that
you were with Sykes.
It still worked out
good, though.
Look, Team Thomasina
needs three guys, right?
All right, well, I heard
the little pipsqueak
broke his arm.
Now you become part
of the onstage action,
and you'll have
a much better chance
of blowing
this party apart.
[Tommy V.O.]
No, wait. He's crazy.
He doesn't know
what he's doing,
and this is how he wants
to make things up to me?
He's been
a big help so far.
Yeah, and why?
I mean,
I don't trust him.
First he
changes from sadist
to saint overnight.
And he's done a lot
to become your friend.
But for what?
Maybe he didn't mean
to do what he did
to me today,
but, Grandma,
I wouldn't be surprised
if he greased
the floor in Home Ec
just to get on the team.
[ chuckles ]
Oh, bello.
I'm getting so close,
Grandma.
You were all
doing beautifully.
Suppose I do let him
on the team and we lose?
Teams lose every day.
[ sighs ]
This isn't about a team.
It's about winning
this thing so--
I-It's about winning,
all right?
It's not
about making friends
or taking in a stray.
Well, it would seem to me
that a good athlete
would be motivated
to win, too,
don't you think?
[ groans ]
[Matt V.O.]
So Abby finally agreed
to have dinner with you
after eight years?
[Kyle V.O.]
Seven. Shut up. Stay on point.
Don't forget
to let me know
as soon
as Dolen tells you.
Got my own idea
about Friday night.
Buena suera, granya!
Ciao, ragazzo! I got it.
This Friday, Italiano!
We'll do an entire
Italian feast.
Everything from
ribolletto to pignoli.
[ laughs ]
You gotta
teach me how to speak
Italian, Gran, prego!
Women love guys
who talk foreign.
Look, I want
to learn everything,
including how
to make some wine.
Check it.
♪ La-da, da-da, da-da ♪
♪ Da-da-da, da-da, da-da ♪
♪ Da-da, da-da, da-da ♪
♪ Hey! ♪
♪ Ho ♪
And then
you catch it here,
you see?
Uh-huh.
All right, man.
Nice.
It's your turn.
Okay.
Wait.
Are your hands clean?
I could wash them
a 16th time.
All right.
Okay.
Aw, man, we should
call it a night.
It's almost 11:00.
Well, I figured
since we were off
for the teachers
meeting tomorrow,
maybe I could
spend the night here
i-if that's okay.
Uh, yeah, sure.
We can keep working.
My, uh, dad had
some old sleeping bags
up in the hall
closet, so...
All right.
[ clatters ]
Yeah.
[ timer dings ]
Ah, oops. Um...
the oven, man.
It's time.
Okay, okay.
You got this.
All right.
Here we go.
No, dude,
the oven mitts.
Right. Right.
[ overlapping
conversations ]
I haven't been
in a kitchen
cooking since...
ever.
It's different
than grilling
in a backyard.
Don't--Don't you
miss your friends,
uh, from swimming?
Ever wonder why,
when the moonlight
is so bright,
you just forget
all that's gone down?
No, but I
was wondering--
I don't understand
why you're such a--
I don't know.
Why you flipped
the switch so fast.
I--I told you. The pool
and then all the other...
Yeah, but,
I mean, why do it
in the first place?
Why spend
so much time--
I mean,
it's just not you.
People expect you
to be a certain way.
They laugh if you are.
They laugh at you
if you're not.
And i-it's like school
and the whole town.
You have to fit
the cookie mold.
I guess I just
wanted to...
To belong?
Yeah, I get that.
T...
I really am sorry
about everything.
Please know that.
That moonlight
is pretty bright.
Night, buddy.
Night...
buddy.
[ birds chirping ]
[ telephone line rings ]
Hey it's Matt, leave a message.
Ms. Sykes said that
you and Matt Prylek
are working together
on the school's
anti-bullying
campaign?
[ laughs ] You two
make a curious team.
Yeah, tell me about it.
I hear you two have
quite a history.
But it could make
an interesting article.
How about I interview
you two together
for the school blog?
How about you do it
at my place tomorrow night?
Me and Gran
are having Matt over.
How about I
do it next Monday
between classes?
I don't get
a good vibe
from your buddy,
and I would prefer
to keep my time
with him short.
We can always do
my part of the interview
over lunch, say, Friday?
I think
we'd be distracted
when you get mobbed
by your groupies.
♪ I was thrown ♪
♪ Into the sea ♪
♪ To face a world
that bet against me ♪
♪ Told me sink or swim
as I slowly sank ♪
♪ Asking what I'd done ♪
♪ To have
to walk the plank ♪
♪ Maybe everyone comes
a little bit undone ♪
♪ But we patch the holes,
and we move along ♪
♪ All I know is
I can't be the only one ♪
♪ Who fights
to keep his head up ♪
♪ Smiling in the sun ♪
♪ But it's
a-a-a-all right now ♪
♪ Oh, it's
♪ Yeah,
it's a-a-a-all right now ♪
♪ It's gonna be
all right for now ♪
Before,
the only times
I was ever
in the kitchen cooking
were to help my mom.
She taught me
how to make this.
In Philly, I was
overweight big time,
so she got me
into swimming,
always said
I'd make the Olympics.
I've never
forgotten that,
never let anything
hold me back.
That's what you gotta do
with this contest, T.
Just gotta keep
pushing forward...
no matter what.
[Dennis V.O.]
Looks great.
DENNIS: Thanks, Rip!
We thought
we'd highlight
the simple
British cuisine
of an earlier age.
I feel so blessed
to wear these rags
a-and dress
like my impoverished
teammates.
There are no words.
[ laughs ]
[ applause ]
[Rip V.O.]
Thank you, Team Dennis!
Ladies and gentlemen,
I want you to now
enter the Chunnel
with me as we leave
the United Kingdom...
Whoa!
and we head to France
with our favorite
mademoiselles.
[ applause ]
Ou est le mademoiselles?
My foot.
I think it's broken.
Mademoiselles?
We can help you up.
What are you doing?
Your cue to come out
was when Team Dennis
left the stage.
You're late. Let's go.
I'm so sorry!
Thank you!
According to contest rules,
if you're ever late
for a second entrance,
you're out!
Will, that's terrible!
What are you giving them
the heads-up for?
Get me a latte. Go.
Kyle, it's Matt.
Where are you?
Thanks, Bartosh cousins.
And next up for tonight,
Team Tommy.
[ applause ]
[ TV Announcer ]
Don't touch that remote.
Team Tommy
will be right back.
Matt's gonna
double over in pain.
The pig'll go flying,
hit the ground.
Contest over.
Matty's not busted.
Chef Girl-ar-dee
finished.
Pizza joint leveled.
And we're back
in 3, 2, 1.
[ applause ]
[ groans ]
[ audience gasps ]
[ applause ]
And Team Tommy
wins again,
thanks to you.
It was instinct.
For a second, I thought
it was all over,
but you surprised me.
Nice save.
Congratulations.
Dinner's on me tonight.
Can I invite my teammates
to come too?
Sure.
You want
to catch those guys
before they leave?
Sure.
[ coughs ]
Don't ever
do anything
like that again.
Walk home.
[Abby V.O.]
I was so nervous for a second.
[Tommy V.O.]
So was I.
Oh, me, too.
Oh, hey, um,
Philip and Bobby
already left,
but Tommy
and his grandmother
would love to join us.
W-We'll have to take
a rain check.
Matty and Joe decided
to go for burgers.
It's amazing
how much Matt's changed
in such a short time.
Well, I've been
trying to coach him.
It's not easy raising
a teenager all alone.
But you know that.
By the way,
love your pizza.
Best in town.
[ telephone line rings ]
Hey.
JOE: Hey.
Feels like I'm going
behind his back talking
to you like this.
No!
He needs perspective!
This morning,
I heard him tell Dolen
he wanted them
to take a drive
to Hillview later.
What?
Can you believe it?
He's been acting
so weird lately.
Call him. Tell him
you want to work out.
Stall him
until I get there.
Then while
I distract him,
I need you to plant
a little device
in his bag.
No, man, that's so---
Hey, do you want
things to get back
to normal or not?
[ hangs up ]
Hey, Matty.
Look, I know you're--
Joey.
Hey, will you
give us a sec?
I want
to talk to Matty.
Well, you better
make it quick, 'cause I'm
meeting up with Tommy
after my workout,
and I need your car.
I'll wait in there.
Well, what do you want?
[Kyle V.O.]
Dad always said kill
each other in fun,
but don't raise
your hands
to your brothers
even once in anger.
I screwed up.
I'll do better
at keeping things
under control
from now on.
We moved up here
after the fire
in Philly.
Some cheap
electrical wiring.
Kyle had taken me
camping that weekend.
People assume that we
lost our parents
and our little brother
Eddie in the fire,
but Mom made it out.
She couldn't
handle it, though,
so we moved her
up here.
And then Kyle moved us
to Saint Raymond
so we could be nearby.
I come up to see her
whenever I can.
TOMMY: Can I, uh--
I mean, would you like me
to come in with you?
No, but next time,
though.
Thanks.
[ giggles ]
Looks hot.
Oh, thanks.
[ giggles ]
You already
apologized for it.
I don't want there
to be any weirdness
between us.
Bro, can you imagine
living like this
every day?
We can once
I close this deal.
Kyle, I don't want
to do this anymore.
You're still mad at me?
No. Tommy and I
are friends now.
And these past few weeks
not pushing
anybody around,
I like it.
Plus the whole school
bullying campaign?
You can still be
Mr. Anti-bullying guy,
and you can still
be friends with Dolen
if you want.
He'll never know
you were the one
that ruined --
No.
You want college,
swimming career,
incredible future?
Got it.
I would
have liked that, too,
but right
after high school,
I had some
instant grown-up
responsibilities.
I just can't make
the connection.
I mean, Matt was
being weird up there
because he wasn't
feeling well.
But he kept glancing
up at his brother
the whole time
he was on the stage.
'Cause he was sick,
you know,
the same way you'd
look for your parents
or I'd look for Gran.
I mean, there's really
no big mystery or drama.
Then tell me
how Tommy losing helps.
I'm not sure I can
trust you with that.
How am I supposed
to decide if I don't know?
There's no decision
to make!
Matty, you and I have
been on the same team
since the day
you were born.
How do I know I'm
not gonna get caught?
If that happened--
If I get this gig,
college won't matter.
We'll be set.
Yo, Kyle.
It was really weird,
almost like--
Do I detect
concern for me--
um, someone
at this table?
I tried.
We're gonna do it
the other way.
What's the big rush?
You'd better
get in there.
[ laughter ]
Hey, come on.
Play it again!
Play it. Do it.
Let's hear it! Come on!
Play it again, dude.
MATT: ...couldn't handle it,
though, so...
[ laughter ]
we moved her up here,
and Kyle moved us
to Saint Raymond
so we could be nearby.
I come up to see her
whenever I can.
This lady's nuts.
Fine. Don't believe me,
but I'm telling you,
steer clear.
He just
found out he lost
his dream college
opportunity because
of his suspension,
and he blames you.
Matt and I are friends.
You don't get it.
Your whole friendship
has been a joke.
He laughs at you
behind your back.
The joke's over.
Stay away, man.
Are you all right?
Will be
in two minutes.
Matt, you do
anything to him now,
and you're gonna
get expelled.
Look,
keep a low profile.
Take care of him
Friday night
in the contest
like you were planning to.
( bang against locker )
Hey, are we
still on to meet
outside the library?
Actually, I'm sorry.
Now's just not the time,
all right?
Oh, look. There's
your best friend now.
I-I'm sorry.
[Kyle V.O.]
Thanks.
Using my place
would have been awkward.
No, nobody will.
Not even if they
knew who owned it.
No. No,
he'll be much
more cooperative now.
Besides,
I'm running another plan
on a parallel track
just in case.
Yeah, gotta go. Later.
Here it is. There are
three teams left.
We'll help you get rid
of those girls tomorrow,
and you be ready
to do a little
something for us
if we should need it.
Like what?
Like something
that'll guarantee
you win this contest.
Sweet. But they have
all these strict rules,
and if I get caught
shafting anyone, I'll be--
[ laughter ]
[ splash ]
♪ Everyone's talking
just to fill some space ♪
♪ And everything's nothing ♪
♪ Till it means heartbreak ♪
♪ Words without power ♪
♪ Just evaporate ♪
♪ Don't want
to hear it today ♪
Achoo!
♪ Today ♪
♪ Hello, hello ♪
♪ This is my voice ♪
♪ Hello ♪
♪ Through the white noise ♪
[ crowd gasps ]
♪ Words only hurt ♪
[ laughs ]
♪ When you let them matter ♪
♪ Don't let them matter ♪
♪ It's only chatter ♪
♪ White noise ♪
Look sympathetic.
♪ Words only hurt ♪
Inna?
♪ When you let them matter ♪
♪ Don't let them matter ♪
Where is she?
Inna? Inna?
♪ It's only chatter ♪
Hmm. [ snorts ]
S-Sorry.
You're the most
beautiful girl
I have ever seen.
[ giggles ]
Not a very good night
for Team Tommy.
[ applause ]
Next up is that
wonderful trio of cousins,
Anya, Inna and Lada.
Girls, come on out.
Girls?
[ giggles ]
[ Rip V.O. ] We're still
missing a contestant.
Baby,
I've never believed
in love at first sight...
[ Rip V.O. ] We're still
missing a contestant.
until now.
[ crying ]
Shh.
[ Rip V.O. ]: Inna?
[ sobbing ]
[ Rip V.O. ]  Inna Bartosh, last
call.
[ RIP V.O. ] Last call.
[ shushing ]
Unfortunately, according
to the contest rules,
we must
regretfully say goodbye
to the Bartosh cousins.
[ groaning, applause ]
And while
Team Tommy's performance
was way off tonight,
they have still
earned enough points
from previous episodes
to make it into tomorrow's
final showdown.
Tommy, Philip,
get that spark back.
Matt was the only one
who kept his cool
and kept your team
alive tonight.
Poor kid.
He did his best
to help.
Hey, I should go spend
some time with him.
I'll call you
in the morning.
Okay.
Matt, thanks
for keeping things
going tonight.
Uh, I was thinking
maybe we could
all go back
to my place, you know,
and practice for...
Hanging with
friends tonight.
[ door slams ]
[ music playing ]
What are you
still doing here?
You...
said we were
going to--
All right,
well, I changed my mind.
We should strategize.
Do you want to be
team captain?
Do you?
We just had
an off night.
I am so sick of "we,"
all right?
I need to just--
[ knock on door ]
Called it about Matt
and his brother!
The second that Matt
walked onstage--
Actually, Matt was
the only person
who didn't screw things up
out there, so...
Something was weird,
though.
His brother
kept looking over
at this other guy.
Somebody told me
who he was,
so I Googled him.
Turns out he owns--
I don't care,
all right?
I--I need to get home.
But you
have to hear this!
Look,
I know you're upset,
and I don't know
what's going on
with you and Matt,
but the connection
between this and...
I don't know what's
going on with Matt either,
but, you know, maybe it
has to do with, um,
people sticking
their noses in places
where they don't belong.
Meaning what?
Meaning everything
was going fine, all right,
until Matt's buddy
and you
decided to go
looking for trouble,
and now--now it
seems that everything's
just falling apart.
What? Whoa. Okay,
hold on a second.
I am just trying
to help you out here.
Maybe you're, you know,
more of a drama queen
than a--a blogger.
You know,
likes to stir stuff up
and then make sure
her own gossip comes true?
Right. I think...
you need to--
Be left alone?
Yeah, Philip.
Y-You're 100% on that one,
so if you can just leave?
Please?
I'm in big trouble.
I don't care
about what happened
out there tonight.
I--I thought
with everybody
so off their game,
I could
just play it straight,
and we'd lose anyway.
I did--That way,
no one could tag me
for sabotaging--
Whatever! Tomorrow night's
do or die for me.
I need you to come through.
No more runaround.
Forget what's happened.
Let's just get this done.
What kind
of trouble, Kyle?
No, bro.
All I've ever done
is protect you.
I can't change now.
Better you not know.
But I--I need to know
I can trust you to...
[ cellphone vibrates ]
Uhh. What now?
Hey, wait for me
in the car.
I gotta deal with this.
Hey, I got a plan
for tomorrow night,
foolproof.
Thanks.
It's good to be
a team again.
Yeah?
JOE: There already.
I broke
every speed limit.
I didn't
have to break in.
The back door
was unlocked.
You sure about me leaving--
Uh-huh.
Traitor just
lied to my face.
He needs
to learn loyalty.
And after
he's expelled,
you'll be the man
on the swim team.
[ cellphone vibrating ]
[ Tommy thinking]  Where
am I gonna find two...
GRAN: Friends?
[ boys laughing ]
[Matt V.O.] Night, buddy.
[Joe V.O.]You don't get it.
Your whole friendship
has been a joke.
He laughs at you
behind your back.
The joke's over.
[ somber music playing ]
Hey, have you
seen my hat?
I'm gonna
go work out!
♪ I wish I had a ♪
♪ Wishing well ♪
♪ Then all my dreams ♪
♪ Would come real ♪
And where have you
been all night?
I-Is Gran okay?
You're very lucky
you live two doors away
from the world's
best doctor.
[ sighs ]
♪ I wish I had a ♪
♪ Wishing well ♪
♪ Then all my dreams ♪
♪ Could come real ♪
[ static buzzes ]
[Matt V.O.]
I come upto see her
whenever I can.
[Tommy V.O.]
Can I, uh--
Would you like me
to come in with you?
No, but next time,
though.
T, I'm so sorry.
Why? What did you
do to her?
What?
You worthless
piece of garbage!
Get out! Get out!
Get out of here.
GRAN: Tommy!
Tommy!
I don't think he had
anything to do with this
any more than you do.
Deep down...
there is an answer,
but w-we just don't
know what it is yet.
I do know why you entered
the contest, though.
There was a letter
from the landlord
when I got home
last night.
I can
still win this.
I mean,
I'm the best chef
up there.
Bello, bello,
what you did
was--was wonderful,
and I'll always cherish
how you wanted
to take care of everything
by yourself,
but this is our problem
to fix, not yours alone.
We're--We're a team,
just like you're part
of a team in this contest.
It's not about
being the best chef
or--or winning
or saving the day
by yourself.
Well, besides you,
I can only trust me
to take care of--
No, you have to stop acting
like you're on your own,
because you're not.
You are connected
to everyone on your team--
But Matt's
swimming buddy told me
that Matt thinks
this whole thing is just
a huge joke and--
And your team is
in the final round, hmm?
I like Matt's
sense of humor.
But he's been lying
this whole time.
You don't know that.
You don't know
what he's been doing
until you
hear it from him.
I don't know about you,
but I'd like to hear what
your teammate has to say.
Why don't we
give him a chance?
Hey! Abby and I are
back together for good!
Yo, Matty!
[Matt V.O.]
I told you I'm fine,
and we're set.
I'll be heading
over to Tommy's
to pick up
the pizzelle dough,
and I've already got
the extra ingredient.
You seem totally okay
with all this.
You're my brother.
I don't want anything
to happen to you.
And the more I think
about how he set me up,
I can't wait
to burn him.
And you haven't heard
from Dolen yet?
No. Wasn't
expecting to. Why?
No reason.
Hey, Matty...
I knew you'd
come through.
Things are gonna be
getting a lot better.
Stuff I'll
tell you about later
with me and Abby.
Let's just
get through tonight.
Get through?
All the good stuff
starts tonight.
See you there.
Ready to go through
with our plan?
[ line rings ]
I should be the one
to refrigerate the dough
at the studio,
just in case Kyle's
gone totally overboard
and has
video surveillance
or something like that.
With all this
who's bluffing who
between you
and your brother,
how do I know you're
not just bluffing me?
I guess you just
gotta trust me.
Thanks, Gran.
Moonlight's pretty bright
for daytime.
And...
we have a restaurant
to save.
Joey, it's Kyle.
Listen,
as much as I want
to trust Matty,
I just don't.
He's supposed to put
the liquid laxative
into Team Tommy's
pizzelle dough
before the show,
but he was
way too agreeable.
I think he's gonna
double-cross me again,
so those two little kids
from Team Doofus are
gonna take care of it.
And now I've got
something I need you
to handle. Call me.
Look, just give me
five minutes, all right?
After 30 seconds
of nonstop apologizing
and groveling,
I have to tell you
the most incredible story
that you have
to post on your blog
after tonight's show.
Okay, but only if
you tell me the story
in 30 seconds
and spend the rest
of the time apologizing
and groveling.
[ laughs ]
[ Announcer ]
Ladies and gentlemen,
please take your seats.
The "Teen Chef"
final showdown
will begin momentarily.
All right, let's go.
Make you guys look poor,
"Oliver Twist" effect.
Awesome. Let's go.
You kidding me?
Come on.
231, 232,
233, 234.
Buddy, uh, the girls
aren't here anymore.
I just...
love the way
I'm starting to look.
[ Announcer ]
Mealtime Network
proudly presents
the "Teen Chef"
final showdown.
And now here's your host,
Rip Barker!
[ applause ]
Our teams will present
their meals
in courses to our judges,
who will score and evaluate
each meal progressively
until we're down to dessert
and the selection
of the new Mealtime
Network champions.
Gentlemen,
start your enchiladas.
♪ Time's up, and the light
is fading fast ♪
♪ This time, nothing's
gonna hold me back ♪
♪ Darkness can't
overtake me ♪
♪ My eyes are open,
and I see ♪
♪ The pools around me
throw some light ♪
♪ That's where ♪
♪ That's where hope begins ♪
[ laughter ]
♪ I know that life
is too crazy ♪
♪ To drive me insane ♪
♪ And when I'm sinking ♪
♪ I'm thinking
I'm used to the pain ♪
♪ When waves
are crashing me up ♪
♪ And they're
testing my will ♪
♪ I'll face them down ♪
♪ It's just a spill ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ I don't drown ♪
♪ I just get wet ♪
♪ Water's up above my head ♪
♪ I won't drown ♪
♪ I'm not done yet... ♪
While our judges
take a breather,
our contestants
will now prepare
their final dessert round.
[ applause ]
Team captains,
join your sous-chefs.
[ applause ]
Stop!
[ audience gasping ]
That dough's
no good!
Let's go
to a commercial break.
We'll be right back.
He told me he messed
with his dough
to sabotage him.
My producer's telling me
we won't be going
to commercial break.
Sweeps week.
Nice try, pal,
but this dough
is fine.
[Joe V.O.]
No, I mean it.
He put enough
liquid laxatives
in there
to suck out
the judges'
small intestines.
[ audience gasping ]
WILL: It's true.
Otto and I saw him
put something
in the dough today.
No, he didn't,
all right? It's fine.
I trust Matt completely.
Thank you.
Me, too!
He's my brother!
He'd never
do anything
like that!
If there's any chance
that anyone--
Test it!
I want that dough
tested now.
I vouch for
Matty's integrity.
We'd like
to thank the producers
of "Cooking with Zayde"
for allowing us
to continue with our
extended live show.
They'll return next week.
Our news isn't good.
It appears that
Team Tommy's pizzelle dough
was in fact tainted.
[ audience gasps ]
And so now--
"Any interference
with ingredients
"or procedures
disqualifies
the team
whose member did
said interfering."
Thank you. But the rules
go on to say
that, if the team captain
decides to dismiss
the offending individual
from the team,
they can go on to redo
the round in question.
Tommy, you have
a decision to make.
You and Dennis
can go head to head in
another dessert round,
but only if you fire Matt
from your team.
[ gasping, murmuring ]
RIP: What's it gonna be?
I--We're a team.
[Rip V.O.]
Okay,
but just so you make
a fully informed decision,
going into this last round,
Team Tommy
was in the lead.
You may want
to take a minute.
Win or lose,
we're a team.
So the winner
of the Mealtime
Network contest
is Team Dennis!
[ applause,
groaning ]
We're out of time now,
but we'd like--
Thank you so much!
I just want to say
how honored I am.
Where do I begin?
I have
my own show now.
We here
at the Mealtime Network
would like to invite all
of our contestants and
our in-studio audience
to join us tomorrow for
a very special afternoon
edition of our show
live from
the beautiful lake house
of our network owner,
where we will thank
all of our contestants
and officially
welcome Team Dennis
to our TV family
immediately following
"Brunhilde's Biscuits."
Thank you, and good night.
[ applause ]
[ Director V.O. ]
And we're out.
I'll interview
both of you after
the ceremony tomorrow.
MATT: I taught him
everything he knows.
[ laughs ]
Dude!
It's your speech.
You two are gonna resign
from the team today.
I'll keep you to help
behind the scenes,
but, uh,
in the fan email
that I've gotten
since last night,
it doesn't seem
like a good idea to...
split our audience's
focus among all of us.
Ooh!
[Tommy V.O.]
Even though I'm bummed
about losing
my dream of saving
the pizza parlor,
I realize that, if this had
all happened a month ago,
I would have bailed
on coming here today.
I would have just curled up
and disappeared
under the radar,
but I'm not. I'm here now
with my teammates,
and no one can break us.
And what I'm hearing
from this kid,
it seems like we're
not the only ones
who have been
pushed too far.
Sounds like this one's
pushing back.
[ Announcer ] "Teen Chef"
continues live.
Never mind that
we're not even really
urban poor kids.
Our mom's the live-in help
for his family.
Well, was, I guess,
after today.
But our team
is not
the rightful winner
of this contest,
and aside from me,
there are three guys who
made Team Tommy lose--
him...
[ gasping ]
What?
him...
and especially him.
[ chuckling ]
Here's how it
all went down.
[ music playing ]
And that's it.
I'm really, really sorry
for my part in this,
but I want you
to know that my brother
didn't have anything
to do with it.
My brother says,
"Yes, I did..."
"and we're a team, too."
[ applause ]
[ laughs ]
Ladies and gentlemen,
the real winners
of the Mealtime contest,
Team Tommy!
[ cheering ]
Congratulations,
Matt and Tommy.
What are you
gonna do with
your prize money?
I--I hear there's
this great old pizza
restaurant for sale.
[ laughs ]
Awesome.
Hey, maybe you can
tape your new TV show
from there.
Yeah!
Sounds good to me.
[ cheering ]
Ladies and gentlemen,
more with Team Tommy
right after
this short break.
Mm.
As you
may have guessed,
the demolition's off.
And as far
as any future work goes,
why don't you move
to Antarctica?
Let's hear
from our winners.
Um, thank you,
everyone.
Um, our...
[ slapping ]
Ow! Ow! Ow!
[ laughing ]
Ow! Hey.
[ groans ]
Relax, bro.
It'll only sting,
like, a week.
Or six!
Ah, ah, ah, hey.
[ laughter ]
When I'm ready,
I'll walk home.
So, T,
finish your speech!
Speech! Speech! Speech!
[ chanting ]
[ cheering ]
Uh,
boy, it's getting
pretty hot out here.
Sure is.
Yee-hoo!
Uh, team swim!
Everybody,
come on, join us!
♪ Make your change,
and you will see ♪
♪ One small step
is all we need ♪
♪ Ohh ♪
♪ There is an answer ♪
♪ There is no difference
between you and me ♪
♪ It lies
beyond our history ♪
♪ And if we only
take the time to see ♪
♪ We're all we need ♪
♪ Just take my hand ♪
[ whistle ]
♪ And see me as a brother ♪
♪ Look inside,
and you will find ♪
♪ Love exists
in every kind ♪
♪ Ohh ♪
♪ There is an answer ♪
[Tommy V.O.]
I think once you put aside
your first impressions
of people,
take the time
to give them a chance
and get to know
who they really are,
you might end up
being happily surprised
with the new friends
you discover.
They're the keepers,
you know,
the ones who will always be
on your team no matter what.
It also helps to stay strong
when things get tough.
Always remember
those people in your life
who care about you,
and move on from the ones
who never will,
and be cool
with taking the help
and the friendship
of those keepers.
Beats flying solo.
Trust me.
Even better, trust us.
♪ I will survive ♪
♪ And when we
carry this love ♪
♪ We're gonna light up
the night ♪
♪ Singing we're keeping on ♪
♪ We're keeping on ♪
♪ I was high in a daze ♪
♪ Sold my soul
for lemonade ♪
♪ A kingdom come
and set me free ♪
♪ I was blind,
but now I see ♪
♪ I will survive ♪
♪ And when we
carry this love ♪
♪ We're gonna light up
the night ♪
♪ Singing we're keeping on ♪
♪ We're keeping ♪
♪ I will survive ♪
♪ And when we
carry this love ♪
♪ We're gonna light up
the night ♪
♪ Singing we're keeping on ♪
♪ We're keeping on ♪
♪ On ♪
♪ Keep keeping on ♪
[ new song begins ]
♪ Everyone's talking ♪
♪ Just to fill some space ♪
♪ And everything's nothing ♪
♪ Till it means heartbreak ♪
♪ Words without power ♪
♪ Just evaporate ♪
♪ Don't want to hear it today ♪
♪ Today ♪
♪ Out here on a tightrope ♪
♪ And ♪
♪ High above a long rope ♪
♪ What's the point
of wishing ♪
♪ And ♪
♪ When nobody's listening? ♪
♪ I'm listening ♪
♪ Hello, hello ♪
♪ This is my voice ♪
♪ Through the white noise ♪
♪ Words only hurt ♪
♪ When you let them matter ♪
♪ Don't let them matter ♪
♪ It's only chatter ♪
[ new song begins ]
♪ The dam's
about to break down ♪
♪ The water's so cold ♪
♪ My heart is on the ground ♪
♪ I'm losing control ♪
♪ But I don't know
which way to turn ♪
♪ Don't know which way to go ♪
♪ When it seems
the more that I learn ♪
♪ It's the less that I know ♪
♪ When waves
are crashing me up ♪
♪ And they're
testing my will ♪
♪ I'll face them down ♪
♪ It's just a spill ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ I don't drown ♪
♪ I just get wet ♪
♪ Water's up above my head ♪
♪ I won't drown ♪
♪ I'm not done yet ♪
♪ I'm breaking the surface ♪
♪ It's hard to see,
and I can't breathe ♪
♪ Caught in the undertow ♪
♪ It's dark and deep ♪
♪ But still I know ♪
♪ I know that life
is too crazy ♪
♪ To drive me insane ♪
♪ And when I'm sinking ♪
♪ I'm thinking
I'm used to the pain ♪
♪ When waves
are crashing me up ♪
♪ And they're
testing my will ♪
♪ I'll face them down ♪
♪ It's just a spill ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ I don't drown ♪
♪ I just get wet ♪
♪ Water's up above my head ♪
♪ I won't drown ♪
♪ I'm not done yet ♪
♪ I'm breaking the surface ♪
♪ Yeah ♪