- How about that?
- Nice meet!
Or maybe it was luck.
- Just like before, huh?
- Yes, except for your uniform.
They were specially made for us!
Silvio, soon you have to decide,
what you intend to do?
If you start, it means
free time, girls and money.
It's totally green...!
- Why don't you want to?
- Why would I do that?
Get up, I said!
If you make it across
the river, you get to go.
What are you up to?
They shoot you..!
Go away!
I will try to stop them!
CORBARI
A member of the National Guard
was murdered this afternoon..!
If the culprits don't
report within 24 hours...
"It was I, Corbari,
who killed the soldier."
"He was my friend,
but that doesn't count."
"From now on everyone
takes care of themselves."
What should we do with the sign?
Shoot it down...!
What are you doing here?
Turn it off, I can't see a thing!
I appreciate your visit.
But do you think you
will find your way home?
What I intend to do,
I will do alone.
- I want to join.
- I thought so...
Professor, this is not for you.
You are wanted now.
The only sensible thing
is to join the partisans.
Go now! You don't think I'm
going back to the army, do you?
From now on, no one
will give me any orders.
Go back to school.
- What are you waiting for?
- I have finished my work!
Join the partisans and
become a tin soldier...!
You laugh... but the
resistance movement...
You don't understand...!
- The resistance movement
is our renaissance!
- What did you say?
It's too deep for me!
"Corbari kept joking with me.
But I was his first follower."
"I wasn't going to leave him."
"Now it began...two men,
two hand grenades and a revolver..."
"We had known each
other for several years.
In the autumn of 1943, we not only
became brothers in arms,
but true friends."
"I didn't know where we were heading.
We lived from one day to another..."
"Like the partisans, we had to
improvise...learn from scratch."
"Corbari learned quickly..."
"It wasn't long before our
two-man army expanded..."
"Our second recruit was Miguel,
a convict..."
"Carlo and Duilio were the next two."
"And with them came Nicola,
a youngster we should
have sent home again."
"But the kid didn't want to go."
Quiet now...and not a sound!
You can't miss the bus...!
Are you sick, kid?
Let me be!
To tell the truth, we were
probably all a little scared.
Cease-fire!
"We freed 50 men who were going
to concentration camps in Germany."
"They joined us. Now Corbari's
partisans were to be reckoned with."
"But Corbari wasn't happy.
Everything was getting harder."
"But his vitality
was contagious..."
Different vintages could
write their own history.
I can't live here any more.
Maybe I'm a coward
but perhaps you can persuade my husband
to let me go to Switzerland this winter.
This year I can supplement with
a delicious thing: Corbari 1944.
A brand new vintage...and
a very ambitious one at that.
I find it wasteful... not
to mention insulting!
On the contrary...it reveals a lot.
Yes, I put it on the front page...
It was the worst thing
that could have happened.
The less publicity, the better.
Especially since he seems to be
able to do good advertising on his own.
Everyone is talking about Corbari.
The workers certainly intend to strike
to show their approval.
- What does the government intend to do?
- These are hard times...
Corbari are still at the local
level and are therefore our enemy.
And as the winemaker said:
"Invite the enemy to party
and glam, or destroy him..."
We should probably eliminate Corbari.
"Underground organisations started
supplying us with arms and ammunition.
"Those who retrieved this avoided
detection by disguising themselves."
"But one day…"
A car has been shadowing
us for the last few kilometres.
Check out what's
in the car behind us!
Turn off here!
Get out!
Your papers..!
Inez Agostini...
- It says that she is studying medicine.
According to the German commander..?
I also work as a midwife.
- When I'm not assisting my father.
- Who is he?
Professor Agostini...chief
surgeon at the hospital.
Well, a real big shot...
We were getting worried…
Has something happened?
- Someone shadowed us...
- Michele and Carlo checked it out.
- Get the weapons..!
- Shouldn't Corbari go there?
Why did you have this
wanted notice in the car?
I think you're a spy.
- That's why you followed us.
- No preconceived notions now...
I want to join you...and I knew
about the weapons delivery.
- My father is also a resistance man!
- I'm sure she's a spy.
We have to get rid of her.
I'm not a spy!
Michele, don't shoot!
Are you crazy?
You would have murdered
her if I hadn't stopped you!
- She's lying! She's a spy!
- Corbari...
I have been looking for you for days!
Let her go...I'll find out
if she's telling the truth.
- What are you writing today?
- That Corbari and the prisoner make up...
I'd had enough. At first
it was fun to get married.
We were like grown up children...
...as long as the honeymoon lasted.
Then he started to become like my father.
Business came before everything else.
The marriage blew out the window…
I couldn't stand that.
- You were wondering what to do next?
- Not any more.
- Could you have killed her?
- Well, I thought she was a spy.
I would have shot her.
Take the car and go home now.
I tell the others that
you were allowed to go.
I intend to stay with you.
OK, but I will be
in charge of you.
- Don't start hanging out...
- I'll come with you up into the mountains!
Just the thought is ridiculous.
I don't mind, but the
others wouldn't understand.
Calm down now!
Be sensible...
Should I be sane, you should
start acting like a man!
Right now you're acting like shit!
Hit me again! So they get
to know what they really are!
- What did you find out?
- He's up in the mountains...
A large headquarters
with about 20 soldiers.
So what...we'll blast him away!
Corbari here! You have
two minutes to disappear!
Massimo, go and check.
They went out the back door!
We found two prisoners in the basement.
Dad!
"Unbelievable, but we took the
town without firing a single shot."
"Apparently the name Corbari
said more than we had thought."
Is this what you want?
"I had always tried to find
out Corbari's motives."
"Now he had got
what he was looking for
"and we sat up all night
discussing the future of the town."
"His enthusiasm was so great
that nothing seemed impossible."
You must be Corbari? I am Juvara,
commander of the second brigade.
We have a lot to
deal with together.
I decided to occupy the
area and manage it my way.
- Napoleon..?
- Yes, what a man!
Call me what you will, but I
want to create a republic here.
It's an old dream. I divide
the land between the farmers.
You are an Alpinist...without
the Tyrolean banner.
I prefer the plains
to the mountains.
Outside the window I see
open landscape...and fascists.
People see me up here and see
that here you can live without fear.
- That's why I'm not coming with you.
- Calm down now...
We have set an example for them
and we have to agree wholeheartedly.
No, they must be allowed
to choose for themselves!
Did you hear? He wants us to go
up into the mountains and tend sheep!
- You are a clown..?
- Yes.
I'm a clown, but I perform in public.
Not behind closed doors.
- Corbari, I know I'm right.
- Convince me...
We are very few...our first
task is to organise ourselves.
The time is not right
for what you want to do.
If we don't unite, we're out.
- You're probably too stupid to understand.
- How do you measure intelligence?
Forget all the clichés...We must
raid the enemy and then escape.
- I want to get more out..!
- Teach the men to fight!
We must become part
of a comprehensive plan.
- What more do you want?
- There are many things.
- One thing is clear: I want more!
- He wants more...
Fanatic..!
- It is impossible to talk to you.
- Talk? You give orders!
- Stay here...
- No, you are an impossible man.
- You don't hate me, do you?
- Only your flaws.
- They don't know I have any.
- Good luck...
This must be our free zone.
Martino, will it work?
Sure...You know one thing?
This should have been
done a long time ago.
We need to name it...something
everyone can remember.
Trajano's free zone?
No, that wasn't good.
- "Free Zone"... but with
another name before it.
- Like Corbari..?
"Corbari's Free Zone"...
that sounds good, I think.
Look here, Corbari! I picked him
up on the way from the mountains!
- He probably doesn't like us!
- That's why the bells fell silent?
- What are you doing, Father?
- This is no place for me.
There are as many faithful
souls here as before!
Toll the church bells!
You will surely have a
large congregation today.
This is the first service
in this free area.
"Free area" means
liberated land...your own land.
- The village is yours. What day is it?
- Sunday...
- Which saint, Father?
- San Guiseppe.
In the future, Saint
Guiseppe will be your saint.
Each must harvest his piece,
enjoy the fruits and defend it.
For example... 40 hectares
entitles you to four rifles.
- How do I take care of myself?
- Nice...
My colleagues and I will liberate
new areas. Return, let's leave again.
We should both be
here and not be here.
Some stay and teach you.
There must be no doubt.
You stand on your own two feet..!
Well done!
"Schoolboys want to
learn how to handle guns..."
"Military training every day..."
You won't be able
to shoot like that...
"The administration is growing,
but the procurement of
food is becoming difficult."
"The population is cooperating patiently."
"Freedom is an unexpected gift,
something one doesn't surrender easily."
I never learn the signature...
Tear it apart, I know..!
Who is it late? Mario Bunaldi!
"The Committee on Prosperity
has started making its own decisions
"and this to the great
delight of the local people."
Check out Martino...
he's happy as a lark!
He has come up with a new way
of describing freedom to people…
"...all debts and bank
loans have been settled."
Corbari, a new republic shouldn't
be burdened with debt, should it?
"The raids against the fascists are
becoming more and more common."
"Corbari has promised to disarm
the zone, but there are still weapons..."
"Tonight we had the honour
of executing three Germans."
"I'm beginning to realise more and
more how difficult and cruel our job is."
So, are you awake yet?
You're agree on the
free zone, don't you?
- You're not mad at me, are you?
- Don't..!
Something is happening now!
There are 20 of us...
Can we meet Corbari?
No, I want to see Corbari dead!
When I return they shall be
happy if the area of ​​Trajano
only gives them a small corner.
To be buried in...
Sabotage, strikes... agitators
trying to overthrow law and order.
There is only one thing... send
them to the camps in Germany!
Such action must be taken, but we
don't have sufficient strength here.
This is politics... your
words no longer hold.
- Our properties are threatened.
- Is that an ultimatum?
I was promised that my
properties would be protected.
The protection of private property
must exist in every regime.
We want to see action now!
That's why I moved
my brigade here...
You probably don't know my gut.
His brigade is the most powerful.
Of course they cost a bit,
but they do the job.
- They are here tomorrow.
- Corbari is going away...
...he must not be given the
chance to harm the entire population.
I order an attack
straight from the front.
In this case, it is necessary
to understand one's enemy
to be able to take
advantage of his shortcomings.
What are you thinking about?
I want to get this
done a little faster.
If we're going to defend ourselves...
we need to be able to do it soon.
The whole town needs to
realise what might happen.
- Tell them tomorrow.
- Don't worry.
And tell them not
to have any illusions.
We must not worry
about the risks.
The important thing
now is to finish it.
Let him speak clearly..!
Tomorrow is a big
day for Trajano and us.
"The population must gather to
appoint a council to manage our zone."
"Corbari has handed
over command to Martino
"and I feel that he already
has other things on his mind."
Now we have direct distribution,
lower prices
to the delight of all housewives.
What do you want?
The people of Kadrejago need you!
We have occupied the town
and need someone to defend it!
- It's outside our zone!
- It's only three miles...
Miguel, we're leaving!
- There is a meeting tomorrow!
- You can start without me.
I might expand the zone
to include Kadrejago too!
You're leading me into a trap...
you're a spy aren't you?
Ridiculous...wait and see.
The whole town is waiting for you!
An ambush, huh?
Where would it take place?
Where?
- After the Magnesoli crossing.
- How many soldiers?
I don't know...maybe 30-40.
- What else do you know?
- They just told me
to jump off before the intersection.
Then the shooting would begin.
Down the street..!
I feel good...
Are you hit?
- It is nothing.
- Quiet...
It's a splinter.
What the hell is that..?
Trajano...
"We were about a week
from Guiliano's headquarters."
"Michele and the others had
tried in vain to get him to stop."
"His condition was critical."
"He couldn't forgive
himself for being late."
What is going on?
- We retreat...
- You were lucky to find us.
Guiliano has moved
higher up in the mountains.
Corbari, why didn't you
tell me you were injured?
Let me look…
It was close...
Cotton and alcohol..!
Relax... I'll take care of this.
Just let me rest...
You know what they did?
- I was fooled...all the people...
- It could have happened to anyone.
- Take it easy.
- I was tricked...
We might be able to drive
them away from Trajano...
Then we can discuss
what can be done.
We can't attack yet.
We must cooperate and wait.
The Allies have promised to help,
but we are not ready yet.
Are we ready for spring...
- Are you listening?
- No, I don't want to listen.
- Lay down. You have a high fever.
- I must be an idiot.
Coming here and talking to you...
it was completely pointless.
Fighting for freedom
is not revolution.
- I'm asking for your opinions...
- Shut up, or we will.
Shut up, he's ill!
- You are alone now, Corbari.
- You don't know what
you're talking about...
Cassade, tell him..!
- Has he gone?
- I don't know...
- I'm here...
- Tell him.
- They were all killed.
- You and Nicole are alive!
- We can start over!
- You have to face the facts!
- What is he saying?
Take off the bandage,
I can't hear anything.
It's time for you to wake
up from your dream.
- I don't hear, Professor.
- Listen, for God's sake!
- Don't scream... you
don't have to scream...
Are you sleeping?
We wait another day,
so it's just sleep.
A group of partisans will
arrive here tomorrow evening.
I hope Guiliano appoints
you head of the group.
Are you awake?
Inez was not killed!
She is here with us...
You are not sleeping..?
You just don't want to know.
"I wanted to find a way to
show that I believed in him."
"My feelings for Trajano
had been as strong as his."
"I wanted to thank him…
but couldn't find the words."
So he has abandoned everything?
Trajano, the Republic, the followers.
It looks like that.
- I don't believe that.
- He's coming with us.
I don't think so.
CORBARI IS DEAD
"Corbari left us yesterday
and Inez has not been seen."
"According to him I am more
dead than the friends of Trajano."
"I'm glad I'm free from
him and never met him."
- What are you doing in my office?
- I have news for the newspaper.
And since there is no electricity,
I turned off the light.
The way you are dressed,
I thought you were a man.
What news is that?
- It must be a front page headline.
- The presses are already running...
But if Hitler challenged
Mussolini to a duel,
I'll stop the presses.
- Corbari is alive and well.
- Where is he then..?
Here...
... alive and well.
Now you do believe that, don't you?
Sit down...
Call the press and change
the headline to: "Corbari is alive".
Change the front page to a
nine-column... "Corbari is alive".
I'll explain later!
It is a new political thrust.
Tell me about more
space for a N.B.
- How many columns?
- A small one is fine.
Leave a column free
for the time being.
You probably think it's a lie,
but it was nice to meet you.
I have always admired you...
and especially your courage.
You fight for justice and salvation.
I don't need your admiration,
you scumbag!
What do you mean?
I admire you!
I thought you were alive,
but was forced to publish it!
- I'm only following orders...
- From who? The names..?
OK...Visciati, Orlandi...
the big landowner..!
They are the ones responsible..!
This speaks against you...
The headline is ready
and will soon go to press.
And the empty space?
The unexpected...death...
...for our editor.
This way!
"Corbari is alive"...
He knows a lot of tricks.
You have to have a lot of experience
to handle a person like this.
How about this?
"Our editor has passed away..."
Corbari will probably try again.
It's just a matter of waiting...
Corbari is dead...
- Hopeless...I'm done now.
- Not as long as I believe in you.
It's no use, Inez.
Who do you see in the mirror?
It's Corbari...
Do you recognise him? A lifetime
of living Corbari, with company.
- Sorry, you didn't sign!
- I do it in the car.
You are welcome...
Try nothing!
They got rich by taking
advantage of the workers.
Then came Corbari.
What are you waiting for?
Cut him down!
Hurry up!
What are you staring at?
Wait in the car..!
Down there...down there!
A few more minutes...
Suddenly I heard a shot..!
- Did you see them?
- There were two men...I shot...
I think it's that car!
You there..!
There they are!
They ran out into the backyard!
- How many were they?
- Two, I think.
They have gone...
They should all be shot!
You are incompetent!
It's almost treason!
It is incomprehensible!
It's not just once he
slips away...but trice!
- Eluded capture again!
- We discovered two of his hiding places.
After they moved, yes!
Did he leave the address..?
He's still on the move!
How can you let one man make
such a laughing stock of you?
We have to apply to someone else!
Start by interrogating them!
If this continues, half the town
will probably be interrogated!
I know...he has to get out
of here. No danger, Inez.
Don't cry.
"I never wanted to see him again,
but the news of him got me
to realise that I could not
be separated from him."
"I spoke to Guiliano and
got his permission to go."
"He probably respected
Corbari's individuality
"and when I left,
all the others followed."
Come here!
- Maybe I've overlooked something.
- They were only a few seconds ahead.
The woman opened the
door and said they had left.
- Corbari doesn't exist!
- The men who were killed, then?
They just said it was Corbari!
You have done enough now.
We leave while we can.
No, I have to follow
through on the plans.
It's too late to back out now.
If I don't take the last one,
everyone thinks I've given up!
They shouldn't get
that satisfaction...
Bring all the women, who had
anything to do with Corbari, here.
- In person or a photograph.
- There can't be many.
His assistant is a woman.
It is a logical conclusion.
Remember the woman
who led them astray?
- That woman..?
- Keep her under constant surveillance.
They force everyone to
somehow pay for those killed.
I think it's nasty.
It's hard to find something to eat.
Everyone must have a ration card.
That's all we have.
The funeral is
tomorrow evening at 9.
It's dark then
and it fits perfectly.
Corbari and I ambushed
the first Germans here.
I'll never forget
how scared I was.
Everyone without exception
must attend the ceremony!
I want the whole town there!
- The patrol force, then?
- The whole brigade will be present.
- All preparations are done.
- Good...
- It could be her!
- Maybe it...
The big eyes are familiar.
She's the one we're looking for.
She will lead us to Corbari.
Bring plenty of copies.
Make sure everyone
gets a photograph of her.
- There are no children playing there.
- What time is it?
Don't know...about five.
I saw the sunset.
"No problem...we'll
pick you up at dawn."
We smuggled them out this morning,
but I don't know where they went.
They are probably in the
mountains somewhere.
- Yes, I guess so.
It won't be that difficult.
Good luck...
- There are fascists everywhere!
- I know.
See you...
From now on, you
are a saint, Corbari.
Now we speed up!
- I go to the village and shop.
You are hungry, right?
Be careful, it's dangerous.
What is it?
- Don't forget...
- I'll be careful.
- We can probably build more villages now.
- Probably 10-20 pieces
but we should probably
forget the word "free zones".
- We can liberate entire regions.
- We have to expand the business.
- We have a lot to talk about.
- Right now you haven't said anything.
Everything will go our way...
and even better.
- Did you hear any noise?
- It's just the river.
It's just the river…
Now I heard something...
should I look for it?
You were right...
it's just the river.
"Corbari has changed.
The enthusiasm is still there
"but is now more controlled,
mature."
"What did he mean when
he said we should set a goal?"
"And fight until we achieve it..."
Run!
Keep on firing!
Help is needed here!
Corbari...run!
Disappear!
Come up..!
Leave, you too!
No, I'll never leave you.
I won't leave you…