NETFLIX PRESENTS
Atrocious.
How many more deaths
would be necessary, Sir?
What can we do
if their determination is so strong?
Lucifer seals their lips so tightly
that we could pull them slowly to pieces
and still they wouldn't reveal
the secrets of the Sabbath to us.
What if the Sabbath doesn't exist?
What if it's just a dream?
If it's just a dream,
how is it that so many women
dream the same?
Counting the three from last night,
we've reached a total
of 77 executions, Sir.
We just need to deal
with the sailing towns now.
Sailors.
We haven't seen a man for miles,
just women.
Welcome, Your Honor.
I'm Father Cristóbal de Azpilikueta,
at your service.
The Lord of Urtubi entrusted me…
Your Honor, I'm Father Cristóbal
de Azpilikueta, at your--
Surgeon.
Excuse me.
Your Honor, I'm Father Cristóbal
de Azpilikueta, at your service.
The Lord of Urtubi entrusted me
to be at your service…
Father.
His Honor is tired.
I hope his chambers are ready.
Go.
- My Lord Judge…
- Where would I put so many people?
The soldiers can sleep in the stable.
But they also eat!
Who would pay for such expenses?
His Majesty.
Seagulls are coming
Leaving for Newfoundland
Great dangers at sea
Greater dangers in the heart
Great dangers at sea await
Take the one on the right now.
Has your father
taken you to Newfoundland?
He can't.
Isn't he in charge?
Don't you know women cannot sail?
Yes, they can!
You know nothing!
Have you ever sailed?
I haven't, but María has.
Have you sailed?
No, I haven't.
Not my sister. The other María.
María, the blond one?
She's a friend of mine. I'll ask her.
María "The Seagull."
She was called that because
she was always running along the shore.
She would run and shout.
How did she do it, Olaia?
I want to go to Newfoundland!
Ana, how can you tell
so many silly stories in one day?
-Give me the roll of hemp, please.
-He took her to the forest glade.
-Where we lit the fire?
-There!
Your father said,
"Climb the highest branch."
"Climb, little seagull, climb higher."
"Higher."
"Even higher."
Ana, María, go inside.
We're looking for Ana Ibarguren,
María Ibarguren,
Maider Aguirre and Olaia Isasi.
Why?
What's wrong, grandmother?
What's your name?
Don't move!
Go and get her!
Run!
Get them, soldiers! Catch them!
Don't move.
Come on, go after her!
They're running away! Over there!
Her eyes!
-We didn't do anything wrong.
-Lower your eyes!
Up against the wall!
Don't move.
I'll do it myself.
-That's it, look. That's it.
-Don't look at me.
It's all right. That's it.
Where's Katalin?
This is a mistake.
They have the wrong people.
No, they don't.
We're here because of you.
What?
You and your damn goat!
-Goat?
-Then why else?
It can't be because of the goat.
Then why else?
Up against the wall!
Lower your eyes!
All of you, against the wall!
Up against the wall!
Maider Aguirre.
She's this one.
Lower your eyes!
Katalin, where were you?
-I don't know.
-Why don't you know?
Tell me what they did to you.
Asked questions.
About what?
About you.
About Ana and me?
About all of you.
What did you say?
-The truth.
-What truth?
They want to know when
we went to the forest glade.
What we did there. Where we went.
What else?
They want to know how to get there.
I had to point out the way
to them many times.
and show them on a map.
Everybody in town
knows the way to the glade.
They don't need to lock us up for that.
Apparently, somebody saw us go there.
Who?
I don't know.
And what's their problem?
Katalin.
Then they asked me questions…
-Kind of…
-Kind of what?
I don't know.
Think.
They want to know how
we got home at night.
What else?
I don't know.
I don't know…
What the devil did they ask?
I told you.
When they realize
we haven't done anything wrong,
they'll let us go.
What have you done, Ana?
They'll let us go.
Why me?
Calm down. They'll let us go.
Katalin, who interrogated you?
I don't know.
You keep on repeating "I don’t know"…
They were right there,
and you can't describe them?
No.
I couldn't see them.
Were they hiding?
No.
But if I looked at them,
they'd hit me here.
Up against wall! All of you!
Sir, you're mistaken.
I haven't done anything.
My name is Olaia Isasi. I'm a weaver.
Olaia Isasi.
No.
If this has to do with the goat,
we returned it.
-We just wanted milk.
-Wait.
We haven't done anything.
Stop it, Maider!
Calm down!
Calm down, Maider!
Maider!
Do you want me to calm down?
-That bitch has informed on us!
-What do you mean?
Maider, please.
You heard.
So, what's she doing here?
She's confessed…
to a crime.
What crime?
They wouldn't say.
Did you believe them?
Have you thought
why, all of a sudden, this nice girl
wants to become friends
with a group of simple weavers?
What would she gain?
To be locked up with us?
Let's suppose that Katalin
has done something bad,
something terrible.
Before she gets caught,
she becomes friends with us.
And then she says that we did it
or that we forced her.
Why did you come back so soon?
What did you tell them?
Are you accusing me, Ana?
Since we were small.
How many times have I defended you?
She is not accusing you, Maider.
Look at this poor girl.
Do you think she's capable
of doing horrible things?
With that angel face.
Don't listen to Maider.
She's accused us all.
What?
Ana Ibarguren.
What did Maider say?
Olaia! What did Maider say?
That we are…
witches.
What?
Witches!
Witches?
Father Cristóbal.
You've known us since we were children.
You know we aren't witches.
Talk to me in Christian.
Father Cristóbal, please.
You know very well that we aren't witches.
-I'm not a witch.
-Lower your eyes!
I'm not a witch.
If you aren't one,
how did you know I'd ask that?
You asked the others.
What made you think that,
if they are, you are one, too?
I haven't said I am.
Why didn’t you say so?
Is it a secret?
Because I am not.
What is… a witch?
Don't you know?
I'm asking you.
How could you know you aren't one
if you don't know what one is?
A witch is a person
that hurts other people.
And haven't you ever hurt other people?
Not in that way.
In what way do you hurt other people?
I've never bewitched anyone.
I asked, in what way?
Why do you say I'm a witch?
Did I say you were?
Who said she was?
Did I?
No, Your Honor.
You said it yourself.
One of your friends,
Olaia Isasi, has already confessed.
Do you want to read it?
Second paragraph.
No? Well, I'll read it for you.
"Ana bewitched us.
She forced us to summon
Beelzebub, Satan, Astaroth,
Abaddon, Belial…"
Wicked grin.
Noted, Your Honor.
It's funny that you try
to make us all believe the same story.
Obscene position of the legs.
Noted, Your Honor.
It may just be the opposite.
You may be the victim
who was bewitched by them, right?
Nobody has bewitched anybody.
Never?
-No.
-What did you do then?
Nothing at all.
Do you spend day and night
doing nothing?
-I do other things.
-What kind of things?
-We enjoy walking.
-Do you?
-Like everybody else.
-What else?
We also enjoy the forest and the cliffs.
Sometimes, the night falls
and we walk back in the moonlight.
It's easy if you know the way.
Do you dance?
-Sometimes.
-With whom?
-Just by ourselves.
-Are there any men?
They're all out at sea.
Who do you dance for then?
For Him?
For whom?
Very well.
Let's go back to the beginning.
You told me the facts,
but you didn't tell me the truth.
-I did.
-No.
I have inferred it from your silence.
What does "inferred" mean?
The Judge knows your thoughts
better than yourself.
Now you'll give me the details
of the Sabbath rite.
-I don't know what the Sabbath is.
-Of course you do.
You've just confessed it.
Do you mean the Jewish rite?
The Witches' Sabbath.
-Who do you summon?
-What?
Who do you summon?
Do you sing praises to God?
Yes.
Is it God you want to warm
with the fire of your kisses?
We don't want any other warmth
than the warmth of your kisses.
It's just an old song.
-What's wrong with it?
-Sing it.
Sing the summons.
-Do you want me to sing it here?
-Please.
Listen to the echoes of seagulls
-Excuse me.
-When leaving for Newfoundland
Can you explain to me
what exactly is the Witches' Sabbath?
No.
Because nobody has seen it.
Think you're clever, don't you?
Sing the summoning, the real one.
Did he ask you about the Sabbath, too?
No. When I spat at Father Cristóbal,
they brought me back here.
He yelled at me, "Sabbath, Sabbath!"
That's what he said.
What?
He asked me to remember the Sabbath.
How could you remember something
that you don't know?
The memory lies.
The mind lies.
He said one of you has bewitched my mind
so that I wouldn't remember
you took me to the Sabbath.
That you offered me to Lucifer.
Who is Lucifer?
The devil.
That you made me experience
wonderful things in the Sabbath.
Is that true?
Ana.
María.
Ana, listen to me. Come.
Ana, hurry up. Come.
Oneka, be quiet!
What are you doing?
You have to escape.
Go. They'll hear you.
-You must escape now.
-We know, but how?
I don't know, but we must find a way.
You must leave.
Your grandmother…
What were you going to tell us?
Oneka.
Your grandmother hid me in her house.
She came to try and get you out
but she was beaten away
Is she hurt?
No, it isn't serious.
Is that all you wanted to say?
Your grandmother told me that…
a friend of hers, in the market, told her…
women are being arrested.
They take them to the top of a hill,
they tie them up to a stake
and they burn them…
alive.
Take care, my dear.
Be good.
We just need to wait
until the next full moon.
Always, since I can remember,
sailors come back
soon after the full moon.
The tide is perfect. They never miss it.
Last year, my father
came back two weeks later.
If María says so, then it must be true.
Katalin thinks more days went by
because she always misses her father.
What do you mean?
That my mind deceives me?
That's why I don't remember the Sabbath.
This food…
tastes like shit.
It's disgusting.
Lara is listening.
Good. That'll motivate her.
We've been like this for four months,
and it seems like years.
Will this come to an end some day?
You know what, Father?
We're sick and tired.
In some villages, we had to requisition
barns and mills
because the prisons were too crowded.
Moral corruption is so widespread
that we even had to execute
three parish priests.
They celebrated the Christian Mass by day
and the Black Mass by night.
I cannot understand
why in the Basque Country
there's more sorcery
than any other part of the world.
People here are as fickle as the sea.
The sea, that road without roads
where men get lost.
My father used to be a sailor.
-Of…
-The sea took him.
That's why, at home,
we eat more meat than fish.
Of course.
But he used to beat me.
Punishment is good for curbing vices.
-The sea, that road without roads where…
-What vices?
Vices of the flesh.
Yours, mine.
-Just a few… and out of necessity.
-Women spend half of the year alone.
They are vulnerable to any influence.
We're on the borders
of three kingdoms,
the mountains and the sea.
We were invaded by the Muslims,
by the Jews.
All those false religions
take advantage of poverty and ignorance
to corrupt the people.
And there's something even worse.
The pagan demons,
which have been expelled from the Indies
by the missionaries,
hide inside the whalers
in order to invade Christian lands,
they come through the port.
That's why I devote so much effort
to bless every ship that sails in or out.
Father.
Yes.
Ask them to bring bread
to see if this improves.
Some bread, please.
Give them bread.
How long do you need
to find material evidence?
About six or seven.
Days?
No, infidels.
And they are very hairy.
Give me two days.
Two days.
The sentence must be drafted.
As you say.
Two days to find evidence.
The next day, I’ll pronounce the verdict.
The day after, the execution.
Make sure the carriage
is ready that afternoon.
Basque flies.
I do not want
to question your methods, Your Honor,
but you haven't even asked them
about their curses.
I didn't see them with my own eyes,
but the poor people from the village
have reported them.
Sheep suddenly stop producing milk,
Lord of Urtubi's bad harvest,
abortions.
His Majesty has not sent us here
to resolve neighborhood problems, Father.
We're fighting against a Satanic sect.
Do you know the story of Frau Troffea?
In the year of our Lord 1518,
in the city of Strasbourg,
Frau Troffea began to dance.
God cursed that city
as it gave in to the heresy of Luther.
People barely survived
overwhelmed by poverty.
On that morning, Frau Troffea
went to the riverbank with her son
and drowned him with her own hands
to prevent him from dying slowly,
malnourished, suffering from gangrene.
In the afternoon, she started dancing.
She danced and danced.
Day and night…
until she was dead.
People,
eager for horrifying entertainment,
gathered around her.
But the people didn't know
that, sometimes,
the spectators become the players,
protagonists of horror.
Soon, 153 persons were dancing
day and night in that square.
The soldiers could not stop them
because they were dancing too.
The town authorities
could not issue decrees
because they were dancing too.
Exorcists could not celebrate their rites
because they were dancing like whores.
And that dancing epidemic
in Strasbourg caused 359 deaths.
There's nothing more dangerous
than a woman dancing.
But the most macabre dances,
the obscenest of them,
are those that take place in the forests
because they're secret,
because only Lucifer
and His servants know them,
because only they
have celebrated the Sabbath rites.
If we don't stop them soon,
those wicked witches
will reverse the order of the universe.
Higher.
Higher, higher.
Father…
take care.
Be good.
Lower your eyes!
Witch!
Yes, the Sabbath!
I'm a witch!
Olaia is right.
We must distract him.
Talk nonsense?
Make fun of him?
We must talk about the Sabbath.
Didn't you understand?
They'll burn us whether
we confess the Sabbath or not.
He's convinced we've celebrated it.
How can you be so sure?
Because he said so. And I had to sign it.
If they already think we're guilty,
why haven’t they killed us yet?
He wants to know more.
We must tell him what he wants.
It's the only way to buy some time.
What if we don't have time
to buy any?
-Yes, we do.
-There's one week left before a full moon.
One week…
Distract him for one week just by talking?
It's impossible.
It isn't impossible. I assure you.
What do you know about the Sabbath?
We know there's dancing,
there's singing…
Children are sacrificed.
Did they tell you that?
The devil is invoked. Lucifer!
I know only one person in the world
who can talk constantly for days.
Really?
How many stories should we tell?
There are six of us.
If each of us can speak for one day,
we'll be safe.
I couldn't do it.
Not even for one hour.
We can do it!
Let's make a story up
for each of us!
For example,
you could have drowned
every sailor you didn't like.
Of course!
So I'm the only witch here then!
No. We will all do the same.
María will say
she has fireflies in her belly.
And she has fucked Lucifer!
Really?
Have you noticed how they look at us?
Ana.
I can’t remember anything.
What shall I say?
You'll tell the story
of María "The Seagull."
Every time she complained
because she couldn't follow
the sailors to Newfoundland,
your father would tell her,
"You're still too young
to grow wings,
but next year, they'll grow.
Now leave me alone."
She used to ask her friends
to look at her back
to find out
if wings were beginning to grow.
Until one day when I said
"come here, little girl."
I took her to the forest glade.
But this is a secret.
A secret between us.
I made her climb
the highest tree in the world.
To the highest branch.
I told her,
"let go of one hand."
And María let go of one hand.
Then I told her, "let go of one foot."
Then, "let go of the other hand."
And María
let go of the other hand…
and…
Did she fall?
-Did she die?
-No.
She flew away.
Did she go to the Sabbath?
Listen.
She'll drive him crazy.
Maider!
Is she breathing?
Olaia?
Spider’s web! Hurry up!
Hurry up!
What did you say, Olaia?
Huh? What?
What did they ask?
-Didn't they ask anything?
-Ana, please!
It's for our own good.
Calm yourself.
María Ibarguren.
I am the witch.
Me too.
Show me the mark of Lucifer.
Come on, girl.
You can prevent unnecessary suffering.
He didn't mark me.
It's a painless mark.
If you scream when they prick you,
they'll continue until…
Why should I trust you?
-Do you have any choice?
-Father, if you use that devilish language
you'll pass to the side of the accused.
What a strange language.
They're rustic languages
used to talk with the beasts.
Dialects.
Dialects are languages to hide things.
I'll write it down, Your Honor.
Here.
Where?
He marked me here.
False hope.
I'm sorry. I've made a mistake. I'm sorry.
It's always the same, Father.
The evil one likes to hide his mark.
If it's not under the hair,
he hides it in the shameful parts.
Even inside the nose or here,
for example.
In the arm.
Where?
Here?
Listen to the echo of the seagulls
When leaving for Newfoundland
It isn't there. She's suffering.
She isn't suffering.
She's twisting with pleasure.
Great danger on the sea
Greater danger in our hearts
Just like the tree
The roots in the ground
And the branches towards the sea
This is my spirit
If you leave me here
In the deep well of my soul
You sail, my love
Visit me each night…
Listen.
She's summoning her master.
Visit me every night
I'll open the door for you
From Newfoundland to this port
From the forest to the cliffs
We don't want any other warmth
Than the warmth of your kisses
Stand up.
Swear to renounce your master.
Yes, sir.
From now on, you'll tell the truth.
Sit down.
I'm the witch. I'm the only witch.
I bewitched them all by myself.
They don't even know
what has happened to them.
How's that possible?
Don't you believe me?
To believe you,
I need to know what happened.
-With all the details.
-Lower your eyes!
Look at me.
It was the darkest of nights.
I was having a bath
in a copper bathtub.
A horrible old lady
emerged from the flames.
I hadn't seen her before.
Did she apply an ointment?
Yes.
Then…
I felt something in my body.
A force.
It was the call of the Sabbath.
As my sister
didn't want to come with me,
I turned her into…
It's cold.
a lamb.
A devil's lamb?
Your sister, a lamb. That's strange.
Certainly,
she wanted to satisfy the evil one
by incarnating
the very symbol of innocence.
Go on.
I turned Maider into a donkey.
Katalin!
Dressed in a priest’s cassock.
-Blasphemy!
-Father.
I had to turn Oneka into a goat
dressed as Lord of Urtubi.
Girls, please.
I want to go to the feast, too!
And I turned Katalin into a pig.
Were you the only one in human form?
-Were you naked?
-No.
I was wearing a dress,
a beautiful yellow dress.
Because only I am
the chosen one of Lucifer.
And where is that dress?
After the Sabbath, I gave it to Izaro.
Bring it to me.
None of them wanted to come.
Olaia.
-Hello.
I went after them,
one by one, and bewitched them.
What's up, Olaia?
I bewitched them by playing a flute.
Tell me to stop.
It's your turn.
In the forest, near the cliff,
I made a great feast.
I conjured up hams as big as tree trunks,
dozens of cheeses,
jars and jars of cider,
and wine, lots of wine.
Do you want mushrooms?
-They're all for you.
-No.
One, two and three!
Do you like it?
And we swallowed up black hosts
made with the blank mushroom
that grows under oaks.
Did you celebrate a Black Mass?
They didn't. I did it.
But you just told me
that they were there too.
Because I made them believe
that it was a real mass
and that they received
real hosts from the priest,
but it was all just an illusion.
How did you create that illusion?
With smoke.
And in that smoke…
demons came forth.
I just need to close my eyes
to see my sweetheart.
I always look at him with my eyes closed
because he's very ugly.
But I don't mind his face
because he has a big…
What else? Green and with spines?
We swallowed them, spat them up
and swallowed them again.
Did you swallow the demons
through your mouths?
Through our asses.
I conjured up a drum,
a huge drum, a violin,
the skull of a male goat
and rattles for all of us.
From Newfoundland to this port
From the forest to the cliffs
We don't want any other warmth
Than the warmth of your kisses
Than the warmth…
Do you want me to sing the summons?
We don't want any other warmth
Write that melody down.
Your Honor.
What?
It's a chromatic scale.
Chromatic scale?
It can go on endlessly.
And Lucifer?
Describe his physical appearance.
He dresses in black.
Beard, light eyes.
Beautiful.
Does he have a tail?
Yes.
At the front or back?
At the front.
What was it like?
Describe it.
Green and full of thorns.
It gives pleasure from the front
and pain from behind.
Did he try to introduce it into you?
Lucifer pulled my girdle off and…
And?
And…
I cannot describe it.
Say it in your own language.
I mean it. I can't. It's…
It's too much. I can't.
I'm… I'm exhausted.
I can't think.
Can we continue tomorrow?
Do you know the Transverberation
and Ecstasy of Saint Teresa?
Of course, Your Honor.
It's said that
she saw an angel in bodily form.
And it had a long spear of gold
and, at the point, a little fire.
"And it penetrated me through my heart
deep inside my body."
"And, when he took it out,
he took part of myself with him."
"It was so soft
that I felt scorched by the love of God,
in a great love of God."
"And the pain was so extreme…
it was such an extreme pain
that I moaned."
"It wasn't a physical pain."
"It was spiritual, although
the body also played a little."
-Of course.
-Yes.
Yes. It was just like that,
but it was… it was…
It was intense. It was much more intense.
It was like…
It was like this…
-What are you doing?
-I'm sorry, Your Honor.
This whore was trying to
bewitch you with her eyes.
Take that off. Go away!
Go on.
And…
we flew.
We flew… like seagulls.
Are you all right, Your Honor?
Yes, of course.
Shall I make her sign her confession?
The night has fallen.
Proceed.
I haven't finished.
You must sign, girl.
Sign it, Ana.
-Won't they release the others?
-You've done the right thing.
Now, sign it.
Is that it? Is it over?
Are you going to kill me?
Sign it.
What happened, Ana?
Nothing.
It's all right.
He believes anything I say.
Do you think that witches always lie?
They lie like they breathe.
Don't you know that?
That young woman
has confessed to being a witch.
If, as you say, witches always lie,
then she isn't a witch.
Salazar, don't you get tired
of inventing syllogisms?
What I mean…
is that we have listened
to unique and wonderful confessions,
but they're just words, a witch's words.
If we don't witness
the Sabbath ourselves,
we'll never know
if it's a reality or a dream.
Tell me what's going on.
Are they getting ready to burn me?
Nobody tells me anything.
What are they going to do?
Nobody will hurt you.
How do you know?
Because you have power.
What does he want to draw?
What you have, but I have lost.
What have you lost?
Not even your virginity!
What have I lost?
I used to be like you.
Young,
defiant,
and wild.
But I paid a high price.
Then, I learned.
This cap covers our hair perfectly well
as they ordered.
But…
they all know it looks like a big cock.
But nobody dares to say so.
Men are afraid
of fearless women.
Why don't you help me
instead of telling me stories?
That's what I'm doing, girl.
But what's the use of talking
if you don't have ears.
Go back to your duties, mistress.
Are you going to show
these drawings to His Majesty?
I'll have someone make an engraving
of the stages of the Sabbath.
People need to see to believe.
This first engraving represents
the witch applying the ointment
to the initiated young girl.
It perfectly shows Lucifer's main weapon.
What do you think that is?
-Lies.
-No.
Beauty.
If the devil
wanted to sow evil ways in you,
how would he do so?
Would he ask this lady?
No.
Lucifer has other means.
Lucifer doesn't choose
his servants randomly.
He knows perfectly well
that only charming and delicate women
who have just left childhood behind
can enchant us
until we become voracious animals,
dogs devoted to pleasure.
Dress her.
I want to see when she bewitches.
I want to see
when you bewitch your friends.
Why celebrate a false Sabbath
if we can celebrate the real one?
Would you celebrate the Sabbath for us?
Of course, My Lord.
Your Honor…
But I can only do it
when I feel Lucifer's call,
on nights when the moon is full.
Your Honor…
Magic!
Look what I've got.
Listen carefully.
That fool wants to see how I bewitch you.
He'll come on the night of the full moon,
and we'll drive him crazy.
What are we going to do?
Lucifer!
Very well.
Drum, violin, wine,
ham.
-Have you told him?
-No.
When are you going to?
I can't tell him that.
You cannot hide it.
Is this skull okay?
It's a cow's skill.
I'm sorry, Your Honor.
We couldn't find
the skull of a male goat anywhere.
Not good enough. Keep looking.
The donkey is outside.
We're looking for the cassock
to dress it.
Black mushrooms…
Your Honor,
two of the guards
have run away from the village.
Last night?
I saw them. Why did they run away?
The mothers and grandmothers
of the prisoners
have spread the rumor
of a forthcoming bloody revenge.
-Revenge by whom?
-The sailors.
Three years ago, in a less complicated
conflict than this one,
several of Lord of Urtubi's guards
were stabbed.
Are you saying they fear
some miserable fishermen?
It is my duty to warn you.
If you keep postponing the verdict,
you'll be exposed to real danger.
Sailors usually come back
soon after the next full moon.
The next full moon.
Yes, because of the tide.
That witch is buying time.
Announce the execution.
Yes, Your Honor.
On this glorious day,
Thursday 6th November,
in the Year of Grace 1609,
an exemplary trial is drawn to a close.
It will leave a mark
in the history of the Devil's works
Thanks to the unprecedented testimonies
of Ana Ibarguren, repentant witch,
we were able to reconstruct
for the first time
the complete and detailed chronology
of the most atrocious of crimes,
an offense of divine lese-majesty,
the Witches' Sabbath.
The execution ceremony
will take place tomorrow at dawn.
The accused, Ana Ibarguren,
María Ibarguren,
Oneka Albisu, Olaia Isasi,
Maider Aguirre and Katalina de Ugalde,
who were found guilty
of participating in the Sabbath,
shall be burnt at the stake.
Their ashes
shall be thrown to the wind,
and their property
shall be confiscated by the Crown.
Ana, I saw him.
-Who?
-Lucifer.
-When?
-Last night.
-Where?
-Here.
He came to illuminate your dreams.
He looked just like you described him.
Beard and light eyes?
Yes.
I have him bewitched!
He won't let them kill us.
He'll wait until full moon.
He'll come for us.
I swear!
He's stronger than us.
He's made fun of you.
No. I'm serious.
He cannot live
without witnessing the Sabbath.
He needs to see me dancing for him.
I've seen it in his eyes, María.
Ana is right.
Lucifer will come for us.
Up against the wall!
What are you doing?
Call the Judge right now!
They're like beasts.
Your Honor.
Don't you think this is ridiculous?
Perhaps.
He wants us to show him the Sabbath.
Lucifer!
Oh! I've been turned into a pig.
And? What do you say now?
If the Sabbath is a dream.
Then we are all dreaming the same.
We don't want any other warmth
Than the warmth of your kisses
From Newfoundland to this port
From the forest to the cliffs
We don't want any other warmth
Than the warmth of your kisses
From Newfoundland to this port
From the forest to the cliffs
We don't want any other warmth
Than the warmth of your kisses
From Newfoundland to this port
We don't want any other warmth
Than the warmth of your kisses
Lucifer!
We don't want any other warmth
We don't want…
Than the warmth…
We don't want any other warmth
Lucifer!
Your Honor.
Take the prisoners away!
You have no authority to impose orders.
-In the name of God.
-In the name of Your Majesty.
I demand obedience.
Let go of me. Let go.
Go away. What are you doing?
Let go of me.
Look at them in their eyes!
In the last full moon of Autumn
High tide and the flight of seagulls
Let's jump.
We'll fly. Right, Ana?
Yes.
They fly.
Subtitle translation by: