COWARDS BEND THE KNEE
or THE BLUE HANDS
Chapter One
SPERM PLAYERS
GUY MADDIN
Rover with the Winnipeg Maroons
MO MOTT
His best friend
SHAKY
Maroons Captain...
...and Police Captain
Guy's first headknock
of the night
Shaky's vengeance
MADDIN SR.
Voice of the Maroons
Guy's second headknock...
...his girfriend, VERONICA.
In trouble...
DR. FUSI
Team physician...
Patches up Guy's
beleaguered head.
THE ALLAN CUP!
"Be sure to visit the hospital."
"Your mother asks for you."
"Your mother."
"I promise."
Waiting...
Delirious from
his two knocknocks...
...Guy tries to remember
his mother, his dying mother...
...while forces beyond his control
conspire to shunt him off...
...onto a depressing detour.
End of
CHAPTER ONE
Chapter Two
A SQUEEZE OF THE HAND
Fusi, Shaky & Guy
take Veronica to the...
NIGHT CLINIC
The Glum Couple
TWO LONG,
TWO SHORT.
THE BLACK
SILHOUETTE SALON
Beauty salon by day...
Bordello by night.
A piece of warm pie...
The calling card of...
LILIOM
Proprietress...
...and Shaky's sweetheart.
Fusi goes to work.
META
Liliom's daughter
The joy, joy, joy
of meeting someone new!
"No sugar before pie!"
Meta never eats
her mother's pie.
To stay or go?
And so Guy forgets another
mother... the mother of his child.
What sharp amnesias!
Addled Guy unknowingly performs
operations of his very own -
upon human hearts!
And without anesthetics!
But, let's not worry too much
about Veronica. She's in the
hands of experts.
End of
CHAPTER TWO
Chapter Three
UPON A PILE OF HOCKEY GLOVES
MAROONS DRESSING ROOM
"I love you, Guy."
"I love you, Meta."
"NO HAND SHALL TOUCH ME..."
"Until my father is AVENGED!"
"MY FATHER'S HANDS!"
"They're blue!"
"We made prints in cement..."
"We play-fainted!"
DADDY!
THE FINEST MAN!
CHAS!
The sweetest hairdresser!
Murdered!
"By my whore of a mother..."
"And her foul paramour..."
"SHAKY!"
"MY FATHER'S HAND!"
Tightly bound by wire!
Severed!
By Shaky!!
"These are my father's hands!"
"I keep them always!"
"They're blue!"
"From his lovely
hair dyes."
BENEATH THE SINKS...
THOSE ROARING CATARACTS!
DADDY!
Meanwhile...
VERONICA!
CHECKED OUT
OF THE NIGHT CLINIC.
TO SEEK HER GUY
So Guy's heart falls into the
grasp of Meta, the new girl!
He loves her strong sense
of family, her fierce coyness,
her deep nostalgias.
This quivering, leaping heart
of his knows exactly what to do.
But how to do it with a head
worried by such new complications?
End of
CHAPTER THREE
Chapter Four
META'S BEDROOM
BLIND GRANDMA
An Icelandic hand-charm
"Happy birthday to you..."
"Happy birthday to Liliom..."
DAUGHTER'S DEAF EARS
META TAKES GUY
TO STEAL FLOWERS
AT THE GRAVEYARD
Veronica's Ghost?!!
BACK SAFE IN BED
UNWELCOME NOISES...
FROM MOTHER'S BEDROOM
ENTER DR. FUSI
"Sew my father's
hands onto him!"
"IMPOSSIBLE!"
"Do it!"
"Yes, Meta."
A QUEER PRANK
A FAKED TRANSPLANT
BLUE PAINT
AFTER THE 'SURGERY'
"They live!"
"Gramma! Daddy lives!"
End of
CHAPTER FOUR
Chapter Five
FISTY
LILIOM HIRES
THE GHOST OF VERONICA
THE NEW GIRL
"TONIGHT!"
"DADDY GETS VENGEANCE!"
YOU...
SHALL...
SHAMPOO...
MOTHER!
You'll...
KILL...
MOTHER!
GO!!!
LILIOM CLEARS THE SALON...
FOR A PRIVATE INTERVIEW
GRAMMA'S MUSIC
THOSE FATAL SINKS!
BUT HANDS HAVE MEMORIES!
OF A HONEYMOON?
Guy wins a job at the salon.
CAUGHT IN A HAIR NET
LILIOM'S CLAW
"No more mirrors!"
Jealous Liliom and Meta
demote Guy from coiffuring
grown women.
End of
CHAPTER FIVE
Chapter Six
WAX TRYST
On his way to visit his sick mother,
Guy sneaks into the Arena...
...for old times' sake.
Up in the rafters...
A FORGOTTEN WAX MUSEUM
THE HALL OF
THE ALL-TIME MAROONS
His precious hockey cards...
His tarot.
The new girl!
The joy, joy, joy
of meeting someone new!
Sweet oppression of fresh love!
Un-trysting themselves,
Guy and ghost return...
"I've been visiting Mother.
She's doing well."
"That's interesting.
She died last night!"
"You poor, poor man."
FEEDING TIME
AT THE WAX MUSEUM
DESPERATE TO PLAY
HOCKEY AGAIN!
Guy promises to strangle Shaky,
if only he can rejoin the Maroons.
The Soviets arrive to
challenge for the Allan Cup.
The fear, fear, fear
of playing someone new!
"Shaky dies!
...Tonight!"
"You said that dead girl
wasn't your girlfriend!"
"She wasn't!"
"Then quit staring
at that spot!"
SHAKY GRABS
SOME GOOD LUCK
THE SOVIETS
TAKE A 9 - 0 LEAD
"You ought to be ashamed!
You're a coward!"
End of
CHAPTER SIX
Chapter Seven
THE BLUE HANDS OF VENGEANCE
Maddin shoots!
Scores!!
Celebrations!
A perfect time for revenge!
A MURDER UNNOTICED!
Checking for pulse...
NONE!
"You always did have
soft hands around the net!"
TWO LONG,
TWO SHORT.
ICE BREATS
WRACKED WITH GUILT
GUY FOLLOWS BEST FRIEND MO
TO THE POLICE STATION,
TO CONFESS!
I killed Shaky
"Mo! Sorry!"
"Sorry!"
End of
CHAPTER SEVEN
Chapter Eight
ANOTHER WAX TRYST
With Meta sent out on an errand,
Liliom orders Guy to wax her legs.
LATER...
Guy tries to stop the ghost
from having an abortion.
WITH MOTHER?!!
FINALLY!!
"Are you happy NOW?!!"
Liliom dispatched!
Guy's promise kept! ...
...He now believes his
obligations to the vengeful
daughter are complete.
"PLEASE CUT THESE
WRETCHED MURDERERS OFF ME!"
"You silly boy!
These are your own hands!"
"The transplant was a hoax!"
"You silly, silly fool!"
Capricious Meta awakens
from her swoon to a world
hung in black.
META CHEWS SLOWLY...
THE LAST PIECE OF PIE...
BAKED BY HER MOTHER...
BEFORE SHE DIED.
End of
CHAPTER EIGHT
Chapter Nine
HANDS OFF!
"We're through, Guy!"
"Just confess.
You love the new girl."
"Well, I guess... I do."
"Then I want my
father's hands back!"
MINUTES AFTER THE OPERATION
NEWLY FREED GUY GOES
DIRECTLY TO THE ARENA
THE CARDS FORETELL
A MYSTERIOUS APOCALYPSE
MEANWHILE...
BACK WITH HIS BUDDIES
"I see you still need
your hand held."
"You're as cold as I am!"
"I LIKE IT, SOMEHOW!"
"Tonight you shall know
how it feels to have
a slain father!"
MAROONS SWEAR
VENGEANCE ON SOVIETS!
Up on the catwalk,
a game of a different sort.
Veronica's ghost traces
and retraces her steps
high above the rink...
...stepping cruelly
across the surface of
Guy's fevered brain...
...and onto his panting,
aching breast.
End of
CHAPTER NINE
Chapter Ten
THE FURIES
THE SUMMONS
OF THE ICE BREAST
TO THE CATWALK!
LOOKING FOR A KILLER.
GUY'S BELOVED!
"SON, MEET YOUR
NEW MOTHER."
"Please, my love.
Remember your heart."
"I've loved your father
my entire life!"
"Wax Maroons!"
"Immortals!"
"Awake!"
"Put an end
to this travesty!"
"Julian Klymberger!
Awake! I need you!"
Hind Bauer!
Awake!
I need you!
"The rest of you!"
"Great men!"
"WAXMEN!"
"Hear my pleas!"
Awake!
"Father?"
"Daddy!"
THE WEIGHT
OF A DAUGHTER...
TOO MUCH FOR
A FATHER WITH NO HANDS.
"Wait..."
"NO!"
NEXT SEASON
THE NEW FIXTURE
"Like the French Foreign Legion,
the Museum is a sanctuary...
...in this case, for cowards, for
husbands afraid to face the burdens...
...nay, the terrors... of living
with wives and families.."
(Maddin Sr.)
End of
CHAPTER TEN
english subtitles transcribed by
.:: Norgen (norgen@centrum.cz) ::.