Passed year 2000. No problems.
There's disintegration.
The epicenter is in Japan, around 1570 AD.
The Age of Civil Wars?
This sure smells like a crime!
Time Patrol Headquarters.
This is Patrol-tei T2327X.
Rings-to-Storm.
Please reply.
That's funny.
This isn't an area
with communications problems.
Anyway, I'll go to the site.
Autopilot.
Set: Japan. 1570 AD.
Roger.
Estimated time of arrival?
Scheduled to be one hour.
Warning! Object at speed of light heading
toward target planet in opposite direction.
Probability of contact within 25 seconds: 98%.
What?!
Computer! Analysis!
Dimensional analysis.
Make: Back Corporation Time Hater CPX
Accuracy of Estimate: 98%.
Trouble!
Computer! Cancel auto-pilot!
Bring the controls here!
Roger!
Warning! Multiple objects at light speed...
So, I've finally sighted you!
Acceleration status check!
Current battle status reading!
Energy loss! Energy loss!
Won't last at this rate!
I'm exiting into normal space.
Engine gear!
It's do it or die!
I wonder what age this is.
Here.
Subtitles by Wasabi Anime
OCR by Inactive (Fansubs.ru)
Crayon Shin-chan
Intrigue of Unkokusai
One, two, three, huh!
Powerful! Powerful! Powerful happenings!
Right, Misae?
It's another power-packed stupid day!
If you're going to pick up on girls
Just leave it to me
For 3 and 4, the stars are important
Come on baby! Come on baby!
Do you eat green onions?
I get embarrassed when you look at me with those eyes
Ele~phant! Ele~phant!
I'm a popular guy!
Panic! Panic! Panic! Everyone's in a flurry
I'm super!
I'm a genius!
I'm looking forward to my future!
Nowadays, TV games are so well done!
It's that again!
I'm pretty strong, aren't I?
Prepare yourself, Action Kamen!
A. B. B. A. A. B. B.
Right. Right. Left.
No way! What was that?!
It's a special weapon!
That's playing dirty!
It's the difference in ability.
I guess you can't beat kids.
Get up already, you guys.
No! No! It's all no good!
I'm lucky I'm syill alive...
but there isn't one system that works correctly.
Oh, and you know that while I'm doing
this, the past is in danger!
Computer!
This isn't going to work.
Did it!
I can use the Micro Machine and emergency kit!
I'll get by with this somehow!
Eject Micro Machine!
Sorry! I don't have any time today,
so bear with leftovers, okay?
Today?
Yesterday was like that, too!
The reason you don't have any time
is because you overslept, isn't it?
I love you, Misae.
Really? What part of me were you attracted to?
That you're a bit forceful and playful?
I love the way you're so honest!
I blame my own insecurities.
Take that! Choco Missile!
Kantamu Megaton Punch!
We did it, Kantamu Jr.!
It's all because of you, John-san.
John and Kantamu Jr. defeated
the mysterious robot, Karaku...
but at this time, who could possibly...
Oh?
You don't have to watch anime
first thing in the morning.
Hurry up and eat your breakfast,
or you'll be late to kindergarten.
And Shiro is waiting for you
to take his breakfast to him!
First thing in the morning it's the
Old Lady Yak-Yak Monster.
Now, hurry up and eat breakfast.
Okay...
Save me, ButtFace Man!
What are you doing to Shinnosuke-kun?
It's ButtFace Man!
What IS that?
Shinnosuke-kun is a good boy!
You shouldn't be mean to him!
Okay! I get it.
Quit it, Shinnosuke!
My name is ButtFace Man!
I'm really going to get mad now.
I'm mad now!
Bishoujo Kamen Misalin, appears!
masked beautiful young girl
As an adult, aren't you embarrassed
to be doing such things?
Don't worry about it!
Oh, I want to go to a world far away from here.
If not that, at least let me have breakfast soon.
Wait a minute!
Don't you know what'll happen if you don't stop?
Shinnosuke! Quit it!
Lucky!
It's a mammal!
I only have one chance.
Contact!
A... A...
A E I U E O A O
KA KE KI KU KE KO
UNKO
Hello?
Can you hear me?
What year is this?
I'm "Rings to Storm" of the Time Patrol.
I'm borrowing your body for just a while.
Please try and answer.
Hmm... that's funny...
Did I mess up "contact"?
Oh no! This is a dog, isn't it?!
Shin-chan, after you eat breakfast,
bring some to Shiro too, okay?
Oka~y!
Shiro! Shiro! Shiro!
Thanks for waiting!
Shiro, good morning!
Here's breakfast. Eat hearty!
Before that, I have something I want to tell you.
What?
Um... A dog talks and you're not surprised?
Wa~h! Shi-- Shiro spoke!
You don't have to be that surprised.
So my name is Shiro, right?
Huh? Shiro's talking.
It seems our conversation is just puzzling.
Puzzling. Not Nuzzling.
You, is your mother or father at home?
I have something important to say.
Huh?
Shiro! Did you forget my name?
What happened to our friendship!?
I can't breathe!
Your name is?
My name is Shinnosuke Nohara.
A 5 year old who's a bit on the shy side.
That's was it, Shinnosuke-kun.
What's wrong?
You're acting like a stranger!
It's between you and me!
You can call me Shin-chan!
Shin-chan?
Wha~t?
There. Forget anything?
Nope. Nothing. Thank you.
Mom! Dad!
Shiro said he wants to talk!
Sorry, but Dad has work.
And you go get ready for kindergarten, too.
I have something to tell you.
Shiro!
Spoke!
Thank goodness.
It seems that I've come across someone
who can carry a normal conversation,
unlike Shin-chan.
I'm not all that...
I'm not praising you though...
Huh?
So let's clear this up.
You are an employee of the Time
Patrol from the 30th century.
Your machine broke down, is buried
in the ground under Shiro's doghouse,
and you can't move it.
So you borrowed Shiro's body,
and are talking to us.
And, the reason for all of this is...
In Japan's Age of Civil Wars, something
is scheming to destroy something.
Is that right?
That's it!
Wow! You're amazing, Dad!
I'm not all that...
At this point, I have a request.
I would like you to go to the
Age of Civil Wars with me.
Us?
To the Age of Civil Wars?
To pick up some older chicks and
go to a disco together and...
That's not what we're saying!
Not what we're saying!
But I have to go to work before
we go to the past, and...
Wouldn't it be better if you went to
the police for something like that?
The Time Patrol hasn't been formed
in the 20th century yet.
And if it's about time...
It's 7:50 am now.
If we leave soon, investigate the
Age of Civil Wars together...
Get back at this age's 7:55 am...
In actuality it's only been 5 minutes...
You won't even be late to work.
I'm just not that hot about science fiction.
I love it!
Action Kamen and Kantamu Robot!
That's not science fiction.
That's just a special hero film
and a big robot anime.
You're really a fanatic, huh dad?
Anyway, what will we get from helping you?
If you just let this alone,
the whole world will be in chaos.
Your existence will no longer be guaranteed!
Please! Now that I've become Shiro,
you are the only ones I can believe in.
I'm going to help Shiro!
- Shinnosuke!
- Shinnosuke.
Cuz me and Shiro are best friends!
World peace doesn't mean
anything to our family.
But since Shinnosuke says so,
guess we have no choice!
Let's go!
Here!
Then, I'll call the Emergency Time Machine.
Huh? What's going on, Shinnosuke?
Shinnosuke Nohara! Start to ready!
You mean you're ready to start.
Leave the Action Kamen Badge
and the Kantamu Robot.
No way! No! No! NO!
I wonder if we're going to be alright?
Then, I'll call the Emergency Time Machine.
Come out! Come out!
Time Machine!
...isn't necessary to say...
But it makes everything feel more
exciting, don't you think?
Please put on the time suits that
are provided with those seats.
The passionate red for me!
This is really like a serious
science fiction movie!
Yes!
[ Time Patrol ]
But not really.
THIS is a Time Patrol uniform?
It looks bad.
You look like Pyonkichi, Shinnosuke.
It is formatted when you wear it.
Later when we time travel, it has the ability
to turn into the right costume for the age.
And Shin-chan's suit has a
built-in "3x Save" feature.
Yell, "Save me kit," when you're
in trouble to activate it.
No! Don't say it!
Save me when you're in trouble to activate it!
Nothing happened, Shiro.
It's because you didn't say the keyword right.
King War!
What's that?
We don't have time.
Let's leave right now!
You're such a cold dog.
Are you prepared?
Yeah.
It's squishy, Shiro!
It's an emergency one, so bear it.
We're taking off!
I'll take a quick look.
I wonder what's happened to Shin-chan?
There's no doubt. He overslept again.
How troublesome.
We're always late because of this stop.
Good morning!
Nohara-san!
I'm bored already.
Hold on just a little bit longer.
It's hot!
I want some ice!
There's nothing I can do.
I'm even beaten by this heat!
And when I think that we have
to ride this on the way home...
It isn't going to be this machine
on the way home.
This is for emergencies.
It can only go one way.
Then how are we going to get back?
We'll find out why the past is changing.
And return it to the way it should be.
And if we can't stop it?
We can't go back.
We haven't heard about that part!
What is this place?
It seems like the remains of a fire...
More importantly, please change your clothes
quickly before anyone sees you!
Oh, yeah.
What am I supposed to do with this?
Put the collar up.
Collar?
Putting up the collar of a jersey?
Looks bad...
What? This isn't a samurai.
This isn't a princess!
It's a system that automatically determines
the most suitable clothes for a person.
Dad, Mom, it's a stenching!
You mean it's stunning.
Guess this is it.
Guess so.
It's burnt down, now, but it seems
that they had very big buildings.
Who~a! Nice view!
Be careful, Shin-chan.
What's this place called? What age?
The latter part of the 16th Century.
What you would call the Age
of the Civil Wars, right?
There are no differences in the coordinates...
So this should be Kasukabe castle
in Musashi's Country, but...
That there was such a castle in Kasukabe...
But it's all burnt down...
Well, it is the Age of Civil Wars.
The aftermath of the dreams of warriors, eh?
What's that?
What's that sound?
Hey, what are these guys?
Dunno.
"Dunno"?!
You can't be saying that after bringing us here!
But I brought you here because I wanted
to know what was going on here!
That's so irresponsible!
Anyway, please calm down!
It's a game, eh?
I'm good at that, too!
There's no way it's a game!
Umm...
We aren't suspicious people.
Right! Right!
Just a normal salary-man
and a normal housewife!
...and a good 5 year old kid and a kinda
strange dog that can speak.
Don't say unnecessary things!
We actually weren't talking to you...
We'll apologize, if we bothered you.
Let's not bring out those dangerous things...
Where did you buy those?
- How much?
- Quit it!
What? What?
My bag!
Forget your stupid bag!
I've been waiting.
Waiting?
I'm Fubukimaru.
I am the heir of Hidetsuna.
Katsuga Hougu no Kami, the lord of the
now destroyed Kasukabe Castle.
You are the ones in the legends handed down
through the generations of the Katsuga family.
The "Three Heroes and One Dog", right?
Who are you?
Why are you acting so big?
And I can't understand what you're saying at all.
What?
We are that "Three Heroes and One Dog."
We came from another world to meet you.
This dogs speaks?
Whoa! It's not just a dog, is it?
He's called Shiro!
This one's name is Enji.
He's got a rough temperament,
but he's this country's best horse.
I'm the Yochi-Enji
(kindergartener)
Shinnosuke Nohara.
Nice to meet you.
Hey.
Forgive him.
Since Enji is so high strung,
sometimes he jokes like...
You're haughty for a horse.
I'll teach you that I'm more important.
Stop it!
Enji won't let anyone but me ride!
Quit it! Calm down!
Please! Hey! Enji!
Hey, why did you say that?
Yeah, yeah!
That we're the "Three Heroes and One Dog."
More importantly, Shin-chan!
It's okay!
If you're surprised at things like
that, you won't last long.
But..!
See?
Why do you turn red?
Who knows?
Though a small country, my father ruled it well.
The people were without strife...
Until that hateful Unkokusai
(SmellsLikePooPoo) arrived.
- Smells like poo poo?
Smells like poo~ poo~!
Trapped by Katz, who uses strange magic...
My lord Father and my lady Mother died,
and my younger sister was taken away.
I cried.
Cried and cried...
Cried until I could cry no more.
Then, I pledged to cry no more.
Until I could avenge my parents
and defeat Unkokusai.
And save my sister!
It's already been one year since
the council has been restored.
The time has come!
With you, I shall attack Unkokusai!
Unkokusai.
Strange magic.
Strange.
Unkokusai.
It's a name you really don't
want to say out loud, huh?
Yes.
What?
What'll I do?
In the bag they just took! It had our
savings bank book and our hanko!
Hanko = Seal used instead of
signatures in Japan. Legally binding.
What?
Those guys just now...
were they Unkokusai's?
Yes. They're his henchmen.
That's so.
Why did you bring such things?
I thought it was dangerous to leave them
because we were leaving the house empty...
What are you going to do?
That's everything we own!
We can just get them back, then!
It's difficult to understand what
these people are talking about.
What are you doing?
I thought you were maybe a girl.
But I found ball-balls.
They were bigger than Daddy's.
Eh?
Ah... I lost.
It's only natural I have them. I'm a man.
There, there.
I couldn't sense him coming closer at all.
We can do it.
Stinky! Stinky!
Horse's butt! Horse's butt!
My lord Father, my lady Mother,
I shall go now.
Shin-chan, let's try really hard, okay?
Try what?
"What"?
We're going to Ukokusai place.
What?
I don't like smelly poo poo.
Must be nice to be the one who
commands from a safe place.
But... for me...
If something should happen to you,
I'll be stuck in the ground and die!
"If something"?
Like it'd be fair if that happened!
Hey, why don't we just tell that
Unkokusai person the circumstances...
and have him return at least
our bank book and hanko?
Even if he returned just that, it's no use
unless we can return to our time!
What's wrong? Let's get moving.
We have no choice but to go.
Shit!
I'll show him the spirit of a salaried man!
Shinnosuke, what's with that sound?
It sounds like all the strength is going away.
Come on, we're ready to go.
Oh! Ready to ho!
Unkokusai-sama, please give
this gold object to Ginmei.
Do as you wish.
Then I shall dispose of those people...
No, I'll do it.
It's MY prey! Don't get in my way!
The god of Wine and Females is Love.
I'll be wanting to whiff the smell of blood soon.
MatatabiNekoNoShi, go.
(CatnipKillerOfCats)
Unkokusai-sama.
Why did you not command me?
Ogin. Don't you understand Unkokusai-sama's
wish that you stay by his side?
You say such things as do not
need to be said, Tamashiro. (WhiteBalls)
Hmm...
It's so peaceful.
It reminds me of the country.
That's so true.
Kasukabe used to be such
a laidback place like this.
It's quite a city now, huh?
There's a lot of people and cars, the
land is expensive, we have 32 years
left on our home loan, and...
Misae, I'm thinking that we should
stay and live in this age.
What?
I'm tired of a life of working
just to pay back a loan.
Don't say such stupid things!
Besides how would we live?
In this Age of Civil Wars, advancement
is determined by your wit alone.
Section Chief... Department Head...
It's all so pretty! So pretty!
To be king of a country, it's not a dream here!
Huh?
Then if it happens that way, I'm a princess?
If Unkokusai is a person from the future,
then he'd definitely think that way.
It's a joke.
You know, don't come out the way out
here just to talk about loans, okay?
I know that!
I also know that you don't have such courage.
What?
Rude brat!
You've touched my sword with your filthy hands!
Though you may be a child, I can't forgive this!
Sit there and bring disgrace to your family!
Attention!
Deflate (disgrace).
Is this okay?
You!
Please forgive us Samurai-sama!
Our son did something, but as you
can see, we're just farmers.
Please forgive us! Let us go!
Okay, since you put it that way,
then I'll forgive you.
You're supposed to apologize!
What?
Unforgiven!
I'll slice the whole family then!
It's the doings of a child.
Forgive him.
I ask of you also.
NO!
Then what would you have me do?
I should execute them.
But there's no advantage in executing
these vulgar people.
I would withdraw from this situation
for one silver piece. How about it?
You. Your beard is quite overgrown.
What?
How about one silver piece to
pay for the beard trimming?
I was just thinking that I needed a trim, too...
Thank you so much!
And so we've no debts now!
He blackmails, and he calls himself a warrior?
I dislike people with no strength,
and plenty of bluff!
If you're a man, come with your fists!
Come with your sword!
So cool!
It's just like historical TV!
But you are heroes, aren't you?
Why did you indulge in such base behavior?
Uh...
No, aaah... that was...
Uh, right.
To defeat your foe, is not the
only solution to a problem.
Meaningless fighting should be avoided.
He's saying something that sounds true.
After all, Dad's good at excuses.
You're a bit noisy!
Victory without violence.
Trickery, that's strategy!
I shall remember it.
Yes, it's a strategy. Strategy!
What's a strategy?
I don't know.
Oh!
Yummy!
What's "Oh, yummy"?
You don't even know that?
Um, it's basically...
Isn't it "delicious"?
That's it.
Oh. If it's delicious, then
you say, "Oh, yummy!"?
Oh! Yummy!
Like that?
Well, yeah. That's the way.
Is eating stuff like grass good?
These dango are good.
(Japanese confection)
Want to eat some?
Hey!
If you do stuff like that, you'll get bitten!
Hey baby! Scold me more!
You ate my dango!
Then I'll eat yours, too!
Awful!
Fubuki-maru-san, how much farther
is it to Unkokusai's castle?
It's 15 more li's toward Inui.
15 li?
How far is 1 li?
1 Li is about 3.9 km, so we still
have about 58.5 km to go. (36 miles)
It's half a day if you let your horse run...
But since you are on foot, we should
be there by tomorrow evening.
Why did you not come with horses?
Oi!
Won't you hurry and come?
Dad! Mom!
Well, you're riding a horse!
Well, he was a prince before y'know.
He doesn't understand the
feeling of the unfortunate.
Call a palanquin! Palanquin!
They are those with weak feet.
Can they truly fight?
In contrust, you are quite
admirable, Shinnosuke.
Oh! I'm quite admirable!
I thought it'd end up like this.
Shinnosuke, you...
Shh...
I'm tired.
We shall rest here tonight.
Be sure you leave no tiredness for tomorrow.
You should lay down, too.
You need not worry for me.
I haven't laid down to sleep once this past year.
What?
Why?
I don't know when I could be attacked.
That's such a burden for one so young...
I'm not young.
I'm already 15.
It's an age where it wouldn't be strange
for me to welcome a bride anytime soon.
Even my mother had me when she was 16.
Wow!
What?
These are small breasts.
It's amazing you were able
to raise a child with these.
NO!
What is it?
My chest!
This kid touched by breasts!
No, he didn't touch it, he grabbed it!
Did Mom have enough breasts to grab?
Nope! Nope!
I'm the one who knows the best!
Go ahead and say it again!
Hmm... We can do it.
Hey, lay down.
No. I'm fine this way.
It bugs me when you're like that.
It's fun when all the guys sleep together!
Right, Dad?
Uh...
Well, then...
Uh, not that way...
I'm sorry about that earlier.
Forgive me.
It's okay since... you apologized.
Dad, dad! He's doing "that".
Leave it be! He's still a kid.
I'm an adult already.
Dad, daddy! He's saying "that".
Misae, I love you.
What about me did you fall for?
Huh?
Why does that stump you?
Sorry.
Geez!
Fubukimaru.
My lady Mother! Here!
Please look a this!
One whose life is so fleeting, you
must not capture it as a game.
You do not know whose reincarnation it may be.
Oh, my feet are so heavy.
Mine too.
Misae. Is it hard for you?
No. I'm okay.
Don't worry.
Don't call someone else's wife
by her first name so easily!
Hmm? Are you jealous?
What?
Who'd get jealous?
Don't be so embarrassed.
You're wrong! Don't get so happy!
Good. Good.
O!
Whoa!
What an amazing oil flower garden!
In summer, they'll be able to get some good oil.
What?
You can get oil from Na flowers?
They wring the seeds.
Haven't you heard of "Na seed oil"?
Oh! A butterfly!
Come on!
What's with "Oh! A butterfly!"
at HER age?
Dad.
Jealous Dad is so cu~~~te!
It's not like that!
It's beautiful.
It's unusual for a boy to like flowers so much!
You don't like boys like that?
No. I think it's a good thing.
Shin-chan, someone's coming.
Hmm... A lady?
That man.
Misae.
Move!
I'll ask to be sure.
You're not mistaking me for someone else?
Fubukimaru, you're lucky to be
able to die among flowers.
He's good.
Don't say things like that. Save him!
But that samurai is super strong!
Shin-chan!
Use the "3x Save" feature!
It's finally my turn to shine!
Hurry! Yell, "Save me kit!"
Save me! Eat it!
Wrong!
Savor meat fit?!
Wrong! Wrong!
I killed your mother.
Save me... kit!
Icky! A cockroach!
Shinnosuke?!
I thought I was going to die.
Shinnosuke!
Shin-chan!
I'm so glad that you're okay.
Wai!
She's cute, but it seems that she has bad habits.
That's my bag!
This?
This is mine.
You must be kidding!
Now hurry up and give it back.
Sorry, but could you please return it?
Why are you being so polite about it?
You're so weak when it comes
to good-looking women!
Give it back!
What are those?
I shall give these to you.
I don't need those things!
Give me back my bag!
You're a loud woman!
What about Misae and Hiroshi?
Dad and Mom became balls.
What?
Fubukimaru.
Should you wish to return them to their
normal state, come to PooPoo Castle.
YOU!
We shall rest here and leave for PooPoo
Castle in the middle of the night.
Rest your body well.
Shin-chan!
Cheer up!
Let's put our strengths together
and defeat Unkokusai!
Then...
Shinnosuke.
I understand how you feel about having
your parents changed into balls.
But here is no use in mulling over things
that have already happened.
It's not that Misae and Hiroshi have died.
All will be well as long as we defeat Ukokusai!
Cheer up.
You can't get me with the Noogie-Noogie Attack!
If that makes you mad, come get me! Get me!
This is neat.
You are...
Here.
Put them in there and hang it from your neck.
Be sure that you don't lose it.
My balls have become four!
Won't you stop that, you
"child-that-makes-your-parents-miserable"!
What is it?
There's hot springs at the river.
Go in then.
O! Hot springs!
I'll go in!
Let's go together!
No, I'll go later.
Go by yourself.
I'll wash your back.
I said it's alright. Hurry and go!
Okaaay...
If you go now, there's a young lady in there...
Young lady! Shall I wash your back?
Oh yeah?
Well, thank you kindly.
Shin-chan!
He's a guy but he doesn't have a wee wee!
Maybe he got an operation?
I think it's not that he was a guy,
but that she's a woman.
Who's there?
It's you, Shinnosuke.
You needn't hide.
Come out.
I'm not Shinnosuke!
I'm ButtFace Man!
So you were a lady after all.
I can't win against you.
Why did you pose as a man?
My lord father never had a heir.
So no boys were born?
And so he raised me as a man, and
thought to have me take his place.
I don't know how serious my lord father was...
but soon I shall mature into a woman's body.
It's nothing that could be avoided.
But I felt your ball balls!
What happened to your ball balls?
You mean these.
Just like mine!
Then, in there...
...it's my younger sister, Yukimi.
So it is.
Nice to meet you.
I didn't think that you'd believe me.
So I said that my sister was taken away.
But I didn't think that Misae and Hiroshi, too...
The "Three Heroes and One Dog"
have become just you two.
Excuse me.
Could you tell us that Legend of the Heroes?
Short enough so that a child
won't get bored, okay?
When the Kasuga family is faced
with an imminent emergency...
three heroes and one dog will appear.
Those left with their lives, will
cast their lot with them.
With these balls, and the protective sword...
"Number Seven Chin-Chin-Maru",
we will stand up fight to the evil.
"Number Seven Chin-Chin-Maru"?
(Wee Wee Maru)
I'm glad I've met you.
You've made me look forward to
the battle and have given my soul
courage without being broken.
I'm peaceful.
I think this is all because of you.
I thank you.
I'm not all that...
After this, the only thing left to lose is life.
Night has ended.
Let us go.
Yes!
Who are you?
Just as expected of you.
I'm FreedKin WhiteBalls.
Freed Ball Balls White?
Fubukimaru!
I shall receive your neck.
Shinnosuke, don't move!
Fubukimaru!
Shin-chan! The "3x Save" feature!
Save me! Save me!
Wrong.
Save me kite kite!
Save me kit!
Right!
Whoa!
What use is this, Shiro?
Not good, the water spiders!
It seems I won't have to play a part.
That you, Shinnosuke?
Ye-s!
Why don't you ride?
Okay!
It's shuriken!
Shinnosuke! Fly!
I don't need it.
Here I come.
A sword will not affect me.
What will you do, Fubukimaru?
It seems as though you are tiring, but...
The moment the sword blades
part, will be the moment you die.
You're fast, Enji!
This is the first time Enji has
let anyone other than me ride!
It seems that he has
accepted you as one of us.
A YochiEn-ji (kindergartener)
riding En-ji.
As if...
Shinnosuke, is that supposed to be funny?
No... not really...
I see.
I'll go inside first and open the gate.
Wait here until then.
Okay.
Is it going to be all right?
Oh no!
It's a trap!
Retreat! RETREAT!
- There's so many coming!
- What are you going to do?
Cut my way through!
Begin!
Out of my way!
What's wrong?
The smell of fire weapons!
Tanegashima! (Muskets)
What's that?
Guns!
It's no use!
You can't shoot down Fubukimaru
with arrows from afar!
Come out!
Don't you want my neck?
Cowards.
Mom will get mad if you go in a
house without wiping your feet!
We only need to cross this
bridge, and it's the castle tower!
Wait a moment, please!
What is it?
I sense the enemy's
resistance isn't serious.
They are luring us in on purpose.
If you know, then we have to plan
something or it'll go as they planned!
No!
They're moving right now.
We'll dive deep into the heart
of the trap and find an opening.
There's no other way to victory for us!
And if the enemy doesn't
show us an opening?
We're prepared for the
worst from the start!
But that's...
reckless!
The bridge!
Enji!
That's enough.
You've done well to get us this far!
You are my pride!
Rest here, ok?
Let's go!
Yes!
Wait.
Okay!
Don't stop! Run!
- Yes!
- Okay!
Stop.
Really!
Run. Stop. Wait. Don't stop...
You sure are willful.
Above us is Unkokusai-sama's pavilion.
And the thing that noisy woman
said to return is also there.
But, for both, you must defeat me first.
I do not wish to kill a woman,
but I have no choice.
Oh, you're so frightening.
Why does it not cut?
Really, why doesn't it?
It is only thin, weak silk.
You're a woman, aren't you?!
I can tell by the smell of your skin.
A woman, eh?
I hate women!
Especially women who try to get
close to Unkokusai-sama!
I am...
I am NOT a woman!
In Japan, there's a saying,
"a woman's hair is her life"
It was a doll, then?
Shinnosuke. Come.
Okay!
My body will not listen to me.
It was that gas, just now!
I beg you.
Hurry, take it.
But Mama said children shouldn't
have things with blades on them!
My sister.
Lady!
It's alright. She's only paralyzed.
What'll we do, Shiro?
Luckily we have one more
use of the "3x Save" feature.
Then we have to believe in
the power of that sword!
I want to be a dog...
Shin-chan! Fight!
Aren't you a heroic warrior?
Take a stand against evil!
Now!
Damn! So what about PooPoo!
Poo-Poo-On-The-Underwear-Rolling-Thunder!
So you've finally come all the way here.
One dog and one child.
I shall praise you, though I shall
not present you with a belt.
You're Unkokusai, right?
And so I am.
Smells like... PooPoo. (Unkokusai)
Show your true form!
We already know that you
are a person from the future!
What did you say?
Paul McCartney?
As if...
How about that? Isn't that a
popular gag in the 20th century?
He's not funny, Shiro!
As I thought.
He is a 30th Century History freak.
That is correct.
Well, nice to meet you.
Typical businessman introduction
This is what kind of person I am, here.
Please treat me well.
I'm Shinnosuke Nohara, 5 years old.
Typical kindergartner introduction
Nice to meet you.
This isn't the time to be doing
formal introductions!
History, Trend Creator and
Culturalist, Pierre Jakoman.
Hurry up and put it away.
Oka-y.
And? What will you do?
Quit interfering with history
right now and turn yourself in!
Yeah! Yeah!
I don't want to.
I don't like violence, but...
What would you do if I liked
picking on dogs and kids?
Yoo Hoo.
Shiro. What'll we do?
Number Seven Wee Wee Maru is calling!
Draw the sword, Shin-chan!
Okay!
Shin-chan!
It's too heavy. I can't hold it!
What are you trying to do?
Shin-chan, use the "3x Save" feature!
Save me Todatodachichi!
Maybe you're doing that on purpose?
Save me Kit!
Adult Shin-chan appears!
Shin-chan! Hurry up and catch Pierre!
O-kay!
That's a foul, you guys.
He's getting away!
Wait!
No.
You guys who cheat all the
time are law-breakers.
I'll just give you the death sentence.
I won't lose!
Right now I am Shin-ly strong!
At least I feel that way, probably...
I'm counting on you, Shin-chan!
O..okay!
Then shall we?
There's no sense in killing
you if you're too weak.
So make a little effort okay?
I'm invincible!
That's nice.
You're good!
You're pretty strong.
Let's change the menu.
The things I like are hotcakes
and bouncy young girls!
Hotcake...
Bouncy young... Ah, I messed up.
You're so irritating.
Really...
Really... Really...
Really... Really... Really... Really...
Strong... now.
I am a hundred million times stronger!
You are such a child.
It's not really that much...
You did it now!
You're strong!
You're strong, aren't you?
This is the best!
You. That's unsightly.
And just when I thought you looked cool.
That's no good!
Huh?
It ran out of time!
I'm back to normal!
Shin-chan!
Ouch!!!
That hurt!!!
It's coming again, Shiro!
What is it this time, Shiro?
Shiro won't talk anymore.
Who are you?
Rings ToStorm, 30th Century Time Patroller.
I was the one talking through Shiro.
The lady who never came in handy!
Yeah, that's it.
I'm sorry.
Putting you in such danger.
Though Shin-chan, you looked really cool.
Thank you very much.
Shinnosuke!
Did you do it?
Fubukimaru-san!
Who are you?
I don't think you'd understand
if I told you, but...
I'm someone who's life you saved.
If it weren't for you, by now I'd be...
I can't think that you are a stranger.
Yes.
Shinnosuke! My sister?
I... don't know.
My chest is so hot.
Have I fallen in love?
Dynamite Boobs!
- Dad! Mom!
- Shinnosuke!
Shin-chan!
And then a pretty lady!
Yoohoo...
Yukino!
Elder sister!
Sister?
She must have meant elder brother.
Dad and Mom, you're so behind the times!
Fubukimaru was really a lady, you know.
Oh, is that what it was?
Why are you so disappointed?
Huh?
Milady elder sister...
I am ever grateful for the viewing of thine
face for once in such a long course of days.
I am understanding that you are
in extremely beautiful health.
Of that I am most glad because of my
extremely deep attachment to you.
What did she say?
I don't know.
You've been a long time prisoner.
I am in disbelief that you are so well.
Stupid. Don't cry.
It is all over.
Hey baby!
Why don't you cry all
you want on my chest?
Shinnosuke, Yukino is a man.
No way!
From the time he was born,
Yukino's believed that he was a girl.
No matter how we try to fix him,
he won't get better.
My lord father was quite distraught.
So I became a man.
You mean you're an okama-san?
(Transvestite)
This is a scam.
Everyone, let's leave the
long conversations for later.
We needn't overstay our welcome.
Let us part from this place now.
What?
You are woman?
I am a woman!
I'm so glad!
Daddy.
Mommy.
Ring.
Fubukimaru.
Yukino.
Enji.
Shiro.
Boy, are there a lot of us.
Everyone, thank you for working so hard.
Well. Let's go home.
Is this the horse of the
three heroes and one dog?
How prestigious.
Press to us?
That sounds kinda ecchi.
Don't say such stupid things.
Hurry up and come.
Shinnosuke. This is goodbye.
I can't thank you enough
for your peerless work.
I give you my thanks.
When you thank someone, you say,
"Thank you very much."
Like that.
Thank you very much.
How was that?
You're heading in a pretty good direction!
Won't you marry me?
I refuse.
Though I would not mind...
I don't want a boy lady!
Farewell, heroic warriors.
Fubukimaru.
Milady mother.
And just when we are preparing for war...
Father is already surrouned by subjects.
My soul feels as though I had
been gazing upon a long dream.
Was it a good dream then?
I don't know.
I've brought you a change of
clothes from the 20th century.
Please change into them later.
I really can't thank you enough,
but please help yourself.
I have to bring you all home...
then bring Number Seven
WeeWee Maru and their legend back
to Fubukimaru's ancestors...
then my job is done.
Bring their legend back?
Fubukimaru knew of us, didn't she?
Who do you think was the first to tell
the Kasuga Family of that legend?
It's my last job after this.
I don't understand at all.
You're so stupid, Misae.
I see, then a time paradox won't occur.
The main support of a family has to
have some understanding of Sci-Fi.
Alright! 7:55.
I'll make it to work in time!
Shin-chan, please hurry and
get ready for kindergarten.
Right.
Since she was bringing clothes,
she could have brought my suit.
Geez, people from the future
aren't very thoughtful.
I forgive her since she's beautiful.
To tell the truth, so do I.
The kindergarten bus is here.
Nohara-sama! Good morning!
Sorry! Good morning!
- Good morning!
- Good evening!
Everyone is waiting, so please hurry.
Yes.
Is something the mat--?
What's happened to your appearance?
But...
- Shinnosuke!
- Mommy! My clothes!
What happened?
Kazama-kun. Nene-chan.
Matsuo-kun. Bo-chan.
You're all weird.
What are you saying?
- What are you saying is weird?
- The clothes are weird!
Shin-chan, you're wearing
the same thing, aren't you?
There's nothing weird
about it at all.
But it's weird!
Weird.
It's not.
Ah.. uh.. Excuse me...
What's with your clothes?
Misae!
What is going on here?
Don't I have to go to kindergarten?
You'll have to miss today.
In short...
This is...
What is this?
Don't know.
That's it!
Let's turn on the TV!
...and returning to "Arts Noh
Play Flash Wide."
And it's live footage of that star.
Ah! Matsukaza-san has
just come out of the car!
And in the back seat, the
rumored lover, foreign dancer...
Jeff, Harry, Tomas, Nick, Jerry,
Mac, Abraham, Gideon, and Charles!
Actress: Ume Martsukaza (24 years, single)
Ume-san!
Just one word!
Ume-san, just a word, please!
Don't call me Ume!
Matsuzaka-sensei!
What is this?
What about the other channels?
Japanese Society
Sensei, we're going to hear you talk
about today's modern Japan, right?
Yes, that's right.
Right now Japan is in
year 7 of Hei-Hei-Ho.
And this is all due to the one who
began his rule over Japan, reviving
Japanese Culture... Really everything
is because of Japan's president,
his Excellency, Jokoman...
It's that bad guy!
What did you say?
...really grateful...
Special Report Program
We interrupt this program
with an announcement.
His Beloved Excellency President
Jokoman-sama's new laws for today.
All channels have been changed
to the government frequency.
And so people of the country,
his Beloved Excellency President
Pierre Jokoman-sama.
Please listen reverently.
Hey, people of my country,
are you all well?
No, it's okay. It's okay.
Then I'll announce today's laws, okay?
Country of Japan. Constitution #389:
These three, they're called Hiroshi,
Shinnosuke, and Misae Nohara, but...
I'll give 20 billion yen to the
person who catches them.
And well, that's that...
If they die en route, it's half.
10 billion yen, okay?
We are truly grateful for those words...
from our Beloved Excellency, our
president Pierre Jokoman-sama...
Why does he use such awful pictures?!
I don't think that's the issue here.
Daddy. Mommy.
There's something strange
about this world. It's weird!
You don't have to tell us,
we already know!
That's it!
Hello there.
This world is weird.
Please respond!
That's right!
Please answer!
Hello? Save us!
Hey!
You're so stupid. Shiro's a dog,
so there's no way he can talk.
That sound!
They're here!
Save me kit!
It's no good.
It's gotta be a lie!
Is this the end already?
Niyaa!
That was a close call!
What part?
It's true!
You may not have been able
to see it with human eyes...
but this Meow-On suit can move
at over 20 times the speed of light.
But the enemy's ninja stars hit it.
They're really frightening.
I won't be able to use this
suit anymore, will I?
Big sister Ring!
I'm so glad you're ok, Shin-chan.
You were scared, weren't you?
It's all right now.
It was scary.
No-
Kids are so lucky...
What do you mean?
Nothing...
I think you've already realized...
but now, Pierre Jokoman, Unkokusai's
real identity who didn't die in the Age of
Civil Wars and escaped to this age...
is changing history once again.
But, why did only our memories
and Misae's clothing not change?
The Nohara family passed three
days in the Age of Civil Wars...
so there is a lag of three days
before time catches up with you.
And then I came to get your clothing,
so there is a lag of one hour.
Probably Hiroshi-san and Shin-chan,
you changed in this world?
Now that you mention it...
Soon, Misae-san's clothing will
change due to the readjusted time.
5... 4... 3... 2... 1.
What? That's why I just don't
understand SciFi and I hate it!
Hey, isn't it strange that
you understand so much?
I've not talked about it to you until now...
During my high school days,
I was in the SciFi club.
Even though I look like this,
I'm a SciFi fan.
Oh really.
Hey! Don't despise me.
We don't have time.
We will go to where Pierre is.
We're going, too?
How are we going to fight?
We have a very good
chance for victory!
And Shin-chan holds the key.
"Holds" has a kind of heart-rending,
ecchi perverted ring to it...
It's not ecchi at all!
Grown ups just don't understand.
Capitol: Tokyo
We're taking off!
Time criminal, Pierre Jokoman,
you can't escape anymore!
Quietly accept the rope!
Not that...
I mean... Time Crime Dictates #12,
I will arrest you!
Oh. Oh. Is that so?
That you know my name...
I guess I've become a
really famous person.
It seems my name will
live on in history.
Pierre Jokoman.
The gentleman who governs
20th century Japans.
Oh, but if I get caught here, then
everything will return to normal.
My hard work will become
bubbles upon water.
Oh, I don't like it. Don't like it.
Things like this.
You who get in my way, I'll kill you!
You're so small.
You're so small! You're so small!
What is that?
Say, why don't we run away?
Don't worry.
As long as we have faith,
the Time Patrol won't lose.
Time Reactionary Hat Hat!
If you press the switch on the
side of this box, it will shine.
You have to heighten the power
of this super dramatic tool.
- That's nice, but...
- And so what's going to happen?
At this point, we need the
cooperation of a child.
That's me!
I'll wear it! I'll wear it!
Of course!
Electromagnetic waves are coming out!
Because we need it, you can
see the electricity of the future.
Oh, that makes sense.
Then...
Let's go!
We'll connect to Shin-chan's
sense of aesthetics and...
change into a robot
that can defeat Unkokusai's robot.
It's too convenient.
Normal people like us,
just can't keep up.
No need to worry.
Even if you don't keep up, time
will flow of it's own accord.
It's enough to just do what
we have to do now.
I'm counting on you, Shin-chan!
Kantamu Robot arrives!
What? What's happening?
This robot is created entirely
by Shin-chan's imagination.
What's the power supply, Shinnosuke?
It's Mice-san!
The computer is Shiro.
Too much! This is just too much!
That's why I hate SciFi!
It's not all that, really.
We're not praising you!
It's getting to be interesting.
It's getting near the end.
It's getting to be so I'm not bored.
A. B. A. B. Left. Right.
Buri Buri PUNCH!
It feels goooood!
Misae PUNCH!
Alrigth! Got him!
It's an amazing weapon!
The Misae Punch doesn't work.
It's not my fault.
What are you going to do Shinnosuke?
Time for the Action Beam Gun.
Action Beam Gun?
Dad. Mom.
You do the commands with me!
A. B. B. A. A. B.
Right. Right. Left!
What's that?
I can't learn it.
It's the Action Beam Gun!
SET!
I won't just sit here and lose.
Love and Truth-chan.
Fire!
A. B. B. A. A. B.
Right. Right. Left!
Oh! A mistake!
We've messed up the code.
Oops. It's me.
I messed up, too.
It'll be over in one more shot, eh?
Super Effective.
Sin and Punishment-chan. Fire!
I'm counting on you, Shin-chan,
Hiroshi-san, Misae-san!
I love you, Misae!
I know!
I  l o v e  y o - - - u !
Game over.
Time up.
Is it over now?
It's over.
We can go home, right?
You can go home.
Won't you marry me?
I will not.
...and with the prevention of the
destruction of the environment...
and the preservation and further
propagation of nature's animals...
also came a bright
parent-child realtionship.
Why don't you just say the
"Peace of the Earth?"
I just wanted to say that once.
It's okay now.
I'm in debt to you, the
members of the Nohara family.
I'm sorry, but according to the
doctrines of time, I'm forbidden
to give you physical itmes.
All I can give you are words of gratitude.
Thank you so very much!
Just those words are enough.
I don't need anything else.
A toast to your eyes.
You guys!
Quit it already!!
Are we back?
Probably.
So everyone, please take your seats.
Please get in closer!
She's still here.
We were a bit early, then.
She's pretty clumsy, isn't she?
Is everybody ready?
Yeah.
And we didn't even know what
disasters were waiting for us!
Do your best, Nohara family!
Well, I'll be going!
Good morning!
Good morning.
Yoshinaga-sensei.
You're even cuter today!
What?
Hey! Midori!
Hey!
- Good morning!
Shin-chan, you're early today.
How admirable.
I'm admirable!
After all I protected and
preserved the peace of the earth!
It's just something kids say,
please don't take him seriously!
Of course.
I'm used to it.
Ready to Leaf! My meef!
My butt is cute, but Misae's butt
is big, so big! And to top it off
she's a breastless gal! Misae!
Hey!
Just when you think he made
it to the bus on time...
Really, those people never
make any progress.
So much energy for the morning.
Everyone a paradise
you've never experienced
Ricochetting red shoes
Chasing you
Both of my eyes
you easily don't meet
Thank you, Senorita!
I'm only serious about you
Act as though you don't know
Don't do that
Heart explodes!
Save me Kesta!
I'm mellow mellow
I'm totally Festa
Love Love Festa
Save me Kesta
It's a club!
Chance is now
Love Love Festa
When you get that feeling
Anytime is okay!
With both arms open
I'm waiting! Ole!
Under the bright sun
The one who hid
under the sun umbrella was
don't hurry
stop you
a feeling of suspense
The happiness of the whole world
sprinkle it among shining sweat
I waited and waited
The moment I
My heart explodes
Save me Kesta!
I'm mellow mellow
I'm totally Festa
Love Love Festa
Save me Kesta
It's a club!
Chance is now
Love Love Festa
When you get that feeling
Anytime is okay!
With both arms open
I'm waiting! Ole!
And so well, that's how it was!