New York is place
where people come
to have
their dreams realized.
And I think
that's why so many people
not only come
to this city,
but, ultimately,
make their way to Tiffany.
Do I know how to give
good fucking bites,
- or what, people?
Look, just roll away
and then I'll babble on.
Tell me when it's boring.
Well, you know, I mean
a company like Tiffany
which is very old,
you know,
there's a lot
of context to it.
I'm not uninterested in it.
Do you think
we should celebrate brands?
No.
I called up my manager
and I said, "i have to pay
my jewelry bill."
I said, "any movie
that comes down the pike,
any horrible
piece of crap."
So I did
this horrible movie--
there are few American
retail outlets
that are true institutions.
Bergdorf,
Tiffany's...
7-Eleven.
I'm wearing
lots of Tiffany today.
Are you?
I'm wearing this
Jackie o cuff,
and...
My zipper necklace.
- Fuck! Yes!
I want something
that I feel amazing in.
Like, the look
we're trying to create
for this particular--
-event.
-Event.
Tiffany box.
- You're getting--
-engaged?
--You're getting engaged!
-Oh, my god!
-Oh, my god--
-no, stop it.
-What are you d--
-stop it.
-No! No!
- You can't-- -
the branding, that blue box
with the white ribbon,
is unequivocal.
If you see that box
under the Christmas tree,
if you see that box
on a birthday,
you know
you're getting something
really, really special.
And that is not an accident.
That is a lot of very,
very clever people
spending a lot
of time and energy
thinking about
this brand positioning.
Where they're gonna sit
in relation
to their competitors,
and exactly where
they want to be.
It's our most recognizable
brand quality
and therefore,
it has to be perfect
and it has to be right.
People have a big affinity
with that color.
I think it's such
a recognizable brand color
that, of course,
people have very positive
associations with it.
You know what? I'm just
gonna take it all away.
'Cause that way, you'll just
really learn the lesson, okay?
All righty.
Well, I'm gonna run
a couple of errands
and I will see you
at dinner.
She took all my stuff.
Yeah...
Everything but
the little blue one.
That's the best one.
Oh, my god.
Thank you so much.
I would love to have
many of those
little blue boxes.
So, yes, as a woman
i definitely understand
the addiction to those
little blue boxes.
It happens to be
such a beautiful color.
The Tiffany blue
is what you would call
a "Robin's egg blue."
It's a sophisticated color
but it has
some green undertone.
Obviously,
working for Tiffany,
we use it
day in, day out.
We apply it
in so many different ways
and I think we really try
to get that right,
it's a very difficult
color to mix,
it's a very difficult color
from a production standpoint
to get right.
It changes
depending upon
whether
it's a painted surface,
a printed fabric surface,
a sprayed finish.
The number of Tiffany blue
is 1837.
And that was specifically
requested by Tiffany
as the time when Tiffany
first started.
The Tiffany blue formula
is a closely guarded secret
that pantone has developed
specifically for Tiffany,
and that's something
that is only sent out
by Tiffany
to their privileged partners.
People are trade marking
dumb stuff these days
but an institution
like Tiffany's
deserves to own
that color blue.
They made that blue.
That blue was nothing
until Tiffany's came along.
When Tiffany wanted to create
this image and consistency
with all their packaging
and media,
we knew that we had
to infuse that color
with some of the same
strong pigments,
and consistent pigments,
into that color
to allow consistency.
Otherwise, it'll fade.
Color is synonymous
with the brand.
So we're seeing this
more and more.
Even celebrities today
are branding themselves
with, uh, we produced
a color for Jay-Z.
He has his own signature blue.
But kanye west
had come to us--
I don't know, we got--
we got into the rap world.
I'm not talkin'
about "rich,"
I'm talkin'
about "wealth," okay?
about the white family
that owns
all the fuckin' similac,
those rich motherfuckers,
okay?
I'm talkin' about
the white family
that owns the color blue.
Those rich bastards,
okay?
No choice of color
has ever been so successful
in the history of marketing.
In 1853,
the empress eugenie
was the greatest fashion icon
of her period.
She was our kind
of 19th-century grace Kelly.
And, as empress of France,
she chose an official color,
this Robin's egg,
pale turquoise blue,
as her official color
since whatever
the empress eugenie did
was going to be
a worldwide success
and followed by everybody.
And that blue
was going to become
the world's
number one color.
Mr. Tiffany brilliantly
jumped on the opportunity
and immediately made it
Tiffany's official color.
Tiffany blue
is such a well-known color.
I actually got
the pantone swatches
and had a fabric
matched to it.
I kept trying to say,
"i want this blue,
I want this light blue,
it's all about a light blue."
And they kept coming back
with a Robin's egg.
And I kept saying,
"no, no, no, no.
Tiffany blue.
Tiffany blue."
And then,
i finally had to go
and we dip dyed, um,
fabric and a dress to match.
And you'll be seeing it
on the red carpet
very soon.
Estee.
That's amazing.
- Give it to me.
With the--
with the bathing suit tan.
- That's hilarious.
- -I mean, you have to just,
-you have to just go--
-you just have to go--
-own it, and be like--
-yes. Yes.
... "yep, off I go."
-Jeans are incred--
-jeans are brilliant.
The rubber band around the--
look at my watch.
- Whoopsie.
It's fun, but it's...
It is intense
because it's not--it's not
to be taken lightly, you know?
-Right.
-You're presenting yourself
-in a particular way
-right.
- Because it's my business.
- -Right.
But, you know, I was 19--
not wearing high heel
flip flops anymore.
Right, no more
high heel flip flops
- and tan lines and crop tops.
- -Right.
I didn't know any better.
--Most people don't.
This is no event
in the whole world
as important as the oscars
in terms of celebrity
product placement.
Everyone sees it.
And--and when
i do magazines
or advertising,
my mom sees it,
and my friends see it,
my peers see it.
But I don't think it has
this sort of, like, broad reach.
Jewelry on the red carpet
is a very complicated game.
I think it's big
because it's so competitive,
it's so valuable
for brands.
It's different
with everybody.
I mean, I have
a handful of jewelers
that I work with
for a red carpet dressing.
And I've had
relationships with them
for a very long time.
I've had a relationship
with Tiffany
for many, many years.
I've had tremendous
success with them--
jewelry, there's
a tremendous amount
of payola,
tremendous amount.
It is not unusual
for jewelers
to be courting the talent
with checks.
The stakes are high
and the payoff is great.
The brands want
that positioning,
and the actresses also want
that exclusivity
of being the only girl
in the best dress.
The only girl
with the best necklace.
Oh, my god,
it's so gorgeous.
Yeah, have a look.
Pass the mirror
and look at that 'cause
that's really fabulous.
- You see?
-Yes, I can.
- It is so crazy.
-What do you think?
How does it feel on?
-It feels... perfect.
-I mean, it feels
amazing, doesn't it?
And just the way it sits
and the way it moves.
- It's... amazing.
- -It's gorgeous.
Wow.
What's great about the oscars
is all of a sudden
these exciting pieces
that you've never seen before,
you know, magically appear
'cause I think they...
Everyone keeps
like, a little--
their little special stash
for that time of year.
Gorgeous.
- Isn't it? Isn't it?
- -It's so beautiful.
I don't even know
what to say about it.
What kind of stone is that?
That's an aquamarine.
-So beautiful.
-My birthstone.
- Is it?
- -Wow.
--See, I knew this was--
I was kindred spirits
with this Jewel.
You knew
you could feel it.
-It was calling you.
-God, I love this.
So, Jessica's amazing.
She has that mixture
of--of glamour,
which can go back
to another time,
but she's also
very contemporary.
This is where I, sort of,
put all my designs up
and this sort of gives
a good idea
of the overall feeling
of where we're going
as a design team.
And this is
the initial drawing
for your necklace
that you have on.
It's already yours.
We've been looking at doing
these fabulous earrings,
drop earrings,
and a bracelet
with tassels
that, again, will have
that fluid feeling.
We did a lot of wreaths
in the past,
but the beauty
about this piece
is that there are
pear-shaped diamonds
going in one direction.
It's having a presence,
and it's having a presence
on somebody, you know,
as gorgeous as her.
I mean, especially
around "blue book."
Especially when people
will come to "blue book"
and they will see
some of the pieces
that she wore at the oscars.
It adds an enormous amount
of value.
The "blue book" is an upper.
You know, when it comes
in the mail
no one's allowed
to throw it away.
You can just look at it
and you can dream with it.
A lot of people
just collect Tiffany, you know,
and--and look forward
to "blue book" all year.
"Blue book"
is about stones.
It's about finding
the most phenomenal stones.
Some of the pieces
are just gonna be so stunning
and so seductive,
I'm hoping that I will
fall in love with one of them
and so will, you know,
one of the wealthiest people
in the world.
Now, being a mother
of twin 8-year-olds
I rarely have time
for the cathartic
retail experience.
But they do know
about Tiffany's.
Those wonderful, blue books
that arrive at the house
and they see mommy
looking at the jewelry,
and I show them
the jewelry.
And, in fact,
this past Valentine's day,
one of my twin daughters
came up to me and said,
"mommy, what do you want
from Tiffany's
for Valentine's day?
I'll tell daddy."
And--and it was
very cute.
She told him I wanted
the love ring,
only my husband
ended up buying
the Elsa peretti love ring
and I was actually
talking about
the Paloma Picasso
love ring.
And so, I was
very fortunate.
At the end,
i got both rings
because both of my daughters
wanted to be represented
in this Valentine's moment.
With a sense of fantasy
and luxury and imagination.
I have a pin
of the, um, little bird
standing on--sitting on
a stone, which I love.
Every time I wear it,
people go, "oh, my goodness.
That's amazing.
It's a remarkable piece."
I'm wearing this ring now
that had been my grandmother's
that, I think, is from--
it's Paloma Picasso
when she first started.
I think from
mid-seventies.
It's two stones.
It's a, um, an amethyst
and I think
it's an aquamarine,
but it might be
a blue topaz.
My grandmother
gave it to me.
She often would, you know,
give you a piece
here or there,
and this she gave me.
- Hi... oh!
- Oh, no!
-What happened?
Fluffy--oh, sorry.
- What happened?
-It's my daughter.
Are you wearing
anything Tiffany?
Uh, no, I'm not.
She has, though.
Yeah, she's next in line
for everything.
--Either Serena or fluffy,
and I don't think
fluffy wants it, so...
- Oh, he can come here.
It's all right,
he can come in.
Come in, come here.
- Wow, look at that.
-Big baby.
So Francesca's
blue book theme is "water,"
-did you know that?
-I did hear it, yeah.
- You did hear that?
-I did hear that, yeah.
She can be quite
secretive, Francesca.
She definitely can
'cause I haven't seen a thing.
It's more that she's,
i think,
focused on something
and maybe, you know,
not ready to sort of pull
it out and bear it just yet
for me to go, "ugh,"
or me to go, "wow."
Or me to go,
"what the fuck are you doing?"
Or, you know,
or any of those things.
But I do remember
sort of hearing whispers
that there were possibilities
that she was gonna get this job
at Tiffany, and it was one
of those ones where suddenly
it just felt all the stars
had aligned in the right place
and Francesca was right
in the epicenter.
It felt right, it felt like
she had earned it
because she has been
doing this for a long time.
I think there's
two things that help me.
One, I'm a woman.
Surprisingly, the first
design director
for Tiffany
that's a woman.
And it's kinda great
'cause, you know,
i try the jewelry on
and I wear it,
and I feel it.
I have to, I mean,
i want to.
If I don't wear it,
i can't make decisions on it.
This is something that needs
to sit on the body.
I have to wear it.
And then, secondly,
is the fact
that I'm-- I'm a trained
jeweler.
So I'm gonna think
about the construction.
It's just
ridiculously perfect
that she looks
like Audrey hepburn,
and she's designing
for Tiffany.
The way that I design
is I really start
with a concept.
And then, from the concept,
i create a story.
When you're going through
"blue book," you know,
you'd sort of feel
very happy in here,
"aren't these fun?
"Aren't these great?
Oh, these are a bit unusual."
And I think here you have
an element of surprise
that then leads you
onto here.
We've obviously pushed
the boundaries this year.
You know, this is not
going to be
your everyday "blue book."
It does have
classical pieces,
but it also has
some very unusual pieces.
Which, I think, is why
we're so excited about it.
There's two things
that I'm thinking while
I'm doing that--
so one is the look
and feel of it,
and the other thing
was just to fragment it
into, you know, ice,
snow, dew drops,
to create these...
These different subthemes,
in a way.
And then how they're gonna
rhythmically sit
one next to the other.
You can approach it with,
you know, colored stones.
You can approach it
through diamonds.
through something much bigger.
Here we have about...
I'd say over $20 million
worth of diamonds.
So, these are all
fancy colors.
So we've got a bit
to play around with today.
That one... so this
is a sort of...
Beautiful.
This is like rain.
- Nice splashes of rain.
- -It's wonderful.
But we don't wanna go down
the route of fountains
and showers, you know?
We want to keep it
really pure.
And the style has to sit well
with what's happening
with watches,
let's say for example.
And it has to also reflect
what we're doing
in the fashion jewelry,
so that it's one voice.
It becomes-- it becomes a
vocabulary,
so that if you're wearing
a Tiffany watch
with a Tiffany necklace,
I know, you know?
I can see it from
the other side of the room,
that's Tiffany.
And how long did it take you
to set the Tiffany diamond?
-I think about two hours.
-Two hours.
That must have been
quite a moment.
Well, it's amazing
if you think
the history
that stone has.
It's quite amazing.
Don't you just love it?
Love what?
Tiffany's.
Isn't it wonderful?
Do you see what I mean,
how nothing bad
could've happened to you
in a place like this?
It isn't that I give a hoot
about jewelry,
except diamonds,
of course.
Like that.
There are only two women
in the world
that have worn her.
Uh, in 1961,
Walter hoving,
being the entrepreneur
and the publicist
that he was,
uh... decided to have
some film shots taken
here at the store.
And Ms. hepburn
wore the necklace,
uh, wore the diamond
in a necklace
designed by schlumberger.
In order for the production
to get access to Tiffany's,
they granted Tiffany's
a little photo shoot
with Audrey wearing
the Tiffany diamond necklace.
So they did a little bit
of a trade.
Paramount got
the store and...
The company got Audrey.
So she was the second woman.
The first woman
was a socialite in 1957.
Tiffany and company
was co-hosting a charity ball
up in Newport, Rhode Island.
And the co-hostess,
Mrs. Sheldon whitehouse,
was actually the very first
woman to ever wear her.
He found the diamond,
the rough,
in the Kimberly mine
in South Africa.
It was 287-carats,
huge rough.
And he had the opportunity
to buy it.
Of course, enormous risk
to buy something like this.
One is never quite sure,
with that size of rough,
truly what you're going
to get out of it.
When you're cutting a rough
to a smaller diamond,
often many of the pieces
you're cutting away
are so included
that they're not really usable.
Maybe some
of the smaller pieces were,
but predominantly,
that is all weight loss.
So he took the risk,
he had a sense that there was
something within that
that was special.
So he bought the rough.
The rough was sent over
to Europe
and the first cut was made.
But there came out
the most incredibly brilliant,
beautiful diamond
with 82 facets.
Quite unique at that time.
Diamonds were not cut
with that many facets.
The wonderful thing
is you look at that
Tiffany diamond now
and it looks as modern
as if it were cut
last week, or a month ago,
or a year ago.
It's incredibly advanced.
So that's very special,
this is a very special diamond.
The security of her
is extremely tight, obviously.
But during my time
on the main floor,
we had, uh, a procedure
that after the store closed
and the stainless
steel doors were locked,
she was withdrawn
from the vault
on the main floor.
You had to wear
the white gloves,
and she was put
in her carriage
and whisked away
for the night.
There is a little secret.
One night, when I was removing
her from the case,
for just a moment-- I thought
about miss hepburn,
I thought about
Mrs. whitehouse,
they had both worn it
in a necklace.
And I thought... "A tiara.
I could be the first person,
the first woman,
the first employee
that wore her as a tiara."
So, for a second,
i put her in my quaff
and I stood there,
and I was actually transformed.
Life is not measured
by the number of beats
that your heart makes,
life is truly measured
by the moments
that take our breath way.
- And that moment I will never forget.
- -It truly did?
Oh, it did.
I was breathless.
There's something amazing
about the fact
that the film begins
with the windows.
The windows
are the first opportunity
to spread
the Tiffany magic.
And that's why the film
begins that way.
You know,
she gets out of the car,
she look at the window
and she's instantly
transported.
In window one, she was looking
at these tall wooden structures.
They were kind of, like,
multifaceted wooden pieces
with beautiful
schlumberger bracelets on them.
In window two,
it's miniature chandeliers
suspended beautifully
with brooches
suspended within them.
They're tremendously
beautiful windows
and those were very iconic
gene Moore displays.
Perhaps that was
the first time that people
saw, on a global scale,
gene Moore's work.
It's fun.
It's all part
of the whole thing.
It's fun to do.
I love doing it even,
uh, after all these years.
Gene was really a pioneer
in modern window display.
Because in the past,
the idea was
cram as much as you could
into the window
and have
all the price tags on it
and it's all about
pushing the merchandise,
but gene distilled it.
He would show one
or two pieces,
but it was the way you got in
was you wanted to see
what he was gonna do
with the windows.
People have forgotten,
the new generation
doesn't really know.
I don't think that they know
the whole story.
I've been known to break
a glass in the window.
And that was fun because
people would call up and say,
"you know you have
a broken glass in the window?"
I say, yes, I know.
There's the hammer right
beside it that broke it.
I learned to do
things different--
uh, to make a difference,
because
I wanted to see how much
attention people paid to it.
And they would
call up and say,
"do you know you have
one knife turned backwards?
Or one key
turned backwards?"
I said, "yeah."
And then I knew that
people looked at it.
It's the only way
i could check up.
Gene Moore had a wonderful
sense of wit in place.
He understood the whole theatre
of window design.
He took it to a place
that would use
incongruous objects
with beautiful jewelry.
I would walk around
the floor with gene,
you know, selecting product
for the window.
He used to love to use eggs.
You know,
he used to blowout eggs
and use eggs
a different way.
Eggs, to me,
is the most perfect shape
in the whole world.
I like 'em the way
they come right out of the hen.
I don't believe in
painted eggs.
Eggs are not to be painted.
They are so beautiful
in themselves
that I'd leave them
the way they are.
It was always sort
of juxtaposed jewelry
and something unique.
He just did
whatever he wanted.
The labor that went into
creating those things
and the artists he engaged
because he did engage people
to work with him.
And they were on
his rolodex.
They were not on
anyone else's rolodex.
You were nev-- and they were
very true to him.
One of his most
spectacular windows
was a giant white sphere
hanging over
a strand of pearls.
And I'd put them in
and I thought,
something is wrong.
You know, it's-- it's too clean.
It's wrong.
So, I broke a string of Pearl--
i thought I'll catch hell,
but I broke a string
of pearls
and I had the pearls,
you know...
And it helped the window.
It made the window
as a matter of fact.
And only gene
would have been able
to get away with showing
damaged goods
in the windows at Tiffany's.
They the--teasing glimpse
into a world
that you want to be part of.
It was very humbling
to be thinking
I'm part of something
that's ended up
in a window at Tiffany's
on fifth Avenue.
I mean,
it's a privilege and a joy.
Imagine a house
of Tiffany's saying,
hey, go and make
anything you want,
and work with these
extraordinary crafts people
upstairs
who literally still
hand make the items.
Is that you, my lovely?
Daisy Buchanan,
"the golden girl."
A breathless warmth
flowed from her.
A promise that there was
no one else in the world
she so wanted to see.
Do they miss me in Chicago?
Uh, yes. Um--um,
at least a dozen people
send their love.
How gorgeous.
I've just been in China.
I've just released
"the great gatsby" in China.
Yes, they're dazzled
by all the luxury.
But they're also very aware
of the heart issue of the book.
And that is this paradox
between this roaring '20s,
where there's "such an orgy of
money," to quote Fitzgerald.
And then there's
this kind of devastation
in the American dream,
if you like.
There must be a center
and there must be meaning.
In the last ten years,
the people
have just experienced
a tremendous change.
Not just in their lifestyle,
but in the--
in the way they feel
about themselves.
A lot of Chinese
were starting to get wealthy
and they thought
with that wealth
they should treat themselves
a little bit better.
And they've got
to this point now
where, finally, they can
live a beautiful life
and they can start thinking
about what they really want
and not just
what they need.
This idea
of the American dream and--
and when you think
"American dream,
"Chinese dream,"
and the vision
that they both speak to,
you realize
that all the values
that they're selling
are universal.
I don't even want to own
anything till I can find a place
where a million things
go together.
I'm not sure
where that is, but--
--i know what it's like.
-It's like Tiffany's.
-Tiffany's?
-You mean the jewelry store?
-That's right.
I'm crazy
about Tiffany's.
Although Tiffany in its-- its
current incarnation
is not
a celebrity-driven brand,
the one celebrity
who is beyond reproach,
who is enduringly popular,
who will always
be associated
with the brand
is Audrey hepburn.
I was definitely
familiarized with--
with the whole notion
of Tiffany's
through the movie
"breakfast at Tiffany's."
For me when I was younger
seeing that movie,
seeing her and seeing
the name "Tiffany's,"
embodied everything
that was glamorous,
and slightly unattainable,
about New York.
Well, no, because
of the title,
great product placement
without needing-- without
meaning it.
Tiffany got lucky,
sort of in the same way that
Campbell's soup got lucky
with Andy warhol.
It just happened
that this film was made.
It was not made for any kind
of advertorial purpose.
It's perfect.
It's a perfect image.
A lot of people confuse me
with Audrey hepburn. Um...
There are good things about it,
there are horrible things
about it.
- What's horrible?
-Mickey Rooney.
--Ugh! Ooh!
Mickey Rooney,
"breakfast at Tiffany's"?
Where's his Oscar?
Come on!
In 30 seconds
i got to call the police!
That's grotesque.
And, of course,
it was never actually "okay."
It was just allowed.
You know, all kinds of things
were allowed,
doesn't mean they're okay.
I genuinely admire the movie.
I admire the risks
that were taken
by Audrey hepburn,
by Blake Edwards.
Mancini and, uh, givenchy.
You want a character
you're gonna love.
Well, at the time,
i--i--
I thought it was a very
interesting choice.
I mean, she had style.
She had class.
She had a quality, I think,
that--that worked.
I don't think people know
that she was sort of like, uh,
a prostitute-- high end kinda
prostitute in New York City,
trying to claw her way
up to the top.
I think when now they see it,
she looks like a socialite.
They think she is a socialite.
Won't you join me?
Yes, join Audrey hepburn
as you've never
seen her before--
kicking over the traces
and bringing to life
Truman capote's
"breakfast at Tiffany's."
Well, the first time I saw
"breakfast at Tiffany's,"
it didn't-- didn't cross my mind
that she was a prostitute.
Capote doesn't come
right out and say it,
but if you read
between the lines
it's something that
he wanted you to consider.
My mom told me afterwards,
and I was like, "what?"
Really? What'd she say?
She was like, "by the way--"
yeah, she was like,
"you know that she's
a call-girl?"
And I'm like, "wh--why?"
"What gave you that sense?"
But, yeah, I mean,
in retrospect,
I'm like, "okay,
it's a bit obvious
once you have that
in your mind."
- She's a hooker?
- -Are you surprised
they would make a doll
out of a hooker?
Why'd they do that?
- Seriously? She's a hooker?
- -Yeah.
Then why is she
dressed like that
going to Tiffany's
for breakfast?
Think about what
you're seeing on screen.
The sun is coming up...
A beautiful girl,
in evening dress,
is getting out of cab.
Why? What is she doing
in an evening dress
at that hour?
Is she going out
to a party at sunrise?
Probably not. More likely,
she's coming home
from a party at sunrise.
-And then the next--
-this is not a good examp--
-and the next morning...
-Oh! So she... oh!
So she hooked up
with a rich guy,
-and she wants that guy--
-no. Well, not exactly.
Then what's up
with her outfit?
She wants extra cash
on the side,
so she's always
hooking up with men, right?
Well, yeah, I mean--
she was... a gal
who did take money
for entertaining guys,
it didn't--it didn't
specifically say
it became a sexual
situation or not. But, uh...
I don't think,
in the film,
you look at her as
an out-and-out hooker.
She's got too many
other elements.
You love her kookiness.
"Kook" was one of the words--
it was kind of a code word.
It was a-- it was a euphemism
to, um, comfort
nervous audiences
who knew a little bit about
what capote's novel was about,
and get them to feel,
sort of, more comfortable
with the idea that
they were seeing
a friendly movie,
a safe movie.
It may not have been
capote's original concept,
then I guess that
was a studio decision
for what they wanted
Holly golightly to be like.
Marilyn is closer
to the Holly golightly
in the novel.
So, on a certain level,
it makes sense that Truman
would want her.
Man, you guys-- you guys
are lucky that we just woke up.
-We're really raw
-yeah, we're really raw.
Can we--can we talk about
the song,
"breakfast at Tiffany's"?
Sure, go ahead.
But we were out in montauk
a couple years ago,
we were deejaying
our friend's wedding,
and we found ourselves
on the beach
trying to start
a bonfire.
And, uh...
Before we knew it,
we were joined by a bunch
of Ukrainian or...
-Eastern European, Ukrainian
-eastern--eastern, yeah.
Like, really good-looking,
eastern European teenagers
because that's who works
in montauk for the summer.
And suddenly, one of them,
the young boy,
-breaks out a guitar--
-yeah.
And starts singing
acoustically
"breakfast at Tiffany's"
with a heavy Ukrainian accent...
In a slow jam,
it was amazing.
In this very broken
sort of English, um--
which made it
kind of better, somehow--
he's singing it
and everyone's singing along.
And I'm looking at them
and I'm like,
"you guys are 16,
and 17, and 18.
First of all,
you're way too young
-to know this song--
-also, they're ukranian.
-Yeah, like, how did you--
-they were communist
a few years ago,
and now they're singing
a capitalist song
about breakfast at Tiffany's.
I thought if I could
get that phrase,
"breakfast at Tiffany's,"
into a song
that people might like it.
It sounds great,
but you can't just say...
You know?
It's a weird song.
"And I said, what about
'breakfast at Tiffany's?'
she said, I think
i remember the film
and, as I recall, I think
we both kinda liked it.
Well, then, I guess that's
the one thing we've got."
Almost nothing poetic
about it.
It's the inflections.
Yeah. Yeah.
What's the next verse?
I have had people
who I went out with
swear up and down,
"oh, no, this is about me
because we watched
that movie."
I'm like, "no, we didn't."
And so all these people think
that it's somehow
about them
and it's completely
fabricated.
The size of the diamond
or the quality
of the diamond?
The quality.
- Scarlett?
-Maybe the size.
No, I think the size--
i mean, what if it's like
a really ugly diamond,
and it's, like, so big
-that you just
can't stand it?
-Then you return it.
I think we should
stop here for a minute.
Maybe we should go
in there and find you
the most beautiful ring
that they have.
- All righty!
From that moment on,
Charlotte would tell everyone
that right in front
of Tiffany's,
out of nowhere
Trey popped the question
and she said, "all righty."
The engagement ring
as we know it
was introduced
by Tiffany himself.
Charles Tiffany
created a ring
that was more brilliant
than all others.
It was a beautiful ring
where the stone was lifted
up off the band
and held up so that
the light could scintillate.
This is the one
you see in cartoons.
I got a surprise
for Betty.
Get a load of this.
Wow!
Ooh-woo-woo-woo-woo,
what a sparkler.
I remember when
we first got engaged,
walking in there
and being so shocked
at the prices.
I said, "we gotta look
somewhere else."
- Is that right?
-Yes.
I think I was 20-- 24,
25-years-old at the time.
I couldn't quite
afford Tiffany's, so--
really? You're a Mara.
I--yeah, but...
I was a struggling
young lawyer at the time.
I--i think it
was some place
- on 47th street at the time.
- -47th street?
- Yeah, yeah.
- -That'll get you.
Yes, yes.
The whole engagement thing
at Tiffany's
- is just a story in itself.
- -What do you mean?
It's a mystery.
I just see people there
and kids
and grownups, like--
- does anyone ever buy
an engagement ring there?
No, actually, today we have
a lot of self-purchasers.
And so, the larger,
the purer,
the rarer, the better.
They all want picassos,
but on their fingers.
Um, here I have...
I only have one--
actually, I have about
two and a half million
dollars right here,
2.5 million.
It allows you
to get a ring
for her for every occasion.
So, one for every day.
This, actually,
is very reasonable.
$306,000.
One for dinner--
this is a Tiffany lucida.
This is a 5-carat,
it's a d-20 flawless.
And one for the gala--
and this also is 5-carats.
So Tiffany's setting
the 5-carats at d, vvs1
and it's $923,000.
Still a bargain,
just sub-one million.
By the way,
we do accept cash.
Think that most people there
all aspire to have that,
and then girls try it on,
but I would think
it's disappointing,
'cause then I don't know
if they actually buy it.
And then they will
have to walk down 15 blocks
to go get
a copy of the...
--Ring.
It always goes like this--
"oh, my cousin knows
someone on 47th street."
Did you get a blue box
when you got engaged?
- I didn't.
- -You didn't?
No, and I asked why not.
-But, you know, this is-- -
director] At that moment?
-Listen--no, no.
-Before he even asked you?
I didn't. I didn't,
but we were very young
and he was a waiter, and...
You know, I don't think
blue boxes really came
a lot very often
at that time-- I was, like, 22.
If we ever did get married
which, we don't believe in
marriage,
-it's a great institution.
-Yeah, but who wants to be
part of an institution?
- Tiffany. Right here.
- -Is that right?
- So then let me ask you this.
-My wedding ring.
So then, obviously,
you know that
-they put out
this gay ad, right?
-No.
The famed Tiffany and company
thinking outside
of the little blue box tonight.
Check out this new ad
for engagement rings
featuring a real-life
gay couple.
It's going viral tonight.
Tiffany says, "it's part
of a modern approach
to love and romance."
Oh, how great.
Now, why is that great?
Well, because
it's about time.
A spokesman for Tiffany's
said that everyone,
whether they are
gay or straight,
should have the right
- to grossly overpay
for jewelry.
It's a right we all have.
Well, yeah,
but they're also
supporting
their bottom line.
They realize there is
this whole new category
of people
who can get married.
They wanna see those people
wearing Tiffany rings.
'Cause whenever you get
a Tiffany ring,
you, like, "know"
it's from Tiffany's.
- How do you know?
-I mean, 'cause--
first of all, the style
and the color of the box.
But even if you didn't
have the box,
just something
in the diamond--
they're really white,
they're really beautiful.
I think that if you
get it from, like--
um, other jewelry brands--
see, I don't know that many.
'Cause I know Tiffany,
that's it.
And the more he spends...
What does that mean?
The more he loves you.
- Or the more he's rich.
- -Do you believe that?
-Well, the more he spends--
-the more he wants
to win you over.
The more he wants
So I was first introduced
to Tiffany and company
when I was in
the eighth grade.
My Nana took me to pick out
my first piece of Tiffany's
and from there on,
i became obsessed.
Uh, then I met
my now-husband
and he proposed to me
at the Tiffany and company
in Boston.
So we were watching
"sweet home Alabama" one night
when we first
started dating.
And I just,
offhanded comment, said,
"that would be
the most magical,
amazing proposal."
And he somehow remembered.
And so, from there,
i decided to follow the theme.
And we did a Tiffany
and company-themed wedding,
I did a Tiffany
and company-themed
bridal shower,
bachelorette party.
I'm pretty sure,
when I have children,
I'll probably do a Tiffany
and company-themed baby shower.
Thanks, now people
are gonna think I'm crazy.
They're gonna, like, take me
to Tiffany-rehab after this.
When I first wrote
"sweet home Alabama,"
I wrote a normal scene
where a guy
just, uh, proposed
to his girlfriend.
And that, I think,
was a very private moment.
So, wrote the movie,
turned it into the studio.
The studio said,
"we love the script,
but we think you could
do better with the proposal."
Can we come up with something
just a little more dazzling
because the Patrick dempsey
character was supposed
to be this kind of
really cool guy.
And he was the, you know,
"the most eligible bachelor"
dating Reese Witherspoon's
character.
So, I went home that night
and my wife said, "so how did
it go at the studio?"
And I said, "well,
it's all really good
but they now want me
to come up with
the best, you know, proposal
that's ever been on film."
So we started throwing ideas
around at the dinner table,
and she said, "well, you know,
i was proposed to once
at Tiffany's."
And I was like,
"wait, what?"
And so I found out
that night that my wife
had been proposed to
about five times.
- What?
-And, um...
So I was like, "huh."
So I say, "well,
so, what happened?
You mean he walked you--"
and then she said, "well,
he walked me into Tiffany's,
and he said 'pick one.'"
and I was like,
"why didn't you say yes?"
Andrew, are you on
some sort of medication?
What's going on?
Where are we?
Oh, my god.
Oh--oh, my god.
I think the scene
in Tiffany's
is one of my most
recognized scenes.
I mean, that's why my wall
is Tiffany blue.
I mean, I literally--when
i was moving into this office
and my, you know, the guy
who was decorating it.
I just said,
"there's gotta be some sorta
Tiffany color in here."
Has to be a tip of a hat
to a very successful movie
and a very successful scene.
Yes.
Yes! Yes!
Yes!
Pick one.
Come on, come on.
I actually went
to bora bora with my wife
as sort of
a second honeymoon,
and we ran in--you know,
we ran into honeymooners,
and as we started talking
and getting to know them,
they found out
i was a film director
and when I said
"sweet home Alabama,"
they were like,
"oh, my god! Tiffany's!"
Well, I needed
to use jewelry
in the "ocean's" trilogy,
and I had to dress
some of the most beautiful
women in the world
with some of the handsomest
men in the world.
So I figured I'd better go
to the most important
jewelry company
in the world.
When a person puts on
a great piece of jewelry,
and a Tiffany jewelry,
they feel a certain way.
It gives them a certain
joie de vivre
that they don't--might not
have without that.
I mean, Julia has it
either way.
But it makes her feel good,
makes her feel like she has
something important on,
which she does.
With movie stars
like Julia Roberts
and so on and so forth,
I don't say, "wear this,
and wear it now!"
I sit down with them
and I say,
"this is jewelry
from Tiffany's.
Take a look at it and see
what catches your eye,
see what you enjoy."
And then they find things
that they like
and they try 'em on.
And they try 'em on
with the dress they're wearing
and they try 'em on again
and again and again.
And they change their mind
four, five times.
So... and then they finally
settle in on a piece.
You are up to something,
Danny. What?
And don't say
"you came here for me."
You're pulling a job,
aren't you?
Well, know this.
No matter what it is,
you won't win me back.
Tess, I just came
to say goodbye.
I got you something,
and, um--
-aw, it's a Tiffany box.
-Thank you, yeah.
I wasn't--i wasn't invited
to the wedding.
--No.
Yeah, we don't know
each other.
Not well enough for you
to come to the wedding, no.
--It would've been really odd.
I know I don't know you,
but I just wanted
-to give you something.
-Okay. Well, thank you.
-You can share that
with your wife.
-Can I open it now?
Yeah, go ahead.
Please, please do.
Is it, uh...
Wow, it's--wow, it is
really a Tiffany thing--
oh, come on.
I'm on network, now, man.
Of course it's gonna
be a Tiffany.
This isn't
comedy central swag.
- It's engraved.
-It's engraved.
What does it say?
It says, "i don't know you."
"Someone will move away,
someone will come home,
someone will
finally graduate..."
What we're doing
when we do this
is to explain Tiffany's
purpose in the world
to, maybe,
a younger generation
that is not familiar with it.
It's a little lost
on my generation
'cause I think
it's a bit... tired.
And there's a lot
of psychological components
to Tiffany's.
We touch on
the products we sell,
like engagement rings
and gifts for special occasions,
but there's
no direct selling here.
It's just an attitude.
It's a feeling
about our customer,
and who we are.
I think it is
a little bit of a brainwash.
A lot of the ads
are white families.
It's--it's a little bit
of a 1950s kind of feel to it.
We want to speak
to our customer
as a human being,
as someone who has a family.
Maybe have children,
maybe wants to get married.
It stretches true love
so much,
it's such an unrealistic
true love.
Which also, I think,
gives us
a little bit
of a "yuck."
I was about 11 years old
and I saw the ad
in the "New York times,"
where Tiffany's ads
have always been,
I saw an ad for a ring.
And the ring was--
cost $176,000.
I remember thinking
that was just
an inconceivable amount
of money.
I was the son
of two writers,
we were not rich by any stretch
of the imagination,
and that just
seemed incredible.
And so I wrote this letter.
And, on the one hand,
it was... I could
do the math, and so
it was a slightly
snarky letter, I suppose,
but at the same time
i was 11 years old.
I remember thinking,
"well, you never know."
"Dear Tiffany's...
"Sincerely, David joblanski."
"Dear David..."
Well, there's one man
who agrees with that.
His name
is Walter hoving
and he is the president,
chief executive officer
of Tiffany, a store
of which you may have heard.
-And here's tom brokaw.
-Thank you, gene.
Walter hoving has been
in retailing
for 60 years now,
and he has been affiliated
with places as different
as Montgomery ward's
and bonwitt and teller
and lord and Taylor.
And for the past 23 years,
he's been the chairman
of Tiffany's.
Last week he placed an ad
in a newspaper, it said...
Mr. hoving, why aren't you
open on Sundays?
After all, this is
the biggest time of the year,
i would suspect,
-for Tiffany's.
-We think our customers
need a rest.
So we keep closed
on Sundays.
Mr. hoving, you have
on sale at Tiffany's
an emerald necklace
that is worth $1,700,000
and you have a diamond
that is worth $7 million,
- I think, all together.
-That's right.
What if someone
were passing through town,
and decided that they wanted
to buy one of those two items,
but they were only
available on Sunday.
Would you open the store to sell
them one of those two items?
- No, we would not. No.
-You'd pass
on that sale?
- That's right.
- -Walter hoving,
outspoken chairman
of the board
of a little store,
as we like to say on
the corner here in New York,
called Tiffany's.
Is it heavy
when you pick it up?
Uh, not really, no.
But I remember
being handed the trophy
and remember thinking
"please don't drop it,
you're on national television.
You got millions
of people watching."
So I think I held it
with two hands,
but it's really
not very heavy at all.
But it is--it is beautiful
and, uh, we sure like
the four that we have
and that's your goal.
And it's a tough goal
to achieve
'cause there are 31
other clubs out there
trying to do the same thing.
By the time
the trophy is coming out,
usually we're, like,
divvying up, you know,
our winnings or our losses
and not paying
a lot of attention
to that super bowl trophy,
but I bet the players are.
And I bet when those players
get that trophy,
and their wives
or their girlfriends
are standing
just off the side,
they say,
"i want my trophy."
George steinbrenner bought
the Yankees in 1973.
At that time, I think
the top hat logo
was more in use.
It adorned
every team publication,
it was more commonly used.
He was more attracted
to the interlocking "n-y."
He thought there was something
very classy about it.
So, almost immediately from
the time he owned the team,
that was the logo of choice.
Tiffany had designed
that interlocking "n-y"
on a police medal
that was given in 1877
to a wounded New York City
police officer.
One of the Yankees'
two owners
in their first decade
of existence
was William devery,
who had been chief of police
of New York City.
William devery probably kept
that "n-y" design
in some form
of circulation
and he was still half-owner
of the team in 1909
when it first appeared
on the yankee uniform.
You may get another
announcement in a second.
Yeah, shoot--say it again?
When the clock
was first installed,
why was Tiffany chosen?
Got it. Okay.
Here in
grand central terminal,
many people believe
and testify
that our magnificent October,
starlit, zodiac ceiling--
which happens to be made
of Tiffany blue
to represent the sky--
that there may
be a correlation.
It's one we're perfectly
willing to accept.
It's all surrounded
by the world's largest,
most magnificent piece
of Tiffany glass,
the clock, that just
identifies this terminal.
There's been a billion movies
made about New York.
Every possible building,
statue, has been in a movie.
This has never been
in a movie.
That's how I convinced
Marty to do it.
It's so beautiful,
that clock,
that from the back
that clock is beautiful.
And people, you know,
don't really see
the clock
that I came out of
because you can only see it
if you're going
up park Avenue.
Our Tiffany clock,
all the original parts
are still there.
The original motors,
the original gears.
With all these pieces
a hundred years old,
it's accurate
to within one second
every 1,400,000 years.
Well, I can say
that I was thrilled
to read the biography
of Steve Jobs
because I had not realized
that Steve Jobs
had appreciated the design
and the work of Louis Tiffany.
One of the illustrations
in that book,
it depicted Steve Jobs
sitting on the floor
in a virtually empty
room in his home
where the only object
was a floor lamp.
What the book
went on to say
is that he couldn't
furnish his home
because he couldn't find
anything that met his standards
and there you have
a Tiffany lamp.
He appreciated
the beauty in it
and the cleanl--
what he was
trying to say.
Well, Tiffany was about
beauty, and he was too.
It was about design-- and
perfect design.
When you think
of the magnolia,
you harken back
to nature.
And then,
even if you go further,
you think
of Japanese culture
because Tiffany
travelled tremendously
throughout the world
and he brought
many of his influences
from traveling
into his design aesthetic.
So you can relate to it
in very different ways.
One of his quotes was
"nature is always beautiful."
I think that
was very inspirational.
Color was
so important to him.
He was--he considered
himself a colorist
and it comes through
in everything that was made.
By the time that
Charles Lewis Tiffany dies,
Louis has really mastered
all of these different forms.
And I think that
the jewelry really
is such a continuation
of his aesthetic.
Again, the emphasis on color.
The emphasis on nature.
Louis went on to do
very much the same
as his father did,
which was to create a brand
and to open this
incredible luxury, sort of,
retail emporium,
and very much followed
in his father's footsteps.
The sidewalks
along fifth Avenue
are always crowded
with shoppers.
Fran and Sally
did some shopping, too.
They were just
window shopping here, though.
Yes, this is "the" Tiffany's,
the world famous
jewelry store.
Well, this was, of course,
the summer of 1945.
And we were looking
for a summer job.
We had been turned down by
most of the department stores
and when we went
up the Avenue,
suddenly-- there
we saw Tiffany's.
We loved to be
on the main floor
because we wanted
to watch the door
for all the celebrities.
That was a dazzling moment,
to see Judy garland.
When she walked in
with her new husband,
she looked so happy,
and to hear that famous laugh
ring through the store...
Who knows what
she was laughing about?
But what she purchased
as a gift from mgm
were emeralds, which made me
think of "the wizard of oz."
They said that was
her wedding present,
she could choose anything
she wanted at Tiffany.
This watch is incredible.
This is, um, quite amazing.
This is from
our archive.
This is fdr's last watch.
Now, we've made a lot
of watches for presidents
and it's surprisingly small,
i have to say.
When you wear it,
it literally sends
shivers down your spine.
You can see here
how much he loved it
and how much he wore it
'cause all of the stitching
on this side
is completely worn off.
We have this amazing history
of watch making.
I found it
extremely inspiring.
I think my first blue box
was around when
i was 12 or 13.
And I remember being
rather disappointed
on my 16th birthday when
there were multiple blue boxes.
And there was a large one,
and I was really excited
to open it up
and see what was inside.
It was, of course,
the first box that I went for.
And when I started
opening it up,
inside I found
an etiquette book.
I think my
first exposure was
the Tiffany's etiquette book
for teenagers.
I came to the U.S.
when I was eight or nine,
so we weren't so well-schooled
on American etiquette.
They were like,
"this is a good book
to learn from."
Beyond chopsticks.
My first memory of Tiffany's
is... they have
an etiquette guide
for teenagers--
"Tiffany's table manners
for teenagers."
I remember the Christmas.
I was probably 13,
maybe 14 at the time.
An etiquette book isn't
what every teenager wants
for Christmas.
I think it's such an iconic,
respected American brand
so, I think parents
might think
that's it's a great thing
to give to a young girl.
-So that was a little bit
of a disappointment, but-- -
director] The etiquette book?
Yes,
the Tiffany etiquette book.
But apparently, I guess
i learned a few things from it.
And it wasn't until
i was older
when I realized that
I'm gonna move to New York,
if I'm gonna make it
in the big city,
I should know
which one is a salad fork,
which one
is the soup spoon.
And so, I found myself,
sneakily, stealthily,
looking for that book
and reading a few chapters.
And I actually just
bought it for my son,
and he's nine,
and we were at breakfast
and I gave it to him
and he looked at it.
And he looked at me,
he goes,
"my name is not Tiffany
and I'm not a teenager.
Here you go,
you can have it back."
I was super lucky
that for one of my birthdays
my team literally
captured me, blindfolded me--
they actually took me
on this surprise trip
and when I opened my eyes
I was on the second floor
of this Tiffany's
and they had created this
wonderful breakfast for me.
So I literally had
breakfast at Tiffany's.
--Who--who else had
a birthday?
I think Katie Couric
had her birthday there.
-Did you know about that?
-Katie Couric? No, I don't.
But I'm very happy to share
that experience with Katie.
Katie's a very jolly lady.
They let glenda baily
have a party at Tiffany's?
I thought
i was the only one.
I was turning 50
and unlike a lot of people,
i love birthdays.
And I love parties.
It was an inside job
basically,
my friend Carole
works at Tiffany.
I was trying to find
a really cool, fun,
different space.
We had a cocktail party
on the first floor.
We served tiffaninis,
which looked
dangerously like,
um Ty-d-bol.
But they were delicious.
And strong.
I think it will probably
go down in history,
my personal history,
as my best birthday ever.
I am a scorpio,
just like Elsa peretti.
And Elsa peretti
of course designed
this beautiful necklace
which was a present
from my team.
And it reminds
everybody
that the qualities a scorpio
is supposed to have.
And all I can tell you
is that Elsa
is one of the most
passionate, strong,
and focused individuals
I've ever had
the pleasure to meet.
On my wish list,
of course is the scorpio.
J'adore.
She's divine.
My first piece
i wanted
was the bone cuff
from Elsa peretti.
Oh, everybody should have
a peretti Sterling cuff.
I mean, I had client
in here earlier today
who collects peretti
and was wearing a pair
of peretti earrings.
And it's just like,
it's always good.
When Elsa started at Tiffany,
it was the mid 1970s.
And Elsa peretti
was hot, you know?
I mean, she was part
of halston's entourage,
she was a model.
She had been
designing jewelry
that was on the catwalks
with halston
and giorgio di sant' Angelo.
And the jewelry
was a hit.
I really like the design
of the Elsa peretti pieces.
So for my editorial work,
and also with fashion shows
I've used it a lot
'cause it's some
of my favorite jewelry
that exists.
Well, this is
the first piece of jewelry
that Elsa peretti
designed at Tiffany--
one of the first pieces
but she really designed
it before she started.
You know there's a necklace
that's like a bud base.
That an orchid
could fit in.
She said
she designed it
because when she saw
the girls in Capri
wearing flowers
in their hair,
she thought that was
the most beautiful thing
in the world.
But she didn't want
her flower to die.
So she made
a bottle pendant to put
the flower in.
And that's
what it's for.
But like, there's
sort of a suggestion
that you could also keep
your drugs in there.
I mean...
No, like, you know.
It's cool.
What she able to do
in terms of communicating
her language
and her aesthetic
through jewelry,
she certainly
paved the way
for people like myself
and other jewelry
designers today.
And there's not a lot
of places that wanna
bring other designers
in under their umbrella.
Being a part of vogue
and being a part
of the c.F.D.A.
Is wonderful because
they really do foster
new designers
and help companies.
You know,
i can't even tell you
what the last year
has done for my business,
just being a part of it.
When I won runner-up,
I got a really nice gift
from Tiffany
and I was in heaven.
The idea of jewelry,
and to succeed
as a jewelry designer,
I think is something
that even clothing designers
have aspirations for.
The year Monique pean won,
she was a runner-up winner
she won $100,000
and her choice of mentor.
Went into
Anna wintour's office
and she said if you could
have any mentor,
who would you choose?
And I said, "you know
if I could have anyone,
I would love
to be able to work
with Michael Kowalski,
the ceo of Tiffany."
What intrigued me of course,
was her intense interest
in the materials
that she uses.
And her commitment
to--to sustainability
not only
in terms of materials,
but in terms of the folks
who provide those materials.
And I thought it was
a--a wonderful story,
and I think it's relevant
for luxury today.
Rather than
taking from the earth,
finding things
that you can reinvent,
fossils are so incredible
because they're
almost like nature's
photographs.
And that they're able
to tell a story through time.
And I use a lot
of fossilized woolly mammoth
and fossilized
dinosaur bone.
This is fossilized
woolly mammoth,
the cream parts
that have been
trapped in the ice
over tens of thousands
of years.
And then in the center
is fossilized woolly mammoth
the root of the tooth
and the salt minerals
over 35,000 years
changed the color
to these deep blues.
And then in the middle
is fossilized dinosaur bone.
That's from
the Jurassic period
and 150 million years old.
In jewelry designing,
talented new artists like
Jean schlumberger
originated labyrinth ideas,
which are the despair
of manufacturers
who serve the mass market.
I love the, um...
One of my favorites
is the--shit.
I can--can never
pronounce him.
"Schlum--sumberger."
- "Schlum-ber-Jay."
-Schlumberger. Mm-hmm.
Yup, make them Jewish.
- "Schlum-burger."
"Schlum-burger?"
Oh, my god. That's
so embarrassing.
- You corrected her, right?
I mean, you got--
of course, the...
Oh, my god,
why am I thinking
of "Cho-ba-Jay"?
"Show-ba-Jay."
I'm saying it wrong.
- Well, it's like--
-it's close.
- "Schlum-ber-Jay.
" -And they brought out the broach, and they said,
"this is "schlum-ber-Jay."
Is that how it's pronounced?
- Well, it's like--
-it's close.
- "Schlum-ber-Jay."
-Schlumberger.
"Sean--schlumberger."
The schlumberger--
these are heirlooms.
These are family heirlooms,
and they are from the 1940's.
They're early schlumberger.
I love
the schlumberger pieces.
Whenever I go in
to the Tiffany store,
that's where I go and just
sort of
pet the cabinets and...
And drool.
--The seahorse
is one of the very first
schlumberger pieces
that I bought.
He really was attracted
to themes in nature.
What he's most known for
are the schlumberger
enamel bracelets.
Jackie Kennedy
used to wear them
all the time.
And those are fantastic.
I'm really a fan
of big, big, big pieces.
This broach I'm sup--
I'm really partial to.
I used to read
Elizabeth Taylor,
my love affair with jewelry."
It was
my very favorite piece
in the book,
and I thought
I always wanted it,
and then when this came up
for auction--
I think it went
for about $1 million.
- Yes.
- $550,000 then, and selling.
$550,000.
At $6,300,000 then.
Here we are...
Sold for you, sir.
$7,800,000.
--Thank you very much.
I thought,
"well, I'm never gonna get
the Elizabeth Taylor one."
And so, I got this
and I think it was...
Don't quote me.
Like $60,000 or $70,000.
But there's only
six of these.
This one was made
in the 80s.
The designs that we have,
we don't change.
We try and recreate.
Some designs
were never made.
Some sketches
were only part-sketched.
And sometimes
you have to guess.
But it's all in
what he left.
There's nothing
that's being adapted
or changed.
-Diamonds...
Are a girl's best friend.
-Are a girl's best friend,
and what better night
to sparkle than on Oscar's?
Thank goodness.
Thank goodness
for Tiffany and co.
Look at this.
Look how gorgeous.
To die.
-And by the way--
-you can't take it--
-...this is one
of her favorite pieces.
-...From her.
I know, well we brought that
after she was, uh--
-yeah, she was--
-she went right to that
and was
really drawn to that.
Yeah, she'll be
very excited about that.
-So, we wanted to make-- -and so
am I.
Which we, of course,
are also partial to
because it's so close
to the Tiffany blue color.
Oh, right, got it.
Jessica biel here
on the red carpet.
Hi. How are you?
There you are.
-How are you?
-I'm well, thank you.
-Good to see you.
-Good to see you too.
So, tell me
about your dress.
Let's start with
the e! Fashion.
-Okay.
-Yes.
-This is Chanel couture.
-Mm-hmm.
And I'm basically
just decked
-head to toe in Tiffany's.
-You've got arm candy
but not
your other arm candy.
-He's out on tour, isn't he?
-Yes.
Yes, out on tour,
busy working.
I'm watching it on TV
with PR's
and other stylists.
- Yeah.
- With other stylists?
Yeah, I have
a couple stylists
I'm friends with
in L.A.
So we usually
watch it together.
Oh, it's so mean.
It's awesome.
Everybody's trashing everybody
except their clients.
- Everyone? Really?
-Yeah, you have to be
really careful.
Let's just get it
on the table,
who did who,
and let's all be nice.
Yeah, I mean, what do you do
when you watch the oscars?
You comment on
what everybody's wearing.
You know? And it's-- it's a
great, fun TV moment.
Oh, it's amazing.
I'm a great commentator.
- And I do have--
- you're a hater, too?
I am not a hater.
It's not from hate.
It's from the desire
to not be mediocre
and to really have
incredible style.
And to take all these
incredibly beautiful
pieces and things
that people are creating
and to really
celebrate them.
And not in a silly way.
In the old days when
they did celebrate beauty,
I mean, when Liz Taylor
won an award,
Liz was fabulous
and I would hope
that we would
get back to that day.
'Cause those
were incredible days.
At Hollywood's
pantages theatre
it's the motion picture
industry's night of nights,
and the film capital's
top stars turn out
for the annual presentation
of the coveted oscars.
Jessica! Jess!
Jessica, I need those eyes!
The right piece
on the right celebrity
is the best p.R.
You can't buy that p.R.
It's, uh, a photograph
that is seen worldwide.
Um, one photograph
is picked up
by countless blogs
and you are focusing
on that jewelry.
The dress, yes,
but the jewelry
really makes
that photograph.
And the accessories
really make that outfit.
And at the end of the day,
the dress is easily
knocked off.
The jewelry is priceless,
it's invaluable.
And people know
that jeweler.
It's like--it reminds me
of mineral in the ocean.
It's different
'cause...
It's kind of like a motto.
Jewelry stores don't really
have a theme
to what they do.
Besides Tiffany,
no other stores
really have, like,
a theme to their jewelry.
It's all just tropical.
When you're young,
you want to wear a diamond.
You're gonna want to wear--
when you're old and you get
divorced, like, five times,
you don't--you don't need
any of that stuff.
Well, ultimately,
we're talking about
a jewelry store.
How it is this pop-culture
kind of... circular weirdness.
All women everywhere
know that song.
- Do they really?
-Yeah.
You can go ask any woman
you pass on the street
and they'll--they know
that song.
So when this ends up
on the cutting room floor
of this film--
this'll make it.
Just let us know 'cause
we got stories about Carlyle.
The Carly--
yeah, I lost my virginity
in the Carlyle.
-Oh, shut up.
-With Elaine stritch.
The music video was filmed,
like, right here
I actually wrote it
on this guitar.
I had an actress throw out
a pair of earrings.
Like, it makes me
sick to my stomach.
They were in tissue,
and she cleaned her room
and looked everywhere and said,
"i think I threw them out."
'Cause she's paranoid
that she's a celebrity
and doesn't want to leave
a messy room
'cause then the housekeeping
will say she's a slob.
And she totally
threw them out.
Well, there aren't
many ways
you can get a lotta,
like, well-known names...
- Free in a film.