(intense suspenseful music)
(intense instrumental music)
(gun firing)
(suspenseful instrumental music)
(grunting and scuffling)
(intense instrumental music)
- You're getting better.
- I had a good teacher.
(grunting and scuffling)
- [Man] Hey kid, I'm proud of you,
let me help you up.
- Rule number one,
never trust the opponent, remember?
(laughing)
(gun firing)
(intense instrumental music)
(guns firing)
(dramatic instrumental music)
(gun firing)
(suspenseful instrumental music)
(guns firing)
(bombs exploding)
(suspenseful instrumental music)
(guns firing)
(grenade exploding)
- Okay, gentlemen,
you've just witness the raid
on General Ortega's secret drug camp
in Sumander South America.
The raiding party consisting
of all four branches of the armed forces,
code name NAMA.
The raiding party completely
destroyed the camp,
which produces enormous quantities
of elicit drugs on the world market.
Now all the members of
the special forces team
have either been killed or wounded
by what we suspect is
General Oretga's hit men
in retaliation to the raid.
Gentlemen, the killings must be stopped.
- What about the surviving members,
have they been forewarned?
- No, not yet.
That's why I brought you two together,
to help develop a special plan
to safeguard them and their families.
- And how about their team leaders?
- Mark Mitchell, code name Cobra,
and Ray Davis, code name Black Mamba.
Gentlemen, you must do everything you can
to protect them.
After all, the American government
owes them this much.
- We'll do everything we can, sir.
- Yeah, we'll even give them
round the clock protection
if you want us to, Chief Brent.
- Good luck.
(suspenseful instrumental music)
(gun firing)
- Leaving so soon?
(screaming)
- [Woman] Let me go!
Let me go!
(gun firing)
- Out sucker, out!
Come here.
You see that?
(suspenseful instrumental music)
- [Man] No, no.
(gun firing)
(sobbing)
- You're a lousy lay, you slut.
(gun firing)
(guns firing)
- What's the matter,
cop, you trying chicken?
(laughing)
Come on.
- You have the right to remain silent.
(loud exploding)
- Pure grade.
- Come on.
Where's my money?
- It's all here.
(funky instrumental music)
- [Man] There's the police!
They've got you surrounded!
- I shouldn't have come here,
I thought we were safe.
Dumb shit.
- Let's go, let's go.
(funky suspenseful music)
- Freeze, you maggots!
(guns firing)
- Come on!
(gun firing)
- You can't outrun old Smithy.
Now drop it.
Against the wall.
Come on, you too.
Come on, punk.
Against the wall, against that wall.
So you're the big fish.
Come on.
(suspenseful music)
- Freeze!
Who are you guys?
And what the hell are you doing here?
- No wonder they call you Cobra,
you're really fast.
I'm agent Wagner and these are my men.
Now you take it easy on that gun,
I'll bring out my credentials
and explain everything.
- Watch it.
- It's okay.
- So you're with the big boys.
- Sorry to barge into your apartment but,
we wanted to make sure that no one is here
waiting for you in ambush.
- Ambush?
I know I'm not very popular
in this neighborhood but,
what the hell's going on?
- Most of your men have been killed
involved in a raid on General Ortega,
that's why we're here.
To warn you and to protect you.
- But that raid on Ortega happened
a long time ago.
- We've also sent a team
to look after your wife and your sister.
- Well I guess that's just
the hazards of the trade.
What do you say?
- So I hope you don't mind me and my men
staying here close to you,
wherever you go, whatever you do.
(guns firing)
(gun firing)
- Catherine.
- Don't worry Mrs. Mitchell,
your husband is safe.
I assure you, right now,
a whole contingent of our best agents
are watching over him.
Nothing can happen to him
while we're on the job.
- I have total confidence
in my brother, Mr. Phillips,
with or without your help.
Mark can take care of himself.
- Cobra has an outstanding record.
Our boss, Chief Brent
wouldn't give him this special concern.
Our agency values people
who serve their country well.
- I'll go check the kitchen out.
Catherine, Mr. Phillips, excuse me.
- You know, I don't like what's going on.
I wish Mark would quit.
- It's okay, honey,
they know what they're doing,
don't worry about it.
Breakfast ready yet?
- I'll go check.
(eerie instrumental music)
(scuffling)
(gun firing)
(suspenseful instrumental music)
- Take cover.
(gun firing)
(screams)
- [Man] Where's Mark's sister?
- [Man] Not around.
- Well spread out and find her.
Let's go.
- Catherine!
Carol!
No, Catherine!
No, Catherine, please.
Don't be dead, Catherine.
No, Catherine.
No.
Oh Catherine, please.
Why, why!
(energetic suspenseful music)
- Hey!
- Hey, Ray!
(scuffling)
- You got three seconds to talk, talk!
- Hey man, hey quit it man.
We're in the same league.
We only came to fetch you for Chief Brent.
- Now I wanna see some IDs.
Now slowly, babe.
Slowly, nice and easy.
That's it.
CIA, Jesus, you dumb shit!
You almost bought it, shit.
You guys should know better
to follow a cop.
Sorry about that.
- Okay Ray, I'll get to the point.
We've asked you here
because we need your help.
Your friend Mark, code name Cobra
has been kidnapped.
- Kidnapped?
You must be mistaken,
no one can kidnap Cobra.
He's mean and he's bad.
- I wish I was mistaken Ray,
but they've got him
and we need you to help rescue him.
- Sure I'll do it.
Who's responsible?
- General Ortega.
- Shit!
That son of a bitch never learned.
When do I leave, sir?
- We've prepared some forged documents
to help you get in the country.
Your flight leaves tonight
and Ray, I'd appreciate it
if you keep me posted on
what's going on there.
- Consider it done.
Sure.
(eerie suspenseful music)
(bomb exploding)
(dramatic suspenseful music)
(gun firing)
(guns firing)
(grenade exploding)
(gun firing)
(airplane whooshing)
(gentle upbeat music)
- Driver, take me Sumander Military Camp.
- [Driver] Si, senor.
- Quite impressive, sergeant.
We need instructors like you in our camp.
Take Sergeant Davis to his quarters.
Welcome to our camp, sergeant.
Hope you'll enjoy it here.
- I'm sure I'll do, sir.
- This man will show you to your quarters.
- Thank you.
- I can't understand
why we have to hire a mercenary, sir.
- They'd do anything for money,
even kill their own mother.
They're practically your slaves
ready to do your bidding.
- Here's your breakfast, senorita.
- Thank you.
(gentle instrumental music)
Want some?
(dramatic suspenseful music)
- And where do you think you're going?
- Ah, Bermudez, come in please.
Come in.
You don't know how happy I am
at the exemplary execution of your duties.
This is why I invited you here,
to personally thank you
for a job well done.
- It is nothing, me general.
- They should know better
than to tangle with General Muriel Ortega.
Now it is too late for them!
Commandant, I want you to squeeze Cobra
until he's dry.
Drain every last drop of his blood.
I want him to suffer excruciating pain.
And when you're finished
feed his bones to the dog.
Only then will he be able to compensate
for the humiliation
that I have suffered at his hands.
You don't know how terrible it is
to lose face by a drug clan.
I boasted of guaranteed protection
for the drugs sent here to our laboratory
for refinement.
And what happens?
They're blown away like that.
I become the laughing stock of the world
because of what they did.
It's terrible.
Commandante, the
humiliation, it's terrible.
- He will suffer, me General,
I promise you.
(speaking in foreign language)
But before you go, I want
you to see something.
(speaking in foreign language)
(foreboding instrumental music)
Commandante, I would like
to present Senorita Carol,
the sister of Cobra.
She is my guest.
An insurance you might say
against any rescue attempt on Cobra.
- I see.
And when I have accomplished everything?
- She will be yours.
(speaking in foreign language)
(foreboding instrumental music)
- [Guard] Stand up!
- [Guard] Get up.
(laughing)
- Harder harder!
- Hut two three four,
hut two three four.
Hut two three four.
- Come on.
Come on.
- Hut two three four.
Hut two three four.
- I said move it!
- [Commandante] And this
is where we keep assholes
that fight against our government.
- [Ray] It seems that most of the cells
are empty, Commandante.
- [Commandante] So you've noticed that.
It's always like that, sergeant.
They usually don't stay
in their cells too long.
After a day or two of torture,
they're executed at once.
It helps to reduce the
maintenance cost that way,
you know.
(foreboding instrumental music)
- Commandante.
When's the big day for this one?
- The general wants to prolong his stay
here for a while.
He says he wants more special
treatment for his crimes.
You can expect to see him here
for a long time yet.
- Commandante, I have just received
confidential information.
That the captured drug shipment
will be escorted out of Guatemala tomorrow
by government troops.
I want you to grab that
shipment, do you understand?
- Si, general.
I will prepare the men immediately.
The drug shipment that was captured
will be taken out of Guatemala tomorrow.
We will cross the border tonight
and wait in ambush for the convoy.
Assemble the men, we move out at once.
(speaking in foreign language)
(suspenseful instrumental music)
- Hold it!
What are you doing here?
This is a restricted area!
- [Ray] I was just checking the roof.
(scuffling and grunting)
- Hey!
(gun firing)
(suspenseful instrumental music)
- [Soldier] Let's go.
- I see him!
Down there!
Shit, go over there.
(guns firing)
(foreboding suspenseful music)
(upbeat piano music)
(phone ringing)
- Colonel Bermudez.
(speaking in foreign language)
- How can you know
when you've not informed
me of your hiring!
You know how particular I am
when it comes to personnel
and sensitive positions.
They can ruin us!
Shut up and listen to me.
You find that black sergeant
and bring him to me.
I will make him talk personally.
Do you understand?
- Si, general.
- I want Cobra terminated immediately.
Before that black sergeant can get to him.
Do I make myself clear?
- Si, general, si.
- Now go!
- Si, general.
Rodriguez.
- Sir!
- Sound the alarm.
That black sergeant is an imposter.
Get him.
- With pleasure.
- I will attend to the
execution of Cobra personally.
(foreboding instrumental music)
(laughing)
(shouting)
(suspenseful instrumental music)
- This guard duty really stinks, you know.
- Yeah, you're right.
- Hey guys, got a light?
- [Guard] Sure.
- Is that a motor pull over there?
(scuffling and grunting)
- Run!
- Thanks buddy.
(speaking in foreign language)
(foreboding instrumental music)
- Hold it, senor.
This is a restricted area.
- Something's wrong with my pistol, see?
(dramatic music)
- [Guard] Hold it right there!
Get up.
(scuffling and grunting)
- [Guard] Drop it.
- Mark, get down!
(gun firing)
(guns firing)
When I heard accommodation was bad,
I decided to pay you a visit.
- You're a little late, pal.
I already checked out, let's go.
- Okay, I got a truck waiting outside
so let's get the fuck out of here.
- What's happening here?
- Sir, the prisoner has escaped!
(speaking in foreign language)
- Search the grounds!
After them, pronto!
(guns firing)
Cut them off at the perimeter wall.
(suspenseful instrumental music)
- [Ray] Hey Mark, I
got it all set up here.
We're going down here.
- You really
took care of everything.
- [Ray] Okay go ahead, I'll cover you.
(guns firing)
You okay?
Come on, let's go.
(gun firing)
And I got something for you, partner.
Here.
I got the rest in the back of this truck.
Let's go!
Let's move it come on.
(speaking in foreign language)
- Leave us alone.
I've got news for you.
Your brother has just escaped.
But not for long.
He will be recaptured
because my dear, you will be the bait.
Unless you want to make me happy.
Then you and your brother
will go free, promise.
You will both crawl like
snakes under my feet,
I promise you that on my parents' grave!
- [Man] Stop, stop!
Stop!
Oh please, you gotta help us!
- Mark, we gotta go now!
- Please help us!
- We ain't got time!
- Hold it.
Get in the truck.
- Oh thank you.
- What?
- Come on let's go.
- This is the second time
you failed, Commandante.
However I'll give you one more chance.
If you fail to catch them
it's the end of your
career, do you understand?
- How could you let
them slip through hands?
Now I have to answer
for your incompetence.
- We'll soon get them, sir.
We've got the choppers.
- Well you better, for your sake.
Now call airbase.
- Si, Commandante.
- Look, up there, chopper!
(suspenseful instrumental music)
- Damn.
- We got to find cover!
(rockets firing)
- Get out of the truck.
Come on.
Move it.
- Go ahead.
(rockets firing)
I say.
Guatemala's two or three
days away from here.
Now, if you keep on the right direction
we can make it on time.
- I'm sorry, Ray.
You just have to go on without me.
- What?
- I've still got some
unfinished business later on.
- Business shit!
Business?
This is fucking suicide.
Ortega's gonna eat you
alive when you get there!
- That son of a bitch killed my family!
- Okay.
I'm gonna make a deal with you,
when we get to guatemala--
- No deal!
- What do you wanna do,
take a whole fucking army?
- Hold it.
I've got to finish my
fucking business with Ortega.
Only then I can find peace.
- You son of a bitch.
You crazy son of a bitch!
- That's quite alright.
I've already made up my mind.
- Listen, if you think
you can make it out there,
I doubt it, go ahead,
go ahead and get stuck.
Don't expect me to bail you out again,
because I'm not!
And believe me, I'm not gonna.
(speaking in foreign language)
- You did something right.
Finally.
Are you sure they were both in the truck
when the chopper blasted them?
(gentle suspenseful music)
Very good, Commandante, very good.
I'm once again overjoyed
to have you in my command.
I'm sorry for misjudging you.
Goodnight, Commandante.
Looks like I won't have
to use you anymore.
Your brother's dead.
You better believe it.
Dead.
(suspenseful music)
- Say your prayers, Ortega.
- No.
It's you who will say your prayers,
or you both will die.
Now drop your gun.
(speaking in foreign language)
What a wonderful reunion.
Soon the two you will be reunited
in death.
- You know that kind of talk's
bad for your health?
And this is for all the
trouble you've been giving.
- Well done, Ray.
Alright?
Get down!
(gun firing)
- Come on Mark, this way.
Come on, let's move it.
- Come on, we're going home.
Carol, everything's okay.
Right?
Thank you, Ray.
- Hey.
So let's get out of this hellhole
and head on back for the border.
- No, no Ray I can't.
I won't be able to live
with myself if I run away.
You go and take Carol with you.
- Man, you're really
something else, you know.
Okay, promise me one thing though,
you take care of yourself, okay?
- Sure.
I promise.
- Take it easy, I'll
take good care of her.
- How dare you give me false information.
Can the dead do this?
- Look me general, the pilot reported--
- Enough.
I don't want to hear
anymore of your excuses.
I want you to find them.
Even if you have to cross
the border, I don't care.
Bring them back.
I've never seen such incompetence
in my entire career.
You two are the worst.
- [Soldier] Pardon, me general.
Don Cordoco wishes to request
an audience with you.
- Tell him I'll see
him in the living room.
- [Soldier] Si, me general.
- As for you two,
don't come back without them.
Now go.
- Si, general.
- Hello, Ray here.
No he ain't here.
Let me explain.
Now he refused to come here
not unless he settles
his score with Ortega.
That's what I'm trying to tell you,
he's doing a little Rambo back there.
Okay.
You copy?
Okay, we'll do that.
Okay bye.
Listen.
- What'd he say?
- We gotta meet this guy
in Magumbo Hotel right over the corner.
And we got a little over
10 minutes to make it.
- 10 minutes?
- Yeah.
- Let's go.
Mark and I grew up separately.
You know, parents divorced, one kid each.
But I've always had a
brother when I needed one.
- Yeah.
He's always talked about having a sister
who's a smart ass.
You know what,
you're lucky to have a brother like Mark.
(door knocking)
Bathroom.
Who's there?
- [Man] Chief Brent sent us.
- Say what?
- It's about time.
- Freeze.
Where's the girl?
- You mean my wife?
- Where's Carol?
- Oh, Carol.
Honey, the milkman is here.
- [Carol] Okay, send him in.
- Go get her, she's in the shower.
- Hey come on, guys.
- Shut up!
(glass breaking)
(grunting)
(gun firing)
- [Ray] It's me.
Let's go, come on.
(suspenseful instrumental music)
Holy shit, watch out!
(guns firing)
Go, fire escape.
Go on.
(gun firing)
- What now?
- [Ray] Well.
We're going down.
(suspenseful music)
- Where's Ortega?
- In his palace.
- No he's not.
Tell me or I'll break your neck.
- I don't know.
- Where is he?
For the last time
Rodriguez, where's Ortega?
- Yankee, even if I know
I wouldn't tell you.
You're wasting your time.
- Fair enough.
- Hey!
What're you doing?
No, you crazy Yankee.
No!
- If you know what's good for you,
where's Ortega?
- Alright.
Alright.
He's at the rancho.
A few kilometers from here.
- Good boy.
- Hey!
Where are you going?
Don't leave me here!
Hey,
hey!
You could get robbed!
- We now have a decision
on your request Mr. Davis.
We are willing to look after your friend's
daughter while you're here in Guatemala.
- I'm most grateful father.
I know that this is the only place
that she will be in safe hands.
Carol, baby, please don't
ever ever leave this place.
Wolves in sheep's clothing
abound in the city.
If you know what I mean.
- Surely, you watch out
for those wolves, too.
- Well Father, thank you very much, sir.
Please take good care of her.
Bye, my dear.
You will be okay.
- Please come right this way, my child.
- Okay.
- I don't know how they
got wind of this hotel.
Now how sure are you that there's
no leakage in your organization?
We almost got our ass
racked down here, man.
Say what?
Okay okay okay.
I'll be careful.
Where?
What time?
Okay, we'll be there.
We'll meet you.
Okay, bye.
Fuck.
(foreboding suspenseful music)
(train whistling and chugging)
(suspenseful instrumental music)
(guns firing)
(gun firing)
(dramatic suspenseful music)
(guns firing)
(bomb exploding)
(bombs exploding)
(guns firing)
- After him!
Bermudez, with me.
(guns firing)
(bombs exploding)
(grenade exploding)
(gun firing)
(suspenseful instrumental music)
(guns firing)
(gun firing)
- I think I got him.
- Make sure he's dead.
(dramatic suspenseful music)
(guns firing)
(suspenseful instrumental music)
(gun firing)
(somber dramatic music)
- Oh, Mark, Ray.
Come on, have a seat.
What's the meaning of this?
(soft dramatic music)
- You betrayed us.
You sold your soul, for what?
For money?
- Look, you don't understand,
they forced me to do it,
there was nothing I could do, believe me.
- God.
- Look at this way, they threatened
to show it to my family, you know.
I can't let that happen.
- It ain't no reason to murder people.
So we'll start with murder
one, how's about that?
Hey partner?
- Look, I'm sorry.
I'll make it up to you, I promise.
What do you want, money?
One million?
Five million?
I've got it, all you've
got to do is take it
and don't tell anyone about my weakness.
They'll never forgive me.
- You know what,
I've been waiting for
this for a long long time.
Take him.
Five million dollars.
That's 30 years of work.
Just kidding, come on let's have a beer.
Come on.
- Father.
How are you?
Now I'd like you to
meet Mr. Mark Mitchell.
- [Mark] How are you, Father?
- Be seated.
- Thank you.
- I'll fetch her.
- What's taking her so long?
- Just relax, you know how women are.
They love this powder and that shit.
- Mark?
- Carol.
Are you okay?
- Yeah.
Thanks to everyone.
- [Mark] I'm so happy to see you.
Thank you, Father.
(upbeat dramatic music)