TOHO and TBS present
A Toho Pictures Inc. Production
Executive Producers: TORU
SHIBATA, TOSHIKAKI HARADA
Screenplay: KOTA YAMADA,
MASAHIRO YOKOTANI, SHUSUKE KANEKO
Music by KOW OTANI, Theme Song
"The One Thing" by Every Little Thing
Are you alone?
l"ve got no friends, either.
Play by yourself, okay?
Who are you?
Original Story by MIYUKI MIYAKE
Yes?
What?
A boy was killed?
Directed by SHUSUKE KANEKO
You must not get angry.
You must not hate.
Please try not to cry, either.
Okay?
You"re not like other kids.
Don"t go near your friends...
...or something horrible might happen.
Aren"t I a human being?
Of course you are, Junko!
You"re a lovely little girl!
Fishing fires that
glimmer off the coast...
...aren"t only for attracting the fish.
In those ancient times, our ancestors...
...secretly rowed out alone at night...
...to release hatred that
accumulated in their bodies.
It became a legend,
the legend of the Sea Fire.
My late mother used
to warn me all the time...
Wrath can grow in your heart like a fire.
Once the flame of wrath
starts to burn, you can"t stop it.
It will burn until it
consumes you as well.
PYROKINESIS
AKIKO YADA
HIDEKI ITO
RYUJI HARADA
MASAMI NAGASAWA
YU YOSHIZAWA, HIDENORI TOKUG YAMA
TOSHIYUKI NAGASHIMA
KAORI MOMOI
Company Dorm Party
You are coming, right?
It"s Sunday, right?
Are you going?
Hunting boys?
If I get married to a dorm boy,
l"II end up living there forever...
l"II pass!
Come on, don"t be so mean.
Please come!
Why don"t you invite her?
She"s too morbid.
She"d ruin the party.
I really don"t like her.
Me neither.
There"s something strange about her.
You must have been terrified.
l"m sorry l"m late.
Was she raped?
No, it"s just like the last case.
What the...
Are you okay?
Thank you.
That damn Trucker!
Everybody is in a rush
on a rainy day like this.
Miss Junko Aoki from
General Affairs, right?
Yes.
Um, l"m...
Mr. Tada from Sales.
Oh, you know me?
Right, that"s your job.
You returned here to the
head office last month, l"ve heard.
Yes.
Now l"ve been assigned as a new
member of the dorm party committee.
Will you...
Hey, look!
Are you okay?
It"s drying because of my body heat.
You mean you have a fever?
Have you caught a cold?
You shouldn"t go out
in this kind of weather.
l"m okay.
I get it...
How could any human
have such a high fever!
The former victim was alive when
she was left beside the Arakawa river.
This one was already
dead when she was left there.
Is it the same killer?
Obviously, both of
them were hit by a car.
Yes, then they were carried
away to cover up the hit & run.
I believe the weapon was a car.
They were bruised
and lacerated all over.
Get me ketchup.
The killer played a
cat and mouse game.
There you go, madam.
Thanks.
He enjoyed it.
He"s a devil.
It"s delicious!
Ms. Ishizu, how can you eat
while thinking about things like this?
Righteous fury makes me hungry.
Toho Pulp Dormitory
You came!
Looks good.
It tastes great.
Try some.
Hey, is she your girlfriend?
No, not yet.
Not yet.
You want herto be someday?
This is Yukie, my sister.
Hello.
You"re my type!
You"re totally my type.
Idiot!
You cook at home?
Well, I live alone, so...
I envy you, I wish I could live alone.
Not you.
Why not?
You"re still a kid.
That"s what you
want to believe, brother!
l"II be all right.
Everyone is nice, right?
He"s talking about business stuff.
My brother is boring, don"t you think?
I don"t think so, he"s a very nice guy.
Just "nice" huh?
No good as a boyfriend.
You are tough.
He"s square, and
he"s totally old fashioned.
Sorry, I didn"t mean
to ask you to babysit.
No, l"m enjoying her company.
It"s like she"s my little sister.
He came to tell me to go home.
Our neighborhood
hasn"t been safe lately.
I am going to the same
direction, l"II take her home.
That means I get to
stay here a bit longer.
Hey, Ms. Aoki has to go to
work tomorrow, you know!
Thanks for coming.
It was fun.
Yukie"s cute.
We used to quarrel every day.
Really?
Enough about her...
How about a date?
Sure.
Actually,
l"m thinking of studying abroad.
Where?
England, l"II study theatre.
I want to be able to
read Shakespeare in the original.
Your brother will be worried.
Hey, can you speak English?
"That is the question."
Yeah, "that is the question."
I once wished to die
in the water, like Ophelia.
Yuck!
Not anymore, right?
No, no more.
Can I call you "Sis?"
l"ve always wanted a sister.
My brother is too much older.
Make sure to take a cab.
It"s not far, l"II walk.
l"II come with you, then.
I promised Mr. Tada.
My brother would kill me if he
found out you walked me home.
You could be in
danger on the way back.
How considerate!
I try.
Bye!
Okay!
It"s just a party.
Let"s have some fun tonight.
No!
It can"t be true!
Yukie!
Yukie...
Why...
A boy from the Toruen gang called us.
A tip?
We are in luck.
Could I interview you for a minute?
l"ve heard the killers are juveniles.
The police have an idea who they are.
l"ve heard they"re
bragging they aren"t afraid of cops.
Even if caught, they won"t be
severely punished because they are minors.
But how could they
get away with such a crime?
That"s the law in this country.
Hey, don"t you think it"s
getting hot in here all of sudden?
I think so, too.
l"II kill them.
I'll kill them.
Teramachi Police Station
Mr. Kogure, your
son is the key suspect.
How do you feel about that?
As an ex-district
attorney and commentator...
...what do you think about this case?
My son did nothing wrong.
It was just a party.
Masaki Kogure, Age 18,
unemployed, is this correct?
Who are you?
Have we met?
Where is your card?
Here, l"m Ishizu.
You"re a talkative one.
You can"t stop bragging
about your crime, huh?
What happened to
the lawyer my dad hired?
He can"t be here.
It"s a little unlike American movies.
That"s lame!
That"s so lame!
Be honest with us...
...and you"II get off light.
You know that, right?
I feel sorry for how you live,
at your age with a cheap cop salary.
Look, you"re an old
maid, got no lover, right?
l"m married.
You used violence!
You saw it too, right?
l"m here to accuse the department of
conducting a rough police investigation...
...and to prove my son"s
innocence in these cases of murder.
With no evidence against my son,
the police alleged him as culpable.
They used violence
to force him to "confess."
This is inexcusable!
I bet he did it.
Look at his face!
Even though his father is famous...
We made up our mind to come out
in the public and appeal to the world...
...in orderto disclose the
oppressive conduct of the cops.
Lately, it is said that cases of juvenile
delinquency are increasing, however...
Guilty, or not guilty?
The boy killed the girls?
Police squeeze confession.
Suspicious enough.
But not enough evidence.
The boy is protected.
Investigation at deadlock.
I am not the killer.
The Cops use violence
and forced me to confess.
He suggests that he did it on purpose.
I bet he expose his
defect in court, easily!
But the prosecutors were
positive that we couldn"t win.
No evidence, and his lawyer"s shrewd.
Wait, don"t jump to conclusions.
Kogure is saying you
used violence against him.
He"s going to sue us.
I barely touched the kid!
Calm down.
Anyway, continue the investigation.
We are dropping the case at this
point, but we are happy to cooperate.
Good...
It"s nice having someone who
appreciates you at the head office.
I wish I had someone
appreciate me in my office.
Excuse us.
Mr. Masaki Kogure just finished the
live interview and is about to come out.
Let"s ask him what"s
really going on in there.
Mr. Kogure, a few words, please!
I am not saying that l"m not a bad boy...
...but I could never be a murderer.
Let"s pray forthe souls of the dead.
You"re not guilty?
Of course not.
Is it true the cops were rough?
Yes.
How do you feel about
being treated like a celebrity?
You shouldn"t turn into a killer.
What happened?
Did you do that, Ms. Aoki?
No, of course not.
l"m going crazy.
Your killing him will ruin your life.
Yukie won"t be happy about it, right?
It wouldn"t bring her back, I know.
But I must do something,
otherwise, they"Iljust live on...
...while Yukie is dead.
It"s so unfair.
I won"t forgive them!
I won"t!
l"II punish them...
...for you, Mr. Tada.
What?
I can, without leaving any evidence.
l"ve hated this
power since my childhood.
But if I can be of help to you, using it...
Wait a minute.
Use it?
What are you saying?
How can I believe such a thing?
This is a no parking area.
Why not punish him?
Hey, hey, hey...
What the hell is this?
What?
Hey, put out the fire!
That car"s burning!
Stop!
Hey, someone put out the fire now!
Ms. Aoki.
That"s enough, stop it!
Stop, Junko!
Do you believe me now?
What is it?
Is it Kogure related?
No, not at all.
We have no clue how the fire started...
Right, you used to
be in charge of arson.
That"s why I asked to look at this case.
Now is not the time forthat.
Kaori Kurata was here all day that day.
She didn"t go out at all.
I see.
Sorry to bother you again.
It"s him.
Kogure!
Are you gonna do it now? Here?
I believe he did it.
I want to kill him...
...but l"m not one hundred percent sure.
I am still hesitating.
I spoke with him
What?
I told him I was a reporter forthe
weekly magazine and interviewed him.
I also wanted conclusive evidence.
But he managed to elude my
queries, avoiding direct answers...
Telling lies tires me.
To tell you the truth, I did it.
Murdering is my hobby.
Is it okay...
...to tell me this?
The cops dropped the case against me.
The prosecutor is not doing anything.
l"m untouchable.
l"m the lion now.
Sure.
Let me take some pictures.
Damn him!
He"s not human.
What"s going on?
Help!
Somebody help!
Please help!
Help!
Hey you, are you okay?
No!
Get away!
It"s too hot, too hot!
Stop it!
Why?
I can"t stop it.
Take me where I can get some water.
Fire!
Come here!
Put out the fire!
Look, there"s a fire!
Get some water, quickly.
Come on!
I couldn"t stand watching it any longer.
I know.
l"m so weak.
If only l"d sent her home...
If only they attacked me instead...
I keep thinking about that.
I thought I heard Yukie"s voice...
Telling us to stop.
It has your sister"s name on it.
It"s a souvenir from her
Junior High school trip to Kyoto.
She wanted something...
...not a typical souvenir.
l"m scary, right?
I don"t think so.
That"s all right if you think so.
l"m afraid of myself.
Honestly, I was afraid.
I was afraid you were
going to collapse in the car.
You had a vacant look...
Like you were a different person.
What we were trying to do was wrong.
If we stoop to that level, we"re
no betterthan the rats who killed Yukie.
Let"s stop it now.
You told me your secret for my sister.
You tried to avenge her.
That"s all I need.
That"s enough.
Or did you...
...just want to try out
using your special power?
Are you in some
kind of trouble with Junko?
No, not particularly.
Then why are the cops here?
What?
She quit yesterday.
Did she come by?
No, just a phone call.
The girl has no sense of responsibility.
l"m sorry to bother
you, I know you are busy.
My condolences on your sister"s death.
Did you know that Masaki Kogure
suddenly began to burn in Chuo park?
No.
The same day, a car sped to
a gas station, smoke pouring out.
The driver didn"t want
to report it to the police.
But an attendant
memorized the license plate number.
Take a look.
As I drove, smoke
suddenly began coming from the car.
It"s an old car.
You were with a girl, right?
Yes, a friend of mine.
All right.
Kogure had an interview the day before.
He went to the park
to take some photos for it.
Wasn"t the interviewer your friend?
Are you saying that
I burned Kogure out of hatred?
I didn"t mean that.
I still wish I could kill him.
If only the police did their job...
Was Junko Aoki your friend?
No.
On December 14, you took
herto a restaurant in Aoyama.
I don"t remember.
Where did Ms. Aoki move to?
l"m looking for her, too
If you find her, please let me know.
You were right, Mother.
Pyrokinesis?
It refers to a type of psychokinesis
that can set things on fire.
You mean that"s what
burned Kogure and the car?
There was no
gasoline cans or oily rags...
There was also no
trace of flammable gas.
No possibility of
spontaneous combustion at the scene.
How can a fire start
without means of ignition?
It"s pyrokinesis, what else could it be?
Don"t give me that crazy
look, it reminds me of my dog.
Hello, is this Junko Aoki?
Who"s this?
I saw what happened in the Chuo Park.
You"re great...
A bit scary, though.
You are the world"s strongest girl.
l"II ask again.
Who"s this?
This is 19th Century Canada...
...a 14 year old girl
named Jenny Bramwell.
The things she pointed at burned.
So she was called a
witch and driven from her village.
This was just 14 years ago.
A 13 year-old boy
named Sahsa in the Ukraine.
Furniture and
clothes around him burned.
He was suspected to be a pyromaniac
and hospitalized, but the fires continued.
The Soviet Medical
Academy called him an ESPer.
The newspapers said so.
There were many
cases of pyrokinesis reported.
Pyrokinesis is a powerthat agitates
molecules to produce intense heat.
Just like a microwave oven.
That must be convenient in the kitchen.
Hi, young lady, do you have a minute?
Can you help me with a survey?
A date, right?
Then keep me company
until your boyfriend comes...
We"re distributing free makeup
samples at the building overthere.
Give it a rest, man!
Was I talking to you, huh?
Hey, nice left!
Waiting long?
Pleased to meet you.
l"m Koichi Kido.
What was that?
I gave him an
impulse through my touch...
...and it was sent
directly to his brain as an order.
If I touched Julia Roberts,
I could make her do a striptease.
How did you know me?
I wanted to touch
Kogure so he"d kill himself.
So I went to Chuo park.
Are you putting a
heat barrier around you?
Don"t try to touch me if
you don"t want to be burned.
I wouldn"t try that, we"re ESPer friends.
l"m opening my heart to you...
Who was with you in the car?
A boyfriend?
None of your business!
An ordinary man
can"t last as your boyfriend.
You shouldn"t date normal guys.
We are the chosen ones.
Like Jesus Christ and Mohammed.
What you were trying to do was right.
Somebody must punish
those teenage monsters.
Isn"t that what you think?
They"re a cancer on humanity.
As ESPers, it"s our job
to rid the world of them.
A little autistic, but her IQ is
normal, and she"s well behaved.
She"s old enough
to leave this home, but...
There have been some incidents
of combustion, so you"re worried.
Hello!
Do you believe she has...
...that special talent?
Kaori Kurata...
Her parents died
soon after she was born...
...and she had no relatives,
so we took custody of her.
Strange things have
happened since she came here.
Like what?
One night, when she was still a baby...
I saw a fireball
hovering above her like this.
What can I say...
It looked as though
she was playing with it.
Kaori was smiling at it.
Let"s get rid of them.
If you and I team up, we"II be invincible.
I touched one of them
and made him confessed.
They"II do it again tonight...
...at a deserted factory
not far from your apartment.
Another innocent girl will fall prey.
Why not stop them yourself?
With your power, you don"t need me.
I want you to do it.
We want to rope you in.
Punishment is what you are after, huh?
This is what they"ve done.
You"II see.
Junko Aoki.
You know her?
I told her nothing.
She feels what you
feel by touching you.
You know what l"m thinking?
Is that what you thought?
What are you
waiting for, put out the fire!
Hurry!
Yes!
You didn"t think it was a trick, did you?
I remember, you were good at
card tricks at the new year"s party.
lfJunko has the same kind of power...
Then everything would make sense.
l"m sure she was nearthe
Mercedes when it burst into flame.
She is extremely
dangerous if we let her run loose.
Let me go!
Please, spare me!
What?
I can"t hear you.
Don"t kill me!
Sorry.
The death scene is what sells.
I want to make good
money forthis video.
Cry and writhe a bit before you die.
What the hell?
Get up!
It"s a chick.
She"s not bad looking!
Bitch!
It"s that girl!
Are you okay?
You were watching?
Don"t burn me!
It"s you.
T-They kidnapped
Natsuko and brought her here.
Who"s she?
My assistant.
We were working on getting the
scoop on Kogure and the others.
l"II go save her.
You saw nothing, okay?
Haseyama Street,
third building from the corner.
The Plaza Bar...
Let"s chase him by my car.
But before that,
l"II erase this guy"s memory.
Don"t waste yourtime, let"s go!
He"s a reporter.
He"II talk.
I won"t, I promise!
Forget it and hurry!
Should we tell the police?
It"s too late.
l"II go.
Sorry, I didn"t expect a gun.
That aside, you were amazing.
Shut up and drive!
We have to save her!
Here we are.
I see, this is where
they made their copies.
You"re not to blame.
It was my fault.
What"s the matter?
Help!
Mother!
Hey, are you okay?
Hey!
Forensics couldn"t
identify any combustible agents.
Even the organs and
bones were burned down to ashes...
...with intense heart in
a short amount of time.
The boys were members of a
gang suspect in serial murder cases.
It might be the result of internal discord
or maybe personal revenge forthe victims.
Natsuko Mita,
the victim, was a reporter.
Toshimitsu Asaba was her boss.
It seems she was covering Kogure
and the others, but ended up falling prey.
Asaba didn"t witness the murder, but
stated that a strange woman saved him.
I believe he is
covering up forthis woman.
Can you be sure that
the woman was Junko Aoki?
An anonymous photo that was
taken by a passer-by was sent in.
A woman resembles
Junko was seen nearthe factory.
That was Junko Aoki, I am sure.
The motive is to avenge Yukie Tada.
The weapon is pyrokinesis.
What"s wrong?
Makihara...
You sound excited.
Any grudge against her?
No.
I wouldn"t let my personal feelings
get in the way of an investigation.
A strange woman
spotted at the scene.
What is it?
Tell me.
I had a brother-in-law.
He was a problem child.
He used to kill dogs and cats.
Now, I don"t know exactly what
he was trying to do to this girl, but...
That day, I saw it from far away...
I was on my way home...
Suddenly my brother was aflame.
I ran to him.
Have you ever built a bonfire?
Of course, everyone used to.
At certain point, piled
firewood starts to collapse, right?
Just like that...
My brother"s bones
burned and disjointed...
...and fell like a puppet.
He was crying for help!
I couldn"t do anything.
And what happened to the girl?
"l"m sorry, I burned him," she said.
Was she Junko Aoki?
She told me her name.
But it was such a strange
story, I couldn"t tell it to anyone.
If I did, l"d be suspected...
...because I didn"t get
along with my brother.
Soon after, the girl moved away.
The police couldn"t find any suspects.
Afterthat, my family was scattered.
Before my mother died, she asked me...
"Did you become a cop
to atone for what you did?"
I told her she was wrong.
"I didn"t do what you think I did", I said.
She asked no more questions.
That girl grew up to
be a vicious murderer.
You slept for 40 hours.
Where am I?
My place.
I didn"t see what I wanted to see.
I closed my eyes.
I didn"t touch you either.
Please, believe me.
I could nevertouch a girl I actually liked.
If I did, it wouldn"t be fair.
l"m such a poor guy, right?
You spent too much energy last time.
It could kill you.
Us ESPers don"t have long lives.
Kogure is dead?
No, that was another boy.
That"s right, it wasn"t Kogure!
Wasn"t he there?
Did you look?
The guy had a gun,
I had to take you away.
You know I can"t use fire.
I haven"t thanked you
for saving me, have I?
Forget it.
It was my fault.
Thank you.
What is it, young girl?
I went to your apartment,
but the police were watching it.
My clothes?
You should rest longer.
I must find Kogure...
I must...
Your clothes were
torn and had blood all over.
Some are your usual
style, others are different.
I don"t need this many.
Just wear what you like.
I really don"t want to thank you again.
You don"t have to.
Thank you.
Forget it.
So you want to finish Kogure, right?
She used to come here alone.
Her favorite table is overthere.
l"m sorry, but I don"t remember.
Have you found Ms. Junko Aoki?
She has...
...nothing to do with this.
Can"t she burn
things with psychokinesis?
What are you talking about?
Let me ask you, did you
see the car burn here, too?
Are you sure Kogure
is the one who died?
The remains were carbonized.
We are testing the DNA now,
but we"re pretty sure it was him.
The cops forgave him, but God did not.
Look, it"s not like we forgave him.
But we can"t just lynch him, right?
Would God permit that?
Mr. Asaba.
I didn"t say anything.
I know.
l"m sorry I couldn"t save Ms. Natsuko.
Who the hell are you?
What were you doing there?
Somebody told me...
Was it the Guardians?
What?
Are you a member, too?
What are you talking about?
Stop, stop, no!
Don't kill me!
That"s...
This belongs to Natsuko.
What"s on the tape?
Nothing.
Anyway, what are the Guardians?
You didn"t come to kill me?
No way.
Why do you say that?
Do you know where Kogure is?
What?
He"s dead, isn"t he?
He"s alive.
The body was another boy.
What did Ms. Natsuko know?
Who knows, she"s dead!
Something inconvenient to you?
I kept secret about
you, now leave me alone.
Were you involved in
making the videotapes?
I don"t know, I told you!
Help!
She"s a stalker!
Monster!
Ms. Junko Aoki.
The spelling of his first name is...
Here"s the name of the
victim, Toshimitsu Asaba.
Another reporter who was after
Kogure with Ms. Natsuko Mita.
What about the
woman spotted at the scene?
Junko Aoki.
Security camera caught herthis time.
She did it again, right?
This time, it"s different.
We found a part of a detonator.
Three charred bodies were found at a
deserted factory in Nishimoto, Arakawa.
A woman was shot and a man was
burned at Plaza Bar in Haseyama, Arakawa.
A man died in an
explosion in Komatsu, Bunkyo.
In each case, the same
woman was seen at the spot...
...an ex-employee
of Toho Pulp, Junko Aoki.
We decided to pick
her up for questioning.
Also, a video recording Yukie Tada"s
murder was seized at her apartment.
We suspect Aoki was
involved in the serial murder cases.
Gentlemen, try your best
to capture Junko Aoki at once.
Do you mean you
suspect Aoki killed all of them?
No, we must
not assume that at this point.
We"re just saying
she"s suspicious enough.
I can assure you that Junko Aoki didn"t
kill those three at the Plaza and Asaba.
Because...
Has anyone heard
the term pyrokinesis?
Makihara, No!
Listen!
Mr. Makihara needs
psychoanalysis, not psychokinesis.
The bodies at the
factory were burned instantly...
Besides, no fuel at all was used.
The autopsy confirmed it.
Makihara, what was the weapon, then?
Can you write
psychokinesis on the indictment?
I feel we have
something in common in our blood.
Why do we have such power?
My mother once told me.
Our ancestors went
through endless hardships.
They developed a hatred for people.
Their hatred intensified and
gave them the powerto make fire.
I never saw my parents.
I can"t replace your mother, but...
You"ve killed people.
In this world, some
people are worse than devils.
I know.
So that"s okay, you can kill them.
What?
l"II do it, too.
No, you can"t do that, Kaori
Aren"t I good enough?
It"s not that.
I wanted to save this lady...
Even at the cost of my life...
But I couldn"t.
Nothing everturns
out to be the way I want.
Every time I burn people,
I feel like I am walking in the dark.
l"m always scared, afraid of myself.
I don"t want you to be like that.
What"s the matter?
A man shot her!
You can see that?
What do you mean,
Junko could be threat to us?
Won"t you reconsider?
If she joins us, she could
be a great fighting power.
I see.
But I don"t know where she is now.
Wow, it"s a feast!
l"m going out after dinner.
Where to?
I won"t tell you.
The cops are looking for you,
they suspect you are the killer.
This man is a real brute,
be careful while l"m gone.
He"s a nice man.
He touched you?
He likes you.
He likes any girl.
No, he really loves you...
...so desperately, he wants to cry.
Let"s eat.
Sit down, both of you.
She"s joking, right?
You didn"t touch her, did you?
That"s my Junko.
Don"t call me that.
l"m not your girlfriend.
All right, all right.
Yes, I understand.
Kaori"s been missing forthree days.
She might be looking forJunko.
What if they join forces?
They can open a barbecue restaurant.
Or a Yakiniku restaurant...
...a roast Yakitori
shop sounds good, too...
l"m Junko Aoki.
Ms. Ishizu?
Kaori said I can trust you.
Turning yourself in?
No.
Anyway, sit down.
Was it you who burned the
three boys at the deserted factory?
Yes.
What about the
videotape in your room?
That"s the reason why I killed them.
They killed Yukie to
make the videotape...
Only for fun.
I couldn"t forgive them.
You mean you punished them?
It was to save Ms. Natsuko Mita.
I couldn"t do anything, though.
No matter how malicious they
are, It won"t justify your killing them.
I know I won"t be pardoned.
But I don"t care.
When I went to the Plaza,
she was already shot dead.
Kogure is still alive.
Somebody"s backing him.
What?
It"s him.
What"s this?
Chief Hasegawa?
Kaori"s psychic photos.
Is it somebody you know?
We can"t trust psychic photography.
Isn"t this a composite
photograph or some kind of trick?
It might not be admissible
as evidence, but it"s the truth.
Kogure said he could get
a lot of money forthe tape.
Asaba mentioned "the Guardians."
I don"t want to get involved anymore.
I want to leave the rest to you.
Oh, my!
You killed my brother.
Are you...
It was a big mistake that I
didn"t tell anybody about you.
I...
Try to burn me.
l"m not going to do that.
Did you everthink about
how they felt as they burned?
Makihara.
Drop it.
She"s dangerous.
She could use fire at any moment.
You"re the dangerous one.
Go back to your job.
Let"s talk overthere.
I met Mr. Tada at the
restaurant in Aoyama.
He was trying hard to defend you.
He did?
But you know you"re guilty?
You are saying that
if I were found guilty...
...and served my sentences,
everything would be okay?
Everything will be solved?
What are you saying?
You broke the law,
you"II be punished, that"s all.
Then l"II go find my way,
and l"II survive somehow!
After her!
Idiot!
You"d be fired.
What"s this?
This is pyrokinesis.
Then, it"s not a trick, is it?
Is that what you thought until now?
Forget the barbecue...
Hey, what about this?
Psychic photography
would be easy forthem.
No, the contents!
It doesn"t make any sense!
What"II we do?
Let"s look into this.
What I don"t understand is
why you killed Asaba like that.
The police can"t execute Junko Aoki...
...unless the public get the impression
that she is a dangerous terrorist.
Asaba sold the "snuff film".
Why pin it on Junko?
It seems unreasonable.
We execute vermin escaping the law.
We make them realize
their sins, and suffer agony.
That"s the Guardians" job, isn"t it?
This case"s complicated.
I understand how you feel,
but follow my instructions for now.
Of course.
My life is in your hands, chief.
Mr. Tada!
l"m so happy to see you.
Have you been looking for me?
I couldn"t think of any other place...
I said such a horrible thing to you.
I couldn"t forgive myself.
I wanted to apologize.
They"II suspect you
if they see us together.
I don"t care.
l"II save you...
No matter what!
l"m nothing but a murderer.
No more!
Stop it!
Live with me.
That"s impossible...
l"ve been watching you...
Talking to you in
my mind for a long time.
Really?
l"II never forget you.
Good bye.
Ms. Aoki...
You"re back.
Where"s Kaori?
She"s with me.
Is she safe?
Don"t worry.
Are you sure?
l"m not interested in
laying hands on little girls.
What"s Hasegawa to you?
We work forthe same purpose.
Comrades.
He killed Natsuko, did you know?
Not until Kaori told me.
She told you?
I touched her.
She touched me first.
I unconsciously touched her back.
I trusted you.
Did you touch me, too?
Come to the
amusement park where we went.
We"II talk in person.
That"s not fair!
I know.
Asaba is well
acquainted with illegal videos.
We"ve heard the rumor
that he secretly sold them.
This is the list of his customers.
No real names, though.
Yes, this e-mail address is
used at police Headquarters.
Can you trace the message?
No, you have to go to
the Headquarters forthat.
No?
You should get a new face afterthis.
If you are reborn as a soldier,
you can kill as much as you want.
Will you kill me someday?
I could"ve killed you
at the Plaza if l"d wanted.
Let me ask you,
why did you join the police?
First, I sought justice.
But soon...
I realized both killers and
victims are no betterthan trash.
Help!
This is a masterpiece.
It gives me power.
It"s betterthan real killing.
Going to kill Junko?
And another.
Junko Aoki...
...has turned up at Amuseland.
The riot police and
SWAT are on the way.
Snipers?
Amuseland has been
completely sealed off!
The order has been issued...
...if she makes one wrong
move, they"II shoot to kill.
That"s final.
Are we allowed to
do that in this country?
She"s just a girl in her
twenties, she has no criminal record.
She tried to burn down
this building, don't forget that.
Who know what kind
of lethal weapons she has!
She"s a Ione terrorist.
Her mental state is abnormal.
She"s a tiger in the street.
We must destroy her.
It"s all Chief Hasagawa"s idea, isn"t it?
Excuse me...
Listen, I saw the
psychic photo Junko brought.
Even if it"s
suspicious, he"s still our chief.
l"II inform the prosecutors about it.
Will you just go easy on him for now?
He"s fond of you.
l"ve known you over 27 years, and
that"s the dumbest thing you"ve ever said.
Get moving, men!
This way.
Ms. Ishizu.
It"s Junko...
Please save her!
Attention, customers.
We were just advised by the fire
department of a temporary evacuation.
Please follow the instructions,
and evacuate the park immediately.
I paid to get in here,
I shouldn"t have to pay forthis too!
Thank you for your cooperation.
Kaori.
I miss the day we
walked here together.
When did you touch me?
I should"ve nevertrusted you.
I can read a pure
mind without touching.
You liked me a bit, didn"t you?
What"s your group"s real purpose?
To get rid of
corruption in human society.
Why the snuff film?
I didn"t know about it.
Asaba bought it from Kogure to sell it.
Natsuko found out,
so he sacrificed her.
They were both vermin, after all.
Hasegawa is the one who
ordered the video to be made.
He killed Natsuko.
He must be hiding Kogure somewhere!
He has his reasons, then!
Hasegawa is a devil.
He"s using you!
Junko.
Take a look at those hoods.
They"re worthless.
They"II harm innocent
people if we leave them alone.
No!
You"re horrible!
l"d say we just
prevented some future crimes.
Don"t get Kaori involved in this!
She"s making a heat barrier for me.
Fight fire with fire, right?
I had been hoping you
wouldn"t try to burn me.
But I was wrong.
We can"t be friends after all.
How could we be?
You kill people for fun.
It"s the same with Hasegawa.
He started just killing
criminals, but he began to enjoy it.
You"II be a devil like him.
I thought we could be friends.
l"II execute you.
You"II be happierthat way.
Stop!
Junko...
Good job.
Kaori!
Forgive me, Junko.
I can"t change who I am...
I didn"t make Kaori say
I loved you by touching her.
I really loved you.
So desperately I could cry...
She"s unrelated to the video tape.
Do the police believe
such a ridiculous story?
I told you, she is just
a key witness at this point.
Then who"s the real killer?
How should I know?
She wants to be a plain girl.
We deciphered Asaba"s memo.
It"s the date of order from
somebody whose name starts with an H.
The mail address was the
same as the one you found.
So is it Hasegawa, the chief?
Don"t throw his name around.
There"s a fire at Amuseland,
several casualties reported.
It seems that Junko Aoki is
firing an unidentified weapon.
The park is being evacuated.
No!
Stupid, it"s a trick!
A trap!
That man is planning
to pin his crimes on Junko!
What man?
Mr. Tada, wait, please!
Junko Aoki"s weapon is unknown...
However, its explosive power
is strong and extremely dangerous.
Even if you can"t verify she"s
in possession, you must shoot.
You mean we
should kill an unarmed girl?
Get ready!
That"s her!
She"s with a child.
Fire!
We can"t!
Aim at that girl nearthe gate!
Ready!
Please don"t shoot!
Spare this girl!
Hey, stop!
Come back!
Commence fire!
Come on!
Fire!
If you don"t shoot, I will!
Stop!
What are you doing?
Who do you think you are?
All right...
You bastard!
Mr. Tada!
What are you waiting for?
Shoot now!
She"s a serial killer!
Commence fire!
Get the hoses!
Fire!
Hey, let me pass!
Make way!
Ms. Ishizu!
What the hell is going on?
Please, help Kaori!
We first need an ambulance...
Let"s go.
What about you?
It"s our last party, let"s enjoy it!
I arrested Junko Aoki!
Ishizu...
l"II take herto the police station.
All right?
Don"t shoot!
Please, okay?
Now get in.
l"m not going to let you!
Can you burn me, Junko Aoki?
Kogure!
Junko, l"m sorry.
Mr. Tada.
Use fire, and he"II be burned.
Freeze!
That"s Masaki Kogure!
Don"t shoot the man!
He"s got a gun!
Bitch!
Thank you, Mr. Tada.
Don"t go!
Don"t leave me!
Good bye.
Junko Aoki, along with
Asaba and Kido, belonged to...
...a group of left wing terrorists.
They made snuff films to raise funds.
Eight civilians were killed
by her bomb at the Amuseland.
Unfortunately, two
officers lost their lives as well...
Fujiki Yutaro, Hiro Sasaoka...
We found that they also
belonged to the organization.
They seemed to be
victims of infighting.
We, the Metropolitan
Police Department...
...made the decision to
shoot Junko Aoki at Amuseland.
Today, the incidents were filed as a
criminal case at the Public Prosecutors Office.
What the...
Sis?
Junko...
I thought Junko Aoki was dead...
You"re doing it, aren"t you?
Kaori?
Please come in.
This is the doll I talked about.
Thank you.
Goodbye, Sis.