Under Saddam Hussein's regime in Iraq,
every family
that named its newborn son
after the ruler,
was generously rewarded.
This movie
is based on a true story.
Is the bread ready?
Come on, soldier!
Let's load the food.
So?
Did they knock him down?
They're doing it right now.
Bring him down!
We have to go.
I'm coming.
That's enough.
Come on... we have to go.
Shouldn't we be happy
that they knocked down Saddam?
Her house is high up...
Ley... LEW-
Don't you wanna tell me, when
you'll get married?
Not before I find my brother.
He's probably in prison...
As soon as they open the prisons,
they'll release him.
By the grace of God
he shall come back home.
I hope so.
He's 25 years old now.
Seven years younger than me.
He's the meaning of my life...
and my mom won't stop crying.
This one.
He's the shadow of my rose.
Thank you, sir.
You're welcome.
Thas's the last time
I'm driving this scrap.
The Americans have already come
and they are bringing us new cars.
God only knows... hopefully.
- Do you have enough fuel?
- Yes, sure.
How much does it cost?
70 dinnars for one gallon.
Isn't it too expensive?
What can we do?
That's the price!
Well, pour one gallon.
Bring it here, Ahmed.
Yes, father!
Damn, you scoundrel!
I missed it because of you!
You poured the fuel
on the ground!
Didn't I pay for it?
Grab the fuel, you idiot.
They came...
They came!
Well done.
Haven't you finished?
It's ready, brother.
Do you see how good my English is?
Like a nightingale!
Yes, yes, it's true my brother.
Life will get better,
now that the Americans are here.
You'll get gasoline and oil
in a tank instead of a gallon.
And at home you can do nothing
but eat and sleep.
Come on...
why are you talking to him like this?
It sounds nice...
I'm not happy yet.
The dictator Saddam
has not been brought down yet.
The arabs will pull off,
but they'll plunder our oil and gasoline.
It's not as you say.
Come on, come on.
I'm telling you,
it will slip out of our hand
and get lost in front of our door.
Look, can you see that scrap?
They deserved even worse!
Now come,
and look at these cannon wreckages.
See those tanks cannon.
Looks as if it was gonna fire right away.
Why don't you fire now?
Something's still missing,
that I cannot grab with this
or the other hand.
I'm ready to die soon,
if Saddam gets his comeuppance.
Anything he could ever go through
wouldn't be as bad
as what he's done to our village!
Hurry up, go faster!
It's too late.
I'll fly now.
You should have become a musician,
not a Peshmerga
(iraqi-kurdish activist).
Aren't you happy that
I'm fighting as a Peshmerga
against Saddam?
They were Saddam's troop of murderers!
That's true!
Safm... Safm... Gareh.
Yeah, yeah...
Where are you?
In zone 22, we should be there
in an hour.
Very well, understood.
Fine and over.
According to that sound you can tell
they must be starving.
Be careful... slowly.
Where did he come from?
What are you doing here?
Go home... go home!
Do you see how dark he is?
So dark that you can't
see him at night.
Go home!
Why did you stop the car?
I'm worried about this kid.
This dirty kid?
Come on, let's get moving.
We have to do something
before we go on.
You know, the group
is waiting for us, my brother.
Why are you crying?
Why are you barefooted,
without any shoes?
Home? Family?
Where is your home?
Come on, I don't speak Arabic...
Please ask him in Arabic.
Come along, it's getting late.
This kid is lost.
Leave this dirty,
filthy creature.
Don't you know
how dangerous this area is?
I'll ask in the houses.
Maybe someone knows him!
Let's go, forget about him.
We have to go!
I'll ask around to find his house.
Come on, my boy.
Which one of these houses
i5 yours?
Which is your house?
Is this your home?
How are you?
What do you want?
Is he your kid?
I don't understand what you're saying.
We've found this kid on the street.
Which family does he belong to?
I don't understand.
Kid... Kid... (Arabic)
Father, there's a stranger at the door.
What do you want?
This kid is lost.
Do you know him?
Do you know this kid?
Why is it no one knows him.
Has he been living under a rock.
Hello, do you know this boy?
Strange, nobody seems to know him.
He certainly doesn't belong here.
Where is your gun?
I left it inside the car.
You're not an elderly person.
Ask him in Arabic
where his home is, and about his name.
What's your name?
Saddam!
What did you say your name was?
Saddam?!
Yay, I arrested Saddam!
You can't be him,
sondern der Schwarze!
What are you laughing at?
Actually, he looks
just like him.
Open the door.
- Why?
- We'll deliver him to the Americans,
and then we'll leave.
Leave this dirty dog here.
I feel so sorry for him. It's a sin.
You feel sorry? A sin?
And what about ourselves?
Have you forgotten the Enfal operation?
Where is your brother?
But he's only a kid.
He knows nothing of these operations.
Open the door to let him in.
I swear to God, he's
not getting in the car, ok?
He'll only be sitting next to you,
he won't bite!
Drop him on the back seat.
In the back!
Come on.
Once Saddam is gone,
you can get yourself a passport
and go abroad.
You can even buy
an artificial leg.
And get an elastic one,
then you can jump as high
as a kangaroo.
I'm hungry... Food... Food.
What is he saying?
Stop somewhere...
He'll break the bowls and make them dirty.
Poor kid, that place is uncomfortable.
Even a dog couldn't sit there.
Come on down. Jump down.
Jump down!
What is he saying?
He's saying that he's hungry.
Let him eat a deadly poison!
I'll give him some rice with sauce.
If you're hungry,
you can have some, too.
You're horrible.
Which one do you want?
This one or that one?
Come on, eat, eat well.
Is that alright?
Come on, Blacky.
Why did you bring him over here?
I feel sorry for the kid...
Do you think he's going to eat you?
He's dirty and he stinks.
Poor kid, what do you want?
Hurry up, let's get away.
Water, water.
Give him some water.
He's choking.
My God, what kind of man are you?
Drink Blacky, drink.
Bastard.
Easy man, what do you want?
The way you slapped this kid
you could even kill me.
Next time I can kill him.
Don't cry, don't cry...
Look...
Come, play something.
Safm... Safm...
Gareh... Safin... Yes, yes.
Go to five.
Ok.
What's going on?
Why haven't you arrived yet?
We have a small problem, but it's ok.
We'll see you soon.
What problem?
Nothing, we'll tell you later.
0k, 0k. Come soon...
Alright, we'll see you.
My stomach...
Oh, my stomach.
Enough!
Stop somewhere. This kid
will make us dirty.
Hurry UP,
go over there.
I told you a hundred times
to take care of the child.
Let's look for him over here.
Maybe we'll find him.
I told you
to look after him.
In the midst of that war,
who was not out of his senses?
Hello sir, have you seen
a small, slender boy?
- No, I haven't.
- Thank you.
I blame you for all of this,
for God's sake.
I'll take him to the Americans.
Go ahead, take him.
Ok, you'll come along.
I don't speak English, you take him.
You'll come too.
I'm not coming.
Come on, Blacky.
We have a company.
Who the hell are they?
Come here.
They are Peshmerga...
Hello, how are you?
- I'm a Peshmerga.
- Nice to meet you.
This is a child.
Yes, a little boy.
The boy got lost.
We found him.
Take him with you,
if possible!
I don't understand him.
I think he wants us to take the boy.
Do you want us to take the boy?
Yes, yes, you keep him.
Safm... Safm... Gareh...
Yes, Gareh.
Where the heH are you?
We faced a problem.
We found an Arab boy.
What are you doing
with an Arab boy?
Nothing... Nothing, but...
Do hurry UP!
Alright, alright.
So what happened?
The Americans refused to keep him.
You know, they called again.
They're not happy over there.
Leave him, let's go.
He only makes trouble.
Which way shall we go?
I don't know, we're lost.
Give it to me!
That's not a toy!
Leave him, just tell me which way to go.
I swear to God...
I should kill you with one strike.
We should take this direction.
Excuse me, sir.
Have you seen a small,
slim boy around?
My son is five, he's called Saddam.
I told you a hundred times
not to mention
his name in public.
You're guilty of
naming my son Saddam.
You just wanted to be rewarded.
The reward was great pain,
torture... and a dead arm.
There are great names such as.
Abdula, Hassan, Hussain, Mohammad.
But no... you chose >!
A name that nowadays
brings us many troubles...
and that we cannot
pronounce everywhere.
What kind of life do we have?
What a damn homeland to live in.
Why did you stop the car?
I'll take him to the mosque.
Let's go... It's late.
We'll only have a look.
Just leave him there and then we'll go.
The door is open...
there must be someone.
No one is in there.
Come on,
It'5 go!
I'm not coming, go by yourself.
I don't speak Arabic.
What should I say?
It's too dangerous for us here.
No, nothing's gonna happen.
There's someone in the Mosque.
Good day in God's name, Master!
Master,
this kid
is lost (Arabic).
Please announce that, so that
his parents can come.
Master,
announce it through the speakers,
in order to
find his parents (Arabic).
What speakers, and with
what electricity?
Can't you see
that it's dark all around?
There is war everywhere.
Go look somewhere else for his parents.
Allah is big... Allah knows it.
That way you'll find his relatives.
I told you we should leave him
with the master and go.
Didn't you hear what he said?
They're stealing our car! Let's get them!
God, it's true.
You're guilty of all that,
you dirty Saddam.
It's all your fault.
Go away from here, to your home.
Leave him alone,
what do you want from him?
Dirty bastard... jerk.
My dear, how many times
have I told you to leave him here?
Why do you put us in danger?
My heart couldn't bear leaving him
in the middle of the street.
Brother, I told you a hundred times:
Leave him there...
What should we do now?
Do? There's nothing we can do.
God has punished us.
Let's go, we have to
look for our car.
Where should we find the car
in this big town?
If we just sit here nothing will happen.
Maybe we'll find it
if we go into this direction.
You wouldn't find it
even if you were able to walk.
So let's go and have a look.
Did he leave something good behind?
He ran away!
You're not coming!
- Did you bring this car?
- Yes.
Where from?
No time for questions.
Let's carry him.
A small kid is missing.
Have you seen it?
Go away... Go.
Look...
Look, that belongs to us.
Ok, you had enough food.
Bastard!
Safm... Gareh... Safm...
Safm... Safm...
Answer me now!
Why don't you answer?
You answer. I wanna see what you
have to say to them.
Are you still hungry?
Haven't you just had a dish of rice?
Shall I pour some for you too?
You should be ashamed!
Cause I want to eat something?
Why don't you think first
about those people
who are waiting for us?
Aren't they hungry?
I want water.
Do you want some poison?
What is he saying?
He said that he's thirsty.
Well, I'm thirsty too.
Take it, Blacky.
Do you see that?
Yes, I see it.
There's no one inside.
Well...
What should we do now?
What to do? Get in the car.
- Let's go.
- Yeah, we'll go.
The driver was killed inside his car.
We better get away from here.
Look...
What's that?
It's food.
Still hot.
What are you doing?
Eating food, we're hungry...
Why not?
I'm afraid it's not clean.
You won't find anything better
under these circumstances.
Now sit down and eat!
Get in the car my friends.
Ym sorry?
Get inside the car.
No, thanks. Go, go.
What is he saying?
He wants to take us in his car.
Today is the Iraqi's day.
The cannibal Saddam has gone.
People are celebrating.
What did he say?
I don't know.
Get in the car.
Come on, let's get in the car.
Come on Blacky, get in.
WhY don't You get in?
We're all Iraqis,
we're brothers.
I know Saddam has destroyed
Kurdistan and also the south.
Do you recognize this kid?
We found him on the street,
take him with you if you can.
No, I don't know him.
I'm going to Naserese
because I'm very happy today.
Stop, stop!
This is our car.
Don't go!
Let's go, hurry up.
Let's just leave him here.
Can I come along as well?
Safm... Gareh... Safm...
Why don't you answer?
Answer me.
What should I say?
That they're not getting any food?
We'll get some food back. Let's go.
Or just the bowls.
Who said they are still over there?
Of course they are.
They remained there, for sure.
Hey Blacky...
Blacky is asleep.
Where are you going?
We're out of town now.
In fact, I don't know
where I'm going myself.
Stop, let's ask these people.
Our car is out of order.
Could we come to the village with you?
They say there is a mass grave.
Our brother has been missed
ever since an anti-Kurd operation.
My sister and I are looking for him.
Where does this road lead to, Mr. Priest?
This road leads to the top of the hill,
where there's a turn in the road
and then it goes back to the city.
Should we take you to the city?
This road leads into the city centre.
It's very close.
It's my pleasure.
Just a second please...
the hood.
Get in the front seat, Mr. Priest.
I can ride in the back.
- Please get in.
- Thank you.
Thank you so much, sir.
You're welcome, Mr. priest.
Let's go.
Just a minute.
Curse you, Saddam,
may God curse you!
Saddam, Saddam.
Yes p.
The latest news
from the radio:
There were HO WGEPOHS
of mass destruction
among IraqVs missiles.
The news agency Reuters
announced yesterday:
The American forces
are heading to the cities
of Takrkt and Howyja,
where the rest of the Baathy
troops has found shelter.
Donald Rumsfeld, the American
minister of defence, announced
that the plan
to overthrow Saddam's regime
will be achieved in a few days.
The latest news: Due to
the severity of war
in the city of Baghdad, there is
insecurity and chaos everywhere.
People have overtaken
and robbed the government building.
Saddam... my son, where have you gone?
That's enough.
Didn't you hear that
the Peshmergas found him?
Come on, let's go towards them.
Cover your face,
cover your face!
Based on our information
you have a target with two people.
Pursuit this target.
Where is your home?
In this your neighbourhood?
Yes.
This alley?
Where is it?
Near a shop.
What's the name of the shop?
The name is Sabah.
Do you know the shop?
Yes, I buy toys there.
Wait, he says his home is here.
Does he? Isn't your home in this alley?
Yes.
Maybe he's telling lies.
He's not.
He's telling the truth.
Wait, stop the car.
Why are you getting out?
I want to come, too.
No way! Do you want to be stolen again?
I'm taking him, then I'll come back.
Let's go.
Did you take him?
Yes I did. Turn on the car's engine.
That quick?
I just gave him to them,
now let's go.
Who did you give him to?
I'll tell you on the way.
What? Tell me what you did with him!
Oh, let's go. I said
I'd tell you on the way.
Why don't you tell me now?
I took him over there,
and now he'll go home.
He will go home by himself, you say?
Yes, he'll go by himself.
Where are you going? Come on.
I'll go after him.
Come back!
Come back.
He said he'd kill me
if I turned around.
Why did you bring him back?
We barely got rid of the filthy dog.
Why did you come back,
you Arab jerk?
Leave him. That's enough.
The car will get us stuck on the road.
This is playing time.
Turn it on.
Enough... enough.
Where is your family?
Turn it off, that's enough.
Who is that, over there with Blacky?
What is it, Blacky?
It seems that he knows this boy.
Do you know this kid?
Yes, he's our neighbour.
Ahmad... come on, let's go.
Wait, wait...
- Who was that?
- Ahmed.
Get in...
God is my witness,
our child is missing.
What did he say?
<<Just like yourself,
we've been brutally
tortured by Saddam.
And I lost an arm
due to the torture.».
Tell him we'll find a solution.
Thank you, sir.
I swear to God,
if I find my son Saddam,
I'll change his name
to Abdullah.
Do you know
which way they went?
No, I don't know.
I think they went this way.
I'll take him to these houses.
Mother, mother.
Thank God,
we finally got rid of him.
Thanks a million, dear God.
Safin... Gareh... Safbn.
Why don't you answer?
What happened to you?
32-32, this is 40 talking to you.
403-40.
Give me an answer. What happened?
We've been fighting successfully,
we killed two militants.
We've also saved an Arab kid
who was their captive.
Kid? What kid?
Leave him and come back to the base.
Yes sir, understood.
What we can do now?
Leave him?
To the entire force,
everybody back to the base.
Where is the musician?