COUMBITE
(Cooperative labor)
"THE FLOWER BEGINS,
IT JOINS OUR HANDS.
MANUEL IS THE CANAL
THROUGH WHICH WATER FLOWS.
THE WIND BLOWS
THE SAILS OF THE COUMBITE.
MANUEL IS THE PATH
THAT WILL QUENCH OUR THIRST."
Hey, it's up ahead.
- There, there.
- Stop up ahead there.
You can stop now.
Wait, I need to take down
a bag for him. Wait.
- Thanks.
- Okay, let's go.
- Good morning.
- Good morning, sir.
- Are you from here?
- By the grace of God.
I am too.
I've been away for 15 years.
I was in Cuba.
Before, there wasn't such drought.
- Lady Santelia, good day!
- Good day, Anaisa!
- How's your family, dear?
- Everyone's good. How about you?
- Well, my husband's a little sick.
- It'll pass. - God willing.
- So your name is Anaisa. - Yes.
- My name is Manuel.
This is as far as I go.
Anaisa.
- Thanks for being so friendly.
- It's nothing.
I'm not going very far either.
My home is over there.
- Do you know Bienaimé and Délira?
- Yes. - I'm their son.
Oh, my God!
Have mercy on us!
- But the Lord is the creator,
is he not? - He is.
Well, the earth is barren,
so the Lord is the creator of
the earth and barrenness.
Oh, don't torment me, Bienaimé!
Then consider this:
There are so many creatures...
...asking for things...
...that an irritating noise forms,
and God says: "I don't know
who needs or doesn't need water."
You're the one filling the earth
with fussing and bickering.
All you do is argue!
Manuel...
Manuel.
What's that noise?
My goodness!
Boy, get over here
and shake my hand!
Honor and respect, Dad.
- Your mother prayed a lot for you.
- You're really back!
You should've told her
you were coming.
The shock of seeing you
almost killed her.
- Is it good? - It sure is, Dad.
- Well, we'll see.
- What are you laughing at?
- No, it's nothing, Dad. - Yeah, yeah.
He's gotten like this
over the years.
Don't just stand there.
Come have a drink to settle down.
Where's your respect for the dead?
They're thirsty too.
Okay, I'll go tell everyone
that he's back.
- You'll never leave again,
right, Manuel? - Never.
I came to put down roots.
Although the soil isn't good for
putting down roots now.
It's because there isn't
a drop of rain in the sky, son.
- God has abandoned us.
- This isn't the good Lord's doing.
There are earthly things,
and there are heavenly things.
God has abandoned
the black man, Manuel.
No, it's we who have
abandoned the earth.
Hey, don't talk like that.
- I saw that the forest was cut down.
- How else could we live, son?
But without trees,
the land won't absorb rain.
It was Man's axe that did that,
not the good Lord.
I dreamed you were coming, Manuel!
Honor, Delphine.
In my dreams, you were
a big, strong man,
but for some reason,
you were much older.
- Laurélien.
- Manuel.
I said to myself, "A stone thrown skyward
returns to the earth."
You're that stone, Manuel.
- How are you?
- I could be worse.
You don't age, Uncle Bombon.
Hey, don't start!
The ladies still love me.
It's because they know:
"An old stick is the best companion."
Simidor, you're such a mess.
Yes, but you make
the best coumbite songs.
- What coumbite? Have you seen the soil?
- Yes, I felt it.
Well, without water,
the drums have no life.
- What about Fanchó Springs?
- It dried up.
- And Lorie Springs?
- You're persistent, boy.
Not even a drop.
Only Sobi Swamp is left.
It's a pond for mosquitos!
- Hey, Manuel, did they have water
where you were? - Tons.
And their sugarcane was
tall and plentiful.
- It must be nice to live on
land like that. - Well, not quite.
For a black Haitian cane-cutter,
it isn't so great.
We are like pots...
...which cook the food,
and then...
...can't go to the table because
they'd dirty the tablecloth.
That's exactly right.
I could hardly sleep last night.
It's because you're excited
to see your son.
Like hell it is.
It's the damn fleas.
Manuel, why didn't you call me?
When will you stop
treating me like a kid, Mom?
Good morning.
You're the man who
just returned from Cuba?
Yes, that's me.
- You're Bienaimé's son, right?
- Yes, that's me.
Any luck, Manuel?
I tried that once.
I thought there might
be a trickle left.
Either it comes from the sky,
or not at all.
We just have to accept it.
When a man accepts things,
he's left crippled.
Over in Cuba, we didn't accept things.
We staged a strike against the masters.
Maybe men can be reasoned with,
but the heavens can't.
If you do earthly things well,
the heavens don't matter.
- What has your machete gotten you, man?
- This is just the beginning.
Laurélien, I'm going to find water.
If they see you over there,
they'll call you crazy.
- So don't tell them anything.
- Okay, man.
Come on.
If I need you after I find water,
can I count on you?
You bet, man.
My cousin is grown up now
and anyone can see her beauty.
Even wicked men.
- Are you talking about yourself,
nephew? - No.
I'm talking about someone else.
There's always something new
on your mother's head.
I've sent for Madame Joseph.
- Madame Joseph?
- Yes, the mambo.
- She'll get here tomorrow,
God willing. - Ah.
What a pain!
The saints demand so much,
all so they'll grant us water
and end this misfortune.
Are you going to help me?
I have a lot to do, Manuel.
I'll help you, Mom.
Tomorrow I'd like you
to find the white calf for me.
- Why not wait until it's older?
- What'll we live on, then?
There'll always be time to
eat our teeth down to the gums!
It's in God's hands.
Manuel, you don't seem
like yourself.
I was wondering why a man spat
as I went to greet him the other day.
What was he like?
He was a large man
with evil eyes.
- Evil eyes?
- Yes.
- Red like annatto?
Gervilen!
That damn stray dog!
When I came here,
I was walking with a girl.
When she found out who I was,
she turned her back on me.
- Who was she?
- Her name was Anaisa.
Oh.
Rosana's daughter.
Why are we enemies, Dad?
Blood was spilled.
It was over a piece of land.
A piece that ultimately dried up,
like all the others.
Dorisca, Gervilen's father...
...wanted it all for himself.
Salvador, my brother,
had a right to it as well.
Then came the arguing,
and the clairin.
- Dorisca used to badmouth everyone.
- Yeah, and drink all the time.
He insulted my brother
in front of the men.
So my brother decked him,
and it killed him.
I took my share, too.
Then my brother Salvador
died in prison.
- The water hadn't run out by then?
- It was starting to.
- But the coumbites ended, right?
- Yes, for good.
So we started to die
before the water ran out.
- What are you saying, Manuel?
- No, nothing. Nothing, Dad.
- Good morning, Anaisa.
- Get out of my way.
We're going the same way.
- I've looked everywhere for you.
- I said move, Manuel.
- You remembered my name.
- God! What are you, deaf?
Aren't you tired of
this hatred between us?
So help me, Ana.
They might see us, Manuel.
- Let's meet tomorrow at
Los Lataneros Hill. - I don't know.
- I'll be there in the afternoon.
- I don't know...
Philoget! Philoget!
Come here right now!
- Hey, Manuel.
- What's up?
How about your water, Manuel?
Did you find it?
Not yet, man.
This is as bad as
it's ever been, Manuel.
We are cursed men.
Look, we are the earth.
Without us, the earth is nothing.
But we're poor, Manuel.
That's because we still don't know
that we're a single... force.
Some day we'll have a great coumbite
to end this misfortune.
Maybe so, man.
Where is that man
who came from Cuba?
I'm here.
- Yes, Dad.
No, no, no!
- No, Dad.
What's up?
Get me a clairin.
- You're just playing heavy ones.
- It's all I've got.
You're going to pass to me?
I hear you're talking to
the people here.
You're getting involved in
things that don't concern you.
Fine.
Suit yourself, but don't say
I didn't warn you.
Is that all?
Let's see someone beat this!
What are you, an animal?
Legba, your corn, your bread,
make it rain, Legba.
make it rain.
Legba, your corn, your bread,
Mom, come on.
There's hardly any corn.
It's for our old Guinean gods.
First it's a goat and now it's corn,
which doesn't even grow now.
Where is your water?
I'm looking for it, Mom.
I swear I'm looking for it.
Legba, your corn, your bread.
- Hello, Anaisa.
- Hello, Manuel.
- So you came.
- I did, but I didn't plan to.
Earlier, I said I'd go to the market
and now I'm on my way back.
- Manuel...?
- Yes?
I'm a serious woman, okay?
No man has ever touched me.
I came because I knew
you'd respect me.
- You said I could help you?
- Yes, Ana. A lot.
Come with me.
Sit down here so your dress
doesn't get dirty.
Do you see the valley?
If this continues,
everything will die.
First the plants,
then the animals...
...and then, perhaps us.
And what've we done about it?
Sigh and give up.
We've been selling it all
little by little.
We do ceremonies for the souls,
but that's useless.
So you... don't believe in
the old gods from Guinea?
Not really, Ana.
I don't think a goat's blood will
bring rain to the earth.
What would you say, Anaisa...
...if you saw corn down there
that's as tall and full-grown as you?
What if Guinea grass covered
all but the cattle's heads?
What would you say?
What if water flowed
through your backyard?
Will that ever be possible, Manuel?
- Yes, Ana. I promise.
- Really, you?
Yes, me... Manuel Juan José.
- And how will you do all that?
- I won't be alone.
Everyone will help
because it'll be a lot of work.
Oh, Manuel!
Yesterday's friends are today's enemies.
The blood still isn't dry yet.
I know, Ana.
But you see,
the greatest thing in the world
is that all men are brothers.
You're smart, Manuel.
I know you'll find water.
- So you'll help me?
- I don't know what I can do.
- I'm not as smart as you.
- Yes you are.
To prove it, you'll answer
a question for me.
It's a riddle.
Come with me.
Do you see my home?
Now follow that trail down to
the path on the right.
It'll be next to that.
It's a good spot, isn't it?
One could build a home
with a railing...
...two doors, two windows...
...and plant flowers there.
Whose home will that be?
You haven't answered my question.
I have to go now, Manuel.
You haven't answered
my question.
Yes, Ana?
Yes.
But I have to go, please.
What do you want?
Your heart should tell you that
whenever I'm around.
- Gervilen!
- I'm your cousin...
...and I should be your husband.
- Whore.
- Don't insult me!
I know who you were with.
So what, we're friends
with them now?
Aren't you my cousin,
and aren't I Dorisca's son?
Speak!
Answer me!
Then answer me this instead:
Will you be my wife?
You're crazy, Gervilen.
Yeah, I'll show them how crazy I am!
Get out of here! Go!
My goodness!
There aren't enough heads in the city
to sell all these hats.
As if what's inside them is
so important that it needs decoration.
Less talk and more work.
Good morning.
How are you?
How are you, daughter?
He finally left?
He says he can't take it anymore,
and he's leaving now.
He's leaving right now.
What do you want?
- Hey, step aside.
- What's a man worth if he runs?
What do you want?
- Haven't you seen how the soil is?
- It's in the dust I breathe.
You think a man can farm here,
and raise a family?
I promise I'll get you water.
- You? What can you do?
- I promise I'll get you water, Pierli.
Come on.
Good morning, Manuel.
- It's high, but it's
where the pigeons fly. - Yeah, so?
They're waterbirds, and they
don't come around here anymore.
- I know.
- Are you tired?
I'll find it.
I have to find it.
- Délira.
- Yes, Bienaimé?
You're a good woman.
But I'm a pain in the neck.
No you're not.
You have your bad days,
but it's because of all this misfortune.
- I'm a pain in the neck!
- No, you have a very good heart.
- Who would know better than me?
- You're so argumentative!
- Fine, Bienaimé.
- What's fine?
- That you're a pain in the neck.
- Who, me?
- And you're argumentative.
- Me?
Wasn't that what you
wanted me to say?
Go tell the whole world,
why don't you!
He found it! He found it!
He found it!
- What the hell did he find?
- The water! Look at him!
Your son said he'd find it,
and he did!
- Is that true, Manuel?
- Yes, I found it.
Son!
First, we have to
install a line of posts,
to hold the soil in place
and prevent erosion.
Then open a channel
from the hill to the valley.
Each person digs one little channel
to the main channel.
It's a great task, a general coumbite
requiring all of Fonds Rouge.
- Everyone? - Everyone.
- Have you forgotten about Salvador?
A single group can't do it all, Dad.
Besides, it's their water too.
But you found it,
and they're our enemies!
- The water is everyone's.
- That's enough!
So what do you think?
Ash.
For a while now, Salvador and Dorisca
have been just that: ash.
And yet we keep
burning ourselves in it.
I went into deep mourning
after Salvador died.
He was my brother-in-law.
But in my heart,
there's no place for hatred.
Hatred isn't caused by bloodshed.
It's caused by poverty.
That's exactly right.
Hey, boss.
Someone found water.
That guy who came from Cuba,
Bienaimé's son.
That guy named Manuel.
He brought a piece of wood
over there, in his pocket,
a piece of wood
he brought from Cuba.
A magic wand.
He was over there,
but I don't know where.
There was a pile of stones
and he touched it with his wand,
and a hole opened up,
and the hole began to gush water.
But only he knows where it is.
Bienseguro was watching him,
but when he went, he couldn't find it.
Well, we still don't know
if it's true.
We have to be sure.
A lie is like money lent at interest:
it has to yield something.
What interest does Manuel have
in telling this lie? How does he profit?
They'll be able to water their fields.
Yes, and we'll be watching them
and won't get a drop.
Those lucky bastards!
We have to leave Fonds Rouge,
to avoid seeing them enjoy the water.
It's not a question of
them hoarding it.
They want to share it
with us as well.
- Manuel mentioned a general coumbite.
- That's a lie!
At my age... I won't
be called a liar by anyone!
- Who said he wants a general coumbite?
- Anaisa came and told me.
Ha, Anaisa... she sure is
getting along well with Manuel.
- Watch it, that's my sister!
- Then take better care of her. - Hey!
That's enough!
You, over there.
And you, sit there.
You all know the situation now.
What's your decision?
What are you afraid of?
Are you not men?
- That's out of line!
- Shut up! - You shut up too!
Let the others talk.
We need to think this over.
Some men have no pride, like dogs!
Well, there's no rush.
We'll meet tomorrow
and we'll make a decision.
Brother Gervilen!
Brother Gervilen,
I want to talk to you.
Save your breath.
Brother Gervilen!
Dad, I don't think you should go.
You won't have time to return today.
Hyah.
Hyah!
- Délira, I'll be back tomorrow.
- Yeah, all right!
- You'd only be doing your duty.
- Yes, and then some.
You could find that water
before the others do.
Any more time without water
and we'll have them in debt forever.
Just think, that guy is here
to ruin everything!
That Manuel is against the law
and the government.
Well...
I've got no choice.
I'll have to do something.
We have to take the water by force.
But why take it by force
if it's for everyone?
Save your strength
for the coumbite.
- Honor, Larivoire.
- Respect, Manuel.
- Good evening, everyone.
- Good evening.
The rumors are true.
I've found a great water source.
We all must come together
and unite to bring the water here.
Blood is forever,
and blood has been spilled.
Blood is death.
Water is life.
Dorisca died,
and he was my father.
- Or did you forget that?
- And Salvador died in prison.
- Revenge has been taken.
- Not by my hand.
Brother Gervilen...
Don't call me brother.
There's nothing between us.
- Count me in, Manuel.
- You swine!
Hey, Gervilen! Watch your mouth,
or some day you'll regret it!
Now I see. You've sold your souls
for a drop of water.
For clairin, you'd have
sold yours too.
Out of respect for you,
I won't say all that I think.
You've crossed paths twice
with Gervilen Gervilí,
and that's two times too many.
What do you say, Larivoire?
You've come in good faith, Manuel,
but I must give you my answer tomorrow.
Give him a torch
so he can see the road.
Who's there?
Hey, who's there?
It's your son, Mom.
Come quick!
Manuel!
Oh, son!
What have they done to you, Manuel?
What have they done to you, son?
Oh, Manuel! Manuel!
Oh, son!
What have they done to you?
Oh, tell me what they've
done to you, Manuel!
Tell me who did it, son.
Tell me!
Oh, son!
Oh, Manuel!
Tell me who it was
so I can tell Hilarión.
- Tell me.
- No, don't tell him.
Oh, God!
But they've hurt you!
They've killed you, Manuel!
If you tell him,
everything will be lost.
There must be no more revenge.
Okay, son. Okay.
Son.
Easy, son. Drink slowly.
- Mom. - Yes.
- Do you hear me? - Yes, son.
We must save the water.
It's okay, don't worry.
- Ask Anaisa about it.
- Anaisa?
Yes, she's the one who
knows the way.
Don't worry, son.
Good morning.
What, is he sick?
Yes, he brought back a bad fever.
What a setback.
- The lieutenant is asking for him.
- Well, look at him.
- When he gets up, tell him
to come by the barracks. - I will.
Do you want me
to help you dress him?
Thank you, but I'll wait.
- Are you waiting for someone?
- I'm just waiting.
Come in.
- What have they done to you, Manuel?
- Keep your voice down.
It was his last wish that you
not say anything.
Come with me.
Respect, neighbor.
Gervilen is gone.
Yes, I knew.
But nobody else
must find out about it.
I would've liked it
if Gervilen were here,
so I could repeat
my son's words to him.
He said...
...that we made sacrifices
to the loas...
...that we offered
the blood of our goats...
...and the little corn we have,
to make water come.
But it was all in vain because...
...what really counts is
human sacrifice.
He also asked that,
after his death...
...there be a general coumbite.
In other words...
...a coumbite involving everyone.