Miwi, darling...
Get up.
What time is it?
Get up!
Your sister had an accident.
Where is she?
In the living room.
Pack her bag.
Dad, are you ok?
You have blood on you.
Hurry.
Don't worry.
Have your cellphone on hand.
Drive straight, ok?
Ok.
Do you have any money?
Yes.
Take everything with you.
Go get it...
and hurry up.
Miwi...
Juliana
I saw your clothes in the sink.
Juliana tell me what happened, why...
It's Santiago, right?
Hello?
Yeah.
We are fine.
Sorry, I had my cellphone on silent.
Sorry.
We are on our way,
almost at the highway.
No, we didn't get lost,
we are on our way.
Take the next turn.
She's fine.
Juliana never tells me anything.
Ok. I will.
Make a left.
Make a left!
Keep going.
It's a shortcut.
Sorry.
This is hell of a shortcut.
Dad?
Yes I'm ok.
They called me from his cellphone.
Has anyone been to the house?
Shit.
Are you OK?
Do you want some soda?
No.
What did he tell you?
Nothing...
that he loves us and...
that you should drive
with your thumbs on the outside.
Did you tell him that we went
to Santiago's house?
Why did you turn off the van?
We are running out of gas.
What happened?
We got into a fight.
Do you have reception?
Juliana.
What?
Do you know why the police
were outside of his house?
Thanks.
Why don't you answer the phone?
What took you so long?
We just missed the 8 AM bus.
How are you?
How are you Julie?
Your parents are giving
a statement to the police.
But you shouldn't be worried.
You're going to go to Queretaro...
to Efrén's house...
a friend of your dad and I.
Your dad says to call him
when you get there...
and he will give you directions.
Anyway, I printed you out a few maps...
so you won't have any
trouble getting there.
Julie?
Yes Auntie, I heard you.
Get some sleep dear.
No thanks Auntie.
We gotta go.
Open wide.
Wide wide open.
How long have you had that filling?
I got it about a month ago.
It's good that you are
staying so l can fix it.
Auntie...
I have to go with Juliana.
That's what my dad told me.
That I have to take care of her.
Julie?
Julie, what happened?
I broke the mirror. I'll clean it up.
No, don't.
You're going to cut yourself.
Leave it.
Don't worry about it.
The maid will do it.
Are you OK?
I'm all right.
Leave your clothes in the basket.
Thanks, but I'm taking them with me.
No, seriously, leave them here.
Don't worry.
I'll keep them for you.
I brought your clothes.
You sure you're OK, Julie?
I'm fine.
Please stop calling me Julie.
Are you sure you don't want
anything else for breakfast, Miwi?
No thanks.
I have eggs...
Auntie...
Please help me.
Julie!
Put your hand here.
Leave it here.
Hang in there.
What happened?
Juliana.
Why do you have a knife?
Miwi stop it, please.
Where did you park the van?
Right outside.
I won't be able to take
you to the bus station.
I'll take her.
Can you drive?
You can't drive.
You should've seen her.
Of course she can't drive.
Go to my room and
bring my purse.
I told you to bring my
purse from my room.
I think it's best that
you go to Queretaro by car.
Let me see.
I just saw you on the news.
Hello?
In Saltillo, I'll explain later.
Hold on, I can't hear you.
Hello?
Damn.
I don't know what your
father told Efrén...
Give me the keys.
What happened?
I'll tell you in a minute.
What are you going to tell her...
if you don't even know what happened?
Give me the keys.
You should stay here with me.
I already told you...
either we both leave or
we both stay.
Miriana, please listen to me.
Miwi, stay with Auntie.
Give me the keys.
No.
I told you that you are
staying here with me.
Give me the keys!
What did they say about Santiago?
That he's not doing well.
Sixty.
How much are these?
Three.
Do you want a bag?
Yes.
Thanks.
What's up baby?
Do you know anyone here...
that could lend us some money?
Danny.
Straight to voicemail again.
I'm gonna go look for him.
OK.
Ask for Dannysaurio.
No one knows him as Daniel.
Don't bring him along Miwi, please.
Just ask him for money.
A thousand pesos.
Miwis, what's up girl?
What's up Danny, how are you?
You should've called me.
I did, but you never answered.
Really?
Yup.
I need a favor.
We need some money.
Did you come with someone?
Julie!
How have you been?
This job is killing me.
What's up?
Danny...
the money.
Always the damn money.
OK.
Let's see how much we have.
You're going to bankrupt me.
What can we do?
I am sorry, I would love
to help you, but...
I'll end up asking
my mom for money again.
No worries.
Thanks Danny.
No, no. Wait.
I can get a thousand pesos in no time.
What should we do?
Let's call Buki.
Remember him?
Buki! My friend.
A skinny guy that became a rocker.
And he'll lend you money?
Pardo!
What's up dude?
Hey, do you know where Buki is?
I'm looking for him.
Yeah, dude. I need some cash.
You too?
Welcome to the club.
No, seriously can you
lend me something?
Anything?
Is that Buki?
No, that's not Buki.
I don't know who that is.
Actually, Buki's late.
Are you sure this is
the only way in?
Yes, it's the only one.
I think we should leave.
This guy's not coming.
He said he'd be here an hour ago.
Actually if you're going to Queretaro...
leave me at Real de Catorce.
No, Danny.
I'll give you my money.
How much?
About four hundred pesos.
Let me see.
I don't get why you're
going to Queretaro.
Wouldn't you like to go to
Real de Catorce?
We've planned this trip for
ages and we never do it.
We can bring the van.
We go down to the desert...
where the peyote is.
We camp there with the people...
there's always people down there.
In Real you need less
money the in Querétaro...
I don't know what are you
going to do there...
But we don't need that much money.
What we have will do.
I only have phone cards for 200 pesos.
Is that okay?
OK
Here.
It's 200.
Thanks.
Can I borrow a coin?
"Attacks boyfriend and kills child."
Do you need anything else?
No, thanks.
Good afternoon.
Anything else?
No.
Girls...
this is Danny The Freakasaurus.
My friends and colleagues...
call me “the dannysaurius".
In this rap thing...
l don't have any adversaries.
My flow keeps living on word of mouth.
Just feel it. Don't ask for an explanation.
Smoke these rhymes.
Especially dedicated to my cousins.
Miwi and Juliana...
I love them like my sisters.
We continue to rhyme.
Typical.
Fucking people.
You and me, we should
start a band together Miwi.
What's with her?
Juliana...
Juliana!
Juliana.
Want to hear my demo?
Hand it to me, Miwi
it's in the briefcase.
Give it to me.
No, just the CD case.
Play the CD and give me the case.
I recorded this one at home...
with my laptop and a guitar.
Then if you get some money...
you go to a studio...
get it remastered but...
you can start by doing it at home.
Did you find it?
Yes.
Give me the case.
I want to show something to Julie.
Julie, check this out:
Danny the Freakasaurus.
Play track two.
This will lighten you up a little, Julie.
Miwi...
Please turn down the volume.
Miwi.
Remember I told you about CJ?
You know him right?
CJ is my supervisor at the call center.
It's tough to get a
hundred and ten, with him.
Because it's not a hundred,
it's a hundred and ten.
It's motivational bullshit.
Danny, you know what, make a U-turn here.
Oh I'm sorry, I thought
this was the freeway.
Turn around.
Really?
No, no. Keep straight.
Damn it, Danny. Why did
you come this way?
I'm sorry Julie, I fucked up.
Relax.
Buki.
Dude, I've been calling you.
Danny.
Hang up.
It's just Buki, Julie.
Yes, we are on the road...
on our way to Real.
Where are you watching that, man?
Hang up!
Yes, I'm with my cousins.
Wear this.
What are you talking about?
Danny, hang up!
Keep driving.
Calm down.
Thanks.
I told you not to bring him.
Relax, ok?
I told you.
Shut up.
Are you alone?
You sure?
Ok. Yes. I am with Juliana.
No.
She didn't do it.
No, but I'm sure she didn't do it.
Yes. I promise.
I gotta go.
Will you send me texts?
Will you send me kisses?
Do you know that your
cellphones can be traced?
How?
They go to the cellphone company
with a warrant that says
they need to track your cellphone...
and that's it.
You don't even have
to be making calls.
How do you know that?
My job.
My cellphone is off anyway.
What did one Campbell's
soup say to the other?
Let's smile while we can.
Keep my demo.
Danny the Freakasaurus.
Tell Julie she'll like the last song.
OK?
"The Beast roams free".
I told you not to leave the van.
We have to find a cyber café.
You're an idiot Juliana.
You're an idiot!
Stop it!
Excuse me.
I'll be in the van.
Santiago and I made an oath
That we would never leave each other.
Look.
We made a pact.
Hey, I've tried calling several times...
but no one answers...
and I have 16 missed calls from Dad.
The unfortunate news reveal...
that the young man has just died.
The state authorities confirmed...
the death of Santiago Villanueva.
They have announced
a multiple police operation...
to catch the young killer...
Juliana Martinez Garza.
So it's a double homicide.
How sad.
It's so sad, what's
happening in Monterrey...
Help me, please.
What's wrong?
Can't you blame Santiago?
No.
What about you?
I can take care of myself.
Excuse me...
do you know what happened?
An accident.
How far is it?
Walking, about two hours.
Driving...
the same.
Miwi.
What would you like to drink?
I have...
lemonade, milk...
water...
Water, please.
Milk.
Water...
Let's see.
What happened to your hand?
I cut myself.
Water.
That's fine.
And milk.
Thank you.
I'll leave it here...
if you want some more.
Did you tell anyone else...
you were coming here?
No.
Just my dad.
Who gave you my address?
My aunt.
Your aunt...
which aunt?
Bea.
I remember Bea.
How is she...?
Fine.
I'm glad.
What a blessing that Bea.
Do you have a computer
that I could use?
I am sorry?
A computer...
Sure...
Do you need Internet?
Sorry dear...
it crashed this morning.
Watch out, it's hot.
Thanks.
So...
Besides Bea and your dad...
who else knows you're here?
No one.
The thing is that...
we haven't talked with my dad.
I spoke with him two hours ago.
I thought you weren't coming.
Sorry for arriving so late.
Nevermind.
Was it difficult to find the place?
A little.
Can I use your bathroom, please?
Sure.
Actually, I'll go with you.
The knob is broken.
I don't want you to get locked in.
Come with me.
Hi.
Noé, what are you doing here?
I came for a glass of water.
Go to your room right now.
Take the cat with you.
Hey kitty.
Let me see him.
Hi kitty.
I am talking to you Noé.
What's his name?
Bernardo.
Bernardo!
Noé!
I'm going.
Bye.
Sweetheart, you can finish
your dinner in the guest room.
That's where you'll stay.
Are you going to help us?
Help you how?
We need money.
How much money do you need?
About five thousand pesos.
Five thousand pesos.
There is nothing
I can do right now.
Why don't you
get some rest...
and we can talk
about this tomorrow?
Bring your dinner with you.
Thanks.
This way.
Why don't you throw it away?
It freaks me out...
that you still carry it.
I am going to throw it away.
But not here.
Come here.
Juliana, come over here.
C'mon.
Let's find a cyber café tomorrow.
What for?
I want to know if mom and dad wrote and...
see how Santiago's doing.
Wake up!
You have to go.
Why?
What happened?
They're coming for you.
Who?
The police.
Go down by the vacant lot...
and then turn right...
Two blocks ahead
there's an abandoned house.
You can stay there.
There's none here either?
No.
I'm going to the van.
What for?
I don't know.
No.
Why not?
They might be watching
it or something...
it's probably not even there.
Right.
I am really thirsty
and hungry.
We should have gone to Real with Danny.
Does anyone else know
that you came here?
No
Just me and Elias.
He's my cousin.
What's up.
I'm Noé.
Miriana.
That's a pretty name.
Is there a place with
internet around here?
I could bring you a
cellphone with Internet.
Can you bring it later?
Sure I'll bring it at night.
Thanks.
Delete it.
But they're mine.
Please delete it.
What happened?
He took a picture.
Let me see.
You erased them all.
Miwi, let's go.
I can make them bigger.
Let's see.
Do you have a boyfriend Miwi?
No.
Miriana.
Look at me.
Do you have a boyfriend?
No.
Why you are smiling then?
Come on, tell me.
I don't have a boyfriend!
That's it!
Your laughter gives you away.
What do you want me to tell you?
What's his name?
How did you meet him?
What do you like about him?
What does he do?
Fine.
So you do have a boyfriend.
Yes.
What's his name?
Jorge Bernardo.
Jorge Bernardo Vargas.
What?
No?
No.
OK. his name is Kyzza.
C'mon...
That name doesn't even exist.
You just made it up.
I am serious.
Yes..
OK, his name is Kyzza.
OK.
OK so...
I met him at a party...
of a friend from school.
And...
and the party was cool.
So I was there...
hanging out...
chatting...
when he came over...
and he started talking to me..
And he sat next to me and we talked.
He told me about what he does.
What does he do?
Well...
he's in a band.
A punk band.
So, he's punk.
What does he play?
He plays an instrument.
Which one?
The guitar.
And...
He was telling me this and that...
Then he offered me a beer.
And what did you say?
"No thanks, I don't drink."
And well...
he convinced me so I had one drink.
You fell into his trap.
I didn't!
And then...
And then he said,
"Do you want to dance?”
And we danced...
It's true!
I thought he was a punk!
He is a punk and a danger
What were you dancing?
Just to the song.
And then...
he kissed me.
He kissed you?
Yes.
Dancing?
Cute?
A kiss on the dance floor.
A dancing kiss.
And that's it...
that's my story.
And with that kiss...
he swept you off your feet.
Yes.
And we have been together...
for about two weeks.
Two weeks?
Yeah.
Sweet.
Why didn't you tell me?
I don't know.
What are you doing Miwi?
Let me see.
Miwi.
What's wrong with you?
Give it to me.
I wanted to tell you.
I heard it on the radio.
Dad wrote.
He said that everything's
gotten out of control...
that I should turn myself in.
Danny also wrote me.
What did he say?
He asked me if I liked the song.
When I was in sixth grade,
I met Santiago.
But he was in junior
high school.
Actually, I didn't know
him because...
I only saw him when he was
training or at games.
He was the goalkeeper of the
football team.
Then l didn't see
him for a long time...
because he graduated...
and that was it...
he went away.
I was very sad.
I stopped eating for a few days.
I remember it so well.
And then,
two years ago...
l saw him at a Halloween party.
Neither of us had costumes on.
Suddenly somebody poked me...
I turned around and he said "Julie"!
I was like...
"Who are you?”
"Santiago, don't you
remember me?”
And I was like, "No."
Obviously I did.
And he said...
"I do".
"I have been waiting all
these years for you to grow up.”
Can you play this CD?
Play the last song, please.
Thanks.
You're welcome.
Noé had like a crush
on you, right?
Shut up.
Do you recognize it yet?
No.
It's behind the mountain.
I can't see anything.
I'm going to bury the knife.
Can you wait for me near
the cabins?
Ok.
Stay there.
Wait for me.