(dramatic music)
- [Man Voiceover] A good
many years have passed since
that day I arrived
at Golden Sand.
A lot of water under the bridge.
I can still remember how
desolate that mine looked.
Four lost houses in a
lost corner of the world.
I can't really say I have
a lot of good memories
of my stay there but one
thing's sure, in Golden Sand,
a big important part
of me was left buried.
(dramatic music)
I don't know how often I
dreamed of leaving the mine.
It was constantly on my mind.
Then finally exactly
half an hour ago,
everything was behind me.
We were all part and
parcel of a big rat trap.
Maybe we can get out if we try,
but I have my doubts that
it will ever get through
the 400 miles between
here and Fort Green.
Dick Paterson.
Committed enough crimes to
have been condemned by law
to a chain gang forever,
but doctors say that forever
is about six months
at the outside.
(Dick coughs)
Joe Ferrell.
El Comanchero.
Ruthless, blood-thirsty, ice.
He started out plucking scalps
for the Indians and wound up
killing his own brothers
and others of his race.
Chain gang for life.
Slim.
A snake.
A backstabbing traitor.
Life on the chain
gang for murder.
Ray Brewster.
The Torch.
Arsonist, thief, killer.
Chain gang for life.
Thomas Lawrence, Dandy Tom.
Gambler, blackmailer, forger
and naturally, killer.
Hard labor for life.
John Weasel McFarland, sentenced
to life on a chain gang
for robbery, rape and murder.
Has one good quality.
He's probably insane.
Dean Marlowe.
No one knows what he's in for,
but he's got life at hard labor.
(suspenseful music)
- Hey, when are you gonna
stop the damn wagon?
I gotta go bad.
- Do it in your pants!
(Thomas laughs)
(men laugh)
- Order's completed, soldier.
(suspenseful music)
- No matter what
happens, don't bar.
- Thinkin' over
your life, Paterson?
Your whole life passes in front
of ya just before you die.
Great big flashes.
You said it yourself.
- How would you know?
You never died before.
- The rope was around my neck.
So I saw those flashes
alright, dirty as life.
Dirty as your life, Paterson.
Last minute they committed the
sentence to life like this.
- That was bad luck.
- Yeah, that's right.
And this is the worst.
- Hello there, friends, hello!
Old Buddy been waitin'
here quite some time!
- Not a sound.
Not a whisper.
- Now what in the
hell took you so long?
Did you clean out the
whole mine, huh? (laughs)
No, you got nothin' to
be scared of, soldier.
You have to understand, though,
only thing that
interests us is the gold.
Now, you get that to me and
your men are free to go,
to get more gold for me!
Is that right, family?
(loud laughter)
(gun fires)
Don't shoot anymore, children.
They're mighty good folks!
Hold it!
I don't want any more snipin'
at these bastards, ya hear!
Dismount.
(chuckles)
Disarm them.
My son, my youngest.
(chuckles)
Now you leave those alone, Pa!
You sure make me ashamed
to have you along!
His teeth, you should
check his teeth first.
(suspenseful music)
Sergeant.
Uh, who are they?
- Chain gang, they
work in the mine.
We're taking them to Fort Green.
- And uh, the gold?
- We haven't got
any gold, Buddy.
See, you robbed us too often.
(Buddy laughs)
- You damn liar, you!
Terrance, find that gold!
Find it, you hear!
(Sergeant groans)
You dogs in there, I'm
asking you where the gold is.
- You, come down.
(suspenseful music)
(man groans)
Where is it?
- Look in here.
(men laugh)
- Pa, there ain't nothin' here.
(groans)
(Buddy giggles)
- We waited months here, in
the middle of starvation,
cold and calamities and
things, and you wanna know why?
Because I was expectin'
to steal your gold.
Now you listen
real good, my son.
You'll return to the mine, and
you tell your chief he better
send us all that gold or I'll
murder all your buddies here!
And then I'll attack the camp
and I'll burn it to the ground!
Get 'em movin', son.
(horse neighs)
(gun fires)
Have a nice trip, friends!
Good luck and God
bless ya! (laughs)
(Sergeant groans)
(dramatic music)
- Ho!
Ho!
- We gotta get out, no
man can stop those horses!
Chain?
- Whoa!
Hold it!
Ho!
Jump when I tell you to.
Go on!
(dark orchestral music)
(screams)
(horses neigh)
(men grunt and groan)
- Cathy.
Are you alright?
- Yes.
- Come on.
(men groan)
- It's my leg.
It's broken, it's bad.
(groans)
- Look.
What good is that, Sergeant?
No one's getting
out of this alive.
Wagon's destroyed and Slim,
he can't walk an inch.
- Will you cut us loose?
- Mm-mm, you'll go on like that.
- You ain't about to
escape either, Brown.
I expect to watch
you die real soon,
and your daughter
will go before you.
- I gotta get us to Fort
Green, I figure I'm complying
with orders with those
who remain alive.
Load the provisions
onto the horses
and get ready to move out.
Now, get moving.
- What about Slim?
- You'll carry him in turns.
- I have an idea
about that, Sergeant.
- Hold onto it and
do what you're told.
- Let's say I don't.
- Then I'll put a
bullet in your guts.
Won't be at all difficult to
separate you and your chain.
- Exactly my idea.
Do it to Slim.
Empty out the wagon.
(upbeat whistling)
♪ Pig named Brown
♪ You will find
him right behind us
♪ 'Til Fort Green
or some small town
♪ Hard long miles,
black long nights
♪ That he'll try
so hard to endure
♪ But if he winks
or blinks his eye
♪ Forget Fort Green,
he's just manure
(men laugh)
♪ Oh my darlin', oh my darlin'
♪ Oh my darlin' pig named Brown
♪ If he turns his
back on anyone of us
♪ Then the Serge
will be struck down
- I'm scared, Pa.
We'll never arrive.
♪ Only God above knows why
♪ If you can see the
way your treat us
♪ Then watch out
'cause Brown you'll die
(men laugh)
♪ Oh my darling, oh my darling
♪ Oh my darling pig named Brown
♪ You'll always find
him right behind us
♪ Like a vulture circling round
(men laugh)
(moody atmospheric music)
- Hold it.
We'll camp here for the night.
- Daddy.
Ain't you gonna help me?
- There's one way
you could help.
- [Ray] Yeah, all you
have to do is die.
- Divide up these provisions.
They've got to last six days.
- You'll burn before that.
- Amen.
(moody atmospheric music)
(Slim groans)
(suspenseful music)
(Cathy gasps)
- Who did it?
Better give me the truth.
Who did it?
- He would have died anyway.
Hand us the machete.
- Who was it?
- He was a heavy
load, unnecessary.
- Yeah, he was and he is.
The body will still have to
be carried until one of you
decides to speak out.
Cover him with a
blanket and get going.
(moody atmospheric music)
(horses neigh)
Ho.
(horse neighs)
- [Cathy] He's got
a broken leg, Pa.
(horse neighs)
(gun fires)
- You boys ever hunt bear?
You just grab one of the cubs
and hang 'em up by
a paw so he yells.
And papa bear listens,
you wait 'til he gets close,
and then you get him
real good. (chuckles)
Dean, you could trap a
bear cub if you wanted to,
with no trouble at all.
She'd trust you, I think.
- My hands are frozen.
- I'd give up half
my life right now
for a barrel of good whisky.
- If you gave up half your life,
you wouldn't have
time to drink it.
- That's about it for
the provisions, Sergeant.
- I told you six days,
it's up day after tomorrow.
- Just how far do you think
you can push men anyhow?
- Right to Fort Green.
On your feet.
(moody atmospheric music)
Hey, wait.
Go on ahead.
- He'll never make
it with a mare.
- Come on!
(horse neighs)
Get up!
Come on.
Come on!
(horse neighs)
Yah!
Yeah!
Get up!
(horse neighs)
(gun fires)
Don't ever get that close again.
Do you hear?
(dark orchestral music)
Cathy, will you ever forgive me?
- [Cathy] For what?
There was no other way.
We couldn't be separated, so...
- [Brown] I feel
responsible for all this.
My mistakes always come
crashing down on you.
- [Cathy] It's not your fault.
I mean, all the
things that happened.
- [Brown] I never should
have taken you away
from Golden Sand.
- [Cathy] I was happy
to be at your side, Pa.
- [Brown] She begged
me so many times,
for us to pack it
in and leave there,
but I never listened.
- [Cathy] Remember
her last birthday,
how she laughed so hard
she couldn't blow out
all the candles and
we had to help her?
- I only remember
she died too young.
And that one of those
men murdered her.
(men laugh)
(Cathy screams)
(dramatic music)
Take him outta there.
- Go on, do it.
He had an accident.
- Yeah, just a little
spark and, boom. (chuckles)
- He's all ashes and
he smells, Sergeant.
Just one blow of the
machete and he's finished.
Do you expect the men
to carry a load of rot?
- The machete.
(ominous music)
(gun fires)
(clinking)
- Cut it out.
- Gold, it's gold!
- Let me see that!
(dramatic music)
- Look!
(men laugh)
Gold, it's gold!
- Is that true?
- It's gold!
- Enough of that!
- The chain is gold, Sergeant.
You knew about this.
- Your situation remains
the same, gold or not.
- You knew about this.
You're a dirty snake, Brown!
You didn't have orders
to transfer us anywhere.
All you wanted to do was
to transfer that gold
without gettin' robbed, right?
- It could have cost us
our lives, Serge, you know.
- I'm gonna tear you
into bits and pieces
before this thing
is over, Sergeant.
I swear.
- About time to march on.
- What if we don't want to?
- We'll go it alone.
- Without the gold?
- Oh no, I'll take the gold.
- You and you daughter
couldn't pack this load.
Not even a mile or two.
- Now you need all of
us, Sergeant, don't you?
- You're mistaken.
I could bury all the gold
with your rotten corpses
and come back for it later.
- You wouldn't do it.
- Anybody able to stop me?
- You'd like that
a lot, wouldn't ya?
You took us out of the
mines to murder us.
You're still sure that one of
us killed your wife, ain't ya?
- Let's go.
- I ain't takin'
a step from here.
- That's right.
(suspenseful music)
- I said get goin'.
(gun fires)
(screams)
- That makes one less
on your list, Sergeant.
- Couldn't have done
it better myself.
- You didn't have to do that.
- Are you goin'?
(ominous music)
I just had to, Cathy.
It's the only way we'll
ever get to Fort Green.
- To be sure you get revenge,
you're going to have to
murder four innocent men.
- Each one of those men
deserves the gallows.
I just hope you never have
to see what they might do
if they trapped me.
- I've seen what
you're capable of.
- I've been entrusted
with a mission
and I'm going to complete it.
- Don't start lying to me.
I know now why you did it.
- Who are you defending?
All of them or
one in particular?
- That's right, all, and...
One in particular.
(moody atmospheric music)
(strong winds)
- They can't take it
much longer, boss.
- Be more careful.
- This is our chance.
Keep your damn wits about you.
- You heard what I said.
Now watch yourself.
(chuckles)
(strong winds)
- Hey.
Look at him.
(strong winds)
(door opens)
(approaching footsteps)
(chain rattles)
(thuds)
(Brown groans)
(chuckles)
(Cathy sobs)
(Brown groans)
(thuds)
(Cathy sobs)
(Brown groans)
- That'll be enough.
You'll make it too
easy for him to die.
Much too easy.
- I want him to die real slow.
- Yeah.
Like the rest of us are doing.
(Cathy sobs)
(chuckles)
- Leave her alone.
- [Thomas] Are you
standing up for them?
- I said leave her alone.
- [Thomas] Oh,
it's his daughter!
(grunts and groans)
(suspenseful music)
(Cathy whines)
- No!
(Cathy whines and moans)
No!
(men laugh)
(Cathy whines and groans)
(dark piano music)
- God damn chain.
Are we never gonna
get rid of it?
- Don't gripe.
So far luck's with us.
And you've had enough to drink.
- Let me alone.
(chuckles)
Now you look at
me, Sergeant Brown.
Yeah, one of us
murdered your woman.
(chuckles)
Now we're gonna see that
you get fixed up good,
you can be sure of that, Brown.
Because a man like you
deserves a sentence too.
(laughs)
Would you like to know
who murdered your wife?
(chuckles)
You'll be dead and buried
without ever knowing.
(laughs)
(loud screams)
(laughing)
(smashing)
(crackling flames)
Even if it is gold, I'd
give away half this chain
for a nice hunk of bread.
- Yeah, pretty soon you'll
wanna give it all away,
just so as you won't
have to carry it.
- Still carrying the girl.
What's the matter with her?
- Looks if she's gone crazy.
- Lay off, you hear?
- Why don't you turn her loose?
- Settle down.
- Now let me see.
We're about here and those are
the Salmon River Mountains,
right behind Fort Green.
- That's pretty risky.
We might stumble
across a stray patrol.
Better go to the other side.
Towards Lewiston.
- Much too long that way.
We don't have the
strength left to make it
as far as that, Ray.
- A mile away from the fort
there's a farm, Snake Caldwell.
We'll go in by night.
There we can get
rid of these chains,
and get some horses and guns.
Ride out by dawn.
- Are you loco?
There's always soldiers
around there drinkin'.
- Too bad for the soldiers.
(men laugh)
(moody atmospheric music)
(ominous music)
- I've got a good
mind to kill you.
But while we're tied
up by this chain,
the life of each of us depends
on the life of the rest.
Get down.
(suspenseful music)
(gun fires)
- You never shot a pistol
more than three feet.
Across a poker table.
- I remember one time
in San Francisco.
I went to a restaurant
with white table cloths.
The whole place smelled
of roast chicken.
I had me orange duck.
Dry rum.
- Shut your mouth
before I shut it for ya.
- Save your strength, fellas.
We've got a hell of a way to go.
- I always dreamed
of dying filthy rich.
(chuckles)
And I think I'll get to do it.
- Don't worry about it,
I'll close your eyes,
and relieve you of that
weight you're carrying.
(laughs)
- Try to sleep, boys.
(chain clinks)
(suspenseful music)
(gun fires)
(chuckles)
- Dead.
I still got three bullets.
- Don't burn up any
more time with her.
- One more like that
and I'll pug ya.
- Hold it.
Let it drop here.
- Alright but the dead
weight stays behind, see?
- That's right, you
should leave her here.
She's no use to us anymore.
- I'll deal out the orders.
- Since when?
- Just figure the gun
power gives him the edge.
(suspenseful music)
Stop it!
Are you trying to
kill each other?
Hold it!
- [Joe] I'll kill you.
- Did you hear me?
Cut it out!
You've gone crazy!
Keep your head, idiot,
or we'll all die.
- I intend to kill him
the first chance I get.
He got the Weasel, didn't he?
We should be at
the railway tracks.
If you ask me, we're as lost
as a blind man in the city.
We've been going
around in circles for
a couple hours at least.
- The only way is this one.
And if we don't all
die of thirst, we'll
get there tomorrow.
- Just how often do
the trains pass here?
- Don't worry, boy.
There's bound to
be more than one.
(moody atmospheric music)
- I'm not gonna make it.
- The rail.
There.
- Gotta get to the tunnel
before a train passes through.
- I rode that train
when I could stretch my
legs like a free man does.
- You got a damn good idea.
We'll all soon be free.
- When that brakeman sees
us he'll stop the train.
- Don't worry about it.
In that dark tunnel,
nobody could see us.
- We'll just be separated,
that's all, free, no.
We'll never be completely free.
- I'm planning on it.
We'll make it to the
farm and that's it.
- Gold will wind up
choking us to death.
You always feels
like a slave to it.
- A rich slave, though.
- There'll be chains for
men damned to hell like us.
- Wait for us here.
(faint train whistle)
- Hope the wheels don't
slip on the chains.
Could drag us with it.
(train whistle blows loudly)
(clacking train track)
(gun fires)
(train whistle blows loudly)
(dramatic music)
(men laugh)
We're free.
(men laugh and cheer)
(Cathy sobs)
- Will you look at our
romantic lover and his woman.
A bad bet.
He'll never get
her off his back.
- Well I'll help when
I slit his throat.
- Cathy, you think
we're all alike?
(somber music)
- Why do you ask that?
- Ray was asking
why you followed us.
Well I thought
you did it for me.
- I don't know why I do it.
Could be for you, or
because I hate the others.
There are times I think it
would be better if I would die.
I'm all confused.
And tired.
- It'll change before long.
It's just about
over and done with.
- Where does it finish for you?
- I'm not sure.
That gold darn near
cost us our lives.
Hope it takes care
of us from now on.
- I thought you were
different, Dean.
- I was.
Went to jail for a
robbery I didn't commit.
And I figure I'm owed this gold.
I've paid for it,
with my freedom.
- This farm, how far
is now would you say?
- Three days, if he doesn't
decide to go against us.
- I still think we better
stay clear of Fort Green.
- Well I didn't hear
anybody ask your opinion.
- It ain't right to
separate from us, Ray.
You might get killed
trying to make it.
It sure would be a
shame to lose that gold.
(suspenseful music)
- Dirty rat.
Hey!
That rattlesnake marched
right out of here
with all our provisions.
- We better get him.
- Never be able to catch him.
He escaped while
we were sleepin'.
It's better to keep goin'.
- Without any food?
Nah, we'll never make it.
- Hold it.
(strong winds)
(suspenseful music)
(Ray groans and gasps)
(strong winds)
(suspenseful music)
(Ray screams)
(Ray whimpers)
(Ray whines)
- Damn convict must
have got bit by a bug.
- The man's crazy.
- It's gold, Pa.
The Sergeant was right.
They really tricked us.
- Give it here!
There ain't no one
tricks old man Buddy.
Get up!
Son, when I saw you boys
chained in the wagon,
my heart bled for ya.
Where are your friends now?
- You better answer!
(thud)
- That's not the way, my son.
You don't treat a man like that.
Alright, talk!
- They're at the farm.
The one near Fort Green.
- You're lyin'!
That place is crawlin'
with soldiers.
Why in tarnation
would they go there?
- They need a wagon and to
take off their shackles.
- You're in very good
luck, I'll see you get free
of yours without your needin'
to go all that distance.
- Pa, can I pack him in?
- Mm-mm.
No.
Not 'til we are damn
sure he tells the truth.
- I'm wonderin' what'll
happen at the farm.
- Well, Dean could
try murderin' us
the way he did to Weasel.
- I might.
- Or I could get him first.
Or we could kill each
other off for the gold.
Or we could start acting
like smart human beings and
try to help each
other to survive.
- Yeah.
Unless we find something
nobody's looking for.
Life is full of surprises.
(melancholic music)
Why don't you come
close to the fire?
All of us have gone
through dreadful things.
But like it or not, (chuckles)
life is the only thing we have.
- It's not much, is it?
- This morning I could see
what you were about to do.
- You're wrong.
I'm only waiting to
see all of you dead.
- Don't say that.
You know how I feel.
- You've done a lot
of things, Dean,
but don't lie to yourself.
In me you saw only the
possibility of a way out.
- Yes.
At the beginning, yes.
- And now it's too
late for us all.
- Hop to it, sons, we got a
rough trip to Fort Green, boys!
We'll never get
there dilly-dallyin'.
Get goin', you!
- Better move it, Pa.
We gotta grab 'em before
they get to that farm.
- If we overwork the horses,
son, we'll never get there.
(suspenseful music)
(clack)
(gun fires)
(groans)
(suspenseful music)
- [Joe] Well, there it is.
- Guess we'd better
wait 'til it gets dark.
- Do you think Caldwell
will recognize us?
- Your mother wouldn't
be able to recognize you.
(suspenseful music)
Good evenin'.
- A bottle of whisky.
- Cost ya $2.
- Nobody asked you the cost.
- You playin' cards or not?
(suspenseful music)
- Settle down, Caldwell.
We'll pay for it all.
- Where do I know you from?
- You and me had a
long friendly chat.
Long time ago.
Don't you recall?
- Got somethin' to eat?
- No, it's much too late.
- Are you sure?
Go take a look.
(clanging piano keys)
(whispers)
- You got any money?
Caldwell wants to see you.
- [Joe] Is this enough?
(Thomas chuckles)
- Maybe you ought
to look closer.
They're gold.
- It's gold, alright, Serge.
Pure gold.
- Think it's enough
to pay for everything?
- Bring us another bottle.
- Where'd you get it?
- None of your business.
Caldwell, we need a wagon
and six big strong horses.
And we'll swap ya.
A nice long piece
of this here chain.
Can you see to it?
- Oh, no. (chuckles)
You fellas are gonna
accompany me to Fort Green.
You're gonna come up with some
answers to some questions.
- What for, Sergeant?
We already been there.
It's a rotten cesspool.
- Come on, Sergeant.
Don't make things
complicated, huh?
Have a cigar.
(Joe laughs)
- Didn't my friends
order a bottle?
Can you give us a
wagon, Caldwell?
- I don't have any.
- You're lying.
- I swear it.
Why don't you search the place?
- You boys hear that?
- We'll have to
spend the night here.
But about eight in
the morning the wagon
from Fort Green comes
to get provisions.
True, Caldwell?
(Caldwell chuckles)
- Come on, boys,
have a drink with us.
Sergeant.
- [Sergeant] Yeah,
I'd be glad to.
(Joe laughs)
♪ Oh my darlin', oh
my darlin' Clementine
- [Officer] Give
me a swig of that.
(slurred singing)
- It was true.
The corral sure is empty.
- We'll just keep on waitin'.
It's only two hours
before daybreak.
- [Joe] That's enough!
(officers grumble)
- What about the soldiers?
- Get rid of 'em. (chuckles)
What else can we do with them?
- We're not even
crossing the border yet,
gotta get rid of the army.
Let's tie them up and
leave them in the corral.
By the time they're found,
we'll all be on the other side.
- Alright, soldier boys.
Time to get a little sleep.
(officers grumble)
(slurred singing)
- Oh, there's still time.
- Oh, the party's just
about to get started!
- You heard me!
Get out!
Out.
- [Sergeant] Alright, I'm goin'.
♪ Oh my darlin'
- Move it!
♪ Oh my darling Clementine
- What about a toast, to
our forthcoming separation?
What do you plan to do?
- To tell the
truth, I don't know.
- [Thomas] Is she
going with you?
- Yes.
(Thomas chuckles)
- I think you're wrong.
- Not your business.
(clock chimes)
- I guess you forgot, Caldwell.
But you and I have to
settle up an old account.
(chuckles)
Three years ago I passed by
here and wanted a bottle of gin.
I laid $5 on top of the counter.
- Let it lie.
(Joe chuckles)
- I'm bored!
And what's wrong with
talkin' with an old friend?
And you and I are
friends, eh? (chuckles)
(suspenseful music)
Right, Caldwell?
- [Caldwell] Don't know
what you're talkin' about.
- You took me up to Fort Green.
You beginning to recall?
You took the $5 and didn't
even give me the gin, friend.
And then you said, "since
you're going to jail,
"you won't be needing it."
Well now I'm gonna
collect that $5!
(Caldwell groans)
(clunk)
(Caldwell pants)
(Caldwell groans)
(soldiers snore)
(door creaks open)
- Sergeant.
Sergeant!
Wake up!
Wake up.
You've gotta notify Fort
Green to act and fast.
Please hurry up.
There's no time.
Please hurry.
(Sergeant groans)
(slaps)
(whines)
- I caught her trying
to free the soldiers.
(grunts)
(groans)
(suspenseful music)
(Dean groans)
- No!
(dark orchestral music)
(Cathy whines)
(screams)
No!
(sobs)
(clock ticks)
(melancholic orchestral music)
(dissonant piano notes)
- They're out there, get ready.
(suspenseful music)
(explosion)
(dramatic music)