Cyborg
Presented by BlueFixer  Subs
Who will take the world racing championship?
Japan or America? The USSR or England?
It's an incredible race!
Oh, it's Japan's Shimamura Joe!
He's pulling ahead of the pack.
His entire body is like one big mass of reflexes.
The fearless racer, Joe the Hurricane. Will he take the victory?!
Many years have passed since the terrible war.
An automobile race amongst peaceful nations.
Today, standing at the top once again, is Shimamura Joe.
However, on the other end of the course he races down...
A dreadful fate awaits him, one which will pull the world into darkness once more.
The victim? Where is the victim?
Then, that ambulance just now was a fake?!
Heheheheheheh... That went well.
The ambulance is a fake.
Arrest them immediately!
Hey, they're coming after us.
Hmph, don't worry about it.
We've brought Shimamura Joe's corpse.
I see.
I wish I could commend you for your good work, but you two made an unforgivable mistake.
The knife you left at the scene of the crime.
The Black Ghost Organisation demands perfection in all its work!
Mistakes will not be forgiven.
You called?
Bring Professor Gilmore to the surgery room and have him begin work on Shimamura Joe.
Alright, let's begin.
Scalpel.
Good.
Artificial heart.
Respiraton machine.
Joe! Open your eyes!
Open your eyes!
Huh?
Where in the world am I?
Just what am I doing here?
Ah! What are these clothes?
We'll start the test now.
Test?
What are you talking about?
I can't believe it!
Even after being crushed under all that concrete, I'm still perfectly fine!
I can run incredibly fast!
Hey, I'm alright!
Those bullets definitely hit me, but they didn't do a thing!
Okay!
Dammit!
Huh? I'm underwater but I can breathe easily!
Ahh... That was awful.
But I'm not tired at all.
Okay! It's a success!
Who? Who are you people?
The test is over.
You are the greatest cyborg we have ever created.
A test? Cyborgs?
That's right! You received an operation to make you into a cyborg!
A living being turned into something greater than it could ever be naturally by using the power of science.
That is a cyborg.
Your brain has had an artificial brain implanted in it making it many times better than it was before.
And for your lungs an artificial lung has been installed so you can breathe underwater.
All of your bones, muscles and skin have been strengthened with artificial materials.
You are no longer an ordinary human being.
You're a greatly improved cyborg!
From now on, you will be known as Cyborg 009!
Cyborg 009?!
Yes, the ninth weapon working for the Black Ghost Organisation.
009, allow me to introduce your fellow cyborg comrades!
Let's skip the introductions and you can all put your hands in the air!
What was that?! Stop joking around!
A joke? Not at all.
I couldn't do this as a joke!
Stop! Stop! Have you all gone mad?!
No, we're completely sane.
You the ones who gone mad!
That's right! We're not interested in being used as tools for your terrifying plans!
We'll be leaving this place.
Like he said. Sorry, Professors!
A-Are you serious?!
Do you honestly plan to rebel against us?!
Yeah, that's right!
Go!
Woah there! You'd better not try anything funny!
By the way, would you come with us, Professor Gilmore?
What?!
You'll be our hostage. If you value your life then hurry up and get over here!
And you, 009.
You come over here too.
We're like brothers.
Well, you can trust us.
009, from now on you will defend peace. Come with us.
Come on, 009.
Damn!
Alright, everyone, let's take off in the jet we prepared!
Wait, you traitors!
What are you waiting for?!
I can't pilot this.
It'll be fine! I'm sure you'll be able to do it.
First, twy pwessing the gween button.
What? You say the cyborgs escaped?
Please, forgive me! Please, forgive me!
Hmph! You ought to know that our Black Ghost Organisation never forgives mistakes!
Damnable cyborgs...
Do you think you can escape from Black Ghost?
Just when did I learn to fly a jet?
It's okay, 009.
Your superior senses as an auto racer have been multiplied several times by your artificial brain.
That's why Black Ghost was after your body.
But where should I fly to, 001?
Do as I say.
Fwy towards our base at 50°5' North, 35°20' East.
There's an island there.
001 has the body of a baby but he's a Brain Cyborg with ten times more thought power than the average adult.
Ahh, we're safe now.
We're finally free now, aren't we, 004?
Sure are. It was tough, 007.
It's good to be free.
Oops! Professor Gilmore's handcuffs...
I totally forgot.
Sorry about that, Professor.
My, my, I'm glad it all went well, everyone. Good work.
Huh? What did he say?
That's right. 009 didn't know anything about that yet, did he?
009, the truth is, this escape is something that I planned.
Then, Professor Gilmore, you were on our side?
Of course! Gil's our pal in the fight against evil!
It's embarassing to say, but I was being used by the Black Ghost without knowing anything.
But I became afraid of what I had been doing.
Why is that?
Because I found out what they were after!
What is that?
To start wars around the world disrupting the peace and reducing the Earth to a mass of evil.
Then, to take advantage of the chaos to make a huge profit.
That was their goal.
They're terrible!
We were almost used to help fulfill that objective.
And so we ran away.
That's right, if we were going to have to be their slaves we'd rather...
Shh! All of you keep quiet!
What is it, 003?!
I can hear them! Black Ghost's fighter planes!
And there's a lot of them! They're coming after this jet.
003 has super sight and hearing.
She can tell anything that happens within 50 kilometres.
They keep getting closer.
At this rate, they're going to catch us!
Alright, let's get 'em!
Alright, got you!
Ah! There's no bullets!
Oh no, then there's nothing we can do, is there?
They're gonna get us...!
Don't panic, everyone! Use your powers!
Yeah! The enemy are remote contwolled! No need to hold back! Get 'em!
Right, I'm on it!
I'll go too!
002 can fly at Mach 5.
Oh, here they come.
That it? That it?
006 can breathe flames of up to 7000 degrees.
Okay, even I can do this!
005. He has the strength of two thousand horses.
Don't worry about hitting them, 009, this plane's wings are sharp blades made from specialised steel.
Anything they hit will be split in two!
Really? Okay!
Good work, 009!
Whoops!
We go them all! They shouldn't come after us anymore.
That's a relief.
Good work, 009!
For your first time in an airplane, I'm amazed you could fight so well!
Huh?
What's wrong, mechanical troubles?!
Oh no! The engine's out of energy!
So it was no good after all?
We've just got no luck.
And it's onwy 10 kilometres to the island...
If we can make it, there's extwa energy hidden there.
10 kilometres? Okay!
Let's see whether or not we can do it!
We'll glide from here.
Our altitude keeps dropping...
I've got it! The island's right there!
Do your best. The island is surrounded by high cliffs.
If I screw up we'll ram right into the cliffs.
I've got a bad feeling about this.
Ah! We're going to crash!
S-S-Somebody save us!
This is no good! Fine then!
Now we're gonna fall into the sea!
As we fall we'll gain speed. We'll use that speed to rise up again.
That's from your experience as an auto-racer, isn't it?
Now!
It worked.
009, thank you, you saved us.
Hey, you've got some incredible abilities.
That's right, 009, you're a braver and more powerful cyborg than anyone else here.
By helping one another and perfecting your teamwork you'll be able to make full use of your power.
And the only one fit to lead and guide these eight, 009, is you.
Wow, he's our leader!
That's right! He'll lead our battle for peace and fweedom!
We're counting on you, 009.
All right, let's do it!
I'll do it! For peace and freedom!
Hurray!
All right, we've got no time to dawdle around.
Black Ghost ought to be desperately hunting for us.
First we have to decide what our next move will be.
Hmm, about that, for now...
Shh!
Someone's listening!
It must be an enemy spy!
Huh? Where?
Over there. See?
Is that all, 003? It's just a dolphin, isn't it?
No, that dolphin's a Spy Dolphin that's had it's brain modified and a transmitter implanted in its body.
All right, I'll take care of it!
Damn thing's swimming all calm like.
Good job, you hit the bullseye.
Ah, now there's something large underwater.
It's getting closer.
Is it a submarine?
No, it's not. I hear the sound of an entirely different machine.
Dinosaurs!
Everyone, let's run!
They got hit!
It'll be fine, they won't be taken out by something minor like that.
You were right.
Wah, that really suprise me.
Heheh, if I'm a rock too I won't get smashed.
See, I can turn my body's cells into anything.
These are the dinosaur robots that Black Ghost's so proud of.
We can't go anywhere while they're here.
Fine then. Let's wreck 'em.
002, pull me by the arm.
Okay!
Now, let go!
Dammit!
Whoa there!
Thanks.
Alright, now for this missile...
Okay, that's good. We got all of them.
Hurray!
It's too early to relax 007.
Accowding to my calcuwations the enemies will keep on coming.
That's right.
W-W-What's going to come next?
The roar of machines.
Ship engines.
Submarines.
It's a massive fleet!
This island is completely surrounded in both the skies and the sea.
Heh, they're really overdoing this.
There're only ten of us...
I can't blame them. You're all prototypes that may bring about a great change in the future.
They have to bring you back no matter what it takes.
Eeagh, t-t-this's bad. Let's hide.
It's impossible. Look at those.
Aren't those just bugs?
Those bugs' eyes have been tuwned into spy camewas. They're spy insects.
The enemy alweady know where we are.
What detestable bugs!
They know everything about your abilities.
Every moment we spend here puts us at a greater disadvantage.
Somehow, we've got to get out of here and make our way to Green Reef.
But the jet's out of fuel. How are we gonna go?
Alright, let's help ourselves to one of their subs.
Uh, the marine cyborg was 008, right?
Yeah, leave the underwater stuff to me!
I can stay there for hours.
Then, 008... and 007...
Come with me!
Hey, wait for me!
This's no good.
Here they come.
Let's take that sub!
But we can't get near them with that Spy Dolphin there.
007, I'll let you take care of that.
Okay.
Come on over here. This way. This way.
This way. This way. This way. Oops.
Okay, 008, I'm counting on you.
Okay!
Huh? What was that?
Oh, our signal just got cut off.
Our sonar's not working either!
Oh, we've received a transmission.
The cyborgs are nearby.
We've been ordered to surface.
What?
Okay, take us up!
Why you!
Don't move, cyborg!
Hands in the air!
You're the ones who'll be putting your hands in the air.
Say what?!
Throw down your guns!
Don't worry, we won't kill you.
We'll just be taking your ship.
This is good.
Now for the finale.
003, send out a message in Morse code.
Right.
"Submarine #557 has been captured by the cyborgs."
Not 556. 557.
C-Captain, something's strange!
All of our subs and planes are rushing towards this ship!
Eh? What did you say? That's ridiculous!
Uwah! You were right!
That went well.
Now, full-speed ahead to Green Reef.
What's this Green Reef place?
I have a laboratory there.
It's not on the maps and Black Ghost doesn't know about it either.
It's my quiet, secret island.
Nice shot!
Ahh, it's so quiet here...
It's almost too quiet. I'm starting to get bored.
It's been a long time since I've been able to relax like this.
While we're relaxing here those Black Ghost guys may be plotting something.
We should attack their base and put an end to this quickly.
No! I'm tired of war!
War has taken everything from me.
My father, my mother and my happiness too...
It took all of them away from me.
003, you were from France weren't you?
Yes, I was born in the suburbs of Paris at Versailles.
My name was Francoise.
My dream was to become a ballerina.
And to dance around the world.
My mother died...
My father died too...
The war took all my happiness away from me.
Taking me and making me into a cyborg to fight in your war...
It's cruel! It's just too cruel!
I see... I understand, 003.
But you aren't the only one crying about the sad fate thrust upon you by the war.
If we leave a group like Black Ghost alone they'll only create more victims like you.
Do you understand?
The only ones who can topple the terrifying Black Ghost organisation... are us.
Yes, I understand.
We may die fighting them, but if that can make it so all the people in the world can be happy...
If the entire world can be at peace...
Wouldn't that be good enough, Francoise?
If we don't do it, there isn't anyone else left who can, right?
That's right! Let's give it everything we've got!
We'll use everyone's powers to create a world of peace.
That's right. I'll do my best.
We can't dawdle around any longer!
We'll send this world spinning into chaos.
At the same time, we'll bring down the hammer of justice on Professor Gilmore and those traitorous cyborgs.
Begin the plan immediately.
The Black Ghost Organisation took two nations which were already on bad terms...
The Caesar Republic and the country of Divine...
Manipulating both nations in secret they moved them towards a state of war.
Tensions broke between the two nations and the flames of war spread rapidly.
Cannons roared in the cities.
The sound of explosions enveloped the towns.
The people forgot the commandments of their god and cast aside peace.
All without knowing who was behind everything.
What fools! They've totally fallen for it!
If this war spreads, we'll be able to rake in tons of cash!
When that happens I'm sure Gilmore and the Cyborgs won't keep quiet about it.
They're sure to show up.
This is what they call "killing two birds with one stone."
I think this war is clearly Black Ghost's work.
We have to find proof of that and bring back peace.
Everyone agrees, right?
Yeah!
Alright! Let's begin the mission then!
003!
006!
Right.
And 007!
Yes Sir!
You three will come with me.
First, we'll go to the battlefield and see what's going on.
There's no doubt that those Black Ghost guys are up to something!
The rest of you can stay here for now and protect Professor Gilmore.
009, allow me to present you with something nice.
Something nice?
The fruit of my studies.
Now, take this.
Go forth and crush the nefarious plans of those war mongers!
Akai muffler nabikasete.
Their red scarves flutter in the wind.
Sususme saiboogu! Warera no yuushi.
Keep on going, Cyborgs! Our heroes.
Heiwa wo mamoru seigi no hitomi.
Defenders of peace. The eyes of justice.
Yukute wa arashi da. Hoeru umi.
In their way is a storm. The howling sea!
Oozora saegiru kuroi kumo.
Black clouds which blot out the sky.
Heiwa no teki da. Sekai no teki da.
The enemies of peace. The enemies of the world.
Chikara no kagiri tatakau zo!
Fight them with all your strength!
Akai muffler nabikasete.
Their red scarves flutter in the wind.
Sususme saiboogu! Warera no yuushi.
Keep on going, Cyborgs! Our heroes.
Heiwa wo mamoru seigi no hitomi
Defenders of peace. The eyes of justice.
Aa Saiboogu 009
Oh, Cyborg 009!
We're getting close to the Ceasar Republic's base.
Let's dive and do some reconnaissance.
Beginning submersion.
003, use the underwater camera.
Right.
What's this?
I see a new model of tank.
Let's try zooming in a bit more.
Ah! That guy's from Black Ghost!
That's one of their tanks behind him too.
He's saying "If you buy 5000 of these tanks the country of Divine will be no match for you."
What an awful bastard.
He's taking advantage of the war to make a profit.
He what they call a "Merchant of Death".
"Yeah, I gotcha."
"I'll contact military headquarters and have them buy some right away."
Dammit.
Alright! Let's go investigate Divine as well!
He's saying "With these, there's no way you'll lose to the Caesar Republic's airforce."
What horrible people.
"Consider them bought. I'll sign the order form now."
Guys like that are even more cruel and evil then the people actually fighting the war.
Jerks...
Right, 003?
Huh? 003's gone.
003!
Get down!
It's Black Ghost!
Damn... We're not going to let you beat us!
It's a good thing we had 003 carry a transmitter.
They're heading to Phantom Island, as expected.
They plan to carry 003 back to their secret base.
Nothing is more evil than kidnapping a young girl.
Okay, let's go to Phantom Island!
Phantom Island?!
That is terrifying island where we were made into cyborgs!
If we don't act quickly 003 will be in danger!
And that secret base is Black Ghost's headquarters.
If we destroy it and wipe out their resources, we can stop this war.
We absolutely have to do this for the sake of peace.
Understood. "Fear nothing. Summon courage. Strike at root of evil." Right?
Hmm... I don't understand complicated stuff, but if it's for peace I'll do anything!
Okay, let's go!
So you've come, Cyborgs.
Fire ET waves!
It's Phantom Island.
How I've missed it!
What you nostalgic about?!
Listen. Last time, we fled that island thinking only of our own happiness.
But now we're sneaking back in for the happiness of all the people in the world.
It's weird. I feel much calmer than when we were trying to escape.
"To catch tiger cub you must enter tiger den." "Venture nothing, gain nothing." They say.
But be careful.
They're the ones who created us cyborgs.
We don't know what kind of terrifying enemies may appear.
Ouch!
The ship's stopped!
What's going on?!
There is something squeezing the ship.
At this rate we'll be crushed.
Fine, let's go outside!
Oh, it's a giant octopus!
Look out!
I know! They're using special radio waves to make it more aggressive.
Everyone be careful!
Keep still!
Need little more vinegar. This octopus. I- Ow! Ow! Ow!
Now you done it!
Oh, Daddy!
Alright!
I'll grind you up!
Grind, grind, grind, grind, grind, grind.
Okay, I'll use a depth charge!
That did it!
Damn, that thing was even more of a pain to deal with than the robots!
Something else is coming!
Sharks!
Not just sharks... Sharks with guided missiles!
They're Black Ghost weapons.
The shark's instinct to attack is hooked into the missile guidance system.
Ah! They're after the ship!
Don't let the missiles hit the ship!
I know! Break the sharks' guidance systems!
I take care of line over there.
Ninja Art: Shark Transformation
Looks a bit strange, but oh well.
These things are dumb as a sack of hammers.
Ah, I'm exhausted.
Now we safe.
Now, let's hurry. I'm worried about 003.
You traitor.
We're going to give you an operation to make sure you never think of doing such a horrible thing again.
Heheheheheh... You'll lose the ability to think and judge for yourself.
In short, you'll be Black Ghost's loyal slave acting only on the signals we send you.
We've finally made it to the enemy's base. Don't let your guards down.
G-G-God let no ghosts come out.
Ahh! Cobras!
Are these things robots?!
Excuse me.
Have to be very careful.
Mountains, rivers, grass and trees. Nature is terrifying enemy.
Seriously, this place is creepy. I feel awful.
I wish we'd never come here.
There's no resting on this island, really.
-Ah!
-Look out!
It's no good! That bastard's tough.
Nothing we can do.
Hahahahahahah... Is that all the power you can muster?!
You won't be able to beat me like this!
Lets do this!
Ahh! It is getting hot!
Ah! Save me!
Hot! Hot Hot Hot Hot!
Wait...
Compared to the rest of its body... that eye is pretty small.
There's got to be a reason.
Guys! Shoot at the same place that I do!
Yessir!
Now!
Its eyes were its weak point.
Hey! You! The cool guy over there!
What're you?
I'm a new recruit. Just got here today.
You're a bit short, aren't you?
Heheheh... Don't worry about it. Don't worry about it.
Here, a gift between new comrades.
Piece of cake! You can come out now!
Stealthily, stealthily....
Uh oh!
That was dangerous... Alright.
Squeak.
Strange place full of strange things.
No room to let your guard down here.
Ah! Get down!
Damn! That was dangerous...
I have bad feeling.
Stealthily...
Agh! It's a cat!
It's a dead end!
Wink.
W-What's that?!
Is 003!
Hey, 003!
They kill her?
003!
Hey! Hang in there!
Hey!
Namu amida butsu. Namu amida butsu.
What's wrong, 003?
Hahahaha! Good work, 003!
You fools! You've fallen into our trap wonderfully!
003 isn't your comrade anymore.
Oh no! Were we too late?
Hey! There should be one left! Hunt him down!
Sir, we've already captured 007.
Have you? That's good.
007's been caught too?
It because he so scatterbrained.
Shut up! Quit your grumbling.
You! Take their weapons!
Yes Sir!
Okay, now we'll use brain surgery to turn 007 into a loyal slave of Black Ghost like we did with 003.
However, you two won't be so lucky!
Your cybernetic systems are so complicated that further brain surgery is impossible.
As such, you have my sympathies, but you're going to have to die here.
Take aim!
Damn, this is really too bad.
We done for.
Fire!
Now!
Catch!
Who are you?!
Sometimes a rat...
Sometimes a cat...
At other times a soldier of Black Ghost...
But my true identity is the cyborg of Love and Truth, 007!
007!
Why you! Shoot all three of them!
Come. Come. Come this way.
Ninja Art: Bazooka Shuriken!
Bazooka!
Oh no!
Stop!
You jerk!
You can't escape now!
It look like you should give up.
You're the boss, so act like one.
W-Wait!
I'm not the boss of Black Ghost!
What did you say?!
Lying is bad.
I-It's true!
You think you can trick us?!
Wait, there's someone else in this room.
The real boss... The real war profiteer...
Is right there!
Good job, 009.
You did well to figure it out.
You cockroaches... Do you wish to see my true form so badly?
Beagle...
Take responsibility for your failure.
009, as you've guessed, I am the boss of Black Ghost.
Why you!
It's not just Black Ghost...
I've been starting wars between you foolish humans since long ago.
The first and second world war were both my work.
Feeding on the blood of the slaughter, the tears of the suffering and the hatred of one man for another...
I've gradually grown bigger and stronger.
Even when the war ends and the losing generals and politicians are executed...
No one has ever tried to punish me.
They all speak of peace, but all it takes is a little whisper from me and the humans soon begin the killing.
What fools!
You devil!
You're wrong!
I did not create myself.
What created me and helped me grow was the ugly greed that lies in the heart of mankind!
Well, that's enough of that.
It seems the end has come for you.
As a small mercy, I'll let you be sent off to the next world at the hands of your former comrade.
Come forth, my adorable 003.
That's a specially made electron gun.
Ideal for shooting cyborgs.
Now, 003, finish them and don't hold back.
Wait, 003! Don't you recognise us?!
003, wait!
Stop this! Don't you recognise us?
Stop! Give me the gun!
Let go!
003!
Now you've done it, 009!
Hang in there, 003.
What... happened to me?
009, this time it's my loss.
I shall perish but the Black Ghost will not be destroyed.
And now you're finished.
When I die the detonator on the H-Bomb will begin its countdown.
Say what?!
H-Bomb?!
That's right. In five minutes this whole island will be blown away.
Farewell, my brave little heroes.
-T-This is terrible!
-We have to run!
Damn this wall!
It's no good 009! That wall is made with a super special steal alloy!
I-It's only another four minutes!
Okay, we'll put all our power together.
006, use all the heat you can to melt that wall.
Right!
Everyone, shoot the same spot with your ray guns.
I run out of energy soon.
Do your best! Keep shooting for as long as you've got the energy!
It's working! It's started to melt!
Only three minutes left!
How about this?!
It's open!
Everyone follow me!
Hurry! The exit's this way!
Let's hurry and get aboard! The bomb's going to go off!
Not gonna happen, Cyborgs!
We're taking this ship.
Damn...
Alright, everyone, let's set sail. Start the engine!
There's only a minute left.
Later! Just stay there and get blown up!
You guys!
We came after you because we figured something like this might happen.
No time to waste! There's onwy 15 seconds until the expwosion!
Press the flight button!
Three... Two... One...
And so, the devil was defeated and the people awakened.
An end came to the battle and peace returned to the world once more.
The cyborgs' work was finished.
They returned to their original forms and each returned to their homelands.
009, to being the auto-racer Shimamura Joe.
003, to being a ballerina in Paris.
007, to being a mischievous brat in London.
They returned to the lives originally granted to them by God.
However, the evil Black Ghost, that dark dream of war...
The Black Ghost, nurtured by the ugly greed in people's hearts...
Can anyone truly say that they shall never return?
"I shall perish but the Black Ghost will not be destroyed."
When that time come we'll have to gather once more.
I hope that never happens.
Lord, let this peace last forever.
END