- Heave up.
- Anchors aweigh, sir.
- All engines ahead one third.
- Engines ahead one third.
- Anchor in sight.
Clear anchor, sir.
- Secure anchors for sea.
All engines ahead standard.
Engines ahead standard.
- Ready, Captain?
- Ready, Colonel.
Attention all officers of Special Force Six.
Attention. All officers of Special Force Six,
proceed immediately
to the wardroom on A deck forward.
Officers only. Immediately, please.
I was also told today that the Germans
have thickened up the mines on the beach.
Accordingly, a small party of sappers
was landed three hours ago by submarine,
to clear a path across the beach
at the base of the cliff.
They have since reembarked safely,
but your men will avoid unnecessary
spreading out across the beaches.
Now commit yourselves boldly and quickly.
Hesitation won't save casualties,
it'll cost casualties.
We've some hard knocks to take,
but if we start boldly,
more of us will be alive when it's all over.
My only regret is that
I've not had time to get to know any of you,
during the few days that I've been with you.
But despite the unfortunate circumstance
that deprived you
of your original commander,
I feel you have given me
your confidence and cooperation. Thank you.
Now, I've always found it's a good idea
to put the operation completely out of mind
during the last few hours before zero.
So shall we do that, gentlemen?
That's all. Good luck.
If he fights as well as he talks,
those Krauts are in for a bad time.
He will. Don't let anybody say different.
Yeah. I guess if a guy's got it,
you can smell it a mile away. I'll see you.
- Sir?
- Oh, Brooks.
Yes, Captain. I was told
to report to you after the briefing.
Get all your platoon sergeants together.
When we hit the beach, there'll be
no running outside the cleared line.
It'll be marked.
The rest of the beach is mined.
- Yes, sir.
- Oh, Tom?
- Sir?
- How you feelin'?
- Lousy.
- Me too.
- Parker?
- Sir.
- I thought it was you. Feeling a bit edgy?
- Afraid I am, sir.
- I take it this is your first show?
- Yes, sir.
It's the best, Captain Parker.
The first one is always the best.
You have all your luck riding with you.
- How many of these have you been on, sir?
- Off the sea? About half a dozen.
Some duds. Some fairly good.
It's odd, meeting like this.
- She told you?
- Oh, yes.
Treacherous old beast, the Channel.
At least the Germans'll
never expect us, not in this weather.
Try and get some sleep.
Even a minute or two makes a difference.
They'll have to beach us
higher than these breakers.
They'll need luck.
I'm not sending men waist-deep into this sea
with 60-pound mortars on their backs.
Aren't you?
But if the boats don't carry up the beach,
you haven't any choice, have you?
Why don't you take your own advice
and stop thinking about it?
It used to be so easy for you, in the desert.
All you had to do was to think back.
Think back to that wonderful,
unspoiled time before Egypt,
when she didn't owe you anything because
you weren't a hero then, and wounded.
You wanted to ask her a question. It was 1942.
You had so little time.
Bailey, why don't you pop to that pub?
I'll meet you there.
We oughtn't to stay long, sir,
if we're to rejoin that convoy.
All right. You get yourself a beer.
With lights, of course,
it'd be a different story.
Captain Wynter. Come in quickly, sir.
The Brigadier will be so pleased to see you.
- Mala, is Miss Valerie about?
- Yes, Captain Wynter.
- Yes, Mala. Who is it?
- It is Captain Wynter, sir.
It's not polite, barging in on you, sir.
- But all the telephone lines...
- Sh.
.. the arrival of
reinforcements, including American tanks,
is regarded in military circles in Cairo
as certain to turn the tide of battle strongly in
our favor within a matter of days, if not hours.
General Dittmar's weekly broadcast...
- John!
- Hello, Valerie.
What on earth are you doing here?
Some would say a bad thing. I say a good.
In fact, I broke out of a convoy.
- Broke out of a convoy?
- Good for you.
- An embarkation privilege I allowed myself.
- Embarkation?
- Yes. I'm off, Val.
- How do you mean, off?
The division's
only been training two months.
I'm not with the division any more. It's
a reinforced company, a small Commando.
- I volunteered and they gave it to me.
- Did you have to volunteer?
There's no such thing as having to volunteer,
girl. Contradiction in terms.
It's just that I have a rather singular theory.
The quicker more of us go off,
the quicker more of us'll get back.
It's a rather illogical theory too, I suppose.
Don't be annoyed about it, please.
I suppose you can't
tell me where you're going?
- Some place haunted by the lizard, I imagine.
- Ah. Shepherd's Hotel, Cairo.
- Father.
- You're looking very fit, sir.
I am fit. Sit down, Wynter.
Two years. Two years since Dunkirk,
and they keep me on the sick list.
Well, when I do go back,
they'll have to give me a division.
Of course, I know why they're keeping
me here. They're afraid I'll fight.
When you do get your division, sir, I'd be
very proud if I could serve with you again.
And I'd want you, Wynter.
You've got the makings.
You had them at St. Omer in '40.
You know,
I've missed our talks this past winter.
Thank you, sir. Me too.
- Sir?
- What?
Would you mind if Valerie and I
took a walk to the pub?
Nonsense. You'll find nothing there.
- I'll fix you something to keep the cold out.
- Father, please. I would like to.
Oh, my dear fellow.
Please, please forgive me.
I got so used to your official visits, I...
That's all right, sir.
That German bomber again. He always tries
to make the runway at the bomber station.
He never does, though. Can't hit a thing.
There's a boy down the road
with an ak-ak gun.
British, and he can't hit a thing either.
And the grown-ups sit around in Whitehall
waiting for the Americans to come.
- More boys.
- Goodbye, sir.
Well, good luck, then, Wynter.
Get wherever you're going, but for goodness'
sake come to close quarters with the Hun.
A bit of cold steel now is worth
20 American bombers in a year's time.
- Right, sir.
- It sounds old-fashioned, but try it.
You'll find it'll work wonders.
- I'm afraid Father's terribly jealous.
- Of you?
No, silly, of you,
going to the war without him.
I'm afraid he'll die here
if they don't give him something to do.
Well, it can't be very easy
for you either, Val.
I've hardly been a mile
beyond the common in the last two years.
I feel rather like a yearling that's
very much grown up, but still tethered.
You're still in the ATS.
Can't you get ordered to London?
I am. I'm going next month. And ironically,
I'm working for the American Red Cross.
Oh. Won't your father mind?
The Americans, I mean.
No, he accepts the Red Cross,
because it's so universal.
- Val.
- Yes, John?
I wouldn't want anything I'd said
to make you feel tethered.
- But I did want to say that...
- Yes, John?
It isn't life and death
if you don't feel the same.
While I'm gone, in a terribly strong way,
I'm going to need you.
John, I...
Just to be able to think of you,
write to you, to know that you're here.
Because everything
that I'm leaving behind has become...
Well, you, suddenly.
- Bailey.
- Yes, sir.
- I'll be with you in a sec.
- Right, sir.
- Does it make any sense?
- Yes, John.
It makes all the sense in the world.
Please. You're notjust saying that?
Don't you understand that
I need you just as much as you need me?
Just as we started to know each other,
you're going away.
And I'd have felt so, sort of,
safe and useless and alone
without someone to be proud of,
and frightened for,
and to be waiting for when they come back,
and to live for when it's all over.
This is going to have to last me a long time.
I'm glad there's a moon for us.
There'll be more. Lots of them.
Whenever you see it,
the moon I mean, promise to imagine
I'm looking at it at the exact same moment.
In Egypt, the desert, anywhere.
- It'll be the same moon.
- I promise.
- All clear?
- All clear.
Assault craft will be lowered away
at 0420, Colonel Wynter.
- Thanks.
- Good luck, Colonel.
Oh, Chief? How we doin'?
Pretty steady, sir. 10, 11 knots, I'd say.
Be a couple more hours.
- You in a hurry, sir?
- Sure. A hurry to get it over with.
Can't blame you at that.
- Been over here long, Captain?
- Two years, three months.
- Tough.
- Yeah.
But it wasn't so tough. Not at first.
Not when you got to London.
You didn't know anything about Valerie then,
or the sixth of June,
or this feeling of being expendable
for the first time in your life.
You had a well-pressed uniform, a staff job
in London, a pretty wife back home,
You really had it made.
Or did you?
Stop trying to find the war, Parker.
- Means nothing, huh?
- Not in daytime.
Probably just a Messerschmitt 110,
heard a new Captain hit town
and came for a snapshot.
- He'll be 50 miles away by now.
- How's the razor blade situation over here?
Get all you want at the PX.
Blades, soap, and I can get you some Scotch.
Hey, pretty fancy.
- "Brad and Janie." Wives are devious.
- Oh, I don't know. I kind of like mine.
- Did you promise never to take it off?
- That's right.
I can't say that I blame you. She's a beaut.
I heard the Colonel say that
you publish a newspaper in Connecticut.
- My father-in-law is a publisher.
- Same difference.
It'll still make the old man happy.
That's the all clear.
We're late. When you've got an appointment
with Colonel Alexander Timmer,
publisher or no publisher, you keep it.
Here it is, Parker. Headquarters, European
Theater of Operations, United States Army.
Your new home.
Watch it, now. You're gonna be
married to this guy for a long, long time.
- How does he like his eggs?
- Hard-boiled.
Behind that door, you'll find
an ex-car salesman from Minneapolis.
who's conducting
a very vigorous war to make General.
And thank your lucky stars
you weren't at West Point.
- What's wrong with West Point?
- Nothing.
Except that Lieutenant Colonel Alexander
Timmer didn't happen to go there. Good luck.
Yeah.
Captain Parker, sir.
I was ordered to report to you.
All right, Parker. Relax.
That's the way it's gonna be, Ed.
Remember,
possession is nine points of the law.
The General will be
the bestjudge of that, Timmer.
Cry on the General's shoulder
if you want. It's got stars on it.
And he's a West Point man.
Maybe he'll see it your way.
- But those new officers are in my section.
- Your section?
Very well, Timmer. We'll see what happens.
Talking of new officers,
Captain Parker, Colonel Cantrell.
- How do you do, sir?
- How do you do?
- See you, Timmer.
- Right.
Mr. West Point Honor Cadet.
Parker, there's just one thing
I ask of the men under me.
- Can you keep your mouth shut?
- I was briefed on security.
- Where?
- Fort Harrison, sir.
Kid stuff.
Now you gotta live and breathe security.
- You want some coffee?
- No, thanks.
You know why I picked you, mostly?
Those parachute wings.
- I was invalided out of the airborne.
- Yeah, I know all about you, Parker.
I ran a full-scale
security check on you myself.
So, you broke your leg jumping.
Well, for my dough
you're still a fighting man. So am I.
Some of this brass here doesn't
quite realize that, but they will.
So will Ed Cantrell. He thinks he'll get
those chickens on his shoulders before I do.
Well, he's wrong. He's so wrong, Parker.
Where are you billeted?
- Captain Boyce. I'm sharing his apartment.
- Ray Boyce? He's smart. Maybe too smart.
Billeting with Boyce doesn't mean
he's gotta know everything you do.
- Understood?
- Understood, sir.
- And don't be a knuckle man. Speak up.
- Yes, sir.
Now, here are some target tracings we're
proposing for Operation Sledgehammer.
Familiarize yourself with them.
Then you'll run them to 632nd Bombardment
at Barkstow, Lincolnshire. Major Mills.
We'll see if the fellows at operational level
have different ideas.
- Thank you, sir.
- Right.
Hey. Easy on that, Parker, now. Easy.
- Here we are, fellas, back in the graveyard.
- They oughta give the town back to the Saxs.
They were smart. They hightailed it
outta here a thousand years ago already.
- Wow!
- Oh, come on.
Don't rush me. Come on, give me
a break, will ya? Don't rush me.
- Look, Bill. Soldiers!
- I say.
- Hey, fellas, look. The Home Guard.
- Left, right. Left, right.
Oh, here comes the infantry.
- Look at 'em drill.
- Left, right. Left, right. Left, right.
- Taxi.
Left, right. Left, right.
Left, right. Left, right. Left, right.
You know, my grandmother
could lick 'em all and she's two years dead.
Platoon halt!
Order arms.
- You guys really expect to win the war?
- Hey, move over.
Eyes front.
- Look at the little one.
- Like a Boy Scout.
- What is that?
- Look alive, chaps.
This is rifle drill, not cricket practice.
I say, chaps. It ain't cricket, you know.
Cricket? It ain't even marbles.
Come on, get that lead out, dad.
- Get that lead out!
- Don't look now, but we've got an audience.
You men will give me
your names, ranks and numbers.
- You.
- Oh, get lost.
You fellas down at Plans sure have it easy.
An office and a mimeograph machine
and bingo, you're operational.
Asking us to suggest targets
for Operation Sledgehammer!
On the target date they've got here,
we couldn't hit a tin can.
I was just ordered to get some tracings,
and with your help, I will do that.
We'll have 'em in the morning.
Major Mills here.
Yeah. Well, why bother me with it?
Do I have to handle
the provost marshal's work too?
What?
Oh, no. A brigadier?
A wounded brigadier?
I'll be right in.
- You come with me, Parker.
- Me?
Yes, you. It's time you guys in London
found out what we go through here.
- You like three-day passes?
- Yes, sir.
Remember 'em. You won't see any more.
What's your version, Gerbett?
- You often hit old men?
- I didn't see him till after I had hit him, sir.
I don't care if I get busted
back to private for this.
I don't have to take a whippin'
from any of them, sir.
So you ride men
who are doing their best to win the war?
No more than they ride us. They've given us
the silent treatment since we got here.
They act like they're doing us a favor, lettin'
us come here. If we're not good enough,
- why can't they fight their own war?
- That's enough.
- Take them back to base, Captain.
- Yes, sir. Anderson, take over.
Sir. Into the truck.
Hate to see morale go to pot,
but what can I do?
- Aircrew?
- Sure, aircrew.
Soon they'll be flying
combat missions over Germany in daylight.
We'd better get to see the brigadier.
I will inform the brigadier,
but I'm not sure he wishes to see anyone.
Brace yourself, Captain.
She's only the servant.
You'd think we weren't alive.
Gentlemen?
Major Mills,
group adjutant at the bomber station.
This is Captain Parker
of ETO Headquarters.
Yes?
Brigadier, I'd like to offer my regrets for
the behavior of one of our men this morning.
We'll have the man up on charges, of course,
and I think I can assure you
he'll be adequately dealt with.
If there are any ill-effects from the blow,
we will be glad to entertain any claim
for the discomfort you've suffered.
- Do you hear me, sir?
- I hear you perfectly, Major Mills.
But you haven't told me why your men
are permitted to loaf about the village,
shouting and using vile language.
The village is not off-limits
to our men, sir. As to...
Then I suggest
you consider putting it off-limits.
That's a pretty drastic thing to do.
I can think of rather harsher orders I have
issued without the slightest difficulty.
I don't blame you for feeling bitter.
The fact that you were struck
by one of our enlisted men...
- It was I who struck him, Major Mills.
- Surely, sir, you gave him some warning?
I am not in the habit of parleying
with rabble disguised in uniform.
That member of the "rabble" is an American
airman, who's over here to fight a war.
The war has been on
for some considerable time now.
I suggest he begin fighting it.
He'll fight it all right.
And probably die all right.
Until then, he might usefully occupy his time
learning to conduct himself like a soldier.
He'll conduct himself like a soldier
in the gun turret of his B-17,
- flying over Germany in daylight.
- All right, Parker.
You're entitled to slop over
your men if you like. I don't.
And may I now offer you
a glass of sherry, Major?
No thank you, sir. Not right now.
In that case, gentlemen, good afternoon.
I am sorry. We came with the best intentions.
But darn it,
we've got to run our business our way.
Will you please leave, gentlemen?
- Thanks, Parker. When I get mad I dry up.
- Not me.
Who do these characters think they are?
They were licked in '40
and they're taking a walloping.
They won't admit they're dead pigeons.
They need us inferior Americans, who've no
manners but a lot of power and know-how,
- It's killing 'em.
- Hold it.
Let her hear. What's the difference?
My name is Valerie Russell.
You've just seen my father.
- It's just one of those things, Miss Russell...
- Will those men be punished?
- Do you think they should be?
- No, absolutely not.
If your father complains
to the War Office, we'll get a rocket.
Well, he was wrong to do what he did.
I shan't be here after tomorrow, Major,
but I do want to say this.
My father isn't well, and changes
frighten him. Americans mean changes.
- He was wrong, but please try to understand.
- Believe me, I...
Please. You see,
when he was wounded at Dunkirk,
he felt that the England
he had loved had gone forever.
Of course it hadn't,
but he's quite afraid now of lots of things.
He's been through two wars
and quite badly, really,
with all the stupidity and waste of the first
and the angry pride and despair of this one.
But I do love my father,
and I just don't know Americans.
But you are here and fighting the war,
and most of us want to try
and help you and make you feel welcome,
But it's difficult, because some of us,
and the older ones particularly,
are proud of what we've done, perhaps for
that reason prouder than we've a right to be,
and therefore prouder than we've ever been.
But please don't punish those men, Major,
and try to understand us.
We're not awfully good at being thankful.
We haven't had occasion to be thankful
to anyone, except possibly God,
for several hundreds of years.
But we'll try. You'll see.
Well, shut my mouth.
- Parker.
- Hm? Oh.
- Excuse me.
- Good morning, Miss Russell.
- In thatjeep, yesterday?
- Oh, yes. How nice of you to remember me.
- In the army, huh?
- Yes, in the army.
I'm with your people,
the American Red Cross.
Lucky Red Cross.
ETOUSA's where I work.
- European Theater of Operations, U.S. Army.
- Sounds like a nice big place.
- There are no seats back there.
- Oh, dear.
Well, there are none back there either, so...
Luckily, I've brought my own.
- Ah, mind if I share that with you, love?
- Well... Oh.
- Well, actually it's reserved for the Captain.
- Oh.
Americans. Top priority, I suppose.
Always get the best of everything.
Thank you.
Major Mills and I appreciated what you said.
It was like a breath of fresh air.
You must have been dying for fresh air.
All I said was that I don't know Americans.
From a Britisher, that's close
to a compliment these days.
- Oh, we're terrible, aren't we?
- Sort of.
But you people do love to be liked,
don't you, all of you?
- All of us? Let's not get too impersonal.
- Tell the truth.
If you're asking me if I'd like you to like me...
You know jolly well that wasn't what
I was asking. I couldn't care less.
- I guess that puts me in my place.
- I'm sorry.
- We have the foulest manners in the world.
- Let's say "effective."
They're designed to make
strangers feel stranger. They work.
- Cigarette?
- Mm. Thank you.
Are those American cigarettes, sir?
Mind if I try one?
- Go right ahead.
- Do you mind if I do?
- Oh, thank you so much.
- Cigarettes, girls. Look.
- Thank you so much, sir.
- Oh, I say. It's empty.
- You're so generous.
- Two more whole packs here.
- The "Arsenal of Democracy."
- What?
Tell me the truth.
Under these cold, bad manners of ours,
you love to think we're simply
green with envy for you, don't you?
While you may envy us,
you don't respect us, That's pretty ugly.
- That is ugly, Captain Parker. You're right.
- Brad.
- Huh?
- I said Brad. It's my name. Call me Brad.
Oh. Brad.
All right. My name's Valerie.
But please don't call me Val.
- You don't like it?
- Not particularly. But...
- Somebody else calls me it...
- And you don't like him?
Yes, I like him very much.
- In London?
- No, Africa.
- Lonely war.
- I hate it.
Well, I have a love, too. My wife Janie.
- Lucky. What's she like?
- Beautiful.
- Children?
- No, no children yet.
- You probably have friends in London?
- I used to, before the war.
Well, if not, perhaps
you'd share an occasional meal
with a man who seems
due to be pretty lonely.
- You're very kind.
- Which is British for "no"?
Which is British for "I'd love to."
You turn left on Shaftesbury Avenue, and
it's facing you on Great Windmill Street.
It's supposed to be a pretty good show, huh?
Yes, I believe it is, of it's kind, very.
I hope you enjoy the show.
Know somethin'? I was over there
watchin' you a while back,
and I said to myself,
"She don't look like an English girl."
As a matter of fact, you remind me
a lot of a girl I knew back home.
A real peach of a girl.
Boy, did we make beautiful music together!
Really? You'd better run along,
Lieutenant, or you'll miss the show.
- Brad!
- Good evening.
- You know, I suddenly realized,
going out with me may be
kind of a postman's holiday for you.
But I've been
looking forward to it so much, I promise.
May I ask one professional question?
Where's a good place
to take an English girl out to dinner?
- Well, there's a little Italian place on...
- How about a big Italian?
- On the expensive side?
- Preferably.
Wailing violins, false Chianti
and black-market steak?
- Sounds too good to be true.
- I know just the place.
Well, now that you've been with us
for a week, how do you like us?
So far, I've specialized in
very young officers who are very homesick.
- The others make passes, huh?
- Oh, yes.
One man came to my desk
wearing a wedding ring.
He went to the other side of the room,
came back minus the ring,
and invited me to the theater.
- I think you'd better go back to Barkstow.
- Oh, nonsense.
Some of them aren't such fools. They can
catch you off balance. Air Force, especially.
You know, you think of war
and of ordinary life standing still.
- But it doesn't. It moves faster.
- I know.
- How are your brakes?
- Foolproof. How are yours?
Tough as that steak we had for dinner.
Then I'm going to tell you a secret.
That steak we had was horse meat.
Oh.
Very nice, thank you.
Thank you, sir. It's always a pleasure
to play for two beautiful people in love.
You know, it's a terrible...
- Do you mind?
- Thank you. I understand.
I understand.
I'm so glad about this evening.
Because, whatever happens
in England, or at the club,
I'll always be able to imagine America,
because I've met you
and talked to you and liked you.
I was thinking the same thing about England.
All of a sudden, a whole country becomes
the voice and face of a single person.
A very wonderful person, too.
That's terribly nice.
- Would you like to dance?
- I'd love to.
- What's the matter? No good?
- No, you dance very well.
So do you, honey.
- Brad?
- Hm?
Don't be cross, but would you mind
awfully not calling me "honey"?
Sorry.
How about Friday night?
- Well, if you'd really like to, I'd love to.
- I'd really like to.
Till Friday. And I'm so grateful for tonight.
- I'm grateful, too.
- Goodbye.
OK. Suppose you stay this way? Friends?
Do you imagine your wife thinks
you'll be faithful the whole of the war?
I don't know if she thinks it.
She's got a right to expect it.
There's a rule about soldiers' comforts.
They should be physical, not emotional.
Yeah, I've thought about all that.
I'll even admit, when I first saw Valerie
I thought about it. Physically.
She and I were a thousand miles
apart then, and strangers.
Let me tell you, there's such
a thing as being too darn pure.
It boomerangs. You think I'm cheap,
running around with dames in London.
But when I go home, I'll guarantee you
this much. I'll go home to my wife.
The lucky little woman.
- Well, I done the dishes.
- Good girl.
- Finished your little talk, have you?
- I guess so, thanks.
Ray, I think I'll hit the sack.
Good night, Jean.
Good night. Sleep tight.
Hey, there's a big old gal.
I wonder where she's off to.
Oh, India, Africa, America... You never know.
The saddest and
most exciting sound in the world.
Do you know that
you actually looked sad just then?
- I did? That's funny.
- Why? What were you thinking?
About your wife?
You like me to talk about Janie, don't you?
- Why?
- Oh, Brad. Do we have to?
- No, we don't have to.
- All right, then.
It's because it makes me feel safe.
- Oh, thanks.
- Oh, I didn't mean it that way.
- No. OK. I get it.
- Oh, Brad, darling.
Final result! Final results!
- Results of what?
- Depends what you're after, mate.
Thank you, lady. Final results! Final results!
"Commandoes In Action in Desert?"
Oh, that's just one of General Dittmar's
radio commercials out of Berlin.
It says "The 71st Commando Unit..."
John's?
"Demolition raid on Tobruk Harbor."
"Communiqué from Berlin says that the
bodies of 27 men, including eight officers..."
Look, he might not even
have been on the raid.
Even if he was, the odds are
still way against his being hurt.
I'm a coward, Brad,
and I hate John for being so brave.
He's going to make himself die.
And right now, he's in the desert writing
silly, foolish, lighthearted letters
about "getting ready
to singe old Rommel's beard."
And now this.
Look, why don't we go back
to the West End and have dinner, huh?
All right. Butjust let's sit here
quietly for a moment, may we?
Sure.
- Hey, the moon's up.
- Where?
There.
Oh, please, God, let him be looking at it.
He'll be back.
You can bet on it. In a couple of years
the war'll be over and he'll be back.
Long before, probably.
A couple of years?
Oh, it seems like such ages.
The summer of 1944.
Brad, this hasn't anything
to do with the warning,
but would you mind if I just went home?
- Sure, but you'll need some dinner.
- No, I'm not very hungry.
Suddenly everything's rather frightening.
All right?
Nice. OK if I come in?
Yes, please. The awful thing is, there isn't
anything I can offer you to drink in the house.
Why don't I run to the pub
and try to get something?
Brad, I know this is going to sound awfully
ungrateful and stupid and ungenerous...
But you'd rather call it off for tonight?
I understand.
No, it's more than just that, Brad.
It's more than just tonight.
Look, I hate saying this, but your not seeing
me isn't going to help that guy in the desert.
We're still two lonely people.
You think I'm pure and angel-like
because I'm English and my voice is crisp,
and my father's a brigadier.
But I'm not pure and angel-like.
I thought I'd be safe from you
because you're a stranger,
far removed from John and his world
and everything that he stands for.
So I thought.
I wish I could see you now
as I did on that first day,
when you were so gay
and brash and good-looking,
and very, very American.
Not very endearing, but...
Please go, Brad. Please say goodbye.
- Valerie, honey...
- I asked you not to call me that.
Look, I won't make a false move, I swear it,
now that I know it's that way or nothing.
Please go, Brad.
You're not a stranger anymore.
I'm sorry.
Thanks for all the lovely outings,
and God bless.
Go ahead and call her. Bayswater 7546.
- It's making me nervous.
- Making you nervous?
- How long you gonna keep this up?
- For the duration.
I went by that Red Cross club last night.
I didn't see anybody
looked like she's supposed to.
Maybe she's sick or went out of town.
Maybe she got hit in an air-raid.
Who's to know the difference?
- Got something good lined up?
- No, sir. Anyway...
You're a married man
and it's none of my business.
But this office is my business.
I want work out of every desk,
notjust faster than Cantrell's section,
twice as fast, you understand?
Oh, Parker? Hope you make third base.
Now, if you don't mind
ajigsaw puzzle with two pieces missing...
- Not at all.
- Pardon me, miss.
- Yes, Captain?
- Is Miss Russell still working here?
- Valerie? Sure. I'll get her for you right away.
- No, please. It's all right. I...
- Valerie, there's someone to see you.
- Oh.
Brad.
- Hi.
- Hello.
I was just seeing if... if you were the same.
- I've missed you too.
- You've had news?
Three weeks ago. Wonderful news.
You know, I kept thinking that
maybe you'd come to the club one day.
Then I decided you wouldn't.
That's a very nice compliment,
if only it'd been true, but...
- I'm here.
- I'm so glad.
Well, now that we can trust ourselves
not to see each other, couldn't we maybe...
- See each other?
- Tomorrow? If you're sure...
- Terribly sure.
- 7:00.
Brad, if you should change your mind,
please don't telephone me.
It'd be better that way and I'll understand.
I think you know I'll be there.
I'm taking Daphne to
the French Club tonight. Wanna come?
- No, thanks. I've got a date.
- About time. Something tangible, I trust?
- Valerie.
- Intangible. Well, it's still about time.
Parker!
- Sir?
- Brad. You and I are going on a little trip.
One of the best little trips we've ever made,
only one of us may not come back.
Don't worry, Parker.
It won't be you. You'll be back.
- Is it today, sir?
- You bet your life it's today.
And all day tomorrow, too. Only, nobody's
to know. Not even that bunch out there.
I have a dinner date, sir.
Have I permission to cancel it?
- Absolutely no.
- It might look suspicious if I didn't.
Let me tell you something
about security, Parker.
You cancel a date and so do 12 other guys,
soon it's all over London
that something's up.
No, sir, info like that
could cost a thousand lives.
In a minute, you and I walk out of here like
we're going for a drink. Is that understood?
- Yes, sir.
- OK. Call Arkinson.
Tell him to gas up the car.
Yes, sir.
What do you know about Operation Jubilee?
Jubilee? I've heard the code name.
I don't know what it is.
You're about the only one.
Worst security I ever heard of.
Wouldn't be surprised if the Germans
were waiting on the other side.
- What is it? A raid?
- Bigger. About half a division.
Canadians. Tanks, and everything.
- Experimental assault.
- Are we going as observers?
Not we, Brad. Me. Officially,
we're going as observers, both of us,
to watch the embarkation.
But strictly unofficially, a crazy coot called
Alex Timmer is going in with the Canadians.
Going on the assault without orders?
My friends always said Timmer'd either
come home a general or a corpse,
and I guess they were right.
Can you picture Ed Cantrell's face
when he hears the news?
- I can picture the general's face, too.
- But secretly he'll be thinking
"That crazy coot Timmer's got
something the other guys don't have."
Listen, they're scouting around for somebody
to take over Plans up at Second Corps.
The job calls for chickens up here.
Rumor's up and down the hall it's between
Ed Cantrell and me. Now d'you get it?
How did you arrange the deal, Colonel?
Buddy of mine, wonderful guy from
up Toronto way, battalion commander.
- He fixed it up.
- Can you tell me where the assault goes?
Yeah. Dieppe.
- Where?
- Dieppe, on the French coast.
And if you ask me, it's gonna be murder.
Alex, you old fool!
Hiya, Dunc. You didn't
think I was gonna miss it?
You nearly did. We're about to leave.
It'll be quite a party.
- We've been to parties before.
- Not like this, baby.
Oh, Colonel Harkness, Captain Parker.
- Nice knowing you. Sorry we can't bring you.
- Some other time.
- Sure, some other time. Come on, Alex.
- Be right with you.
Brad, zero's at 0430 hours in the morning.
Wait for me.
I'll be back sometime tomorrow afternoon.
Brad, if I don't show, there are a couple
of letters in the center drawer of my desk.
- Stick 'em in the mailbox, will ya?
- Yes, sir.
I was just thinking.
Wouldn't it be like Ed Cantrell to walk off
with the jackpot without gambling a dime?
- See you tomorrow, sir.
- Yeah.
Tomorrow.
Good hunting, men. Good hunting.
Remember, jolly good hunting.
Hi, there.
- Hi.
- Good to see you.
- It's been a long time.
- When did you get back?
- Is this all the casualty lists?
- So far, sir.
All we go in the line of Yanks is a couple
of rangers, a captain and a warrant officer.
Thanks anyway for your trouble, Sergeant.
- The surprise landing...
- Are you upset?
- Your boyfriend isn't on that, is he?
- The Dieppe raid? No, thank goodness.
- No, he's an American.
- I didn't think it was likely.
Fellow was saying just now we have
hardly more than a dozen guys down there.
.. near the Dieppe Casino. Further bulletin...
Georgina, did you say
some Americans are at Dieppe?
That's right, just a handful, though.
Gee, honey, I hope I didn't put
a wrong idea into your head.
- Still no luck, Captain?
- The last ship arrived half an hour ago.
Hey, what do you think of this?
A German helmet, cost me 45 bucks.
Colonel Timmer!
Just about given you up, sir. Glad to see you.
Let's roll, huh?
I never got to shore. Our LCl took
a direct hit a hundred yards out.
One shot, Parker,
and those boys were all mashed up.
So help me,
one shot and they were all mashed up.
You were lucky to get out, Colonel.
- Old Dunc Harkness got hit bad.
- I'm sorry to hear that, sir.
Took his battalion in where it's just murder.
Takes guts to give orders like that in the
military business, but you just gotta have it.
Twice. I was exploded in the water twice.
Arkinson, stop at the next pub.
Go in and bring out a bottle.
They won't sell by the bottle less they know
you, Colonel. You have to drink bit by bit.
Artillery was deadly. Deadly.
Second time I hit the water, I was naked
as a baby. No Mae West, no nothing.
And they were
machine-gunning me out there.
All the time I kept thinkin' "Those
Kraut gunners got orders: get Timmer."
Pull up ahead there, Arkinson.
Come on, Parker,
you could do with a snort yourself.
- Two double Scotch.
- Soda or water, sir?
- Neat.
- Very good, sir.
I just can't wait to see that Ed Cantrell's face.
Go ahead, Colonel. I'll get mine next time.
Two more here, please.
Sorry, mate, but you've had the limit as it is.
One whiskey per customer.
That's the rule this week.
Just a minute.
- Where were you this afternoon?
- This afternoon, sir?
Well, I was out in the back,
digging up the potato patch.
Is that right? Well, I was at Dieppe.
Oh, I see. Well, in that case, sir...
Did I understand you to say
that you were at Dieppe?
- That's right.
- But aren't you an American?
- Just who are you?
- Associated Press. Grainger's my name.
I was at Southampton all day.
You're the only American I've seen.
I went along as an observer.
I'm from headquarters. I volunteered.
You know how it is. There's going
to be a lot of this sort of thing up ahead.
You wanna get the feel of it,
the sooner the better.
- And jolly creditable of you, too.
- Colonel Timmer, sir.
- Is it OK if I get me a quick belt, too?
- Yeah, go ahead.
What section of headquarters
do you work in, Colonel Timmer?
- Why, I...
- Pardon me, Colonel.
Don't you think we should be on our way?
Maybe you're right.
- Well, to the next one.
- What?
Oh, yes. Quite.
I guess Mr. Lieutenant-Colonel Ed Cantrell
lost his big chance, huh?
- I guess so, sir.
- This crazy coot went to France,
and got back all in one piece, right, Brad?
That'll shake 'em, eh?
Hello. Is Captain Parker there, please?
Yes, this is Valerie.
You must be Captain Boyce.
No, I haven't either. Not a word.
Are you allowed to tell me if Brad could
possibly have been on the Dieppe raid?
Oh, I see.
No, you're very kind.
It's very sweet of you, no.
Yes. If Brad should come back,
would you tell him that I said
that I hoped that he would let me know...
No, it doesn't matter how late.
Brad!
- Brad.
- Valerie.
Oh, Brad, I'm so glad you're all right.
I'm so glad.
Oh, I'm so glad.
Wham the hewgag, beat the drums
- What was that?
- Old song.
- Hail, the conquering hero comes
- All right, Ray, knock it off.
I'll be all three monkeys.
Hear no, see no, speak no.
- The Colonel in?
- In his office, no. In the Daily Express, yes.
"Splendid evidence
of Allied cooperation came from
a high-ranking officer
of the U.S. headquarters command."
"Lieutenant-Colonel Timmer volunteered
to cross the Channel with the Canadians."
Pay attention, man.
This little article here has already borne fruit.
That order came from
the general's office not ten minutes ago.
Wow. Just when I wanted
to ask him a favor, too.
Well, maybe he won't see it for a while.
- Morning.
- Morning, sir.
- Colonel, could I see you for a moment?
- Yeah, sure. Come on in, Brad.
Go ahead, Brad. Shoot.
Sir, I've got some back leave due me.
What are my chances of getting to the coast
for two days? Saturday till Sunday noon?
Oh, I thought you wanted
to talk about something else.
- Don't you read the newspapers?
- Yes, sir, I do.
- Pretty good, huh?
- I don't think it'll do any harm.
Do any harm?
Oh, you read this order.
Well, it doesn't mean a thing.
I hope you're right, sir.
- Uh, Colonel, what I wanted to ask was...
- Yeah, I know.
You're worried about the order that
nobody talks to newspapers.
- Right.
- Let me tell you something, Brad.
I know this army. All their little tricks.
First they give you a rap over the knuckles.
Just for the record. Gets 'em off the hook.
But a story like this in the newspapers
has gotta do the army good.
- Itjust has to.
- I hope you're right, sir.
- As a matter of fact, I...
- The answer is no.
We're sweating out plans
for the invasion of Africa.
- Till the landing, nobody gets a leave.
- Sorry, sir.
After the boys land, maybe
you can have a day or so. We'll see.
Yeah?
Well, if it isn't my old friend, Ed Cantrell!
Alex.
Sit yourself, Alex.
Congratulations, Colonel.
Thanks. And you too.
By the way, did you want
adjoining rooms? I forgot to ask.
- Uh...
- We haven't any adjoining, I'm afraid.
- Is that all right?
- Yes, perfectly all right.
If you don't mind the wind, sir,
you've time for a nice walk before tea.
This way, madam, please.
This way, if you please, sir.
- Oh, Brad, it's awful. I feel so guilty.
- What about?
Well, I told you this would be a nice place,
and it's gonna come down in buckets.
I like it. I like the wind, I like the black clouds.
And I like it because you used to live here.
And not so long ago, either.
200 dreary little schoolgirls
in a line along the sea front.
"Russell! Keep in step there!"
And if you didn't, you got your ears boxed.
Yeah, those people on the Mayflower
knew what they were doing.
Sometimes I wonder about that, even now.
- You do, eh?
- Yes.
- Oh!
- Hey! Come on.
- Oh.
- Oh, here.
Oh, Brad, are we really sinners,
just by being in love?
- Why ask me?
- You're from New England.
- You're supposed to know.
- All right. I'll tell you.
You're probably the most innocent and
most beautiful sinner in the whole wide war.
Oh, and you're the most exciting.
People like to blame the war
for everything, don't they?
Sure, when there's one to blame.
- Oh, I'm cold.
- Yeah?
Mm.
- Brad.
- Huh?
- There's a fire in my room.
- Yeah?
No, no. Wait a minute. A real, blazing fire?
Or one of those English things
made out of damp smoke?
A real blazing fire. And we'll have tea there.
- The African landings went well, didn't they?
- Yeah, and am I proud.
I wielded a very valiant pencil.
Oh, darling, that's childish.
You know that in this war, you just
take what they give you, that's all.
Is it? John volunteered.
Well, he did, didn't he?
- Yes.
- So...
So I've prayed every night that they wouldn't
take you and that they'd leave you here.
You're wrong.
Wonderful, beautiful, but wrong.
- I know.
- And I'm wrong.
And right now I don't care. I love you.
Come on.
Anyone not assigned to fifth
division, Iceland, can thank his lucky stars.
Believe me, you're not gonna
like him any better than I do,
but that's the way it is in this man's army.
- Sorry to be late, sir.
- Forget it, boy.
I... I was just telling the men
it doesn't pay to break your back doing ajob.
Our reward just came down from on high.
Looks like a bunch of diplomas, doesn't it?
But it's not. They're orders.
The team's busted up. How do you like it?
Crandall to Second Corps, Washington.
Marcus to OPD.
Halloran to AFHQ, Algiers.
Well, there they are, men. Pick a winner.
Hey, luck's holding, Brad.
Free French liaison right here in London.
Me for the solid life. What'd you draw?
- I haven't looked.
- Go ahead. It only hurts for a minute.
- What happens to you, Colonel?
- Me?
Operation Burial.
Down to Movement Control.
Looks like they're trying to get rid of me.
You know something?
I'm gonna help 'em out.
I'm gonna get into a combat outfit if
I have to take a bust down to captain to do it.
How'd they cut your throat?
Allied Force Headquarters, Algiers.
First available aircraft.
Maybe I can get a transfer to
a combat outfit too, here in England.
Aren't you on limited service?
Broke your leg jumping?
You know as well as I do,
with my combat training...
Sure, I know, Brad. Right now that'll do you
as much good as a slip from the chaplain.
I'm afraid you're stuck with it, and there
isn't a thing in the world I can do to help.
Still no luck, huh?
Well, relax. Pour yourself a Sunday drink.
After all, you could do worse than Algiers.
- Hey, the Kasbah, boy.
- That isn't funny.
OK. I'll play it straight. I do know
somebody who's going to be happy.
- Who?
- Mrs. Brad Parker.
- That's ridiculous.
- Think she hasn't guessed from your letters?
You don't know Janie. She's not like that.
That makes it worse in a way.
What do you mean?
She's a woman, ain't she?
Hello?
Yes, sir.
Yes, I will.
Yes, I have it. Takeoff at 1700. Thank you.
- Try the Red Cross club on your way.
- It's her day off.
Well, leave her a note. It's all you can do.
Yeah, I guess it's all I can do.
Oh, Captain Parker. Valerie left this for you.
- Where is she?
- I imagine she's in Barkstow by now.
- Barkstow?
- She had to go to make the arrangements.
- What arrangements?
- For the services.
Oh, you haven't heard?
Her father died last night.
Died? How?
Someone said
the War Office turned him down.
He killed himself.
Poor Valerie. I feel awful for her.
Thank you.
OK, come and get it. Mail call.
Come and get it, guys.
- Here's one for Palmer.
- Right here.
- Paducci.
- Ho!
- One for you, Puchani.
- Sergeant?
- Yes, sir.
- Anything for me?
I believe there is, Captain Parker.
- Yes, sir.
- Oh, thank you.
"My darling."
"John is wounded and in hospital in Italy. "
"I should only be thinking about him,
but all that's in my mind tonight is that
it's been ten whole months since you left."
"300 empty days."
"There's an air raid going on, just
a small one, on the other side of London."
"The daffodils are in bloom in the park
and they don't mind the noise a bit."
Private Parker! Front and center!
Get your socks and hit the docks!
Dan! Boy, are you lost?
This isn't Fort Henderson!
- I had a hunch you'd be in this place.
- Hey, look who's a major!
And glad to be. That gold-leaf moola counts.
How long you been in this hellhole?
Eight months. You must be
pretty good at killing Germans, too.
Well, my employers are satisfied.
Piccadilly, here I come.
- Piccadilly?
- That's right.
- How'd you get it?
- Give me a drink, I'll tell you.
- That I'll do. Come on.
- Wait for Papa, Lovell.
- There you are.
- Thank you.
Mm. Don't tell me.
Oh, that's good rubbing alcohol.
- How'd you wangle a transfer to England?
- They're getting ready for the big show.
Yeah, I know. Go on,
give me all the details, how you worked it.
You thinking about yourself?
Nah, you don't want a combat outfit.
Not with that doll of yours and all back home.
I remember her from camp that time.
She's too beautiful to cry.
- Yeah, she liked you too. Now go on, tell me.
- Are you nuts, boy?
Listen, when I got embarkation leave,
I figured I might bump into you,
so I called her
on the telephone, long-distance,
reversing the charges.
- You called Janie?
- Yep.
She sounded pretty choked up.
Finally, she said
"If you do see him, tell him I love him."
Janie doesn't talk like that.
She hardly knows you.
- She really goes for you, boy.
- Itjust doesn't sound like her.
- Something's changed.
- Maybe you have.
Answer my question, Dan.
- You still hipped on England?
- More than ever.
- Dame?
- A girl I love.
Dame.
OK. It's a special force of volunteers.
You'll need pull to make it,
all the boys are hand-picked.
- How's that leg of yours?
- It's OK. What's this force called?
Special Force Six. It's a mixed bunch.
Gls, Canadians, limeys.
I don't go for them limeys.
They talk fast but fight slow.
The commander's OK, though.
He's from my home town, Minneapolis.
- What's his name?
- Timmer. He's a chicken colonel.
- Alex Timmer?
- Yeah. You know him?
- Just give me his APO.
- I don't know it.
Come to think of it, I don't even need it.
Brad!
- I need a shave.
- Oh, I don't care.
- It'll scratch your face.
- Let it.
- I wasn't sure you'd be here.
- Oh, I'd have crawled.
- You won't let me look at you.
- Not yet.
I don't want you
to get tired of looking at me.
- That's because you're ugly.
- I know.
Let me. Let me look at your ugly face.
I'm home, darling, I'm home.
Ten days before I have to report.
Breakfast.
The times I've dreamed
of being here, just like this.
Yes. Every night and every day.
With you looking just the way you do.
And no war, no going back, and no ending.
None of it. Not here. Not where we are.
When she writes to you... does she know?
She knows. She never says it
in her letters, but she knows.
- What about John?
- No.
No. All we ever had together
was... was trust, that's all.
Don't think that way.
You mean I've lost the right to?
Now stop.
But I do. Not often, but I do think that way.
And... Oh, kiss me.
Oh, wretched, isn't it, sir?
We can't land for a few minutes.
There's an air alert in London.
Well, after 20 months,
another few minutes won't matter.
I will get past
the medical officer on the field, won't I?
You shouldn't. But if it's that important to
you, I'll give you a pill to carry you through.
Thank you.
Who's he?
Hey, at last, the guest of honor.
Where's Valerie?
Meeting me here. What goes on?
Well, your fierce-looking
friend here dropped in on you.
- What are you doing here?
- Taking a break.
All of a sudden, this crazy captain
whistles up a whole flock of dames.
- When are you reporting to Timmer?
- When my leave's up. Not a minute before.
- Here you are, Dan.
- Thanks, baby.
This kid's a good gin drinker, just like me. We
got a lot more in common than gin, eh, baby?
I hate to have Valerie
barge in on a rat race like this.
Listen, this is London in war. Valerie knows
what it's all about, don't kid yourself.
- Hello, Ray.
- Baby.
- Is that it?
- That is it.
- Mm. Overboard, huh?
- Both of 'em. Without life jackets.
- Valerie, this is Dan.
- Hi, Valerie.
- Uh...
- Suzette. My name is Suzette. Hello.
- Ray you know, and Miss...
- Mrs. Hamilton.
- How do you do?
- Ray, excuse us. We gotta run out on you.
- Oh, no.
- It's a shame, but I'm afraid we do have to.
I love parties
that erupt out of nowhere, don't you?
So do I. Come on, darling.
What will we do when suddenly
the whistle blows, the war's over,
and we all have to scurry home
to our own husbands and wives?
Simple. Go back to 'em.
A drink, please, darling. A stiff one.
- I've a feeling I'll need it tonight.
- Say when.
Good evening, Colonel.
- Bit weak on the pins, eh, Colonel?
- I'll be all right.
I'm sorry.
Looking for anyone, Colonel?
I'm looking for Miss Russell.
Go ahead, stretch out.
Go ahead. It's been
stretched out on many times before.
There you are.
- Miss Russell? You mean Val?
- Yes.
Colonel, I thought you were celebrating.
You're a sick man.
Uh... Georgina,
do you know where Val was going?
She went out with her boyfriend.
Captain Brad something. Parker.
- Where is he billeted?
- Um... Sloane 8347.
Sloane 8347.
Now, you just hold still a minute
and I'll try to get her on the phone.
Please don't bother her now.
I... I just came by on the chance.
Nonsense. I'll get her
on the phone right away.
You just sit there and take it easy.
Boyce's apartment.
Who? Hold it, I'll see.
- Is there a party here named Russell?
- Yes.
- It's for you.
- Oh.
Hello?
Valerie? Just a minute, honey. Someone
here would like to speak with you, if...
The party's left. He was here just
a minute ago. Maybe he's gone up to the café.
But who is it?
An English colonel with a green beret.
He was so weak he could hardly stand.
Oh, no. I'll be right over.
- It's John.
- Where?
He's looking for me, and the girl in
the Red Cross club said that he was waiting.
- I'll take you.
- No, darling, I don't want that.
I'll try and telephone you later.
- Try?
- Yes, I'll try.
- What are you going to tell him?
- I don't know. What difference does it make?
After years of waiting and hoping,
he's here, he's sick,
and he expects me to be with him,
whatever happened while he was away.
That's what I meant by trust. His kind of trust.
You know I love you.
- Right around the next corner, ain't it, Miss?
- Yes, I think so.
Stop here, driver.
Wait here, please.
John!
John. Why didn't you wait?
They shouldn't have let you go, my darling.
They shouldn't have let you go.
I have a taxi. I'll take you home.
I love you so much, Val.
I'm going to take care of you, my darling.
I'll take you home.
Someday this army's
gonna do something the hard way.
Yeah, with a built-in cheering section.
All right, men. Up and over. On the double.
Get it done.
That's nice work, Parker. Darn nice work.
- Thank you, sir.
- Come on down here.
I always thought you had real stuff going.
Reporting for duty a week early proved it.
The problem was, could you stand it
physically? McEwan thinks you can.
- I can, sir.
- If I didn't think so, you wouldn't be here.
I like you, Brad. But not that much.
Well, I guess that buttons it up.
Dog Company is your baby from now on.
Take good care of it.
- Yes, sir.
- There'll be an officers' call at 0900.
You, Waller, Stenick, Parker
and your subordinates. See you.
Between where the British land
and the Americans land is a five-mile gap.
A gap of high ground.
Atop this high ground sits a 14-inch gun,
deeply embedded in the hillside,
which in turn is defended
by machine guns set in concrete pillboxes.
Now, this thing can't be assaulted
like regular beaches. It's on a 90-foot cliff.
It's got to be taken by a small force
just before the main landings
hit the beaches on either side,
in darkness, and by surprise.
Without surprise, there isn't
a chance of reaching that high ground.
And gentlemen, no ifs and buts.
It's gotta be taken.
I needn't tell you that the force taking it is us.
So we go in before the naval bombardment
and a little ahead of the main body of ships.
Before H-hour, D-day.
How do you like it?
- Swig?
- I don't believe so, thanks.
Come on. Keep you warm.
It's not all coffee, you know.
No, thanks.
Between you and me, Brad, this Angel Point
isn't going to be too tough a nut to crack.
Ah, there'll be a lot of fireworks, sure,
and you're gonna hear a lot of noise.
That's what gets you down, Brad,
that lousy noise.
Ah, well, nobody ever got killed by noise,
did they, son, huh?
I don't guess they did, Colonel.
You can cut out
that "Colonel" stuff with me, Brad.
You know the name. Alex.
Well, noise or no noise, you're still
gonna have to give out with those orders.
Takes guts, boy, believe me.
Ah, sure, there'll be
a lot of light stuff, I imagine.
Mostly machine guns and mortars.
What the heck. We'll find out what those
Intelligence johnnies have to say at noon.
Good of you to bring me along, sir.
I figured you could use
an hour or so in London afterwards.
I know I can.
Come on, have some. Calm you down.
Thanks.
Not too happy news, I'm afraid, sir.
Our people in the area suspect
that old Jerry has thickened it up a bit,
moved some extra LMG platoons
into the signals thingumajig,
that's your able company objective.
I must say, it makes a sticky wicket, really.
Why can't the Air Force
knock it out with flying forts?
A series of heavy-bomber raids of sufficient
concentration would be a dead giveaway,
even if they did knock out your gun.
I confess that the mere fact that you
should ask such a question at this stage...
I find it highly disquieting. Highly so.
Forget it. What about mines?
We'll get the word about mines
probably a day or so before you go in.
- Well, that's it. Good luck, sir.
- Thank you, Major.
- Good luck, Captain Parker.
- Thank you, sir.
Meet me back here after...
No, I'll tell you what. Let's see.
Meet me here at 2100 sharp.
I think I'll run up to that club of mine
for a while, maybe find old Dunc Harkness.
- Do you remember him? Dieppe?
- Yes, sir.
See you.
This guy comes into the Colonel's
office. He doesn't look 20 years old.
When the Colonel starts bawling him out,
he unzips his jacket. He's a one-star general!
Boy, you should have seen
the Colonel's face.
Excuse me, gentlemen.
- Brad!
- Valerie.
Oh, you look wonderful, darling.
You look beautiful.
Brad, I'm so glad you're here.
I was hoping to... I've been wanting to...
Look, I haven't got so very long.
Couldn't we go somewhere else?
I'm the only one here right now, but...
Maybe just for a few minutes.
We can go to that awful tea shop.
- At least it's quiet and we can talk.
- Let's go.
Oh, thank you very much, sir. Thank you.
Ought to be stronger than that.
- Who taught you?
- You did.
Well, when you're away from someone, you
start to see their face so many different ways.
Just all kinds of different ways.
I know. I know so well.
Down at the camp, sometimes,
I used to sort of try to kid myself.
You know, just see how I felt.
I'd say "Maybe five years from now
I won't even remember the color of her eyes."
Won't you, Brad?
As soon as I'd say that, I'd know that
I could never forget, not as long as I live.
Well, Valerie, pretty soon,
with any luck, the war'll be over,
and we've got to be thinking about that.
I never can give you up. I never will.
I'm going to be with John, Brad.
Oh, sure, I know. He's sick. He needs you.
He's quite well now, Brad.
I mean, for always.
It's just as simple as that.
You see, he's been waiting for me.
That's all he's been waiting for, for two years.
I never lied to him about us.
I remember when you used
to tell me about your wife, before we...
You go home, Brad, and you'll be glad.
I know you will.
Valerie, I've come to admire so much.
- The things you people stand for.
- It's not...
But if I could only believe
this is really the way you want it...
You, my darling, not him.
It is difficult to believe?
He's a wonderful man.
You're beautiful, Valerie.
I... I listen to you, and I watch your face,
and I know what you're saying,
but your eyes keep me from believing it.
- I never could.
- You will.
We're closing now, sir. Sorry.
That'll be two and ninepence, please.
I love you. I'll come back.
- No.
- Oh, but I will. I swear it.
I'm never going to give you up.
Thank you, sir.
Here you are, Captain Parker.
Been looking for you all over.
- Come with me, please.
- What's up?
You'll find out.
- OK, what is it?
- Sorry to get you down here, Bolthouse.
- It's been plain murder. It's Special Force Six.
- What about it?
Its commanding officer, Timmer,
was picked up by British police tonight
in a doorway in the Strand, talking to
a large street audience about the operation.
- What did he say?
- It was all pretty incoherent.
It seems he's been under heavy
mental stress and tonight he lost control.
It's a shocker.
He's got British under his command.
Well, what did he say?
This is the report
of the constable who picked him up.
"He spoke in my presence the following:
See the gap? Sticks out like a sore thumb."
"Smack between Gold Beach and Omaha."
"The Krauts have thickened it up a bit. Angel
Point, where we go in..." That's a good one.
Angel Point. Angel is right.
And all this before a crowd.
- Is that right?
- Yes, sir.
- What did you do with him?
- Put him in a psycho ward for observation.
- It's all you can do.
- The devil with Timmer.
What about the special force? They go
to the marshaling areas tomorrow night.
If we go by the book?
Second-in-command takes over?
Stenick and everybody else
move up a notch?
We can't take Stenick out of Able Company.
That's the heart of the operation.
Let's get a new guy that's had a few landings.
He can run the show from the beach.
Our personnel people should be
just about comfortably asleep by now.
- Let's get 'em up, get 'em over here.
- By the way, sir.
- Parker came down with Colonel Timmer.
- Captain, how're you divided up?
- Third Canadian, third US, third British?
- Exactly, sir.
Then it's a tossup. One of your boys
or one of ours, it doesn't make any difference.
Captain, go back and tell them that Colonel
Timmer was stricken with appendicitis.
- Acute appendicitis.
- Yes, sir.
Gentlemen.
Sit down, gentlemen.
Tighten your seat belts. We're gonna
hear about the Charge of the Light Brigade.
Well, my name's Wynter and I've been
ordered to take command of this operation.
I thought Major Stenick or Major McEwan
would be appointed to the command.
I feel it's wrong that one of them wasn't.
But of course, I'll do my best,
as I'm sure you will.
As for myself, I'm delighted
to be going into action again,
especially with so fine a force.
We've got a nice, clear-cut operation ahead,
plenty of fighting but nothing complex.
You won't be seeing much of me
till we board the ships,
because I've got
a bit of catching up to do.
Please feel free to barge in on me at any time.
- Now, why don't you introduce me?
- Certainly.
- Major Stenick, sir.
- Major Stenick.
Colonel.
Captain Parker, sir.
- Uh... Captain Brad Parker?
- Yes, sir.
- And Major McEwan.
- How do you do?
How do you do, sir?
Attention all personnel of Special Force Six.
Landing crafts will be
lowered away in seven minutes.
Stellung nehmen.
Volle Gefechtsbereitschaft.
Feuer!
Brooks!
- Sir?
- Locate Colonel Wynter.
Tell him we're pinned down and can't
move without heavy losses. What orders?
Yes, sir.
Sir! Sir. Captain Parker's pinned down.
What are your orders?
Sergeant, keep cover. I'll be back.
Uh!
I'm gonna try moving up
on the ridge on the left flank there.
I might get a crack at the gun
before they see me.
- But you'll be under direct fire, sir.
- Keep up the pressure on that pillbox.
Then it's up to you to get those mortars
on the right flank, at all costs.
Hennessy! Clark!
All right, Hennessy.
Roll it right down the middle.
All right, let's go.
Corporal, your section follow me.
Sergeant, covering fire. Come on!
You four, right flanking. Grenades.
Lob them in the gun embrasures.
We'll cover you.
Fire on my command.
Now!
- OK, Captain. You've had your war.
- Is it all over up here?
Yep. They just sent up
some PFCs to police up the grounds.
- How's Major Stenick?
- He's dead.
Dan... dead?
Major McEwan and Captain Waller
never got touched, though.
Now, I'm gonna give you a nice little shot,
and before you know it,
you'll be back across the Channel.
And then, bingo! Home.
- Home, huh?
- That's it, Captain. The good old USA.
Colonel Wynter. How's Colonel Wynter?
He was hit in the arm. Not too bad, though.
I think he was up here
walking around a few minutes ago.
- But he's had his war, too.
- Thank God for that.
OK, boys. Vorwärts marsch.
Einen Moment.
Good work, Parker. Darn good work.
- Thank you, sir.
- You feeling any better?
Yeah. Thanks, Colonel Wynter.
Feel a lot...
better now.
There's no use saying too much now, Brad.
Let it wait.
You'll have all the time in the world.
Well, they'll have you
back in England for lunchtime.
They'll probably
clear me out of here in a bit, too.
- Good luck.
- Good luck to you, sir.
Do what you can for him.
Watch it, Colonel.
We haven't checked that area yet.
Cigarette, Captain?
- Here you go.
- Thanks.
- Hey, could you do me a favor?
- Sure.
Telephone Miss Russell
at the Red Cross in Mayfair...
Sorry, Captain,
we're sealed off from London completely.
- How long?
- Goodness knows. Days, anyway.
One of our girls
is going into London tomorrow.
I could risk my neck and ask her.
Risk it.
What's the message, Captain?
Tell her I got
roughed up a little but I'm OK.
Same thing goes for Colonel Wynter.
As soon as I know what hospital
I'm in I'll get in touch with her.
Is there absolutely nothing I can do?
Are you sure?
I hated having to be the one
to come and tell you this.
General Frye wanted me
to break the news about John
before you heard about it accidentally.
I'm terribly, terribly sorry.
Are you sure there's nothing?
Then I think I'll say good night.
Thank you, David.
Bless you, darling.
Hello? Yes, this is Miss Russell.
Yes, go ahead.
In here, Miss Russell. Right down there.
Thank you.
Brad?
Brad.
You got my message?
They're shipping you home.
You know, that last day I saw you...
It's such a little while ago,
and so much has happened.
You said "You'll go back. You'll be happy to."
Itjust seemed like
the last thing in the world I'd ever want.
And then the other morning,
on the beach there, Normandy,
when the medic told me I'd be shipping back,
I suddenly thought
"Valerie was right. She knew."
And after a bit, John was standing there.
You know,
just standing there talking, nothing much.
And it all seemed so simple,
just like you said it was, and clear,
and the future seemed very real.
I'll always love you, Brad.
And I'll always be grateful to you
for whatever happens in my life.
You'll be happy, too,
you and John. I know you will.
Yes.
Incidentally, he's a...
he's a pretty terrific guy, that John.
A pretty wonderful guy.
How is he?
Oh, he's still pretty wonderful.
You haven't seen him the way we did.
Shut up, Brad! Shut up!
Don't cry.
I was right about one thing, though.
I always will remember
the color of your eyes.
Afraid I have to break up this little gathering.
It's time to change bandages.
Please, Doc, let her stay.
Now, look. We've already given you a break
by letting this young lady in to start with.
Goodbye, Brad, my only, only...
Goodbye, my darling.
Thank you, doctor.