Myung Films and Lotte Entertainment present
In association with GDCA
and SOVIK Venture Capital Co., Ltd.
And The Diversity Company
Distributed by Lotte Entertainment
Supported by KOCCA
a Myung Films and Odoltogi production
Leafie, A Hen Into The Wild
Come over here, kids!
- Let's lay eggs!
Hi, how's everyone today!
It's our wonderful
dinner time again.
Hey my friend,
what're you looking at?
Hi, Chirpie. Welcome.
Are you still fixed on going
out to the yard?
I'll get out of here
for sure! You'll see!
Here we go again.
Still don't get it, do you?
You'll never get out of here!
So don't even dream about it.
There's no way out.
But there is!
I've stopped eating
for the past three days.
If I pretend to be dead,
I can get out of here.
Starving yourself?
And for three days?
Just the thought makes me
feel horrible.
What's wrong with this place?
They give you food and a home.
Just lay eggs and it's all okay.
Just lay eggs?
Don't say that.
I want to sit on my own eggs.
Snap out of it!
I want to go out to the yard
and walk on the earth.
Look up at the sky...
- And hatch my eggs...
- Come on, try eating again.
Hey! Look here!
Wake up!
There's a dead hen over here!
A dead hen!
Someone save her!
This one's been
wasting away for days...
Darn it!
Watch out!
Be careful!
Thank you so much.
Always beware of the weasel.
It is cruel and vicious and
only eats live prey.
My name is Leafie.
Like a leaf on a tree.
Without leaves,
flowers can't bloom.
So what's your name?
I'm relieved that
you're alive.
Now go back to
where you came from.
No, I never want to go back!
I escaped my cage
to get to the yard.
The yard?
Yes.
I used to stare at
the yard all day.
I've got many friends there
and it's a great place to live.
If you come with me,
I'll introduce you to them.
Hey...
Wow.
Wow, it's you,
The white petals who
dance in the wind!
Magnificent!
Hey, who're you?
Hi there!
Good to see you, Yard Dog!
It's a real pleasure to
meet you up close like this.
Uh, what's this? It feels good.
Uh? Over there!
Please stop!
Hello, everyone!
I'm Leafie!
I know you guys well.
I even named each of you.
Your names are...
Doe, Mee, Sol...
Toe!
How's that? You're always
lined up like musical notes.
Doe.
Mee.
Sol.
Toe!
Who's she?
Oh my!
How pretty!
- Hi, yellow angels.
- Kids!
Get over here, now!
What's her problem?
Hey, you're brooding eggs.
They're bigger than
the ones I laid.
Go away!
Stop poking your
filthy wings at them!
Uh? I didn't see you up there!
You always get up first and
crow with such grand force!
That's why I named you... Morning.
Did you just call me 'you'
and not 'Boss? '
Never address me that way again!
Boss? What's that?
Anyway, I came here
to live in the yard.
Let's be friends from now on.
Has she gone mad?
The barn's crowded
enough with two hens...
And now one more?
It'll cause nothing but disorder!
Right, right. Order's important!
Get out!
- Say something, Boss!
- Leave!
Everyone stop!
I can tell you've escaped
from the egg barn.
Stop causing havoc here.
Just go home and lay your eggs.
Those are the rules
you should follow.
No!
I won't go back!
I don't like those rules!
Silence! That's an order!
If you don't leave right now,
I'll call our Master.
Get lost. You hear?
- But where am I supposed to go?
- That's not my problem!
Back to the egg barn or out
into the forest, I don't care.
Get out!
Lights out!
Now...
Get lost!
Wow, this place is huge.
Hello everyone! I'm Leafie!
So nice to meet you!
Uh, hi.
Hey.
Wow.
Oh my!
Hello, nice to meet you.
You look kind of funny.
Who're you to talk
about my looks?
It must be true that you've
lost all sense of reality.
Huh? Do you know me?
Sure I do. You're the crazy hen
who escaped the chicken farm.
Oh, how nice to meet you.
I'm Leafie. And who're you?
I'm the realtor around here.
I go by 'Living Consultant.'
But if that's hard,
just call me 'Mr. Otter.'
Mr. Otter?
Mr. Otter... Ot...
What about Mayor?
Nice to meet you
Mr. Mayor.
You're not only crazy
but deaf as well.
Anyway, I'm a really
busy person.
No, a busy otter.
As everyone seems to need me,
I can't waste my time
fiddling around with you.
I can see you really are crazy.
Since you're new, here's a tip.
This place cannot manage
without me.
Moreover, I promised the
wild duck I'd find you a place.
Jeez, no one ever
leaves me alone.
Wild duck?
You mean Wanderer?
Did he ask you to do that? Why?
Why?
Go ask him in person...
or in hen.
Now, I'll decide where
you should live, so listen up.
Since these feet
aren't fit to swim,
the stream and
the everglade are out.
And these wings aren't fit
to fly, so the treetops too
are out.
Since your feet aren't fast, the
plains and the woods won't do.
Cause the one-eyed weasel
runs wild around there.
Why d'ya leave the yard?
What for? Why? Why? Why?
I'll find my own place,
so don't bother.
How dare you underestimate me,
the Mayor, I mean, Mr. Otter.
Didn't I tell you this place'll
come to a stop without me?
Just stay put and
wait for my decision.
Hey!
That's it! It will
be the brier patch!
The brier patch?
The thorn and flower camouflaged
bushes are it's strongest points.
Why?
Once you're surrounded
by strong scented flowers
The one-eyed weasel won't
be able to smell prey like you.
I'm just too smart
for my own good!
Someone should steal
- some of my knowledge.
- I'm nobody's prey.
Mayor!
Wanderer! Hey, Wanderer...
They're pretty serious
about each other.
They wanted their own place.
So I found them a
brier patch much like yours.
The brier patch has
become such a hot item.
I'm worried that
demands will hit the roof...
They're a perfect match...
Of course it is. The brier patch
is an environment-friendly
space I've created.
But make sure the brier
flowers don't wither.
Or else that weasel will...
I'm jealous! I want a
sweetheart, too!
NO!
Stop there!
No!
You're still warm.
I will take care of
you like this.
What's his problem?
I can't sleep.
Not bad with just one wing.
But beware.
Cause I won't go after your good
wing, but your neck next time.
Try it and I'll scratch out
the one eye you have left.
By the way...
What's that you're doing
each night on the hill?
Sorry but please stop.
It gets so noisy each night, I'm
worried you'll startle the baby.
The moon's become round.
That means the egg's
about to hatch.
Really?
Then I can see the baby soon?
But the full moon also means
the weasel's stomach is empty.
I'll be fine. Look. My claws and
beak have become tougher.
I won't be beaten easily
even if the weasel appears.
Leafie!
Did you just call me
by my name?
Thanks.
When the baby's born, go to
the everglade past the east forest.
Why should I go to the everglade?
In time you'll understand.
Leafie, you're a great hen.
I've been meaning
to tell you that.
I made a name for you,
It's Wanderer.
Wanderer?
Yes.
Here!
Over here!
Catch me if you can!
Is that the best you can do?
Wanderer!
No!
Wanderer...
My baby! Baby!
Baby?
Mama!
Mama...
Baby...
Baby!
Achoo!
Let's go, baby.
Baby, come over here!
Hello!
I'm Leafie.
And this is my baby.
Don't look at us that way
since we're not staying here.
We're heading to the everglade.
Giddyup, giddyup! Go!
Look who it is! Hey my friend,
don't you remember me?
Chirpie? How nice to see you!
Wow, and I thought
you were dead.
And you never looked better.
How luscious your feathers are!
And who's this?
Say hi my little baby
to mommy's friend, Chirpie.
Mommy? Can a hen
give birth to a duck?
This is news, big news...
I can't stop laughing.
So where're you headed now?
We're on our way to the everglade.
We're going to live there.
No, friend. Come back
to the chicken farm, please.
Without you, meal times
have been hell for me.
Well, bye now.
See you again, Chirpie.
Please come back!
So, this is it!
Wanderer, we finally
made it to the everglade.
This place is really great.
Wow! Everyone!
You all look magnificent!
Huh? Me?
I guess they mean us.
Hey! Who was that?
You mean me?
Who's that?
With such a loud voice?
My baby, please be careful.
My baby must've been
really hungry.
Stay right there!
Baby...
Where are you, baby?
Baby!
No, no! Don't move!
No!
No, baby, stop!
Don't come this way!
Baby!
What the heck do you
think you're dong?
A hen jumping into the water...
Are you gonna try to fly next?
Oh wow, you made my day!
Mayor, please help!
Baby's drowning!
You mean that baby?
Bravo!
Did you see that?
My baby's swimming!
I never taught him. But he
learned all by himself.
Isn't it great?
My baby's a genius, a genius!
'My baby? '
You're surely one crazy hen.
Leaving the chicken farm
for the wild.
And now the everglade, claiming that
green headed duck's your baby?
Green head?
Green head...
That's it! I should call my
baby Greenie from now on!
What a perfect name.
Greenie!
- What's all the racket?
- Greenie!
- Hey, listen...
- Hey! Hey, listen...
- Greenie!
- Keep it down!
Greenie!
Greenie... No.
Come here.
My baby.
Crack open, will you?
Mr. Mayor!
When will you teach me
how to swim underwater?
You forgot to say, please!
The rule to underwater swimming
is breathing. Breathing.
It starts from breathing
and ends with breathing.
Now follow me.
Greenie, don't stray far!
How nice and quiet
everything is.
You guys all look the same.
I envy you all.
That's so cool.
- We look the same to you?
- Really? We can't tell.
You're so different from your
Mom. Is she your real mom?
Right. It is odd.
She never comes into the water.
Can she even swim?
It's so strange! There's even
a flower attached to her tail.
My mom told me,
only mad birds wear flowers.
Uh, what's this?
Darn it!
Darn!
What's wrong, children?
Why're you crying?
It's because of him.
Didn't I tell you never to play
with a strange kid like him?
Honey, let's go. Well, I never!
Honey!
Excuse me!
Mr. Mayor told me to come see you.
Mayor? That good for nothing realtor.
If I ever get my hands on him...
Why the hell is this cave
leaking all day?
Whenever it rains,
this place is a mess.
Mr. Mayor told me a rumour that
when it comes to flying you're
the best around this place.
That's not a rumor but a fact.
Look carefully! Close your eyes,
then use your animal
instincts to take off!
Wow.
What do you think?
Easy, huh?
Wow.
Then shall we start
from the beginning?
First, trying dangling like this!
Huh?
Don't stand there like that.
Hurry up here! Come!
Darn it.
Hey, kid! Come up here.
Hey!
No thanks, mister.
Jeez, look how my
heart's pounding.
Hey, kid, let's be real here.
Are you trying to fly
or die?
But you said it's
all about guts!
You idiot, you call that guts?
Just go home and first
make yourself a man!
I'm so sleepy.
Sleepy, so sleepy...
Darn it!
Mayor, let's be honest.
Does it make sense
that a hen's living here?
I can't fish because
she's such a loud mouth!
Mayor, you suck as a realtor!
Their relationship's
confusing to the children.
- Kick them out right now!
- Okay, I got it. So shush!
Hey!
Hi, everyone!
Hi, angel's wing.
Hi, bird-riding-on-the-bullet.
Hi...
What's up?
Hey, what're those on your feet?
Oh, right.
I need a favor.
Greenie's been acting odd lately.
Skipping trips to the nest.
So, I've decided to learn
how to swim underwater.
OK, I'll give it to you straight.
First, a little voice-tuning.
You've been sick with a cold
for a month.
It's because your feathers
get wet when it rains.
But, Greenie's feathers
are always dry.
You can't swim at all,
but Greenie can.
And I mean really well.
What I'm saying is, you two are
different in breed and lifestyle.
So? What's wrong
with being different?
You're not hearing anything
that I'm saying!
Keep this up and
you'll wither away!
Give it back.
So, I really think it's definitely,
absolutely necessary that
you return to the farm!
The farm? Never!
I'm staying here with my Greenie!
You can't separate a mother
from her child!
You're only challenging
the laws of nature!
But the main problem is
that everyone here hates you!
Oh, no! Darn...
Well, not everyone, I mean...
I've got such a big mouth.
Bad mouth, bad!
Greenie! Where have you
been? I've been worried.
Darn!
Stop hovering near the water!
You can't swim...
The kids keep teasing me.
What? Why? Who's teasing you?
Nobody wants to play with me.
It's all your fault!
I'm...
ashamed of you!
You're ashamed of me?
Stop, I'm serious. My wings
have been so itchy lately.
Why are they itchy? Let me see.
No! You don't understand!
Can't you see I want to fly?
But you know we can't fly.
Stop saying 'we.' I'm
different from you! Different!
Yes, we're different.
So what?
We can be different but
still love each other!
I don't want to be
with you anymore!
Greenie!
Baby!
Stop calling me 'baby! '
I'm not a baby anymore!
Greenie...
Is that you, Greenie?
Oh no!
I'm so sorry.
He said he wanted to fly so
I introduced him around...
Want some? It's fresh...
Wanderer, I'm sorry.
Wanderer?
Right! It was Wanderer.
Greenie looks like him.
He certainly does resemble
that wild guard duck.
I'm not just imagining
things, am I?
Guard? Wanderer's a guard duck?
What's a guard?
Mayor, tell me about Wanderer!
The wind was fierce that day.
Our first encounter... lt was
fatal moment, I should say!
What's this? A sudden
thunderbolt? No, a bird-bolt!
Cool, huh? No one can
slam the brakes on like me.
Bravo. And who're you? You
almost scared me to death!
Pleasure to meet you.
You'll be seeing more of me,
the best guard duck around!
That guard duck was Wanderer...
Among his flock, he flew
the highest and the fastest.
He always arrived first to find
a resting place for his flock
and protect them.
Really? Then why couldn't
he fly when I first met him?
As always, the problem was
the one-eyed weasel.
Ah, he was truly brave.
No one could've fought
that weasel like him.
But then...
He...
Enough...
Wanderer who could no longer
fly was captured by the Master.
And that's how he ended up
in the yard...
Did you just say Wanderer
used to live in the yard?
But being a wild duck who flew
the skies, he could never
be happy there.
I see...
So that's what happened
to Wanderer...
Duck, ducks quack, quack, house
ducks sing Do, Mi, Sol, Toe
to the march of their feet...
Waddle, waddle.
Who do you think you are?!
Who're you?
Uh? You look new.
Yo! How dare you push
your beak into our turf?!
Uh? But he looks familiar.
- Right! He looks just like him!
- You're right!
Who're you guys?
Uh? He even sounds like
that arrogant wild duck.
Wild duck?
He used to live in our yard.
Yeah, he was a wanderer
who looks like you.
Like me?
Yeah. And how he put on such
airs when he couldn't even fly.
He may have been our kind,
but he was one stuck up dude.
Yard? Where's this yard
you're talking about?
Can he be more clueless?
Wanna go there?
Yes!
Yeah, let's go.
Yeah, let's go together.
What a bunch of scrooges!
Fine, I won't touch
your filthy food!
Doe, Mi, Sol, Toe! March to the
front yard, to the back yard!
Hey, I know him...
Isn't that?
He looks like Leafie's kid...
Who're you?
Hi, I'm Greenie.
- You're one sad-looking dude.
- I'm kinda feeling good again.
Where did you come from, kid?
He seems totally out of it.
Look how dazed he is.
Is this the yard? There's
not even any water here.
Hey stupid. How can a duck
live without water?
Have some dignity, will you?
The best place to pee
is in the water.
Yuck!
This must be my lucky day.
A wild duck!
- This one's pretty strong!
- Let go of me!
I'll cut off his wings first.
Be still!
- Greenie!
- Hey, Greenie!
- Where are you, Greenie!
- Greenie!
- Where the hell is he?
Hey friend, what're you doing here?!
Your kid's...
- Yikes! How scary...
- Why you little... Get lost!
Chirpie, did you say you've
seen Greenie?
Yeah, he's in the yard.
There's no time for this!
Master's gonna
cut his wings off.
What? His wings?!
Greenie!
Mom!
- Please help me!
- Stop it!
Stop making such a fuss!
Mom!
Greenie!
Ah, poor kid.
Let go of me! Let me go!
No!
Hey, you crazy hen!
Hey friend, get up!
Go away!
Greenie!
Please save my Greenie.
We have to release everyone.
Help me, Mayor!
Okay, here I go!
Let go of me!
Mayor! You must send out all the
hens. Put on your scariest face.
Okay.
- Okay.
- Hurry, please hurry!
Scared?!
The Mayor, no Otter needs
help over here! Oh my tail! Help! It'sthe Mayor, no, Otter!
Everyone, get out, NOW!
Fire the dung!
Get out!
Hey! Stop the chickens!
Greenie!
Mom!
There's no time for a family
reunion. Let's go!
Let's go!
Where do you think
you're going?!
How could one of my egg hens
give birth to a duck?
Move! We've got to
get out of here quick!
Shut up! You've disgraced
the entire chicken breed!
Furthermore, you've destroyed
the peace in the yard!
In the name of justice,
I will make you pay.
Hey, what's this?
Step away or be stepped on.
Was this all just a joke?
Attention, everyone!
From now on,
I'll be the Boss of this yard!
They all ran for their lives.
Hey, was I scary or what?
Mom, you were really
great back there.
What about me? How did I do?
Mr. Mayor, you were great too.
Can you be more stingy
with the compliments, you brat?
Mom, mom.
Mom...
I'm so sorry. I'll never
behave that way again.
Are your wings okay?
Yes.
Now you really look like a mother.
Why're you always picking on us?
- And the white duck, Wanderer...
- I was just hunting!
When I was hungry,
they just caught my eye.
Like you this moment.
So, who should I eat first?
Mom.
No!
Don't you dare touch my baby!
Run Greenie, run!
My baby... Greenie.
Greenie!
Mom!
Look, I'm flying! I'm flying!
How amazing!
That's my baby!
Wonderful, Greenie!
I'm so proud of you, my boy!
Ah, autumn's here already.
How time passes without notice.
How he has grown.
Hey, shoo. You don't
want to see me mad.
Shouldn't you start grooming?
It's crucial as you get older.
Your face has become as
gaunt as a sick chicken.
And your body seems to
have shrunken as well.
Get lost, leave me alone!
Hey!
Are you happy you're
flying, Greenie?
Yes. But mom, I've been
feeling weird these days.
I never felt this way before.
Like something's coming.
What? You mean the weasel?
No, that's not it.
Can't you feel it, mom?
It's coming, mom.
What is, Greenie? Are you okay?
Mom, my heart's beating so hard...
Oh my, they're coming!
They're coming!
And they're as noisy as ever!
Over here, here!
Welcome to my world!
The flock seems larger
in size this time!
Looks like sales will
skyrocket this year!
When the baby's born, go to
the everglade past the east forest.
Why should I go to the everglade?
In time you'll understand.
Greenie. Go.
They're your friends.
Go and introduce yourself.
Okay, mom.
I'll be right back.
Let me hold you for a bit.
- Hi, I'm Greenie.
- Keep the flight line!
Sorry!
Hey, you! Watch out!
A flight contest will
soon be held.
The winner will become the
new guard duck.
Anyone wanting to compete,
get ready.
- Red Hair, you'll compete, right?
- Definitely.
You'll see. The guard spot's
mine this time.
What's a guard duck?
What? Don't you know?
Are you stupid or what?
Who're you?
- This dude looks suspicious.
- I know.
Never seen him before.
Which flock are you from?
Flock? I don't have one.
It's just me.
What?
What kind of migrant bird
flies alone?
Wait! What's this?
- Humans have tied this on him!
- It's a string!
Look here!
We've got a suspicious one here!
He has a human string on him!
Uh? Hey!
Is that you, Greenie?
Greenie.
Darn.
Greenie, are you okay?
Is something wrong?
I want to live with you
like before.
What are you talking about?
You should be with your friends.
They're leaving in a few days.
Greenie, don't forget that
you're a wild duck.
You can be a brave guard duck,
like your father.
Fly with all your might.
Mommy will be watching.
Mom!
I'm almost done.
Mom...
Could you grab that end?
Hurry, okay?
- Mom, mom, are you okay?
- Yes.
But I can't seem to
untie this knot my child.
Okay, this will be our mark
that you're my baby.
So I can recognize you
wherever you are.
Mom...
Mom!
I've got bulbs and
dried shrimp here!
There's tasty mudfish, too!
And I'll throw in some minnows!
And now's the live broadcast of
the 'Guard Duck Flying Contest.'
We'll start the flying contest!
You may notice there's
a drop in entrants this year...
Yes! That is correct.
Such things like pollution,
rising divorce rate seems
to have caused this decrease.
Bully!
Right, he's built more like
a bull rather than a duck.
You can say he's got
the goods, right?
Next is Blade. Great speed
and clever as a fox.
And then we have Red Hair!
Our strongest contender!
- Who'll win this time?
- Red Hair, of course.
I would like to compete too!
He's the one with
the human string.
Who's that?
I want to be the
guard duck of this flock.
Get lost! This isn't
a contest for tramps...
Shut up!
Let me participate.
What? Get lost!
There's no room in this
contest for cowards like you!
Why don't you drop out?
- What? Why you little...
- Stop!
As a guard duck should
excel in his flying ability,
I'll decide after
I see how you can fly.
- I permit you to compete.
- Thank you, sir!
Now the contest will start.
You must think anyone
can become a guard.
Just watch your back, buddy.
We'll start the contest!
This is nerve-racking, a big
fat nerve-racking moment.
And here they take off!
As expected, Red Hair takes
the lead with incredible speed.
See if you can follow me.
They're supposed to shoot up
as soon as they take off...
Ah! Greenie! What's he doing?
He's using the headwind to fly up.
This is Greenie's first contest!
And he's doing a great job!
Hey, kid! Amazing view, huh?
Brace yourself cause
it's just getting started!
Guts boy, it's all about guts!
Three, two, one, bungee!
Wow, it's Red Hair!
Ah, he should slow down.
Greenie.
Quick, help him!
This is unfortunate. I just hope
he isn't seriously injured.
Greenie! Don't give up!
You can do it!
Greenie's back in the race! And
he catapults forward unscathed!
I'm so proud of you, Greenie!
Mom...
Not bad.
Here we go!
So long, kid.
Watch out.
What? Oh...
Not bad.
Now we're halfway through
the contest.
Greenie is in second place
right as we speak.
Amazing!
Greenie's amazing.
It looks like everyone's
starting to root for him.
What's Bully doing?
Isn't that a foul?
Not really. More serious
incidents occur during flight.
And it should be seen
as part of the contest.
And Bully plummets out
of the race. Serves him right!
See if you can follow me.
What an exciting match
we're having today.
Close your eyes,
then use your animal
instincts to take off!
Watch out, kid.
Greenie's having a race like
we've never seen before.
The rising star of the wild ducks!
Every Tom, Dick and Harry is
cheering for Greenie.
Guess I gotta sweep this place...
Hey!
Having fun?
What're they doing?
It's that wild duck!
Why's he wasting
his time flying?
Right, Rooster?
Huh? Where'd he go?
Now the contest is
reaching its final stage.
Strong winds from high up
makes flyiing difficult.
The experienced Red Hair
descends towards the waterway.
But won't that increase
his flight distance?
I guess he's going for a route
with less wind resistance.
Really? I guess you're right.
Greenie's also heading
for the waterway.
And he slowly gains ground.
They're almost at
the finish line!
Any strength left should go
into the final spurt. But...
Hey, you can't go
through that way!
It's too dangerous!
Greenie.
From now on you can go
wherever you want to.
Fly with all your might.
Mommy will be watching you.
Uh? Who's that?
Ah! And it's Greenie
who's in the lead!
500m, 400m... will it be
Greenie or Red Hair?
Greenie! Greenie! Greenie!
It's Greenie!
We finally have
a new guard duck!
What an overwhelming moment
for everyone.
Join us and give him
a round of applause.
I'm so proud of you, Greenie.
I congratulate you
as the new guard duck!
Thank you!
Your flying skills are great.
Congratulations, kid.
Call me Greenie.
That's my name.
Gotcha, Greenie kid.
Good job.
Thank you, sir.
Our long journey starts
soon. So eat up!
Chief, I need to go
somewhere for just a bit.
As a guard, you should
never abandon your post!
Please, I'll be right back.
We'll be leaving soon,
so don't be late!
Yes, sir!
Is anyone there?
Hey, Mayor, look here.
This place looks drafty...
Hey, everyone wants to
live in the brier patch.
Besides, this place suits you.
I can tell just by looking.
And when it rains?
I hate getting wet.
Jeez...
Then, what about the
bat cave on the hill?
That place is empty.
But, won't it be dark
in the cave?
- I live on my own...
- Are you kidding me!
Then find a new realtor
or go back to the yard!
I don't want to!
I'm now the rooster
who left the yard.
- Mr. Mayor.
- Why isn't it the new guard duck!
What brings you're here?
Aren't you leaving soon?
Have you seen my mom?
Well I've been a bit busy
today that... huh?
Why that little brat!
- Uncle.
- Huh?
Please take good care of my mom.
All right.
Come back safely!
Leave her alone, you beast!
- Get off me!
- Greenie!
Mom?
What are you doing there?!
- Greenie!
- Don't come near!
No! Watch out!
Get away from my babies!
Babies?
These are you babies?
Mom.
- Leave my baby alone!
- Leave my babies alone!
Just leave them, now!
My Greenie has to leave...
With his flock...
Let him go!
Let my babies go!
Fine!
I'll let them go first.
Then you let my
Greenie go as well.
- Now let him go!
- All right, all right!
- Greenie.
- Mom.
Are you okay?
Yes, I'm fine.
You must be hungry.
Just wait a little.
Once I hunt,
I'll be able to nurse.
My babies.
Let's go! Hurry!
Hey, guard! What're you
doing there?!
We have to go!
You have to lead us!
What? Oh, right.
Mom...
I can't just leave you
here like this.
I'm fine. I have enough
memories to cherish.
I remember when you hatched.
When you swam, and
when you flew the skies.
When I close my eyes,
I can see you clearly.
So, I'm not lonely.
Mom, do you really
want me to leave?
If I could fly, I would
never stay here.
You've got to do what
your heart tells you.
Greenie, go out and
see the wide world.
Mom...
I promise I'll come back.
You'll be waiting for me, right?
Of course.
Your mom's not going anywhere.
Come back to tell me
what the world
you've seen is like.
Okay.
I'll come back as the highest flying
and the bravest wild duck.
I'll come back after
I see the wide world, mom.
Yes...
my baby.
You're already the bravest
to me, my baby.
Mom!
Greenie.
Take care!
Bye, mom!
I'm so proud of you, Greenie!
Good bye...
MOON Sori as Leafie
YOO Seungho as Greenie
CHOI Minsik as Wanderer
PARK Chulmin as Mayor
KIM Sanghyun as One-eye
Director OH Seongyun
Original Story HWANG Sunmi
Screenplay KIM Eunjung, NA Hyun
Animation Director LEE Choonbaek
Cinematographer LEE Jonghyuk
Art Director YOU Seungbae
Editors KIM Sangbum, KIM Jaebum
Music LEE Jisoo
Sound KIM Sukwon, KIM Changsub
Associate Producer LEE Hana
Co-executive Producers
Daniel SUNG, PARK Hyuntae
Executive Producers
LEE Eun, SHIM Jaemyung, SON Kwangik
Producers
LEE Eun, SHIM Jaemyung, KIM Sunku