The 41st millenium
The Imperium of Mankind
stretches across the entire galaxy.
Still, tremendous wars
rage at its frontiers.
As well as within.
Only a merciless authority
full of cruelty and scorn
is capable of keeping
the Imperium together.
United in the faith
in their god-like Emperor
humanity has no alternative
than to accept their fate.
But mankind changes,
Psykers are born.
Mutants with supernatural skills.
They are the gateway to the Empyrean,
a parallel dimension flushed with energy,
Which made journeys
between the stars possible.
But inside the Immaterium
the emotions of the living gather
and take shape ...
Those personified nightmares
are haunting mankind as daemons.
And their dark gods
have only one intention:
The subjugation
of the substantial universe.
Inquisitor Lessus.
We will soon exit the Immaterium.
The warp abnormality ...
it grew bigger.
We have never arrived too late.
Inquisitor!
We regret that we
cannot come to your support.
Eldar forces are blocking
the Strait of Calix.
Proceed with your mission.
For the Emperor!
It is the holy duty
of the covertly working
Imperial Inquisition
to hold this menace at bay.
All over the galaxy
they are searching
for the merest hint of corruption
by the rotting seeds of chaos cults.
The merciless Inquisitors
are authorised
to attack
the enemies of the Imperium
at any time, by any means,
to annihilate them.
Welcome back, son of the Conclave.
(Radio traffic)
(Noise)
Halt!
(Radio traffic)
Fire at will.
(Noise)
Unit Three?
Spotted!
He that committeth no sin, on his knees!
Come on, Nira.
Are you dreaming again?
I really wonder what this is all about!
Even recruits would be better for this ops.
Remember: If they refuse, kill them all.
You know our orders.
Osmar Adeodatus, Planetary Defence Force
Sancta Heroica Theta, Special Forces Legion.
Hieronymus VI. von Remus,
Sergeant Corris,
Wodan Dubrovnik,
as well as the absent Oktavian
are as of now put
under the command
of the Planetary Defence Force.
What!?
During operation 312003
you will be accompanied and supported
by Nira Gippus of the Scholastika Psykana,
and by myself.
A witch! Hell, I like it!
What is this operation about?
Suspicious subjects
are rumoured to have gathered
in the old manufactorum inside depth 69.
Our assignment is
to scan this forbidden gathering
and, should the need arise,
cleanse and purge it.
How much?
There will be no pay.
This order came from the highest authority:
The Inquisition!
How can we get to the lowest depth?
We have to take the old supply tubes
in the north east section of the hive.
That’s why we have to depart
as soon as possible.
What about the old assembly tunnels
inside the... Macharius-wing?
Don’t they go straight down?
Those have not been used for centuries.
It is strictly forbidden
to disturb the machine spirits.
We have someone
who gets along with them pretty well.
The sooner we finish this job
the better it is for all of us.
Well, then we’ll meet there.
I guess I made myself clear.
When will you be ready for action?
In six hours at the earliest.
Three hours!
For the Emperor!
Into the Eye with the Inquisition!
I won’t do any dirty work for them!
Come on, let’s get the hell out of here
while we still can!
You can outrun anybody, Wodan.
But not them. You know that.
Nevertheless...
something’s awry with this.
- Why us?
- Exactly.
We haven’t had any big operations recently.
And finally this female psyker!
I had the feeling all along
that she was reading my thoughts.
She didn’t have
a great deal to do with that.
We’ll see.
Hold this position and prepare yourselves,
I’ll tell Oktavian the news.
Await my complete report within 24 hours.
Signed: Adeodatus
Dismissed!
(Prayer)
One thing I’d definitely
like to know, Wodan.
What?
Why are you so scared stiff
of humans with psionic abilities,
but have no reservations
regarding such strange guys like him?
Oktavian is only able to control machines.
I am no fething machine!
At least not completely.
We still should watch that Nira Gippus.
She may be a novice but the Emperor knows
what potential lies within her.
Here they come, our watchdogs.
Very well then, a tech priest.
I’ve never trusted those guys.
If one can call them human at all.
They do not really believe in the Emperor.
Hey!
He seems to be done, finally.
The rites of awakening are finished.
The elevator will
take us safely to depth 63.
Halt!
Adeodatus ...
I guess you don’t have any
information regarding
this „forbidden meeting“,
as I happen to know the
inner workings of the Inquisition.
Considering the military prowess
of this penal squad
they can be nothing but
poorly equipped insurgents.
Do not underestimate us, soldier boy.
If you even had the faintest idea
what we have already seen!
Don’t underestimate the Inquisition.
It is my duty to inform you
that I will record any blasphemous
and heretical actions and statements!
I hope you know that, von Remus.
Quite plain.
Come on, let’s smoke
this lair of heretics out.
Left flank, Wodan.
Room secured.
Gas and radiation values
are within acceptable ranges.
Very good. We’ll advance
to the next possible descent location.
Oktavian, conduct a deep scan
every 10 minutes.
The laws of the Administratum
do not reach this place
and I don’t want any surprises!
They are only armed with light weapons.
Three additional signs
right in room behind that door.
No surveillance sensors
within the perimeter.
I cannot access further sectors.
Good to know.
Must be the walls of the Manufactorum.
Probably.
Adeodatus. Reporting in.
Command HQ? Can you hear me?
Adeodatus for command HQ.
Can anyone hear me!?
Adept Oktavian?
Do you feel it, too?
I do not feel, psyker.
I see.
But the eye of the Machine God is...
embittered down here.
That’s not a good omen ...
And where are the others by the way?
What’s that supposed to be!?
They were meant to wait!
Stop right there! What in the name of
the only true one is your business here?
Because of the only true one
amongst true ones I have come here.
I am searching for my property.
One of my working slaves has escaped.
Your’re in the wrong place here.
We haven’t seen anybody.
That’s odd ...
I was absolutely sure that
he ran in this direction.
But you probably would have seen him
if you hadn’t been so easily distracted.
Interesting approach ...
Let’s hurry up.
There may be more of them near.
Oktavian, keep an eye on the vicinity.
I guess we gathered enough
information for the Inquisition.
Let’s get out of here as soon as possible.
Yeah, exactly!
Our orders are clear, von Remus.
'Cleanse and purge' -
we already bumped off five of them!
Yeah, even without knowing
if they actually posed a threat to us.
I knew it!
What?
There’s a strange symbol on their cowls.
That confirms our suspicion about
this being a forbidden organisation.
We have to get deeper into the complex,
collect more pieces of evidence
for the Inquisition.
Oktavian?
Anything wrong?
Interferences ...
Strange interferences ...
There is... no...
someone was there!
After him!
Great ...
He is moving towards
a big maintenance hall.
Makkabeus sends me.
The preparations have begun.
He wants to talk to you before it starts.
I will be there.
What is it?
I guess we have seen enough, soldier.
You can earn your badges
in another suicide mission.
We follow orders, von Remus.
We don’t retreat until
we know what is wrong here.
I somehow have the feeling,
someone in here had...
deeper insights into certain files, eh?
Be quiet! I think I heard something.
Oktavian?
Very weak.
I’m on him.
Nira?
Where's Nira?
A psychic shockwave!
We’d better hurry up.
Nira?
I’m sorry!
I didn’t mean to do that!
Never do that again!
What happened?
May the Emperor be with us.
I...
felt dizzy.
And then...
he was suddenly there.
Signa accipio.
Approaching.
- Damn, cultists!
- Charge!
Retreat to the hall!
Back into the hall!
Go! Go!
Get them!
Go in and win!
Nira! Watch out,
he's on your back!
Damnatus... est!
I cannot see you anymore...
Maschine empathy.
Finish them!
Heavy weapon, 12 o'clock!
That won't hold them back for long.
Let's go!
Oktavian. Is this the way that
will get us out of here the quickest?
It is the one with
the least enemy activities.
Wodan,...
if we ever survive that trip,
please remind me to award
pleasant Mr. Adeodatus here
with some permanent medals!
We need an exit, now!
Watch out!
Someone’s coming!
In the name of the Imperator,
hold your fire!
The seal of the Inquisition.
An operative.
Things are getting better and better, eh?
You’re lucky I didn’t
aim any higher or lower.
Mhm, just a flesh wound ...
Let’s hurry,
the door can only be opened from inside.
Nobody’s here.
Good. We have to go back.
It will start soon.
A lot of sectors are
not used by the conclave.
When I heard that you fled
to the north-eastern complex,
I did all I could to hurry up to find you
before they did.
Conclave?
What kind of people are we talking about?
You don’t know that?
No, not really.
Strange, this is not the common procedure
with missions of this importance.
Well, I am sorry for your losses.
Unfortunately I lost contact with command.
Otherwise I would have
guided you to a secret entrance.
There’s no need to feel bad.
We didn’t lose anybody.
Inquisitor Lessus didn’t send more?
No.
Damn you, what is this all about!?
One moment. We are almost there.
I got myself access to
stratetically important points
and was able to establish
a secret hideout here.
Not quite comfortable,
but better than to be in the
same room with these heretics.
Do you have any dressing material?
There’s no need for that.
I will personally take care of it later.
Do you have a name or...
is that top secret, too?
Alias: Lechias
Well, Lechias...
Why don’t you tell us why we’re here.
Or even better:
What do you think why we’re here.
You were hired to prevent
an unholy ceremony being held
threatening the planet and maybe
even the whole system.
Witch scum then!
I knew it, I knew it all along!
Not a common sorcerer ...
The so called 'Conclave of Ninity'
is led by Zyriakus Makkabeus,
a traitor, on whose trail
we have been for decades.
He must be stopped
before he is able to put
his insane plan into action.
What are his exact plans?
Ignorance is a value
that has to be protected.
There may be a reason why you did not get
every piece of information, mercenaries ...
Sure thing.
Otherwise we wouldn’t have
gotten stuck with that crap here!
It’s an...
Invocatio Daemonis, isn't it?
You could put it that way, but...
beware your words and thoughts.
We do not want to lure such...
dark creatures.
For months I have had to
fight off this foul spawn
that is spread widely everywhere down here.
Only too well I know
about these nameless things.
Anyway.
I infiltrated this place
to gather information about
the scheming of this Makkabeus.
But then I lost contact with the HQ
and I could only send few data.
Probably the assigned Inquisitor
doesn’t know anything about this situation.
That would explain
why we were sent down here.
We’re definitely
the wrong guys for that mission.
Let the Inquisition send their specialists!
Yeah, right!
Or even the warriors of the Adeptus Astartes!
Time is ticking though!
A fortunate planetary configuration
is in to happen as I have got to know.
Pardon!? Does that mean
it’s all about to start any second
and we’re in midst of this crap!?
What shall we do?
If it is about eliminating the traitor
whose name I do not want to repeat,
I will volunteer for the mission.
Nira and myself are
sufficiently armed for this mission.
I see,
milksop here would like
to be the hero, yes?
Confess, you knew that all the time!
That’s a stitch-up!
You’re all in cahoots with each other!
Didn’t you listen to him?
It's about Sancta Heroica,
my home!
What use would the Inquisition have of
assigning a bunch of dirty mercenaries
to such an important operation?
But we’re perhaps only
supposed to be a diversion!
Personally I don’t feel
the urge to sacrifice myself
for this city or anything else
on this ugly world.
Lower your weapon, Sergeant.
There is no alternative as it seems.
In this universe one is sacrificed
or sacrifices himself.
We could definitely use
some reinforcements.
Right,...
why don’t you just
inform your superior, Adeodatus?
- I...
- His secret uplink
has no connection
since we entered depth 69.
That’s right. I can’t send
any Vid-Log messages since then.
The conclave knows well
how to hide themselves.
But we have that skill as well.
I know a secret passage
beneath the old manufactorum
leading directly to the
inner chambers of the conclave’s lair.
There your will find
the heads of this heretic hydra.
You won’t come with us?
An Imperial operative
with your experience, your skills,
could be very helpful with this.
My strength lies in infiltration,
not in combat.
My skills are rather...
unusual.
This is not my body.
It is the body of
rich merchant Reuel Eisenstein,
an influential supporter of the conclave.
He could move rather
freely amongst the heretics.
Spys, altering their shape ...
I have heard of rumours that the Inquisition
had such operatives at its disposal.
Enough! Let’s go.
I anyway have to go back soon.
Otherwise they would get suspicious.
And under no circumstance
leave the way I showed you!
Don’t worry, Oktavian
has already stored the way.
Very well.
Voluntas imperatoris perficiatur.
What used to be manufactured
here, by the way?
Everything the Imperium
needs for its defence.
Tanks, weapons, ammunition.
Why then was this manufactorum shut down?
Nobody knows that exactly nowadays.
There are many rumours of how it is
connected to the great plague centuries ago.
But there are many old wives’ tales
about this old section of the hive anyway.
What a waste ...
I will send a prayer
to the Omissiah for forgiveness..
Nira!
What’s wrong?
It's... it’s alright.
She suddenly collapsed.
Don’t worry. One gets used to it.
We have to move on.
They... they screamed.
Screaming? Who was screaming?
I don’t know.
Many of them... many.
But when you came,...
they fell silent.
You’re not trying
to come on to me, are you?
No!
I took a vow.
Do not pollute my thoughts.
But it is like you were surrounded
by an aura of calmness ...
It keeps bad spirits away.
A foreign race gave it to me
after rescuing me.
Evil xenos tricks!?
If you like to call it that way.
I can feel it protecting me, but...
I’m willing to lend it to you
if it helps you to focus
your thoughts on our mission.
It is wonderful.
Still, keep it hidden.
What's keeping you groxes?
What’s wrong?
Listen.
Which way now?
That is the way.
So we now hand over
our fate to a playing card.
Like some inquisitors, too.
You wanted to talk to me,
Inquisitor Makkabaeus?
Yes, honoured Eisenstein.
I hope my two guards did not disturb thou.
But after that strange raid -
During which thou as well hast been
wounded, as I can see -
we are forced to act more cautiously.
Those intruders ...
They could be a vanguard!
Perhaps the puritans among my order
are already breathing down my neck.
They rather came across me like...
a bunch of...
shabby archeotech raiders.
Yes, that may be.
But thou shalt never trust
the outer appearance ...
As I see, you already ordered the staff
being taken out of the stasis chamber.
I thought this should only happen
when the time has come?
I only had it brought
into my chamber to study it.
Do not worry. The splinter essence inside
will not fade that soon.
Far from it.
It is alive, very alive.
Please... be careful with it.
I spent my entire wealth
for this precious staff
being taken to Sancta Heroica.
All our hardship
will be remunerated with the undying
blessing of the Emperor, my friend.
Soon,
we will begin.
The stars are on the exact
same coordinates as...
1000 years ago when B’ewesh G’guor -
his false name shall be damned -
spread his foul wings above this planet.
Today, we will bring him
down once and for all.
We will force him into
the righteous chains of faith.
And we will use his power
against his rotten kind.
His breed will burn!
And his retinue
will be erased from the face of
the universe!
Upon my name Makkabaeus.
Sic fiat et non aliter.
Yes.
Yeess, it shall come.
Now, make thy way as soon as possible
to one of the protection chambers.
And place a personal
purity seal upon the door.
During the ceremony huge amounts
of psychic energies will be released.
It may come to pass
that unasked creatures
of the warp may haunt us.
Prepare thyself for that.
In a few hours everything will be over,
and then we will be able
to continue our research.
Eisenstein, thou shalt
lay thyself to rest anyway.
Thou look weakened.
The wound?
Yees, ...
it seems like that.
Then set out.
I will personally
commit a deed that wilst
go down in the annals
of the Imperium!
I don’t get it! We even have
to crawl through this soup here!
Und da vorn wird
das ganze auch noch tiefer.
Hope your sensors are right, Oktavian.
There is nothing
beneath this dirty broth!
Rats, Dubro, just rats ...
I just feel like having a ratburger now.
Do you remember the times
on Necromunda, Corris?
Those were the best ones!
There the sewer was
the most contaminated place.
Yeah! Those were real rats!
It’s ok.
Just a dizzy spell ...
Take me to my chambers.
I have to attend to
some personal affairs.
But...
There’s no but!
I will follow you to the shelter, soon.
I will make it.
One thing is bothering me, soldier ...
And that would be?
If that is supposed to
be depth 69 above us,
where the Horus are we now?
We’re still in depth 69.
But maybe the manufactorum
sunk because of hive quakes.
My hive has exactly
191 heights and 69 depths.
Remember that, merc.
All be quiet.
A... warp storm... approaches.
We’d better hurry up.
What...
What is happening... to me?
It is exceptionally quiet in here ...
That must be the realm
of the inner circle.
Be alert, it cannot be far.
Let’s bring this to an end!
Seem as if they were
less fortunate than we were.
Come on, onwards.
(Summoning formula)
Strange things are happening here.
This summoning is not
what it seems to be ...
Kill them!
Kill them quickly!
We must go on.
Well done, Nira ...
Keep them at bay!
In the name of the damned Inquisition,
I hereby adjourn this meeting!
You shall not...
interrupt us now ...
Not now!
Die,
heretic!
Nooo!
You misguided...
you fools!
If this was not what it looked like, ...
what was it?
Nira?
I... I don’t know ...
You could be right.
Wodan saw an inquisitorial rosette
pinned on Makkabaeus’ cowl
shortly before he burnt the corpse.
Those were no followers of Chaos,
at least no common ones.
I don’t know what we blundered into
and I don’t feel the need to know it.
But when we reach the surface
we’ll take the first available transport off
this planet and get the hell out of here.
We could take you with us, Nira.
... as we will have an esplanade soon.
I will hand over
your engrams to your brothers
having them brought to Mars and
laid down within the machine god’s temple,
as you told me to.
We have to go now,
old friend,
we have to go now.
Omnissias te per
tenebras ducebit.
Hurry.
The same way before it is blocked.
I don’t give a damn
what happened to patrol 9.
Hold your positions!
Too late ...
Flesh...
it is so weak...
so...
weak.
Stay here, cowardly grots!
Go go! All’s clear.
Do you this taste, too?
Tastes like metal or something.
Where’s Osmar got to?
Oh...
The brave soldier is injured
and doesn’t want to show it.
I’ll pick him up ...
What is that!?
Why didn’t you warn us?
What’s wrong with you, Nira?
You did feel it!
Yes, there... there was something.
In the door.
But it is not only in the door.
It is everwhere!
It’s no use!
It’s growing again!
Go on! We’ll find another exit!
Come on, soldier.
Silence, my brothers!
Silence!
Yes.
The ceremony has been interrupted.
You know
what to do, brothers.
Do you think...
they’ll make it on their own?
Corris is a tough one to break.
He’ll make it.
I’m not sure if we came down that way ...
Come on. We have to stay together.
Do you by any chance happen
to know where the exit is?
Of course...
There’s where all those friendly
guys with the masks come from.
That’s a way out of here.
Wait here.
Damn!
Speak of the enemy.
- How many?
- Too many for the two of us.
Do you see the stairs over there?
Yeah.
If we move fast, we’ll make it.
- I’ll watch your back.
- Good.
Go!
There the killers!
Judge them!
Go down the stairs, quickly!
Come on, come on ...
Damn.
Take cover!
What’s wrong, Wodan?
Look at that.
Seventy-one.
This hive seems to have
more depths than people know.
We got lost in any way.
These markings doesn’t
help us on neither.
Come on.
Fortunately the whole
ceiling didn’t come down.
That’ll buy us time.
Come on.
Good.
Good, good, good.
Are you alright?
I'm fine, I'm fine ...
Okay,...
which way?
Which way ...
Don’t panic ...
Just don’t panic.
What in the name... !?
Which way?
Which corridor?
What ...?
This way.
Come on.
We have to take this way.
Looks like a market square ...
or something like that.
That is no market square.
The plague that is said
to have raged down here,
was a soul plague.
The faithful versus the heretics
and the heretics versus the faithful.
That’s why they sealed the lowest depths
and sank them into oblivion.
Let’s keep moving.
Please.
Well, Sergeant...
What’s the deal with your playing card?
In the past, in my regiment,
they called me 'Spade-Ace',
because I always had it with me.
It’s my lucky charm,
Adeodatus.
Got me out of the slavery -
this little playing card.
My owner was drunken
when he raised his bet, and -
well -
it’s been a long time.
Sometimes it feels like
two, three eternities.
Well,...
shortly after I
entered active duty in the Imperial Guard.
I was twelve back then.
Those guys again!
Run, Adeodatus - run!
Hell, I like it.
Praise Him on Terra!
Looks like somebody was here recently.
The conclave actually
digged very deep as it seems.
Either for research or for worshipping.
Probably it was a bit of both.
Hey, Hiero!
I hear them again.
The voices.
So many.
Your charm, it doesn’t help!
Wait, don’t do that.
Who knows what will happen if you drop it.
The air and the walls
weep of psychic energy,
no need to be gifted to -
It is not a gift - it is a curse!
Hold on, Nira.
We’ll find a way out.
Poor thing ...
Damn!
They have welded the door!
I’ll go for reinforcements.
They will be purged for their deed.
Who are you?
No...
no...
no, it can’t be.
Y-you cannot...
Y-you just cannot have
found another host.
No!
It can’t be!
We better blast our way
to the other direction.
And better be fast!
There’s no use in praying Adeodatus.
Actions are the prayers of a soldier
and victories his offerings.
Get in there!
Let’s hope there’s a way out
on the other side.
Corris?
I’m sorry.
His orders.
His orders!
How far upwards do these
stairs actually lead?
I hope far.
The assembly tunnels to
the next depth could be sealed.
But we will see.
Wodan?
Hiero!
Blasted rats.
Wodan!
Damn!
(Prayer)
You, too, will die!
We all have to die.
Some sooner!
Others later ...
Ignorant!
I’d better die now for the cause
than later for HIM!
What’s that supposed to mean?!
Speak, heretic!
We have failed.
HE is free again,
and HE thirsts...
Where is he?
I don’t know.
But I will find it out.
Listen, Nira.
You will pass that bridge,
take the stairs.
You’ll make it,
you know that.
You’re stronger and more
powerful than anyone of us.
But I cannot-
You have to!
In this universe
one will either be sacrified
or sacrifice one-self.
The truth is we can’t even
chose the way we die on our own.
You can’t have gone far.
No!
He couldn't bear themmm.
The visions I showed him
of my realmmm!
Daemon!
Thy weaponsss are worthlessss
against the omnipotenccce of the change.
My host has grown strong.
Who... ?
Ssso easy to manipulate ...
We jussst have to follow you humansss
to strengthen ourselvesss
at your sssoul fire.
Your friends did entertain me for a while ...
Lechias?
Thou art the lassst one.
Ssso she cannot be far.
My plan did not foresssee you
to shield her that well from me.
Time isss running out.
But this game isss
over now!
(Prayer)
Spare thy vigour, young Noviccce.
Do not resist the fate I choossse for thou.
Daemon!
Thou shalt not be here!
I am here
because this is my world!
I came back to claim what once was mine!
And now I shall end what I begun.
Tremendous lies!
Thou roam upon the soil
of the almighty Emperor.
If I cannot stop thee,
his legions will
in his holy name!
How right thou arrrt!
Therefor I mussst open the gate to my realm.
And for this I need thy power!
Thou arrrt not alone ...
Now I sense you,
old friend.
Now I see thou.
Even after I crushed thy body,
thy will tries to cross my plansss?
Just as I frussstrated thine,
Farseer Vintog Phaer?
How ironic ...
Unusual psy activities inside
the depths of Sancta Heroica.
So this is where it will all begin again ...
Transfer the coordinates!
Right from the beginning
thou hast seen through my plans.
Thou hast watched me choose my pieces.
From the addicted changeling,
to the megalomaniac hunter
to the sleeping ssstorm of power.
And now everything is over
as thou brought thy puny
being into the game.
So, this big is thy sacrifice.
The Sphere Gate of Carmanshybed
might be closssed eternally for me,
but thy soul also
is lost forever.
Thou might have tricked me,
but in the plans of the ever-changing
defeats are not included.
As only Chaosss
is eternal!
I predicted
that we won’t be too late.
We are too late.
It is said
that there are more daemons
lurking in the dark
Than there are stars shining in the sky.
But there will be the day,
the stars will stop
existing.