Yes, I'll hold.
Uncle Neil?
Hi, it's Jessica.
How are you?
Really?
Yeah, I'm in Hollywood.
So what have you been doing
for the past five years?
Yeah?
I miss you.
A lot.
When can I come
and visit you?
Can you come
and visit me?
I'd love it
if you came and visited me.
I don't care about that.
It doesn't matter anymore.
I just want to see you.
Okay, I'll try.
Are you ready?
Yes... okay.
Bye.
Heather,
can I get a beer?
- You got money?
- I do.
- How are you doing?
- Haven't seen you in a while.
I haven't been
around in a while.
I've been keeping an eye
on the cover of Rolling Stone
- and haven't seen you there either.
- Keep watching.
- Excuse me.
Mr. Black Cloud.
How are you doing?
Okay.
How are you?
- I want to talk to you.
- I want to talk to you too.
- Hey Bobby,
- Yeah?
Look at this one
that Paulina showed me.
I don't know how to get
into it very gracefully.
Bobby:
That's real sexy.
I like that.
- You do?
- Yeah.
Make sure this guy pays you
before you show him any tit.
- Are we open?
- Yes, ma'am, we are.
- We are?
- Yes.
Fuck,
I have to get dressed!
Look at the difference
between that eye and that eye.
That's a half centimeter more.
And you can't put that out.
- Has anybody seen Jo?
- No, but her shit's here.
She went outside.
Probably sucking some guy's cock.
Tell her
to come in the office.
Tell her yourself.
Probably sucking some guy's cock.
Woman:
Simone's going up for me.
Whatever happens outside
this club is none of my business.
But what happens in here, is.
If he gives you
any shit, let me know.
- I'm in control.
- You're in control.
- I'm just trying to get unstoned.
- Hurry up.
Bobby:
Get dressed, please.
Oh, fuck!
I'm getting signed right now, so-
- Congratulations.
- Finally turning around.
That's so good,
because I need money.
I need to be able to get
things for the little boy,
- or the little girl-
- Listen.
I really want to party.
You know?
Okay, can we not party
for a couple of days?
Because if we meet with
this lady and you're not high,
then she'll think
we're both stable
and you can tell her
you're going to get a deal
- and make a lot of money-
- Am I going to sign something?
Uh... no. Well, you might
have to sign something,
but you can use
a fake name if you
- know the social security number-
- Wait, so I sign something,
and you'll get
a full-grown child?
No, he would be a six
or seven-year-old, probably.
Okay.
- I'll do it.
- Really?
Oh, thank you,
Charlie.
Check this out, Bobby.
Nico.
Yeah,
Carrie Crawford?
Eddie Hazel,
from the Blue Iguana.
Right, down in LA.
We'd like to get Nico in for a party
we're having next week.
She'd be a great addition
to our program as a feature dancer.
She has time
in her schedule?
Yeah,
we're real happy.
Give me a call back.
My number's 937-4444.
Eddie Hazel.
Blue Iguana.
Okay,
I'll talk to you then.
This ain't going
to be cheap.
I ain't worried
about cheap, baby.
We'll fill this club, she's
getting 300 to 400 guys a night.
There's a reason why.
My, oh my,
we got us a full house.
- Good day.
- How are you doing?
- Thank you.
- Be sure to make money.
I don't want you
getting used to this.
Come by later,
I've got to talk to you.
- This is for you.
- Thanks for your help.
Where's Jo?
I think she went outside.
- Hey, Eddie.
- Where the fuck have you been?
What do you mean, where
the fuck have I been? I'm here!
- My shit is here.
- Put that out.
Woman #2:
Thank you for the flower.
Jo:
Where's my flower?
- Thank you, sweetheart!
- Don't think it's gonna be that easy.
You come in here late,
- acting up, smoking.
- Fuck you, fuck you.
- Fuck you.
- Yeah, okay.
You'll get it later,
if you're good.
I was sick, Eddie.
I was sick.
Shut up,
you fucking hyena!
I would appreciate if you didn't
get all over that black guy.
- He's one of my regulars.
- The one with the Jheri-Curl?
- That's one of your regulars?
- Yes, it is.
He's such
a fucking freak.
I would appreciate
if you took that guy back,
'cause he's just an asshole.
Let me give you a suggestion.
You should get a titjob.
Eddie:
Get off. Come here!
- Jo:... take that money-
- Shut the fuck up!
I will
suspend both of you.
And don't call my bluff!
Thank you. It's jealousy.
Can you believe that?
I got my own.
I'll show you how
it's done, all right, boy?
Yeah?
Oh, fuck!
What time is it?
No, I forgot. Okay? I forgot.
No, I have it.
No, I'll be there
in 10 minutes.
All right.
- Hey, Johnny.
- How are you doing?
- Do you have the money?
- Yeah. Here you go.
What the fuck is this?
I told you 40.
- No, you didn't tell me 40.
- I told you 40.
Are you all right?
- Are you all right?
- Yeah, I'm fine.
- Where's the rest of my money?
- I'll give it to you next week.
- See you later.
- Fuck it!
Two.
You got them
from in there?
$2.00 each.
I know you.
You dance at the Blue Iguana.
Right? I just saw you there.
- Yeah.
- What's your name? Jasmine?
- Mm-hm.
- Jorge.
- Hi, Jorge. Nice to meet you.
- Nice to meet you.
- I remember your name.
- Will you come by again?
- Yeah, I should be there soon.
- Can I have my books?
Thanks.
Bye, handsome. Say hi.
I will.
I know that girl.
I didn't know
you went to strip clubs?
- What are you talking about?
- She's a stripper.
- She comes to my poetry readings.
- No, she dances at the Blue Iguana.
She's a stripper.
Why don't you go
in the back and stack?
All right.
- She said I was handsome.
- Hey, big day!
This is Eddie Hazel,
from the Blue Iguana.
I wanted to invite you to a party
here this Saturday night...
- Hi, Jessie, I'm Bobby.
- I'm here for the audition.
- You're late.
- I'm sorry. I like your hair.
It's very snazzy.
- Okay, thanks.
- Hello, Mr. Hazel.
- How are you?
- My name's Jessie.
- I'm here for the audition.
- All right. Nice.
- I like your glasses.
- Thank you.
- Have you danced before?
- I danced at Cheetahs for six months.
Do you have a pen?
Do you have an ID?
I don't have it on me.
It's at the apartment.
Eddie:
We'll need to see some ID.
We've got all kinds
of vice people, ABC coming in.
Are you planning on
stabbing someone tonight?
- No.
- It's a joke.
- This is soft.
- So...
Where did you get this?
Bobby:
Jimmy, put it on.
Hi.
I'm okay. And you?
Good.
Yeah.
We open up at 7:00.
We'll put you in the line-up.
Don't forget your ID.
Thank you, Eddie.
I'll see you tonight.
We run a tightjoint here.
No drugs, no hand jobs,
no blowjobs and no fucking.
You are so handsome.
- Did anyone ever tell you that?
- Thank you.
Yeah, I get it all the time.
Brad Pitt's got nothing on me.
- I think you're a doll.
- That's fine.
The word angle is spelled,
A- N-G-L-E,
whilst the word angel is spelled,
- A-N-G-E-L.
- Angle.
- Angel.
How many nights?
One.
It's 30 plus tax,
that is $34.20.
Hello!
LA paper.
Complimentary.
Tape:
Listen and check your answers.
Practice saying them.
He wears a uniform.
- He wears a uniform.
She's a pilot.
She flies all over the world.
- She's a pilot-
- Angel!
In winter, Alice goes skiing,
and in summer, she plays golf...
Ladies and gentlemen,
she fell from the sky.
The celestial Angel.
Whoo!
You know? Excuse me? Hi.
You're sitting in someone's seat.
It's Angel's seat.
Why don't you sit-
yeah, sit in Jo's seat.
- I'm Jessie, by the way.
- Hi Jessie, I'm Jasmine.
You have beautiful lips.
Do you use collagen?
No, they're natural.
There's some freak hanging
outside in a green Cadillac.
- I saw him.
- Did you see him?
That's fucking freaky.
We ought to tell Bobby,
to get him-
- I saw him twice last week.
- Stormy, did you see him?
No.
- Is he there now?
- Yeah.
Remember that
guy who followed me home?
- Don't go out there.
- I'll be right back.
- Don't go outside.
- I want to see who it is.
If you talk to him,
tell him to fuck off.
I don't fucking believe this.
Excuse me? Honey?
New girl? Barbie?
You're sitting in my seat.
This is my seat.
You might notice
there's stuff in front of it?
There's a jacket on the back of it.
Jasmine, how could
you let her sit in my seat?
- Don't talk to me.
- Find your own space.
Find your own space,
and we'll all get along.
You know that guy
who looks like Colonel Sanders?
- He gave me some bud and I-
- Hey, bitch, you're up!
- I just came off stage!
- Not you, cornflake,
I'm talking to Jasmine.
Jasmine, it's your turn.
I'm not going up.
I'm not ready.
I have to let my rubber breathe.
- Jasmine:... they're saying Jo.
- They're not.
- I can't go. I'm not ready.
- I'll go.
You'll go for me?
You'll do that for me?
You're a really sweet girl.
You know that?
She's Jessie.
She's our new addition.
She gets along with everybody.
We love little Jessie here.
Go on up.
You're gonna miss your-
And now,
making her stage debut...
she's young, she's beautiful,
she's perfection.
Ladies and gentlemen, put
your hands together for Jessie!
Just wondering.
Did you ever get her ID?
Yes, I know who she is.
I talked to Billy.
Did that call from Nico come yet?
It's on the machine.
Come on, Bobby, you said
you were going to tell me.
Mm-hm.
I'm telling you.
Hi, Eddie Hazel,
this is Nico.
So it looks like we're on, baby.
I'll be there.
You have my numbers. Bye.
Are you okay?
You doing okay, kid?
My glasses, my glasses.
Why don't you take them off?
We'll put them right here.
Are you okay with that?
All right, sweetie.
Okay, how's that?
- Everything okay?
- Yeah.
Want to see the bad side?
- All right. Here we go.
- Oh God.
Hi.
Jessie.
- Want to dance tonight?
- Mmm.
Let's go.
I don't have any money for this.
I'll make an exception.
Listen to this.
That's not the message I saved.
Woman:
I realize our ancestral humor
goes through common
longing and resistance.
I know the effort
you will not make
until you are ready
to accept I am not a war.
That was great!
Greatjob.
Thank you, Fiona.
I forgot to mention earlier,
we put some fliers on the chairs
referring to the upcoming
poetry slam in San Francisco.
As you know,
it is the most important
poetry event on the West Coast
so be sure to check it out.
Now, without further ado,
I'd like to bring up Sophie Delvaux,
whose latest collection,
"Autumn Sopranos,"
will soon be published
by the Hubcap Poets Library.
Sophie.
"Dreamboat.
Sleep is a boat moored
in this room at night
And again at dawn.
In between,
itjourneys over the world,
Travels inside
the scheme of things,
Moves out over the stars,
Comes, sailing into port,
its cargo... "
You never read.
No.
So what's that on your paper?
- Your laundry list?
- Mm-hmm.
Maybe you should come
and read your laundry list.
Maybe not.
- Hey.
- Hey, baby.
- Hey, Stormy?
- Yeah.
You don't know
a Marie Hughes, do you?
Marie Hughes, ring a bell?
- What is that?
- I don't know.
Some attorney type dropped
it off for her about 10 minutes ago.
I'll give it to her.
No, I'll give it to her.
Do you know who it is?
- Yeah, it's me.
- You?
Fan mail?
Use your stage name,
not your real name.
You hear me?
Oh my God.
- I think I'm pregnant.
- No, you're not.
Yeah, look at this.
- What the fuck is that?
- It's at the plus.
- That means you're pregnant.
- Where did you get this?
In the bathroom.
I was peeing and I found it
beneath the toilet.
Did you piss on it?
Well, I was standing-
I was hovering
because the toilet is gross.
So I was peeing
and I looked down
and I saw this
right beneath the toilet.
And I think
I might have dribbled on it.
Did you piss on the thing?
- There's piss on it...
- That's gross.
and I might have dribbled on it...
- You're not fucking anyone.
- Nobody right now,
but I heard
on the Discovery Channel
that sperm
can live a long time.
When was the last
time you fucked anyone?
- Six or seven months.
- That is not yours.
- Kathy, this is yours?
- No, it's not mine.
- Tiffany?
- See, it's mine.
- No, it's not.
- This isn't yours, right?
- You didn't piss on it,
- you're not fucking anyone.
- I've been wanting to get pregnant.
- Jessie, is this yours?
- Get off of my things.
- I'd appreciate it.
- Jo?
Where's Stormy?
- I want to keep it.
- Angel, don't!
Why do you want to keep it?
Someone pissed on that.
It's not yours.
Okay, kids, go to town!
Whoo!
Stormy, what do you get
for a blowjob?
$100.
Okay.
- Give it to me. Is this yours?
- What is it?
I don't know
what the fuck it is.
It stinks.
Get it away from me.
- Sit down.
- What?
- Are you pregnant?
Are you pregnant?
What the fuck
is the matter with you?
Do I look like I'm pregnant?
No, I'm not.
- What's going on?
- Angel found it and thinks it's hers.
- But it's obviously not hers.
- Angel found it. It's probably hers.
Angel, honey, are you pregnant?
Congratulations, baby!
You'll make
such a good mother.
Just don't leave
the baby in the park.
Jo, sit down.
Look at me, will you?
Are you pregnant?
- No.
- How late are you?
I'm not late.
- Give it to me!
- Keep your hands off of my pills!
Fuck! What the fuck
is the matter with you people?
- How late are you?
- I'm not late, okay?
All right, I got-
give me this.
- What does that mean-
- It means you're pregnant.
It's a plus, there's
a little blue plus sign right there.
All right, I'm not a moron.
I read the box.
- It's a plus sign, okay?
- Are you gonna keep it?
I'm not going to keep it.
I'm gonna throw it away.
It's disgusting.
What do you think?
If you want, I have a doctor.
- I think I got a defective EPT...
- No, you did not.
- because it was in my...
- It's so beautiful.
Honey, I have a doctor in
Culver City who can take care of it.
Okay.
Can you make
an appointment for me?
'Cause I don't want to
carry it around.
It's okay.
- Hey, Bobby.
- Hey.
- Bobby, you seen Charlie?
- Yeah, I've seen him.
He gave me a tip.
Fucking asshole.
Where is he? I have to arrange
something with him.
You really want to know?
Yeah, why?
What happened?
Come on,
let's go for a smoke.
Why?
What happened?
Asshole!
The motherfucker?
- What am I supposed to do now?
- You'll be fine.
What do you mean?
He told me he was going to come
to the meeting with me.
I give him something and he was
going to be my fiancé,
and he made me a promise.
He said,
"I'm going to come with you,
and then he goes off
with the first- fucking little-
What, you need a leech?
Here, calm down.
Fuck! I need him
to show I'm like
a whole person who's going
to get married and stuff-
Sit down. Sit down.
Relax.
Bobby...
You can do better
than Charlie.
Yeah, right.
Some kid's going to be
lucky to have you as a mom.
That's what
you got to remember.
He wasn't going
to be there with me.
He was going
to go to the interview.
Now what am I going to do?
Let me look
at that tip he gave you.
What are you doing?
That's my money.
- That's my money.
- That's Charlie's money.
You can have this.
I'll tell you what.
I'm going to check with Eddie
and I'll give you a ride home.
Don't be a long time, Bobby.
Miss Willow?
You can come in now.
Miss Willow, why do you
want to foster a child?
Well, because
I really love children,
and I really feel
that I could give them
a safe and happy place to be
while they're waiting
for their parents
to get out of rehab orjail-
Sometimes these kids do come
from very disturbed backgrounds
and it's important to have
a safe and secure environment
and someone with an open mind.
Yeah, I have a very open mind.
Yeah, like your sign that says,
"The hand of friendship has no color. "
I don't look down on Michael Jackson
for changing the color of his skin.
We have people in my building that are-
there's three lesbians
living in one apartment.
All of them sleep in the same bed
and they're the most normal
people that you can ever meet.
Even though they sleep together,
they're so nice.
Oh, I'm sure they actually-
you live in the same building,
so this is an apartment on Whitsett?
- Spec.
- Spec. You moved.
No, it's around
the corner from Whitsett.
That was the direction.
Okay. So-
Okay, so how long have
you lived in Los Angeles?
- For six years.
- And where did you grow up?
- Oklahoma.
- You moved here from Oklahoma?
- Six years from Oklahoma?
- No, I was in Vegas for a while.
What were you doing in Vegas?
- I was engaged.
- Did you get married?
No. I would have, but
he didn't want to marry me
because...
he was a very wealthy man,
but he had some character flaws.
What kind of character flaws?
He liked really young women.
You're a beautiful woman.
I can't imagine him finding
someone younger or more attractive.
Well, thanks, but when I turned 25,
I was just kind of kicked out.
Do you have a significant other now?
Mm-hm. Charlie.
He's my fiancé
and he was going to
come with me today
and I know you might
be worried that he's not here
but he had a big record deal
and they needed him in New York
because he might be
doing some music with Yanni...
- Oh.
- or some other people.
That's very soulful.
- Okay-
- He's very soulful.
What do you fear most in life?
- Death.
- What does that bring up for you?
Not being able to live.
And what about
the most pleasurable thing?
- Love.
- Miss Willow?
- Hm-hum?
What do you think
you can give a child?
Well, I have a Teddy bear
that I had when I was a kid.
And I make a really good
fluffer-nutter sandwich.
You are-
you are very charming.
I want you
to understand something.
Fostering a child
is not a hobby
- and it's not an activity-
- Oh no, I know.
It's very serious.
It's an occupation.
It's a commitment
that you're going to make.
I know, I understand.
I have too many hobbies already,
- so...
- Okay.
Would you look at my ass?
There's something in it.
Is it warts?
- I don't want to have herpes.
- No, it's not.
You just cut your asshole, that's all.
Just put a little...
You might feel sorry for me
'cause I only made one dollar.
- Ha!
- Oh, please!
Jesus, Angel!
Put some
aloe vera on that, Jasmine.
I've been
thinking about little Jo,
because it would
be really easy to remember.
It's like your name.
And it would be
good for a girl or a boy.
Can I get your attention?
Don't forget.
Hello, Tiffany...
Party at my house
the day after tomorrow
for the foster kid.
Sometimes it takes a
while to find the right guy,
and people can piss
off people and the thing is-
- Hello!
- What?
We're getting my apartment ready for
my foster kid the day after tomorrow.
I'll make a map so everyone knows
how to get to my apartment, okay?
Man:
Remember these glasses?
I was wondering if,
maybe, you could hold them
while I straighten things out
with the landlord.
Straighten it out?
Those were my wife's.
She loved them and it's
the only memento I got of her.
That's Stormy!
Eddie, Harry left
his binoculars for you.
- Harry left these?
- Yeah.
Thanks.
- Hey, Desiree?
- Yeah?
- Are you okay?
- Yeah, I'm fine.
Hi.
It's room 2-0-8.
Yes. No,
I am not going.
Yes, I stay
one more night.
No, no problem.
You scared me.
You want me
to get out of your way?
No, I have
nowhere to go.
- Light me one, will you?
- Yeah, sure.
He's here, Bobby.
Who?
Sullivan.
Your brother?
Yes.
He wants me
to go see him.
Mmm-hmm.
He's staying
at the Sunset Hilton.
You know where that is?
Yeah. Yeah.
He's getting married.
He's going
to be a daddy.
- You're going to be an aunt.
- Fuck you.
Fuck no,
I don't want to see him.
How did we do tonight?
We did all right.
Do you want some advice?
Wait until Christmas,
buy them all nice little gifts,
you go home,
you take a picture
and you go home.
I don't want your advice.
I want to see him.
74 Fleetwood.
We drove across the country
in that car.
I always wanted to do that.
Best memories of my life.
- He's right there.
- Where?
Right there.
My brother.
- How do you know?
- I know.
I know he's on
the left side of the bed
and he's smoking
a cigarette and thinking.
I'm not going up.
I don't want to go up.
- You want to go back to my place?
- No, take me back to my car.
All right.
Okay, this is
an excellent guitar, so...
Thank you.
Baby, come here.
You look great with this.
Here, let me tell you.
You hear that sound?
Yeah, this is a '59 Gibson Les Paul.
There is more history
behind this instrument.
You have to hold it
like a precious baby.
Charlie:
Think baby Jesus.
Jessie:
I have the goods.
- I'm so proud of you.
- That'll be four, three,
two, four, seven,
ninety-three. Cash?
- Cash.
- That's cash. Take them.
- Okay. Excellent.
- Are you happy?
Thank you, baby.
I got all this great
stuff at the 99 Cent Store
and I thought-
Wake up!
I got this really
great snorkel.
The kid can use it
as a snorkel in this pool.
Oh, that's so cute!
Where's Jo?
Where's everybody?
I think everybody
had an appointment.
I haven't heard from anybody.
You know that guy
who throws that shit up on stage?
- Presents!
- Yeah, I need to wake up.
So I think we should
smoke it right now.
Yeah 'cause
we need to organize.
We need to concentrate.
- Did you move the couch?
- Yeah, I'm working on the feng shui.
What the fuck is feng shui?
- It's- aren't you from Asia?
- No, I'm from Seattle. Light me.
Well, feng shui
is the ancient oreal-
oriental ritual
of decorating your house.
You move all
your furniture so that chi...
- Oh, fuck!
- energy can go through the house.
It blows from
one end to the other.
Okay,
we can work with that.
- Ange!
- What?
it's a fucking
sty in here!
I know, I'm going...
I'm going
to clean it right now.
I was waiting
for everyone to get here.
Where is the kid
going to sleep?
He's going to sleep in here.
I'll sleep on the couch.
This kid is going to sleep
in a heart-shaped bed?
I was thinking I'd turn it upside-down
so it'd look like a spaceship.
Good idea.
And get rid of the sheets.
- Get spaceship sheets.
- Good idea.
Oh my God,
you have to fix this hole.
Yeah.
I'll tell Bobby
to fix this hole.
We should make a list.
Okay. Dictate.
Fix the hole.
Um... buy wallpaper.
Bobby will know
where to buy the wallpaper.
Okay...
Fix the air conditioning.
It's so fucking hot in here.
I can't fix
the air conditioning thing
because there are
some rats living in it.
- You can't live with rats!
- I like rats!
We're gonna get rid of them.
Jasmine, don't!
I'm not going to kill them.
You've got
to kill the rats.
Tell Bobby
She won't let you keep the kid
if you have rats.
I won't keep the rats.
- I'll put them at your house.
- I am not keeping rats!
Just temporarily.
We can take the unit out
and put it at your house.
The kid needs air conditioning
and he can't live with rats.
She won't let you keep
the kid if you have rats.
I'm against killing them.
Sacrifice the fucking rats!
I'm hungry.
Maybe we should work
on the list outside,
- and work on our tans.
- I want pizza. Do you want some?
- Yeah.
- What kind?
Any kind. You can't
take your top off out there
because Mr. Sherman,
that 100-year-old man, always looks.
- Who's that?
- That's my dad.
Your dad is Adam West?
Well, he's who I like
to think of as my dad.
Don't you think
he kind of looks like me?
Look at his jaw and his mouth,
even his nose and everything.
- Look.
- No.
- Look, if I stood this way.
- Hmm-hm. You don't look like him.
Really?
It's okay. You don't have
to look like him.
Let's get pepperoni. Don't tell
the lady your dad is Batman.
Why?
Ellen.
Ellen Taylor.
Okay, have a seat.
We'll call you when we're ready.
Okay.
- Your name is Ellen?
- Yeah.
That's what we want to name
the baby if it's a girl,
after my husband's grandma.
It's kind of old-fashioned,
but it's so pretty.
Excuse me, Ellen.
You can't smoke in here.
- There's no smoking here.
- I'm sorry.
It's a doctor's office.
You should probably
seriously consider
stopping smoking at this point.
- Why?
- It's bad for the baby.
I'm sorry, Ellen.
You might be able
to smoke outside,
but you can't smoke in here.
And it's- like I said-
it's bad for the baby.
A girlfriend of mine
went for acupuncture-
I don't give a fuck about
the girlfriend of yours, okay?
Everybody doesn't have a happy,
cheerful, chirpy life like you do.
Okay? Everybody's
not here to have a baby.
Some of us-
Fuck you!
Fuck you, bitch!
Some of us are here to have abortion!
- Did you ever think of that?
- I'm sorry, no.
Did you ever?
No, because you don't think.
You rattle on and on
about your happy little husband
and your happy little
grandmother named Ellen
and you don't give
a fuck about other people.
You have a problem, lady!
You think you're the only one
with reproductive organs?
I'm going to have
this fucking baby,
and my baby is going to sell drugs
to your baby on the playground.
You fucking bitch!
Oh my God!
- Ohh!
- What the fuck is that?
- Oh my God!
- What are these for?
Jimmy:
These are for Angel.
- Stacy's Flower Company.
- Who are they from?
The driver said he was not allowed
to tell me who paid for them.
- What are you talking about?
- They're from a funeral parlor.
I'm not dead.
- They look like they're big.
- Oh my God!
- These are so beautiful.
- Nice, Angel. Score.
Oh my God!
Who are they from?
The driver said
he could not tell me.
Jasmine:
Did they give a card?
Jimmy:
No. I don't know nothing else.
I bet they're from Dale,
the guy with the bald head.
- The sweet big man, kind of nerdy.
- The guy drives a bus.
Yeah but sometimes those nerdy
guys are from Silicon Valley.
- He's a poor nerd.
- They invent toilet flushers...
- No, he's just poor.
- See you later.
Angel, these are 200
or 300 bucks! It's ugly, but...
I have an independently
wealthy secret admirer.
I'm going to take one, okay?
Maybe they're from Charlie.
His record deal
might have come through.
Just kidding.
Just kidding, sweetie.
Oh my God!
- I can't believe it!
- You lucky girl.
I know, it's like-
I'm like, so lucky.
We're gonna kick it
into the next gear,
because coming to the stage
is our resident wild child.
It's Jo!
Jo, it's enough!
Dave, get over here.
Get Jo off the stage.
What the fuck is
the matter with you?!
the matter with you?
Bobby:
Get her off the stage.
Angel, get out on stage!
- Fucking asshole!
- Is this her shit?
Yes.
You get the fuck out!
Get out of here!
You're a big man, aren't you?
You fucking piece of shit!
- You shit!
- Let her go.
Dave, you keep her out of here.
Keep her out of here.
I want my stuff, Jessie.
- Give me my stuff.
- Here's your stuff.
Okay, this one's from me.
"Pale shades of gray
loft the clouds
Above the bed,
half filled.
There is no smile
in this room,
No laugh during love.
A pall gently descends
over the space,
Once a sanctum,
now a hollow shape,
As the sun rises,
and my eyes fill with black. "
Thank you. Thank you.
All right.
I have a very special
surprise for us today.
I decided to bring
up a special mystery guest,
and it's someone who's
actually never read before,
so when she comes up,
give her a big encouragement.
Let's hear it for Jasmine.
Jasmine.
Come on up.
You don't want to read?
Come on up, give it a try.
Let's give her encouragement.
We've all been there.
Good luck.
My name is Cathy.
"If in the skylight, tawny
afternoon a drift of care
It's only love,
but gone in the way of everything.
If in the morning of your soul,
a brush of tenderly imagined lips,
It's only love,
but gone in the way of everything.
If in the messy cocktail dregs
of a midnight glass, a teardrop falls,
It's only love,
but gone in the way of everything.
If in the singing twilight of the dawn,
you give your heart unwanted,
It's only love,
but gone in the way of everything.
Then what in the hours
of your life is love?
It's here and gone,
and gives its name to everything. "
All right, well...
that's it for today.
So we'll see everybody next time,
and thanks a lot.
I'll see you later, okay?
Why did you call my name?
I didn't ask you to call my name.
I don't even know you.
That poem was really great.
Cathy...
that was really great.
I don't know what to say.
Yeah, well, thanks.
Do you have any more?
- Yeah.
- You got to get up and read.
That's all.
You've got to get up and read.
- Why?
- Because you're good.
I hate to disappoint you,
but you're really good.
Who is it?
It's... it's me.
It's you?
Yeah, I was sitting in my apartment.
That's me.
This woman
I used to be with, Maria...
she was beautiful.
She was a painter.
She painted that thing.
She was North African,
she had that pretty heavy accent.
She lived in Paris, New York,
all over the place,
and she had me sit five weeks.
Five weeks to do that thing.
You sit still for five weeks, huh?
You can't sit still for five minutes.
Yeah...
And she would talk to me.
She would talk about...
shapes and colors,
light, shadow,
all that stuff- painter shit,
and then she would use all of that,
and that's what
popped this thing to life.
She could look at your body,
and she would paint you,
but she would bring out
the shit that you never see.
You know what I mean?
She was a wild girl, too.
When she got tired
in the afternoon, she said,
"Eddie, you want to eat?"
I was alone in
this room- in this apartment
that I used to live with in Seattle.
He had a lot of books,
so I would sit and read all day.
One day I just couldn't
stand it any longer,
and I shut the blinds and...
kneeled on the floor and-
bawling my eyes out,
and I wrote it.
I tore it up.
I can't believe you
want to hear this stuff.
Were you stripping then?
Yeah.
I was working up in Seattle.
How do you know I'm a stripper?
This kid who works for me
said he saw you dance.
Tell him I said hi.
In this dream I had last night-
remember that cat
Johnny Washington I got in
a fight with in San Diego?
I don't remember him on purpose.
I saw my knife, my hand
cutting, and cutting his face,
blood getting on everything,
blood all over.
Strange, man.
Then I couldn't wash my hands.
Remember that phone call?
The girl crying I played
for you the other day?
Erase it.
I would have
erased it last week,
I would have said,
fuck the bitch, man...
but...
this week, I can't say,
fuck the bitch, you know?
You got some herb with you?
Yeah.
Why don't you roll us a joint?
So, do you go to strip clubs?
No.
Yeah, you don't seem
like the type.
Yeah? What's the type?
You know, married, lonely...
This kid
who works for me, Jorge-
Yeah, he's the kind
of kid that goes.
He said you're
on the billboard.
Yeah,
the Blue Iguana has a couple.
I'm only on one,
since my tits are small.
I'll get them done.
So are you the kind
of guy who likes big tits?
Actually, you know what?
I'm not used to
that line of questioning,
to tell you the truth.
All right.
Do you have any other
writers at your club?
Maybe we could
change the whole venue.
I don't know what
you're doing with me.
What?
You should be
with that French girl.
She's a good poet.
I really want to kiss you.
- Okay.
- No, I really want to kiss you.
I want to kiss the poet.
Do you have a problem
with me dancing?
No.
Angel.
Yeah?
I have something for you.
Again?
- Oh my God! What is it?
- Open it up.
Wow!
Oh my God!
Look at that!
Jewels!
Yes, it's jewels.
And look...
Charlie!
Hey, baby!
- Guess what?
- Charlie?!
They don't want me.
You want to know why?
'Cause I fucking hang
out with skanks like you!
Charlie!
Aren't you pretty?
Aren't you fucking pretty?
Just to fuck morals!
- Come here!
- I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, Charlie.
I met someone.
Okay...
what's his name?
- Dennis.
- Dennis, and?
And?
And I think- I don't know.
He's a poet.
He runs that thing
at the Coffee Ground, and...
he likes my poetry, so...
So you're gonna go
to San Francisco with Dennis?
Yeah, he invited me up there.
There's this big slam and...
And you're going
to support him stripping?
No. I don't know. No.
I thought we'd just
kind of write together-
Does he know what you do?
Yeah, and he's fine with it.
Yeah, he really fucking
loves my poetry,
so he thinks that I can,
you know...
get published or something.
Does he love you?
I don't know, I just met him
three days ago.
That's really
a smart thing to do then.
I think you should go to
San Francisco with Dennis the poet
whom you met three days ago
and write poetry and support him.
I need some more
fucking cigarettes.
- Bad! You are bad! Very bad!
- Very, very bad!
- I've had a bad week-
- I don't care about your week.
I don't care about your week.
Are you hungry?
- Yes, Mistress, starving.
- All right...
- there you go, eat!
- Thank you, Mistress.
All right, enough of this shit.
It's time to take
the little wormy for a walk.
Get down on the ground.
Get down on the ground
and crawl. Crawl!
Crawl like the sub-human
creature that you are-
Who the fuck is that?
All right, you stay right here.
Jessie, what are you doing here?
Hi, I just-
It's 3:00 a. m.
What the fuck are you doing?
I thought you needed
company tonight.
Well, you thought wrong.
I have company.
- Goodbye.
- Who is that?
Jessie, I'm in the middle
of something, can't you tell?
I have a life. Can you go?
Angel said you might need company
on account of the baby.
Angel thought wrong.
Company is the last thing I need.
You got to go.
- Hi!
Don't talk to him.
He's being punished, okay?
Anyway, he doesn't exist,
he's just a pathetic worm.
Get down on the floor!
Did I tell you to sit up?
I don't want
any conversation from you!
Jessie, get up.
- You have been a bad boy!
- I have, Mistress.
All right. Stop!
You don't talk to her.
Don't talk to her, okay?
Can't you see we're
in the middle of something?
Come here, sit down.
- I want to play.
- I'm not playing.
This is business. Do you
think I'd have fun with this?
- This is a client.
- Do you mind if I stay?
- I wouldn't-
- Don't talk. Shut up!
Get down on the ground.
Are you hungry, worm?
Are you thirsty?
Drink! Drink the fucking vodka!
Keep your head-
Jessie! Don't drink that.
That's disgusting.
It's dirty.
May I have two mistresses?
No, you are not
having two mistresses.
Jessie, you have
to get out of here.
No, Jo. Let me stay.
I have nowhere to go.
Let's not get all melodramatic.
All right. Come here.
Get up. Stand up.
What are you looking at?
Do you mind
if I stay tonight?
- No.
- He doesn't mind.
Jo:
Your opinion doesn't count.
Jessie...
what happened to you?
What the fuck is this?
Who did that?
Did Charlie hit you?
No, I just want
to have a slumber party.
Man:
You should put ice on it.
Jo:
Can you stay out of this?
Jessie:
Let's have a slumber party.
Jessie, get up.
You don't know where he's been.
Come on, sweetheart.
Lie down and sleep it off.
This isn't a place for kids.
I don't want to.
I want to play.
All right, you win.
Stay here,
but no more than one night,
'cause I have a life.
- But I want to play.
- No. You lie here.
Be very quiet, and sleep it off.
And don't bother me while I'm doing
business with the nice man.
Just when you get back...
Officer.
Officer,
could you help me with-
could you help me
take a picture of my-
I want to take a picture
of myself in front of it.
- Is that you?
- Yeah.
Really?
I'm a lot smaller in person.
But, um...
See, I think I'm only getting my hat.
You realize you're not
supposed to be down here?
Um...
sorry, I'll leave as soon as I-
I just wanted to get
a good shot of my picture.
- All right.
- Thanks.
- Is it ready to go?
- Yeah. There.
A little wider.
Can you take it a little wider?
- You mean back?
- Yeah.
How is that?
I got it all.
Ready? Cheese.
- Cheese.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Did anyone ever tell you
you look like Fred Gwynne?
You know, the guy
who was Herman Munster?
No one has ever told me that.
I really like him.
He's the great-
Shit!
I locked my keys in my car
and I have to be at work!
Oh no!
Damn it!
You have a hanger?
This side's open.
Would you unlock this door for me?
- Sure.
- Thanks.
This is the lock.
Ma'am, is this marijuana?
I think it's uh-
it's an herbal cigarette.
Step around to the side
of the car, please.
I- I did not inhale. I-
Step around at the side of the car.
It will take a minute.
Well, it's probably just oregano.
You should have it examined
'cause I don't feel stoned.
I'll have it examined.
It'll take a second.
- It won't be long.
- Do you have to handcuff me?
I'm afraid I do.
This will take a minute.
You can find me
at the Blue Iguana every day.
I'm really a good person,
- and I have respons-
- Just stand still for a few minutes.
I'll take a look at the car
for your license and registration.
Okay,
but I have responsibilities,
and children I might
need to be a role model for,
and if I get a record,
it will be really bad.
I understand.
Is this your purse?
Yeah, that fuzzy- the pink.
- This?
- Yeah.
Officer,
is there any way you could-
I'm gonna pay that.
I got an extension, and I-
- Which one is your wallet?
It's the one that
say Bad Motherfucker on it.
Did you ever see Pulp Fiction?
No, I never saw it.
John Travolta's career
came back after-
I was sick when
they took that picture.
- A lot of bills, ma'am.
- Yeah, they're all ones.
You can have some.
- What are these?
They are my friend Jo's
vitamins for her pregnancy.
I think.
Is there any way that-
Officer-
that maybe you could
forget about this?
Because I'm really
a good person.
You can come down
to the Blue Iguana.
They let LAPD all the time for free,
'cause we're a clean club.
- Is that right?
- Eddie gets mad.
Our managers sometimes
can't get them out of the club
because they like it so much.
My friend Jo works
with a lot of LAPD guys.
- She's really beautiful-
- I'm going to ask-
- She'd really like you.
- I'm happy to hear that.
Stay by the car
for a couple of minutes
while I go run the license
and registration, all right?
- Okay. Is that necessary?
- It is. I'll be back.
Officer, is this
going to be on the news-
No, no.
It's gonna be okay.
I really can't- I don't-
I always wanted to be in the Enquirer
but not for getting arrested.
I thought maybe if I had
a handsome hunk or a nice dress...
Is there- is-
- Shit!
- It won't take a minute.
Okay.
Shit!
- Hi, Eddie.
- Where's Jasmine?
She wasn't feeling too well.
- Are you okay?
- Yeah.
- Oh fuck!
- What's the matter?
Fuck! Fuck!
- You have to go to work?
- No. No.
You want me to call your boss?
- I'll call him.
- No! Fuck off. No!
- Don't call him.
- Fuck off. What's his name?
Nothing.
Okay, I'd like to talk
to Mr. Nothing, please?
- No!
- Okay.
Don't.
I want to stay here.
Okay. All right.
But I want to smoke.
You have a great ass.
You can hit it.
I don't want to hit it.
I want to kiss it.
You want to kiss my ass?
Thank you.
Hi, Eddie.
Sorry I'm late.
Better make it good, girl.
I have very bad cramps.
- Yeah, really bad cramps.
- I'm here.
That's a prize winner.
You're here late, God damn it!
Where the fuck were you?
You couldn't call?
I need VIP night off.
Goddamn, you're priceless.
Eddie, I can't work anyway.
My cramps are so bad.
Your cramps are killing you!
How long have you worked here?
You've worked here a year, right?
When was the last
time you got off for cramps?
- Never!
- What's your problem?
What's my problem? I don't want
you to tell me a goddamn lie!
- Jo and Angel have-
- This ain't about Jo and Angel!
I run this motherfucker.
I'm asking you what
the goddamn deal really is.
So don't tell me
about no fucking period!
I can't. I can't. I can't.
I'll come back on Monday.
I'll work the rest of the week.
- I need the weekend off.
- Tomorrow night, you're dancing.
You're one of my star girls.
I need you.
You come in late and
ask for tomorrow off?
- What's the big deal?
- I need to know!
What?
The truth.
The goddamn truth.
Don't fuck with me, Jasmine.
You tell me what's up.
I can't. I can't.
What the fuck do you
care about anyway?
You don't care about
anyone else in here!
I care because I care,
God damn it!
Don't treat me like trash!
I'm not- I have a life
and I need the weekend off.
You ain't got no life!
This is your life!
You got that?
You ain't got no friends.
Two minutes after
you walk out of here,
one of your
double-crossing friends
will come in here
and snitch on your ass!
- Don't fuck with me.
- I fucking quit!
- God damn you!
- Sorry.
- Don't fuck my shit up!
- You have your life. I have mine.
You ain't got a life!
Miss Willow?
It's Sarah.
- Miss Willow?
Becky?
Hello?
- Hey, it's me.
Okay, let's see...
I've taken care of the registration.
We're both signed up.
I got our names signed up.
So, I put your name
up there for the open read.
Don't be scared,
there's a lot of people,
but there's strength in numbers.
It will be really good.
Call me back so I know
what time to get
together with you. Bye.
- Jimmy, what's your favorite?
- And God Spoke.
- Is that a fuck movie?
- This place looks a little different.
Hey, Eddie, what it is?
Go to my car and get
the box I left in there.
- No problem.
- Bobby...
What?
Start things up with this.
Call Jo.
I'm not calling her.
You want to call her?
Call her.
All right, I'll call her.
You're bringing her back to work?
We need everybody.
You got to rent
Behind the Green Door,
'cause the trapeze scene is hot.
Bobby, did you see
the glasses on my desk?
I saw them sitting there last night.
- They ain't here.
- I don't have them.
The motherfucking broads!
Maybe the girls borrowed
them for the opera.
Hey, how are you?
Hey, Eddie!
- This is Nico.
- Let me help you.
Let me get you a place here.
- That's Angel's seat.
- It used to be.
- That's Angel's stuff.
- Let me know if you need anything.
Excuse me?
- That's Angel's seat.
- Eddie gave it to me.
Hello, porn star?
- This is Angel's seat.
- Mind your own business.
Don't start with me again.
Will I have to haul you back to work?
- Get your ass out on the floor!
- Fuck you!
You should take care of this.
Everybody takes advantage of Angel.
Oh, that's so sweet.
- $15, please.
- I'd like to see Jasmine.
- What?
Is it important?
We're busy tonight.
- Yeah. I'm a friend of hers.
- Hold on a second.
Hey, Jasmine.
You got a Dennis out front.
You want me to toss him?
No, I'm on next, aren't I?
Give him a good seat.
He can watch me.
I'll throw
the little boy to the lions.
Ladies and gentlemen,
let's keep going.
Please welcome
to the stage, Jasmine!
Something I can do for you tonight?
How much for a blow?
100 bucks.
Yeah, I can handle that.
Look at me.
Look at my eyes.
Yeah.
- Hey.
- Hi.
Do you want to sit down?
Sure.
I'm so sorry.
No, there's nothing
to be sorry about.
No.
There's nothing
to be sorry about.
I'm looking at this room
with you in it...
I feel safe.
I feel safe now.
Make love to me.
- I can't. I can't.
- Okay.
- I'm getting married-
- Shh...
Nico!
Yes, is Harry Goldberg in?
Yes, Ed Hazel.
I'm a friend.
Has he gone away?
No.
Yeah.
Yeah, thanks a lot.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the fabulous Nico,
the one and only.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the heavenly Angel!
Are you Angel?
I think you're up.
Okay, never mind.
Hey, fellows,
how is it going?
Excuse my breasts, I'm lactating.
I can't get too excited,
'cause then my rubber rolls up.
Dave!
Don't move.
It's you, isn't it?
Dave!
Don't move.
Dave, can you help me
with my money?
Please, could you
pick it up? Don't move!
That Angel, everybody.
Show her your love.
It's the one- the flowers-
Jasmine, it's the guy-
the flower guy is out there.
Oh my God,
he's the most dreamy thing.
You know, the guy with the red dress?
Do you have anything
to straighten me out?
Fuck!
What? What?
Wait a minute.
What are you going away for?
Wait a minute!
Oh my God!
Oh my God.
Jessie?
Yeah?
I can't sleep.
Are you okay?
Jo:
Do you want to come join me?
Sure.
Sing something.
Do you have a light?
Yeah.
Thank you.
You can go home now.
- Can I?
- Yeah.
What time is it?
I don't know.
3:30?
Why are you still here?
- Why are you still here?
- Good fucking question.
Who knows?
I guess I fell asleep.
Is that what happened?
Yeah, you were
asleep for a long time.
Could be worse.
You have pretty hair.
Thanks.
I'm sorry, I forgot your name.
So do I.
It's...
Nico.
- Nico.
- Yeah.
What are you writing?
What?
I'm just trying to keep you here.
I hate this part.
- Going home?
- No.
It's an awkward fucking
transition, you know?
It's like- it's just three
more hours till sunset- sunrise.
Where's your next gig?
You travel around a lot, right?
Yeah.
So where do you live?
At a hotel.
Hotels.
Where do you live?
I lost my house.
No big deal.
What are you writing?
What?
You write, right?
That's what you do.
You write.
You're a writer.
It's so fucking funny.
I mean, you writers,
you all write and you never
want to read what you wrote.
So you strip all night here
and then you
sit back here and write.
I'm safe.
I won't remember it tomorrow.
Is it a song?
No, I don't write songs.
Is it a story?
No.
I write poems.
Poetry.
I have a friend-
I had a friend
who used to write poetry.
He used to call me
and he'd read them to me.
He wrote really good poems.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
It's hard to write good poems.
It would really...
be nice to hear a poem again.
Please?
"When light shattered
across the floor
And briefly,
there was a thunder between us,
If your eyes had held water,
it would have not spilled.
And when we peeled aside
the dreams,
the skin underneath
was still young.
When all was black,
you smoothed aside
the words and said,
It's there, the light.
When you want it,
it'll be waiting for you. '
A certain peace
came into your eyes
That this was no different,
That this was so different,
yet every bit the same,
And your hands stilled
with satisfaction.
You did this without touch,
So that, all around me,
your hands stood
shaped like shelters.
All around me there was room,
And after each hour,
the hallways outside
were like caverns.
And around the corner and down
the stairs, there lurked as always
Light, as ever, light. "
Is it about a guy?
No.
Is it about you?
Maybe.
I'm sorry, I just had a bad day.
- You have a light?
- Yeah.
What is it about?
It's about-
You know how-
You know,
like when you're in here,
and it's always dark.
It's always like 1:00 a. m.
It's about...
morning...
stuff inside you.
Stuff inside you.
Me too.
It's a nice poem.
Thank you.
You know what
a cryptographer is?
Bobby:
I never paid attention in school.
It's a code breaker.
During the war.
That's what Harry was.
There are only two or three
of them in the whole world.
And Harry was one of them.
He was the best, man.
That shit's going to kill you, boy.
I hope so.
- You want to get something to eat?
- Sure.
You know,
I'll give that old Jew one thing.
I hope to God, when I'm that old,
I'll still love pussy like he does.
Even if I have to use
binoculars to see it.
Have you ever sang?
- Sang?
- Yeah.
Like, in public,
in front of people?
- Yeah, a long time ago.
- You did?
Did you get nervous?
Yeah.
'Cause Jessie's going
over to Dimples this afternoon.
They know a place
over in Burbank- karaoke-
and a bunch of the girls
are going. So...
- Our girls?
- Yeah.
Jessie said everybody can sing,
so I thought-
Eddie:
Fuck, our girls can sing?
God damn!
This Russian
motherfucker got shot.
And some shot.
Right through the heart.
In the window of his house
in Woodland Hills.
Bobby:
Quick way to go.
I thought if
you weren't doing anything,
if you'd drop by,
we could do it together.
Like a duet.
Frank and Sammy kind of thing.
- What time is it?
- 3:00.
Ah no, man.
I'll be asleep.