♪
[click]
Miss Shaw, you got five minutes?
Sorry, I don't.
Five minutes for questions.
I don't have the time.
Isis, you can't keep running.
♪
[indistinct lyrics]
[car doors closing]
♪
[indistinct rap lyrics]
♪ Dude, you know that I
finish whatever I start ♪
No, no, no, no.
- No, no, no.
- Come on, Seth.
Not tonight, man.
[indistinct rap lyrics]
♪
Got one.
Oh, God, third one to the left.
He pulling in eight figures.
Yeah.
Okay.
♪
[cellphone dings]
Hey, will you take care of him?
♪
♪ Mm
♪ There's your moonlight
♪ Right there
♪ That's right
♪ Think left, move right
♪ My game's play fine
♪ It's getting close
♪ Oh, it's getting closer ♪
♪ Closer
♪
♪ I love it
[vocalizing]
♪
♪ It's poison
♪ Texture on my tongue
♪ Taste the feeling of
♪ I love
Oh, girl, you killed that shit.
Nephy! Hey, girl.
Thanks for letting me
know about the big tippers
out there tonight.
I got you.
♪
She wasn't lying, though.
That shit was fire.
As always, little baby girl.
Do you mind?
♪
Listen...
♪ I already know the question
and the answer is no.
I'm out.
There's some bigwigs.
I said no.
I wouldn't be coming to you
unless it was necessary.
Seth, why can't you choose
one of these other
girls out here?
♪
Bitch, did you forget?
You are the girl I got.
You're my star attraction.
Now get your ass
up out of this seat
and go get this fucking money.
♪
You want to buy a private
dance from me, don't you?
Yes, of course.
Follow me, daddy.
♪
[indistinct lyrics]
How about we take this
somewhere more private?
My friends, we arrived together.
I have friends that
can come along.
So what do you say?
♪
♪ We some bad girls
♪ Doing what we want
♪ We them bad girls
♪ Doing our own stunts
♪ Here come the bad girls ♪
♪ Boy, you better run
♪ We goin' crazy all night
♪ Crazy all night
[indistinct lyrics]
♪
How much longer
till we get there?
Not long.
Ten, fifteen minutes.
[indistinct lyrics]
♪
Ooh, bitch, you
brought party favors?
♪
Give me some.
What are you girls taking?
Molly.
What's Molly?
Ecstasy, MDMA.
You want some?
♪
I don't know. I
hear those things
can give a man my
age a heart attack.
Oh, don't worry, baby.
I'll take good care of you.
Well, all right, then.
♪
Does anybody else want some?
[indistinct lyrics]
♪
♪ All this booty in the club
♪ I promise to God
I throw it all ♪
♪ Ain't got no problems, girl
♪ I fuck regardless, girl ♪
♪ I got a girl at home
and a girl heading out ♪
♪ There's options, girl
♪ I know my chain stupid
♪ I hear his nonsense, girl
♪ Cut out the nonsense, girl
♪ There's cash
♪ Let me pull that hair
♪ You are bad, bad
♪ I'm like toss that hair ♪
♪ Get nasty
♪ You a baddie
♪ Get ratchet
♪ This cookie cash
♪ Get a bag, quick
♪ Throw that up, sis
♪ Let's say fuck these niggas
and go on a girls' trip ♪
♪ Throw that up, sis
♪ Oh, just think, we in
the hotel getting ready ♪
♪ Throw that up
♪ Throw it, baby
♪ Alternate it
♪ Hotel popping bottles
and we popping labels ♪
♪ Face down
♪ X-rated
♪ I get nasty
[indistinct lyrics]
♪ Then get ratchet,
start clapping,
then talking mad shit ♪
♪ You like that
[indistinct lyrics]
♪
♪ I get nasty
[indistinct lyrics]
♪ Make it ratchet
I thought...
♪
Wait.
Oh, don't worry, sweetie.
This will all be over very soon.
♪
[knocking]
Yeah!
Good fucking shit, lady!
You know the routine, let's go.
♪
Watches, rings, wallets.
Anything valuable.
Be quick about it.
♪
Hey.
Hey, you okay?
♪
Come on, be quick about it.
Where's the old man at?
In the room.
Where you heading to?
We'll give you a ride
when we finish.
I called an Uber.
♪
See? The fuck I'm
talking about.
That bitch always thinks
she's better than us.
Would you leave her alone?
She has a son to get back to.
Man, y'all shut the
fuck up and get to work.
Strip these motherfuckers down.
Put this one on top of that one.
Mike, help me get the old man.
We about to bring his ass
down for this photo shoot.
It's go time.
♪
[birds chirping]
There you go.
[water trickling]
♪
[sighs]
Hm.
♪
Hey.
♪ It's time to get up, we
got to get ready for school.
Hey.
Let's go, come on.
♪
It's coming, this is the bus.
Well, come on, let
me help you up.
Stand up.
♪
Did you want to add a hug?
[cellphones dinging]
♪
"Keep your mouth
shut about this"?
"We have pics.
We're not afraid to send
'em to your contacts.
We'll be in touch."
♪
What the hell happened?
I know you're
looking down on me.
And I'm trying to do my best.
I'm sorry, I didn't
mean to interrupt.
Can I help you?
Oh my God, I am so sorry.
I was just about to leave.
Oh, no, no, no. You're fine.
I wasn't...
Actually, uh...
Here. We can share.
- I can't.
- No, it's no trouble.
Trust me. I'd be
honoring her by sharing.
- Thank you.
- Sure.
If you don't mind me
asking, how did she pass?
Car accident.
Oh, God, I'm so sorry.
- And...
- Cancer.
Ovarian.
Oh my God.
I can only imagine how
hard that must've been.
Yeah.
And same for you.
Don't I know you from somewhere?
I just have one of those faces.
Osiris Hughes.
Oh.
Isis Shaw.
Uh, sorry.
Uh, Isis...
do you think that maybe you'd
want to go out for a coffee?
Oh, I'm sorry, I can't.
I have to get going.
I have to get my
son from school.
Of course, yeah.
School soon.
Well, uh, it was nice
to meet you, Isis Shaw.
Nice meeting you,
too, Osiris Hughes.
♪
[knocking]
Hey, what's up, man?
Damn, you didn't get no
bagels, croissants, or nothing?
Hey, um, did you leave
flowers on Mom's grave for me?
Uh, yes, I did.
You need to take your
ass down there soon.
I'm gonna be out there tomorrow.
So, how we doing?
Poll numbers are
looking good, man,
we up two points.
See?
We up two points.
Yeah. Hey, you're
clearing up your schedule
for this weekend?
What's this weekend?
Seriously?
How about my damn
bachelor party, O?
Oh, yeah. About that...
No, come on. Come on, come on.
You promised me
you'll be there, O.
I know, but come on.
If everyone were
to see me now...
Nigga, you ain't
that damn famous.
Plus, you don't even
got to stay for long.
But you're my big brother,
so I will want you there.
All right, I promise
I'll be there.
Clear up your damn
work schedule, man.
Promise me you'll be there, man.
I said, I promise.
Update that damn schedule.
[indistinct hip-hop lyrics]
♪
- What's up, sis?
- Hi, Mike.
♪
I guess you're here
for your cut, huh?
Even though you left us to
do all the heavy lifting.
♪
Why else would I be here, Seth?
Maybe you just want
to come see me.
I'm not that stupid.
Well, you're lucky
we were able to move
the old man's shit so fast.
Made a decent payday, too.
♪
That's two, maybe three times
what you would've
made last night, Ice.
Doesn't mean it's worth it.
♪
Come on.
Quit with all this
high and mighty stuff.
♪
Rejoin the crew.
You know what kind of
damage we could do together.
I'm aware of the damage, Seth.
♪
I'm not saying that we
do this shit forever.
Just until we get enough.
Last night was my last night.
I'm done.
♪
And I've been done with that.
Growing up in an underserved
and underprivileged area,
certain dreams weren't
afforded to us.
My name is Osiris
Christian Hughes.
I'm an activist,
a business owner,
and a community organizer,
and I'm running for your
state representative.
♪
And then it goes
up? Okay, perfect.
♪
Okay, tuck you in.
Check the meds.
♪
Dammit.
Look, Daddy, I got to
go refill your meds.
Sorry. I'll have Miss
Sara peek on you, okay?
I won't be gone too long.
Ask her to bring some more
of her banana pudding.
♪
[cellphone dings]
[popping, clicking]
♪
All men created equal.
As long as the vision
is dollar signs,
there are tons of Black issues,
but it's like we can't
vibe on the one fact
that we were royal commodities
that made America thrive.
And I realize this
doesn't sell CDs,
but maybe it could
charge some unity.
Maybe it could open up the bars
and stop making the
penitentiary our community.
If we are refugees,
then give us
diplomatic immunity.
Let us pursue degrees
with equal job opportunity
because more men and
more men try to wipe
the mark of shame
off their people.
But they can never stop the rain
that watered the
root of all evil.
We still rock whips and chains
'cause it feels good
to embrace our regal,
but when it's our
skin versus the board,
everything is
separate and unequal.
Thank you.
Hm.
So, this is where
I know you from.
You're running for...
State rep.
Yeah. I didn't know
how to tell you
without sounding pretentious.
So, what is this, some
type of publicity stunt
or something?
What? No.
My brother and I
practically grew up
in this community center.
This is home.
These are my people.
If anything, I'm trying
to use my platform
to shed more light on
some of the injustices
that happen here.
I am so sorry.
I shouldn't have assumed.
Well, I won't hold
it against you
if you can join me for lunch.
I don't know, I should
be getting back.
Uh...
Are you sure?
Because the best taco
truck in the city
is parked right
around the corner.
- Taco?
- Tacos.
You should've led with that.
- Thirty minutes?
- Works for me.
I hope you like it.
♪
The tacos are really good.
Right? See, I told you
♪
So, who taught you
how to play the piano?
Mm, my mother taught me.
She's kind of like a
jack of all trades.
She held down three jobs
and still found time
to make sure that
my brother and I
had some culture in our lives.
Mm, sounds amazing.
She was.
And what about you?
- Adam.
- To Adam, yeah,
what else do you do?
I'm an artist.
Art teacher.
Oh. Damn, okay.
That's what's up.
Yeah, I mean, it's pretty cool.
Art has... painting has
always been my passion.
And you always wanted to teach?
When I was younger,
I always dreamed
of having my own art gallery
and having my
paintings on the wall,
and sitting back and
watching rich people
purchase every
single one of them.
So, what changed?
Life.
Becoming a mother.
And Adam's father?
He's not in the picture.
Mm.
His loss.
Um, so, how did you
get into politics?
Oh, well, like I said,
I practically grew up
at the community center,
my brother and I,
and, um, we eventually
both started working there.
We were coaching basketball,
flag football, everything.
And, uh, one day, this rich
real estate tycoon comes in
and said that he wanted
to build real estate,
like a high-rise there
and turn the whole place
into a parking lot.
What?
So, we band together
as a community
in an attempt to stop the
developer from coming in,
and that is when our
current state rep
decided to jump in
and put his support
behind the developer.
Yeah.
Behind the developer.
Our current state rep's
highest campaign donor.
Wow.
Anyway, once I saw that,
I was like, "Yeah,
my mind is made up.
I got to run against him."
And it all kind of
ballooned from there.
It's very admirable.
Thank you.
♪
Hey, so do you think we can
maybe go out
officially sometime?
Uh, honestly, I don't know.
I don't know if I have
any room in my life.
Oh, I get it. Is there
someone you're already...
No, it's not that.
Oh, I get it. Is there
someone you're already...
Right. Well, hey, no pressure.
Um, take my number and, uh,
if you find a little time
to etch me in, just
a little bit of room,
I don't need much,
give me a call.
If I have room.
- If.
- Yes, if.
Okay. If.
- Yeah, if.
- If.
"If" is good enough for me.
I'm good with "if," yup.
♪
Girl...
It's a downpour out there.
You need to get out there.
Whoo.
Eye...?
♪
Yeah, I'm almost ready.
What's up with you? You okay?
Yeah, it's just...
How much longer do you
think we can do this?
What do you mean? They
out there still tippin'!
No. I mean how much longer
do you want to do this?
You mean, like, dance?
I mean, shit, as long
as the money flowin',
till the fuckin'
wheels fall off.
And all the extra shit?
Parties, Seth and his schemes...
Girl, look at us.
Look at you. Look at me!
We are too fine not to
be stacking right now.
Till the fucking wheels, bitch.
Yeah, well, I feel
like my wheels
have definitely fallen off.
Is Seth trying to get
you to do another job?
No, it's not just him.
It's this life, the hustle.
I just want some sense
of normalcy, you know?
♪
But this is what my
family needs me to be.
I'm sorry, babe.
I get it.
I mean, I might
love this lifestyle,
but I know shit is
hard for you, so...
I support you and anything
that you want to do.
Do what you gotta do
to make you happy.
♪
Come.
Some love, bring
it in, bring it in.
♪
[indistinct announcement]
[applause]
♪
It's James Hughes'
last night of freedom.
We're gonna send him off right.
All dancers report to the stage.
♪ Celebrate
♪ We just celebrate
♪ Elevate
♪ We just elevate
♪ With champagne
♪ Poppin' champagne
♪ Champagne
♪ Celebrate
♪ We just celebrate
♪ Elevate
♪ We just elevate
♪ We campaign
♪ That my campaign
♪ VIP
[indistinct lyrics]
Going to the bathroom.
♪ We gonna celebrate
♪ Paparazzi
♪ Cameras in my face
♪ Champagne
♪ Poppin' champagne
[indistinct lyrics]
♪
Uh...
Isis, Isis, wait, wait, wait.
One minute, we just...
Okay.
♪
Oh, whoa, whoa, Isis,
hold up, hold up, hey!
- Leave me alone, O.
- No, no, no, it's okay.
There's nothing
to be ashamed of.
I am not ashamed of dancing.
It puts food on the table
for me and my family.
Okay, I didn't
mean it like that.
It puts food on the table
for me and my family.
I am not ashamed.
♪
I just don't like for
people to find out this way.
Well, why didn't you just
say something before?
Forget it, O, just go
back to your party.
No, look, you
could've just told me.
♪
I don't tell people because...
they often have
preconceived notions.
Well, I'm not most people.
Okay?
♪
Look, it's cold.
All you have on is this coat.
I'm parked right here.
Why don't we just go grab
some coffee or something
and talk about this?
♪
Man, you see that
chick in the orange?
The way she was going
down on the pole.
She is so thick.
Fuck.
Fuck!
It's Fernando.
Want me to handle that?
No.
It's good.
Just go straight
inside, I got this.
♪
[clattering]
Well, what'd he say?
♪
My shit didn't hit.
Fernando...
Mr. Apopis...
This nigga says I
owe him 78 racks,
plus interest.
Fuck.
♪
How much we got
from the last job?
Nigga, not enough.
♪
It's time to hit the
motherfucking CEO
and his associates.
One of her side
hustles was bartending
at a strip club.
So, growing up,
all my play aunts were dancers.
There was, uh, Pat, whose
stage name was Sizzle.
Then there was Aunt Latte.
Ooh, no, no, Aunt Freddie Mae,
whose stage name was Latte.
And, uh, oh, then
there was Aunt Dinky.
Now Dinky was, uh, kind
of an old-school dancer.
Her favorite move
was the Tootsie Roll.
- The Tootsie Roll?
- The Tootsie Roll.
She liked to get
down low with it...
Yeah, uh...
She was actually my favorite.
Yeah, that is pretty lame.
♪
They were just family.
So, you see?
♪
I'm sorry I lied.
Nah, you ain't got
to worry about that.
You know what? I do.
You deserve that.
I mean, but it wasn't all a lie.
No, I'm not an art teacher,
but I'm so passionate
about painting.
It was my major in college.
Only did a year, though.
The accident?
Yeah.
And then I had to drop out
and take care of my father.
And the year after, Adam came.
♪
What?
I have something on my face?
Uh, yeah, like right in
the center of your face.
Oh my God, I keep
forgetting about that.
I didn't take it off.
♪
Okay, but, no, it's not that.
You remind me of her.
Who?
My mother.
As hard as she worked,
With a smile on her face.
And we knew she was
completely exhausted,
but she never really showed it.
She had this, uh, essence
of altruism about her.
♪
Bold selflessness.
You have it too.
♪
[cellphone buzzes]
[birds chirping]
♪
[gunshot, glass shatters]
[gasps]
Oh, you have a bike.
Yeah, it was my father's.
I had it restored
after the accident.
Mm, try to keep it
in good condition.
Do you ride it yourself?
- No, never.
- Oh.
I mean, when I was
younger, he taught me how,
but I haven't got on it since.
So why don't you sell it?
I can't bring myself to do that.
Yeah, I get that.
Oh, um, thank you so
much for the ride.
Oh, sure.
And for being understanding.
Of course.
So, will I be seeing you again?
Mmm.
♪
I might just have some
time for you after all.
- Might?
- Might.
- It's a big might.
- Okay, got it.
- Yeah, like...
- Might, yes.
- Thank you.
All right.
[laughing]
Oh, um, I need my bag,
not unless you're planning
to give it to your aunts.
[laughing]
Yeah, I would need this.
Well, enjoy your day.
You too.
Take care.
♪
- Thank you again.
- You're welcome.
♪
[chuckles]
[knocking on door]
♪
What the hell are
you doing here, Seth?
You act like I can't
just come visit you.
What happened to you last night?
You just disappeared.
That's none of your business,
and you need to leave.
No.
That's none of your business,
and you need to leave.
Arthur Lamb.
Yeah, we've been blowing him up
and this nigga ain't answering.
No, I'm not doing it, get...
No...
He's already seen
your face, Ice.
♪
He's already seen
your face, Ice.
- That's it.
- Absolutely not.
I said I was done, Seth.
Look, you don't understand...
Dad? Daddy!
Hey, look at you.
Looking more and more
like papa every day.
Man, is you being a
good boy for Mommy?
Yeah, I've been
good for school too.
Mm.
Daddy's little soldier.
Yeah, let's get some breakfast.
♪
No.
What?
Seth.
♪
Hm.
Well, did you know
that your mother
is the most incredible
dancer in the whole world?
♪
That when she dances...
It's like... it's like
she's floatin' in the air.
Seth.
It's like... it's like
she's floatin' in the air.
[pan sizzling]
♪
You're gonna want
him to know this.
♪
Anyways.
Addy, when... when I met
your mom for the first time,
I went and put on
my finest tuxedo,
'cause I wanted to
go see Mommy dance.
♪
And when I did...
I knew right then and there
that she was gonna be the queen
and change my life.
Why are you doing this?
She did.
♪
[sighs]
Because she gave me you.
♪
You two are the best thing
that ever happened to me.
You know that, right?
♪
I'm gonna need you to
run that errand for me.
I'm not doing it.
[sighs]
Dad, Dad, want to
see my farm animals?
I need you to eat your food.
You hear Mommy and
Daddy talking right now.
Mommy and Daddy have
nothing to talk about.
♪
[sighs]
I'm standing here
outside the home
of local CEO and
philanthropist Arthur Lamb
where police are investigating
his apparent death by suicide
for signs of foul play.
Hear what his
friends and neighbors
for signs of foul play.
Tonight at 10.
♪
What the fuck?
Oh, shit.
♪
You fucking piece of shit.
You chicken shit motherfucker.
Dude, we're gonna
have to fuckin' scrap
this whole job now.
No, no, no, bro, no, onna
we should be good though. p
We used burner phones
and we edited out all
the girls' photos.
What the fuck you mean
we're gonna be good?
Nigga, that was a
big fuckin' fish.
♪
And we're gonna have to find
a replacement like yesterday.
♪
Hm.
Hi.
Thank you.
Wow.
[sighs]
What is it, Mom?
Uh, it looks like
someone bought us dinner.
Smells like tacos.
Tacos? Who did that?
Was it Daddy?
Nah, I don't think so.
Did somebody get us flowers too?
Yeah.
Let's go eat those tacos.
Yay.
[Isis chuckles]
♪
Wow.
You look lovely.
You don't look too bad yourself.
Come in.
♪
[laughing]
Well, I hope you left
room for dessert.
I ordered cheesecake too.
Well, I hope you left
room for dessert.
Satisfaction looks good on you.
Who said I was satisfied?
♪ Won't waste this feeling
♪ I won't hesitate
♪
♪ We've got all this
time to make it right ♪
♪
♪ Won't waste a minute
♪ I won't be afraid
♪
♪ You are all I
want in this life ♪
♪
♪ Tonight
♪ It's you and me in flight
♪
♪ And I
♪ Will always be by your side
♪
♪ By your side
♪ Won't waste this feeling
♪ I won't hesitate
♪
♪ We've got all this
time to make it right ♪
♪
♪ Won't waste a minute
♪ I won't be afraid
♪
♪ You are all I
want in this life ♪
♪
Hey, Daddy.
Hey.
♪
Who do we have here?
[they chuckle]
How is it going, sir?
My name is Osiris Hughes.
♪
Man, it is cold
as a motherfucker.
Yeah, it is.
That's that one you
were talking about
the other day though.
Yeah, that's it right there.
Hey.
Twelve.
What you wanna do?
This motherfucker.
We're good, don't trip.
- Come on, we're playing.
- I ain't playing, man.
Mr. Calloway.
Detective Moreland.
What can I do for you?
You can tell me what you
know about Arthur Lamb.
Who?
Arthur Lamb.
Look, man, if you don't
mind me asking, Detective,
what the fuck does
that gotta do with me?
Well, it seems someone
was blackmailing him.
Witnesses place him at
the Showgirls Cabaret
the same night you
were in attendance.
So, is, uh, extortion
your new thing now, huh?
Come on, man.
You know me.
I'm only there for the
ass and the titties.
Beautiful women though.
You should come check it out.
Is that what you were
intending with Samuel Powell,
it just didn't
work out that way?
I know we're not
doing this again,
'cause I didn't have shit to
do with that motherfucker.
Well, that's funny.
What I do know, that you've got your hand
in this somehow, th that motherfucker.
And I'm gonna nail
your ass to the wall.
Is that right?
[chuckles]
Good luck with that.
♪
You gonna give us a ticket?
Or are we free to go?
You're free.
For now.
♪
Get your hand off your gun.
[vehicle doors close]
[engine starts]
Did you place the tracker?
Under the rear bumper,
just like you said.
♪
Good job.
[indistinct TV chatter]
I got you something.
You did?
Mm-hm!
Happy birthday.
What? My birthday was
like four months ago.
I know, but I didn't
know you four months ago.
So, open it.
Aw, what did you do?
[sighs]
Oh, wow, what is this?
It's a symbol for
mind, body, and soul.
And the black stones
are tourmaline,
and it's supposed to protect
you from negative energy.
Oh, like a force field.
Don't make fun.
I meant this more in a physical,
that when you're out
fighting for the people,
that you are always reminded
to protect yourself.
Wow.
You like it?
Like it? I love it.
You know, this last
month has just been...
Never felt so at peace
with someone before.
You feel like home.
Ditto, Mr. Hughes.
[traffic sounds]
Where are we going?
I called in a favor or two.
We have the whole
place to ourselves.
What's going on?
Just wait.
I have a big surprise for you.
I don't know if I can
trust your surprises.
What? You don't know if
you can trust my surprises?
I don't know.
Aw, that hurts my heart.
- Really?
- Really.
♪
Wow.
Oh, it's right here.
♪
Oh, wow.
Wow.
- Look at that.
- Yeah.
♪
What is this?
You were telling me about some
of your favorite Black artists
and how you never saw
their work at a museum.
So, I thought this would
be the next best thing.
♪
Thank you.
What?
And you didn't tell me?
Who, girl?
Okay, if I tell you,
it has to stay
between you and I.
Oh, bitch, of course.
Oh, wait, he's not
married, is he?
'Cause you know those
be the best ones.
Girl, you know he's not married.
What am I lookin' at?
No, it's him, Osiris Hughes.
Osiris, the guy from the
campaign commercials?
Yeah, oh my God, girl!
No, look, it's the smile for me.
How you bag a politician?
Oh my God.
A series of wonderful
coincidences.
Ice, look at you.
He's really making
you happy, huh?
He's off to a good start.
Good. You deserve it.
Especially after everything
that's going on right now.
What's going on?
Oh, Dee and the other
girls are trippin'.
They're talking about
leaving town and shit.
It's a whole mess.
- Why?
- Girl,
it was all over the
news and everything.
The old guy that we worked on
our last job killed himself.
Now the cops are asking
questions and shit.
- Oh my God.
- Yeah.
But Mike and Seth said that
we should be straight though.
They took us out of all
the photos that we're in
and dumped anything that
looks like we're connected
with this man, so, hopefully.
Anyways, I gotta run.
Um, I just wanted
to check on you
and make sure you were
still alive at least.
[chuckles]
and make sure you wUm,
yeah, I'm okay.least.
Thanks for stopping by.
Of course, I love you, girl.
Enjoy your new man.
Love that for you.
[laughs]
♪
[ethereal vocalizing]
[banging on door]
♪
Miss Shaw, did I catch
you at a bad time?
Detective Moreland, is
there ever a good time?
Good point.
I don't know if you heard,
Of Arthur Lamb.
Apparently, he was
being blackmailed.
Wouldn't happen to know
anything about that, would ya?
Um, no, I wish I could help...
He was a patron at the club
on the night I saw you last.
Oddly enough, I seem
to be the only one
who actually remembers
seeing him there.
Everyone else from the club,
manager to the dancers,
even his coworkers,
all seem to have amnesia
about that night.
Even the damn security
footage from the club
and Mr. Lamb's house was erased.
Can you explain that?
- How would I?
- Miss Shaw,
how long are we gonna
be playing these games?
We can help you, you know.
Set up you and your family in
Witness Protection if need be.
Uh, like I said,
Detective Moreland,
I wish I could help but I can't.
Have a good night.
♪
Who was that?
Um, just some cop.
What?
Cop?
What was he doing here?
Uh, he was just telling me
how some CEO tech
guy died by suicide.
Oh yeah, I heard about that.
Yeah, apparently he was at
the club a week or two prior.
I guess he's going
around asking the dancers
if they've seen him there.
Damn, did you... did you
remember seeing him there?
No, not really.
♪
Okay, um, well, is
there popcorn in there?
Yeah, there is.
♪
[energetic vocalizations]
♪ Big girl with
big balls energy ♪
♪ Big world, the people
gon' remember me ♪
♪ I'm a icon, call
me legendary ♪
♪ I'm the real deal,
you imaginary ♪
♪ You a smart guy,
don't be a dummy-dummy ♪
♪ End up on the wrong side
with the funny money ♪
♪ Call me a tortoise, I'm
covered in the green ♪
♪ Bears walkin',
bears talkin',
♪ Call me a tortoise, I'm
covered in the green ♪
♪ Why you fakin' and
hatin', you dig ♪
♪ You keep always small
talkin', I be makin' it big ♪
♪ Pullin' up in somethin'
I already paid for ♪
♪ Spendin' money and
I already made more ♪
♪ Do that thing,
do that thing ♪
Why you ain't
answer when I call?
We have nothin' to talk about.
♪
I'm trying to put
a play together.
We are not about
to discuss this.
♪
All right, everyone get out.
I said get the fuck out.
♪
No, see, I'm tired of everyone
keeps playin' with me.
They think they can threaten me?
♪
Huh? Disrespect me?
You got me fucked up.
♪
I said...
Oh, I said, I said, I said.
♪
Never fucking play with me.
Seth, that's enough.
Don't ever play with me.
You're drunk, you're...
[gun thudding]
Huh?
Give me my fuckin' respect.
♪
Don't ever fuckin' talk
to me like that again.
You hear me? Huh?
This shit ain't over with.
You're still my star
fuckin' attraction.
You fuckin' hear me?
Don't play with me.
♪
[whimpering]
[knocking]
♪
What the hell you want?
To be your new star attraction.
♪
Is that right?
Why don't you come show me
how you supposed to do that?
♪
♪ What's done is done now ♪
You know, I meant to
tell you something.
I love you.
- What?
- I said I love you.
♪
[unintelligible]
[snorts]
♪
Damn, this bitch
wasn't lyin' though.
Tell you, dog.
This don't even feel right, man.
What?
I said this... this ain't right.
Nigga, this is whatever
the fuck I say it is.
♪
You're gonna let me
fuckin' find out.
♪
Let me find out you tryin'
to fuck my baby mama.
♪
What?
She basically family.
Yeah, nigga, well, she ain't.
Nigga, she ain't blood.
Nigga, I am.
So if I say that Isis and
the new man is the next mark,
then, nigga, they the next mark.
♪
Do you understand?
Yeah.
Yeah, I understand.
[crickets chirring]
Here, I'll take him.
Oh, okay.
So I'll see you
for lunch tomorrow?
Yeah, of course.
I love you.
I love you too.
[indistinct TV chatter]
[TV turns off]
[light clicks on]
♪
Shh.
He hasn't moved
since I got here.
What are you doing here?
♪
I saw you.
I saw you at the park
with your new man.
♪
Do you love him?
That's none of your business.
Well, I'm makin' it
my fuckin' business.
♪
Seeing you with this
nigga had me hot at first.
♪
But then I thought, shit,
you might have just
found the answer
to my motherfuckin' prayers.
♪
I won't do it.
You know you will.
♪
[whimpers]
This Moreland, that cop,
yeah, he's been asking
a lot of questions.
I don't know...
What if I just give
him all the answers
that he's been looking for?
Hm?
♪
The fuck I wouldn't.
[whimpers]
You wouldn't do that.
Yeah, fuck, fuckin'
play with me, man.
♪
And don't worry.
I'll take care of our son
while you're in prison.
I will take him so
far away from here,
you will never see him again.
♪
But then...
who's gonna take care
of your dear old dad?
♪
Or should I just
do it right now?
[whimpers]
♪
Nigga!
Get your hands off my daughter!
What the fuck you
gonna do, old man?
Huh?
You ain't shit.
You ain't no man.
You're the worst thing
that ever happened
to my daughter.
No.
No, you are.
Look at you...
Look at you.
♪
You think you're her protector.
[sniffling]
You ain't nothing
but a fuckin' burden.
♪
This is my family now.
I'll shoot you in your
motherfuckin' face.
♪
Okay.
What was that?
Come again?
I said okay.
♪
Shit didn't even have
to be all this, Ice.
♪
[sniffles, whimpers]
I knew you'd come around.
♪
Get your fuckin' ass goin'.
Get dressed.
♪
[doorbell rings]
Mm.
♪
Like I always said,
my star fuckin'
attraction, baby girl.
♪
You're my star
fuckin' attraction.
♪
[gasping]
[breathing heavily]
[distant siren wailing]
Excuse me, Mr. Hughes.
Can I have a word with you
for a second, good brother,
if you don't mind.
Sure, of course.
Seth Calloway.
Okay, how can I help
you, Mr. Calloway?
I believe you know
my son's mother,
Isis Shaw.
♪
Oh...
All right.
You're Adam's father.
Bingo. Got it.
What the fuck you want,
Seth Calloway? Hm?
Damn, no foreplay.
You just wanna jump straight
to the business, huh?
I like that,
but I'm gonna need you to
be a little more patient.
We'll get there.
♪
Get the fuck outta here.
No, whoa.
♪
You might wanna come
take a walk with me.
I got something to show you.
Won't take long, promise.
♪
Just wondering,
got the time now?
♪
What the hell is this shit?
Whoa, ease up, ease up!
How did you get this?
[Seth laughs]
How the fuck you
think I got this?
Oh, shit.
Look at him, cuzzo.
Damn.
You actually thought
Isis loved you, huh?
Man, you were just a mark.
We've been gamin'
you from the start.
What do you want?
See, I told you we'd
come back around to it.
I want one third of
your campaign funds,
and by my calculations,
that's about 3.3 million.
What? You're insane!
No, I'm a businessman.
I'm an entrepreneur.
You see, I thought
about taking half.
I did.
You're a man of the people
and all that good shit,
and so, how could I?
I can't just go pull
out that kind of money.
It's illegal.
What that gotta do with me?
I don't care how you get it.
Write it in the books as
a campaign expenditure.
I don't give a fuck.
But either have my money...
or this shit's gonna go public,
and your political aspirations
are over, my good brother.
All right.
I need time.
You got two days.
Two days?
I'll call you with the detail.
And if you don't
get the message...
[necklace tearing, clattering]
♪
Stay the fuck away from Isis.
And my son.
Let's go.
[door opens]
[sighs]
[knocking]
♪
What the hell have you done?
O, please.
I should call the police on you.
Maybe you should.
But I want you to
know the truth.
The truth? The truth?! Huh?
What, like how I was just a
mark for you and Seth? Huh?
Where'd the cameras
come from, Isis?
You set me up!
[Isis sobs]
You know, I... I
just wanna know why.
Was it all a lie?
Was it just some...
fucking game for the two of you?
No.
You have to believe me, O.
He set me... I mean,
he made me do it.
Please, I lo...
Oh, don't you say it.
Don't you dare say it.
[Isis sniffles]
I just want to know why.
After all this.
Meeting your family,
spending time with your son.
Just for you to rip me apart.
Why?
♪
After the accident,
I went from naive college
kid to caretaker overnight.
♪
I didn't know how much
debt my parents were in,
that they were in danger
of losing our home.
♪
That's when I started dancing.
It was good money,
but it wasn't enough
to help us stay afloat.
♪
I met Seth at the club.
He was a lot different then.
He was encouraging
and supportive.
He even helped
out when he could.
But the bank was relentless.
One banker in particular,
Samuel Powell,
refused to help me.
One day, he came into the club,
and he made me an offer.
Said he would give me an
extension on my mortgage
if... I agreed to
sleep with him.
I told Seth, thinking
that he would be
as angry as I was,
but he wasn't.
♪
Instead, he...
came up with this plan.
Said that we should
set him up, rob him.
♪
And I stupidly agreed.
[heavy breathing]
♪
He was only supposed
to scare him.
He...
The gun wasn't even
supposed to be loaded.
♪
[gunshot echoing]
Seth did drugs.
I guess a little more than
usual this time around,
to calm the nerves.
♪
All I know is that
when we left that room,
Samuel Powell was...
dead.
♪
To make matters worse,
this... excited him
and gave him a rush,
like he started to
feel invincible.
[heavy breathing]
♪
And when I snapped out of
it, I yelled, I screamed,
I told him, "We should
go to the police,"
but he refused.
I told him that, out
of anger, I would go,
but that was stupid,
because Seth did
something that he said
would bond us for life.
He made me put my fingerprints
on the gun instead of his
and said that he would
tell the police that...
I killed Samuel Powell myself.
Six weeks after that, I...
found out I was
pregnant with Adam.
♪
What made matters worse...
Samuel Powell had agreed
to approve the extension
on our mortgage.
♪
But Seth had already
built up this plan.
After that, he started
targeting more wealthy men,
robbing them, blackmailing them.
I mean, the money
was good for a while,
but more money meant more drugs,
vice, gambling, you name it.
Even though we're
no longer together,
periodically he has
me work his marks,
and if I refuse,
he says that he's gonna take
the weapon to the police.
♪
I can't have that.
Is that what happened
to Arthur Lamb?
Yes.
[sighs]
So where is the gun now?
I don't know,
but he swears he still has it.
And how do I know that this
isn't all part of the con?
O, I'm telling you the truth.
I never wanted you to get
mixed up in all of this.
Just being with you made
me feel like I had hope.
♪
I am so sorry.
[sniffles]
[sighs]
♪
You should've said
something in the beginning.
♪
I'll figure out
how to handle Seth,
but after this is all over,
I don't want to see you again.
♪
[sobbing]
[door closes]
♪
Daddy, I really
messed up with O.
♪
Daddy?
No, Daddy, wake up!
Please wake up, Daddy!
[sobbing]
Please, wake up.
Wake up, Daddy.
[sobbing]
Wake up, please.
♪
[clicks]
Please, Mr. Apopis.
Just give me 24 more hours.
♪
Just gil promise I'll get
24 more all your money.
All of it.
♪
[metal scraping]
[slicing, groaning]
♪
Twenty-four hours, Seth.
No more, no less.
You haven't got my money,
this will be the last
24 hours of your life.
♪
[sighs, sword clatters]
[clattering]
♪
Fuck.
[groaning]
♪
Oh, fuck.
Yo, you straight?
These motherfuckers
aren't playing.
Fuck this shit, I'm about
to smoke this motherfucker.
No, Seth, Seth, no, look.
[groaning]
Seth, Seth, Seth, Seth, Seth...
Man, chill!
Chill, we're gonna get this
figured out, cuz, calm down.
Man, where the fuck was you at
when they just came up in here?
I was on the couch,
like I always do.
I was asleep.
Oh, you were asleep?
Fuck, Seth!
Huh? You set me up?
You let these
motherfuckers in here?
What?!
What's wrong...
Huh?
How could you?
How could you? Huh?
You workin' with Fernando?
You trippin'!
I'm your... I'm your cousin,
I wouldn't do that to you!
♪
Fuck! Fuck!
[smashing, clattering]
[screaming]
[birds chirping]
[door opens]
[cars honking in distance]
I can't believe you're
doing this, man.
Yeah.
Neither can I.
Thank you.
Yeah.
All right, all right, all right.
We'll have plenty of time for
that later in our jail cells.
[indistinct rap lyrics]
[groaning]
♪
[phone vibrating]
[clicks]
♪
Yeah?
Is that right?
♪
All right, good man.
I'll text you the address.
♪
♪ Holla, listen, I am bad ♪
♪ I am bad
♪ Gimme a second to prove it
♪ Know that I'm
reckless and ruthless ♪
♪ Get in their head and
you fools is like deuces ♪
♪ You better get used to it,
you're one of the useless ♪
♪ We move it right
inside of the sky ♪
♪ It's not a surprise
what we're doin' ♪
♪ Why the confusion?
♪ We sharper than knives
and livin' the
life we pursuin' ♪
♪ Higher than moons,
arriving to do this ♪
You better have my
money, I'm a fuckin' god.
[door creaking]
Oh, Isis.
I'm so sorry. I'm so sorry.
Geb was...
Miss Sara,
you've been wonderful.
Actually, you've been...
the most reliable person in
my life since my mother died.
[sniffling]
I hate to ask,
but I don't trust
anyone in this world
to watch Adam other than you.
Oh, of course.
I don't have a lot of
time to explain, but...
I really need you to
watch Adam for me.
Of course, of course I will.
Just tell me how
long you need me to.
That's just it.
It could be for a while.
Honey, are you in
some kind of trouble?
♪
I'm finally taking
my father's advice,
but if things don't go right...
I have some documents
in the drawer.
Adam's medical
records and insurance,
and I even have a signed
document of the house
so you're able to
take care of him.
[sighs]
[birds chirping]
Isis...
I've known since the accident
that you had some
hard decisions to make
to provide for your family,
and you've done an amazing job.
And I've known you since
you were Adam's age,
and I am so proud of you
and the woman that
you have become,
and I know your parents are too.
So you... you just do
what you have to do,
and then you come
back here safe.
You hear me?
Yes.
Hi, Miss Sara.
Hey, baby.
Adam...
♪
Mommy has to go now, okay?
I don't know how...
[sighs]
Ju... just promise me
you'll be a good boy
for Miss Sara, okay?
Okay, I will.
I love you.
I love you too, Mommy.
♪
[birds chirping]
[engine starting]
♪
[engine rumbling]
[knocking]
♪
[door creaking]
Seth!
- He ain't here.
- Where is he?
Gone to meet your boyfriend.
- Shit!
- Yo, Ice, hold up.
- Mike, I don't have time...
- Hold up, I just, I just...
Please let me tell you
this, I have to say this.
I ain't never told you
how much you meant to me
when I...
when I came to you
about my truth.
You really kept that shit, Ice.
Mike, of course.
I'm honored that you would
even trust me with your truth.
My fuckin' cousin, man, just...
You know, I grew up with
Seth and his brother,
and he always treated
me like one of them,
like third brother.
Seth's always been an asshole,
but lately, he... he...
Come with me.
What's going on?
Look, I'm sorry for
what he doin' to you,
and I'm even more hurt that
I played a role in that shit,
and I can't make it up, but...
[metal clinking]
I can make sure you get this.
Mike...
I shoulda gave you that
shit a long time ago, sis.
Well, what about you?
I'm good.
I'm about to hit this road.
I met somebody.
I met this guy from
Alaska a few months back.
You know, we only been
datin' a few weeks, but...
it seems promising, you know?
He said I can come up
there and stay with him
for a little while, so
that's where I'ma go.
Love you, sis.
Mike, I can't thank
you enough for this.
No, you could.
[door creaking open]
Seth? Baby?
You get that dude
Osiris's money?
Oh my God.
What happened in here?
Baby?
I'm wearing your
favorite outfit.
♪
Nephy?
Ice...
You...
I can explain.
Told Seth about O?
♪
Ice...
you know your man was the
best mark we've ever had,
and so...
Hm.
[slaps]
Now, where are they?
♪
[glass shattering]
Seth! Where the
fuck you hidin' at?
Huh?!
♪
Huh?
I'm here!
I got your fucking money!
♪
Bring your ass out here, Seth!
You want some money, right?
Huh?
I'm here! Stop fucking hiding!
♪
Seth!
Speak of the devil,
and the devil appears.
♪
So what are we doin' here, Seth?
Oh, you don't know where we are.
Used to be the biggest
bank in the city.
But before that, this
shit was the projects.
This is where I was born.
Shit.
Where I earned my stripes.
♪
My mom,
she OD'd two feet from where
you're standing right now.
And my pops,
nigga died in a
shootout with the police
right in that hallway.
And you askin' what
we're doin' here.
I mean,
it's only right.
♪
This place has seen
my lowest of lows.
♪
It's definitely gonna
see my highest of high.
I don't give a damn about
your family history.
I just wanna get this
bullshit over with.
♪
There's your money.
Now leave us alone.
Wait, what the fuck
did you just say?
You heard me.
I said I want you
to leave Isis alone.
Oh. Oh, this nigga.
Is you really sittin' here
takin' liberty, motherfucker?
♪
You know what?
I didn't know what
happened to her.
Now I do: You.
Isis belongs to me!
The hell I do.
Eye, what the hell
are you doin' here?
Putting an end to this.
What you got there?
♪
Oh, shit.
You fuckin' my cousin too?
Seth, you've always
been an idiot.
Put the gun down.
I'm going to the police
and I'm turning myself in,
and I'm telling them
everything about you.
- Isis...
- What?
Bitch, is you crazy?
What you gonna do
about your dad?
Huh?
My dad is gone,
so you can't
threaten him anymore.
What about our son then, huh?
Myson
is with someone that I trust.
You never got it.
You never fucking got it.
Everything, everything that I do
and I'm doin', I'm doin' for us.
♪
Everything. Look at this.
It's enough for me, you,
and Adam to disappear.
Just us.
♪
- There's no us, Seth.
- I know.
♪
I know.
'Cause a motherfucker
like this is in the way.
Okay, hey...
[gunshot]
♪
[grunting]
Go, Isis, go!
[gun clattering]
[grunting, groaning]
[smacking]
Look what you made me do!
♪
[smacking]
[slams]
[groaning]
[footsteps approaching]
Let me see your hands!
Get against the desk!
Against the desk!
Hands behind your back!
You gotta be
fuckin' shittin' me!
Seth Calloway,
you have the right
to remain silent.
Anything you say
can and will be used
against you in a court of law.
Let's go!
Gotta be fuckin' shittin' me!
♪
[birdsong]
Detective, come
on, please tell me
you're not here to arrest
her at her father's funeral.
No, I am not.
I just stopped by
to let you know
I had a conversation
with the DA.
Seeing as, if it wasn't for you,
we wouldn't have any evidence
on Seth Calloway and his crew,
the DA has decided
to offer you a plea.
If you agree to testify as
a confidential key witness
in Mr. Calloway's trial,
she'll drop all the
charges against you.
[birds chirping]
Oh my God, are you serious?
As a heart attack.
Yes, of course I will.
Thank you.
Thank you, Miss Shaw.
Good luck with the
election, Mr. Hughes.
Thank you, Detective.
You two take care.
[Isis chuckles]
[applause, cheering]
[kissing]
Congratulations,
Mr. State Representative.
Thank you, that does have a
nice ring to it, doesn't it?
It does.
♪
Hey.
So, this... is for you.
♪
It took me a while to
find all 77 stones,
but I did put it back together.
Here.
Now you're whole again.
♪
Thank you, Eye,
but you're the most
important piece of my life.
♪
♪ Tonight
♪ It's you and me in flight
♪
♪ And I
♪ Will always be by your side
♪
♪ By your side
♪ Won't waste this feeling
♪ I won't hesitate
♪ We've got all this
time to make it right ♪
♪
♪ Won't waste the meaning ♪
♪ I won't be afraid
♪ 'Cause you are all
I want in this life ♪
♪ Tonight
♪
♪ It's you and me in flight
♪ And I
♪ Will always be
by your side ♪
♪ By your side