(dramatic orchestral music)
(tense orchestral music)
(audience cheering)
- Bravo, bravo.
- Splendid, as always.
I could watch you dance forever.
Don't, stay with me.
Why go back to Russia?
- Do you know what they
do to family of defectors?
- I love you, Svetlana.
Please stay.
Together we could revolutionize dance.
- You're a great American choreographer,
and I love you.
I cannot stay in America.
I go home tomorrow.
- No.
- Tony.
(tire squealing)
- Svetlana.
- Ladies?
Ladies, your attention please.
Mister Wagner?
- Thank you.
I'd like to welcome you
to Madame Gordenko's
academy of dance.
This is the first time the
authorities have allowed girls
from outside the Soviet Union to attend.
I have been trying to
accomplish this for many years.
Therefore, I shall expect quite a lot.
(screaming)
As I was saying,
I'm not promising that Madame
can turn you into Anna
Pavlovas or Margo Fontaines,
at least not over night.
As is the tradition of this academy,
one of you will audition for
the Petersburg Ballet Rus.
Which one will it be?
- Ladies, to your rooms please.
- That photographer from
the magazine is back again.
I thought I instructed
you to get rid of him.
- I'll ask him to leave.
- As for our heat inspector,
I know him, I know him.
You must be Anthony Wagner, am I right?
I'm James Anderson.
You did get my cable?
- I'm very sorry, Mister uh?
- Anderson.
What's the matter with this country?
- Yes, won't you sit please?
I'm afraid I have no idea
what you're talking about.
- Jessica come down here would you?
- I'm really quite sorry Mister Anderson,
but our enrollment has been
filled for some time now,
and it's by invitation only.
As you can well imagine,
we have to be quite sure...
(eerie orchestral music)
- I love you Anthony.
- Then stay with me.
- Look Mister Wagner, I'm a man who's used
to getting what he wants,
and what I want is for Jessica
to attend your academy,
study under your Madame,
and to dance at the
Petersburg Ballet Company.
- I guess I have to
apologize for my father.
He thinks he can buy anything he wants to,
and I'm not about to go to
your Russian ballet school.
I don't want to be a prancing
old-fashioned prima ballerina.
I loved ballet when I was a kid.
Now I'm gonna dance the way I want to,
and it's not ballet.
- Svetlana.
Svetlana!
(dramatic orchestral music)
Svetlana.
- My daughter'll do as
I wish, Mister Wagner.
- I think maybe we are roommates.
- Yeah, I guess.
Where are you from?
- Paris.
You?
- Everywhere,
nowhere.
Guess this one's mine.
God, I have no idea what I'm doing here.
- How can you say that?
Do you know how many girls
would love to study with Madame?
She's famous, all over the continent.
We are honored to be the first outsiders...
- Don't tell me you're
one of Madame's groupies?
(somber orchestral music)
(girl screaming)
- What's going on up there?
What happened?
What is going on here?
Oh my God.
- No, it was a joke.
I was just kidding, look.
It's fake.
- Now, get up, get to your rooms.
Move it ladies, move it.
Now remember, we have to
get ready early tomorrow.
- I do hope, we are rid
of this journalist, pest Anthony.
- [Anthony] I instructed
Olga to get rid of him.
(whispering)
Don't scold me, Madame.
I have my reasons.
Her father was most persuasive.
Now, look at this photograph,
and tell me what you think
of Miss Jessica Anderson.
- Ah, it is remarkable.
But, can she dance?
- Why it's as if I had a second chance.
- Why do you think it would
have been any different,
if you had a second chance, hmm?
(giggling)
(knocking on door)
- Madame, may I come in?
- [Madame] Yah.
- [Anthony] Come in Olga.
(giggling)
- Was that your famous Madame?
- Of course, didn't you
know they were lovers?
- Oh God, with that face?
- Oh no, not now.
Long ago, he was a great
American choreographer,
and most handsome.
Many years ago, Madame, she
was dancing in New York,
and she defected to America.
She returned to Russia years later,
after a terrible accident.
Some say he is to blame,
for keeping Madame.
Can I tell you a secret?
Some say they are still lovers.
- Oh God, with Olga to help.
(ominous orchestral music)
(heart beating)
(alarm clock ringing)
- Oh come on, we must go, we
get a good place at the bar.
- Ladies, pay attention please.
Let's begin.
E, one, two, three, four.
One, two, three, four.
- I haven't done this in four years.
- I did this yesterday.
- Now, change position.
One, two, three, four.
One, two.
- She's KGB.
- Three, four.
Drop the hands softer.
Three, four.
One, two, three, four.
All together, all together.
- So, which of you wants
to be great dancer?
You, huh?
Now, I realize that some of you
prefer the rock and roll to the ballet.
But not here, not in my class.
No more.
- What the hell are you doing?
- The Petersburg Ballet Rus,
will be to accepting one of
my students for further study.
This provides fantastic opportunity,
to establish one's reputation
in the world of dance.
Now, who is willing to pay
the price for greatness?
(piano music)
Tres bien, mademoiselle.
Next.
- Me? I don't think so.
(piano music)
- Arch, arch.
Again, please.
I would like to see those
steps again, Miss Anderson.
Very well, next?
- Jessica, you're in over
your shit with Madame.
- You mean deep shit.
- That too.
You must show respect for her.
She's a great teacher.
- That may be, but she
doesn't have to be rude.
- Rude?
It was you who was rude.
Jessica, you can be a wonderful dancer.
I will help you.
- Thanks, but I don't think so.
What is it about this place?
Doesn't it ever get dark around here?
- No, not this time of year,
because we are so far north.
It's called white nights.
The sun sets for maybe 30 minutes.
- What's that?
(ominous orchestral music)
Hello?
Anybody here?
- May I help you Miss Anderson?
- Oh, am I not supposed to be here?
- No no, that's quite all right.
You looking for something?
- No, I was just curious I guess.
- Ah, well, you know what
curiosity did to the cat, don't you?
- Jessica, are you all right?
- Yeah, I'm fine.
- I don't usually allow visitors,
but would you two like to step inside?
I think I have some juice you might enjoy.
And perhaps you will indulge
me if I have a little vodka?
Here we are.
I heard about your little
problem with Madame today.
- Jessica is a wonderful dancer.
- All the great ballerinas were brunettes,
like Claudine here.
Have you ever considered
changing your hairstyle?
Or perhaps the color?
- I told you I don't want to
be a ballerina, all right?
Claudine, let's go.
- [Claudine] Come on,
we've got to do this.
- I know, but I told you this
ballet stuff suffocates me.
And Claudine, Claudine,
no matter what, I'm not
changing my hair color.
- I agree, but I'm not
letting my new American friend
be humiliated by Madame again.
(Olga speaking in foreign language)
- Nyet Olga, English, we must to speak.
English our students from west
are attending our academy, understood?
- Yes, of course, but the
academy will never be the same
this new students.
- Nonsense, students from the west
could only enhance the
reputation of my academy,
so I have learned.
- Other side, okay?
Up and up and.
Your shoulder, your arms,
here, yes that's it,
that's it, like that.
More, that's it, okay?
I think you're hiding out, yes, okay?
- You go ahead, I need
to work at this thing.
- I could stay and help you.
- No.
- Are you sure?
- It's my thing, thanks.
- I'll be in the spa.
- That sounds great.
I'll meet you in a bit.
- Okay.
(rock music)
71 got a feeling that
something's starting
(eerie music)
77 And feel the heat on me
7 Gonna get my body moving
7 And set it free
7 I'm gonna turn it out
3 Gonna take that hammer down in my soul
3 And take my chances and lose control
(rock music)
(tense orchestral music)
(heart beating)
- Jessica, is that you?
(rock music)
(heart beating)
Who's there?
Come on guys, it's not funny.
(heart beating)
Angela, is this one of your jokes?
Look, if someone's there,
say something, please.
(rock music)
(heart beating)
(screaming)
Why are you doing this?
- Claudine?
Are you in here?
Claudine?
Claudine, are you in here?
- Hello?
How's the water?
- Hi, what are you doing here?
- Warm, huh?
Do you want to get wet with me?
- Who are you?
Where's Claudine?
- Who's Claudine?
- Do you work here, or what?
- She like bubbles?
- You didn't answer my question.
- So, you don't want to get wet with me?
That's cool.
- Hey you, wait up.
- What?
More questions?
All right, Alexander Dugrov,
Moscow Ballet Magazine.
- Am I supposed to be impressed?
- I hope not.
- So, what do you do for
fun in this mausoleum?
- Isn't it against regulations?
- Whose regulations?
Wait I'll change.
(motorcycle starting)
(alarm clock ringing)
- Claudine, I met this
great guy last night.
I'll tell you about it later.
And thanks to you,
I'm gonna show that Madame a thing or two.
She wouldn't have left.
- Look at this.
Three different fly times to Paris.
- It doesn't make any sense,
okay, she loved it here.
Look, she would never leave
without the music box.
- What is that?
That's yours.
It is on your dresser, isn't it?
- It belongs to Claudine.
- Well, then she must have forgotten it.
- She wouldn't ever.
- She's gone home, Miss Anderson,
and that's all there is about it.
Her parents will have to be informed.
And by the way, your class
begins in 20 minutes.
You'd better get dressed young lady,
and don't be late.
(piano music)
You're late, come here.
Listen, I was right.
You don't know your friend
as well as you thought.
Her parents informed us
about some boy from Paris,
who got in some trouble with the police,
and I guess she wanted to be with him
more than she wanted to be here.
- Claudine never mentioned a boy...
- She's gone.
Now, get warmed up.
Madame will be here any moment.
(piano music)
- You're not working hard enough Jessica.
You're still too much thinking.
I think that your steps,
it is like looking at great portraits,
and knowing it is forgery.
You must to hide the mechanics.
Hmm?
Yeah?
(giggling)
(hands clapping)
- Girls, we've got still work to do.
Get to your bars.
(piano music)
- Notice how Angela's work
has an apparently seamless quality.
Olga, ask Miss Anderson to come forward.
- Miss Anderson, come here please.
- I would like for you to
perform the variation again.
This time, together.
- Madame, I don't think
that's really fair.
I mean, I don't know the
variation of the music.
- Fair, Miss Anderson?
Dance.
(piano music)
Bravo, Angela, exquisite.
I told you the American girl had talent.
- Yes, of course, Madame,
you were right as always.
Tell Mister Wagner to
come here immediately.
- Ah, I believe he's
not available right now.
- Just, to bring him here.
- Of course.
- Do you understand?
- Yes, I understand.
(music box playing)
(romantic orchestral music)
- Hello?
- You scared me.
- Are you okay?
- Yes, yes I'm okay.
- [Jessica] Where'd you get the music?
- I don't know, something I picked up.
It's just good to dance to.
- Claudine uses that music.
- Who is Claudine?
- My friend from Paris.
They say she left the academy.
- You want one?
- No thanks.
- We all have our little vices.
I would be lost without my little friends.
They help me dance,
they give me that extra edge that I need.
(classical music)
- Do you know that
Claudine's not here anymore?
- Olga mentioned it,
something about a boyfriend back in Paris?
- It's pure bullshit.
She would never leave without
saying something to me.
- What are you saying Jessica?
- Something's happened to her.
I just know it.
- I don't understand.
What happened?
- I don't know, just something bad.
- Well, I think your
imagination's run away a bit,
but I'll tell you what,
I'll look into it if you wish.
I understand you were
quite good in class today.
- All right, I guess,
until that bitch of a Madame
of yours got on my case.
I mean how am I supposed to
dance if I don't know the steps?
- Good point.
Maybe I could help.
We Yanks should stick together, hmm?
- Would you help me?
(dramatic orchestral music)
- Are you all right?
- Yeah, I'm fine.
- Look, if you really want to impress
the Petersburg judges,
you must dance in a style they understand.
What you're doing is nice,
but you need to be more traditional,
more of what they expect to see.
- I know, I'm not trying
to impress the Petersburg,
I just want to get through class.
- Svetlana.
- What?
- Nothing, I was just thinking of Madame.
Well, we should be getting back to work.
You have a lot of competition
from a lady from London.
- I know.
- And.
- One, two, three, four.
One, two, three, four.
- You must to be the
condition of Olympic athlete,
to be good dancer.
Now, Olga just told me you've
worked very hard this week.
Therefore, a special privilege.
The Saint Petersburg Ballet Rus
has been kind enough to allow
us the use of their stage
for our lesson tomorrow.
And use of their male
dancers, to assist us.
- Men.
(bright orchestral music)
(stage murmuring)
- What are you doing?
You may wait in the wings.
- I was just wondering if it was a sock,
or if it was real.
- It's disgusting, it's disgusting.
I'm not going to stand here
and to watch you hoodlums
defile the ballet with your filth.
(eerie music)
- Who's there?
Come on you guys.
(heart beating)
You can't fool me.
It's Angela, remember?
(heart beating)
(tense orchestral music)
- We must return to the academy.
Come girls.
- I'll go get Angela.
Angela?
Angela, Madame says it's time to go.
Angela, are you kidding around?
Angela?
Angela, is that you?
Angela, stop clowning around.
- What are you doing here?
- Madame says it's time to go,
I was looking for Angela.
Have you seen her?
- No, I haven't.
I suppose she just left,
like your friend from Paris.
You know sometimes I'm wondering,
is everything a sick joke for you girls.
- Where's Angela?
- Jessica?
Psst, Jessica.
- What are you doing up there?
- Looking for you.
What are you doing here?
- I'm looking for Angela.
- We've gotta talk.
Do you really think it's
some sort of coverup here?
- Yes, I sure do.
They're just trying to
keep the school open.
Angela and Claudine
wouldn't just take off.
- Well maybe they did take
off, each with a boyfriend.
- Are you kidding?
This place is like a convent.
You're really hot.
- What about you?
Are you seeing anyone?
- No such luck.
- It's strange.
- Someone's coming.
- You shouldn't be out alone at this hour.
- I wasn't alone.
- I just wanted to make
certain you were safe.
How well do you know this magazine fellow?
- Well enough.
- Great dancers need their rest,
if we are to revolutionize dance.
- I don't know about
revolutionizing anything.
I just want to get through
class tomorrow with Madame.
It's a nice thought though.
Good night.
- The authorities say, they
have no more information.
But, I cannot help but
to worry that something
has happened to our Angela.
Therefore, I must to be
considering canceling this session.
- Angela wouldn't want us
to do that, I know her.
She's probably having a good
laugh about all this right now.
She does love ballet,
and I am certain that
whatever she's doing,
she'll be back soon.
She wouldn't want us to change anything.
- Do you girls agree with Ingrid?
Yeah?
And so do 1.
Our Angela will return.
She's making a practical
joking on us, hmm?
Now, on to more pleasant thoughts then.
Today's lesson.
(piano music)
(class applauding)
Very good, Natasha.
Because of strain, and concern for Angela,
I'm granting you second privilege.
Olga will chaperone you
to the city this night.
(disco music)
- Come on, let's get up here.
Come on.
7 More than I should, we're
runnin' in my neighborhood
3 There's something back there new
7 To take my mind off of you
7 Baby what did I do
- [Jessica] Come on.
- Not a chance.
- Come on, get up here.
Come on.
- No, no.
- Come on.
- Tom, come on.
/7 Talkin' about things I
shouldn't be thinking of
7 Losing my reasoning
7 I still think of you
I Because no one else will do
7 Say I'm a fool
- Look, Jessica,
Madame wouldn't approve of
you dancing with this man.
- I dance with whoever I want.
- Look, watch me dance.
7 Baby I've got something for you
- How are you?
- Just fine.
- Ivan must leave for the
last train at the Metro.
- Oh, that's too bad.
I really liked the way
you danced out there,
especially that.
- I'm gonna walk him.
And, cover for me with the gustapo, shhh.
I'll be back before Olga knows I'm gone.
Bye.
- You're a pretty good dancer out there.
- Thanks.
- Sasha, the news and not the girl.
- Sorry.
- You want something to do Alex?
- Okay, well, I have to leave right now.
When's Olga taking you
back to the academy?
- I don't know, I'm not sure.
I don't know where she went, she's gone.
- Okay, I'll be back
as soon as I can, okay?
- This will make you feel better.
- You don't need this, Ingrid.
Nobody does.
You're a great dancer,
you, not the pills, you.
- You sound exactly like my parents.
- I'm your friend, Ingrid.
- These little friends, gives me energy.
Let's dance.
- That was fun.
See you tomorrow.
- Telephone me tomorrow.
Bye.
(screaming)
- So what happened to
your magazine friend?
Did he find somebody he likes better?
- Yeah, maybe he did, he's
been gone a long time.
- Well girls, we're going home.
What's happened to Natasha?
I don't see her here.
- Natasha met a guy she
likes, she's walking him home.
- Madame will be furious.
(dramatic orchestral music)
- What are you doing here? Be quiet.
- I'm coming up.
- Are you crazy?
- Yes, about you.
- Be careful.
(tense orchestral music)
- [Madame] Anthony, have we
heard anything about Natasha?
- No, the police know nothing.
Girls have the west have no discipline.
Maybe it was unwise, letting
them come to the academy.
Svetlana.
- Sorry.
Sorry I couldn't, sorry
I couldn't make it to the
club before you left,
I had some business to take care of.
- Sure it wasn't some other girl?
- Girl, me?
No.
- Okay, two rules.
One, you can't spend the night.
And two, we're gonna have
to be quiet about this.
(eerie orchestral music)
- Jessica?
- Shhhh.
(alarm clock ringing)
- I'm gonna take a quick shower,
and then change before class begins, okay?
- All right.
- We have to make this a quickie.
Go get the condom.
- We ready.
- Jessica, I'm so sorry about last night.
I was so out of line.
I just wanted to tell you
that, may the best dancer win.
- Thanks.
- So, what happened to
your boyfriend last night?
- Oh, I think he had a good time.
- [Anthony] Ladies?
- Girls, please, gather together.
- I have some very bad news.
There was a terrible accident last night.
I'm sorry to report
that your friend Natasha
has been tragically killed.
- What a minute, Angela
and Claudine are missing,
and now poor Natasha's dead?
- Obviously there will be no lesson today,
Madame is far too upset.
I shall give your condolences
to Natasha's family.
Let's um, let's leave this to the police.
- Jessica, there's something
I'd like you to know.
About the pills, no more, no more drugs.
I threw them all away.
- Good girl.
- Madame, Jessica will
audition for the Petersburg.
Isn't that wonderful news?
- Madame does not wish to discuss
your young American friend.
And besides, you're becoming
too fond of this American.
She's not the best dancer we have.
This girl from Germany
is every bit as good.
- You may leave Olga.
Madame and I will discuss this in private.
- As you wish.
(romantic orchestral music)
(heart beating)
- I'm sorry, I didn't mean to be up here.
What's wrong?
(heart beating)
Why are you doing this?
- Ingrid, did you really think
you dance with the Petersburg, hmm?
Did you?
(crashing)
(dramatic orchestral music)
- Ingrid?
(screaming)
Ingrid!
- Are you telling people it was suicide?
- There will be an official announcement.
- Ingrid was my friend,
I'm not waiting for you
to concoct some story.
- Jessica, please.
- She didn't write this.
- We found it in her room, her
body was full of narcotics.
- Uh uh, she stopped using.
She didn't, she promised me.
- So, how many more
students have withdrawn?
- I don't know, about 20.
- And Jessica?
Is she staying?
- Is the American girl all you think of?
- And just what does that mean?
- Two girls missing, two girls dead.
All we care about is Jessica.
- Yes, that's right.
We must have someone represent the academy
at the Petersburg audition.
Why not Jessica?
Hmm?
- Wait a minute,
Jessica is the best dancer
left at the academy.
And it looks like as if it was planned.
- Now what does that mean,
that I planned to have
those poor girls killed,
that I arranged to have Jessica
get into the Petersburg?
- No no no no no no, of
course not, of course not.
I've been with you and Madame, you know,
and helped you with Madame much too long,
to even consider such a thing.
No of course not.
I was only meaning that Jessica
is the best dancer we have now.
Right?
That's all.
- Yes she is.
She is the best.
Have
Madame prepare herself, would you?
I must speak to her.
- Yes, of course my dear, as you wish.
- Alex?
Alex?
(tense orchestral music)
- Mister Dugrov?
Do you really think you
can get away with this?
- What are you talking about?
Get away with what?
- We'll just see what
the police have to say.
- What police?
Look, look I was just trying
to see what's going on.
- I understand.
What is this?
- What's what?
- Relax, it's just play knife.
You see?
- You're crazy.
- Yes I am, probably.
It doesn't matter.
I don't understand,
this belongs to Angela.
- [Alex] So?
- So, what is going on here?
- That's a good question.
Where are you going?
What's in there?
- [Olga] Mister Wagner's things.
- Come on, we don't have all night.
- [Olga] I'm doing this.
(door creaking)
- What's this?
- Claudine's luggage.
Oh my God.
(door closing)
- Jessica.
- Olga, oh my God.
You killed them.
- No.
- You killed Angela,
Claudine.
- No no, no Jessica.
- Alex, why?
- You don't understand
what you're talking about.
- You're crazy.
- No, it wasn't me
Jessica please, no wait.
Please Jessica, you don't
understand, I didn't do it.
There's so much Jessica
you don't understand.
- My God, what's happened?
This can't be.
- I love you.
Our secret is safe.
- Of course it's your decision Jessica.
The academy's officially closed.
The rest of the girls will
be gone by this afternoon.
I understand if you wish to leave.
- I want to go to Alex's funeral.
- I'm sorry, that's impossible.
His remains have been sent
to his family in Moscow,
the service is there.
Jessica, listen to me for a moment.
You must try to put
all of this behind you.
It's such a shame, you worked so hard,
but I truly believe you could be accepted
by the Petersburg.
- I want to stick with Madame.
- Well I'm afraid all this business
has been too much for her.
She's confined to her
bed, and will see no one.
- I just can't believe how
crazy that Olga must have been.
- Yes, tortured people in this world
do things we may never understand.
We should be discussing you Jessica.
Don't you think Alexander
would want you to
take advantage of this opportunity?
- I suppose so.
- It's up to you,
but whatever you decide,
please, please let me help.
I could prepare you,
I could help you to
become prima ballerina,
off the Petersburg Ballet Rus,
and Madame, Madame would be so proud.
- Okay.
(ominous orchestral music)
- She's wonderful, she's fantastic,
just like you.
Just like you were.
You must trust us.
We know what the
Petersburg is looking for.
- When do I get to see Madame?
How's she doing?
- Oh, much much better.
I tell her your progress every night.
Tomorrow, the Petersburg.
- You've been great Anthony.
When can I see Madame?
I want to see her, please can I see her?
- Very well, I'll tell you what,
you shower and get a bite to eat,
and I'll tell Madame you'll
be up at say, eight o'clock?
And don't excite her too much, all right?
- I won't, I just want to see her
before tomorrow's audition.
Madame?
It's Jessica.
May I come in?
Madame?
It's Jessica.
Did Anthony tell you I'd
be coming this evening?
How are you feeling?
Tomorrow's the big audition.
I hope to make you proud of me.
- Anthony,
everything,
Anthony,
Svetlana.
- What?
- Two of us.
Two of us.
- Anthony.
Anthony?
There's something wrong with Madame.
- [Madame] You will not
give that girl everything.
- Anthony?
Madame, sorry to bother you.
Do you know where Anthony is?
Madame?
- You won't replace me.
Please,
Svetlana,
don't make me use this.
You see, together,
we could revolutionize dance.
It's not too late, my beautiful swan.
I thought I lost you,
so long ago.
But you came back.
I brought you back,
as part of me.
It wasn't my fault.
No, it was an accident.
Oh yes yes yes yes yes I know, I know.
You blamed me.
You went away.
No, no, no.
And now,
come back to me,
in the flesh.
Forgive me,
to dance for me.
But you will dance, yes.
You'll dance in the Petersburg Ballet Rus,
because there's no one left to dance.
You'll dance for me, my choregraphy,
together, we will revolutionize dance.
The world will only remember your glory,
not your pain.
- A dream.
A nightmare.
To Svetlana, my beautiful,
forever yours, Anthony.
No.
(knocking on door)
- Good morning, you have
one hour to get dressed,
and get ready for the Petersburg audition.
Svetlana?
- You can't make me do this, Anthony.
I won't do this.
- Now now, we mustn't
disappoint Madame, must we?
You're the only one left
to dance for the academy.
Oh, what's this?
I see you received my flowers.
Don't disappoint me Svetlana.
I can use this if I have to.
- No, you won't have to use it Anthony.
Will Madame be coming to the audition?
- My dear Svetlana, you
don't understand do you?
Madame wants to be you,
and if she comes,
she'll kill you.
(gentle orchestral music)
(tense orchestral music)
- I am not Svetlana.
- Oh, stay away from her.
Don't come near her.
It's better for you.
Stay away from my Svetlana.
- Brava.
- Grazzi.
- You haven't got it, little bitch.
You could never to replace me.
No, no.
No.
Svetlana.
I love you.
(dramatic orchestral music)
Svetlana, my love.
You danced again.
You danced for me.
(bell ringing)
(dramatic orchestral music)