- Okay, all right. - Cheers, Dad.
Cheers. Look in the eyes.
Look in the eyes.
Aah.
It's a good potato vodka, that.
So what do we have here?
[Adam Bardach, voiceover] Growing up, we always
celebrated Dad's birthday on May 7th,
but that's not the real date.
He was always known as Gene,
but that's not his given name.
Was our family Jewish?
Until recently, I had no idea.
In retrospect, I think my Dad had good reason
to want to protect us from the truth of what happened.
He carried it, or maybe buried it,
for most of his life.
What good would saddling his children
with this burden do?
In 2001 Dad was invited by his friend, Roman Polanski,
to work on The Pianist.
I think that the experience
of revisiting the Occupation on film
was cathartic for him.
Slowly, he started to open up about the past.
Maybe his story of survival wasn't a burden to be hidden,
but a triumph to be shared.
So I went to Poland,
and together we drank some vodka
and dusted off the old photos and memories.
[Gene Gutowski, voiceover] I was born as Witold Bardach.
Under the German occupation
the Gestapo was looking all over the place for me.
It was necessary for me to change my name.
I was not even safe to get out on the street.
It was then the Polish underground
provided a set of documents, identities for me.
I became Eugene Gutowski.
[pleasant Polish song playing ♪]
[Gutowski, voiceover] My families on both mother's and father's side,
lived in Lwow.
Lwow was a extraordinarily interesting city,
a mixture of Poles, Ukrainians, Jews, Armenians.
There were churches,
synagogues of every religion.
The architecture ranged from Renaissance to the...
...Viennese Secession as they used to call it,
sort of a Viennese equivalent of French Belle Époque,
and it was a highly, highly, enjoyable,
pleasant place to live.
I have some of my happiest memories
of my childhood
in that wonderful city.
I was very, very close to my father,
I admired him.
He used to take me on Sundays,
beautifully dressed in his grey flannels
and a dark, uh, jacket
and a Borsalino hat at a dashing angle,
take me by the hand in my little sailor suit
to the restaurant in Lwow
which served the great Polish delicacy,
flaczki or tripe,
and I still have...
...the memory and the taste for that food to this day.
The strong males in my family,
whether it was my father or Uncle Bronislaw,
even my Uncle Andrew
left an impact on me,
this desire...
...or the need to be elegant.
And this probably has helped me survive the war.
At no point, even at the worst moment of the Occupation,
Soviet or German,
was I ever unshaved, or not beautifully dressed,
or what have you.
Now come on now, what German would dare
to kill such a nice looking,
good smelling, elegant, young boy?
They wouldn't dare that.
Mother was a very beautiful lady,
I mean gorgeous, in fact.
She studied music...
...and wanted to make a career as a concert pianist.
Every day,
in the morning...
...there were sounds of...
...piano in our house, that was...
...part of everyday's background,
was her practicing.
[Film Narrator] Jews have lived in Lwow since the 14th century,
100 years after its establishment.
During these centuries,
they lived in two communities.
One outside the city walls and one inside.
The two communities suffered all the troubles
that visited the city.
Invasion by the Tatars, the Turks,
the Sweeds, the Cossacks,
and the great fires which burned down
the city's wooden houses.
[Gutowski] Both mother and father,
though they were born Jewish,
they're absolutely non-practicing.
As I say, I've never
took part in any holidays
or-or didn't even know what they were.
I was never inside of a synagogue, uh,
though I used to go to churches quite a bit.
It's a very difficult world to describe to--
particularly to people
who only sort of think in terms of black and white,
who don't understand the areas of greyness
and maybe even look with contempt
on people who totally assimilated,
but that was the history of many Jews in Poland.
They simply assimilated.
The Jewish background became a liability
only under the Nazi regime
when they suddenly, with the Nuremberg laws,
if you only had one grandparent,
according to that, you were Jewish.
And that suddenly made one realize, wait a minute...
...we're Jewish, or at least...
...we're looked upon by the Germans as being Jewish,
though feeling that we had nothing to do with it,
but I was wrong,
of course we had something to do with it...
We were one of them.
Our charmed life
came to a rapid end
with an outbreak of war in 1939.
[Newsreader] On September the first 1939,
the Nazi army smashed into Poland.
[Gutowski, voiceover] The defenses of Poland
collapsed on the western front
and the Germans were moving rapidly in our direction.
We packed up things quickly from the house,
taking all the wrong things
and leaving all the valuables, and paintings and...
...furniture, and antiques because we had no idea,
we were going to come back,
we thought maybe oh, just only be a few days.
You know, nobody had any imagination
what it was going to be like.
So we left, never to come back.
The roads were packed with refugees.
It was complete chaos and...
...frequently, German fighter planes would...
...swoop low and strafe,
uh, the people on the road so many times we had to run,
abandon the car and so on, or run into the ditches,
run into the woods
and they were simply strafing the civilians, leaving bodies.
As we were heading for the Romanian border,
in some little town not far from the border,
a local official with two policemen,
stopped the car
and at the point of a gun,
he requisitioned the car from us
to put himself and his family and escape to Romania,
leaving us on the road.
So, in that respect,
our fate was sealed then and there.
[man speaking Russian]
[Gutowski, voiceover] The Soviet army entered from the east,
crossed the Polish borders,
then to our great shock,
the Bolshevik hordes were upon us.
This was a result of the Ribbentrop-Molotov Act.
Ostensibly, they were coming to...
...liberate the Polish peasants
from the oppression of the land owner,
which of course was a lot of bullshit,
they just came to take over that part of Poland.
This was totally, uh,
a different crowd than one is used to seeing now.
Russian millionaires dressed in Armanis
and driving, uh, big foreign cars.
No, these were the primitive,
unwashed, part-Mongolian troops,
for the first time encountering the West.
Because for them, Poland was West.
Subjected to years of Communist propaganda
where people in the West were starving
whereas they were living in a paradise.
They were somewhat shocked to see exactly the opposite.
That the shops were full of, uh, luxury goods
and people are beautifully dressed and so on.
[speaking Polish]
[applause, cheering]
[Gutowski, voiceover] My father was in jeopardy because
he was a reserve officer,
secondly, he was a lawyer.
He's a man of culture, of education and so on.
This was not what the new order was about.
My mother's parents were property owners.
They owned buildings, apartment buildings
in the city of Lwow, until one day,
people came to make them sign...
...papers allowing these properties
to be nationalized.
Overnight they became poor
and owning absolutely nothing.
So there was this continuous battle...
...of-of survival,
under the Soviet Occupation.
At this point, I sort of had enough of education.
I felt it was getting me absolutely nowhere,
so I managed to get myself into an art school.
Under Communism, there are constant mass meetings,
there are constant marches,
there are constant demonstrations.
They always carry banners,
they always carry large pictures of the leaders,
Lenin, was Stalin, was Marx, was Engels,
was Voroshilov and Khrushchev even.
So there was a tremendous demand
for their large portraits.
The students of the art schools
were engaged to make these portraits
and I managed to get into that group.
Now...
...being the youngest...
...uh, they gave me something nobody wanted to do,
which was Marx.
Marx was particularly labor intensive
because he had long, curly hair
and a big beard.
They were paying 30 Rubles per glorious leader,
which was very good money in those days,
but provided you could turn them out.
So...
...after my unsuccessful life with Marx,
I was managed,
I don't know what I did, bribe somebody or something like that
to allow me to do Lenin,
and Lenin became my greatest friend
because I could really, I could do him,
I could do him, I could do him to this day,
I can, with my eyes closed, I can paint Lenin.
He had no hair, he was bald,
he had a little hair on his side of his head,
a little pointed beard,
and a sort of Mongolian cheeks
and Mongolian squinty eyes
and he was glorious.
I could knock out two of him in a night
and I was rich.
So... I must admit,
I was a teenage purveyor of Communist propaganda.
So, I don't know...
...if I'll ever have to be responsible for that,
but I admit, I was.
The lives under the Soviets, while it was not...
...pleasant or comfortable,
it was not life threatening.
The various nationalities were...
...jockeying for-for position.
The Ukrainians, under the Russian occupation,
uh, claiming that they were liberated by the Russians,
again, everybody was being liberated by somebody.
The Polish serfs were being liberated,
Ukrainians were liberated,
poor Jews were liberated...
Nobody liberated me.
[man speaking German]
[Gutowski, voiceover] With the German surprise attack,
the Soviets were in panic.
They just didn't believe,
or at least Stalin didn't believe until the last moment that
that would ever happen.
He thought he had established a relationship of friendship
with the Nazis, with Hitler, but...
...it wasn't so.
They were evacuating in a panic, in a hurry,
and, uh, the Germans were advancing very rapidly
so that Lwow was taken in a matter of days.
[ambient music ♪]
My family were
quite foolish in their thinking,
both my father and grandfather being German or...
...Austrian officers,
they thought they had nothing to be afraid of,
whereas they had more to be afraid of from the...
...from the Soviets.
When the first German troops
were riding into the city, they were Austrian troops,
my grandfather was practically out in the street
crying with joy.
He thought, oh there's-- at last, these are,
as he said, these are his boys,
the Austrian soldiers.
Well, little did he know that a year later,
his boys would kill him.
German officers, Wermacht or SS,
came to my grandfather's house,
looked over the apartment and...
...he was very proudly greeted him in German
to tell him he was a colonel doctor
in the Austrian army,
show him his medals and decorations and so on.
Well, they slapped him around, they broke up the...
...cabinet with the medals,
called him a dirty Jew...
...and left.
I felt terribly sorry for my grandfather,
but I was also, you know...
...just frightened.
The official orders and announcements
concerning the Jewish population in particular
were very quickly announced.
The first order, they had to wear an armband.
Immediately, I decided that...
...I didn't want to be a part of it.
I didn't want to wear an armband,
I just wouldn't wear an armband.
I moved freely through the city.
There was nothing in my looks,
in my speech
which in any way...
...would give away that I was a non-Aryan.
My, by that time, fluent
knowledge of the German language,
which was very unique,
uh, helped me a great deal.
Only on one occasion,
somebody had recognized me in a streetcar
and started yelling aloud that there's a Jew
and I should be caught and arrested.
Obviously, I was able to, uh, get away.
The Nazis started actions to...
...arrest and deport
large portions of the Jewish population.
They would come in sort of waves
and so everybody for that particular period of time,
knowing that they are...
...rounding people up, would try to hide
and try to survive that particular period.
My family...
...by giving the last pair of diamond earrings
from my grandmother,
made a deal with a driver for the Gestapo...
...where my whole family was hidden
right behind a headquarters of a Gestapo.
In Lwow there were garages.
So, in one of those garages,
on top, under the roof,
they were...
...lifted there, even my own grandparents,
into that hiding place for the--
to keep them there for a few days
until the worst action was over.
How they managed to stay quiet there,
all I know is that I had to...
...sneak in through the...
...Gestapo motorpark... at night...
...to help empty their chamber pots
and also bring them some food and water.
Somewhat of a risky operation that was.
Lwow was a- was a death trap.
It was getting rapidly worse and worse,
the degradation, the hunger,
the striving for supply of food.
There was still street executions,
there were people being hung out of balconies,
which I was a witness of.
This is when I decided
that I have to separate myself from my family,
uh, then the age of 16,
and I had to escape
or I was going to die.
My-my-my sense of survival
and feelings of survival were so strong,
I just didn't want to die.
I saw my grandparents, my mother's parents,
being loaded onto the truck,
two old people who quarreled all their life
because he was unfaithful and she was jealous
and suddenly those two old people supporting each other
were taken onto the--
helped onto the truck and shipped off.
[somber music ♪]
The last time I saw my mother
was in the summer of 1942.
At that time...
...uh, to help support us...
...she, the beautiful lady, the concert pianist...
...was selling...
...cakes from a tray.
I remember...
...stopping by, running through,
busy as I was, to say hello to Mum,
and she gave me a cake and kissed me,
told me to be careful and that was the last time I saw her.
Then, a day or so later...
...I ran into my father...
...who was...
...standing on a street, leaning against a fence...
...sort of like completely...
...worn out, and desperate, and was crying,
and when I came, I said, "What's the matter?" He said...
"They've taken Mother."
♪
[heavily accented English]
[Gutowski] It is my beautiful mother I think of the most here, yes.
For a while we lived in the hope that maybe
she was able to buy her way out.
There was so many rumors that people were able to escape.
Nobody escaped from here.
Nobody.
Nobody bought their way out, nobody escaped.
They just went to their death...
...and, uh...
...I think it with...
...great sadness...
...of what horror she must have gone through,
this beautiful young woman,
naked, no hair,
being pushed
into a crowded gas chamber.
Nobody, friends or family near her...
...but...
...so many others have died like that
and the rest of my family.
[speaking Polish]
So...
I'm happy that she's here...
...and, uh...
...the whole world coming here...
...can see what a beautiful young woman she was.
♪
What bestiality, what animals they were to...
...have brought that horror upon people.
To this day,
I don't have an answer, I really don't know.
I can't understand it.
I found myself at the Lwow railroad station.
The train for Warsaw was leaving in the morning.
As my capital, I took with me,
I think five or six sets of forged birth certificates,
which I was hoping to sell in Warsaw
because there was a demand for it
and these were very good birth certificates
I obtained with the help of a Parish priest,
so I had them with me, lying there in the corner,
waiting for the train in the morning,
and I thought, "Well I'll be in Warsaw,
sell that thing and I'll be safe
and maybe be able to help my parents."
A light shone in my eyes and it was a...
...Ukrainian militia
and a German SS man, Bahnhofschutz,
demanding documents.
So I produced mine which were already under a false name,
and the Ukrainian laughed and looked at me, says,
"I know you.
You maybe not remember me, but I used to be a painter.
I used to paint your grandparents' house."
So, the son of a bitch
who probably had a good job and got well paid,
he was now going to turn me in, which he did.
Janowska Street, which became infamous,
was like a concentration camp.
The selections were taking place there.
Some... fit for work...
...stronger young men or women were kept there,
others were sent off to, uh, death camps,
primarily to Belzec.
It was a big assembly field
full of people sitting, waiting and so on.
There were guard towers.
Policemen were coming with baskets,
asking everybody to deposit their money, valuables,
what have you and so on.
[muffled morose music ♪]
There was a orchestra playing...
...and one of the camp commanders,
Scharführer Rokita I think he was called,
he said even himself, he was a musician,
uh, he played in a band at one time,
always liked to work with the Jews
because they were very musical,
and even, I remember, he made a few...
...dance steps in the mud, you know,
tango steps to show how...
...you know, he was good on his feet.
♪
They were hanging some people
for whatever crimes they might have committed
in that camp, they were being hanged.
The rope was short...
...and, uh...
...so one of these men was hanging, but choking,
he was not really-- it was not enough of a drop
to break his neck.
Rokita ordered a kid to...
...assist with the hangings which the guy couldn't do.
Uh, he broke down, he was crying, so...
...Rokita took his Luger and shot him.
He ordered me to throw myself at his feet
and give it a good pull to help him die.
It was not an offer I could refuse very well, so...
...I was hanging on this guy's feet, helping him die.
These bodies were cut off
and they were being taken in wheelbarrows
to an area like sandpits.
The barrels were tipped
and the bodies were rolled and pushed down into that pit
and eventually some lime or something was thrown over them.
So at this point...
...the Ukrainian guards...
...wanted me to go down there also
and I realized once I go down, they're going to shoot me
and execute me, so one less witness.
At this point, I started screaming at him in German,
saying that I was...
...Scharführer Rokita's personal assistant
and interpreter
and they'll be really punished if any harm comes to me
and sure enough they didn't shoot me,
and so I marched myself back.
Then at night when it got dark,
open staff cars came in with some...
...Gestapo and SS officers
and they started a selection.
So people were going line up
and if you're old, you're here,
you're young, you're here,
there's going to be death or life.
I was trying always to stay out of that circle just...
...trying to find out what really was going on
before I commit myself to either...
...one or the other, and true enough...
...they always, they formed a third group...
...because as it often, in such mass actions,
some people were...
...arrested on the streets, who had valid documents,
maybe they worked for the German army,
uh, maybe they shouldn't have been arrested,
whatever they had good reason to be released
and a small column was being formed...
...for them to march out of the camp,
but they had to sleep outside of barbed wire
in a ditch there because there was a police hour
so they couldn't actually go back to the city.
Somehow, I managed to get myself into that group,
uh, Rokita recognized me,
even said to his other German officers, you know...
..."Er ist ein finer junge" he's a good boy,
he really helped me."
and I joined that group
and I marched out of the gate.
Next to me was a girl
and she held my hand and she obviously was quite nervous
and yet gave me courage.
Once we got ourselves out the gate,
in the dark, in a ditch,
having to spend the night together,
we made love there,
quietly in a ditch outside of Janowska Street.
It was sort of like a celebration of life.
[ambient music ♪]
[pleasant song playing quietly ♪]
[Gutowski] I made it to Warsaw, which was...
...to us, escaping from Lwow,
it seemed like a promised land.
There were beautiful red tomatoes
being sold everywhere,
so that for a long time
until they real-realized some money with whatever I had,
I was living on tomatoes.
They were very tasty though.
I contacted my aunt, Stasia,
because of her pre-war connections
to some high ranking Polish officers.
One of those friends
was then commander of the Polish underground army,
General Grot-Rowecki.
She was his personal liaison.
She didn't particularly want to have any...
...close contact with me,
but she did help me to get a place to live.
I was completely on my own...
...which was, when you're looking back at it
was a terrifying thing to be on your own
when you're sixteen years old,
pretending that you're older,
and, yet know, you have to totally depend on yourself
because what could my poor parents do for me
while they were still alive? Nothing.
Absolutely nothing.
My father...
...to this day I'm not sure how he, how he died.
I understand, I've been told...
...that...
...he tried to...
...with a group of other ex-officers,
friends of his, Polish officers,
uh, they tried to escape to Hungary,
through the mountains and so on,
but somebody betrayed them
and so he was arrested in-in Lwow and executed.
My brother, Roman,
was then 12 years old...
...stayed in the custody of my uncle, Bronislaw.
Roman wrote to me...
...pleading, pleading letter...
...would I come and save him?
You know, my dear brother, you know, could I save him.
Of course, I couldn't.
So...
...some months after that
when the now Ghetto was being formed in Lwow,
with the wires or walls around it, and...
...their position became untenable...
...uh...
...my uncle, Bronislaw...
...uh gave my brother poison.
Being a doctor he had it, cyanide, so...
...he killed him, he killed himself...
...in-in 1943.
I wasn't streetwise at all.
I became streetwise.
Suddenly, you had, uh,
360 degree vision.
You knew exactly who may be looking for you
just a little too long,
whose taking interest in you,
how to deal with that, how to walk away.
It's amazing how quickly
one can get used to living in fear.
It becomes a way of life, really.
So it's a question of living in fear
or-or-or trying to be fearless.
I'm not quite sure what it gave me the.
I cannot think of a better word than chutzpah
to behave the way I did.
Maybe the very fact that I...
...had few times encounters with the Germans that I was...
...let off free, nobody arrested me,
made me more and more self-assured, and-
and risk-taking.
People were dying left and right
and being taken to camps, imprisoned, executed.
I had a strange sense of immortality.
[big band song playing ♪]
I managed to get myself a job
working for the Junkers
German Aircraft manufacturers
at the Warsaw airport in Okcie.
They had a big repair base
for the Ju 88s, 87s,
which would come in shot up from the Russian front,
were repaired and sent back.
Speaking German, I used to crawl...
...through the plane, the bomb compartments,
the cockpit and everything, check that all the wiring,
there was proper, there was no damage,
destroyed and so on, and make a report.
And it didn't take very long.
When dealing with equipment, a scheme has occurred to me,
which could be formed both patriotic and profitable.
I made a point of becoming friendly...
...with the German Luftwaffe soldier
also working in that radio storage,
he was a radio specialist,
and it didn't take me very long in a private conversation
to establish that he was very, very, anti-Nazi,
in fact hated Hitler, they hated the whole thing,
and was ready...
...to work with me,
possibility removing some...
...of that equipment from the airport,
knowing that it would go to the Polish underground.
I made contact to...
...the Polish Underground and they said, well,
they would want to see one set on a trial basis.
Karl Christian, being a technician,
drew up a connecting scheme
because it wasn't simple.
At that time it wasn't just one unit.
Obviously, I couldn't take it out of the airport,
there were guards at the gate,
which he, in a uniform, could do.
A Luftwaffe with a rucksack,
nobody even bothered to stop him.
He would walk over to the house where I lived,
he would come up and give me
the piece of equipment,
which then I put under the bed,
and he would stay, I would feed him,
vodka, sausage,
and send him back on his way.
There was a Christmas I had a lot of vodka,
we both got drunk.
At one point Karl Christian let out a big fart,
and he stood up...
...raised his arm, and yelled "Heil Hitler!"
Well, that started us off,
and through the rest of the evening,
we were drinking, farting and yelling, "Heil Hitler!"
One day, in the morning, I got a call
that the Gestapo with dogs
came looking for me,
obviously because of the radio stations,
and I was quite correct,
the business got a little too big.
I figured it would take them about ten minutes
for the SS or for the Gestapo to...
...get over to where I was living
because I was sure they were given the address.
I left everything behind and I ran over to my...
...girlfriend's house to speak to her mother,
Dr. Zenona Rewerska,
and tell them my predicament,
and she said that she would hide me,
that she would keep me.
Being a non-Aryan out on the street,
without an armband,
that in itself was
immediate deportation or execution.
Not only were you at risk,
but anybody who helped you.
Anybody who helped a Jewish person,
even with food, drink or shelter,
there was a death penalty for that.
Dr. Zenona Rewerska became my surrogate mother.
Loved me like a mother. She, at the risk of her life,
let me stay in her apartment in this building.
Uh, there was the entrance right here.
I remember that on a few occasion,
this man who was looking for me because-
what was his name? You remember his name?
- Kozowski - Ah, you see...
- Targowa fifteen. - Hmm?
Targowa 15 street, Targowa street.
Yeah, yeah, you have a perfect memory.
Mr. Kozowski, who-- he was the--
my landlord in Targowa 15
and so when the Gestapo couldn't find me,
they told him that he has to help find me
otherwise they're going to take him.
[chuckling] So...
...on various occasions he tried to break into your apartment.
[speaking Polish]
[Gutowski] Yes, what happened was
that he was, you know, really persistent.
He tried to even just sign in as your mother's patient
to be able to uh,
come into the apartment to see if I was there.
[speaking Polish]
[Gutowski] Those basements were connected with each other
where you could enter the basement
in one part of the building,
you could exit all together
in a different part of the building.
You can exit in a different street.
[Rewerski] For you and for us
it is very comfortable in this time.
Yes it was.
So, you were also helping to save my life, no?
Yes, it is true.
- Absolutely. - It is true.
When the time came, you know, for me to--
really I had to leave,
I couldn't uh,
you know, risk...
...your and your family's- your mother's life.
She...
...she got me a set of new documents.
Yes, I remember.
[speaking Polish]
As far as the family's concerned, he says
"What is this Gene? I mean, he's always been Witek to us,
and he's Witek, and he remains Witek,
which is from Witold, which is obviously my name,
Witold Bardach.
We've been good friends ever since.
[Gutowski] I started me a new life
as Eugeniusz Gutowski,
courtesy of the Polish underground.
A common way for people to,
uh, change identities and...
...get out of the city would be to join a labor organization,
German labor organization working for the...
...uh, German armies everywhere was Organization Todt.
Riga became available.
There was a company, Polish company called Metzger,
and I signed with them
in my new capacity as a bookkeeper.
I mean I've never kept books,
I know nothing about the accounting.
The train was...
...blown up by the partisans...
...before it got to Riga,
but apparently it was sort of a daily occurrence,
nobody was particularly hurt,
they had to put a locomotive back on the track
and we continued to go to Latvia.
[ambient music ♪]
In charge were two Polish gentlemen...
...who greeted me warmly and said...
..."I'm so happy you came here
because we must go to Warsaw
to consult with the main office,
but we'll be gone only two, three days, we'll be back.
Would you please, in the meantime...
...look after everything for us?"
I said, "Sure."
Except that they've gone and they never came back.
The German supervisors came
and said, "Where are they?"
"I don't know. They've gone to..."
"And you?" "I'm the bookkeeper."
"Okay, you're the boss now."
So, suddenly I find myself
as a head of a construction company
of about a hundred guys
who were totally unwilling to work.
I became somewhat of a local...
...celebrity...
because with Christmas coming, we had a big Christmas tree
but absolutely no means of decorating,
and I had an idea
and they have got boxes of, uh,
German army condoms...
...which were issued to the soldiers.
I blew them up
to make balloons out of them
and painted figures of saints,
Santa Claus, you know, these things on the...
...blown up condoms,
and strung up and made a condom tree--
Christmas tree.
It was a big success.
Ah, the German officers, you know,
used to come from all over Riga
to look at it, congratulate me,
and so, you know, I was getting...
...extra rations of booze, cigarettes, and so on.
[Film Narrator] After advancing as far as Riga,
the Russians were temporarily
forced back a short distance
during the second week of August.
It is this short-lived success,
which the Germans are here exploiting.
Tanks and motorized units
cut through the Russian barrage in front of Riga
and a large number of Stukas
re-establish land communications
with combat divisions in Latvia.
[Gutowski] This was Germany on the verge of defeat.
These were very dangerous days because...
...they were on site executing deserters,
executing people left and right,
so one really had to be careful not to be,
uh, shot.
With the advances of Soviet army,
uh, the Germans were running away from Latvia
and they were...
...loading up on ships
to make the perilous crossing of the Baltic
to the German harbor.
I have decided I didn't wish
to be liberated by the Russians again.
I've had the pleasure once before,
and I said, "Thank you, I'll pass."
I managed to persuade the transport officers that...
...me and my company were essential to the German victory
and that we have to be loaded on the ship
to continue our...
...essential work for the further glory of the Nazis.
Some bribes got me
onto one of the ships, and the convoys
were then crossing the Baltic,
losing most of the convoy
to the Russian submarines.
I remember staying on a deck of the ship,
wrapped in a life jacket
I stole off a sleeping German soldier.
Rather he drowns than me.
Quite spectacular in the night
to see them exploding and going down.
Put us in trains
and moved us all the way from the Baltic
being strafed by American and British planes,
right across Germany into Austria.
I didn't like that journey because you know, so,
what a silly way...
...to get killed at the end of a war
by your own planes.
And thus...
...I found myself...
...in a little town in Austria
aptly called Judenburg.
I had to work in the woods,
cutting trees
and carrying the logs
onto the trucks.
Then suddenly, it was all over.
The guards ran away.
The Soviets were approaching,
so I took
all my earthly possessions,
uh, which were very, very few,
but one of them was my,
uh, lovely...
...Gary Cooper double-breasted suit,
which I was carrying with me
just for the occasion of liberation
so I can dress up very nicely
and join the free world again looking like something.
It was an extraordinary journey because...
...there were masses of humanity...
...on the road, day and night,
running away from the Russians.
I can't even tell you the mixture.
There were former enemies,
there was the SS,
there was escaped prisoner of war,
there were concentration camp inmates,
there were Jews, Poles,
uh, Italians,
Romanian Air Force,
I mean, the whole mixture of people
who became subjugated
by the Germans or the Nazis
or collaborated with them,
now escaping jointly, saying, "Okay,
we'll settle our differences later.
Now, let's get out of harm's way now."
Nearing the River Enns...
...I put my rucksack on the little...
...horse-drawn wagon of some Hungarians who had it,
and I went forward on foot.
People from the back started yelling
that the Russian tanks were coming
and true enough looking back, I could see,
from a distance, the dust clouds
of the Russian tanks were making on the road.
I said, "Well,
I'm just now going to wait for them."
I could see, crossing the bridge,
that they were American tanks
and American military vehicles
on the other side.
I ran across the bridge,
just about collapsed at the feet of a--
of an American soldier.
He helped me, and I said in perfect English, you know,
"Thank you very much," you know, sort of, "thank you."
He was absolutely amazed that he found such a nice boy
who spoke English
and, uh,
went in to his vehicle, got me a first taste of whiskey,
and that was that.
German army units, with their officers,
with their vehicles, that came across,
ready to go into prisoner of war camps,
this being the first moment,
so the American officers, and MPs, and Jeeps
were herding them like shepherds.
In fact was a total chaos.
This obviously was a front unit,
there was a colonel and other American officers
and there were German officers
who were reporting to them and asking for instructions.
They starting translating.
They were high ranking German officers, I think,
there was even a General
asking me to please tell the American officer
this and this, and this one would tell him that,
and I said, "Well, that's the place to be."
I looked at myself and I looked absolutely awful.
I looked around, nowhere could I find
my Hungarian cart with my suit,
in this dirty old Organization Todt uniform,
which looked suspiciously like an army uniform
and I figured out, the quicker I get out of it
the better
because somebody's going to stick me into the wrong,
you know, compartment here
and I'll find myself in a German camp.
I went into town,
looking how I could get myself
something to wear.
Walking the street I saw Men's Tailor,
Herrenschneiderei.
Knock, knock.
Finally somebody opened, they said,
"Look, there's nothing, absolutely nothing.
There's no clothes, no suits, zero",
and tried to close it in front of my face
at which point I produced my P38.
He opened it, realized I was not going to shoot him
and in perfect German, I said, "Look, I just need a suit."
"I don't have any more. Well let's see what I have."
Took me down to his, uh, workplace
and indeed there were a lot of...
...mostly uniforms, which were not collected,
never will be, you know of various Nazi officials
and a few private suits sort of finished were hanging there.
I found one, which...
...just about fitted me, I was pretty skinny in those days.
Maybe it was not my Gary Cooper suit,
but I certainly looked different
that what I did when I arrived.
I, uh, went back looking for my...
...American officers
and they suggested
that I should go further north
where there were headquarters
of the Counter Intelligence Corps,
uh, for the 20th Corps,
who they were sure could use my services
as an interpreter.
That'll be 35 Russian,
12 Belgians,
three French,
and three Yugoslavs.
How many of those are women?
28 Russian women...
...and 11 Belgian boys with a priest.
Yes sir, we'll be ready for them.
There were very few linguists
really in the CIC, unfortunately.
I was very welcome.
So, at the end of the day,
I was safely,
in a clean bed
as part of an American unit.
So, it was...
...a very long day, but in a way a very happy day,
so that was the end of the war for me.
[quiet dramatic music ♪]
The first few days after the war was extraordinary.
The bridges on the autobahn were blown up.
The remnants of war material was still on the road,
there were shot up tanks
and a lot of German planes
were using the autobahns as landing and starting places
were pushed and parked still on both sides of the...
...of the autobahns.
Having lost my entire family,
I enjoyed seeing a defeated Germany...
...and they were truly defeated.
There was chaos, there was no food,
there was millions of...
...refugees milling about, not only Germans,
but also the other nationalities of which...
...the Germans had brought into Germany as forced labor.
There were inmates of concentration camps,
every nationality had to be dealt with.
Allied forces determined that
anybody who has held certain rank,
above a certain level,
in any party or...
...military or paramilitary, or SS, Gestapo organization
was to be automatically arrested,
thrown into an internment camp,
later to be dealt with.
We had more than our hands full,
uh, just simply arresting people.
Very shortly, I was officially pronounced
as an acting agent...
...in the Counter-Intelligence Corps.
I was given the privilege of wearing an officer's uniform
with the insignia
and save for the fact
that I was not an American citizen,
had the same duties and responsibilities
and the privileges of other American agents.
Our powers were absolutely unlimited at the time.
I would go to the office and pick up my days work,
and by myself with a big .45 pistol,
which was very, uh, persuasive
because it was very large, and a pair of handcuffs.
I would take off and, uh, arrest people,
give them, very politely,
give them three minutes to pack up their things,
say goodbye to their families,
which was more than they used to give me in my day,
then back them into a Jeep
and bring them to the prison in Starnberg.
At one time I actually lost my temper.
Otherwise, I tried to be very level-headed,
behave uh, properly...
...wouldn't touch anybody, wouldn't push, wouldn't shove,
wouldn't, uh,
beat anybody up,
except for a couple of suspected Werwolves,
which were young Nazis,
they were trained
to eventually sabotage the Americans.
I remember then when we captured a few,
we gave them a good beating...
...but they deserved it.
On this particular occasion, a-
a German general walked in
with all his decorations and medals.
I was sitting alone
and he wanted to know if there was an officer around
because he wanted to give himself up.
I very politely said, "Well,
I'll take you in, you know...
...it's my pleasure."
Uh, no, no, no.
He-he-he could only turn himself to somebody of-
of an officers rank, and who was I?
I mean obviously, he was looking at me with such contempt...
...and then something snapped in me...
...and I tore his epaulettes off
and I tore his medals off,
so much for giving himself up to a...
...uh, to somebody of an equal or an officer's rank
because he, as a general he couldn't be arrested
by plain Polish or even Polish-Jewish refugee.
[speaking Polish]
I was doing my job well,
but I also learned of privilege.
First living in this baronial castle
on the lakeshore of Starnberg
with a beautiful estate with it's own boathouse
and which we had a motorboat and a sailboat.
There was six of us drawing rations and food
for about 145 people
with plenty of drinks with plenty of servants and so on.
I quickly learned that I could commandeer any car I wanted
because they were requisitioned from the Germans
and standing in the garages
where anybody, particularly from CIC, can come
and pick anything they want.
Well, was I ever picking.
Our excuse was
that we needed those cars for undercover work.
I mean, give me a break,
I had a big supercharged Horch,
a Mercedes, even a Maybach
for undercover work.
I quickly became...
...the entertainment director for the unit.
Using my connections we were giving weekend parties.
We became very famous for the party-giving.
I was in charge of the talent.
Jugglers, dancers,
all kinds of little nightclub acts,
so we could give those wonderful parties
on Saturday night,
and this is how I met my future wife, Zillah,
who was an American, and she came to Europe
with the Allied Control Council.
Somebody brought her as a date to her party.
So we met, romanced, fell in love,
and eventually travelled all over Germany,
together on weekends,
in any one of my cars.
Zillah and I decided to get married.
At this point, I was in full denial
so I was thinking there's going to be a big church wedding
in St. Lucas Cathedral,
and I was paying everybody with cartons of cigarettes
because that was the established currency.
It took I don't know how many cartons of cigarettes
to get the singers from the Munich opera.
It was a good wedding, and a big party after.
[quiet dramatic music ♪]
The national visas
are granted based on the country of birth.
Most surviving concentration camp inmates
and the survivors,
most of them were born in Poland.
All the Jewish immigrants going to America
were going on a Polish what's called a quota.
They passed a new law
in the State Department...
...and they decided to divide the Polish quota 50/50
to give the non-Jews a break.
Okay?
So when I learned about it,
obviously Zillah told me about it,
and I was then qualified as a bonafide non-Jew...
...I jumped at the opportunity.
Uh, it was a priest,
who, writing on his knee,
issued me with an affidavit of support
on the basis of which I got my visa.
To add to my complicated life story,
I entered America...
...on a corporate visa, on an affidavit visa,
by the Catholic Refugee Organization.
[accordion music ♪]
We left in 1947.
First went to Paris for a few days with Zillah,
had a wonderful time with her,
went clubbing, went to restaurants,
bought her a beautiful hat with flowers,
she always wanted to have a French hat...
...and went on the SS America
to the United States.
[waves splashing]
It was as a rough passage, in fact,
and uh, oh my God, there were a group of nuns
sitting on the deck, refusing to go down
and only continuously getting sick
all over the place, so...
...as I say I always have this vision of vomiting nuns.
There was a very handsome...
...Irish...
...dark-haired Irishman,
who just went to Europe to visit a family
after the war in Ireland.
He got off the boat before I did,
so by the time I came down the plank,
he was already standing at the pier
with open arms, yelling,
"Welcome to America! Welcome to America!"
Passing the Statue of Liberty that day
obviously I was very excited.
It was a new land,
a new experience,
a new chapter in my life...
...and it was just lovely. It was wonderful.
I didn't know what to expect, I was hoping for the best,
that the best, only the best will happen for me now.
[traditional Polish song ♪]