Good evening, Mrs Craig.
Let me help you with that.
- I can make it.
My pleasure, Mrs Craig.
You're welcome.
Glad to be of any assistance.
Apples.
Oh yes.
Good.
You know the old saying:
An apple a day keeps the doctor away.
What do you use to keep policemen away?
[ Radio music ]
Eight points.
"Ladies and gentlemen.
This is station WNAC."
"When you hear the gong .."
"The time will be exactly ten
seconds to seven o'clock."
"The Battle of Brains is on the air.
Good evening, ladies and gentlemen."
"This is Don Wilson."
"Tonight, Tom Taylor Cigars bring
you that popular quiz contest."
"The Battle of Brains."
As you know, each week we try to get you
the most interesting and capable teams.
To compete in this spontaneous
and unrehearsed contest.
This evening, all the questions I ask
will be regarding crimes and criminals.
And I'm extremely proud to announce ..
A real battle is in the offing.
For our contestants will be
famous city police detectives ..
Versus celebrated
detective fiction writers.
First, allow me to introduce the
captains of the respective teams.
For the detectives.
Inspector Joseph Clinton.
And for the detective fiction writers ..
Mr Barry Craig.
What a ham.
Incidentally, Mr Craig has quite a
reputation as an amateur detective.
And by the way, Mr Craig.
You know Inspector Clinton, don't you?
Yes. On several occasions when I've been
engaged in a little amateur sleuthing ..
I've bumped into the inspector.
Then you're old rivals, eh?
Quite the contrary.
On the several occasions Mr Craig has
bumped into me as he so aptly puts it ..
I have found him to be an
exceptional and capable detective ..
Fiction writer.
Are the judges ready?
Alright, Inspector.
It's your first question.
What is a panopticon?
A panopticon is a circular prison ..
In which the cells and their occupants
are visible from a central tower.
Correct, Inspector.
Now Mr Craig. Your first question.
What prison has an Indian
name meaning 'Stony Place'?
Would you mind repeating
that question please?
"What prison has an Indian
name meaning 'Stony Place'?"
Sing Sing.
Sing Sing, you dope.
"No coaching please."
Sing Sing.
"Sing Sing."
"Correct."
I don't know what you'd do without me.
Now, detective Gatling.
Here is your question.
Mr Gatling, who invented
the machine gun?
Who invented the machine gun?
Why, that was ..
I know that as well as
I know my own name.
That ..
Would you mind repeating
the question please?
Who invented the machine gun?
Mr Gatling.
I know who that is as well
as I know my own name.
Who invented the machine gun?
- Yes, Mr Gatling.
Why, that was ..
Sorry, detective Gatling. Time is up.
That eliminates you.
Who invented the machine gun? I know
that as well as I know my own name.
What is your own name?
Gatling.
That's right, Mr Gatling. The machine
gun was invented by another Gatling.
But you are too late.
"Now, our next contestant."
"Author of a hundred mystery novels,
Rufus Scott, needs no introduction."
Jane.
- Julie.
You nearly scared me out of my skin.
- Where's Barry?
What's the matter, darling?
- I must see Barry now. Where is he?
He is on the radio. It's a quiz contest.
- When will he be home?
When the program is over.
What's the matter?
You look like you've seen a ghost.
- Where's the matte?
Someone was going to commit murder
in the darkroom. Chloroform.
He flashed a light in my face.
- Wait a minute.
Sit down and get your breath.
You're a little hysterical.
I'll get you some sherry.
I don't want any sherry.
I suppose it will take
Barry ages to get home?
Forget Barry for a minute. Take it easy.
Here. It's good for what ails you.
Now look. Will you stop the
double talk and speak slowly ..
And say what happened.
Nothing has happened yet.
That is, nothing serious.
But there's going to be a
murder unless we stop it.
Who is going to murder who?
- I don't know, Jane. I don't know.
But whoever was with me in that darkroom
this afternoon was there to kill.
He had a handkerchief in his
hand reeking of chloroform.
Then he put a flashlight in
my face and I screamed.
Then all of a sudden I heard the
door to the darkroom open and close.
Evidently whoever was there
was after someone else ..
Because when he put
the light in my face, I ..
Now wait a minute. Come on
over and sit down. Try to relax.
Sorry to prattle on like an idiot.
But you are excited, sure. Look Julie.
You talk about all this happening in a
darkroom. What do you mean 'darkroom'?
I am sorry. I thought you knew.
For the past 3 months I've been working
for the McCormick Photography Studio.
Oh, I see. And by 'darkroom'
you mean a developing room.
That is right.
- Have you quit the theater?
I'm afraid the theater quit me.
So, I took a job posing
for the McCormick studio.
I sort-of worked myself in until I am
now chief cook and bottle washer.
I see. Now we have all that clear
suppose you start at the beginning.
Well, Mack ..
That is Mr McCormick, has been having
rather a rough time of it lately.
As a matter of fact.
Kirk Fenley, the photographer, and
didn't even get paid last week.
And then came our big break.
Yesterday, the Cottrell Silver Company
said they would give us a terrific deal.
If we could get Mrs Isabel Fleming
to endorse their product.
You mean the Isabel Fleming?
- Yes.
The wealthy society lady?
Yes.
How can you hope to get a snooty old gal
like her to pose for an advertisement?
Well, her niece Erika
McCormick is the boss's wife.
Oh.
Did you swing the deal?
We took the photograph an hour ago.
Everything went like clockwork.
And after that I went into the darkroom.
And then is when it happened.
I thought, first I'd tell Mack and then
I decided I'd better get Barry's advice.
So I sneaked away and came over here.
[ Telephone ]
Excuse me.
Hello?
Oh. Just a minute.
It's for you.
Hello?
Yes.
What was wrong?
Don't you know?
Yes. I'll be there.
Goodbye.
- What's the matter?
We have to take the picture
over again tonight.
The negatives are missing.
We can't find them anywhere.
Isn't that a rather odd thing to happen?
Jane, I am scared.
Do you see? Someone took the negatives
so we would have to retake the picture.
So we would all have to come back there.
Whoever it is wants another chance.
Maybe tonight he will ..
Won't bungle.
Chilly, isn't it.
If Barry were only here.
Who was that on the phone?
Mack. Mr McCormick. The boss.
But how did he know you were here?
I left word with Pop the elevator man
to call me here if anyone wanted me.
What are you going to do?
- I don't know. I must get back.
Listen. If I were you I'd
tell Mack immediately.
What's the matter?
Are you afraid that he
might be the one who ..
Of course not.
I'll tell him.
Then you'd better tell the others too.
As soon as Barry gets
home I'll rush him over.
Thanks.
"That only leaves Inspector
Clinton for the detectives."
"And Mr Craig for the
detective fiction writers."
"Now we have the jackpot question."
In a moment the attendant will hold
in front of you gentlemen ten objects.
You will have only ten seconds to look
at them and memorise as many as you can.
They will then be taken away and you'll
have five seconds to name each article.
Alright, Miss.
Now ..
Mr Craig, if you step over here
to this microphone please.
And Inspector, if you
would come up on my left.
Alright, gentlemen. Are you ready?
Alright. Here we are.
One second.
Two seconds.
Three.
Four.
Five.
Six.
Seven.
Eight.
Nine.
Ten.
Alright. Take it away.
Alright, Mr Craig.
It's your first guess.
A pair of handcuffs.
- One.
A ring.
- Two.
A revolver.
- Three.
A cartridge clip.
Four.
A knife.
- Five.
A silver dollar.
Six.
A flashlight.
Seven.
A watch.
Splendid. That's eight.
Alright, Mr Craig.
Come on Barry. Come on, Barry.
A key.
Excellent.
And now, Inspector.
The last one.
I'm sorry, Inspector.
But your time is up.
As so often happens, Inspector.
You overlooked the obvious.
Let him have four of my five seconds.
That's a very sporting gesture.
Alright, Inspector. Go ahead.
If you are so smart, what is it?
The great big beautiful tray that the
other nine objects were resting upon.
Correct.
And that's the guy who can't
remember to mail a letter.
And now for the final score for the
losing detective team: 200 points.
And for the winning detective
fiction writers team:
210 points.
And now ladies and gentlemen, the
Tom Taylor Cigar program is happy ..
To present to the captain of the winning
detective fiction writers team ..
This beautiful 21-jewel wristwatch.
Thank you.
And to the less observant
captain of the losing team.
The Sherlock Holmes magnifying glass.
Hiya, princess.
What's the matter with the lights?
On the blink again?
Jane.
Hey, Jane.
It's nearly three o'clock.
Could she have left me?
I haven't done anything wrong in days.
Wait a minute. When was it I squawked
about the Yanks? No, that wasn't it.
If she's upstairs playing
gin rummy again ..
Jane.
Oh, sweetheart.
What's the matter? What happened?
How did it happen? Did you fall?
Are you hurt, sweetheart?
Why, it's Mrs Swanson.
Thank heavens it's you, Mrs Swanson.
I felt sure it was my wife.
Lie down. You'll be alright.
I'll get you some water.
Easy does it now. You are alright.
There you are.
Oh, Mr Craig.
Alright. What happened? You fell down?
- No, sir.
He struck me.
- He did?
Who did?
I don't know. I never did
get a good look at him.
Is Mrs Craig alright?
- Yes. Of course.
I mean I don't know. I searched
around but I can't find her.
I do hope nothing happened.
You can say that again.
What was this man doing?
He was listening at the door and your
wife was talking to another woman.
I could just hear their voices.
What time was this?
- Let me see.
I finished scrubbing the
upper floor at 7 o'clock.
I came down here to put away my mop
and my bucket and look at the furnace.
Always, Mr Weaver has me tend
the furnace before I go to bed ..
Alright. But what happened?
As I came down the back stairs
I saw this man. His back was to me.
He was listening at your door and
I called out. I don't know why I did.
I guess I thought I could frighten him.
He turned to run down the hall.
I made a grab for him and he struck me.
You didn't recognise the voice of
the woman talking to my wife?
Did you?
- No, sir.
Here, take a little drink of this.
Listening to my wife.
Now, why would anybody
want to listen to my wife?
I wonder what she's got
herself mixed up in now.
Bad news?
- I hope not.
You'll find an ice-bag in the
bathroom, Mrs Swanson.
You'd better put some cold
applications on that head.
Help yourself to anything
you want, Mrs Swanson.
Just make yourself at home.
[ Female scream! ]
What's the matter, lady?
I'm sorry. I ..
I? I what?
For a minute I thought it was real.
Well, that's just splendid.
Too bad you aren't the advertiser.
I'm sorry.
Say, who told you to barge
in like this anyway?
I was looking for Miss Julie Taylor.
She's in Studio 2. Second floor.
Close that door when you go out.
We have work to do here.
Excuse me.
Julie.
Jane.
I was just going to telephone you.
What about? What is wrong?
- Nothing. Nothing is wrong.
As a matter of fact, I was going to
tell you not to bother to come over.
Everything is going smoothly.
We're all set to take the picture.
I don't get it. Didn't you tell Mack and
the others what happened this afternoon?
No.
No, I didn't.
- Why not?
Well.
Because I came to the
conclusion that I ..
I was just imagining things.
You mean, you imagined
someone trying to grab you?
You imagined you smelled chloroform?
It could have been
someone playing a joke.
A joke?
Besides, this picture means
everything to the boss.
If it doesn't turn out, he's finished.
He is through.
If Mrs Fleming and the others find out
there's no telling what will happen.
They might walk out on her before
he gets the picture and then ..
Mack would ..
- I see.
You're in love with Mack, aren't you?
Mack is married.
That doesn't answer my question.
No.
No. I'm not in love with him.
Does that answer your question?
Well. It's an answer.
He's a grand guy, Jane.
If you met him you'd understand.
- Why don't you introduce me to him?
I'm sorry. I didn't mean to be rude.
Of course I'll introduce you to him.
I want you to meet all of them. Kirk can
do it too. I've told them all about you.
Jane.
You won't say anything?
- Of course not.
What about Barry?
I left a note for him to come here.
Don't worry. I'll get to him
first and explain everything.
You're an angel.
- Well, thanks.
You'd better open the door a little
wider and let my wings through.
Excuse me.
That's alright.
[ Whistle ]
That's it. Hold it.
Now, move the candelabra
a little more to the right.
A little more.
Just a little more.
Hey, boys.
Boys, I want you to meet Jane Craig.
You've heard me speak of her
and here she is in person.
She really is cute.
Mrs Jane Craig, Mr Fenley.
This is Kirk.
- How do you do.
This is Harry Duerr,
the assistant genius.
Kirk, let go of her hand.
Oh.
How do you do.
- Yeah.
Mack. I want you to meet
my pal, Jane Craig.
Hello.
Mack.
- Huh?
Oh, I am sorry.
This is Jane Craig - Mr McCormick.
Mr McCormick and I have met before.
- Really?
You have?
Yes. I ran into him downstairs.
He told me how to find you.
Oh, yes. I remember.
Sorry if I was rude.
That's alright. I had no
business barging in like that.
That's okay. Everything set, boys?
All set.
Better round up the people, Julie.
- Yes, Mack.
Look, if you'll stand right over here
you can see exactly how it's done.
I'll only be a minute.
Miss Lawrence.
- Coming.
Whenever you're ready, Mrs Fleming.
I'll be right there.
Alright, folks. On the set please.
- Okay.
You owe me a dollar and a half.
- I know. I know.
What time is it anyway?
- Nine o'clock. Right on the dot.
Don't say this thing comes off on time.
- I hope so. I've got a date.
Alright, folks. Take the same positions
at the table you had this afternoon.
Miss Lawrence, you sit here please.
Careful of the silverware, folks.
It has all been counted.
Joke.
- The joke is over.
How does it look, Kirk?
Terrific. Will you quit worrying?
I'm not worrying.
We're all set. Bring on Madam Queen.
Alright, I will get her.
Miss Ralston, as we do the take, can you
look at the silver and not the camera?
This picture is for Cottrell Silverware,
not your Hollywood agent.
Now look, Mr Fenley. If you don't like
my work you can get someone else.
Now, now, Miss Ralston.
He didn't mean any harm.
Just kidding.
Well, I don't like the way he kids.
I was just coming for you.
- Evening, Ralph.
Good evening, aunt Isabel.
I hate dragging you out on a
miserable night like this, but ..
I promised to deliver the
photograph in the morning.
Don't be absurd. I like rainy weather.
I always did.
My husband used to say I
was a regular mud hen.
You know, I cannot imagine what
happened to those negatives.
Ralph.
Yes. What is it?
That woman in the far corner.
She wasn't here this afternoon.
No, no.
We couldn't locate the model who posed
this afternoon so we've a substitute.
Well, I'm sorry. But she won't do.
Won't do?
I don't understand.
I mean I will not be
photographed with her.
I don't like her.
But aunt Isabel ..
- Let's not argue.
Get someone else.
I'll be in my dressing room.
Folks, everyone go out and have a smoke.
We're having a little technical trouble.
Technical trouble?
What are you talking about?
I said 'technical trouble'.
Oh.
Miss Lawrence.
The model who posed this
afternoon just arrived.
I think she's a little
more suitable so ..
I'm afraid we won't need you.
I'll send you your check in the morning.
Yes, Mr McCormick.
I understand perfectly.
What's this all about?
- Mrs Fleming objected to her.
Why?
- She didn't say why.
What do you know?
- Julie.
Get changed quick.
You'll take her place.
We haven't time to get another model.
- Alright.
Mind if I tag along, Julie?
- No. Come on.
Didn't she give any reason at all, Mack?
- No.
[ Crying noises ]
That reminds me.
I must write Barry's uncle.
Boy.
Whoever tore up these negatives
certainly, did a good job.
Why would anyone do it?
- I don't know.
How did you happen to find them, Harry?
- Well, I ..
Threw an envelope in the basket
when I worked in here today.
And I suddenly remembered
there was an address on it.
So I came in here to get it and ..
There you are.
- Where is the envelope?
I ..
It's right here.
Wasn't it underneath the negatives?
Underneath?
Why, no.
I didn't pay particular attention.
I think it was to one side.
You got a pretty tight
story anyway, Harry.
Wait a minute, Kirk. If you're
insinuating I tore those negatives ..
Why, Harry. Nobody is
accusing you of anything.
Why did he say he's not accusing me?
I'm sorry. I'm just a bit jittery today.
Things have been so upset.
Come on, boys.
Let's get back to the set.
Good evening.
Decidedly. Assuming one is a duck.
I'm looking for my wife.
Rather an unusual night to play
hide-and-go-seek, isn't it?
I was going to meet my wife here
at the McCormick studios, but ..
This place seems to
be practically deserted.
Maybe she's on the second floor.
That's where they're taking the photos.
I beg your pardon but if you
are still looking for your wife ..
Gee, is this as fast as this thing goes?
Yep. Got it wide open.
She don't go up like no rocket but
she don't fall down like one either.
How long have you been
running an elevator, skipper?
Well, now let me see.
I got out of the
Spanish-American war in '99.
I was a bartender for ten
years but had to give it up.
My liver went bad on me.
Let me see. That was '08.
The same year I lost my teeth.
Yep. I remember exactly because
I got my plates in 1911.
In '14 I got married.
I didn't work for four years.
Let me see now. My wife left me
in '18 so I went back to work.
So I have been here 23 years.
Excepting 3 weeks back in '33 when
they repealed the 18th amendment.
So you tried bartending again, huh?
Nope. Celebrating.
Now my gallbladder is no good.
Let me see. That makes
23 years minus 3 weeks.
That's 22 years, 11 months and
one week I've run this elevator.
This has all been very interesting.
Now, will you please open the door?
Say, this is the second floor?
Nope. The third. The second
floor is the next one down.
Going down to the second floor?
- Of course. Certainly.
Alright.
Second floor it is.
By the way, skipper.
You said you lost your teeth one year.
And you didn't get your
plates until 3 years later.
That's correct.
- What held you up so long?
Now that's a long story.
For goodness sakes.
We'll end up in the basement.
Nope. You'll end up back on the third
floor. It takes a round trip to tell it.
Are we here already?
It does a little better downhill.
Hello, princess.
- Hello.
Hi, Barry. Be with you in a minute.
Tell Mrs Fleming her secretary
is here to drive her home.
Yes. Certainly.
What's it all about, princess?
Well, if you're through
looking at the scenery.
Sit down and I'll tell you.
[ Female scream! ]
Julie.
- Julie, what happened?
What's happened to her?
She saw that.
Shut the door, Jane.
Inspector.
- Yes?
I'm Ralph McCormick.
- How do you do.
Not so good.
It happened on the second floor and I
felt it best to keep everyone up there.
Mr McCormick.
- Yes?
Was it you who phoned headquarters?
- That's right.
Going up.
The report said Mrs Isabel Fleming.
That's right.
Say, old-timer. Can't we
make a little more speed?
Not unless you want to take the stairs.
That is an idea. Drop her down.
This thing will shake your teeth out.
Not mine. I keep them
buttoned up in my pocket.
Step down please.
So I fell down.
Ride with the old boy in the
elevator and see what he knows.
It's down the hall, Inspector.
Step up please.
Alright. Let's go.
Now, old-timer. I want to
ask you a few questions.
Fire away.
What's your name?
Edward E. Philpot. What's yours?
- Gatling.
Hey, I'm asking the questions.
How long you worked here?
Well, let me see now.
I was mustered out of the
Spanish-American war in 1899.
Got a job right off bartending.
I hung on to it up until the
year after the panic in 1908.
The same year I lost my teeth.
Look. All I want to know is,
how long have you worked here?
Now you got me off the track.
Let me see now. As I was saying.
I got out of the Spanish-American
war in 1899.
Mr Kenyon, did you by any chance
see Miss Lawrence leave?
No I didn't.
You knew her personally, didn't you?
Only slightly.
What do you do, Mr Kenyon?
I'm a dancer in a nightclub.
Where's this nightclub?
Just off Sheridan Square.
The Club Cupid.
Oh sure. I know that place well.
That is, I've walked by it a good
many times and saw the sign.
It's a dump.
But I won't be there always.
- Where do you live?
322 Bank Street.
That is ..
The same building Mr Snyder lives in.
Yeah.
We live in the same apartment.
Yeah. That's right.
Right this way, Inspector.
Good evening, Inspector.
- Evening.
The body is in dressing room Number 2.
Number 2, huh?
What are you doing here?
Just moseying around.
Asking questions, taking notes.
I have written them down. If you're
interested you might save repetition.
And by the way, I'd like you to
meet my wife - Inspector Clinton.
How do you do, Inspector?
You made good time getting
over here, Inspector.
It only took you fifteen minutes.
Why Barry, isn't that a new watch?
Yes. The Inspector made
me a present of it.
Oh Inspector. How sweet.
Do you mind telling me how
you happen to be here?
I just .. happened to drop
in to pick up my wife.
I see. And she just happened to be here?
No. You see, I ..
Yes.
You see, I happened to
drop in to see a friend.
Miss Taylor.
Who happens to work here.
And then the murder happened?
You don't happen to know who did it?
Unfortunately, no.
You've done a very thorough job here.
- Thank you.
You don't mind if I look
at the body, do you?
Not at all. Go right ahead.
- Thanks.
What have you found out, Doc?
The jugular vein was severed
with a sharp instrument.
Never knew what hit her.
What did you find, Temple?
- Only a handbag.
The money and jewels are still in it.
A pair of scissors.
Could it have been the scissors?
- No.
The wound is big enough to
have been made by a bayonet.
Mathews.
Am in your way?
No. I can see over your shoulder.
Mathews, have the men look around.
See if they can find the weapon.
There's a whole table full
of knives out in the studio.
You see, they were taking a
picture advertising Cottrell silver.
You can read all about it in my notes.
Here. Take your notes and ..
Go and sit down someplace.
Where's the studio?
I will show you.
If you need me just holler.
It took me about thirty minutes
to get here from the house.
Fifteen minutes in the car and
fifteen minutes in the elevator.
When I got here, naturally
I asked for Mrs Fleming.
Miss Taylor went to find her and ..
That's when they discovered it.
What's your name?
Roland X. Smith.
Roland.
Smith.
Please. 'X'.
The name is Roland X. Smith.
What is the X for?
To distinguish me from all
the other Roland Smiths.
Listen, baby. I want to ask
you a couple of questions.
Okay. Shoot.
Why did you come over
here in the first place?
Julie came to the apartment.
After you. She expected
something like this.
What's that? I didn't quite catch you.
Get over here on the other side of me.
I can talk better over here.
Don't act like a child, Barry. Come over
here and I'll tell you all about it.
Let me see now. I got out of the
Spanish-American war in '99.
I was a bartender for 10 years but I had
to give it up. My liver went bad on me.
Who sat here?
No-one sat there. You see, this end
of the table wasn't in the picture.
Oh.
Mrs Fleming sat at the head.
Who sat here on Mrs Fleming's right?
Miss Lawrence sat there originally.
- I see.
She's the woman Mrs Fleming objected to?
That's right.
Who took her place?
- Miss Taylor. My assistant.
Look at that table.
Isn't there a piece of cutlery missing?
Yes. The carving knife is gone.
Within the easy reach of
anyone who was seated there.
Yes. But anyone might have picked it up.
- Let me see that negative again.
This picture was taken while
Miss Taylor was seated here, wasn't it?
Yes.
Miss Taylor is my ..
It's absurd to think ..
No pictures were taken while
Miss Lawrence was here?
No.
Have another look.
The knife is missing from the picture.
Therefore, Miss Lawrence could have
been here when the knife disappeared.
Yes, I suppose she could have.
What do you know about this
Lawrence woman, Mr McCormick?
Practically nothing.
We used her on several occasions.
She always seemed to be a rather
mild, quiet, good-natured woman.
You have her address?
- Yes.
I suppose you have some photographs?
Yes. I think we have a model's
directory in the reception room.
Oh.
Let's take a look.
Julie.
Will you help us out please?
Get the Models Directory.
Yes.
How did you prevail on so prominent
a person as Mrs Fleming ..
To pose for you, Mr McCormick?
She was my wife's aunt.
Oh.
I may as well tell you that my wife is
the sole heir to the Fleming fortune.
Well, that doesn't necessarily
place you under suspicion.
You seem to have an
up-and-coming business here.
Haven't you?
- I'm on the verge of bankruptcy.
As a matter of fact I
probably will go broke now.
You see ..
Mrs Fleming's death is really
a terrible blow to me.
How is that?
Well.
I was very fond of her.
She was very fond of me.
In fact, she planned to
help me with my troubles.
We had a long chat when
she arrived tonight.
She promised to lend me thirty thousand
dollars to carry on my business.
Indeed?
Yes. That is true. I know it's true.
Mr McCormick would be stupid to do away
with the person who could save him.
Wouldn't he?
Did you hear Mrs Fleming promise
to lend him the money?
Well ..
Not exactly.
You see .. I ..
I told her.
Now I get it.
- Get what?
Why Julie changed her attitude.
You said that after begging you
to have us come over here ..
She treated you like a
stepchild when you arrived.
Yeah.
Don't you see?
Julie was afraid that it was Mack.
Who was going to commit the murder.
That's the new stuff they
use instead of nylon.
Is that so?
Then when she found out ..
That Mrs 'rich witch' was going
to lend him the money ..
She figured the necessity
for killing her was gone.
So she wanted us to forget
about the whole thing.
I think you have something there.
You know, that stuff looks nice.
Mrs McCormick.
- Erika.
Erika, if there's anything I can do ..
My deepest sympathy.
- Hello, dear.
I tried to get you at the apartment.
I was out to dinner.
I want you to meet Inspector Clinton.
Inspector, this is my wife.
- Mrs McCormick.
I'm sorry to meet you under
such unhappy circumstances.
Won't you take a seat?
I would like to ask you a few
questions when I can get to you.
Here it is, Inspector.
'Madge Lawrence'.
'Height 5 feet 9'.
'130 pounds. Eyes brown. Hair gray-ish'.
You have Miss Lawrence's address?
- Yes. I have it downstairs in my files.
Mind giving it to officer Temple?
- Not at all.
Better take a couple of men with you.
- Alright, Inspector.
From 1911 to '13 I went back
to my old job as bartender.
I had to quit. My liver again.
Mrs McCormick.
When was the last time
you saw your aunt?
I had lunch with her yesterday.
Did she give any indication at that
time that she feared for her life?
She has never at any time
expressed fears for her life.
Oh.
What's the matter?
I beg your pardon?
I said, what is the matter?
Nothing, sir.
I suppose that was just your
tonsils backfiring, huh?
Yes, sir.
I mean, no sir.
If you're asking my opinion.
Which you're not.
I think he got a little shock from ..
This picture.
Do you know Miss Lawrence?
- Miss Lawrence? No, sir.
Do you know this lady in the picture?
No, sir.
Then what startled you?
I don't know. I'm a bundle of nerves.
The whole thing is silly.
I'm just imagining things. That's all.
Imagining what? What is silly?
I felt I knew the woman in
the picture, but it can't be.
I've not seen her for ten years.
This woman looks younger than
she should after 10 years.
Who?
Mrs Fleming, of course.
Mrs Fleming?
If that's Mrs Fleming,
who's that in there?
The second Mrs Fleming.
And that is the first
Mrs Fleming, isn't it.
Yes.
Then you did recognise her?
I ..
I don't know.
Of course you do.
A person doesn't change
much in ten years.
Why, I bet you haven't yourself.
Well.
My hair is a little thinner.
Nonsense. I doubt you had more hair when
you worked for the first Mrs Fleming ..
Than you have now.
Really, I never worked
for the first Mrs Fleming.
You did know her, didn't you?
- Only by sight.
I saw her at the trial.
- Trial? What trial?
Now, wait a minute. I hate to interrupt
what seems to be a private conversation.
Inspector. Give me a few minutes and
I'll clear this whole thing up for you.
Quiet.
Inspector. We're only
trying to help you out.
I realize that and I'm
Matthews, open that door.
You mean ..?
- That's exactly what I mean.
Well.
If that's the way you feel about it.
We're only trying to be off assistance.
This thing was just beginning
to simplify itself nicely.
Inspector, you're nothing but a silly
self-centered, grumpy old man.
You spoke about a trial.
What trial was that?
Inspector.
Roland has been a loyal employee
of my aunt for many years and ..
Is obviously reluctant to
drag out family skeletons.
Perhaps I can tell you
what you want to know.
Good.
Is that the first Mrs Fleming?
I wouldn't know.
It happened when I was young and most
of it was kept from me for many years.
However, being curious I finally
got to the bottom of it all.
My uncle divorced the first
Mrs Fleming fifteen years ago.
A few months afterwards
he married aunt Isabel.
Later, he died and left his
entire estate to aunt Isabel.
With the exception of $500,000 which
he left to the first Mrs Fleming.
The trial which Roland
spoke of was about the will.
My aunt Isabel resented my uncle's
first wife so deeply that ..
She declared my uncle insane
in order to break the will.
Are you through questioning me already?
Already?
Not until I learn to write
with my left hand I am.
Hey you.
Wait a minute.
If it isn't machine-gun Gatling.
Lieutenant Gatling - my wife.
- How do you do.
What you doing around here?
- Nothing, Lieutenant.
We're just going home.
- Maybe you are and maybe you ain't.
Does the inspector know you're around?
Huh?
Yes. Of course. Certainly.
We just left him.
He told us to go on home.
He did, huh?
How long have you been around here?
Since before the murder, but ..
And the inspector told you to go home?
Before you go, he'll say
he told you to go home.
He'll say alright.
- Come on. We go upstairs.
The inspector won't
like you bringing us.
Don't tell me what he don't like.
I've been with him too long.
You're to stop the whispering too.
Sorry.
How long have you been
running this elevator, Pop?
Well, let me see now.
I got out of the Spanish-American
war in 1899 ..
Oh, no you don't.
We'll walk.
The Spanish-American war.
Come on.
Step down please.
Hey, chief.
Look who I found trying to
sneak out of the building.
Surprised, ain't you?
There ain't anybody sneaking out
on you while I'm around, boss.
[ Telephone ]
Now I'm hearing bells ringing.
McCormick Studios.
Yes. Just a moment.
It's for you, Inspector Clinton.
Huh?
Hello.
Yes, Temple?
Dead?
Are you sure?
Are you sure, Joe?
She's either dead or my watch stopped.
Positively.
It looks like she took an
overdose of sleeping tablets.
Yes, sir. The place is right around the
corner. You can get here in 5 minutes.
Hey, Charlie.
Look.
Hold on a second, Inspector.
I think Henderson has found something.
Yes, sir. We have found
that missing knife.
Good work, boys.
I'll be right over.
Madge Lawrence, the first Mrs Fleming,
murdered Isabel Fleming.
And then committed suicide.
Alright. Thank you all
for your cooperation.
You can all go home now.
[ Scream! ]
What is it? What now?
What's the matter?
- I left a pot roast in the oven.
There they go. Come on.
The case is closed.
Why go looking for chloroform
cans at this time of the morning?
Because usually the druggist's
name is on the label.
I want to find out who bought that can.
Give me a hand. It's slippery.
Help me up.
You stay there, princess.
Where it's safe.
You stink.
[ Scream! ]
Hello. Hello.
Wake up.
Police.
The McCormick Studios.
Darling. You alright?
- Who was it shooting?
I never asked.
Why did you scream?
I saw a ghost.
- Nonsense.
There's no such things as ghosts.
That's what I thought
until a minute ago.
Turn out the light.
Look.
- What's the matter?
It's back again.
- What's back again?
The ghost. Back again.
Where? I don't see it.
Over there.
- Where?
Come out of there.
Darling.
Are you alright?
Say something.
I got out of the
Spanish-American war in 1899 ..
It's only poor old Pop.
He probably thought we were thieves.
I got a job bartending ..
[ Police siren ]
The police.
- Yeah. I called them.
We'd better get out of here before we're
arrested for breaking and entering.
Get away from me! Don't you touch me!
Lay a hand on me and I'll kill you.
Good morning.
- Morning.
Thank you.
Bill. Bad.
Bill.
Mail. Anything for me?
- They are all for you.
How wonderful.
Make sure to get the paper.
I got it.
Barry, will you put the
garbage out in the hall.
I was just going to.
You don't have to watch me, baby.
Oh boy. Oh boy. Oh boy.
Jane. I'll be back in a little while.
I'm going down to police headquarters.
Wait a minute.
I can't wait.
I must go right away.
What's the idea? You're not going
there without me. I want to go too.
Now, princess. What do you
want to do, stop traffic?
Now, Jane. You know you can't go out
in the cold right after a hot shower.
I won't be gone long.
All I want to do is ..
Gee, you smell good.
So soft and warm.
Hey, what am I doing? I have to hurry.
I have to.
Do you, darling?
It's murder.
Maybe that will change your mind.
I found that in the back hallway.
Just outside the door of my apartment.
The man listening to
Miss Taylor and my wife ..
Likely dropped it fighting
the housekeeper.
So?
So that proves the eavesdropper
was from the McCormick Studio.
How?
Good heavens, man. It has got
'Prop Room' marked right there on it.
Obviously it's the key to the prop
room of the McCormick Studios.
Does it say McCormick
Studios on the tag?
No.
There are hundreds of
property rooms, Mr Craig.
Every theater has a property room.
Every furniture store
has a property room.
'Prop room' is quite a common term.
But it all ties up.
Madge Lawrence, or the first
Mrs Fleming as you call her ..
Was not engaged until evening.
Someone tried to chloroform
Julie Taylor in the afternoon.
That same someone followed
her to our apartment.
When she called on my wife.
Furthermore, it was a man.
Not a woman.
Mrs Swanson glimpsed him
before he knocked her down.
Then the first Mrs Fleming couldn't have
murdered the second Mrs Fleming, huh?
That's right.
Then why was the knife that
killed the second Mrs Fleming ..
Found in the first
Mrs Fleming's apartment?
Planted.
- Planted?
That's ridiculous.
Nobody left the McCormick Studios.
And yet you say somebody planted that
knife in the Lawrence woman's apartment.
I've got it.
Whoever killed Isabel Fleming ..
Put the knife in the first Mrs Fleming's
suitcase before she left the studio.
Probably, she never knew she had it.
How did the murderer get her to take
an overdose of sleeping tablets?
Coaxed her over the telephone?
Maybe the overdose was an accident.
You yourself said she was in the
habit of taking sleeping tablets.
Yes. And I found out she had a motive.
And I found out she had the knife.
And I found out everybody
else has an alibi.
And I begin to find out that
you're getting to be a pest.
If you pardon me I have some work to do.
- Then you won't reopen the case?
Not on the strength of the
puny evidence you brought up.
Alright, Inspector.
But I'm going to find out
who killed Isabel Fleming.
I'll bet you 5-2 it wasn't
Madge Lawrence.
When you find out Mr Craig, will you let
us know so we can arrest them please?
Will you answer me just one question?
We aim to please.
Did you check to see if the Lawrence
woman's fingerprints were on that knife?
Okay.
Imagine that cluck.
Of course you checked if the Lawrence
dame's fingerprints were on the knife.
Didn't you, chief?
Sure. I knew you did.
And her fingerprints
were not on the knife.
Huh?
Hello, Lewis.
- Hi, Craig.
Hey, Mr Craig. Wait a minute.
Barry.
How about a story on the Fleming case?
- Stand aside. Let me get this picture.
Have you any theories, Barry?
Yes, of course. Quite a few.
Go ahead. Let's hear them.
It's my opinion that the death
of the first Mrs Fleming ..
Had nothing to do with
the murder of the second.
What do you mean?
I mean, I believe the murderer of
Isabel Fleming is still at large.
Still at large?
Put it right on top, son.
Give him the money, dear.
My name is headlined in
every newspaper in the city.
Princess, you're married
to a very famous man.
Yes. And so modest.
- I can afford to be.
I wouldn't be surprised to find newsreel
cameramen inside to take pictures of me.
Barry. I think the lock
has been tampered with.
Don't be silly.
Oh, Barry.
Let me go.
- Let her go.
Honey.
What?
What's this all about?
Who are these guys?
I don't think they're the
newsreel cameramen.
Here. Let me help you up.
Now look, fathead.
You've been running off at the
mouth all day about what you think.
And what you suspect. You know?
If you want to stay healthy, keep your
mouth shut and mind your own business.
You know?
Don't get any more ideas
about the Fleming case.
Or you'll wind up in the headlines again
but you won't be able to read them.
You know?
- Whoever hired you must be ..
Whoever hired me told
me to give you this.
Darling.
When he wakes up, you'd better
remind him what's good for him.
You know?
I'll get you a drink.
Here. Take this.
Wait a minute.
I'm the one who got hit.
- Sorry. I'm all confused.
He pulled a Sunday punch on me.
He'd never have got away with it
if he hadn't pulled a Sunday punch.
You know what this proves?
Madge Lawrence's suicide had nothing
to do with Isabel Fleming's death.
Right. Her death just happened to
work in favor of the real killer.
You know, my theory was
that Madge Lawrence ..
Overdosed on sleeping tablets. You know.
Maybe accidentally. Maybe on purpose.
But her only part in the case was ..
That the murderer planted
the knife in her bag ..
Knowing her true identity would
come out and she'd be blamed.
But darling, I know that.
You've bent my ear all day telling me.
Can't you see it's true? That's why the
killer got hoodlums to scare me off.
I'm getting hot on the trail, you know.
And if you don't watch out you
will cool off in the morgue.
Not me. I know how to
take care of myself.
Sure you do. I bet you broke that
hoodlum's fist with your jaw.
Oh? So a guy gets knocked down and
you lose all your confidence in him?
Now Barry, I didn't mean it that way.
I have all the confidence
in the world in you.
That's why I want you to
go on with this thing.
You will get closer and closer ..
First thing you know, you'll get killed.
This is dangerous business, Barry.
Drop it.
Are you suggesting that
I behave like a coward?
I'm just suggesting you behave.
Listen, princess.
Someday, we hope to have a child.
And I don't want the child to grow up to
point the finger of shame at its father.
Then we'll teach him not to point.
No use trying to kid me out of it, Jane.
My job is to get to the bottom of this.
To the bottom alright.
Of the east river.
Look, honey.
I'm just going over to the McCormick
Studios to have a look around.
I want you to stay here.
Don't be silly.
After all, if I end up as a widow
I've a right to see how it's done.
[ Buzzer ]
Who do you suppose that is?
- I don't know.
But this time they're not going
to pull a Sunday on me.
Whoever it is, is going to
have to fight fair and square.
Good evening, Mr Smith.
Have a seat.
- Thank you.
Sit down, Mr Smith.
Would you care for a little sherry?
Thank you, no. I believe not.
- You're sure?
On second thoughts I think I will.
I need something to quiet my nerves.
Let me take your hat.
I feel like I've been
run through a ringer.
What's bothering you?
Your theory in the papers. Thank you.
Ever since I read it I have
been on needles and pins.
I just didn't know what to do.
First I felt I'd have a talk with you.
Then I thought I mustn't talk with you.
Then I said Yes to myself.
Then I said No to myself.
I'm all worn out from the argument.
I know exactly how you feel.
Thank you.
Now you're here, old man.
What's on your mind?
Lee Kenyon.
Lee Kenyon?
- Yes, darling.
He's a model who works in the nightclub
where you read the sign walking by.
Oh yes.
What about him, Mr Smith?
Just this.
Two days before Mrs Fleming was ..
Before she passed away.
This Kenyon person came to the house.
I don't know if it was by appointment.
But just before he arrived ..
Mrs Fleming sent me to the bank and
had me draw out $10,000 in cash.
I thought it was extraordinary too.
But that isn't all.
This morning, I checked Mrs Fleming's
effects and the $10,000 is gone.
I'd better run down to that nightclub
and have a talk with Kenyon.
My car is outside. I'd be
very glad to run you over.
That's so sweet of you, Mr Smith.
You only have a small coup,
haven't you Mr Smith?
Oh no. I have a large sedan.
That's what I said.
Good evening, Mr Craig.
This way, Mr Craig.
So, you just walked by the place?
They probably saw my
picture in the paper.
I told you not to take that last drink.
[ Door knocks ]
Come in.
A friend to see you, Mr Kenyon.
Oh. Mr Craig.
Come in. Have a seat.
- Thank you.
Doesn't this left shoulder
look a little too padded?
Not at all. A beautiful suit. New?
- Yes.
Now, Mr Craig. I have been reading
about you in the paper today.
Oh?
- What can I do for you?
Do for me?
- Yeah.
I'm not egotistical enough to think
you came here just to see me dance.
I see.
Whatever questions you
want to ask me, go ahead.
I'll try to answer them if I can.
Alright. Who is your tailor?
Max Morris.
Oh. Forgive me for even
asking that question.
He charges about $200 for
a suit of clothes, doesn't he?
Yes.
Yes. He is rather high, but ..
A man has to wear well-tailored
clothes when he's before the public.
Of course. Besides, what's two hundred
dollars to a man who has ten thousand?
Ten thousand dollars? Me?
Ten thousand? Why ..
Where would a guy like me
get ten thousand dollars?
From the late Mrs Isabel Fleming?
Look, Mr Craig. You can't get
me mixed up in this thing.
I don't know anything about it.
I swear I don't.
I admit I got ten thousand
dollars from the old lady.
But I had nothing to do
with knocking her off.
Maybe. Maybe not.
But you're not telling me she gave you
that money just because she liked you?
No.
No. Of course not.
She gave me the money
to stay away from Erika.
From Mrs McCormick?
Yeah.
You see, Erika told her she was going to
divorce Mack and marry somebody else.
The old lady thought it was me.
So she called me up there and offered
me ten grand to stay away from Erika.
Naturally, I took the money.
Well. I thought it was a
good joke on the old lady.
Especially since I hadn't
seen Erika in over a year.
You mean, you weren't the
man Erika was in love with?
Certainly not.
Erika and I used to be good friends
but that's all it amounted to.
Where did you meet her? Through Mack?
No. I knew her before Mack did.
Harry Duerr introduced us.
As a matter of fact, Duerr
introduced Mack to her.
She and Duerr were kids together.
Having a good time?
I was.
Is that all you came down here for?
Just to have a good time?
What else?
Where is your boyfriend?
I was just wondering about that myself.
He must have wandered
away somewhere, I guess.
But he'll come back. He always does.
That's swell.
We'll hang around and have another
little chat with him. You know?
You don't have to. He made up his mind
to keep his nose out of the whole thing.
Good, We will wait.
And congratulate him on using his brain.
Alright.
Suit yourself.
Do you mind if I leave you for
a minute to powder my nose?
Wait a minute. You don't want to
get this coat covered with powder.
You know. Leave it here.
It will be here when you get back.
Very well. But keep a good eye on it.
I just got it.
Barry.
What is it? What's the matter?
Barry. Those two hoodlums.
They're waiting out front for you.
Kenyon, is there any way out of here
without going back through the caf?
There's a fire door in the chorus room.
But the girls are making a change.
Oh? Come on.
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
Blindfold yourself, dear.
I'll see if it's alright.
Girls.
Come in.
Listen, girls. I'd like to bring
a gentleman through here.
But it's a matter of life and death
and besides, he'll be blindfolded.
Okay. Bring him through.
Thanks for everything, girls.
Why, it's Mr Craig.
Hello, Mr Craig.
They must know me from my books.
Don't tell me they can read too.
Phillip.
Here is the money for our drinks.
- Thank you, sir.
Look.
Next time, they will know better.
You know?
What did you find out from Kenyon?
- I'll tell you on the way to Julie's.
Taxi.
What can we find out from Julie?
- Taxi.
You thought she was in love with Mack?
- Yes.
Well, when a dame is
in love with a guy ..
It's only natural for her to know
who the guy's wife is in love with.
Hey. Taxi.
We'd like to see Julie Taylor please.
Just tell her it's Mr and Mrs Craig.
I am sorry. Miss Taylor checked
out about fifteen minutes ago.
Checked out at this time of night?
Where'd she go?
I don't know, sir. She didn't
leave a forwarding address.
That's strange.
Yes it is.
After being here for two years.
I asked her about her mail
and she didn't answer at all.
She just rushed right on by.
Thanks very much.
[ Telephone ]
Hello?
I wonder if that can have been ..?
No.
No?
- No.
Hey, maybe it was ..
No.
No?
- No.
What time is it?
It is ten after twelve.
[ Telephone ]
Hello?
Yes. He is here. Who is calling?
This is Erika McCormick.
Oh. Just a minute.
It's Erika McCormick.
Hello?
Mr Craig?
Mr Craig, you've got to help me.
I just found out something.
I know who killed ..
Hello?
Cut off.
Now what?
I'll go over there to
have a talk with her.
Maybe she'll ring again.
Why not call her back?
I've a hunch something's
happening over there.
Whatever it is, I hope it
happens before we get there.
Hey, give us a line on this, will you?
It was the McCormick dame, wasn't it?
- When can Inspector Clinton talk to us?
When the Inspector wants to talk to
you guys, he'll talk to you guys.
How about talking to
Henderson or Gatling then?
Nobody gets inside. Do you understand?
Did you tell the boys to come up?
- I sure did, Doc.
What did you find out, Doc?
She was strangled alright.
We may find out more with
an autopsy but I doubt it.
Do you feel like answering a
few questions, Mr McCormick?
If I didn't, I'd have to answer
them anyway, wouldn't I?
No. Not necessarily.
Still, it might help.
Go ahead.
How long were you here before
you telephoned headquarters?
I told you before. I had just arrived.
I went into the bedroom and found ..
I found her and I called
you immediately.
You were out all evening?
Yeah. I was at the studio
working on the books.
I suppose you can supply witnesses
to corroborate your statement?
I'm afraid not.
Unless the elevator man
happened to see me.
No. Unfortunately for you he didn't.
We've already checked with him.
Alright. If you think I did it, why
not arrest me and have it over with?
You seem more concerned with your own
predicament than with your wife's death.
You were on friendly terms, I suppose?
Well ..
I may as well tell you.
You will find out anyway.
This afternoon my wife told me that ..
She was going to divorce me.
Well, Mr McCormick.
I'm afraid we will have to hold you.
Good morning.
- Morning.
Thank you.
- Don't forget the paper, dear.
I'm glad you don't deliver the milk.
Bill.
Hey. There's one here that isn't a bill.
Good. Good.
Barry, it's a letter from Julie.
What is so exciting about .. Julie?
'Dear Jane'.
'I suppose it's cowardly for me to run
away but I can't bear to hang around ..'
'And see the grandest person
I've ever known suffer'.
'Yes. You guessed it from the start.
I love Mack McCormick'.
'But he doesn't know I'm alive.
However, I want to help him if I can'.
'That's why I am writing to you, Jane'.
'He's in so much trouble
and the reopening of this ..'
'Case will just make it more
difficult for him, so ..'
'Won't you please ask Barry
to let the matter drop'.
'I am sure the police have the proper
solution to Mrs Fleming's death'.
'There's no need to ask questions'.
'They only bring out a lot of
gossip and unpleasantness'.
'Please Jane. Devotedly, Julia'.
'P.S'.
'I just called Mack at the studio'.
'If only you could
have heard his voice'.
'So tired and unhappy'.
The poor kid.
New York Central stationery.
Evidently, she wrote the
letter at the railroad station.
Let me see the envelope.
Picked up at .. 1am.
She obviously thinks Mack did it.
Uhuh.
Running away to keep
from being questioned.
She probably doesn't even
know about Erika's death.
Barry, Mack was at the studio.
She followed him there.
I wonder at what time.
Where is my hat?
- Here we go again.
Show him the letter.
When did you get this?
- This morning.
Why didn't you tell the
police Julie called?
That would prove you were at the studio.
I dragged her into this.
- What time did she call?
What time did she call?
About a quarter past twelve.
That's when Erika phoned you.
And she was killed right then
to keep her from talking.
That proves you didn't do it.
Erika called you? What is that?
Mack. We've no time to answer questions.
We have time to ask one.
Will you answer it?
If I can.
Who engaged Madge Lawrence
to pose for the picture?
I don't know. But Julie would know.
And we don't know where Julie is.
Well, unless we find Julie ..
Hey. I've got it.
Come on, princess.
You wait here until we get back.
Don't worry. I will.
What now?
Listen, baby. You used to be an actress.
Do you think you could sound
like Julie over the telephone?
Why .. I don't know.
Make up your mind. Yes or no?
Well.
Maybe.
- Good. Come on.
Oh Barry. Whatever you're
figuring on doing ..
I don't like it.
Hello, boys.
Hello Craig.
Just what do you want around here?
I just wondered if you had seen Julie.
- No.
She checked out of her
apartment last night.
You know that.
- Yes. But how do you know?
We called her apartment
house this morning.
The clerk said you'd been round
looking for her last night.
Or rather he said, a nosy guy
with a good-looking woman.
Sounds like you.
Did you find her?
No. But my wife received a
letter from her this morning.
I have it right here.
What did I do with that letter?
I must have lost it.
Yeah. I'll bet you did.
Here's the envelope.
You can see it was mailed last night.
What do you want around here, Craig?
What are you after?
Oh, I was ..
Just trying to find out who killed ..
Isabel Fleming and Erika McCormick.
I think Julie can tell me.
Alright. So why don't you go
and find her and ask her?
I know where she is or
I will in a few minutes.
She'll phone me here at .. ten o'clock.
You see, gentlemen.
There are only four people
who could possibly be guilty.
Mack. Kenyon.
You.
And you.
Whoever it was planned Isabel
Fleming's murder beautifully.
The aim of the murder was
to get the Fleming fortune ..
Into the hands of Erika McCormick.
According to that reasoning it was Mack.
He's the only one who'd profit by it.
Mack was terribly hard up I know, but ..
I don't believe he did it.
No. Mack wouldn't profit by it. You see,
Erika had already applied for a divorce.
I didn't know that.
- Didn't you?
Well, Erika was in love
with another man.
That man wanted her to
get the Fleming fortune.
Before he married her.
And .. that man is the murderer.
Somehow Erika found out he was the
murderer so he had to kill her too.
Now, let's take Kenyon.
Whoever killed Isabel Fleming ..
Hired Madge Lawrence knowing the story
of the family feud would come out ..
And she would be blamed.
Kenyon, who was only another model,
could not possibly have hired Madge.
That leaves ..
Just you two.
Jabber, jabber, jabber.
When Julie telephones ..
She will tell me which of
you employed Madge.
That's all I have to know.
Why don't you go away?
How do you account for Lawrence's death?
Oh. An accident.
She was nervous over the scene
she had with Isabel Fleming ..
And took an overdose
of sleeping tablets.
But the knife?
It was planted in her bag
before she left the studio.
Very interesting.
Yeah. It sounds like another
one of your corny books.
[ Telephone ]
Hello?
Who?
This is Julie.
Who is this?
This is Kirk.
Kirk, is Barry Craig there?
Yes. He's right here.
Hello?
Julie?
Julie, I want you to answer
me just one question.
Now think hard.
Who was it that engaged Madge Lawrence?
Who?
Is that really Julie?
No. It's Craig's wife.
Alright, boys. You win.
It's no use. It didn't work.
Okay.
Goodbye.
Well .. I tried.
And a good try it was too.
But I warn you about one thing.
Julie will show up the minute
she finds out Mack is in jail.
[ Telephone ]
Hello?
Long distance?
Yes, yes. I'll take the call.
Hello?
Julie.
Where are you?
Yeah.
Yeah, Mack is in jail.
Yes. It looks pretty black for him.
Sure. We're doing all we can ..
- Give me that phone!
Julie, this is Barry Craig.
We can help Mack if you'll
tell me just one thing.
Who was it who made the phone call
that engaged Madge Lawrence to pose?
Alright, Craig.
You can put that phone down.
And keep your hands in the air.
Now turn around. Both of you.
If not for your meddling, Craig,
I'd have got away with it.
So, I owe you something.
Now I'm going to pay you back.
If you have a prayer to say
you'd better make it quick.
Now listen.
- Keep out of it, Harry.
This guy has been begging for a killing
since he first walked in this place.
And now he's going to get it.
Alright. Are you ready, hotshot?
He's alright. He just fainted.
Good work, boys.
Ah, it was nothing.
Will you help me get him on the bed?
Barry.
Your husband, Mrs Craig.
He just fainted.
Darling. Wake up.
What has happened to you?
Are you hurt?
Oh, darling.
Hurt?
I'm dead.
If this is heaven, how
did that guy get in here?
It's lucky for you we happened along.
Happened along?
I knew you were following me.
What detained you?
Dear, did I sound like
Julie on the phone?
No. He recognised your
voice immediately.
But then I got the first break I've
had since I've been on this case.
Just after you telephoned,
Julie herself called.
But that wasn't Julie. That was me too.
You?
Yes. I called the second time
and Duerr answered the phone.
So I pretended I was long distance
and then that I was Julie.
Princess, you're wonderful.
Congratulations, Mrs Craig.
Thank you, Inspector.
Darling. Do you feel strong
enough to go home now?
Sure.
I'm as steady as a rock.
Well, Inspector.
If you ever get in any trouble again.
Let me hear from you.
Look out, Craig!
Dear.
..w-g..