Mm mm mm mm mm
Good morning.
What's this about?
What do you mean?
You left this on the pillow right
next to my head.
No, I didn't. Why on earth would
I do such a thing?
Penelope.
Who you think else would have done it?
I don't know. Things
just happen sometimes.
A ghost didn't put this by
my head to kill me.
I could've poke my eye right
out my socket
waking up blind woman!
I told you I didn't do it.
How you suppose it got there, huh?
I don't know.
Maybe some ghost did it,
putting it there to warn you.
The creeper is you.
I done seen you lurk
around these halls.
Like uh little phantom I tell ya.
Don't be silly.
The truth is being told to you.
Alright, now you up
in the darkness,
up in the midnight hour.
And now it looks like you
trying to kill me in my sleep!
Don't be silly.
Ain't nothing silly about me woman.
You need some help!
I don't remember doing anything.
I truly don't.
That's the problem.
Now, Hailey Lynn
could have gotten hurt.
Then what?
You know good and well,
I would never hurt my kids.
Not intentionally.
But what if you did?
What if that knife was in her
room and not ours?
You're right.
I don't know what's happening
to me.
I'm sure they got some kind of
treatment for sleepwalking.
You know.
Who is they?
They-The doctors.
Maybe some kind of underlying
illness
that we just don't know about.
Doctors.
Do you really think
I need help like that?
Can't hurt, can it?
I don't think so.
It's not that serious.
The evaluation wouldn't
take longer than a couple days.
A few at the most.
Valuation!
What kind of doctor
are you talking about!
The kind that'll help
get your mind right!
You want me to admit myself?
I'm not crazy, Jasper.
I didn't say you were alright.
It's just to find out what's
wrong.
Don't you wanna know
what's wrong with you?
Maybe I don't.
I'm happy the way I am.
I really.
I believe so.
You don't sound too
sure about that.
Now listen here honey.
It's...
It's nothing for you to worry
your pretty self about, alright.
I'm telling you,
I'll come back for you.
I'm not comfortable
talking about this.
Are you trying to get rid of me?
Oh, don't be silly, alright?
I just I think it'll do some good.
By signing my rights away.
Being at the mercy
of someone else?
I don't think so.
I don't like this, not one bit!
Everything will be fine.
Alright.
I promise you.
That doesn't make
me feel any better.
Penelope, everything's
going to be okay.
I swear it.
Now I'm not the kind of fellow
that'll lie to you.
Here...
It's delicious ain't it.
♪ Mmmmm ♪
How you doing honey?
What are you doing here?
Here to bring you home.
They didn't tell me I was leaving today.
I wanted to surprise you.
They won't let me leave here.
They say I have to stay in my room.
Naw, naw, honey you can come home
with me t-today, right now.
Home.
This is my home.
This is my bed.
This is my clothes.
You better leave before
they see you.
You don't belong here.
I don't want to get in trouble.
They do bad things to you
when you're bad here.
Honey, do you know who I am?
You don't have a white coat on.
I'm not sure.
It's so hard for me to think.
Think, Think, Think, Think,
Think.
Here-don't, don't you worry
none.
Just...
Can you see me now Penny?
I'm brought you these clothes
so you can, you know,
look real nice like.
Me-me help you get undress.
Don't touch me.
Don't you touch me.
Leave me alone.
Get out of my room.
I Just...
Get out!
Sorry, I didn't...
Trying to hurt you none.
I just...
Ok, I'ma...
I'ma go-go over there and
let, let you get dress, okay.
Don't be sad, Mommy.
Why are you crying?
These are happy tears, baby.
I've missed you so much.
It's been so long.
You're a big girl now.
I'm cute, too.
Go ahead Mom, have some cake.
Hey, it's time to celebrate
y'all.
Mama's home!
Hey Mom!
I'm really glad you're home.
Me too son, me too.
We need us some music up
in here. I wanna dance me a jig.
Come on baby dance with me.
Come on, dance with me.
♪ Welcome to the meat grinder
to judge you...
we're brains
in the sky. ♪
Everybody seemed to have
a real good time last night.
Oh, did you see the twinkle in
Hailey's eyes when she saw you?
Oh, that's a sight for sore eyes.
I tell you.
I want a divorce.
♪ You are the object
We are the subject. ♪
Say what now?
I just bought you home
so we could be a family again.
What-what's going on here?
I want you to leave.
Naw, naw!
This can't be happening, can it?
It is.
This ain't, this ain't right.
Don't, don't do me like this darling.
And I mean, come on.
That was supposed to be
a happy occasion and...
Just what's going on.
And tell me the truth.
I just don't need you in my life anymore.
Don't do this to me.
Not to us.
Hailey Lynn just got her mama back.
And now you want her daddy
to go away?
Maybe you just, you just tired, you know
a little overwhelmed a bit, that's all.
She's not your daughter.
She is to me.
And I love you, honey.
Love has nothing to do with it!
The heck it don't!
It's got everything to do with it
once I put that ring on your finger!
I'm sure you can understand
why you're a smart guy.
Yeah, I'm wise as an owl too!
You still blaming me for them
kids going missing ain't cha?
Where are the kids?
Uh...
Yeah!
I got to tell you something.
What!
I'm making their favorite
peanut butter sandwiches.
Yeah.
Where are the kids.
Abo-about that, um.
They've gone, honey.
Gone where?
What did you do to them?
Not nothing.
Not a thing, I swear.
Where are my kids, Jasper?
I'm so sorry, baby.
There was nothing I could do.
What are you saying?
Zoey and Paige they are-
They're gone.
The woods took my munchkins away
and they...
And they ain't coming back.
See, I knew you would figure it out.
You didn't watch them.
You knew they shouldn't go in those woods,
And you left them alone anyways.
So tell me what were you doing
in a psych ward?
Counting down the days
until you'd come and get me.
Those days turned into months,
even years that never seemed to end.
You done gone and turned into
a heifer on me, huh?
Because the way I see it,
you've been waiting and planning for a day
such as this to strike this blow on me.
You don't even know
what a heifer is.
That don't matter.
Every–thing mat–ters!
Did you do it?
It sure looks that way, doesn't it?
Ain't that about a blimp!
I can't seem to apologize enough
for you to get it.
Ain't a darn thing I can do
about that now, Penelope.
I can't change the past.
You're not sorry.
You're pitiful!
And I can't stand your presence near me.
Not!
Wait, hold on now.
Don't say such a thing.
Harmful words coming out
your mouth, woman.
I know.
But I do.
Okay, just he-hear me please,
please hear me clearly now.
I took my eyes off of them
for one moment, and that's it.
They were out here
playing around and everything.
I Just-I let them be.
Why would you think they
wouldn't go into those woods?
They were kids, curious to know
what was in there.
I wasn't thinking.
No, you weren't.
Our little ones are gone,
Jasper.
Yeah, I know, I know.
You know, I ain't wont harm
to come to them kids.
You left them alone.
And I...
I, went in there straight away
after them.
And...
Everything just got silent on
me.
Complete silence swept the air.
And they were gone with it.
It's nothing I could do.
Silent!
I told you something was in
there.
And!
Stop pretending, the darkness
isn't real!
You were there with me, Jasper.
I know you felt it too.
Why didn't you believe me?
You don't think I feel guilty?
I search for them kids.
I searched for Zoe and Paige.
I couldn't find them anywhere.
They were gone without a trace.
But you wanted me to forget
about them. Why?
Just what had to be done.
It was my blood that ran
through their veins.
Not yours alone!
I know you don't understand it.
I know, but I tried to stop
the darkness from attacking you.
Really?
Yeah, really!
I was protecting you.
Just stop!
You didn't allow me a day to
mourn for them. Not one!
Ya just gotta let the dead lie.
That darkness will creep up on ya
and ya won't know it until it's too late.
Now I'm letting you know
it won't let you go.
You had me... walk around
as if they never existed.
And like a fool, I did it to
appease you!
Who does that?
Those were your children, too!
You don't think I love my kids?
I don't know, Jasper.
How could you forget
about them so quickly?
I thought we were over this.
In my subconscious.
I walked in my sleep.
I searched in the dark shadows
for those ghosts.
And you locked me up
with the insane for it.
You needed help.
I needed comfort.
Something you never gave.
You like a zombie
Roaming around in the darkness
just disappearing in the midnight hours.
What else was I supposed to do?
Penelope you'd be gone
for hours and sometimes days?
Nobody even knew where you were.
You were losing your
raggedy mind up in this house.
You left me there, and forgot
about me.
I didn't see or hear from you
for years.
Not 1 or 2 but 5 years!
I just couldn't see you like
that.
Your light had dimmed.
Like you were fading away on me.
My children were my sunshine.
My light...
My life...
You took that from me!
And I needed-
Needed time to refocus.
You, you needed to be fixed.
You needed to get a grip on life
so your light could shine again.
I couldn't do that for you.
You took my family away from me.
What did you think a piece of cake
was supposed to make everything better.
Make everything okay?
Yeah, I sure did.
I did.
It's just the way it had to be.
Have you full of happy thoughts.
Let go of the pass Penelope.
Oh, you're right. You're right.
You're right. I will forget
about the past.
And all that garbage
out of your mouth with it.
I don't believe in divorce.
I'm not interested in what you believe.
How much more am I to take?
What am I supposed to do?
Forgive me as many times as
it takes.
I'm not a saint!
This can't be fixed!
I will never forgive you for this.
Look ah here!
I made a covenant with God,
and this right here ain't
something for you to be breaking.
Don't bring God into this.
Why not?
I made a covenant with Him.
You and I stood in front of God
and we told him,
till death do us part
and you ain't dead yet.
I will not divorce you women.
For better or for worse.
You remember that, don't you?
I need my space.
Take your things and leave.
Head on onto the other property
a little bit.
I won't be gone long.
I'll be back real soon, you
know.
So don't you get too comfortable
living without me!
Are you alright, sweetie?
You don't see them mommy?
See who?
They're talking to me.
I don't see anyone.
What y'all falling behind like
a couple of lost puppies for?
Bring yourselves up here,
I want to show you something.
All of this...
Is wealth...
In the palm of your hands.
Man, Uncle Jasper.
I knew you had land, but...
I'd know you had all this.
Naw, this ain't even half of it.
You know, one day I'm the big
belly up floating around in that blue sky,
watching over y'all.
Don't say that.
Awl it's true young fellow,
it's true.
Everybody ends up
pushing up daisies at some point.
My petals might be dropping
sooner than later.
But when that day comes,
all this belong to y'all.
All of it?
That's right.
Split between both of you.
Hum.
I don't know what to do with
all this.
Whatever you do, can't sell it.
Alright.
Keep this in the family.
Hold on, hold on.
Something ain't right here.
I don't hear no birds chirping,
no critters moving around.
Alright don't move.
Y'all just stay right here.
Run!
You ran out of there
like a bat out of hell.
I didn't think you had it in you
to run like that.
Ain't no time to be dilly-dallying around
when it's time hightail out of dodge.
You hear me?
Yeah...
Well, now that Caleb's not around.
What was back there?
I just know I am about to be
the one getting snatched up just yet.
Snatched up!
By what?
You need to mind your business.
Alright now.
Sometimes you need to know
when to shut up.
But Jasper, what's with the secrets.
Secrets ain't meant to be told?
So stop asking.
So that's the best answer
you got.
That's the one I'm giving.
Now I just saved your life back
there boy, you better be grateful.
Really?
From running from a ghost.
You ask too many questions.
Look, what I see is
somebody who has secrets.
And I want to know what for.
So what was back there in
those woods of yours.
That's another question.
I'm uh have a drink, you want
a drink?
Just what I need to quench my
thirst.
So are you going to answer my
question?
Do I look like somebody
who would answer your question?
You know I think it's time
for you to leave.
No!
Not until I have answers.
Oh, okay.
Look who has grown themselves
a pair of balls over the years.
What do you think,
you can challenge me, boy.
You know you ain't so grown where
I can put you in a grave, now.
You know...
I'm not a little kid anymore.
Okay.
So what you plan on doing?
You better stand down, boy.
Before you get yourself hurt.
I'm the wrong one
to be playing games with.
Now that you quiet.
Let me tell you something.
If you pay attention to that
forest,
it'll speak to you.
You know them critters in there
they ain't silent for nothing.
They usually the first ones to
know something ain't right in there.
Now if you don't pay attention
to the signs before you go in
there, you may not make it out alive.
So is that what happened to
my sisters?
What do you mean by that boy?
They just went into the woods.
Never to be found again, didn't they?
Yeah, that's right.
All those little cubs left
the field of Lillies...
got stanched-up by that there forest.
Never to be seen again.
Jasper, how can you be so
cavalier about it?
I can't change the past boy.
What is, is!
And that's it.
Yeah, but you sure can learn from it.
I'd be a fool if I harped
over something I couldn't change.
And you know I ain't
nobody's fool.
I'm plumb tired now.
It's time for you to be leaving.
Gone get the stepping off my property, boy?
What about Paige and Zoe?
What about them?
Isn't there more to the story?
Look they gone...
Alright, they ain't coming back.
So you say.
I'm going to find out what's in
those woods of yours.
One way or another!
You a fool one way or another.
Hey, Hailey.
Are you okay?
Where's Mom at?
She's in the basement,
washing clothes.
Well I have to talk to her.
Can I have some?
You want some of this?
You can have it.
You say she's downstairs.
Close your eyes...
I want to show you something.
You can open your eyes now.
What am I supposed to see?
You don't see them.
Looks like your imaginary friend
is only for you to see.
I'm not pretending.
You really see something?
Why can't the bigger people
see like I do?
I don't know.
They told me to tell you,
they'll be talking to you soon too.
They want to talk to me.
Mom!
Hayden's here.
I wasn't expecting to see you here.
What brings you here?
What, I can't visit
the best woman in the world to me.
The hat.
Thank you.
Now you know you're always
welcome here.
Yeah, I know, I know, I know.
Listen, Ma.
I wanted to talk to you about
something.
What is it?
Oh!
So we're serious.
Okay. Yeah. Let's be serious.
Um...
Do you know what's in the woods
of Jasper's property?
Why are you asking me about that?
You know something, don't you?
Now, before you answer, don't lie.
I can see it on your face.
Don't go in those woods.
It's not safe.
Why?
What's in there, Mom?
Darkness.
What do you mean, darkness, Ma?
It's something you can feel...
but can't touch.
Smell...
but not see.
All I know is many have gone in
there, but few have come out.
Ma.
That's rather bizarre.
Are you sure?
It's the only way I know how
to explain it.
The darkness moves in silence.
We live in a day of uncertainty.
We don't know when we will
take our last breath.
Why are you so serious?
Because, I don't want to
lose you too son!
I've had enough heartbreak
to last me a lifetime.
Ma, look, I'm not going anywhere.
I know you Hayden.
Once you've made up your mind,
There no changing it.
Look Ma.
Whatever I'm going to do,
I'll be sure to be careful.
Okay.
Don't let your feet lead you down
a path of sorrow and dreaded end.
Mom
Tell me...
Why are you so afraid of the
woods?
Because I was in there when it
came.
It chased me and Jasper out of
there.
I never went back in there.
Nothing is moving.
You thinks some spook is coming
to get you.
Come on.
Don't worry your pretty little head about
this here little silence.
You know I'll protect you.
I'll never let any harm come
ta touch ya.
It feels like the air is
being sucked right
out of my lungs.
Honey, I, I don't feel nothing.
How can you not feel this?
Oh. Oh. Something dark is in
here.
And we are walking straight to it.
It's getting hard for me to
breathe.
We have to leave.
Something is here!
We have to go now!
Jasper and I would walk
through there all the time.
In fact, I loved it there.
The beauty of it all intrigued
me.
Okay. And?
There was a shift.
The atmosphere changed.
He thought I was losing my mind
until he felt it too.
But then want happened?
You couldn't see it.
Invisible things lurk in the forest.
And it moves in silence.
How do you know this?
It's the only way I can
explain it to you, son.
The animals even know when it
comes.
They stay still,
not making a sound.
So...
let me get this straight.
Nobody went in to find Paige
and Zoe,
because of the invisible
things in there?
No.
Bobby and Jasper searched.
All I know
is they were never seen again.
My babies were gone.
Ma.
Don't cry.
It's Okay.
I just miss them so much.
Yeah.
Yeah, me too, me too.
So, Ma.
What's that about?
I'm just keeping my house clean.
From what?
Spirits.
Ma...
Spirits!
Are you okay?
I'm just...
trying to protect my little
Hailey Lynn.
Look, that sage ain't gonna
do nothing but smell up your house.
What makes you think something
is after her anyway?
I don't know!
But she said something is here.
Yeah.
She said the same thing to me,
too.
I didn't really think
anything of it though.
So why are you?
Let's just say, I'm paying
attention.
Listening to every sound.
Looking at every movement.
I can't help but wonder,
what is in here.
Hold on.
So first you're telling me
something is in the woods,
and now something is in here.
Mama, I don't really know
what to think about all this.
Why are you looking at me like that?
You don't believe me, do you?
I'm just listening.
Taking it in as you speak to me.
I'm not crazy for wanting
to protect my family.
Ma, I didn't say you were.
Don't be so defensive.
I will do whatever it takes
to protect my family.
To protect you.
Ma,
I just want to make sure that
you're okay.
Why wouldn't I be?
I mean, the sage is a little extreme Ma.
I just want to make sure that you're okay.
I'm good.
I, I just don't know what else to do.
Are you scared?
Maybe,
just a little.
So...
you really think ghost are in here.
Something is.
Have you thought about...
seeing a therapist again.
No.
So, you think I'm losing my mind?
Hey, look, I'm just trying to help.
It worked for you last time.
Maybe it'll work again.
I see.
Do you know what they did to
me, last time? -No.
Maybe if you would've a came to visit me,
then you would have known.
I try many times, okay.
They wouldn't let me see you.
Jasper must have told them
not to let me in.
My hands were tied.
No, mine was!
I didn't know what else to do,
but to wait till you came
home. I'm sorry.
Don't blame yourself.
It's not your burden to carry.
Yeah, but still.
You were gone...
And I hate that.
And I hate him more for leaving you there.
I just...
I just wish that I could have done more.
I see Jasper's trickery left me there,
to be forgotten.
Maybe it's best I didn't see you.
I think it would have torn my heart apart
to see you suffer and do nothing.
Apparently nobody did.
I was left alone in misery,
fighting off demons.
Maybe it was the meds,
had you hallucinating.
None of it was real.
I saw those demons when I got
there and they didn't leave.
I was touched by a spirit.
Spirit.
Something invisible was in my room.
I heard it speak to me.
It had no face.
No lips to speak.
It spoke to me in the spirit.
I was sleep.
And I felt,
the bed dipped, as if a body
sunk down the mattress.
Something...
invisible was in my room.
Are you telling me,
ghosts came in your room.
I'm going to recommend,
that you do not tell Jasper.
Okay.
He might lock you up for good this time.
I'm never going back to that place.
Hailey!
I'm about to go!
Hailey...
Hailey!
I'm scared, Mommy.
Somethings in there.
God please!
Don't take my baby away!
Please!
Come back!
Where did you go!
Don't do this to me again.
I' m...
Please.
Trying to protect you!
Anybody see y'all out there?
I don't know.
Alright.
Alright leave the doll with me!
I'll take care of that.
I don't want any trace of Hailey Lynn.
Alright-
Means we got to get rid of everything
in this house.
The only child you have is Hayden.
I'll stay here awhile,
until you get your mind right.
It watched us.
Looking at our every move...
and waited till I wasn't paying attention.
Who is they?
The invisibles.
Alright, I want you to go in the back
room for a spell.
Uhm.
You need to rest
that frazzled brain of yours.
Yeah!
Yes, it's a bit, a bit too much for you.
I get it.
Naw, yeah, naw I get it, I get it.
You's a bit tired that's all honey.
You get nothing.
You weren't there.
Rest isn't going to change
what happened!
Yeah.
I know it's a bit much to take
in for a day.
Um.
But I'll take care of you.
Don't, don't worry none.
Go on.
Everything will be alright.
Gone now.
This here has tipped the scale...
to no return.
It's alright,
I'll make it right.
Make it right-
Make her as comfortable as possible.
Tearing my heart to pieces.
What you doing here girly?
Bout made my heart skip a beat.
I wanted to surprise you.
Alright.
Where...
Where your mama at?
She's outside.
Gone pull-up a chair.
You take that doll of yours
everywhere you go, don't you?
What kind of mother would
I be if I left her behind?
You gonna be a real good mama one day.
I'm hungry.
What's this here, your mama
didn't feed you?
I like your cooking.
Oh.
I want some squirrel.
Oh, is that right.
I suppose I can
mustard up a little something.
Put'em out there on, on the pit,
and burn'em up real yummy.
Yeah I'm getting me some grub.
Look uh there.
You done turned little country
girl on me after all.
Yep.
Alright, well
got to go out there
in the back of the woods to
fetch it.
You coming?
Nope, I don't like the woods.
It's spooky in there.
You ain't got to worry none.
The trees might come alive
and get me,
and I won't be able to see you anymore.
Okay. Well, If I'm gone...
my wise old owl will take care of you.
He's always watching
with those big old eyes of his.
Come on let's go fetch us some vittles.
How do I tell Hayden
his sister is gone missing.
So much to figure out.
So much to do.
So how am I going to tell your boy,
that his baby sister has
vanished into thin air?
That's the truth.
Why do you act like he's not your son too?
Why you changing the subject, huh?
I didn't say he wasn't.
Maybe it's the truth he won't believe.
It's still the truth, Jasper.
Why you keep staring out this window?
Till my baby comes home.
I really hate to break it to
you like this, darling but...
that little sweetness of heaven
ain't coming back.
How do you know this?
Maybe the spirits
in the sky took her cause...
you forgot about your first love.
Who are you talking about?
You know, you worship that little girl.
Maybe God took her away because...
wanted you to focus on him.
It's not fair.
You crossing the line now, Penelope.
You're wrong.
It can't be true.
Then how do you explain it, huh?
A leprechaun didn't slide down
a rainbow and take her away.
Things don't just vanish
into thin air, Penelope!
You never believed me.
You think I've been lying?
Why else would you be acting this way?
Think about it for a moment.
I don't know who took her.
For your sake...
I hope it was God that snatched her up.
Cause things can get real ugly if it ain't.
What are you saying?
You sound like you know
more than you're telling.
What I do know is that you
better get on your knees and pray.
Alright, It's not the first
time people done gone missing.
Do you remember what happened in the woods?
I don't wanna remember.
Our kids disappeared.
I done told you now I don't
want to talk about that.
Something is in those woods,
and you know it.
You just don't know
when to be quiet, do you?
I know you felt it, too.
I heard the growling, Jasper.
The smell of sulfur.
I can't forget it.
The air was so dense,
it was hard to breathe.
It brought chills through my
body, scaring me out of my boots.
Why couldn't we see it?
Just let it be, woman!
I think the Invisibles are here.
Let me tell you this much...
God don't let anyone or anything
come before him and you knew that.
But you did it anyway.
Now look what happened.
Our Hailey Lynn is gone.
Sometimes you need to know
when to be quiet.
I don't have the patience to be
listening to this foolishness.
How long...
does my heart have to bleed?
All you do...
is pour salt on my wounds.
Are you getting some kind
of sick pleasure out of this?
Look!
You did this to yourself.
Can you just shut up?
I hate being in this dark place.
It's time for you...
to move on with your life now.
Could you just stop talking?
Well, if it ain't God
that snatched them up.
You better hope they
don't come for you next.
If not me, you.
How many times do I have to
say it.
Thee invisibles took her.
You know, I can't keep listening
to this nonsense.
Kid of yours is gone, and nothing
could be done about it.
Why don't you stop looking out
this here window.
Listen, I'll cook you
up some vittles and...
And I'um just head on back home.
You're leaving me.
It's time for you to...
get your life back again.
You know, I'm just holding you back.
I'm crippling you with my presence here.
No you're not.
I need you.
I'll still be loving you just
from a distance, that's all.
Oh, no, no, I...
Please don't leave me,
I, I, I can't function without...
I can't function anymore.
It's just.
It's just for a time.
Please don't, please don't leave please.
Please.
All this time, I'll
come back and be with you
just right now at the time.
I need you here with me, Jasper.
No, no, no, no, you don't.
You need the man upstairs it's good for you
to just have some time with him alone.
Just you and him.
This, this is what's, what's best for you.
Alright.
I can't keep holding ya.
I can't believe you're...
blaming me for this.
Well!
You better believe it.
You know, sometimes the truth
is a tough pill to swallow.
You gotta just digest it and move on.
That's all you have to say.
I'll be praying for you.
I'll be sending my prayers
up to heaven for you.
Hope you get better.
It's the best I can do.
Can't do no mo!
Mommy!
Hailey Lynn, is that you?
Don't cry, Mommy.
I love you.
Come back.
What you doing sneaking
around my property for boy.
You said all this will belong
to me one day, didn't you?
I ain't dead yet.
Figured I'd come check it out.
Yeah, alright.
This here property is pretty wide and deep.
I'd hate for
anything bad to happened to you.
Like what?
Never you mind it.
Hey uh.
Who's grave you got dug up back there?
It'll be one for you if you
keep asking all them questions.
Are you threatening me?
Take it how you will, boy.
Now, be no fool, don't be no fool.
Don't do that.
I will beat you dead with my
bare hands right at my feet
messing around with me;
and you know I'll do it.
Not if I get you first.
You really trying me, huh?
Now I warned you!
Best turn around and be gone.
I ain't saying it twice.
Look, I didn't come here to
shed blood with my dad.
No, you didn't.
You came here being nosey,
trying to see the site list!
Did I?
What's with all this hatred
built up in your soul for boy?
I think you know
the answer to that already.
You need to just cut it out,
alright.
Cause all this right here
is enough to wake the Seekers.
Seekers?
Jasper what the heck are Seekers?
You just need to step cautiously,
cause they know you're here.
So there is something in here.
Jasper is that what happened to my sisters?
Hey!
Mind your business.
Use those legs of yours and get
out of here for you end up as bait.
Now gone get stepping off my property
for you end up dead!
Hey where you at darling.
Oh, you got the door wide open.
What you inviting all the heathens
of the earth to come on in here?
Did you shut it for me?
Yeah, of course.
You know, I don't uh smell
the aroma of vittles cooking!
I don't eat much lately.
What, you living up in here
starving ya self?
It's nothing like that.
Okay.
I'm just not eating heavy food.
I've been eating lite.
Would you like an apple?
I have plenty.
Does it look like I'm on some
kind of diet or something.
It's suppertime.
I'm gonna need something
that's gone stick to my ribs.
Where the meat and potatoes at?
Not here.
I'll go head on back home then.
I uh...
Now I was expecting
to share a meal with you.
I guess I'll see you
another time then.
Say what now?
So just like that you're
gonna kick me out yo house.
Our house!
What you trying
to get rid of me or what?
We don't want company today.
Now who the heck is we?
Now who you got hiding up in
these closet of yours Penelope?
It's nobody here, Jasper.
so you say!
Come on out here so I see you.
I want to know who
this cowardly fellow is.
You need to stop!
You need to get out of my face.
I'll check for myself.
Just stop!
C'mon out here so I can see yah.
I want to know who this cowardly fellow is!
You know what.
Yeah, I, I will, I mean...
You want me to take my hair down?
Okay.
I...
I usually wear it down.
But...
I decided to wear it up today.
Yeah, you like it?
Stop it.
You are so out of order.
Why would I bring another man here?
So ain't nobody here?
He in that basement?
No!
It's time for you to leave.
You overstepping your boundaries.
Look'u here woman.
I come over here whenever I want!
Leave!
We don't want you here.
You have this bad habit of just
popping up when you're not invited!
Ain't this about a blip!
We are separated, remember?
You are my wife.
And don't you forget it.
You are so crossing the line.
Searching my house
like some jealous husband.
Go home!
Ya got my draws fired up something awful.
Now just, just hush up now.
What are you going to do?
You're in my house, on my property.
Your intimidation don't work on me.
Who, who is this?
Who are you?
Where my Penny at!
And, and this is our house.
And don't you forget that.
She's still in the woods waiting
for her daughter to come back.
Yeah.
Well she better come on back to me quickly.
And I, I, I do mean quick.
Stop calling me Penny.
She's dead!
She died with her daughters.
All three of them.
I'm still loving yah.
Honey I mean can't, can't you see that?
What's with this bush wrapped
up in this twine like this fo'?
You doing some kind of hocus pocus
or witchcraft or something.
Is that, is that why you've
been acting weird on me?
There's nothing wrong with me.
Naw I knew something
wasn't right over here.
We want to be alone.
We, ain't no we here!
I thought you were leaving.
Naw, you know what imma...
Imma stay here a spell.
Yeah park my round rump
right there on that sofa till I'm
plum ready to leave!
Stay if you want.
I don't care.
He's not leaving.
Who!
Who you talking to?
Be quiet?
He can't hear us.
Is that uh...
Is that rubber room calling ya?
I'm telling you,
you keep this nonsense up and...
Imma call the white coats on you.
There's nothing wrong with me.
If you don't stop all this crazy talk I...
I'll put you away.
I'm telling you,
I'll throw away the key!
I mean it!
Don't be mad at me
because you can't hear his voice.
I'm not crazy.
Yeah you are.
What the hell is that?
Hi!
Hey.
How you doing?
hey.
Menus here.
Drinks are on one side, food on the other.
Feature menu is here.
Whatever you like, let me know.
Know what you want?
I'll um-I'll have a regular hot chocolate.
Okay. Hot chocolate with cream?
Yeah.
Okay.
I'll take uh a sweet tea.
Sure!
hot tea,
honey.
Okay.
How about English breakfast with honey?
Yeah.
Alright. Well, that would be
$5.89 and I can make them up
and bring them out to you. How's that?
Sounds great.
Okay, great.
Alright, out of $6.
Thank you very much.
♪ Some guy kicked me off
my bike ♪
There you go.
Thank you.
Alright. I'll bring them out.
Thanks.
Not bad, how are you?
You really got your-well
you got your hat...
There's no cream or milk.
Naw that's fine.
Usually, typically it's 3 minutes.
And then you take this and you
go like this, you take this
go like that; then after you
do that you go like this.
Oh, okay. Thanks.
Why were you on the
floor crying a river last night?
What's going on in
that pretty head of yours?
I feel like I'm losing my mind.
Something is in that house
and I can't see it.
I was in the bathroom and it
tried to get in the room.
Now that was just me at the door.
No.
I know what I saw.
You in there sniffing bubbles?
The fragrance got you,
got you doped up with illusions.
I'm telling you something
mystical is happening in there.
Maybe it's time for you to...
get some help again.
You promised...
you would never
put me away again.
Oh, come on, you.
Almost...
Almost gotcha!
Yeah.
This is he.
No.
I left her in your care.
So what happens now?
Yeah.
Thank you.
Hey!
I thought I find you here.
Yeah. What's going on?
Well...
I went over to Mom's house,
and there was no answer.
So I sat...
for hours.
She never came home.
Jasper. I'm getting
kind of worried about her.
You know, the last time we spoke.
Well, let's just say
it could have been better.
I hate to break the news to
you like this son, but.
Your mama gone, and so is your sister.
Gone!
Gone where?
Did they move without telling me or what?
Angels in heaven called them home, son.
What!
No.
What happened to them?
Just calm yourself now.
Just tell me.
What happened?
All I can tell you is that...
She told me...
She just vanished right before her eyes.
She said some demon after her...
took Hailey.
She was gone.
Never seen again.
You believe that?
Well, she believed it
and she went crazy.
Penelope lost her mind Hayden!
Talking to ghosts, and such...
White coats came and got her.
And they took her away.
What?
Now all of a sudden, you can't
understand my speech boy!
The psych keepers.
I had to put her away
so she could collect some sense.
Really!
She was losing her
raggedy mind up in that house.
I had to do it now.
I...
I feel mighty guilty for what I did.
I saw her and she was...
bound up, chained like some darn dog.
When did all this happen?
It's uh, awhile back.
About three months ago.
You know, she's always been
a tad touched in the noggin.
Three months!
Why didn't I know about this?
I'm telling you now.
Alright.
She turned into a lonely tune on me.
A plum D nutcase!
She was talking to nobody and
and listening to nothing.
Now, I'm telling you, son.
She had a couple of screws
loose up in that head of hers.
She went crazy right before my eyes.
I didn't know what else to do.
I tried calling you.
You didn't answer your phone.
So, let me get this straight.
So after all this time,
you didn't try to call again?
I didn't have time to.
I needed to get my mind right.
Alright.
You don't know what it's like over here.
You just don't know.
No.
You had time.
You just didn't choose to take it.
You weren't here.
You don't understand it all.
It was so much going on.
I mean, she said she was...
hearing voices in her head.
Hailey could see them.
You say what now?
She said something was in the house.
Lord hold my hand tight, and calm my mind.
Are you kidding me?
All this trickery
of my mind, it ain't right.
Son, I'm telling you it ain't
right. Do you hear me?
Oh, I hear you.
Are you listening to me?
Cuckoo birds whistled a special
tune just for her ears to hear.
It's like she was talking to
the ghost and...
and listening to it.
Tricks!
Yeah, all the poof now you see me,
now you don't. What was going
on over there, huh?
How she up and just disappear?
I don't know.
All that uh...
dabbling in the spirits...
stirring up spooks and stuff.
I mean, I don't play
that kind of games boy.
No.
It wasn't nothing like that.
With my own two eyes, I saw her.
Yeah!
I saw her twirling rocks.
And, and burning sage all over the house.
Like a like a witch from hell.
If it was a spirit she was talking to,
she brought it there;
conjuring up the unknown, boy!
That's where you're wrong.
She was scared, Jasper.
Scared of what?
She was burning it to make sure
the spirits would go away.
They were in the house.
Jasper she was trying to protect Hailey.
It's got my mind spinning boy!
It's got my mind spinning.
I mean she said that
they were whispering in her ear.
What kind of nonsense is that?
Maybe they did.
Are you crazy?
You been spending so much time
with her that
the crazies that latched onto you.
How dare you.
She was my mom.
Yeah It sounds like a hereditary situation.
I'm done.
Now wait, now wait Hayden.
Listen to me.
Little girls...
don't just go poof and vanish into nothing.
I mean, you do know that, don't you?
All I know...
is that my whole family's dead.
Son you're not alone.
I'm still here.
I ain't going nowhere.
What good is that?
You locked my mother up
because she was full of grief.
Are you kidding me!
Just now calm yourself.
That's not going to happen.
I still love you.
You're my blood. My only son.
My only son.
My mom...
was scared...
living in the house by herself alone.
And nobody tried to call me.
Nobody...
tried to find me.
Scared.
So you and Jozetta just keeping
your mom secrets, huh?
Secrets.
It was plain to see, man.
You know what?
It doesn't matter.
Everybody's dead.
What's really in the woods, Jasper.
I know you know the truth.
You just mind your business.
Alright, just let it be.
You still won't tell me.
Why our kids being kidnapped.
Hey, you let it be
and just let the dead
lie in peace!
You know what, I'm done!
What are you doing?
Banging on my door like some fool.
How'd you even know I was here anyway?
I didn't.
You weren't home so...
I figured you was here.
Look Jasper!
Those things are real.
Boy, I ain't in the mood
for no riddles, now!
What kind of sense of humor you got?
What is your marbles rolling
on the floor or what.
Something is in the woods.
Calm down now.
What you out there
doing on my property anyway.
Those things in the woods.
Say what now?
You got some kind of...
monster back there hiding in the woods.
Just what did you see?
It's not about what I saw.
It's what I felt.
See you being nosey,
bout got you killed.
You satisfied now?
No!
It like to bit you in the buttocks
or ripped your head clean off.
Didn't I tell you not to go out there.
You know, you lucky you
didn't get dragged away...
disappearing into the darkness.
What the heck is out there?
Why can't you mind your business boy?
Ain't it enough that it chased
you out of there.
Something invisible is out there.
Invisible.
So now, now you,
you feeling invisible things.
Does that make any sense to you?
Does it?
Stop pretending that you don't
know what's going on.
Okay, It's snatching up bodies
and you know it.
How many people must die
before you confess?
You need to hush up!
Count your blessings.
And don't go back out there.
And if I do?
Foolish people do foolish things.
Are you a fool?
No, I'm not.
Okay.
Alright.
Well, you might not make
it out there alive.
Listen here.
Listen to me clearly.
I ain't about to go
out there fetching for ya.
Ya end up...
cooked goose
just like the rest of them!
♪ I saw a Buddha on a
dashboard the other day ♪
♪ Well I rode in a limo once ♪
♪ It was kinda gay ♪
♪ I had to get my pedal bike ♪
♪ Just so I can say goodnight
to you ♪
♪ Riding late at night ♪
♪ Everybody wanted to fight ♪
♪ Some guy kicked me off my bike ♪