Not bad, Maria.
F?r the next time l w?uld like you
to w?rk ?n the intonati?n.
lt's imp?rtant to keep watching how
the bow is sliding ?n the strings.
When you practice, try to accent
the notes as much as you can.
-See you next week.
-Yes, say hi to J?hanna for me.
DARK SOULS
N?, Judith,
you're d?ing it completly wrong.
Yes, you have to put the. . .
Y?u have to put
the cartridge in the printer first.
?hen you must press the little
green button, not the red ?ne.
?he green ?ne,
located just below "power ?n".
?hat's right.
Yes.
Ok, n?w you sh?uld hear
a rumbling n?ise.
Yes, it means that it's w?rking.
Yes. . .
Are you ready?
Are you taking notes?
Good .
Female, in her 20's. . .
Maybe younger.
Yes, that's n?rmal,
it's just the printer warming up.
?he skull looks smashed .
F?und an h?ur ag? by. . .
Wait a second .
Kristine.
-What's the name of the witness?
-Maia Stokke.
Maia Stokke.
D?n't touch anything
before the forensics get here.
N?, we can't, it's imp?ssible
to drive a car up here.
Ask Lars to pick us up
near Vettak?llen.
We will have to perform an autopsy
and inform the family. . .
l'll take care of that.
?i, sweetheart,
did you have a good day?
l h?pe you're hungry.
This is lieutenant Askestad
from the Oslo Crime Squad.
-May I speak with Morten Ravn?
-Yes, it's me.
Good evening, Mr. Ravn.
I have bad news, unfortunately.
S?mething happened?
We found your daughter dead
in the forest this afternoon.
Could you come
and identify her body...
lt's imp?ssible, l just said hell?
to her. She just came h?me.
-Are you sure?
-Yes of course l'm sure!
Wait a second, d?n't hang up.
J?hanna. . .
lt's the p?lice ?n the ph?ne.
?hey found your dead corpse
in the forest!
What sh?uld l tell them?
Y?u must be mistaken,
my daughter is right in front of me.
-Must be an error in the register.
-Yes, check your register.
Sorry...
Goodbye.
J?hanna. . .
Did you fall in the mud
while jogging, ?r what?
?here's food for you in the kitchen,
if you're hungry.
J?hanna?. . .
Are you still ?n the lnternet?
?ELP ME
She's lying here,
in the li?ing room . . .
-l'll turn ?n the light. . .
-What happened?
She came h?me after running. . .
Sat there with?ut saying a w?rd . . .
She jumped at me and started
to ?omit this black substance. . .
-?as she said anything?
-N?. . .
She's breathing,
but l can't find her pulse. . .
But l have something ?n the scope. . .
We're taking her to the h?spital.
Y?u'll be sitting in the front, sir.
-Please?
-Same for me. . .
-We're g?ing to my place. . .
-Y?ur place?
-Where is it?
-Over there, it's not that far.
l have to piss.
?ell??
Y?u fucking prick,
are you watching me piss ?r what!
Seri?usly!
Assh?le! What the fuck. . .
lt doesn't seem right. . .
?rue. Look at this.
Yes, that's her. . .
l d?n't get it.
She's suffering from
some kind of disorientati?n.
?eadaches foll?wed by v?miting,
neurological disorder -
- and epileptic seizures.
-She was dead . . .
l saw it myself.
?he scanner reveals the presence
of a pathogenic ?rganism -
- probably injected
after the perforati?n of the skull.
Metastasis are rapidly devel?ping, -
- damaging
the frontal and temp?ral l?bes.
-Metastasis?
-Mitoses.
Cell degenerati?n.
Cancer!
When?
Ok, l'm ?n my way.
?hanks. Bye.
-D? you think she'll recover?
-N?, l d?ubt it.
?he ?nly certain thing is that
her attacker knows what he's d?ing.
T? drill the skull the way he did
with?ut damaging the brain is a feat.
?ere.
Call me if there's anything new.
Wait!
Y?u're Askestad, right?
We talked ?n the ph?ne last night.
Oh yes, Ra?n.
S?rry ab?ut your daughter.
?his is crazy, isn't it?
Sure. . .
l've never seen anything like this. . .
-But l'm in a hurry, l have to g?.
-But what ab?ut J?hanna?
Y?u're g?ing
to find the attacker, right?
?he assh?le that took away my. . .
Y?u can count ?n us, Ra?n.
Mr. Ra?n. . .
?he results are not good .
Y?ur daughter is very sick.
She has a tum?r
in the central nerv?us system . . .
? tum?r?!
l d?n't understand . . .
? cerebral bi?psy is needed .
We ha?e to rem?ve it.
lt's growing and spreading quickly.
lt's a high risk ?perati?n. . .
l need your permissi?n.
Y?ur daughter has a very small
chance to survive this ?perati?n.
But if we d?n't d? something quick,
her conditi?n might deteri?rate. . .
Dr. ?ansen!
Come quick, there's a problem
with ?ne of your patients!
J?hanna?!
-She w?ke up and jumped ?n me!
-Must be a reacti?n to the medicine.
Well, that's imp?ssible,
l didn't give her anything yet!
What have you d?ne to her?
What the hell have you d?ne to her!
?he corpse arrived very late
and Peter didn't notice that. . .
?hat the girl was still alive?
-Peter is new here, it was late. . .
-l understand . . .
Y?u were tired .
S? you didn't notice that the girl
you put in the fridge was alive.
Y?u didn't even notice when she
wandered ?ut into the corrid?rs.
l understand, you were tired .
Overw?rked .
?hese corpses just arrived .
N? ?ne has touched them yet.
Are you sure
that they are dead this time?
?ave you checked?
?hese are exactly the same w?unds
as the other young w?man.
?he male body has the skull
crushed several places.
?e's unrecognizable.
Autopsy?
N?, like l said
the bodies just arrived .
lf she struggled, there may be traces
of the attacker under her fingernails
Tweezers?
Hi, lieutenant,
it's neurosurgeon Hansen calling.
l'm quite busy right now, so. . .
I must inform you, something
happened just after you left...
J?hanna went into hysteria
while her father was in the room .
N?w he refuses to give
permissi?n for the girl's ?perati?n.
He wants to bring her back home.
lt's ridiculous.
But why did you call me?
Well, you could con?ince him
to lea?e her here in ?bservati?n.
We could perform m?re tests,
find ?ut what she's suffering from . . .
lt could tell us
something about the attacker...
Well, it's his daughter,
we can't force him to. . .
?ell??
Askestad?
30 days later
. . .we've never seen
anything like this.
You'd have to be
experienced in surgery -
- to accomplish such horrors.
The inability of the police to
solve the case is also outrageous.
It's a disgrace, and it is obvious
that we need help from abroad.
How many have to die
before the police understand -
- the seriousness of the situation.
Chief commissioner, it's under-
standable that people are scared -
- when you apparently
have no leads whatsoever. . .
We need to relax a bit here,
you're exaggerating a lot.
You're making heavy accusations.
We're doing the best we...
It's the biggest serial killer case
we've had in hundreds of years.
It can be compared
to Jack The Ripper.
And you are telling us
how efficient you are...
You're exaggerating again.
-These are not homicides. . .
-Not homicides?! lt's even worse!
Innocent people are drilled
in the head and are left to rot, -
- and they practically live as
vegetables, rotten vegetables!
They are left in a state
comparable to -
- how the police
are handling the case:
Completly vegetative!
How many victims
are we talking about now?
Well. . . the exact number
of offences is around. . .
"Offences"?!
?he total is n?w well ?ver -
- 30 ?ictims. . .
lt must stop.
?he chief commissi?ner
is ?n my back, he wants results.
?he press is all ?ver it,
making exaggerati?ns.
S? tell me, what's new ab?ut -
- this "Toolbox murder"?
Eckhoff, the hardware sh?p lead,
is it g?ing anywhere?
Can l have the pictures, please. . .
We are n?w certain that the killer
uses this particular drill model.
An all-in-one drill.
? comm?n tool,
easy to get h?ld of -
- at any hardware sh?p in town.
We also have a suspect. . .
Kjetil Ulteig.
? soci?path, well kn?wn -
- to the psychiatric services
of Osl?.
And he also w?rks
at a hardware store, -
- and has recently been fired .
D? you have
anything better to say, Askestad?
l'll let you know
if l think of anything.
3 days before. . .
?hese patients are stable,
they are completly impassive.
?he agressive ?nes are ?n the floor
ab?ve. ?hey're in padded cells.
Look. . .
?his sample was sent to the lab.
?his liquid is comp?sed of
n?n-oxidized chains of carb?n.
Organic chemistry.
Crude ?ils. Petrol.
?his substance has been taken from
the body of ?ne of the ?ictims.
Actually, it's ev?l?ing inside every
single ?ictim of the attacker.
-Y?u're kidding. . .
-Not at all.
And its m?lecular formula is some
kind of unkn?wn hydrocarb?n.
-Where the hell does it come from?
-Good questi?n. . .
Psych?path still running free
Wanted madman
might be in Sweden
Good afternoon. This is the news.
A young man has been attacked
at his home in Grefsen.
He was severly wounded,
and is now hospitalised.
The police stated that this might
be the work of the same attacker.
At 7 pm last night
the victim's mother came home -
- and found
her son severly injured.
Her son seems to be
victim number 37 -
- in a series of identical attacks
in the last weeks.
Again a person in orange jump suit
was seen fleeing the crime scene.
Apart from that, the police once
again have few leads to follow.
?ry to get some sleep, J?hanna.
Good night, sweetie.
-Good evening, Maria.
-?i.
lt's been weeks since we
last saw you at school. . .
l've had some other things
?n my mind .
l d?n't have time to teach anym?re.
lt's understandable, with all
that's happened and everything. . .
Actually, l came to see
how J?hanna is d?ing.
Can l come in?
Yes. . . J?hanna is very sick.
W?uldn't she be better off
in a h?spital?
Oh n?, n?. We are fine here,
the tw? of us.
She's getting better and better.
lt's ?nly a matter of time.
But you came to see your friend . . .
Wait here a second, l'll g? get her.
l can come back some other time
if she's sleeping. . .
N?, it's fine.
Besides. . .
She doesn't sleep anym?re.
Look wh?'s here, sweetheart!
lt's your friend Maria!
Y?u remember her, right?
D?n't be scared, Maria. . .
She's getting better, you kn?w.
Look.
She can stand alm?st by herself.
Good, that's my girl. . .
Now you understand why
l've put up the plastic sheets.
Yes?
What d? yo want?
What are you d?ing?!
J?hanna, it was him, right?!
We got him, J?hanna.
N?, it's too dangerous. . .
Fuck it.
l'll be back soon.
Come ?n.
Over here.
S?, what's it g?nna be
for you tonight?
Y?u've had a l?ng day. . .
? l?ng day?
D?n't you want
to take off your mask?
D?n't. . .
S?, Mr. Ra?n. . .
What were you d?ing there exactly?
l've already told you,
l foll?wed my daughter's attacker.
One m?re time, from the beginning.
l parked my car near the ?ydro+
factory in the industrial area.
l was just looking around . . .
And then a w?rker appeared
and attacked us with a drill!
l got ?ut of it, but. . .
But instead of lea?ing,
l decided to ?bserve him .
?e left the factory in a Jeep.
-And you foll?wed him?
-Yes.
l foll?wed him
to some kind of motel. . .
l went up the stairs,
hid in a room and . . .
And l saw everything.
Listen to me! l've seen
what they d? to their ?ictims!
Wait. . . Y?u said "thet".
Yes there was an ?ld man
wearing an ?ld-fashi?ned suit. . .
?e was together with the attacker.
?hey had some kind of machine
that sucked ?ut the liquid from . . .
And then they injected
a dark substance. . .
?he same that my daughter. . .
?ere, l took pictures.
Proof of everything l've told you .
Y?u sh?uld ha?e contacted us first.
Come ?n, l' m gi?ing you
evidence ?n a silver platter!
l even marked the p?siti?n
of the factory ?n that map!
Well, good j?b,
inspector M?rten Ra?n.
S? what d? l d? n?w?
Sh?uld l put
all the w?rkers under arrest?
Listen to me n?w.
l'll let you g?.
But you can't leave Osl?.
And stop your stupid quest
for revenge. Let us d? ?ur w?rk.
But l've just found him!
And l know where he's hiding!
l understand what you're
g?ing through. Y?u can g? now.
Farewell.
?i, Maria. . . lt's M?rten Ra?n.
N?, not very well.
Could you d? me a fav?ur?
Excuse me. . .
D? you know another way
into the factory?
Why are you so interested
in that factory?
Are you a spy? P?lice?
My daughter was attacked,
l think the culprit is in there.
l want to find ?ut.
Attacked . . . She doesn't look
so good then, l guess.
l w?uldn't hang around here -
- if l were you,
they're g?nna find you .
Ok, l'll figure it ?ut, thanks.
Wait a second!
l've been unempl?yed
quite l?ng now, -
- so a little help
w?uld be appreciated .
?hat's all l've got. . .
S?rry.
-Th?se binoculars look quite nice.
-Ok, that's en?ugh n?w.
S?, tell me what you kn?w,
poor bastard . . .
?hink l like being here?
Yes, a bastard like you say!
l've l?st everything! My wife,
my h?me, my health, everything!
-Yeah sorry, l didn't mean it. . .
-Thanks to me this country is rich!
Me and some other di?ers. . .
lf it hadn't been for us, you
w?uldn't be sitting in your ?illas -
- drinking B?rdeaux, complaining
ab?ut your 6 h?ur w?rk day!
S?. . . you're a diver?
Yes.
l w?rked for ?ydro+. . .
?hank God l'm d?ne with it.
We were pi?neers, you know.
Day after day, 1 00, 200, 300 m . . .
Di?ing, drilling, mending,
in the cold and dark sea. . .
l l?st a lot of friends there.
Accidents because of the pressure.
All we got was a pat ?n the back,
and off we went again!
Oil had to fl?w,
n? matter what the cost.
l ended up w?unded
and they fired me.
l tried to w?rk as a carpenter,
but it was imp?ssible!
l kept ?n ha?ing dizzy spells.
Since then l've been
a poor bastard, that's true.
And every night l drown, -
- again and again.
But what are you d?ing here?
D?n't you have somewhere to g??
S? curi?us, so curi?us!
l'm sorry ab?ut your daughter, -
- you seem alright,
so l'm g?ing to help you ?ut.
At that time l had a friend,
a french di?er called Jean.
?e came here for the m?ney,
to become rich.
S? he w?rked all the time,
m?re m?ney, m?re m?ney!
But ?ne day, what sh?uldn't
have happened, happened .
At 300 m depth,
something went wrong.
?e went berserk, and panicked .
?e went up, with?ut any safety stop.
?e cut the safety line, sending all
his colleagues deep to their deaths.
l paid him a ?isit at the h?spital,
and l have to tell you . . .
?e was not the same guy l knew,
my ?ld friend Jean.
?e looked completly empty,
and his face seemed eaten by. . .
l d?n't kn?w what. . .
?e ?omited
some disgusting black mess.
And he kept repeating: l've seen
the Darkness, it's inside me!
l never heard ab?ut him after that, -
- and even th?ugh
he was my friend . . .
l was relieved!
En?ugh ab?ut that!
Where does that lea?e me?
With brain damage and ?n welfare.
But l'd rather be a poor bastard
than end up like Jean.
But that day. . .
S?mething came up
from the abyss. . .
l d?n't kn?w what it was.
But it was not ?il.
l d?n't want to kn?w!
N? ?ne must kn?w!
J?hanna?
lt burns. . .
My God . .!
J?hanna!
?he patient in bed 3
keeps ?n throwing up.
Start the projector, -
- so l can synchronise my speech
with the pictures.
Wendy?
-Wendy!
-Yes, Dr. ?ansen?
D?n't just stand there!
We ha?e a lot to d?.
S?rry, Dr. ?ansen.
?ell??
Wendy?
?his came from the lab.
Must be the pictures.
l'm g?ing to check ?ut
this factory after all.
Our dear "inspector Ra?n"
might be right.
Sh?uld l call Eckhoff?
Excuse me? Eckhoff?
After 200 m,
turn left in the roundabout.
Second exit,
then stay on the left lane.
Turn left in the roundabout,
second exit. . .
Take the. . .
Shut the hell up!
Calm d?wn.
Take it easy.
Untie me.
Untie me, you crazy fucker!
l told you to take it easy.
?ell??
Are you ?k?
Maria?
J?hanna?
N?!