Ladies and gentlemen,
thank you for joining us
for another episode of "Edible Desires".
Before we begin, please welcome
my fabulous co-host, Nikki.
- From the outside looking in
it would seem like Nikki has
everything under control,
that life is glamorous, full
of joy, excitement, luxury,
all the things.
And sure, while some of that is true,
there's always more
than what meets the eye.
We often only see the surface layer
and that's for good reason.
Most people don't wanna go deeper
out of fear for what they might find.
Whether it's in their minds
or in their physical existence,
humans tend to trap themselves.
Not Nikki, though.
She will find a way to be set free.
From the outside looking in,
her life could even
seem like a fairy tale.
But every fairy tale has a villain.
- Her boyfriend
Ethan was a genius,
always working hard on the next big thing.
This time it's something
involving binary sound waves.
- Hey, babe.
- Which keeps him
busy enough not to notice.
- Mmm.
- One ordinary day,
while out walking her dogs,
she noticed the most
handsomely attired man.
He looked different.
As if he was headed to a
grand event of some sort.
He behaved a bit like a white
rabbit from a fairy tale,
caught in a time warp
as he stared her way.
Sometimes he visits her in her dreams.
Rose has done a lot for Nikki.
But she can't help but feel
like there's more out there for her.
- Who would have thought I would have
to give up these so soon?
I knew you'd be popular.
You are quite different from the others.
Oh, my sweet Nikki.
- Rose.
You protected me.
When I was lost, you took me in.
I'm never gonna forget that.
- Your parents would be so proud.
If only they could see you now.
- She remembered
how one naughty man
played very mean with her.
He gave her nasty medicine
and left her behind like a broken doll.
Maurice still haunts her.
She really believed that he
was a good man deep down.
Will she ever heal from the trauma?
- Ladies, I've worked
very hard on this piece.
You've all been paid well.
I hope you're prepared.
The premiere's tomorrow.
No, no, no, don't nod.
I sing, you repeat.
I sing, you respond.
Respond.
- No say.
- Si.
I sing, you repeat.
I sing, you respond, respond.
- No say.
- To papa!
- Layabout,
- Remember her, Sarah,
this is the female form, a divine nimbus.
- Oh!
- I'm just gonna tickle you!
- How's it coming along?
- It's not good.
I have my presentation
for the grant in two weeks
and I'm shit creek fucked!
Can you hear those damn dogs barking?
It shouldn't be happening.
Not at this frequency level anyway.
- You're gonna figure it out, don't worry.
You're too smart not to.
- Wish I could take you with me
to the review board.
Yeah, I can get this.
- Ethan!
Honey, are these yours?
Wow, what is this place?
- Nikki, wake up!
Are you okay?
Wake up, it's me.
It's okay.
Hey, come on, come on, breathe.
Come on, it's okay.
- Getting tighter.
- I got you.
I got you.
It's okay.
It's okay, I got you.
- One is told
to stick to the devil
they know best.
But what if one knows multiple demons?
What to do?
- Tomorrow, let's go to our favorite spot
for a nice picnic.
You need some rest.
- Why so disappointed?
You know I can't give you them all.
Overhead is high, I'm losing money.
All the hotel rooms for you girls, rent.
Credit cards, security, travel,
dining, car leases, fucking cat food.
The new girls especially don't
have their shit together.
He's calling again, isn't he?
- Who, Maurice?
Unfortunately.
I've changed my number three times.
He just does not quit.
At least he stopped threatening
to barbecue my dogs.
- You have that effect on people.
- I make them wanna murder my pets?
- No, but you're dangerously enchanting.
I'm shocked that more of your clients
don't take things too far.
Does Ethan know?
- Hell no.
After what happened last time,
Ethan would castrate him.
- Maybe that would be for the best.
You have to think of your own safety.
- Maurice is harmless.
Besides, Ethan is so stressed
out with work right now and
the last time those two had an encounter,
one was in the ER,
Ethan was in handcuffs.
I have enough drama in my life right now.
- You know what's best, you always do.
Just let me know if you'd like me
to speak to Maurice, I
can be very persuasive.
- I will.
- Come on, boy.
Come on, go on, go fetch it.
Go on, go on.
Oh, boo boo.
- Hey.
- Hi.
- The last few months have
been beyond intense, huh?
I don't know how you're not burnt out.
I could barely drag my ass
out of bed this morning.
- Trust me.
I share your exhaustion.
But I don't know.
Ethan wants me to go
away with him somewhere.
What's going away somewhere gonna do?
It's not gonna change anything.
- I just wanna be free.
You know, I had this dream last night
that I was flying.
And I was hovering above the earth.
And I saw my mom down there
and she was waving and calling to me.
I just wanted to sweep her up
and take her with me.
But then, for some reason,
I just, I passed her by.
And then when I looked back, she's gone.
What do you think that means?
- It means you should stop
fucking your therapist
and actually talk to
him about your problems.
- Then I would have to pay him
instead of the other way around.
- A dream
child wandering to a land
far and new.
A friendly chat with bird or beast
and hath believe it true.
- What's that from?
- It's this poem.
I had to memorize it for an English class.
You know, it pops in my head
whenever I get really stressed out.
It just relaxes me, makes me feel better.
- You are one strange girl, Nikki.
- The strangest.
And that's why you love me.
- Sit.
I told Amy you were an eager one.
She has weaseled her way
into your mind, hasn't she?
She's playing us against each other.
Just give me two weeks
and this whole town will
be crying out your name.
You'll become a fucking
legend, I promise you.
Ah, you're a stubborn one, aren't you?
Just like your father.
- My father?
How'd you know him?
- I'm shocked.
You've forgotten?
Ah of course, you were very, very young.
Rose took you in
and raised you as if you were her own.
Of course, she had her
best interests in mind.
There are things going on here
which are way beyond your control.
There's things you could
never even have imagined
in your darkest fantasies.
Watch your back.
- Come.
Come here, come here.
Quick, quick, quick, quick, quick!
Before they see you, come, yes.
Yes, yes, come.
Come, come, come.
Come inside.
You're safe here.
Yes, yes, yes.
You've been through quite the journey.
You look famished.
- Where?
- Here, have some tea.
Yes, yes.
All better.
- Who are you?
- Who am I?
Who are you?
- Oh, enough with this nonsense.
I have zero tolerance for games.
- Ready to play?
- You're not making any sense.
- Oh, but I am.
All sense is nonsense.
Where did you get this?
- I don't know.
- Here.
Yes, yes.
Here, here, take this too.
You won't need it.
Until you do, until you do.
- Which way does this thing go?
- Any way you like.
Up, down, left, right, in, out.
The only difference is it
makes no difference.
- I must be dreaming.
- But how can you dream
when you're not asleep?
- This is batshit mental ward crazy.
How the fuck do I get out of here?
- Where do you wanna go?
- Anywhere.
Anywhere but here.
- But which is it?
Anywhere?
Or anywhere but here?
Whatever choice you make is right for you
but I must say if you go right
there's a mad being there today, yes.
- A mad being?
- Yes.
- Okay then I'll go left.
- No, no, no!
Don't go that way.
That's where she is.
And she's even madder.
You see, we're all mad here.
Oh, I have something for you.
Yes, yes, yes.
Yes, yes, yes, here, here.
Here, take it.
Here, yes, yes, yes.
Open it, open it, yes.
It's for you.
- An invitation just for you.
- For you, it's for you.
- The queen wants to see what you can do.
Join us for the Red Rose Roy.
- Join us, yes, yes.
- And happily dance the night away.
Look, I'm not really into dancing,
and yeah, have fun in your tree.
- Travel well.
Bye Nikki!
Bye!
Be safe out there!
Goodbye!
Bye, Nikki.
Come back soon.
- Why were you in the water?
I got you.
What's happening to you?
Nikki, talk to me.
- What?
- You were underwater
I don't know for how
long until I found you.
You seem lost, not there.
I'm worried about you, Nikki.
I can't lose you.
- I'm fine, I'm fine.
- But I saw you.
Still, motionless, almost dead.
Your eyes were open but you were gone.
Why were you trying to drown yourself?
- I wasn't.
I'm the happiest I've ever been, okay?
I love my life.
I don't know what happened,
I must have blacked out or something.
- You're working too hard.
Fuck, we're both working too hard.
Look, soon as I get that grant money,
I wanna take you somewhere.
Somewhere special, okay?
Just you and me.
- Sounds good.
- You had me worried.
- Nikki closes her eyes
and the memories of the night are erased,
if only for the moment.
A new day begins and a
chance for redemption,
another chance to prove
something to herself.
- Please, and lock it.
Scene one, take one, mark.
Traffic.
- And action.
Ladies and gentlemen,
thank you for joining us
for another episode of Edible Desires.
Before we begin, please welcome
my fabulous co-host, Nikki.
All right, let's get to it, so.
You have some dough here.
Add some nuts to it, right?
Again, mix it and mix
it and mix it, right?
Now, give me your hand, okay.
We're gonna put together okay?
Okay, slowly.
Yeah, that's enough.
- Cut.
And action.
- Oh, right.
See?
Mmm.
- Cut.
Yeah, put it back in her mouth again
and take it out again.
- Cut.
- Oh of course, to the camera.
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
- Got it.
Oh, oh, very nice.
See?
Surprise.
Good?
Mmm.
- Cut.
You got it, you got it.
- Where do you want my face?
- Cut.
- Don't listen to Edna.
All that sow does is sit
around on her fat ass,
eating away at the profits.
This is showbusiness.
But if you want to join
her sideshow, be my guest.
- Believe me, I don't.
I'm loyal to Rose.
- Don't even mention that
manipulative cunt to me.
We could have run this town.
But she'd rather sit on
her antique high horse
judging people who
aren't stuck in the 50s.
Maybe I'd buy her a rotary phone
so she can call for help
when she's going down, pfft.
- Sure, she's old school but
she's always been like a mother to me.
I can't leave her now.
- Don't you see you're
just a payday to her?
But to me, you're a star.
Rose doesn't care about
you or anybody else.
She's using you.
Come with me, Nikki,
and the world is yours.
So we have a deal, no?
Kay, bring me the FCDA document.
- The document, sir.
- Welcome aboard.
- How could you?
How could you turn on me like this?
- But Rose, I, please-
- No!
I don't wanna hear it.
What's done is done.
I would have expected something like this
from Sarah or Greta.
But you,
I always held you so high.
You're my baby girl.
- Rose, I have to do what's best for me.
- Save your excuses.
I know how it is out there.
Whatever!
I don't have time for hurt feelings.
Let's have a drink.
For old time's sake.
Could you go any more slowly?
Get down, down, down boy!
- Yes, my lady, sorry, sorry.
- That's all, now bark!
Bark!
Do you know know how to bark?
Have you not heard a fucking dog?
- Woof, woof!
- Woof?
Woof woof?
- Woof, woof, woof!
- Now crawl, get out, get out, get out!
Crawl, crawl, not walk,
crawl, crawl, crawl!
We've had relations.
You know.
To new beginnings.
- Rose gave
Nikki her first taste.
She'll never be the same.
- Swallow.
- Silence in court!
Silence!
The court has come to a decision.
Nikki, as punishment for her crimes
must give eternal servitude to the queen.
Any failure to do so
or attempt at escape will result in quick
and painful death.
- No!
You can't do this!
- Court in session, silence!
- Silence!
- There is an exception if you so please.
If you can complete the queens challenges,
you'll walk free.
But if you fail to do so,
you Nikki, will be sent
to eternal quarantine.
What is your decision?
- Bring it on!
- Let the challenges begin!
Now let's see what you're made of, haha!
- 3403N, 118
15W, what city?
- Madrid!
- Oh, you call that sportsmanship?
- 4331 12N,
122 40W, what city?
- French lick?
- Oh, that's just childs play.
Cut your head off!
- 5033, 23 56E, what city?
- Chicago!
- Two looks hate.
- 4880, what city?
- London.
- 832N, 86, what city?
- Los Angeles.
- How can this be?!
- The queenie pie is crying.
I thought this was your queendom.
- This magical
green substance is her escape.
It seems to make everything okay
at least for the time being.
- Welcome.
- We've been expecting you.
- Such a pleasure to see you.
- Right this way.
- You honor me.
You honor my family.
- Welcome, Nikki.
Fantastic to see you, come have a drink.
- Ah!
There you are.
I thought you'd never come.
Didn't anyone tell you
this was a mad party?
A party of epic proportions
and tea party!
- Hey oh, wasn't my fault that I was late,
I tried to be here on time.
But it's not my fault, it's not my fault.
Everything was set,
everything was planned.
There was this thing,
this thing in the road.
And a tree, there was a tree and a thing.
There was a thing and a tree and a lady!
This old lady was in the way,
I couldn't get around her, I tried.
I really tried, I tried to get around her
but no no, she was in the way.
But I had everything set today, set, set!
I was late, oh,
I'm late!
- I love tea parties.
Hooray!
Woo, woo!
Now we can begin.
Ladies, gents, let the show begin, woo!
- Are you okay, honey?
- Yeah.
I'm fine.
Go back to sleep.
- The dreams
are getting more intense.
It's hard to tell what's real anymore.
Will she decide to stay
in this fantasy realm
or will she face her true reality?
Behind the glitz and glam
there's a darkness that follows her.
A world where she's a prisoner
stuck inside her own mind.
- A toast to my darling Nikki!
- Detached from true
feelings of love and peace.
Where will she go?
- Well what do we have here?
You guys started without me.
- My name's Maurice.
Thanks for coming tonight.
Yeah, this is Greta.
We used to perform together.
- You're new here, aren't you?
- I think so.
I'm not sure.
- You must be.
I'd never forget a face like yours.
- I think I've seen you someplace before.
- Of course you have, darling.
I'm quite famous.
- Let the show begin.
- Is this my sweet prince come to save me?
Ooh.
So strong.
- Maurice is here.
And somehow he seems different.
- Ooh.
He likes you.
Wow, oh, oh.
- I loved you.
- But now I'm gonna hurt you!
- Wha, wait a minute.
That's it, okay.
45, 76, one.
And 110!
That's it!
That's it, I did it!
I did it!
Yes! Yes!
Oh god, I can't believe it!
Woo, woo!
I did it, I did it!
Yes, woo, woo!
Haha, woo!
Yes!
You first, then you!
And you mister, I want
to hear you all together!
One, two!
Yes! Hahaha!
Ah!
I can't believe this.
- Are you okay?
Good.
'Cause you're on in five.
- Nikki knew in her heart
something was off with Greta.
But she just trusted.
They were friends no matter what.
- Bravo!
- Why is he here?
He would never be invited to such a party.
- Bravo!
Bravo!
- Chap, chap,
chap, chap, chap, chap,
chap, chap, chap, chap, chap, chap, chap,
chap, chap, chap, chap, chap, chap, chap!
- Wait, wait, wait, wait,
wait, wait, wait, wait.
Oh, look at this.
Have a fish, really good fish.
Try, try, try, try.
Yes, kissy, kissy, kissy.
Need some spices.
Hold on a second, hold.
Okay.
Wait, wait wait.
Last one, last one, last one.
I can live with that.
All right.
- Taste this!
You sick, maniacal fuck!
Bastard!
You sick fuck.
You maniacal motherfucker.
You bastard!
- Get your hands off him!
Who the fuck do you think you are?
You think you can just come into our world
and destroy everything that
Kemper and I have built?
- You ungrateful harlot.
Did you forget about
the contract you signed?
You're mine now, forever!
To do with as I please!
You'll soon learn your place.
- How could you do this to us?
To me after everything
that we've been through!
- I don't know you and I
don't wanna fucking know you.
You stay the fuck away from me!
- You've left me no choice.
You shouldn't have done that.
- Nikki, darling.
It's a shame we could not work things out.
You had so much potential.
- You've ruined everything.
This was our shot at the big time.
- Finish her!
- No!
I'm so sorry.
I feared this was going to happen.
I should have never left your side.
What should we do?
- Let's teach that
self-righteous prick a lesson!
Sweet dreams, asshole.
- Nikki
started at the beginning.
She's reached the end and
now she's ready to stop.
No longer stuck in her mind.
Her body no longer merely a toy.
The power is hers, free.
>>>>oakislandtk
www.opensubtitles.org