One evening in November ...
- Wait. Be careful!
- Yes.
The security guard will pull
down the gate in 5 minutes.
Look! They are leaving...
- Betty! Betty!
- Bob!
Come over here, quick!
Take the car-jack.
Shit, I didn't know about this.
- Goddamnit.
- Come on... let's go!
Stop the car! Stop!
Are you crazy? You gonna kill him!
Betty... Betty, what's wrong with you...
There's another one, let's have a look at him.
It's Fletcher. I'm afraid he's dead.
THE ROADHOUSE OF THE VIOLENT DOLLS
After she was sentenced to 10 years in jail
for robbery with death of a policeman,...
...Betty Williams was transfered to the
women's prison in Balmoral in January.
Already the first months in
this evil and terrible environment...
...turned her into a tough,
withdrawn and embittered person.
There were still no leads of the
whereabouts of her lover and accomplice.
That's how it seemed at
least, until one day in spring...
Attention!
- Come on, hurry!
- Keep your mouth shut.
Don't you want to know
why you are being transferred?
I stopped asking questions.
You are becoming more reasonable.
You can get some facilitations for that.
The C Block is our 'high-end area'.
No solitary confinement.
I'd prefer to not get beaten up.
That totally depends on you.
We can't treat you like a raw egg.
One can get along with me.
Your new 'apartment'.
This is lady Esther and princess Sylvia.
They belong to the high nobility of shoplifters.
Get along well, girls! Don't let them ruin you.
My name is Betty Williams.
- Is this luxury couch available?
- Yes.
We have heard about you.
10 years, that's a lot.
I have to do 3.5 years.
We are repeat offenders, you know.
It's my first time in jail. I wanted to rob some
jewelry with a friend of mine and disappear.
And we wanted to get married
and buy a shop in Rio de Janeiro.
They guy has stood you up, huh.
They have never caught him.
Should he get himself caught then?
He would have got life for killing the policeman.
- There is nothing else he could've done.
- What? That's what I call love.
And now he is in Rio without you.
- And in Rio he is grabbing someone else's ass.
- You...
What do you want, huh?
Don't get all upset.
What do you know? My Bob is not in Rio!
We are no longer interested in
gentleman stories anyways.
If we would think about men in
here as well one would go crazy.
- Am I right, darling?
- Yes, for real.
Huh, so that's how it goes.
Yes. If you are nice to us
you might have some chances.
- Not with me. I'm totally normal!
- Oh, how original.
I don't deserve to be in here one minute.
I told you a thousand times that I'm
innocent and how everything happened.
Oh, of course. We are all innocent in here!
You didn't sell any cocaine. The others
over there didn't steal anything...
...and my child drowned
by accident in the canal.
You are disgusting!
- And who else complained about me?
- No one. You know that everyone is afraid.
But if another report goes to the
Ministery you will be into trouble.
Sometimes you beat them pretty bad.
I manage a prison and not a hospital.
You know that excessive punishment
corrupts them even more.
As long as we have to lump
together hookers, thieves,...
...killers and notorious criminals
there's nothing we can do.
They all corrupt themselves without our doings.
But sometimes we can help them.
Bullshit. Who becomes a prison ward, huh?
There are only a handful of trained prison wardens.
Superintendent Nipple. What?
Take all three to the watch point.
I'll pick them up myself.
What happened?
Three of the new ones were caught at the main gate.
The stupid cows were hiding inside the trash cans.
This hasn't happened in ages.
Yes. And we will make sure that it
won't happen again for a long time.
Let's hurry up girls!
- The others have to get in here, too!
- Same thing every morning...
- Stop it!
- Open your mouth
- I like to hear you sing so much.
- Watch it, you stupid bitch.
- What's going on here?
- Dirty dog! - Jane!
And you?
- What is this?
- It's my fault. I slipped.
How clumsy...
Beat it!
... lied to and cheated.
He had killed his father if he had come...
...I didn't want it ...it just happened
...I don't even know...
You can go and ask them. I don't want
to leave. They will forget about me...
I have to get out of here and
see him. It doesn't matter how.
Keep quiet. You've gone crazy
since I told you where Bob is.
- Did you see him again?
- No. It's a long way from here.
- If me and John hadn't happened to just pass by...
- And you really think that he didn't recognize you?
I didn't say anything to him, because of John.
He didn't even pay me any attention.
I told you that he has changed a lot.
He calls himself "Hill" or something.
Maybe I'm wrong. But the big scar on his hand...
That's from the robbery, definitely.
The area makes sense, too.
He knows his way around
up there from the time...
Listen Judith, you have to help me.
I don't want to get
sucked into this, understand!
John and me want to get married this year.
Shall I write him a letter about
you being an ex-prostitute?
What do you want from me?
Are you still the last person to
leave the department store?
Let the delivery entrance
unlocked over the weekend.
Visiting time is over!
Come on! Hurry up! Let's go!
Hurry, hurry! Faster!
Make yourself comfortable.
Or are you afraid?
Pour us a drink. The scotch is great.
There you go. I dont like it if
someone is just messing around.
We are all grown-ups. Why all this foreplay?
I've liked you for a while.
- Forget about any stupid ideas.
- You bitch!
Keep quiet! I'm getting out of here.
- How did you get hold of the keys?
- If you do what I say I'll help you.
Isn't this the coat from Nipple?
I hit her over the head.
She will be sleeping for a while.
They gonna catch us in no time.
It's all planned out. We'll get new
clothes and a car at a department store.
Then we drive up to the Highlands.
Bob works there as a barkeeper.
He will help us. Hurry up!
- With no money?
- I know where we will get some.
If we keep on talking they will catch us.
I hope that Williams will get us out of here.
Let's go.
Hey. All dressed up darling, huh.
But you wouldn't leave without me, right?
Hurry up and open the door.
- And if I don't do it?
- I scream and all hell will break loose.
Come on, let's hurry up!
And what about her?
She has to come with us.
She has heared everything...
...and if they interrogate her
she will tell them everything.
Don't, I'm afraid!
You are not gonna ruin this for the rest
of us, if have to break your neck myself.
Come, hurry!
Come on, let's hurry up!
Hm, she is still not giving her
control sign. Oh, there she is.
Something must have happened.
Let us in! Anyone who tries to stop
us will get a hole in their stomach.
They gonna lock you up again anyways.
If you go back to your cell I won't say anything.
Shut up! And no tricks.
Hurry up!
This one is for the first gate and
the staff entry in the back yard.
- No one is there right now.
- The guard there will check every 30 minutes.
I should shoot you in the back of the head.
Leave it. We tie them up first
and then tie them to the big pipes.
You are stuck here.
Make sure we don't have to go
back because it didn't work out.
If we run into one of the guards I'll shoot you.
You better make sure we don't get caught.
She'll sleep until we are gone.
Hurry up!
If the door is really open
do you know where to go?
- I've worked on this plan for 3 months!
- Someone is coming.
Let's get in here. Hurry up!
Shit! The night watchman.
- Is he on patrol?
- No, he is laying eggs.
Hide somewhere so he can't see you.
Let me tell you one thing: If you keep on
being this scared we gonna leave you behind.
Pull yourself together and don't be hysteric.
If he notices something we'll pull him inside
and say 'Good Night' to the night watchman.
Holy shit. That was close!
Hurry up.
Choose whatever you like but pick some
proper clothes and put some in a suitcase.
We have to be out of here in 10 minutes.
Let's go.
All the cash registers are empty.
They are not gonna keep them all
filled up over the weekend just for us.
If they have my size?
Maybe there is a safe in one of the offices.
Sure, but unfortunately
I'm a tailor and not a locksmith.
Maybe Jane can bite it open?
Somehow we'll get some money.
Better hurry up, this is not a fashion show.
Oh girls, finally I'm wearing real clothes again
and I feel like a real human being again.
- Hurry up.
- Yeah, yeah.
...failed catching the three women that
broke out of the prison yesterday evening...
The public has been warned. The women are armed
and we are worried that they will use their guns.
The murder of Francis Nipple, the manager
of the prison shows how relentless they are.
- She was...
- You goddamn liar!
No we are deep into it because of our "Gold Betty".
- The stupid cow killed Nipple.
- I knew it.
But they can't blame us for this.
Exactly. It's my problem and without
me you'd still be stuck in this cage.
We should kick you out you crazy bitch.
All you want is to inherit some money
and get in bed with a guy again.
Shut up and check what's going on over there.
Shit, the cops again.
- What are we gonna do?
- I'll get off this road.
If anyone want's to split they
can go. It's not far to the police.
Hurry up, we have no time.
We have to change cars.
- Yeah...
- Calm down. We are all gonna stay together.
It feels so good to be free again.
I'd rather played another game with you, Jim.
Well, I'll drive over to Marsh Village then.
- Business comes first.
- I'm not too keen of your services, Oskar.
- You think they have any money?
- No, too risky.
- Maybe there are more men inside the house.
- There couldn't be too many men if you ask me.
Look. The car with the old guy.
He is probably well known among the
locals so they most likey won't stop him.
- Your hearse needs a lot of gas.
- Yeah.
I have it since the war. An American
traded it for some homemade brew.
Maybe that's why it's drinking so much gas.
Well, hopefully the coffin has the right size for her.
Worst that can happen is that
she has to take off her high heels.
- Bye bye.
Do you need any help?
That's right! We need someone who can
get us through the police checkpoints.
Well, sure. You are the five
girls that escaped yesterday.
- How did you make it all the way up here?
- Don't ask any questions.
And remember this: If they catch us
you will become your own customer!
We gonna hide behind your seat and don't
forget that you have four guns pointing at you.
Get in there and behave yourself!
Let's go!
Where are we?
On the road to Dunbar.
It's another 30 miles to the coast.
You let us out at the Sheephelm Woods!
- But then you let me go, ok. I'm a poor man.
- Too bad!
- We thought you were Aga Khan.
- I won't say anything.
Alright grandpa. We would kill the cops
before they could even breath and you, too!
Yes, I understand. Nothing will happen.
Help! Being threatened! Careful!
Quiet now. Two cops.
I'll get rid of them, watch out.
Close the curtain.
- I'm scared to death.
- Shut up. Stop it!
- Hey guys, what's up?
- Hello, Oskar. Did someone die again?
Yes, over there in the village. It's a sad job.
You get used to it. We are looking for the
girls who caused the trouble in Belmoral.
- Up here in the Highlands, oh dear?
- That's what I said. Just a routine check.
An order is an order.
But we'll be gone in 2 hours anyways.
- Here, please.
- What, your papers?
Who want's to see them.
We know that you are a good guy.
- I thought I'd better be correct.
- You are crazy.
Can't even grab your papers right, huh.
Maybe it's time to suspend your licence.
Ok then, go to your funeral.
Come on, let's go.
Out!
- What do you want from me?
- Let's go!
Come on grandpa. We get you off
the road and then we let you go.
What are they doing with him?
Sylvia, they promised to let him go.
- You can't let this happen.
- Stay here.
- You did it, now we are sitting in the same boat.
- Damn it, don't start arguing with me.
How much longer until we get
to this goddamn roadhouse?
We still have to make it through the marshes.
We will be at the Ellis Inn in one hour.
You should take a gin
as well if David is paying for it.
Thanks, but I'm still on
duty until 5:00 PM. Overtime.
Oh yeah, because of the 5 girls. As if
they would come here to Sheephelm.
If you ask me not even a pickpocket
would come here, it's a boring place.
- I like it here.
- Some fishermen and hunters, that's not much.
When I'm off I drive around here and there.
London isn't the only place
with accomodating women.
Yeah, you civilians have it
easier to pick out the raisins.
Derek, I tell you. The tourist bus
last week was full with Swedes.
Don't believe a word he is saying.
The bus was full with old women.
Hill is anything but a womanizer.
- Thank you, boss.
- You are like a father to me.
I really am. I've treated you like
a raw egg since you came here.
You won't find someone easily who
would run this boring place with you.
- Mr. McIntosh.
- Oh, the Police President in person.
Unfortunately I'm still a Sergeant, Sir.
Well, if you think about it Winston Churchill
was already a Major when he was your age.
And when A.Lincoln was your age, Mr. McIntosh,
he was already the President of the USA.
If you've got nothing in the head
you'll have to become a policeman.
The old deadbeat gets
the worst room we have.
- Good day.
- Good day. Our beloved salesman is back.
- Let me carry up your luggae, ok.
- I don't like people wasting things.
How long are you going to stay this time?
Until I'm done with this area.
I also have women's clothing now,
in case you need something for a girlfriend.
I will get a discount if I spend
one night out of the house, right?
Yes, we take it off the bill. Same
with the breakfast without butter.
And if you don't want
any jam it gets even cheaper.
That sounds good. Gluttony is
unhealthy but austerity is a virtue.
You are very friendly Mr. Ellis.
Shabby freeloader.
Betty! Betty, how did you get here?
- You have no idea what I've been through.
- Be quiet.
Who told you where to find me?
Are you one of the five who escaped? Betty!
Is that all you have to say?
You have to understand me. If they catch you they
will get me too. You have to leave immediately!
I didn't come alone.
You have to help us, Bob!
Since our trouble back then I've been hiding.
No one knows who I am.
You have to try it elsewhere. Betty!
- Bob Fishman!
- My name is Bob Hill!
- You know that I'm not alone.
You will hide us here
and try to get us some money.
But what about David Ellis?
We are waiting in the barn. Make sure that
no one finds us and that we get some food.
Do you think I went to
prison to be sent way now?
Don't try any tricks. If they
catch us they will get you, too!
- We'll discuss the rest at the barn.
- Betty, what are you thinking?
What are your plans?
We gonna kidnap Mrs. Oland
and get 20.000 Pound.
And with that money
we will get out of England.
Oland? The land owners insane wife? But...
- Hello, Bob? Did someone arrive?
- No, boss. I'm closing for today.
Did she jump straight into
bed with her sunny boy?
And what if she takes off with the guy?
We are right here. He'll come over in a
second. I could talk to him for a minute only.
- And?    - As soon as the old
men is asleep we will see.
- See what?
- I already told you we gonna do this.
We gonna kidnap that rich woman I
used to work for. I've worked it all out.
She has all the money from her husband.
Every day she drives to the doctor in Sheephelm...
...and she visits the cemetery there.
Her name is Marilyn Oland.
Every time you come with
me you mess up my schedule.
Doris always gets me here on time but
with you I have nothing but trouble.
- The doctor will be mad of me.
- Why?
Because he has been making a
fortune from you for years by...
- ...convincing you that you have some diseases?
- It's my money, right.
I'm sorry, Jack. I meant to say
that it's my part of the inheritance.
Masterson is an excellent
doctor and he understands me!
Yes, of course darling.
It's important that you get well again.
You heal the soul with love
and patience and not with medicine.
It was my mistake to not
take the Jeep to run my errands.
Shall I take you upstairs, madame?
For weeks I've been walking around by myself.
I'm not insane so don't treat me like a lunatic.
- May I get the magazines and the usual
things then, madame? - Yes, my dear.
In 30 minutes you'll pick me up again and
then we visit Johnny at the cemetery.
Are you coming, too?
- If I dont get hold up at the police station.
- Of course.
The building licence for the
tractor hall is more important than me.
- If she want's she can walk like a weasel.
- You have to pull yourself together.
- We have to find a way... We have to!
- Go now before we look suspicious.
Money. Always the goddamn money.
- This time you can solve the case in no time.
- Case, how absurd. That isn't even a case.
It is murder! Yes!
The parrot of Mrs. Sweetcake
did not die of natural causes!
Proof it!
Katie Lissat bought rat
poison at the pharmacy...
...although there aren't
any rats in all of Sheephelm...
...and she hated her neighbour's parrot...
...because it used to call her
a dumb Dora when she passed her house.
Ok. I will order a dissection,
cross examine Katie Lissat...
...and get some specialists from London.
Would that be good enough for you?
So you are making fun of me, huh?
Hercules! Come here you bad dog.
Don't try to eat the policeman
or you will get a bad stomach.
What a nice little guy.
You could've given him some
of your ham sandwich.
Then he might like you better.
- He is fat enough!
- And so are you!
- Good day.
- Good day Mr. Woodland.
Good bye Inspector.
- Did she have another horror story for you?
- She is getting even worse.
What can I do for you, Sir?
My gun licence has
expired and I want to renew it.
Masterson says that a change of
scenery would do me some good.
He said I'm strong enough to walk.
I asked him how I should
do something like this.
I can't leave Dolly behind me
with all the terrible people.
Hello Mrs. Oland.
I've been meaning to visit you.
But then the murder of the parrot happened
and I had to take care of Mrs. Sweetcake.
Sure Mrs. Twaddle.
I have to lend you this book
that reminds so much of you.
It's about a woman who tries
to commit suicide after her child died.
Then they put her into an insane
asylum and when she gets released...
...she finds out that her husband is having
an affair with a younger woman and kills...
Oh well, here the story changes and
hasn't got anything to do with you.
But the beginning of the
story has touched me so much.
I can see that. Bring me the book, I'm
interested to find out how the story ends.
Let's go my dear.
Good-bye, Good-bye!
What an arrogant person!
I've locked everything.
I put the pigs head in the freezer.
We can cut it up tomorrow.
- Are you in a bad mood?
- Nah.
I just want to get out of
here again for a day or two.
We aren't busy at the moment anyways.
Sure. So the policeman got
some funny ideas in your head.
Oh, no. I got a message from a friend
of mine. She is visiting Glasgow.
- So I was right then.
- Why?
I thought I heard you talk
to someone in the bar.
No. I mean I got a call.
I was on the phone.
Huh, that's weird. I didn't hear the phne ring.
Do you think that I'm lying?
Why shoud I think that?
It's your business anyways.
Excuse me boss.
I didn't mean it.
You have to get cranky if you don't have
some change. Have a nice two days off.
- Hello, Mr. Ellis!
- Yes.
What does he want now?
The five female fugitives are still on the run!
I invited myself for dinner at a friend of mine.
He lives over in Red Coast.
Right by the harbour. I will
probably stay there over night.
Good for you. I will go upstairs.
Good night gentlemen.
Thank you. People who
sleep can't commit any sins.
- Come with me. I'll let you out.
- Very nice of you.
I've got to take care of
something in the backyard.
Betty, we have to be careful. You
can't been seen outside the barn.
I knew that I can count on you. The others
are suspicious of you. Come with me.
See, this is Bob!
- Well then, good evening.
- Hello, I'm Jane.
Hello, how was the trip?
- Shit! But now we are here.
- Esther!
It's not this easy.
You can't stay here!
And if we lock up the old guy
until we have finished the job?
And if someone asks we tell
them that he is visiting someone.
Doesn't he have anything saved up,
a box of gold or something?
Maybe a handful of change but that's all.
- Who is this?
- This is David.
I didn't know that...
How should I know?
I mean, you could've just told me that you have
friends here and hadn't bothered you, Bob.
You bring in an akward position, boss.
You aren't gonna hurt me?
Of course I'm on your side.
I give you my word. You
can always depend on me!
I never told on anyone.
Why don't you come inside the house
to warm up and eat some food.
- He knows who we are so it's all his own fault.
- Well, I can imagine.
It's in all the newspapers and it
was all over the radio and TV.
- But Bob? What are they going to do?
- Most problems solve themselves.
I think we should make ourselfs comfortable
first and keep our host from betraying us.
I do whatever you want.
Please, come with me.
Sylvia, take the teary one with you.
And we will fill you up with brandy.
- That's what we all should do.
- I will get wasted like a group of Cossacks.
I feel so dizzy. All the excitement.
And the alcohol, I can't take it...
- Thank you. My heart is too old for this.
- What's going on here?
Did I fall asleep?
Damn whiskey!
Shitty stuff.
- Where is...
- Your Adam is upstairs with Jane.
I bet they are playing daddy and mommy.
Open the door!
- You dirty pigs!
- Are you crazy! Betty!
- Don't touch me you dirty dog!
- Stop it!
That's what I went through all of this for?
I gonna kill you!
I gonna kill the both of you!
You dirty pigs!
- I gonna show you...   - Let me exlain.
- She went crazy.
- I gonna bash your head in!
- Stop it!
You are all idiots!
You goddamn idiots!
Let go of her!
Do you want to kill each other?
- Sort it out later.
- We were just talking.
Why all the drama?
- Where is the old guy?
- Downstairs, with Linda.
- Hurry, they gonna be back in a minute.
- Hello, police!
Watch out!
Why are you looking at
me like this? I shot him!
One more or one less doesn't really matter.
What had you done?
Let thim call the police?
Wait a moment!
There is someone.
It's Cooper. He must've seen the
light or have heard something.
You two get her upstairs
and keep her mouth shut!
And you hide the body!
Wait for me in the backyard.
Don't tell us what to do!
You better distract the policeman.
Shut up, you whore!
- Open the door!
- Yes, I'm coming!
One moment!
Stupid lock.
I saw that the light is still on.
Yes, good evening. We were
opened a little bit longer today.
- Why are you still on patrol?
- Because of Oskar.
- Have you seen him?
- Not today, why?
He and his hearse have been
missing since this afternoon.
Danning sent me, maybe
something happened to him.
What should've happened to him?
- That's what I said.
- Coke or beer?
Coke please.
- Oh, you have guests?
- Why?
- Oh, you mean because of this.
- I thought I've heard some women's voices.
Here you go. Well, that's possible.
Mr. Hill where did my...
Good evening Sergeant.
This is Sergeant Cooper.
And this is David's niece.
- It's my pleasure Mrs. ...
- Elders.
Excuse me, I didn't know...
Are you gonna stay for a while?
Only for a couple of days.
Uncle David is in Glasgow.
Our family has inherited some money
and he has to take care of some things.
Until then I will help out around here.
So I was right about the female voices.
Did you bring your sister with you?
Only a friend of mine
but she just went to bed.
My uncle didn't want to
leave me alone with Mr. Hill.
Yeah, yeah good old Bob.
You might meet her if
you come back tomorrow.
We were celebrating and
she had a little bit too much.
- Smart uncle David.
- May I make a call real quick?
- You can call right here from the bar!
- He's under the table.
I can call from here, just want
to know if there are any news.
Hello? 0-1-1.
Yes, please.
Hello, Inspector. Cooper
here, I'm at the Ellis Inn.
No, no one has seen him.
No, nothing. Ok, Sir. Excuse me?
Ok, boss. I'll drive down to
the moor and then come back.
- Excuse me miss but I have to leave.
- See you tomorrow then. Good night.
Good night, Sergeant.
See you tomorrow.
Good night.
- Is he gone?
- Yes, he is gone.
- But this guy has to go as well.
- Bob has to get rid off him.
It's too dangerous today.
It's gonna be tomorrow soon
and we have a lot of things to do.
There is room enough in here.
- You got some nerves!
- And tomorrow I gonna need them again.
And now I need a couple of hours of sleep.
No... No...
- What's the matter?
- It's all good between us again.
I don't know.
I don't even know if I'm still able to love.
We have to go through this together
and then forget everything.
Forget?
How could I forget?
My faith in a way to a better life, huh?
The prison? Full of meanness,
perfidity and hatred. And Nipple...
It was self defense. What else could you've done?
Yes, I just fought back.
Also against two old
man reporting us to the police.
To bring us back to this hell.
And the realisation that I don't
mean anything to you anymore.
- No, Betty. You have to...
- Yes, I know it.
All my life I have fought against everything.
Against my parents and against
everything that made sense.
Against people who
only had the best intentions.
But I never fought against
one thing: The bad and the evil.
- Try to get some sleep.
- Not everyone has the same kind of morals.
Everything that happens in
the world is good for something.
What I did, too?
And what I will do, too?
Because there's nothing else I can do
and because there is no turning back.
Get lost! You annoying thing!
Hercules! Come to mommy.
Leave this whiskey bottle in a uniform alone.
Maybe it's time I order
you to give him a muzzle.
Sure, muzzles for the tax payers and
muzzles for people who voice their opinion.
As long as we have you no one
will dare to come to our area!
I doubt that. Have you
taken care of the new murder yet?
Who is it this time? The teacher's goldfish?
Or the pastor's guinea pigs?
Mr. Oskar has been missing since yesterday.
I would be worried about that. Even if I
was a cop who doesn't use his brain!
Good day Inspector!
Please, Mrs. Ellis.
You don't have to wait on me.
I'm always allowed to eat in the
kitchen when your uncle is here.
But today you will be spoiled!
I'll give you a first class service.
What could make this morning better
after I've already made your acquaintance?
I will try to get my commissions
done real quick today.
Maybe we can have a
little chat later tonight, huh?
And maybe I'll get to meet the friend
of yours Mr. Hill was talking about.
- Sure, Mr. McIntosh.
- "McIntosh", please call me Lupus.
Lupus is latin for "The Wolf".
Ok, Lupus! We have to clean up
around and you are just in our way.
Oh, I'll just take a lemonade
out of the freezer then and leave.
No!
Don't!
We just put fresh game in there
and it has to freeze properly.
- The lemonade is outside at the bar!
- Thank you. I'll grab one for my route then.
See you tonight then, Mrs. Ellis.
Good day, Mr. Hill.
- What an idiot!
- Do you think he recognized anything?
We have to hide the old guy somewhere
else. Let's put him in the storage room.
Bitch is freaking out,
maybe she's gone crazy.
Grabs my gun and wants
to do things her way now.
Give me the gun and
don't freak out here.
Do you really think they'll take you
for Queen Elizabeth in that outfit?
They'll catch you right away
and then they'll get us too!
- Don't come any closer or I'll shoot!
- What the hell are you doing?
There is nowhere to go without any money.
We have enough problems already!
I want nothing to do with you! Maybe it's
not too late for me yet if I turn myself in.
I won't tell anyone where to find you.
And if they tear me to shreads.
- But let me go!
- You stay with us until everything is over!
Come here, give me the gun!
Stay there. Stay there or I shoot!
Shoot!
Shoot at me if you dare!
Why aren't you shooting
you stupid thing!
Don't try anything like this again, understand!
- Stop!
- Oops! Hello. What a greeting.
You probably wanted to hug me, huh?
Please, don't let me stop you.
I'm Gary Cooper, the nicest
Sergeant in all of Sheephelm.
And I'm the only one.
Good morning beautiful
man. This is my friend.
- You scared her like she's seen Dracula.
- I'm sorry, it's only the uniforme.
Hey Gary. Starting early today?
- Any news about Oskar?
- No, that's why I'm driving over to Red Coast.
Maybe police headquarters
will have to take care of it.
Let's have a drink!
Just one wrong word
and all hell breaks loose.
Would be a pity for the
nice little man, right?
Do you want to see the area
or have you been here before?
No, never. This is the first time.
Hopefully not the last time.
I don't know anyone around here.
I just happened to come here by chance.
Well, this policeman right
here is pretty impressed.
I'm off in two days and it would be
an honour to show you around.
Oh, yes. I'd like that very much but
I don't know if we... If I'm still here.
You can be happy to see something Mary.
Otherwise you'll just sit around here and...
...you don't have to be afraid of
this heavily armed James Bond.
We are not armed, but I guarantee
that I will bring her back in one piece!
Right, you poor guys don't
even carry a revolver.
No, only on special occassions.
But you remind me that duty calls.
Thank you Bob! Good-bye Mrs. Linda.
And don't forget our 'date'.
- If you like, huh?
- Good-bye Mr. Casanova.
That's what they call love at first sight, huh?
I'll take you to our other couple.
I hope they don't find the coffin
maker before we are out of here.
I have to be in Sheephelm in two hours!
Yeah, that's about
the time she is there.
I asked around and
it's still the same time.
But do you really want to go by yourself?
You are too well known in the
area, but I'll take Jane with me.
You want to take Jane?
Yes. I hate her guts but
at least she's got balls.
The cop is gone.
Betty wants you to join her.
- I've heard everything you coward.
- Why are you calling me a coward?
Because you are afraid of her and...
...because she got you down on
your knees and into her bed.
She is unpredictable.
She could've get us all
caught because of her rage.
Yeah, what if I'd do something like that?
You are way too smart for this.
You know that we have a
whole life ahead of us. Together!
Get some fresh flowers, Miss Doris!
You know what kind.
What are you waiting for?
Take your time. I want to talk a
little bit longer with Johnny today.
I didn't bring you any candy today, darling.
Dr. Masterson is against it.
He says it's bad for your teeth.
Are you in pain again?
Be patient.
It's your birthday next week.
What would you like?
Yes Johnny? A bicycle? You should have it then.
But you have to promise not to ride it too fast!
The son of the Sweeping's family had a fatal
accident with his bicycle. I told you, remember?
Yes. He is dead.
Excuse me, I didn't want to scare you.
I won't do it again. I promise!
Good day Mrs. Oland.
- Betty? - Yes.
- Did my husband send you to pick me up?
- He said we should hurry.
- Did something happen?
You have to tell me. Not like the other time
with Johnny when no one told me anything!
- Has there been an accident, Betty?
- Not a bad one, just a little accident.
- I have to go see him immediately!
- Do you have a pair of car keys as well?
That's ok, the keys are in the car. Doris
can figure out how to get back by herself.
There is someone I don't know.
Does she work for us?
But Mrs. Oland, that's our new cook.
Listen, yesterday's pheasant was
terrible. You have to try harder.
Ok, aunty. I'll try to remember.
Mrs. Oland! Mrs. Oland!
To Mr. Jake Oland. Urgent.
Hercules! What's the matter.
Come back here!
What are you sniffing around for?
Ugh, Hercules!
Stop it. Come back here you dirty dog.
Betty is back! She parked the car inside
the barn. I've seen her from upstairs.
We have to get the old guy out of the
house. In here it's too dangerous.
Esther is with the old woman.
We can take care of the old guy later.
- Alright then.
- Where did you take me?
I don't understand.
What is this about?
I want to go back to my husband now!
Alright, but you'll have
to stay with us for a while.
How dare you!
Who are you anyways?
The new cook my dear.
And if you don't do what
we tell you I'll beat you up!
- Bring her upstairs into room # 5.
- You are hurting me. What have I done to you?
- Did everything work out?
- For now at least...
He should've got the letter by now.
It's gonna be a nice surprise for Jake.
If you want to get back
your beloved wife well...
...and alive put 20.000
Pound in small denominations...
They say they are going
to kill her if I call the police.
- And if it's a trick of hers?
- No way. I know her better than that.
- The letter is real, Doris. Real!
- What are you going to do?
Whatever they ask me to do. I will not call
the police to not risk the life of my wife.
I will come up with the
money and hand it over.
The kidnappers must be well informed.
But not well enough!
I don't understand.
- You don't have to.
- You wanted to tell me something?
Don't worry about it. I will do
what's best for the both of us.
Murder!
Don't think about jumping out
of the window. It's pretty high.
Our darling want's to get back to
her husband in one piece, right?
But not before he gives us the money.
And that wouldn't be very good for you.
Of course Jake will pay for me.
He would do everything for me.
I hope he doesn't forget Johnny's birthday.
Our son wants a bicycle.
He is a very nice and good kid.
Leave her alone.
- Mine would be around 4 years old now.
- Why did you do it?
I hated it. I didn't
even know who it was from!
Three drunken sailors raped me. One after
the other. And no doctor wanted to help me.
My boyfriend was in the military when it
happened and I wanted to keep it a secret.
- Mr. Hill. Help me! - What's going on?
- You have to call the police!
A terrible murder in the marshes...
his dead body... Mr. Oskar...
I found him. No, Hercules my dog has
found him. Oh my God, how terrible.
Calm down Mrs. Twaddle!
I'm alone here. Mr. Ellis...
I know, I know. Cooper told me.
We have to call him. Quick!
Dead! He is dead!
- I've seen it with my own eyes!
- Maybe you are wrong.
No, believe me! You have to call the police
and they have to search the whole area!
Maybe the killer is still
hiding somewhere around here.
Calm down Mr. Twaddle.
Here, have a drink first.
Here we go.
I go and call the Inspector.
Hello? The police please!
Yes, hello. Is this you, Inspector?
This is Mr. Hill from the Ellis Inn.
I'm with Mrs. Twaddle.
She has found something terrible.
Not far from here.
The body of Mr. Oskar. Yes. Yes.
You are coming? Good.
We are waiting for you.
The Inspector is on its way.
Excuse me, I'll go and change my shoes.
Here, have another one.
It will do you some good.
Murder! A real murder. In Sheephelm.
Hercules! Come here!
Damnit. Hercules what's the matter?
She wanted to call the police
but I distracted her for a while.
But once she realizes that the
Inspector isn't coming it's all over.
- You have to get rid of her.
- Not her too.
But we have to do something.
She mustn't be by herself for too long.
What are you doing? This is
Mr. Ellis' place! Here, have a look.
Stay inside, goddamnit!
Please help me! Oh my God!
Calm down. If you keep quiet
nothing will happen to you.
No, don't touch me. Don't
touch me! I don't want to die!
No! Careful!
What is happening here?
I have got to say this is a nice evening.
I haven't been entertained
like this in a long time.
- Cheers, Lupus!
- I never drink this stuff.
You are a drinker just like me!
We even have the same moves.
I don't even know why you
are treating me like this.
It's for being a regular customer! I can't let
you go up to your room all sober, can I.
That's right. Never sober!
But you still haven't
introduced me to your girl friend.
She went to bed a while ago. She isn't used
to the country life. But we'll do it tomorrow.
- Am I not good enough for you, Lupus?
- No, not like this. You have to come closer.
But Lupus! Mr. Hill could be back any
minute. He just went to the kitchen.
He can stay where he is! Oh, I'm sorry.
- I didn't mean to... Excuse me.
- That's ok. I get new glasses.
- Just calm down. Ok?
- Ok.
I'm all calm.
We gonna party. With Lupus
McIntosh, the pride of Scotland.
I think he is finally totally drunk.
There has almost been an accident.
We have to leave in a couple of
minutes to pick up the money.
Give her the sleeping pills
if you are staying here alone.
I'm on it.
Take these Mrs. Oland
and you will fall asleep. Good sleep.
And when you wake up it will be all over.
He is falling over any minute.
That's how drunk he is.
Good for him.
You filled him up pretty good.
What's the matter?
Oh, am I disturbing you?
Well in that case, good night everyone!
Stop him!
Someone is sitting on the toilet!
Sorry, wrong room.
Lock him in his room! And get Jane
down here! What about Mrs. Twaddle?
I got rid of her.
- And the dog?
- What do I know.
Shit, this is risky. We should've
taken the drunk guy's car.
The car will show Mr. Oland
that we really have his wife.
- No one is out on the streets around this time.
- What if he is waiting for us with the police?
It's my game! And my stakes!
We'll be there in a minute.
- I can't believe it worked.
- Check if the money is inside.
- Do you want me to count it?
- What for? We can count it at the Inn.
He wouldn't dare to rip us off.
Now all we have to do now is
find a ship and sail southwards.
- It's not over yet.
- With money you can do anything.
We have to leave the Inn immediately.
Bob should've prepared everything.
What about Mrs. Oland?
We just leave her there and once she
wakes up again she can walk home.
If she wakes up...
Have you ever seen
this much money at once?
Let's count it!
Damn, I don't believe this.
He fooled you like the worst idiots. Not
even the notes on the top are real ones.
- What the hell?
- This dirty dog!
Stop it! Stop laughing!
What's going on?
War? Goddamn it!
Oh, a thunderstorm! What the
hell is all that noise downstairs?
I have to go to the toilet.
Sir, are you always screaming around like this?
There are other guests too. Behave yourself.
You fucking idiot!
How did this happen?
She is dead!
I don't know. Maybe it was the
excitement or the sleeping pills.
This place looks nice.
Go and ask them.
We can't keep on driving.
Emily needs a bed.
The night is almost over. I don't know
if I can get someone to open the door.
The light is on and it's
probably not too expensive.
Hello! Please open the door!
Please let us inside!
There is someone inside but
maybe they don't want to upon up.
Try again!
Let me through.
- But he has seen us from the outside.
- Doesn't matter.
We can't need any company now.
Mrs. Oland is dead, too!
What happened to her?
What if it's the police?
We can't look suspicious. Go up to
Esther's room. Betty you go to the kitchen.
- Thank you very much. We thought you are...
- We are closed. What do you want?
Excuse me, I thought
I had seen someone.
Maybe, we are completely full.
You can stay in Sheephelm.
Good morning!
Thank you for letting us in.
Here, you left the bag
with the money in the car.
My name is Haynes.
This is my wife and my daughter.
Could you make some
tea for them please.
Unfortunately we can't stay here.
They are totally full, Anne.
That's too bad. Maybe we
can get something for Emily.
I can make you a tea but that's about it.
We have been driving for 9 hours.
We are taking Emily to a specialist
at the hospital in Glasgow.
He will operate on our little
girl so she can walk again.
We had to borrow money from everyone
we know. The operation costs 2000 Pound.
Don't worry.
I'll hold on to the bag real good.
Oh, the little girl is sick. I had no idea.
How should you?
But she will be well again, huh.
Well, in this case... I give
you a room that was booked.
You can have a rest
there for a couple of hours.
Thank you.
- What do you say. That's really nice of him.
- Yes.
- This might get us out of here.
- Yeah, maybe.
If we make it to Red Coast,
Freddy can get us...
...across the canal
if we give him some money.
- And how do we get their money?
- When they are sleeping.
It's almost day. The night is almost over.
I know, I'll put something in their
drinks so they fall asleep faster.
And I'll make some sandwiches
they can take up to the room.
- Good morning!
Here is the tea. I will bring
the sandwiches in a minute.
The boss is making them.
Just a moment.
Here you go, this will make you feel better.
- Did you recognize her?
- Who?   - The girl!
Betty Williams the alleged killer of
the prison manager is still on the run!
Yes, you might be right.
Or maybe she only looks like her.
It's her, I'm sure.
Paul, we have to warn the guy.
Maybe she swindled her way in here...
Anne, let's stay out of this.
Let's pay and go.
Here is a little snack for you.
I'll show you to our rooms in a minute.
Good that you are here.
We have to tell you something.
Anne, please.
The girl that brought us
the tea. I recognized her.
We have to do something. You were so
nice to us. I thought you should know.
Too bad. You better hadn't
stopped here. But don't get upset.
We want to get out of here
without any trouble. Betty!
I have good ears. You are reading too
many papers. We'll have to improvise then.
Hercules, where are you coming from!
Hercules, come here! Hercules!
Mrs. Twaddle! Mrs. Twaddle!
Are you here?
The cars are ready! We go together and
the other three follow us in the other car.
Jane and us take Mrs. Oland's car!
Take the child and let's go!
No, don't! Don't take the child!
Take the money and take me
with you but not the child.
Mommy what do they want from us?
We have to make sure you are
not sending the police after us.
If we make it to Red Coast without any
problems we will let her go! I promise!
Here. Take it! Why don't
you shoot. You bastard!
You'll get the child
only over my dead body!
We'll see about this! Come on, Bob!
- Leave me alone.
- Oh no.
The child stays here! You animals!
Shoot!
I only wanted to help.
Hurry up! Let's go!
The car is to slow, they
gonna outdistance us.
- Nah, we know where they are going.
- But they have the money and the child.
If things get tough it will help them to
keep the cops in check. We can't do that.
I wish we'd all day.
When we are in Red Coast you can
go and drown yourself. We don't care.
- Inspector!
- Is it you, Sergeant?
Yes, Inspector!
I've followed the dog to the street,
he is running towards Ellis Inn now.
You go there! I get two cars from the
headquarters and meet up with you.
Ok, Inspector!
- Shit, there we have it. The police.
- Keep on driving right towards him.
- Stop!
- You stupid bitch!
I gonna kill you!
These are the... They are...
I will... I gonna get them.
No, not them. The others. They
have a baby, we must follow them.
What others?
Betty Williams and Bob Fishman
they took her as a hostage.
Come with me, quick.
They are far behind us.
They'll catch up. We are not
gonna waste any time on them.
They can die for all I care.
- When are we letting the child go?
- When we are safe.
I want my mommy.
Please let me go to my mommy.
Of course you'll see your mommy again.
Take care of Mr. Oland.
Yes, we have evidence.
She has been strangled.
- They have forced me. I was so desperate.
- If you are lucky you will get probation.
- You think so?
- Yes, I testify that you weren't an accomplice.
We are still looking for Mrs. Twaddle.
No news from Cooper yet?
We have informed Red Coast. Get back to
me as soon as the child has been found!
We are doing all we can, Mrs. Haynes.
Why don't we drive to Red Coast?
Why not? I can't...
They are way ahead of us,
it wouldn't make sense.
Maybe they are going elsewhere.
Inspector, we just got a report.
Patrol # 3 has caught two of the girls.
- It's Esther Burton and her girl friend.
- At least something.
Well, we still have to write up
your testimony Mr. McIntosh.
Please consider the condition I'm in.
I'm injured, maybe even fatally.
- That's just a scratch.
- That's enough for me.
Are you sure that the man you saw in
the hallway last night was Jake Oland?
Of course!
Are you saying that I was drunk?
Well, if my initials are on it,
the bag must be my property.
Why didn't you tell the police
about the kidnapping of your wife?
- They threatened to kill her.
- And you paid them?
- Of course I did, what do you think.
- In scraps of paper you did.
You must be mistaken. Jake...
I mean Mr. Oland did...
You stay out of it, Doris.
And how do you explain your
presence at the Ellis Inn last night?
- You were there? Jake!
- We have a witness.
And your MG leaves
very destinctive tire marks.
- Does that mean...
- I am afraid so!
Ok. I'll have to come with you then.
I'll just get my coat real quick, if I may.
You better come with us, too.
He isn't here, just a note
that he'll be back soon.
I get the child out of here.
Betty, hide the car behind the
warehouses so they won't it right away.
You come with me! I'm
so used to your company...
...and I don't want the two of
you to be together without me.
Not so fast!
What? The spot is perfect,
no one will see us here.
Exactly. The same goes for you.
You must be crazy. Bob will kill
you if you come back without me!
Hold your breath!
I know that the both of
you wanted to get rid of me.
But I won't let a dirty whore
like you steal my man.
A man I did everything for.
Even murder!
- Betty, don't go crazy.
- My mind has never been this clear.
I know that I still love Bob.
Despite everything.
He will forget you and stay with me.
And we will live together without you.
Stop! Over there!
There's the child with the limp leg.
There she is!
Emily! Goddamnit!
Emily, don't worry. We are coming over.
You stay here. I go!
- Freeze, Fishman!
- Stay where you are.
Don't come any closer!
I'm armed and I can see the child.
Shoot if you want.
If you want to take the risk.
You won't get away with this.
I'll shoot if you don't back off!
Where is my mommy?
I want to go to my mommy!
Pull up the leg first.
Yes, just like this.
Come over. Jump!
Get away there you idiot!
What have you done?
You... You...
He fell down.
Give me the gun.
It makes no difference now.
It's all over.
Stop! Come back here!
Come back!
What are you doing? Stop!
Stop! What are you doing?
Don't look!
You have nothing to be afraid of, Miss!
They will definitely take all the things...
...that you did for Emily and
her parents into consideration.
Thank you, Sir.
It won't take too long, Linda.
And then we have
to have our rendezvous.
The rendezvous, remember?
- Thank you, Derek. Good-bye!
- See you soon, Linda!
Come here you little orphan.
We can need a hardworking assistent.
You damn beast. Get away from me.
Fansubbed by Monstroso & Necropolis
for www.cinemageddon.net
November 2010