It's a scandal.
- A crying shame it is.
Never again will I step in that
church until that creature is gone.
Saints protect us.
I'd have the hair of that hussy.
There she sits.
Pure as a lily.
The devil himself in her eyes.
Oh, you are a dark one, young Miss.
A dark one and a strange one.
- Throw her out.
Get rid of her. It's not the likes of
her that we want. Drive her out of here.
The Priest himself should
be told to send her away.
And high time too.
- Or we'll do the sending for him.
With not a stitch on her back.
Father, we have come to
speak to you about that girl.
Yes. Emmy Beaudine.
- She's got to go.
We've been asked by the women of
the village Father, to speak to you.
We're not going to let our parish
be upset by a girl the like of that.
She is ..
- Yes?
She's what?
Well, Father, she's a bad influence.
She's young, I know.
But the men ..
- Oh. The men.
Well, Father. You know what men are.
Being unmarried myself fortunately.
It's no concern of mine
one way or the other.
Amy is .. peculiar .. very peculiar.
The women see something
in her Father, that's not ..
Not modest.
She unsettles the men.
Father, send her away.
We don't like her here.
I'm aware of this attraction
she has for our opposite sex.
But she's highly strung and emotional.
And she tries to avoid trouble,
God help her. I've seen it myself.
But she's my servant.
Here at least I can
watch her and help her.
I warn you, Father.
We won't have any peculiar
girls in a community like ours.
It's your responsibility.
Get rid of her. At once.
Please be quiet.
I beg your pardon, ladies. I am ..
Forgetting myself.
I know you have the welfare
of the parish at heart.
I know that well indeed, but ..
Let me think.
I beg of you to ..
Let me think about it.
[ Organ music ]
No, Emmy.
Not that kind of music.
I don't like it.
Child.
What is it that gets into you?
Emmy, tell me.
I am always like this
when the organ plays.
Something terrible rises
up in me and I ..
I can't breathe, I can't breathe.
I'm not myself anymore.
I'm all alone.
Father, I'm all alone and lost.
Father, I am not bad.
There's good and
bad in all of us, child.
But while you are in
this house of God ..
Let it be only good.
Good old Ireland.
And you can have it.
You give me the Elephant
and Castle any day.
And what do you say, eh?
[ Gaelic language ]
Sure I will. Be that, be that.
So, three more days and
we're back in England.
Aye aye.
We're here.
It's the fair. It's the fair.
Come on, it's the fair.
Come on, boys. You've
got exactly five minutes.
Listen, George. You get these bills up.
Come on, get on with it.
We've got a lot of work to do.
Well, if it isn't Mr Murdoch himself.
Boy it's good to see you again.
Come and have a drink on the house.
Go on, get us a drink quick.
Look, it's the fair. Over there.
Hello, Betty.
Isn't it exciting. The fair is here.
Come on, Betty. Give us a smile.
What's wrong, Betty?
Aren't you going to speak to me?
My mummy says I mustn't speak to you.
But why, Betty?
I am not so terrible, am I?
Now am I?
Look, do you like my flowers?
They're nice, aren't they.
Well, they're all yours.
Don't you touch my
child you brazen slut.
The sooner you're run out of this
village the better for all of us.
Stop crying you.
I told you not to talk to her.
Go on. Get in there.
Here. What's going on?
You broke it. The glass.
- That's alright.
You want me to go back
and kick the rest of it in?
Oh no.
Okay.
You say the word and I'll
pull the whole shop down.
Here, I was watching you and that kid.
You're not the most popular
girl in the school are you, eh?
They've fairly got in
for you haven't they.
It's just silly.
I don't know what it is.
They're always at me and ..
Well.
Thank you very much for what you did.
I haven't seen you before.
I mean, you're not from
the village, are you?
Not me.
I'm with the fair.
You are?
That's right. I fight.
In the boxing booth, you know.
Battling Dan. The Heavyweight Wonder.
Yes, that's me.
Here, why don't you come and watch me?
Oh, I've never seen a
boxing match in my life.
Well, now is your chance.
You're going to the fair, aren't you?
I shouldn't think a pretty girl like you
would be short of a boy to take her out.
Well, I haven't been asked.
Well, I'm asking you.
Now how about coming with me, eh?
After the fights.
No, I couldn't do that.
- Why couldn't you?
I don't know you.
You'll know me well enough
after a night on the beer.
No. No. Really, I couldn't.
Fine. Then that's settled.
Take your tickets now.
The first bout tonight will
be a middleweight contest.
The first of five bouts.
Between Joe Fisher of Bermondsey.
And one of your own Irish boys.
Lenny Devlin.
Come on, give the boy a hand.
This bout will be followed by a dynamic
heavyweight contest between ..
The Chocolate Drop brought here
regardless of expense from Chicago USA.
He will fight Battling Dan who
recently defeated Billy Chester ..
Heavyweight champion of South London.
Ladies and gentlemen, I present to you
the Chocolate Drop from Chicago ..
And Battling Dan of England.
Give them a hand.
Ladies and gentlemen we are
about to present the evening bill.
Every bout fought according to
Marquis of Queensberry rules.
Get inside. You hunk of Romeo.
Pass along, ladies and gents. Take your
tickets and see this wonderful program.
Possibly the greatest thrill in
boxing that you have ever seen.
Ladies and gentlemen you're fortunate
to come to Murdoch's fair tonight.
Because we have nothing but
the best in every weight and class.
Seconds out.
Time.
What's the matter, Dan? Something wrong?
Fight, you darkie. Fight!
Come on. What's the matter with you?
One.
Two.
Three.
Four.
Five.
Six.
Seven.
Eight.
Nine.
Ladies and gentlemen.
The winner of this contest.
Is battling Dan Lambert.
Hello, Joe.
A good scrap, eh?
- Who for, the girl?
Girl? What girl?
I'm not blind. One more scrap like
that and you go out on your ear.
Now look here, Joe. I was
only playing to the gallery.
You must give the customers
a run for their money.
Don't you worry about their money.
I'm worried about mine.
The Chocolate Kid won't
be fit to fight for days.
Thrashing the life out of him like that.
Listen, Joe.
- Shut up.
You're not punishing my lad so that
you can show off to a bit of a girl.
Who, me?
- Yes, you.
I don't want no boxing Casanova
in my outfit. Remember that.
Where do you think you're off to now?
- I'll be back in half an hour.
Going out for a breath of air.
- So that's what you call it, is it?
Well, see you are back in time.
Because if you are late ..
She can have those beautiful
big muscles of yours.
And have them for good.
Happy?
I've never been so happy.
Not in all my life.
Good.
Well?
Could you have done
better with anyone else?
Go on, say it.
Aren't you glad it was me?
Yes Dan, I am.
Why not let me ..
You?
Better than wasting them
on Betty Grable here.
Well, what's wrong with me?
There is nothing wrong with you, Dan.
Only I don't want to.
You like me, don't you?
Dan, let's go.
Sit down.
What's all this innocent stuff for, eh?
You don't need it with me.
Now look at me, my girl.
Come on.
Pretending you've never been out under
the moon with one of the village lads.
You know.
There is something about you, Emily.
I don't know what it is, but it kinda ..
It kinda gets me.
Yes. Honest, Emily. I mean it.
Yes, I know. That's what
they say to all the girls.
But sure as I'm here it is true.
Yes, you've got something alright.
Emmy.
Emmy!
Hey lads, here's a bit of fun.
Emmy Beaudine.
Let me go. Let me go.
Let me go!
Emmy.
Is something wrong?
No, Father.
It's nothing.
It was dark and I ran.
You've been to the fair.
Ah well. I suppose the fair is the fair.
Come, my child.
I must talk to you.
Come in, child.
Sit down.
Emmy.
There is something I have to say to you.
Something I haven't found it
easy to bring myself to do but ..
I can no longer avoid it.
Emmy.
You've been a good servant to me.
I am going to miss you very much.
Miss me?
Yes, child.
For you are going away.
But I don't want to go.
Emmy.
Try not to make it
harder for both of us.
Try to understand.
For months now your life in this
place has been clouded with hate.
The women, you know, they see
something in you that they fear.
Something.
Unusual and strange that ..
Perhaps only women understand.
So, all this hatred,
all this persecution.
It must end.
I'm afraid, child. I must ..
I must consider the peace of the parish.
And while you are here it
seems there can be no peace.
But don't cry, child.
Look, Emmy.
I've written to some friends of
mine on a farm in England.
Good, kindly people there.
You'll be happy with them, I know.
And you'll be as fine a servant
to them as you have been to me.
But I don't want to go, Father.
I don't know any other life.
Father, I am all alone.
And I have only you to help me.
Please, Father.
Please tell me I can stay.
It's the women.
They hate me.
They always have.
What have I done that's wrong?
Can help it ..
If wherever I go the
men's eyes follow me?
If I go to the village.
The farm boys stare at me.
Men in the pubs look over
their glasses and grin.
There is no mystery in
every word they say.
All of them.
Staring and whispering.
The women.
So dreadful to me.
It is .. it's no fault of mine.
Emmy.
Alright, Father.
I will go.
Here we are, Miss.
Look, that's Larry Tallent.
He'll show you the way.
Larry.
A young lady for the farm.
Come along. I'll take you up now.
Well, come on. They won't bite.
Whee ..
Go on.
Are you interested in sheep?
Oh yes, I eat them.
We specialise in them. We breed them.
You are not from this part
of the world, are you?
No. I am from Ireland.
Why then, you are the new girl.
Here, come on. Give me your bag.
Jacob, take them will you.
We're going up to the house.
- Alright.
There it is.
Well, come on.
They're all in a bit of a scramble.
You know what it's like
when we're shearing.
Come on, Major. Come on.
There's a good boy.
Say, just look what Larry
has found for himself.
One of them is a fast worker
and I bet it isn't her.
It must be the new girl from Ireland.
Come on.
Bess.
Bess, this is Emmy.
Come in, won't you.
We weren't expecting you so soon.
Father Cocoran didn't
say you'd come today.
You're Emmy Beaudine, aren't you?
- Yes. How do you do?
You must have had a tiring journey.
I was a little bit sick on the ship.
Oh. Poor thing.
You'd better sit down, hadn't you.
Bess. Did I or did I not ..
Who's this?
It's the new girl dad. You know, the new
girl Father Cocoran wrote to us about.
Oh.
Well, make yourself at home.
You'll soon get to know us.
You.
You came rather suddenly, didn't you?
I mean.
We didn't know you were coming, did we.
Oh yes, it was all rather sudden.
I'm like that, you know.
Everyone in the village said:
'No Emmy, you mustn't go.
You must stay here with us'.
When I make up my mind
I never waste time.
They liked me, you know.
Perhaps you would like to hang your
coat in the kitchen, would you.
'It was all rather sudden.
I'm like that you know'.
When was she born?
Not what we expected, is she.
- A luscious bit of goods.
Well, if I can help ..
No, I don't want you to start work yet.
Perhaps you can wash your hands
and then I can show you round a bit?
You are very kind.
I say Bess, hurry up with the tea.
The men are parched.
Emmy, you'd better meet Saul.
Julie's young man. You'll be
seeing quite a lot of him.
How do you do?
- I knew I heard your beautiful voice.
Nothing else to do but worry us here?
Nothing else to do? Breaking our backs
out there and not one cup of tea.
Well, don't bother us. We work here.
- Come off it.
Give us a kiss.
- Mind my lipstick.
Don't take any notice of them, Emmy.
When you two have quite
finished spooning.
That's alright. Passes the time.
Take Emmy with you, will you?
I'd like her to find her way about.
Of course.
There you are, Emmy.
See what our farm is like.
Tell me when you're ready for supper.
- Right. Can't be too soon for me.
Come along.
Goodbye.
- Goodbye.
She's a marvel, isn't she.
Wouldn't say boo to a goose.
What do you think of her?
The men will like her.
- I'll say.
Why? Don't you?
I don't know.
You'll feel a bit strange
around here, won't you.
Yes. I've never been
out of Ireland before.
What did you say your name was?
Saul?
- That's right.
The bible says that Saul was a
choice young man and goodly.
Do you ever read it?
Well, not often.
Oh, it's very interesting.
If you know the right parts to read.
Well. How about that.
Bob. Tea is up.
A bit late, aren't you?
Emmy, this is Bob. Bess's old man.
Not so much of the 'old'.
And this is Emmy.
She's the new help.
- How do you do?
I hope you'll be very happy here.
Hang on a minute and have some tea.
And then you can take the cups back.
Forty shearings I've seen
on this farm, man and boy.
And I'll tell you something.
As sure as I'm here, every
shearing brings a wedding.
And every wedding brings a christening.
You've done your share, Jacob.
Well, who's the next blushing
bride for the ball and chain?
Young Julie, eh?
That happy lad yonder is
going to have his hands full.
Don't you look at me Jacob
you old goat. What about you?
Now Jacob, when are wedding
bells going to ring for thee?
Not me. As my old dad used to say.
It's a wise man that chases a woman
but only a fool catches up with her.
Give us a tune.
I'll give you a tune. Here you are.
Listen to them.
Best lads in the country.
Do you like it here, Emmy?
Oh, Mr Tallent.
This is like a home and
I've never had a home.
And you are all such
good and solid people.
I'm going to be very happy here.
Hoy!
Is the Tallent farm
somewhere around here?
Down the road. Over that way.
About two miles down.
Turn at the right fork.
Hey, I said down there.
Don't worry. It will keep.
Emmy is very quiet, isn't she.
- Why shouldn't she be?
Just look in there and see
what she's doing will you.
Oh, Bess.
Yes, Julie?
Oh nothing, Emmy. It's quite alright.
I do wish you wouldn't
make me spy on her.
What was she doing?
- Polishing the silver.
And enjoying it.
You don't like Emily, do you.
- Have I ever said that?
You never needed to.
Your eyes are enough.
Who's that beer for, Emmy?
Why, Larry. In the stables.
Oh.
Will you tell him supper
will be ready soon.
What are you smiling at?
I don't know.
Perhaps I just like to smile.
Now, just what have you got against her?
Nothing.
Nothing at all.
Some beer, Larry?
- I can do with that. Thanks.
Have some yourself.
- Sure, I never touch it.
You don't know what you're missing.
Supper is nearly ready.
I'll be in to wash as soon as
I get the nags out to graze.
Come on, Tom.
There's a good boy. Come on.
Hello, Brian.
Glad to see me, are you Brian?
Come on, here. Look what I have for you.
There. For your sweet Irish tooth.
Hello.
Are Bess and Julie home?
Yes they are, surely.
It's sweltering hot outside.
What do you think?
I wouldn't know.
Whatever you think, will do.
Now don't go.
Is Larry about somewhere?
Strange you should ask me that.
You must have passed him just now.
So, you're not fooling me, you see.
You are very young, aren't you.
Am I?
It's a great pleasure to have
you breathing down my neck.
Like it?
If it wasn't so draughty.
It's thirsty work in
the fields, isn't it.
Why do you ask?
I just smell that you have quenched it.
I never know when you are joking, Emmy.
You are a funny thing.
Indeed. How I must make myself laugh.
Now, you mustn't stand so close to me.
If someone were to come in it would be
a great pity to make a fool of yourself.
You like me. Don't you?
I haven't given it a thought.
Emmy, there is ..
There is something about you that ..
That ..
You know what I mean.
Don't you? Don't you?
Indeed, I hope I don't.
Now I feel it would be much better if ..
Very quietly, you were
to tiptoe out and go.
Stop it.
I don't know what the
devil has got hold of me.
When I come near you, I ..
I don't seem to be able to ..
I never seem to hold myself.
I can't. I can't.
Why are you laughing at me?
Let me look at you.
Then don't joke with me.
You have a very deep chest.
You are stronger than I thought.
No. No, you mustn't kiss me.
You.
Why, you.
Julie, shut up.
- Shut up?
I'll scratch your beastly face
you skirt-chasing cad.
Let me alone.
- Julia, please.
Don't touch me.
- What is all this?
This smirking ape can't be left alone
with a maid for half a minute.
He goes like a bull at her.
You cheap little rotter.
I ought to pull my nails down your face.
- Julie, that will do.
Emmy, come here.
It's not Emmy's fault.
It's that man.
Julie.
You've been making rather a
fool of yourself, haven't you?
Bess, I don't know what came over me.
No, I don't think you do.
Haven't you seen a good-looking servant
before that makes you behave like a ..
A clown with ours?
Sorry.
Now listen to me, you turnip.
You contact a story Julie
can pretend to believe.
I'll do the rest.
Just a minute, Emmy.
I haven't finished with you.
You are by way of being
a bit of a flirt, aren't you?
You shouldn't say that.
Well, I do say it.
And you needn't look so pious.
Butter wouldn't melt in
your mouth, I know.
Well, you don't bring
those habits to this farm.
It's terrible the things you say.
I'm not a bad girl.
What made you leave
your village in Ireland?
Father Cocoran.
- I want to know why. Tell me.
He wrote to you for me to come here.
They didn't like you, did they?
They didn't, did they? Why?
Why?
Leave me alone, can't you.
Where's Larry?
How often must I tell that young
man to be on time for lunch?
Come on, let's start without him.
I'm starving.
Here he is.
Trust him to arrive when
there's a smell of food about.
Say, what do you know?
Murdoch's fair come to Matrick.
Oh, I'm sorry.
That's alright, Emmy.
Feeling a bit off?
Can't have Emmy going down on us.
Well, have you been
slave-driving her, Bess?
Oh Bob. As if I would.
You do look a bit pale, Emmy.
No, I am alright.
Really, I'm alright.
Now, Dad. Just you look at this.
'Murdoch's mammoth fair. Boxing ..'
Don't flap that thing in my face.
Well, you might read it.
Come on Dad. Be your age.
How about you and I hitting the high
spots tonight? Just the two of us.
A couple of young lads on a spree.
- Let's all go. It might be rather fun.
I wouldn't even think of it.
Ha. I'm an Alderman.
It wouldn't do for me to be seen
mixing up with gypsies and the like.
I don't know. It may do you good.
What do you say, Bob?
Alright.
Come on, dad. Stop being chairman
of the gas committee for once.
I repeat, I will not.
- Good. That's settled.
Then, we'll celebrate.
We'll take my new car.
Good grief. It goes.
Goes? What do you mean, goes?
Got it up to 30 on the flat.
Where's your coat, Emmy?
My coat? I'm not coming.
Of course you're coming.
A bit of excitement will do you good.
You've had some chickens in this.
- Don't be so fussy.
Fresh air will soon blow that away.
I don't want to go to the fair.
Please, I don't want to go.
Now don't argue.
You can do with a bit of fun.
Come on, plenty of room on top.
Now then, Larry. No speeding, my boy.
What on earth would I do
with a thing like this?
I ask you. Here, you have it.
- I don't want it.
Don't give it to me. You can have it.
- No.
You know, it will look
wonderful in your study.
Oh no.
Let's all go on the skid. Come on.
Hello, Emmy.
Remember me?
What's this, then?
No glad words?
No welcome for your old friend Dan?
It's a bit of a shock
for any girl, isn't it.
When someone pops up
from nowhere and says ..
'Hello, Emmy. Remember me'?
- Well ..
Do you?
Of course I do, Dan.
I'm glad to see you, only ..
Only you were kind of hoping
you would never meet me again.
Well, you know me, Emmy.
Always turning up like a bad penny.
I'm talking to you.
Look at me.
I'm looking.
That's better.
They told me in that Irish village
of yours where you'd gone.
So I thought to myself, I can wait.
And one of these days
I'll look old Emmy up.
Yes. Emmy will always be glad to see me.
Very likely she'll faint with
joy when she sets eyes on ..
My face.
Eh? Isn't that so?
Dan, I'll see you some other time.
- Why?
Afraid your fine friends
may see you with me?
Because I could tell them one or
two things about you. Couldn't I?
Couldn't I?
Yes. A dark horse, you. Ain't you, Emmy?
Here. You remember this, eh?
Remember it?
You tried to spoil my beauty didn't you.
Well, I haven't forgotten you, Emmy.
No.
You're not the sort
of girl anyone forgets.
Dan, let me be.
I'm happy.
Happier than I've ever been
in the whole of my life.
Don't follow me, Dan.
Let me be in peace.
You're breaking my heart.
Now you listen to me, my girl.
I found out a few things about you
in that village after you'd gone.
Those women knew you, didn't they?
Yes, you're not as simple as you look.
Take your tickets here for the
greatest boxing show on earth.
Once seen, never forgotten.
And that's you, Emmy.
No. It's no use, Emmy.
I can't get you out of my mind.
I ought to keep away from
you after this, but I can't.
I can't let you out of my sight.
It's not like old Dan, is it eh?
To be mad about a girl like you.
Well, you are not leaving me tonight.
Come on.
- No.
Not with your dog. He frightens me.
Okay.
You don't like Emmy, do you?
I wonder why.
Go on, be quiet.
Go on, get back in your corner.
Why, you ..
[ Scream! ]
What's the matter with you?
Yelping like that.
Where's Dan, old fellow? Shut up.
Danny, are you in there?
Dan.
Alright, you're no blinking canary.
Cut it out, will you.
Shut up.
Dad, you properly let your hair down.
What an evening. I'm limping.
Look. Do you think we ought
to go without Emmy?
Lord knows where she's got to
in that fairground all alone.
I shouldn't worry about her.
She'll be alright.
Come on. Jump in, Emmy.
What on earth happened?
Did you get lost in the crowd?
I met a friend.
- Oh? Who?
There was no-one to introduce
us, so I don't really know.
But he was ever so nice and gay.
He took me everywhere.
The shows and the roundabouts.
It didn't take you long
to get fixed up, did it.
Isn't it funny. It never does.
Hold tight. Here we go.
[ Dog barking ]
Just you listen to that.
After the chickens, I'll be bound.
Better go down and see, eh?
- Hmm.
Well, go on.
- Who me?
Go down yourself.
Drat you. Just let me get
this near you, you wretch.
[ Dog howling ]
Get out of it.
Larry. Breakfast, Larry.
Alright. Coming.
Night starvation.
That's what's wrong with me.
Come on, girls. Get in
there. Go on. Go on.
Get in there.
It's alright, Emmy. I'll do that.
Fetch the milk, will you.
Alright.
Where's the towel, Bess?
Bess.
Hey.
What's the matter? You look a
million miles away this morning.
I'm sorry.
- What you been up to?
Keeping the housekeeping money
to buy yourself a new hat, eh?
Bob, I may have been dreaming but ..
Did you hear the church organ
being played last night?
Hear what?
I woke up suddenly.
Must have been about 3 o'clock.
At first I thought I was crazy.
Then I had the oddest feeling
somebody was playing the organ.
It was very soft as if it
didn't want to be heard.
Who would play the organ
in the middle of the night?
But Bess, I heard it too.
Hello, what's up with you?
I thought I was daft. I woke up and I
could swear I heard the organ playing.
So quiet, like a graveyard.
And the moon frightened me so I
put my head under the sheets.
Of all the fishy stories ..
Some joker, I suppose.
Or the Parson stealing
in for a spot of jazz.
It's eerie. It's made me come
all out in goosepimples again.
Hello Dad. Did you hear it too?
Here is some news for you.
There's been a murder near here.
Young gypsy fellow found
dead in Smithers' barn.
He came from the fair
at Matrick so they say.
We were at the fair last night.
- How horrible.
We might even have bumped into the chap.
The things that are happening in this
village of ours. Organ playing, murders.
It makes you wonder what
is going to happen next.
Well come on. Let's have breakfast
before the bacon gets cold.
Get the bread Emmy, will you.
Come on, dad. Spill it. Let's
have the worst of the news.
In a proper state, old Smithers.
No-one likes to find a young
gypsy dead in his barn.
Wouldn't know who
it was but for the dog.
Dog?
- Hmm. A big brute of a thing.
He kept Standing over him.
Wouldn't let anyone get near.
There was a chap hanging
around here. He had a dog.
Up to mischief, if it was him.
He has found it now.
For what we are about to receive may
The Lord make us truly thankful. Amen.
I wouldn't stand there too long.
No?
And why not?
It ain't healthy. You'll have the sea
over your feet before you know it.
Very tricky, these tides.
The sea comes flooding round
the headland there, and ..
Quick as a flash, you'll
be under water there.
Still, you wouldn't expect a farm
girl to know much about tides.
And how do you know where I come from?
Oh, I keep my eyes open, I do.
You work up at the
Tallent farm, don't you.
You are Emmy Beaudine.
It's nice to be famous, isn't it.
Well, I know you too.
You are David Price.
Many is the time I've
wanted to talk to you.
I've seen you here before.
Standing just the way you are now.
Looking out to sea.
Not many people come to this cove.
But you and me have the kind
of feeling it belongs to us.
You do like it here?
It's my favourite spot.
It is so.
I just stand here alone.
Watching that sea come rushing in.
And thinking maybe ..
It's just like me, that sea.
Nothing holds it back.
You would never think
it had such strength.
And then its hands come out and
crash on the rocks and tear at them.
And all the thunder is in your ears.
You know, you are not
like a servant girl at all.
I'm sorry. What I mean is, you ..
I know what you mean.
Then I'm not like any other girl, am I.
Oh. Here she comes. I told you so.
Here, let me help you.
Would you like me to show you
somewhere where it is safer?
Quieter. You know.
Yes. I would like that a lot.
Thank you very much .. David.
'Police enquiries are now being made'.
'Any information should
be sent at once to ..'
David Price.
Got himself into the papers at last.
I know where David is.
- Oh you do, do you?
And where, might one
ask, Mr Sherlock Holmes?
Having a bit of fun in York.
That's where he is.
I don't blame him either.
This village is as dull as death.
People are worried about him though.
It's odd for a lad like David to just
disappear off the face of the earth.
Bob. The earth is big enough
for him to be somewhere on it.
He's only been missing a few days.
[ Dog howling ]
Why, there's that dog again.
They ought to get the
poor creature rounded up.
It's been out on the moor
since that gypsy was found.
Pathetic, isn't it.
It's frightening too.
I can just imagine that ..
Poor brute wandering around the
place where his master was found.
Knowing as little as we do.
I'm getting a feverish imagination.
Saul. Give Julie a hand, will you.
- Yes, right.
Bob .. just a minute.
Don't go yet.
You are upset, aren't you.
A little.
What is it? David Price?
Do you know .. I don't think
we shall ever see him again.
At least, alive.
Don't look at me as
if I were crazy, Bob.
I feel it.
I am certain.
And it's a curious thing.
Whenever I think of him that
fairground boy comes to my mind.
What was his name? Dan?
There's no connection between the two.
You're letting it prey on you, Bess.
Now come on. Let's snap out of it, eh?
Bob, I'm frightened.
- Hey.
I'm sorry.
I know it's not like me
to be upset this way.
Remember the night I told you the church
organ played and that boy Dan was found?
You're not going to bring
that silly business up again.
I can't get it out of my mind.
It seems to haunt me.
They seem to belong.
What the devil is the connection ..
Between some fathead playing the organ
and the death of that gypsy fellow?
One is just daft.
The other is evil.
Don't you see? They may both be evil.
There is Larry.
You know what's the
matter with you, Bess?
Your imagination is working overtime.
Bob, Bob. Bob!
The barn is on fire. Bob!
Bob, quick. The barn is on fire.
Bob.
Bob, quick. Some fool has
been smoking in here.
Smoking, be damned.
Do you smell that paraffin?
Saul, Julie.
You go and help Bob.
I'm going to get the horses out.
It's no use. We won't do
any good with these.
Get some water on it.
- Come on, Mickey.
Come on, Mickey. Come on.
I'm going to help Larry with the horses.
Come on Julie, get out of here.
Water. Quick.
Bob, the irons are still in there.
Bob, go!
Come on Fritz. Get out of here.
It's alright.
Alright Bob, I'll take him.
- Okay.
Come on, Larry. Give us a hand in here.
Is that better, Jacob?
- Aye. It was nothing but a clout.
The hay is gone.
Right heart-breaking it is.
Planted on you too.
The place fairly reeked of paraffin.
It was fixed alright.
Saul, your hands are blistered.
Nothing to worry about.
- What's the matter with Larry?
What's wrong, lad?
What's the matter?
Larry, what is it?
Better get the police.
We've found David Price.
It doesn't seem possible.
David.
Always laughing, joking.
Now, don't you carry on.
- You can pretend to be brave.
But I'm not.
Don't cry girl. You're just like a tap.
When everybody ought
to keep their heads.
[ Dog howling ]
It's odd, isn't it.
To think that that dog may know.
And we don't.
You look tired, out all of you.
Go upstairs and wash. You need a rest.
Goodnight, Bess.
- Goodnight, Larry.
It's not going to be
very pleasant, is it.
With this .. creature .. in our midst.
Never knowing where
it's going to strike next.
Do you think it's going to
be nice to sit in church and ..
And suddenly look round at seemingly
respectable people and think ..
Maybe it is him.
Maybe.
Bob. I want Emmy to go.
Emmy? Go?
I .. I won't have her here.
She repels me. I can't tell you why.
Has she been impudent?
No.
Bess, you're beyond me sometimes.
I can't make you out.
She does her job.
She's cheerful. She tries to help.
Why you should have such a down
on her I just don't understand.
Bob, please.
- Now don't stop me.
I am going to the police.
[ Dog yapping ]
[ Dog howling ]
What's the matter with you?
You startled me.
I should say someone has
been before me, in doing that.
What have you been up to?
I came across the moors.
That dog.
Followed me.
He frightened me.
- You're back early, aren't you.
Don't you enjoy your evenings off?
We went to the pictures.
Really?
What was on?
Just a minute, Emmy.
Don't go.
I feel very upset.
I should like to go and lie down.
And if you're going to throw
hard words against me ..
It would be much better for
both of us if I were to go now.
I'm very .. sensitive.
And I do my work well, you know.
You do.
If I were to go to your husband and
tell him you're persecuting me ..
You threaten me?
I have my rights.
I try to be helpful.
And you answer me back by unkindness.
Emmy.
Look at me.
They found David Price this evening.
Dead.
In our own barn too.
Whoever killed him tried to cover
it up by setting the barn on fire.
But you wouldn't know anything
about that, would you.
You were at the pictures, weren't you.
What should I know
about a fire in a barn?
David Price?
A wide-set boy.
With his hair curling in the wind.
Little freckles behind the ears.
And dark eyes always
with a smile in them.
You are very observant.
Did you know him?
No. No, I didn't know him.
Emmy, you can explain a lot of things.
But there are some
things you can't explain.
I have felt a sense of horror ever
since you came to this house.
I won't believe you are as naive
as all this. I believe you are rotten.
Rotten, am I?
I may only be a servant.
But no-one ever talked to me like that.
Maybe you're jealous.
Get out of here.
I beg your pardon.
I'm sure I don't know what came over me.
[ Dog barking ]
Let us pray.
I would ask for your prayers
particularly this morning ..
For the repose of the
soul of David Price.
Rest eternal. Grant them, O Lord.
May he, along with all the
souls of the faithful departed ..
Rest in peace.
Let us pray.
Oh God.
Whose property is ever to
have mercy and to forgive.
We humbly entreat thee for
the soul of thy servant David ..
[ Organ music ]
Larry, what are you doing down there?
Bess, don't be silly.
- Take that coat off.
It has stopped now. Do you hear?
Never mind. This boy doesn't set
foot outside this house tonight.
Bess, I don't want to miss the fun.
A whole crowd is going.
Whoever plays that organ, we're going
to pin the joker down once and for all.
Look. What's going on?
Don't we need to sleep? Get back to bed.
Get back to bed yourself.
Listen.
There is someone in the lane.
Are you hearing things too?
- I tell you I heard someone running.
There.
- So what?
Don't get all worked up.
It's no ghost, see.
It is only Saul. We arranged to meet
the next time the organ played.
Saul?
- Let it wait. I'll go.
Good evening. How nice of you to call.
But Bess, I did ..
- Come in, Saul.
Are you coming in too?
- Yeah.
I beg your pardon, ma'am.
We'll wait outside.
Are you coming, Larry?
- Of course he's not coming.
Now don't you boss me about.
We're not married yet.
Bess, don't be a spoilsport.
A crowd is surrounding the church now.
10-1 they'll lay hands on the fellow.
You don't know the itch I have
not to lay hands on you.
That will do from you.
Go and make these idiots some coffee.
Bob.
- Yeah?
Go and get dressed, will you.
You and Larry had better see Saul home.
But ..
It will all be over before we get there.
Alec, see what's going on.
That's a nice thing to come
popping in out of the night.
Take you ugly face away from
that window, Alec Wilson.
I frightened her, I did.
We can't wait here all night.
Come on. Let's go.
What happened?
- They're not coming.
Come on.
Here comes the storm.
I wonder if it will wake Emmy.
Bess is off on her pet warpath again.
Curious isn't it, how soundly she
slept through all this racket.
I would've have thought the noise you've
been making would have wakened anybody.
[ Thunderclap ]
What a night of scares.
[ Organ music ]
Go on.
You go on. Not me.
I got an idea.
- What?
Let's all go in.
[ Organ music. Loud ]
It's stopped. Go on. Quickly.
Look.
[ Thunderclap ]
Go down.
I would like to go to bed.
Do as you are told. Go down.
You were watching through
the window, weren't you.
No.
No, not me.
- Yes you were. I saw you.
Where have you been?
You'd better tell me.
Then perhaps you'd
better not threaten me.
I heard it.
I woke up and heard
the organ play, so ..
So I thought I'd creep
out and see who it was.
I ..
I saw someone run out
of the back of the church.
And go across the moors.
Well.
My heart was banging away.
I was too frightened to
follow all on my own.
Then I saw the men from the village.
They frightened me too.
And I suppose you saw my
husband and Larry with them?
Yes, that's right. I saw them too.
Both of them.
A vivid imagination you've got.
Because my husband and
Larry didn't go with the others.
You needn't pretend any more, Emmy.
I know who's been playing
the organ all these weeks.
It's been you.
- It's a lie.
And you're going to tell me
what's behind this filthy thing.
I'll shake it out of you.
Let me go.
You're hurting me.
- Answer me.
See what you've done to my wrist.
I wish I could make you suffer for that.
[ Dog howling ]
It never leaves me alone.
Never.
A great dog.
Yellow eyes.
Why are you so frightened of it?
Stay with me for a little.
I don't want to go to bed.
When I go to my window at night.
And there's that dog.
Standing in the yard.
So quiet.
Just looking.
And looking.
Emmy .. you are terrifying.
There is something dreadful about you.
Whatever it is,
it's getting out of here.
You'll pack your things the moment
it's light and get out of this house.
You can't do that to me.
I've nowhere to go.
I don't care where you go.
So long as you go.
You are a heartless, wicked woman.
Just throwing me out like that.
I have to have a roof over my head.
Get out!
My notice?
I'll pay your notice.
And don't come to this
part of the world again.
You'll be sorry for this.
Sorry.
Just you see.
What's going on?
What's the matter, Bess?
Not now, Bob.
I couldn't bear any more.
- Well, what is it?
I've just sacked Emmy.
Have you?
Well, that's alright.
Bob.
There's no need for you
to be so upset about it.
Come on.
You need a good night's sleep.
She'll be gone in the morning.
You can bank on that.
You've had quite a day
one way and another.
Larry. Switch the lights
off and lock up, will you.
Yes, Bob.
Major, come on.
Come on, Major.
Time for you to go to bed.
Lie down. Go on, lie down.
Have you behaved yourself today?
I bet you haven't.
Lie down. Lie down. Go on, lie down.
Larry.
You'll catch your death of cold.
Yes. Constable Manley speaking.
Who's that?
George, drat you.
Do you know the time of night?
What's that?
Larry Tallent. Dead.
That girl?
Out on the moors, you mean?
Aye, best thing.
Block all the roads quick.
Yes George, I'll be with
you as fast as I can.
She's out by Loomis's farm.
Out on the moors?
Well, she's welcome to it in this.
Alright lads. Spread out and
keep your eyes skinned.
Come on, gang. Ready, Saul?
I'll get Bob.
- Alright.
Bess.
Don't try to console me anymore, Bob.
You mean well.
Just don't.
You are so quiet and calm.
I wish you wouldn't try
and hold it in like this.
I wish you would cry like Julie.
She'll feel better for it.
I'm not the crying kind.
I've just got to sit.
And think.
Bob. We're ready.
Hello, Bess.
How's Julie?
Better now.
Mum got her to sleep.
I sent the wire to your dad.
The train ought to get
him in by morning.
Thank you, Saul.
Be back presently.
Try and get some rest.
You loved him too, didn't you.
[ Dog howling ]
Yes, Emmy.
I knew you'd be here.
Are you afraid of me?
Why have you come here?
Don't you know?
No.
Don't come near me.
Don't.
I beg you.
Can't you see I'm all alone?
Cold and wet with no-one to turn to.
Not there.
We heard them.
The men in their cars.
All after me.
Hunting me as if I were a beast.
What do you want with me?
What did you want with Larry?
I'm sorry.
I liked him, you know.
You liked him?
Do you know what he meant to us?
We loved him.
All the way here I said to myself.
Larry is gone.
She'll never see him again.
I wanted to kill you with my own hands.
But now.
Now?
You keep torturing me.
And I'm not well.
How could I help the way
a man looked at me.
The terrible things that came over me.
No-one will ever understand.
No-one.
Now, everything is closing around me.
I'm sorry for myself.
Am I going to die?
Don't look at me like that.
I couldn't help it. I couldn't.
Please help me.
I'm not even human when I look at you.
As long as I live I shall think of you.
And hate you.
You killed my brother.
You'll answer for that.
Perhaps he's waiting for you now.
And David Price.
And that fairground boy, Dan.
At least I hope they are.
Now you can go.
Go?
I don't understand.
You will.
Why are you doing this for me?
Get out.
Out.
[ Dog growling ]
[ Dog growling. Loud ]
..r-s..