[Majestic Music]
♪
- ♪The Country Was Big ♪
♪When It Was New ♪
♪The Best Men Was Big ♪
♪And Their Yarns Was Too ♪
♪And Their Tallest Tales ♪
♪Folks Believed Was True ♪
♪So The More They Were Told ♪
♪The More They Grew ♪
♪Davy, Davy Crockett ♪
♪King Of The Wild Frontier ♪
♪History Remembers ♪
♪The Name Of His Gun ♪
♪And Some Of The Deeds ♪
♪He Really Done ♪
♪But Most Of His Chores ♪
♪For Freedom And Fun ♪
♪Got Turned Into Legends ♪
♪And This Here Is One ♪
♪Davy, Davy Crockett ♪
♪Helpin' His Fame
Spread Wide ♪
♪Had A Lotta Furs ♪
♪That He Aimed To Ship ♪
♪And He Set His Mind ♪
♪On A River Trip ♪
♪When A Braggin' Boatman
Give him some lip ♪
♪A-claimin' There Was No Man
He couldn't whip ♪
♪Davy, Davy Crockett ♪
♪Tangling With Big Mike Fink ♪
[Frogs Croaking]
[Light Comical music]
- them Kentucky ants
got a bite like a alligator.
- sure ain't particular
what they chaw on.
- look at that, would ya?
This is the longest hunt
we ever been on.
- biggest bunch of pelts
we ever got, too, georgie.
- leastwise, the heaviest.
Them packhorses is plum
wore out, and so am I.
How much longer you figure
we gotta walk anyhow?
- I figure we'll reach
the old Ohio pretty soon.
- yeah, sure am lookin'
forward to that boat ride.
Nothing to do all day
but sit in the sun
and fish all the way down
to natchez.
That's a mighty good idea
of your'n, davy.
- at least we'll get a better
price for our furs there.
- you ain't foolin' me none.
You ain't thinkin' about
the price of furs.
You're thinking about
all that new country
we're gonna be lookin' at.
[Splash]
Ow!
[Squirrel Squeaking,
chattering]
[Thunk]
Hey, you,
you get away from here.
- just ain't your
night, is it,
georgie?
- I'm gonna turn in
afore something else happens.
[Frogs Croaking]
- them fellas
sing worse than you.
- ain't nothing living
gonna keep me awake tonight.
[Suspenseful Music]
♪
Hey, davy.
- now what?
- there's something
in bed with me.
- well...kiss it good night
and go to sleep.
- [Sniffing]
[Lighthearted Music]
[Extended Horn note]
- there's our boat ride.
- get a move on, mahalia.
It ain't much further.
[Extended Horn note]
- ♪Listen To The Thunder ♪
[Dog Barking]
♪Hear The Winds Roar ♪
[Horse Neighing]
♪Hurricane's A-comin' ♪
♪Board Up The Door ♪
♪Load Up The Cannon ♪
♪Call Out The Law ♪
♪Worstest Calamity ♪
♪That Folks Ever Saw ♪
♪Girls Run And Hide ♪
♪Brave Men Shiver ♪
♪He's Mike Fink ♪
♪King Of The River ♪
- what's goin' on here
anyway?
- I don't know, but something
sure got their fur riled up.
- landin's over there.
- ♪A Real Depopulator ♪
♪Oh, What A Deep
Divin' catfish ♪
- well, boys,
hope they don't run out of
monongahela red eye
this time!
[Laughter]
- ♪Born Too Mean To Die ♪
[Comically Somber music]
- oh...oh!
- that ought to keep her
from drifting.
[Laughing]
- say, Mister,
which one of them fellas
is captain of this boat?
- what did you say?
- he wants to know
who the captain is.
[Laughter]
- how long you bushwhackers
been holed up
in the backwoods?
Everybody knows
who the captain
of the gullywhumper is.
It's me, mike fink,
king of the river.
- well, captain,
meet up with davy crockett,
king of the wild frontier.
- davy crockett, huh?
Well, it sure
is a small world.
You're about a foot shorter
than you ought to be.
- don't worry,
he's still a-growin'.
- I like them yarns
they keep spreading about him.
- mighty hard to live up to
sometime.
- well, I don't
have no trouble
livin' up to mine.
I am the original
ring-tail roarer
from the thunder
and lightning country.
I'm a real snorter
and a head-buster.
I can out-run, out-jump,
out-sing, out-swim,
out-match, out-shoot,
out-eat, outright--
- out-talk?
- yeah, out-talk,
out-cuss and out-fight
anybody
in the whole Mississippi
and Ohio rivers put together.
- mighty interesting,
but all we wanna know
is how far down the river
you're going.
- why, all the way
to new orleans, of course.
Told you I'm mike fink,
king of the river.
This is my own private river.
- well, have you got room for
a couple
of private passengers?
- where you bound?
- natchez.
We got some furs
we aim to sell down there.
- well, you get a better price
for your furs in new orleans.
Tell you what I'll do,
seeing as how it's you.
I'll make you a special rate.
- well, that's mighty
nice of you.
- yes, you and your furs
all the way to natchez,
or new orleans, for only
a thousand dollars hard money.
- why, that's plain
uncivilized piracy.
- [Laughing]
Ain't no question about it.
Now, make up your minds
and let me know afore morning.
You're keeping me
from my drinkin'.
- a thousand dollars?
Who does that big windbag
think he is?
- seems like he told us.
- well, he might be
the king of the river,
but he ain't got
the only boat.
- howdy, there.
- howdy.
- this your boat?
- yep.
Bertha mae out of marietta.
- sounds like a racehorse.
- pretty hard to beat
if she's handled right.
- which way you going?
Upriver or down?
- ain't going no place
right now.
- barrel's marked
for new orleans.
- that's right.
But my crew up
and deserted me.
- what'd they do that for?
- heared about the injuns.
- didn't know there was
any injun trouble around here.
- oh, it ain't here.
Downriver somewhere.
Other side of shawnee town.
Them red devils
are attacking everything.
Flatboats loaded
with settlers.
Even on the keelboats.
Got so bad,
nobody'd sign on.
- don't seem to be scaring off
mike fink none.
- him and them pittsburgh
pole-pushers of his,
they ain't human enough
to be scared.
- looks like we picked
the wrong time
for a boat ride.
- hey.
Are you really davy crockett?
- why, sure.
- I'm captain cobb.
- this is my friend,
georgie russel.
Glad to know ya.
- howdy.
- you fellas
got quite a reputation
when it comes to
injun fightin'.
Now if folks knew you were
going downriver with me,
we could get ourselves a crew.
- what do you think,
georgie?
- beats paying a thousand
dollars...that we ain't got.
- how many men would it take?
- six, if they're as strong
as you be.
- well, if they don't know
any more about boating
than georgie and me,
it'll be some crew.
Better split up.
We're gonna cover the town.
- don't you be a-feared
of tootin' your
own horn, davy.
- well, mind what you
go promisin'.
Don't want anybody to think
this's gonna be a frolic.
- that one's about
the right size.
See you back at the landing.
[Grunts]
Ah!
- ah!
- oh!
[Laughter]
- now, anybody else
don't care for my cee-gar?
- kind of handy with
them fists of
your'n, ain't you?
- I'm better at kicking
and bitin'.
- you're just the
kind of fella
I been looking for.
Have a drink on me?
- you're just
the kind of fella
I've been looking for, too.
Well,
here's mud in your eye.
- wanna know something?
Sleepy little old
river town like this
ain't no place for a man
of your talents.
- Mister, that's a fact.
- have another?
- ha.
- what's your name?
- jocko.
- mine's georgie.
- well, I'm pleased
to meet you.
Ah, it's kind of tasty,
ain't it?
- [Whispering]
That'd grow pink whiskers...
That'd grow pink whiskers
on a hound dog.
Hey, jocko,
how'd you like to see
a little something
of the world?
- what you driving at,
georgie?
- I'm gonna
let you in on something.
Me and davy crockett
is getting up a little party
to take a boat ride
down the river.
- take a what?
- boat ride, on the bertha mae.
Clean down to new orleans.
- [Chortling]
- what's so funny?
- that's the gall-bustingest
joke I ever heard.
Hey, mike!
This clodhopper
is trying to sign old jocko
on the bertha mae.
- you tired of livin'?
Nobody tries to steal
one of mike fink's crew.
- well, how did I know
this little hyena...
This little squirt...
One of your hyenas?
- I accept your apology.
Couple of mike fink specials.
I thought you and
davy crockett
was a couple of smart fellas.
Turnin' me down for a bumblin'
old coot like cap cobb.
You heard about them injuns
downriver?
- yeah, but injuns
don't scare davy none.
Our only trouble is,
we can't get a crew.
- well, you ain't gonna find
no keelboatmen around here.
If any of these cornhuskers
are crazy enough
to join up with you,
you'll end up in a sandbar
for sure.
- yeah, it's risky, all right,
but we get a free ride.
- well, it's your funeral.
[Bubbling, Hissing]
As we say down in new orleans,
bon voyage!
Hey, down the hatch!
- well, I already had
a little more
than I'm used to.
- oh, come on now,
square off.
You're gonna be a river man,
you gotta learn
how to drink like one.
[Drink Gurgling]
[Stomach Gurgling]
[Laughter]
- that's funny.
No sign of my friend russel
anywhere.
- you go look for him, davy.
We'll find the rest
of the fellas you need.
- yeah, it may take
a little persuading,
but we'll have a full crew
on the landin' afore morning.
- mighty obligin'
of you fellas
to join up with me.
- well, anything for you,
davy.
- well, let's get some men.
[Hooting, Hollering]
- yee-haw!
- yee-hoo!
Ha ha!
Whoo hoo hoo!
Yee-hoo!
Hey! Hiya, davy!
- what in thunder
got into him?
- only a couple
of mike fink specials.
- well, georgie
ain't a drinkin' man.
- that's what he claimed,
but look at him!
[Laughter]
- hey, davy! Yee-hoo!
Yee-hoo!
Ah hoo hoo!
- georgie russel, quit making
a fool out of yourself
and get off...
[Laughter]
- oh, leave him
alone, crockett,
he's enjoying hisself!
- ain't had so much fun
since I slid down
old smokey on a barrel stave!
Don't worry, davy,
we'll beat 'em easy!
- beat 'em?
What's he talking about?
Beat who?
- me. Looks like you got
a race on your hands.
- race? What kind of race?
- well, keelboats, of course!
The gullywhumper
against the bertha mae.
To new orleans.
- we can't race you.
- well, that's
what I told him,
but he wouldn't believe me.
Bet your furs
against two barrels
of my monongahela whiskey.
- he knows better than that.
It took us all winter
to get them furs.
- my crew's gonna look mighty
fancy in coonskin caps.
[Laughter]
- yee-hoo! Ah-ha!
Whoo-hoo-hoo.
[Whooping, Laughter]
- george,
get down from there!
[Crash, Clatter]
[Glass Shatters]
[Laughter]
- hey!
Hey, hey,
have a little heart.
That's awful wet!
- if you're gonna be
a river man,
you gotta get used to water.
- I'm awful sorry, davy.
- bein' sorry ain't gonna
get us to new orleans
ahead of mike fink.
- well, couldn't tell him
I was only foolin'?
- you think he's the kind
to let you off that easy?
- no, I don't reckon he is.
I'll never do it again, davy.
- well, you better not.
- now we really gotta
find ourselves a crew.
- well, not in your condition.
You get on back
to the boat and
have cap cobb put you to bed
while I gather up the gear.
- thank you, davy.
You're mighty understandin'.
[Overlapping Chatter]
- citizens of maysville,
you are about to witness
the start
of an historical event,
which may well be remembered
as the classic contest
of all time--
a keelboat race
between the intrepid
davy crockett of Tennessee...
[Cheering]
And the undefeated mike fink,
king of the river!
[Cheering]
- are the captains ready?
- I'm ready.
- I guess I'm as ready
as I'll ever be.
- hey, crockett, might as well
give me them furs right now.
- you ain't won 'em yet.
- well, if I don't,
I'll eat my hat,
red feather and all!
[Laughing]
- one of these days,
that big blowhard's
gonna get what's
comin' to him.
- take your starting
positions.
- stand by!
No, no, no!
[Laughter]
Jumpin' catfish!
Do like I told ya.
Go forward
so we can walk back.
[Laughter]
- now remember, no one starts
until the cannon fires.
- get ready.
- get ready, boys.
[Drum Roll]
[Hissing]
[Boom]
[Cheering]
♪
- ♪Listen To The Thunder ♪
♪Hear The Winds Roar ♪
♪Hurricane's A-comin' ♪
♪Board Up The Door ♪
♪Load Up The Cannon ♪
♪Call Out The Law ♪
♪Worstest Calamity ♪
♪That Folks Ever Saw ♪
♪Girls Run And Hide ♪
♪Brave Men Shiver ♪
♪I'm Mike Fink ♪
♪King Of The River! ♪
- ♪Oh, He's
A ring-tail roarer ♪
♪And A Tough Old Alligator ♪
♪Oh, He's A Bull-nosed Bully ♪
♪And A Real Depopulator ♪
♪Oh, What A Fightin' Devil ♪
♪He'll Spit
Right in your eye ♪
♪He's Gonna Live Forever ♪
♪Born Too Mean To ♪
[Bass Voice]
♪Die ♪
[Laughter]
- it ain't no use, davy.
We ain't gonna catch 'em.
- we just ain't got
the hang of it.
What we need's a song
like they've got.
- well, let's sing one, then.
- ♪He Don't Take Nothin'
From no man at all, ho! ♪
♪The Bigger They Brag ♪
♪The Harder They Fall, Ho! ♪
♪The Tougher They Are,
The louder they squall ♪
♪When They Get Wet Through
In a free-for-all, ho! ♪
♪Davy,
Dave crockett ♪
♪King Of The Wild Frontier ♪
[Continues In background]
♪Ain't No Trick At All ♪
♪To Pole A Keelboat ♪
♪We Can Beat Mike Fink
With anything that floats ♪
♪We Got The Hang
While we feel our oats ♪
- look at them clodhoppers,
would ya?
[Laughing]
- ♪Davy, Davy Crockett ♪
- was I snorin' again?
- on your feet!
They're catchin' up!
- don't strain yourselves,
boys.
They ain't gonna catch us.
[Suspenseful Music]
♪
- wait till they find
theirselves
going down dead man's shoot!
[Laughter]
- stand by!
All righty, let's pole!
1, 2, 3, 4!
1, 2, 3, 4.
- much obliged
for relievin' me, davy.
- how we doin'?
- we're gainin' on them.
They're just around that bend.
- yeah, so's the falls
of the Ohio.
- falls?
- that's what they call 'em.
Actually,
it's a stretch of bad rapids.
Used to be real dangerous
till they put
in the channel marker.
That's funny...
River must've
cut a new channel
since my last trip.
Gentlemen, let's have
a moment of silence
for them poor unfortunates
what took the wrong channel.
[Banging, Cracking]
Hey,
you stumble-footed idiots!
What are you trying to do,
send us to the bottom?
- pass them poles!
- hey, cap.
It's getting rough.
You sure
we're in the right channel?
- jumpin' jehosaphat!
We're in dead man's shoot!
Somebody
must've moved the marker!
[Waves Crashing]
- hey, can't afford
to lose you now, cap.
Better get below.
- hey, davy, look out!
There's a rock dead ahead.
[Waves Crashing]
- pole, you lop-headed
baboons!
They're beatin' us!
- let's pole!
- hey, davy,
we're still leadin'.
We might just win this race.
- georgie, don't go skinnin'
the bear till we shoot him.
- hey, cap, what's
them lights up ahead?
- shawnee town.
And we better put in.
- put in, and let them hyenas
get ahead of us again?
- can't be helped.
Everything below
is soakin' wet,
even our powder.
And them injuns
is apt to jump us anytime now.
- hey, mike, listen.
It sounds like
they're puttin' ashore.
- uh-huh. So are we.
- what? You crazy?
Why, now's our chance
to get way ahead!
- what's the sense
of bustin' our backs
when there's an easier way?
Here, take over.
- pretty late.
Sure hope davy'll
find somethin' open.
If they don't take long,
maybe we can get started again
afore that mike fink shows up.
- ain't no sign of him yet.
Hope they don't sneak by us
in the dark.
[Frog Croaking]
- what's that?
- just an old bullfrog.
[Laughs] If that ain't
just like a city fella!
Don't even know a bullfrog
when he hears one.
[Frog Croaking]
- little old rascal's
getting pretty
close, ain't he?
- oh, the whole riverbank's
full of 'em.
[Frog Croaking]
- what'd you do, fink?
- me?
- yeah, what'd you do?
What'd you do?
- nothin'.
Seems like a couple bolts
rusted off their rudder
when they wasn't looking.
Don't figure it can hang
together too much longer.
[Laughter]
- hello, there!
Come on ashore!
- [Falsetto] Yoo-hoo, boys.
Come on over, boys.
Have a good time!
- we got liquor
and some fine entertainment.
- [Falsetto] We're lonesome
for some dancin', men!
- you won't be sorry!
- well, what do you know?
They made that old cave
into a tavern.
Fetch your poles
and hold her, boys.
- [High Voice]
Yoo-hoo, boys!
- don't overdo it.
They're stoppin'.
You injuns get ready.
- ain't you gettin' mighty
ambitious, mason...
Takin' on mike fink
and his crew?
- we'll take them as easy
as we did the others.
- sure wish we had
some of that cologn-y water.
BOTH: [Sniff]
- yeah.
Ah! Mike, look!
I'm afraid them sir-eens
is gonna be disappointed.
- oh, ain't
that rudder busted yet?
That crockett's
got a real gift
for spoilin' my fun.
- yeah!
- see you gals on
the way back!
- yoo-hoo! Yoo-hoo!
- now to them poles!
- ah, it didn't work,
they're going on.
- they won't get far.
Take the horses.
- stay in the saddle.
Wanna leave
footprints all over?
- injuns! Get braced
for some fun, boys!
[Bullets Zinging]
- this is what
we've been waitin' for.
- carnation, davy.
Can't we let mike fink
try braggin' his way
out of this one?
- yee!
[Shouting, Gunshots]
[Laughing]
- keep poling to 'em, boys!
[Bullets Zinging]
[Yelping]
- where the devil did that
other boat come from?
- don't know, but let's get!
- anybody get hurt, mike?
- how could we?
You chased 'em off
before we got started.
- [Sneezes]
Help, help!
Hey, help!
[Crack]
[Laughter]
Now what made that
bust loose?
- you fellas are sure having
tough luck, ain't you?
Sorry we can't help you none.
Shove off, boys.
We got a race to win.
- that puffed-up polecat
had something to do with this.
Wait'll we catch up
with him again.
They didn't leave nobody
on the gullywhumper,davy.
Now's our chance to get even.
- sure would be easy
to swap rudders, all right.
No, we gotta win this race
fair and square.
- there's a good ship fitter
here.
I'll wake him up
and get him right to work.
- how long you figure
it'll take?
- oh, won't take
no time at all
to hang a rudder.
That is, if he's got one
already made up.
- I sure hope he's got one,
because mike
ain't gonna wait around
once he knows we're here.
[Whooping, Laughter]
- mike seems to be
enjoying himself.
Maybe you and me can keep him
entertained a while longer.
Give us a signal when
you're ready to shove off.
- I'll do that.
- why,
you milk-livered city folk
done been took in
by them tall tales
about this here davy crockett.
King of the wild frontier,
my eye!
There ain't room
in this country
but for one king,
and that's me!
- yes, sir, Mr. Fink.
- why, that squash-headed
beanpole of a bear hunter
ain't no match for my shadow.
I can beat him at anything
you name.
Take shooting, for instance.
Them paper targets he uses,
ain't no test
of a man's nerve.
Now, hold still.
Hold still.
But with a target like that...
If a man ain't awful careful,
he could make
a mighty serious mistake.
- wait a minute, Mr. Fink.
You ain't aimin'
to shoot this off my head?
- that's good whiskey
you're spillin'.
There ain't nothin' to it,
if you'll hold still
like this...
[Gunshot]
- like that, mike?
- lucky thing for you fellas
that mike fink's
got a sense of humor.
Come on, belly up!
Seems like the proprietor's
gone on a sudden journey
and left me in charge.
Drinks is on the house!
[Cheering]
Come on, join us!
- we'd admire to,
but me and georgie
don't hold with drinking
when we got a race to win.
- why, I thought you fellas
would be ready
to give up by now.
- you don't know davy.
He ain't never quit nothin'
in all his life.
- these hillbillies are sure
hounds for punishment,
ain't they?
[Laughter]
Why, we'll be halfway
to natchez
before you get
that rudder fixed.
Come on, boys, drink up,
and let's shove off!
- hey, mike.
I'm surprised at you.
- why?
- lettin' that shot of davy's
stand without no challenge.
- ha ha, you call that
a shot?
Why, any kid
back in pittsburgh
could do the same
if his pa'd let him
waste a whiskey.
- with the same target
you was gonna use?
- yeah. Only I was
gonna do it backwards.
- backwards?
- in the mirror.
Here, I'll show you.
- oh, no, you don't.
- you scared, too, crockett?
- lot of difference between
being scared
and downright foolish.
- all right,
I'll show you a
real trick then.
I'll shoot it off my own hat.
- this we gotta see.
[Lighthearted Music]
♪
Back out of the way,
everybody!
- that's tolerable
good shootin'
for a river man.
- tolerable?
- I suppose you can do better?
- I might just try.
Charge up old betsy for me.
I ain't so sure about this.
Better duck your heads.
[Ping, Ding, ping]
- I just don't believe it.
[Overlapping Chatter]
It is not humanly possible
to leap up
and catch a ball
in your mouth.
- why, you...
- what's going on around here?
Who shot again?
Now, fellows, stop fighting!
[Crashing, Thudding]
Now, fellows, stop fighting.
- aah!
- I said stop fightin'!
I told you to stop fighting!
You guys stop fighting!
[Objects Smashing, clattering]
- hey! Hey!
Hey! Come on, get me!
I need some help!
- I wonder what he wants.
- I don't know.
Hey, cap,
swing into that island.
- thank the lord you stopped.
You're the first
souls I've seen
since my flatboat
went to pieces
and marooned me here.
I near starved to death.
- we can fix that.
Come on aboard.
- thank you kindly, son.
Mind waitin'
till I fetch my livestock?
- livestock?
[Clucking, Grunting,
squealing]
Hey! We ain't got time
to load all them animals!
Here comes the gullywhumper!
- cap's right.
- we just can't
leave him here.
- even if we did
get him aboard,
we ain't got room to pole.
Hey, forget about
them critters,
grandpa, and get aboard.
We're in a hurry!
- I can't leave my stock!
- it ain't right
that he should.
Come on, boys.
Let's give him a hand.
[Cow Lows]
[Pig Squealing]
- now, ain't that obligin'
of them cornhuskers,
waitin' here for us like this?
Hey, crockett,
what you doin'...
Recruitin' a new crew?
[Laughing]
- this ain't
no laughin' matter.
[Piglets Squealing]
- [Goat Bleats]
- [Grunts] Oh!
What are you
belly-aching about?
We're doing all the work.
- now I know exactly
how noah must've felt.
- so much obliged for all
the trouble I put you to.
That's my place yonder
on the bayou.
Got time to break bread
with us?
- admire to, but we got
some time to make up.
- excuse me, please.
I got to look
after my critters.
- well, I sure gotta hand it
to you, davy.
You just don't know
when you're up.
- well, not everybody
can come in first.
Maybe the good lord didn't
intend for us
to win this race.
- well, then what are we
breaking our backs for
to get to new orleans?
- we gotta deliver some furs
to mike fink.
- so long, cap.
Sorry your boat's so big.
- what's the matter
with the size?
- well, if she was
a might smaller,
you could save 40 miles
by takin' this here bayou.
I been down it in my skiff
plenty of times.
Runs back into the Mississippi
just above new orleans.
- think we got a chance
at gettin' through?
- well, it'd be a
tight squeeze,
but if you cut a few trees
out of the way
and don't mind scraping
the bottom a little,
you might make it.
- georgie, maybe we ain't
lost this race yet.
[Alligator Snarls]
- we been practicing
long enough.
Now let's show 'em something.
- go to them poles,
you scummy river rats!
If you don't get me to
that landing afore crockett,
so help me, I'll turn every
mother's son of ya
into catfish bait!
- push, boys!
Push like you never
pushed afore!
We're beatin' 'em, boys!
Push!
- moose.
Give 'em
the pittsburgh punch!
- aah!
So you want to play rough?
- ah!
Give it to 'em, jocko.
- oh!
- give 'em what for, davy.
- [Laughing]
- use that pole, man!
Hit 'em! Hit 'em!
Uh...uh!
[Laughter]
- hey! You thought you was
gonna wear our pelts!
You thought we was
gonna be trailin'!
- what's the world gonna say?
Mike fink, king of the river,
losin' to a pack
of landlubbers.
- I don't reckon we want
anything but our furs.
That's all we started out
to do.
- you mean, you ain't gonna
lay claim to my red feather?
- there's only one king
of the river, mike.
- yeah, that there bayou
we just come through
ain't rightly
a part of the mississip.
- where's my hat?
♪They Were Darn Good Friends
From that day on ♪
♪Davy Sold His Furs
And then was gone ♪
♪Sailin' North With Mike
To the land of the fawn ♪
♪Where A Man Could Live
By brain and brawn ♪
♪Davy, Davy Crockett ♪
♪Off For The Woods Again ♪
♪From The Mouth Of The River
Up to its head ♪
♪Boatmen And Travelers
Was filled with dread ♪
♪'Cause Redskin Pirates
Was raisin' old ned ♪
♪And The Whole Blamed River
Was a-runnin' red ♪
♪Davy, Davy Crockett ♪
♪The Man
Who don't know fear ♪
- put your backs into it.
What do you think this is,
a free trip?
- why, you ungrateful polecat,
we shove and dragged
this old tub of yours
all the way up
from new orleans.
- I gotta admit, for a couple
backwoods bear hunters,
you ain't done bad.
- those are mighty kind words
coming from you, mike.
You can put us ashore
any place along here.
- I can't see why you
bristle-headed varmints
can't land at a settlement
like civilized passengers.
- how do you like that?
He works the tar out of us,
then he calls us "passengers."
- it's the quickest way
to get home.
- sounds like
a mighty long walk to me.
- who's walkin'?
We're gonna get some horses
and sit down for a change.
- now, where are you gonna
find horses
in a lonesome place like this?
- chickasaws.
This is their country,
and they're real friendly.
Been a real pleasure
knowing you, mike.
- I ain't likely to forget you
two, neither.
Hey, you forgot your sack!
[Thud]
- oh, that's yours.
- mine?
- just a little something
to remember us by.
Open it up.
- well, ain't she a pretty
little pop gun?
"To mike fink,
king of the river,
from his admirers,
davy crockett and g. Russel."
- oh, now that we're leavin',
we figured you needed
something to protect you
against them
redskin pirates upriver.
- don't reckon
I'll need her for that.
But she'll sure
come in mighty handy
for letting tavern
keepers know
mike fink's a-comin'.
- there's something else
in that sack for you.
- uhh.
- aw. You shouldn't
have done it.
- georgie and me didn't want
nobody thinkin'
you still wasn't king.
- never was no danger of that.
You bushwhackers
ever get a hankering
to be river men again,
look me up.
All right,
get back to your poling,
you fork-tailed scorpions!
And pull!
Put your backs into it!
Shove on them poles!
What do you think this is,
a pleasure cruise?
We got a cargo to move!
- hey, here's a trail.
Probably lead us
right to a chickasaw camp.
- ♪Off Through The Wood
We're a-marching along ♪
♪Makin' Up Yarns
And a-singin' a song ♪
♪He's Ringy As A Bear
And twice as strong ♪
♪Thinks He's Right
'Cause he ain't often wrong ♪
♪Davy, Davy Crockett ♪
♪Back In The Woods Again ♪
What's the matter?
- if you'd been listening,
you'd know ain't nothin'
but you singin'.
- yeah, that's right.
Not a sound.
Not a bird or a squirrel.
Something must've scared 'em.
- must be a chickasaw
huntin' party
somewheres nearby.
- well, they ain't huntin' us.
Let's find them.
- I reckon they'll find us,
if we stay on this trail.
You quit the caterwaulin'.
No need to
scare off their game.
- davy, where are ya?
- hey, you darn idiot!
Cut me down.
- [Chuckling] So you stepped
in a old deer snare, huh?
It's a good thing mike fink
can't see the king
of the wild frontier now.
Ow! Ooh!
[Muttering Angrily]
[Whooping]
- what's the matter
with you crazy chickasaw?
We're friends!
- you're making
a terrible mistake!
Don't you understand,
it's davy crockett
you're trying to hog-tie.
Don't you understand?
Davy crock--
[Speaking Chickasaw]
- now you know where
they was taking us.
- yeah, but what are they
going to do with us?
- you've seen red hornet
stirred up before.
Shouldn't be too
hard to guess.
Mind your manners, georgie.
This is the chief.
- I am told you are the hunter
white men call davy crockett.
- he sure is, chief.
- you are known to us
as friend of the red man.
- we both are,
and look how
you're treating us.
- you and your friend
will not be harmed,
but you will remain prisoner.
- why are your men
in war paint?
- we go to avenge the murder
of our brothers.
This messenger has come from
the chief of the kaskaskias.
White men have been killing
his people without reason,
hunting them down
like animals.
- kaskaskias?
They're up on the Ohio
around cave-in rock.
- well, no wonder folks
been shootin' at 'em.
They've been attacking
every boat comes
down the river.
- do you understand
what they say?
- [Spits] They are white.
They hear only
white man's lies.
- now, listen here, you.
This ain't something we heard.
We seen it, didn't we, davy?
- sure did.
- when was this?
- not more than
three months ago.
- yeah, we helped break up
a raid on a boat
just below the big cave.
- more lies.
Three moons ago my people
were hiding far
from the river,
driven there by the white men.
- then it must have been
some other tribe.
- there are no other red men
in the land of the kaskaskias.
We have always kept the peace.
- I believe you.
Georgie, you know what
this means?
- well, it could mean
some white skunks
are dressing up like indians
so these poor devils
get the blame.
- we're going to find out
who they are.
You say you know me.
Then you know
davy crockett's word is good.
Turn us loose,
and we'll chase those varmints
out into the open.
- and if they ain't indians,
we'll see to it
everybody finds out about it.
- it is too late.
Already more messengers
have gone to the shawnee...
The Miami, the kickapoo.
And the chippewa.
- then call them back.
Send out runners of your own.
Tell the chiefs
to keep the peace.
- know this, davy crockett.
We have always wanted peace
with the white man.
But he does not want peace
with us.
He makes treaties
and calls us brother.
But he believes any evil
he hears of us.
- that's right.
But it works two ways.
To strike back at a few
no good murdering whites,
you'd turn the whole frontier
into a needless war.
- I will send runners.
But we will wait
only until the
full of the moon.
[Speaking Chickasaw]
- sure hope
that oldgullywhomper
didn't pass
'fore we got here.
- they ain't had time.
We got a long way
ahead of them,
thanks to them indians.
- what makes you think mike's
gonna want to
throw in with us?
- it's his river
we aim to clean up, ain't it?
- yeah.
That old chief
didn't give us much time.
Won't take long for that new
moon to fatten up.
- leastwise we ain't gonna
waste no more time here.
- you know, davy,
you showed rare good sense
in getting old mike fink
to help you.
Don't make no difference
whether them pirates
are red or white.
Me and my skull
busters'll make
mincemeat of them.
- we gotta find 'em first.
- well, ain't certain
they'll show theirselves
after that
whopping I gave them
comin' downriver.
They're sure to recognize
the oldgullywhomper.
- hey, mike!
Look what's comin'!
- why, that's
themonongahela belle.
But where's her crew?
Prepare to grab her
as she comes alongside, boys.
- aye, aye, captain.
All right, hold onto
this mud bank,
you scummy river rats.
[Dramatic Music]
♪
- I knowed old cap donovan.
Looks like he put up
a real good fight
before they wiped him out.
- yeah.
- thought you said
these pirates wasn't injuns.
- well, they ain't.
No redskin ever
made this arrow.
- let me see that.
Yeah, you're right.
Ain't no tribal markings,
ain't feathered right.
I wonder how far downstream
she drifted
since the massa-cree.
- ain't no way of telling.
Nah, they didn't hardly
leave nothing.
- well, they left these.
Try it on for size.
- uh-uh! I wouldn't be
caught dead
in a monkey suit like that.
- well, it ain't gonna be hard
to disguise thegullywhomper,
but something's
gotta be done about you.
Now, put it on.
Put it on.
[Men Shouting orders,
chattering]
- good name for her, garth.
Hey, moose.
Hide this below where
we can get it in a hurry.
- what's so heavy
in that sack?
- rocks.
- rocks?
You featherheaded idiot!
I'll find out
what's going on here.
What in thunderation
you up to?
- you're a banker, ain't you?
- yes, sir.
King of the
bankers, that's me.
On my way up to shawnee town
to open a new establishment.
But what's these here rocks
got to do with that?
- can't run a bank without
money, can ya?
- no. Don't reckon.
- that's your capital.
Genuine spanish gold.
- say....
We're rich, ain't we?
- that's what we're hopin'
them pirates will think.
I figure if we stop
in a couple of towns,
those folks'll hear about
our rich cargo.
Word'll get upriver
faster than we can.
- ♪Oh, The River Is Long
And the moon is high ♪
♪And I Want A Gal
Before I die ♪
♪Pretty Little Gal
With a turned-up nose ♪
♪And Dancin' Music
In her twinkling toes ♪
♪Oh, Her Cheeks Is Pink ♪
♪And Her Smile Is Shy ♪
♪And Her Hair's
The color of midnight ♪
♪Midnight Sky ♪
- set 'em up again.
- ♪Color Of Midnight,
Midnight ♪
♪Midnight Sky ♪
- [Applause]
- that banjo player's
got real talent.
- oh, yes. He hits this town
every once in a while.
- plays to drum up business
for himself.
- who is he?
- a peddler from back east.
He calls himself colonel plug.
- I sure do admire
classical music.
[Gags]
What the devil is in this?
- it's just your usual
sarsaparilla, sir.
- delicious, ain't it?
- I don't believe
I got your name, stranger.
- mcgillicuddy...
J.j. Mcgillicuddy,
on my way up to shawnee town
to open up a new bank.
- ah, Mr. Mcgillicuddy,
I feel it my duty
to inform you
that river travel
is not safe anymore here.
- well, if you're
referring to them
injun pirates,
we ain't carrying nothing
they'd want.
No guns, no powder.
Not even no whiskey.
Just a cargo
of old spanish gold.
[String Twangs]
- a cargo of gold?
Well, I'm surprised that
your captain would risk that.
- well, you ain't scared any,
are you, cap?
- not about the gold.
- we'll believe them injuns
when we see 'em.
- those butchers are real,
all right.
Wrecks of boats drift by
all the time.
- what happened
to their crews?
- dead men don't talk,
pretty much,
but plenty of bodies
are fished out of the river
scalped and chopped to pieces.
- no use to try to scare us
off, mister.
- we been hearing
them injun stories
all the way up
from new orleans.
- listen, you know who
mike fink is, don't you?
- who is he?
- mike fink,
the keelboat man.
Calls himself
king of the river.
- oh, that big blowhard.
What about him?
- yeah. What about him?
- I've heard that even he's
going to quit the river.
- you heard what?
- yes, sir.
Even that brained jackass
is too wise to risk it.
- jackass?
[Straining, Wood cracking]
[Glass Shatters]
- mind your manners,
Mr. Mcgillicuddy.
- I'm okay now, boys.
Just one of my seizures.
- excuse me, Mr. Mcgillicuddy.
I just couldn't help
overhearing.
But do you really intend
going on upriver?
- you don't think I'd go
this far if I wasn't, do ya?
- well, now,
I admire a man of courage.
Just so happens
that I'm mighty anxious
to get on up
to shawnee town myself.
- we're pretty
crowded already.
- oh, shucks,
I don't take up much room.
All I got's my sample case
and my banjo.
- a little music wouldn't hurt
none, would it?
- this ain't no
pleasure cruise.
- listen.
You may be the captain,
but I'm the boss banker
of this outfit, ain't I?
What I say goes.
- did he get aboard this one?
- yeah, just went into
the cabin.
"B-o-n-a-n-z-a."
You ever hear of her?
- you know I can't spell.
- well, hello there, fellas.
Say, I got a new verse
I want to try out
on Mr. Mcgillicuddy.
[Whistling]
- something mighty fishy
about that peddler.
Why'd you let mike
bring him aboard?
- 'cause he's the first sucker
that nibbled at our bait.
- hello. Nice day.
- mighty pretty,
this Ohio river country.
-La belle riviere.
That's what the frenchmen
used to call it.
Parlez-vous francais?
- huh?
- you speak french?
- oh, sure.
♪
- I've been saving this song
for a time just like this.
♪There Was A Widow
In new madrid ♪
♪A-smokin' A Pipe
And a-chawin' on a quid ♪
♪When She Puckered
Up Her Lips,
I run for my life ♪
♪But She Run Me Down,
And now she is my wife ♪
♪Oh, Her Lips Is Red ♪
♪And Her Eyes Is Bold ♪
♪And Her Hair's
The color of yeller ♪
♪Yeller Gold ♪
♪The Color Of Yeller,
Yeller ♪
[Shouting] ♪Yeller Gold! ♪
- ♪The River Is Long,
And the moon is high ♪
♪I Want A Gal
Afore I die ♪
♪A Pretty Little Gal
With a turned-up nose ♪
♪And Dancin' Music
In her twinkling toes ♪
♪Oh, Her Lips Is Red ♪
♪And Her Eyes Is Bold ♪
♪Her Hair's Like Yeller,
Yeller ♪
♪Yeller Gold ♪
♪The Color Of Yeller,
Yeller ♪
♪Yeller Gold ♪
[Loud Music and chatter
[Laughter]
[Fiddle Playing]
♪
- wait a minute!
Wait a minute here.
[Crack]
[Laughing]
♪
- what you doing, mason?
Smokin' up a new batch?
- won't keep if I don't.
- you already got
your mattress stuffed.
What you want
with more scalps?
- got to keep folks thinkin'
we're injuns, don't we?
- hey, the harpes is coming.
- did you hear that, mason?
The harpes just come in.
- yeah.
[Object Shatters]
- more business for us?
- yeah, and a
fat one this time.
And the colonel is aboard.
- good. What's the cargo?
- gold.
- yeller, yeller gold.
- mighty obligin'
to ship it our way.
[Chuckles]
- this waiting's
making me nervous.
Time's getting short.
That moon was
half full last night.
- we still got a few days.
- gonna take a few days
to get word back to chickasaw.
- reckon we ain't got long
to wait now.
- my boys is all ready--
chock full of fighting
and itching to get at 'em.
- not so loud.
Don't want
colonel plug to hear.
- aw, he's still sleeping.
- better make sure.
Take over, Mr. Mcgillicuddy.
This is called a tiller.
[Snoring]
[Laughs]
- this is just about the place
they jumped us afore.
Ooh, I've worn
this monkey suit
long enough.
[Grunts]
- [Chuckling]
Rocks. Just plain rocks.
"Mike fink"?
"Davy crockett"?
Oh...oh, excuse me, boys.
I was having a little
difficulty getting to sleep.
I thought maybe you fellows
might like to hear
a little music.
♪
♪It's Crockett And Fink ♪
♪And Down In The Hold ♪
[Muffled]
♪There's A Cannon Instead ♪
♪Of Yeller, Yeller Gold ♪
- that sounded like plug.
But what's he singing about
this time?
- what difference
does it make now?
He'll be skulling 'em
pretty soon.
- you can't do this to me,
consarn ya!
- hey, davy.
Bring up my cannon
when you come.
- [Grunts]
If I'd knowed I was
gonna have to tote this thing,
I'd have argued for a pistol.
- hey, moose.
Come aft and be gunner.
[Creaking]
[Groaning Sound]
- what'd you
slow her down for?
Close in on 'em.
Lay them poles!
- what do you think
we're doing?
- [Muffled Shouting]
Help!
- mike, we're dragging bottom!
- well, it's them confounded
rocks you brought on board!
Get 'em outta there!
[Colonel Plug muttering]
- we're sinking!
[Muffled] Help me!
- we're sinking, mike!
- sinking? We're sunk!
- [Whooping]
- grab your wee-pons, boys,
and let 'em have it!
- dang it,
you can't do this to me.
I'll have the law on ya.
I'll have the law on ya!
- they're attacking us
from the rear!
Get the powder!
Come on, fill her up!
- I scalped him!
- aah!
[Gunshot]
- ah!
- oh!
- [Laughing]
Oh!
- what's holding them up
out there?
- them boatmen's putting up
an awful good fight.
- we'll fix that--get
the powder canoe in the water.
- give me a hand.
- hey! I'm on your side.
- [Whooping]
We got 'em on the run!
- no wonder.
Look what's coming.
[Laughter]
- somebody's
playing awful rough.
Why, that's sam mason
and the harpe brothers--
the orneriest skunks
on the river.
- hey, they're getting away!
- oh, no, they ain't.
You take the rest of them in.
Georgie'll run
them varmints down.
- boot tracks.
They're the ones we want.
- big harpe,
stay here and keep watch.
- wait a minute,
what about my share?
- you'll get
what's comin' to you.
- leave that big stuff.
We can't carry that
on horseback.
- that's enough for now.
- we can't leave all this
for somebody else.
- nobody's going to find it
till we can get back.
That's what
that keg of powder's for.
[Both Laughing]
- somebody's
coming up the trail.
- get out of sight.
- cave-in tavern
ain't doing much business.
- don't think it ever was
a tavern, georgie.
- you mean
this is their hangout?
- it's gotta be.
- davy! You ain't
going in there?
- them varmints
went someplace.
- this is worse than crawling
in a hollow log after a bear.
[Clanking]
- hey, davy.
[Whoosh]
Kinda drafty in here.
Look what I found.
- what was you
muttering about?
- looky. Same kind we found
sticking
in that wrecked keelboat.
- here's where
they changed into injuns.
Them three that we followed
in here must
be the ringleaders.
Stay here, and I'll see
if I can smoke something out.
- [Whispers] Hey, davy,
what's keeping you?
- there's plenty of loot
in there.
- well, they wouldn't go off
and leave it.
Reckon they're still around.
- this ought to
lead to something
mighty interesting.
- [Sniffing]
[Boom]
- oof!
- aah!
[Clank]
[Crack]
- why, you--
[Thud]
- aah!
[Object Shatters]
[Crack]
[Thud]
[Boom]
[Laughter]
[Thunk]
- oh!
- well, here we are
splitting up again,
you bushwhackers.
And if we never meet again,
remember,
I'm still king of the river.
- oh, you're better
than a king, mike.
You're a first-class friend.
- yeah?
- fact, you're the finest
fighting man I know.
- aw!
[Laughing]
- after davy.
- all right,
ring-tail scorpions!
Start pulling!
- ♪Kept His Promise
To mike and his crew ♪
♪Kept His Promise
To the injun chiefs too ♪
♪For The River Was Clear
All the way through ♪
♪And Blaming The Injuns
Was a-proven untrue ♪
♪Davy, Davy Crockett ♪
♪King Of The Wild Frontier ♪