Provided by explosiveskull
https://twitter.com/kaboomskull
Sleepin' already?
Someone must've worn
me out.
That looks good on you.
It's so fancy.
What do you think
we can get for it?
I wanna keep it.
Hey, Marie, stay inside.
Everett?
Did we drink all the beer?
Everett.
Hello?
Shit, shit, shit.
Hey, hey. We have to
go right now, okay?
Come on.
It found me.
It's inside me.
No!
Oh, yeah. Yeah,
this is perfect.
See, this is exactly
the kinda place
I was talkin' about, guys.
It's a shame Dennis isn't here.
He'd love to see this.
Knowin' the popular
culture behind Bigfoot
is a great way to
learn more about him.
In fact, with any
kind of cryptid-
- We just need that
lighter fluid, Oz.
Hello.
Hey, hi. Could you turn
that down for a quick sec?
Hello? Yeah, hey.
Yeah, sorry. I saw you called.
Did you try... Yeah, yeah.
No, did you try the zip file?
Yeah, no problem. Happy to help.
Okay, bye. Bye bye.
Your work know you're going
off the grid this weekend?
Oh, well, Isabelle
said there'd be
service at the cabin, so...
Oh.
Shoot.
Well, uh, maybe this
is a good thing, right?
Give my boss a chance to
Google something for a change.
Where is everybody?
Pit stop.
So what class is
this for anyway?
It's called cryptozoology.
We study mythical
folklore animals.
Wow.
What's your major?
Photojournalism.
Oh.
Huh.
We're all just trying
to finish up our masters.
Everyone said this class
was an easy A, so...
Oz in there is our TA.
He'll give you an
earful, if you want it.
Good to know.
So, uh, you and Isabelle, huh?
Yeah.
You know, we've only known
each other two months, but,
I don't know.
She's cool, but uh...
A nice guy like you?
Honestly, she'll chew
you up and spit you out.
Well, um, I haven't exactly
gotten chewed up yet, so...
We're
probably good, right?
Pretty slow today, huh?
Always is in the Dead Month.
Every year around this
time, people go missing.
Explains why the
cabin was so cheap.
What do they just get like
lost in the woods or something?
Well, no one knows for
sure what happens, but uh,
there is a theory.
- Oh, god.
- Yeah.
I thought you told us
that Bigfoot is harmless?
Well, no, he is, he
is. I said it's a theory.
It just happens to be a bad one.
Tell you what,
I'll be right back.
Let me try to call Professor
Kasdan again, yeah?
Awesome.
Our buddy here
thinks we're gonna
run into Mr. Sasquatch
this weekend.
You ever see anything?
That beast you're lookin' for.
It's out there.
There's an unspeakable evil
livin' out in those woods there.
And you better hope it
doesn't sense your presence,
because if it
knows you're there,
they'll be coming
for ya.
Okay, then.
What's the damage?
$52.
75 cents.
Yeesh.
Hey, keep the change.
Dead Month and everything.
Safe journeys.
Hey, are you sure
it's okay that I'm here?
I didn't realize I'd be the
only non-student tagging along.
Oh, yeah. No, trust me.
Professor Kasdan
is like thrilled
to have another person
forced to listen to him.
Just, you know, relax.
Try to have fun.
You didn't wanna
wear your khakis?
Oh!
No, I, I love them.
Now?
Yeah, I mean, I got
them for you to wear.
Right.
Right, yeah.
I mean, I'm not sure they're
exactly meant for hiking.
But uh,
I'll give it a shot.
Yeah?
Okay.
- Oh, I have to pee.
- Oh.
Sorry, babe.
You're in for quite
a treat this weekend
as we delve into our
new area of study.
In the last 20 years,
there've been over
two dozen sightings in the area.
Today is about
exploring the territory!
Finding clues, evidence!
And that could be tree markings,
that could be footprints.
That could be feces.
Anything that sheds light
on the existence of Bigfoot!
Hey.
How did the snowman feel
when he got the flu?
Abominable.
Hey, you know we should probably
catch up with the others.
Oh, yeah. Totally.
My little explorers,
keep your eyes peeled,
and you might wind up
in tomorrow's headlines.
Back in 1811-
- Hey, guys!
I think I'm gonna stick around
and watch this
black-capped Chickadee.
Anyone wanna join?
You know what? We'll just,
we'll wind back around.
Oh, yeah.
Cool beans.
Explorers say that
Bigfoot often throws rocks
at trespassers, as a warning.
It's so refreshing
to be with someone
who actually listens for once.
I mean, Chris is literally
the opposite of Dan.
He's such a douche bag.
I mean, you like him, right?
You mean the human
dad joke back there?
Maybe that's what I need,
though. Someone uncomplicated.
Simple.
Hey, guys.
Let's turn here.
Shouldn't we
stay on the trail?
I doubt Bigfoot does trails.
Bigfoot doesn't do trails.
Hello.
Are you a tourist?
Camera give it away?
What're you lookin' at?
That is a mark
of a goddamn beast.
Bigfoot?
What the fuck else?
Hey, do you mind if
I get a picture of you?
Where are y'all staying?
A cabin.
Where at?
The woods.
You know, you
oughta watch yourself.
Skinny little girl
off the trail.
All alone.
It's lookin' like prime
bait, if you ask me.
Especially in Dead Month.
Well, hey. This has been
great but I'm gonna head off.
Oh, hey.
If you see Squatch,
tell him "hi" from me.
Aw, damn it.
Oh, whatever did this is huge.
It's Bigfoot.
What're you
gonna do, taste it?
Jeez!
Fuck me.
We gotta report this. There
was service near that shop.
Look, let's
just take a second here.
Oz, there's a
fucking dead body.
No, skeleton, all right?
It takes eight to twelve
years for a body to decompose.
Great tip. You
should be a doctor.
All right, let's go.
Guys, guys! There's
no rush to report this.
I mean, whoever this was,
they've been missing
for a very long time.
What's a few more days?
Oz, I know you have a
huge hard-on for Bigfoot
and everything, but we didn't
sign up to fucking obstruct
a missing persons case.
Is this ideal? No.
But Dennis and I
have been waiting
all semester for this trip.
I say we stay the weekend.
All right, so, you
prefer to go back
and listen to more
lectures instead?
Trust me, I have a lot
to say on this topic,
and without this
hands-on experience,
I'm gonna need twice the
amount of essays from you guys
to make sure you
know your stuff.
We report this
the second we leave.
The moment the
trip is over, yes.
Okay, yeah. Fine.
It probably goes
without saying, but,
we shouldn't mention
this to the others.
Don't wanna stir up
a panic over nothing', right?
And uh, we can't tell Dennis.
Yeah, I mean, god forbid
the loonie professor
with the not-so-secret
alcoholism gets in trouble.
I'm serious. The less
he knows, the better.
Hey.
Quite the view.
Yeah.
I thought I saw
something in the woods.
It could've been a
deer or a moose or-
- Or...
Something else.
I think it's time we head back.
All right.
So he spit on me,
and he was trying to ask me
where we were staying at.
- Did you tell him?
- Fuck no, I just left.
There's gotta be matches
around here somewhere.
Whoa.
Jake, check this out.
Whoa, buddy. Put that back.
Oh, all right. Okay.
Oh, hey.
Found 'em.
Let's get this fire
started, huh?
Oh, man.
You know, it's
really interesting.
Babe, I was just telling you
about this the other day.
Do you remember? Do you
remember what I said?
Okay, well, so, correct
me if I'm wrong,
but most people think that
Canadian beer is much stronger
than American beer, right?
But that's actually false,
so, in Canadia
they use the
alcohol-by-volume method,
but in America, we used to use
the alcohol-by-weight method.
So, just a cool little
tidbit for you guys.
God, I can't do shit
without the internet.
Can I have your keys? I
have to make a work call.
You hurt her...
I swear to god.
Oh, babe, I'll come with you.
No, it's okay.
It's just a work call, so it's
gonna be like super boring.
So why don't you just stay
and get to know everyone,
and I'll back.
- Sorry, babe.
- Yeah, okay.
Coolio.
I'm gonna go shower.
Oh, sure. Get
clean.
Yeah, I'm gonna hit the sack.
Hey, Professor, are
you not weary that
not one of these guys believe
in anything that we say?
As long as we're able to
dismantle people's basic inherent
fear of the unknown, even if
it's something as fantastical
as Bigfoot, or any
other cryptid for that matter.
You know, it just means
the world to us, as humans.
Hey, cheers to that, right?
Hey, um, I know we talked
about this earlier, but,
are you at all worried about
the possibility of, you know,
other sightings?
I mean, what if there is
something dangerous out there?
You know, maybe, maybe
a little danger is exactly
what's needed for us
to question everything.
Enough with all that. So, how's
that thesis of yours goin'?
Oh! Oh, hey, it's
comin'.
I hit a little lag last week
because it was my
girlfriend's birthday.
Yeah.
Listen, Dennis.
I should let you know that, um,
on our hike earlier, we found-
- I, I gotta go. I'm sorry.
Excuse me.
Oh.
Okay.
- Isabelle.
- Oh, my god.
Professor Kasdan,
you scared me.
I'm so sorry.
Listen, uh, do you mind
if I come with you?
'Cause something
unfortunate has come up.
Yeah, what happened?
Well, as it turns out,
it's my wedding anniversary,
and no wonder my wife was
short with me before we left.
I gotta call her.
Yeah.
Sure.
Yeah. No, just um, hop in.
Thanks.
All right.
Maybe some reading.
Hmm.
What's this?
Huh.
"Forest Unseen."
Wow.
Creepy.
"The darkness of
the night brings out
the evil that is the wendigo.
But night's end brings the dawn
and with the dawn
comes the light."
Lilly, I need to go!
Give me a minute, man!
Come on! I gotta go pee!
I swear to god, I'm a
quiet pee'er! Let me in.
Jake, you even try,
you'll be walking out
with a concussion.
Come on.
Fuck off!
Okay.
Jake, what did
I tell you, man?
Yeah, I know I suppose I
concentrate on my studies
a bit too much, but you know,
my wife has absolutely no idea
the concept of budget cuts.
I'm the only one supporting us.
Financially, that is.
Have we hit service?
Who is that?
Who?
That.
So weird.
I thought I saw something.
Isabelle.
Are you all right, Isabelle?
Are you all right?
Professor?
Oh, shit.
Okay, I'm just
gonna pee outside.
Yeah, all right.
Here we go.
What...
Yeah.
That's why it's here.
Okay.
Um...
Okay?
Oh, my god.
Oh! Hey there, tourist.
You oughta watch them
showers. They'll get ya.
Oh!
Hey!
Ain't had one of these in years.
They'll kill ya.
You ever hear anyone die before?
I have.
Every fuckin' night I
still hear those screams.
Yeah, like skin's gettin'
ripped off her bones.
You don't forget shit like that.
What's that?
If I offended you...
It ain't about that at all!
Look, you already got
your free fucking peep show!
Hey, come on now!
It ain't about
that either, okay?
You got your god damn
shirt back on, don't ya?
Hm?
No, you are just my
bait, little lady.
Nothin' personal.
It's Bigfoot, he's out
in these woods.
Now, you can doubt
him all you want.
He don't give two shits
whether you believe in him.
You can rest assured on that.
I can tell you're
not a bad guy.
No.
No, you're goin'
for somethin' heavy.
I get that, I really do.
Whatever you're
planning on doing to me,
things are gonna be bad for you!
Your fingerprints are
all over my clothes.
Mine are in this truck, I mean,
my DNA's on the
fuckin' cigarette!
Yeah, I'mma kill him.
Get that fuckin' rock, too.
That's all there is to it.
Now.
If you die in the
process, well...
Shit, so be it. Why don't you
hang onto that DNA for us?
Izzy, where you been?
Izzy?
Are you okay?
Hey, you guys seen Dennis?
I realized we gotta change
somethin' in the schedule.
Izzy, are you okay?
Look at me.
Where is my car?
I don't remember.
Isabelle, dear, what
happened? What's goin' on?
- I don't remember.
- Okay, what do you remember?
Just, just calm
down. Just, just...
Isabelle, look at me,
sweetie. Where's Dennis?
He's...
He's dead.
I'm really, I'm really hungry.
Jake, where
are the others?
I don't fucking know.
Lilly!
Chris!
Dennis!
Hello!
- Guys, where are you?
- Why would they answer that?
Shit.
Oh, no.
Help!
One, two, three.
Go, go.
Shit.
I saw him.
Told you.
Guys, this is all my fault.
I knew it was the Dead Month
and I still insisted
that we come here.
Did you guys bring any
other way of communication?
We actually thought
it'd be a good thing
not to have service.
Less distractions for everyone.
God, I'm such an idiot!
Okay, okay.
Where's the gun?
Oh, I must've dropped it,
while I was getting
dragged through the woods.
All right, all right.
Let's just think, all right?
So, the shop was the last place
that we had service, right?
- Now how far was that?
- About an hour's drive.
And if they had such a bad
accident that Isabelle left
my car there, then I doubt
it's still fuckin' drivable.
Okay, we can walk
until we hit service.
What?
That's a terrible idea.
That thing almost killed me.
Trust me, Chris. If it wanted
to kill you, you'd be dead.
- It was trying to warn you.
- Warn me? About what?
Spirit of the flesh.
What'd she say?
Wait.
Wait, you guys.
I found this book.
It talks about all kinds of
crazy shit like creatures.
Right.
- Bigfoot.
- No.
The wendigo.
It's this creature that-
- Cannibalistic beast
that preys on the selfish.
- Yeah.
- Yeah, I know.
"The wendigo turns
those overcome with greed
into the embodiment
of their weak morals."
That's the spirit.
It's what gets in your head.
And that's what you become
once the spirit finds you.
He knew.
I brought up the wendigo
sightings to Dennis,
before we even started
planning this trip.
He told me the claims
were phony, but,
he was more worried about
losing his department.
He knew the wendigo was
out there this entire time.
God damn it!
All right, listen. We need
to get the hell outta here.
- Right now.
- Wait, hold on.
You're telling me that Bigfoot
isn't the only
monster out there?
Yes, and it's pure evil.
The torment it inflicts
on those its chooses
is beyond anything you can
imagine, and if it finds us...
We're better off dead.
Isabelle?
It knows we're here.
They're coming.
Tree.
Turn around.
Now...
I'mma tell
you somethin'.
Get the fuck off me.
Now, I don't want it to be
all bad blood between us, okay?
This isn't my intention.
I'm Everett Dylan Grunn and
I'm sorry what's happened here.
Ow!
You stupid bitch.
- Get back here!
- No!
- Come back here!
God!
- That's it.
- Fuck you!
Get against the
tree. You stay still!
Stay still!
Give me your fuckin' hands.
Jesus, here I was thinking
I was only fighting
a Squatch tonight.
Now...
You keep
up that squealin',
and that Bigfoot will be
here before you know it.
God damn.
Fuckin' psycho
asshole motherfucker!
Woo-oo!
Let me hide first.
Help!
I couldn't
find any results for,
"Kill and consume the blood
and flesh of the others."
♪ Fast as you can ♪
♪ Everett's gonna
shoot you down ♪
♪ Run, run ♪
♪ Fast as you can ♪
♪ Everett's gonna
shoot you down ♪
That's one stubborn bitch.
All right, all right, maybe
Lilly found the crashed car
and walked into town for help.
And walks 60 miles into town?
Maybe a driver picked
her up or, or maybe...
Isabelle?
Jake!
Oz.
I don't know what's
happening.
Oh, shit.
Okay, okay, just stay right
there. Please just don't move.
Isabelle, I'm serious,
please! Just stay right there.
Don't move!
Please, please, please
don't make me do this.
Please don't make me do
this. Don't make me do this!
- Oh, god!
- No! No, please don't!
No, please don't!
Please don't hurt me.
- Come on.
- Please don't hurt-
- No, no, no, no.
It's okay, it's okay.
No, no. Shh, shh, shh.
- I'm sorry.
- It's okay, it's okay.
We can fix this, I can fix this.
We're gonna figure it out.
- I'm sorry.
- It's okay, it's okay.
- It's okay.
I'm gonna go find Chris
and, and we'll fix it.
We'll get something
together, okay? Just, just...
I'm so hungry.
Hello?
We need to go, now.
What the fuck?
Hi, Jake.
I can't find Isabelle.
The other ones are coming,
alright? We are going.
Jesus.
You know what?
I just got here and
it seems like I care
so much more about the
others than you do.
You don't give a shit
if they live or die.
Dude, they would do
the same exact thing.
Isabelle wouldn't.
Chris, we don't
have time for this.
Look, you can think I'm
an asshole all you want,
but the truth is, I
live in fuckin' reality.
Look, it's great
you got this whole puppy dog
thing going on, really,
it's seriously endearing,
but you're a fuckin'
pushover, Chris.
You sacrificing
yourself here doesn't change that
it just makes you a dumb ass.
Let me check the
rest of the house.
Please.
Five more minutes.
Then I'm gone, whether
you come or not.
You're right.
I do think you're an asshole.
God damn it.
Hi, babe.
Fuck.
Lilly?
They're inside.
Now are you ready to leave?
Run!
Let's go.
So here's the plan.
We find the creeper that
kidnapped me, grab his keys,
get to his car and get
the fuck outta here.
What the fuck are these things?
I don't know.
I don't know, it's whatever's
happening to Isabelle.
What's happening to Isabelle?
I'm not sure, I think
it's called a wendigo.
Hey.
What?
Thanks for not leaving me.
Do you hear that?
What?
Lilly?
Where
the fuck are they?
- Lilly, we have to go.
- Not until I find the keys.
Lilly, right now.
Got 'em.
Come on.
What the...
Lilly! Look at me,
look at me, look at me.
Look at me. It's okay.
Hey, Lilly? It's okay,
it's okay, it's okay.
Lilly, stay with me. Come on.
Baby, please. Please.
Please, please.
Lilly. Lilly, Lilly.
Lilly?
Oh, shit.
Come on, come on, come on, come
on. Just do it, just drive.
Just drive, please. Come on.
They would do the
same exact thing.
- Isabelle wouldn't.
- Sorry, babe.
Sorry, babe.
You're a fuckin'
pushover, Chris.
Hi, babe.
I feel like you're
pushing you away, Chris.
No, please. Please.
Shit.
Oh, shit. Fuck, fuck!
Oh, Jesus.
I hate your fucking khakis.
Fuck.
Jesus Christ.
Okay.
♪ Everett's gonna get you ♪
♪ Run, run ♪
♪ Everett's gonna
chase you down ♪
You do this?
Mr. Monster Killer!
My name is Everett Dylan Grunn,
and I don't know you...
It don't matter anymore.
I used to come to this place
every fuckin' year for a month.
Every single year,
every single...
I thought it was about
Bigfoot, and the girl.
Gee!
I always did kinda lie
to myself about that.
Wasn't about no girl.
Or even the Squatch.
It about this here goddamn rock.
I don't know what...
A test.
This spirit of flesh.
Wendigo.
That wendigo, he knows
me inside and out.
He got into my head,
and squeezed his way in there.
He made me do things...
I ain't proud of.
That don't matter none now.
Neither does this here rock.
'Cause the only
fuckin' thing I know
is how goddamn hungry I am.
I'm just tickled pink,
thinkin' about sinkin' my teeth
in that pretty leg of yours.
♪ Run, run ♪
♪ Everett's gonna get ya ♪
♪ Everett's gonna get you ♪
♪ Run, run ♪
♪ Everett's gonna get ya ♪
♪ Everett's gonna
shoot you down ♪
You better run.
I'm so tired.
♪ Gonna get ya ♪
♪ Run, run ♪
♪ Everett's gonna get ya ♪
♪ Everett's gonna
shoot you down ♪
Dead Month?
Provided by explosiveskull
https://twitter.com/kaboomskull