This is a tale of long ago...
when there were still knights.
The story happens in two kingdoms:
the land of King Unauwen...
... and the land of King Dagonaut.
They are good friends.
King Dagonaut is a good and just ruler.
There is peace and security in his country ...
... thanks to his many valiant knights.
In the west, beyond the great mountains,
... lies Unauwen.
King Unauwen has two sons,
who are twins.
One is called Iridian, the crown prince.
The other son, Viridian,
is the ruler over the land of Eviellan in the south.
Viridian is the enemy of his father...
... and has often tried to invade the land of Unauwen ...
... with his Red Riders.
But the story starts in the City of Dagonaut,
just before the great day...
... on which five young squires wil be knighted by the king.
Tiuri!
It's going well, right?
No, not well at all. Again.
Tiuri! What are you doing?
Ouch!
Finish it.
You are now dead, noble knight.
One of the squires about to be knighted...
is Tiuri, son of the famous Sir Tiuri the Valiant.
Well? Are you looking forward to tomorrow?
Yeah, but...
But?
I could have waited another four years, Mother.
Look there! The knight-to-be.
How did it go this morning?
All right.
Good. Now for tonight...
... and tomorrow is the big day.
You have now passed all the tests, except one.
You have been pages, served with a lord,
been your proud fathers' squires.
But after tomorrow you will really have to prove ...
... that you are honest, helpful and brave.
And now, the final test.
A vigil in the chapel on the hill.
You shall wake through the night.
You may pray, dream about your knighthood,
... but you must keep silent.
Speak to no one.
Not eat or drink.
And you may not open the door for anyone-- for anyone!
And not leave the chapel...
... until tomorrow at sunrise ...
... when your fathers will come to take you to the festive procession.
If you break one of these rules...
... you will not be knighted tomorrow.
(Knock on the door)
Anybody there?
(Knock)
(Door latch)
Open in God's name!
(Moaning)
(Rattling latch)
(Knock)
Please, help me!
Have you no heart?
(Rattling latch)
Help me, I'm wounded!
Help me!
Thank you. I crave your help.
Quick, quick, there is little time.
I may not speak to anyone, I'm to be knighted tomorrow.
No! No!
Oh, no.
What's your name?
Who are you? What do you want of me?
This letter is very important.
It's a matter of life and death.
It is addressed to the king of Unauwen.
My knight, the Black Knight with the White Shield...
... has to deliver it.
You must bring the letter to him.
But why have you come here? The city is full of knights you can trust.
They are too conspicuous.
- Am I not, too?
You aren't known.
Here.
Go! Quick! Take my horse.
My knight is hiding in the King's Wood near here.
May God reward you.
Tell him Vokia sent you.
(Moaning)
Who are you?
Tiuri, my lord.
Tiuri... I know that name. Sir Tiuri the Valiant.
That's my father.
Your father. He and I have...
But what are you doing here?
I've come for you.
- For me?
Vokia sent me. --Here.
This letter is for the king, the king of Unauwen.
It's vitally important for his country, but for your country as well.
Now I can't deliver it myself...
... you have to do it.
Me?
- Yes, you. There's no time to lose. Listen carefully.
Travel to the west, by the Blue River...
... until you get to the wellspring in the mountains.
There is a hermit living there, Menaures.
Here, take this ring.
If you show it to him, he'll know that I sent you.
He'll get you over the mountains safe.
That's the shortest way to Unauwen.
Why can't someone else do that? I can't.
I'm not suited for it, really.
Look at me. You, you must do it. You can do it.
But beware: there are enemies everywhere.
The Red Riders. They want the letter.
Never open it, unless you're in danger of your life.
Then you must read and destroy it.
Are you listening?
Before...
(Shouting)
I don't have a letter!
He's got the letter! He's got it!
Where's the letter! Tell!
- Finish him off.
I don't have a letter! Aargh!
Well, we're in this together.
What's your name?
This ring will protect us.
(Voices)
Stop!
Whoa!
Stand still!
Follow us!
(Shouts in the distance)
Thank you, good beast.
Come on! We're in a hurry!
Give us your money!
What do you want? I don't have any money, I have nothing.
Then what's this?
Let me go!
You're not getting the ring. You won't get it!
So if I just took the ring?
I implore you... I got this ring from someone who just died.
It's very precious to me.
Precious? Precious?!
I have a proposition.
If you get to choose between your ring and your horse, which do you keep?
Both?
Choose! Or I'll chop off that finger!
The ring.
- The ring?
Beat it, stupid. Beat it with your ring!
Who'd have thought the little...
(faint voices)
I haven't done anything!
Mercy, lord, mercy!
For a coward like you there is no mercy.
Where did you get that horse?
Got given it.
How did you get that horse?
The horse is mine.
- You're lying!
We know that horse. It's Ardanwen.
Ardanwen.
Someone gave it to him.
- A lad we met.
Liar!
A lad with a... with a ring.
So what did that lad look like?
Well, er, it was dark, he was wearing a long shirt, a bit whitish.
How old is that lad?
About fifteen, sixteen.
You stupid oaf. You should have killed the boy!
Where is he now?
No idea, he went that way, can't be far.
Next time you'll swing. We're keeping an eye on you!
(Banter)
Whoa!
Good morning, brothers.
God be with you, young traveller.
- Thank you.
Are you by any chance going west?
We're bound for the Brown Monastery, it's that way.
Could you please give me a ride?
Of course, my son.
Thank you.
Are you cold? Here, put this on.
Thank you, Brother...
Martin.
-Martin.
I suppose you're hungry too.
- No.
Well, yes in fact.
May I know where you're bound?
I'm going to the spring of the Blue River, in the mountains.
You're going to visit Menaures, the old hermit.
- Yes. Do you know him?
Er, yes.
(Shouting in the distance)
Stay where you are!
- Whoa!
Tell us! Where are you going?
We're on our way to the Brown Monastery, my lord, not far from here.
Hoods off!
Er, our young brother is blind, my lord.
Come!
Why did you do that?
I can't tell you now. It's a bit complicated.
Whoa. Giddy-up!
Hey, keep that.
Oh! Thanks.
So you go that way.
Make good pace, you'll get to Castle Mistrinaut before dark.
They're very hospitable there.
Thank you, brothers.
I'm sorry I couldn't tell more about myself, but...
... I hope you trust me.
Have a good journey.
You don't trust him.
Someone is looking for him.
Good evening, brother.
Good evening,.
You want to spend the night?
Yes.
And you are?
- Brother Martin.
One moment please. Have to write that down.
Lord Rafox always wants to know who his guests are.
All right, go on.
Thanks.
(Talking and singing)
Come sit here, brother.
Sit down.
(Bell)
Get up, stand.
Yes, she's a beauty, isn't she? Or isn't a young monk supposed to enjoy that?
What kind of man is the lord here?
Lord Rafox, well, he's a strong just lord.
Used to be different, he was in some sort of...
(Hooves)
(Bell tolls, cock crows)
(Dog barks)
Hey, brother... what was it?
Martin.
Ah, yes, Martin.
Such a bother here, never had that before.
Gate closed.
Do you know why?
Well, there were some knights who came in the night...
... friends of Lord Rafox's, and now the gate is closed.
But I have to get out with my basket, so...
Well, try again...
You again?
The gate stays closed.
So how do I get to the next castle then?
Hey, Brother Martin, it's no use, the gate is closed.
I don't know either, Lord Rafox, he's going off...
I told him the gate is closed, it's (??)
Good morning. The brother from the Brown Monastery, I presume?
Let me ask you, reverend brother.
Did you by any chance meet a boy on your way...
... about sixteen years old ...
... brown hair, blue eyes?
A boy? Not that I remember, my lord.
What's your name again, brother?
Martin.
Would you take your hood off, please?
Yes, may I ask why?
Look there. Brown hair and blue eyes.
Why, my lord? You're mistaken, you've got the wrong one.
What's going on, Father?
I'd like to introduce you to a couple of friends of mine.
If you aren't the one they're looking for nothing will happen.
I think this is the boy you're looking for.
Maybe.
Does he have the ring?
May I know who you are?
Where is the ring?
Ring? I don't know what you're talking about.
Were you travelling through the King's Wood?
No, I came from the Brown Monastery.
Search his clothes.
Why don't you just tell me who you are?
Do something! I'm your guest, I claim your protection!
Stop it! Stop it, I've got a ring.
This is the ring.
He's the one we've been looking for.
Rafox, he's ours now.
Take him away.
Lord Rafox, believe me. I've done nothing.
Believe me!
Let me go!
I am Tiuri, son of Tiuri the Valiant!
But I am the son of Tiuri the Valiant!
Hold your tongue, liar.
Wrong. Wrong.
I was wrong about you.
Who are you?
Are you really Tiuri the Valiant's son?
- Yes.
Why are you in disguise?
Because I...
Did you steal the ring and the horse Ardanwen?
- No!
I can explain everything.
Later.
Take your robe off, quick.
Put this on.
Why are you doing this?
I'm not to know anything...
... but I heard my father talking excitedly about you with the Grey Knights.
The Grey Knights?
They want revenge.
Revenge?
They want to avenge the death of a friend.
They'll come for you presently.
Why? It's not as if I...
My father has doubts about your guilt too.
But they have...
(Rattling at the door)
Come on!
Come on, here.
I think I know something.
At the back of the castle there's a rowboat in the moat.
If I take you...
Quick.
And thank you.
Come on!
Stop!
Come! Here!
You.
Stop! Here!
What do you want of me?
Please, tell me what you want.
Kneel.
Bendoe, you.
Tell me who you are!
Or are you some of the cowards who killed the Knight with the White Shield?
Stop!
Stop.
Why are you fleeing?
Only someone with a bad conscience takes flight.
You'd already condemned me.
Father! You think he's innocent.
So help him!
Tell him who you are, Ristridin.
I am Ristridin of the South.
These are Sir Bendoe and Sir Arwaut.
This is Sir Ewijn, he is from the West.
And you?
Are you Tiuri, the son of Tiuri the Valiant?
Yes.
Then tell me how in God's name it's possible that you left the chapel...
... the night before you were to be knighted.
That is not only unheard of and against all the rules...
... but you have also shamed your father, Tiuri the Valiant.
There was a reason. Which, I can't say.
No, of course not.
Because you can't say either who you got that ring from...
... and how you got the horse, Ardanwen.
How did you come by that ring?
Someone gave it to me.
Gave it.
A murdered knight.
He was ambushed ...
... by the Red Riders from Eviellan.
He told me that, just before he died.
Then he gave me the ring.
To a squire like you, I suppose.
Yes!
You must believe me, you knew him!
You were his friends!
Let's go inside.
Why didn't you go back at once that morning to seek help?
From your father or the king.
I promised not to say more than I've already said.
It's often that the mask of innocence hides falsehood and treason.
I'm not a traitor!
Much of this is unclear.
But I believe you.
And I want to apologise because I doubted your innocence.
Thank my daughter Lavinia that you're still alive.
Here, the ring.
And we'd like to accompany you for a bit tomorrow.
I must thank you that you believed me.
You were very brave.
Later, when I come back, I'll tell you everything.
I won't ask you what it is...
... but I suspect that Sir Edwinem entrusted you with a mission.
That your road is longer than to the hermit Menaures in the mountains.
Is Sir Edwinem the Black Knight with the White Shield?
Sir Edwinem of Foresterra.
Unauwen's noblest knight.
You know that Viridian, the Prince of Eviellan...
... is a son of the King of Unauwen?
Yes. Viridian is the younger of the twins.
Iridian is the elder. The crown prince.
Exactly. And Viridian hates his brother because he'll be King of Unauwen, not himself.
Viridian is his father's greatest enemy.
That is, he was.
A few months ago he suddenly wanted to make peace with his father.
The king sent some of his best knights to Eviellan at once...
... to negotiate.
Something went wrong.
We don't know exactly why, but Edwinem had to flee.
Well, you were the last person to speak to him.
Yes, but-- I still don't understand why...
Red Riders!
You stay with Tiuri!
Give me the letter!
Stay down, Tiuri.
Stay down.
You defended yourself well.
Whoa!
How's your arm?
Better.
Here our ways part, Tiuri.
You'll have to go on foot in the mountains.
Do I have to leave you again, Ardanwen.
You'll have him back as soon as your mission is done.
But he's not mine!
He is yours.
And take the robe. It's cold up there.
Take this rope, Tiuri. And my dagger.
Ilmar is your master now.
Until I 'm back.
And thanks Ilmar, you were really brave.
Valiant of you.
It's all right, Tiuri.
Thank you! Thank you all!
Watch out for strangers!
Good journey, Tiuri!
(Footsteps)
Wait! Traveller!
Greetings, pilgrim. What a climb!
I'm so glad to see you. I'm not very much at home in the mountains.
I suppose you're going to see the hermit Menaures?
Yes.
Is it all right if I travel with you?
To be honest I'd rather travel alone. I'm in a hurry.
I'm sorry, brother.
I didn't mean to impose.
I'll rest here for a while.
Goodbye.
I didn't mean it like that. Of course you can come along.
I'm sorry I was so rude.
I promise I won't be in the way.
I'm Jaro. I live in the valley.
I am ... Martin.
Brother Martin.
Shall I go ahead?
We should go up there. On top, along the chasm.
Aah! Aargh!
Help me!
Take my hand.
Grab the rope!
It's no use.
I'm coming!
Stand on my knee!
Aargh!
- Stand on my knee!
Help me up!
Help me!
Why didn't you help me?
Good evening.
Good evening to you too.
You've come to see Menaures?
Yes.
Menaures? Menaures.
Visitors.
Welcome, travellers.
What brings you here?
Er, well, I er...
- As for me, I'm bound for the other side of the mountains...
... holy man.
I'm not a holy man.
Who are you?
Er, I'm Martin, and this is...
- Jaro.
I've heard that you know the way through the mountains like no other.
Ways I know, yes. Unfortunately I can't follow them myself any more.
Perhaps you can show them to us?
Even then. It's impossible without a guide.
And, brother Martin, wat is the goal of your journey?
Er, yes, I want to...
I 'd like to talk to you about something.
Hm?
I'll wait here.
Let's go into the hut.
My name isn't Martin.
I'm not a monk.
That's what I thought.
I am Tiuri.
Sir Edwinem sent me. This is the ring he gave to me.
Sir Edwinem. Bearer of the White Shield.
He is dead. He's been murdered.
That is sad news indeed.
I've known him for a long time. He's been here often.
Sit down, Tiuri, and tell me more.
You're hurt!
A little.
And your mission will become harder still.
I don't know if I can do this, Menaures.
Why didn't someone else, a knight, get the mission?
Don't give up now, Tiuri.
I'll give you a guide.
One you can trust like yourself.
My faithful helper Piak, the boy you saw outside.
But don't you need him yourself?
This is more important.
Thank you.
Put this on. That mail shirt is far too heavy to wear in the mountains.
(Door squeaks)
I couldn't sleep.
Menaures, do you know what is in the letter?
No, I don't know. Any more than you do.
But you don't have to know. Your only charge is to deliver the letter.
Do you know King Unauwen and his sons?
Yes.
I'm his brother. His twin brother.
(Thunder)
The king's twin brother!
Then you must know that Viridian wants to make peace with his father.
Yes, perhaps he wants that.
It's not easy being twins.
(Thunder)
What do you think of Jaro?
I think he can't sleep either, just like us.
You go. I'll keep watch.
Thank you.
You really have to squeeze it, Piak.
And roll it up better.
Good morning, Jaro. Are you ready to travel?
- I'm leaving.
Leaving? What do you mean?
I'm going back. You beat me, yesterday.
Beat you? How?
I'm one of the Red Riders sent to kill you...
... so the letter you carry with you would never reach the king of Unauwen.
I wanted to pull you into the chasm and then you were foolish enough to save my life.
And by your folly...
... you made me powerless.
I can't kill you. Not any more.
Farewell.
But what will you do now?
That's none of your business.
And don't think the danger is over now, either.
If I don't return in time he will do everything to arrive before you do, by the main road.
Who is 'he'?
Slupor.
There's no one meaner or more cunning.
Be careful. Very careful.
Yes, it's all right, Piak.
See that Tiuri gets across the mountains as quickly as possible.
Go with him as far as is needed.
Thank you, Menaures.
Auspicious journey.
Fancy your father being a knight. So are you his squire?
Yes.
So you've learnt swordfighting, archery...
Living in the mountains is splendid too.
All my family is from the mountains.
My father fell into a chasm one day.
Because he was a daredevil, they said.
Are you a daredevil, too?
Don't worry.
I can't see a thing! We have to find shelter.
I know a cave. Come on!
We have to stay awake. Don't go to sleep!
(Footsteps)
Hey! Stay awake!
Were you dreaming?
I think so.
Of what?
My father.
Your father?
Yes, my father, I think.
And I know about your secret mission, too.
The letter.
But you can trust me.
I do trust you, Piak.
But you must never let anyone else know what you know.
Okay.
Not that my name is Tiuri, either.
Look, Tiuri: Unauwen.
I'm wondering so much what the country is like.
I've never been there.
What is it?
Weren't you going to take me over the mountains...
... and then go back to Menaures?
Can't I come any further?
Well, you promised Menaures that you...
That I'd go with you as far as you need me.
Did he say that?
I don't need you any more, Piak.
You hate it, don't you, to be...
Piak, listen. It's just plain too
Dangerous? Two can do much more than one, can't they?
Tiuri, please. Let me come with you, and then...
Then I'll be your squire and obey you in everything.
- Stop that nonsense!
We're just... fellow travellers.
That's all right too.
Yes?
Okay.
Do you know the city of Dagonaut?
Yes, I've been there a couple of times.
Do you come here often, in Dangria?
Yes, every now and again. Used to be more often.
Good afternoon, Lord Ardoc.
Who are your companions, if I may ask?
Two young men from Dagonaut, from the mountains.
Well, then I've got a pleasant surprise for you.
Our mayor is always very interested in news from Dagonaut.
I'm sure he'll like to meet you and dine with you.
Very nice of the mayor, but we're rather in a hurry.
An invitation from the mayor? I know what I'd do.
I wouldn't refuse that.
And if you want to tell about it, I'm in the White Swan Inn.
- Come along!
Wait here a moment.
The mayor will be along presently.
Well, well, what a surprise. Young men from Dagonaut.
Welcome to my city.
Thank you, Lord Mayor.
I thought there were two of you.
Yes, my friend is somewhere around here.
He's quite impressed with the hall.
Let him have a look around.
My secretary will see that you have a nice room.
All right. Then we'll go upstairs now.
Martin! It's a trap! The letter! I've got it here!
Stop him!
I'll deliver it!
Hey, you. After him!
Stay here! Come back! Come back!
Yes, there!
Open up! Open!
(Banging on the door)
The key's gone.
Go!
Open up!
Open that door!
Open it!
He's here. Lads!
Use the other door.
... from the other side ...
Here he is.
Ek byor ... what is this?
Call the gatekeepers. Search the whole city!
Inns, cellars. Move, lazybones!
The door's been bolted from the inside.
Clumsy oafs. Break that door.
No, get an axe!
Open up!
- Ek byor ... (etcetera)
This is the mayor speaking.
Come out. You can't go anywhere.
(strange language)
For the last time: give yourself up!
This is my final warning. Open that door!
All right, stubborn little git, stay where you are.
We'll take care of that friend of yours first.
Piak!
Hands on your head! Stand still.
I'll shoot you if you move.
Good.
And now back slowly, very slowly.
Backwards.
Turn! Turn!
Hands on your back!
Now to the wall. To the wall!
(Footsteps)
(Banging on the door)
Help! Help! He's locked me in!
Stay!
Hands up!
Who are you?
- That's not important.
Apparently the mayor was expecting you.
He gave orders to the gatekeepers that every young man...
... between fourteen and eighteen who passed the gate ...
... was to be brought to him.
How do you know?
A few days ago he got a message from the east.
By carrier pigeon.
I wasn't allowed to read it or to file the letter.
Who was the message from?
I don't
You probably know that a lot better.
It's safe.
Why do you want to help me?
Because lately there's a lot happening in the city hall and in the city that I don't like.
With the mayor...
- Piak! My friend!
They've caught him. I have to help him!
Well, better go right now then.
You can help your friend best if you're free.
I'd hurry if I were you.
Excuse me, do you happen to know where the White Swan Inn is?
I know the way. I'll show you.
If you want to be caught, do keep carrying that bow and arrow around.
Wait here.
(Noise)
Tiuri!
Piak!
I was hiding behind here. I don't dare go inside.
Oh, I'm so glad that they didn't ...
- Not you, either?
The secretary.
The whole city is ...
-Go, go, go, go!
... have a look, because they entered the city with this merchant Ardoc.
The mayor closed all the gates, so we should be able to find them.
We'll keep looking, Master Secretary.
- I'll keep looking for them too.
Your friend hasn't been in.
Ah! All right, you must go. Now.
I know a way. Come on!
I'll go to the City of Unauwen as soon as I can to inform the king.
Listen. Over here, then to the right.
Go on until you get to the Rainbow River and cross the toll-bridge.
Yes.
- Go!
Thank you.
- Thanks.
Here you are, and goodbye!
Come, let's go.
Three gold pieces!?
Hi Warmin.
Whoever crosses the Rainbow River for the first time has to pay the toll.
But we don't have that much.
Then you can't pass.
So poor people can never cross.
Oh yes they can!
They can earn their toll money by working on the lord's farms, over there.
Each week that you work you earn one gold piece, so...
We don't have that much time.
That's what everybody says who wants to cross for free.
Anyone who tries to cross some other way ...
... is caught and locked up for three weeks.
All right, let's go work on the farm. Come on.
You didn't mean it about the farm, did you?
No, of course not. We'll have to think of something else.
I can't swim.
You can still go back.
Why? Do you think I'm scared?
Yes.
I've got an idea. But we'll have to wait until dark. Come on.
I don't mind if you start a little later ...
Are you all right?
We're almost there.
I see.
Piak!
Piak! Piak!
It's so much water.
We've made it.
Tiuri! You rescued me!
What are you talking about? Of course I rescued you.
Not listening, eh? Now you're even worse off!
Three weeks in the lockup.
No! I want to speak to the lord!
Wait what?
- I've got something! I can pay with this.
It's worth much more than three gold pieces.
I was really given it, my lord.
Given? By whom?
You're babbling! Look!
There are only twelve of these.
It's a personal gift from the King of Unauwen.
Don't tell me any lies! How did you get this ring?
My lord, I got it from someone I think you know.
Sir Edwinem.
Are you claiming that Sir Edwinem gave you this ring?
- He's been murdered, my lord.
What did you say?
- He's been murdered.
By the Red Riders from Eviellan.
Murdered.
Whoa!
I'm on my way to Unauwen.
Ah! The secretary. Good evening.
- I have an important message for the king.
Have a good journey.
I don't understand any more what's going on in this country.
But I do understand now why you are in such a hurry.
I just hope we can stay ahead of that Slupor.
Do you have any idea of what he looks like?
- None, my lord.
Here. Give it only to the king himself.
Marwinni, see that he and his friend Piak ...
... get horses and weapons, they must be off at once.
Certainly, my lord.
Thank you.
Where did you learn to ride like that, little horseman?
On a mountain goat, little knight.
Go ahead.
(strange language)
Piak, do you have a good memory? Words and things?
Words? How, words?
Er, yes.
Ek byo jor adleggia alt kappa.
- What? What did you say?
Those are some of the words from the letter.
I think you should learn them too.
You said that my mission is yours as well.
If anything happens to me, then... then you...
Hm. Say something?
All right. Listen.
Ek byo jor adleggia alt kappa.
Ek byo jor...
... adeggia ...
- ... adleggia ...
... kappa.
- Alt kappa.
Alt kappa.
You know what, Tiuri? We ought to sing it.
Sing it?
- Yes. That makes it easier to remember.
(Singing) Ek byo jor adleggia alt kappa ...
Not so loud!
(Humming)
Come. Shh.
Did you hear that?
What was that?
I don't know.
(Footsteps)
What are you doing?
- I'm going to look. You stay here.
Piak, he helped us, and now ...
Don't move!
There, by that tree, on the hill.
Come on!
If he's there our lives are at stake.
Who? Do you think ...
- Shh!
Come on, come on!
They must be here somewhere. I can tell by the tracks.
I think that's Warmin.
Martin! Piak!
Who are you?
I am Warmin, the tollbridge warden,
to offer you protect you.
Er, we just found someone.
Dead. There.
I'll see to it that he's buried.
Iminir let the black stranger through ...
... who asked whether two young men, friends of his from Dangria ...
... had passed through.
I told him that I'd let through a young horseman from Dangria ...
... with a sealed message for King Unauwen.
Then he looked at me with very scary eyes ...
... and he wanted to know what the young man looked like.
And he spurred on his horse right away.
Yes, I thought it was so strange, I went to tell the lord at once.
You search around here.
Catch him, dead or alive. Go!
We'll accompany you to the inn at Ingewel.
Why did you let us sleep?
You were exhausted.
Yes, but we have to go quickly.
I know; eat first.
Eat something.
There's a messenger here wants to speak to the warden. Is that you
- Yes.
Are you Master Warmin from the toll bridge?
I have a message for you.
And for the two young men travelling with you.
Go on.
Tonight in our village your men caught the one ...
... who killed that young man from Dangria.
He had a strange name, Sloo... Sl...
Oh! Slupor, I think.
Slupor!
First he denied being the killer, but when we'd locked him up ...
... he started to curse and swear like anything.
It fair scared me!
But fortunately he's locked up now.
They've caught him, Piak.
Thank you very much for this good news.
No thanks, Master Warmin.
I'll be getting back home. Good day.
Well lads, you've heard it.
- Yes.
You can go on alone.
We're there! Almost.
Come on.
There.
Excuse me, do you know where the palace is
- That way.
Thank you.
Friendly people here.
- Yes.
A penny please ... Please, a penny ...
Please, travellers, a penny!
Shall we give him our last coins?
- Yes. For luck.
Thank you, stranger.
May you achieve in your life what you deserve.
Slupor!
- You fool!
Give me the letter!
Get that beggar! A traitor! A murderer!
Tiuri! Catch!
See him lying there.
Sir Tiuri the Valiant's spoilt little boy.
Everything has gone wrong.
No letter for the king and not a knight.
It was all in vain, little man.
Pride goes before the fall.
Come on, strike!
Hey! Or don't you have the guts?
Another attack of compassion?
Coward!
Let go of me!
A curse on you, Tiuri, and on your famous father.
Blood be on you, the king, and this whole despicable country.
Dead!
Tiuri! The ring, the ring!
I've got a very important message for the king!
This ring is proof. You must believe me!
You must believe me!
All right. To the palace.
The king can receive you now.
- Good luck.
Come closer, messenger.
Sire, I bring you a message from Sir Edwinem with the White Shield.
Rise. First, rise.
I have to tell you that Sir Edwinem ...
... is dead,.
Before he died he gave me a letter to deliver to you ...
... and his ring as well.
Give me the letter.
I don't have it any more.
Sir Edwinem laid it on me to destroy the letter ...
... if there was any danger of it being taken from me.
So I did that.
But I know the contents by heart.
Who are you?
Tiuri, Sire.
Well, Tiuri, I'm listening.
I have to think.
My friend, he's waiting outside, he knows ... he's made a tune ...
(Hums)
Ek byo jor ...
Ek byo jor adleggia (etcetera)
That's all.
Call the crown prince and all knights and councillors of the realm ...
... for a very pressing matter, at once.
It has been known to you for some time ...
... that the Prince of Eviellan, my son Viridian, sought to make peace.
But then, the letter arrives ...
... which tells us what danger would have befallen us ...
... if we had accepted his proposals for peace.
It says that after the treaty the crown prince, Prince Iridian ...
... would have met with sudden death.
Viridian was plotting to poison his brother ...
... his twin brother! ...
... as soon as nobody suspected him of any malice any longer.
To have him murdered.
And he himself would have been heir to the throne ...
... and so, after my death, ruler of our beloved realm, Unauwen.
And from here he would also have been a threat for the Realm of Dagonaut ...
... the homeland of Tiuri and his friend.
It is a sad tale, a very sad tale, that I had to tell.
But now we know where the danger lies.
Therefore I would call you, if it is needed ...
... to take up arms together against him.
Which of you will join me?
(Cheers)
Menaures!
Piak. Welcome.
Tiuri.
- Good day, Menaures.
Come on in.
Everybody is grateful to you, Tiuri ...
... for what you have accomplished together with Piak.
Have you missed me, Menaures?
Certainly I have.
And-- what if I went with Tiuri to Dagonaut?
That I have missed you doesn't mean that I can't do without you.
There will always be something you miss, whether you go or stay.
You have to make up your own mind, Piak.
Goodbye.
- Goodbye.
Whoa!
Tiuri! You're back!
Sire.
That you ran away from the chapel,
that has never happened of here before.
And I consider it a very serious transgression.
Now go, and give my regards to your father.
Tiuri!
- Mother!
O darling, I've been so worried!
How is Father? What does he think ...
I don't know. He's been very upset. I ...
(Footsteps)
Father, I ...
If in four years you get another chance ...
... to have a wake in the chapel ...
... and there would be someone asking for help again ...
... what would you do?
I'd do the same.
You'd do the same.
I'm so sorry, Father.
I'm so glad you're standing here in front of me again, son.
And that you're alive.
That you're alive, my son.
But I'm not a knight.
I've heard that you have behaved in a knightly way.
Not all the time.
Father, may I be your squire again for the next four years?
That is for the king to decide.
And that is why our knights also, with their men ...
... will go to the southern border ...
... to stop the power-hungry Prince Viridian.
But in the letter I was sent by King Unauwen ...
... which has been delivered to me by Tiuri, son of Sir Tiuri ...
... there is more.
And that is why I now ask him to come forward.
Tiuri, son of Tiuri the Valiant ...
... you know that in this palace ...
... squires are knighted only once every four years.
You have forfeited your chance.
If that night in the chapel you would not have answered ...
... the plea for help ...
... then you would now have been ...
... a knight, like the four others.
But--
But now that you have done that ...
... and kept your promise to the murdered Sir Edwinem of Foresterra ...
... and so spared both Unauwen and our country a disaster ...
... would you not be a knight?
You haven't been dubbed ...
... but you have shown yourself to be a knight.
You can be a knight even without sword and shield.
Give me your sword.
Kneel.
Sir Tiuri.
You shall have Sir Edwinem of Foresterra's shield.
And that the shield is white also means that you, at his express request ...
... shall also serve the King of Unauwen.
Because you saved both our countries from disaster.
Arise, Sir Tiuri.
I vow to serve you faithfully as a knight, and also all your subjects ...
... and whosoever seeks succour from me.
I vow to wield my sword only for good, against evil ...
... and with my shield protect those that are weaker than myself.
Long live Sir Tiuri with the White Shield!
(Applause)
Tiuri spent that night in solitude in the chapel ...
... to prove himself in the knight's final test after all.
Now all his adventures seemed a dream.
He thought of the people he had met ...
... of his future as a knight ...
... and above all of Lavinia.
But that Piak had chosen to leave Menaures ...
... to become his squire ...
Piak
- Tiuri!
... was more than he had dared dream.
Is that Lavinia?
Yes. That's her.
Subtitles: Irina Rempt 2011
irina@valdyas.org