[dramatic music]
- THE POSTER SAID,
"JOIN THE ARMY.
SEE THE WORLD."
I'D JUST GRADUATED FROM COLLEGE
WITH NO FUTURE PLANS.
THE WORLD TURNED OUT TO BE
THE DESERTS OF THE MIDDLE EAST.
THE PERSIAN GULF WAR
HAD BEEN OVER FOR FOUR YEARS.
SO FAR, MY FIRST YEARS
IN THE ARMY HAD BEEN UNEVENTFUL
UNTIL NOW.
¶ ¶
[helicopter blades whirring]
[indistinct radio transmission]
CORPORAL JANIS MCKENZIE
REPORTING.
ARE YOU CAPTAIN BEN ROGERS?
- NO, CAPTAIN ROGERS IS
ON ASSIGNMENT.
I'M CARLYLE.
I SEE YOU KNOW WHO WE ARE.
- I WAS BRIEFED AT HEADQUARTERS.
- DO YOU HAVE A NICKNAME,
OR WILL JANIS DO?
- JANIS WILL DO.
- THIS IS
PRIVATE BERNARD SCHWARTZ.
- SCHWARTZ?
- THEY CALL ME BERNIE.
- WE'RE BRITISH
SPECIAL AIR SERVICES.
WE'RE A SECRET UNIT.
WE OFTEN WORK WITH DELTA FORCE.
- I KNOW SADDAM HUSSEIN
AND HIS ARMY
ARE THREATENING TO INVADE AGAIN.
BUT WHY AM I HERE?
- WELL, YOU'RE GONNA BE
OUR LIAISON TO HEADQUARTERS.
GIVE HER A CLIPBOARD.
BUT IN THE MEANWHILE,
I'VE GOT SOMETHING
FOR YOU TWO TO DO.
THIS IS SECTION "D."
IT'S SUPPOSED TO BE DESERTED.
I WANT YOU TO GO THERE,
RECONNOITER THE ENTIRE AREA,
AND BRING ME BACK
A FULL RECONNAISSANCE REPORT.
GIVE HER THE M9.
[gun clicks]
NOW, YOU KEEP THAT HIDDEN.
ALL RIGHT,
YOU TWO ARE DISMISSED.
- IT SOUNDED LIKE A NICE BREAK.
SURE BEAT THE TEDIUM OF A DESK
AT ARMY INTELLIGENCE.
HOW COULD I KNOW TODAY
WOULD CHANGE MY LIFE FOREVER?
RELAX, BERNIE.
THIS SECTOR'S DESERTED.
SERGEANT SAID SO.
- I KNOW, BUT SOMETHING
JUST DOESN'T FEEL RIGHT.
WHEN YOU'RE OUT IN THE OPEN,
YOU CAN'T BE TOO CAREFUL.
- DON'T WORRY.
I'LL BACK YOU UP
WITH MY CLIPBOARD.
- HMM, I PREFERRED YOU HAD
YOUR BERETTA LOCKED AND LOADED.
- OH, I GOT THAT TOO.
HEY, YOU STILL WANT A MERCEDES?
- [scoffs]
- [chuckles]
- JANIS, SADDAM HUSSEIN
HAS A VERY LARGE ARMY,
READY TO INVADE AT ANY TIME.
THIS IS SERIOUS.
- I KNOW.
TRY THE DOOR?
- UH, DON'T DO THAT.
- SAYS HERE, "AUTO REPAIR SHOP."
- [chuckles]
LOOKS LIKE A JUNKYARD.
[plastic rustling]
- I DON'T THINK SO.
UH, NOW YOU'RE GONNA RELAX?
- JANIS, HOW MANY IRAQIS
DOES IT TAKE
TO FIRE OFF A SCUD MISSILE?
- HOW MANY?
- THREE:
ONE TO LOAD IT,
ONE TO FIRE IT,
AND ONE TO WATCH NEWS TV
TO SEE WHERE IT LANDS.
[laughing]
JANIS...
UH, THAT WAS A JOKE.
- BERNIE, THIS PLACE
IS NOT DESERTED.
- WHICH COULD LEAD TO CONFLICT.
LET'S GET THE HELL OUT OF HERE.
[explosion]
- SADDAM HUSSEIN'S
STILL AT THE BORDER?
- 'FRAID SO.
HE WON'T INVADE.
- THAT'S WHAT YOU YANKS SAID
FOUR YEARS AGO.
STILL GOT MY DESERT STORM PATCH.
SO WHAT'S NEWS AT HEADQUARTERS,
CAPTAIN?
- I SEE YOU'RE READY.
- YOU KNOW, YOU DELTA GUYS,
THE MOST SECRET WELL-TRAINED
GROUP IN THE ARMY,
YET YOU WEAR CIVILIAN CLOTHES.
- WE HAVE TO SWIM IN A SEA
OF PEOPLE, SERGEANT MAJOR.
- I KNOW WHO SAID THAT.
YOU JUST GIVE ME
ONE LITTLE SECOND, AND I'LL--
OH, CORPORAL MCKENZIE REPORTED
THIS MORNING.
NOW, SHE'S NOT A DELTA OPERATOR,
IS SHE?
- NO, MILITARY INTELLIGENCE.
SHE'LL COLLECT OUR FINDINGS
AND REPORT BACK TO HEADQUARTERS.
SO WHERE--
WHERE IS CORPORAL MCKENZIE?
- SENT HER AND SCHWARTZ
OVER TO "D" SECTION,
THE DESERTED SECTION.
- YOU DID WHAT?
THAT'S WHY
I WAS AT HEADQUARTERS.
TERRORISTS ARE MOVING
INTO THAT AREA RIGHT NOW.
- BETTER GET OVER THERE.
- HE'S GOING TO A DRUG PROGRAM.
THAT'S IT.
- NO!
- YES, YOU ARE.
- YOUR FATHER GOES TO WORK
EVERY DAY TO EARN THIS PLACE,
AND YOU JUST GO
AND THROW YOUR LIFE AWAY!
- GET OFF OF MY CASE.
- YOU'RE GOING
TO DRUG TREATMENT,
AND THAT'S IT.
- SHUT UP.
I'M GOING TO KILL YOU.
I'M GOING TO KILL BOTH OF YOU.
- BERNIE...
BERNIE...
- JANIS, JANIS, I CAN'T SEE.
- BERNIE, GIVE ME YOUR GUN.
- [speaking Arabic]
[gunshots]
- AHH!
AHH.
[gunshots]
- YOU'RE DEAD, JANIS.
- [screams]
- JANIS.
- JANIS!
[pounding]
COME OUT, JANIS!
- [screaming]
[helicopter blades whirring]
- WHOA, HO, HEY, HEY, HO, HO.
ALL RIGHT, ARE MCKENZIE
AND SCHWARTZ IN THERE?
- MCKENZIE, SCHWARTZ,
AND A PILE OF DEAD TERRORISTS.
- JANIS, JANIS, JANIS!
HEY, OKAY, IT'S OKAY.
IT'S OKAY.
- JANIS, HEY...
- IT'S OKAY.
IT'S OKAY.
THEY'RE ALL DEAD, OKAY?
THEY'RE ALL DEAD.
JANIS, WE'RE GONNA
GET YOU OUT OF HERE.
YOU'RE GONNA BE FINE.
JANIS, EASY,
[echoing voices overlapping]
ALL RIGHT,
I'M CAPTAIN BEN ROGERS.
I'M HERE TO HELP YOU, ALL RIGHT?
ROGERS.
YOU'RE FINE.
COME ON, GET UP, COME ON.
YOU CAN MAKE IT.
COME ON, YOU CAN MAKE IT.
COME ON.
GO CHECK BERNIE.
- ALL RIGHT.
- WE'RE GONNA HEAR ABOUT THIS
AT HEADQUARTERS.
THEY'LL BE SINGING YOUR PRAISES.
- WHAT ABOUT THEM?
- THE DEAD DON'T SING.
- SORRY, BERNIE.
- COME ON.
- KADIR, THE LEADER...
[electronic beeping]
- DR. LATZ, GO TO PEDIATRICS.
- HELLO, DOCTOR.
- HI, HOW ARE YOU?
- IS THIS
CORPORAL MCKENZIE'S ROOM?
- UH, YES IT IS.
- I'M CAPTAIN ROGERS,
HER COMMANDING OFFICER.
- I'M COLONEL ASKINS,
ARMY MED CORPS.
- NICE TO MEET YOU.
HOW'S SHE DOING?
- SHE'S OUT OF INTENSIVE CARE,
AND THAT'S A GOOD SIGN.
BAD SIGN IS, SHE'S NOT GONNA
WALK FOR A FEW MONTHS.
- THANK YOU, DOCTOR.
- GO AHEAD.
YOU'RE HER FIRST VISITOR.
- THANK YOU.
- DR. LANE IN SURGERY.
[electronic beeping]
- SERGEANT CARLYLE.
- NO, CARLYLE'S OFF
ON ASSIGNMENT.
BUT HE TOLD ME
TO TELL YOU HELLO.
- YOU MUST BE CAPTAIN ROGERS.
- YEAH.
- BERNIE DIDN'T MAKE IT,
DID HE?
- BERNIE WOULD HAVE BEEN
REALLY PROUD OF YOU.
YOU TOOK OUT
ALL FIVE TERRORISTS.
- AND YOU CARRIED ME
OUT OF A DEATH TRAP.
I REMEMBER NOW.
THANK YOU.
- I SHOULDN'T TIRE YOU.
I JUST CAME BY TO GIVE YOU
A BIG HUG.
- [scoffs]
PLEASE DON'T.
EVERY INCH OF ME HURTS.
- IT'S JUST A JOKE.
CAPTAINS DON'T HUG CORPORALS.
I BETTER GO.
- PLEASE, STAY.
A FEW MONTHS LATER,
BEN DISAPPEARED.
IT WOULD BE THE LAST TIME
I SAW HIM.
[camera clicking]
- HI, THERE.
I'M CAROL DODD.
I'M THE MANAGER HERE.
- OH, HEY,
JANIS MCKENZIE.
- NICE TO FINALLY MEET YOU,
JANIS.
YOU'RE DOING THE PHOTOGRAPHY
FOR THE NEW BROCHURE, RIGHT?
- YEAH.
GOSH, YOUR CLUB IS BEAUTIFUL.
YOU'RE MAKING MY JOB
REALLY EASY.
- THANK YOU.
TODAY'S MY DAY
TO CHECK THE TROOPS.
I DON'T KNOW WHY I SAID THAT.
- SUBLIMINAL MESSAGE MAYBE?
I WAS IN THE U.S. ARMY
FOR SIX YEARS.
- WOW!
I BET YOU HAVE STORIES
TO TELL.
SORRY, I HOPE
I DIDN'T PUSH A BUTTON.
[camera clicking]
IS THAT FOR THE BROCHURE?
- NO, THAT WAS FOR BLACKMAIL.
- [chuckles] LIKE I WAS SAYING,
TODAY'S MY DAY
TO COVER THE GROUNDS--
LANDSCAPING,
TENNIS COURTS, POOL--
SO IF YOU NEED ANYTHING,
JUST GIVE ME A BIG TEXAS HOLLER,
AND I'M BOUND TO HEAR YOU.
- OH, I'LL GIVE YOU
A BIG TEXAS HOLLER, ALL RIGHT.
- OKAY, JANIS.
- THANKS.
[engine revving]
- LOOK OUT!
LET ME HELP YOU.
HE COULD HAVE KILLED YOU.
MAYBE WE SHOULD CLEAN THAT UP.
- LOOK, I'M FINE REALLY.
I HAVE TO GET TO TOWN.
WESLEY ADVERTISING'S
WAITING FOR THESE PICTURES.
- IF YOU'RE SURE...
- YEAH, I AM.
THANK YOU, THOUGH.
- THIS ONE'S GREAT.
THIS ONE'S PERFECT.
THIS ONE, YOU NAILED IT.
- THANKS.
- I NEED YOU
TO COME WORK FOR ME.
- OH, COME ON,
I ALREADY WORK FOR YOU.
- FREELANCE, FREE-LANCE.
I NEED THIS.
I NEED YOU FULL-TIME.
- CAN'T DO THAT.
YOU KNOW WHY.
LISTEN, WE HAVE BEEN OVER THIS
A MILLION TIMES.
I CAN'T WORK FOR YOU FULL-TIME.
JUST--I WANT TO BE FREE,
AND I DON'T WANT
TO FEEL TIED DOWN.
- OKAY, OKAY, FREELANCE IT IS.
I'VE GOT A JOB FOR YOU.
I NEED YOU TO SHOOT DOWN
AT THE BEACH BAR.
IT'S DUE BY FRIDAY.
- OKAY.
I CAN DO THAT.
FREELANCE.
- NEXT TIME, YOU'LL SAY YES.
- I'LL THINK ABOUT IT.
[tires squealing]
- OH, MY GOD, JOEY,
ARE YOU OKAY?
HE NEVER STOPPED.
I DON'T THINK HE EVEN SAW YOU.
- OH, HE SAW ME.
- I THINK FIONA WILL BE PLEASED
WITH THOSE SHOTS.
- GOOD.
- SO IS THAT IT FOR THE DAY?
- THAT IS MY LAST SHOT.
- EXCELLENT.
WHY DON'T WE GO INSIDE
FOR A DRINK?
- NAH, I CAN'T.
- SURE, YOU CAN.
I SAVED YOUR ASS YESTERDAY.
- FAIR ENOUGH.
GIVE ME JUST A COUPLE MINUTES.
I HAVE TO PUT THIS STUFF AWAY.
- SEE YOU INSIDE?
- YES, I WILL SEE YOU INSIDE.
- HEY.
- YOU MADE IT.
- YEP.
- GREAT.
- GET EVERYTHING
ALL PACKED UP?
- I DID.
- EXCELLENT.
- HI, GIRLS, HOW'S IT GOING?
- GOING GREAT.
- YOU A TEXAS FAN?
- OH, YEAH, HOOK 'EM HORNS
ALL THE WAY.
- YES, TEXAS LONGHORNS,
MY ALMA MATER.
WHERE'D YOU GO TO SCHOOL, JANIS?
- FLORIDA.
- ME TOO.
- BULL.
DON'T BELIEVE HIM, JANIS.
HE HAS A HAT FOR EVERY PLACE
IN THE WORLD.
BOOMER, MEET JANIS MCKENZIE.
- OH, HI, JANIS.
GOOD TO MEET YOU.
- SHE'S DOING THE PHOTOGRAPHY
FOR OUR BROCHURE.
- WONDERFUL, WOULD YOU LIKE
SOMETHING TO DRINK?
- WHAT ARE YOU HAVING?
- SARASOTA GOLD.
- I'LL TAKE ONE OF THOSE.
- COMIN' UP.
- ARE YOU ALMOST FINISHED?
- YEAH, JUST ABOUT.
- I'VE SEEN YOUR WORK.
YOU'RE VERY GOOD.
- THANKS.
- SO WHAT'S BUGGIN' YA?
'CAUSE YOU'RE LIKE
TALKING TO A DEAD MULE.
MY GRANDDADDY USED TO SAY
THAT TO ME
WHEN HE KNEW
SOMETHING WAS WRONG.
SO?
OUT WITH IT.
- I ALMOST GOT HIT BY A TRUCK
YESTERDAY.
- YEAH, I KNOW.
I WAS THERE.
- NOT THAT ONE.
ANOTHER ONE.
- TWICE IN ONE DAY?
WHAT A COINCIDENCE.
NOT A COINCIDENCE?
JANIS, YOU NEED TO TALK
TO SOMEONE.
- I DON'T WANT TO TALK TO--
- PLEASE TAKE IT.
- SHRINK?
- NO.
A PSYCHOLOGIST,
AND SHE'S VERY GOOD.
SHE HELPED ME
THROUGH MY BAD TIME.
- [sighs]
MARIE BARBEAU.
- HI, I'M MARIE BARBEAU.
- HI.
- I KNOW.
I SHOULD'VE BEEN BORN
IN THE 18TH CENTURY.
UH, LOUNGE OR CHAIR?
CHAIR, I THINK.
BORN AUGUSTA, GEORGIA,
36 YEARS AGO.
I SEE YOU'RE A COLLEGE GRADUATE.
WHERE?
- FLORIDA.
- UNIVERSITY OF, I ASSUME?
- MM-HMM.
- UNIVERSITY OF FLORIDA.
YOU MAJORED IN...
YOU DIDN'T FILL IN THE BLANK.
- OH, ENGLISH.
- ENGLISH.
POPULAR IN SCHOOL?
JANIS, I'M NOT A DENTIST.
IT IS NOT MY HABIT TO PRY
INFORMATION OUT OF A PATIENT.
IF I'M TO HELP YOU,
YOU HAVE TO HELP ME.
IS THAT UNDERSTOOD?
- YES.
- GOOD.
NOW, JANIS,
WERE YOU POPULAR IN SCHOOL?
- MY BROTHER
MURDERED OUR PARENTS.
- YOU'RE DEAD, JANIS.
- WHAT DO YOU THINK?
- COME ON, MCKENZIE.
YOU'RE DRAGGING.
- WHAT ARE MY CHANCES?
- PAROLE?
[chuckles]
NOT GOOD.
HOW LONG?
- HOW LONG FOR WHAT?
- HOW LONG YOU BEEN IN PRISON,
SMART-ASS?
- SINCE YOU PUT IT THAT WAY,
NONE OF YOUR DAMN BUSINESS.
- LET'S GO, SIT DOWN.
[telephone ringing]
GOT JAMEY MCKENZIE HERE
FOR A PAROLE HEARING.
[telephone continues ringing]
- WHAT ARE YOU LOOKING AT?
I'M TALKING TO YOU.
- HEY, HEY, NONE OF THAT.
- KNOCK IT OFF.
- ANYMORE OF THAT CRAP,
AND YOU GUYS WILL NEVER
GET OUT OF HERE.
- MCKENZIE,
THEY'RE READY FOR YOU.
- LET'S GO.
- YOUR BROTHER, JAMEY MCKENZIE,
WHERE IS HE NOW?
- PRISON.
- ONE MOMENT, PLEASE.
CAROL AND I WENT TO CHINA
TWO YEARS AGO.
THAT'S QUAN YIN,
GODDESS OF WISDOM AND MERCY.
SOMETIMES I THINK OF CAROL
AS QUAN YIN.
[chuckles]
- CAROL SAID YOU HELPED HER.
- SHE DID?
WHAT DID SHE SAY?
- JUST THAT YOU HELPED HER OUT
OF A BAD TIME.
- HMM, WELL, ANYTHING ELSE,
YOU GET FROM HER.
- DOCTOR-PATIENT PRIVACY?
- SOMETHING LIKE THAT.
YOUR BROTHER IS UP FOR PAROLE.
DID YOU KNOW THAT?
- HOW DID YOU KNOW?
- I CHECKED, JUST NOW.
ARE YOU IN CONTACT WITH HIM?
- ALL THE TIME.
- REALLY?
THAT'S SURPRISING.
- NOT IN THE WAY YOU THINK.
YOU SEE, WE'RE TWINS.
SOMETIMES, I JUST KNOW
WHAT HE'S THINKING.
- WHAT IS HE THINKING?
- JANIS, I'M GONNA KILL YOU.
- I STILL DON'T UNDERSTAND
WHY HE WANTS TO KILL YOU.
- MY TESTIMONY SENT HIM TO JAIL.
- WELL, THAT WOULD'VE
HAPPENED ANYWAY.
- HE DOESN'T SEE IT THAT WAY.
- DO YOU DREAM AT NIGHT?
- NIGHTMARES.
- DO THEY CONCERN YOUR BROTHER?
- I GET THESE
ABOUT ONCE A MONTH.
JAMEY KILLED MY PARENTS--
- WITH A BUTCHER KNIFE.
- AND HE'LL TRY AND KILL ME
WITH THE SAME WEAPON.
- WHAT ABOUT THE TRUCK?
WAS JAMEY INVOLVED IN THAT?
- WARNINGS.
YOU SEE, JAMEY THINKS
HE'S MESSING WITH MY HEAD,
BUT HE'S NOT,
'CAUSE I KNOW HE WANTS
TO KILL ME HIMSELF.
[telephone ringing]
- I DON'T THINK HE LIKES YOU.
HOW MUCH TIME YOU DOING?
- 20 YEARS.
- DAMN, BOY, WHAT'D YOU DO?
- I SLICED, DICED, AND FILLETED
MY PARENTS WITH A BUTCHER KNIFE.
WHAT DID YOU DO?
- STOLE A CAR.
- SO HE SENDS YOU THESE THINGS
ONCE A MONTH.
MAY I KEEP THIS?
- HOW MANY DO YOU WANT?
I HAVE A WHOLE BOX FULL OF 'EM.
- ONE IS SUFFICIENT.
GET TO KNOW CAROL.
DON'T LET THAT TEXAS BRAVADO
FOOL YOU.
SHE HAS A WAY OF RECOGNIZING
PEOPLE WHO NEED HELP.
- BECAUSE I'M DIFFERENT?
- DO YOU THINK YOU'RE DIFFERENT?
- YEAH.
- NO, YOU'RE NOT DIFFERENT.
THE WORLD IS FULL OF PEOPLE
LIKE YOU.
AS A CHILD, YOU EXPERIENCED
A HORRIBLE TRAGEDY.
YOU LACKED THE EMOTIONAL
MATURITY TO DEAL WITH IT.
CONSEQUENTLY, YOU BECAME
AN EMOTIONAL VICTIM.
- I WILL NOT BE A VICTIM.
- AND WHAT ARE YOU GONNA DO?
TOSS JAMEY OUT OF A WINDOW?
- SINCE I WAS 16 YEARS OLD,
I'VE KNOWN MY BROTHER
WOULD COME FOR ME.
I'M READY.
- JANIS, DO YOU LIKE YOURSELF?
DO YOU WANT TO CHANGE?
WOULD YOU CHANGE?
- I LIVE WITH DEMONS, DOCTOR.
NIGHTMARES AT NIGHT,
SINISTER SHADOWS BY DAY.
YEAH, I WOULD LIKE FOR THAT
TO CHANGE.
BUT HOW DO YOU
GET RID OF DEMONS?
- YOU DON'T FEED THEM.
[telephone ringing]
EXCUSE ME.
HELLO?
CAROL, YES, MM-HMM.
SHE'S RIGHT HERE.
GOOD, MM-HMM,
OKAY, YEAH, BYE.
THAT WAS CAROL.
THIS IS YOUR PRESCRIPTION.
- YOU CAN'T WRITE PRESCRIPTIONS.
- TAKE THIS.
[sighs]
- OKAY.
I'LL SEE YOU SOON, DOCTOR.
- HEY, I DIDN'T THINK
YOU'D COME.
- DOCTOR'S ORDERS.
- TENNIS WITH CAROL
THREE TIMES A WEEK,
OVERDOSES PERMITTED.
- HI.
- YOU WANT A TOWEL?
- SURE, THANK YOU.
- [chuckles]
- HI.
HI.
- I'M PETER.
- OKAY, PETER, THANK YOU.
- WHAT?
- OKAY, PETER, BEAT IT.
- OH!
BYE.
- BYE.
- BYE, PETER.
[both murmuring indistinctly]
- THERE'S THE OTHER HALF
OF OUR FOURSOME.
- HI.
- I'M AUDREY.
- HI, NICE TO MEET YOU.
- HI, DIANE.
GOOD TO SEE SOME FRESH BLOOD
OUT HERE.
- I HOPE YOU TOLD HER
THAT WE PLAY FOR
SOME PRETTY HIGH STAKES.
- OH, YOU BETCHA, YOU KNOW,
DRINKS AT THE BAR,
AND THE LOSER PAYS.
[laughter]
- WELL, I'M GONNA GO CHANGE.
I'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
- BYE, MALIBU BARBIE.
- TOODLES.
- COME BACK AS TENNIS BARBIE.
YOU KNOW
EVERYTHING'S GONNA MATCH.
- I KNOW THERE'S PINK SHOES
COMING OUT.
- OH, YOU CAN BELIEVE THAT.
- YOU GOT FIVE MINUTES,
MCKENZIE.
[rotary dialer hissing]
[cell phone ringing]
- HELLO?
- MICKEY.
UNCLE MICKEY.
HOW WAS THE PARTY?
- COOL AS AN ICE CUBE, MAN.
CLASSIC IT WAS.
TOO BAD YOU WEREN'T THERE.
- I BET SHE PISSED HER PANTS.
- WELL, ACTUALLY...
- ACTUALLY WHAT?
- ACTUALLY, UM...
- MICKEY...
- SHE FELL DOWN, YOU KNOW,
AND WHEN SHE GOT BACK UP,
I MEAN, SHE JUST LOOKED AT ME.
- SHE ALWAYS WAS
A TOUGH LITTLE...
[mouthing words]
GIRL.
LOOKS LIKE I GOT TO GO.
GOOD-BYE.
- YOU DID SO GOOD.
- EXHAUSTING, BUT FUN.
- HEY, BOOMER.
- HEY, GIRLS,
WHAT YOU DRINKING TODAY?
- AH, WHAT WAS IT LAST TIME?
- HA, DRINKIN' RUM
AND COCA-COLA.
- [laughs] WE HAVE SOMETHING
DIFFERENT EVERY TIME.
- HOW ABOUT SOMETHING SPECIAL?
- LIKE A SURPRISE?
- UH-HUH.
- OKAY.
- BE RIGHT BACK.
- DON'T PANIC.
I'VE HAD HIS SURPRISES BEFORE.
- I KNEW YOU WERE COMING.
- THAT'S NOT LEMONADE.
- WHAT EXACTLY IS THAT?
ALL RIGHT, HERE IS
TO A GREAT TENNIS MATCH.
- GREAT MATCH.
[glasses clinking]
GOOD WORK.
WHOO, PERFECT.
- THANK YOU.
- THAT'S FANTASTIC.
- WOW.
THAT'S WHAT YOU NEED
AFTER A HARD MATCH.
- EXACTLY.
- SO YOU'RE NOT MARRIED, HUH?
- MARIE DIDN'T TELL YOU?
- NO.
SHE JUST SAID THAT YOU
WENT THROUGH A HARD TIME
AND THAT YOU'D HAVE TO TELL ME.
- HMM.
MY HUSBAND
WAS KILLED IN IRAQ.
- SORRY.
- THANKS.
MARIE REALLY SAVED ME.
IT WAS PRETTY ROUGH.
NOW YOU KNOW WHY I FEEL
SO STRONGLY ABOUT HER.
- THANKS FOR SENDING ME TO HER.
- JANIS.
- YEAH?
- HOW ABOUT A FULL DAY
WITH CLOWNS?
- OKAY.
- I NEED YOU
TO SHOOT THE CLOWN STATUES
AT THE PAL SAILOR CIRCUS.
- CLOWN STATUES, OKAY.
- IT'S GONNA BE GREAT.
THEY DON'T MOVE.
THEY DON'T TWITCH.
THE LIGHTING
DOESN'T HAVE TO CHANGE.
IT'S PERFECT.
IT'S FREELANCE.
IT'S THE KIND OF GIG YOU WANTED.
- YEAH, OKAY.
- YOU'LL LOVE IT.
- THANK YOU.
- WELL?
- WE'RE ON.
- WE'RE ON FOR WHAT?
- FOR WHAT WE TALKED ABOUT,
YOU IDIOT.
- WHAT DID WE TALK ABOUT?
- NEVER MIND.
JUST DRIVE.
[tires squealing]
[brakes squeaking]
[door knob jiggling]
[knocking]
- LEON!
[soft calliope music]
¶ ¶
[door creaking]
LEON!
[calliope music continues]
¶ ¶
HELLO?
LEON?
[calliope music]
¶ ¶
LEON--
[music stops]
ANYBODY IN HERE?
[camera clicking]
LEON?
ARE YOU HERE?
[dramatic music]
¶ ¶
[seagulls squawking]
[cell phone buttons beeping]
MARIE, IT'S JANIS.
I GOT TO TALK TO YOU RIGHT NOW.
YES.
UM, I'M AT THE DOCK.
JUST COME AS SOON AS YOU CAN.
THANKS.
- JANIS, JANIS, WHAT'S WRONG?
TALK TO ME.
- I KILLED A MAN.
- WHY?
WHAT DID HE DO TO YOU?
- HE CAME AT ME
WITH A BUTCHER KNIFE.
- WHAT MAKES YOU THINK
YOU KILLED HIM?
- WHEN HE CAME AT ME,
I THREW HIM AGAINST THE WALL,
AND THEN EVERYTHING WENT BLACK.
- ARE YOU SURE HE'S DEAD?
- WHEN I WOKE UP,
HE HAD A BUTCHER KNIFE
STICKING OUT OF HIS CHEST,
AND THERE WAS BLOOD
ON THE FLOOR.
I PANICKED,
AND I JUST RAN.
- WE NEED HELP.
HEY!
- YOU CALLED THE COPS?
- HE'S A FRIEND.
HE AND CAROL WERE IN LOVE ONCE.
THEY BROKE UP
OVER SOMETHING SILLY
LIKE HIM STEPPING ON HER FEET
WHEN THEY DANCED.
I TOLD CAROL
SHE WAS BEING STUPID.
- HEY.
- HI.
- YOU LOOK MARVELOUS, DARLING,
SIMPLY MARVELOUS.
- EASY, FRED ASTAIRE.
WHAT WOULD CAROL THINK?
- SHE'D THINK I WAS BEING SILLY.
- [laughs]
- HI, I'M ABE.
MARIE SAYS YOU HAVE A PROBLEM.
- YOU'RE A COP.
- YEAH, I AM.
BUT I'M ALSO A FRIEND.
- IT'S OKAY.
- WANT TO TAKE A WALK?
COME ON.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
- OKAY.
- SO...
- DO YOU THINK SHE BOUGHT IT?
- OH, YEAH, THE CLOWN LYING
THERE IN THE POOL OF BLOOD...
YOU BET SHE BOUGHT IT.
SHE RAN OUT OF THAT CIRCUS TENT
LIKE AN OLYMPIC SPRINTER.
[chuckles]
- SHE KNEW IT WAS
A BIRTHDAY GIFT
FROM HER BROTHER?
- OH--OH, YEAH, YEAH,
WHEN SHE WOKE UP, MAN,
I MEAN, LIKE, WOW,
SHE FREAKED.
- THAT'S WHAT I WANTED.
ONE BIG CIRCUS SURPRISE.
GREAT HAUNTED HOUSE, HUH?
FAKE BUTCHER KNIFE AND ALL?
- SHIT, I FORGOT
TO LEAVE THE DRAWING.
- DOESN'T MATTER.
THE CLOWN LYING THERE,
ALL THOSE OTHER CLOWNS...
IT WAS FUN, HUH?
- HEY, BUT WON'T
SHE EVENTUALLY FIND OUT
THAT THIS WAS ALL A HOAX?
- OF COURSE.
BUT FOR NOW,
MY DEAR SISTER KNOWS
HOW MUCH I LOVE HER.
- TALK TO YOU SOON.
- HEY, LEON.
- HI.
- HOW'S IT GOING?
- ALL RIGHT.
- HAS ANYTHING UNUSUAL BEEN
HAPPENING AROUND HERE LATELY?
- I'VE BEEN HERE ALL WEEK.
HAVEN'T SEEN ANYTHING.
- OKAY, THANKS.
- SURE.
- SO WHERE'S THE BODY AT?
- IT'S OVER THERE.
[scoffs]
IT WAS RIGHT THERE.
- HMM...
IT'S KETCHUP.
- I DON'T UNDERSTAND
WHAT'S GOING ON HERE.
- WELL, IT WAS PROBABLY
PRETTY SCARY IN THE DARK.
YOU SURE
WE'RE IN THE RIGHT PLACE?
- YES.
- OKAY.
WELL, LET'S GO THROUGH IT AGAIN.
YOU CAME THROUGH THAT DOOR,
TOOK A FEW PICTURES,
AND THEN YOU WERE ATTACKED
BY THE CLOWN.
TELL ME THAT PART.
- THEN I THREW HIM
ACROSS THE ROOM.
- HMM, REALLY?
YOU THREW THE CLOWN
ACROSS THE ROOM?
- YEAH, DO YOU WANT ME
TO SHOW YOU?
- NO, IT'S OKAY.
- WHAT'S THAT?
- IT'S, UH, KETCHUP.
- HMM, LOOKS LIKE BLOOD TO ME.
WHAT'S GOING ON HERE?
- JANIS WAS ATTACKED BY A CLOWN.
- [sighs]
[children laughing and shouting]
- EXCUSE ME, MAY I?
- SURE.
- THANK YOU.
[camera clicking]
- HEY, WE'LL LEAVE THE LIGHT ON
FOR YOU, JAMEY.
[sniffing]
- OW, UH!
- OH, MY GOD.
- HELP, MISS, COULD YOU--
- OH, ARE YOU OKAY?
- OH, EH, I TRIPPED OVER
MY OWN CANE.
- HERE, LET ME HELP--
- [chuckles] WHOA, HEY, MAN,
YEAH, CAN YOU--
- YEAH.
- CAN YOU HELP ME GET
TO THAT BENCH OVER THERE?
THANKS.
OH...
OH.
- YOU OKAY?
- YEAH, THINK SO.
THAT'S AN EXPENSIVE CAMERA.
YOU MUST BE A PROFESSIONAL.
- FREELANCE.
I'M WORKING
FOR SRQ MAGAZINE TODAY.
- DOES THAT MEAN
ANYONE CAN HIRE YOU?
- UH-HUH.
- HEY, LET ME TAKE YOU TO LUNCH.
NO, NO, SORRY, SORRY, NO, NO,
I DIDN'T MEAN--LOOK,
YOU KNOW, I'M A WRITER.
I'M PLANNING A SPECIAL BOOK
ABOUT SARASOTA.
- WHAT HAVE YOU WRITTEN?
- FIVE NOVELS.
- I'M IMPRESSED.
- DON'T BE.
THEY'RE ALL IN A DRAWER
WITH 73 REJECTION LETTERS.
BUT NOW, THIS BOOK
ABOUT SARASOTA
COULD BE MY BREAKTHROUGH.
- HMM.
JANIS MCKENZIE.
- HEY, DIDN'T I SEE YOUR NAME
ON A BOOK?
- BEHIND THE MYSTERY?
- YES, I LOVE MYSTERIES.
- I DID THE PHOTOGRAPHY.
STUART KAMINSKY
DID THE NARRATIVE.
- OH, KAMINSKY'S THE BEST.
NOW, YOU SEE, THAT'S WHAT
I WANT TO DO WITH THIS BOOK,
ONLY ABOUT SARASOTA,
ITS PEOPLE AND PLACES.
- SOUNDS GOOD TO ME.
- WELL, IF YOU'RE WILLING,
I'VE FOUND MY PHOTOGRAPHER.
- YOU'VE FOUND HER.
- ALL RIGHT.
- HERE, LET ME GIVE YOU A CARD.
- OKAY.
- GIVE ME A CALL
WHEN YOU WANT TO GET STARTED.
- YOU BETTER BELIEVE IT.
- ALL RIGHT,
TAKE CARE OF THAT KNEE.
BE CAREFUL.
HERE WE ARE.
- WAIT, YOU LIVE ON A BOAT?
- YEAH.
- TOO COOL.
- COME ON, I'LL SHOW YOU.
- AWESOME.
- OKAY, NOW, WATCH YOUR STEP,
SINCE THIS IS YOUR FIRST TIME.
JUMP.
- WHOO!
[laughter]
- LITTLE MORE WINE, CAROL?
- UH, LICK THAT UP,
YOU SPILLED IT.
- [laughs]
THAT'S AN EXPENSIVE
BOTTLE OF WINE.
- OH, HERE IS TO GOOD FRIENDS--
- GOOD FRIENDS.
- TONIGHT IS KIND OF SPECIAL.
[laughter]
- LIKE, I'M TALKING
ABOUT A HUGE PERSON...
CAROL, GET YOUR MIND
OUT OF THE GUTTER.
- IT'S NOWHERE IN THE GUTTER.
NEVER IN THE GUTTER.
CLEAN CAROL.
[laughter]
- LET ME GET THE UMBRELLA
FOR YOU.
- OKAY.
IT'S JUST ABOUT TO POUR.
- BE CAREFUL.
- THANK YOU.
IT WAS FUN.
- IT WAS.
- BYE...
- WE'LL DO IT AGAIN SOON.
- OKAY.
- BYE.
- [screaming]
[knife clattering]
- ARE YOU OKAY?
- YES.
- WHERE'D IT HAPPEN?
- ON THE DECK.
HE HAD A BUTCHER KNIFE.
- I'M GONNA GO
AND CHECK FOR FINGERPRINTS.
OKAY?
- OKAY.
- TAKE CARE OF HER.
[thunder rumbling]
[sirens wailing distantly]
- [hyperventilating]
- NO, NO, IT'S OKAY,
BACKUP'S ON THE WAY.
- WHAT ARE WE GONNA TELL THEM?
- THAT SOMEBODY TRIED
TO KILL ME?
- ACTUALLY,
SOMEBODY TRIED TO KILL JANIS.
THIS IS HER BOAT.
THEY ALMOST GOT YOU BY MISTAKE.
- I THINK IT'S TIME I TOLD
YOU GUYS ABOUT MY BROTHER.
[sirens wailing]
- OKAY, THAT ONE RIGHT THERE.
OKAY.
OKAY, LOOK,
I'VE TRIED THIS FIVE TIMES.
I DON'T GET IT.
- THAT'S BECAUSE...
- [chuckles] AMAZING.
YOU KNOW, I THINK
I'VE SEEN THIS BEFORE.
YOUR TIME IN PRISON WASN'T
TOTALLY SQUANDERED, WAS IT?
- JAMEY MCKENZIE
INTRODUCED ME TO THIS GUY,
COST ME 300 BIG ONES.
- AND YOU LEARNED THIS TRICK?
- NO, I LOST $300 GAMBLING.
HE SHOULDN'T HAVE LAUGHED
AT ME, THOUGH.
I SLAMMED HIS FACE
AGAINST THE WALL
AND MADE HIM TEACH ME.
- [chuckles]
WELL, A WORTHWHILE INVESTMENT,
IF I SAY SO MYSELF.
THOUGH WITH
WHAT JAMEY MCKENZIE'S
GONNA BE PAYING US,
THIS SHOULD BE
A SIGNIFICANT INCREASE
IN OUR REVENUE STREAM.
- REVENUE STREAM?
- LET ME WORRY ABOUT THAT.
[knock at door]
GET THE DOOR.
WHOA, WHOA,
WHOA, WHOA, WHOA, WHOA, WHOA!
- AH, COULDN'T HELP IT, BOSS.
- SHE HIT ME IN THE BALLS.
- WITH AN UMBRELLA!
WITH A STUPID LITTLE UMBRELLA.
- ACTUALLY, IT WAS QUITE LARGE.
- SHUT UP!
YOU WERE SUPPOSED
TO SCARE JANIS.
- AHH...
- NOT MAKE HER LAUGH.
[camera clicking]
- CORPORAL MCKENZIE.
- CAPTAIN ROGERS?
- COLONEL ROGERS.
I'VE BEEN PROMOTED.
- CONGRATULATIONS, COLONEL.
IT'S GOOD TO SEE YOU.
- IT'S REALLY GOOD TO SEE YOU.
I WASN'T SURE
YOU'D WANT TO SEE ME.
- FOUR MONTHS
IN THAT ARMY HOSPITAL--
YOU WERE THE ONLY ONE WHO CARED.
- WE ALL WORRIED
YOU MIGHT NOT MAKE IT.
- YOU DON'T HAVE TO WORRY.
I'M TOUGH.
- [chuckles]
YOU HAVEN'T CHANGED A BIT.
- I WANT YOU
TO LISTEN CAREFULLY,
BECAUSE THIS IS VERY SIMPLE.
YOU GOT THE CHLOROFORM?
- UH-HUH.
- YEAH?
GOOD.
YOU'RE GONNA GO TO THE MARINA.
YOU'RE GONNA WAIT FOR JANIS.
YOU'RE GONNA GRAB HER.
YOU'RE GONNA CHLOROFORM HER.
YOU'RE GONNA TIE HER UP,
AND YOU'RE GONNA WAIT FOR ME
TO GET THERE.
YOU THINK YOU CAN DO THAT, GUYS?
- SURE, WE CAN DO THAT.
- ARE YOU SURE YOU CAN DO THAT?
- YES.
- YEAH?
GOOD.
- DON'T MESS THIS UP.
- GOT IT.
- SO HOW DID YOU KNOW
WHERE TO FIND ME?
- YOUR FRIEND CAROL DODD TOLD ME
YOU WERE DOING A PHOTO SHOOT
AT JUNGLE GARDEN.
- INTERESTING.
AN ARMY COLONEL,
INTELLIGENCE BRANCH--
YOU ARE STILL INTELLIGENCE,
RIGHT?
- RIGHT.
- WHO JUST HAPPENS
TO PASS THROUGH
A COZY FLORIDA BEACH TOWN
AND RUNS INTO AN OLD FRIEND
AT THE JUNGLE GARDENS?
COME ON.
WHAT GIVES, COLONEL?
- [sighs] TEN YEARS AGO,
YOU HAD A SHOOT-OUT
WITH FIVE TERRORISTS
ON A BACK STREET IN KUWAIT.
- AND A YOUNG AMERICAN PRIVATE
WAS KILLED.
- MM-HMM,
PRIVATE BERNARD SCHWARTZ.
- BERNIE WAS A GOOD KID.
- YES, HE WAS.
GRAY'S REGISTRATION FOUND
FOUR DEAD TERRORISTS, NOT FIVE.
COULD WE HAVE MISCOUNTED?
- NO, I DON'T THINK SO.
- SCHWARTZ'S IDENTIFICATION
DISAPPEARED.
FOR A LONG TIME, HE WAS LISTED
AS MISSING IN ACTION.
- SO WHAT DOES THAT MATTER?
- IT MATTERED.
SCHWARTZ RECENTLY ENTERED
THE UNITED STATES,
OR SOMEBODY WHO CLAIMS TO BE
BERNARD SCHWARTZ.
- FORGED PASSPORT?
WHERE IS HE NOW?
- WELL, WE TRAILED HIM
FROM KUWAIT TO FLORIDA.
APPARENTLY,
HE CHANGED HIS APPEARANCE
BEFORE HE DISEMBARKED IN MIAMI.
WE LOST HIM.
- THAT'S TWICE YOU'VE SAID "WE."
- DEPARTMENT
OF HOMELAND SECURITY.
- HOMELAND SECURITY?
- JANIS, THIS MAN,
HE'S SWORN TO KILL YOU.
- HOW DO YOU KNOW?
- WE HAVE INFORMANTS.
DO YOU REMEMBER
SERGEANT BRONSON?
- YEAH, OF COURSE.
HE WAS YOUR SERGEANT IN KUWAIT.
- YES.
KADIR MURDERED HIM
THREE YEARS AGO.
HE BLAMES YOU AND BRONSON
FOR THE DEATHS OF HIS RELATIVES.
JANIS, THIS MAN IS COMING
TO KILL YOU.
- WELL, TELL HIM TO GET IN LINE.
- YOU'RE MY LAST APPOINTMENT.
COME ON.
LET'S GET A DRINK.
[soda can fizzing]
[liquid pouring]
- A SODA?
MARIE...
- IT'S BEFORE 5:00.
I SPOKE TO CAROL.
SHE SEEMS TO HAVE RECOVERED.
JANIS?
DON'T DO THIS TO ME.
OH, DON'T GIVE ME THIS
"I DON'T KNOW WHAT YOU MEAN"
LOOK.
- I'M SORRY, MY MIND--
IT'S JUST SOMEWHERE ELSE
RIGHT NOW.
- JAMEY WAS RELEASED
FROM PRISON YESTERDAY.
DID YOU KNOW THAT?
WHAT ARE YOU GOING TO DO?
- I'M GONNA WAIT.
- YOU'RE GONNA WAIT FOR JAMEY?
JANIS, JAMEY IS A KILLER.
- SO AM I.
- IS THERE SOMETHING
YOU NEED TO TELL ME?
- I'M BEING FOLLOWED,
AND IT'S NOT JAMEY.
[seagulls squawking]
[camera clicking]
- CAN I SEE?
- SURE.
- SORRY, DID I FRIGHTEN YOU?
- NO.
I KNEW YOU WERE THERE.
- BRILLIANT.
IT'S EXACTLY WHAT I WANT
FOR THE BOOK.
- GOOD.
- WHERE DO WE GO FROM HERE?
- I'LL MEET YOU
OVER AT THE STATUE.
- WHO'S YOUR FRIENDS?
- IT'S LIKE A VIGNETTE
FROM THE END OF WORLD WAR II.
PRETTY IMPRESSIVE, HUH?
WAR'S OVER.
EVERYBODY'S HAPPY.
- JANIS.
- CAROL,
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
- I'M ON THE COMMITTEE
TO KEEP THIS IN SARASOTA.
- GOOD LUCK ON THAT.
I LOVE IT.
- OH, HEY, THIS IS ROD BARRETT.
HE'S MY NEW CLIENT.
HE'S DOING A BOOK ON SARASOTA.
HE'S GONNA USE MY PICTURES.
- GOOD TO MEET YOU, ROD.
I GOT TO FINISH THIS CALL.
I'LL CATCH UP WITH YOU LATER.
- OKAY, BYE.
- NICE LADY.
- YEAH.
- OH, YEAH, GREAT STUFF.
WHAT'S NEXT?
- THE CATS.
- JUST TELL IT TO THE JUDGE
TOMORROW, RELAX.
[cell phone ringing]
- YEAH?
- ABE, WHERE ARE YOU?
- I'M AT THE POLICE
HEADQUARTERS.
I'M WAITING ON A FAX.
- WE WERE SUPPOSED
TO HAVE LUNCH.
- I KNOW.
I--I CAN'T.
I'M WAITING ON...
WELL, YOU KNOW,
SOMETHING REALLY IMPORTANT.
- ABE?
WHAT'S GOING ON?
- ALL RIGHT.
I THINK JANIS IS
INTO SOME TROUBLE.
THERE'S A TERRORIST COMING IN
FROM KUWAIT TO KILL HER.
LOOK, I'LL EXPLAIN MORE LATER.
JUST DON'T BREATHE
A WORD OF THIS TO ANYBODY.
HOMELAND SECURITY THINKS
HE'S ALREADY HERE.
- I UNDERSTAND.
KUWAIT.
[lion roaring]
- YOU'RE RATHER QUIET,
AREN'T YOU?
[lion roaring]
ARE YOU ALWAYS LIKE THIS?
MOST WOMEN BY NOW
HAVE A MILLION QUESTIONS.
YOU KNOW WHAT I MEAN?
LIKE, WHAT DO YOU DO?
[camera clicking]
WHERE ARE YOU FROM?
ARE YOU MARRIED?
- YOU'RE A WRITER.
YOU'RE FROM ANOTHER COUNTRY.
AND YOU'RE NOT MARRIED.
- VERY GOOD.
PERFECT, IN FACT.
YES TO WRITER,
BUT YOU ALREADY KNEW THAT.
YES, FROM ANOTHER COUNTRY,
AND...
YES TO NOT BEING MARRIED.
[tiger growling]
HOW DID YOU KNOW
I WASN'T MARRIED?
- NO RING.
- [chuckles]
WE MATCH.
HOW ABOUT DINNER?
- I ALREADY HAVE A DINNER DATE.
HEY, BOOMER.
- HI, JANIS.
- YOU'RE ALWAYS POLISHING MUGS.
- OH, THE LAGER LOVERS CLUB.
GOT TO TAKE CARE OF THE MEMBERS,
YOU KNOW.
- [chuckles]
- I'M A MEMBER TOO.
- REALLY?
OH, "BOOMER."
- MM-HMM.
- THAT'S QUITE A NAME
FOR A BARTENDER.
- HEY, I WASN'T ALWAYS
A BARTENDER.
WAS A TIME WHEN I WAS
A PROFESSIONAL BASEBALL PLAYER,
HOT PROSPECT,
USED TO HIT THE LONG BALL,
YOU KNOW?
OUT OF THE PARK.
THAT'S WHY I GOT THE NAME,
BOOMER.
- SO WHY'D YOU QUIT?
- PITCHERS FOUND OUT
I COULDN'T HIT A CURVE BALL.
- SHE'S AT THE BAR...
TALKING TO THE BARTENDER.
- TALKING?
JANIS THE MUTE?
WELL, THAT WON'T LAST LONG.
- I'VE GOT THE CHLOROFORM.
- YOU KNOW
WHAT I TOLD YOU TO DO,
YOU NEED TO DO IT QUICK.
WHEN SHE COMES DOWN THE LADDER--
- I GOT IT.
- UNDERSTAND?
IF I MISS, SHE'LL KICK MY ASS.
- DAMN RIGHT, SHE'LL KICK
YOUR ASS, COME ON.
COME ON, WE GOT TO GET TO
THE BOAT BEFORE JANIS DOES.
- MR. ROGERS.
- HI, BOOMER.
HEY, SWEETIE.
- HEY.
- HEY, BOOMER, HOW ABOUT
A BOTTLE OF PINOT NOIR?
- COMING RIGHT UP.
- ALL RIGHT.
[telephone ringing]
- ABE, GO HOME.
ARREST SOMEBODY.
STOP LOITERING
BY THE FAX MACHINE.
HEY, LISTEN,
IF THE FAX COMES IN,
I'LL CALL YOU.
- DO YOU STILL HATE ME?
- I NEVER HATED YOU.
- YOU SHOULD HAVE.
- I JUST DIDN'T UNDERSTAND.
I THOUGHT WE WERE IN LOVE.
- WE WERE.
I STILL AM.
I BOUGHT AN ENGAGEMENT RING
WHEN YOU WERE IN THE HOSPITAL.
- REALLY?
WELL, I HOPE YOU GOT
A FULL REFUND.
- THAT SAME NIGHT,
TWO MEN IN SUITS
CAME TO MY DOOR.
THEY SAID...
- EMILIO VARGAS?
YOU HAVE 30 MINUTES TO PACK.
- HE HAD THE WRONG PERSON.
- NO.
MY SUPERIORS CREATED
A NEW IDENTITY FOR ME.
I WAS GOING UNDERCOVER
IN A NEW COUNTRY.
- WHY YOU?
- NO FAMILY, FLUENT IN SPANISH,
AND I WAS TRAINED.
- [sighs]
SO WHY DIDN'T YOU CALL ME?
- NO COMMUNICATIONS ALLOWED...
WITH ANYBODY.
THEN JUST AS I WAS TO COME HOME,
I WAS DISCOVERED.
MY CAPTORS DIDN'T TAKE KINDLY
TO MY DECEPTION.
THEY TORTURED ME
FOR THREE YEARS.
WHEN I ESCAPED,
I HID OUT IN THE JUNGLE
FOR THREE MORE YEARS.
I WAS IN PRETTY BAD SHAPE
WHEN I FINALLY GOT RESCUED.
AND THE ONLY THING THAT KEPT ME
ALIVE WAS THINKING ABOUT YOU.
I DIDN'T GET A REFUND.
I'VE NEVER STOPPED LOVING YOU.
I MISSED YOU.
- I LOVE YOU.
[moaning]
[birds chirping]
- GOOD MORNING.
YOU'RE REALLY HERE.
- I HAVE TO GO.
- NO, DON'T GO, JANIS.
DON'T GO.
- I JUST HAVE TO GET
A COUPLE THINGS FROM MY BOAT.
AND THEN I'LL BE BACK.
[pen tapping]
- YOU CAN'T STILL BE ON DUTY.
- DOES IT LOOK LIKE
I'M STILL ON DUTY?
- THIS WHO
YOU'VE BEEN WAITING FOR?
WHO'S THIS GUY?
- HE'S A TERRORIST.
AND HE MAY BE IN SARASOTA.
- SON OF A BITCH.
MAX!
WHAT THE HELL ARE YOU DOING?
- WHERE IS SHE?
IS SHE HERE?
- SHE'S NOT HERE.
- AHH...
- GET OUT OF HERE.
- HEY, DAMN.
- WHAT'S THE MATTER WITH YOU?
- WHERE'S SHE AT?
OW.
- FOR CRYING OUT LOUD...
- HEY, SWEETIE.
JUST PULLED UP.
OKAY, I'LL BE UP IN JUST
A COUPLE MINUTES, ALL RIGHT?
YEAH, RIGHT, SWEETHEART,
I GOT TO GO, BYE.
HEY, BUDDY...
- OH!
- I KNOW WHO YOU ARE, THINKING
YOU'RE GONNA COME INTO MY TOWN.
BUT YOU GOT THE WRONG TOWN.
- DO YOU HAVE ANY IDEA
WHO YOU'RE DEALING WITH HERE?
- OH, SAVE IT.
- THANKS, PAL.
- THE PLAN WAS SO SIMPLE.
I WANTED JANIS TO SUFFER.
I WANTED TO INTIMIDATE HER.
I WANTED TO SCARE HER.
THEN WHAT HAPPENS?
YOU GUYS MAKE LIKE
THE THREE STOOGES.
- BUT THERE'S ONLY TWO OF US.
- WHAT?
- WELL, THERE'S THREE STOOGES,
AND DAD AND I--
WE'RE, LIKE, TWO.
- SHUT UP, MAX.
JUST SHUT UP.
JAMEY IS QUITE RIGHT.
PERHAPS WE SHOULD'VE PLANNED
A MORE VIABLE LINE OF ATTACK.
- WHAT IF JANIS HAS AN ACCIDENT?
- WHAT DID YOU SAY?
- WHAT IF...
JANIS HAS AN ACCIDENT?
- JANIS HAS AN ACCIDENT.
JANIS HAS AN ACCIDENT.
- THAT'S NOT BAD FOR A HALF-WIT.
- THANKS, BOSS.
- I LIKE IT.
[lock clinking]
[door squeaking]
- HELLO, SISTER DEAR.
- HEY, ABE.
HEY, YOU ONLY GOT HALF THE FAX
LAST NIGHT.
YEAH, AND COLONEL ROGERS
NEVER SHOWED EITHER.
- WHO'S COLONEL ROGERS?
- HOMELAND SECURITY.
HE'S LOOKING FOR THE SAME GUY
YOU ARE.
THAT WAS HIS PICTURE
YOU TOOK LAST NIGHT.
- SHIT.
- JAMEY.
- LAST ONE, SISTER DEAR.
- UH!
UNF...
- SHH...
- WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
[camera clicking]
- YOU COULD'VE WALKED AWAY
THAT DAY.
YOU COULD'VE SAID,
"I SAW NOTHING," BUT NO.
YOU HAD TO TELL, DIDN'T YOU?
- YOU KILLED OUR PARENTS, JAMEY.
- COULDN'T LET YOU LEAVE THIS
WORLD WITHOUT SAYING GOOD-BYE.
SAY HI TO MOM AND DAD FOR ME.
BYE-BYE, SISTER DEAR.
[door sliding]
- JAMEY, COME ON.
JAMEY.
[telephone ringing]
- LET'S GET THOSE OFF YOU.
SORRY ABOUT EVERYTHING
HAPPENING LIKE THIS.
IT WAS NOT MY INTENTION...
TO BRING IN AN INNOCENT MAN.
[clears throat]
- AND WHACK ME OVER THE HEAD?
- OKAY, HERE'S WHAT HAPPENED.
- EXCUSE ME, SIR,
DID YOU SEE A BOAT
LEAVE THIS SLIP?
- WELL, YEAH, ABOUT MIDNIGHT.
TWO UGLY DUDES COULDN'T GET IT
STARTED AT FIRST.
THEY HAD TO CALL IN A THIRD GUY.
- DID THEY SAY
WHERE THEY WERE GOING?
- YEAH, THIS JAMEY DUDE TOLD
THEM TO TAKE IT STRAIGHT OUT.
- JAMEY?
ONE OF THEIR NAMES
WAS JAMEY MCKENZIE?
- WELL, YEAH, THAT'S WHAT ONE OF
THE UGLY DUDES KEPT CALLING HIM.
- DID YOU SEE
A PRETTY BLONDE GIRL?
- OH, YEAH.
[cell phone buttons beeping]
- IT'S OKAY, YOU'RE
PROTECTING JANIS, RIGHT?
[cell phone ringing]
- THAT'S RIGHT.
- GOOD, GOOD.
NOW, HEY,
JUST GET ME OUT OF HERE.
- CAROL?
- ABE.
ABE, LISTEN TO ME.
JANIS HAS BEEN KIDNAPPED.
- WHAT?
- SOME GUY NAMED JAMEY MCKENZIE.
YES, HE SAID HIS NAME WAS JAMEY.
- YOU SURE IT'S JAMEY MCKENZIE?
- I'M SURE.
I'LL GET A BOAT.
JUST MEET ME AT THE MARINA.
- ALL RIGHT,
WE'LL BE RIGHT THERE.
[engine turning over]
- COME ON.
JUST GO STRAIGHT OUT.
[engine revving]
I DON'T SEE ANYTHING.
- WE CAN'T GIVE UP NOW.
- WE WON'T GIVE UP.
- MOTOR VESSEL ANTICIPATION
WITH COLONEL ROGERS ON BOARD.
THIS IS C.M. AT SARASOTA MARINA.
- THIS IS COLONEL ROGERS.
- ROGER, CAPTAIN.
TWO MEN IN A SMALL BOAT REPORTED
AS SEEING A SAILBOAT SINK
APPROXIMATELY 30 MILES WEST
OF BIG PASS.
DO YOU HAVE
ANY FURTHER INFORMATION?
- DID THEY HELP?
- GOOD COPY, CAPTAIN.
I DON'T THINK SO.
THEY WERE TOO FAR AWAY.
THE TRANSMISSION CAME IN
VERY BROKEN AND UNREADABLE.
- SURVIVORS, ANY SURVIVORS?
- NO, I--I DON'T THINK SO.
[radio static hissing]
- NO!
- YOU KNOW,
I WAS BEGINNING TO THINK
I MADE A MISTAKE
HIRING YOU TWO GUYS.
BUT AS SOMEONE ONCE SAID,
"ALL'S WELL THAT ENDS WELL."
[laughter]
- IT WAS...
IT WAS SHAKESPEARE.
- WHAT WAS SHAKESPEARE?
- WHAT YOU SAID,
IT WAS A PLAY WRITTEN
BY WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE.
[bottles clinking]
[helicopter blades whirring]
[engine revving]
- [snaps]
- FLORIDA SUNCOAST HELICOPTERS
DISCOVERED A SINKING YACHT
SOME 30 MILES OFFSHORE
FROM SIESTA KEY.
THE HELICOPTER PILOT REPORTED
THAT WHEN HE WENT IN CLOSE
TO INVESTIGATE,
HE DISCOVERED A WOMAN
IN THE WATER.
CIRCUMSTANCES AS TO
THE SINKING OF THE YACHT
ARE UNCLEAR AT THIS TIME.
THE WOMAN'S NAME
AND WHY SHE WAS ALONE
ON THE YACHT ARE UNKNOWN.
[cameras clicking]
POLICE INVESTIGATING--
[table clattering]
AND NOW, LOCAL NEW--
- JAMEY MCKENZIE
TRIED TO KILL JANIS.
HE PUT A HOLE IN HER BOAT
AND EXPECTED HER TO DROWN.
HERE'S JAMEY'S PICTURE.
- NASTY-LOOKING AS HOMEMADE SIN.
WATCH OUT FOR THAT CREEP.
- I WISH IT WERE THAT SIMPLE.
THERE'S A SECOND MAN
TRYING TO KILL JANIS.
JANIS.
- IT HAPPENED
DURING THE GULF WAR.
KUWAIT,
1994.
- YOU WERE IN THE GULF WAR?
- YEP, CORPORAL JANIS MCKENZIE.
BEN WAS MY COMMANDING OFFICER.
- JANIS WAS IN A FIREFIGHT
WITH A TERRORIST NAMED KADIR
AND FOUR RELATIVES.
ALL DIED EXCEPT KADIR.
- AND NOW HE'S HERE
IN THE UNITED STATES
UNDER A FORGED PASSPORT GOING BY
THE NAME OF BERNARD SCHWARTZ.
- FAKE DATES, FAKE PICTURE.
- WHAT DOES HE LOOK LIKE?
- DARK SKIN, BEARD, BROWN EYES.
- THAT WAS TEN YEARS AGO.
HE'S A MASTER OF DISGUISES.
THANKS TO A HIDDEN CAMERA
IN MIAMI,
WE KNOW WHAT HE LOOKS LIKE NOW.
- OH, MY GOD.
JANIS, ISN'T THIS...
- THAT'S ROD BARRETT.
- YOU KNOW HIM?
- YEAH, ALIAS "KADIR."
- JANIS, YOU SPENT LAST WEEK
WITH THAT MAN.
WHY DIDN'T HE KILL YOU THEN?
- I DON'T KNOW.
- THE CAT PLAYING WITH HIS PREY.
- DO ANY OF YOU HAVE GUNS?
- I DO,
AND I KNOW HOW TO USE IT.
- WELL, I DON'T.
ABE.
- CAROL, NO.
YOU'RE GONNA END UP
GETTING YOURSELF SHOT.
WE'RE GONNA BE
TAKING CARE OF IT.
FEDERAL AGENTS
ARE COMING IN TOMORROW.
RIGHT, BEN?
- THAT'S RIGHT.
- WE ALREADY ARRESTED
THE CRASS BROTHERS YESTERDAY.
THEY WERE TRYING TO ROB
A CONVENIENCE STORE
OR SOMETHING.
BUT YOUR BROTHER
IS STILL AT LARGE.
- FINE.
MEANWHILE, WE ALL NEED
TO STAY CLOSE TO JANIS.
- JANIS, DO YOU HEAR THAT?
YOU'VE GOT FRIENDS
THAT WILL STICK BY YOU.
- NO, THIS IS SOMETHING I DID.
ME.
I NEED TO DISAPPEAR.
- JANIS, BE REASONABLE.
SOONER OR LATER,
AND PROBABLY SOONER,
ONE OF THESE MONSTERS
IS GONNA COME AND FIND YOU.
- I SAID NO.
YOU'RE GONNA GET HURT,
SO JUST STAY AWAY FROM ME,
ALL OF YOU.
- NO, JANIS, YOU ARE NOT
GONNA DO THIS.
EVIL ONLY WINS WHEN GOOD PEOPLE
DO NOTHING ABOUT IT.
- AND WE'RE NOT GONNA
LET THAT HAPPEN.
- COME ON, WE'LL WALK YOU HOME.
- IT'S OKAY.
I HAVE MY BIG STRONG SOLDIER
TO PROTECT ME.
IT'S BEEN QUITE A DAY.
THANKS.
- DON'T LEAVE HER SIDE.
- I WON'T.
- GET SOME REST.
- I WILL.
- YOU, COME HERE.
- HELLO.
[gunshots]
- [groans]
OH, GOD.
- WHAT?
- YOU'VE BEEN HIT.
- WHOA.
[gunshot]
- YOU GOT A GUN?
- MY LEFT LEG.
- I LOVE YOU.
[slow gunshots]
- WE MEET AGAIN.
DROP THE GUN.
TOO BAD THIS HAS TO END.
WHEN WE WERE OUT
AT THE BIG CAT HABITAT,
I THOUGHT YOU WERE BEGINNING
TO LIKE ME.
- I LIKED YOU BETTER
WHEN YOU WERE DEAD IN KUWAIT.
- WELL, MY FAMILY YOU KILLED.
[gunshot]
[gunshots]
- SISTER DEAR.
I HEAR YOU'RE AN EXPERT
AT MARTIAL ARTS.
LET'S JUST SEE HOW GOOD YOU ARE.
[guns clattering]
- HUH!
UH!
UGH!
HA!
- UH--
- AH!
- [screaming]
- IT'S ALL OVER, LOVERBOY.
- DON'T HURT HIM, JAMEY.
- YOU WOULDN'T SHOOT
YOUR BROTHER.
[gunshot]
- ARE YOU OKAY?
- YOU GUYS OKAY?
- YEAH.
- JANIS, MY GOD, WHAT HAPPENED?
- CLOSURE.