No! My baby!
The baby...
Something's...
Something's wrong with the baby.
The baby's fine.
Don't worry about the baby.
Mia.
Mia?
Mia!
Oh. Sweetie.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Mommy didn't mean to scare you.
- Mommy scare me.
- Mommy just had a bad dream.
I love you, Mommy.
I love you too.
Okay, let's get you
back into your bed, okay?
I don't want to be alone.
You wanna sleep
with Mommy tonight?
- That sound good?
- Yes.
Come over here, sweet girl.
Do you want more?
Good job!
Got it?
Oh, nice!
Is it better to eat
one at a time, I think?
A lot easier, right?
Can you eat two more for Mommy?
Good girl. Oh, yeah.
Yeah. Dripping all over.
Are you slurping, silly girl?
You're getting so big,
aren't you?
You're big.
You're a big girl now, huh?
There's a peach.
You're right.
Mommy loves you, Mia.
Come here. Put that down.
Up with Mommy.
Hello, Daniel.
Hello, Rachel.
How you doing?
Fine.
Listen, you have a minute
to talk?
Sure, go ahead.
I don't know how to say this, so I'm just...
I'm gonna say it.
Rachel, ever since
our separation,
I'm having a really hard time
paying the bills.
I mean, between the mortgage
payment, the credit cards,
the cars, you name it.
I don't know if you noticed,
but the city's placed us
on furlough, and I...
I'm just in way over
my head, and I can't...
I just can't keep
paying for everything.
You're a lawyer, Daniel.
You can handle
our living expenses.
I'm a city attorney, Rache.
I don't make the kind of money other lawyers do.
You know that.
What about the money
that we've been saving
for the past five years?
I've been plowing through it
just to stay afloat.
That's really unfortunate,
Daniel.
The worst part of it is...
if things don't get better,
I'm gonna lose the house.
You mean, I'm gonna
lose the house.
You can look at it
however you want to.
How else am I supposed
to look at it?
I don't know, Rachel,
but I'm gonna have to pull back
on the money I've been
giving you and Mia.
I just don't see
any other way around it.
I'm sorry.
So am I.
You seem to take really good
care of yourself, Daniel.
Have you even once
considered Mia?
Of course I have!
How could you even say that?
Because it's true.
You hardly ever see her.
As soon as I have enough money,
I'm gonna finalize this divorce,
and I'm gonna demand enough
alimony and child support
to take care of us.
You can live in a studio
apartment for all I care.
I'm not the one
that wanted to get separated.
You cheated on me.
I know.
I know I did.
I'm not perfect. Rachel...
I know I made a huge mistake.
I wanna go to counseling.
I'm willing to do
whatever it takes.
And to think
that I actually loved you.
You still love me, Rache.
No, I don't.
Don't flatter yourself.
I still love you.
No, you don't.
You just can't stand to lose
something you thought you had.
Well, you screwed up, Daniel.
At least one of us is happy.
- Hey, Mia, who's that?
- Me!
That's you!
- Do you like the picture?
- Yeah.
Oh, you're gonna draw too?
Thank you.
I know. You're not tired,
but it's bedtime, okay?
It's time to go night-night.
It is a big blanket for you,
but it's bedtime, sweetheart.
Okay?
Look outside,
look outside for me.
Can you see?
♪ Mama's gonna buy you a mockingbird ♪
Dinner is served!
I just put Mia down.
I am so sorry.
It's Brock's fault.
Come in. Yeah, come in.
- It's so good to see you.
- You too, sweetie.
- And he falls right over.
- What?
You okay?
Yeah, I'm good.
No, you're not.
I'm good.
What's not to be good about?
You are lying.
I always knew you were psychic.
No, I just know you better
than you know yourself.
She says
that very same thing to me.
So what's going on?
Daniel called this morning,
and, um, he's having
some financial problems.
He's gonna be cutting
the allowance for Mia and I,
and turns out
we might lose the house.
What? How can he do that?
Oh, no.
I can't believe that.
Why? How can that be?
I don't know,
but it's happening.
Well, he's lying.
Do you know
if he's dating anyone?
No. I don't know,
but I don't care.
I just, um...
Because we're not gonna be
getting any more child support,
I'm gonna have
to go back to work,
which means I have
to put Mia in daycare.
- Really?
- Yeah.
But I thought you swore
you wouldn't do it.
I did, I know,
but I don't have a choice.
- I have to go back to work.
- Why don't you hire a nanny?
No. That would be a nightmare.
Well, you know
how I feel about daycare.
I think we need
to socialize our kids.
They need to find
their independence.
And virtually every study says
that daycare is beneficial
to a child's growth.
Little Ones Daycare,
it's a wonderful place.
Seriously, I always felt
like the kids were so safe.
And they were happy.
Barbara, the director,
she really knows
how to keep those kids busy
all day long.
And they were just
so well-adjusted
by the time we got them
from preschool to kindergarten.
Okay, how about
if I take you there tomorrow
and introduce you to everyone?
Now that is a good idea.
You have time to do that?
For you?
And for my goddaughter?
Of course I do.
Okay. Uh, yeah.
Okay, I'll do it, but,
you know, no commitments.
Just to look at it.
Rachel, what a surprise.
Hey, Martin.
Uh, I'm coming back.
Got any room
for a starving artist?
There's always room for you.
There's a case starting
tomorrow morning.
You can jump on that.
Yeah. That would be great.
Okay, I'll see you then.
See you then. Bye.
Hey, girl.
Come give your auntie a hug.
Hi, sweetie.
- I love you.
- Oh, my gosh.
- So this is Rachel.
- Hi.
As you know,
both of Melissa's kids
graduated from here
at Little Ones.
In fact,
Barbara was their teacher
before she became
the school director.
I was.
Okay, the classroom is just
right around this corner.
Oh, great.
Right this way.
Now we flip it over.
There's a picture here too!
Look at that!
All right. We're gonna do this.
It's gonna look fantastic.
I know we call it a daycare,
but it's really a preschool.
I mean, we are not babysitters.
Our purpose is to make sure
that they're enriched
every moment that they're here.
Wow. It's really,
it's really impressive.
I mean, the kids all look
so happy.
I don't think
I've heard one cry yet.
Oh, no, no, no.
That does happen.
But they're usually
pretty happy little busy bees.
But when they're not playing
or eating or napping,
they're preparing for
the next phase of their life.
This is Miss Wright.
She's been with us
for three years.
This is Rachel, and this is Mia.
Oh, hi.
She's thinking about bringing
Mia here to Little Ones.
Oh.
You look familiar.
Have we met before?
I don't think so.
Maybe we've just
seen each other around.
Maybe the market or salon
or something?
Yeah, I'm sure we've
crossed paths at some point.
Yeah. Yeah, that's it.
Miss Wright, we need you.
Oh, well, I should go.
But it was very nice
to meet you, uh...
Mia.
Mia. That's a very pretty name.
All right, guys, thanks.
Let's see what you guys
are doing over here.
Are you playing with Play-Doh?
That's pretty cool.
We even have a bigger
playground in the back.
Oh, wow. Your place is
so warm and pretty.
Oh my gosh, you have a vegetable
garden with real vegetables.
Okay, I have to confess.
My husband, he's the one
with the green thumb.
He's here every weekend
planting something.
And if he's not
planting something,
he's building a new fence,
he's putting together a new toy,
or he's painting a mural
on a wall.
Wow. This place is amazing.
What do you do if there's
a problem or an emergency?
All of our teachers are
fully trained in first-aid,
but if anything happens,
we'll call you or your husband
right away.
Oh, we're not together
anymore, but, um...
He's around.
I'm the point person.
Okay. I understand. Look...
it's our job to support you,
make your life easier.
So?
Listen, You don't have to make a
decision today. Take your time.
Just bring Mia by
when you're ready,
and we'll sign her up.
Okay, good.
It was so great to meet you.
Nice to meet you.
And it was great
meeting you too.
See you later.
Bye-bye.
I gotta run, but just
give me a call anytime.
- Thank you.
- Bye, honey. Okay.
Barbara!
It's a no-brainer.
Little Ones is perfect for Mia.
Great. You won't regret it
and neither will Mia.
We know.
What do you say
we go get her comfortable?
Okay. Come on.
I'm really happy
that you decided
that Little Ones
was the home for Mia.
And, please, call me Gabby.
Oh, okay, so this is Miss Gabby.
Okay? Can you say Gabby?
- Gabby.
- Oh, good job.
I have to be admit,
I'm a little nervous
to leave her with a stranger.
I mean, I've left her with
people she didn't know before,
but this is different.
Oh, no, no,
but we're not strangers.
Are we?
- No.
- Aw, come here.
I'm gonna make sure that you are
the happiest little girl
in the whole world.
She likes you.
I like her very much.
Hey, how about I introduce you
to some of your toys?
And then you can meet
some new friends
once they get back from recess.
Look at our cool castle.
She's gonna be fine.
I have an idea.
Why don't you come with me
back to the office,
fill out some paperwork,
and then we'll come back
in like 15 minutes
and check on her, okay?
Okay.
That's a really good idea.
Hey, Mia. Hi, sweetie.
Okay, Mommy's gonna be gone for
just a couple of minutes, okay?
If you need anything,
you talk to Miss Gabby, okay?
- You gonna be okay?
- Yes.
Thank you.
I know that this is my job,
but these kids are my life.
They make me whole.
So here's
the Little Ones contract.
Nothing shocking.
Just your information,
month-to-month pay,
release of liability, etc.
Wow. You sure have this place
covered in cameras.
Yes... As a matter of fact,
you can log in to the school website
and view any
of the cameras remotely.
I don't know, I just thought
it would give the families
an extra feeling of comfort.
- So what do you do for work?
- I'm a courtroom artist.
I'm the one who gives the visual
when cameras aren't allowed.
Did you go to art school?
I got my undergrad at UCLA
and then my MFA at Art Center
and then I did go on...
Mia. Is that Mia?
Mia!
Mia?
Oh, no, this is Angela, and
her mother just dropped her off.
She'll be okay
in a couple of minutes.
You looking for Mia?
Mia's in the other room.
She's just playing
with the other kids.
Mia, your mommy's here.
See? No worries.
She's adjusting just fine.
Okay, sweetie, Mommy's gonna
have to leave right now, okay?
But if you need anything,
anything at all,
you say something
to Miss Gabby, okay?
- I love you.
- I love you too.
Don't worry, Rachel. We're gonna
take very good care of her.
Thanks, Gabby.
I appreciate it.
Come here, Mia.
Thank you.
We'll see you
in a few hours, okay?
It's gonna be all right.
Rachel! It's good to see you.
We missed you.
So you got kicked out
of the courtroom?
Unfortunately, yes.
We're depending on you now.
Well, I was looking over
the briefing and the sketches,
and it looks like
it's gonna be a long one.
You'll have plenty of sketches.
Can't wait to start airing them
on the 5:00 news.
Find me when you've got me.
I'll be around.
- Sure.
- Oh, and, Rachel,
you know that Daniel's
the lead prosecution attorney.
You could've told me that
last night.
Thought you might not
want the gig.
Yeah, you're probably right.
All rise for
the Honorable Judge Joyner.
Good morning.
As you all know,
we're here today to listen
to the case
of the State of California
vs. Richard D. Fowler,
who is charged with the murder
of Cynthia Fowler.
The baby!
Something's wrong...
Ladies and gentlemen,
before I begin,
I'd like to thank our jury
for their service.
- The baby.
- The baby's fine.
No, I think something's wrong
with the baby.
The baby's fine.
- It's not fine.
- Are you okay?
...on the evidence
as presented in the trial.
The opening and closing
arguments of the lawyers
are not evidence.
Do you have a question for me,
Mr. Stevens?
Proceed the bench, Mr. Stevens.
Where did you go, Mia?
Unfortunately,
ladies and gentlemen,
we will have to take
a brief recess.
We will adjourn in 15.
Hi, Barbara. It's Rachel.
I'm so sorry to call,
but I logged onto
the Little Ones website,
and I'm looking at the camera
feed, and I don't see Mia.
That's odd because
I see her clearly here.
If you log on again,
you should see her now.
Oh.
I see her. Thanks.
I'm sorry.
It's okay. Unfortunately,
the cameras don't cover
every area of the room.
To be honest, I was a little
hesitant about the cameras
for this very reason.
Everything okay?
Uh, yeah, that's okay.
You know what? It's day one.
I'm sure that my fears
will dissipate
after a few years.
Don't worry.
You can call me anytime.
Okay. Thanks, Barbara.
I'll be there to pick her up
in two hours. Okay, bye.
Everything okay?
I saw you run out.
Don't you need to be
in the courtroom?
The judge is just working out
some scheduling issues.
Nothing my assistant
can't handle.
So you're okay?
Yeah. Uh...
It's Mia's first day in daycare,
so I'm on pins and needles.
Yeah, I can tell.
If you want to, I can take you
to your favorite restaurant
during the lunch break.
Really, Daniel?
It's Mia's first day at daycare,
and you want to go rekindle
an old flame
that died a long time ago.
Don't be so sensitive.
I was just asking you
out to lunch.
I have to go, um, do a sketch.
Okay.
If both the prosecution
and the defense
are satisfied with the schedules
going forward,
I'd like to begin
with the opening statement
from the prosecution.
Thank you, Your Honor.
Wow. You made it all the way
to work and back in three hours.
Is it all right
if I pick my baby up?
Of course. You can get her
anytime you need.
Just be sure and let Gabby know
when you sign her out.
Thank you.
All right, bye.
Rachel.
- Oh. Hi, Gabby.
- Hi.
- So how did she do today?
- She was fantastic.
You and Mr. Miller
must be very good parents.
Well, actually, it's mostly me.
He and I aren't
together anymore.
Oh, really?
That's unfortunate.
I'm so sorry. A child really
needs both of her parents.
Well, he's around and just...
Studies actually show that
children who have both parents
do better in their reading
and math scores
and overall
just socialize better.
Well, that's not happening
anytime soon.
Oh.
Life has a way of taking us
on a path we don't expect.
I hear ya.
- I'm gonna go pick up Mia.
- Okay.
Oh, you know something,
I just realized,
I was commenting
on your personal life.
I didn't mean that.
Oh, that's okay.
Um, you know what?
I figure we'll get really close
in these next couple months,
and we might as well start now.
Okay. I'd like that, yeah.
Mia, sweetie!
- Did you have fun?
- Yes.
Oh, good. Come on.
I'm so glad.
- Thank you.
- No problem.
Seems like she had a great time.
Thank you for bringing
such a cute little girl
to our daycare.
All right, let's go.
It was her.
What?
I know it was her.
How can you know that for sure?
Because, Troy,
I can never forget a face.
She was covered in blood.
You had a concussion.
Her face...
is etched in my memory.
Her face haunts my dreams.
I can't get that night
out of my head,
and all I want to do
is forget about it.
It's okay, honey.
Daddy just needs to stretch
his legs a little bit.
Show me how
your game works, Crystal.
I can't do it.
You can. You can do it.
Nnnnrrr!
I need to make it like Miss Leo.
Hey, can you guys help us out?
We've been driving around
in circles. We're lost.
That is quite obvious.
You know how to get
to the 385 from here?
I'm not really from around here.
I drive through here all the
time, but I'm not quite sure.
I think you can keep going west
on this road and you'll hit it.
Actually, you know what?
It might be east.
I'll just ask my wife.
She'll know.
No, it's all good, man.
Thank you.
- Are you sure?
- Yeah, I'm sure. Thank you.
Don't you have a GPS
in this car? No?
It's not worth fighting over.
Have a good one.
Wow. That guy's
seriously stressed out.
Why don't you
go back to Hollywood?!
Sorry, babe. Some people
just don't appreciate you.
I tried to help.
I tried.
- Get in the car.
- Okay.
I love you.
I love you too.
- What's that guy doing?
- What?
Those lights. They look like
they're coming straight for us.
Troy, Troy, swerve to the right.
Gabby, we're gonna get hit!
Troy, swerve to the right!
No!
Oh, God!
Rachel! Rachel!
Are you all right?
Are you okay?
- The baby...
- The baby's fine.
I know something's wrong
with the baby.
- Don't worry about the baby. Are you okay?
- I don't know!
- Are you all right?
- My feet... - Are you okay?
Gabby, Crystal...
Crystal, Mommy's coming.
Baby?
We're okay, we're okay.
Okay.
Ohhh...
No!
No! No!
Oh, my God!
No!
I looked in her eyes.
We connected.
And I saw Crystal.
Our baby was there.
God has a plan for us.
She's gonna be ours soon.
Gabby...
what are you talking about?
What, do you think this was
some sort of coincidence
that Rachel brought her child
into my classroom?
That's not a coincidence.
Gabby, that wasn't Crystal.
Crystal's dead.
No. No, I saw Crystal.
I was with Crystal.
Oh, Gabby, please.
Please just
get yourself together, okay?
It was just a coincidence.
That's all.
Sweetie?
Dig deep with me.
Think about this.
God gave us
a second chance here.
He's done the work, and now
we have to do the rest of it.
Baby, we can be whole again.
No. No, we can't be whole.
Gabby, I'm paralyzed.
I'm never gonna be able
to walk again.
You have no idea what it's like.
Not what I meant.
That's not what I meant.
I meant...
I meant that we could be
a family again.
I meant that we can move on
with our lives from...
this.
I care about Crystal.
I care about her so much.
I want this. Give me this.
Then we'll just go pick her up
and take her home tomorrow.
Don't be stupid.
It's too easy.
No one can suspect anything.
We're gonna be raising
a little girl.
We can't be running from the law
for the rest of our lives.
No, Mia and I need to spend
some time together,
and I need to get to know her,
and she...
She needs to love me.
She's three years old.
Give her a teddy bear.
She'll love that.
Tell her that's her mother.
Don't say that.
She's a human being.
She's smart.
What about her mother?
She recognize you?
No.
She didn't recognize me
because we're nothing to her.
She didn't care
about Crystal then,
and she doesn't care
about her now.
What about him?
They're divorced.
He's just around Mia when
it's convenient for him, so...
Look, he's a bad father.
You're gonna be a good father.
God chose you.
Come here.
Baby, this is our second chance.
Can't you see that?
I'm sorry, baby,
with all my heart.
We were dealt a really bad hand,
weren't we?
Well, yeah, we were.
But this is the way
to make it right.
I love you.
I'll do anything for us
to be a family again.
You know that, right?
Yeah, I know that,
and I love you too.
Okay, so today
Mommy's gonna be gone
a little bit longer
than I was before, okay?
The day was fun.
Oh, good.
And do you like your teachers?
- I like Miss Becca.
- Do you like Miss Gabby?
- Yes.
- Yeah?
- Hi.
- Oh, hi.
Hi, Mia.
She had a really
great time yesterday.
And you're gonna
have fun again today too.
Mommy, not go.
What's wrong, honey?
Mommy, no work.
I know.
Mommy has to work.
Okay, I'm gonna
give you guys a second.
Bring her in when you're ready.
- I have to get the kids started on another activity.
- Okay.
Sweetie, listen,
Mommy has to work, okay?
How about this? How about
when I pick you up today,
I take you to the pier,
and we go get ice cream?
Does that sound like fun?
Sounds good.
- Ready?
- Yeah.
We're gonna have a blast!
Okay. Uh...
Come on, let's have a good day.
Bye, sweetie.
Mr. Fowler, would you be so kind
as to describe your upbringing?
Objection, Your Honor.
The jury does not need
to hear about
Mr. Fowler's family history.
It's an unnecessary drama
used specifically
to pull at the heartstrings
of the jury.
Mr. Fowler's childhood
is not necessary in this case.
No need to waste court time
on an overwrought narrative.
Objection denied.
You may answer the question,
Mr. Fowler.
Sure.
Well, my parents were very poor.
When I was born, we lived
on a farm with no power.
Okay, guys, here you go.
What color crayon do you want?
I want purple.
The purple?
Here you go.
Good job.
Okay, kids, now we are all
gonna hand in our pictures
when we're done,
and I'm gonna give you
stickers for it.
No, I don't want to.
You need to learn
to follow directions.
Your assignment was to draw
a picture of you and me
living together in a house,
not a horsey.
Rebecca, could you please
get some popsicle sticks
from room 403?
Tell Mrs. Choi
that we will get her back.
Sure, Miss Wright.
No daughter of mine
is going to disobey me.
Do you understand?
Look at me.
You need to understand.
I love you more than
your birth parents, okay?
And someday soon
your name's gonna be Crystal.
Do you like that name?
Do you like Crystal?
- Say "Crystal."
- Crystal.
Okay, good.
Let's go back to the kids,
and I'll give you a treat
if you're good.
Okay.
I wanna make
one more picture.
Oh, good, okay!
Well, then you should
definitely make one.
You gonna be good now, Crystal?
Here you go, sweetie.
Good job, guys.
Very proud.
♪♪
You need to understand that
that was not good, okay?
Not good.
You don't do that again.
Don't let me catch you
doing that again.
Is everything okay?
Yes.
Um, well, no.
Mia and I were just having
a bit of a talk about sharing.
She took another child's toy,
and we needed to have
a discussion about it, so...
- You did?
- No like school.
Well, is everything okay?
Yeah. No, no,
everything's fine now.
Okay.
I'm gonna sign Mia out.
See you tomorrow, Mia.
I might be out of place here,
but what's up with you
and that child?
What are you talking about?
I'm her teacher too.
I should know what's going on.
You're not her teacher.
You work for me.
Where's your master's
in child development?
Where's yours?
I hear you talk about
all of your education successes,
yet I've never seen
any proof of them.
Ask me one more question,
you're fired.
I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to hit a nerve
like that.
You did.
- Is everything okay?
- Oh, yeah, it's fine.
We just had a bad day today.
We'll see you tomorrow.
Okay.
Hi. Do you mind if I talk
to you about something?
Do that, babe.
Ouch.
Oh, I'm sorry, sweetie.
Did Mommy hurt you?
Yeah.
What happened?
How did you do...
Mia, listen to Mommy.
How did you do this?
Can you tell Mommy
what happened?
- Gabby.
- Something happened with Gabby?
Did you fall?
You fell.
Okay, well, I'm glad that
Gabby was there to help you.
Mommy's gonna have
to talk to Gabby.
Well, do you remember
who's coming for dinner?
- Yeah.
- Who?
- Daddy.
- Daddy!
Daddy's coming for dinner.
And you know what?
He's gonna kiss those boo-boos,
and he's gonna
make it all better.
How does that sound?
- Good.
- Good!
Okay, let's go see who that is.
Come here, sweetie.
Okay.
Who is it?
It's Gabby Wright.
- Hi.
- Hi, Gabby.
What are you doing here?
I'm so sorry to intrude.
I was in the area,
and Mia left this at school,
so I thought
I'd return it personally.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Are you gonna invite me in?
Oh, please, come in.
Yeah, I'm sorry.
That's okay.
Hey, little one.
Oh, she's tired.
It's a long time
to be at daycare.
Oh, my God,
your house is beautiful.
Um...
I don't think
that this is Mia's jacket.
How long have you lived here?
Five years.
Daniel and I bought it
right after we got married.
That's sad.
What is?
Oh, I mean that you're divorced.
I mean, with a house like this,
you're gonna want
to raise a family.
Hey, Mia, I'm sure you want some
brothers and sisters, right?
- Yeah.
- I'm sure she does.
- What are you cooking?
- It smells amazing.
- Uh...
Gabby, this isn't Mia's jacket.
Oh, I could've sworn that I saw
her wearing that this morning.
It's like the size
of a third grader.
You know, if the mommies just
labeled their kids clothing,
I wouldn't have to be running
around and returning things.
Um, doesn't the school
have a lost and found?
Mmm!
I'm really happy
that you came by
because I was
dressing Mia earlier,
and I noticed bruises
all over her arms.
Oh.
Do you know anything about that?
Oh. Barbara didn't
talk to you?
- No.
- Yeah, no.
That's strange because
I told her to let you know
that Angela, the little girl
that cries too much,
she's really rough
with the other kids.
Angela did that?
Yeah. She's got
two older brothers,
and she's just used
to roughhousing.
I guess that makes sense.
Oh, are you expecting
someone else for dinner?
My husband.
Oh, your husband.
Daddy!
Hey, there's my little girl!
Be careful.
She has bruises on her arm.
- You got some bruises?
- Yes.
Yeah. She'll be fine.
Well, thanks for the invite,
girls.
- Hello.
- Hi.
Oh, this is Gabby.
She's Mia's daycare teacher.
You must be Mr. Miller.
You know, I've heard a lot
about you.
I've even seen you on the news.
You're a city attorney, right?
I am.
That's a thankless job.
But I mean, you know, it takes
someone very special to do that.
Oh, thank you, Gabby.
Hey, have we met before?
You know, I said the same thing
about your wife.
She must have
one of those faces.
Yeah, that must be it.
- Is that it?
- Yes.
Thank you, Gabby, for coming by
and dropping off the sweater.
Um, oh, I... I just thought
I was staying for dinner.
I didn't invite you.
Oh, um, okay.
I'm just gonna head out.
Uh, Gabby.
Thank you for everything
that you've been doing for Mia.
We really appreciate it.
Oh, it's no problem.
It's my pleasure.
I love all my kids,
but Mia here is extra special.
I gotta go somewhere anyways,
so it's probably best
that I'm not staying for dinner.
All right,
I'll see you guys later.
- Okay.
- Bye, Mia.
- What was that?
- That was creepy.
So that's her daycare teacher?
Yeah.
Come on.
Okay, let's go get some dinner.
What are you gonna make me?
Ducks? Really?
You have a good day at school?
Yes, good.
So what do you think
about scheduling
a meeting with Barbara?
She's the director
at Mia's daycare,
and I just think
we should talk to her
about the bruises
on her arm, you know?
And Gabby's intrusion was weird.
Well, what if Gabby's the one
causing the bruises?
What if Gabby's
abusing our child?
No, that's not possible.
I mean, there's cameras
in every room.
And there's an assistant
with her at all times.
Listen, this stuff
does happen, you know?
Don't be so naïve.
What? I'm not naïve.
I know, I know.
That's why I married you.
Right?
- Yeah.
- Yes.
Maybe we should make
these Wednesday night things
a regular thing?
Ooh, I like that.
I think that it would be
really good for Mia.
I would like that.
Are you okay?
No.
Rebecca didn't show up
for work today.
That is just not like her.
I mean, she never misses work.
If something's wrong,
she always calls me.
And her phone just keeps going
straight to voicemail.
Well, you know what?
I'm sure she's fine.
She's a smart girl.
I don't know.
I'm worried.
Does that mean that there
won't be another teacher
in the room today?
I don't have anyone else.
I would really like it
if you would
periodically check in on Gabby.
That's a lot of work
for one person.
Of course I will.
Of course.
Thanks.
I really don't mean
to bother you,
but I would really like
to have a meeting with you.
Anything wrong?
I don't want to bother you
about it today.
Just at some point.
Okay. Anytime tomorrow
should be fine.
I'm sure that we'll know
where Rebecca is then.
Sharks. Did you know
they have poor eyesight?
They can't really see
in the front of their eyes.
I didn't know that.
They have to rely on smell.
- Look.
- School.
Oh, look who it is, guys.
Stay here, stay here.
Hi!
Are Mia's bruises
getting better?
They are. Thanks.
I called Angela's parents.
I told them about
inappropriate behavior,
and it's not happening again.
Oh, you didn't have to do that.
No, I did.
I definitely did
because no one hurts Mia
and gets away with it.
Uh...
Okay, I have to be downtown.
Will you call me
if anything else happens?
- Of course.
- Okay.
But nothing will.
It'll all be okay.
All right, let's go play.
You wanna sit right next to Mia?
Okay, here.
You can sit there.
I know.
And do you know what they eat?
Mice.
No, that's not what they eat.
You look familiar.
Have we met before?
Mia.
That's a very pretty name.
Is everything okay?
No. No, it's Rebecca.
What? What happened?
They found Rebecca.
She was hit by a car.
It was a hit-and-run.
They said that the driver
just sped off
and left her in the street.
Is she all right?
They aren't sure.
Oh, my God.
I'm so sorry.
You know, she was
just such a sweet girl.
I mean, the thought of her
being in pain is just...
so upsetting.
Did Rebecca have any
relationship issues,
enemies, anybody
that didn't like her?
I don't know. Why?
Because we have reason to believe
that this was not an accident.
Oh, my God.
How?
Witnesses said that they saw
the driver of the vehicle
heading straight for her.
That is terrible.
No, no, she's a nice girl.
She comes from a nice family.
There were no issues.
She never missed a day of work.
Do you know
what kind of car it was?
Unfortunately,
the streetlights were very dim.
All we have so far was
that it was a late model
dark-colored sedan,
no license plate.
One of the witnesses did say
that they saw something hanging
from the rearview mirror.
Something like
a handicap placard.
Wow. Okay, I'm gonna go
pick up Mia.
I'll be back to check on you.
I'm okay. I'm gonna go
to the hospital and see Rebecca.
We thank you for your help,
and we're very sorry.
- Thank you, ma'am.
- Thank you.
All right, guys, today we're
gonna talk about photosynthesis.
Can you all say photosynthesis?
- Photo-syn-this!
- Syn-the-tha!
Good job.
Okay, so this is a plant.
I know you guys all
like plants, right?
Okay, guys, just sit here
for a second, okay?
I'll be right back.
- Hi.
I was just teaching the kids
about photosynthesis.
How are you doing?
Huh?
What?
Have you not heard the news
about Rebecca?
Oh, yeah.
Just terrible.
Terrible.
But between you and me,
she wasn't
a very good assistant.
She didn't have
those motherly instincts,
like you and I do.
I didn't know
that you were a mother.
I'm not, but, you know,
when the mommies are at work,
I'm their mommy.
And Rebecca, she just...
She didn't really embrace
that part of the job, so...
Okay, Gabby,
you know she might die.
That's not what I heard.
Oh, no, no, no.
I heard that she's just,
you know,
she's gonna be in the hospital
for a couple months.
I actually think the time off
will be really good for her.
Yeah, well, we'll pray
for her speedy recovery.
Yes, me and Troy will
definitely do that tonight.
- Who's Troy?
- I haven't told you about Troy?
- He's my husband.
- Oh.
I've just never even heard you
talk about it. Him or...
Well, you know, he's
handicapped, so...
- Oh, my gosh, I'm so sorry.
- He doesn't get out much.
No, it's okay, you know,
he's learned to deal with it.
I'd better get Mia home.
You know, maybe we can get lunch
later this week
and get to know each other
a little better.
I would love that.
That'd be great.
Mia, sweetie, hi.
Okay. All right, say bye.
- Bye.
Bye.
I saw you learning about
photosynthesis and everything.
I love that she taught you
about that.
All right.
Here we go.
Watch your head.
How was daycare today?
Miss Gabby made me treats.
- Oh, she did?
- Yup.
- No hurt today?
- No hurt.
That's good.
Oh.
Hello, Daniel.
- Hey. Everything all right?
- Sure.
There's just something
about Mia's daycare.
It's those damn video cameras.
Every time I see Gabby take Mia
to the corner of the room,
I just get freaked out.
I can understand that.
She's fine though.
She's with me right now.
She said it was a good day.
No problems in school,
although...
one of the teacher's assistants
was in a car accident,
and the police said that
she was run over
and...
- And what?
- And that it might have been intentional.
That's frightening.
My mind is spinning,
running rampant
with all sorts of thoughts.
Thoughts like what?
Like am I doing the right thing
by putting Mia in daycare.
I have to be honest
with you, Rachel.
Mia's teacher did seem
pretty strange the other night.
I really wanna know what Gabby
does in the corner of that room.
Why don't you just stick
a video camera in the corner?
That's a really good idea.
I wasn't being serious.
Oh, but it's still a good idea.
I thought you just said
everything was fine.
There's just
something about Gabby
that I can't put my finger on.
If you think Mia's in danger,
you should be taking her
out of school immediately.
I don't... I don't think
that she's in danger.
I just think that Gabby's
taking a special interest
in our daughter,
and sometimes it's like they're
having a secret dialogue.
Secret dialogue?
- About what?
- I don't know.
I don't know.
That's why I...
wanna put the video camera
in there.
You can't just go sticking video
cameras in the corners of rooms.
Why not?
It's illegal for starters.
Who's gonna find out?
Well, what if they do?
What if they find out?
And then what? They're gonna
put a concerned mother away
for videotaping a classroom?
Besides, you're an attorney.
You can make sure
I don't go to jail.
Oh, great.
Now I'm an accomplice.
I have to go, okay?
We'll talk about this later.
How many times have I told Steve
to stay off my desk?
I'm trying to do my work.
I need time to fix this stuff.
Maybe if I turn this
upside-down.
Oh, that'll work.
How'd that get on the Internet?
Hi.
Hi. How can I help you?
I'm looking to secretly
video record someone.
Well, you've come
to the right place.
Cheating husband?
No. That was
a couple years ago.
But I'm actually
looking to record
my daughter's daycare teacher.
Really?
Well, that's a new one.
All right, well, let's see.
We have um, we have cameras
hidden inside dolls,
pens, books, teddy bears.
Do you have anything
with live video feed?
Yeah. You know what?
As a matter of fact, I do.
- Okay.
- Follow me.
Hi, Gabby.
Oh, hey, Rachel.
I am so glad to see you.
I was just
cleaning up some stuff.
Actually, I have to...
I'll be right back, okay?
- Just stay here, stay here.
- Sure.
Ohh...
I told them to...
Hey, you know...
Are you here for something?
Oh, I was just gonna
check in on Mia.
Oh, she's at recess.
You can go out back.
- Sure. Thanks.
- No problem. Bye.
Bye.
What's a good song?
Let's play hop in a line.
Get behind me.
♪ A, B, C, D, E, F, G ♪
♪ H, I, J, K, L, M, N, O, P ♪
♪ Q, R, S, T, U, V ♪
♪ W, X, Y and Z ♪
♪ Now I know my ABCs ♪
♪ Next time won't you play with me ♪
Okay, everyone, nap time.
All right, everybody,
let's pull out our beds.
Mia, you stay here.
Look, I don't want trouble.
You do exactly what I say.
I don't understand
why you don't understand.
No child of mine is gonna cry
like that, okay, Crystal?
You're gonna be stronger
than that, okay?
Tell me what what your name is.
No. It's Crystal. Crystal.
Say "My name is Crystal."
And I'm your mom.
Sit, okay? Sit.
I'm your mommy, okay?
Who's your mom?
Look at me, look at me.
I am your mommy.
Look at me.
We're gonna go away from here,
and you're gonna have
a new daddy,
It's gonna be great.
It's gonna be awesome.
Where do you want to go?
Disneyland?
We'll go, we'll go.
Where do you want to go?
Do you want to go
to a water park?
Listen, okay? I need you
to understand something.
No child of mine is gonna cry
like that, okay, Crystal?
No.
Now you tell me
what your name is.
Crystal. That's right.
Who's your mom?
- No.
- I am.
That's right.
Because I'm your mother.
No.
Now, if anyone asks you,
play the little game.
But I'm your mom.
Soon enough, we're leaving.
Okay?
Do you understand?
I'm your mother.
You don't have to disrespect
your mother like that, okay?
You listen to everything
that I say to you, right?
Because I'm your mother.
Okay, Crystal?
Never do that again.
Rachel.
Is it time to sign Mia out?
You know how to get to the 385
from here?
We need to go.
Um, you don't look well.
You're breathing really heavy.
Hey, can you guys help us out?
That's my wife.
Let's ask her.
Maybe you should sit down
while we finish our song.
Um, Rachel.
We should really
do that lunch, you know.
You know, to get to know
each other better.
Maybe next week.
Barbara.
What's wrong?
It's Rebecca.
She's dead.
Oh, my God.
She died this morning.
Barbara, do you know
Gabby's husband?
Yes, I met him once. Why?
Does he drive?
Sometimes he picks up Gabby
from school.
Why, Rachel?
You need to call the police.
What? Why?
Now!
Okay, fine.
Let me just tell Gabby
about Rebecca.
No. You need to call the police
right now. Right now!
911. What's your emergency?
Yes. We have reason to believe
that my daycare teacher
was involved in the murder
of Rebecca Hart.
We need someone to come to
the school as soon as possible.
Where you going?
I can't leave the children
alone with her.
Oh. Be careful.
I gotta make sure
the children are okay.
Gabby!
Hi, honey.
Where's Miss Gabby?
Where's Miss Gabby, huh?
She's gone.
How could you have been
so stupid?
- What?
- What do you mean, what?
What did I do?
You took the license plate
off the car,
and you left
your handicapped placard
hanging on the rearview mirror.
- So?
- Oh, just, you know,
Rachel now knows.
She figured it out.
So what?
It was an accident.
Sound familiar?
Oh, you think you're just gonna
get away with this, huh?
Like they did?
At the worst, the cops are gonna
consider it a hit-and-run,
and I get a slap on the wrist.
There's no way they can prove
that I intended
to kill that girl.
Her name was Rebecca,
by the way.
Right, Rebecca, the girl
that you told me to kill.
You're gonna blame this on me?
You told me to do it.
So if I told you
to roll off a cliff,
you would do that, huh?
No, Gabby, I wouldn't.
- I need you, Troy.
- Gabby, listen to me.
Get ahold of yourself.
The neighbors are gonna hear us.
- I don't care, Troy!
- Where are you going?
Where are we going?
We are going to get our child.
- Hey!
- Get her out of the car.
- What's going on?
What's going on?
Okay, sweetie,
let's play a game, okay?
Here we go. Quick.
To the house.
Rachel.
Hey, Rachel.
Rachel, stop.
What is happening?
What's going on?
- It's her.
- It's who?
You wanna pretend like it didn't
happen and forget it about it,
but I can't do that, Daniel.
Rachel, what are you
talking about?
The accident.
Daniel, Gabby is the mother
from the accident.
What?
You sure about this?
Look at me. I've never been
so sure about anything
in my whole life.
This is for us.
I know.
I don't know. Do you think
that she planned this,
or is this just a coincidence?
- What does she want?
- She wants Mia.
Who is it?
It's Gabby.
Grab Mia.
Sweetie.
Take her upstairs
and call the police.
- Okay.
- And be quiet.
Be safe.
- Hello, Gabby.
- What are you doing here?
I thought you guys
were divorced.
We are.
Oh, so you're just,
you're getting back together?
That's sweet.
Okay, sweetie, okay.
I need you to be very quiet
for Mommy, okay?
Don't say a word.
Can you do that for Mommy?
Can I help you with something?
I'm looking for Rachel.
I needed to speak with her
about something.
Unfortunately,
Rachel's not here right now.
Oh, so you're just alone?
You're just alone with Mia?
Yes.
Oh, okay, well, you know,
I could help you watch her.
You know, you can do some work,
and I can watch her
while you wait for Rachel.
No, that's good, that's good.
Thank you though, Gabby.
Appreciate it.
So who's that?
Oh, that's just, uh...
That's Troy.
You don't recognize him?
I'm really sorry.
He would get out of the car,
it's just he can't walk.
You don't recognize him?
I mean, you nearly killed him.
It's gonna be okay.
Yes, hi.
Please send
the police immediately.
Yeah, it's 4705.
Yes, thank you.
I don't understand.
Drop the act.
I mean, you told the police
it was an accident?
Yeah, no, it was murder,
and at the very least it was
vehicular manslaughter,
but you got off,
because you're an attorney,
on a ticket
for talking on the phone.
Yeah. Uh...
Do you remember that night?
Do you remember the night
that you killed my child?
Take it easy.
Do you remember that?
Gabby, I'm sincerely sorry
for your loss.
My loss? My loss?
My child is dead,
and my husband is a cripple,
and I can't even have
another baby with him
even if I wanted to.
You call it a loss?
That's really amusing.
I would call it a catastrophe
that destroyed my life.
You're right, Gabby, I shouldn't
belittle your situation.
You should've been there.
You should've
taken accountability
for what you did to my family.
Gabby, the police told me
it was not my fault.
It was your fault!
Gabby, Gabby, look at me.
It wasn't my fault.
It was an accident.
An accident? No.
There are no accidents.
In life, these things,
they happen.
God does not create accidents.
Every time you get into a car,
you take that chance.
And how many people have you
prosecuted for accidents, huh?
Gabby, get back in the car now!
Please just get in the car!
Would you just get in the car
now, please?
What are you doing?
Troy, why are you leaving?
See, that...
was an accident.
Rache...
Rachel!
Rachel.
Crystal!
Mommy's home.
- Mommy.
- Shh.
Rachel!
I'm here for my baby.
You should just give her to me.
That way I don't have
to hurt you.
Rachel!
Hey!
You hurt her, I will kill you!
Rachel!
If you hurt her, I'll kill you!
Sounds like it came
from around back. Let's go!
Stop running.
You're gonna hurt her!
Where is she?
Stop!
Rachel!
10-71, shots fired!
She's not your child.
Yes, she is.
What do you think, this is
some sort of coincidence?
God made this happen.
This right here,
this is where fate meets!
So where is my child?
Rachel!
Sir, are you okay?
- Yeah.
- We got you.
Think about what you're
doing here, Gabby.
Think about it.
Why would God do this?
Why would he take your baby
away from you
so that could take my baby
away from me?
It doesn't make sense.
Life doesn't make sense!
If it made sense,
I'd have your perfect life
instead of
my pathetic existence!
So this...
this is my chance!
My chance of making it right!
I'm so sorry
that you lost your baby.
I am. I really am.
My heart broke when
I heard you scream for her.
Did you know that I was pregnant
with Mia then?
I was.
We almost lost her.
I almost lost my baby too.
Your baby lived.
My baby died.
I don't know why things
happen the way that they do.
I-I...
There's nothing that we can do
about it now, okay?
Yeah, there is.
Tell me where Crystal is!
She's in heaven, Gabby.
Maybe one day
you can be with her.
Why would you say that?
You don't know that!
Okay, you're right,
I don't know.
I don't know if that's true.
Wouldn't it be wonderful
if that were true?
LAPD! Put the gun down!
I think you're right.
Put it down!
I'm coming.
No! No!
No!
Daniel. Daniel.
- Daniel?
- Hey.
I told you you still love me.
I still love you.
Where's Mia?
Mia.
Sweetie!
Mommy's here!
I'm right here!
Mia, sweetie, Mommy's here.
Mommy!
Oh, sweet girl.
Oh!
I love you, Mommy.
You did such a good job.
You did great.
Mommy loves you.
Okay, let's go see Daddy.
Hey! Hey, there she is!
- Mia!
- Our baby's okay.
Oh, you did so good.
I love you.
Come on, get in the car.
Rachel!
You took everything from me!
Everything!
Don't listen to her, sweetie.
♪ This time ♪
♪ I'll take the time to hold your hand ♪
♪ And this time ♪
♪ We'll build those castles in the sand ♪
So you ready
to do this again?
I am. I'm more ready
than when we said "I do."
- You are?
- Yeah.
I think that
we weren't ready then.
We needed to live and learn
what's important in life.
I know that it's you and Mia
that's important in my life.
Do you think it's fate
that brought us back together?
I think fate set our path.
But it's up to you and me to
decide if we wanna be together.
I've decided.
I can't live without you.
Me too.
I love you, Rachel.
And you too, kiddo.
♪ This time ♪
♪ I'll feel the wind upon my face ♪
♪ Ah ♪
♪ And think of you ♪
♪ With every breath that I take ♪
♪ Life, it passes ♪
♪ But I won't let it pass me by ♪
♪ Ooh ♪
♪ My heart may be broken ♪
♪ But at least it is open this time ♪
♪ Hey, it's just the rain ♪
♪ Falling down ♪
♪ On my skin ♪
♪ All the gray ♪
♪ Yesterday ♪
♪ It's far away ♪