Shit! Damn it.
Hello?
Hello? Anybody here?
Lie still.
You were very lucky.
A concussion and a sprained ankle.
You could have broken your neck.
Are you better now?
Lie still
The police wants a word with you.
If you are ready?
Please lie still. You must lie
still a couple of days -
- and by the way behave
yourself
Alright, Duus Jensen. Please be brief.
He's just awakened.
How do you do. Duus Jensen.
This is my colleague Sgt Hald.
We won't disturb you long.
We found your papers in your clothes.
Peter Sander. The Home Guard
in Copenhagen. Peter Bangsvej 114.
- Is that correct?
- correct.
- On what business did you come here?
- I ran out of gas.
- Then it's your car up on the road?
- KA 32946.
Yes. I went back to
borrow a phone.
- Why exactly up here?
- I saw a light when I went by.
But then Ifell,
and when I got up again -
he shot at me.
- Shot at you?
- Yes.
- Who?
- I don't know?
The killer, I suppose.
- The killer?
- Yes.
- Did you see him?
- No. It was dark.
- Then, how could he see you?
- I suppose he couldn't.
- Then, why did he shoot at you?
- I suppose he could hear me.
- I see. Then what?
- Then I knocked at the door.
When nobody came, Iwent in.
It wasn't locked.
The light was on.
They were all gone.
- Who?
- The guests.
The only thing I found was
the body in the bedroom.
When I came back to the front door
it was locked from inside with a hinge
So I went upstairs
and then the lights went out -
- and then he pushed me
down the stairs.
I see.
Did you catch him yet?
- Who?
- The killer.
You need to take it easy
and get some rest.
We will be back shortly.
- You don't think I did it?
- We don't think anything about anybody.
Dr. Lindberg committed suicide.
- That can't be true.
- It is beyond any doubt.
He was found
with his gun in his hand.
There was no gun.
It has been put there.
He was murdered.
- Why didn't you call us?
- The phone was disconnected.
I see.
We have called several times
this morning.
Listen. Something is wrong.
Someone is trying to fool you.
- Have you talked to any of the guests?
- Dr. Lindberg was alone all night.
His maid was off for the night.
How will you explain
the dinner table?
The dinner table?
Is that gone as well?
It was set for three people. There was
food on the plates and lit candles.
I'm sorry,
but there wasn't any dinner table.
I think we better...
Dr. Lund will only get mad at us.
It's obvious, that you hurt you head.
Just one information.
Your position?
Writer.
- What kind of books do you write?
- Detective novels.
- Good day.
Merete Lindberg.
I hope you slept well.
I did, thank you.
Are you hungry?
You slept most of the day.
Yes, perhaps a little.
Then I will get you some food.
Dr. Lund told me you need rest.
You must stay until you are well.
- Very kind of you.
- I will send miss Joergensen.
- Call me if you need anything.
- Thank you very much.
- Feeling better?
- How do you think I look?
Not bad.
Considering your age.
- Thanks. Better or worse?
- Much better.
Do you have a cigaret'!
- Do you think that's wise?
- I think I could get up.
I would strongly advise you not to.
You are not wearing any clothes.
They were dirty and soaked.
We had to undress you
and wash you clothes.
- Are you family?
- My name is Eva Lindberg.
It was my uncle, Joachim,
you found in the bed room.
I'm sorry.
Merete was married to my older brother,
who died in a plane crash five years ago.
She is alone with her son, John. He is
twelve years old and not an easy boy.
- Do you live close by?
- Arhus. But we have a cabin here.
Merete and John have been living here for a week.
I only came this morning.
I was supposed to come with Bertel,
but I couldn't find him.
Bertel is my little brother. He studies
law. That's it, the whole family.
Poor miss Joergensen. She is the only
one having a hard time.
- You were not particularly close to...?
- We weren't getting along very well.
Merete is probably hurt the most.
She lived by his grace -
- and he thought she was too fussy.
He bullied her.
He was only kind to Bertel.
He thought that boys must be boys.
A girl on the other hand
is not supposed to act like a slut
Like me.
Listen, you aren't eating anything.
I will let you get rid of me.
You can stay if you like.
That's right. You think uncle Joachim
was murdered.
Not only do I believe it...
It's not nice of you to think so.
Only three people have a really good
motive for killing uncle Joachim
He was very wealthy. Both Merete, Bertel
and I are in dire need of money.
Are you John?
Did she talk about me?
I know all about you.
You don't have to leave.
Come on in.
Do you want some food?
Why aren't you in school?
I'm on vacation.
- Now. That's a strange time of the year.
- It's only our school.
I see.
And only the best students.
I was the only one in my class
who got off.
That's nice to spend a little
time in the country.
- It's boring.
- okay.
If only uncle Joachim didn't get nailed.
- Nailed?
- Yes.
He committed suicide.
They say you are mad.
' Who?
. Evel'ybouy_
- The cops, mom and the doctor.
- I see.
Because you hurt your head.
I'm the only one in the world,
who don't think you are crazy.
I believe everything you say.
The murder, the shooting and
the phone.
The man pushing you down the
stairs and the dinner table.
How do you know all that?
I was spying outside the door
when the cops were here.
Is it true that you write
detective novels?
Yes.
Like this one?
Maybe not exactly like that one.
Why don't we solve the case?
- We'?
- Yes. You and me.
I don'! know.
It could be fun.
You got up too soon. You were supposed
to stay in bed for a couple of days.
I'm feeling alright. Besides I can't
trouble you by occupying the guest room any longer
- Where are you going?
- I was on my way to Norway.
A skiing trip?
You don't have to do that now.
Concussion and sprained ankle.
Why don't you stay for a couple of days.
- If you insist.
- Oh, I don't.
- It is very beautiful.
- Yes it is...
Besides dr. Lund insists you
take it easy.
- Then we have much better time
- Time, for what?
Solve the murder of course.
He and I made an agreement.
- John, why don't you go out to play?
- Play? why?
- It is cold as hell.
- Then put on some clothes.
- What am I supposed to play?
- Whatever. Just go.
- Can I do whatever I want to?
- yes, yes.
I think he heard something
through the door.
- He is quite a lively boy.
- Do you know the one about the toad and the prince?
I tried kissing John twice,
and he didn't turn.
- Once he even bid me.
- It's not easy.
I thought a change of air maybe...
And you're on holiday
- Holiday?
- Did he tell you that?
He told me it was a price for
being clever at school.
He was kicked out of school
last week.
I see.
I have to get a hold of this. It
takes so long with the hand dryer.
I have to tow my car.
I have some gas to spare. Normally
only girls run dry.
I need to get some clothes on
then I will take you.
Miss Joergensen?
Just wanted to thank you for the clothes.
It's as good as new.
You're welcome.
I was thinking about something,
miss Joergensen.
You were off duty monday night.
The night the doctor...
When you came next morning, did you
notice anything particular in the kitchen?
Yes, something odd about the kitchen.
What?
Everything was just odd that morning.
But there was something in particular.
H ow?
The doctor': coffee cup.
Yes?
I had already done the dishes.
Just before I left
I put the cup on the kitchen table.
The next morning it was clean.
But the doctor never washes his cup.
And none of the ladies had been
in the kitchen.
It was all very odd.
How long have you been with the doctor?
Eight years.
- But you didn't live here?
- No.
People would've talked.
They are so busy talking.
The lady asked me to move in now.
Why don't you move in the guest room then?
I might as well...
This is fine for me.
I don't mind.
John!
- John, where are you?
- Here.
Oh God, I thought...
- What are you doing?
- I'm playing.
- How can you do something like this?
- I could play whatever I wanted, remember.
But you can't...
We have to try to put this out.
- Not much to do I'm afraid.
- It's full of papers and paper boxes.
It's almost burned to the ground.
It's horrible. What am I to do
with this boy?
I can take him for a trip.
I'm going anyway for some gas.
- Would you really?
- yes, yes.
That's awfully nice of you.
Well, I have to get finished with
this hair.
Thank you.
- What did you find?
- Five.
Down in the pocket.
Are you not mad at me at all?
It wasn't my shed.
It wasn't my damn shed either.
Come on.
Nice car you have.
Fancy!
- I thought you were still angry from this morning.
- I am.
You can't keep a secret.
I'm sorry. Are we not going to
solve the case then?
- Maybe.
- I won't tell anybody.
Even if they stick me with needles
or pull off my nails.
Thank you. That will do.
How are we going to start?
First we have to find out
who's got a motive.
And then we need to find out
if they got an alibi.
What they did monday night,
when the doctor was killed.
What did you do monday night?
- Are you saying it could be me?
- Of course. Why not?
Can'! you take a little excitement.
Give me the knife. That's not
something for small boys.
Nonsense. You said it yourself,
it could be me.
- It can't.
- Why not?
Because the killer didn'tjust
murder the doctor.
He also cleaned the table and
washed the dishes.
He even washed one cup too many.
- You see, it can't be you then.
- No.
- I was in the cabin sleeping, anyway.
- Yes, of course. What else?
Well, I wasn't quite sleeping. I was reading.
I pretended I was sleeping when mother looked in -
when she left I kept on reading.
- Wasn't your mother at home?
- No she came back and looked in my room.
But then she left again.
- When did she come back?
- I don't know. Guess I fell asleep.
But it was late.
I see.
I need to say hello.
You can take care of the car.
Somebody must have washed that cup.
I'm having a hard time realizing
what's so unusual.
Ifjust someone was being busy
he could have missed...
That's true. That suspicious story.
Are you perhaps a detective?
I am curious to find out how
crazy I was.
But if I find out anything
I will let you know.
I have to advise you not
to do anything.
We will take care of this.
You are only unnecessarily
complicating things.
Well.
But don't you find it peculiar
about that coffee cup?
It doesn't prove anything,
but of course I will put it in my report.
You must be mad. You are
supposed to be in bed.
- I'm fine.
- Nonsense. You were delirious.
So does the police think.
Of course. Joachim took his own life.
- You don't seem surprised.
- It wasn't a surprise.
He was feeling lonely and
was experiencing depressions.
He even occasionally
talked about saying goodbye.
You were a close friend of
dr. Lindberg?
Perhaps his closest. We were
sometimes having dinner.
What were you doing monday night?
That's none of your business.
Oh, we missed the gas station.
Well, I'll go there tomorrow.
- Can I come?
- Yes, yes.
Great. I also want a sports car.
Might be one like this. How fast
can it go?
Fast enough.
Well, of course it's old.
There was once an accident here.
Right here.
It was a Iumberjack. He came
from within the woods.
He was on a moped,
and he was hit by a car.
The car took off. It was from Alborg,
but they never found it.
It happened last sommer.
A year and a half ago.
He was all crushed. All blood and
mud and brain matter.
- Thanks, that's enough.
- And his moped was all flat.
They've probably let that damn rat out.
- The rat?
- Yes. Those stupid bitches.
Was it a rat you kept in a
box this morning?
Yes, one i caught. I took it
in to feed it.
They just had to meddle.
I even wrote on the box.
"Do not open until Christmas"
- I let it go.
- Hero.
- I grounded him.
- Hopefully for the rest of his life.
- May I borrow your car this afternoon?
- Yes.
Here you are. Where are you going?
I'm going to town. I'll be back
for supper. Thank you, goodbye.
- Let me.
- Thank you.
Tell me, when did you last clean
in here, miss Joergensen?
- What do you mean?
- I mean when did you last vacuum and such?
I cleaned the house this monday
before I left.
You didn't clean anything since
monday night then -
since the doctor...
"Car salesman H. F. Kaergaard"
He is not at home. He was going
to talk to the police.
He took his bike,
so it'll probably be a while
You might run into him at the station
if it's important.
May I borrow your phone?
Be my guest.
- The phone is right there.
- Thank you. Do you have the number to the station?
- There's a phonebook.
- thanks.
- Is it your daughter?
- Daughter in law.
- So your son is the priest?
- That's right.
I see.
Mrs. Kaergaard, where was your
husband monday night?
I don'! know.
- Was he at home?
- Yes, he was.
Yes, hello?
Yes, hello.
How is your head?
Well, that's nice.
Kaergaard? Not yet.
Oh, he's on bike. Then it'll be a while.
He called me privately.
- What do you care?
- It's a long story.
But you are in for a surprise.
A surprise?
What the hell is this?
What? Yes, of course you can come.
You're welcome. Goodbye.
Those folks from Copenhagen.
- Goodbye.
- Goodbye, Hald.
What is it that you want'?
Who are you?
Did your husband worry a lot lately?
Yes, perhaps a bit.
And he wasn't at home monday night, right?
You have to talk to him yourself.
Perhaps that won't be necessary now.
The killer?
- I suppose it could be me.
- Yes, so you say.
- If, there is a killer.
- But there is.
Yes, so YOU say.
I haven't got an alibi for
monday night.
I was home alone doing my nails.
Nobody will believe it can take
a whole night.
It is only a three quarters of
an hour drive to Arhus.
And I really need the money.
Currently I know no wealthy men.
Not wealthy enough at least.
- How well do detective novels do?
- Not that well.
I could use a brandy.
Would you mind?
- I gave up on being a writer.
- It didn't pay off well enough?
I found out I couldn't write.
- What are you doing now then?
- I'm a journalist.
Natural development
when you can't write.
By the way I once reviewed
one of your books.
I have my own column now,
But earlier I took everything I could get.
- How was your review then?
- Bad. The killer annoyed me.
Killers can be annoying.
On a psychological level he
was not right.
Was it the specific review,
which ended with:
"The author seems to find his
psychological insight in the gossip press"?
"As a writer he will soon be
as dead as one of his corpses"?
"He should commit a couple of murders
himself in order to survive"?
Neatly written, right?
I then decided that my first murder
should be that particularjournalist -
- but I couldn't find time to
go to AArhus.
Now is my chance, right?
On a psychological level he
was not right.
- Did you study psychology as well?
- I am too old. lwas shy.
Young men with beards and girls
and messy hair make me shy.
But well shaven men with
simple thoughts...
fit me just perfectly.
I'm sorry.
- May I clean the table now?
- Yes, please miss Joergensen.
- God knows what's keeping Merete.
- I will keep some supper for her.
Oh, I have an appointment with the
police. I have to go.
- Isn't this a beautiful living room'?
- Yes.
Uncle Joachim had an eye for aesthetics.
Perhaps not so much for comfort.
You should see our cabin.
It's nice.
And there is peace and quiet.
Excellent idea.
Tomorrow afternoon.
I'm so sorry. I was delayed.
I hope you've already eaten.
What has happened?
This is what's happened. We want
to know what you know.
Then it is true.
I think we did you wrong.
This was found on the floor in the living room.
I think Kaergaard was
one of the guests.
He was going to tell something
but was prevented.
Maybe. You must admit it
looked like suicide.
And you had bumped your head.
That's why we were suspicious.
Well. That's what you get
payed for.
But who on earth would want
to kill Joachim? Why?
Kaergaard there. Do you suppose
a woman could have done it?
Anybody could have killed a
man with that thing.
- Of who are you thinking?
- Just a thought.
- You have to tell if you know something.
- Yes, if I find out anything.
Don't try finding out anything.
You don't find us sufficiently skilled?
Iwill keep quiet.
Am I allowed to ring you?
Yes, please do.
John, is that you?
Who screamed?
My God. Miss Joergensen!
What's happened?
No! He was going to kill me.
- Did you see who it was?
- I was blinded by the light.
- I'll get the first aid.
- Let's turn on the light, like that.
I don't think it's...
It hurts a little.
Easy now. Let's take off the clothes.
- Does it hurt a lot?
- Yes.
Bertel, what a time to arrive.
The police.
It's you. What is the matter?
I see?
Miss Joergensen?
I'll send Hald immediately.
I am waiting for a call from Arhus.
- This is the tool.
- Funny that he didn't take it with him.
I think he most likely was looking for
something. Not to steal anything.
Nobody must touch this. We need it
dusted for finger prints.
- You don't look too well.
- You don't look too well yourself.
No, all this messing around at night.
I wasn't aware you lived here.
Miss Joergensen only moved in yesterday.
Somebody who knew the house well would have
thought the living room floor empty then.
A drink anybody. I really need one?
- You arrived immediately after the assault?
- Yes
Peculiar time.
I wasn't able to leave earlier.
I was busy.
Hans Joergen says hello by the way.
I have classes with mr. Hald's son.
- When did you leave Arhus?
- at half past one.
Any witnesses?
I've just arrived and already I'm
accused of murder and arson etc.
You didn't catch a glimpse of
the perpetrator?
I was blinded by the lamp.
I couldn't see him.
But you are certain that it
was a man?
Well, I don't know. Why would
a woman...
It was Sander's idea.
I think it's all for now. I will
be back again tomorrow.
Are you mad, kid?
There was no danger. The safety
was on.
Where does he learn things
like that?
He found it in my coat.
John, it is not nice to go in people's
pockets. Hurry up to bed.
Goodnight.
Thank you, Bertel, you're the best.
How about Perry Mason there.
Don't you need one?
Thanks.
It is too bad about that boy.
Can I have a drink as well?
I wonder what he was looking for.
Something on the floor.
Something he missed.
If it was a lady it could have
been a hairpin.
- That is very compromising.
- Or a bra.
- Shame on you little brother.
- Just a moment.
- John?
- Yes, what is it?
- What are you doing there?
- I was supposed to come, right?
- We should solve this together.
- Yes, that's right.
As a matter of fact that's why I...
Tell me, John, what's in your pocket?
I don! know. Why?
- Why don't we give it a look?
- I suppose we could.
What are you going to do with
that disgusting mouse?
I would stuff it,
but then I forgot about it.
Is any of that something you
found in the living room?
Yes...
That one.
- When?
- Today.
Do you remember exactly where?
Yes.
Right there.
- We are all suspects.
- The ladies in particular.
You too.
Yes, I'm painfully aware of it.
I'm not particularly popular around here.
I'm off after the lawyer reads us
the will.
Mr. Sander wants to know where you were
monday night. Right?
Yes, please.
Monday night? lwas in
dr. Oscar Philipsen's class.
Like every monday night.
Bon appetite.
- We are going in fifteen minutes.
- I will be there.
- I suppose you are going going out.
- For some fresh air perhaps.
- How's your foot?
- Well.
We can go to the cabin
when I come back.
If you dare spending time
with a murder suspect.
- Be nice.
- Maybe.
Your mustn't do that.
You can't go around killing people.
Not with this.
What if it was one of the girls?
It was obviously you. You have a limp.
Do you know anybody around here
who has a limp?
Why?
Because the one who shot at me
the other night couldn't see me
- But he could hear me.
- Perhaps he thought you were someone else?
- Somebody with a limp?
- exactly.
Yes, clever.
I know someone with a limp.
Yes, it's him.
He is very scary.
And very strong.
He once beat up Bertel
in the city.
- Bertel? Why?
- I don't know.
- Who is it?
- He works in the lumberyard.
- I don't want to talk with you.
- Did you know dr. Lindberg?
You are that man from Copenhagen, who tripped
and fell at the dr. 's. I know him by reputation.
- But his nephew, Bertel?
- That scoundrel.
- Why did you beat him?
- Because he is a scoundrel.
- Where were you monday night?
- None of your business.
- Did you know that kaergaard is dead?
- Dead?
- Yes, murdered. Last night.
- Says who?
He was on his way to the police
to tell then something.
Did you know Kaergaard?
You still don't want to tell
where you were monday night?
Let me tell you something else.
Around here we take care of our own business.
We don't like strangers
sniffing around.
Keep your nose to yourself. Otherwise
it might end up broken.
- What's next?
- Home.
Are we not following him.
We can easily catch up with him.
- I need to go home to make a call.
- Afterwards then. We have to solve these murders.
- Aftenrvards I have a date.
- With who?
It's none of your business.
You should be a little more careful.
She's having a crush on you.
- Who?
- Eva. Girls are stupid.
Being wealthy is great.
He was much richer than we thought.
Bertel went off for Arhus immediately
to use his part.
- Bertel was not at school.
- How do you know that?
I called dr. Oscar Philipsen.
I see. Not that I am surprised the least.
He is not particularly determined.
He's been confused and restless.
He claims that law study is boring.
We are going up there.
Were you hurt?
I don'! understand.
I always make sure the car is in gear.
I'm certain I put it in gear.
I made you a drink.
I think we need it.
- That was close.
- The question is, who did it?
- What do you mean?
- I don't think it was an accident.
Please stop. You are fixated.
Cheers.
- That is the timber merchant.
- How do you know it was him?
I payed him a visit this morning.
He threatened me directly.
And I saw his car in the woods.
- Why did you visit the timber merchant.
- Because he has a limp.
I'm certain that your uncle's other
guest was him.
- He does look like a killer.
- I don't think it was him, though.
He looks like that and everybody
would be satisfied if it was him.
I suggest we call him the killer then -
and act awfully simple.
I'd rather you suspected me.
It would be wise. You don't know
what I can do.
My God!
It seems you are right once again.
He was struck down and was
unconsciousness when the car went down.
I can't see the connection between the doctor,
Kaergaard and the timber merchant though.
Why did they have to die.
And by who. I don't understand.
I've lived here most of my life.
I think I know people around here.
They are righteous and honest people.
I don't understand.
The timber merchant once
beat up Bertel. Did you know that?
Yes, he was flirting with his daughter.
She was a beautiful and lively girl.
Hard to image her as a wife of a priest.
She married a priest.
Kaergaard's son.
Yes, they married.
A year and a half ago.
John told me something.
Something that also happened here
a year and a half ago. An accident.
- But there is probably no connection.
- Perhaps there is.
Because it was Bertel who drove
the car.
It was the timber merchant's car.
And his daughter was with Bertel.
I remember that accident.
It was never solved.
We searched for that car but
without luck.
The blood test showed the
man was drunk -
- But no heirs and no life insurance.
Case got closed.
Let's see.
Yes, I remember.
There was a witness.
Dr Lindberg. He said it was a
car from AAlborg.
Lindberg lied to cover for Bertel,
and the two fathers avoided a scandal.
Kaergaarcl was priest and the man from the carpenter's
shop was proud to have him as son in law.
They agreed to keep silent and
hid the car at Kaergaard's workshop -
but somebody must have known.
- Blackmail.
- It doesn't quite fit.
Why would a blackmailer kill
his victims?
And why were they having dinner?
So far you are the only one
who have seen that dinner table
May I use your phone?
Hello?
- Lovely. Are you coming home now?
- Soon. Is Merete at home?
No, she's with dr. Lund.
Miss Joergensen is off. John is at sleep.
- Do you know what I am?
-I guess you are alone.
- All alone. Are you coming then?
- Very tempting.
- I have a surprise for you.
- What is it?
I know who the killer is.
The killer. Well, who is he then?
I will tell you if you come immediately.
- I have to take care of something first.
- Aren't you the least interested?
Yes. We are very interested in who
the killer is.
And of course you are looking for
some villain.
But there are none here.
All righteous and honest people.
- Even the killer is an honorable man.
- An honorable man?
But of course you are too stupid
to figure it out.
And you are the most stupid
if you don't come now.
- I'm all alone.
- I will be there as fast as I can.
You sound just like a tired husband.
How sad.
Listen. Could uncle Joachim cook?
- Not even an egg.
- That's what I thought.
So long.
Dr. Lindberg couldn't cook,
and miss Joergensen was off.
Merete Lindberg wasn't in the
cabin that night. John told me.
If she cooked the food, then she
knows the guests and perhaps even the killer.
If she knows, she might be in
real danger.
- Where is she?
- With dr. Lund.
I'll call you if there's anything.
Yes. That is right.
I did the cooking.
But for whom I don'! know.
Dr. Lindberg was terribly silent that day.
- Why didn't you tell us'?
- Awfully wrong of me, I know.
- Where were you the rest of the evening?
- That's exactly why.
Iwas afraid that I had to tell...
Mrs. Lindberg was with me.
We have been seeing each other some time -
- but we've been very discrete
to avoid the talk.
I was getting a divorce,
and today it is settled.
That's why I asked mrs. Lindberg
to come.
Well. We can ask mrs. Lindberg then
She had a theory that our killer was
a righteous and an honorable man.
I see.
Oh, is it you?
Just a couple of questions about
the burglary last night.
If it's alright?
- Let me.
- Thank you.
I brought this back. There were
no important fingerprints.
I am short of a few informations
for the report. If we could just...
Excuse me for a moment.
Hello. Thank heaven. You must
get back immediately.
- Are you still being alone.
- He's here.
- Who.
- I'm certain. Everything fits. Even the button.
Hello! Eva. Hello!
You already guessed it?
And mr. Sander?
- He doesn't know who.
- But he is coming?
We better wait for him.
- What are you going to do?
- Let's sit.
- Mr. Hald, don't you think...
- How did you find out?
Mr. Hald, you are not a
criminal.
You are an honorable man. Nobody will
think you are capable of crime.
But when we stop looking for
a villain you're the only one left.
The death of Kaergaard for instance.
Only four people knew he
was going to the police.
His wife, Duus Jensen, mr. Sander
and yourself.
Others will probably find out
soon, mr. Hald.
Peter Sander perhaps. But no
other. And we are waiting for him.
It is easy to imagine.
You saw the timber merchant's
car in Kaergaard's workshop.
You asked questions.
Kaergaard was nervous.
And then there was uncle Joachim.
He called me and asked me to come.
Your uncle was very authoritative.
He didn't think those young people -
- should ruin their lives
because of an accident.
I have a son myself.
I had to understand.
- I left the doctor with 1000 DKK.
- And promised to keep quiet.
Only too late did I realize.
I wanted to give the money back -
- but I was too tempted and when
I had spend all the money...
- You began to hate him.
- It was his fault and the others.
They were protecting their children.
Why shouldn't I protect my own?
My son's studies. They were
expensive. They payed -
- until the doctor finally didn't
want to anymore. He called the others.
I went out here and arrived just
in time. He couldn't convince the others.
The doctor got excited and
threatened us with his gun.
I tried to disarm him and then
the gun went off.
- That's how it went.
- An honorable man turned into a killer.
Kaergaard couldn't take it but
the man from the carpenter's was tough.
He asked me to get rid of the
man from Copenhagen. He was too curious.
The carpenter's was right, but
he shouldn't have talked to me like that.
Like I was a criminal.
He shouldn't have done that.
I am certain everybody will understand
when they hear the truth.
The truth?
The truth is that I am an
honorable man.
And nobody will ever know
differently.
Nobody will ever know.
You won't get away with this.
It will be revealed.
No, no. Nobody could ever
dream about thinking such of me.
I have always been respected.
Nobody will be suspicious.
Please be calm and come to your
senses, Hald. Put that gun away.
No, I have to use this gun now.
I have never done it before -
- because we have to account for
the bullets -
- but right now I will make an
exception. I am going to use it.
Ha! It doesn't work.
No bullets.
I found it in your coat.
I took out all the bullets.
No! You are lying.
Well, partner. You did fine.
You better give me those bullets.
Those are not toys.
Tell me, what is in your pocket?
What is the matter?
You can't take a little excitement?
I think you are a hero.
Translated by: adflictatio
Proud member of CG, 2010