Death of a Corrupt Man
Xav, do you love me?
Say that you love me.
Go to sleep!
Why don't you want to say that?
But I do.
Why don't we live together?
- Do I bother you?
- No.
Then, tell me that you love me
and will never forget me.
Just like in that song.
Oh God!
You skid sometimes.
What does "skid" mean, Xav?
Go to sleep!
- Who's there?
- It's me, Philip.
- Are you alone?
- She is asleep.
- What time is it?
- Five in the morning.
You could ask that on the phone.
I'm in trouble.
- Is it serious?
- Very serious.
Serrano.
I killed Serrano.
- Xav, who's there?
- Nobody! Go to sleep!
What a scumbag he was!
But he made you a deputy.
Exactly.
This was the beginning of the end.
You never complained before.
I was getting something.
Well, of course, not billions.
For example,
fees for building permits,
purchase of land and so on.
I wanted to stay.
But Serrano pulled out my receipts.
And I had to start all over again.
Bribes, like a swamp.
With the latest scam on the Rue de
Vaugirard, I almost got caught.
And that bastard demanded
that I resign.
Serrano is a moralist!
It's ridiculous!
I got it,
they've decided to present
Dupere's candidacy at the next election.
Dupere on my place!
Scoundrels!
This resignation would ruin
my political career
and my whole life.
The resignation letter was ready.
He said that if I didn't sign it,
he will give all the compromising
materials to journalists.
My dossier, three or four pages
of typewritten text.
He put it in a folder in the safe.
But he didn't lock it.
He said:
"You don't have to be a deputy"
He just made fun of me.
I flared up and gave him a slap.
We grappled.
He began to strangle me,
and I grabbed the first thing
that came to hand.
It was a paperweight.
I twisted and hit him.
He fell,
and I was not going to kill him.
That's all!
When did this happen?
- In the evening, about ten.
And then what did you do?
I went immediately to a meeting of
parliament in the Palais Bourbon,
so that they could see me there.
When I entered the hall, the clock was
five minutes to eleven.
And until that moment you have no alibi?
That's the thing.
Well, and you?
- What did you do last night?
- I was with you.
Then this is how it's going to be! Listen!
Yesterday you had dinner
here with me and Christian.
At half-past ten, I went to the parliament,
and now I must go.
Did anyone see you here?
- Only Kebir.
- He won't whistle.
Then I'll see you at 12.
Wait, there will be a lot of people at
Serrano's. You should show yourself.
I understand, but I... I...
- I will go.
- Thanks.
- Who was it?
- Santa Claus.
- Have you been to Xav?
- Yes.
And what?
He had dinner last night with us.
Then I went to the parliament.
Listen to the latest news.
This morning, deputy Michelle Serrano
was found dead in his office.
- Well, see you in the evening?
- We'll call each other.
The first observation suggests murder.
Our correspondent was able to meet
witnesses at the crime scene.
- Monsieur Gonsales, are you a cleaner?
- Yes, I am.
- Did you find the body at 9 in the morning?
- You could say that.
Many people were going to work,
and we'd been rubbing since 7:00.
- Where were you at that moment?
- Upstairs! On the 32nd floor.
- Tell us more.
- Well, I was yelling, right to left, as usual.
And suddenly I saw a man
with his head on the table.
I stopped rubbing. I thought he might be
sleeping or drank a lot the day before.
I called my partner.
We started knocking on the glass.
But the man wouldn't react.
Absolutely.
Then I realized that something was wrong.
- And you called the police?
- That was later, I won't miss any details.
The cabinet of deputy Serrano
is in the one of the black mirrored towers.
Square Defense.
- I'm Xavier Marechal.
- You can't come here, monsieur!
- Representative of deputy Dubaye.
- I'll call the foreman.
I desperately need to
make some shots.
You can't!
Soon the vultures in
limousines will start to arrive.
One villain killed another. When will
we cleanse ourselves from this infection?
Here is the gentleman.
- Are you Monsieur Marechal?
- Yes.
Come in. Commissioner Perne is
waiting for you on the 32rd floor.
You can't come here! Stand back!
My colleague Moreau
from Criminal Police.
I understand that the death of
Mr. Serrano shocked Mr. Dubaye.
They're good friends.
Well, we would like to...
I was almost going to say 'to interrogate'
I would like to know
what he thinks about this disaster.
I represent deputy Dubaye.
He's now at the meeting of the parliamentary
commission,
which was called due to the death of
Monsieur Serrano.
And do you know when and where
Dubaye saw Serrano for the last time?
No, but I can tell you when
I last saw Monsieur Dubaye.
And of course, it was yesterday
evening at about 23:00.
Yes, we had supper at his place.
And, of course, Madame Dubaye
prepared my favorite dish,
fish with oranges.
Of course! All the important issues
are solved in France during dinner.
Monsieur Marechal, you only
represent your friend, and you,
are apparently surprised
with our questions.
But I'm going to surprise you even more,
because I'll say
that the murder of the deputy
Serrano was inevitable.
The fact is that he possessed
some very dangerous documents.
People were afraid of him,
but you can't fear forever.
What? Policy?
I would say that this crime is both political,
and criminal.
The goal was not a robbery,
we found eight million in his safe.
But Monsieur Serrano kept a diary.
You are probably
unfamiliar with that kind of literature?
Certainly not.
Wait! There's something wrong!
There are other details here.
Regarding the excellent dinner with
Madame Dubaye.
Durieux!
I'll get.
So, Monsieur Marechal, your
statement about yesterday's dinner,
I was almost going to say 'the alibi of
Monsieur Dubaye'...
you are ready, of course, to confirm
it under oath, it's clear.
But some statements are contrary.
You mean the testimony
of Mademoiselle Braco?
Yes, Marceline Braco,
the secretary of deputy Serrano.
Mademoiselle!
- Hello!
Mademoiselle Braco, r epeat please
to Monsieur Marechal what you told us
about Monsieur Dubaye.
I heard Monsieur Serrano said that Monsieur
Dubaye will be coming to him in the evening.
- Time?
- At ten o'clock
Did you know about this meeting, Monsieur
Marechal?
No, but probably
Monsieur Serrano cancelled the meeting
and didn't tell Mademoiselle Braco about it.
But, usually, my boss...
Couldn't he go to the toilet or
change his tie without warning you?
He surely could.
Enough! You are free. Thank you.
It was her who called the commissariat.
And before the police arrived, she was
able and had time to steal the notebook.
- What notebook?
- I mean the diary.
The dossier, which I mentioned.
- How? Was it stolen?
- Didn't you know about it?
I'm not clairvoyant, am I?
You told me that they had no
intention to rob him, and now you say
that the diary was stolen.
Who needed it?
Do you at least understand the motive?
Thank you, Monsieur Marechal.
That's very kind of you to come, Monsieur
Marechal.
Hopefully you'll help us next time.
On the other hand, should we disturb you
again? What do you think about it, Moreau?
I wouldn't mind watching again
how you act being surprised,
hearing about the theft of the diary.
It was played perfectly!
- Slander!
- And the scene with his secretary
was really nicely directed. Always at your
service.
Thanks.
Good morning, Monsieur Xavier!
- Good morning, Monsieur Xavier!
- Good morning, Françoise.
Everything's the same.
The Dutch were here.
- What do they want?
- I think a delay of payment to the fifteenth.
They gave me a box of chocolates.
Chew the chocolate and tell them
that I won't be here till sixteenth.
And this?
Monsieur Fondari called and asked to
call him back. He said it's urgent.
Hello! Monsieur Fondari please!
Monsieur Fondari,
Monsieur Marechal speaking.
You already know about Serrano!?
We need to talk.
- Today?
- As soon as possible.
Hello!
Monsieur Brumaire and Monsieur Lalo.
- Nice to meet you.
- Good morning, Monsieur Marechal.
- Hello.
- You want to drink?
- Yes, Kir-Champaign.
Marcel! Two Kir-Champagne!
So what?
His secretary knew that you were
coming in the evening.
Damn it!
It's OK, she didn't see me.
- Marseille, how long do we have to wait?
- Coming right up!
- You know a guy by the name of Moreau?
- No. What's the matter?
He is from the criminal police, sarcastic
and he does not believe in your alibi.
- They'll make him to believe.
- And if they can't?
I was told there that some diary is missing.
I know everything.
Let's not discuss it here.
- Are you going to dine?
- No, Fondari is waiting for me.
- Fondari?
- Yes.
- There's Christiane.
- Monsieur Lacour!
I'm coming, Mr. general manager.
- Good day!
- Hi, Xavi!
- Hi, Philip!
- Hello!
Hello, Mr. general manager.
Hello! Nice to see you.
The police didn't say anything on Serrano
case.
And do you know anything?
- You look wonderful.
- Thanks to the influence of alcohol.
- Stop talking nonsense.
- It's not nonsense.
- You at least tell her not to drink.
- Xavier, you have to influence me!
Where did you disappear anyway?
Last time I saw you...
Yesterday.
Really, you shouldn't drink.
I was just kidding.
- Everything ready, Monsieur deputy!
- Wonderful. Come!
Listen, and didn't Fondari
invite me to dinner?
No, only me.
- Well, how do you like them?
- Whom?
Investigators
Professionals. Nothing more. But the
case is big, they might want to flash.
- You probably know Moreau?
- He's competent.
Did they ask about the diary?
They were actually
asking if I knew it existed.
I said 'no'.
And did you know about it?
I knew that Serrano kept a diary.
- Whom was he blackmailing?
- Nobody.
Or rather he didn't have to.
But he really had somebody
in his hands.
That's what I wanted to talk to you about.
While the diary was in the safe,
everybody knew what they have to do.
And now they're afraid that it got into their
hands that don't know the rules of the game.
I personally have nothing to do with.
- The more Philippe.
- Monsieur Tomski.
Monsieur Tomski.
Welcome.
- I was just passing by, that's why I didn't call.
- That doesn't matter!
A table for Monsieur Tomski.
Please!
You know you're always welcome in my
restaurant.
This way, please!
Bon Appetit!
I recommend turbot.
So what shall we get?
Xav, we must find the diary.
- First the killer.
- And the killer has got the diary.
Can't say that.
- This is for you, Monsieur Marechal.
- Thanks.
- Hello?
- Hello, this is Kebir.
I called you in the office.
Police was just here.
First they asked the concierge.
Then they got to me.
They wanted to know when did you come
back last night if you've been coming out.
And if I saw Philippe's car here.
Thank you for warning.
Sure I will!
I'll be calling. Bye.
Philippe was saying 'hello'.
I'd like to chat with him.
And did the cops ask about him?
If they ask me, I must say the same thing,
right?
- He was with me last evening.
- Ok, I got it.
You just take note that for
my friends that diary means death.
You and Philippe must consider.
If you know anything - Talk!
Otherwise, both of you
are in a big trouble.
Stop tomfooling!
You said about 3 pages
and now everybody is saying
that a diary has been stolen from the safe
Who are you fooling?
Relax, Xav.
How many names are there
on those 3 pages.
Ok.
Serrano kept a diary,
he wrote down
the amounts and dates
of some contracts.
With the names of recipients.
Do you realize what kind of bomb is that,
especially, on the day before elections?
Voters would throw rotten
eggs on the candidate
who's taking bribes
and is involved in frauds.
Well, with that diary
Serrano had deputies by the balls.
Well, the kind's dead!
Long live the king!
I never blackmailed anybody
and I will never do that!
In that case destroy the diary!
I've been thinking about it.
But I'm a politician after all.
Oh, politician! Politician!
Such policy doesn't suit me!
I'm out of it!
You think I'm not fed up
with all that?
Look, I'm not going
to settle scores with anybody.
But I must protect myself.
If I become a minister...
- Come down to earth!
- And why not?
Why not? I can say why.
Because you are suspected of murder!
They interrogated me,
then Kebir, Braco!
And they wll interrogate Fondari!
They'll smash your alibi,
in which they don't believe,
besides, if they find out you have
the diary, for you it will be the end.
It's in a safe place,
they won't get it.
I recently bought an apartment
in the Rokankur park.
They won't seek there.
- And the money? You paid them yourself?
- No, with a credit bank.
- But do they have you in their lists?
- There are many other people!
They don't give a shit about the others.
It will take the police 24 hours to find
your name in their list.
Then they'll search the place
you're calling 'safe',
if only Fondari doesn't go there tonight.
Lurch him. Sometimes even 2 minutes
can settle it.
What's wrong with you?
Feeling bad?
You know, Xav, that Fondari,
those cops, I'm crocking up.
Why am I going to Lyons?
All issues can be resolved on the phone.
But there they'll leave me alone.
I'll have there breathing space.
I can't take it anymore.
Do you understand?
You should have said that at once.
I'll go and get the diary.
- I will draw a plan.
- I know Rokankur.
No, no, no, you can lose
your way there. Look!
Hello, Kebir?! Xavier!
Can you get me a car for 2 hours?
Thanks.
You're helping me a great deal.
Meet me at the district boulevard,
where the road to Pontoise begins.
In an hour.
OK, see you.
Look! First to Sourenn,
then highway to Versailles.
Rokankur is here.
First you'll see new houses.
Building 5, will you remember? 4th floor,
second door on the left from the elevator.
4th floor,
second door on the left
There's a small chest in the second room.
The box in the middle is closed.
Here's the key. And keep in mind,
you'll see there a girl.
In the chest box?
She's a friend of mine,
she doesn't have any apartment.
Philippe, Philippe.
Christiane's having an affair with
attorney Lacor, you know about it.
OK! I'll leave the diary in a box locker
at the station.
- Shall I bring you the key?
- That'd be great.
- OK! See you!
- See you!
By the way, have you warned
the lady from the chest box I'll be coming?
Your car broke down?
No, but there are lots of cops
in front of the office.
We must turn near the racecourse.
- What?!
- We're being followed.
We have to lose them.
They were probably on my tail since I left
home.
Kebir!
Run, Xav! Run!
- Did Philippe call you?
- He did, who are you?
Xav.
We're leaving.
Get dressed.
- Won't Philippe be going to Lyons?
- He will.
We were supposed to go together.
Something's changed?
- Didn't he say anything?
- He said: "Xav will explain everything".
- No.
- Yes!
- He didn't say Xavier.
- He said 'Xav', but I don't like it.
You don't? Hurry!
They mustn't catch us here!
- Who can catch us?
- Killers.
Wait!
- Did you get the keys and passport?
- Yes.
Let's go!
Don't turn off the light.
- Can you explain?
- No!
- Is there another way out?
- I don't understand.
- Another way out?
- Through the kitchen!
Here!
It's the matter of Philippe's life!
Don't come back here!
Meet you at 3
at the Montparnasse Station!
- Got it?!
- Got it!
- Good evening!
My car! Martha!
He stole my car!
Stop, scoundrel!
This is my car!
It's me, Philippe!
Philippe!
Are you alone mademoiselle?
They made passes at me the entire evening.
And I've been drinking
coffee all the time.
You know how long I've been
here hanging around?
What happened?
Have you been asleep?!
Listen.
Philippe's dead.
An accident?! No, Christiane.
I understand.
Yes, may be.
Yes.
He's been waiting for that all the time.
Do you have the permition for
the funeral, madame Dubaye?
Please come into my office.
Come in.
Wait!
I know you were very good friends
with Monsieur Dubaye.
And I don't doubt you're suffering from his
death.
Two deputies repeatedly!
Isn't it too much, Monsieur Marechal?
Serrano's diary is a dangerous thing,
Monsieur Marechal. It attracts the killers.
- You think Monsieur Dubaye had it?
- You know my opinion.
- Dubaye killed Serrano, and nobody else.
- But you know commissioner that...
Yes, yes, that you had dinner with Monsieur
Dubaye at the time of the murder.
However, let me tell you,
that it wasn't a very good fiction.
If you, Monsieur Marechal, didn't
have dinner with him that evening,
we would still have him alive.
Let's suppose Philippe killed Serrano.
And did you find Philippe's murderer?
No.
I'll see you through the service entrance.
Perhaops Madame Dubaye doesn't
want to talk to journalists.
- Who killed him?
- I have no idea.
But I know that the money Philippe left
will not last long.
- Do you have the Serrano diary?
- What makes you think so?
- If I had it, I would sleep restfully.
- Sure. You would sleep forever.
Well, it's nice to be honest, but poor.
Not much.
Being alive is already good.
- Why don't you support me?
- I don't have enough income.
- Everything'll be OK, believe me.
- Unlikely.
Get away from the entrance!
Go away!
Monsieur Marechal? I'm Nicola Tomski.
An old friend of Philippe Dubaye.
I was shocked when I read
about his death.
I'm planning to stay
a few more days in Paris.
So if you encounter some
unexpected difficulties, just call me.
- This is my card.
- Thank you.
See you soon, Monsieur Marechal!
Express train, N 3608
from Brest at the 18th track!
She's not very smart, but cute.
I didn't see her.
- He invited us on saturday.
- That's very nice.
There'll be a big company. Frankly I
don't like when it's so many people.
- Thanks. But it'll be rude to reject.
- That's the thing!
- When will be free tomorrow?
- Like always.
- Shall we go to the movies?
- As you wish.
- I'll get the tickets.
- OK.
Stay here.
Have a nice day!
A Lotos pack, please, and coffee.
Hello! is it cafe? I was to meet
a girl in your cafe.
She's waiting for me at the counter.
Never mind. Say 'girl from Rokankur'
Girl from Rokankur?
- Girl from Rokankur!
- Yes?
There's a phone call for you!
In the basement, cabine 1.
Thanks.
I'm telling you
I have nothing to do with it!
Nonsense, absolute nonsense!
Brief, be at nine on the same place.
As you wish.
Hello!
What? Philippe?
This is a nightmare.
Yes, this is all terrible.
But where can we meet?
I'm being followed by two guys.
You have any friends in Paris?
I have a friend.
She lives on St. Jean street.
Give me the phone number.
Seven, two, zero,
two, seven, zero, three.
- Whom I should ask for?
- Valerie. Valerie Agostinelli.
Go there and stay.
I'll try to come tonight.
Wait.
- Valerie, quickly leave the cabine!
- Why? What's wrong?
Go to the bathroom. Anywhere.
Hurry!
I'll come on Sunday.
Did you come to me?
Hello, Nicole?
Anybody called?
Yes.
Tell him, I'll take care
of it after the 15th.
What else?
Commissioner Moreau?
Let him wait in my cabinet.
- Hello, commissioner!
- Monsieur Marechal!
- What can I do for you?
- Oh, a lot!
I was sitting,
while you were not here, and thinking.
About me?
About your actions.
When there's such a important case,
false evidence can cost you dear.
- I don't understand.
- Is that so? And Kebir?
Do you understand that question?
I'm not asking where you've been tonight.
I don't doubt
that you were invited
to a dinner to eat chicken.
But poor Kebir was found dead in a car
that didn't belong to him.
He didn't have his own car.
Can you explain this?
- It's a mystery for me too.
- But you knew him well, didn't you?
- Yes, I did. And you know that.
- Yes, I know.
Now you see?
You know everything!
Not yet.
There's still a lot I have to know.
Me too.
For instance, who killed Philippe.
Then help me.
Tell me what's the connection between you,
deputy Dubaye and you, Mr. Marechal?
- Our past.
- And that's all?
Not so little.
Anyway there are so much strange and
inexplicable coincidences.
Judge for yourself!
Kebir found dead
near the house
in which deputy Dubaye sheltered
a girl but she's not there anymore.
It's not a coincidence,
it's simply a list of facts in the case.
And of course you know
nothing about that girl.
Absolutely.
There she is.
Tomorrow that photo will be published
in all morning newspapers
as a wanted poster.
And something tells me we'll be
not the only ones looking for her.
The thing is who will be faster.
Me or Kebir's murderer?
And it's better for the girl
that I find her first.
Whom are you looking for?
Valerie Agostinelli.
I'm Xavier Marechal.
We were friends with Philippe.
Thanks.
Valerie!
- My name is Leslie. Leslie Collins.
- Nice to meet you.
What a terrible thing happened?!
- Let me introduce you.
- We already made the acquaintance.
- Feel better?
- Yes.
- It was such a shock for Valerie.
- I rushed here like demented.
Dashing aside from everybody.
Even from the police.
You don't need to be afraid of everybody. And
what comes to police, they're looking for you.
Tomorrow in all french newspapers
there will be your photo.
As the saying goes,
of all the rotten luck!
- You have the papers here?
- Yes.
If you feel hungry,
everything's in the refrigerator.
Will you be late?
I don't know, may be,
I'll spend the night in the studio.
- Good-bye!
- Why was Philippe killed?
- Because of this.
And what is it?
Here we have the names of some
very respected citizens.
Anthology of bribery,
directory of corruption.
- And what are you going to do with it?
- Use, but yet don't know how.
First we have make a copy of it.
But you can't go
to a photographer with this.
Can you trust me one more time?
Good! Bravo!
Bravo, Leslie!
Start whirling! Hurry!
Smile! Bravo, Leslie!
Wonderful! Can you do it a little more?
Smile and whirl.
There you go! More! Good!
Bravo! Wonderful!
- Load the camera. Leave the same object glass.
- Ok.
- Allow me, girls. Well?
- Out of focus.
Christoph! Be so kind, 135th.
- Here you go!
- Thanks.
You're welcome.
Attention girls!
We'll continue shooting!
- Ready!
- Not a bad start.
Villiers, the famous prefect, himself, his
wife, son, son-in-law - All bribetakers.
The list is neatly made.
Go on!
This one is more serious!
Helmut Tiller, bribes of millions.
Nuclear power plants, airplanes.
Here Serrano missed.
To get this one, you have to take higher!
Much higher.
Something interesting?
- Philippe?
- Yes.
- What could he have with them in common?
- Politics.
- If the police finds me, what shall I say?
- They mustn't find you Valerie.
Don't leave the house.
If you need me, call me in the office,
at home or in the car.
Phone numbers. Good night.
And thanks.
Good night. See you.
- Taxi! Taxi! Help!
- I'm going to the park.
Taxi! Help!
Help me!
They are chasing me.
The last express train to downtown
leaves in 3 minutes.
I repeat, the last express train
to downtown leaves in 3 minutes.
Hello?! Valerie, what's the matter?
Where are you going, miss, don't leave us!
Some soldiers were passing bye.
I told them that I was being followed
and thought of something.
The glass on the door was broken.
Maybe it had been thieves?
I'm going crazy, but now I'm fine.
Fasten your seat belt.
You just love to kill each other.
Sorry!
I'll take you to a safe place.
That's it. In 5 minutes
you'll be drowned in sleep.
- Do you need pyjamas?
- No thank you!
- Good night!
- There. Have some rest!
- I'm already asleep.
She's sweet and courteous.
You got it wrong.
She was Philippe's girlfriend.
Philippe. What can you do?
Philippe liked only beauties.
And Christiane was beautiful
before she started drinking.
He was a good, but not serious guy.
Paul, let's talk about something else.
For instance, about you.
- When did we see each other last time?
- I think 3 years ago. On Christmas.
You didn't become younger.
Yes, but at least it's not the drunkenness
that ruins my health, no!
Art burns me!
You don't imagine,
how difficult it is to draw for kiddies.
They want to see something new all the time,
something unusual.
Will you still be drawing dogs
and cats in 2000?
Why not?
Michelangelo portrayed
bearded men all his life.
God, Moses, they're all bearded.
You know what I'm going to tell you?
I'll be back to painting someday.
- Like Michelangelo?
- Don't laugh!
I'm absolutely serious. Drawing for
myself like Sezanne and Van Gogh.
I've been thinking about it a lot recently.
I even believe in what I say.
- Perhaps I should enter politics.
- Maybe, well go on, I'm listening.
And on what Philippe tripped?
You know, on in such a position you can
provide services, and in return receive thanks.
However.
Because of that he got killed.
- In gratitude?
- Don't.
Take care.
- Are you angry with me?
- For what?
For Philippe.
I shouldn't blurt.
You were friends,
you knew him better than I did.
Everything's OK Paul.
Xav! Let the girl stay longer
at my place!
At least I'll be seeing you.
Hello? Does Monsieur show up?
Finally!
Are you alive?
I called all night.
I thought you had left me
without saying good-bye.
Sure, that's my style!
Dinner tonight?
I'll call you back. Somebody came.
Don't hang up, if I hear shooting,
then I won't roast your portion.
Very witty!
- Who's there?
- Monsieur Marechal?
- Yes? - Monsieur Fondari sent us,
he has business to discuss with you.
What is the phone for?
Monsieur Fondari is sure that
phones have ears and too many.
I'll talk to him.
- May I come in, Monsieur Marechal?
- No.
Unique sculpture of
How much did I pay? 30 million.
But it's worth 35 in the shop window.
all from the collection of Empress Xu.
- To me it says nothing
- Me neither. But there are consultants.
- And do you know Schliben, the expert?
- No.
I never thought I would fly up so high.
In our family I was the twelfth child.
I started working at baker's when I was 8.
Can you imagine?
When I was 20
I burst into the bank with a gun.
I'm the most honourable client of that bank
now.
I was making my way with fists, and those that
resisted I was sending to the better world.
Whom for instance?
Sorry, I understand much better
with concrete examples.
No,no, no! I didn't kill Serrano!
And my men had nothing to do with that.
- You can believe me.
- And Philippe?
We could buy him.
Why should we kill him?!
Oh, by the way, I don't understand,
what do you want from his mistress?
That girl is celebrity now.
Cops are pissed off.
Where did you hide her?
And who's got the diary now?
The same questions, only a bit earlier,
I was asked by commissioner Moreau.
- But to me, Xav, you have to tell the truth.
- Why is that?
Because I can cause you bigger
trouble that the commissioner.
We'll see.
Look, Xav, I can see you're going
to work for yourself.
And that's dangerous
and very risky.
You're overestimating your opportunities.
You better keep working as an assistant.
- Less money, but life of ease.
- Thanks for the advice.
I'll soon be 50, son.
I'm rich.
Still I depend on people
that can destroy me.
Crush and destroy.
They instructed me to return
Serrano's diary at all costs.
At any cost
But I would not want to spill blood.
Do you have the diary?
Give it to us.
You? Interesting News!
So you're just a minion?
An executive and
obedient assistant.
I don't have the diary,
but if I had it...
- You're playing with fire, Xav!
- Not yet.
First you have to be
instructed by your master.
I won't be long.
Monsieur Marechal has two visitors now.
I'll wait.
- Monsieur Marechal?
- Yes?
- Monsieur Lacor is here.
- Ask him to come to Mr. Dubaye's cabinet.
- Master himself!
- Hello Xav!
- How is Christiane?
- Wonderful.
She's fine, she's holding on.
I'm still her attorney.
Sure.
- How are you?
- I'm fine.
The Dutch contract is signed,
I'll send copies to you and Christiane.
OK.
- Do you have any other affairs with me?
- No.
Oh, I completely forgot.
I brought to you an invitation to the
exhibition.
There! The exhibition is called
"French quality"
Thanks, you're very kind,
but I have a lot to do.
It's important.
Influential people would like to meet with
you.
- We can do that in the office.
- They want to meet you by a chance.
- I'll try, but I can't promise.
- Come, you won't regret.
Oh, by the way.
You may not know that I'm a member of
society.
- That's what it is? What? Salvation army?
- No.
It's an organization like Masonic Lodge.
Members of this society
must help each other.
- And so on. Didn't you understand?
- No, I didn't.
- You just don't want to.
- I'm doing enough listening to you!
Now there can't be any doubts that soon
everything will start swinging in the country.
If we're talking about the same country, then
everything has been swinging in it since Valois.
It's too right!
We have no illusions.
Collectivists can not be allowed to come
closer to the pie.
They'll grab a piece and won't give it back!
Then society must take measures.
Buy weapons, build attendance, transfer
money to Switzerland.
We still have time, but the organization,
preparation,
- establishment of funds.
- Yes.
- Are you their treasurer?
- You guessed correctly.
Leadership appointed me, and I'm very
flattered.
This is surely a sign of confidence.
By the way, if you need it,
I have all the money.
Thanks, but I'm not going to enter into any
society.
- Not my style.
- Think first.
- OK!
- See you in the evening.
I didn't promise anything.
Ok, but I promised them
that you will come.
Don't ever promise on my behalf.
- I might really let you down!
- How?
Between ourselves, Lucien,
do you know what I'd love to do?
No.
Hit you in the face!
Good-bye.
Sorry.
You haven't visit us for
a long time Monsieur Marechal.
- Good afternoon!
Who's here?
A bunch of politicians, several bankers,
clowns, countess, whores.
Overall, french quality,
but fortunately there are some friends.
You know, when I learned about Philippe,
I felt bad.
Thanks. You're very nice.
- Hello, Xav!
- Hello, Armel!
I thought you won't be coming.
I was already going to call you. Shall we go?
I wanted to come long ago, but now
everything's on me.
- Armel!
- Come on in. I'll be right over.
- I won't be coming tomorrow.
- Why?
Excuse me.
One beer, please!
Xav!
Hello, Xav! Nice to see you.
They're waiting for us.
I'll go and tell them you're here.
No need to sprinkle ashes on your head.
- Am I shocking you?
- It's a bad taste.
I don't give a shit what people will say.
Get a grip on yourself.
Don't ask me to act like an inconsolable
widow
of people's elected representative.
- This is what I'm going to say...
- Ok, say it, only quietly.
Sure!
If you ask me, I may say it quietly.
During the life of Philip
I was betrayed wife,
but now, after his death
I'm his widow.
- Alone in both cases.
- And the attorney?
What are you talking about?!
When you don't get what you want,
you take what you can.
If I were rich
would you marry me? Tell me.
- You shouldn't drink.
If I get Serrano's diary,
I'll be rich.
Please, shut up!
- Listen, how much do you want, Xav?
- Christiane! Xav, they're waiting for us.
I'm coming.
Ok
Mr. general manager, let me
introduce you Monsieur Marechal.
- Monsieur Lansac!
- Could you please excuse me?
Take a seat, please, Monsieur Marechal,
very nice to meet you.
We're fellow sufferers.
You lost your friend in Dubaye's person,
and we lost a wonderful colleague.
You'll surely agree with me,
Monsieur Marechal,
that our main aim is
to save his reputation.
The aim is noble,
but by what means?
Nothing complicated! Destroy all the
traces and forget about everything.
Simple solution! However I'm
sure it's not the best way out.
No, no, no, you're surely right,
not only the materials compromising Dubaye
must be destroyed, we're also
obligated to finish the clique of scoundrels.
The thought of the pact which we are
about to make, they are already shaking.
I think it's premature.
I fully share the feelings of Monsieur Lansac,
his desire to save Philippe's reputation,
and to curb the criminal clique.
but, sorry, I don't understand what kind
of role in this campaign I'll be playing.
A very small one, Monsieur Marechal,
nothing special will be demanded from you.
I'm not asking you to give me Serrano's diary.
But perhaps in there is also mentioned...
In that case I would ask you
to give me the pages,
in which the name of
that personality is included.
- And why?
- To show them.
Not to everybody, but only to those
that should see it.
And of course! That personality
won't exist any longer!
He will be discredited!
Scrapped!
I'm asking you!
Please be so kind!
If I had it,
I'd be happy to give it to you.
But Xav.
That firm Sozhoka you're running,
in which Monsieur Lacor is the legal adviser,
would probably like to expand the market.
For instance, have an access
to Luxemburg, Germany.
The same thing that my father
used to call 'milch cow',
is now called European four,
nine, ten...
Possible combinations.
I will not deny that,
even without having your wits,
I'm earning a lot.
And you.
I imagine how much you'll expand.
- How much do you want, Xav?
- Excuse me?
No. I'm sorry. I was talking to myself.
Well, I have to go to present awards.
And you think all to the mustard,
but do it quickly.
There's something that
Lansac didn't tell you.
We need the diary, but the most important thing
is that it shouldn't get into its owner's hands.
What owner?
Serrano's dead.
But his post still remains,
and another person is holding it.
Look, Xav, I wouldn't want
to see you hit by a bus.
I'll try to gain time, I'll tell them
that you and me carry on negotiations.
But after that they won't
stand on ceremony with you.
For now the general manager is willing to
help
Tell him that I was touched
by his concern for my well-being
Good-bye.
Xav, I am getting bored.
Let's go to my place.
Why?
Tell me.
Do you want to know who killed Philippe?
Christiane, I was looking for you.
Excuse me, Xav.
You coming?
Dear friends! Attention!
'The best exhibit' awards
will be presented by general manager,
Monsieur Lansac.
Were you getting instructed by the master?
So what did he say?
- Who?
- General manager.
What were you talking about?
About old-age pension
and future of youth.
You're getting on my nerves.
I don't understand. What's wrong with you?
- You were always with us!
- With Philippe.
- I was his boss.
- But not mine.
- I will be yours too.
- We'll see.
Why are you jibbing so much?
In the most difficult situations
I always covered Philipe.
You know that. And that wasn't easy.
But the rates increased.
Serrano, Philippe, your Algerian.
Who's next?
I warned you.
And now, friends, general manager,
Monsieur Lansac.
You scared me.
You... you could come in like all
decent people do. Ring at the door.
How did you come in?
Why do you keep silent?
You used to be more talkative.
What do you want?
You wanted to scare me?
Well you did! And that's enough!
Take a seat!
Tell me. What do you want from me?
What are you doing?
Can't we safely negotiate with you?
I'm sure there are no issues that can't be
settled.
Keep in mind that I'm expecting someone,
and do you know what happens
if he'll find you here?
Enough! I'm warning you!
It'll cost you dear!
Leave me, I'll scream!
I'll call the police! Help! Help me!
Nothing surprising,
from the 8th floor.
And her husband too recently.
Three pages.
Yes, from Serrano's diary.
Don't take it if you don't want to.
Exceptional case.
So what?
Tomorrow morning, your competitors
will print in their newspapers that...
If you want...
I thought so.
You'll receive the package in 2 hours.
Whom to address?
Dubreuil.
OK, thanks.
- Do you realize what you're doing, Xav?
- I realize what they can do.
Xavier! It's ready. Take a look.
Choose any.
No surprises here,
you know what you're pulling out
Different scales.
Dupere!
Look, Dupere is a moralist!
He spoke out against long hair.
Against abortion and strip,
but not against the arms trade.
Dupere!
- How many copies shall I print?
- Ten.
We'll choose the three most prominent
villains.
You'll destroy them this way.
- And what if these people only...
- Made a mistake?
May be they did wrong?
In that case, your act is very cruel.
- Monstrous.
- And what did they do to Philippe?
And was Philippe better than them?
Without prejudice.
I don't want to be unprejudiced.
it's just an empty word.
Dupere.
One, two, three.
Three into each envelope.
- And why not four?
- Philippe, Christiane, Kebir.
- Is Serrano still alive?
- I have my own count.
Latest news!
Regarding Serrano case!
Last night an unknown person phoned
the editorial offices of the Paris newspapers
and offered three pages from
the notorious diary.
It begs the question of who
the unknown person is?
These pages expose
the improper actions
of famous political figures.
Everyone who saw
Madame Dubaye said that
she was not acting like
an inconsolable widow.
I could understand if she took
an overdose of sleeping pills.
But such a suicide.
It's more like a pretence.
Pretences of that kind are easily
in the spirit of your department.
I don't know where you got such information.
Madame Dubaye left at 12, and
you almost followed hard on her heels.
Coincidence.
That's what you're saying.
Mr. Lacor accompanied Madam Dubaye
to the door of the house.
That's what he says.
So, we have already 2 suspects.
- Well, we can find more.
- But you prefer me?
Yes, it's much easier.
Here I have the testimony of
Maixant Lucien, the headwaiter
I heard Madam Dubaye
telling Monsieur Marechal
"If I get Serrano's diary,
I'll be reach"
You left the club 5 minutes after she did.
You were seen outside her house.
Isn't that enough for you?
I think it will be more than
enough for the investigator.
Excuse me, colleague! I was told
Monsieur Marechal is in your office.
He'll stay at whole allowance.
Only not in your department.
Investigator Fave just signed the
warrant for Mr. Marechal's arrest.
I'm not going to prejudge
the results of the investigation
but I'm still investigating
the Dubaye case.
There are 2 Dubaye cases.
I wonder by what miracle you're going
to separate them from each other?
The investigator won't need
a miracle for that.
His conclusions are based on pure logic.
Deputy Dubaye kills Serrano
and steals the diary.
A few days later
Monsieur Marechal kills Dubaye
and sends part of it to the
newspaper editorial offices.
There!
The investigator apprehends that the
publicity will affect other people.
Perhaps even those who are
above any suspicion.
Murders are investigated in the criminal
police, so this is my merchandise.
Don't you think that now in the eyes of the
authorities'
the main point is not the murder.
There is another aspect of the issue.
Judge for yourself.
Libel, disinformation,
exposing to the detriment of national
interests.
That is, an attempt on the
internal and external safety
My merchandise!
Two departments are fighting for me.
Please come with me to make an arrest.
Nice to see such a primer, such a zeal.
Why did you pull me out of his clutches?
I... Please.
Frankly speaking, I'm very pleased.
So, two departments argue,
and the murderer of Philippe is at large.
You know that I didn't kill him!
I know that better than anyone, because
I am the auhor of the official version.
Dubaye was killed by his mistress,
of course, who is hiding from the police.
Yes, by the way, don't you think
it's time for her to show up?
At least for a time.
- And Christiane Dubaye?
- Despair, hopelessness!
The version of newspapers suits me.
Hello, Mr. Prosecutor.
Yes, Monsieur Marechal's with me.
One moment!
- Hello?!
- Monsieur Marechal? Hello!
There's a person here with me,
who would like to talk to you.
Pass the phone to
commissioner Perne after.
Please.
Monsieur Marechal?
It's Tomski.
I think the moment has come
when we should meet again.
On the day after tomorrow
I'm leaving France.
but before leaving I'll be glad
to have you here at my place.
I am organizing a hunt for my friends
at eight o'clock in the morning.
Lamotte-Beuvron, yes, yes.
Thirty kilometers after Orleans.
I know.
All this is excellent.
But there is one obstacle, I'm under arrest.
Yes.
I'm giving the phone
to the Commissioner.
Prosecutor!
Hello?
Yes, Monsieur Prosecutor!
Yes.
I understand, little courtesy?
I would still like to receive
a written order.
Is investigator Fave aware
of the matter? Ok.
In that case, my compliments,
Monsieur Prosecutor!
I can only wish you good hunting,
Monsieur Marechal.
- Who's that Tomski?
- As you can see, a person of influence.
I rescued you from one wolf,
and they attacked in packs.
The circle closes, and they will do
everything possible to seize the prey.
You're free.
Good-bye.
Xav!
I know that influential people
are looking for contact with you.
My friends are ready to do anything.
Keep in mind, anything,
that your meeting did not take place.
Take note of this.
- Monsieur Lacor!
- Coming!
Calmed down, Monsieur Marechal?
- Hey, Jacques!
- What?
You crushed him great!
Just like they ordered!
I drove slowly, so that
he could not get around me.
Yes, I saw.
Look! Your car!
Take the spike out!
- Holland-Holland?
- Do you like light weapons?
- No.
- Then I'll advise this!
- I don't like weapons.
- But you recognized the brand immediately.
I know many things, but don't like them.
Same with people.
It's worth talking about these things
and people. We'll do it after the hunt.
- So the hunt will be organized?
- Of course.
Please, excuse me.
I'll be back in a moment.
Excuse me.
I didn't tell you anything. Not a word.
Got it?
I didn't think you'll come.
Monsieur Lacor!
You go with Baron de la Frene.
Ok.
Go, and you'll come with me!
Didn't Philippe told you about me?
Well, he told me about you.
He loved you very much.
And you? You love me too?
Or are just going to love?
A bad shot, I guess.
- First trophy.
We should've got him earlier.
I was told what happened to you on the road.
Own telegraph?
Don't worry.
Nothing serious.
We should get him to hospital.
And quickly.
Ok, doc.
- Is it serious?
- Charge fractions in the lumbar region.
I see.
If the kidneys are damaged,
then there's only one outcome.
Doctor says it's nothing.
Everything will be fine, buddy.
Well, of course everything will be fine.
Monsieur Marechal, it's time to go back.
Since the sporting part is over,
let's start, dear Monsieur Marechal,
the next phase,
more constructive.
Now then, although you will not
find my name on any piece of paper,
the dairy you possess -
is my property!
Or, if you want,
I am responsible for it
to certain people.
Since the political climate now is very
unfavorable,
your exposure can only harm
the interests of the country.
- You don't have to worry about my country.
- Certainly.
About the others too, though.
But as long as the power has not been
captured by the Internationale of workers,
it entirely belongs to the
Internationale of bankers.
And it has its own laws, the new ones.
Words as "enemies" or "allies"
have lost their significance.
There are no friends,
only partners.
Suppliers appeared instead of enemies.
Capital does not recognize any borders.
Corruption doesn't either, I think.
That's why posting Serrano's diary would not
help.
I'll have to resign.
Two, three political clowns will be replaced.
You will go to jail!
But essentially nothing will change.
Still the public opinion should not be
discounted.
Did Lockheed's fraud change anything?
And Nixon's case?
No, there was not a question of money,
but morality.
So, morality exists?
Well, it'll remain the scandal
of the century, Monsieur Marechal.
Your honesty is old-fashioned.
Now that product is not in demand.
I remember, your great head of the
state once called us "calves".
Should the calf get upset,
because some bureaucrat
or a minister has quickly become rich?
Don't you think that this may affect
the overall economic system?
The main thing is to produce as much as
possible.
Well and calves must be given
food, swill, and entertainment.
That is all they need.
And then peace and quiet will prevail in the
country.
- Come in.
- Gentlemen are here.
Ask them to come in.
- Hello!
- Monsieur minister!
Let me introduce you to Monsieur Marechal,
the perpetrator of the recent scandal.
It's a dirty slander!
There isn't a single word of truth in here.
Why don't you sue, Monsieur minister?
Journalists are all venal creatures.
You have to buy all of them.
Or invite to hunt.
Ok, we'll buy the diary! How much?
I think Monsieur Marechal's
compliancy costs 2 million.
- We'll discuss it.
- No need.
Do you have any requests, Monsieur
Marechal?
Only the name of Philippe's murderer.
If I knew it, I wouldn't tell you anyway.
- But I don't know who the murderer is.
- He has gone mad about it.
Don't you think that such condition
only leads to a dead end.
It's only a precondition.
Stop bulling!
We don't give a shit about Philippe.
- Whoever killed him...
- Your mission is over,
since Monsieur Fondari's mission
is about to begin.
I'm really sorry,
you didn't listen to me.
- I'll stay.
- No.
I want to see him writhing with pain.
No! I'm starting to believe in
what newspapers write about you.
You are a worm, Monsieur minister!
A pathetic worm.
You've chosen an uneasy way,
Monsieur Marechal.
I'm really sorry.
- Did you book Amsterdam?
- Oh, I forgot about you, Monsieur Fondari!
I'll order to contact Amsterdam.
Now you got yourself into a mess!
I warned you!
But you preferred to rebel.
You could become a rich man.
You would be flush with money!
I told you - always keep me informed!
- But no, you imagined yourself a sheriff.
- I'm looking for a man who shot Philippe.
He won't get away from me.
Cops think you killed him. So do I.
It doesn't matter what you think at all.
Marseilles!
Give this man an injection.
It's pentabarbital of sodium.
Nazis used them to refresh the brain,
affects memory better than fish.
Could you please roll up your sleeve?
Hey! Come on, wake up, son!
Hurry! Guests have arrived!
With your face I would have become a pimp.
Monsieur Marechal,
you're under arrest!
Durieux!
You are accused of embezzlement,
perjury
as well as complicity
in the murder of Serrano.
Take him away!
Monsieur Fondari, I'll be waiting
for you tomorrow in the department.
You still live there?
Yes, and my phone number is still Louvre
26-33, but I doubt the prosecutor will call me.
He caught a cold.
You should know that
in the upper atmosphere
temperature is drastically reduced.
By the way,
grab a blanket and clean linen.
Just in case.
This is the place!
Durieux! Take that car.
See you at the office.
Ok.
If there wasn't a woman by your side,
your perfect alibi wouldn't help you.
She helped you out.
- Thanks.
- I had to tell them the whole thing.
- You had such a long talk?
- No, we had a long typing on a typewriter.
Do you accuse me?
Did you find out who's behind all this?
Nobody.
Politicians, dealers, lobbyists...
Firms, passing from one hand to another.
No specific person.
There are mediators like Tomski.
Apprentices like Fondari.
Clowns like Dupere.
Assistants...
- ... like Dubaye?
- Serrano.
I'm not interested either in Dubaye
or Serrano.
I'm only interested in the diary.
Not to burry it, on the contrary,
to put up for show!
I will report about everything
straight to the Minister of Justice.
- Straight to the Minister?
- Yes, Monsieur Marechal.
I've always acted according to my conscience
and worked with honest people.
Well, and if you're right,
I'll collect my pension earlier
and go fishing.
Frankly, I can't wait.
Give him the diary!
Those people will kill you.
We'll see.
She speaks like everyone else:
'those people'. And who are they?
I will not rest until I find the name
of the person who killed Phillippe.
I'm not taking vengeance, Valerie.
I'm just being faithful.
Look out!
Who killed Philippe?
- Who killed Philippe?
- Leave it.
- I might die!
- Sure, but first you'll suffer.
I promise.
Think what you're doing to me.
I have a bullet in my knee, I'm bleeding.
No!
Let him answer for his deeds.
You can kill him!
I'll tell you everything.
It was done by... it was done by...
It's impossible! The Commissioner can't
disappear, leaving 4 corpses!
- If he had been kidnapped, they would call here.
- Urgent call!
- Yes, Report on the job.
- Hurry! From the city...
Hello! Hello! Yes!
Who's speaking?
Oh, I see?
That's interesting.
And where I can find you?
Yes, yes, alone.
- Where to?
- Defense subway station.
- Why did you make up your mind?
- I'm afraid.
Fear is a good adviser.
- So, can I consider it as a present?
- I don't make presents. Diary for name.
- Whose?
- Philippe's murderer.
I don't know the name.
Well, commissioner!
People forget their wives,
mothers, phone numbers,
but it's impossible for a man
to forget his own name.
Adrien Moreau.
The commissioner of the criminal police.
- Commissioner - by day, a criminal - at night.
- I have never heard such nonsense.
No, it's not nonsense.
I understood everything after
the attack on Perne.
Since Fondari was shooting at the commissioner,
then he was sure, he'll be covered.
And only a cop could cover him.
There are 2 cops in this case:
you and Perne.
That attack excludes Perne.
So, everything's clear.
Fondari was always a fool.
Perne and Fondari are two poles of stupidity.
Donkey and Pithecanthropus.
Fondari's law violated for twenty years.
But Perne is more dangerous, since in his
case stupidity acts in the name of the state.
- And Fondari works for himself.
- You too, I presume.
You think so?
I work for the common good.
I have information about entire Paris.
- I say hello to dregs, I go to see them.
- And kill them.
I can't stand scoundrels, Marechal.
Because of them this country dies.
Dregs in France make statements
from the stands.
they control newspapers,
fund elections.
Their proteges extract them with
new markets, new areas of influence.
This is today's elite.
Tomorrow their sons will become aristocrats!
Era of scoundrels.
With the grace of God, but with the help of
that diary, I'll nip that filth in the bud.
We share a common goal.
When I kill Dubaye,
and you blow Dupere,
we both bleach our society!
- And Christiane Dubaye?
- She drank too much.
And talked too much.
She wanted to tell you the whole thing.
But we are soul mates!
We want to liberate the country
from a malignant tumor.
Do you understand that this is a historic
moment?
We have become significant people,
Monsieur Marechal.
Robespierre and Saint Just
felt the same excitement.
- Psychiatrists will find it out in court.
- What court?
Yours. They would surely say that
you are obsessed, paranoid.
But they won't say the word describing
who you really are,
because that word is not accepted
in the jurisprudence.
The word is 'fool', Moreau!
But don't get upset!
You're not the first.
History has already known Savonarola,
Fouquier de Tinville.
Over-ordering is not less
dangerous than chaos.
I hate corruption
as much as your morals.
Just listen to yourself!
I can't stand scoundrels, Marechal.
Because of them this country dies.
Dregs in France make statements
from the stands.
And everybody for Philippe Dubaye.
You are saving a whole gang
of villains to avenge a fop.
Surrender Moreau!
The station is surrounded!
Moreau!
- Thank you, thank you and bravo!
- I didn't want that to happen.
Senior Commissioner Moreau
was a fierce humanist,
but also a wonderful cop.
"Competent",-as Fondari said,
another humanist.
What will happen to it?
One copy goes to the investigator,
the second one, to the Minister of Justice.
I presume Philippe Dubaye
isn't mentioned there.
Of course not.
Why should he?
Take this!
And goodbye, commissioner.
- And what will be the end of all this?
- Nothing.
If commissioner Perne is an honest man,
he'll retire and go fishing.
If he's not,
he'll become the Prefect of Police.
Some of the people's representatives
will stay on their toes, but not for long.
I assure you, time will pass
and they will have
new masks of honest Republicans.
Like old women,
who tighten the skin on their faces.
No!
No, it's only the fish that should
tremble for it's life.
Sleep soundly, Parisians.
All is well.
Subtitled by Sado and Rafayeal
for Cinematik June 2010