DEATH IN A FRENCH GARDEN
Excuse me. Are you David Aurphet?
Yes, I am.
I was worried I was late.
Julia Tombsthay.
My husband and daughter are here,
anyway. My new neighbour.
I'm Edwige Ledieu.
I moved in this morning.
- Let's introduce ourselves right away.
- Good idea.
- Julia Tombsthay.
- Mr Tombsthay?
No, Mr Aurphet is my daughter's
guitar teacher.
- Excuse me.
- The future teacher...
- Are you happy with your moving men?
- Very much.
Well, see you soon. Delighted.
Goodbye.
Who knows?
Are you coming?
You wouldn't think you're in the city.
No, you'd think you were in a garden.
My new neighbour's house.
I think my husband's waiting for us.
We were pleased when we learnt
that you were available.
Isn't that true, Graham?
After what we heard, my husband
wouldn't have any other teacher.
- By the way, where is she?
- Reading in my office at the moment.
I'm coming.
Viviane, my daughter. Mr David Aurphet.
- Hello, Miss Tombsthay.
- Hello.
You're able to earn a living
by teaching guitar?
No. I'm also a French teacher...
principally.
But this year, I gave up French...
Will three times a week be all right?
That's perhaps a little... That's fine.
- At your house, or here?
- I prefer that it be here.
As do l.
Here.
Do you want to see my guitar?
I warn you, it's pretty worthless.
Well, in that case...
I propose that we buy Viviane
a much better instrument.
- It will motivate her.
- When? Tomorrow?
If you want. Will you help us,
Mr Aurphet?
- Happily.
- Tomorrow, at eleven?
At the Oiseau-Lyre.
- What are you doing?
- I'm seeing you out.
Sorry, I mean, my factory makes
instruments for measuring vibrations.
All kinds of vibration.
I think they liked you.
But we didn't discuss your fee.
- 1 00... 1 50 francs per lesson.
- Perfect. See you soon.
Goodbye, sir...
- What did I lose?
- This.
Thank you.
I look like I've rushed over,
but don't believe it.
I didn't find your tuning fork
right away.
Where was it?
On the couch. It had slipped...
I hesitated before calling you,
then coming, then I changed...
I hesitated about that, too.
How do I look?
- Fine.
- Good. All right, then, I'll...
- Sit down.
-..sit. Where?
There.
All right, I repeat:
I sit down on the bed.
- You're playing this at the moment?
- Yes. Brahms.
- We're listening to it?
- No.
- It's pretty.
- What we're listening to? Yes.
I think my husband liked you a lot.
- Does the stove work?
- Yes.
But you have to wear a gas mask.
It smokes up the room.
Can I offer you a coffee,
or plum brandy? I don't have much.
I'd like that.
- Some brandy?
- Yes.
I like your place.
- A pity. I'm moving in five days.
- Why?
A habit.
Shall we organise a date now,
or wait till you have an address?
Thank you.
It's a small place, all alone in a park,
surrounded by other houses...
- So it's not alone, then.
- Yes. The others have been demolished.
One day, your place
will also be demolished.
Yes.
- You'll move again.
- Yes.
As for the next meetings,
we'll wait a little.
- You have a pretty ring.
- Yes.
Know why you're so desirable
at the moment?
Yes... No.
Because you're not trying to be.
I'll be on my way.
Watch your head!
Hi, Dad.
- What?
- That's right, your mother's returning.
- You're pleased?
- Yes.
But I'll need time to get used to it.
- When will she be here?
- In a couple of weeks.
Frankly, I never knew what she saw
in that Swiss.
- And your bomb, it's coming along?
- It's coming along.
What are you up to at the moment?
Stuffing myself like a pig,
then buying a guitar.
- For yourself?
- No, for the young woman.
Perhaps that one will do?
Which would you choose for yourself?
If price weren't an issue, this one.
So be it, darling.
Now I know how much it costs
to make you more agreeable.
Thank you. See you tomorrow.
- I don't like that boy.
- Nor do l.
- Can we see each other this afternoon?
- I'd like that.
- At the same time?
- Yes.
I'm parked down there.
- Is that her boyfriend?
- I don't know. Probably.
Does your husband not care, too?
He spoke to me about you again.
He'd like to hear you play.
I didn't tell you last night,
but I think you're beautiful.
See you soon. I can't wait.
- Hello.
- Things are going well...
- Well.
-..with the moving?
- Yes.
I've just got to hang a few things
on the wall.
- Photos?
- Amongst other things.
Can l... offer you a drink?
I... Why not?
You've been teaching guitar
to my neighbour's daughter for long?
No, tomorrow will be the first time.
You've always lived here,
or are you from somewhere else?
No, I've always lived here.
With my mother.
She died three weeks ago.
Three weeks only.
You had a look at her cleavage?
Ah... yes. Daring.
Plunging! You could count the hairs
on her pussy. Did you count?
- I didn't look that far down.
- Really?
Miss! There's a little fly
in the gentleman's drink.
- I don't see a fly.
- David, you swallowed the fly!
- Seventeen.
- That's all?
I didn't have much time.
Have you noticed how blondes' pussies
differ from those of brunettes?
Quite different. You can't see anything
with brunettes.
I'm a brunette, as I hope you've
noticed... You can't see anything.
It's hidden, buried away,
in the thick hair.
A brunette's pussy is mysterious.
And therefore, very exciting. No? Yes.
With blondes... Do you want me
to call the waitress back?
..you really get to see the pussy.
A blonde's covering is so fair,
so fine... It's transparent.
- Therefore, more immodest, no?
- Yes.
No. It's more innocent.
It reminds one of little girls' pussies.
- And a redhead's pussy?
- I've never seen one.
- But I'm still young!
- Me, too.
Where's my cane? There it is.
I've got to get home. Thank you.
Why do you stay with your husband?
Because I love him.
And him?
He loves me, too.
No.
No, maybe he hates me.
I don't know.
I don't know him very well.
- You hate him, too.
- I don't know.
You don't know yourself very well.
What does this drawing mean?
A magic sign.
It "bolsters" the pillow.
Do you get it?
Yes... Yes, I do.
I had a drink with your neighbour
this morning.
At her house?
No, in town.
And...?
She's a good talker.
That's all?
I wonder if she saw us say goodbye
in front of the shop...
Obviously she saw us.
You don't know me very well.
Hello, I'm just leaving.
I hope you will be pleased with Viviane.
I'll try to do my best.
Before I go: my wife and l
would like you to come for dinner.
- Next Monday?
- Perfect.
Julia will tell you more.
I leave him to you.
See you later, Mr Aurphet.
Come. She's in her room.
- He loves you, it's obvious.
- I hate you.
Can I keep calling you "Mrs"?
It's more arousing.
I might not be free tomorrow.
See you later. Work hard.
I like your home. It feels
like one is elsewhere.
- Yes, but one really is here.
- That's its charm.
It's good. Perhaps the right hand
should be more... flexible.
Did my mother tell you
that I sleep with everyone?
- No, why would she?
- And if it were true?
That's no one's business but your own.
My mother likes you.
And when she likes someone...
That's no one's business but my own.
- Yes. Goodbye.
- Till Friday.
What a pleasant surprise.
You've bought some records?
Can I have a look?
I can tape a few records
for you if you want.
- Rare ones.
- I bought this, as well.
- Can l...
-..offer you a drink? I...
..won't say no.
The street side... The Tombsthay side.
- Those are your photos?
- Guess.
- Yours.
- Or not.
- Some coffee?
- No.
I would. I'll bring you an orange juice.
I'd prefer a cognac.
Put on a record, you choose.
Then go for a look around the house.
Back soon.
Know what I was thinking to myself?
I have a "nice backside", as they say,
"a cute arse", as they also say...
Mine's not too bad...
Can I touch it?
Excuse me?
Do you think I'm a melon?
"Can I touch it?"
We're not at the Montelimar market,
my friend.
Cavaillon. Montelimar is for nougat.
- What's Cambrai, then?
- Near to Waterloo.
Exactly, the Berezina.
We'll say no more about it.
Did you know my esteemed neighbour
Graham Tombsthay is wooing me?
- That's not true.
- Quite right. In fact, it's not true.
How could it be possible,
I've only known him for two days.
Between us, in two days,
obviously not...
Sometimes I say pointless things
as well!
Could you turn that lamp on
over there?
If you want to go and look
out the window, do it!
The Tombsthay side...
The street side.
You like night-time? For you,
how does it differ from the day?
It's like... day and night!
- There are no children out at night.
- Or buses.
Do you know these lines:
"The time of day
when the children roam the streets...
"The time of day when...
beautiful women run around."
- Yes, it's by me.
- Only half of it.
Do you know who that woman is?
A whore.
Do you like whores?
I saw her one night
behind the Prefecture,
in the shadow of a street light.
The street light was broken.
- And then?
- Oh, another time...
I... find you very elegant this evening.
Me, too. You're going to be late.
And my mother's waiting for me!
Put your hands flat. Your wallet?
In my back pocket.
- Are you hurt?
- No, just a clumsy kick.
- I can call a doctor.
- lt'll be all right.
Thanks for helping out.
That lout stole my wallet.
- Are you all right?
- I'm fine.
- Can I offer you a drink?
- I'd like that.
- I don't want to inconvenience you.
- Not at all.
- It doesn't hurt any more?
- It's gone.
One moment, I'll just go
put some water...
Let me have a look.
- He had powerful hands.
- Not too bad. You'll have a bruise.
Sit down.
- Will you file a report?
- I don't know. Maybe for my lD papers.
- Could you see the guy?
- Not very well. He wasn't young.
- Were you scared?
- Yes, a little.
I think I've seen you before.
Two days ago and yesterday, in a car.
- You have a grey Rover, don't you?
- Yes.
I've got a job here in the city
which leaves me a lot of free time.
If you weren't there,
he would have knocked me out.
I don't think he would
have knocked you out.
If he'd wanted to, he'd have done it
straight away and then robbed you.
- But he...
- He was aiming for your hand, not head.
But why?
- You're a musician? A guitarist?
- Yes.
If he'd struck you with this,
he would have smashed your hand.
- You do it for a living?
- Yes. And the wallet...?
To lead you off the track.
Just imagine...
The first idea
that comes to mind...
- A jealous husband...
- I don't know any of those.
I said, just imagine.
- Can I ask your name?
- Daniel Forest. And yours?
David Aurphet. You're very clever
in your deductions.
My professional training, I suppose.
- What do you do?
- You wouldn't believe me.
- You'll think I'm crazy.
- Tell me anyway.
My job is to get rid of people.
You... You're a killer?
An ugly word... but yes.
If it's true, I don't think you would
have told me. Not so quickly.
You're mistaken. One makes this kind
of admission without thinking.
Because the desire to do so
is too strong.
And you have... a job to do
in this city?
Yes.
Excuse me. I felt
a sudden need to talk...
- You've killed before?
- Yes.
I'll leave you.
You're not worried that I'll report you?
I know when I can trust people.
I'm never wrong.
Be careful.
Here's my telephone number.
Feel free to call me.
Even for no reason...
I'd be pleased to see you again.
You're thinking that it's dangerous
to know a killer?
I assure you that it's not.
If you lie to me,
I'll rip your head off!
My downstairs neighbours.
- Goodbye. Thank you, again.
- You're welcome.
- See you again, maybe.
- Maybe.
I love you.
My hands love you...
My legs love you...
My stomach loves you...
My mouth loves you...
My eyes love you...
We love you so much.
And you?
- I don't care much for myself...
- Come now!
..except when I love you.
- I was frightened!
- Of me?
I always hear it a little early...
No, not at all. Tomorrow evening.
We'll do that. Eight o'clock. Till...
The man who saved you yesterday,
- that was him on the phone?
- Yes.
He invited me to dinner tomorrow night.
- At his house?
- No.
You don't think it odd that he happened
to be there when you were attacked?
And would your husband be capable
of sending someone to smash my hand?
Yes. He can become quite violent.
- But with you... No, I doubt it.
- Why?
- He would have told me.
- Are you sure?
No, not totally.
I'm getting old, it's a drama.
Not a tragedy, a drama.
See you.
I won't be home later.
Be good with Viviane.
- She's a beautiful girl.
- Very.
- Very good?
- Very beautiful.
I'm going to the country with friends.
I'll miss Monday's lesson.
That works out well, I'll be moving.
- Can I ask you something?
- Of course.
I'd like to film your fingers
while you play.
So I can study the position
of the fingers.
- Goodbye.
- Is it nice, where you live?
Yes. A house in the trees.
- You'll be living alone?
- Yes.
Goodbye.
I didn't want to leave.
Am I disturbing you?
No, I've almost finished.
A friend is coming to pick me up,
but a bit later.
- My piece?
- Yes.
Want some coffee?
I was just making some.
No, thank you.
A piece of Gruyere, some plum brandy...?
That's right, I've got no more...
A frozen mushroom, ham
and cheese pancake?
No, nothing at all, thank you.
Does the stove work?
No. That's the reason I'm moving.
You have a pretty ring.
Yes. It came from my mother.
- Do you know this house?
- No.
Could you call me a taxi?
Thank you.
One of my pupils.
Why did I tell you that?
Yes, why did you tell me that?
Shall we go?
I have to change first.
It's Saturday, the restaurants
will be full. We'll go to my place.
- That's not a problem?
- No.
Nice furnished apartment you have.
SOLD TO G. TOMBSTHAY
80,000 F
Your pupil, the one before.
I think I've seen her before.
- I wonder...
- No need to wonder.
I was when you were walking
in her neighbourhood.
Don't think I've been
up to anything with her,
and that her father sent a hand-smasher
so I could no longer teach her.
I'm not thinking anything.
It's you doing the thinking...
Why did you smile a few days ago
when you looked at my neck?
Smile? I don't remember...
Ah, yes! But I shouldn't...
I told you that you'd have a bruise.
Getting a bruise from a bruiser.
You don't think that's funny?
Yes, it is.
It's good to laugh a bit.
- Why? Your job isn't fun?
- Sometimes.
- Does it take long... a contract?
- Yes.
I don't gun people down on the street
two hours after receiving the order.
I'm... meticulous.
And expensive.
- You're pulling my leg.
- I promise you, I'm not.
What do you have to do here, exactly?
Kill a man and steal an item from him.
An item.
- In which is hidden...
-..microfilm, no doubt!
Yes.
If you don't believe me,
stop asking questions.
It's true, this is like
an interrogation.
What was the guy like?
Normal? Suspicious? Sinister?
No, not sinister. OK, he had...
A head like a spoon?
Like a small spoon?
Or like a big spoon?
Or was his head always shaded?
OK, a... shady... Iook, very well,
but not si... nis... ter.
So what's on these microfilms?
I don't know, and I don't want to know.
Sometimes diplomatic secrets,
sometimes scientific secrets,
or industrial secrets.
In this case, probably industrial.
I don't know what to think of you.
Don't think anything.
It doesn't affect you, killing people?
Do you really want to discuss it?
How did it begin?
Very simply.
You meet someone who knows someone.
That lasts for two years, and after that
you meet someone
who suggests introducing you
to someone
who could offer you
something interesting.
- How old are you?
- Forty.
- You've never been married?
- Never. And you?
Thank you.
Good luck with the move.
Call me if you want, I'd like that.
- Hello? Edwige Ledieu?
- Here I am.
- Thanks for letting me come so soon.
- What's that, a porno?
I don't know. An anonymous gift...
Push this button here.
I'll leave you.
- I received...
- Me, too.
I've been trying to call you.
- Is it your husband?
- I don't know.
I'm calling from your neighbour's.
- Are you having a change of heart?
- No.
- Are you alone?
- Yes.
Can you come out onto the terrace?
Your dinner tonight, should I come,
or find an excuse?
- You must come!
- Are you enjoying this?
- And you?
- No.
- Did my neighbour watch the video tape?
- No. You'd like her to see you...
..naked, making love to you? I'd have
liked that. See you this evening!
Can I come back in? I'm waiting...
Me too. Don't forget the drinks,
I'm thirsty.
- So then, the video tape?
- I imagine you heard everything.
Not at all, I heard a click
and thought that you'd hung up.
It was the other one,
but don't tell me who it was!
Come on, don't sulk, tell me the story.
- It was indeed a porno.
- Will you show me?
Someone took it upon themselves
to film my... most private life.
- You, by yourself?
- No, there was someone else.
Let me guess. A married woman?
- Yes.
- The old story.
- Either it's the husband...
-..or it's not the husband.
No, I mean, some headcase.
They do exist!
I even met one recently...
Bring him over here!
Or else... it's you.
No, excuse me, l...
No need to excuse yourself, it is me.
I like to have fun.
- Are you serious?
- Are you?
- I don't know.
- Nor do l, then.
- Speaking of tapes, you promised...
- Sorry.
You haven't had the time?
No. I think that... I'm a little drunk.
And a little crazy.
But I don't care. Now go.
I'm just here for the lesson.
I'm moving in with some friends.
- You'll be able to go there?
- Yes.
Don't worry, my parents
will keep paying you.
I'm not worried at all.
- I'm sorry. Are you mad at me?
- No.
And if I don't join you tonight,
you won't be mad?
No.
A great car, but the fifth gear
seems a bit far away.
A bit far, yes. You've got to get
on all fours on the passenger side,
dust yourself off, take your seat again
and thank God if there's no bend.
Excuse me.
I think he likes you very much.
Come through here, it's better.
It doesn't seem like
he's received the tape.
Don't trust the way he looks.
I hope you will agree to play
something for us.
Sorry, I didn't bring my guitar,
and I think that Viviane took hers.
By the way, did you see,
she brought out the VCR.
We gave her a VCR and a video camera.
They amused her for a week...
Have you seen
what beautiful hands he has?
You have to watch out
for your hands with your job?
Yes, one imagines things...
At least a guitar is less dangerous
than a car or motorbike!
By the way... I keep on saying
"by the way" this evening!
I had an accident today,
a very minor one.
I had stopped at the lights,
and someone ran into me from behind.
The guy, or should I say road hog,
clearly under the influence
of a few drinks, got out,
went to the back of his own car
and called out to me,
"It's all right, there's no damage!"
You should be careful, my darling...
You've had a tiring day.
Look how much David resembles
your younger brother.
Excuse us.
What were we talking about?
Oh, yes, accidents...
Thanks for coming here so late.
I've looked around the house,
I didn't see anything.
I didn't hear you.
- You don't look too good.
- I drank too much today.
OK, I'll ask you the question again:
does anyone have any reason
to hold a grudge against you?
Tell me everything. From the beginning.
- Do you want some coffee?
- Yes, with lots of sugar.
Is there any more?
Stories about jealous husbands
are commonplace,
but they can be dangerous.
Don't forget, people are crazy.
Sorry to have bothered you,
but I panicked.
I'm afraid. In this house
which doesn't lock, or so badly...
- I can stay here tonight.
- Yes? You don't mind?
Not at all.
I was just thinking about it.
It would be best if you didn't see
that woman for the next few days.
Or her daughter, or anybody.
You, if need be...
- Do you still go walking in the park?
- Yes, I went yesterday. Why?
This Mrs Tombsthay, could she have...
- The attack?
- For instance...
The video?
Naturally I'd thought about it
I think she fell into your arms
a bit too quickly.
I think that you're under my feet
a bit too much.
Really? You think that?
I'm sorry.
I've already made a fool of myself today
with the Tombsthay's neighbour.
I straight out asked her
if she sent the tape.
- What did she say?
- She said she had.
Do you feel unwell?
Sorry. This happens
every now and then.
When I arrived in this city,
I remember thinking
that I would die here.
What does that feel like?
It depends. It changes...
I don't have any pyjamas to lend you.
It doesn't matter.
Good night.
- How are you?
- Fine. Have you seen this wind?
- You know what woke me?
- The wind!
No, the smell of the toast.
It's like the smell of coffee.
- Perhaps it was the smell of coffee.
- No, the coffee smell doesn't wake me.
Have you sorted out your lD papers?
No, not yet. It's nice
not being anyone.
- It would be better to be someone else.
- Who?
- And how?
- And why?
I suppose you often change.
Change identities, I mean.
Sometimes.
The police!
- I came...
- Blew in!
..to see your house, and invite you
to come over this evening!
No, no more meals at your house!
Graham is going away
for three days this afternoon.
Did you know my dear husband
had a boyfriend some years ago?
More than one, perhaps...
It smells nice here.
Will you show me around?
Would you like a tour?
No, since you're busy.
Will you come?
Is that all the effect I have on you?
You pulse hasn't quickened at all!
You know I'm more of a night person...
- See you tonight.
- Not at your place, I don't like it.
But we must. It's much
more interesting at my place.
David, I'm off, but before I leave,
let me say something:
beware of Graham Tombsthay.
- He's about to go on a trip.
- That doesn't change anything.
Believe me, you should stop
seeing that woman for a while.
Daniel, thanks for everything.
You've been very kind...
Graham Tombsthay is the man
I have to eliminate.
- And then steal...
- Steal what?
- What is this microfilm thing?
- A small antique globe.
- You're going to kill him?
- Yes.
- What...
-..an embarrassing...
-..situation.
- Yes.
If you're uneasy,
come and stay at my place tonight.
You know, the people to be eliminated
are often dangerous.
I'm seeing Julia Tombsthay tonight.
At her place.
Don't worry, I'll be careful.
I brought a gun last night, just
in case. I'll leave it, if you want.
It's small and ugly,
but efficient and silent.
It will do much better
than a kitchen knife.
It's loaded. That's the safety catch.
- OK, thanks. What about you?
- I have another one. Much larger.
- Hello?
- It's me.
- Hi, Dad.
- It's ready.
- What's ready?
- It's a surprise. Hurry over.
OK, then, I'm coming over.
- So, then?
- You took your time.
Come on, let's go down to the cellar.
Here it is. I've finished.
It's wonderful.
- What's it good for?
- Nothing. But it proves I could do it.
So the company was wrong to fire me.
Hooray! You'll be the first
to win a prize for early retirement!
Look, it's so simple.
You set the timer on the dial,
one minute, five minutes,
press here and goodbye!
Imagine, if you were to set this off
under a horse, for example,
there'd be no more horse.
The teeth, hooves, horns...
Wait, horses don't have horns...
The skin, the bones... all gone.
Pulverised.
A thimble full of ash.
If I gave that to you, would you ask me:
"ls that a horse?"
No, but what did the horse do to you?
Viviane shouldn't be long.
Not only does she have the cheek
to disturb you outside of the lessons,
- but on top of that, she's late!
- It doesn't really matter.
What a day! I was supposed
to catch a plane
but at the last minute it was cancelled.
Some minor technical fault. Come in.
Where is Julia?
Mrs Tombsthay is in her room,
or elsewhere. Who knows?
She's so strange, and lies so well.
You as well, let it be said in passing.
But it's time for me to end this game.
Again, in passing, I congratulate you
on your acting skill!
Although now, cameras run on batteries.
- Before, they were spring-loaded.
- Quite right!
Did you think, my pretty sir,
that I'd let you fuck my wife
with impunity?
On your knees. On your knees!
I'm going to kill you, my handsome.
If you only knew how much I'll enjoy it!
It's all been worked out.
Failed robbery, attack, self-defence.
If need be, a "crime of passion".
Are you afraid?
I bid you farewell, seducer!
Someone is going to kill you!
Steal your globe and kill you!
Well done! You've won a moment's
reprieve. Tell me what you mean...
- What's going on?
- I've killed Graham...
What?
Two bullets...
You'd better get rid of this.
Or return it to your friend.
It's his, isn't it?
Don't touch anything! Come with me.
I'm calling the police.
But first, we've got to make it look
like a robbery...
You like it?
Take it, I'll say it was stolen.
- It's beautiful. It must be expensive.
- lndeed.
It's exactly what would be stolen.
Do you know its true value?
Better than you think.
It meant a lot to Graham.
You're not able to?
Now, leave.
I suddenly feel so good!
You wouldn't understand.
We can't meet for a while.
It's too dangerous.
We mustn't call each other, either.
But how will I know about you?
If you don't hear anything,
everything's fine. If not...
I'll find a way of warning you.
Come on, go!
And take care of yourself.
Come in! Good morning! I'm coming!
That's how it is. My eyes hurt today.
That said, don't take anything
I say too seriously!
I found it! It was in the kitchen.
You look rather strange.
Is something wrong?
My neighbour's death? Did you hear?
But of course, you knew him.
There's not enough salt.
Such a to-do since this morning!
The police questioned me.
I saw nothing! I dined out
and got home at three.
I knew you'd be interested.
That's why I called you,
not just to thank you for the tapes.
I also wanted to show you
my recent photos...
Nothing amazing, but I like them.
It's only a selection, of course.
What I like in this one is that
Mrs Tombsthay seems different.
You might say lost, distraught.
It suits her.
It makes you want to take her
in your arms, no?
And look, her husband.
I didn't really like him much.
He seems happy. But you can't see
what he's looking at.
A snake, perhaps, or his daughter...
No, it wasn't the same day.
Viviane, isn't it?
The name doesn't suit her.
But then again, I'm called Edwige...
The teacher and his pupil.
Did you know that whenever you go
in or out of my neighbours',
you always glance in my direction?
It's very flattering.
The girl has regained
her airs and graces.
What was I saying?
But you never saw me.
Am I mistaken? No, I'm not mistaken.
That's the most recent. One hesitates,
wonders... but doesn't ring.
You did the right thing, I wouldn't
have answered. I was busy.
Finally this one,
taken from further away.
I kept it because it's the first photo
I took of you.
A moment later you led me
to that sordid bar
with that hussy of a waitress.
I was so embarrassed.
That's it. I hope you've had
a pleasant time.
We'll keep the sound of your voice
for next time.
You were right to warn me.
Have you seen the newspapers?
Come.
Do you know who we suspect?
Tombsthay's wife.
And you can bet the globe's gone.
You came here to tell me that?
I'm afraid for you,
and I want to help you.
It makes no sense! If Julia wanted
to kill him, why invite me over?
How would you know? Perhaps you're part
of the plan without knowing.
Piss off. Leave me alone.
I was afraid for you.
What did you do with my pistol?
I hid it in the power
meter cupboard. Bye.
Bye. It was a pleasure knowing you.
- What's happening?
- Viviane's been kidnapped.
You know what ransom they're asking for?
The globe.
How did you guess?
You kept insisting that I take it...
I seem to recall you
being very interested in it.
- Was it a man who called you?
- Yes.
What was his voice like?
Like yours.
You seem to be keeping
bad company at the moment.
Yes.
Go away.
Go home. I'll go and get the globe.
Don't worry, she's alive.
- Seducing minors, now...
- Yes, that's it.
We can't leave her there.
I'll explain first. Then your sarcasm.
But I'll leave before that.
You bore me, David.
So there it is. I took her,
and I brought her back. Nice of me.
This is just a sample
of the pressure I can exert.
You're not the strong ones,
Mrs Tombsthay and you.
Do you believe me?
- What happened?
- Don't worry, it's all over now.
He's a friend.
We're at my new place. Stay there.
I'll see my friend to the door,
then I'll be back.
- Do you know the word "picaresque"?
- You think I'm illiterate, too?
You're the one
who's been telling stories!
The night your mistress's husband was
killed, you were there. I followed you
because I was uneasy... about you.
Mrs Tombsthay is cunning. A break-in?
I saw it all from the park.
Why wait till now to tell me this?
Because I wanted you
to be the one to tell me first!
- Fine, then. I killed him.
- Unbelievable!
You're still trying to defend her!
I saw her kill her husband.
On the terrace,
in front of the French windows.
Are you going to try and deny it?
All over again! You're crazy. Piss off!
You make me sick.
I don't know exactly
what you two are up to,
but I'm certain
that you have the globe.
Do you know the orders
I got this morning?
To retrieve it, at any cost.
And eliminate the person who stole it.
You cheated me. You make me sick.
You've already said that.
Come on, admit that it's you
that has it, David. Admit it!
Yes, I have it.
In that case, you now know
what I have to do.
I warned you. I'm sorry.
It's you who makes me sick!
- Do you feel better?
- I'm OK.
- Is your friend in trouble?
- Yes, he couldn't find his car keys.
- Shall I take you home?
- Yes, please.
- To your parents' place?
- No, to my friends'.
Thank you for everything.
- Did my parents hurt you?
- Yes, I believe so.
They enjoy that.
At least, they did.
- I tried to warn you...
- And I told you it was my business.
You know...
I'm not very pleased
with myself, either.
- Yes?
- It's Julia. Did you receive...?
- Just now. Have you seen it?
- Yes.
- Can I be recognised?
- By someone who knows you, yes.
- Was it filmed from your neighbour's?
- Maybe. I can't tell.
- I must hang up, I have a visitor.
- Take care of yourself.
- Where were you?
- Around the house.
It's a large place.
- Why? What do you want?
- The globe.
It's buried in the garden
with your pistol.
I thought it was in the power meter
cupboard. You've lied non-stop to me.
Take it and piss off.
And please, put that away.
You don't understand, David.
I have to kill you.
I said the deal would be finished
today, and it will be.
Stop it, Daniel. Think!
What are you going to do?
I'll take a holiday,
like I always do after a job.
I will send the globe to Felix Andre.
Felix, that's his first name.
Poste restante, rue Turgot, Paris 9.
Soon after, I will receive
my pay here, in the same way.
PO Box 51 at the central post office.
Mr Dominique Lenaour,
that's my name in this city,
will receive 300,000 francs,
and he'll never be heard from again.
Despite what you believe,
the most important exchanges,
and the most dangerous,
take place simply by post.
I didn't take the microfilms.
Won't you check?
No, I told you, I always know
when someone lies.
At least, almost always...
If you had believed me...
Did Julia lie to me?
I don't know her. But without her,
we wouldn't be here like this.
I'm sorry, David,
but there's nothing else I can do...
Goodbye, David.
GOOD LUCK DAVlD
I received another tape.
So did Mrs Tombsthay.
Filmed from your place, wasn't it?
I don't like your tone.
How does your story
about the whore end?
What whore? I don't know any whores.
- The tape, it was you?
- Yes.
- The first time, as well?
- No.
- I know.
- It was you who gave me the idea.
Do killers make you... No.
Excuse me, I was going to say...
I'll try again.
Killers... Sorry, I'll start again.
- Do you like killers?
- Do you?
Have you watched your tape?
I haven't. Mrs Tombsthay has.
You can call her Julia.
Did she tell you about it?
No, I already know what happens.
- You think?
- Please, no!
Please, allow me this pleasure!
You recognise yourself,
Mr Aurphet? Even filmed by me?
From far away,
and at night-time. Not easy!
Impossible to mistake him,
it's Mr Tombsthay.
I never heard the gunshot
with all that wind.
I couldn't make out
why Mr Tombsthay fell.
I saw you throw down the revolver,
then I understood what happened.
What a strange idea
to throw it away.
Is that what's called
"losing one's head"?
Anyway, end of act one,
or rather, the first set,
for in fact it's the second.
The match is in three sets.
A few minutes earlier...
I assume that you recognise
Mrs Tombsthay.
That's what intrigued me.
I rushed for my camera...
What was Mrs Tombsthay
watching so intently
in Mr Tombsthay's living room?
Now onto the third set.
You've just shot Mr Tombsthay,
and gone into the living room.
Now, look carefully!
You missed Mr Tombsthay.
He's merely injured.
But, surprise, surprise,
Mrs Tombsthay returns.
She picks up your revolver
and match point!
Mrs Tombsthay didn't miss Mr Tombsthay.
The curtain falls.
Well played, Julia!
Don't be a bad loser.
The blame perhaps lies...
Yes, I know. I fell into her arms
a little too quickly.
What are you going to do?
Leave... tomorrow.
I hope to come into some money.
And... until tomorrow?
I don't know.
Would you like to stay here?
Yes.
- Is your mother well?
- Yes.
I start working with her next week.
- What do the two of you do?
- Detective work.
- That can't be true...
- Do you take me for a liar?
- What about the cane?
- I collect them.
The day I moved,
I was holding one, so I limped...
- Why?
- To draw more attention, Mr Aurphet.
Now I remember
the story about the whore!
What whore? I don't know any whores.
She's waiting for a customer
by the broken street light.
A guy comes up and asks,
"How much?" She says, "200".
He says, "No, that's too much, 1 50."
She says, "No, 200."
He says, "Too bad," and heads off.
He soon returns.
He says, "OK, 200."
She says, "No, 250."
The guy's taken aback. "But..."
She says, "Now, it's 250."
He says, "Why?"
She says, "That's the way it is."
He leaves. Soon he returns,
saying, "OK, then, 250."
Now the woman hesitates.
Finally she says, "OK,
but I hope you fuck well, because you
haven't got a clue about business."
No, don't leave.
- David.
- Please.
I think you know everything now.
Yes, it was me who killed him.
He hated me.
I hated him. And I loved him.
You happened to come by...
I'd have preferred you to be strong
enough to kill him all by yourself.
You proved yourself
pretty clever as well, though.
You and your friend were already
after the globe when we met.
It's no drama. But you've aged as well.
We're through. I'm through with you.
I'll... carry on somewhere else.
"And the cursed lovers
never meet again. "
A pity. I could have loved you.
Bye.
My respects to you, my neighbour.
If anyone comes out of this well,
it's you: rich and loved.
Off you go. All the best to Viviane.
And my congratulations.
I can't stay, but I'll be back... soon!
Look, I still have it!
I wrote that I was going
to commit suicide.
Don't believe it. It was a joke!
I'm going on a trip.
- Do you want to come with me?
- Yes. When?
Right now.
I'll get my things ready.
Come...
I'm ready.