DECEPTION
10:53 pm.
Sorry for scaring you.
I was just heading home.
We met before in the can.
- Oh, you're Wyatt, right?
Yeah. So, you working late or
you downloading a multitude of porn.
I have to be out of here by tomorrow
so I'm just trying to finish up.
What about you?
- You kidding? This is an early night.
Hard to believe once upon a time...
it was a measure of a man's success
on how little he worked.
What's the deal? Our firm hires you
to bless our books they send you?
I'm the audit manager, yeah. I handle
the same 7 or 8 clients every year.
I must've done Stern
for something like 4 years now.
Wow. So you like this work?
- I do. The order of it appeals to me.
The symmetry.
It's alright, I guess,
if you like workin' with numbers.
Do you like being a lawyer?
It's alright, I guess,
if you like workin' with assholes.
I'm probably disturbing you, so...
- Hey, no, it's alright. I'm almost done.
Really.
- Oh.
So...
Worth and Berman, huh?
Did they headhunt you?
Yeah. My senior year of college.
They subsidized my graduate degree.
Ah, I see.
So you were poor, right?
I guess I was kind of poor.
I was brought up by my mom on her own...
and she died when I was 19
so it was kind of like a lifeline.
Wow. Sounds like you needed it.
- I'm sure there's a lot of people
that had it worse.
- Not here.
Practically every suit I know
is Harvard by way of Andover.
Are you?
- Oh, hell no. No, no.
I'm Princeton by way of Exeter.
- But that's like the same. Oh yeah.
So, Jonathan...
I think I have something here
which might help you to focus.
You smoke?
- Not for a long time.
Good. This'll give you a real buzz,
then.
I don't know...
I just sometimes feel so, uh...
you know... removed.
I work for one of the biggest
accounting firms in the world...
and there's not so much as a desk there
to prove it. My new senior manager...
I haven't even met him in person yet.
I try and meet people at work
but it's always the same.
To the accounting staff I'm a pain because
for 2 weeks they must hold their breath.
They hope I don't pick up
any of their screw-ups.
To everyone else I'm just a temporary fixed
so I bother them.
Sometimes...
I sit and I look through the glass,
and I see life..
Iiterally passing me by.
- Jonathan.
Yeah?
By the clock on that wall you have been
talking for 37 minutes straight.
I don't remember a word I said.
So, God says to Jesus...
I haven't felt this good
since I sawVan Halen in '97.
Stand clear of the closing doors, please.
Is this the train to Canal Street?
- Yes, this is the right train.
So, I guess that's it.
This is my report for Mr. Cross.
Could you point me towards
Wyatt Bose's office, please?
Who?
- Wyatt Bose. He's one of your...
Hey, quit looking down Daphne's shirt.
So, get in, get out, huh? So where's next?
Clancey Funds on Friday
and then Clute-Nichols after that.
Sounds like fun.
Wait up a sec.
Good to meet you, Jonathan.
- You, too.
So... wait.
You have the day off tomorrow?.
How's your backhand?
I'm sorry.
- Good game.
Commiserations, McQuarry.
You develop a killer instinct,
you'll beat the crap out of me.
When these things first came out,
I think I was a frosh at boarding school.
Geez, where did you get this thing?
You steal it from Jimmy Connors?
What is this? Ntural gut, hm?
- No, natural gut and Kevlar.
I should have 'em replaced.
They're pretty frayed.
Those two girls were so pretty.
You don't get much, do you?
Do you mean sex?
- No, flood insurance.
How many women have you slept with?
Of course you know. Everyone knows.
Maybe four.
- Maybe four?
Alright. Four. What about you?
Me? I have no idea.
- You just said everyone knows.
I meant everyone like you.
C'mon, hurry up. Let's go for a drink.
You can borrow something of mine.
Ah. Guten Abend, Herr Kleiner.
This way, Jonathan.
Like it?
It's a Gerhard Richter. Actually,
Kleiner, the guy we just saw downstairs.
He's a hotshot art dealer.
He hooked me up with this
fantastic gallery in Munich.
I'll be back in a second.
Try this one.
What?
C'mon, Jonathan.
You remind me of this guy, Jamie Getz.
I met him my freshman year at Princeton.
Oh, he was real smart. He was witty, too,
when you loosened him up. But he had...
It was bounday. Nowyou assume
that it was never scaled out.
The truth is he was the only one guarding.
What happened to him?
- Oh, he killed himself.
What?
You're kidding.
Go get changed.
- Down here?
Down there.
Second door on the right.
Okay, Jonathan, so just the four, huh?
Oh, come on.
Now, look...
I've never been too adventuresome.
What's the lamest?
- Well, I once...
No, c'mon, share it with the group.
- I once phoned one of those sex lines.
Alright, nowwe're talking.
- I talked to girl named Star.
I ended up explaining a Section 179
deduction on the new Escalade.
You paid to give tax advice on a sex line?
- That's about the size of it.
Oh, thank you for sharing, Jonathan.
That is pretty lame.
Oh, hello.
Do you... is she looking at me?
- Yeah, she's looking at you.
No, she's not. C'mon.
- Maybe it's the suit?
Listen, you don't think
women have the same urges?
Successful women working their asses off
to stay that way?
And?
Well, let's just say there's a way
that it can be taken care of.
You make it sound like a mob hit.
Had a good time tonight?
- I had a really good time tonight.
I did. I had a great time.
- Whoa. I wasn't sure at one point.
No, I'm shy. But...
Thank you. And thanks for the tennis
and for takin' me out.
It's okay. Tennis anytime.
Particularly if you play that badly.
At the corner, please.
The Waldorf Astoria.
I gotta go meet somebody.
Take care. Have a nice night.
- I'll call you tomorrow.
Any problems,
you'll want to see Julie Levinson.
She's our Assistant Controller.
But, like I said,
I don't anticipate any problems.
Never had any before.
- Okay. Thanks.
It's really nice out here.
I usually just brown bag it.
You have to get outside. Those fluorescent
lights will kill you. I read about them.
Hello.
Shit. No, I got it here. Hold on.
See if you can change it to the 6:30
ut of JFK flight nbr. 4. Right. Yeah.
Rutherford wants me to join him
in London asap.
We're papering some finance with Lloyds.
I tell you about this? - No.
I'll be gone a couple weeks.
- Sounds sort of interesting.
Gonna be as boring as sin, but...
Anyhow, I gotta get back.
Ready?
- Alright.
That's disgusting.
I don't want to hear that.
Why?
That's repulsive.
Don't ever tell anyone that. Ever.
You're the kind of girl that pees
in front of men, aren't you?
What goes in the Xerox Room
stays in the Xerox room.
Jonathan McQuarry, hello.
Hello?
Wyatt? I've got your cell phone. I guess,
you've got mine. What a pain in the ass.
You're probably in the air right, so,
if you get this, call me on your phone.
I'll speak to you later. Take care.
Mr. Lewman. Hi.
- Hello.
Actually, Mr. Lewman, there was something
I wanted to talk to you about. Excuse me.
Hello?
(woman) Are you free tonight?
Look, this isn't actually...
Sorry, could you just hold on a sec?
Mr. Lewman, my bedroom...
I think I have a leak.
I was hoping you could take a look.
McQuarry. 631.
Right. McQuarry. Yeah,
I'll get to it soon as I can.
Hello? Anyone there?
Hello?
(oman) Are you free tonight?
Actually, I am, but this isn't Wyatt.
- Sorry, I didn't get that.
Well, I am free, but...
- Could you be at The Dylan in one hour?
I guess so, but...
Are you waiting for me?
- Yes, I think so.
Would you like a drink or something?
- No, thanks.
I've got a conference call
with Tokyo early in the morning.
Shall we go?
- Yes.
Have you been in this hotel before?
- No.
Look, the person who you thought
you were talking to isn't me.
You're not who I spoke to on the phone?
- No, no... Yes, yes, I am.
But...
- What's wrong?
Are you not attracted to me?
- Oh, you're beautiful.
It's just you called me
and I came here but I don't...
You don't?
- I'm not too sure what's going on.
You're not too sure what's going on?
Sit down. Sit down.
Hello.
- Hey, you're up early.
Hey! How's London?
- Rainy. So you got mine, I got yours.
Yeah, I must've grabbed it at lunch
before you left.
No big deal. I already had my work calls
forwarded here. - Oh, alright.
So, did I get any calls?
- Yes, you did.
And?
- Well...
What the hell was that?
- I knew it. You met up with someone.
I thought you would call me back.
- Oh, spare me. I woulda done the same.
So howwas it?
- It was really amazing, actually. She...
Shit. I'll call you later. The want me
in a meeting. I wand to hear all about it.
Alright.
- As for my phone, feel free to use it.
Okay. Thanks.
(woman)
Yes?
Hello. Uh...
- Are you free tonight?
(woman) Where?
- Where, right.
The Dylan Hotel.
- Perhaps The Park Avenue.
In the bar, half past eleven.
If you are who you don't seem to be,
you're late.
Excuse me?
- Are you?
Late, orwho I'm not supposed to be?
Either.
Yes, I am late,
and I am who I don't seem to be.
Alright, then.
Could you put this on the room, please?
- Yes, ma'am.
I don't have a room.
You're rather newto this, aren't you?
The initiator is responsible for the room.
That's one of the rules.
Oh. So I should...
- Precisely.
Oh. Excuse me.
Frankly, I'm surprised whoever
sponsored you didn't explain more.
Downstairs, you talked about a rule.
Are there others?
No rough stuff. If that's your thing,
take it elsewhere.
No business talk, and no names.
- Right.
How did you get into this?
- A friend of mine...
He introduced you to the list
but failed to explain the basics?
Well, he had to leave town.
I'm doing something wrong here, aren't l?
It's not that. You just strike me
as something of a stowaway.
If it wasn't for the $4,000 suit,
I'd say you didn't belong here at all.
This is us.
Although,
someone obviously thought you did.
And I'm a sucker for bashful boys.
Can I ask you something?
Why do you do this?
- For the same reason that men do it.
The economics of the arrangement.
Intimacy without intricacy.
I work past midnight almost every night.
The last dinner I had that wasn't business
was about a year ago.
Hey, Wyatt, it's Jonathan.
I haven't heard from you, but...
I guess
you must be pretty swamped over there.
Look, I just wanted to say thank you.
Wait. Wait. Before we...
The thing is, I knowyou.
I mean, not "knowyou" exactly.
We met before in the Times Square
subway station. It had been raining,
and you asked me if the train stops
at Canal Street.
No.
Wait. It just feels a little strange,
that's all.
Why? Because you've seen me before?
Maybe. It's just...
- C'mon, what's the problem?
Okay...
I guess it is a little bit
of a gear shift.
Maybe some other time.
Oh, no, please. What I mean is...
By any chance... are you hungry?
Mm, you have a little bit of...
of ketchup on your chin.
Oh. I'm sorry. I'm a messy eater.
- No, it's okay. So am l. Here.
There you go.
- Thank you.
You have a little piece of...
- Oh, what, onion in my hair?
So what do you do for a living?
I sit behind glass
and I watch people pass like fish.
You work in a bank?
- I'm sort of an accountant.
I bet that's what you always
dreamed of being when you grew up.
Oh, yeah, I'm livin' the dream.
Feel free to leave now.
Still here.
But how about you?
- No.
No, no, no, I'm afraid that we're
still on you.
Frank.
- Frank?
You look like a Frank.
By the way, my name is...
- Oh, sh.
You knowthe rules. No names.
Yeah, but the rules seem to specify
no conversation either.
Okay. How 'bout I tell you my name,
if you guess.
Oh, you're in real trouble here.
You see, I am very good at this.
What are you very good at?
- Problem solving. It's what I do.
I'm very good at identifying hierarchical
relationships and binary posits.
Is that right?
- Absolutely.
And this talent can be applied
to finding anything.
For example,
I knowthat your name begins with an S.
How do you knowthat?
- I sawyour key chain on your purse.
Wow. Excellent work.
- Thank you. So, the things we know are
A, your name begins with an S.
B, you have a white coat.
And C...
And C, you do not know
your way around the subway.
That's true.
Now all I do is extrapolate from
these known qualities and your name...
is...
Sybil.
Sophie. You're definitely a Sophie.
- Wait, with an "ie" or a "y"?
Either.
- Neither.
How about Syd, as in Syd Charisse?
- No, she was Syd with a C.
Yeah, but maybe you spell it with an S.
- I do not.
Sexy Steffi was lookin' for a train...
- No.
Sunbeam.
- Oh, God, do I look like a Sunbeam?
Absolutely.
Well, then, that's it.
I told you I was good at this.
- I'm very impressed.
I'm crashing.
I'd really like to see you again.
Not in a hotel.
Hm, well... we'll see about that.
Maybe tomorrow?.
- It is tomorrow.
Hello?
(Wyatt) Are you free tonight?
Hey, are you back?
- I wish. It's friggin' anarchy here.
Hang on. Hello?
Housekeeping.
- Uh, could you come back? Thanks.
Sorry.
- Where are you?
I'm in the Soho Grand.
- Soho Grand, huh?
Sounds like you've been enjoying yourself.
- I have. I met this girl last night,
and I broke all the rules and I had
an honest-to-God conversation with her.
(Wyatt) That's extremely naughty of you.
Who is she, Romeo?
I have no idea, really. I don't know
very much about her yet, but...
I'm gonna see her again.
- I don't want to dampen your spirits...
What?
- You met her through the list.
She's different. Trust me.
So when are you back?
- Hard to say.
It's back-to-back bullshit here.
But next week, I hope.
Well, good luck.
I'll see you when you get back.
(Wyatt)
You, too.
Hello?
(woman) Are you free tonight?
I'm sorry, you have the wrong number.
Hello?
("S") Hey, are you free tonight?
Can you meet me in Chinatown,
on Doyer Street? Say, eight o'clock?
Okay.
I got you a present.
Thank you.
- It looks great on you.
Let's go.
- Yeah.
We'd like... we'd like one of these.
And... one of these...
oh, and that.
Thank you.
What did you order?
- I have absolutely no idea.
How do you knowwe'll like it?
- How do you knowwe won't?
This is so not my life.
Ever since that night on the subway
I haven't stopped thinking about you.
I'm not sure I believe you.
I mean, you're in a sex club.
I'm not judging you. I'm in there, too.
But don't say you've been
solemnly holding a torch for me for...
Iong now, one month?
- Point taken.
I got you a present.
Oh, he is so cute.
Thank you.
Here.
- Thanks.
What is that?
Ginseng gum.
It's terrible.
I guess
it does sort of taste like hairspray.
I think I got it now.
I think your name is Suki.
What? What are you thinking about?
I don't want to complicate your life.
- No...
I want all the complications you've got.
Maybe you should go?
Maybe you should stay.
I knowwe decided not to rush, but...
Just for the record, I'm doing everything
I can just to apply the brakes here.
Oh, me too.
Our parents would be proud.
But just say...
Say what?
Ifwe acted...
just suddenly tore off the rest of these
clothes to consummate their deep...
human needs in a frenzy of...
Fucking and sucking.
Beautifully put.
You were saying?
- Well...
Who could blame these two people?
- Who could possibly judge them?
Who would know?.
I got it.
- Where are you going?
Ice.
Oh, you gonna get some ice, huh?
There's a machine out in the hallway.
I'll be right back.
I'll get the ice.
You stay here, I'll get the ice.
Jonathan. Wait.
- No, I'll go.
Would you like some help?
I can manage. Thank you.
I can't get the card to work.
Hello?
Hello!
Sir. Sir!
Mr. McQuarry, Detective Russo.
How're you doing?
- Not too good.
This is Detective Burke.
I need a background check.
Last name McQuarry, first name Jonathan.
Andyou don't know anything about her?
Where she works, where she lives,
her phone number? - Like I said,
all I know about her
is her first name starts with an S.
Is she a prostitute?
- No.
I told you, she's a friend.
- A friend you met in a sex group.
Look, who else is in this sex group?
- I don't know. It's not like that.
It's anonymous.
You walked into the room and saw blood?
Yeah, I saw blood and then someone hit me,
and when I came to she was gone.
And you didn't see who hit you?
- No, they were behind me.
They must've been hiding in the bathroom.
- Well, was there anything stolen?
Your wallet, or jewelry or anything?
- No, I have my wallet.
Look, Detective, please,
you've got to find her.
We can't do anything
until I understand what happened tonight.
I told you what happened tonight.
Have you ever had
experiences like this before?
No. What're you talking about?
- We spoke to the desk clerk,
and he only recalls seeing you check in.
And as for the blood you say you saw,
we checked the room and found nothing.
In fact, the only blood we found
is where you hit your head.
Look, I knowit all sounds...
But I swear there's a woman
in serious trouble right now.
A woman whose name you don't know.
Yes.
Look, clearly, you had a tough night.
- I'm not crazy.
I tell you what. Go home, and if you
remember anything, you give me a call.
Hey, Wyatt, it's me, Jonathan.
Look, something happened to me last night.
Could you call me back
when you get a chance?
I really need to speak to you.
Can I help you?
- I need to speak to Wyatt Bose.
He's one of your attorneys
and in your London office right now.
Maybe I can speak to his assistant.
I need to get in touch with him.
Of course. Just a minute.
Are you sure that you have the right firm?
- Yes, I met him here when I was working.
Wyatt Bose, he's six-one,
he has black hair. Wait.
I have his... I have his card.
You see? Look. Wyatt Bose.
I can assure you there is no one
by this name working in this firm.
No, but I've seen him in these halls.
We smoked pot in the conference room.
Excuse me?
Wait! Hey, wait
I'm trying to get hold ofWyatt.
Who?
- Wyatt Bose. I sawyou talking with him.
You cracked jokes with him in the lobby.
- I crack jokes with a lot of people.
Are you trying to tell me you don't...
- Hey! Easy with the hands. What is this?
He said he was going to London
with a Mr. Rutherford to paper a deal.
Mr. McQuarry, Mr. Rutherford
is presently recovering from hip surgery.
In New Jersey.
Yes?
- I'm sorry. I'm looking for Wyatt.
Excuse me. Wyatt?
- Yeah, Wyatt Bose. He lives here.
Uh, in, in this building?
No, I'm sorry, he must be new.
No, not in this building.
In this apartment.
No, wait, that painting.
It's a Gerhard Richter, right? - Yes.
From the gallery in Munich
that Herr Kleiner handled.
The art dealer downstairs.
Downstairs you must mean Mr. Moretti.
But he's in the carpet business.
Young man, are you alright?
She's a looker.
You weren't kidding.
I can see
why she had you all hot and bothered.
Oh, Jesus Christ, it was you.
Where is she?
Wyatt...
I need you to listen. You're starting
next week at Clute-Nichols, yes?
Who are you?
I'm your only shot
at seeing her alive again.
I asked you a fucking question.
- Yes.
Have a seat. Sit down.
As a part of their audit you've temporary
access to all accounts and wire protocols.
That's what this is about?
- Jonathan.
I want you to locate some accounts for me.
You're gonna move some money around.
I can't.
- What?
They're client accounts. There's safety...
- Listen!
I never said client accounts.
I mean some sub-accounts that I know of,
outside the realm of your audit.
Masked accounts. Slush funds.
Typical insider stuff, you know.
20 mil or so,
skimmed into a quiet account
for a rainy day.
You don't think they'll notice
when it's gone? - Eventually, yes.
But they won't do shit about 'em
'cause it's dirtymoney.
I can't.
- This isn't a negotiation, Jonathan.
Besides, we're friends, remember?
I'm warning you. Don't try and be a hero,
'cause people are gonna get hurt.
And you go to the cops, I'll make it look
like you cut her pretty little head off.
Don't hurt her.
- Just do as you're instructed,
and you'll have her back in no time.
- And why should I trust you?
Everything you told me was a lie.
- Oh, not lies, Jonathan.
That was foreplay.
And nowyou're fucked.
I'll be watching.
Hello?
You have one new voice message.
New message one.
Are you free tonight? It's me, Tina.
I'm in town. I want to see you again.
6 months is way too long.
I'm at The Rhiga, Room 802.
You better show. You owe me.
After all, I was your first.
Hello. This is the front desk.
Your guest has arrived.
You can go on up.
- Thank you.
Who are you? What are you doing here?
- I believe I was invited.
You have the wrong room.
- You didn't leave me a message,
asking if I was free tonight?
I must've dialed the wrong number.
Look, I meant to call someone else.
I'm sorry.
I need to speakwith you about Wyatt.
I just need to ask you a few questions,
okay?
I'm sorry, I don't know any Wyatt.
- Bullshit. You left him a message,
asking him to meet you here.
- I thought you said...
Who are you? How did you...
What? No! I just need a few answers.
My name is Jonathan McQuarry.
I knowyou have no reason to help me,
or even to believe me,
but I need to know about Wyatt.
I told you, I don't know any Wyatt.
- That's the name of the guy you called.
No, it isn't.
I'm sorry.
I'm really sorry.
I'm really in trouble,
and this guy, he's...
he's dangerous.
It was in Chicago about a year ago, at a
private function sponsored by my firm.
He was attending as a guest.
- A guest of who?
A guy called Hollaway. Rudolph Holloway.
I think they played tennis together.
He told me he'd just moved from Frisco
and was in-between jobs.
He was extremely smart.
I know it sounds silly, but he had this
way of making me feel close to him.
I found myself telling him things.
I told him about this.
You told him about the list.
Yes.
There was something about him.
Something terrifying.
So why did you call him again?
You knowwhen it's so good
you'd rather die than stop?
You want to kill someone. You wanna kill
the person you're doing it with.
Fuck it. Y'knowwhat?
He was a good lay.
Okay, so what's his real name?
Jamie.
- Jamie?
That's his name. Jamie Getz.
Jamie Getz.