To
save the 130-year-old bank
from collapse, there is talk of cutting
200 jobs over the next week.
The European Central Bank has
made the decision to downgrade
its growth forecast next
month, as new data has shown
one in four Italians are now unemployed.
More on that another financial
news later in the show.
In local news, a man claiming to be
a Catholic priest arrested
in Gatwick Airport
after he was caught carrying cocaine.
Jesus.
How did you get in here?
Shit.
This week feels like it's lasted a month.
This month feels like a year.
Time tends to drag when every day
is as uneventful as the last.
I can't remember the last time
I was excited about something.
It's like there was this
void that just gets bigger
and bigger no matter what I fill it with.
Wake up, go to work, come
home, watch TV, go to bed.
There has to be more to life than this,
this painful, monotonous existence.
You have four new messages.
Hey Ed, it's Carrie.
Call me back when you get this.
Hey Ed, it's--
Hey Ed.
Good evening
Mr. Arkham, it's Dr. Rathkin.
I was disappointed when you didn't
turn up for our session on Tuesday.
I'm calling because I
honestly felt as though
we were making progress,
up until our last meeting,
which was disconcerting, to say the least.
Please call me when you get this message.
Thanks.
Hi, Ed.
We must stop meeting like this.
How come you didn't come over last night?
Carrie lives next door.
I got back late last night.
I didn't get a messages till this morning.
Okay, well, how about
you come over tonight?
I'll cook some food, and we can
watch a movie, or something.
I'm sorry, I can't do tonight.
Stop making excuses.
We went out a few weeks back.
One thing led to another, and
I ended up back at her place.
You can't treat me like this.
Okay, maybe it happened more than once.
Look, you know I've just
broke up with Laura.
Oh, come on, it's been almost a year.
And that's not what you said last week
when you were begging me to let you do
exactly what you wanted.
You're having that
shit for breakfast now.
What?
I'll do whatever I want.
Don't you ignore me.
That woman scares me.
There seems no escape.
From what exactly, I'm unsure.
But the only place I'm ever truly at ease
is here in the car.
Morning, Mikey.
Morning, Edward.
Edward.
David Snodgrass.
Backs-stabbed his way up the ladder,
and is universally despised.
Snodgrass.
What's it like up there
in development, then?
It's good, thanks.
They should use people like
him for product testing
in laboratories, instead
of innocent animals.
Aren't you working on that?
Dealing software for KBank?
Yeah, that's right.
Heard, you went way over budget, Eddie.
It's not a good place to be these days.
Well, we--
Why don't you tell me on the way up?
Right, so Ed, what floor are you again?
Seven, please.
Seven, seven.
Ah, there we go, seven.
And four, right, great.
So, please continue.
Well, we had a few issues
with the accounting modules,
but other than that, the
application's pretty much done,
so it's not too bad.
Hmm.
I see.
That's good, good.
Now, these accounting
modules that you speak of,
what stage are we at at the moment, Ed?
Because we were thinking, that is,
me and my team were thinking,
So, that's where we are with
management at the moment, and,
Fourth floor.
That's your stop, isn't it?
Oh yeah, fourth.
I've been meaning to
have a chat with you, Ed.
So maybe I'll come up with this
afternoon and I'll find you.
All right?
Did you get my email last week?
About the party tonight?
Christian's over from the States.
I've got a meeting with
him in, like, five minutes.
We'll chat later, okay?
Am I invited?
Probably not.
Sometimes, you sound
like such a loser, Steven.
Mind your own business, Pablo.
Fuck you.
No, fuck you.
Enough.
What's this party she's talking about?
I hear there's going
to be a lot of bitches.
It's a birthday party at the Forge.
The Forge?
Yeah, the Forge, remember?
We've been there before.
No, but go on.
It's gonna be a pussy fest.
We have to go.
Big boy condoms,
penis enlargement, free Viagra.
This place, it's eating me alive.
Cooped up 10 hours a day, meetings,
deadlines, reports,
annoying office politics,
subjected to the same dull
personalities every day.
Morning, Eddie.
And I hate it
when people call me Eddie.
Hello again.
Have we met?
In another life, perhaps.
I don't believe in that stuff.
Maybe you should.
I'm quite happy living
in the real world.
Of course.
Nicholas Lemarchand.
Your hand is freezing.
Edward Arkham.
It's a medical condition.
I've had it for as long as I can remember.
What is it?
Don't worry.
It's not contagious.
So, what do you do here, Ed?
You don't mind me calling you Ed, do you?
I'm a software analyst.
Senior software analyst.
And how long have you been here?
It'll be five years in October.
A long time.
Five years.
Yep.
Are you okay?
I didn't sleep too well last night.
Did you see that?
Did I see what?
Sorry, I've just got a thing about.
Bugs?
Yeah.
It's funny how such small,
helpless little creatures
can provoke such terror.
They aren't so helpless.
One of those little bastards
stung me this morning.
Hurts, doesn't it?
Yeah.
Well, everything
happens for a reason, Ed.
For the greater good, I guess.
Or evil.
I'll see you around.
Sure.
Sorry mate, can you go around?
I've known people like you.
Can't live the life you
really want to live,
because the law forbids it.
Boundaries set by so-called
modern society to stop people
acting on their impulses,
their natural instinct.
But it doesn't have to be that way.
Conformity is weakness.
Let go, Edward.
They don't care about you.
Nobody does.
You are alone.
Equal their depravity in vengeance.
What are you looking at?
Get a grip, Ed.
Get your own calculator.
It is estimated that
50,000 people in the UK
are severely allergic to
stinging insect venom.
Every year, 12 deaths from
stinging reactions are reported.
Hey, Ed.
What do you want?
Just wanna talk to you about
testing environments.
What about them?
One of the guys needs to install
some updates on Dev-6, but I,
I thought I'd run it past you first.
You thought you'd run it past me first?
You came all the way up
here just to run it past me.
Did you ever think of using one of these?
You are obviously busy.
I'll come back later.
No!
You all right?
I'm fine, thanks.
I'm fine.
Everything all right?
How's it hanging?
Shit.
They say talking to oneself
is the first sign of madness.
I'm not talking to myself.
Sure.
I'm sorry if I startled you.
You know, we're not supposed to be here.
Rules are there to be
broken though, aren't they?
Not around here, they're not.
Are you feeling all right?
Why do people keep asking me that?
When was the last time
you looked in a mirror?
What do you do here?
Humans think they're
so important, don't they?
I said what do you do here, your job.
From up here, you see
them as they really are.
No more important than rats.
Always fucking with each other.
Like people need to fuck with other people
just to feel good about themselves.
You know what I mean?
I digress.
I work in a very specialized field.
I'm a mediator.
A mediator?
Mmm.
Oh, Edward.
You deserve better than this.
You are not like them.
Like who?
The rats.
Who are you?
You know exactly who I am.
You better run along, or you'll
be late for your meeting.
I'm always around, if
you want to talk later.
Where is that report?
Ah.
Guys, I'm gonna be in
a meeting till 11:30.
Okie-dokie.
Have either of you seen
anybody stepping around my desk?
When?
I dunno, whenever.
No, I haven't seen anyone.
How about you?
No.
Yeah, who's your daddy?
You're late.
Nice one.
Punctuality is the soul of
all business, remember that.
Now, get out.
I'm fucking with you, take a seat.
You said 10:30, Silas.
No.
I'm sure I said 10:15.
Both of you, shut up.
Yes, sir.
While we were waiting for you, Ed,
Silas brought up some issues he has
regarding the user experience
for the KBank application.
Sure.
He's new blood, pick his brains.
You're never too experienced
to learn new things.
I don't think that's the best--
You're familiar with Bill Gates, right?
Of course.
Mark Zuckerberg?
Yes.
Retards.
I was developing accounting software
when I was nine years old.
I started this business
when I was 15 years old,
and I didn't make the Fortune 500
not knowing what was best
for my own goddamned company.
I'm sorry, I didn't mean to offend you.
You think I'm that easily offended?
I, um--
You apologizing for offending
me is fucking offending me.
I'm sorry.
Relax, Ed, I'm just fucking with you.
Oh man, just trust me on this, okay?
Okay.
Not that I'm giving
you much of a choice.
Anyway.
Now, I had Keith over in New Business
conduct a feasibility study last week,
and he doesn't seem to
think there is any need
for us to outsource any more design work.
So, I'm appointing Silas as team leader.
Team leader?
I love it When you die.
Any questions?
Yeah, Ed?
Ehm, yeah, team leader.
Yes.
Team leader.
Oh, boo.
No, don't be an asshole about it, Silas.
You said work under Silas.
Before, you said with Silas.
Ed, technically it's--
Technically, you will be temporarily
working under him, but
it doesn't mean anything.
This is all about what's best
for our company and our customers.
We've got a lot of work to do, Ed.
Yes, you do.
We're in a lot of trouble.
We've just lost three
of our biggest clients
in the last two months.
I know.
People just aren't spending money
like they used to, and I don't blame them.
Can't compete with the Far East,
so this is really about
our reputation, our brand.
Now, I've had to make some
really tough decisions in recent months.
I've had to let a lot of good people go.
Not because they weren't
good at their jobs.
A couple of 'em were phenomenally shitty,
but for the most part, it's
because we can't be overstaffed.
I would hate to see
the same happen to you.
Or you, Silas.
You're lucky you've got brains.
Edward.
David.
Mr. Arkham, how you doing?
I'm good.
Are you looking for something?
No, not really.
I was just being nosy.
Nosy?
Well, I'm a director, Edward.
Above you, if you remember.
Well, a few floors below
you in this building.
A few floors up in the old food chain.
A few floors
up in the food chain?
That doesn't even make
sense, you fucking moron!
If you know what I mean.
How could I forget?
No, I've actually come up here
to ask for your help on something.
At your service.
Well, I don't know if you know,
but I'm conducting an internal audit.
Yeah, I heard.
Well, what I'd like you to do
is to create a report on
the efficiency of your team
and the processes and the
procedures that you employ.
Well--
- Also, if you could add
a few notes and how
things could be improved,
that'd be a great help.
You know--
- Shouldn't take you
no longer than a day or two.
So, you want me to
conduct an audit for you?
No, not exactly.
I'll be conducting the audit.
You'll just be helping me out.
So, what do you think?
I've got a lot on at the moment.
I'm not sure I've got the time.
Well, I need this by middle
of next week, the latest.
So, I'd like you to drop everything
that you are doing and do this for me, Ed.
You'll be handsomely rewarded.
And Ed, let's just keep this
between ourselves, yeah?
Sure.
I'm gonna be slipping out
a little bit early today.
Got a little bit on the side,
take them away for the weekend.
Anywhere nice?
Nah, not really.
Let's not forget what
we spoke about, yeah?
I won't.
Hello babe, give us a kiss.
You smell lovely.
You sloth.
I'm not gonna be one of his slaves.
You know, it's not cows on the bus.
They've been lovers for years.
I know, but someone has
to do something about him.
Well, go kick his ass, then.
You'd be doing a great
service to every employee
of this company if you
decided to take a stand.
Have either of you guys
got any moisturizing cream?
Why, you're planning on
making love to your own hand?
If it's serious, maybe
you should see a doctor.
It's just dry skin.
Laura?
Dear Laura, fuck off and die.
Why don't you go down on me?
Why don't you swallow, swallow?
Guys, I'm gonna go for a bit of lunch.
Swallow what?
Feel I'm with my wisdom
from the darkness
Stop, it's coming closer
Rye, one on a toasted bagel,
and the rest on white.
Okay, and a salad also?
Eh, don't know, didn't say.
No, no salad.
What have I got so far?
Oh, chicken and bacon.
So, ham and cheese on
brown with mayo, no butter.
Now, can you make sure
there's no butter at all?
Because he's lactose intolerant,
and you just can't have butter.
Okay.
Oh, for for fucks sake.
Right, that's it.
Oh, sorry, and one Caesar
salad, and that's it.
Oh no, no.
That's so silly.
We're missing a salmon and
cream cheese on a bagel, yeah.
Caesar bagel, has to be Caesar's.
Right, I'll sort this out.
Hello, my dear.
How are we this afternoon?
I'm very well, thank you.
Finally.
What can I get for my favorite customer?
I need six salads, three
potato, with one chicken Caesar,
one normal Caesar, and one crayfish salad.
Vitton, do we have any crayfish left?
I'm sorry.
And one ham and cheese and mustard.
Oh, my God.
Did you see what happened?
Half an hour to get a bloody sandwich.
Ed?
What?
Can I?
If you take my calculator one more time,
I'm gonna cut your hand
off, shove it up your arse.
What is wrong with you?
I seriously think you
should see someone, Ed.
Maybe a doctor.
Asshole.
I only said it because I care.
I wasn't talking to you.
Although you're an asshole, too.
What the?
He's just messing with me.
I've seen this stuff before.
What?
Steven, have you met new
guy around here called
Nicholas Lemarchand?
It does sound vaguely familiar.
So, you've met this guy.
I didn't say that.
I said the name sounds familiar.
Pablo, how about you?
Who?
Nicholas Lemarchand.
Nicholas Lemarchand?
Have you met a guy
called Nicholas Lemarchand?
No, doesn't ring a bell.
What's wrong with you?
I dunno.
I feel like I'm losing my mind.
You're not losing your mind.
It's just been a rough week, that's all.
Now, my uncle, he lost it, totally.
One day, he got into
the neighbor's backyard
and raped their dog.
That poor dog, he fucked it up for life.
After, he wouldn't eat a drink
for, like, two weeks, and then he died.
He raped a dog.
Yes.
And after that he shot
himself up the ass, and he died.
Why'd he shoot himself up the arse?
He was so messed up in his head.
He thought there was a
demon living up his ass,
so he tried to shoot it.
A demon up his arse?
A demon.
I need a cigarette.
My day.
Whore.
You can do a lot better than her, Ed.
You know that.
Remember that weird birthmark?
Not very attractive.
Why don't you mind
your own bloody business?
I'm just telling it as it is.
So, what's the deal with that video?
That's you.
It looks a lot like me.
Ed, sometimes you're not
supposed to understand things.
The world bears many mysteries.
Whatever it is you're trying to do,
you'd better stop, right now.
I mean you know harm, Ed.
So, what do you want from me?
Why don't you tell me?
This is crazy.
Birthmark?
How do you?
2,000 highly skilled IT professionals,
who will customize our
revolutionary solutions.
Hey, Mikey.
Oh.
Sorry, mate.
Hey, have you heard about the suicide?
No.
Goldberg Finch.
Guy jumps out the 11th floor.
Really?
Yeah, everybody's
talking about it.
Listen, I need your help with something.
There's this guy, Nicholas Lemarchand.
Met him in the kitchen this morning.
I don't know who he is, but
I don't think he works here.
He's been harassing me all day.
Harassing you?
In what way?
I dunno, he's weird.
Asking me questions about things.
I thought he might be a security risk.
Well, you've come to the right man.
Better to be safe than sorry, eh?
Yeah, I thought that.
Let's check the old visitors list.
You said you met him in
the kitchen this morning.
What time was that?
About nine?
Nine.
What does he look like?
Gray hair, 40s, suit, well-dressed.
I'll tell you what, I'll check
out the surveillance video.
Once I got a visual on him, he
won't be able to track down.
Have you seen him anywhere else?
No.
You sure?
Yeah.
Ed, I meant to say this morning.
Are you all right?
You just don't see yourself at the moment.
I'm fine, I'm just a bit stressed.
Don't let the bastards get you down.
Life's too short.
Cheers, mate.
All right, mate.
So, are you coming tonight, Ed?
Are you okay?
Sorry, I don't feel so good.
No, Ed.
It's my birthday, you're coming.
And you are already on the list.
Seriously?
You're coming, and that's that.
I need you as a wing man.
All right, just for a few.
Cool, I'll see you there.
So beautiful, so innocent.
I'd fuck her like my
uncle fucked that dog.
It's Christian, get up.
You look a little pale.
I'm fine.
Please accept my apologies
for this morning.
No, no, look, don't worry
about any of that, all right?
I know you guys are
under a lot of pressure.
I've been there myself.
Just don't let it get to you.
I don't wanna see you
jumping out any windows.
You hear about that?
Banker that jumped out of his window,
happened just around the corner.
Hmm.
- Anyway, I need you focused.
What's going on with
Silas, you getting along?
I haven't heard from him yet.
You gotta be proactive, man.
Pick up the phone, sometimes people
just need a little tickle.
A tickle?
Yeah, you know, a little tickle.
Yes, sir.
KBank is a very big client.
I don't wanna risk losing them.
Everything's gotta be perfect.
I know he's an asshole, okay?
But I really liked his ideas.
I figured I would give him a shot.
I did the same for you not so long ago.
But they were my ideas.
I discussed them with him at
the beginning of the week.
I'm flying back to the States,
and I'm gonna be back in a month.
I need to see some
results, you understand?
Yes.
Be a little more focused.
Hello there, sir.
That's funny.
I just came down to speak to Ed.
Speak of the devil.
I emailed you earlier on today, Ed,
and you didn't get back to me.
Why's that?
I never got your mail.
You sure?
Have you checked your
deleted items folder?
You might have deleted it by accident.
All right, I suggest that you guys rest
or do whatever it is you gotta do
to make sure you're ready
to work on Monday morning.
Or we could start tonight.
Silas, I love your enthusiasm.
Thank you, sir.
Get your shitty nose outta my ass.
Excuse me, sir.
See you guys in a month.
I'm expecting big things.
I'll walk out with you, sir.
I've actually got a few new ideas.
Silas.
Brown-nose little prick!
I've got that Friday feeling.
I seriously don't feel so good.
You'll be okay, once
you got some girls on you.
Hmm?
Let's get out of here now.
Yeah, I guess.
Yeah?
Ed?
It's me, Mikey.
Yeah, have you got anything from me?
Kind of.
What do you mean?
Well, I had a look at
the surveillance video,
and, well, you're the only
person that was in the room.
No, that's impossible.
You sure you looked at the right day?
Oh yeah, I'm sure, yeah.
I thought it was a little strange,
so I had a look at the
footage for the whole day,
but that's the only time
that you was in the kitchen.
In the video, your back's to the camera,
but it still looks like you
are talking to somebody.
Then, you make yourself a cup of coffee,
take a sip, you put it
down, and then you leave.
I don't even drink coffee.
Well, as you go to leave, it looks like
you're gonna collapse like
you've gone dizzy, or something.
Look, are you all right Ed?
You looked really sick when I saw you.
Ed?
Ed.
Have you ever seen something
that wasn't really there?
Or something that nobody
else could see, a person?
You just need to get drunk.
You know, you've been
acting weird all day.
And now, with this seeing things shit?
I've got this rash, and
it's really bugging me.
Rash?
It's not--
- I got stung
by something this morning, and
I haven't felt right since.
It must be some kind of reaction to it.
You should get that checked out.
Maybe you're allergic.
You're beginning to sound like Steven.
I'll leave it until tomorrow.
If it's not right then,
I'll go and see a doctor.
I'm sure it's nothing a
few vodkas won't cure.
Style creator, number-one hater
Number one hater, Number one hater
So, I heard they kick Snodgrass,
after Tim's last birthday party.
It was at that shit hole
bar around the corner.
Bar Mambo.
I know, wanna know why?
Yeah, go on.
Snodgrass goes in there and
gets shit-faced, as usual.
But I mean the kinda faced
that would put you in a coma.
Yeah.
So always a couple of girls at a table,
drinking a bottle of
champagne, having a nice time,
minding their own business.
Snodgrass goes up to one of
them and starts talking to her.
But she's like.
Fuck off.
He doesn't take too
kindly to this, however.
Grabs a bottle of her
hand, necks it in one go,
drops his pants, and starts
taking a in the ice bucket.
Now way.
- Seriously, man.
Apparently, when the bouncer came across
to kick him out, he was still shitting.
So, how you're feeling now?
Yeah, I feel better, yeah.
Here, try some of this.
It tastes like shit.
The worse it tastes, the better it is.
Hm, yeah.
Hoo.
It's 9:30.
Let's do it.
Style creator, number one hater
Try some of that.
Yeah, that's good.
Told you it was here.
I'm gonna take a piss,
I'll see you in there.
Can I help you?
No, I'm fine, thanks.
Talk to the lady.
Are you on a guest list?
Yes, we're with Sams and Spruce.
We?
It's Edward Arkham.
I'm here for my friend's birthday.
Hmm.
No, I can't seem to find
your name on my list.
Sorry, there's nothing.
Do you have any girls with you?
No, we're meeting a
bunch of girls inside.
Like I said, we're with Sams and Spruce.
Well, I'm afraid I can't
let you in this evening.
Why not?
You're not on my list.
Are you serious?
Sorry, not tonight.
Hey.
- Hey.
- Hey, how ya doin'?
Nice to see you.
Members.
My name is on the list.
Look, you've heard the lady.
Just go somewhere else.
Lemme talk to the manager.
Sorry, the manager is
unavailable at the moment.
You can try again tomorrow.
Why don't you just go home?
Why don't you eat shit and die,
you uneducated imbecile?
Do you realize how pathetic your job is?
Please, let me go.
Standing outside a
door, wearing some cheap,
shitty suit, trying to look important?
Please.
I'm on the list.
I'm on the fucking list.
What do you say I go through it?
Townsend?
Ladies, this is Edward.
Hi.
Ed, have you met Anton?
Ed, Ed?
What are you on?
It looked like.
What are you doing here?
Are you okay?
I'm fine.
I saw you on the bar.
I just thought I'd come over and say hi.
So, how have you been?
You look shitfaced.
That's because I'm shitfaced.
Ed, why do you do it to--
Who are you here with?
Just this guy I've been seeing.
Yeah, what's his name?
Tye, you kind of met
him before, actually.
Are you okay?
Why haven't you called me?
I thought we were gonna be friends.
Hi.
I know it must be a bit awkward
Are you serious?
Ed we talked about this,
why can't you just forget?
I have forgotten about it.
You're the one who keeps emailing me
and sending me messages.
Because you said--
I don't wanna be your friend, all right?
I can't believe you'd be okay with this.
It's not my fault.
Fuck you.
Let's go.
Oh, sorry.
Let me get you a drink.
Watch yourself.
It was an accident.
What are you having?
How are you doing, Ed?
What's happening to me?
Huh, how are you doing this?
Huh?
What have you done to me?
I haven't done anything to you.
That looks nasty.
You oughta get some cream for that.
Why is this happening to me?
You're the smart one.
A senior software analyst,
looking out for yourself.
I meet you for the first
time in my life this morning.
You start asking me all these questions,
then all this weird stuff
starts happening to me.
And now, this.
This, whatever this is.
Are you saying this is my fault?
You made all the choices.
No one made them for you.
This is all your own creation.
My own creation?
You really have no idea, do you?
Ed.
I'm afraid you're fucked.
Been looking for you everywhere.
What's the matter, Ed?
Ah, not talking to me.
Leaving already?
Very sensible.
Thanks for coming.
Ed.
There you are.
I need another drink
Fuck off, Pablo.
What?
He is totally gone.
Ed?
Ed.
Look, I'm worried about him.
What if he gets mugged or something?
He'll be all right.
Please, go after him.
We can drop him off on the way to mine.
Look, I'll never forgive myself
if something happens to him.
Edward.
What?
Shut up.
Edward.
Tye.
Why'd you come after me?
Emergency operator.
Yeah, I need an ambulance.
I'm on St. Marcus's Passage, E1.
Please, please come quickly.
Why'd you come after me?
It's not my fault.
Fuck you.
Ed?
You're awake.
Where am I?
Well, Edward, you've had
quite a nasty knock on the head.
One of your neighbors found you
lying outside your apartment.
What's the last thing you remember?
Nothing.
I can't remember anything.
Do you know what your name is?
I heard you called me Edward.
Yes, you told the paramedics
your name was Edward. When
they resuscitated you.
Resuscitated me?
Let me fetch you a doctor.
Time heals all wounds, Edward.
What happened to me?
You received a nasty knock to the head.
But you're gonna be fine.
Who are you?
We've had this conversation before.
Nicholas Lemarchand.
Your hand, it's freezing.
I'm Dr. Rathkin, by the way.
.I've been treating Edward for some time.
Is he okay?
He suffered a minor skull
fracture due to a heavy fall.
He has a concussion, but he
should make a full recovery.
He was in an awful state when
he arrived, very distressed.
Mumbling about some sort of rash
that had apparently
spread across his body.
Ed.
You look like shit.
Why do you torture
yourself like this, Ed?
Yes, his condition seems to have
deteriorated quite significantly.
You remember me?
I remember.
Steven.
We're here for you, Ed.
We're not going anywhere.
At our last session,
Edward exhibited symptoms
indicating a kind of psychosis.
As far as I can ascertain,
Edward has a form of
paranoid schizophrenia.
Half an hour to get a bloody sandwich.
This calculator is mine.
You know what brought it on?
Laura?
Some people just crack
under the strains of life.
Edward came home one night
to find his girlfriend
in a compromising situation,
and that was enough to
push him over the edge.
Alcohol and illegal substances
didn't exactly help his mental stability.
I've got something
that will get you in the mood.
Try some of that.
Presumably, he's on medication.
Oh yes, indeed.
I had him on antipsychotics.
But when I saw him on Tuesday,
he accused me of trying to poison him,
said that he hadn't been
taking his medication.
I suspect he's been off
them for some time now.
Edward, you need to make a decision.
We can help you make it.
But you need to stay with us.
Going into cardiac rest.
Get a defibrillator in here, now.
Clear.
- Clear.
Nothing, again.
Clear.
I have a
feeling we're gonna be seeing
a lot more of each other.
It's a dangerous place
And you'll know how to behave
He killed her heart
She took his soul
On the subject of cutting
It all feels numb
When you can't was off the smell
You really don't want to live
You really just want to
So much blood
Too much blood
Where'd you get your delusions from
One, two, three, four
Blood in my eyes
I've got blood in my eyes
I've got
Blood in my eyes
I've got blood in my eyes
Reconstructive surgery
You can specify how old you want to be
Snake heads
They're just snake heads
They're gonna get chopped off anyway
When men start mutilating
their favorite girls
Then something scary has
been let loose among us
I feel like an explosion,
the smoke, the sheet
Indescribable
Too much blood
Where'd you get your delusions from
Come on
Blood in my eyes
I've got blood in my eyes
I've got