'One.
'Two.
'Three.
'Foun
'Five.
'Six.
'Seven.
'Eight.
'Nine.
'Ten.
'Eleven.
'Twere.
'Thirteen.'
And what was your last job?
Well, er... I've kindajust done
odds and ends to get by, er...
You know, waitress, cleaning.
I just really would like a job
doing something
where I could feel
like I was doing something good.
This is our training room.
We don't get to use it that often, but
it's great to have when we get to use it.
We help support individuals
with disabilities in the community
to live in their homes
and have lives just like you and I.
And here's our kitchen
where the dsp stores serve food
and prepares their lunches.
The hours are kinda crazy.
You come in
and work two days on.
Then you come back
and work two nights on
- and you have to stay awake all night.
- Ok.
I... I don't sleep much anyway
so that'll be fine.
This is the area they come in
if they want to do puzzles or whatnot.
- And this is Patricia.
- Hi.
Patricia, can you say hi
to my friend, Katie?
How are you?
Hi, Barbra.
Can you say hi to my friend, Katie?
- Hi there.
- Hi.
- How are you?
- Good.
Good.
You guys said hi
to my friend Katie?
- Hello.
- Hi. How are you doin'?
- You getting sleepy, Ricky?
- No, I ain't sleepy.
We're getting ready to eat, ok?
- This is Jeffrey.
- You getting hungry?
- Danny.
- Yeah.
- And this is Stephanie.
- Hi, Stephanie.
Hi, Stephanie.
This is my friend Katie.
She's gonna be working
in your home.
- Hi.
- Is that ok?
Yeah.
- This is declay.
- Hi.
Brittany.
Hello.
This is Katie. She's gonna come
to work for us, guys.
Look at that pretty colouring.
What are you colouring?
Are you colouring?
What's that?
That's pretty.
And this is Brandy.
She's gonna be who you're following
for the next few days.
- Hey.
Can you take her on?
I'm gonna go up.
I've got some things I need to do.
- Sure.
- Finish the tour.
- Thank you.
- Mm-hmm.
So this is our room
we use for the clients for the jobs.
They train in here for that. They're
all out for the day right now, though.
Ok.
Our computer room.
You do your notes
and stuff like that in here.
- A lot of employees just gossip mainly.
- All right.
We use this area over here
for our planner outings in the morning.
- That's what are they.
- Ok.
We have puzzles.
They love working on puzzles.
Pretty.
We usually hang them up
but we got a couple
that rip them off the walls.
If they get tired
they can rest in there or whatever.
- Ok.
- Here... it's the moors.
Is what their medications they get,
what the doctor prescribes,
all health information.
We use this room
for physical therapy.
If they're sick and wanna take a nap,
they'll just come in here and lay down.
You make sure you keep
your medications locked at all times.
And you lock the door
when you go out.
You'll get used to it,
it ain't no big deal.
That's a lot.
- Are those your trophies over there?
- Yeah.
What'd you win them for?
Basketball!
- You must be good.
- Oh, yeah. Good.
- How many trophies do you have?
- Two.
Two, two, three.
- So you like fishing?
- Yeah.
Where do you usually
go fishing at?
What kinda fish
do you like to catch?
How do I help you?
What's on it?
Fish! Ah! Er...
Large fin. Like this.
And... oh!
I don't know.
Fish!
- Are you making me a picture?
- Yeah, your picture.
Oh, it's pretty.
- Do you want help colouring?
- No, I can do it.
You can do it yourself? Ok.
I might mess it up.
Can you put your name on it?
You wanna do that in red or green?
Green? Yeah.
You have a lot of friends in here?
Yeah?
Oh, I love it.
- It's for me?
- Yeah.
Done.
I'm done.
Oh, hey.
How was your first day?
It, er... it felt really good.
Brandy said that you did
really well with the clients back there.
It was... it was a lot of fun.
So where are you staying at?
I know you're new in the area.
I actually got a place
in the country.
It needs a little work,
but I'm hoping to stay there for a while.
'Your family didn't understand you.
'They didn't deserve you.
'You have a new family now.'
'The devils.
'They listen to the sounds
of the innocent.
'One.
'Two.
'Three.'
'This is Katie.'
she's gonna be our guest
for a while.
Go on.
You're ready for this dance.
All right. Let's go get in.
All right, come on
and get in over here.
- Go around the front.
- Do you sit up here in the front?
Getting in on this side?
Do you wanna get in
on this side or the other side?
- Yeah. The other side.
- Yeah?
Do you want me to bring
Stephanie over there?
Right, I'm gonna scoot over you
if you don't mind.
- I don't mind.
- Can I sit by you, Steph?
Thank you. Oh, thank you.
All right. Are you buckled up?
- You need a tissue?
- Yes.
Well, you got two in your hand.
Who's ready to go dance?
- I am.
- You are? You excited, Petra?
- Er... I guess so.
- We're almost there.
Hold on.
Don't take your seatbelt off yet.
All right, come on.
Let's go dance.
Hold on, stephie.
- Stephie kinkle!
- Uh-oh.
- Hold on.
- You gotta sit down and wait your turn.
- Are you ok?
- Yeah.
My... my head'sjust hurting me
all of a sudden.
Let's go ahead and have a seat.
Go ahead, Jeffery.
All right.
All right, Petra.
What kind do we have?
I think I just want cheese.
Can I sit by you? Ok.
Ok. I'd like to take this time
to welcome Katie to our team.
Can you say, "hi, Katie"?
- Hi.
So if she needs anything
you guys help her out
cos we need her
to hang around for a while.
Thank you.
She's never done this
for anyone else before.
Are you ok?
Yeah, I'm just getting a headache again.
Can I use the client bathroom?
Yeah, that's fine.
It's gonna be fine.
It's too soon anyway.
You sure you're ok?
Yeah, I'm good.
"'The blood shows the devils
the way."'
'For a life is given
and the devil is born.'
You're at the group home
tomorrow night, don't forget.
- Ok.
- I hope your head feels better.
I'll be ok. Thanks.
All right. Call me
if you need anything, ok?
'You are so special.
'If you only knew.'
Hello. We're home.
We have some pretzels.
Hey.
- Hey.
- Let's shut this for ya. Oh, careful.
- All right.
- Ok.
- Does this just go down?
- Yep.
All right.
All right, watch your fingers.
You know, this door will usually
be unlocked. But this will let you in.
Ok. Sounds good.
Here, let me get the door
for ya.
- It's nice.
- Yeah, it's cosy. They like it.
So this is stephie's spot
and she comes in and she plops down.
Don't try to take her spot
cos she's gonna let you know.
Is this where you
always sit, Stephanie?
Stephie, talk to ms Katie.
- Stephie?
- That's ok.
I want chicken and bread.
Chicken and bread.
She's talking about dinner.
You're already ready to eat?
- You wanna say hi to ms Katie?
- Yeah.
Hi. How are you?
This is the bathroom.
Steph's gonna use it so...
- All right.
- A little small.
Yeah.
- This is ms Patricia's room.
- It's pretty.
This is stephie's room.
She's gonna be up and down
all through the night.
You have to be awake,
very important.
Ok. I don't sleep much anyway,
so it's good.
Her pjs are in the third drawer.
Socks is in the second drawer.
Day clothes is in her closet.
All of her toiletries,
it's gonna be in the bathroom.
It sounds pretty easy.
I'm getting ready to head out.
All right.
Uh-oh!
Vehicle keys are here
if you need them.
Nothing too crazy happens,
you can call me.
Anything really crazy,
emergency contacts on the board.
We'll be good. I'm sure.
Bye, ladies.
See you in the morning, stephie.
Yeah.
All right. Have a good night.
Thank you.
You too.
What's in it?
Can you show me what you got?
- A dog.
- I like that dog. That's cute.
- And I got cell phone.
- You do? Who do you call?
- My brother.
- Yeah? What's his name?
Charles weber.
Ok. Brenda, do you have a birthday
coming up?
- When?
- The mall.
- Well, happy birthday.
- Thank you.
- What are we gonna do?
- Eat cake.
- What's your favourite kinda cake?
- Chocolate... chocolate cake.
- Me too.
- You too.
- Do you like it with chocolate icing?
- Yes, I do, yeah.
Hey.
- What are you doing?
- Hey.
- Yeah. Are you getting tired?
- Yeah.
Yeah. You gonna go to bed?
- Do you need some help?
- No.
No? Ok.
Your Walker's right here.
- Ok.
- All right.
You go ahead and go to bed then.
- Ok.
- All right. Here you go.
I'll help you get your Walker.
There you go. Night.
Night-night.
Hey, Brenda.
You ready to go to bed?
Yeah? Ok.
Let's get you up.
All right.
Here we go.
Let me get ya.
All right.
Here, give me your hand.
Hey, Steph, I'll be back to put you
to bed in just a minute, ok?
- Yeah.
- All right.
Hey, Steph.
Who are you talking to?
Yeah?
- You tired?
- Yeah.
Yeah?
Why don't we go ahead
and get up and go to bed, ok?
You can bring your pictures.
Come on.
All right.
There we go.
- Yeah.
- There you go.
All right. Good night.
Ok. Good night.
Get some rest, ok?
All right.
Good night.
'The blood shows the devils
the way.'
Well, you guys is up
and ready to go.
Yeah, everything went great.
That's awesome.
You guys must've knew
you was in good hands, huh?
Yeah.
All right. Who's is this one?
- That is ms stephie's.
- Ok. This is yours. There you go.
- Patricia?
- Yeah.
All right.
And there's yours, Brenda.
And what time
do I need to be back?
- Mmm, maybe back here around three.
- Ok.
Oh, good. Good.
Ok, guys. Centre time.
Hello?
Hey.
I didn't hear you come in.
Sorry. I, er... I knocked,
but I didn't hear anybody.
You need somethin'?
A cow heart if you've got one.
Come on, come on.
Get over here. Come on.
There you go. Come on.
So we use them all
to know when they're comin'.
You feel that down here.
You can feel that.
You can feel it beat.
It works a lot better
when it's not inside.
Be careful.
- Well, hey. Welcome back.
- Hello.
You wanna go in here?
You wanna go in and sit down?
- I'm gonna sit down.
- You gonna sit down there? Ok.
Hey. How are you?
Did you have a good day?
Let's go to your chair.
Sound good?
Ok. Hey, Steph.
You all rested up?
Well, I...
Oh, yeah. Like I said,
I don't really sleep much so I'm good.
Hey, er...
How was Stephanie today?
She stayed by herself
most of the day.
Why?
It was probably nothing.
I just...
All right.
Let's get you in here.
- Is that good, Steph?
- Yeah.
Ok.
Here you go.
That look good?
There's your spoon.
Steph, are you ok?
It's ok.
Stephanie is sick.
I'll get this out of your way.
'Where are you, mummy?'
'stop it!'
'mummy! Help me!'
'Please help me, mummy!'
Take a big breath in and out
one more time.
Ok, good.
Now...
Ok. Did you say
she got sick last night?
Yeah, but I didn't notice
a fever or anything though.
Ok.
I think she might have just a little bit
of a respiratory infection
and we'll just watch it for now
and maybe get some lab work
and see what that shows us, ok?
- Thank you.
- You're doing good. You're good.
Ok.
Hey.
We can't have you getting sick,
you hear me?
I'm not gonna let them
get you too.
Yes.
"'The devils.
"'They listen to the sounds
of the innocent."'
What you writin'? Stories?
No, I just... I just write things down
so I don't forget them, so...
I drink every night
to do the total opposite.
Are you ok though?
I just...
I just worry a lot, you know?
About Stephanie?
She hardly ever gets sick.
She just exaggerates everything a lot.
I hope so.
'You are so special.
'If you only knew.'
- Hey, Charles.
- Goodbye, ms Kenny.
Have you seen Stephanie?
You know where she's at?
I don't know.
Stephie, you wait on me, ok?
Unbuckle.
- Hey.
Sorry, it took us forever
to get here this morning.
Is she ok?
Yeah. She was like,
stuck in the bed.
I don't know,
it's like she was glued down.
'The blood shows the devils
the way.
'The devils.
'They'll call out for you
if you listen.
'Listen.'
'One.
'Two.
'Three.
'Fouh
'five.
'Six.
'Seven.'
"'A sacrifice
will keep the devils away."
On the left-hand side of this
are our dogs and our cats.
There are adoptions we like
to make sure that they have a yard.
- Do you have a yard?
- Mm-mm.
So we're needing something small.
Here are our cats.
- Who's this one?
- That's mr will pickle.
- There you go.
- All right.
- Thanks.
- Yes, ma'am. Be careful.
Hey.
You just won't be quiet, will you?
I'll come back for you
in a little bit, ok?
Hey, Steph. Did you do ok today?
Yeah. She threw up
on and off all daylong.
Is she doing any better now or?
No, we had her doctor's appointment
rescheduled for tomorrow.
Maybe they can do something
cos she's just getting worse.
All right.
Well, I'll take care of her.
- All right. Have a good one.
- You too.
Guys, stay in here.
I'll be back.
Hey.
Shh...
Beat a cat once,
they never come back.
Give it a place with a lot of food.
It'll keep coming.
Why so many?
To protect us. To call them.
To protect us from them.
To call them.
I'll teach you soon enough.
Stephie, you feeling ok?
Yeah.
We're gonna get you
all better, ok?
- Yeah.
- Poor thing.
Let's grab our lunch boxes.
Take this one, ok?
- Did you get a cat?
- What?
- A cat.
- Er...
I... I used to have one.
They're fixing to come back
and get her.
- Do you wanna go back with her?
- Yeah.
If she's good with it.
Stephie, you're gonna let ms Katie
go back with you?
- Yeah.
- Ok.
All right, Stephanie.
You ready to come on back?
All right. Come on.
We're gonna draw some blood, ok?
- Ok.
- Uh-oh.
Uh-oh. It's gonna be ok.
It's ok. Relax.
I'm just gonna tie this
around your arm, ok?
Hey, Steph,
you wanna look at me?
- Let's see your arm.
- Hey.
It's ok. Hey, it's ok.
All right.
- Ok.
- It will be quick, ok?
- A little sting.
- It's ok.
- Ok.
- Ok. It's ok.
You did good.
All right.
I'm just gonna clean you, ok?
With the alcohol.
It's ok.
See, that wasn't so bad, was it?
You need to rest up, ok?
Come on.
Come on. All right.
"'But if the devils find them,
their entrance must be blocked
"'by something that was once
part of the living."'
'Once part of the living.
'Find them.
The devils find them.'
Hello?
Hello. Hello.
All right.
"'Their entrance must be blocked
"'by something that was once
part of the living."'
'Once part of the living.'
'I can't wait
to show you the house.
'You are loved now.
'One.
'Two.
What the hell?
- Stephanie?
- Brandy, wait. Stephanie.
Brandy, just let me explain
for a minute what's going on.
Brandy.
Seriously?
Brandy!
Brandy. Brandy!
First off, Katie is writing
this weird devil shit in her notebook.
I came back to check on Steph,
Katie was asleep in the house
with this burnt-up cat.
- Just crazy ass shit.
- We can't have that.
The girl is just fucking crazy.
Can you sign this, please?
Listen, Stephanie is in trouble.
I'm just trying to help her.
She's not your concern any more.
Sign this so I don't have
to call the cops, please.
'It's gonna be fine.
It's too soon anyway.'
"'They must be taken
to the house.
"'It's the only way to protect them
from the devils."'
'From the devils.
'They'll call out for you
if you listen.
'Five.
'Six.
'Seven.'
Be careful.
Up, ms Brenda.
Let's go get ready.
Put your night clothes on,
get a shower, the good stuff, ok?
Here we are.
I'm gonna...
I'm gonna get your shoes on.
You got it? Be careful.
Hey, you wanna go
and get a drink?
- Yeah.
- Ok, let's go get it.
Come on.
I have it outside for you.
- I brought you a special drink outside.
- Oh, yeah.
Come on, let's go get it.
Come on.
Hey, look. It's right outside.
Look. Do you want it?
- Yeah.
- Ok. Let's go.
I'm gonna go get it.
You wanna come with me?
Come on. Good job.
Great. Good job.
- We'll eat later, ok?
- Ok.
All right, come on.
All right, girl.
Come on, come on.
We're gonna go this way.
Ok, stay on the road.
I'm gonna get the door for ya.
Ok. Here we go.
All right, girl.
'Listen.'
You want some chocolate?
Yeah.
It's ok.
I'm gonna help you feel better real soon.
I promise.
Yeah.
Ok.
Uh-oh.
- Ow.
- Ok, careful. Come on.
- Ok. You wait right here, ok?
- Yes.
"'Once the person
is in the house,"
a flame will draw the devils away.
'A flame will draw the devils.
'The devils.'
'One.
'Two.
'Three.
'Fouh
'five.
'Six.
'Seven.
'Eight.
'Nine.
'Ten.
'Eleven.
'Twelve.
'Thirteen.'
Stephanie.
Help.
Please. Please.
Stephanie.
Stephanie? Where are you?
Stephanie!
You will be the head of those
to deliver to them
the innocence he deserves.
There will be many in your path.
I'm scared.
They thank you, they thank you.
But you will not remember this.
'One.
'Two.
'Three.
'Fouh
'five.
'Six.
'Seven.
'Eight.
'Nine.
'Ten.
'Eleven.
'Twelve.
'Thirteen.'
'For a life is given
and a devil is born.
'But you will not remember this.'