The Serious Game
Subtitles by Nostromo
Lydia!
Once together with me
the priest shall ask you
if you want to be
my chosen friend
Bravo,dear dad! What are you going
to call it,"Pine in the sun"?
Routine!I suggest "Sun over pines"!
-But that, ah
Filip,don't joke with Dad!
Edvard Bergh discovered
the Swedish birch grove
Dad discovered the archipelago
pine. Well done
Painting it is not an art either,
I'm painting as well as I did 40 years ago
But selling it,that's art!
It takes time to learn
You're a great artist, dear dad!
Freutiger is coming here tonight.
Then we'll sing together!
-Baron Freutiger alone?
-Yes,that would be a nice quartet
Oh, no, clerk Lovén
and candidate Stjärnblom are also coming.
Lovén, that loudmouth?
Then please let me disappear
I would like to see that
A tenor who can shut
up when he hears others sing
I've never heard of anything like that!
You can sing according to your style
Yes, yes, but there will
be not much of a banquet
Perch, smoked ham, herring and
potatoes, that's all there is
Vodka and punch, beer and brandy.
What more is needed,
all glorious gifts of God!
-Good day, everyone!
-Good day Miss Lydia ...
Welcome
Do you have any brandy, little thief?
We have whiskey
That's fine. Then we'll drink the whiskey
and save the brandy
The moon, he shines,
the water glitters calmly and cold
The lilac, jasmines
spread the scent all over
The butterfly in gold and green
glimmers on the flower beautifully
The worm soon crawls
out of its gravel
It must be wonderful to have such
a beautiful voice as that of the clerk!
The born King of the songs
No, now I must go in and make sure
we get something to eat
Yes,please do that nice, good,
and beautiful sweet Miss Lydia!
Are you going to have
an exhibition this autumn?
For what purpose?
One can't,damn me,learn all
modern dirty tricks,I'm too old. Cheers!
-Cheers
Too old! When it comes to toasting all
nights and boozing like a trooper
then they are not too old!
Thank God for that Augusta
We have seen the bottom
of the world's swindle!
Lovén,he can only
look upwards because he is a tenor.
Stjärnblom, he is young.
Young people only see themselves
Consider us older as
pure staffage in the painting.
-Isn't it so, Arvid?
-Cheers
-Lydia?
-Meow
What do you think about it that?
-You and Lydia? To be married?
-Sure, why not?
None of your cheek,you old swine!
Cheers!
Just that you would
be in Stockholm this winter
and that we might see and
meet each other occasionally!
That's just enough for me
-Do you start at the Nationalbladet?
-Yes
It's one of my fifty-eleven
cousins ​​who has picked me
His name is Markel,
he is deputy head of the editorial office
I can just do that,like something else
You have to do something while you wait.
Waiting for what?
I don't know
Maybe for nothing at all.
That I could do
something that works out
Your future
The future, yes. What do we know about it?
Do you think
Do you think that you and I
could create us
a small world for ourselves?
We must try.
The table is served on the verandah.
At last, a piece of food should
really taste deliciously on the verandah
Yes, I promise
Singer! Here's the first!
I believe in you. I believe in you.
and I can wait!
... he only thinks of parting
Good night, my dear!
Good night, my dear
my dear love!
-Did you propose?
-When could I have the possibility?
-But she probably understood me.
-Sure! Your song was symbolic.
What do you mean?
I'm just thinking about your false notes.
Well yes, we are both young
and we can wait.
I couldn't stand the thought
of someone waiting for me.
Take it easy, you will
probably be the one waiting
One is expecting something from me
If I have that thought all the time,
then nothing will become of me
But it's Roslin!
Lydia, Lydia, have you seen what
a nice traveling companion we got!
May I say it was a
pleasant surprise!
Does Miss Lydia recognize me?
Well,wouldn't I remember Dr. Roslin?
Well, there's a few years ago.
Miss Lydia has become the
great lady!
The grand beautiful lady
-Miss Stille,my sister Esther.
-Good day
So you're done with sail ship
paintings?Had enough time for it
Yes, now I'll go in and sell them
You might need a couple of pines
to freshen up your castle walls?
Yes, I could
Yes, why should my gallery
be worse than the National Museum?
Or the Luxembourg gallery
But you know I have
a painting in the Luxembourg gallery
Well, I've heard that.
Yes, we'll see
It would be nice also
to revive our old friendship.
Dr Doncker Chief Editor
-Is Dr. Markel still here?
-Yeah,he is
Do you have the duty tonight?
Yes, I have, but now I'm going to go
and get a piece of food.
Good afternoon
You can say what you like, but
meatballs and brown beans
In any case, surpass
all the delicacies of the Orient.
Or what do you think?
Of course funny talk
What did you say?
Whom did you greet?
A girl I met in
the archipelago this summer
A family girl?
Sure, a family girl
Damn you,beware of that! Such acquaintances
are very good during summer
but if you continue with them,
you can get caught before you know it.
No,I'll probably will be beware of that
But maybe you can go
ahead and marry her?
On my income as a proof reader
and journalist volunteer?
No, dear Markel, I don't think so
Honors to your judgment,thank you
Before we hacks reach the time we can
defend bringing children into the world
With any luck
we'll be so old and ill-equipped
that we can no longer defend it.
And seduce her? Well, it has its risks
If you succeed, you will lose
all respect for her
and if you fail
then you'll lose all respect, which you
perhaps had for yourself.
-You don't know the girl
-No,if I did that
Then maybe I would have a
completely different view of the matter
Lydia! Some short summer days
of sun and happiness
And now the autumn has arrived
So, Mr. Stjärnblom
whistling Pathétique?
Whoops! I apologize
Well, by all means
But it fits perfectly. Then you
will go to the Opera and review tonight!
-Shall I?
-Yes
It's a little girl who will
make her debut as Margareta in Faust.
But our regular music reviewer
has become ill
I usually substitute for
him myself, but I'm going to dinner
Goodbye, goodbye!
Though my heart is stabbed deeply
Girl - watch out!
Remember, with ring on the finger
first you should kiss!
Remember with ring on the finger
first you should kiss
first you kiss
should!
Yes, that sounds good,generally
The girls probably know best themselves
in what order it should come
isn't it like that,Miss Stille?
Hope so. You get so much
expert advice these days.
There you got it!
Lydia doesn't need any advice
Thank you for the trust, dear Dad.
No, now I have to leave.
Are you staying long?
No,I'll stay for a while
and then I will come home
Yes, but this is good!
"Miss Klarholm's voice and singing talent
points to almost unlimited possibilities."
"Her acting, however, indicates
a lack of instruction."
"Margareta will only
go insane in the prison scene"
"but Miss Klarholm played insane
almost from the beginning"
"This Margareta
seemed born insane."
That was not bad! People don't like
to hear too much praise about others.
However,the one who receives the
praise thinks it is never enough
and the others become jealous.
But if a critic scolds a
commander or a singer
then ONE will be sad and
all the others will be happy.
So just go on scolding,you should try to
spread some joy among humanity!
Thanks
Good evening!
-Yes, yes, old Stille is dead.
-What are you saying?
What is it? How can it affect
you in any way?
I knew him a bit.
Yes, he was old
and we are all going to die
Almost everyone
As Louis XIV's court preacher added when
he saw that the king's face went gloomy
I've not heard at all
that he has been ill
No, he hasn't been either,
it was a tram accident.
How did it happen?
He had been binging
with some happy blokes
And then he would take the tram home
did not think he was
more than sixty years old
He tried to jump on the trailer,well
then he fell and hit his
head on the street.
Here is the obituary
from the Nordic Family Book.
Can you be kind enough and take it
because you knew him
You could probably write to something
that is a little more personally tinged
I'm going down
and look at the printer's error
Excuse me,where's the advertising and
announcement department?
Please, it's up there.
I was going to ask to
publish a small notice
Thank you for everything beautiful
that was written about dad
-But I couldn't find the way.
-I can show the way.
Thanks
But why such a hurry?
Don't you want to sit
with me for a while?
Yes, if it is possible
Aren't you going to take off your hat?
If it is suitable? Someone might come
that will look awkward
No one is coming.
Is this where you sit and write?
Sometimes
Most of the time I sit in the
large editorial room
along with fifty other poor hacks
But if someone wants you for something?
You take it very easy
You can take it easy
It is not that much respected
in this editorial office
but one thing is respected
unconditionally, a closed door.
What are you going to do
now when your dad is dead?
I'll try to find a place.
Yes, I have to work. Dad did
not leave much behind.
Thank you for sending the wreath
-What are you're going to work with?
-With anything
If the Lady in the
house wants to shop
I don't have any special abilities.
Domestic work is the only thing I can do.
Do you remember when we saw each other
at the restaurant?
You were in the company of a gentleman.
That was Doctor Roslin.
Markus Roslin, the cultural historian
and archaeologist? -Yes
An old friend of Dad. He has an estate
in Sörmland called Stjärnvik.
I have to tell you something.
The next day I felt a completely
irresistible longing to talk with you.
So I went up to the house where
you live and rang the doorbell
Lo and behold.
But you only rang once.
I couldn't imagine that it was you.
I don't like to ring more than once.
I also respect a closed door.
Lydia
May I ask you a question?
Yes
You must promise me not
to get angry with me
No
Are you..?
Are you ... an innocent girl?
Yes, you witnessed that
Are you angry at me for asking?
No
Do you know what I was thinking
when you didn't open?
I thought like this
"Then I have nothing
to save myself for."
-Yes but ..
-That's it
Lydia
I can't think of marriage ...
other than as in a distant future,
you have to understand that.
Yes
But if you wanted to be
my secret lover...
No, I don't want to be a burden for you.
Everything else, but
not a burden for you
I must go now.
-Am I not allowed to see you some time?
-I don't know
I want to whisper something in your ear
I want to, but I don't dare.
"I want out .and so far, far
away" Lydia(In Norwegian)
-Damned!
-What then?
Look for yourself!
Engaged
What do you think of that?
That girl is not content with trifles!
Markus Roslin! At least 600000!
-600 000?
-Not a penny less.
And can you imagine
She's the only girl I've ever
loved. Seriously, you see!
Two weeks after old Stille's death
I wrote to her and proposed
Honestly,correct
As I believe with exact information about
my fortune, a little over 200000 crowns
I got an answer immediately.
Signed "Respectfully"
Then you can roughly imagine the content!
- "I want out"
-What did you say?
Nothing.
Well, then of course I thought
she found me too old
Forty-six years and she nineteen.
I must admire her steadfastness
in the prospect of being well supported
But Roslin is over fifty, so it was
not the age that was wrong with me
That was not the cause
Dear Freutiger
you don't think seriously
that the difference in wealth
was the decisive factor for her?
Yeah,what the hell are
you else going to think?
You must have money for living
But a little more or less,
she has probably not thought of that
No,perhaps not
I guess she just thought Roslin
was a little more in shape than I was.
And then she can expect to become a widow
a few years earlier with him than with me
We should hope that she soon finish him
off, he is a frail weakling
That she would be in love with
him is out of the question.
Would you like to have dinner with me?
-Thank you but I probably can't.
-We'll eat well, drink like hell!
Thanks,thanks
I have to go to the newspaper.
No,but Markus
Do you like it?
Like it? It's wonderful!
It's more than that, it's a relic.
A relic? Tell me!
I bought it thirty years ago
for a woman I loved.
But she betrayed me before she got it.
Then I promised myself that
no one else would wear it
Than the woman who would mean more
to me than anything else in the world
And that woman ...
That woman is you.
-If you let me down ...
-No Markus
We have just returned
home from our honeymoon
-You're young, I'm old.
-But we will share my youth
Then I will share your old age.
If you let me down, you'll never
wear that ring again, you promise me.
I promise!
But then you must also
promise me something.
Yes
Taste this omelet
before it gets cold
I just got it ready
Yes, that's fine,I'll have a look!
Thanks
Will you come and have
dinner with the builder Randels?
-Absolutely not
-Why not?
You've given me a reason,
I'm not invited.
It doesn't matter
I have some cards here that I have had
to hand out among desirable persons
So just put the name in there.
Come on, never hurts to
show up,I'll tell you
I must admit that Randels doesn't
exactly belong to the highest society.
Yes,then welcome !
The Director and Mrs Jacob
Randel have the honor
to invite Mr Editor Arvid Stjärnblom
to dinner 13th October at 6 pm
Nice delicious study,isn't it?
Refined
And so similar ... so natural, I mean.
Extremely natural
I got it in Paris.
The French they know!
6000 francs! A nice sum of money!
But it's worth it,isn't it?
I don't know if it is,you can get
a real alive much cheaper.
How can Mr Markel know that?
I know someone who has tried.
Dagmar! Dagmar!
Is no one inviting you to dance?
No! But I
was just going to invite Mr. Stjärnblom!
I dare not even dream of such an honor!
Gallop!
It was strenuous!
You start getting old.
Yes, we all do
Isn't it fun to be with the
grown ups and play too?
-I will be 26 years old on the 20th
-Yes, it's awful.
What should I say when I
turn 28 on the exact same day!
But really, do we have the same birthday?
Yes, that was funny!
-Do you want something to drink?
-Thank you,with pleasure
Well,there we have the conqueror
Yes,I saw her just when the
girl came here with her
Damned you! Beware!
Randel has an atrocious business.
You've already told me that
-It's nothing I want at all
-You don't realize it
This rose costs two crowns
this season,at least!
The girl wants to get married.
Look, Markel, you don't want to imagine me
that I,with my small salary would be
a favorable match in her eyes?
No, it's she who imagines
that her father is rich
and that she is a favorable party.
-And she wants to get married!
-But not I.
What does it help
You don't choose your destiny
not your wife,your mistress
and your children.
You get them, and you have them.
You may lose them.
But you don't choose.
-Good day,Mr. Stjärnblom
-Good day, Miss Randel.
-The letter was to you.
-To me?
Just a small thank you
for the beautiful flower.
I feel unworthy and broken-hearted
I had not sent you
any flowers!
No, why would you do that?
It is neither in the Bible
nor in the Catechism
That you shall send
flowers for birthdays
You only do it when you feel like it
And so I got the urge
-Where are you going?
-Yes, I was going to have dinner.
-Are you very hungry?
-No
Do you not feel like taking a
short walk then?
I was just going to suggest it
You understand that I
can't think of getting married at all?
No, that's something
I've not be thinking about
I understand quite well that
you don't want to get married.
Almost all marriages become
unhappy nowadays
Is it your stepmother you're lamenting?
No, Dad's probably fine.
That's fine
But Arvid
when you don't want to get married
is it just because you can't afford it?
I never said I did not want to,
I've said I can't.
-Yes but
-But what?
Dad has said that if I get married then
he will contribute to the household.
My dear, I don't want to be
financially dependent on your father.
But dependent, Arvid..
So far, I've been able to
sort myself out somewhat.
It's evident you'll
sort it out yourself
Tomorrow I have to go straight to my father
and mother out to the countryside again.
Who knows when I may be
able to travel into town next time
In a way suits us both
Doncker and I have just agreed
that I will do the continent this summer.
Do the continent?
Travel about a few weeks
watch some cultural events,
do some great interviews
And music?
Mm, everything possible, you have
to try staying all-round.
Who knows, in a few years I may
be the foreign editor of Nationalbladet
-And still music reviewer?
-Mm
Then with double pay?
But Markus
why don't you want a child?
Because I'm a genius!
Yes, it is said between us
And don't spread it
But I'm a genius
and children of geniuses
often become idiots.
That's why I don't want children.
But it is possible that the
child would take after me
And I'm not a genius.
Of course you are,
a diplomatic genius.
But you are first and foremost
my wife.
I'm a woman!
I would like to have a small child.
It's probably not part of his program
No, he bought me as
his legal mistress!
But Lydia?
Don't think about that.
Now you are going to travel
Travel?
And look at the latest harvest of Greek
vases and ancient broken statues!
Dagmar! What is that?
What is it?
Dagmar
What is it,little child?
-Has something happened?
-Yes
Just don't
My stepmother had heard some talk
about us and so she gossiped to my dad.
It was not malicious,she is not mean
but she lives in gossip.
Dad became terribly angry
and interrogated me.
Of course,first I thought of
denying everything
but then I was ashamed and you know
I couldn't
And when I said ..
Yes,what did you say?
That we were secretly engaged.
But what did you want me to say?
Well,no
No, you couldn’t say otherwise.
Well, what did your father say?
At first he called me
a slut and enjoyed the pleasure
But then he calmed down
But then he said that he stood by
the two thousand if it came to marriage
He said nothing bad about you.
Is it really that impossible
for you to get married?
It seems to me
rather impossible.
Don't cry,dear!
Don't cry
We must try to do
the impossible
Arvid
Welcome, Mr. Stjärnblom! Yes, little Dagmar
has prepared us for your visit.
And that's probably how
"La belle Hélène" sings:
"We must have love, but never too small"
My husband is waiting for you
inside his room please this way
Jakob!
-Welcome, Mr. Stjärnblom!
-Thanks
Yes, my daughter has
told me how it is ...
Does Mr. Stjärnblom want to drink
a glass of punch?
Thanks
Please
Well, the newspaper business is not as bad
these days as it used to be before
No, by all means, you can
drag yourself forward.
The youth must not have
too great pretensions.
But to begin with, we can
drop the titles. You can say uncle. Cheers
Cheers, uncle
Yes, your newspaper is going forward!
Yes,probably.
I met Dr. Doncker
at a dinner the other day.
He wanted me to buy
some shares in the newspaper.
Well,now I'll enter into
a form of clash of duties
As an employee of the newspaper,I should,
of course,advise my uncle to buy shares
but as my uncle's possible
son-in-law, I must advise against it
Well,it doesn't matter
I have nothing to buy for
These are bad times.
Well, have the gentlemen come to any
result? Food is served!
Ask Dagmar to come here.
Yes,my little girl,now you'll
get the man you wanted.
And above all, I want to
put to your hearts
a small verse from the old book of Psalms
"Thou shalt not commit adultery,
as that would be a great torment."
But Dad !
Yes,that's really true is,
I know it from my own experience
Now we'll go and have a
schnapps and a sandwich, come on!
Married
Arvid Stjärnblom and Dagmar Randel
-Ester
-Yes?
Who's coming
to dinner today?
The old ordinary. Stångbergs. Wulfcronas,
Gaddes, and Lundgrens from Sjötorp.
Mrs. Lundgren has had
a couple of cousins ​​visiting
so there is always a bit of variety.
And Captain Linde at Berga?
Yes, of course, what
else would the girls say?
My husband travels tomorrow to the
Archaeological Congress in Amsterdam.
Lydia
Lay down
Now you must sleep
There you go
Good night, sleep well
Well,now,how do you think I look like?
Nice. Adorable.
It's awful just wearing this old dress
when,for once,we are going to Donckers
I can imagine you wish for something
Last year, we at least had Dad's
quarterly contribution to fall back on
It was not fun for you
when it dried up.
Dear Dagmar
Frankly, I never thought we
would receive that appanage
more than the first year
I didn't dare to think further
I have nothing at all to blame your father.
I had no illusions.
You, if they were to ask me to sing
tonight,what shall we suggest?
Let us hope they'll not ask you.
Where is the ring?
- Emma! -Yes, my Lady
-Has Emma seen Mr. Stjärnblom's ring?
No
Oh, my God, he must have his ring
Yes, it doesn't matter,
we can't be late to Donckers
The ring may be found later
Emma, ​​it's probably not that late tonight
Emma doesn't go out,I mean
if the children should wake up
That's all right, come on,
come on, let's go.
Do you, as a matter of principle,
never wear a wedding ring?
No, I make it a principle
never to have principles
-I forgot it, quite simply.
-Can you forget something like that?
You can forget just about anything.
-Forget what?
-The wedding ring!
What? Forget the wedding ring, listen
Now just confess why you
put it in your vest pocket
No, I certainly didn't,
I forgot it.
-I have placed it somewhere
-Yes, that is absolutely true.
Is that true?
Arvid is certainly not
that kind of husband
who puts the ring in the west
pocket when it suits him,doesn't he?
There you have it,I'm exonerated
No, now I unfortunately have to leave
-Opera.
-Yes of course
Mrs. Klarhom-Fibiger as Senta in
The Dutchman for the first time
Yes, it can't be passed unnoticed
The second act begins just
before 9 pm,just in time
- Will you come and pick me up later?
-Of course
At what time?
I must go down to the newspaper after
the opera I can be here at 12 o'clock
Or one o'clock or two o'clock
Yes,I know that
No, go home right away.
Unfortunately, I have to go home early.
I can never be sure that our
maid stays at home with the children.
That's a tragedy
-Yes,good night
-Good night to you
Yes,not easy to be the wife
of a journalist,isn't it?
It's getting worse, Mrs. Stjärnblom
Worse? Why?
Yes, he doesn't know anything yet,
but can you keep a secret?
Indeed
Senta's Aria from Flying Dutchman
Are you happy?
No human being is happy.
You have to live anyway,
as best as you can.
Yes, you have to
Did I scare you? I knew
it would be late because of your newspaper
I found your ring.
-Well, where then?
-In my bed.
What are you doing?
I'm just checking the accounts
You handle the bank
loan properly,don't you?
Yes,you stay calm
Yes that would be awkward
if Baron Freutiger and Dr.
Doncker regretted signing
I don't think that would happen.
It'll probably get better soon, you'll see.
Dr. Doncker told
me something today.
Later tonight when you had gone
Guess!
You will be the foreign
editor in the new year.
And still have the music column left!
Think how much money
you're going to make, huh?
Then everything is fine.
Are you coming soon?
Who were with you at the Opera?
My sister-in-law, Ester Roslin.
She is so fond of Mrs. Klarholm-
Fibiger, like you, I understand.
What have I written?
"Mrs. Klarholm-Fibiger's voice is
of that kind."
"which evokes dreams and illusions" -
- "about a happiness
over all human and earthly happiness."
"about sensual pleasure
above all other sensual pleasure ..."
"... about eternity and bliss,
and eternal bliss."
- Did I write it last night?
-It looks like that.
It must have been because I was sitting
by your side when I heard her.
-It's a beautiful ring.
-Yes
I got it from Markus.
He took from me the promise to never
wear it again if I let him down.
And have you kept that promise?
Lydia!
Can you tell me one thing?
Where is Taunitzer See?
Taunitzer See?
Taunitzer See
I don't know.
It's probably somewhere in
Germany or Switzerland
Are you going there?
I probably wanted to
If only I could find out
where it's.
It should not be that difficult.
I'm afraid that will not be easy
I was awake last night thinking of
a place in "NÅR VI DØDE VÅGNER"(Ibsen)
And all the time it rang in my ears:
"Nice, nice
was life at Taunitzer See!"
And so I thought that lake
certainly doesn't exist ...
No, of course not.
That lake may not be
so easy to find on the map
Maybe that's just the beauty of it.
Do you remember the time
when you appeared on Nationalbladet?
Yes
I asked you something ...
I asked you for something
I remember ...
A bit vague. But I remember.
You replied,
"I want to, but I don't dare."
Did I really say that? Yes
Yes, that was that time.
Have you possibly become a bit
more brave since then?
Perhaps
Do you remember?
Yes ... and you've hidden it!
You got what you wanted.
Do you long for even further,
even further away?
Now I would like to change
that line like this:
"I want home, I want home
to my real home."
I just don't know where it is.
When did you write this?
Some years ago.
It was probably a short
time after my marriage.
"It has since become autumnal."
Yes, it has been early autumn
for both of us.
Ultimately,it depends upon ourselves
if we want to make do with the autumn
or make us a high summer.
Do you still care about me?
I can never in time and eternity
care about anyone else but you.
Once in your poor life,
you should still be allowed
-to try to find your way
to your Taunitzer See
I get up before you
Which room?
Number 12.
I was just missing going through
the rest of my life
without ever having belonged to you
That was just missing!
Taste this.
Is it as usual ?
Are you afraid of being poisoned?
In that case,it wouldn't be the first
time an old husband went that route!
The usual taste,I think
Are you saying that?
That was good, I feel it.
Yes, yes,my dear Lydia, I understand ...
You're uncomfortable here at Stjärnvik.
You would rather live in Stockholm?
Yes, I probably would like that
And why now?
Theaters, social life, and so on.
Maybe that too.
But that's not the important thing.
And the important thing is?
That I don't love you
and that married life
with you is a torment for me.
Love? Dear Lydia,I'm an old man,
but I'm not an idiot.
Have I ever asked
if you loved me?
No
I have to admit that
I have a suggestion for you
Of course,you'll get your freedom,
and 5,000 crowns a year in maintenance
provided you spend
three months here each year.
Two summer months, and one month
around Christmas and New Year
And in these months
everything would be as before between us.
I would be very happy if you would
give me 2000 a year, without conditions.
You still wear my ring
Yes
Why should I not do that?
No,why would not you do that?
And yet as it has become between us
lately ...
Especially these weeks
after your Stockholm trip before Christmas
I can't have the slightest doubt
that you have fallen in love with someone.
Your conclusions may
be at your own expense
Yes,my conclusions ...
my conclusions and the consequences!
The obvious consequence
of your new love is-
that you wish me dead and buried
every day and every moment !
-Am I not right?
-No but Markus
You don't have to answer.
But I don't want to be the reason
that one day will occur
some dangerous and criminal
thought in your dear little head.
I've been very much in love
with you,dear Lydia
and still I am
very much in love
And now you should get what you want.
What an idyll! Are you going to divorce?
Yes, we have agreed.
Congratulations. How much?
5000 crowns per year,
quarterly in advance.
No thanks, 2000. I don't want
more than I need for a living
But think about your reputation
People might think that you have
broken your marital duty
been fired with a paltry sum
But I don't care what people talk about.
And luxury I've never cared about
No but a small apartment in
Stockholm with two rooms
and included furniture,then
I've everything I could wish for
Then let me at least give
you money for the furniture.
I thank you for that, Markus.
"Dear brother Arvid! You have promised to
come out to me sometime ..
and look at my paintings. "
"You are most welcome tonight. There
will be also some..
other blokes "
"You have to stay overnight.
The last train leaves at half past twelve "
"and at that time we are enjoying
ourselves most.Your friend Hans Bergling."
Yes, he's not much for going to
bed at half past twelve
that chap Hans Bergling
Are you planning to go?
Well, what do you think?
But can you take time
off from the newspaper?
Yes, it's probably okay.
I absolutely think you should go
Would be fun for you to
come out and get a bit of variety
Well, maybe
Well, then I'll go
Cheers, Brother Bergling.
Think about when I wrote that letter
then Hans Bergling became almost
a living person for me.
-How does he look like?
-He is small and stocky
He has thick black brushy hair
Gray-yellow hanging mustaches
and a lot of paint smudged on the vest.
Shouldn't you give him
a pointed beard too?
No,it doesn't fit at all for his type!
As you wish
Imagine being so fake!
Yes, that's not normal.
Love one woman,
and be married to another.
It's a life which at most
could be excused if I were a poet.
A poet is excused
for just about anything
Nobody is a case unless wanting to
Poets are considered
less sane people
Have you ever loved your wife?
I have loved her in a Lutheran way.
What is that?
Dr. Mårten Luther had almost
four hundred years ago the opinion-
-that true love
arises of itself between
spouses when they do the
deeds of nature and love with each other.
And there may be a grain
of truth in that,possibly
but not much.
No not much
By the way, according to Luther, love
only belonged in marriage.
Outside of marriage ,
it was not love but fornication.
All sorts of ugly things
You may love me in a pagan way.
-Lydia
-Yes
I was thinking of something
when I went here.
What were you thinking?
I thought, is it really
that impossible
that you and I may one day live
and grow old together?
That I might one day die
with my head in your sweet lap?
You have a wife
that you love in a Lutheran way.
I may well be divorced
from her in the future
Right now it's not possible,
it would look too bad
Her father has been wealthy
but is ruined
Yes, I've told you that
Yes,yes
I haven't asked for anything else.
We have to adapt ourselves as we are.
As long as it can't be changed for us
I'm glad I got my name back
And myself
It is as if I have regained something
that I have lost or neglected.
Did you see my nameplate on the door?
Lydia Stille.
Nothing more and nothing else.
And other things should
never be on my door either
Neither Roslin, Stjärnblom
or anything else.
I don't pay much attention to
a name on a door
-but I sometimes dream
of a future for the two of us.
and you're not doing that
I love you.
Now you get to blow on it, blow on
It was fun to
see you in a good mood!
It's been a long time since
you were seen laughing
My dear, I'm so busy all the time.
-Emma
-Yes,my Lady
Now you have to go and drink chocolate.
Imagine yourself,
music reviews, foreign editing!
And every now and then a whole
evening with your friend Hans Bergling,
well then, I know that.
Maybe we should have binged a little less.
I don't grudge you that
Listen,speaking of him,should
we not invite him here ?
Yes, maybe we should
You know, a pretty weird
guy, that Bergling
He only cares about two things
in this world: painting and drinking.
In a family he would be unhappy!
Oh my God,but then it's
not worth us inviting him, is it?
No, I don't think so either
By the way, I have so
much else to do.
Yes, the summer break  is a concern
Yes, but it was kind of
your father to ask me and the girls
to stay with him all summer, huh?
It's just fun for
him to have you with him
He is well alone on his farm, of course
No,I don't think so.
An old forest officer is used
to having nature as his best friend
Yes of course
But in any case it will be fun
No, I don't have time with you!
I am so busy
Emma
But it was really your fault that
I didn't keep my word to my husband.
Yes?
I had just read your wedding ad
and I also wanted to live once
-And you kept your ring on?
-Why not?
Illusion and happiness it was
one of Markus's favorite ideas.
I applied it on him
and let him keep his illusions.
It lasted a long time?
No, hardly a year.
Why did you tell this today?
Because I met him yesterday.
I couldn't understand at all
that I had ever loved him.
What are you thinking about?
Nothing
Something that
I am not allowed to know.
No
I was thinking of something
that once might come
And what yet not is, nothing is
You must not think such
ugly stupid thoughts
Not today!
Don't you see where we are?
Can't you see the water?
It's Lake Mälaren.
It's not Lake Mälaren
It's Taunitzer See.
What does it stand for?
I have to learn Russian.
A foreign editor who can't
read Novoye Vremya, it's a scandal
Then how do you manage?
I have a young man I've placed who comes
up and reads the newspaper once a day
-His name is Kaj Lidner.
-Kaj Lidner
A deeply depressed young man.
25 years more or less.
At that age, everyone is
probably depressive
But it's a beautiful name he has
Kaj Lidner
Well, was there anything
in Novoye Vremya today?
Not much.
But
Here I have translated a piece
that might interest you
-Yes, why not ...
-But ..
you can easily decide to
delete my comments.
No. No, by all means.
Mr Lidner has strong sympathies
for the opposition, I understand?
Anarchist,perhaps?
Yes, you have to be something
while you wait for the end.
Why wait?
Mr Stjärnblom is right.
It would be better to take your own
life. If you only had a decent pretext.
That wouldn't be difficult to produce.
That you are poor and
that you are starving yourself
I don't call that a
decent pretext.
No, there are undeniably better pretexts
Yes
Thank you, thank you, Mr Lidner.
Oh, is that you ...
I've told you not to come
to me other than I'm waiting for you
Could have someone here visiting,
yes Ester Roslin or someone else.
It's something special today.
My father is ill.
He might die.
I have to go to him.
Forgive me.
Forgive me for speaking
so harshly to you.
You should never speak harshly
to the person you are in love with.
Is your father very ill?
Yes, it looks like that.
He is 74 years old, and he has never
been to bed before in his whole life.
Oh really
Yes, then you must go.
When are you going?
Tomorrow morning.
That was all with that dream.
I had enjoyed myself so much
that we should have this short
summer to ourselves.
Only the two of us...
My dear...
We'll see each other again.
You never know.
No one prevails over life and death.
But I don't know what else
would separate us?
Don't go! Not now, not tomorrow.
Wait a while and see if it is necessary.
I'm sure your wife is
exaggerating your father's illness
to attract you
Her letter is simple and factual
Don't make an impression of
exaggerations or other motives.
Just the fact that Dad is in bed
shows that it is serious
Yes, yes, the duty above all.
You go!
Goodbye!
Goodbye.
Arvid
We should not be separated this way?
Do you want to stay with me tonight?
Certainly.
As we have had it this summer,
we'll never get it again.
-Never again
-Lydia
When you come home again, you have
your wife and children with you.
And you have your work and your comrades
A whole world that is closed to me.
And the day will come when I will be
more trouble for you than joy.
But Lydia! I'm leaving,
but I'll be back!
I love you!
Why should we not love each other
always, always?
Of course
Always, always!
Or at least until tomorrow morning!
Here, where I lie,
I see through the window-
-how the Plough travels backwards
as usual.
It means...
... that I myself am moving forward
in comparison with the Plough.
All movement is relative.
My dear boy ...
I'm afraid you're weak for women.
Yes, it doesn't need to dishonor
a man-
-but it can drag him down-
-break his path
and close his way.
Arvid I have belonged to another man,
while you were away.
I felt so lonely, and I constantly
saw you together with your wife.
This is over now
I wanted you to know before we meet again
I couldn't have told you verbally
Lydia
Who was it?
Well, I've deceived and been deceived
I have deceived my wife with you
and you with my wife.
The only thing missing from the symphony
is that my wife is deceiving me
Even then do I have the right to complain
Admittedly, I had imagined that which
was between you and me
would be something special
something unique
something outside retaliation
laws and such baseness!
And of course, I didn't think when I
buried my old father
in the small cemetery of my hometown on
a quiet September day-
-that you were out
on gallant adventures at the same time!
But you have to accept everything.
I have to take it as we are
But one thing, dear Lydia,
I want you to bear in mind...
In the case of a woman's lovers
you usually apply the arithmetic
of the Australian Negroes
You only count to three.
And any addition is called many.
Thank you, that's enough.
Yes, that should be enough.
I was prepared for
reproaches but not for this
Really
You were prepared for reproaches
It surprises me
that you did not expect praise.
Lydia!
What do you want from me?
A woman with gallant adventures on
her conscience can't be something for you
Gallant adventures
What do you call it yourself?
You wrote that it was not love
No,it was not love
but neither the other.
Don't think about it now.
Who am I to judge you?
Actually, I've already forgiven you
Thanks
I have no use for your forgiveness .
You will never see me as a
repentant Magdalena
And never again will you see me
as a horrible beggar of love at your door!
Thank you, that's enough,you can leave now.
I want to be alone.
Lydia
Never look for anything more from me.
This can't go on.
I surrender to your mercy
I can't think of living without you.
You didn't want my pardon.
You scoffed it.
But I want your forgiveness.
Forgive me. Arvid
Arvid ...
I thought I saw you from my window
but I was not sure it was you
Come up with me.
No
You've delayed too long.
You've been torturing
me too cruelly and for too long.
Forgive me.
You came when
I saw you getting so desperate
This is the last time I ask you,
if you say no now ...
At least show him
the mercy of extinguishing the lights
So he doesn't have to see
lights in your window
when he goes down to the
cemetery and stares here
He has probably already
seen the lights by me
It's better that way.
Best that he once and for all got
it definitely that I am gone for him.
Thank you for coming.
I didn't dare to ask you.
I was so afraid of a no.
It was a beautiful funeral.
So it was him?
Oh he did the right thing!
I wish I could do like him.
Lydia ... Dear Lydia ...
What have I done?
He was so kind ...
There are many nice boys, and
you can't play with them all.
”Arvid!" Lydia...
"I belonged to another man
while you were away."
"I felt so alone."
"I saw you constantly in front of me
with your wife."
So you're still up?
How are you? Are you ill?
I happened to open the secret drawer
in the chiffonier
Now you know how it is
And you imagine I'm going to
accept that you are having a mistress
No, dear Dagmar,I haven't thought
of it,even for a moment
I sincerely wish,on the contrary,
that you don't want to put up with it
but filing for divorce
as soon as possible
Divorce? What do you mean?
Dear Dagmar,you must not have
really understood what it is like
I love another
Who deceives you, yes!
And you forgave her ...
That may not be the right word.
It's too much to sort it out.
But I don't want a divorce.
You've been unfaithful to me,that's
ugly enough of you
If you don't choose that it can be forgiven
Forgiveness implies
repentance and improvement.
I can't promise neither one
nor the other.
Don't cry, Dagmar.
I'm not worth that much crying.
I beg your pardon
Would you take the
forgiveness in that sense?
It's because I've hurt you
Maybe we both have
something to forgive each other
before we now part.
What do you mean?
-Have you heard anything about me?
-Not at all.
I'm thinking about that with
our secret engagement.
Yes? What's the matter with it?
You knew very well
that I didn't want to get married
You tricked me into
marrying against my will.
A marriage that begins in that way
must always be a little fragile.
Why would I open
that miserable box
If I had not done it,
then everything would have been as before
My dear,it couldn't have gone on like this
Everything must have an end.
At least tell me who she is.
Can you believe such a thing?
I'll probably find out.
Your Lydia may not
be that difficult to track down
Lydia is a signature.
In reality, she is called something
completely different.
I'm not as stupid as you think.
You can greet her from
me to be careful.
It's late now Dagmar
Shall we not say good night?
I'm lying here on the couch tonight.
By all means, I'll not stop you
from sleeping. If you can sleep!
Good night
Well, you're left! That's nice
Then we can drink our night grog here.
Maybe the gentlemen don't know each other?
They are Editor Stjärnblom and Mr. Törne.
Ture Törne who sang so beautifully
at our friend Kaj Lidner's funeral.
Yes, singing at a funeral is fine,
it's at least something personal
but by the way, it's the devil's
work being a singer and an actor
I thought it was a profession
that completely captured a person
In advertising, yes,
but it's a hell of a life
I hate to sing and play theater
-I want to write.
-I think so
Write, that's the future!
Just look at Stjärnblom!
Proofreader, music reviewer,
foreign editor
And now Doncker has appointed him
our flying correspondent as well
Cheers!
Cheers
Not bad
-Travel to the continent next week.
-Well? Alone?
Don't know. We'll see.
Yes, travel books are probably fine
but I will write theater,
I want to be a poet.
One has probably several
strings on one's lyre.
I already have a play ready.
Nearly
Here you will hear.
What kind of theater grandiloquent
at this time? No thanks!
Yes, but it's not
quite finished, I say
You can probably only listen
to a few test pieces
It will be a pleasure for us.
The play is about a young woman, Laura
von Stieler, is her name
Who is married to an old man
Historian and philosopher,
with a great name and very rich.
He owns a castle in Västmanland
and the first act takes place there.
But she doesn't love him.
She loves a young officer
who,however, abhors
his murderous profession
and wants to become a poet
Her father is also in the play
He is a painter with a
world-renowned reputation.
And has a whole wall full of
paintings in the Luxembourg gallery
Well, here we have their scene.
Laura to the man:
"Do you want to know the truth?"
He in a superior mood
"I don't care to know "
"The truth is harmful"
"It's illusions and delusions.
which is the essence of all
human happiness. "
Not so bad,eh?
Not stupid at all, a very
sensible remark.
It is on a terrace by a lake.
"Do you see the water?" she says.
"It's not Lake Mälaren
"It's Taunitzer See."
Which is it now? Mälaren
or Taunitzer see?
Taunitzer see, in "Når vi döde vogner".
Construction my boy! You
never get that on any stage!
Hello. Yes, I'm coming soon.
Too much text, of course.
Just as the last print form
Just a moment
"Construction"
That can be himself.
In fact, I made Laura
right after a living model.
I can just imagine that.
But don't ask me what her name is.
You never betray a lady.
Sure, of course not.
We've had a relationship with
her for a month or so
Now it's almost over.
But we might make a little
trip to Norway this summer
Is it already almost over?
Yes, one should beware of getting stuck.
You should at least
live a bit first
But how you look! How is it?
Has anything happened to you?
-Oh yes, in a way.
-But what is it then?
Can't you speak out?
I'll try.
I have heard incidentally
that you plan to make a short
trip to Norway this summer.
Well?
Where did you hear it from?
Is there more than one
I could have heard it from?
But Arvid, now get it over with
and tell me what it is!
There's not much to tell.
You're just the main character
in a theatrical play by Ture Törne
Written according to a living model
The author has also had a
relationship with that model for a month
A relation?
In one month?
He didn't mention your name.
He's a discreet young man.
Yes, I really do know Mr. Ture Törne
I don't know why I
didn't tell you
I haven't been in a
relationship with him
In that case
then Ture Törne would be able to become
a real damned good poet for the future
-Don't you believe me?
-Yes
Of course I believe you
If I may tell you the whole truth
so we've really kissed
each other a bit.
And so it has become a whole play
for him!
Yes, as I said, he will probably become
a damned good poet!
Arvid, you yourself have
probably understood
that it can't continue like this anymore
But if you still care about me
-And don't want to lose me
-Yes
Yes then you have to go through
the whole long story
With divorce new
marriage and everything
As hitherto,it can't continue any longer
Dear Lydia ...
I'll be leaving here soon, and
I'll be away for a very long time
Yesterday I thought,
"Soon my divorce will be over."
"Then I will ask Lydia to follow me
- now and always."
But a piece of the moon
has fallen since then.
Do you really think
this is the moment
is it appropriate to talk about marriage?
Well yes
So I have nothing to save myself for.
Where are you going?
I'll be the newspaper's
traveling correspondent.
When are you going?
In a week or so.
Good bye then.
Goodbye.
I wanted to say goodbye and also
I wanted to give you a memory of me.
It's just a small thing
A thing that you may have
use for sometimes.
Then maybe you'll think of me.
And you?
Don't worry about me.
I've made my choice.
And stick to it?
I love him
have never loved so much!
Be seated!
Pleasant journey.
Thanks
-When is Dad coming?
-He has left.
-When will he come back?
-I don't know. It can take a long time.
But he's coming back.
I know he's coming back
I just met him
whom I used to love.
and then I couldn't understand at all
that I had ever loved him.
Subtitles by Nostromo