25.000
Yoseph Shiloach
Yona Elian
Muhammad Bakri
Desperado Square
Editor:
Yoseph Greenfeld
What's the matter with Yisrael?
He overslept.
I don't know, he always wakes
the neighborhood up on time.
Photography:
Dror Moreh
Pull!
Pull.
- Be careful not to fall.
Don't worry,
Baruch.
Yisrael the Indian is arriving.
- He's late today.
Yisrael,
you asshole!
You're 10 minutes late.
I should be the alarm clock...
You? You'll have us
sleeping till noon.
No way.
I'm precise as a Swiss watch.
Yeah, sure...
Come down already.
It's getting hot here.
Producers:
Amir Harel & Haim Manor
All together now...
Director:
Benni Torati
It weighs a ton...
Did you speak to the synagogue
about the memorial service?
Everything's arranged, Mom.
How about the notices?
Yisrael plastered notices
all over the neighborhood.
Nissim.
Nissim!
I had a dream about Dad,
blew my mind.
I saw Dad standing
in front of the old theater.
You and Aaron were there too.
The whole neighborhood
was gathered around.
Dad was nailing the door
of the theater shut.
Everyone was crying
like little children.
Quite a dream.
- There's even more to it.
Then Dad tries to pry loose
the boards nailed to the door
but he doesn't have the strength.
He grabs me by the collar,
like this... Like this.
He asks me to help him.
But my arms are weak
and the boards won't budge.
Then Dad, with tears
in his eyes,
makes me promise I'll do
one final screening
to undo the vow.
A vow is no laughing matter, Nissim.
I'll tell you his exact words:
"Screen one last movie
to undo the vow."
"Memorial service -
Morris Mandebon"
How are you, Yisrael?
Avram?
Seniora.
You won't believe it.
Avram is back.
Avram? Which Avram?
Avram Mandebon. I just saw him
in the street, honest.
Seniora, he hasn't changed.
He looks exactly the same.
Yisrael.
Which Avram? Dad's brother?
I swear, Nissim, I just saw him.
I wouldn't lie to you.
What is he doing here?
He finally came to
his brother's memorial.
Enough.
- Why? Because he's an uncle?
Have a seat.
Want some coffee?
I've dislocated my shoulder!
One... two... three...
It weighs a ton.
Be careful!
What happened?
- You got up late today...
I'll play you a song
that'll set your hair on fire.
What's this?
- A mast for the bonfire.
Tie a rag doll to the top
and it'll be a great bonfire.
Make the doll a Brezhinev.
- No. This year it's De-Gaulle.
What?
Lt'll look better if you
twist it around like this.
You twist yours!
Do you owe me any money?
- I don't owe you anything.
Just asking.
Want to play again?
Show me some money.
Enough?
Pull up a crate.
Both face cards lose,
the ace is the winner.
Watch carefully.
Don't whine later.
Three cards: King here,
ace here, and queen here.
King here, queen here,
and the ace here.
Where's the ace?
- Morad, it's in the middle.
It's in the middle.
How do you flip a match?
Morad, do me a favor...
- Get lost!
Show me how to flip a match.
- Get lost, you Jellyfish!
Both face cards lose,
the ace is the winner.
David, how are you, honey?
Wait a second,
I want to talk to you.
Wait a minute!
Give me back my stockings,
you thief!
Do you hear me, David?!
Sarah, go home.
Your food is getting cold.
Queen loses, king loses.
Where's the ace?
Queen.
Let's play again.
He's broke.
Let him play for credit.
- I need a guarantee.
Where can I get a guarantee?
- He hasn't got anything.
He can wager the "mop".
- What?
Wager the "mop".
- Over my dead body!
Suit yourself.
Wait a minute, dumbo.
Morad, don't worry, he'll lose.
I can feel it this time.
Alright, the "mop"
against the entire pot.
Winner takes all.
- Agreed.
Sit down.
Stay out of it.
This time I'm on my own.
Morad, we'll hex him.
No hexing!
- Oh, alright.
Both face cards lose,
the ace is the winner.
Where's the ace?
Are you sure?
Up to your tricks again?
- No tricks.
You can still change your mind.
- This one.
Damn!
Give me the "mop".
Once he brings the money,
you give it back.
Remember, you give it back.
Bring the money,
get the "mop" back.
If he doesn't return it,
we'll pluck out his eyebrows.
Take good care of it!
Taking him for a joyride?
- Hi!
Oh my goodness!
- What is it?
What have you done to yourself?
He looks good like this.
He lost the "mop" to Yisrael.
He'll give it back to me
once I pay.
Sure.
So, planning to set
the neighborhood on fire?
The bonfire they put up
in the Ezra quarter
is nothing compared to ours.
It wasn't the real thing.
They only had tires to burn.
We'll use wood.
Isn't this a tire?
- No, it's for sitting on.
Will there be hot potatoes?
- Charcoal, more likely.
Who's that yelling?
Climb aboard.
Let's get moving.
Step on it, Baruch!
Don't take my gas canisters!
- I'll bring them back.
No, don't take them!
- I'll bring them back!
What's going on?
- Nothing. Clear the area.
He's taking my canisters.
I told you,
I'll bring them back.
Mrs. Leah, please step aside.
Now put them back
and beat it.
And don't raise any dust.
Do you think you're
the law around here?
It's between me and her,
so keep out of it!
Beat it before I spatter you
all over the place.
Enough, Nissim.
If I see you here again
I'll chop off your legs.
Get lost.
Mrs. Leah, don't worry,
we'll put back the canisters.
Bless you. He keeps
stealing them all the time.
Don't worry, he won't be
back again. - Thank you.
Wow, almost...
Aim it higher...
You did it, Morad.
You're the champ.
It's caught fire!
Morad. Here's Aaron.
Ask him about the clothes.
Playing with fire?
Aaron, how are my clothes?
The trousers are all right,
but the shirt...
Come later,
I've got a shirt for you.
What happened
to your hair?
Yisrael's got it.
- Playing cards?
I'll get it back but...
- Natural looks best.
Don't block the passage.
Let me try once.
Need any help?
- Hey, Aaron.
You've grown stout.
We're not children anymore.
How are you?
All right.
It's been 25 years.
Gone in a flash.
How did he die, Aaron?
Merciful God, Morris's heart
gave way in his sleep.
He went to bed
and didn't get up again.
Was he angry at me?
Ever since you left
something inside of him died.
He was never the same again.
He loved you, Avram.
He missed you a lot.
I made a mistake.
I should have come back
to talk to him before he died.
At least you'll say Kaddish
at the service.
Yonatan, make sure
the potatoes don't burn.
Don't worry, I'll manage.
How long has Avram been gone?
20, maybe 15 years,
I don't know exactly.
Much more.
At least 30 years.
He left the night Morris
and Seniora got married.
Shoo away the smoke.
I remember that wedding.
People drowned in tears.
Why did he leave?
Why? He and Morris
argued over the theater.
Go.
What's he come back for?
What for? To say Kaddish
for his brother.
He's a year late.
He asked about you.
Your turn.
Aren't you going
to talk to him?
What's there to talk about?
- Life.
Whose life?
We'll use a large board.
- Yes.
Here we install the crossbar
of the bicycle
and these are the handlebars.
The white wheel goes here...
One wheel over here,
and another over here.
What about axles?
- Axles?
One plank here,
and another over here.
How is it going to hold?
- Size 10 nails.
We overturn this crate
and install it up here.
It can carry lots of wood.
- A real jet wagon!
I can't get that dream
about Dad out of my mind.
That's because
of his memorial service.
George, he wants us
to undo the vow.
The place's been closed for
30 years. It's all in ruins.
So what?
We can get it
organized in a jiffy.
Hi there.
What are you up to,
building a spaceship?
We'll use it
to carry the lumber.
A lumber shuttle to
clear the entire neighborhood.
What are you doing?
I've been trying to open it
for half an hour!
Try the other way around.
- I knew it!
Any coffee?
- It's on its way.
Binyamin, how are you?
Okay, Mrs. Seniora. And you?
Fine. How much is this?
- 5 shekels.
And the apples?
- 6 shekels.
Need anything else?
- No.
Weigh them for me, please.
Hello, Seniora.
Weigh them, please.
Look at this.
- Great.
Now take it apart.
We need the fork.
- Alright.
Come on, Morad,
do your Tarzan bit.
Lay off it, George,
we've got a wagon to build.
Come on. You haven't
done it in a long while.
Just once for the gang.
Go for it.
You guys are something...
What's this yelling
first thing in the morning?
I almost lost my breath.
- Aaron, how are the trousers?
Bend your leg.
What is this?
- Gabardine.
This is gabardine?!
Even I can't tell what
this could possibly be.
Go to the tailor,
he'll make you a decent pair.
Tell him Aaron sent you.
Right on, Aaron!
Any coffee?
Aaron, could you operate
a movie projector?
Are you trying to rub
salt into my wounds?
Why do you ask?
We want to screen
a movie in the theater.
Which theater?
- Dad's theater.
Dad's theater is dead!
Dad came to Nissim in a dream
and told him to open the theater.
To undo the vow.
I swear, Aaron,
those were his very words.
You've got to ask your uncle.
What's he got to do with it?
He owns half the theater.
You're paying him
too much respect.
That's not the issue.
You should ask him.
Dad vowed to stop screening movies.
He never said not to go inside.
I'm going to open it.
He's not joking. We're going
to open the theater.
I'm going in.
What?
It's stuffy.
Look what we smoked
in the old days.
Our orangeade.
"Day of Vengeance,"
starring Juliano Jemma.
There's Lee Van Cleef.
Not with the scissors.
Don't cut any hair, Leon.
Put your hands here.
That's it, that's the way.
From here
and then round it out.
It's impossible, Yisrael.
- Spray it, then shape it.
How does Fuad
keep his mustache stiff?
Are the Mandebon brothers
going to reopen the theater?
Why would they?
Who goes to movies these days?
So what were they
doing there inside?
They can't go into the theater.
It would break the vow.
- What are you talking about?
I saw them with my own eyes.
Yisrael, get up.
Have a seat, Avram.
How have you been?
A shave?
"Desperado Square"
Hey, who invented the cart?
It's Morad's design.
He put together a jet!
You've got a criminal mind, Morad.
Sarah, what are you doing here?
Waiting for Jellyfish David
to come out of the club.
Did you bring the telephone pole?
You bet,
we busted our asses.
Don't worry, I'll find you more.
Who'd like to braid my hair?
Me, Sarah, please.
- Me, sweetheart.
No, me.
- Let me do it.
Yonatan first, then Baruch.
Let me iron out the curls.
Maybe later.
Give me your hands.
Your hair's tough as nails.
- Watch your language.
Don't pull it tight.
- Focus on the game.
You always blow it.
From beneath...
Dances well, doesn't he?
Yudakis says
you have a fine voice.
Fine for the shower.
I'll set you one onstage.
Sophisticated, huh?
Aren't you bored alone?
- No, I like it this way.
Your son is working hard.
That's okay, let her
wear him out a bit.
What's this?
- It's what they do in Greece.
So go to Greece,
before I kick your ass!
Morad, how are the braids?
- Better than Yonatan's.
George, tell Nissim
not to kick me in the ass.
You're driving him crazy.
But he kicks me
in front of everybody.
I'll tell him,
not in front of everybody.
What now?
- Sarah's sitting over there.
So wait till she leaves.
We don't need more eggplant,
but bring some pickles.
And more olives too.
Why won't he listen to me?
- Enough. What now?
What's the matter? - What?
- Hurts, doesn't it?
Where are my things?
- What things?
My cassettes that I gave you.
I returned them,
you don't remember.
And the stockings you stole.
What did you do with her stuff?
- I swear she's forgotten, Yonatan.
Give it back before
she pours out your brains.
Where's all the stuff you stole?
- Answer him.
Alright, I'll give it back.
I'm sick and tired of you.
- Bring it back quick!
Everybody here's a witness.
The cassettes and the stocking.
You can all sit on my dick!
Catch the sonofabitch!
What a jerk.
Nissim, don't kick him in the ass
in front of everybody.
He came crying to you?
Did you see his prick?
He dangles it in front of me.
Check out Yisrael
and his fancy hairdo.
He's doing Raj Kapoor.
Who's Raj Kapoor?
- The great Indian movie star.
Yisrael had seen
lots of movies, hasn't he?
He used to peep in
from the roof of the theater.
Till one day your dad caught him
and knocked him out cold.
Next day he'd show up again,
as if nothing happened.
Aaron, which movies were
the big blockbusters?
First there was Godzilla,
then Machista, then Hercules.
Then came Zorro,
then the cowboys.
Once we started
showing Indian movies,
that was all people
wanted to see.
3 hour long movies,
full of singing and dancing.
The show would start
at 16:30.
By 15:00 people were
already lining up for tickets.
When the theater shut down
people went crazy,
got really depressed.
Especially Yisrael.
He scribbled
"Desperado Square" on the wall.
Which movie should we screen?
If you screen an Indian movie,
the neighborhood will go wild.
Which one?
Ask Yisrael. He'll know for sure.
Yisrael!
Yisrael, come over here.
Turn around for us.
It's a perfect fit.
- Thank you, George.
Have a seat.
"The Wanderer".
- Who made it? - Raj Kapoor.
Who played in "Mother India"?
- Nargis, Sunil Dat, Rajandra Kumar.
Ask something really hard.
Yisrael, which Indian movie
was the biggest hit of all time?
There are a few.
- Not a few, the biggest.
The one movie that
everyone loved the most.
"Sangam."
I swear, George.
Isn't it?
"Sangam" was a big hit,
it played for half a year.
Until Morris shut the theater.
- Too bad about the theater.
What was the name, "Sangam"?
In Indian it means "meeting."
- It has a great story-line
about two lifelong friends
named Goppal and Sundar,
both of them in love with Radha
but neither knows about the other.
When Goppal discovers that
Sundar is in love with Radha too
he bows out in his favor
on account of true friendship.
Quite a story.
For years Goppal suffers silently
because he loved Radha
and Radha loved him.
A real man!
He gave up his true love
for the sake of friendship!
It all turns out
very sad in the end.
Your mom can tell you
what a great movie it was.
Cheers.
Besides, the stars of the movie
are Raj Kapoor, Rajandra Kumar
and Vyjan Tamila,
really great actors.
The songs are in color.
There are 31 acts,
it's almost 4 hours long.
They don't make them
like that anymore.
That's the music
I heard in my dream.
No kidding?
"Sangam" is it.
Is "Sangam" going to play again?
Calm down,
Yisrael.
Why "Sangam"?
Why, isn't it the best?
- No, it isn't the best.
Aaron and Yisrael both say
it's a blast.
Where will you find it?
- At the dealer's.
Forget about Indian movies,
people won't come.
What are you talking about?
People love them.
Forget about "Sangam,"
try a different movie.
Mom...
What's gotten into her?
Did you see that?
- I was sure she'd be pleased.
Since when do I drink tea anyway?
Hey, asshole, if you don't stop
I'll bash in your face!
Hi, Pyramid.
What's up?
He's splitting my head
with that song of his.
Same tune all the time.
I've begged him to stop.
He wants to be a singer. Where's
the projector? - Under the canvas.
Pyramid, can we
take these boards?
Only the ones on top.
You've got lots.
Show some generosity.
I need them.
Can you lift this projector
by yourself?
Even with my teeth.
Come on, Pyramid, do Hercules
against the Titans for them.
Not now.
- Come on, one little Hercules.
Just once for the gang.
I'm going nuts
from the damn "pom-pa".
We'll put everything
back in place.
Just a quick one.
Morad, get him the stick.
He looks just like Steve Rivers.
Just like a Roman.
From here he looks
more like a Crusader.
No way, like a conquistador.
No conquistador and no Crusader,
I'm going to teach him to sing.
Where are you going?
That "pom-pa" can really
drive you nuts.
Finally got here, Pyramid?
- You've fucked my mind!
You want to be a singer?
You've ruined my health!
It's his legs!
No, it's his kneecaps.
I can tell by the sound.
Now it's the legs!
Hello, George. Hello, Nissim.
Nothing wrong with Yudakis, I hope?
No, don't worry.
I thought maybe
you'd come to find a new singer.
Where would we find such a voice?
- Nowhere. He's a great singer.
To what do I owe the honor?
- We're looking for a movie.
A movie? Which?
- "Sangam."
What's wrong, cat got your tongue?
- This is a real surprise.
Whatever made you
think of "Sangam"?
Never mind,
just look for it.
If I had "Sangam"
would I be sitting in this office?
Look for it.
How about cowboys, a western?
No westerns.
Just get us "Sangam."
Okay, let's take a look.
"The Wanderer", "Mother India"...
"A Night in Paris"...
Here, see for yourself.
"Sangam"...rubbed out.
It's been rubbed out.
I told you I didn't
have the movie.
Jango is lying in the mud
as the Mexicans kick him
mercilessly in the face
and smash the palm of his hands
with their rifle butts.
"Where is the gold?"
"In the cemetery,"
he says.
So Fernando Sancho
lets out a huge roar:
Muchachos... amigos...
tequila.
And the Mexicans
begin to celebrate.
Meanwhile Jango
manages to escape
but he doesn't
forget to take the coffin
he's been dragging
the entire movie.
He opens the coffin
and takes out a huge machine gun
with revolving barrel and hand-crank.
He mounts it on a grave
and waits for the
Mexicans to arrive.
Meanwhile, he pulls out
a bottle of whiskey
and gulps down a few sips.
A few minutes later
Fernando Sancho shows up
with 50 or 60 roughnecks,
each one uglier than the next.
They get off their horses.
Jango takes his time.
He tosses away the bottle and
strips the blanket from the gun,
grips the hand-crank and...
In just seconds he mows down
the entire band of Mexicans.
Some of them fall this way,
others fall that way.
So he killed all of them?
- Rubbed them out completely.
He plugged them full of holes
so the tequila poured
out of them.
In short, the Mexicans
came looking for gold
and got hot lead instead.
They made great movies
in the old days...
Yonatan, who's stronger,
Hercules or Machista? - Machista.
Are you kidding?
Hercules is stronger.
No way, Machista is stronger.
Aaron, who's stronger,
Machista or Hercules?
Machista is no competition,
Hercules was much stronger.
What did I tell you?
So, do we have a projector?
- You bet.
How about the movie?
The movie? The dealer says that of
all the movies he bought from Dad
only "Sangam" is missing.
- Where could it be?
Only your uncle could have it.
But wait and I'll find out.
Hey, Avram.
How's it going?
- Alright.
Tell me, have you got "Sangam"?
What?
The movie "Sangam,"
haven't you got it?
What do you want?
We want to screen it
in the movie theater.
No movie, Aaron.
The dealer says that of all the
movies he bought,
only "Sangam" is missing.
So where could it be?
Only you could have it.
Tell me, is Seniora behind it all?
Enough, Avram,
don't be stubborn.
Come see how we've put
new chairs in the theater,
a new screen and projector.
Come on, let's relive
our old dreams.
The past is dead.
It's dead.
Raise it a little more.
Some more. That's it.
Watch out, Morad,
you'll burn down the theater!
Are you mad?
Bored?
Why do you think I'm bored?
Watch my little girl, I'm going
to get her something to drink.
How are you, Amalya?
- Alright.
Look at me.
How do I look?
- Handsome.
What does your mom say
about me? - Cute.
Cute means imbecile.
- That's right.
Won't you put in a word for me?
- Do it yourself.
You're just like your mom.
He'll spoil your girl.
- Don't interfere.
Why are you mixing her up?
- This is serious conversation!
Playing the bogey man...
I heard there's a new singer.
No, she only sings
in the shower.
I bet you'd love
to do backing vocals.
Did I say anything?
No, you're a real silent movie.
Come on, honey.
Got the hots?
I'm burning!
Now it's my turn.
Sarah, I'm in a big hurry.
I don't want to play anymore.
Sarah, it'll be easier
to hit him from here.
Sarah, I've got things to do.
Morad, you said that
we'd change places.
You promised, Morad.
I don't want to play anymore.
Enough, Morad!
Morad, I swear that I'll
give her back the stocking!
Release him right away.
We were just fooling with him.
- Stop fooling with him.
Nissim, he asked for it.
- Okay, clear out of here.
Nissim, I want him to give back
my stocking and my cassettes.
Alright, move it.
Clear out of here.
7 against 1? Shame on you.
- You shut up!
Come here.
Come over here!
What's this?
It's Sarah's.
This is Sarah's?
You had everyone alarmed,
we were sure it was real.
Go on, take it apart and
return the stocking to her.
Go on,
return it to her!
Don't like resistance,
do you?
It runs in the family.
Aren't you going to sing?
We'll pay him,
how much does he want?
It's not a matter
of money, Nissim.
So what's the problem?
What does he want?
You can't give him
what he wants.
I could get it in a cinch.
You pay him too much respect.
Be patient, Nissim.
Yisrael.
Is it holding in the wind?
- Like concrete.
If it doesn't hold,
use thumbtacks.
Have you got the jitters?
- Have I got the jitters?
My stomach is churning,
I'm counting the minutes.
Come here, sit down.
Now you won't have
to climb on the roof.
Now you'll have a ticket.
Yeah, but it'd better be
a good seat in the middle.
Yisrael, how many times
have you seen "Sangam"?
A 100 maybe 200 times.
From the matinee show
until 4 in the morning.
Why do you always
exaggerate?
No exaggeration, I swear.
First, the matinee show...
then the evening show...
and the late night show
with Avram and Seniora.
I swear.
I'd peek from the roof.
What an amazing view.
- Which roof?
The roof of the theater.
You saw Avram and Seniora
from the roof?
They used to watch "Sangam."
- Did you ever tell anyone?
No, I swear.
Yisrael.
Don't speak like that
about Seniora
because it could make
the wrong impression.
I won't say anything.
Go on inside.
Is that the truth
or is he making it up?
You think Dad shut down
the theater without a reason?
So?
Do you mean to tell me that
Mom was involved with Avram?
I really don't know.
For the eternal soul of Morris,
the son of Rebecca Mandebon.
May the spirit of the Lord
be his guide to Paradise.
Amen!
Amen.
- Amen.
What's the matter with you?
Everything's alright, Mom.
We're going to the synagogue
to check if everything's ready.
Get up already.
Go on, get up!
Go straight!
What do you thing you're doing?
That's it.
You can park here.
Come on, Morad.
Look how much wood Yisrael's got!
Did I split my skull?
- No, just a tiny bump.
Damn this board!
- What's the problem?
This board is the problem!
- Let's take it to the bonfire.
It's good for the bonfire!
Pull, pull hard.
It's no good this way.
Come over here.
- No, I'll go there.
All together now:
One, two, three, pull...
Oh no, look what we've done!
Now he'll be able to get
the motorcycle inside.
We've made him a garage.
Come on, let's take the boards.
Dear Morris,
God bless his soul.
Seniora.
Life is a flowing river and
we're not getting any younger.
Whatever is left unresolved
will remain that way forever.
You should talk to him.
I'm not going to talk to him.
It'll turn out badly,
I'm telling you.
Nissim is furious.
You're the only one
he'll give the movie to.
They can screen
a different movie.
There's no point now
in opening old wounds.
Will there ever be
an end to the story?
It ended long ago.
Know when, Aaron?
That night when I waited
for him beside the theater.
"I'll just go talk to Morris,
I'll be right back," he said.
I waited all night.
Until morning.
Until the sun rose.
That's when it ended.
Be careful.
- Move aside.
You're a whale, damn you!
Enough, Morad,
or I'll drown you.
Yisrael, come in! What are
you afraid of? Come on!
What's he doing here?
Why has he come now? He didn't
bother to come to the funeral.
Let him be.
- Why should I?
He's won't give the movie
yet has the nerve to come here!
Enough, Nissim, not now.
The sons of the deceased
will say Kaddish.
His brother too.
- He's not saying Kaddish for Dad!
Calm down, Nissim,
he's his brother.
He's not saying Kaddish
for Morris Mandebon.
Not for Dad.
What's the matter with you?
He came to say Kaddish
for his brother
and you go crazy on him?
In the synagogue,
for all to see?
You think I don't know why
Dad shut down the theater?
Aaron.
- What?
Tell us what went on there.
What do you mean?
You screened it for them.
- Yisrael told us all about it.
It's true.
I screened "Sangam" for them
when everyone had gone.
So, was Avram
in love with Mom?
Everybody was.
But as for her, she had
her heart set on Avram.
Did Dad know about it?
If he'd known, he would
have stayed away from her.
But the parents arranged a match
and it put Avram in a terrible jam.
His only way out
was to disappear.
That's why he won't give us
the movie?
George, it's not just
any movie.
"Sangam" was their movie.
"De-Gaulle"
Morad, straighten out the doll.
Watch out for nails, Baruch,
or you'll hurt yourself.
We have to reinforce it, Yonatan.
There won't be any "Sangam."
- Why? Too bad.
There's no "Sangam"?
- Avram won't let them have it.
What a pity.
I saw the movie with my mother
30 years ago.
Everyone cried.
It was so much fun.
I really wanted to see it.
Badriya told me about the
movie for 3 hours, crying,
and she said it was nothing
compared to the movie itself.
Seniora.
Why did you come here?
To talk to you.
Not a day passed that
I didn't think of you.
Thought of me?
So why didn't you
talk to Morris?
You promised
you'd tell him about us.
I didn't have the courage.
He was so happy.
When I came to talk to him, he
asked me to be his best man.
The words stuck in my throat,
I couldn't speak a word.
So you ran away?
Had I stayed, it'd be like
living in a cage all my life.
I had to go.
Had you talked to him,
he would have understood.
I made a mistake, Seniora.
Now there's nobody
to talk to anymore.
What used to be
can never be again.
Seniora.
"Morris Mandebon - R.I.P."
You'll blast us to the sky
with your bonfire.
We'll light the bonfire when
everyone leaves the theater.
It'll be just like fireworks.
Hey, Avram?
Come have coffee with us.
- Some other time.
Come and get "Sangam."
Right on!
I'll send Yisrael to pick
it up on his motorcycle.
Come see the movie.
I'll save you a seat, Avram.
"Sangam"
Morad, put these fuel tanks inside.
Hide them well.
Morad! Look, it's leaking.
Bring it over here.
Plug it with this.
Wait a minute.
I have a better idea.
You and your gizmos.
I hope this works.
Good for you.
Morad, put it inside
so nobody will find it.
Put the board back
so nobody can see it.
Bet you it's going to be
the biggest bonfire ever.
We worked hard, didn't we?
Who'll guard the bonfire?
How should I know?
We'll post Jellyfish David.
We'll be watching the movie.
Okay, Jellyfish David,
he'll be the guard.