WAR IS ALWAYS THE SAME.
IT IS YOUNG MEN
DYING IN THE FULLNESS
OF THEIR PROMISE.
IT IS TRYING TO KILL A MAN...
THAT YOU DO NOT EVEN KNOW
WELL ENOUGH TO HATE.
IT IS A CRIME
AGAINST MANKIND...
THAT SO MUCH COURAGE
AND SO MUCH WILL...
AND SO MANY DREAMS...
MUST BE FLUNG ON THE FIRES
OF WAR AND DEATH.
WE, THEREFORE,
SAY AGAIN TONIGHT,
LET US CHOOSE PEACE...
AND WITH IT THE WONDROUS WORKS
OF PEACE.
AND THE DECISION
THAT I MADE IN CAMBODIA
WILL SAVE THOSE LIVES.
IT WILL BRING THE PEACE
THAT WE ALL WANT, IN MY OPINION.
WE SHALL COMPLETELY DESTROY
JAPAN'S POWER TO MAKE WAR.
I HATE WAR !
HE COUNTED ON AMERICA
TO BE PASSIVE.
HE COUNTED WRONG.
THE UNITED STATES
WILL LEAD THE WAY,
AND WE EXPECT OUR ALLIES...
TO WALK WITH US
HAND IN HAND.
NO NATION...
WILL BE PERMITTED TO BRUTALLY
ASSAULT ITS NEIGHBOR.
I CALL UPON
CHAIRMAN KHRUSHCHEV...
TO HALT AND ELIMINATE...
THIS CLANDESTINE,
RECKLESS...
AND PROVOCATIVE THREAT
TO WORLD PEACE.
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
I BELIEVE WE CAN HAVE
PEACE WITH HONOR.
2007 IS THE YEAR...
IN WHICH THE UNACCEPTABLE
MILITARY THREAT
IMPOSED BY CHINA...
WILL COME TO A HALT !
AND TO THOSE
WHO CHALLENGE MY RESOLVE,
I GIVE YOU
TWO SIMPLE WORDS:
TRY ME.
[ Man ]  THE PRESIDENT,
ON THE OTHER HAND, HAS SPENT
THE DAY IN COLORADO.
FIRST FLYING INTO
THE AIR FORCE ACADEMY...
WHERE HE GAVE
A SPEECH ON THE PRESENCE
OF AMERICAN TROOPS IN KOREA...
AND LATER SPENDING THE DAY
AT HIS COLORADO CAMPAIGN
HEADQUARTERS...
IN DOWNTOWN
COLORADO SPRINGS.
SO AT THIS POINT, HOW LONG
IS THE OPERATION GOING TO LAST ?
I KNOW GOVERNOR ROMER
HAD CALLED FORT CARSON
NATIONAL GUARD...
TO BE ABLE TO BE MOTIVATED,
BE ABLE TO HELP
IN THIS SITUATION.
WE'RE ALSO GETTING REPORTS
FROM THE PIKES PEAK AREA...
THAT THERE WAS
A HUGE SNOWSTORM
GOING THERE.
UH, THAT'S WHERE
THE PRESIDENT IS,
OF COURSE.
IT'S SUPPOSED TO BE
NEAR BLIZZARD CONDITIONS.
AS FAR AS WE KNOW,
THE SNOWSTORM HAS HIT COLORADO
JUST WITHIN THE PAST HOUR.
MOST COLORADO CITIZENS VOTED
IN THE MORNING OR AFTER WORK.
[ Man On Radio ]
EAGLE LEADER ONE,
WE'RE BELOW FIVE MILES AN HOUR.
REGS REQUIRE US
TO FIND A NEST.
RECON HAD THE DINER
A HALF A CLICK UP.
ROGER THAT,
SCOUT LEADER.
JESUS CHRIST,
WHERE THE FUCK ARE WE ?
♪♪ [ Rock ]
♪ PAST SIX O'CLOCK
AND IT'S TIME TO ROCK ♪
♪ AND MY HEAD IS BEATIN'
LIKE A CHIME ♪
♪ IN THE FLOW OF DAYLIGHT
I FEEL LIKE SHITE ♪
♪ AND I CAN'T REMEMBER
[ Lyrics Indistinct ] ♪
♪ THEN THE FOREMAN SAYS
COME ON NOW, BOYS ♪
♪ STICK YOUR FINGERS
DOWN YOUR THROATS
AND GET TO WORK ♪
♪ AND I WISHED TO CHRIST
I'D STAYED HOME LAST NIGHT ♪
IT HASN'T EVEN BEEN
TEN MINUTES.
IT HAS BEEN
WHAT IS SHE DOING,
TRYING TO WIN
A TALENT CONTEST ?
[ Woman ]  MAYBE SHE THINKS
WE'RE NOT GOING ANYWHERE.
[ Man ]  THAT'S NOT
FOR HER TO THINK.
FOR ALL SHE KNOWS,
I GOT A SLED AND TEN
SIBERIAN HUSKIES.
I JUST WANT
TO GET THIS PAID FOR.
COME ON, LIZ.  LIZZIE.
YOU MADE THE SAME MISTAKE
YOU MADE A MILLION TIMES.
I TOLD YOU BEFORE.
DON'T MOVE OUT YOUR QUEEN
TOO EARLY.
LOOK, YOU PLAY YOUR GAME.
I'LL PLAY MINE.  OKAY ?
[ Newscaster ]  GOOD EVENING
AND WELCOME TO THIS SPECIAL
EDITION OF THE IBS EVENING NEWS.
I'M GERALD IRVING.
PRESIDENTIAL PRIMARIES
WERE HELD TODAY...
IN CONNECTICUT AND COLORADO.
THE POLLS ARE
A FEW MINUTES AWAY FROM CLOSING
IN THE ROCKY MOUNTAIN STATE...
AND HAVE BEEN CLOSED NOW
FOR TWO HOURS ON THE EAST COAST.
AS OF THIS MORNING,
PRESIDENT EMERSON IS LEADING--
HEY, HARV.
- HOW 'BOUT WE PUT
THE NUGGETS' GAME ON ?
- TALK TO KATIE.
- CARE TO WATCH THE NUGGETS ?
- THE GAME WAS SNOWED OUT,
RALPHIE.
[ Scoffs ]
I CAN'T BELIEVE YOU DON'T
CARE ABOUT THIS STUFF.
[ Newscast Continues ]
PLEASE.
&quot;SNOWED OUT.&quot;
HOW DO YOU SNOW OUT
A BASKETBALL GAME ?
BASKETBALL'S A BULLSHIT
SPORT ANYWAY.
THE PRESIDENT IS LOSING BY FEWER
THAN THREE PERCENTAGE POINT.
BUNCH OF GENETIC FREAKS...
OF FUCKIN'S NATURE,
IF YOU ASK ME.
OH, IT AIN'T THE STIMULATI''
EXERCISE LIKE POOL, HUH ?
LET ME TELL YOU SOMETHING
ABOUT THIS HERE GAME OF POOL,
ALL RIGHT ?
HARV, IT'S ALL ANGLES.
YOU KNOW,
YOU HIT A BALL HERE,
IT GOES THIS WAY.
YOU HIT A BALL THERE,
IT GOES THATTA WAY.
[ Newscast Continues ]
ALL GEOMETRY.
- WHO YOU CALLING NOW ?
- SALLY.
CAN'T YOU LEAVE
THAT POOR GIRL ALONE ?
IT'S ALMOST MIDNIGHT OVER THERE.
I DON'T PAY THAT GIRL
TO BE LEFT ALONE.
YOU SHOULD LAY
YOUR KING DOWN.
YOU'RE A LOSER HERE.
HEY, SAL.  [ Chuckles ]
WHAT'S GOIN' ON WITH THE JAPS ?
THIS MIGHT BE THE MOST EMOTIONAL
ELECTION IN RECENT AMERICAN
HISTORY.
A POPULAR PRESIDENT DIES,
A VERY LOYAL VICE PRESIDENT
TAKES THE REINS.
IT SEEMS
A NATURAL CONTINUUM.
BUT WE SHOULD BEAR IN MIND
THAT EMERSON WAS
AN APPOINTED VICE PRESIDENT.
AFTER VICE PRESIDENT BUCHANAN
WAS FORCED TO RESIGN,
LESS THAN 50 PERCENT
OF AMERICANS BACKED
EMERSON'S APPOINTMENT.
YOU'RE BREAKING UP.
LISTEN.  CAN YOU HEAR ME ?
[ Newscast In Background ]
YOU'RE BREAKING UP.
THE OVER/UNDER'S ABOUT 200.
OKAY, IF IT COMES IN
LESS THAN--  SHIT.
HERE YOU GO,
BOYS AND GIRLS.
I'LL TAKE IT.
WISHFUL THINKING,
DON'T YOU THINK ?  MAYBE YOU
GUYS WANT TO START A TAB.
OH, I LOVE YOUR ACCENT.
ARE YOU FROM FRANCE ?
OH, I SPEAK FRENCH,
BUT I'M NOT FROM FRANCE.
SHE'S FROM CANADA, LIZZIE.
PROBABLY QUEBEC ?
OH, BRAVO, MONSIEUR !
THAT ONE IS ON ME.
AH--  AH--
DID I ASK FOR THAT ?
WHAT THE FUCK IS UP
WITH THIS BURGER, HARV ?
WHAT ARE YOU
TALKIN' ABOUT ?
THERE'S
SOMETHING CRUNCHY IN IT.
THERE'S SOMETHING CRUNCHY
IN THIS FUCKING HAMBURGER.
IT'S LETTUCE, RALPHIE.
EAT IT.
HAMBURGERS ARE SUPPOSED
TO BE JUICY, NOT CRUNCHY.
COME ON, LIZZIE.
I'M THINKING.
I'M THINKING ABOUT
WHAT YOU'RE THINKING.
THAT'S WHAT YOU TOLD ME TO DO.
I DIDN'T THINK IT WOULD TAKE
THIS LONG.  DO YOU WANT ME
TO TELL YOU MY STRATEGY ?
I'LL TELL YOU WHAT MY
PLAN IS.  THEN YOU CAN--
IF I LOSE, I LOSE.  OKAY ?
IT'S NOT LIKE IT'S
THE FALL OF THE REPUBLIC.
THAT'S THE PROBLEM.
[ Car Doors Opening, Closing ]
&quot;IF I LOSE, I LOSE.&quot;
IT MEANS NOTHING TO YOU ?
IT'S A PROBLEM ?
BECAUSE IT'S A GAME.
SO, WHY ARE WE PLAYING ?
HE PUT FUCKIN'--
COULD YOU TRY NOT
TO COMPLAIN FOR ONCE ?
YOU KNOW IT IS
THE BEST FOOD FOR MILES.
IT'S THE ONLY FOOD FOR MILES.
IT'S ONLY ANYTHING FOR MILES.
LET ME ASK YOU
THIS QUESTION, HARV.
WHEN'S THE LAST TIME YOU HAD
AN INSPECTION HERE ?  HUH ?
YOU'RE SUPPOSED TO DO THAT,
MAKE SURE IT'S CLEAN.
THAT'S IT.
GET THE HELL OUT.
COME ON, HARVEY.
TAKE IT EASY.
NO, NO.  WHEN A MAN
INSULTS MY JOINT,
HE INSULTS THE MEMORY
OF MY FATHER.
YOUR FATHER EVER SEE YOU
IN THAT CHEF BOYARDEE HAT ?
WHY YOU KEEP
MESSIN' WITH ME ?
IT'S A SACRED TRUST.  YOU PUT
SOMETHING IN SOMEBODY'S FOOD--
[ Doors Whoosh Open ]
[ Ralphie ]
WHERE DID THEY COME FROM ?
HI.
I SURE THOUGHT I'D SEEN THE END
OF CUSTOMERS FOR THE NIGHT.
OH, EXCUSE ME.
YEAH, STANDARD PERIMETER
DEPLOYMENT.  EXODUS IS IN.
I NEED REPORTS INTO CHANNEL 34
ON THE STAT.  I NEED DELTA TEAM
IN SIX MINUTES.
HI,
I'M SPECIAL AGENT DEXTER.
UH-HUH.
DO-DO YOU GUYS WANT A BOOTH ?
NO, THANK YOU, MA'AM.
THIS IS SPECIAL AGENT WILLIAMS.
HELLO.
HI.
YOU THE PROPRIETOR ?
I'M THE PROPRIETOR, SIR.
DO WE HAVE A PROBLEM HERE ?
I'M NO STRANGER
TO LAW ENFORCEMENT--
OH, DON'T MAKE
A PRODUCTION
OUT OF IT, HONEY.
GOOD EVENING, FOLKS.
HI, GOOD EVENING.
HELLO.
I'M SPECIAL AGENT DEXTER.
THIS IS SPECIAL AGENT WILLIAMS.
WITH YOUR PERMISSION, WE NEED
TO SEE SOME IDENTIFICATION,
CHECK YOUR PERSON FOR WEAPONS.
SURE.
UH, WHAT'S THIS
ALL ABOUT ?
IS THERE A PROBLEM, SIR ?
WELL,
THERE MOST CERTAINLY IS.
LIZZIE, SIT DOWN.
LIZZIE.
COME ON, TAYLOR.
THEY'RE JUST TRYING
TO DO THEIR JOB.
MR. TAYLOR ?
ALL RIGHT.
MY FIRST NAME'S TAYLOR.  RIGHT.
YEAH,
CHECK HER OUT.
TAYLOR FLETCHER WOODS.
AND THIS IS LIZZIE CLARK WOODS.
[ Device Beeps ]
MS. WOODS.
OOH !  [ Giggles ]
HEY, HOW DID YOU DO THAT ?
[ Chuckles ]
IT'S NOT COOL
THEY KNOW WHO WE ARE.
WHAT'S THE JUICE HERE ?
HOW DO WE KNOW YOU ARE
WHO YOU SAY YOU ARE ?
UH--
MR. WOODS.
UH, TAYLOR--
I'D SURE APPRECIATE
SOME COOPERATION HERE.
EMERSON'S A DIFFERENT BREED
THAN WE THOUGHT.
HE SEEMS DISPOSED TO CONTINUING
THE DECEASED PRESIDENT'S...
HARD-LINE APPROACH
ON NORTH KOREA,
COMMITTING TO KEEPING THE VAST
MAJORITY OF U.S. TROOPS THERE--
FUCKED UP MY CAMERA.
THANK YOU, MR. EMERSON.
SEND NOAH TO COLORADO.
AT LEAST YOU GOT
LOADED UP ON SOME
GOOD STUFF TODAY.
WE GOT YOU
SOME GOOD STUFF !
GOOD FOOTAGE.
ANY MINUTE,
THERE'S GONNA BE A CRAZY MOB
BREAKING IN THROUGH HERE.
THAT'S NOT A PROBLEM,
MR. HOWARD.
YOU GOT THAT AREA CLEARED ?
IT'S ALL SECURE, SIR.
THANK YOU.
GOOD FOOTAGE.
REAL STUFF WE WANT.
STAGED FOOTAGE.
MAKE IT REAL FOR ONCE.
THERE'S NO EGRESS,
BUT POST IN THE KITCHEN.
TRUMP,
VICTORIOUS IN CONNECTICUT.
WE GOT BRAVO TEAM
ON THE ROOF--
PRESIDENT EMERSON'S CAMPAIGN...
SEEMS TO RIDING
A CREST OF SENTIMENT.
IT'S FREEZING OUT THERE !
SELECTING THEODORE SLATER
FROM WYOMING.
NO STATEMENT YET
FROM THE PRESIDENT,
WHO, AS WE SAID,
IS IN COLORADO.
THANKS, BILL.
PRESIDENT EMERSON
MAY FIND HIMSELF AS THE FIRST
NONELECTED INCUMBENT...
TO WIN HIS PARTY'S NOMINATION
SINCE GERALD FORD IN 1976.
GIVEN EMERSON'S LACK OF
EXPERIENCE IN POLITICAL POSTS,
THE RUMORS OF AN IMPENDING
SHAKE-UP IN HIS CABINET...
HAVE TAKEN ON A NEW IMPORTANCE.
[ Irving Continues, Indistinct ]
YOU'RE ON.
OKAY.
YOU KNOW
WHO THAT IS ?
MY GOD.
[ Man On Radio ]
DELTA TEAM IS IN POSITION.
HI.  PLEASED.
WALT EMERSON.
NO KIDDING.
OH, MY GOD !
[ Speaking French ]
HARVEY.
I'M REALLY SO EXCITED.
PLEASE TELL ME YOU'RE
OLD ENOUGH TO VOTE.
WHAT IS
YOUR NAME ?
KATIE.
SUPPOSE YOU TELL ME
ABOUT THE SPECIALTY
DE LA MAISON.
OH, WE'VE GOT
A GREAT CHICKEN POT PIE
AND CHICKEN CROQUETTE--
- MR. PRESIDENT, A SECOND
OPINION'S IN ORDER HERE.
- PLEASE.
THE CHILIBURGER IS
HARV'S SPECIALTY.
HE'S A MONSTER AT IT.
I CALL IT MY USUAL.
YEAH.
IS THAT RIGHT ?
PLEASURE TO
MEET YOU, SIR.
MY PLEASURE.
CHILIBURGER, HUH ?
FINE, THEN.
ABSOLUTELY.
LET'S SEE WHAT
THIS FELLA'S RAVING ABOUT.
CHILIBURGER IT IS.
- WOULD YOUR FRIENDS
LIKE SOMETHING ?
- YES.  ORDER UP, EVERYBODY.
- WHAT DID YOU SAY
YOUR NAME WAS ?
- KATIE.
- I'D LOVE A CUP OF JOE.
- SURE.
UH, COFFEE ALL AROUND ?
MA'AM ?
NOTHING, THANKS.
WE'RE GONNA
BE HERE A SPELL.
THERE'S A LOT
OF WHITE STUFF BETWEEN HERE
AND AIR FORCE ONE.
GOOD THING I GOT
MY CAMPAIGNING IN.
ABSOLUTELY.
- I DIDN'T VOTE.
- KATIE.  COULD HAVE
USED YOU OUT THERE TODAY.
[ Chuckles ]
I'M SURE YOU DID FINE.
THAT'S WHAT
THEY'RE TELLING ME,
BUT PERHAPS YOUR VOTE...
COULD HAVE TAKEN ME
FROM VICTORY TO MANDATE.
HE LOOKS A LOT OLDER
THAN ON TV.
[ Emerson ]
OKAY.  LOOKING FORWARD
TO THAT CHILIBURGER.
DON'T SAY ANYTHING STUPID,
OKAY ?
YOU'RE TELLING ME THAT ?
HE'S COMING OVER.
HOW DO I LOOK ?
HI THERE.
WALT EMERSON.
HI.
HI, I'M, UM,
LIZZIE WOODS.
PLEASURE.
NICE TO MEET YOU.
WALT EMERSON.  HI.
TAYLOR WOODS.
IT'S AN HONOR, SIR.
TAYLOR.
YOU'VE GOT
THAT NEW YORK SENSE
ABOUT YOU, NO ?
VERY GOOD, SIR.
GOLDMAN SACHS.
I'M THE OIL AND
MINERAL ANALYST.
OF COURSE YOU ARE.
WHOSE MOVE IS IT ?
UH, THAT WOULD BE
MY MOVE.
MAY I ?
OH, YES, YES.
HAVE A LOOK HERE.
UH-HUH.
WELL, WELL, WELL.
WOW.  IS THIS, UH,
KASPAROV DEEP BLUE,
GAME THREE ?
I-- I DON'T
THINK SO, SIR.
[ Chuckling ]
NO, I'D SAY SHE'S
ABOUT SEVEN MOVES AWAY.
HMM.
REALLY.
SO, YOU TWO, UH,
SATISFIED AMERICANS,
WOULD YOU SAY ?
- ABSOLUTELY, MR. PRESIDENT.
WE'VE BEEN SO HAPPY THIS YEAR.
- MY ONLY--
MY ONLY PROBLEM--
EXCUSE ME, I JUST
WANT TO GET THIS--
I JU--
I JUST WANT TO GET
SOMETHING IN HERE.
MY ONLY DEBATE
WITH YOU IS THE
SOCIAL SECURITY ISSUE.
IS THAT RIGHT.
I THINK YOUR MOVING
THE AGE TO 73...
FOR BENEFITS
ON PENSION FUNDS
AND STOCK PORTFOLIOS...
IS JUST GONNA TRIGGER
PANIC SELLING.
ANY IDEA HOW WE CAME ABOUT THE
AGE OF 65 FOR SOCIAL SECURITY ?
NO.
ACTUALLY, UH, NO,
COME TO THINK OF IT.
I MEAN, WHY NOT
70 OR 80 OR 64 ?
I HAVE NO IDEA.
WE ADOPTED
THE SOCIAL SECURITY SYSTEM...
[ Cameraman ]  RELOADING.
FROM BISMARCK,
HOOK, LINE AND SINKER.
BISMARCK WAS AN S.O.B.
JUST LOOKING TO BOOST
HIS POPULARITY...
WITH HIS SOCIAL
WELFARE SYSTEM.
SO HE GOES TO HIS ACTUARIES,
AND THEY ASSURE HIM--
THIS IS
THE LATE 1800s.
SO THEY TELL HIM
THAT EVERYONE'S GONNA BE DEAD
BY THE AGE OF 65.
- OF COURSE,
TODAY IT'S EQUIVALENT TO 105.
- UNBELIEVABLE.
FASCINATING.
IT'S 9:00,
MR. PRESIDENT.
OKAY.  SO THAT'S HOW
WE'RE STARTING TO THINK
IN TERMS OF 73.
I HOPE
I DIDN'T INTERRUPT THE GAME.
I SHOULD GO CHECK THE RESULTS.
NICE MEETING YOU BOTH.
THANK YOU.
EDIFYING.
THANK YOU
FOR THE TIP.
GOOD LUCK TO YOU.
OOP.
I'M SORRY.
GOT IT.
YOU'RE GONNA NEED
THAT ONE, HUH ?
THAT'S OKAY.
GOOD LUCK.
GOOD LUCK
TO YOU.
YOU HAVE OUR VOTE.
[ Exhaling ]
KASPAROV
DEEP BLUE.
HE'S VERY SHORT.
WHAT DO YOU TWO
HAVE IN THE POOL ?
FIFTY-EIGHT.
FIFTY-NINE.
THE POLLS IN COLORADO
HAVE NOW CLOSED.
SIXTY-ONE.
HERE AT IBS, WE ARE READY
TO PROJECT A WINNER...
IN THE COLORADO PRIMARY.
WITH ALL PRECINCTS
HAVING REPORTED,
IBS IS PROJECTING...
THAT PRESIDENT WALTER EMERSON...
AND... YES !
THERE IT IS.
CASPER THE FUCKING GHOST.
WILL WIN THE PRIMARY WITH 63%--
WE GOT THE PRICK
BY THE BALLS.
HERE'S WHAT WE DO.
CALL HIM UP AND TELL HIM
THE DEAL'S STILL ON, BUT HE
HAS WITHDRAW BY NOON TOMORROW.
OTHERWISE, NO DEAL.
HE'S GOT NO MANEUVERING ROOM
TO EVEN CHANGE THE PLATFORM.
SO, WE MAKE HIM FEEL
LIKE HE'S GOT A LITTLE
WRIGGLE ROOM, RIGHT ?
CUT HIM OFF AT THE KNEES,
MAKE HIM THINK HE CAN WALK.
WHY DON'T WE
JUST PROCEED AHEAD ?
WE'RE GONNA WIN ANYWAYS.
LET'S JUST--
NO, HE'S AT THE HYATT.
I'M GONNA CALL HIM NOW.
IF HE'S COZY IN THAT
HOTEL ROOM WITH A BLONDE,
HE'S A LOT WISER
THAN I.
WHEN DO YOU THINK
WE'RE GONNA GET OUT
OF HERE, BY THE WAY ?
TRACEY'S GOT A BALLET RECITAL
TOMORROW, AND ALEXANDRA'S GOT
MY BLOOD OATH ON THIS ONE.
WELL, UH, AIR FORCE ONE
IS ABOUT 20 MINUTES FROM HERE
AT PETERSON AIR FORCE BASE,
AND AS SOON AS
THE WEATHER GETS BETTER--
IT CLEARS UP, IT'S SAFE--
WE GET MARINE ONE TO COME,
GET US OUT OF HERE--
23-SKIDDOO, WE'RE ALL SET.
OKAY.  WELL,
LET'S JUST DO
WHAT WE NEED TO DO.
WHAT IF CASPER
WANTS TO TALK TO YOU ?
WELL, I'LL--
I GUESS I'LL--
NO, NO, NO, NO, NO, NO, NO.
YOU DON'T WANT
TO TALK TO HIM.
YOU'RE TALKING
TO YOUR CONSTITUENTS.
MAYBE WE SHOULDN'T BE
SURPRISED THAT HE RECEIVED
THE VOTES THAT HE DID.
MANY PEOPLE VIEW EMERSON
AS NOT PRESIDENTIAL.
HE'S VERY VICE PRESIDENTIAL,
VERY SECOND BANANA.
HIS EXPERIENCE IN FOREIGN POSTS
HAS CERTAINLY BEEN STRONG.
HE BOASTS PROBABLY
ONE OF THE BEST RESUMES
SINCE GEORGE BUSH.
TRUE, BUT HE DOESN'T HAVE
THE PHYSICAL BEARING
OF A PRESIDENT.
TRAITS THAT WELL COULD HAVE
BEEN ASCRIBED TO HAR--
HOLD ON ONE MOMENT.
OKAY, THIS ISN'T--
I'LL SAY THIS QUICK.
THINK ABOUT IT.
WE'LL ALL BE HAPPY
IN AUGUST, OKAY ?  HUH ?
[ Irving On TV ]  APPARENTLY
THIS IS A MASSIVE MILITARY
ACTION FROM THE MIDDLE EAST.
OUR FIRST INDICATIONS ARE...
NO, I SAID IF YOU--
WE'LL ALL BE--
THAT THERE IS
A LARGE TROOP MOVEMENT
IN THE GULF AREA.
OKAY.  APPARENTLY ISRAELI RADIO
HAS JUST ISSUED...
GOOD NEWS OR BAD NEWS ?
A NATIONWIDE CALL-UP
FOR THEIR RESERVES.
THAT'S IN RESPONSE
TO WHAT APPEARED TO BE...
SIR, YOU SHOULD CHECK THIS OUT.
A LARGE-SCALE MANEUVER FROM
THE IRAQI ARMY AND AIR FORCE.
WHAT IS IT ?
[ Marsh ]  WHAT'S
THE STORY, HOWARD ?
WHAT'S HAPPENED ?
NO INDICATION OF
AMERICAN TROOPS IN THE REGION...
HAVING ENCOUNTERED
ANY HOSTILITIES.
GAYLE ?
OKAY.  BEAR WITH ME,
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN.
THIS IS--  LET'S JUST
GET THIS TOGETHER.
OKAY.  ALL RIGHT,
HERE WE GO.
WE HAVE SOME INFORMATION
FROM AT LEAST TWO CORRESPONDENTS
IN THE MIDDLE EAST.
THIS HAS NOT YET BEEN VERIFIED
BY ANY GOVERNMENT SOURCES,
AND WE SHOULD UNDERSCORE THAT.
BUT--  OKAY.  OKAY,
WE ARE NOW GETTING WORD
FROM OUR CORRESPONDENTS...
IN BAGHDAD AND KUWAIT.
UDEI HUSSEIN,
THE DICTATOR OF IRAQ,
HAS TAKEN A MILITARY FORCE
AND HAS CROSSED...
HIS SOUTHEAST BORDER
INTO KUWAIT, HEADING DIRECTLY
FOR KUWAIT CITY.
BOY'S GOT SOME BALLS.
[ Irving On TV ]
OKAY.
ALL RIGHT.  OUR INITIAL REPORTS
ARE THAT THE UNITED NATIONS-LED
AMERICAN PEACEKEEPING FORCE...
HAS BEEN OVERRUN.
HOWARD, GET SECDEF
ON THE LINE.
WE'RE TRYING TO NAIL DOWN
THE SIGNIFICANT DETAILS.
CAN-- CAN WE--
OKAY.
WE HAVE JOHN MARINO
ON A CELL PHONE.
HOW IS THIS HAPPENING ?
WHERE DID THIS COME FROM
ALL OF A SUDDEN ?
I-I-I DON'T KNOW.
[ Irving ]
JOHN, CAN YOU HEAR ME ?
JOHN ?
MARSH ?
- [ Irving ]  OKAY,
WE'RE HAVING SOME PROBLEMS.
- [ Emerson ]  MARSHALL.
IBS MILITARY ANALYSTS
WILL BE WITH US SHORTLY.
SO FAR, NO CONTACT
FROM THE WHITE HOUSE,
OTHER THAN A STATEMENT THAT
THE PRESIDENT IS MONITORING
THE SITUATION CAREFULLY...
AND THAT HE IS
GRAVELY CONCERNED.
[ Emerson ]
I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
WHAT ABOUT OUR SATELLITES ?
HOW COME WE DIDN'T--
THAT'S A QUESTION
FOR SECDEF, SIR.
HE'S BEEN DISTRACTED
BY THE KOREAN MESS.
YEAH, I SHOULD SAY,
WHEN A NATION CAN INVADE
ANOTHER NATION...
AND OVERRUN
AMERICAN TROOPS.
SIR, MAYBE WE DON'T KNOW
BECAUSE IT DID NOT HAPPEN.
IT HAPPENED.
IT'S ALL OVER THE NEWS
WE DON'T HAVE
CONFIRMATION.
WE HAVE TO ASSUME IT HAPPENED.
DOESN'T THIS BASTARD
GET IT ?
I'D SAY NOT.
I DIDN'T EVEN KNOW
WE HAD TROOPS IN KUWAIT.
TECHNICALLY, WE DID NOT.
THEY WERE UNDER
U.N. SUPERVISION.
IT WAS OUR TURN
IN THE HELSINKI ROTATION.
HOW MANY TROOPS WERE THERE ?
THREE--  THREE-TWENTY.
I'M NOT SURE.
YOU'RE NOT SURE ?
THERE'S A BIG DIFFERENCE
BETWEEN 300 AND 320.
EITHER WAY, I'D RATHER HAVE
NO TROOPS THAN A SMALL FORCE
THAT ACTS AS AN INDUCEMENT.
JESUS.
[ Irving On TV ]
THE GIGANTIC ISRAELI RESERVES--
WELL, DOES HUSSEIN THINK THAT
WE'RE JUST GONNA LET IT STAND ?
[ Irving On TV ]
THE ISRAELIS HAVE BEGUN
A FULL MOBILIZATION.
[ Marsh ]
I THINK HE DOES,
THE LITTLE FUCK.
I DON'T NEED THAT, MARSH.
WE NEED TO MAKE THIS VERY,
VERY CLEAR FOR HIM.
WE WILL.  WHEN WE GET HOME,
WE'LL SEND THE BASTARD HOME
WITHOUT ANY SUPPER...
AND WE SLAP HIM
WITH EVERY ECONOMIC AND
DIPLOMATIC SANCTION THERE IS.
SIR, I HAVE
SECRETARY HANCOCK ON THE LINE.
WELL, WE'RE DOING SOMETHING.
[ Marsh ]
YES, WE ARE.
OKAY, LET'S
GET TO IT.
DO WE HAVE
SPEAKER CAPABILITY ?
IT'LL JUST TAKE A SECOND, SIR.
MARSH, MS. REDFORD,
I NEED YOU TO LISTEN...
TO THESE CONVERSATIONS
CAREFULLY.
DECISIONS WE MAKE
MUST BE MADE INSTANTANEOUSLY.
MARSH, TALK TO THE IBS FELLOW.
MAKE SURE HE'S NOT TAPING.
THE PHONE IS READY.
THE SECRETARY OF DEFENSE.
PUT YOUR CAMERA DOWN, PLEASE.
OKAY.  DON, SUPPOSE YOU TELL ME
WHY I'M HEARING ABOUT THE START
OF WORLD WAR III ON THE TV.
[ Secretary of Defense ]
THAT MAY BE OVERSTATING IT
A BIT, SIR.
MR. SECRETARY, I MAY ONLY
BE HOLDING THIS OFFICE
FOR FOUR MONTHS,
BUT THE PRESIDENT
SELECTED ME HIS SUCCESSOR...
BECAUSE OF
MY UNILATERAL UNDERSTANDING
OF FOREIGN AFFAIRS.
HELL, I DEPUTY-CHAIRED
THE NATIONAL SECURITY COUNCIL.
SO WHY DON'T WE FOREGO
THE PATRONIZING CRAP...
AND HAVE YOU EXPLAIN
TO YOUR COMMANDER-IN-CHIEF...
WHY HE'S HEARING
ABOUT THIS ON IBS.
WE'RE GETTING
THE PIECES TOGETHER, SIR.
THE S.O.B.
OVERRAN OUR POSITION ?
IT APPEARS TO BE
A COMPLETE ANNIHILATION.
WE HAVE A REPORT THEY EXECUTED
THE FEW PRISONERS THEY TOOK.
THE WOMEN TOO ?
THERE WERE NURSES AND
ADMINISTRATIVE PERSONNEL THERE,
SO, UH, YES,
WOMEN TOO.
ONE OF THEM WAS
AN APACHE HELICOPTER PILOT.
WOMEN ?  THAT'S IMPORTANT.
THAT GIVES US
HIGH MORAL GROUND.
HOW COULD WE HAVE BEEN
TAKEN BY SURPRISE LIKE THIS ?
WE SAW THE ACTIVITY,
BUT WE THOUGHT IT WAS
A MILITARY EXERCISE.
GULF WAR PROVISIONS FORBID
ANY IRAQI MOVEMENT IN THIS AREA,
EXERCISE OR OTHERWISE.
[ Secretary of Defense ]
IT'S NOT THE FIRST TIME HE'S
VIOLATED THE U.N. PROVISION.
WE DIDN'T FEEL
IT WARRANTED TAKING YOU
FROM YOUR CAMPAIGN.
FRANK, UH, COME IN.
GENERAL LANCASTER
JUST WALKED IN, SIR.
IS IT JUST
THE TWO OF YOU ?
YES, SIR.
GENTLEMEN,
I WANT TO REMIND YOU...
THAT WE SHOULD
KEEP THE NATURE
OF THE CLASSIFIED CONTENT...
THAT'S BEING
DISCUSSED HERE
TO A MINIMUM.
THE PRESIDENT IS NOT
IN A SECURE LOCATION.
WE WILL BE
IN A FEW HOURS.
[ Lancaster ]
I'M AFRAID WE DON'T HAVE TIME.
FRANK, DOES HE HAVE IT ?
WHAT ?  HE HAS WHAT ?
NUCLEAR WEAPONS ?
NO, SIR,
BIOLOGICAL AND CHEMICAL.
[ Secretary of Defense ]
WE'RE LOOKING
AT A COMPUTER SCREEN.
THE IMAGERY APPEARS TO DISPLAY
LAUNCHING PADS FOR IRAQI...
TACTICAL, CHEMICAL
AND BIOLOGICAL WEAPONS.
[ Lancaster ]
THE SITE THAT WE HAVE THERE...
CONTAINS EIGHT
CANVAS-COVERED
MISSILE TRAILERS...
AND FOUR DEPLOYED
PROBABLE MISSILE LAUNCHERS.
HOW FAR ADVANCED IS THIS ?
I'VE NEVER SEEN...
THIS KIND
OF INSTALLATION BEFORE.
THESE ARE
M.R.B.M.s.
OKAY.
ARE THEY READY TO BE FIRED,
ANY OF THEM ?
[ Secretary of Defense ]
THAT WOULD DEPEND
ON THEIR GROUND SUPPORT.
I'M HESITANT TO SAY,
BUT CONSERVATIVELY,
THE EARLIEST
THEY COULD LAUNCH
IS IN ONE HOUR, FORTY MINUTES.
THEY LOOK POSITIONED
TO ATTACK TEL AVIV.
TEL AVIV.
IN ISRAEL,
SIR.
THANK YOU.
AND GREECE
AND TURKEY AS WELL.
- WHERE ARE THESE LAUNCH PADS ?
- OUTSIDE RABAT, A FEW CLICKS
FROM THE TURKISH BORDER.
THEY'RE MOBILE.
THAT EXPLAINS WHY
WE HAD NOT YET SEEN THEM.
JESUS.  MARSH,
WHO'S RUNNING THE SHOW
OVER AT IBS ?
CARL ISAACSON.
ISAACSON.
HOWARD, YOU WANT TO HOOK UP
THIS ISAACSON FELLOW
WITH MARSH ?
THEN GET ME BEN-RAZZI.
I'M SURE HE'S ON TOP
OF THIS ALREADY.
MARSH, I'M GOING
TO HAVE TO ADDRESS
THE NATION.
- LET'S TALK TO THIS IBS GUY--
- NO, NO, NO.  NO, I DON'T THINK
YOU SHOULD ADDRESS THE NATION.
I DON'T THINK
THAT'S A GOOD IDEA.
JUST MAKE IT HAPPEN.
BUT THE WRITERS
AREN'T EVEN HERE.
PLEASE.
OKAY.  UH, HOWARD,
AS SOON AS YOU GOT
ISAACSON, LET ME KNOW.
BRING HIM
RIGHT UP.
GIVE ME WHAT OUR TROOP
MOBILIZATION STATUS IS.
WE CAN BEGIN DEFCON 1
AND MOBILIZATION
OF 3,000...
IN LESS THAN
AN HOUR.
WE WOULD RELEASE
THE TACTICAL FIGHTER WING
AT LANGLEY...
AND THEN
THE DIVISION READY BRIGADE
AT THE 82nd.
AND THAT WOULD
PUT THEM IN IRAQ WHEN ?
PARTIAL PROLIFERATION
IN TEN DAYS.
THEN WE'D HAVE
TO SLASH OUR TROOP STRENGTH
IN THE KOREAS.
BUT I BELIEVE--
I'M SORRY, SIR.
MAY I INTERRUPT ?
I BELIEVE PREMIER KIM
WHEN HE SAYS THAT
A DOWNSIZING OF OUR TROOPS...
ON THE 38th PARALLEL
WILL PROPEL HIM...
INTO A FLAT-OUT INVASION
OF NORTH KOREA.
I'M NOT GONNA DROP A DOMINO
AND ALLOW CHINA TO WALK
INTO JAPAN, BOTTOM LINE.
I'M CERTAINLY
NOT GONNA OFFER UP
ANOTHER TINY FORCE,
NAKED AND VULNERABLE
TO HUSSEIN IN THE GULF,
NOT LIKE THE 300
THAT JUST DIED.
YEAH.
RIGHT, SIR.
ARE YOU TELLING ME
THAT WE HAVE NO MANPOWER
IN THE GULF AREA ?
- THERE IS ONE CARRIER.
IT'S THE U.S.S.--
- WAIT.  HOLD IT.
WHY DIDN'T YOU TELL US
THERE WAS A CARRIER ?
WHAT DO YOU THINK THE POINT
OF THIS CONVERSATION IS ?
SIR, I WAS JUST ABOUT TO--
NOW YOU'RE TELLING US
THERE'S ONE CARRIER.
THEU.S.S. POWELL.
UH, HOLD ON, SIR.
HOLD ON, PLEASE.
YES ?
WE'RE JUST GETTING
THE PICTURES
FROM THE N.P.I.C.
[ Marsh ]
WHAT'S THAT ?
IS THAT OURS ?
IBS CORRESPONDENTS
HAVE CONFIRMED THAT THREE
IRAQI DIVISIONS--
THE HAMMURABI,
THE MEDINA LUMINOUS...
AND THE IN GOD WE TRUST--
ARE IN KUWAIT.
THE KUWAITI MILITARY FORCE
OF A FEW THOUSAND TROOPS...
MUST NOW CONTEND
WITH A HALF A MILLION
IRAQI TROOPS.
UDEI'S NOT GONNA MAKE
THE SAME MISTAKES
HIS FATHER MADE.
HE'S NOT GONNA WAIT FOR US
TO BUILD UP OUR STRENGTH.
ALL RIGHT.
THERE'S NO TOUGHER
MILITARY PROPOSITION
THAN REVERSING AN INVASION,
BUT THAT'S EXACTLY
WHAT WE'RE GOING TO DO.
I'M GONNA HANG UP THE LINE.
I'LL BE BACK TO YOU
IN TEN MINUTES.
WHEN I DO, I EXPECT TO BE ABLE
TO CONFERENCE CALL.  HOWARD ?
CONFERENCE CALL MAKES
OUR LINE UNSECURE, SIR.
HOW MANY SPEAKERPHONES
CAN WE SET UP, THEN ?
WE HAVE FOUR SECURE
SATELLITE SPEAKERPHONES
LIKE THIS ONE.
THEY'RE TRAINED ON
THE SIERRA SYSTEM.
BUT WE'VE GOT SOME
CELL PHONES, DON'T WE ?
NO, THOSE ARE UTTERLY IMPOSSIBLE
IN TERMS OF SECURITY.
I THINK WHAT WE SHOULD DO
IS WE SHOULD STICK
WITH THE SATELLITES,
AND I'LL PLACE THE CALLS
THROUGH MY Q-LINE.
THERE ARE SEVERAL UNAUTHORIZED
PEOPLE HERE.  I DON'T THINK--
THAT IS MY DECISION.
I WANT CABINET MEMBERS
AND ANY ESSENTIAL MILITARY
PERSONNEL AT THE READY.
[ Marsh ]
MAJOR CODDINGTON.
YES, SIR.
TAKE A POSITION BY THE BOOTH,
AND ACCESS ONLY
TO THE PRESIDENT, MYSELF
AND, UH, AND REDFORD.
NO PROBLEM, SIR.
ALL RIGHT.
YOU GOT A MAP ?
UH, I DON'T THINK--
I CAN CHECK IN THE VAN.
YOU LOOKING FOR A MAP
OR A GLOBE ?
A MAP.
HOWARD, WHAT ABOUT, UH--
YOU GOT A LAPTOP ?
CAN YOU PULL UP AN ATLAS
ON THE INTERNET ?
SIR, THE I-LINE MEMORY'S
NOT GOING TO ACCOMMODATE THAT.
I THINK IF YOU GET RID
OF ONE OF THESE PHONES--
NO, I NEED THE PHONE LINES.
ARE YOU TELLING ME
ALL I HAVE AT MY DISPOSAL
TO BATTLE GLOBAL CRISIS...
IS FOUR PHONES
IN A DINER ?
FOUR SECURE
SATELLITE PHONES, SIR.
SIR ?
[ Emerson ]
YES.
SIR, WE HAVE A MAP
IN THE BACK.
FINE.  THANK YOU.
COULD YOU GET IT, PLEASE,
AND SET IT UP OVER HERE ?
SIR, I HAVE
MR. ISAACSON FOR YOU.
HELLO.  MR. ISAACSON.
HEY, HOW ARE YOU ?
YEAH.  YEAH.
OH, WELL, HOLD ON.
[ Places Handset
On Cradle ]
YEAH, THIS IS MARSHALL THOMPSON.
MR. THOMPSON, HOW ARE YOU ?
YOU JUST GOT ME.  I WAS
HEADING OUT THE DOOR.
UH, YOU'RE AWARE
OF OUR SITUATION ?
YEAH, WELL, OF COURSE.
I'M HEADED TO THE STATION.
YEAH, YEAH, WELL,
IT'S OBVIOUSLY VERY GRAVE.
NOW, THE PRESIDENT NEEDS TO MAKE
AN ADDRESS TO THE NATION.
OKAY, WELL,
THAT'S GREAT.  SURE.
WE HAVE ONE OF YOUR GUYS HERE
DOING A SORT OF &quot;DAY IN
THE LIFE OF THE CAMPAIGN&quot; DEAL.
YEAH, RIGHT.  NOAH BOYD.
HE'S ONE OF OUR TOP GUYS.
YEAH, WELL, I NEVER
LIKED THE IDEA, BUT WE
COULD TURN THIS AROUND...
AND MAKE THIS BENEFICIAL
TO ALL OF US, OKAY ?
IN WHAT WAY ?
NOW, IT'S
THE DARNDEST THING.
SEE, WE'RE STUCK HERE.
WE'RE TRAPPED IN A DINER IN--
WHERE ARE WE ?
[ Katie ]
MORTY'S ROADSIDE DINER.
NO, NO, TOWN, TOWN.
- AZTEC, COLORADO.
- YEAH, WE'RE IN
AZTEC, COLORADO.
A-Z-T-E--  WHAT ?
HOME OF THE
SCREAMING BEAVERS.
HOME OF THE SCREAMING BEAVERS.
A-Z-T-E-C,
AND, UH, WE WERE
OUT CAMPAIGNING,
AND, YOU KNOW, UH,
THEN THE STORM
CAME OUT OF NOWHERE.
THE CARAVAN WAS ON ITS WAY
BACK TO AIR FORCE--
ANYWAY, WE'RE IN A DINER.
SO THE PRESIDENT
HAS TO MAKE AN ADDRESS
TO THE NATION A.S.A.P.
WELL, NO PROBLEM.
CAN YOU GIVE ME TO NOAH ?
UH, YEAH, HE'S RIGHT--
- NOAH.
- YES, SIR, I'M HERE.
HE'S RIGHT HERE.
IS THIS POSSIBLE,
NOAH ?
NOTHING'S EVER A PROBLEM, SIR.
WE CAN GO THROUGH
THE I-COM LINE.
TAKE ME LESS THAN
A MINUTE TO BOOT IT UP.
[ Isaacson ]
OKAY, THAT'S--
THAT'S THAT, THEN.
NOAH'S GOT
YOU COVERED.
ALL RIGHT.  UH--
[ Clears Throat ]
NOW HERE'S THE DEAL.
THIS SPEECH IS YOURS EXCLUSIVE.
ALL RECORDING DEVICES
WILL GO ON AND OFF
ACCORDING TO OUR INSTRUCTIONS.
OKAY, LET ME
TALK TO NOAH.
[ Marsh ]  YEAH.
YES, SIR ?
[ Isaacson ]
GOT THAT NOAH ?
LOUD AND CLEAR.
GOOD.
OKAY.  ALL RIGHT.
I'LL GET WORD
TO HIGHLAND HILLS.
NOW, LISTEN.  I DON'T WANT
ANY OF THIS 60 MINUTES
HIDDEN CAMERA BULLSHIT.
STRAIGHTFORWARD.
YOU GO OVER THERE.
SIR, I HAVE PRIME MINISTER
BEN-RAZZI ON THE PHONE.
MR. PRIME MINISTER.
YES, SIR, I'M FULLY
AWARE OF THE GRAVITY
OF THE SITUATION.
YES, SIR, WELL,
SOON MY COUNTRY WILL BE
AT A STATE OF FULL READINESS.
I UNDERSTAND.
WHAT ?  NO, SIR.
SIR, I BEG OF YOU
TO RECALL THOSE PLANES,
OR AT LEAST
KEEP THEM IN YOUR AIRSPACE
FOR THE NEXT TEN MINUTES.
NO, NO, I SEE THIS
NO DIFFERENTLY
THAN BUSH DID IN '91.
AN INCURSION ON YOUR PART
WILL ONLY FORM AN ALLIANCE
AMONG THE ARAB NATIONS.
WELL, MR. PRIME--
MR. PRIME MINISTER,
I'VE MADE ARRANGEMENTS
TO GO ON IBS LIVE...
IN A COUPLE OF MINUTES HERE.
GLOBALLY, YES.
EXACTLY.  EXACTLY.
THAT WOULD--
THAT'S ALL I'M ASKING.
THAT WOULD BE GREAT.
YES, SIR.
I DON'T THINK YOU'LL HAVE
ANY NEED TO TAKE AN OFFENSIVE
ACTION AT THAT POINT.
ALL RIGHT.
THANK YOU, MR. PRIME MINISTER.
OKAY.
THE PRIME MINISTER
HAS AGREED...
TO KEEP HIS AIR FORCE
IN ABEYANCE UNTIL AFTER
THE ADDRESS.
LET'S KEEP AN OPEN,
SECURE LINE THERE.  OKAY.
LET'S GET READY
FOR THE ADDRESS.
OKAY.
ALL RIGHT.
NO, OFF, OFF, OFF.
WE'RE NOT READY YET.
[ Marsh ]
FACTS, FIGURES, LOCATIONS
ARE NOT IMPORTANT RIGHT NOW.
THE IMPORTANT THING
IS TO CONVEY A SENSE
OF DETERMINATION...
ABOUT WHAT IT IS
WE'RE GONNA DO AS A COUNTRY.
THAT'S WHAT THE AMERICAN PEOPLE
HAVE TO HEAR.  THAT'S WHAT
THIS SPEECH IS ABOUT.
I CAN VERIFY
WHAT HAS TAKEN PLACE,
OBVIOUSLY.
YES.
AND THEN I NEED TO BE
VERY, VERY SPECIFIC.
YEAH.  IF YOU FIND YOURSELF
IN GENERAL WATERS,
BE VERY SPECIFIC ABOUT IT.
EXCUSE ME, MR. PRESIDENT.
AS YOUR NATIONAL
SECURITY ADVISOR,
I MUST INFORM YOU...
THAT WHAT YOU'RE ABOUT TO DO
IS NOT IN YOUR BEST INTEREST
OR THAT OF THE COUNTRY.
NOTED.  ON THE RECORD.
HOWEVER, HE IS GOING ON
IN A FEW MINUTES.
SO IS THERE ANYTHING
THAT YOU CAN ADVISE
THE PRESIDENT...
THAT WOULD BE HELPFUL
FOR WHAT HE IS ABOUT TO SAY
TO THE AMERICAN PEOPLE ?
IF UDEI IS IN KUWAIT
ON HIS WAY TO SAUDI ARABIA,
THAT MEANS
THAT HE HAS CLEARED OUT
ALL OF THE MINEFIELDS.
WE ARE NOT TALKING
BRIGADES HERE.
WE ARE TALKING ARMIES.
I APPRECIATE THAT
VERY MUCH--
THE REPUBLICAN GUARD...
IS OUT IN FULL FORCE,
AND THAT IS A TOTALLY
DIFFERENT MATTER HERE, SIR.
THE DEBATE IS OVER.
I'M GOING ON THE AIR.
NOAH ?
YES.
WE HAVE TO BRING THE MONITOR
OVER WHERE I CAN READ IT...
AND THE PRESIDENT
CAN SEE IT.
[ Noah ]
I'M JUST GRABBING
MY TRIPOD.  JUST A SEC.
I'LL WATCH THE MONITOR
AND MAKE SURE THAT IBS--
REMEMBER,
IBS IS WAY AHEAD
OF EVERYBODY ON THIS.
EVERYBODY KNOWS BASICALLY
WHAT'S GOING ON.
I NEED TO GO ON
AND BE VERY SPECIFIC
ABOUT WHAT I'M DOING ABOUT IT.
YOU'RE THE ONLY ONE
WHO CAN DO THAT.
LET'S DO THIS.
[ Marsh ]
WAIT, WAIT, WAIT.
HOLD IT, HOLD IT.
WE NEED A DIFFERENT CHAIR.
THIS CHAIR IS NOT ANY GOOD.
IT'S THE ONLY CHAIR
WE GOT.
THIS IS RIDICULOUS,
THIS CHAIR.
THERE ARE AT LEAST THREE
ARMORED DIVISIONS IN KUWAIT.
OKAY, NOW, LISTEN.
IN THE RED ?
BAD COLOR.
IT'S A DISTRACTION.
IF YOU COULD JUST--
EVERYBODY, ACTUALLY,
JUST MOVE TO THAT SIDE.
[ Irving ]
IRAQ STILL USES SOVIET MIGs
IN ITS AIR FORCE.
I THINK YOU SHOULD WEAR
A BLAZER.
OKAY.
ALL RIGHT,
UH, COULD YOU
GET A BLAZER ?
AT LEAST ONE MORE IRAQI DIVISION
HAS ENTERED THE FRAY--
FORTY-FIVE SECONDS
BEFORE WE GET LIVE !
DEX, DEX.
NO TIME.
ALL RIGHT, COME BACK.
WE NEED TO GO OVER YOUR SPEECH.
[ Man ]
ONE THING IS CLEAR, AND THAT IS
THAT THIS IS A LARGE ARMY.
EMERSON THE DIPLOMAT,
EMERSON THE PEACEKEEPER,
EMERSON
THE COOLHEADED.
I HEAR YOU, MARSH.
IT'S GONNA BE GOOD.
[ Emerson ]
IT'S GOING TO BE FINE.
THANK YOU.
- WE'VE JUST RECEIVED WORD--
- BACK AGAINST THE WALL.
PLEASE BE QUIET DURING THIS.
THE PRESIDENT WILL BE
ADDRESSING THE NATION.
THERE IS NO TIME DELAY.
WHEN GERALD GOES TO YOU,
START SPEAKING NATURALLY.
RIGHT HERE.
I'LL BE WATCHING THAT.
...FROM A DINER
IN AZTEC, COLORADO.
NICE AND STILL.
WATCH FOR MY CUE.
[ Irving ]  READY ?  VERY GOOD.
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
THE PRESIDENT
OF THE UNITED STATES.
HERE WE GO.
MY FELLOW AMERICANS,
AS THE WORLD NOW KNOWS,
THE LEADER OF IRAQ,
UDEI HUSSEIN,
IN COMPLETE DEFIANCE
OF U.N. RESOLUTIONS
687, 773 AND 883,
HAS INVADED
THE EMIRATE OF KUWAIT
AS HIS FATHER DID IN 1990.
IN THE PROCESS,
HE HAS KILLED SEVERAL
HUNDRED AMERICAN TROOPS...
SERVING AS
A PEACEKEEPING FORCE.
OUR INTELLIGENCE
ALSO INDICATES THAT AT LEAST
EIGHT IRAQI DIVISIONS...
ARE HOLDING KUWAIT
AND PROGRESSING TO SAUDI ARABIA.
THIS IS NOT THE ACT
OF A WARRIOR NOR A LEADER...
BUT THAT OF A BARBARIAN.
WE MUST NOW ASSUME THAT
UDEI HUSSEIN'S OBJECTIVE...
IS ONE OF A MANIFEST DESTINY.
AT PRESENT,
NEARLY 80% OF OUR TROOPS...
ARE ON THE SEA OF JAPAN
OR THE 38th PARALLEL.
TO PUT IT
AS BLUNTLY AS POSSIBLE,
THE UNITED STATES OF AMERICA
DOES NOT HAVE THE CAPABILITY...
OF DEALING
WITH THE IRAQI INVASION FORCE
WITH CONVENTIONAL EXPEDITION.
THERE ARE DEFINING MOMENTS
IN THE HISTORY OF EVERY NATION,
MOMENTS WHICH DELINEATE
OUR STRENGTHS AND OUR CHARACTER.
OFTEN THESE MOMENTS REQUIRE
THAT A HARDER RIGHT BE MADE
OVER AN EASIER WRONG.
IT IS WITH THAT IN MIND THAT
I NOW WISH TO SPEAK DIRECTLY
TO THE IRAQI PEOPLE.
UNLESS YOUR LEADER,
UDEI HUSSEIN,
IMMEDIATELY WITHDRAWS
FROM HIS POSITION IN KUWAIT,
LEAVING ALL WEAPONS BEHIND
WHERE THEY ARE,
AND TURNS HIMSELF IN
FOR ARREST...
AT THE AMERICAN EMBASSY
IN KUWAIT,
I WILL AUTHORIZE THE DROPPING...
OF A MULTI-MEGATON
NUCLEAR DEVICE
ON THE CITY OF BAGHDAD.
I'M NOW GIVING YOU,
THE CITIZENS OF BAGHDAD,
ONE HOUR AND TWENTY MINUTES
TO LEAVE THE CITY,
SAVE YOUR LIVES
AND THOSE OF YOUR CHILDREN.
IT IS MY DEEPEST AND MOST
HEARTFELT WISH AND PRAYER...
THAT UDEI HUSSEIN
ACCEPT HIS RESPONSIBILITY...
AS THE SOVEREIGN OF A NATION
AND A RESPONSIBLE MEMBER
OF THE INTERNATIONAL COMMUNITY.
THAT IS IT FOR NOW.
GOD SAVE US ALL.
THANK YOU.
OKAY, LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
IF YOU ARE JUST JOINING US,
THE PRESIDENT
OF THE UNITED STATES
HAS JUST GIVEN WHAT MAY BE...
THE MOST DRAMATIC SPEECH EVER
GIVEN BY A SITTING PRESIDENT.
[ Marsh ]  JESUS.
WHAT ?  WHAT ?
WELL, I MEAN,
THAT WASN'T EXACTLY
PEACEMAKING, WAS IT ?
SUBJECTIVE, ISN'T IT ?
ALL RIGHT, THANK YOU, EVERYBODY.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
HE WOULD ORDER
THE DROPPING OF A NUCLEAR BOMB
ON BAGHDAD UNLESS:
ONE, UDEI HUSSEIN WITHDRAWS
AND RETREATS FROM KUWAIT;
TWO--
[ Lancaster ]
ACCORDING TO WEATHER INTEL,
NAVIGATING AN AIRCRAFT
TO YOUR POSITION
IS IMPOSSIBLE.
WE COULD RISK IT AND TRY
SENDING A HELICOPTER TO YOU.
NO, NO, NO, NO.
WE COULD RISK SENDING
A HELICOPTER HERE,
BUT WE CANNOT RISK
PUTTING THE PRESIDENT
ON A HELICOPTER OUT OF HERE.
[ Defense Secretary ]  AGREED.
NORAD HAS DISPATCHED A WINTER
A.P.C. TO YOUR POSITION.
IT SHOULD BE THERE
IN ABOUT AN HOUR.
ALL RIGHT.
WHAT WILL MY ABILITY BE
TO COMMUNICATE
ONCE INSIDE THE A.P.C. ?
THERE ARE SHORTWAVES
ON ALL THE A.P.C.s,
HOWEVER THE LINES ARE NONSECURE.
IF THEY'RE NONSECURE,
FORGET IT.  BOTTOM LINE,
WE WORK FROM HERE.
MR. PRESIDENT,
ADMIRAL MILLER HERE,
CENTRAL COMMAND.
WITH YOUR PERMISSION,
I'D LIKE TO SPEAK TO YOU
OFF SPEAKER.
ADMIRAL, HUSSEIN'S WEAPONS
GO HOT IN AN HOUR AND A HALF.
I WILL NOT HOLD
YOUR COMMENTS
AGAINST YOU.
OKAY.  SIR, I MUST OBJECT
TO YOUR THREAT ON IBS.
HUSSEIN'S WEAPONS CAN BE
DEALT WITH CONVENTIONALLY.
OUR HIGH-TECH WEAPONS CAN DO
ALL THAT THE NUKES CAN DO--
NO, NO, NO.
WE'VE BEEN DOWN
THAT ROAD BEFORE.
THAT'S
A GOOD POINT, SIR.
THAT'S NOT A GOOD POINT.  WE'VE
BEEN DOWN THAT ROAD BEFORE.
LISTEN, PEOPLE !
LET'S BE CLEAR.
IF WE ATTACK, WE ATTACK,
AND IT'S GONNA BE MAJOR.
I'M NOT GONNA SEND OVER
A COUPLE OF TOMAHAWKS,
AND GET ON THE PHONE AND SAY,
&quot;HOW DO YOU LIKE THEM APPLES ?&quot;
IT'S NEVER WORKED BEFORE.
HUSSEIN'S LIKE HIS OLD MAN.
HE'S A SURVIVOR.
AFTER EVERY CALAMITY, HE EMERGES
DUSTING OFF HIS UNIFORM ASKING,
&quot;IS THAT IT ?&quot;
[ Lancaster ]
EVEN A LIMITED AIR ATTACK
IS AN EXTENSIVE AIR ATTACK.
IT'S NOT 20 OR 50 SORTIES
BUT HUNDREDS.
[ Miller ]
WHICH THE U.S.S. POWELL
CAN'T ACCOMMODATE.
RIGHT.  THEN WE'D HAVE
TO MOVE INTO THEIR PLANES,
AIRFIELDS, SAM SITES.
[ Miller ]  GRANTED,
BUT EVEN THAT DOESN'T LEAVE US
WITH JUST THE NUCLEAR OPTION.
OKAY, OKAY.  BEFORE WE
CARRY OUT THE &quot;SHOULD WE
OR SHOULDN'T WE&quot; DEBATE,
LET'S ENSURE
WHAT WE IN FACT CAN DO.
GENERAL RILEY,
WHAT DO WE HAVE ?
WELL, MR. PRESIDENT,
AT STRATCOM
UNDER START 2,
OUR MISSILES ARE NOW SET
ON A TRAJECTORY THAT ENDS
IN THE ATLANTIC.
WHAT BRILLIANT
COMMANDER-IN-CHIEF
CAME UP WITH THAT ONE ?
HOW LONG TO RESET
THE TARGET ?
OUR RECORD'S 20 MINUTES.
IT USED TO BE SHORTER,
BUT WE DE-ALERTED
FIVE YEARS AGO.
[ Emerson ]
WHAT DO WE HAVE
IN OUR ARSENAL ?
[ Riley ]
SEVERAL TRIPLE WARHEAD
EXCALIBUR 3 NUCLEAR MISSILES.
- WE COULD HIT OUR DESIGNATED
TARGETS IN TWO HOURS.
- [ Emerson ]  TWO HOURS ?
NO, THAT'S UNACCEPTABLE.
WE HAVE TO HIT IRAQ BEFORE
THEIR WEAPONS CAN GO HOT.
HOW THE UNITED STATES
WOULD LAUNCH A NUCLEAR ATTACK,
PARTICULARLY WHEN IT MUST BE
INITIATED AND COMPLETED IN LESS
THAN AN HOUR AND A HALF...
IS VERY LIMITING.
WE DO HAVE FILE FOOTAGE HERE.
THE U.S.S. POWELL IS
OUR ONE AND ONLY WARSHIP
IN THE GULF REGION.
THE POWELL IS ONE
OF ONLY TWO SURFACE SHIPS
TO CARRY NUCLEAR WEAPONS...
SINCE PRESIDENT BUSH'S
NUCLEAR BAN INSTITUTED IN 1992.
[ Emerson ]
OKAY, WHAT WEAPONS
DO WE HAVE ON THEPOWELL ?
[ Lancaster ]
THE FASTEST DEPLOYMENT
WOULD BE BY TOMAHAWK.
DETONATION
IN 40 MINUTES.
OKAY, BUT IF WE DO THAT,
WE HAVE TO GIVE HUSSEIN
ENOUGH TIME TO COMPLY.
WE COULD LAUNCH TOMAHAWKS
45 MINUTES FROM NOW.
HE WOULD HAVE THAT TIME
PLUS AN ADDITIONAL 40
TO COMPLY, CORRECT ?
[ Miller ]  NOT REALLY.
ONCE THAT MISSILE'S
ON ITS WAY, IT'S ON ITS WAY.
THERE MUST BE SOME WAY
TO DIVERT IT, RIGHT ?
[ Lancaster ]
WE CAN DO TWO THINGS...
IF HUSSEIN COMPLIES
WHILE THE MISSILE
IS IN FLIGHT.
FIRSTLY, WE CAN DETONATE.
THEN WE'D HAVE NUCLEAR RAIN
ALL OVER THE DETONATION AREA.
POSSIBLY
A FRIENDLY ONE.
EXACTLY, MA'AM.
WE CAN ALSO
DEACTIVATE THE BOMB.
THE PROBLEM IS THAT, THEN,
WHERE THE BOMB LANDS,
IT LANDS.
AND THAT'S LIKE
GIVING HUSSEIN
A FREE NUCLEAR WEAPON.
[ Lancaster ]  SIR,
I'D SAY OUR ONLY OPTION IS TO
ACTUALLY DROP A BOMB ON BAGHDAD.
WE COULD USE OUR B-2s
BASED IN SAUDI.
HOW LONG TO LOAD HER
AND PUT HER UP IN THE AIR ?
ON YOUR ORDERS, SIR.
THE GOOD NEWS IS
THE B-2 CAN BE RECALLED
AT THE LAST SECOND IF NECESSARY.
WE CAN STRIKE
WITHIN AN HOUR.
THIS IS PROBLEMATIC.
THE B-2s WE'D HAVE TO FLY
OVER SAUDI TERRITORY.
WE'D HAVE TO GET PERMISSION.
THIS GUY IS INVADING
THEIR OIL FIELDS.
OF COURSE WE'RE GONNA
GET PERMISSION.
THERE IS NO &quot;OF COURSE.&quot;
I KNOW THESE GUYS.
SHARING A LITTLE BABA GHANNOUJ
AT A STATE DINNER...
DOES NOT
MAKE YOU KNOW THEM.
OKAY.  ALL RIGHT.
WE'RE GONNA PUT
THE B-2 UP.
WE DON'T HAVE TIME
FOR PROTOCOL.
SIR, IT IS NOT
A MATTER OF PROTOCOL.
IT'S INTERNATIONAL LAW.
UNDERSTOOD.
CONSIDER IT AN ACT
OF CIVIL DISOBEDIENCE.
GET ME SECRETARY OF STATE
AND, UH, GIVE ME
A FEW MINUTES, FOLKS.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING ?
USE SOME COMMON SENSE.
COME ON.
MM-HMM.
SPECIALTY OF THE HOUSE.
OH, WOW.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
BITCH OF A SITUATION
YOU'VE GOT ON YOUR HANDS.
YES.  YES, IT IS.
- IF I WERE YOU--
- EXCUSE ME.  MAY WE HAVE
A WORD HERE, PLEASE ?
I'LL GET THAT.
OKAY.  WOULD YOU
LIKE SOMETHING ?
NO, I'M FINE.  THANKS.
MR. PRESIDENT,
I WAS THINKING--
GAYLE.
WHAT CAN YOU
TELL ME ABOUT
ADMIRAL MILLER ?
MILLER ?
YES.
DO YOU
KNOW HIM ?
HE WAS ONE OF THE PRESIDENT'S
NOMINEES FOR CHAIR OF THE J.C.S.
TWO YEARS AGO.
HE LOST OUT TO LANCASTER.
HE'S BEEN RUNNING
CENTRAL COMMAND EVER SINCE THEN.
SOUTHWEST ASIA, THE MIDDLE EAST,
THOSE ARE HIS TERRITORIES,
BUT HE'S BASED IN McDILL,
IN FLORIDA.
THE ARAB COUNTRIES
DON'T WANT US
IN THE GULF AREA.
MY GUESS IS
HE'S PROBABLY FEELING
LIKE A PAPER TIGER.
YEAH, I THINK SO.
THAT CERTAINLY EXPLAINS
THE GIANT CHIP ON HIS SHOULDER.
IT'S A CHIP YOU NEED
RIGHT NOW, SIR.
MADAM CHAIRMAN, WE JUST MIGHT
HAVE TO DROP THAT WEAPON.
IF WE DO--
[ Sighing ]
YOU KNOW, TRUMAN DEBATED
AGONIZINGLY BEFORE HIROSHIMA.
NOT SO MUCH
ABOUT DROPPING THE BOMB...
BUT WHETHER OR NOT TO FOREWARN
THE JAPANESE PEOPLE.
WE'D HAVE
WON THE WAR
EITHER WAY,
BUT HE WOULD HAVE
SLEPT BETTER
THE REST OF HIS LIFE.
I'M DETERMINED TO SPARE
AS MANY LIVES AS I CAN,
AND I JUST, FOR THE LIFE OF ME,
CAN'T IMAGINE...
HUSSEIN IS GONNA LET
THE CITY OF BAGHDAD DIE.
OUR STRATEGY IS
TO ROLL THE DICE...
THAT HE'LL COMPLY.
WITH ALL DUE RESPECT
TO YOUR VEGAS METAPHOR, SIR,
NUCLEAR WARFARE
IS NOT ABOUT GAMBLING.
IT'S ABOUT CERTAINTY.
STRATEGIC CERTAINTY.
MORAL CERTAINTY.
SECRETARY CLIFT
IS ON THE PHONE.
DO I SEEM UNCERTAIN
TO YOU, GAYLE ?
HUSSEIN, FOR EXAMPLE,
COULD WITHHOLD THE OIL FROM US,
OR HE COULD FLOOD
THE WORLD MARKET.
IN ANY CASE, HUSSEIN WILL HAVE
THE LEVERAGE TO MANIPULATE
OIL PRICES AT WILL,
AND YOU CAN ASSUME THAT--
WELL, DON'T FORGET, GERALD,
IN 1990, THE ONLY PEOPLE
SMILING WERE THE BOYS
AT EXXON AND SHELL,
WHO SAW GAS PRICES
AND STOCKS--
DEBRA, WHERE ARE YOU NOW ?
I'M ON MY WAY TO STATE.
UH-HUH, AND WHAT
ARE YOU SENSING ?
WELL, I'M NOT
SENSING SUPPORT.
JUST ABOUT EVERYBODY
IS DEMANDING AN AUDIENCE,
AND ANDREA IN GREECE
IS GOING TO DEFCON 1.
DEFCON 1 HAS GOT TO BE
THE LIMIT.  IT CANNOT ESCALATE
ONE INCH BEYOND THAT.
UNDERSTOOD.
OKAY, I'M GONNA, UH,
ISSUE AN EXECUTIVE ORDER
FREEZING ALL KUWAITI ASSETS.
MARSH, WE NEED TO GET ON
WITH TREASURY.
YEAH.
OR IS IT THE A.G. ?
NO, I THINK
IT'S TREASURY.
YEAH.  OKAY.
ALL RIGHT.
IT'S TREASURY.
THE OIL LOBBY
IS GONNA GO APE-SHIT.
YEAH, I KNOW,
BUT GET ON WITH NICHOLS
ANYWAYS AND GET THAT
ROLLING ON THE STAT.
I'M SURE HE CAN WORK OFF
MY VERBAL DIRECTIVE FOR NOW.
DEBRA, YOU NEED TO GET ON
WITH ANY OTHER FOREIGN NATION
THAT'LL DO THE SAME.
WE NEED TO FREEZE THOSE ASSETS
BEFORE UDEI CAN GET TO THEM.
GOT IT.
OKAY,
AND I NEED GESTAING.
MY GUESS IS THAT HE'LL FOLLOW
THE FRENCH PATTERN OF DENYING US
USE OF THEIR AIRSPACE.
GIVE ME SOME TIME.
I THINK I CAN MAKE
HIS SQUARES.
NO, FORGET THAT, OKAY ?
WHAT I NEED IS TO SPEAK
WITH GESTAING.
VERY WELL.
AS YOU WILL.
WHAT HAS BEEN MUCH LOUDER--
THIS IS COMING FROM
THE CONGRESSIONAL SIDE--
IS WHAT SEVERAL MEMBERS
OF THE WHITE HOUSE--
EXCUSE ME,
SEVERAL MEMBERS
OF THE HOUSE--
ARE CALLING
A DELIBERATE VIOLATION
OF THE WAR POWERS ACT.
WELL, UPDATE US
ON THAT.
SIR, IT'S THE OVAL OFFICE,
LINE TWO, MR. OMARI.
NO, NO, NO, NO,
NO, NO, NO.
MR. PRESIDENT,
THIS IS INAPPROPRIATE.
YOU SHOULD NOT NEGOTIATE
WITH AN EMISSARY
FROM ANOTHER HEAD OF STATE.
YOU SHOULD LEAVE THAT
TO GAYLE OR MYSELF.
ABSOLUTELY.
NORMALLY, YES.
DULY NOTED, BUT I
NEED TO DO THIS.
- ON THE RECORD.
- RECORD.
[ Beeping ]
MR. OMARI ?
IT'S ALICE, SIR.  I HAVE
MR. OMARI.  HE'S WITH
A TRANSLATOR.  GO AHEAD.
MR. OMARI,
THIS IS THE PRESIDENT.
[ Speaking Arabic ]
[ Translator ]  I CALL YOU
ON A MATTER OF GRAVE CONCERN
TO MY GOVERNMENT, MR. EMERSON.
YES, THIS IS VERY GRAVE.
YOUR ANNOUNCEMENT HAS CREATED
HAVOC IN OUR STREETS.
OUR HOSPITALS ARE FLOODED
WITH YOUNG CHILDREN,
THE VICTIMS OF STAMPEDES.
I REQUEST OF YOU
A TAKING BACK OF YOUR COMMENT.
MR. THOMPSON, SIR--
[ Emerson ]  GIVE US
ONE SECOND, PLEASE.
WHAT IS IT ?
FORGIVE ME,
MR. PRESIDENT,
BUT, UH,
THIS MAN ISN'T TRANSLATING
CORRECTLY FOR YOU, SIR.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN ?
WELL, IT'S A LOT
OF THINGS.
THEY'RE SMALL THINGS,
BUT THEY COULD ADD UP
TO SOMETHING BIG.
LIKE ?
HE SAID,
&quot;I REQUEST OF YOU,&quot;
WHEN WHAT I HEARD
THIS OMARI REALLY SAY IS,
&quot;I DEMAND OF YOU.&quot;
HE'S GOT A TONE
IN HIS VOICE, SIR.
SO YOU SPEAK ARABIC ?
YES, SIR.
I'M U.S. ARMY, RETIRED, M.I.
- I WAS A DECRYPTOR
IN DESERT STORM, SIR.
- IS THAT RIGHT ?
YES, SIR.
YES, IT IS.
ALL RIGHT.
WELL, THEN,
WELCOME ABOARD.
YOU'RE OUR TRANSLATOR.
WHAT'S YOUR NAME ?
I'M SPECIAL AGENT DEXTER, SIR.
I'M IN CHARGE
OF YOUR DOMESTIC
TRAVELING DETAIL.
SHIT !
I SHOULD KNOW THAT.
I'M SORRY.
PLEASE, SIT DOWN.
EXCUSE ME, SPECIAL AGENT.
I JUST WANT YOU TO KNOW, SIR,
THAT THIS IS NOT PRUDENT.
THERE'S A SPECIAL TRAINING
THAT GOES ALONG
WITH THIS LINE OF WORK.
NATURALLY.  THERE ISN'T
TIME FOR THAT.
I JUST WANT YOU TO KNOW THAT.
I APPRECIATE IT.
OKAY.
YOU'RE WELCOME.
UH, LISTEN CAREFULLY,
SPEAK CAREFULLY,
OBVIOUSLY,
AND, UH,
DO YOUR BEST.
I WILL, SIR.
OKAY.
[ Marsh ]
OKAY, AND ALL SET ?
READY.
EVERYONE READY ?
MMM.
GO.
MR. OMARI,
I NOW HAVE A TRANSLATOR.
WE'RE READY WHEN YOU ARE.
MR. EMERSON, YOUR THREATS
ARE THE MOST BARBARIC ACT...
EVER PERPETUATED
AGAINST OUR NATION--
UH, PEACE-LOVING NATION.
I BELIEVE YOUR PEOPLE
TO BE PEACE-LOVING.
YOUR LEADER, HOWEVER,
IS CLEARLY IN VIOLATION
OF U.N. RESOLUTIONS.
OUR SATELLITES HAVE DETECTED
LAUNCH PADS FOR BIOLOGICAL
AND CHEMICAL WEAPONS...
IN RABAT AND OTHER LOCATIONS--
WEAPONS WHICH ARE OUTLAWED
BY U.N. RESOLUTIONS NUMBER--
I SUGGEST THAT
YOU REEXAMINE YOUR--
HE SOUNDS ANGRY NOW, SIR.
BELLIGERENT.
WE WILL NOT STAND
FOR YOUR ACCUSATIONS.
ARE YOU DENYING
THE EXISTENCE OF CHEMICAL
AND BIOLOGICAL WEAPONS ?
OKAY, SIR.  HE'S CONFERRING
WITH SOMEONE BEHIND HIM.
I CAN'T QUITE MAKE OUT
WHO IT IS, HOWEVER.
HE SAID
SOMETHING ABOUT--
OKAY, SIR,
HE'S BACK.
WE, UH, HAVE EVERY RIGHT
TO DEFEND OURSELVES.
IT IS THE RIGHT
OF EVERY SOVEREIGN NATION.
YOU KNOW AS WELL AS I DO
THAT DIRECTING FULLY ARMED...
CHEMICAL
OR BIOLOGICAL WEAPONS...
AT ANY OTHER SOVEREIGN NATION
IS BY EVERY STANDARD
AN ACT OF AGGRESSION.
I MUST WARN YOU,
MR. AMBASSADOR,
MY SPEECH WAS NOT IDLE.
YOU MUST MEET OUR TERMS
UNCONDITIONALLY...
IN JUST UNDER
40 MINUTES.
THERE IS NO NEGOTIATION.
HE'S RATHER HYSTERICAL NOW, SIR.
YOU ARE A, UH,
PUPPET OF ZION.
YOU ARE NOT AN ELECTED LEADER
OF YOUR NATION.
I AM THE PRESIDENT
OF THE UNITED STATES.
WHEN AN ELECTED LEADER...
IS IN PLACE,
PERHAPS THEN
WE WILL NEGOTIATE.
UNDERSTAND, UH, THE, UH,
SPLIT SECOND...
THAT YOUR AIR FORCE CROSSES
INTO IRAQI AIRSPACE--
YOUR AIR DEFENSE HAS NO CAPACITY
OTHER THAN PRIMITIVE SYSTEMS
WHICH WE CAN EASILY OVERCOME.
I ASSURE YOU, OUR AIR WING
WILL BE OVER BAGHDAD PROPER...
SEVERAL MINUTES BEFORE YOU'VE
REACHED LAUNCH CAPABILITY.
I REPEAT, WE WILL TAKE
NECESSARY ACTIONS.
AND I REPEAT,
UNLESS I HAVE PROOF
AND AM CONVINCED...
THAT YOUR WEAPONS
WILL NOT BE HOT, WE WILL
MAKE GOOD ON MY PROMISE.
UNLESS I AM CONVINCED
BY OUR SATELLITES THAT YOU
ARE LAYING DOWN ARMS...
AND EQUIPMENT
AND RETURN--
SIR.
HE'S LEFT THE PHONE, SIR.
WHAT ?
HE'S CONFERRING
WITH SOMEONE
BEHIND HIM, SIR.
I CAN'T MAKE OUT
WHO IT IS
OR WHAT IT IS,
BUT IT'S SOME KIND
OF ARGUMENT, SIR.
OKAY, HE'S BACK.
I WILL NOT NEGOTIATE
WITH A JEW.
IT IS MY, UH,
DEFINED DUTY
AND OBLIGATION...
AND INSTRUCTIONS
NOT TO NEGOTIATE
WITH A JEW.
THIS IS WHY I TOLD YOU
THIS WAS NOT A GOOD IDEA.
- HE HUNG UP, SIR.
- HE WHAT ?
HE HUNG UP ?
YES, MA'AM.
HOWARD, RECONNECT.
ARE YOU SURE ?
NO, IT WAS
DISTINCT.
DEFINITELY THE SOUND
OF A PHONE SLAMMING DOWN
ON A RECEIVER, SIR.
[ Redford ]
THAT WAS INEVITABLE.
ISRAEL WILL NOT TIRE
IN ITS DEFENSE,
AND THE I.D.F. WILL CONTINUE...
BALANCING BETWEEN
DETERRENCE AND RESTRAINT.
IT SHOULD NOT
BE AN ISSUE,
AND IT WILL NOT BE.
I THINK WHAT
GAYLE MEANS IS...
I KNOW WHAT GAYLE MEANS.
IT'S ONE THING
IF GEORGE BUSH DROPPED
A BOMB ON AN ARAB COUNTRY.
IT'S WAR.
IF YOU DROP IT, A JEW--
- IT'S JIHAD.
- A HOLY WAR.
THE PROBLEM
WITH JIHAD IS, YOU KNOW
WHEN YOU'VE LOST THE WAR.
- YOU JUST DON'T KNOW
WHEN YOU'VE WON IT.
- THAT'S RIGHT.
WHEN DO YOU STOP FIGHTING
FOR ALLAH ?
AT LEAST SADDAM WAS SECULAR.
UDEI'S BEEN PLAYING
THE ALLAH CARD FOR YEARS.
YES.
WHICH IS WHY WE HAVE
TO WIN THIS WAR NOW.
DROPPING AN ATOM BOMB
ISN'T A WAR, SIR.
[ Marsh ]
THAT'S RIGHT.
KATIE, SIT DOWN.
ARE YOU FOLLOWING
ANY OF THIS ?
I THINK SO.
IT IS DIFFICULT
NOT TO.
YEAH,
I IMAGINE SO.
MY STAFF HERE THINKS
THAT MY BEING JEWISH...
MAY AFFECT MY DECISION
ABOUT WHAT TO DO
WITH HUSSEIN AND IRAQ--
THAT I HAVE SOME BIAS,
SOME RACIST--
SIR,
YOU'RE TAKING THIS
WAY OUT OF CONTEXT.
THAT'S NOT
WHAT I MEANT.
NO.
WHAT DO YOU THINK ?
I'M NOT ONE TO SAY.
THERE'S NOT A LOT
OF JEWS IN AZTEC.
I MEAN, SOME MAY PASS BY
IF THEY'RE TRUCKERS,
BUT FOR THE MOST PART,
I CAN'T MAKE A COMMENT...
ON THINGS
HAVING TO DO
WITH JEWS.
IS IT OKAY TO SAY &quot;JEWS,&quot;
OR DO I HAVE TO SAY
&quot;JEWISH AMERICANS&quot; ?
YOU'RE DOING FINE.
WELL,
THE ONLY THING
I KNOW IS...
THAT YOU GUYS
DON'T BELIEVE IN JESUS,
AND THAT MEANS THAT...
[ Clicks Tongue ]
IF YOU ARE THE PRESIDENT
OF THE UNITED STATES,
YOU HAVE NOBODY
TO ANSWER TO
BUT YOURSELF ?
YOU KNOW,
THE TRUTH IS,
I'M AN ATHEIST.
EVERY PRESIDENT
MUST BECOME AN ATHEIST.
YOU TAKE THE OATH,
AND THEN YOU MUST
LEAVE BEHIND...
ALL THOUGHTS
OF AN AFTERLIFE,
A BETTER PLACE BEYOND.
MY RESPONSIBILITY,
MY PURPOSE...
IS TO PRESERVE
OUR EXISTENCE
HERE ON EARTH.
OKAY.  WELL, THANK YOU
VERY MUCH, YOUNG LADY.
NOW, I'D LOVE
A FRESH CUP OF COFFEE.
YOU WANT SOME MORE ?
YES, SOME MORE
COFFEE.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
IF YOU COULD--
HOW 'BOUT
SOME DECAF ?
NO, REGULAR COFFEE.
YEAH, REGULAR COFFEE.
OH, OKAY.
THAT'S WHAT YOU DO,
THAT'S WHAT WE DO.
THIS IS WHAT--
WE'RE ALL WINNERS.
ARE YOU TRYING TO GET
THE VEGAS VOTE WITH
THIS ATHEISM BULLSHIT ?
I GOTTA TALK TO BEAN.
COULD YOU--
HOWARD, LET'S GET
THE FIRST LADY
ON THE PHONE !
PRESERVE THE SECURE LINE
AND GO WITH
THE PHONE BOOTH.
SIR, I'D APPRECIATE IT
IF YOU'D PUT
THAT PHONE AWAY.
OH--
WE COULD
TAKE IT FROM YOU
IF YOU'D LIKE.
NO, YOU DON'T HAVE TO
TAKE IT.  NOT DOING ME
ANY GOOD ANYWAY.
APPRECIATE THAT.
YOU'RE HELPING US OUT.
NO PROBLEM.
WE GOT A VERY TOUGH STORM STILL
IN SOUTHERN COLORADO,
EVEN THOUGH IT'S MOVING THROUGH
COLORADO SPRINGS, I HOPE.
PEOPLE, STAY IN,
STAY OFF THE ROADS,
AND WE'RE WORKING
VERY HARD TO GET AHEAD
OF THIS SNOW REMOVAL.
- CAN I GET
SOME COFFEE, PLEASE ?
- YEAH, SURE.
[ Man On Walkie-Talkie,
Indistinct ]
[ Sighs ]
THANK YOU.
YOU'RE WELCOME.
AH, MS. GAYLE REDFORD.
YOU KNOW, I, UH,
I READ ABOUT YOU.
MM-HMM.
TIME, NEWSWEEK.
EVEN READ AN INTERVIEW ABOUT YOU
IN ONE OF THEM GIRLIE MAGAZINES.
WHICH ONE
WAS THAT, NOW ?
PLAYBOY.
THAT'S RIGHT.  THAT'S JUST
WHAT IT WAS.  YEAH.
YOU LED PROTESTS
AGAINST DESERT STORM.
ALMOST COST YOU
YOUR CONFIRMATION.
I'D RATHER THINK IT WON ME
MY CONFIRMATION.
YOU KNOW WHAT ?
YOU MAY NOT GET
A SHRINK TO SAY SO,
BUT THAT MAN
IS PLAIN INSANE.
I'M TELLIN' YA,
THAT MAN,
OUR LEADER...
IS GONNA RAIN DOWN
THE END OF THE WORLD
ON US.
HE THINKS
THE UNITED STATES...
HAS TO PLAY BIG BROTHER
TO EVERY PIPSQUEAK
NATION IN THE WORLD.
I'VE BEEN LISTENING.
THERE'S NOT ONE
LEGITIMATE REASON...
FOR HIM
TO EVEN BE CONSIDERING
WHAT HE'S DOING.
I DON'T HAVE
TO EDUCATE YOU...
ABOUT NUCLEAR WINTER,
MS. REDFORD.
CAN'T YOU STOP HIM ?
HMM.  I GUESS NOT.
I GUESS
NO ONE CAN.
♪♪ [ Fanfare ]
THIS IS GERALD IRVING
WITH AN ONGOING
IBS SPECIAL REPORT.
WE ARE TRYING TO FOLLOW
EVENTS ACROSS THE GLOBE...
AS EFFICIENTLY
AND QUICKLY AS POSSIBLE.
ON A SATELLITE PHONE, WE HAVE
JOHN DESIMIO FROM RIYADH.  JOHN.
GERALD, HI.
HEY, BEAN.
HELLO, WALTER.
HOW ARE YOU ?
JUST WHEN I STARTED GROWING INTO
THE JOB, IT GOT BIGGER ON ME.
THIS IS SOMETHING ELSE,
HUH ?
YES, IT IS.
LISTEN, WALTER--
LISTEN, UH, LET ME
TALK TO TRACEY FIRST.
IS SHE THERE ?
YEAH, SHE'S RIGHT HERE
NEXT TO ME.
DON'T TELL HER
ANYTHING, OKAY ?
COME ON.
OKAY.  DADDY WANTS
TO SPEAK TO YOU, HONEY.
HI, DADDY.
HEY, MUGGINS.
HOW'S MY ANGEL ?
DADDY, I'M NOT YOUR ANGEL.
I'M YOUR PRINCESS.
OH, THAT'S RIGHT.
I'M SORRY.
HOW'S MY PRINCESS ?
DADDY, KNOW WHAT ?
TELL ME.
GUESS WHO WAS
SPECIAL PERSON
AT SCHOOL TODAY.
YOU.
NO, DADDY.
TIMMY.
IT WAS HIS TURN.
WELL, WHEN IS IT
GONNA BE YOUR TURN ?
I DON'T KNOW, DADDY.
DO YOU WANT TO SPEAK
TO MOMMY AGAIN ?
YEAH.  I LOVE YOU.
MOMMY,
DADDY'S ON THE PHONE.
HEY.
TELL ME YOU'RE NOT
REALLY GONNA DO IT.
I HAVE TO.
I MAY HAVE TO.
I DON'T KNOW.
YOU REALIZE YOU'RE KILLING
JUST CIVILIANS, WALTER.
NO SOLDIERS, NO UDEI,
JUST CIVILIANS.
I MAY NOT HAVE A CHOICE.
YOU'RE THE PRESIDENT OF
THE UNITED STATES.  YOU'VE GOT
ALL THE CHOICE IN THE WORLD.
ALEX, HONEY,
I NEED YOU WITH ME.
I'M NOT
YOUR EVA BRAUN.
DO YOU THINK HISTORY'S
GONNA FORGIVE THIS ?  DO YOU
THINK IT'LL FORGIVE US ?
IT'S GONNA BE FINE.
NO MATTER WHAT HAPPENS,
IT WILL NEVER
BE FINE AGAIN.
LISTEN, I'M NOT GONNA BE
ABLE TO GET YOU AND TRACEY
UP IN THE LOOKING GLASS.
THE HARDER RIGHT
OVER THE EASIER WRONG ?
LISTEN, IT'S NOT--  I JUST
NEED A WORKING GOVERNMENT.
I NEED EVERY SEAT,
THAT'S ALL.  I--
DON'T DO IT.
I LOVE YOU, BEAN.
WE, UH-- WE GOTTA
GET THE LOOKING GLASS
TO ANDREWS.
YEAH.  OF COURSE.
I ALREADY CALLED IT IN.
GOOD.
HOW'S TRACEY ?
[ Exhales ]
SHE'S A KID.
SHE'S GOOD.
BEAN ?
I DON'T KNOW.
UH--
I NEED THE CABINET
ON THE GROUND, SO WE
SHOULD PUT THE DEPUTIES UP.
WE SHOULD ALSO
PROBABLY BOARD
SPEAKER HAZEL.
AW, JESUS.  THAT FAT,
SMELLY FUCK IS GONNA LOAD
THE WHOLE SHEBANG DOWN.
GUY COULDN'T SHOVEL SAND
IN A RAT HOLE.
I SUPPOSE HE'S NEXT
IN LINE, BUT WHY DO
WE HAVE TO GET HIM UP,
PUT HIM IN CONTROL ?
IT WAS ALL FOR NAUGHT
GETTING THE NOMINATION.
NO, HERE'S WHAT WE DO.
WE MAKE A CONSTITUTIONAL PLAY.
WE ARGUE THAT TEDDY SLATER IS
THE DE FACTO VICE PRESIDENT.
NOT HAZEL.
YOU DON'T THINK WE'RE ON
THE TIGHTROPE ALREADY ?
WHY DON'T WE JUST PLAY
THIS ONE BY THE BOOK ?
ALL RIGHT, I'LL PUT
FATSO IN THE AIR.
MAYBE IT'LL CRASH.
[ Chuckles ]
[ Emerson Sighs ]
YOU HANGIN' IN THERE ?
YES, SIR.
HMM.  THIS WEATHER'S
SOMETHING.
YOU WENT TO SCHOOL
AROUND HERE, DIDN'T YOU ?
THE AIR FORCE ACADEMY, RIGHT ?
YES, SIR.  COULDN'T
GET INTO WEST POINT.
YEAH.
MMM.
DO YOU, UH, EVER LOOK
INSIDE THAT THING ?
OH, YES, SIR.
WHAT'S IT LOOK LIKE
IN THERE ?
IS IT OMINOUS ?
NOT AS OMINOUS
AS IT SHOULD BE.
I GUESS THESE THINGS
NEVER ARE, HUH ?
LISTEN, NICK,
I JUST WANTED YOU
TO KNOW...
HOW MUCH
I APPRECIATE
THE FACT THAT...
YOU MAY BE THE FIRST
OF YOUR KIND TO EVER
ACTUALLY HAVE TO DO HIS JOB,
AND IT MEANS A LOT TO ME
TO HAVE YOU ON THE TEAM.
THANK YOU, SIR.
THANK YOU.
[ Man On Radio ]  ROGER THAT,
BRAVO TEAM LEADER.  WE BELIEVE
THAT WAS JUST A DEER.  OUT.
[ Man #2 ]
ROGER.  OUT.
FOR A MAN WHO HAS SENT
THE WORLD INTO TURMOIL,
IT IS SURPRISING
HOW LITTLE WE KNOW
ABOUT UDEI HUSSEIN.
CARLA LIVINGSTONE IS A FELLOW
WITH THE TUMAR INSTITUTE
IN PHILADELPHIA...
AND IS CURRENTLY
WORKING ON A BOOK
ABOUT THE HUSSEIN DYNASTY.
CARLA, WHAT ADVICE DO YOU
GIVE TO PRESIDENT EMERSON
GIVEN WHAT YOU KNOW ABOUT--
WE'RE DONE.  THE SPEAKER
WAS ALREADY AT ANDREWS
WITH HIS FAMILY.
HIS FAMILY ?
YEAH.
THE BAD NEWS
HAS BEEN CONVEYED.
[ Livingstone ]
IF YOU LOOK AT OUR HISTORY,
IT'S FILLED WITH...
PROGNOSTICATING
THE BEHAVIOR OF WORLD LEADERS
AS IF THEY WERE ALL RATIONAL.
THINGS ARE
A LITTLE DIFFERENT...
FROM WHEN
WE WERE AT PRINCETON.
HMM.
LITTLE LESS HAIR,
A FEW MORE POUNDS.
I WAS QUARTERBACK.
YOU WERE
THE RUNNING BACK.
YES, BUT, AS YOU SAID,
IT WAS PRINCETON.
YEAH.
BACK THEN, YOU WON
AT EVERYTHING, MARSH.
DEBATE CLASS, POKER,
CHEERLEADERS.
UDEI ACTUALLY KILLED
HIS FATHER'S VALET--
BUT YOU GOT BEAN.
HE WOULD PUMMEL HIM TO DEATH
WITH A CLUB AT A PARTY
HONORING HOSNI MUBARAK'S WIFE.
YOU'RE NOT WITH ME
ON THIS ONE, ARE YOU ?
THE GARDEN OF EDEN WAS IN IRAQ.
DID YOU KNOW THAT ?
NO.
YEAH, YEAH.
THE GARDEN OF EDEN
WAS IN IRAQ.
WALT,
DID YOU EVER READ
THE TEST RESULTS
ON LOS ALAMOS IN '45 ?
IT WAS A MOTHERFUCKER
OF A FIREBALL.
IT ROSE TO 10,000 FEET
BEFORE IT DIMMED.
PEOPLE COULD SEE IT
180 MILES AWAY.
SHATTERED GLASS
A HUNDRED MILES AWAY.
OH, YEAH, IT WAS--
IT WAS BEAUTIFUL.
VERY IMPRESSIVE.
IT, UH, IT CREATED A CRATER THAT
WAS A THOUSAND FEET IN DIAMETER.
AND THERE WAS THIS-- THIS...
STEEL TOWER.
IT WAS ABOUT
TEN STORIES HIGH.
IT WEIGHED
220 TONS.
IT WAS KNOCKED RIGHT OFF
ITS FOUNDATION.
AND THEN...
[ Mimics Explosion ]
JUST EVAPORATED.
JUST LIKE THAT.
NOW, WHAT YOU ARE
GOING TO DO IN BAGHDAD...
IS GONNA MAKE THOSE TESTS
LOOK LIKE MOSQUITO BITES.
YOU ARE GOING TO BE
WIPING OUT BAGHDAD.
THERE'S GOING TO BE
NOTHING LEFT.
NO REBUILDING,
NO AID, NOTHING.
JUST COCKROACHES.
YOU WILL BE WIPING OUT
A CIVILIZATION...
WHERE CIVILIZATION BEGAN.
AND, MY FRIEND,
YOU'D BETTER DAMN WELL
BE OKAY WITH THAT.
[ Howard ]
SIR, GENERAL RILEY IS
CURRENTLY AVAILABLE AT OFFUT.
GENERAL RILEY ?
YES, SIR.
WHAT STATUS REPORT
CAN YOU GIVE US ?
WELL, SIR, THE REPUBLICAN GUARDS
MOVED 20 CLICKS
FROM SAUDI ARABIA.
THERE'S NO HINT OF WITHDRAWAL ?
NOT AT ALL.
IN FACT, IT NOW SEEMS
THE SYRIAN AND IRANIAN ARMIES...
ARE MOVING TROOPS
TO THE ISRAELI FRONT.
THE ISRAELI MILITARY
IS FULLY MOBILIZED.
ARE THE ISRAELI FIGHTERS
IN THE AIR ?
NO, SIR,
BUT THE ISRAELI
NUCLEAR SILOS--
THE ONES THAT DON'T EXIST ?
YES, THOSE ONES.
THEY'VE GONE HOT.
EXCUSE ME.
MR. PRESIDENT ?
GENERAL RILEY, HOLD ON A SECOND.
YES, GENERAL LANCASTER.
WE, UH--  WE'VE
LATCHED ONTO EVERY KNOWN
NUCLEAR SILO ON THE PLANET.
AND ?
AND IT SEEMS EVERYONE
HAS GONE HOT, SIR.
[ Howard ]
MR. PRESIDENT,
IT'S CARL ISAACSON AT IBS.
[ Marsh ]
WELL, NOW, THIS CERTAINLY
SHOULD BE INTERESTING.
MR. ISAACSON.
MR. THOMPSON,
HOW ARE YOU ?
YEAH, UH,
QUITE A MESS
WE HAVE GOING ON.
WHAT COULD WE DO
FOR YOU ?
WELL, LOOK, UH--
WE GOT
A SITUATION HERE.
WE'VE BEEN APPROACHED
BY HAFFEZ OMARI
ABOUT GOING ON THE AIR.
OH, UH, WHA--  IT--
[ Nervous Chuckle ]
HE WANTS TO GO ON THE AIR ?
THAT'S RIGHT.
AND, YOU KNOW,
GIVEN THE CIRCUMSTANCES,
WE'D LIKE TO GET
A GREEN LIGHT.
HOLD ON.
[ Whispering ]
YOU CAN'T BE SERIOUS.
REALLY ?
YES.
WHERE IS HE ?
AT HIS OFFICE
AT THE U.N.
WE HAVE A CREW,
AND WE'RE READY TO GO.
OKAY, PUT HIM ON THE AIR.
OKAY ?
YES, OKAY.
OKAY, WE'RE TALKIN'
LESS THAN A MINUTE.
ALL RIGHT.
THANK YOU FOR
CONSULTING WITH US.
NO PROBLEM.
[ Beeping ]
[ Clears Throat ]
YOU KNOW, YOU THINK
THERE'S A PANIC NOW,
WAIT TILL THIS PRICK
FINISHES HIS SPEECH.
AND IF YOU COULD SAY
ANYTHING TO UDEI HUSSEIN
TONIGHT ?
I'M SURE I AM SAYING IT
TO HIM.  HE IS
A HUGE FAN OF IBS.
GO AHEAD, THEN.
ABU HUSSEIN
ON IBS.
LOVE YOUR COUNTRY.
LIVIN' LARGE
IN PROVIDENCE, R.I.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH,
MR. HUSSEIN.  ABU HUSSEIN,
THE NEPHEW OF--
OKAY.  WE'RE MOVING
FAST HERE, FOLKS.
STANDING BY
AT THE UNITED NATIONS
IS HAFFEZ OMARI,
THE IRAQI AMBASSADOR
TO THE U.N.
MR. OMARI, THANK YOU
FOR JOINING US TONIGHT.
[ Speaking Arabic ]
[ Translator ]
YES.  THANK YOU.
[ Irving ]
ALLOW ME TO BEGIN BY ASKING
ABOUT YOUR SPECIFIC INTENTIONS.
[ Translator ]  I HAVE
NOT AGREED TO BE SUBJECTED
TO A HOSTILE INTERVIEW.
I INSTEAD HAVE A STATEMENT
OF SOME URGENCY TO MAKE.
OKAY, THEN.
GO AHEAD.
[ Translator ]
ONE HOUR AGO,
YOUR NONELECTED PRESIDENT...
ANNOUNCED THAT
HE HAD ORDERED
THE DELIVERY...
OF NUCLEAR BOMBS...
TO BE DROPPED WITH--
NO-- ON THE PEACEFUL
PEOPLE OF IRAQ.
FIVE MINUTES AGO,
SURVEILLANCE INDICATED...
THAT A FLEET
OF WAR PLANES...
HAVE LEFT A BASE
IN SAUDI ARABIA...
WITHOUT SAUDI APPROVAL.
WE DO NOT FEEL THE NEED
TO ENGAGE IN A WAR
WITH THE U.S.A.,
AND SO
WE MUST DO...
YES !
WHAT WE HAVE TO TO STOP
THE AGGRESSION.
THEY'RE GONNA CAVE.
[ Marsh ]  THEY'RE GONNA CAVE !
CONGRATULATIONS,
MR. PRESIDENT.
THEY REACTED
AS YOU EXPECTED.
SO IT HUMBLES US TO COME...
TO THIS LEVEL.
I HAVE BEFORE ME A LIST
OF PRECISE LOCATIONS.
I HAVE JUST NOW
SENT THEM...
VIA FACSIMILE
TO THE OFFICE...
OF THE AMERICAN CHAIRMAN...
OF THE JOINT CHIEFS--
THIS VERY LIST.
THESE ARE THE LOCATIONS...
OF LAND-BASED AND
SUBMARINE-BASED MISSILES...
GENERAL LANCASTER.
ARMED WITH
NUCLEAR WARHEADS.
[ Translator ]
THE MOMENT THE AMERICAN
WING OF FIGHTERS CROSSES...
IRAQI AIRSPACE,
WE WILL LAUNCH
A FULL-SCALE...
NUCLEAR ATTACK...
ON FIVE--
FOUR LOCATIONS...
INSIDE AMERICA, ISRAEL...
AND EVERY MEMBER OF NATO.
KNIGHT TAKES ROOK.
[ Translator ]
THAT IS ALL FOR NOW.
MILLER HERE, SIR.
WE HAVE ONE OPTION NOW.
MISS, LET ME GET
SOME MORE COFFEE.
CONVENTIONAL ATTACK, OR NO ?
NOT EVEN THAT
ANYMORE.
I THINK WE MUST
CAREFULLY CONSIDER
WHAT OMARI SAID.
[ Lancaster ]  OUR SATELLITES
HAVE BEEN ON THE LISTED
LONGITUDES AND LATITUDES.
I SHOULD HAVE
A REPORT IN FIVE MINUTES.
ADMIRAL MILLER, I WANT
THE B-2 TO PROCEED FORWARD
TILL IT REACHES THE BORDER.
SIR, IN LIGHT
OF THIS NEW DEVELOPMENT, I MUST
AGREE WITH ADMIRAL MILLER.
WE DON'T EVEN KNOW
IF THEY'RE GOING TO FIRE
CHEMICAL WEAPONS AT ALL.
IT'S EVEN LESS LIKELY
NOW THAT ARAB FORCES
ARE MOVING TOWARDS ISRAEL.
THEY'LL BE FIRING
ON THEMSELVES.
EXACTLY.
SO WHY RISK AN INTERNATIONAL
NUCLEAR ATTACK ON SOMETHING THAT
PROBABLY WON'T HAPPEN ANYWAY ?
SIR, WE RISK
ALMOST NO CONDEMNATION...
IF WE FIRE ON THEM
USING CONVENTIONALS.
[ Marsh ]
LOOK, EVEN IF THEY DO
FIRE THOSE WEAPONS--
LET ME BE FRANK.
IF IT MEANS SACRIFICING
ISRAEL OR TURKEY, SO BE IT,
AS LONG AS WE SAVE
AMERICAN LIVES.
SOMETIMES THE TOUGHEST DECISIONS
ARE THE ONES WITH ONE OPTION.
UH, EXCUSE ME, SIR, BUT YOU
HAVE CREATED A MISTAKE HERE.
YOU'VE CREATED A MONSTER.
BUT THAT DOES NOT MEAN
THAT WE CAN'T DEAL
WITH THIS THING METHODICALLY.
WE TAKE OUT
THEIR CHEMICAL WARHEADS
USING CONVENTIONALS.
UPON RETURNING
TO THE WHITE HOUSE,
WE DEAL WITH HUSSEIN...
CALM, COOL AND COLLECTED.
LANCASTER BACK, SIR.
I'M HERE.
IT'S BAD.  LET ME
GIVE YOU THE LAYOUT.
OKAY, HOLD ON A SECOND.
HOWARD, YOU GOT A PENCIL ?
I HAVE A RED FELT PEN, SIR,
BUT NO PENCIL.
PLEASE, GIVE IT TO HIM.
DIDN'T ASK FOR
A RED FELT P--
FELT PEN IS FINE.
AGENT WILLIAMS,
GENERAL LANCASTER IS GOING
TO GIVE US SOME LOCATIONS.
MARK THEM ON
THAT MAP OVER THERE
WITH THAT RED PEN.
YES, SIR.
THANK YOU.
READY WHEN YOU ARE,
GENERAL.
WE HAVE
UNCONTROVERTED INFORMATION...
THAT NUCLEAR WEAPONS
ARE NOW UNCOVERED.
ON THE TIP OF TRIPOLI,
WE SEE TWO MISSILES.
TRIPOLI.
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
IBS HAS LATCHED ONTO...
THE LATITUDES AND LONGITUDES
OF ALL THE LOCATIONS...
PROVIDED BY
THE IRAQI GOVERNMENT.
OUR SATELLITE CAMERAS
CAN NOW CONFIRM...
THE FOLLOWING LAUNCHING PADS,
WHICH SEEM TO COME FROM
LAND BASES ALL OVER THE WORLD,
AND, REMARKABLY,
SUBMARINES.
THE FIRST APPEARS TO BE
IN TRIPOLI.
[ Lancaster On Recording ]
WE HAVE UNCONTROVERTED
INFORMATION--
[ Irving ]
THE MISSILES IN TRIPOLI
ARE AIMED AT ROME.
CRUISE MISSILES
ARE DIRECTED AT NEW DELHI.
TOMAHAWK MISSILES ARE POISED
TO STRIKE AGAINST ADDIS ABABA.
MISSILES BASED
ON INLAND CHINA...
ARE AIMED AT TOKYO
AND HIROSHIMA.
[ Lancaster ]
WE NOW CONFIRM
THE FOLLOWING AMERICAN TARGETS.
[ Irving ]
THERE'S ALSO AN INDICATION
THAT NEW YORK, WASHINGTON, D.C.,
AND PENSACOLA, FLORIDA,
ARE TARGETED.
IRAQ'S LANCELOT MISSILE
IS PROGRAMMED TO HIT NORAD
IN COLORADO SPRINGS.
SIR, MR. OMARI
IS BACK ON THE LINE.
SO MUCH FOR NOT
NEGOTIATING WITH A JEW.
YEAH.
CONSIDERING THIS SITUATION,
I'M SURPRISED HE WANTS
TO NEGOTIATE WITH THIS JEW.
OKAY, I'M READY
FOR YOU, SIR.
BACK UP, DEX.
GO AHEAD.
AND... YOU'RE GOOD.
[ Speaking Arabic ]
[ Translator ]
I ASSUME YOU HAVE
CONFIRMED OUT POSITIONS.
[ Emerson ]
WE HAVE.
I ASSURE YOU,
THE MOMENT YOUR AIR FORCE
PASSES INTO OUR AIRSPACE,
WE WILL CONSIDER THAT
A FIRST STRIKE BEFORE THE FACT.
I UNDERSTAND.
WE WILL FIRE...
ALL OUR WEAPONS
SIMULTANEOUSLY.
WE HAVE NEVER BLUFFED
A MILITARY ACTION,
AND WE WILL NOT NOW.
- I ASSUME NOT.
- WE ARE, HOWEVER,
WILLING TO REACH
AN ACCOMMODATION
WHICH SHOULD, UH--
MAY RESULT
IN A PEACEFUL RESOLUTION.
I'M LISTENING.
TURN YOUR PLANE AROUND,
AND WE WILL STOP LOADING
MISSILES IN RABAT.
IN ADDITION, WE WILL LOWER
OUR NUCLEAR READINESS...
AND, UH, DISABLE
OUR NUCLEAR MISSILES.
WHAT ABOUT
THE INCURSION
INTO KUWAIT ?
THAT REMAINS.
THE UNITED STATES
HAS NEITHER THE RIGHT
NOR THE PRIVILEGE...
TO INTERFERE
IN THE INTERNAL AFFAIRS
OF THE GULF STATES.
BUT, UH, SINCE YOU...
ATTACH YOUR ECONOMIC FUTURE
TO THE SAUDI OIL FIELDS,
WE'LL BE WILLING
TO SIGN A TREATY...
FREEZING OIL PRICES AT...
CURRENT OPEC LEVELS
FOR THE WORLD.
WE WILL ALSO BEGIN
PEACE NEGOTIATIONS
WITH, UH,
MR. BEN-RAZZI.
CARTER
AND CLINTON...
HAD THEIR MOMENTS
AS MIDDLE EAST
PEACE BROKERS.
NOW-- NOW YOU
CAN AS WELL.
NOT ACCEPTABLE.
YOU MUST WITHDRAW
FROM KUWAIT IMMEDIATELY.
THIS IS NOT A NEGOTIATION,
MR. EMERSON.
ALL RIGHT.  WELL, THEN THE B-2,
OF COURSE, WILL BE OVER YOUR
AIRSPACE IN ABOUT FIVE MINUTES.
HE WANTS TO SPEAK
DIRECTLY TO YOU, SIR.
HERE GOES.
PUT HIM ON SPEAKER.
HE'S UP.
THIS IS
THE PRESIDENT.
[ Omari ]
MR. PRESIDENT,
UNDERSTAND THIS.
WE HAVE THE POWER.
WE HAVE THE OIL.
I HAVE THE MATCH.
&quot;I HAVE THE MATCH&quot; ?
IS THAT YOUR RESPONSE, SIR ?
THAT'S MY RESPONSE.
OMARI IS RIGHT, SIR.
IF THERE'S ONE THING THESE GUYS
DON'T DO, THEY DON'T BLUFF.
NO, HE'S NOT BLUFFING,
BUT NOTHING'S CHANGED.
SIR, 23 NUCLEAR MISSILES
AIMED AT US
AND OUR ALLIES...
IS A DEFINITE DEFINITION
OF SOMETHING HAVING CHANGED.
GENERAL LANCASTER,
YOU STILL WITH US ?
RIGHT HERE, SIR.
THERE MUST BE SOMEWAY
TO CONFIRM WHERE THE IRAQI
NUCLEAR ARSENAL CAME FROM.
WE HAVE PAUL RUBENSTEIN
ON IT.  HE'S OUR FOREIGN
MUNITIONS EXPERT.
HE'S LOOKING AT
OUR SATELLITE IMAGES NOW.
OKAY, LET'S NOT LET THE B-2
ENTER IRAQI AIRSPACE.
I WANT TO HEAR THIS
FIRST.
[ Miller ]
GOOD MOVE, SIR.
I DON'T SEE
WHAT DIFFERENCE IT MAKES
WHERE THEY CAME FROM.
THEY HAVE THEM.
THEY'RE READY
TO USE THEM.
WE EITHER CALL
THEIR BLUFF, OR WE ABORT
THE NUCLEAR MISSION.
[ Miller ]  MR. PRESIDENT,
I'D BE HAPPY TO GIVE
THE ORDER TO ABORT MISSION.
I DIDN'T SAY ANYTHING
ABOUT ABORT MISSION.
I SAID HOLD POSITION.
DON'T PLAY
A FUCKING GAME
WITH ME, ADMIRAL.
THIS IS THE BOMBER
THAT OUR SOURCES IN THE PENTAGON
ARE TELLING US...
WILL BE USED TO CARRY
AND DROP A NUCLEAR WEAPON
ONTO THE IRAQI CAPITAL.
THIS MULTIBILLION-DOLLAR
STEALTH BOMBER
HAS BEEN REVAMPED--
SO WE CAN ASSUME THAT
THEIR BALLISTIC MISSILES...
CAME FROM AN EXCHANGE
OF TECHNOLOGY FROM CHINA
AND/OR NORTH KOREA.
PAKISTAN.
PAKIST--  CHINA
AND NORTH KOREA, SIR.
I WOULDN'T JUMP
TO THAT CONCLUSION
JUST YET, GAYLE.
LET'S HEAR WHAT
THIS RUBENSTEIN FELLOW
HAS TO SAY.
MADAM SECRETARY ?
I'M ON WITH BLAIR
IN A MINUTE.
THE REST OF THE DEPARTMENT
IS ALREADY IN COMMUNICATION
WITH THE OTHER HEADS OF STATE.
WHAT ABOUT
PRESIDENT GESTAING ?
HE'S BEING TRANSPORTED
TO A SECURE PHONE.
[ Irving ]
IT HAS BEEN 60 YEARS
SINCE ANY NATION...
HAS DROPPED
AN ATOMIC BOMB
ON ANOTHER.
SIXTY YEARS IN WHICH
THE DEADLINESS OF THE WEAPON...
HAS RISEN IN DIRECT PROPORTION
TO THE ADVANCES
IN SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY.
OUR TWO PAIR
CANNOT BEAT HIS BOAT.
WHAT ?
[ Redford ]  MAJOR CODDINGTON,
WOULD YOU EXCUSE US, PLEASE ?
NO, HE'S FINE.
HEAR ME OUT.
TAKE AWAY UDEI'S OFFER
FOR PRICE STABILIZATION.
ASSUME HE'S GONNA
BUMP THE SHIT OUT
OF OIL PRICES, OKAY ?
THAT'S GONNA SEND US
INTO AN ECONOMIC TAILSPIN.
HE STILL HAS THE WEAPONRY
TO LAUNCH ON US AND
A DOZEN OTHER COUNTRIES.
NOW, ONCE WE HIT IRAQ--
[ Redford ]
IF.
IFWE HIT IRAQ, THERE'S
NO REASON FOR ANY COUNTRY
TO ATTACK BAGHDAD.
DAMAGE IS ALREADY DONE.
THEY'RE JUST GONNA SIT BACK
AND TAKE A LICKING.
SO ONCE WE ARE
IN BAGHDAD AIRSPACE,
THERE'S NOTHING
THAT CAN DETER HIM
FROM HITTING US OR OUR ALLIES.
NOW YOU UNDERSTAND ?
THIS IS WHAT'S HAPPENING ?
WHAT ARE YOU
TELLING ME ?
TO CAVE IN ?
ABSOLUTELY NOT, SIR.
YOU PRESENT IT
AS HIS CAPITULATION.
HE HAS COME TO YOU WITH THE IDEA
OF PRICE STABILIZATION.
HEY, WHEN HAS THAT
EVER HAPPENED ?
[ Marsh ]  NEVER.
WALT, THIS IS
THE THING.  NEVER.
NOT IN ANY ADMINISTRATION.
THIS WILL BE A FIRST.
ON TOP OF THAT, YOU'VE SAVED...
THREE COUNTRIES
FROM CHEMICAL ATTACK.
SIR, THE LEVEL OF HEROISM HERE
IS AT LEAST AS HIGH AS THAT
OF KENNEDY IN '62.
POWELL IN VENEZUELA.
STOP IT
RIGHT THERE, SIR.
I APPRECIATE YOU GOT A JOB
TO DO, BUT I'D LIKE TO HAVE
A WORD WITH THE MAN.
I JUST WANNA
TALK TO HIM.
NOT NOW, OKAY ?
I DON'T UNDERSTAND
WHY YOU'RE GIVING ME
THIS STATIC.
YOU NEED TO CALM DOWN.
THE MAN
HAS A WEAPON.
I PAY MY TAXES.
I CAN SPEAK MY MIND.
YOU KNOW HOW MUCH I PAID
IN TAXES LAST YEAR ?
I CAN UNDERSTAND.
THREE LARGE.  YOU KNOW WHAT
THAT'S LIKE FOR A GUY LIKE ME ?
YOU KNOW
WHAT THAT IS ?
ALL RIGHT !
- LET'S HEAR
WHAT HE HAS TO SAY.
- YES, SIR.
KEEP IT
UNDER CONTROL.
I GOT IT.
THANK YOU.
THANK YOU.  I PAY
MY TAXES, YOU KNOW ?
YES, I HEARD THAT.
OKAY, I JUST WANTED
TO SAY THAT, SPEAKING FOR
THE COMMON MAN, WE'RE WITH YOU.
THANK YOU.
[ Scoffs ]
YEAH.
LET'S CRISPY-CRITTER
THEM MOTHERFUCKERS,
YOU KNOW WHAT I MEAN ?
TEACH THAT LITTLE PRICK
A LESSON HE AND HIS DADDY
NEVER LEARNED.
KEEP YOUR HANDS AT YOUR SIDES.
YOU DROP THAT BOMB,
YOU GOT MY VOTE
AND THE VOTE OF
EVERY REAL AMERICAN.
MY BUDDY ACE AND I WERE
HAVING THIS CONVERSATION
THE OTHER DAY,
AND ACCIDENTALLY
I LET SLIP
THE WORD &quot;FAG.&quot;
MY BUDDY GETS
BENT OUT OF SHAPE,
SAYING, &quot;RALPHIE, BE CAREFUL.
YOU DON'T KNOW WHO'S AROUND.&quot;
THEN HE TEACHES ME
THIS LITTLE TRICK.
EVERY TIME WE SEE
ONE OF THEM HOMOSEXUALS,
WE USE THE WORD &quot;WATERMELON.&quot;
YOU SEE A FAG,
YOU SAY, &quot;WOULDN'T SOME
WATERMELON BE NICE NOW ?&quot;
I SAID, &quot;GEEZ, ACE,
THAT'S INGENIOUS !
WHAT DO YOU CALL BLACKS ?&quot;
HE SAYS, &quot;TEXANS.&quot;
I SAY, &quot;WHAT DO
YOU CALL SPICS ?&quot;
HE SAYS, UH--
HE SAYS,
&quot;TRUCKERS.&quot;
FINALLY, I SAY,
&quot;WHAT DO YOU CALL
THEM ARABS ?&quot;
HE LOOKS AT ME AND SAYS,
&quot;HELL, RALPH, WE JUST
CALL THEM SAND NIGGERS.&quot;
SEE WHAT I'M SAYIN' ?
NOBODY GIVES A SHIT ABOUT
NO DIRTY-ASS SAND NIGGER.
AND AS FAR AS THEIR NUKES GO,
THEY'RE SO STONE AGE BACKWARDS,
THEY PROBABLY NEVER SEEN
A BUTTON, LET ALONE KNOW
HOW TO PUSH ONE.
RALPH, IS IT ?
YEAH.
RALPHIE.
RALPH, UH--
IS THERE
ANYTHING ELSE ?
NO, THAT ABOUT COVERS IT.
OKAY.  HOW 'BOUT,
UH, IF I PROMISE
WHEN ALL THIS IS OVER...
TO PASS
A PRESIDENTIAL DECREE...
FOREVER RELINQUISHING YOU
FROM PAYING TAXES ?
WOULD YOU PROMISE
TO NEVER SPEAK TO ME AGAIN ?
GENTLEMEN.
OKAY.
STEP OUT, SIR.
THANK YOU.
IT'S FINE.
SIR, GENERAL LANCASTER
HAS MR. RUBENSTEIN AVAILABLE.
FINALLY.
MR. PRESIDENT,
WE HAVE MR. RUBENSTEIN.
THIS SHOULD BE INTERESTING.
MR. RUBENSTEIN,
THIS IS WALT EMERSON.
IT'S AN HONOR, SIR.
ALL MINE.  WHAT DO
YOU GOT FOR US ?
SIR, WE HAVE AUTHENTICATED
THE NUCLEAR WEAPONS THE IRAQIS
LAID OUT FOR US.
YES, WE KNOW THAT.
YEAH, BUT WHAT
YOU DON'T KNOW IS--
I MEAN, THE THING OF IT IS,
THESE ARE AMERICAN-MADE WEAPONS.
AMERICAN-MADE ?
YES, SIR.
ARMS DEALERS ?
NO, NOT ARMS DEALERS.
THE MARKINGS ARE CLEAR.
THESE WEAPONS
WERE FRENCH PROPERTY.
THE FRENCH GOVERNMENT ?
THAT IS EXACTLY
WHAT I MEAN, MR. THOMPSON.
IT'S FRANCE FOR SURE.
OUR ANALYSTS AT DEFENSE
ARE SWEARING BY IT.
SOMETHING DOESN'T
JIVE HERE.
YOU'VE BEEN INVALUABLE,
MR. RUBENSTEIN.
GOOD LUCK, SIR.
I'M HERE IF
YOU NEED ME.
THANK YOU.
[ Howard ]
EXCUSE ME, SIR,
BUT MONSIEUR
LE PRESIDENT GESTAING
IS AVAILABLE NOW.
- I GOT HIM ON TWO.
- FUCKING, COCKSUCKING,
MOTHERFUCKING FRENCH...
- MARSH.
- PIECE OF FROG SHIT.
WE CALL THEM MILKMEN.
&quot;MILKMEN&quot; ?
SHUT THE FUCK UP,
RALPH.
[ Marsh ]
OKAY.
IT'S ONE THING
FOR THEM TO HAVE
SYMPATHY FOR IRAQ.
IN FACT,
I ALWAYS ADMIRED THEM
FOR THEIR-- THEIR--
HUMANITARIANISM ?
YEAH, BUT THIS
IS DIFFERENT.
I MEAN, THIS IS
OUTRIGHT TREASON.
HOW THE FUCK DO THEY THINK
THEY CAN GET AWAY WITH THIS ?
SIR, GESTAING IS NOW AVAILABLE.
THAT'S NOT A CONCLUSION
YOU WANT TO JUMP TO, MARSH.
HENRI.
MONSIEUR PRESIDENT.
COMMENT ALLEZ-VOUS?
CA VA BIEN.
SO THE MOSQUITO
IS BACK.
I'LL SAY.
INEVITABLE.
YES.  HENRI, I MUST ASK YOU
ABOUT THESE WEAPONS IRAQ HAS.
YES.
IT SEEMS THEY'RE ALL FRENCH.
OUI.
THAT THEY'RE YOURS.
- THEY COME FROM FRANCE.
- OF COURSE.
[ Mimicking Gestaing's Accent ]
OF COUR--  HOW CAN HE SAY THAT--
IT'S QUITE A SITUATION.
OUI.
I UNDERSTAND.
YOUR ADMINISTRATION--
NO,
IT WAS NOT ME.
IT WAS BOUVIER.
PERSONALLY, I FIND IT TO HAVE
BEEN HIS MOST HEROIC ACT.
WELL, NOW THAT EVERYONE
KNOWS WHERE THEY'RE FROM,
I HAVE TO FIGURE OUT
A WAY TO EXPLAIN IT
TO THE AMERICAN PEOPLE.
TELL THEM THE TRUTH.
THE WORLD SHOULD UNDERSTAND
WHY FRANCE HAS TAKEN
THIS POSITION ALL THESE YEARS.
AND YOU'VE ALSO SOLD THEM
SOME SUBMARINES ?
THE SUBMARINES
WERE IMPROVISATIONAL--
BOUVIER LOOKING
FOR AN EXTRA DOLLAR.
COULD HAVE TOLD US.
IT WAS DISCUSSED
WITH PRESIDENT BUCKINGHAM.
HE WAS ANGRY, BUT IT WAS DONE,
AND WHAT WAS DONE WAS DONE.
WELL, WE'LL DISCUSS IT
AT GATT NEXT MONTH.
FOR NOW I NEED TO DO WHAT
I NEED TO DO, AND SO DO YOU.
SO, CAN YOU SEND OVER
A PORTFOLIO WITH ALL
THE WEAPONS YOU SOLD IRAQ ?
I'VE JUST SENT THE LIST
TO GENERAL LANCASTER'S OFFICE.
IT SHOULD BE THERE MOMENTARILY.
IT IS THE MOST UPDATED LIST.
JUST TO ACKNOWLEDGE,
WHAT IS THE EXACT VINTAGE
OF THESE WEAPONS ?
EXACTLY AS WE USED
THE PAKISTANIS.
THEY'RE ALL POST-1996,
EVERY ONE OF THEM.
OKAY, HENRI.  I'M ALSO
BEING TOLD THAT A MISSILE
IS HEADED YOUR WAY.
WE SEE THAT.  YOU KNOW,
THE BASTARD PROMISED THAT
THEY WOULDN'T DO THAT.
WE PREDICT IT WILL LAND
IN ORLY.
RIGHT.  WELL, UH, JUST DON'T
LAUNCH ANYTHING OFFENSIVE.
NO, NO.
UNDER ANY CIRCUMSTANCES.
WE'LL SAVE OUR BOMBS
FOR QADDAFI.
TALK TO YOU LATER.
AU REVOIR.
[ Beeping ]
[ Marsh ]  DID YOU HEAR
HOW CAVALIER HE WAS ?
- [ Redford ]  I DON'T GET IT.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
- AM I MISSING SOMETHING ?
OKAY, OKAY.
HERE'S WHAT WE HAVE TO DO.
WE HAVE TO GET GESTAING
BACK ON THE PHONE.
[ Redford ]  ABSOLUTELY.
THE FRENCH SUPPLIED THEM.
THEY HAVE THE MEANS
TO DISARM THEM.
WE HAVE TO GET GESTAING'S
COMMITMENT ON THIS.
ALSO, CALL A MEETING
OF THE GENERAL ASSEMBLY.
THIS IS UNACCEPTABLE BEHAVIOR
FROM A MEMBER OF NATO.  THEY
CAN'T JUST SUPPLY THE WORLD--
MARSH.  YOU'RE
MISSING SOMETHING.
WHAT ?  I'M ALL EARS.
GENERAL LANCASTER ?
YES, SIR.
DOES GESTAING'S
LAUNDRY LIST CORRESPOND
WITH OUR SURVEILLANCE ?
PERFECTLY.
IRAQ CAN HIT,
BY OUR ESTIMATIONS,
OVER A DOZEN NATIONS
AT ONCE.
ALL RIGHT, THEN.
SEND THE B-2 INTO IRAQ.
WE'RE GONNA LET HER FLY.
- GONNA LET 'EM FLY ?
- THAT'S ILLEGAL.
IT'S ABSOLUTELY ILLEGAL.
THEY WILL IMPEACH YOU
BEFORE YOU'RE ELECTED.
OKAY.  YOU KNOW WHAT ?
WE NEED TO HAVE A CHAT.
-WHERE'S MY COAT ?  MS. REDFORD,
WOULD YOU JOIN US OUTSIDE ?
-[ Redford ]  CERTAINLY.
MY COAT.
[ Howard ]
I HAVE IT, SIR.
AGENT DEXTER,
I WANT YOU TWO
TO STAY INSIDE.
IF THERE'S A SHARPSHOOTER
IN THAT SHIT STORM OUT THERE,
HE DESERVES A TARGET.
MAJOR ?
I'LL BE READY,
SIR.
[ Howard ]
YOUR COAT, MR. THOMPSON.
NO.
HEY, LOOK AT THIS !
OKAY, SIR, YOU CAN'T
SIT HERE.  COME AWAY
FROM THE WINDOW.
POOR BASTARD'S GOIN' TO HELL.
HE'S GONNA TAKE US WITH HIM.
WHAT THE HELL
ARE YOU TALKIN' ABOUT,
MR. CRISPY CRITTER THEIR ASSES ?
RALPH, YOU JUST TOLD
THE PRESIDENT HE SHOULD
DROP THE BOMB ON IRAQ.
THAT WAS BEFORE KATIE TOLD ME
THAT OUR FEARLESS HEBE LEADER
DIDN'T BELIEVE IN GOD.
THEY'RE GOING TO BE NUKES
FLYING AROUND LIKE TENNIS BALLS
AT WIMBLEDON.
WHY ARE YOU PEOPLE
DISCUSSING THIS ?
- YOU THINK EMERSON'S GONNA COME
BACK IN AND PUT IT TO A VOTE ?
- WHEN HE COMES BACK IN HERE,
WE'LL SIT HIM DOWN AND WE'LL ALL
TALK SOME SENSE INTO HIM.
WHAT DO YOU THINK THIS IS,
A.A. ?  WE'RE GONNA HAVE
SOME KIND OF INTERVENTION ?
OKAY, FOLKS, I NEED YOU
TO CLEAR THIS WINDOW AREA,
PLEASE.  THANK YOU.
[ Ralph ]
I GOT EMERSON'S EAR.
WE HAD A GOOD DIALOGUE GOING.
HE'LL LISTEN TO ME.
[ Lizzie ]
GIVE ME A BREAK !
- THANK GOD
KISSINGER'S ON THE CASE.
- [ Gunshot ]
- [ Glass Shattering ]
-[ Screaming ]
SHIT !  SON OF A BITCH !
WHAT THE FUCK ARE YOU DOING ?
DROP THE WEAPON, PAL.
DROP THE WEAPON !
[ Grunting ]
PUT IT DOWN,
BUDDY.
[ Coddington ]
SHIT !
[ Dexter ]
DROP THE WEAPON,
MISTER.
PUT IT DOWN.
[ Ralph ]  WHY DON'T
YOU JUST SHOOT ?
[ Dexter ]
PUT IT DOWN, NOW !
PUT IT DOWN !
[ Katie ]
HARVEY !
DON'T GONNA BE
NO APOCALYPSE HERE.
NOT ON MY WATCH !
HARVEY !
DON'T YOU DO IT
TO YOURSELF !
DON'T YOU DO IT !
HARVEY !
[ Gunshot ]
JESUS !
JESUS, WHERE'D
THE FUCKING SHOTGUN
COME FROM ?
[ Dexter ]
WILLIAMS, SECURE THE WEAPON.
NEST IS SECURE.
JESUS, MOTHER MARY.
SIR,
WE'RE UNDER CONTROL.
UNDER CONTROL.  YEAH.
[ Line Beeping ]
[ Redford ]  THAT'S THAT.
HE'S THE ONLY PERSON WITH THE
COMBINATION TO THE BRIEFCASE.
ALL RIGHT,
LET'S CALL STRATCOM.
- HOWARD !
- YES, SIR.
[ Marsh ]
CALL STRATCOM,
CHAIRMAN, JOINT CHIEFS, MILLER.
RIGHT, SIR.
GET 'EM
ON THE PHONE.
I'M SORRY.
OKAY, UH, GENTLEMAN,
WE'VE, UH,
HAD A RATHER
SERIOUS INCIDENT HERE.
AS A RESULT, OUR MAN
WITH THE FOOTBALL HAS BEEN SHOT.
[ Lancaster ]
SHOT ?  WHAT HAPPENED ?
[ Marsh ]
THE COOK HERE,
HE LOST IT.
HE TOOK OUR--
HE KILLED CODDINGTON.
HE WAS A FINE YOUNG MAN
AND A GOOD GUY.
I DON'T WANT TO DIMINISH
WHAT'S HAPPENED HERE,
BUT WE MUST KEEP FOCUS.
INSIDE THE BRIEFCASE ARE
THE CODES NECESSARY TO LAUNCH
OUR WEAPONS, OF COURSE.
I'M ASSUMING ONE OF YOU
HAS THE COMBINATION.
[ Lancaster ]
NOT HERE, SIR.
CAN WE JUST SHOOT IT OPEN ?
OH, NO.  NO, NO, SIR.
YOU CAN'T DO THAT.
ANY KIND OF FORCED ENTRY AND
THE COMPONENTS SELF-DESTRUCT.
[ Emerson ]
RIGHT, BUT THERE'S
GOT TO BE A BACKUP, RIGHT ?
[ Miller ]
I HAVE IT, SIR.
THANK GOODNESS.
[ Miller ]
EVERY JOINT CHIEF RECEIVES
THE COMBINATION CODE...
AT THE WEEKLY BRIEFING
IF OUR ARM IS CARRYING
THE FOOTBALL.
ALL RIGHT.
LET'S GET THIS GOING, THEN.
ADMIRAL MILLER ?
MR. PRESIDENT,
I RESPECTFULLY DECLINE.
- &quot;RESPECTFULLY DECLINE&quot; ?
- [ Emerson ]
BRING ME THE BRIEFCASE.
- RIGHT AWAY, SIR.
- I HAVE FOUR MINUTES
TO ACQUIRE THOSE CODES.
WHAT I NEED IS FOR YOU TO SET
ASIDE YOUR PERSONAL FEELINGS
AND DO YOUR FUCKING JOB !
[ Secretary of Defense ]
MAY I REMIND YOU, ADMIRAL,
THAT THIS IS AN ACT OF TREASON ?
[ Miller ]
SIR, THE COMBINATION...
IS 0-8-0-6-1-
NINER-4-5.
AND, SIR, ALONG WITH THAT,
I MUST SUBMIT
MY RESIGNATION.
[ Lancaster ]
SIR, LET ME REPEAT THAT BACK.
0-8-0-6-1-
NINER-4-5.
OKAY, GENERAL,
I GOT BINOCULARS
AND A KEYBOARD.
I HAVE NO IDEA
WHAT TO DO.
OKAY.
PUT YOUR EYES TO THE LENS,
AND YOUR RETINAL CODE...
WILL ENABLE YOU
TO SEE A TEN-POINT
ALPHANUMERIC CODE.
- CAN'T ANYONE
LOOK THROUGH THESE ?
- THEY COULD TRY,
BUT THEIR RETINAS
WOULD BE BURNED.
JUST AN N.S.C PRECAUTION,
SIR.
I'M ALMOST CERTAIN THAT
WE'VE REACTIVATED THE SYSTEM...
USING YOUR SPECIFIC
RETINAL INFORMATION.
- &quot;ALMOST CERTAIN&quot; ?
- YES, SIR,
I'M PRETTY CERTAIN.
OKAY.
I SEE...
LATITUDE, LONGITUDE...
AND THE CODE ATOP.
OKAY, SIR, LOOK BACK
INTO THE BRIEFCASE,
TYPE IN THE LATITUDE AND
LONGITUDE THAT YOU NEED--
HOLD ON.
WE HAVE IT
RIGHT HERE.
OKAY.
IT IS 33.14 NORTH,
[ Tapping Keyboard ]
AND 44.22 EAST.
ALL RIGHT.
YOU SEE
THE CODE, SIR ?
YES, I SEE THE CODE.
ALL RIGHT, RELAY IT TO US
IN THE PHONETIC ALPHABET.
THAT'LL CONSTITUTE
YOUR AUTHORIZATION.
7-5-JULIET-KILO-ROMEO-
LIMA-8-GOLF-5-NINER.
LET ME SAY THAT AGAIN.
7-5-JULIET-KILO-ROMEO-LIMA-
8-GOLF-5-NINER.
7-5-JULIET-KILO-
ROMEO-LIMA-
8-GOLF-5-NINER.
SIR, YOU ARE
AUTHORIZING THE RELEASE
OF FREE-FALLING,
STRATEGIC NUCLEAR WEAPONS
ON BAGHDAD, IRAQ.
THAT'S RIGHT.
MR. PRESIDENT,
YOUR CODES ARE NOW BEING
ELECTRONICALLY DELIVERED
TO THE B-2.
WE HAVE FINALLY BEEN ABLE
TO MAKE SATELLITE AUDIO CONTACT
WITH ERIC VINCE,
OUR CORRESPONDENT IN BAGHDAD.
ERIC ?  ERIC,
CAN YOU HEAR ME ?
- ERIC VINCE, ARE YOU THERE ?
- YEAH, I CAN HEAR YOU
JUST FINE NOW, GERRY.
- ARE YOU OKAY ?
- [ Vince ]  I'M HERE TO TELL
YOU THAT HERE IN BAGHDAD--
PANDEMONIUM THAT I HAVE NEVER
SEEN IN MY ENTIRE
PROFESSIONAL CAREER.
I CAN TELL YOU--
HONEY,
I'M GETTING THROUGH.
REALLY ?
YEAH, MAYBE
THE STORM--
HELLO ?
YEAH, H-HELLO ?
YEAH.  HELLO.
MRS. FISHER.
YES, MR. WOODS.
YES, I KNOW
IT'S LATE.
I'M SORRY TO WAKE YOU,
BUT LIZZIE AND I WANT
TO TALK TO DYLAN.  IS HE--
NO, NO,
I'M SURE HE'S ASLEEP.
OF COURSE HE'S ASLEEP.
WE JUST WANTED
TO GET ONE--
HI, THIS IS LIZZIE.
WE JUST WANT TO TALK
TO DYLAN, OKAY ?
ERIC, I SHOULD TELL YOU,
IF YOU DO NOT ALREADY KNOW THIS,
THAT IT IS
MORE THAN UNDERSTANDABLE...
FOR YOU TO PUT DOWN THE PHONE
AND HEAD OUT OF THE CITY NOW...
FOR YOUR OWN PROTECTION.
WELL, GERRY, I SEE
12 MILLION PEOPLE ON THE STREET,
ALL TRYING TO GET OUT
OF THE CITY.
THEY'RE EITHER ON FOOT
OR THEY'RE IN CARS.
I'M TOLD MORE PEOPLE HAVE DIED
BY BEING TRAMPLED TO DEATH
THAN DIED THE ENTIRE GULF WAR.
HOW MANY REPORTERS
GET TO SAY MORITURI...
AS I DO TO YOU
AND TO MY FAMILY,
MY FRIENDS AT IBS.
NOT MANY, ERIC.
WHEN DADDY GETS HOME,
HE'S GONNA GIVE YOU...
A MILLION,
ZILLION...
GOOD NIGHT DREAM DROPS.
WHAT THE FUCK
ARE YOU DOING ?
MR. WOODS, WE WERE
VERY CLEAR ABOUT THIS.
WE ASKED YOU REPEATEDLY TO STAY
OFF THE PHONE.  WE'VE BEEN
VERY CLEAR ABOUT THE PHONE.
I'M--
GIVE ME
THE FUCKIN' PHONE BACK.
HELLO.
[ Sighs ]
NO.  NO, YOUR DADDY
WILL CALL YOU BACK,
OKAY, BUDDY ?
THAT'S MY--
I'M JUST SPEAKING
TO MY KID.
THEY'RE DROPPING
A BOMB ON MY KID !
THAT'S MY SON ON THE PHONE.
GIVE ME THE FUCKIN'--
LET ME TALK TO HIM !
YOU MOTHERFUCKER !
PLEASE TRY TO LOSE
YOUR THREATENING TONE.
PLEASE, SIR.
ARE YOU GONNA
SHOOT ME NOW ?
ARE YOU GONNA SHOOT ME NOW ?
MR. WOODS,
YOU'RE GONNA HAVE TO
CALM DOWN RIGHT NOW.
TEN MINUTES BEFORE WE ALL DIE,
ARE YOU GONNA KILL ME ?
YOU HAVE TO CALM DOWN.
THAT MAKES A LOT
OF FUCKING SENSE.
WE'LL ALL BE FINE.
I'M FINE.  GIVE ME THE F--
[ Emerson ]
COME ON.
YOU CAN UNDERSTAND STRESS
AT A TIME LIKE THIS.
PLEASE, TAYLOR, PLEASE.
SIT DOWN, MR. WOODS.
LET THE MAN STAND, PLEASE.
I APPRECIATE WHAT WE ALL
HAVE TO DO HERE.
IF YOU HAVE SOMETHING
YOU NEED TO SAY,
PLEASE, LET'S HEAR IT.
LET'S HEAR IT NOW.
WHAT IS IT ?
YOU--
YOU HAVE NO RIGHT.
REGRETFULLY,
I AM THE ONLY ONE
THAT DOES HAVE THIS RIGHT.
[ Woods ]
NO, YOU HAVE NO MORAL RIGHT.
YOU WERE NEVER ELECTED.
YOU CAN'T EVEN MAKE
THE SHALLOW ARGUMENT YOU HAVE
A MANDATE OF THE PEOPLE.
YOU MADE A CHOICE
THAT YOUR EGO WILL NOT
ALLOW YOU TO BACK OFF FROM.
TAYLOR--
IF YOU BOMB... BAGHDAD,
WE'RE ALL NEXT.
I UNDERSTAND YOU'RE AFRAID.
EVERYONE'S AFRAID.
THE WHOLE WORLD IS AFRAID.
I'M ASKING YOU
TO BELIEVE ME THAT
IT'S GONNA BE OKAY,
NOT BECAUSE
I AM TELLING YOU TO
BUT BECAUSE...
IT'S THE TRUTH.
[ Lancaster ]  SIR, THE B-2
SPIRIT HAS ACKNOWLEDGED RECEIPT
OF THE PRESIDENTIAL ORDER.
YOU'RE ASKING TOO MUCH.
I HAVE A SON IN NEW YORK.
IT'S HEADING DUE EAST--
I HAVE A DAUGHTER.
TRACEY, RIGHT ?
DYLAN !
I LOVE MY CHILD
NO LESS THAN YOU
LOVE YOURS.
HE'S GONNA BE FIVE !
[ Bawling ]
PLEASE TRUST ME.
[ Lancaster ]  WE HAVE
AN IRAQI LAUNCH...
IN TRIPOLI.
WE NOW HAVE
TWO MORE LAUNCHES, SIR.
WHAT'S THE E.T.A.
OF THE DETONATION IN BAGHDAD ?
SIX MINUTES AND TWENTY SECONDS.
AND THE E.T.A. OF THE TRIPOLI ?
WE NOW HAVE EIGHT MORE
IRAQI LAUNCHES, SIR.
E.T.A. OF THE TRIPOLI LAUNCH.
UH, 17 MINUTES
IN ROME, SIR.
OKAY, SO THAT'S
12 IRAQI LAUNCHES THUS FAR ?
YES.  NO--
NO, WE NOW HAVE--
SIR, WE HAVE CONFIRMED
THE LAUNCHING OF A LANCELOT
MISSILE, TARGET POSITION--
SIR, IT'S COMING IN
ON NORAD.
THAT'S NOT FAR
FROM WHERE WE ARE.
SIR, A.P.C.s HAVE ARRIVED
AT YOUR POSITION TO GET YOU TO
SAFETY AND HANDLE CASUALTIES.
- WHAT ABOUT THE OTHER
AMERICAN CITIES ?
- WASHINGTON, D.C.,
MIAMI AND NEW YORK.
I WOULD NOT BE
OVERLY CONCERNED
ABOUT THOSE CITIES, SIR.
OUR SPACECOM AT PETERSON
SHOULD BE ABLE
TO DEAL WITH THEM.
- AND WHAT ABOUT OUR POSITION ?
- SIR, WE DON'T HAVE
THE AIR DEFENSE CAPACITY...
TO ACTIVELY
ENGAGE THE LANCELOT.
WE DON'T HAVE THE CAPACITY ?
SIR, NO ONE
ANTICIPATED...
THAT WE'D HAVE
TO DEFEND OURSELVES
AGAINST OUR OWN TECHNOLOGY.
ISN'T THAT
TERRIFIC FORESIGHT.
[ Lancaster ]
ONCE THE MISSILE ENTERS SPACE,
WE LOSE OUR LOCK ON IT,
AND WE CAN'T REGAIN LOCK
UNTIL--
THE A.P.C. OUTSIDE
YOUR POSITION IS FAR SAFER
THAN WHERE YOU ARE, SIR.
I'LL BE STAYING INSIDE,
GENERAL.
NO, YOU WON'T.
MR. PRESIDENT, ALLOW US
TO ESCORT YOU OUTSIDE.
I'M STAYING INSIDE
WITH THESE BRAVE PEOPLE.
YOU'RE THE PRESIDENT.
YOU HAVE TO GO INTO THE A.P.C.
IF I ASKED YOU
TO WAIT...
IN THE A.P.C.,
WHAT WOULD YOU DO ?
- [ Marsh ]  I WOULDN'T GO.
I'M NOT THE PRESIDENT.
- EXCUSE US A SECOND.
YOU HAVE TO TRUST
WHAT I TOLD YOU OUTSIDE,
WHAT PAUL TOLD ME
ON HIS DEATHBED,
AS FANTASTIC AS IT SOUNDED.
IT WAS INSANE.
HE WAS A GREAT PRESIDENT
UNTIL THE END.
IN THE END, HE WAS
A HALLUCINATING FOOL
HOOKED ON PAINKILLERS.
[ Lancaster ]
SIR, ISRAELI DB-12s
DESTROYED ONE OF THE ICBMs.
YEAH !
YEAH.  ALL RIGHT.
SIR, STRATCOM IS REPORTING LESS
THAN FIVE MINUTES FROM BAGHDAD.
STAY HERE.  BE A FUCKIN' HERO.
GENERAL, WHO'S IN THE B-2 ?
THEIR NAMES,
YOU MEAN ?
YES, THEIR NAMES.
WHAT ARE THEIR NAMES ?
JETER AND MEYERS,
COMMANDERS BOTH.
CAN YOU PATCH ME
THROUGH TO THEM ?
IT WON'T BE SECURE, SIR.
I UNDERSTAND.
PATCH ME THROUGH.
YES, SIR.
[ Riley ]
SIR, STRATCOM IS NOW
LATCHED ONTO THE B-2.
IT IS APPROXIMATELY
TWO MINUTES FROM POSITION.
ONE OF US WILL HAVE
ONE HELL OF AN &quot;I TOLD YOU SO&quot;
WHEN THIS IS OVER, HUH ?
[ Lancaster ]
GENTLEMEN, PLEASE GIVE
YOUR ATTENTION TO THE PRESIDENT.
SIR, THESE ARE
COMMANDERS JETER AND MEYERS.
COMMANDERS.
MR. PRESIDENT.
IT'S A PRIVILEGE.
YOU FELLAS
HANGING IN THERE ?
YES, SIR, WE ARE.
HELL OF A JOB
YOU GOT PICKED FOR.
A HELL OF A JOB.
MORE PEOPLE
HAVE WALKED THE MOON
THAN HAVE DONE WHAT WE MUST.
SO, I GUESS THAT'S WHY
WE GET THE BIG MONEY.
YEAH, WELL,
YOU'VE, UH--
YOU'VE GOT TO KNOW...
YOU'RE SERVING
A GREATER CAUSE FOR MANKIND.
RIGHT, SIR.
[ Lancaster ]  ELEVEN MINUTES
AND THIRTY SECONDS, SIR.
ALL OF THE MISSILES APPEAR
ONE MINUTE TO THIRTY SECONDS
BEHIND YOUR E.T.A.
[ Riley ]
SIR, LESS THAN
ONE MINUTE FROM TARGET.
- [ Emerson ]
WHERE YOU MEN FROM ?
- [ Jeter ]  KENNEBUNK.
MEYERS IS FROM HAWAII.
WE WERE CLASSMATES
AT THE UNIVERSITY OF MAINE.
- WE PLAYED FOOTBALL TOGETHER.
- YEAH.  YEAR OF
THE NATIONAL CHAMPIONSHIP ?
[ Jeter ]
UH, A LITTLE LATE
FOR THAT, ACTUALLY.
SIR ?
YES.
SIR, MEYERS AND I
HAVE THOUGHT, AND, UH,
WE DON'T KNOW HOW
WE'RE FEELING ABOUT THIS.
YOU'RE GOING
TO BE OKAY, SON.
[ Lancaster ]
ELEVEN MINUTES TO DETONATION
ON YOUR POSITION, SIR.
YOU JUST HAVE TO REMEMBER
ONE THING.  YOU'RE NOT
DOING THIS, I AM.
YES, SIR.
IT'S AN ARGUMENT
I'VE HEARD BEFORE.
[ Riley ]
EIGHT SECONDS
TO BAGHDAD, SIR.
MEN DON'T GO
ON THIS KIND OF MISSION,
AND, WELL, MEYERS AND I
HAVE TALKED, AND WE FIGURE WE'RE
JUST HORSES WITH BROKEN LEGS.
YOU'RE GOOD MEN.
GOOD LUCK TO YOU BOTH.
[ Riley ]  ...THREE, TWO--
WE'VE REACHED TARGET, SIR.
[ Riley ]
SIR, THE B-2 HAS ARRIVED.
SIR, STRATCOM NOW CONFIRMS
THE DETONATION...
OF A 100-MEGATON
NUCLEAR WEAPON--
[ Crying ]
[ Lancaster ]
TEN MINUTES E.T.A....
ON YOUR POSITION, SIR.
[ Irving On TV ]
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
IBS SATELLITES NOW CONFIRM...
A GIGANTIC EXPLOSION
OVER BAGHDAD.
WE CANNOT CLARIFY
THE NATURE OF THIS EXPLOSION.
HOWEVER,
OUR EARLIEST INDICATIONS
SEEM TO ESTABLISH...
THAT, IN FACT,
A NUCLEAR WEAPON
HAS BEEN DROPPED...
ON THAT IRAQI CAPITAL.
THIS WAS JUST
A FEW MINUTES AGO.
[ Howard ]
SIR, IT'S INCREDIBLE
WHAT'S GOING ON HERE.
OKAY.  LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
IBS SATELLITES ARE MONITORING
THE ACTIVITY...
OVER THE IRAQI CAPITAL.
WE DO HAVE A PARTIAL IMAGE
FROM BAGHDAD THAT WAS CUT OFF
IN MID-EXPLOSION.
HERE IT IS.
[ Pilot ]
EAGLE LEADER,
STATUS REPORT: SECURE.
OKAY.  OKAY.
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
IBS SATELLITES
HAVE NOW LATCHED ON.
CAN WE GET THE SATELLITE IMAGES
ON THE AIR ?
OKAY, AS YOU CAN SEE,
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
THESE ARE, INDEED,
HOSTILE WARHEADS--
IRAQI WARHEADS
THAT ARE IN FLIGHT
AT THIS TIME.
THESE ARE WARHEADS
CONFIRMED TO HAVE ORIGINATED
FROM THE LOCATIONS...
PROVIDED BY THE IRAQI SPOKESMAN,
THAT IS, THE IRAQI AMBASSADOR,
MR. OMARI.
THIS FOOL
IS GONNA CREATE A PANIC
THE WORLD HAS NEVER SEEN.
THERE'S A LOT TO SORT OUT,
AND WE'RE DOING SO IN REAL TIME.
OUR NUCLEAR EXPERT,
DANIEL GOLAN, IS ON THE LINE...
CALLING FROM OUR SATELLITE
SURVEILLANCE CENTER.
- DANIEL.
- GERRY, FROM OUR VANTAGE POINT,
IT'S CLEAR THAT AT LEAST
22 MISSILES ARE IN FLIGHT.
OUR TRAJECTORIES INDICATE BOMBS
TARGETING NEW YORK CITY,
PENSACOLA,
WASHINGTON, D.C.,
AND NORAD
IN COLORADO.
THERE ARE SEVERAL EUROPEAN
CITIES TARGETED AS WELL.
AUSTRALIA
IS ALSO PROJECTED.
DO YOU HAVE ANY ESTIMATE
ON THE ARRIVAL OF ANY
OF THESE WEAPONS, DANIEL ?
WELL, THEY'VE ALL BEEN
IN FLIGHT FOR A WHILE.  MANY
OF THE WEAPONS ARE TOMAHAWKS.
THE ONE HEADED TO NORAD
APPEARS TO BE A LANCELOT.
WE SHOULD, OF COURSE,
POINT OUT THAT NORAD...
IS WITHIN 40 MILES OF THE
PRESIDENT'S CURRENT POSITION.
[ Golan ]
OKAY, GERRY,
WE'VE JUST GOTTEN WORD.
A WARHEAD
HAS LANDED IN ATHENS.
IT'S LANDED ON A SMALL BUILDING,
AND THERE ARE NOT YET
ANY CASUALTY REPORTS,
BUT GERRY,
WE CAN REPORT NO DETONATION.
OF COURSE,
THERE WILL BE CASUALTIES
ASSOCIATED WITH THE IMPACT.
UH, GERRY, WE NOW SEE THERE IS
NO DETONATION OF THE BOMBS
LANDING IN DJIBOUTI.
WELL, THIS IS REMARKABLE.
DANIEL, GIVE ME A SECOND
WHILE WE GO TO SYLVIA CHARLES
IN TOKYO.  SYLVIA.
GERALD, THE BOMBS
PRESUMABLY HEADED FOR TOKYO
HAVE LANDED IN THE SEA OF JAPAN.
MORE IMPORTANTLY,
ANOTHER BOMB HAS LANDED
IN THE PARK IN HIROSHIMA.
THERE'S NO DETONATION.
IT'S ABSOLUTELY INCREDIBLE,
GERRY.
- WE'LL GET BACK TO YOU
SOON WITH MORE...
- THANK YOU, SYLVIA.
INFORMATION ON
THIS SITUATION.
FOLKS, YOU'VE JUST HEARD WHAT
I HEARD, WHICH APPEARS TO BE
AN ODD PATTERN...
IN THAT
MANY OF THESE BOMBS...
DID NOT DETONATE
AFTER HAVING HIT THEIR TARGET.
[ Irving On TV ]
WE ARE NOW GETTING WORD THAT THE
LANCELOT MISSILE FIRED FROM--
NOAH,
HOW WE DOIN' ?
ON IN JUST
A FEW, SIR.
...NORAD IN COLORADO SPRINGS,
HAS LANDED IN THE ROCKIES,
HOW ARE YA ?
[ Groaning ]
AND LIKE MANY
OF THE OTHER BOMBS,
WITHOUT DETONATING.
WHAT ARE YOU
GONNA SAY ?
I'M GONNA GIVE IT
TO THEM STRAIGHT, I GUESS.
WHAT DO YOU THINK ?
I LIKE YOUR TIE.
[ Irving ]
...IS LESS THAN 50 MILES
FROM THE PRESIDENT'S POSITION.
FINAL LOOK.
PRESIDENT EMERSON AND HIS
ENTOURAGE ARE APPARENTLY SAFE.
STANDING BY.  RIGHT HERE.
THE PRESIDENT WILL NOW
ADDRESS THE NATION...
EXCLUSIVELY HERE
ON IBS.
DO WE HAVE
THAT PICTURE NOW ?
OKAY.
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
THE PRESIDENT
OF THE UNITED STATES.
MY FELLOW AMERICANS.
PRESIDENT ROOSEVELT ONCE SAID,
&quot;WE HAVE NOTHING TO FEAR
BUT FEAR ITSELF.&quot;
BY GOD, THAT IS TRUE.
FEAR IS OUR NATION'S CANCER.
IT SUCKS THE MARROW
OUT OF OUR ECONOMY
AND OUR NATIONAL PSYCHE,
AND FEAR IS THE DRAGON
THAT EVERY PRESIDENT MUST SLAY.
AT 1:47 A.M.,
EASTERN SEABOARD TIME,
A B-2 SPIRIT BOMBER,
ON MY LAUNCH CODE ORDERS,
DROPPED A 100-MEGATON
NUCLEAR DEVICE...
ON THE IRAQI CAPITAL
OF BAGHDAD.
OUR AERIAL REPORTS
HAVE CONFIRMED...
A SUCCESSFUL DETONATION AND
THE DESTRUCTION OF THAT CITY.
NUCLEAR WEAPONS, 23 IN TOTAL,
WERE LAUNCHED BY IRAQ...
SIMULTANEOUS TO OUR B-2
CROSSING THEIR BORDER.
OUR ANTIBALLISTIC MISSILES
SUCCESSFULLY DESTROYED
18 OF THOSE BOMBS.
FIVE, HOWEVER, LANDED
ON THEIR TARGETED CITIES,
ONE OF WHICH,
A LANCELOT MISSILE,
LANDED NOT TOO FAR
FROM WHERE I'M STANDING NOW.
NOT ONE
OF THOSE FIVE BOMBS DETONATED.
I WOULD LIKE TO NOW
TELL YOU WHY.
SEVERAL DECADES AGO, WE BEGAN
A BAN ON NUCLEAR TESTING.
IN THE EARLY '90s,
THE UNITED STATES...
CREATED
THE TERAFLOP COMPUTER,
THE MOST SOPHISTICATED
SIMULATOR...
OF NUCLEAR DETONATION
KNOWN TO MAN.
THE EFFICIENCY OF THE TERAFLOP,
WHICH CAN LITERALLY PERFORM
ONE TRILLION CALCULATIONS
PER SECOND,
BECAME THE ENVY OF THE WORLD.
A FEW YEARS AGO,
WE BEGAN TO SELL
NUCLEAR WEAPONS TO IRAQ.
OUR MOTIVATION
WAS SIMPLE.
THE ONLY WAY TO STOP
HUSSEIN FROM BUILDING
A NUCLEAR ARSENAL...
WAS TO SUPPLY HIM
WITH ONE, AND WE DID
THROUGH AN EMISSARY.
THE FRENCH GOVERNMENT
SUPPLIED IRAQ WITH AS MANY
NUCLEAR WEAPONS...
AS THEY WOULD EVER NEED
AND A TERAFLOP COMPUTER
TO VERIFY THEIR EFFICIENCY.
AS SOME OF YOU
MAY HAVE GUESSED,
WE SOLD THEM
A BILL OF GOODS.
NOT ONE OF
THE NUCLEAR WEAPONS WE SOLD IRAQ
THROUGH THE FRENCH GOVERNMENT...
EVER HAD THE CAPACITY
TO DETONATE, THOUGH THE TERAFLOP
COMPUTER THEY RECEIVED...
ASSURED THEM THAT THEY WOULD.
THROUGHOUT MODERN HISTORY,
IT WAS BELIEVED THAT
THE NUCLEAR ERA DE FACTO...
WOULD LAST TWO DAYS,
FROM HIROSHIMA TO NAGASAKI.
WHEN THE FIVE MEMBER NATIONS
OF THE SECURITY COUNCIL...
WERE CONFIRMED TO HAVE
NUCLEAR ARSENALS,
IT WAS ASSUMED
THEY WOULD NEVER BE USED.
THE DOMINO EFFECT WAS
SIMPLY TOO OVERWHELMING.
DETERRENCE
WAS OUR GLOBAL SHIELD.
TODAY, THE UNITED STATES
SENT A MESSAGE TO THE WORLD.
IF OUR NATIONAL SECURITY
IS THREATENED,
WE HAVE NUCLEAR WEAPONS,
AND WE WILL USE THEM.
TOMORROW NIGHT
AT 9:00 P.M.
EASTERN TIME,
I WILL MAKE
A SIGNIFICANT ANNOUNCEMENT
FROM THE WHITE HOUSE.
UNTIL THEN,
I WISH TO EXPRESS
MY ETERNAL SORROW...
FOR ALL THE LIVES
LOST TODAY.
GOD BLESS YOU,
ONE AND ALL,
AND GOD BLESS
THE UNITED STATES OF AMERICA.
WE KNOW THE NEWS
OF THIS EVENING...
AND WE'RE OUT, SIR.
IS COMING IN AT
A FRUSTRATINGLY RAPID RATE.
WE'LL SORT EVERYTHING OUT
AS SOON AS THE DUST SETTLES.
SIGNIFICANT ANNOUNCEMENT ?
WHAT'S THIS ?
THAT'S IT.  IT'S OVER.
[ Marsh ]
WHAT'S OVER ?
I'M WITHDRAWING FROM THE RACE.
WHAT ?
WHAT--
WHAT DID JETER SAY ?
&quot;I'M A HORSE WITH A BROKEN LEG.&quot;
SO, A-ALL THIS--
EVERY--  NOTHING.
FOR NOTHING ?
COME ON.
THERE'S A BIG DIFFERENCE
BETWEEN STRATEGY AND TACTICS.
WHEN CHINA BACKS DOWN,
WAS IT ALL FOR NOTHING ?
MARSH--
[ Sighing ]
I GUESS I'LL LEAVE THE FUTURE
IN YOUR HANDS, GAYLE.
[ Marsh Scoffs ]
WELL, SIR,
THE FUTURE ISN'T
WHAT IT USED TO BE,
IS IT ?
NO, I GUESS NOT.
SIR,
HERE'S YOUR JACKET.
KATIE, CAN I
HELP YOU UP ?
NOAH ?
YES, SIR.
COME UP WITH IT,
PLEASE.
ALL RIGHT.  GOTCHA.
THIS WILL PROBABLY
BE THE LAST TIME.
I'M ON TOP OF IT, MARSHALL.
AGENT WILLIAMS ?
YES, SIR.
TAKE THAT DOWN, PLEASE.
YOU BET, SIR.
MR. PRESIDENT ?
WE HAVE A DEAL.
[ Emerson ]
WELL, WHY DON'T WE--
MR. WOODS.
[ Emerson ]  YOU KNOW WHAT,
GIVE ME A SECOND.
MA'AM.
THANK YOU.
MR. PRESIDENT,
FOOTBALL IS SECURE.
WE'RE READY WHEN YOU ARE, SIR.
[ Emerson ]
THANKS.
TAYLOR.
I'D LAY DOWN
THE KING.
YOU'RE RIGHT,
SIR.
LET'S GO.
[ Woman On Radio ]
EAGLE TWO TO AIR FORCE ONE
AT PETERSON.
REPORTING ALL SYSTEMS--
[ Door Closes ]
[ Wind Whistling ]
[ Watch Ticking ]
[ Franklin Delano Roosevelt ]
I HAVE SEEN WAR.
I HAVE SEEN WAR
ON LAND AND SEA.
I HAVE SEEN BLOOD
RUNNING FROM THE WOUNDED.
I HAVE SEEN CHILDREN
STARVING.
I HAVE SEEN THE AGONY
OF MOTHERS AND WIVES.
I HATE WAR !