[MOTORCYCLE ENGINES ROARING]
[MOTORCYCLE ENGINE STARTING]
[BIKE TIRES SCREECHING]
[SCREAMING]
[INDISTINCT TALKING]
MAN: Somebody
call an ambulance.
Get up!
[ENGINE STARTING]
MAN: They're getting away!
[INDISTINCT TALK]
[SURFER ROCK
MUSIC PLAYING]
Foosh.
[BLOWING KISSES]
[INDISTINCT CHATTERING]
[CHUCKLING AND CHATTERING]
[WHISTLING]
[WHOOPING]
[CHATTERING AND CHEERING]
[WHISTLING]
[HOWLING]
[BIKE ENGINES ROARING]
-Grog.
-Yeah?
Have you ever been a father?
I used to have a father once.
How'd you like to be mine?
Are you some kind of a nut?
[WHOOPING]
[MUSIC STOPS]
Good strain.
CODY: He didn't mention
it to me, Leroy.
Did he mention it to you?
-Didn't say a word
to me, Cody.
-Huh.
The point is, uh...
-That Gage just
snuffed a citizen.
-Yes, he did.
CODY: And that makes
one dead dude,
one hot Skull.
Now, I'm not mad at you, Gage.
I'm not mad at you.
[CHUCKLING] Anybody could
do what you did,
just run away like that.
Yeah, we could have done
the same, right, Leroy?
Yeah, yeah. Right, Cody.
But you know,
that's hit and run,
which means the man
is looking for Gage,
which means by coming here
he's brought heat on us...
Which means I ought
to push you right
around the block.
[ALL LAUGHING]
The point is that Gage's bike
is hotter than he is.
So let's strip it the hell
down and get out
of here, huh?
All right, we ain't got too
much time now.
No goof and let's
get it done, huh.
Hey, do I smell pizza?
Rip off a hunk.
[CHUCKLES]
Oh, yeah, Gage is a bad face.
LEROY: Have you taken a good
look at yourself lately?
-Uh, did you get packed
for the big run?
-Yeah, I guess.
-LEROY: You got us packed?
-Uh-huh.
You better have us packed
'cause we're not coming back.
Oh, we got to be
back by Thursday
'cause it's another
dance contest.
-Forget it.
-What do you mean "Forget it"?
Forget it. He says forget it,
I say forget it,
'cause he is me
and I is he
and we is we.
JOEL: Hey, Cody?
You know Hank Fredericks
is still in the hospital?
LEROY: Yeah, so?
JOEL: And Pete McCarthy
almost got busted on Thursday?
You know Matt the Hat's
still doing 15 to 20?
And Will Perkins
we haven't heard from
since the run to Big Bear.
Well, nothing new
there at all, is there?
Ooh! Stop!
Listen, what I'm saying is,
if five years ago, we...
Yeah, I know what
you're saying.
JOEL: Man, we are washed up.
Well, maybe we're washed up...
When I die,
and I'm there and you're here,
throw a lily on my grave.
Careful when you
burn down the engine nose.
Don't make no deep scratches
and don't try
to save the tires.
They have to bust
every one of us
to get my bike now.
Gage, sometimes I think
you guys want to get busted.
You know, five years ago
there were 200 of us
and the town knew it.
And now there are 26 left
[CHUCKLES]
and we got to sneak around
like a bunch of dips.
Look, the dumb squirt
got right out in front of me,
I couldn't help it.
Yeah, well, I'll tell you
one thing, you're lucky
the Man wasn't around.
The Man was there.
Every time we go out we come
face to face with the Man.
We take one drink
and there's the Man,
and we hop on our signals
and the Man is on our tail.
Now look, the Man is out there
and he's going to bust us all.
Joel. Joel.
Uh, tell 'em that story
about Butch Cassidy,
you told me.
Hmm, Cassidy.
He was an outlaw.
He had maybe
400 men under him.
And they had their own town,
a place called
Hole-in-the-Wall.
They had a cannon
up in the pass
and the whole cavalry
tried to take him
and couldn't.
Like they was home free.
Never did get took.
Yeah, well, I've decided
we're going to split
from this pad.
We're going to pick up
our old ladies and whatever
little we have
and we're going to put
on our colors and we're
going to roll.
And neither man nor beast
is going to stop us
until we find a place where
we can blow our own peace,
and we're going to
love each other.
-I love you, Leroy.
-Cody, I love you.
[ALL TALKING INDISTINCTLY]
Anybody got anything to say?
Yes, I'm going to have a baby.
[ALL LAUGHING]
[MOTORCYCLES REVVING]
[ENGINES ROARING]
Okay, you all set?
Yeah, we got the food
and the extra oil and the
fuel tanks are full.
We don't have to stop
till we get to Lenning.
Okay, let's pick up Funky,
we'll go on the bridge.
You really think it's smart
to bother with Funky?
His head's pretty twisted.
He really wants to
be a citizen.
Don't you worry
about ole Funky!
Funky!
-[LAUGHING]
-Hey, by the way,
where are we going to end up?
Hole-in-the-Wall!
Hey, Cody, I don't think
it's fair to have to leave my
partner in the dance contest.
There ain't going to be
no dance contest.
We're not coming back,
we're going to
Hole-in-the-Wall.
When God created Woman
he made her pretty stupid.
Let's go!
[ENGINES ROARING]
[DOG BARKING]
[MOTORCYCLES APPROACHING]
Hey, did a cat named
Funky Davico do this?
-It's as pretty as a picture.
-Yeah, which way does
the old funk live?
-Brown house on
top of the hill.
-That way?
-Bye.
-[LAUGHS] That way.
Thanks a lot!
Funky!
ALL: [YELLING] Funky!
[INDISTINCT SPEAKING]
Funk? Where's the Funky?
[ALL LAUGHING]
I hate to tell you this, Cody,
but Funky's in the can.
-[CHUCKLES] Oh, no.
-Yeah? What did he do now?
Nothing! Not a damn thing.
Except he got a little loaded
and he painted this picture
on the town hall.
-Yeah, we saw that!
-[ALL LAUGHING]
They put him in the joint
for public indecency.
LEROY: That's what you get
for trying to be a citizen.
-How much is the bail?
-Oh, $500.
Ah, we don't have $500,
but we'll grab his chopper
and we'll go into town.
We'll get him out
of there somehow.
Hey, and then guess what?
We're all going
to the boondocks
and live forever.
Oh, no.
-The boondocks?
-Yeah.
-Gee, I don't know.
-Why do I love her?
See, we got this house here.
I guess we're kinda
crazy about it.
Not that the town's too
crazy about us, but...
[ALL LAUGHING]
Listen, you haven't
heard the best part yet.
The Stompers is having
a party up the bridge
and we're going to get us
girls to wisty.
-ALL: Yeah!
-Leroy.
Party with the Stompers?
Oh, hell! Wait till I get
my toothbrush...
[ALL CHEERING]
-Leroy!
-Cody!
Leroy, I love you!
[MEN WHISPERING] Funky!
[WHISPERING] Funky!
Funky! Funky!
-[YELLING] Cody!
-ALL: Shh!
-Leroy, Joel, Gage, Bruno!
-Shh!
-Man, what's happening?
-ALL: Shh!
We'll let you outta here
if you just shut up!
Cool, man. Cool.
[LAUGHING] I love you guys!
I love you!
[LAUGHING]
-Man, it was one original
mistake moving to this town.
-Shh.
-[SPITS] It stinks!
-They all stink!
-[SPITS]
-Let's hope they have no jails
in Hole-in-the-Wall.
Yo, man, Hole-in-the-Wall
ain't even in the state
of California.
-[BOTH SPIT]
-Okay, let's go.
[ENGINES ROARING]
[INDISTINCT YELLING]
I'll do it. I'll do it!
I'll do it!
[LAUGHING]
Oh, Funky, it's good
to have you back
running with us again.
Well, I got a hot news
for you guys,
Funky Davico ain't about
to settle down again.
Not now.
That's what I was going
to say. "Not now."
That's what I said.
Not now.
-Nor never.
Nor never!
-I'll drink to that.
-Hey, man. [LAUGHING]
I'm not going to stay
around here and listen
to this pack of lies.
Come on, you mule.
Come on, you mule!
-[IMITATING KISSES]
-[LAUGHING]
[LAUGHING]
Watch how I give
my old lady a kiss.
-BOTH: Eee!
-[LAUGHING]
Oh, our leader,
ain't he beautiful.
[LAUGHING]
Thanks.
Climb out of that
sleeping bag.
-Huh?
-Get out of the bag.
-I can't get out of the bag,
Cody, I'm stone naked.
-Good.
That's good, isn't it?
Come on, get out of that bag,
I got to cover up my chopper
in case it snows.
-[BOTH CHUCKLING]
-You're putting me on again.
If you want this bag
you're gonna have
to take it off of me.
That's just what I'm going to
do if you're not out of there
-by the time I count three.
-Don't you touch me, Cody.
One!
-Two!
-No, Cody!
Three!
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
[LAUGHING]
[ENGINES ROARING]
Hey, fill her up!
[INDISTINCT TALKING]
-I'm hungry.
-Let me go.
Hey, dude.
Now don't you
holler at Robot.
Don't you know that he's
got seven discs fused
in his spine, man?
Leroy, Leroy, Leroy.
Don't you know this is the man
behind the man behind the man
behind your bike?
-I'm hungry, Leroy.
-Robot's hungry, Cody.
Hey, man.
This is the time
to stock up, look.
-Joel!
-JOEL: Let's go!
-Bye bye. Come on, eat!
-[INDISTINCT YELLING]
I never laid a club on him!
And we're going to go in there
and we're going to act like
a bunch of dudes!
Yeah, we're dudes!
We're dudes!
And we're going to go
in there and we're not
going to steal anything.
[YELLING]
All right, okay.
We might
steal something.
[CLAMORING]
[LAUGHING AND YELLING]
-How you doing, man?
-Hey, baby.
-Hey!
[WHOOPING AND CHATTERING]
What have we got here.
Check this out.
[GLASS CLANKING]
[HUMMING]
Should have made a list,
what have I forgotten?
Beer?
-Beer?
-Mmm.
No, not beer.
Hey, man, that's groovy. Yeah.
Hey, Daddy, I stole it
so it's mine.
All right, it's yours!
Will there be anything else?
-Will there be anything else?
-Will there...
Will there be anything else?
Anything else! Anything else!
[INDISTINCT CHATTER
AND YELLING]
FUNKY: Anything else!
Anything else! Anything else!
[ALL CLAMORING]
All right, wait! Hey!
[WHISTLES]
[BIKERS QUIET DOWN]
-Let's split.
-What about my store?
Hey, cool it, huh.
Hey, come on.
[LAUGHING]
-[BALLOONS POPPING]
-[LAUGHING]
Hey, man, you forgot
my green stamps.
[SHOUTING]
Get in!
The bill comes to $43.76.
We ain't got any money, man.
-You got any money?
-No, I ain't got no money.
You?
Hey, you people just
ripped my shop.
Who's going to pay
for all this?
Look, we'll pay for it on
the way back, okay?
-The police...
-There ain't going to be
no police now, is they?
Is they?
-How much do I owe you?
-Uh, the whole total
is $43.76.
-$43.76?
-$43.76.
Okay.
[COUNTING BILLS]
Now look,
if you don't cut it out, man,
we're going to come
back after you.
Now beat it.
-Hey, they're gone!
-[YELLING]
Another perfect day into
another perfect vacation.
[ENGINES ROARING]
[SCREAMING]
[LAUGHING]
-[YELLING]
-Move 'em out!
I can't figure out what
to do with this. [LAUGHS]
[ENGINES ROARING]
I hope you've got this
camping business out of
your system now.
Okay, honey, next year
we'll get a boat.
[CARNIVAL MUSIC PLAYING]
All righty!
Have the girls got
all their tomatoes?
GIRLS: Yeah.
How about our victim.
Ready as I'll
ever be, Royce.
Okay, girls.
[GIRLS GIGGLING]
Let him have it!
[CROWD LAUGHING]
[WHISTLING AND CHEERING]
[DOG BARKING]
There ain't a soul
to be seen, man.
Must have heard we was coming.
[LAUGHING]
Funky.
So we don't scare anyone,
I'll run down to
the campground
and see if I can find a place
to sleep for the night.
This is as dead a town
as I ever did see.
Uh, let's take a walk
and see what's shaking.
Funky, cool it, will you.
I'll get back.
[ENGINE STARTING]
Ooh, I sure could use me
a beer, Robot.
Oh, didn't Cody say
for us to stay around
here, Leroy, huh?
Yeah, he did.
Now let's get us
a beer anyway, huh?
Wa... You sure it's all
right to leave, Leroy, huh?
-Yeah, it's
all right, let's go.
-Okay, yeah, beer!
[CHATTERING]
[CROWD CHEERING]
Now I know one or
two of you out there is
not planning
on voting for
Charlie Henderson
as sheriff.
[CROWD REACTING]
But he's got my vote as
the best sport in town.
Now how about that?
-[CROWD CHEERING]
-[WHISTLING]
I feel just like a pizza.
[CROWD LAUGHING]
And now,
while Charlie's
being cleaned up,
we're ready for the finals
of the beauty contest.
Now let's give a hand
to our home grown beauties!
[CROWD CHEERING]
We're full-up.
You're full-up?
Yes. We're full-up.
You're full-up.
Well...
Uh, we've come a long way
and we're tired.
We need a place
we can lay down.
Well, how many?
Just you two?
That's right.
Just we two.
Here. And there are
32 more down there.
We're full-up.
Yeah, it's the world's
most beautiful woman.
[CROWD CHEERING
AND WHISTLING]
ROYCE: Let's hear your vote!
[CROWD CHEERING]
ROYCE: Thank you.
Thank you, Susie Hamilton.
Now will the next
gorgeous creature
step forward and
face the music.
[MAN CHEERING]
[CROWD CHEERING]
[BIKERS BOOING]
[LAUGHING]
Folks,
this is Marianne Fielding.
Now Marianne's family
is new in town,
so let's give her an
extra special hand
to welcome her to Brookville!
[CROWD CHEERING]
[BIKERS BOOING]
[WHISPERING]
Charlie Henderson
back here, fast!
Now I guess you all
know who this next one is.
Will the third girl please
step forward?
[CROWD CHEERING
AND WHISTLING]
[BIKERS BOOING]
Well I guess that's that.
The winner, and the most
beautiful girl in Brookville
and maybe the world,
is Clara Hayes.
-[BIKERS BOOING]
-[CROWD CHEERING]
Mayor, the cup.
Congratulations, Clara.
Hear, hear!
MAN: Hey, come over here.
What's happening, Cody?
They won't let us stay
any place tonight.
-No room?
-What do you mean?
No room for us.
-Wait, why?
-It's ridiculous, right?
[LAUGHING]
Who are those
ruffians out there?
What's this, Leroy?
You hit the stump with the
hammer and try to ring the
ding-dong, Robot.
[GIGGLING]
Give me, give me.
[THUDDING]
[BELL DINGING]
[CHUCKLES]
Ding-dong.
Come on, throw it!
What is this, man?
Come on, throw at it.
-I can't believe you.
-[WOMAN SCREAMING]
Vandals.
Filth.
-[LAUGHING]
-[SHOUTING]
My old lady! My old lady!
[LAUGHING AND CHEERING]
Hey, Funky, I ain't
done this in years.
Now you can stop
complaining I never
take you no place nice.
[KISSING SOUND]
[CACKLING]
Hey, short skirt!
-Come over here.
-Let the man in.
Come over here.
How about you
give me a kiss, yeah?
Sorry, sir, but only
residents can play.
-[CHORTLING]
-The hell you say.
GIRL: I'd like to
give you a kiss.
ALL: Oh.
What else
would you like to sell?
Marianne, go and get another
roll of tickets from Hank.
Aww.
[GRUMBLING]
So you're not going
to sell us any kisses?
-MARIANNE: That's right.
-[BLOWS RASPBERRY]
-Maybe I talk to her
a little bit. That's all.
-That's it.
Hey, are you a mama?
Hell no, I'm just pregnant.
[SURFER ROCK
MUSIC PLAYING]
There you go, mama!
[WHOOPING AND CHEERING]
You like it, huh?
Yes.
Want to go for a ride?
Oh, I...
I don't know.
Ah, come on.
Okay.
[ENGINE REVVING]
[MOTORCYCLE DRIVES OFF]
BIKER 1: I bet you a six-pack
against a couple of joints
I can beat you.
BIKER 2: I think you're on.
[BIKERS CLAMORING]
Hey, mister, better look
out for Theodore.
He stinks.
[BIKER IMITATING
RABID DOG]
Hey, wait a minute.
Where did you get that stuff?
I stole it.
I stole it from a crippled
old grandmother.
Hey, Funky,
come on now.
JOEL: Hey, that's right, dude.
And he broke
both her arms too.
-[IMITATES SOUND]
-[CHUCKLING]
-Look, I happen to be the
mayor of this town...
-Oh!
Funky Davico.
Glad to make
your acquaintance.
-What I'd like you to do...
-Don't talk to him, Mayor.
We'll need help.
Listen, mister. Funky didn't
steal this stuff. He won it
fair at the horserace game.
[FUNKY LAUGHING MANIACALLY]
Shut it down, right now.
[CARNIVAL MUSIC STOPS]
[PEOPLE COMPLAINING
AND BOOING]
Well, now, don't you tell me.
I paid two bits for a chance
on the Thunderbird
and I ain't...
I want my two bits back.
Get your filthy hands off me.
-Charlie.
-Leroy.
Leroy.
What's happening here?
Are you the leader
of this outfit?
Yes, sir, I sure am.
Well, get them out.
What did they do? Break
some law or something?
What do you want here?
Trouble?
Oh, no, sir.
Anything but.
We're just looking for
someplace we can
flake out.
-We don't want you here.
-Why not?
Why would anyone want a pack
of junkies in filthy clothes
plastered with emblems?
Who constitute a mobile
disturbance to the peace
and do everything possible
to antagonize and frighten
the general public.
We're just looking for
some place we could
flake out.
If I let you sleep on the
beach, will you stay put
and be out by sun up?
You got my word on that.
Good, because I'm holding
you personally responsible,
is that clear?
Ain't nothing to worry about.
I'm not worried.
I've got a hotline direct
to the highway patrol.
You know how popular
you are with them.
You've got five minutes
to hit the beach.
Life may not be beautiful
if you cooperate with the law,
but it'll be a lot simpler.
Take the south end
of the beach,
below the camp ground.
And clean it up
before you leave.
Okay, Sheriff. Come on,
let's get out of here.
[GROANING AND MUMBLING]
The Man ain't all bad, Leroy.
You said they can
stay on the beach.
That's right. They'd
be isolated, where I
can keep an eye on them.
Charlie.
You made a big mistake.
Oh?
Such as?
They're not gonna give you
any votes, Charlie.
Those are the Skulls.
Adult delinquents.
They steal things, Charlie,
they smell bad.
They use foul language.
They have a hobby of
wrecking small towns.
They've already
wrecked our party.
Now you've got to get
them out of here, right now.
Royce, you're going to
give yourself an ulcer.
Now, look here, Charlie.
Page 15, paragraph 12,
rider zero.
This is police business,
Royce. I know
what I am doing.
Those people
are riot potential.
I don't think I know what
you're talking about.
You want me to
rile those kids up?
Give them a reason to
go crazy and start trouble?
If not here, then five
miles down the road?
They promised.
Promised?
You can't talk to them,
Charlie. They are animals.
They've had their warning.
They'll keep their place.
I know my job, Royce.
Of course you do, Charlie.
And you're going to do
everything you can to keep it.
-Thanks for the ride.
-That was nothing.
Come on down to the
beach party and I'll show
you some real tricks.
Oh, party.
[LAUGHING]
-[CHEERING]
-[SURFER ROCK
MUSIC PLAYING]
[LAUGHING]
[GIRL SCREAMING]
[CLAMORING]
[CHUCKLES]
We could go into town.
Are we going to fix the Man?
Cody?
Cody, tell them.
They don't know, Cody.
Tell them you ain't going
to keep no promise
to no Man, Cody.
Leroy, forget it.
Cody.
We go into town...
And we're going to get
all the nice, safe people
out of their safe houses
and we're going
to ride our scooters
to have a party
and we're going
to show 'em what
beautiful people do, Cody.
Cody, I love you! Cody!
[TIN CAN CLANGING]
Stolen.
Cody!
[GRUNTS]
[HECKLING]
You shut your mouth.
Cody?
Are we really going to stay
in Hole-in-the-Wall?
Forever.
You mean we won't be
going back at all?
No.
Why not?
There's nothing out
there for us.
I've got things there.
No cops and...
No Man in Hole-in-the-Wall.
Yeah, if there's no cops,
you can bet
there's no connections.
Where are you going to score?
I will work that out somehow.
The idea is to...
Idea is to get there.
Cody, there won't be
anything at
Hole-in-the-Wall.
There's no place
that's got good things
that hasn't got cops.
-Cool.
-It's true.
Ain't true.
Remember the...
[CHUCKLES]
Remember the time
on that big run up
to Patagonia?
We had fun there,
didn't we?
Yeah, that was great.
I couldn't stay there
very long. It's too quiet.
I'd go crazy.
You'll dig it.
Well, I dig being with you.
But they won't dig it.
Well, they're gonna now.
Oh, my God.
Honey, they're Skulls.
If there's one thing they
can't stand and you can't
stand, it's being glued down.
We want to roll, and you
want us to sit around
like a bunch of old folks.
Hey, what do you think
this is all for, anyway?
Hey.
Want to hear a ghost story?
EVERYONE: Yeah.
Well, it seems that there was
this motorcycle cop.
And he was goofing down
the freeway, one night.
One foggy night when
he hears a mysterious
voice saying...
"Hey, man, what's happening?"
And that cop draw up
as tight as a bullet
in flight time and he say,
"Who that?"
EVERYONE: Who that?
And the mysterious voice say,
"I am the ghost of
Rinker the Stinker."
[LAUGHING]
"I used to be a Skull,
don't you remember?
"You snuffed me,
"you dirty, rotten,
beady-eyed,
"cold-blooded deadhead."
And the cop say,
"I didn't mean it.
It was an accident,
Rinker the Stinker.
"Honest it was."
And the ghost of
Rinker the Stinker say,
"Hey, man,
you know I was clean.
"I was putting along
on my scooter,
minding my own business,
"when you nailed me with
the 155 millimeter
anti-aircraft cannon!
"And now I've come back
to haunt your empty soul."
[HOWLING]
And the cop say,
"Oh, please,
Mr. Rinker the Stinker,
I didn't know you was clean.
"I saw you coming out
of that liquor store with
a package in your hand
"and I seen you was
wearing your colors.
"And I could smell you
from half a block away.
"And I just knew that
you had robbed that joint."
Amen!
The nose
is the best part
of a cop.
"Well, according to
my instructions,
it was to shoot first
"and wonder about it later.
"I've done my duty,
"so it wasn't my fault,
Rinker the Stinker."
Go haunt
City Hall!
[YELLING]
[ALL LAUGHING]
It's you!
You're the one.
What?
The Ouija board don't lie.
You're the father
of my child to be.
It's you.
-Oh, my.
-It is.
What are you,
some kind of a nut?
It's you.
Ain't you cold?
Getting warm.
Come on, crawl
in here with me.
You'll warm up fast.
I know you guys.
[LAUGHING]
That's what you think.
Hey, hand me a beer, huh?
Oh.
That's how I used
to pinch earrings
from pierced ears, remember?
Can I have a beer too, please?
[LAUGHING]
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
-Heh.
-Tonight.
-For sure.
-Yeah, yeah.
Did I ever tell you
guys about the time
I drowned a
lady traffic officer
in a barrel of brew?
[EVERYONE LAUGHING]
We've heard it.
Is this all you guys do,
is race around,
raise hell and have fun?
-Yeah.
-Almost all the time, we do.
Except when we're
quailing, of course.
You do a lot of quail hunting?
Most all the time.
Dirty legs.
[ALL CHORTLING]
Ain't you scared to be
down here among all
these wild men, little girl?
I'm not so little.
That's right.
You ain't.
[WHOOPING]
[LAUGHING]
Hey, when was the last time
you went quail hunting,
big boy?
Talking to me?
Uh, let's see, uh...
Thursday. No, no, no.
It was Friday.
Well, anyhow, here, see.
We takes this here quails,
see?
-Oh, here.
-What's that?
What's good. Good.
[CHUCKLES]
-Good what?
-[LAUGHING]
This here, man.
This here is the finest blend
of Mexican and domestic grass.
Guaranteed to
bend your brain.
[COUGHING]
[ALL LAUGHING]
-[MUSIC PLAYING]
-[CHUCKLING]
All right. All right.
We know Charlie Henderson's
got a good head
on his shoulder.
And he's been a
pretty good sheriff.
Now I think we all agree
on that, don't we?
-Yeah.
-Shut that thing off.
Anyway.
-[MUSIC STOPS]
-He said that he
handled this Skull business
in the correct manner.
Well, maybe he has.
Maybe he's right.
And we'd be foolish to provoke
these second-generation Okies.
I don't quarrel with that.
But I do quarrel with
passivity in the face
of that danger out there.
Well my wife is setting
up in the orchard right
now with a shotgun.
Good.
Now I want to play
fair with Charlie.
But remember.
We've all been
friends a long time.
And we've got to live with
each other when this is over.
Well, the thing is to get it
over with right now.
Right!
But we shouldn't
interfere to the point
where we might generate
some unfortunate incident.
But we should be prepared.
I'm sure Charlie can take care
of this just beautifully, but
we're still out on
a pretty long limb.
Okay, I'll get the
bowling league together then.
We'll play poker
here all night.
How's that sound?
Fine. Fine.
[MUFFLED EXCLAIMING]
No!
[SOFTLY]
No.
Tell me about
the quail hunting.
[CHUCKLES]
Well you take
one old quail, see?
And you get her
good and stoned.
-[GIGGLES]
-Then you beat on her with a
club till she's soft and ripe.
-[GIGGLES]
-And then you tie her
to an anthill.
And then you strip off
all her clothes.
[LAUGHING MANIACALLY]
[HOWLING]
Ah!
[GRUNTING]
[SCREAMING HYSTERICALLY]
Let her go!
She'll bring the heat on us,
sure as hell!
Cool it! Cool it!
[LAUGHS]
Don't knock down
too much, Charlie.
You may need your wits
later on.
I'm a shoe-in.
[SOBBING AND PANTING]
[THUDDING]
[SOBBING]
Frank. Come on.
Nice going, Charlie!
Chapter nine, page 15.
Paragraph zero, rider zero!
You're finished, Charlie!
[PANTING]
Did they rape you?
No, they didn't.
They might as well have!
They've done it before.
And they'll do it again.
But they didn't.
Charlie would use
that as a technicality.
We've got no more
time for technicalities.
[SIREN WAILING]
What's up, Sheriff?
Would did you do
to that girl?
Nothing.
We didn't do anything.
We'll see what she
has to say about that.
It doesn't matter
what she says.
Don't bet your life on it!
Oh, look, we, uh, put her on
a little bit and
we teased her, but...
Nobody laid a finger
on that babe.
That's right, Sheriff,
nothing happened.
If you're gonna lock up one of
us for rape, you've gotta
lock up the whole bunch!
Your word lasted about
two hours but mine
is a little more durable.
I'm holding you.
Come here!
Now the rest of you,
get going and keep going!
I hear of any of you in this
area again
I will hunt you down
like a pack of rabid dogs.
Take off.
Move!
You really gonna let them go?
What do you want to do?
Build a concentration camp?
Tail them to the city limits.
Come on.
You let 'em go.
They rape a girl
and you let 'em go.
You made another
big mistake, Charlie.
Chase them
but for God's sake
don't catch them.
Roy.
How fast can you
get to Pritchard?
Like the wind.
Well get the Stompers
and tell them
they're in for a rumble.
Bye, bye.
[BIKE ENGINE ROARING]
Now, we got to be ready
with a plan by the time
they get back here.
Got any ideas?
Sure.
How do you feel, honey?
All right.
Fell like telling me
what happened?
They just kind of scared me.
They teased me and
made fun of me and
got me a little high.
That's all.
But you talked to the mayor.
He said you'd been hurt.
No.
Thanks, honey.
-May I go?
-Yes, get some sleep.
Thank you, Sheriff.
Thanks, Charlie.
There was no rape,
you knew that.
Don't make another mistake,
Charlie.
Just what are you
trying to do?
Look, Charlie,
that girl was raped.
Who said so?
I said so.
The point is we were trying
to protect our community.
Now that was supposed to be
your job.
There's an election
in two weeks
and everybody knows
what happened.
I hope you're not about to
make another speech.
What are you doing now?
What do you think?
I'm letting him go.
Oh? Are you always so gracious
to felons?
Just allow them to walk out
without a trial?
Just what did happen, Royce?
Suppose you tell me.
Regardless of what laws may
or may not have been broken,
we have been terrorized
and brutalized.
Now your job, your real job
is not to interpret
a set of books.
Which nobody
bothers to read anyway.
It's to make us feel
safe and comfortable
in our own beds at night.
On your feet.
Come on.
Here's your keys.
Now get out.
If I ever see any one of you
in this town again,
I'll see to it that
you're put away for 20 years.
Don't worry.
I wouldn't come back
to this burg
if you handed it to me.
[BIKE ENGINE RUMBLING]
Bucky.
Hey, somebody bailed
our president out.
-Huh?
-Hey.
Cody!
[LAUGHTER]
Cody. [LAUGHS]
Cody!
-Buddy.
-Cody.
ALL: Cody, Cody.
Cody, Cody.
Cody, you made it.
All right. All right.
CODY: Are we ready to roll?
Yeah.
And we got the plan down pat.
And what's this plan?
Billy's got a righteous idea.
Oh yeah?
What's this righteous idea?
You have a righteous idea?
What is a righteous idea?
All right, you guys
go finish getting ready, huh?
We're gonna go back
into that town
and take that place apart.
-How about that, huh?
-Haha, yeah!
Now hear this!
We're not going back to
any place we've been before.
We're going to
Hole-in-the-Wall.
We've got a score to settle.
I'll keep score around here,
all right, Gage?
Cody. Cody, come here.
Come here a second.
-Hey, Billy, what is this?
-Aw, come on.
Didn't you hear me? Let's go.
Cody, they're bugged.
I mean they're really bugged.
To tell you the truth,
I'm pretty bugged myself.
If we go into that town,
we're really gonna get busted.
It's too late, they already
took a vote.
Yeah, well I wasn't here.
We'll take another vote.
Hey, what is with you, man?
These guys ain't gonna listen
to no jazz about no
holes in the wall.
They want it even.
Yeah, what do you want,
snotnose?
What do you want?
Hey, wait!
The main thing is that
they kicked us out of the town
for raping a girl
we didn't even rape!
That's right. I never heard
the Skulls taking that
from nobody!
-I don't believe you.
-Billy.
Go off somewhere, will you?
[SHOUTS]
Move!
Cody, listen.
I'm gonna level with ya.
The guys have got
their blood up.
They like Billy's plan.
And if you take a vote,
you're gonna lose, man.
And if you lose this one,
you might as well
go off to Hole-in-the-Wall
by yourself.
Joel, we're not strong enough
to go into that town.
Oh, yes we are, Cody.
Come here, I wanna
show you something.
-Come here.
-[SNICKERING]
It's right down the road here.
-Hey, Cody.
-Hey, man.
[CHUCKLES]
How do you like that
for reinforcements, Cody?
200 Stompers, baby.
Hey, man, what's happening?
We've got some, uh,
unfinished business
in Brookville.
When we go in,
you let our boys pick out
the citizens they need.
And all you have to do
is stand guard and
keep a lid on the town
until we get done.
We was hoping for some
razzle dazzle.
Razzle dazzle?
That's right, man,
razzle dazzle.
Okay.
Razzle dazzle.
[ENGINES ROARING]
[ENGINE STARTING]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[DOG BARKING]
[DOOR OPENING]
-Fellas
-Easy baby.
-Fellas.
-Atta boy.
Fellas. Don't!
[BIKE ENGINES ROARING]
[MUFFLED YELL]
[GLASS SHATTERING]
BILLY: Hey, hey, hey, Sheriff.
Truce, man.
Now you boys are
really in for it.
You're all under arrest.
All 200 of us, Sheriff?
'Cause that's what we got,
man. There's 200 of us
in this town right now.
Now if you wanna be smart,
I suggest you dump
all the hardware.
I said dump it!
Do what he says.
There you go, babe.
No problems, see.
Everybody's happy.
[GRUNTS]
MAN: Get them up.
Hey. Hey!
I didn't give you any orders
to beat up the Sheriff.
Hey, I'll tell you what.
Why don't you go to hell, huh?
Take him over
to the big steel, let's go.
[BIKE ENGINES RUMBLING]
Billy boy, we have
the situation under control.
You said it.
Now all I want you to do is
keep your eye on the Stompers.
See that
they don't start anything.
Why me, man?
'Cause you're a bright boy,
Billy boy.
[LAUGHS] Right?
Hey, look,
I can't guarantee...
No. Right, right, right.
Now look.
You're a bright boy.
You've got a cool head.
And you know
how to handle men.
-I still can't...
-Right, right.
Now listen, you make damn sure
that they sit still
and do nothing
unless I send word
that we're in trouble.
Right?
-Right?
-Hey, right. Right.
-Right. Right.
-Right.
[JUKEBOX MUSIC PLAYING]
[MUSIC STOPS]
All right.
We don't have much time.
I want you all to be quiet.
Nobody speak out of turn.
Now what we're gonna do here
is we're gonna give these
fine folks a fair trial,
just like the one
they didn't give us.
Joel-the-Mole is gonna be
the prosecuting attorney.
And uh, these seven fine boys
are gonna be
the unbiased jury.
-Guilty.
Call your first witnesses.
Chick who was on the beach.
Come on up here, honey.
Did you get raped last night?
All right,
don't worry about it.
Don't be afraid. Tell him.
No, I didn't.
Well did you tell anybody
that you did?
No.
You didn't tell him?
Or him?
No.
All right, you two bums.
Stand up.
Come on then,
you heard the man, stand up.
Did she tell you that
she was raped?
Bruno?
Bruno will see to it
that the witnesses answer.
No. No, she didn't.
But you pretended
that she did. Right?
Well we felt it was
our duty to protect
the citizens...
So you did! How do you plead?
-We won't plead to you.
-CODY: The verdict is guilty.
CODY: Has the jury decided
on a sentence?
Yeah. Take them out
and beat 'em raw.
CODY: All right.
You can't do it, Cody.
Overruled, let's go.
-Let's go!
-Oh, wait a minute.
For Christ's sake!
You're savages!
Oh, wait a minute.
[LAUGHS]
You boys are digging
a deep hole.
Maybe.
Now you stand up.
And you keep
right on standing.
You know, we came
into this burg
in a peaceable manner.
And all you nice citizens did
was to insult us
and rough us up
and throw us out of here
like a pack of mad dogs.
Now, don't you think
you owe us something for that?
You've already taken enough
to put you in jail for years.
That's right. That's right,
we sure have,
because you just got to win.
No matter how wrong you are,
you're right
and you just got to win.
You say we raped a girl
and right away,
we're sentenced and convicted.
You're not gonna
get away with it this time.
You say we're guilty of rape?
Well I say, we got a rape
coming to us.
Overruled.
Why? That's the way it is.
All right, just forget it.
Forget it? Hell, ask the jury!
The jury says...
-Yeah.
[SCREAMING]
[ALL CLAMORING]
[FABRIC TEARING]
[INDISTINCT CHATTER]
[WHISTLING]
My boys aren't too crazy
about playing cops.
Yeah. Well that's 'cause we're
still in kindergarten, man.
We've been offering to
let you guys join up with us.
What's the big deal? You won't
let us keep our colors.
Well, you can have a little
Skull patch on your butt
if you want.
Hey, wait a second.
Is that invite still open?
Any time.
Now's the time.
The town's all yours, babe.
[LAUGHS]
Let's make it.
Let's burn this town!
[BIKE ENGINE STARTING]
[WHOOPING]
[BIKE ENGINES ROARING]
[SCREAMING]
[BIKE ENGINE REVVING]
[YELLING]
Where's Hole-in-the-Wall,
anyway?
There's no such place.
What do you mean
there's no such place?
It doesn't exist.
I made it up.
You made it up?
Cody, you're the only one that
needs a Hole-in-the-Wall.
Just like you need Funky,
and you need Leroy,
and you need all of us
to pat you on the back.
Just like I need you?
Just like you need me!
[YELLING AND WHISTLING]
[GLASS SHATTERING]
[SCREAMING]
[LAUGHING]
[LAUGHTER]
Hey, Cody.
Come on, let's go.
Where're we going, Cody?
We're going to
Hole-in-the-Wall, you and me.
But I'm having a good time.
[WHISTLING]
[SCREAMING AND CHEERING]
[BIKE ENGINE STARTING]
[WHISTLING AND CHEERING]
[BIKE ENGINE RUMBLING]
[BIKE ENGINES RUMBLING]
[POLICE SIRENS WAILING]