Welcome to the premiere
of "Pacific".
We're about to see
Hollywood's hottest couple,
Diana Díaz, DiDi,
and Steve Richards.
I heard the applause
and I felt I had achieved
what I'd been fighting for.
Even though I was having
the hardest time of my life.
MADRID, 5 YEARS EARLIER
- See you tomorrow, girls.
- See you.
Mary, Trankimazin and booze
will blow you away.
I know, sweetie.
But I need to relax.
Go on, come with us.
You've had a weird time,
you need a good party.
Not weird, unbearable.
I'm sick of it.
I can't do this job anymore.
I'm leaving.
How? Where will you go?
Since I started doing this
I've stopped acting.
And that's my dream.
That's what I want,
not this shit.
I'm going to Miami.
Miami?
Do you think
the Yanks will accept you?
You're tired. Ask David for
a few days off and think it over.
I've made up my mind.
María!
What about me, Diana?
I need you.
Come with me.
Me?
I can't.
I can't leave David.
- Think it over.
- María!
He's stronger than me.
Are you coming, or what?
- See you tomorrow.
- Okay.
Here.
Not now.
When I tell you to do something,
you do it.
Got it?
Up!
You're mine.
You know that?
Damn it.
Mine.
María.
- Hello?
- Mom?
Diana? What time is it?
Are you okay?
- Did I wake you up?
- No, it's okay. What is it?
I'm leaving.
Can't you come here?
I can't end up a hairdresser
without having tried.
In the end, without knowing it,
I took the most important
decision of my life.
I moved to Miami.
I'd heard the Latin connection
worked well there
and that it was
full of opportunities,
and I was ready to find them
and go for them.
Towels aren't included.
The room's up there.
Thanks.
MARÍA, MIAMI IS GREAT,
YOU'D LOVE IT. THINKING OF YOU.
Diana Díaz.
I went to every casting in town,
until I ran out of money
and energy.
I felt empty.
VISITING AGENCIES ALL DAY.
RUNNING OUT OF CASH
I was lost and far from home.
In another world.
I was alone, truly alone.
Don't come back here
without money.
We don't want to see you again.
- Don't come back here.
- Okay, okay!
I've been to some castings,
one of them will take me.
And how are you?
I'm fine.
I made a cake, that one you like.
The biscuit and chocolate?
Yes, cookies and chocolate.
Are you all right?
Yes.
I was thinking about the cake
and how much
I'd like to be there.
Diana, something's wrong,
I can tell.
No, Mom, it's just a bad line.
I have to go, I'II call you later.
Take care, okay?
Call me again tomorrow.
I love you so much.
I love you too, Mom.
Bye.
Is something wrong?
Are you okay?
Yes.
I'm looking for work.
Your job is to mop.
Mop and mop,
and when you get done mopping,
mop some more.
There's always something dirty.
There's your mop.
With no papers, the pay isn't much,
but you'll survive.
So when do I start?
Now!
Let's go!
Let's get to work!
Wake up!
Let's move!
So it's settled then.
Pay me what you can
until you find a better job.
It's only small,
but we'll make room.
This is a sofa bed.
I didn't know
we could bring food home.
We can't, but I do it
when they're not looking.
It's the least we deserve
for that shitty pay.
Look, I've got chicken,
beans, rice...
I hide it in the bins
and then I bring it home.
- Are you hungry?
- Starving.
Then get stuck in.
- Are you hurt?
- I'm fine.
Apart from feeling like a fool.
I thought you were perfect.
I never saw anyone
fall over so well.
What's your name?
Diana.
I'm Robert. Nice to meet you.
You could teach me
how to fall some time.
We arrive on time here!
I'm taking those ten minutes
out of your pay.
- How was it?
- Awful.
They'll never take me.
But I met a cute guy.
Really? You tiger!
He's gonna call me.
Not only is she late,
now she's chatting!
You're here to work.
Everyone, get to work!
Have you've been here long?
About three months.
And you?
- Do you live here?
- No. I live in Los Angeles.
I'm an assistant,
but I really want to direct.
I always wanted to go
to Los Angeles.
Of course.
But most girls there
just want to bluff it,
do crappy roles
and get into Hello magazine.
They don't want to act,
they're happy doing perfume ads.
I don't know
if I should tell you this,
but I like you,
I want to help you.
I don't want to see you
in the Latin actress meat market.
They get invited to
all the producers' parties,
go with some gringo actor,
and will do anything
to avoid going back home.
They're victims of the agents,
producers and even themselves.
I don't want that for you.
Hey,
my friend Nora and I are going
to the beach later.
You want to come?
You bet.
If you make a film,
I could be your actress.
- You'll have to seduce me.
- What?
You'll have to seduce me!
I thought I already had.
Over here, girls!
I can't do it! I can't go!
Who's got the biggest?
Viva the Latina piss!
Bye, girls. See you tomorrow.
See you tomorrow.
Hey, take the rubbish out,
and we can go.
What have you got there?
Nothing.
Nothing, huh?
I know you steal food
from my uncle.
So let me feel your tits
or I'll tell him.
- Get off me!
- You like that, huh?
Let go!
Eat shit!
You horny Cuban bastard!
- I'll kill you!
- Easy, baby!
Let me go!
- Let go, you fucker!
- Back off, bitch!
What the fuck are you doing?
- He's a pervert.
- You two are sluts!
Come on, you scum!
Out! Both of you!
Get the fuck out!
Anything interesting?
Same as always.
Waitress in a hotel or a bar.
What are you smiling about?
Who's lit up you face?
It's Robert.
I like you.
I can't believe that
now I met you I have to go.
I don't want to leave you.
Then don't.
I told you, I always wanted
to go to Los Angeles.
Would you come with me?
I'VE MET AN AMAZING GUY.
I'M GOING TO LOS ANGELES.
I'M IN LOVE!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!
Girls, a bit more to the right.
That's it, smile!
Sir, can you step on it?
I want to get there!
What a lovely house.
This is yours, Nora.
When I arrived from Mexico,
there were five of us in here.
Then the landlord kicked them out.
- The bathroom's over there.
- Thanks.
And this is my room.
I've reserved a mansion
in Beverly Hills for you.
Really?
Where am I going to sleep?
I think you'll have to sleep with me.
Oh, yes?
I'll introduce you to everyone
I know in the movie business.
I want you to meet Aldo Vega.
Who's that?
A friend.
His series is massive right now.
Really?
I'd like to wake up with you
every day.
Me too.
GOOD MORNING, PRINCESS.
FOLLOW THE ARROWS
HAVE A WONDERFUL DAY!
GET DRESSED UP.
PARTY TONIGHT
AT THE ANAHEIM CENTER.
Diana?
How are you?
Great.
I'm at Robert's place.
It's really cool.
I'm crazy about him,
you'll have to meet him.
Yes.
He's incredible,
he made breakfast for me,
with croissants!
When are you coming?
You have to meet him.
- I'm sorry I can't be there.
- Me too.
And how are you?
Pissed off.
David is an asshole, he can't
keep his eyes off Susi's ass.
You should just dump him.
You know what? You're right,
I'm gonna ditch the bastard.
- Diana, I'll call you later!
- Okay, speak to you then.
María!
Look, that's Aldo Vega.
Come on, I'll introduce you.
Aldo!
Excuse me a moment, ladies.
I'm so glad you made it.
This is Diana.
- Hi, Diana.
- Hi.
Robert tells me you want to act.
Yes.
- You know what I love about cinema?
- What?
You can reach out from the screen
and touch people's hearts.
- You really want to act?
- Yes.
Perfect. You have an appointment.
- Can you play something lively?
- Of course, darling.
Hey, bro, play "La Prima".
Now you're talking!
You don't look Latina,
that will help you.
What?
You don't look Latina,
that will help you a lot.
I need to make a book.
Will you help me?
Sure, we'll get some photos,
I'll introduce you to everyone.
Really?
You'll be a great actress,
and I'll be a great director
with you as my muse.
- Your muse?
- Of course.
- What role will you give me?
- I see you...
being from Egypt.
- Like Cleopatra or something.
- Cleopatra!
Hello?
I GOT THE PART
I dreamed...
I dreamed it went wrong,
they were chasing us.
I dreamed it all...
I dreamed it went wrong,
they were chasing us.
Are you okay?
I hope I didn't make you look bad.
No, don't worry,
you'll be fine.
Deep breaths, relax,
you'll be fine, okay?
- Hello.
- How's it going?
I'm exhausted.
And you?
Really good.
I'm going to live with Joel.
His room-mate is leaving
and he can't afford the rent.
I'm going to miss you.
What's the matter?
Diana.
- Are you okay?
- Yes.
Yes, I'm just a bit tired.
No, you're not okay,
I won't let you leave like this.
Let's go to my place
and work on it.
No, no. I'm going home,
and anyway I look awful.
That's not true, you're beautiful.
I'll get changed and we'll go.
- A long day, huh?
- Yeah.
But this is your big shot
at being an actress.
You're not going to blow it,
are you?
I have to go.
I have to go!
It's okay, Diana, it's okay.
Robert is on his way home.
Aldo, don't.
Diana, it's okay. Diana...
Diana!
Don't leave.
Diana, come back here.
Diana!
Robert?
I'M SHOOTING UNTIL LATE.
DON'T WAIT UP.
I'll never let you leave.
I'm not afraid anymore.
Make your lips nice and soft,
open your mouth...
and then grab me.
I'll never let you leave.
I'm not afraid anymore.
Where are you going?
Come back here.
I thought you were shooting.
Where were you, Diana?
I called, they said
you left with Aldo, hours ago!
Did you screw him?
- Robert...
- No, don't tell me!
- Robert, it's not that.
- Then what is it?
- Robert, forgive me.
- Shut up!
It's over!
I have nothing to say to you!
I've been offered a shoot
in New York, and I'm taking it.
When I get back, I don't want
to see you here. Ever again!
What happened?
I screwed up, Nora.
Robert has left me.
Can I stay with you?
Come on in.
You know you can
stay here anytime.
- I'm sorry.
- It's all right.
How are you?
I screwed it all up, Nora.
I'm so stupid.
- I brought you some food.
- I'm not hungry.
Sit up.
Sit up!
You can't go on like this,
you've got to eat something.
Look at you,
you're just skin and bone.
I'm leaving.
Where to?
So far, I've had one shitty part
and I've ruined my life.
What did you expect?
A fairytale?
The poor Spanish girl
who arrives and conquers Hollywood?
Don't make me laugh.
Now is the time to be strong.
When was the last time
you got dressed?
You won't get anywhere
with this hair.
Go for it, Diana.
Go for it.
María?
I have an agent now.
It's so cool. I did it.
Now I need to get a manager,
and once I make some money,
a business manager.
It's complicated.
But I'll explain it to you.
I have to go to a party now.
Mary?
David is fucking Susi.
But he says
he can't live without me.
I can't go on like this.
Really, I can't.
Don't worry.
I'm sorry.
I'm really happy for you.
I miss you so much, Diana.
I could come and see you.
That's impossible right now.
I'm gonna be really busy.
Mary?
Okay, it doesn't matter.
Diana, we'll talk later, okay?
I don't feel well.
Okay. I'll call you. Bye.
Stop it!
María.
She's a little busy.
Hold on a second.
Diana, it's María.
Mary, how are you?
Looking forward to seeing you.
When are you coming over?
You promised you'd come after
your last shoot two months ago.
I know.
And next week I start a new film.
But, hey, are you okay?
Yeah. I'm doing good.
I've decided
I'm going to leave David.
He denies it,
but I know he's cheating on me.
It's for the best.
That guy's an asshole, Mary.
I mean it this time.
I'm going to quit
and find another job.
Great.
I can send you some money.
Thanks, Diana,
you're the greatest.
But it's okay, I'll find a way.
Hey, Mary, I love you.
Me too.
- Call me if you need to, okay?
- All right.
Who were you talking to?
- What do you care?
- I care.
What's got into you?
Come here, María.
Please.
María.
You're the one I like.
You're the only one.
You know?
You're a pig.
You're the only one I love.
You're such a pig.
I'll tell you about it later.
What are you doing here?
I came to see you.
They said I had to meet
Cosmo Harris.
I'm Cosmo Harris.
It's my gringo name.
I swear, since I changed it
I've got more work.
Look at you, you're beautiful,
you look great.
I hear you're doing really well.
Now it's you
that can help me out.
Have you seen the script?
I sent it to the agency
but I didn't hear anything.
I haven't read it yet.
A lot of the character,
I wrote thinking about you.
This is so weird.
I've imagined this moment
so many times.
What are you laughing at?
At how full of surprises life is.
Just look at yourself.
You look incredible.
You've got it all.
Everything you wanted.
As for me,
I got on with my life.
I got married.
And work is starting to go well.
And if you accept the script,
I'll be able to make my movie.
What is it?
Robert,
why did you come back?
Because I think you're
the best actress for my film.
Diana.
I'm sick of this.
I just want a normal, quiet life.
Diana.
How can you have a normal,
quiet life with all this?
Diana,
you have everything.
Everything.
Do you think eating sushi,
burning incense
and drinking green tea
will bring you peace and harmony?
That is not real life.
Diana,
where are you?
I can't reach you.
Nora,
not you too.
Don't fail me, please.
I won't fail you,
but someone has to tell you the truth.
- Did the transfer come through?
- Yes.
Oh, my love, what's the matter?
I hate to see you like this.
It breaks my heart.
I don't know.
I can't take any more.
Come home, sweetheart.
Come.
Come home, my love.
I can't, Mom.
I need to have you around.
Shall I come over there?
I'll come whenever you say,
just say the word.
Yes.
Don't cry, my love.
I'II come as soon as possible.
Diana Díaz, DiDi, is becoming
uncomfortable with her fame.
Hounded by paparazzi and rumoured
to have an eating disorder.
But she doesn't fit
the usual profile.
DiDi is the first Latin actress
who appeals to both audiences
and make up companies.
Now she just has to prove
she can act.
Her latest film, "Pacific",
opens this week,
in it she plays
one of her best roles.
- Mom, will you go in that car?
- Okay.
I'll see you later.
A kiss.
A lot of people say
you got where you are
because you go out with
Steve Richards.
People think they know me because
I'm in magazines and movies,
but they don't know anything
about my life.
Is it hard being away from home
and in a new country?
Diana has done well for herself.
Diana Díaz.
Yes, it is tough.
But I got my mom
to move out to Los Angeles.
María has arrived.
She's waiting.
As I was I saying,
my mom moved to L.A. And...
Diana can't wait to see you,
but her schedule is really full.
She's doing interviews.
But she asked me
to look after you.
So make yourselves at home.
There's a minibar in the lounge.
Help yourself.
Other actors and actresses say
that this profession
is very tough.
What has kept you fighting
to achieve your dreams?
You're at a fantastic time
in your life
where you can choose two paths,
you can be a star,
or you can be an actress.
Which path do you prefer?
Is it true that you fought
with the director
because you refused to do
certain hot scenes?
No, we didn't fight.
We just spoke about
how to film the sex scenes.
How much of the old Diana Díaz
is there in DiDi?
How do you see the old Diana now?
Have there been times
when you were alone
in your hotel or walking
around Hollywood
when you thought about
going back to Spain
and giving up
this whole adventure?
What about your image
as this ambitious woman?
I think you have to be ambitious
in life to get what you want.
But you know that being
a Spanish woman
who has succeeded in Hollywood
has made you enemies.
María, don't be like this.
I'll be however I want.
Have another drink.
Do you mind being well known
for your private life?
I just do my job,
but people only care about
what I wear or how I dress,
my hairstyle and who I date.
Does a European actress in America
use sex or intelligence to succeed?
What about the American obsession
with using actors initials?
In your case it's "D.D.",
another actress is called "P"...
She thinks she's a diva,
but do you know what?
I don't care anymore.
Because I don't need her anymore.
Not her or anybody.
Leave me alone.
María.
- María.
- Leave me alone.
David.
What were you expecting?
Didn't you want to fuck her too?
Yeah, she left,
so you fucked Susi!
Why don't you fuck Nacho too?
Go on, fuck Nacho!
You're a bastard!
You're a piece of shit!
- And now you're going to be alone!
- María!
Hello?
Diana?
They brought the Paco Rabanne.
You're going to love it.
Diana,
you have to get dressed
and made up.
Stein is on his way.
Look, sweetie, it's beautiful.
Oh, my love,
please don't be sad.
Mom.
Diana, Stein is in the lounge.
I'll go talk to him.
Wait here for me.
Let me be alone with him.
Is it true you went to hospital
for anorexia?
Are you and Steve Richards
going to break up?
DiDi, just one question,
is it true about you
and Steve Richards?
How do you feel about the film, DiDi?
Translation: Daniel Robert Murray
Subtitles: LASERFILM