Children alone
view the world with amazement,
adults alone
view children with amazement.
REPORTED MISSING
Hello.
Insert your hands,
One.
Please turn around.
Position your hands.
One.
Thank you.
No contamination.
Please walk through.
Want a ride?
What?
- Want to come along?
Okay.
- Get in.
Where are you going?
- Down this way.
Can you let me out up there?
- The town's ten kilometres away.
But I want to get out here.
It'll be dark soon...
- Would you let me out?
Fine.
Bye.
Hello.
- Hello.
How are you?
- Well.
Yes?
What, you?
She's not with me, no.
Why should she be?
One moment.
Excuse me.
She doesn't know me at all.
Oh please!
She was six.
She doesn't even have my address.
It's not my business any more.
You wanted Martha for yourself,
so cope with this on your own.
Who was that?
Sylvia.
What did she want?
HEY, what's up?
I don't know,
a friend of hers...
you know,
didn't come back from holiday.
So why's she calling you?
- Don't ask me.
Why do you gel so mad?
- She still drives me crazy.
Excluded the examination
of individual units
that might easily
have been disruptive.
The same is true of alert provisions.
The testing procedure protocol
complements the test protocol...
with its analogous...
readings...
The testing procedure protocol
also furnishes indices.
The reactors were tested
for system alert functions,
which...
Papa.
Did I wake you?
Is it Monday again?
No. I was just in the area.
Is Mama all right?
Why doesn't she visit?
Go back to sleep.
I didn't want to wake you.
For the activation
of electric subsystems
regardless of lock-down conditions
and unit alert signals...
Hello?
Oh, it's you.
- I forgot my key.
Were you expecting someone else?
I did some shopping.
Shall I cook?
Great.
Here.
One like this.
And a pair of jeans.
She's about this tall.
Hair this long.
Her figure is a bit like mine.
Hands like yours.
What are her interests?
Sport clubs? A music group?
She rides occasionally.
Did you call the stables?
- Yes. Of course.
A diary?
They write online.
Blogs and so on.
Did you check the computer?
I don't have the passwords.
Thanks.
You've been so weird recently.
Really?
- Well...
Is something up at work?
- No.
Or is it because Sylvia called again?
She didn't call again.
- She'd called about a friend.
That got cleared up.
You said she didn't call again.
She didn't.
She sent a text message.
There is no friend, right?
Tell me what's up.
I have a daughter.
With Sylvia.
What?
She's thirteen.
I wanted to put it all behind me.
To finish with it. For us, too.
For us?
Yes. I...
I wanted to start over.
Why...
Why what?
Didn't you ask yourself
if I'd have been glad
about this daughter?
Vera,
you don't know Sylvia.
Why are you telling me this now?
Because she's vanished.
Julia!
Do you have a moment?
This is Mr Meinert, Martha's father.
Hello.
You...
are a friend of Martha's?
I'll leave you alone.
If you need me,
I'll be in the staff room.
Thanks.
Did Martha give any hint
of where she's gone to?
No.
Do you have any idea
where she might be?
Nope.
It'd be a relief to us
to know she's well.
If she went away voluntarily.
We want nothing from her.
You understand?
Who is "we"?
Her mother and I.
I thought
you didn't talk to each other.
We do, now.
Now that Martha's gone?
- Yes.
Was that it?
Yes.
Thanks.
Well?
Did you know a schoolmate of Martha's
is missing, too?
A boy from an asocial family.
The parents said nothing
till the school asked
where the boy is.
So that's fine, then?
And did you speak to that Julia?
Yes, of course.
- And did you find it normal?
What do you mean, normal?
She doesn't give a shit
that her best friend disappeared.
And how would you know that?
It leaves her cold as ice.
I took this one for the poster.
Did you see it?
There aren't many recent ones.
She's camera-shy.
Here. Bornholm.
She was so small.
If I'd taken more care of her...
You couldn't have followed her around.
She wouldn't have just left.
She would have said something.
Maybe she's long dead now.
You think it's normal
that children just vanish?
It's not as unusual
as you might think.
Oh, no?
90 percent of all missing people
are teenagers.
80 percent of them turn up in the end.
What about the other 20 percent?
I understand your concerns.
I'm a father myself.
You have my telephone number.
Good bye.
- Good bye.
2005 friends!
How can that be?
She doesn't know them all.
What does it mean, Martha
is a member of the?ying rats group"?
That she's a member.
Can you click for more info?
There's nothing going on.
What does the rat mean?
Nothing. it's just a logo.
What kind of group is it?
We make dates and have parties.
What kind of parties?
We post bottles of beer.
Not real beer, of course.
You realise Martha's vanished,
that she might be dead?
You're the one asking the questions.
MISSING
MARTHA MEINERT
Hello?
- My name is Meinert, I...
I'm the father of a girl
at your son's school.
I'd like to talk to you.
My daughter recently vanished...
- Don't bother me.
Hello?
Yes?
My name's Meinert,
I'd like to talk to you.
My daughter has also vanished.
Like your son.
I share your troubles.
I only want to talk to you!
Do you have news from your son?
Anything?
I only want to exchange information,
that's all.
That must be possible.
That must be possible!
Hey, a new cell phone...
Listen to what it says here:
"The number of missing teenagers
has risen recently.
In comparison to recent years,
the number has risen
by a clear margin.
Police Inspector Heine claims
it is due to the time of year...
It's in the miscellaneous news.
Well, what do you say?
Don't they have school?
Do they always meet there?
- I've no idea.
I gave one of them a ride, recently.
Strange coincidence, isn't it?
Did you see the picture with the rat?
What rat?
A rat with wings.
I don't know, Lothar.
What am I to do about them?
I've no time for other children now.
I think you don't want to know
what's happened.
Because I don't watch teenagers
out the window?
Why did you call me, then?
I thought Martha maybe at yours.
I thought she can't stand me.
Says who?
- You did, if I'm not mistaken.
That's seven years ago.
Exactly. Seven years,
during which I never saw Martha.
Because you just left.
Because you wouldn't let me see her.
- Rubbish.
You never took responsibility.
You still think
the world turns around you.
Now Martha's vanished and what counts
are your feelings.
You're disgusting.
Hey!
- What the hell!
What are you doing out at this time?
- Let go of me.
Get in!
What was that?
- A stone, I think.
Where have you been? It's 10:20!
Good evening.
Is something wrong?
- Your daughter missed the bus.
I drove her home.
What bus?
- Evening.
What's wrong with your bike?
It's got a flat.
You can't come and go at will.
We had an agreement.
I'm off to bed.
I start early tomorrow.
Say thanks at least.
- Thanks.
Any time.
Won't you come in?
I have to go home.
Take good care of her.
What are you doing there?
Did I wake you?
No. I need the loo.
What are you doing there?
They smashed my window.
Hello.
Oh, it's you.
- Is your daughter there?
No. She's still at school.
Would you call there?
Why should I?
Because I don't think she's there.
I don't know what I make of you.
Do you know your daughter
wanders the country during the day?
I think that's none of your business.
No one asked you to keep coming here.
Leave us in peace.
Hey! Stop there!
Hello.
- Hello.
A coffee, please.
Was that a break-in?
The second this week.
Oh yes?
Two girls.
They broke the window,
got in, and off they went.
Did you see the girls?
It wasn't my shift.
They were 13, 14, I hear.
That's all.
What did they steal?
Petty stuff.
Food, crisps, the like.
Oh, crap.
What?
- Can we come in?
- Can we?
Yes.
Hi.
- Hi.
Hello.
One of you can sit in the front.
What brought you here?
We got caught in the rain.
I see that.
Want some?
Yes.
Okay?
It's all right.
And what are you doing here?
- Me?
Yes.
I got caught up in the rain, too.
I'm travelling for work.
I'm an engineer.
For reactor safety.
Atomic reactors?
- Yes.
I check the power stations.
And the waste
just goes on the dump?
The dump?
It's buried
in radiation-proof containers.
You don't believe that yourself.
I'm no promoter of atomic energy.
I just check the security.
Everything okay?
Safety's brainwashing, too.
People like
their standards of living.
This requires energy.
And the population is large.
There are other solutions.
Yes? Like what?
Like killing everyone over sixty.
Isn't that a bit drastic?
Why?
And does that go for your parents?
Sure.
Then my time would be up
in a few years.
Hello! Hello! Hey!
Did you see three teenagers?
Two boys and a girl?
Yes. Right.
- It was a while back.
Where did they go?
- That way.
Martha!
Want to ride along?
Sorry?
- Can I give you a ride?
I've no money.
- It's okay.
Spicy?
Yes, please.
GO AND FETCH
YOUR CHILDREN HOME
Here you are.
Thanks.
I've no money.
Give it back if you can't pay.
I'll bring you the money.
I just have to go to the bank.
Give it back. Hey! Stop there!
What are you doing here?
What?
- What are you doing here?
The door was open.
No reason to snoop around.
Is today the weekend?
No, it is not.
Hello?
Can I have my laundry done?
Yes, please.
Thanks.
What brought you here?
Chance.
I'm looking for someone.
We all are.
I'm looking for my child.
He was among a group that they
found in the woods.
I was so glad when the call came.
Now they won't let him go.
Why not?
They're afraid
they'll all run off again
as soon as they're brought back.
They don't...
have the situation under control.
Someone told me they're lodging
children in a refugee home.
There are too many of them.
If you get your son back,
what will you do?
We'll drive home.
And if he runs away again?
I don't know.
Maybe we have to just let them be.
Would you like to dance?
Sorry?
- Will you dance?
I haven't danced in years.
Nor have I.
Come along.
Have you seen a boy?
What?
- A boy.
I don't think so.
- It's your duty to say so if you have.
But I've seen no one.
Can I see your ID?
Of course.
Is anything wrong?
It's routine.
Do you know
you've been reported missing?
Excuse me?
- Your wife filed it.
Vera Meinert.
My God!
We have to inform her
you're no longer considered missing.
Shall we tell her where you are?
No.
What is the reason for your stay here?
Private reasons. I'm taking time out.
Hey, get off me.
I've done nothing. Let me go.
Ease up now.
- Stay where you are.
Loosen your grip.
All right?
What do you want from my daughter?
Hold you to stick by me.
Hungry?
Where are you all going to?
Do you have a place to stay?
The majority of these children
comes from proper families.
What are your plans?
Vigilante groups are springing up
in some areas
to protect the citizens
from theft and other...
Are you opening a kindergarten?
- No, not yet.
Do you have a leader?
Did someone order you to come here?
Which is the promised land, then,
Mr Glasner?
We don '1 know
what these young people are planning.
They are 16 and less,
they're growing steadily younger.
Anything else?
- They are parasites.
No, thanks.
- Then here's the bill.
18.20, please.
We are being confronted
with a new form of migration.
Is "migration" even the word for it?
My daughter lives in the house
you hang around in front of.
You might know her.
Her name's Martha.
Martha Meinert.
You must know her.
You were standing outside her house.
Whose house?
- My daughter Martha's.
I don't think so.
She's around 1.60,
mid-length brown hair,
thin.
She goes to Silberkamp School.
Hello.
I wanted to ask if everything's okay.
Yes, everything's fine, thanks.
You found your daughter.
- No, not yet.
Who is that?
- A friend of my daughter's.
What do you mean?
We happened to cross paths.
What's wrong with you?
Who's that girl in your room?
Lou, wake up.
- What's up?
We have to go.
Do something.
Call the police.
Who is the girl?
I don't know.
- What age?
Eleven, twelve. I don't know.
Short, dark hair.
Why did you run away?
I didn't like it anymore.
You treat life
as if it were inexpendable.
Better than being expended yourself.
Wait.
Here.
Where did you get that?
From the supermarket.
Want some?
What's it like to get old?
I'm not actually that old.
No. But...
you're older, anyway.
What's there to say?
It just happens.
I don't want to get old.
Recognise any of them?
Not so far, no.
The militia!
What are you doing here?
What business is that of yours?
Who are you?
We have police powers.
Your papers, please.
Show me yours, first.
And those from the police.
Take your hands off my daughter.
Let go of me.
Everything okay?
We need a doctor. Call a doctor.
Stay quiet. Don't talk.
We'll call an ambulance
and drive you to hospital.
I want...
I still want to...
Yes, you will. You'll do so.
Why won't you call an ambulance?
Cut the old folk's balls off,
balls off, balls off...
Cut the old folk's balls off!
Dead! Dead! Dead!
Lou, please. I'm sorry.
Please don't...
for my parents and my daughter Cléo
BABELFISCH TRANSLATIONS