Come on!
I'm ready!
Chocomon?
Chocomon!
There we go.
Oh, Daisuke-kun's going to rage when he sees these pictures.
Pretty much.
Hikari, what's wrong?
Hikari-chan?
I can feel a crying digimon.
It's crying and looking for someone.
What the?
Yamato, you're early.
Chocomon.
Gummymon!
Was Mimi-san taken to the Digital World?
No, it didn't seem like it.
It must be some other world.
I'm interested in that crying digimon you said you felt.
I felt a crying digimon right before Mimi-san disappeared.
It felt very sad.
It's close by.
Chocomon, don't!
A digimon.
Hikari-chan, is this digimon?
It's the crying digimon.
Chocomon, it's me, Wallace.
It's gone.
Hey, you!
Onii-chan!
I just heard his voice.
Taichi-san? Maybe that guy knows something about it!
Takeru, I'll follow him.
Hikari-chan...
Something is... awakening.
Where are we?
It's too dark to see.
I can't think straight.
And it's so cold.
How did we and up here?
How are we getting out?
I don't know.
Takeru, be careful.
Hikari, be careful.
Mom's shopping?
Will you tell her that I'm going to Summer Memory?
No, Summer Memory.
It's OK, I'm gonna call you back again.
OK, I'm gonna call you back. Bye.
Summer Memory...
It's from Hikari-chan!
Daisuke, what's up?
Anything wrong, Daisuke?
Please save my brother.
What's that supposed to mean?
Not only Taichi-san, Yamato-san and Koushiro-san are gone as well.
Anyway, Hikari-chan's counting on me.
How can I refuse?
Miyako-san, you even thought about how to get us there?
Yup.
I don't think anyone will stop if you say we've got monsters with us.
Those are great monsters.
He said these are great toys.
Really?
This guy is weird!
Japanese cars are really great!
He says the car's great as well.
I wish he'd drive better though!
Please keep your eyes on the road!
Made in Japan is really great!
If you say so.
Wallace, I'm tired.
Are we going to that flower field?
Hey, Wallace!
What's with you?
Right back at you.
That might not have been Chocomon, but why did you attack him?
He was serious.
He was seriously trying to attack you.
I could feel it.
So I had to protect you.
Maybe we could have reasoned with him, you didn't have to attack.
But he's no longer who he was.
I don't want to hear that.
OK, I won't say it again.
Your mother must be worried sick by now.
I'll call her later.
It's hot... It's hot... It's hot...
Will you shut up and walk?
It's hot!
We shouldn't have gotten off the train.
Although you do have to call your mom.
It doesn't matter.
Hey, if that really was Chocomon, he'll be at the flower field too, right?
If he is, what should I tell him?
Chocomon didn't like the heat.
Wallace!
What are you doing?
I'll be your hat from now on.
You're heavy.
Don't worry about it.
Daisuke-kun said they're getting on a plane now.
The plane's called Denver Bird.
My D-3!
They're gone!
Everyone on the train is gone.
Goodbye, Mr. Denver!
Thank you!
Where are we?
We're about 500km from Denver.
The hell?
Well, we did get here really fast.
Jeez, when will I get to see Hikari-chan?!
Hikari-chan, wait for me!
You stopped the truck.
That's the power of love!
Oh.
Guess they didn't stop for us.
I'll ask them to let us on too.
They said we can get in too.
Get on!
Let's go.
Up you go.
You guys get on too.
Hello.
What are you doing?
Sorry, it's my cat.
Daisuke, it's a digimon!
Then you're...
The boy Takeru-san was talking about.
I didn't know Japan had digimon too.
Wow, look at my new friends!
He's pretty friendly.
Don't let your guard down.
You can speak Japanese.
I had a Japanese girlfriend.
Wallace did his best to learn Japanese.
Then it wasn't you guys who took Taichi-san and the others to another world.
Call me Wallace.
Your name is Miyako, right?
I like your long hair.
Don't be getting to chummy.
It's good manners to compliment girls.
What's with this guy?!
Wallace-san, where did you meet Gummymon?
An egg came out of my mom's computer one day.
She's always surfing the Internet.
Have you ever been to the Digital World?
Digital World? What's that?
It's...
You look great even when worried, Miyako.
What are you even thinking?!
Wallace-san, do you know anything about that other digimon?
I've always known that he was taking children that had a digimon away.
So you do know something!
You'd better spill it right now!
We found a car!
I have to hurry ahead.
So do we, to save Taichi-san and the others.
Daisuke, you can tell that story in the car.
Hurry up!
And why are you hitch-hiking here anyway?
Weren't you going to Summer Memory?
That's because we got off the train to call Wallace's mom.
Gummymon...
Your mom? Did you hear that?
Daisuke, we'll be waiting at Summer Memory!
Hurry up and get there!
Wallace, we could make it if we run.
Yeah, but I'd feel sorry for Daisuke-kun.
Damn it, I'm never gonna see Hikari-chan!
Guys!
Taichi?!
You got younger.
Taichi-san, how old are you now?
Wallace, we're going the wrong way.
No, that's not what I mean! Listen to me!
Hey, Wallace!
Wallace doesn't listen to a thing I say, but he's really clumsy.
Daisuke is way clumsier.
So he's just like Wallace.
Mom, don't worry.
If you don't stop worrying you're gonna lose weight.
Hurry up, we have to catch up to the others.
Wallace's mom is this big!
That's the opposite of thin.
I'm not running away!
I just wanted to take a manly trip.
Yeah, "manly", yelling "mom" all the time.
Shut up!
No, not you.
I'm hanging up.
Wallace's mom is scary.
That's trouble.
You're such a blabbermouth.
So are you.
You're pathetic.
I guess the Japanese don't care about their parents so much.
What?
What's this?
Daisuke!
Chocomon...
That's the digimon that appeared in New York.
Chibimon evolves to...
V-Mon!
Go, V-Mon!
Digimental up!
V-Mon armor evolves to...
Flaydramon, the fire of courage!
Go, Flaydramon!
Knuckle Fire!
What's going on?
It's mad.
I did feel anger just now.
But whose?
Hey, what did you do with Taichi-san and the others?!
Flaydramon, don't give up!
Stop!
Chocomon, stop.
Wallace, be careful.
Where did you take the Japanese children?
Why are you doing this?
It's no use.
He's not the Chocomon you remember.
Chocomon, do you remember me?
I'm Wallace.
Wallace.. Wa... No...
You're not Wallace.
Where is Wallace?!
Chocomon, don't you recognize me?
Chocomon?
Wallace...
You evolved.
Stop!
Chocomon...
Chocomon, I'll be waiting at that flower field.
I'll be waiting for you!
Will he wait for me?
And it changed again.
Huh?
A blue sky?
It feels like summer.
Yeah, the sun's shining and everything.
What's going on?
I think this might be inside someone's heart.
Why did you stop us?
And why did you tell that monster where you're going?
None of your business.
You said his name is Chocomon?
I don't have time for your questions.
I'm going on ahead.
Daisuke!
What are you two doing?
That looks like fun! Let me ride!
Gummymon, be careful.
Don't worry, Wallace!
You be careful.
Let me ride!
I can't... see...
Well, I warned you.
Next time be specific.
I'm back to Chibimon.
Wallace, you're never straight.
Shut up, Gummymon!
And are you OK?
Yeah.
Well, I'm not.
Japanese children are so sturdy.
So you can evolve like that too, Gummymon.
Back to hitch-hiking! We need to find a car!
Wallace!
I don't think a car's going to come, since the road was destroyed.
I wish you were smaller.
I could fly away with you.
Why are you going to Summer Memory?
What's over there?
Wow, this is easy!
Sorry for crashing you.
Don't mention it.
You said you would meet him at a flower field.
What did you mean?
I'm sorry, V-Mon.
I'm fine.
That digimon, Chocomon, do you know something about him?
Chocomon is...
Gummymon.
Wallace, Chocomon is turning the captured children back the way they were.
What do you mean?
He wants to make them younger.
How do you know this?
Because I'm...
Anyway, we have to get to Summer Memory.
Daisuke, leave it to me!
Digimental up!
V-Mon armor evolves to...
Lighdramon, the roar of friendship!
OK, get on!
Awesome!
This is different from before.
This is great!
Lighdramon, you're amazing!
Which way is Summer Memory?
Don't be shy.
Yeah but...
But what?
Everyone's watching.
Your digimon's great, it has many evolutions.
Well, yeah.
Hikari-chan, I'm coming!
Still not here?
Nope.
Wait...
What is it?
Daisuke-san!
Finally!
Sorry we're late!
This place is so rural.
Unlike New York.
Wallace, you're not very honest.
Why isn't Hikari-chan here?!
You're just as noisy as always.
She sent us an e-mail.
Chocomon appeared on the train.
Because of that the train stopped and they're taking a bus here.
Why?
That's not all.
Everyone on the train disappeared.
All the people?
Wallace-san, please tell us.
What kind of digimon is Chocomon?
I think it's about time you told us.
Where were Taichi-san and the others taken?
Wallace, it hurts...
Are you OK, Chocomon?
Chocomon?
Hey!
He's probably looking for Wallace, and taking people with a Digivice.
He wants to see Wallace.
But he wants to see the young Wallace.
So that's why he kidnapped everyone.
Just tell us already!
How are you connected to that digimon?
I have to get to that flower field.
If I do, I'm sure Chocomon will go back to how he was.
Wallace...
Where are we going?
Let's play!
OK, let's get going!
Hitch-hiking again.
Well, Hikari-chan and Takeru-kun had money, we don't.
Hey, weren't we supposed to do something?
Yeah.
Hey Wallace, is it OK if I call my mom?
If you can find a pay phone.
Wallace, aren't you sleepy?
I'm so... tired...
Hold it.
Going alone?
You know, I've been thinking.
Is Chocomon your digimon?
I'm right, aren't I?
Chocomon was born out of the same egg as Gummymon.
They're twin digimon.
Digimon twins?
I was shocked when two digimon that looked alike came out.
It was hard to keep it from Mom.
Seven years ago, we were playing in a flower field.
Chocomon suddenly disappeared.
Seven years ago?
That's about the time Taichi-san and the others witnessed their first digimon.
The timing fits.
So that's when it happened.
I couldn't stop thinking about Chocomon.
Even after I moved to New York.
We got along so well.
Why did Chocomon turn into that thing?
I hated myself for not saving him.
So we were fighting against your digimon?
Against your precious friend?!
There's no way that was easy for you.
I could never do that.
If V-Mon was ever to become something else, even something terrible, I'd...
I'd never be able to kill him.
Daisuke...
But we have to kill him, to save Taichi-san and the others.
What's the right thing to do now?
This isn't something you should cry over.
But...
If we were to meet... meet again in that flower field...
Chocomon might turn back to normal.
Yeah.
You're right, he will.
And then we wouldn't need to fight him, and we could save your friends.
Yeah, there'd be no need to fight.
Why the heck am I comforting you?
Yeah, that's just what's going to happen.
I can just feel it.
You're such a simpleton.
I'm just easy to understand.
And you're OK with that?
Weren't you praising me?
I was not.
So don't try to go alone, OK?
He's right.
I'm coming too, Wallace.
Gummymon.
I can't let you go alone.
But you loved him so much.
I can't let you two fight!
Wallace.
You know I'm right.
I'll be fine.
I want to come with you.
What will you do?
Let's go back.
I want to see Miyako's sleeping face.
You can look at my sleeping face!
If we don't go back, you might catch a cold.
Wallace!
Who's that?
Wallace! Wallace!
Wallace!
Wallace?
Wallace! Wallace!
Who are you?
They're not right. They're smaller, but they're wrong.
They're wrong! They're all wrong!
Chocomon!
W-Wallace...
Wallace!
Chocomon, do you know who I am?
W... Wa... Wallace...
Let's play together, like before.
Together?
Yes!
Then, let's go home...
Back then...
Isn't that why you came here?
It's cold. There's nobody here.
Chocomon, don't do that.
Out of my way!
Chocomon, how could you hurt Gummymon?!
I want to go back! I want to go back!
I'm sorry, Chocomon, those times are gone.
We have to start from here.
Come here!
Come over here!
But I...
...can't go.
No!
Wallace...
Daisuke...
Can you beat him, Daisuke?
Will you help me do it?
V-Mon... let's go!
Digimental up!
V-Mon, armor evolves to...
Flaydramon, the fire of courage!
Let's go, Armadimon!
Digimental up!
Armadimon, armor evolves to...
Digmon, the steel of wisdom!
Let's do it, Hawkmon!
Digimental up!
Hawkmon, armor evolves to...
Holsmon, the wings of love!
Hey, isn't Chocomon just playing with us?
Playtime is over, Mr.Bunny.
Well said, Flaydramon!
You are very strong, but we won't lose!
I'm still here!
They're all so cool!
Though Digmon's line was a little too plain.
He's just like you.
He ran away?
That can't be!
Is that Chocomon?
Is he trying to change the world?
What a cold world.
It feels like my very heart is frozen.
Were we taken somewhere else?
This isn't our world, it's...
Black snow?
It seems like it's flowing out of his broken heart.
It might seem pretty, but it's proof that his heart is frozen.
Who...
Who are you?
I'm back to rookie!
This is it!
I can't evolve to Flaydramon!
What are you trying to do?
Stop.
You'll pay!
Stop... Please stop!
Gummymon!
Wallace, be careful.
Look out!
Ever since you went away...
...I was always thinking...
...I have to protect Wallace by myself!
Gummymon!
So I have to...
I will protect him!
I know what you mean, Gummymon.
V-Mon!
Hawkmon!
We all want...
...to protect those we love.
Hawkmon, stay with me!
Miyako-san, I can't breathe.
Armadimon!
I will protect you!
I understand.
Daisuke was right, I am naive.
But, Chocomon is not part of you.
No, you took Chocomon.
He's lonely, but he's trying his best.
And you've locked him away somewhere.
If I fight, and defeat you...
...I'll be able to take Chocomon back
I want to fight too!
I want the power.
Wallace, that's why I'm here.
I will be your power.
Gummymon!
Wallace.
You're not naive.
You've traveled so far, searching for Chocomon.
And you're just a kid.
We all have something we want to protect.
No matter how weak we are...
...we will fight to protect.
We will never stop trying!
You got him!
Daisuke-kun!
Takeru-san!
Hikari-chan!
No, you're not the one!
You're not the digimon that was crying!
Holy Arrow!
It's not over, is it?
But where are we?
Is this the Digital World?
It's cold.
Is this where Chocomon was?
All alone?
No.
This is still our world.
The world was modified, for that digimon's sake.
You're back to Upamon.
You're out of power.
I can't feel anything from that digimon.
Wallace, we're in big trouble!
Daisuke, what do we do about this?
Wallace, I'll protect you!
For Chocomon as well!
Poromon, you've done more than enough!
What are you doing?
We're not afraid of you, so come on!
Daisuke!
Daisuke, you've shrunk!
Wallace, what happened to you?
I'm a kid again!
Me too...
This is bad!
If this keeps up, we'll disappear.
Takeru, we need to evolve to Ultimate.
Hikari, evolve me to Ultimate!
I'm sure that will bring about some sort of solution.
Combine light and hope!
Alright!
Let's do it!
Angemon, warp evolves to...
Seraphimon!
Angewomon evolves to...
Holydramon!
This is Angemon's...
Angewomon's...
Ultimate level?
These are your Digimentals!
The digimentals of miracles!
Ours?
Our...
Wallace! Digimental up!
Digimental up!
Did we get him?
I don't know.
We did it!
His heart is so black.
It's too dark, I can't see.
I can't feel anything.
I must protect Wallace.
Who is... Wallace?
Chocomon, Gummymon...
Where are you?
I must go!
No, you can't go like this!
V-Mon, hold on, I'm coming!
Gummymon, I've always made you worry, haven't I?
I can hear someone's voice.
It sounds so familiar...
Daisuke...
Wallace...
I haven't given up yet.
Just like I always believed I'd find Hikari, I'll never give up.
You've always done your best.
I've never doubted you, even for a second.
And I never will.
Chocomon! Gummymon!
V-Mon!
Daisuke!
Wallace!
Gummymon, are you sure?
Yes, please, V-Mon.
V-Mon!
Chocomon?
It's you, isn't it?
Wallace!
Chocomon always cried a lot.
But now, he was smiling.
Gummymon!
One day...
One day, Chocomon will come back to you guys.
Taichi-san and the others are back safely.
I'll come visit you in Japan someday.
Yeah!
But for now, I guess I'll keep traveling for a while.
That's for goodbye!
Hey, what the hell are you doing?!
I'm guessing someone's jealous.
Indeed.
I wonder if he'll really visit?
He's not getting near Hikari-chan!
Mom, I'm going to come home very soon.
No, I'm not saying I hate it at home.
I miss you so much.
Mom, you know that I love you.
You spend a lot of time on the phone.