DISTANT THUNDER
- Will he sell us some?
- Yes!
What is it?
What do you want?
Give me a good price
for the tomatoes.
They look tasty.
Smell good too.
Come in.
Let's go.
So stuffy!
They're like red bulbs!
Don't touch them!
You might ruin them.
This is farmer's hard work.
The tomatoes in the
supermarkets are rotten.
They're red because
they're rotten.
Look closely.
Ours are red too,
but the glimmer is different.
Everybody knows that,
so they sent us to have a look.
- They said you're scary.
- Yes!
We're the special squad!
This is not a tourist farm!
We came to greet you
as neighbours!
What neighbours?
I'll sell you some.
You have containers?
Give us 300 yen of them,
we'll try those first.
Produced by
Hiromi Higuchi
Hiroshi Okada, Shiro Sasaki
Based on the Novel by
Wahei Tatematsu
Screenplay by
Haruhiko Arai
Starring
Toshiyuki Nagashima
Eri Ishida
Johnny Ogura, Rie Yokohama
Sen Hara, Reiko Nanao
Akemi Negishi
Eri Kanuma, Reo Morimoto
Jun Eto, Keizo Kanie
Yumiko Fujita, Casey Takamine
Photographed by
Shohei Ando
Music by
Takuyuki Inoue
Directed by
Kichitaro Negishi
Mitsuo.
I'm hungry. Let me through.
Koji's here.
Koji! Mitsuo's here.
Delivery?
I grew them well.
I'm so busy!
Lunch!
Good timing. Eat with me.
Mrs. Wada, you coming?
The director called me.
He said he wants to talk.
Let's go, Mitsuo.
Mitsuo.
Mr. Hanamura,
my second son Mitsuo.
Welcome.
You are here!
Please wait.
I'm hungry. Menu please.
Curry rice. Coffee.
- The same for me.
- Yes!
Hey. You know her?
She came to the greenhouse,
and bought tomatoes.
We sell liquor at night.
Come for a drink next time.
Will I see your kids
and husband?
Sorry, I'm not married.
Just me and my friend.
We run this together.
We work shifts.
And look after
each other's kids.
Here you are.
Come help me at the
greenhouse some time.
One day?
OK. Next time, you come
to my field and help me.
Hey. Will you really
come to have a drink?
What's up?
You haven't paid.
Sorry.
Murder?
Childbirth?
Happens all the time.
It's like a bomb!
Makes me die sooner!
Doesn't matter.
I'm old anyway.
Granny.
"Apartment women"
have an easy life.
I can't believe it.
You can call an ambulance
when you give birth.
Bothering the Fire Dept.!
"In heaven,
where the sun rises...
I helped hundreds
of people give birth.
When I gave birth
to your father,
no one helped me.
I was weeding and
I felt unwell.
I got home but fainted
in the kitchen.
The moment I fainted,
the baby came out smoothly.
Once I gave birth smoothly
while sleeping with a crying baby.
Smoothly?
I'll make you...
You done eating?
But I went out
and bought something...
A farmer buying vegetables!
Granny.
Switch it off if you
aren't watching.
Stop behaving like
a mad woman!
What's on your mind!
Mitsuo. You have a girl?
What? I was shocked.
Do you have a girl or not?
Don't keep it a secret.
No, I don't.
OK. OK.
I've got someone for you.
Interested?
Mr. Hanamura's daughter.
She went to the same school as you,
she now works at a gas station.
3 years younger than you.
She knows you're hardworking.
How about that?
Think about it.
Let's meet her.
But it won't work out.
Her father...
It won't be easy.
You're right but...
I'll meet her.
You're back.
Koji is here.
- Thanks for coming.
- Good it's raining.
We were just saying,
Koji is much slower than you.
Doing young people's
work makes me younger.
Corny.
You're popular with men.
I've known you for 20 years.
Didn't know you were so popular.
Save that dirty chat
for the construction site.
I won't behave like dad.
I'll go on a blind date.
With your looks,
you'll be turned down.
Apartment women
don't like your type.
- Jerk!
- Let go!
Energetic young men.
If I don't like her,
introduce her to Koji.
Lots of hair wax.
Must be "Regent".
My hair's not dry yet.
Guys. Wanna play?
Just drinking.
We got girls to drink with you.
Beer. All you can drink.
5,000 yen.
4,000 for two of us.
- Stingy.
- No.
OK.
Let's go drink.
Midori, go to table 321.
Ai, calling Ai.
Sorry.
I waited so long.
Too busy. Not enough girls.
Sorry. I'll be back.
No way. Not here.
Want an extension?
I'd extend.
I want to touch some more.
Welcome.
What would you like?
Beer.
Is Chee here?
That's me.
How's my father?
Oh you...
You're his...
You're here to take him home?
I'll call him down?
If I see him,
I may punch him.
I'm knitting a sweater for him.
The sweater of love.
It's getting hotter.
He'll wear it this winter.
Bye.
Don't. It's your dad's shop.
Help yourself.
He sure helped himself.
The glasses, the fridge,
the phone, the chairs,
key money for this place.
The land he sold
pays for all that.
He has it easy!
Welcome.
So glad you're here.
Sorry it's like a cesspit here.
The construction of
the assembly hall is finished.
Lots of workers just came.
They were so noisy.
Your friend came too,
but he already left.
Koji was here?
- That's his name?
- Yes.
Thanks a lot.
On the house.
Thanks.
I'll have a bottle.
I got rich!
TOMATO MAN
It's like a pumpkin.
Let's drink.
Can I have some?
I'll have it straight.
Are you really single?
Divorced.
I'm free, but it's
tough making a living.
How old are you?
23.
Good. You can do
anything you like.
You have the energy
to do anything.
The prime of manhood.
Can't do anything.
And nothing to do.
How old do I look?
25.
Your greenhouse looks great.
Very nice whisky.
I drank something special.
I want to eat tomatoes.
Let's go pick some.
You want to?
Anywhere to lie down?
That feels good.
Super...
Super!
Come on my stomach.
Don't come in me.
I don't want a baby.
Young men are great.
Haven't done it in 2 years,
since I got divorced.
We'll meet here tomorrow?
I'll close early. OK?
I'll be waiting.
Co-op's here!
Mitsuo! Co-op's here!
Mitsuo!
Co-op's here!
Here's the receipt.
Tomato price went up.
You can't sleep now.
Too much hormone last year,
the tomatoes had no seeds.
Grow them well this year.
This is not for fun.
I know that!
These few days are
the most important. Bye.
No matter how many
tomatoes they buy.
Just a sheet of paper.
Won't show you the money.
Cunning merchants!
What the hell!
Who are you?
Who am I?
I'm her husband.
You looked after
my wife last night.
I came to thank you.
What do you mean?
What do you mean?!
She's divorced.
You're not her husband.
You're talking to him.
She loves saying
she's divorced.
She has a kid.
Does she look single to you?
She came home late
last night,
with hay in her hair.
She's sleeping now,
being tied up.
She looks so lovely.
She cried and apologized
till daybreak.
Must be tired.
What do you want?
Money?
Don't screw her again.
That's it.
A clean break.
If you bump into her,
pretend you don't know her.
What's your hobby?
Driving and fishing.
What's yours, Ayako?
Cooking.
Her stew's the best.
She went to cooking school.
She always helps me.
Right, honey?
I farm in a greenhouse.
It's now 0.2 hectares,
I plan to double the size.
I wonder if Ayako
is willing to do farm work.
She has to do it
if we get married.
Beautiful women don't
want such work.
Ayako, go help him.
Start tomorrow.
I don't want a tan.
Even if I wanted to,
I have a job.
Eat! Food's getting cold.
Your son's not working
at the construction site.
- It'd be good if he does.
- Oh well...
We don't talk much.
I learnt more about him today.
Young folks,
go for a drive. Ayako?
Let's be frank.
Stop doing what we
don't like to do.
Being a good boy makes
my shoulders stiff.
You were looking at me, right?
It's a blind date, isn't it?
But you were watching non-stop.
I thought you liked me.
I can work at your greenhouse.
I'm fed up with
the gas station.
Will you pay me?
Let's go to a motel.
No! That's ridiculous!
Let me out!
I haven't met such a guy!
I'll marry you! Promise!
Is that OK?
Is that a proposal?
What about my feelings?
Let's get married.
I want to.
You plan on divorcing me
when it turns out badly?
Too good for you!
You did play around?
I know.
Because I did.
Now that we're here.
Don't sulk. I won't.
Just come in.
- We'll just talk?
- Yes.
Don't fool around.
You did.
You really want to get married?
Yes. For the 100th time.
Short stay or long?
Short. 2 hours.
Nothing more to say.
Just one thing to do.
You do this often?
You planned this?
This is the first time.
That's OK, if you
want to lie about this.
Might be more fun
if we're both free.
So... what do you want?
Nothing.
Do you get it?
I think it's time
to get married.
My parents are impatient.
I've been on 8 blind dates.
It's so tiring to make
yourself look impressive.
Someone like you
is good enough.
Wait.
You'll wrinkle my dress.
Smooth.
What?
Gorgeous body.
Let's say this first.
You're my 5th man.
Why didn't you shave?
Don't want to look
so good on blind dates.
So you weren't serious?
Were you?
You looked better
with a beard.
Wish I could do this every day.
You can, if we get married.
No, before that.
One more time?
Too much hard work
will ruin your body.
You may get night-blind.
Don't pretend
you're hardworking!
It's too early to decide.
There'll be someone else.
You're doing fine.
You're getting married.
I want to get married too.
Show me your girl.
Well... She's not
really good-looking.
I know who she is.
She's Hanamura's daughter.
Brings back memories.
You used to come every evening.
Thanks to you he's
now a fine young man.
He was so skinny,
and you made him eat!
But you've only seen her once?
And you made up your mind?
She's homely and not delicate.
I can make her work.
"Wives are hornless cattle."
Even when they're pregnant,
we work them hard.
You can talk all night.
She's like me.
She can drive
and go anywhere.
She's a good one.
Dad ignores me.
He won't come over
when I get married.
But there'd be
a wedding ceremony.
He won't embarrass his heir.
In the end, he'll come.
Wada speaking.
It's been a while, Mitsuo.
You in Tokyo?
At home. Saitama.
In crampy public housing.
Can you hear the TV?
Money?
There's a good house for sale.
Every salaryman's dream.
You won't understand.
You only inherited your place.
Tie a string through it,
you can catch a carp.
With this, it's easy.
- Really?
- Yes.
I'll get some worms.
Let's go to your dad's.
His carp dishes are yummy.
Don't wanna see him.
No! We'll have lots of fun.
Hey! Is that a bomb?
It's locked!
Go in from side door.
Why are you here?
I took Koji to
see how you're doing.
Long time no see.
How are you?
So so. I don't work
as hard as you do.
Dad, sashimi this.
We'll drink.
No knife.
Get some beer.
I'm your kid.
You're nasty!
You're my father.
Let's take our time and talk,
while we eat this.
I'm leaving.
Take my carp. Enjoy.
It's your family time. Bye.
Business is bad.
I closed the snack bar.
Sold it to a real estate agent.
You still have money
on your account?
Tetsuo wants 3 million.
It's his right
as the eldest son.
How about me?
You came for money?
Come home.
Tomatoes are doing well.
Give me a hand.
Don't go.
I won't give him up.
Shop's gone.
I can't do without him.
I can go back
and work in a bar.
I'll look after him!
We stay as one.
Mitsuo!
You said you needed help,
now what are you doing?
Your day off?
Dad wants to fix the date and
the witness for the ceremony.
Trouble!
We have to talk with his dad.
It's OK if he doesn't come,
but it's better if he does.
It's better if he doesn't.
Lend me some work clothes.
I want to work with you.
All right!
How about my jeans?
Wear my baggy pants.
His jeans will do.
Never wore baggy pants.
You ignore the old,
and eat by yourselves.
When Matsuzo's gone,
you treat me badly.
You don't give me food
because my hearing's bad!
Please eat.
It's all yours.
Take those that are
20 or 30% red.
Those that look like
what you see in stores,
like they're ready to eat,
discard them.
Hey. I haven't done this before.
It's easy!
Put it in.
And cut. You try.
Not like this.
Like that.
How about this?
Too ripe. Discard.
I always looked forward
to visiting my folks back home,
because I could sleep
all I wanted.
My mom cried so hard,
"You must have
a hard time there!"
When it was time to leave,
she gave me money,
though a small amount.
The money wasn't
with me for long.
I spent it all on
things for my kids.
In Tomiko's time,
she had it much easier.
We did a great job, Ayako.
It's very good.
It's too oily for
an old person.
When I came to this family,
if I ever left a grain of rice,
I'd be in a lot of trouble.
"One grain of rice on earth
is one barrel in heaven!"
She picked it up carefully,
said she'd dump
the rice pot in the river.
Actually she put the
rice grains in the pot,
called up all the other
mothers in the village,
"Look what my
daughter-in-law did!"
Want some coffee?
What's up with her?
I said, is something wrong?
Thanks for today.
Let's go to a cafe.
It's late. I'm going home.
What?
You're angry?
I'll be frank.
After I saw them,
I lost all confidence.
We'll move out.
I'm not the only woman.
Oh!
Long time no see.
I saw a new car at your place.
She came?
She just left.
Angry.
We're not made for each other.
I'm ready to dress up.
When's the ceremony?
Congrats.
You're still here.
Your husband made a big fuss.
What about?
Alright.
Kaede told me what
happened between you two.
I never thought of it.
Now you call her by name?
If you touch her now,
I won't forgive you.
You're like your dad.
I have to be careful.
Dad...
You got her drunk, then dragged
her to the greenhouse.
That's low.
You're lucky that
she hasn't gone to the police.
Recently we spent
a night at hot springs.
Last Saturday. Yes?
You meant nothing to me.
Hey!
My bottle...
I'm taking it.
60 yen per kilo!
Do I work for free?
How about
fertilizers and pesticide?
Hey stop that!
I can't help it!
This year's warm.
The produce is out
earlier than usual.
"Switch on the boiler
when it's cold."
"Careful, it'll get
very warm this month."
Bastard! That's what
I get in return!
Don't give up.
Mom!
It's so cheap!
We worked for nothing!
Don't get mad about that!
Farmers move their bodies
and turn the soil around.
But I'm so angry!
No matter how cheap,
we'll get money from the co-op.
Farmers work,
and then they eat.
Alright! Let's work!
Mitsuo!
Come help me.
I'm very busy.
You promised.
I helped you.
Kaede came.
She's so excited.
She wants to see you.
Mom!
I'm going to help Koji.
If I don't work,
I won't be happy.
You look great.
The smell of soil makes
farmers feel great.
Smelling burnt garbage
at the incinerator every day.
Sweating makes my
pores breathe.
This is a 0.4-hectare field?
Why don't you fill this up
and build a greenhouse?
- Hi!
- The tomato man!
You came today?
Machiko,
if you don't study hard,
you'll end up working like that.
You don't like it, do you?
Shut up!
Eh?
He's dead.
What is there to do?
He's not for you.
Here's a good guy.
You put that stone at my place?
They were shocked that
the earth god walks!
How about tonight?
No straws.
Mitsuo. Tomatoes are
dirt cheap now.
You worked so hard.
You must feel very bad.
Heat up the bath water.
- Go!
- Have some.
What's up?
What's wrong with your
dad coming home?
That woman?
We broke up.
Water's not ready!
Now it's your chance.
You can't get ahead if no one
knows you in this village.
Oh yes!
Ask Mr Utsuka to be
the wedding witness.
If you have a rich
guy to do this,
you'll have face
in the village.
This is no longer a village.
It is.
People come and help out
on weddings and funerals.
This is a village.
Mitsuo, drink.
Your dad's come home.
You're broke,
so you came back for money?
I have lots of money!
Millions of it.
Good evening.
Come in.
Uncle, so you're back!
We just said it's time
for you to come on stage.
So you've been expecting me?
And you have a new car!
Mitsuo, let's go for a drink.
My treat.
I'll... be working
at the greenhouse.
Go and have a drink.
You have to relax.
Go have fun with Koji.
I... want to work.
Sorry.
Wow, so clean.
You OK?
You asked me to come.
Is Koji angry?
Have you brought a towel?
What a nerve!
What if her husband is home?
I can't find her!
If I could see her,
I'd be OK.
Perhaps she's drinking?
Go look.
Don't hold up the line.
I know!
Now I'm not in the mood.
Hey you...
What do you think of Koji?
He wants to get married.
- With whom?
- With you.
Glad to hear that.
Mitsuo!
What's this?
I warned you!
What's wrong with that?
She just ignores her husband.
Aren't you too serious?
Stop this!
Your date won't let you?
Once you get married,
you can do it whenever you want.
She asked me to come.
Lie!
It's a lie!
She said she was getting
a divorce, and asked me out.
Would I force her?
It's a lie!
Don't be serious with her.
But she's good to play with.
Your friend asked me to come.
"Don't go with him. Take me."
He said that. It's true!
It's true!
So you'd go with
anyone who asks you?
And spread your legs for him?
Stop it!
You'll leave a bruise!
What should I tell my husband?
If you have a husband
then why make a fool of me?
It hurts!
I called and called!
I even looked for you!
- Don't you know!
- It hurts!
Thank you! Come again!
Welcome! Fill it up?
Fill it up.
Have you eaten?
4 liters. That's 620 yen.
It's your lunch break?
My treat.
You had a perm.
A blind date?
What's wrong with your eye?
Cut the crap.
I haven't got over you.
So are you.
We can't end it like this.
I want the best steak.
I helped at the greenhouse.
I've made up my mind.
You're the best.
I told my friends about you.
I'll be embarrassed
if I lose you.
We'll move out.
That's the bottom-line.
I'll have the 1st floor rebuilt.
A new bathroom,
kitchen, and toilet.
A new iron staircase
outside the house.
No kids for 5 years.
I want to have fun too.
Here's your order.
So is that a deal?
Shall we get married?
They know we went to
a motel after our date.
Mom noticed I took a bath,
and asked me about it.
She said,
"If you get married, then OK."
Let's...
Go there?
Do you feel safe?
I haven't said yes for sure.
This is for life.
So noisy! Elections.
Ouch!
Please vote for Hiroshi Utsuka.
It's done.
I want to see
if this will fit him.
If not, I'll redo it.
Do you know the campaign office?
He's there.
My mom's there too.
What do you want?
I'm not him!
You'll have to redo it.
I went there 3 to 4 times.
When I saw your house,
I couldn't go any further.
I don't mind if you
throw stones at me.
But... he...
You love him that much?
What a waste!
He said he'd come back
after the elections.
"If I don't, then drag me
back like a dog."
Do that.
You can have this, Mitsuo.
Granny, you'll fall.
My daughter-in-law
is starving me!
Where's my food?
Where did she put it?
Wait. I'll make you something.
I've gone soft,
and she's like that now.
Shouldn't give her my wallet.
Hello.
Hey dear. I just quit
my gas station job.
You made up your mind?
You'll marry me?
My friends congratulated me.
From a blind date straight
to a motel. They love the story.
You're a hero.
Are your friends men?
Relax. Just 4 beauties here,
including myself.
They want to meet you.
Can you come now?
OK. Wait for me.
Really?
It's dangerous!
Mitsuo!
Mitsuo! Koji's done
something bad.
Please come over.
Koji took his wife away.
I came home from work
but my wife wasn't there.
The kid's watching TV.
I asked her, she said,
"That farmer came
and took Mom away."
Any evidence it's Koji?
If not you, then who else?
Your wife asks this
and that guy out.
I, for one, am her victim.
Mitsuo. Please, come with
us and look for Koji.
If the police's involved,
he'll be in trouble.
No big deal.
Look at him. He's so calm.
Koji took out a million yen
from our co-op account.
You just let him
take a million?
He said he's the eldest son,
he wants his own business.
But a million!
He can go overseas!
I'm out of here!
Please watch her for me.
When I proposed to her,
she agreed on condition that
she could play around.
She's a beauty,
and I'm ugly.
I was glad that I could pick
the impossible flower.
I let her have fun as promised.
I was so embarrassed!
At least you could have called.
We waited for you for 3 hours,
the one I'm so proud of.
I can't bear seeing them.
You're proud of me?
Idiot!
It hurts!
My friend...
ran off with someone's wife.
We looked for them whole night.
He took a million with him.
When the money's gone,
he'll be back for sure.
A false alarm really.
Playing around is all right,
but do it in style.
Wanna play?
Mitsuo Wada,
thanks for your hard work.
Hiroshi Utsuka is here
to greet you workers.
Hiroshi Ut... Hiroshi Utsuka...
needs your vote.
Hiroshi Ur... Hiroshi Utsuka...
please vote for him.
Hello there.
I'm Utsuka. Thank you!
Thank you! Thank you!
Work hard!
Looks refreshing.
You take one too.
Yes!
Don't stare at me like that.
I feel shy.
It's cold!
It's cold! Stop it!
Do you like farm work?
There's no other choice.
Dad supplements my income
no matter what job I take.
I've got you, that's enough.
Just sweet talk.
A bed and a gas stove.
That's enough as a home for me.
I want to do something big.
Once a woman has kids,
her life's finished.
Look at my mom.
Just the two of us would be happy.
Everyone'd be happy.
My friends will envy us.
That'll be the best thing.
Let's go to Hawaii
for our honeymoon.
Or go shopping in Hong Kong.
I'll ask my dad for money.
OK. Let's go there.
Tomatoes! Very cheap!
Just 100 yen per bag!
Very nice tomatoes!
Cheap tomatoes!
100 yen per bag!
Very nice tomatoes!
During cold nights we turn on
the stove to keep them warm.
The fruit of sweat and tears!
They're so cheap,
we just eat shit!
Freshly picked tomatoes!
Take out your 50 yen coins!
- Just 50 yen for them.
- No way!
They're red, like a baby!
Much better than those in
supermarkets. 100 yen for you.
The money's for dating?
Here's my contribution.
Line up!
Where did you find such
a good girl? Tomato field?
Today's June 14th. Election Day.
You may vote at...
It's good on you.
Like kid's underwear.
It's cute... and sexy.
That's what I want.
A cool look.
I feel hot just by looking.
It's good on young folks.
We'll pay with these.
Count them.
Please put this in a bag.
We'll go eat,
then see a movie.
I don't wanna eat.
I feel sick.
Oh really?
Motel?
Horny stud!
Bastard!
Bastard!!
It's cold! Bastard! Idiot!
- Mitsuo Wada?
- Yes.
Koji Nakamori's friend?
Yes.
A missing person report was made.
Don't you know?
The man and the woman
don't need interference.
They like each other.
It's not a kidnapping.
That's a boorish guy.
You're his buddy, right?
They hired an investigator.
Are you looking for him?
I'm not going to.
Think he's OK.
There are few men here
during the day.
You noticed anything strange?
I'm getting married.
I'm not like him.
Don't worry.
I'm going on a trip.
For good?
Stop it!
Mitsuo. Visitors.
Mr. Matsuzo Wada?
My dad's in jail.
So he's out?
Then we'll talk with his son.
I'm busy.
What are you selling?
It's the other way round.
The land of your greenhouse.
Will you sell it?
We want to set up
a used-car shop there.
We'll pay you well.
Get out!
- A good price...
- Out!
Go!
What's wrong?
Mitsuo.
I must congratulate you now.
So full inside,
I just feel like throwing up.
Sorry.
What for?
I think we'll be happier
just by ourselves.
I know you want to
have fun on our honeymoon.
I'll get rid of it.
What about the wedding?
Trouble.
So we'll have a kid?
It's OK to have it?
You're really a nice guy.
Matsuzo Wada...
Just some simple questions
and we've let him go.
Nothing serious really.
Isn't he home yet?
Thanks.
Come in.
You got something to say?
Say it quick.
Are you crazy?
What's wrong with this?
Yes, I'm useless... so?
Mitsuo. Can you
give me some money?
1,000 or 2,000 will do.
Be a good son.
I dropped this in the ditch.
Uncle!
Tetsuo.
Do me a favour.
Please be the wedding witness.
- The wedding witness?
- Yes.
Your brother as the best man?
That's unheard of! Right?
Right. That'd be strange.
Don't.
Just sit and face
me for a while.
Then the party will begin.
You want 3 million?
Hitomi. Kazu. Come.
Let's play.
We don't have that much.
Let's go and ask dad.
Is Dad... really living
with a bar hostess?
Mom! Why did you keep silent?
That's all I can do.
We're not kids.
I can't force him.
If I were you, I'd just
tie him up and drag him back.
That simple.
That's the way to go about it.
Let's go together.
Do what you like.
You coming?
OK.
We'll back you up.
Do what you like.
You'll wait here?
Let's go.
I'm here now.
That's not what you told me.
They fled.
How about my 3 million?
You sure this is the right place?
Firefly!
There too!
Pretty!
Over there as well.
You're not alone!
Baby's still not moving?
Fool.
Wait until my belly's as
big as a sumo wrestler's.
Those kids...
They thought fireflies were hot.
And can't be touched.
They screamed when fireflies
gathered around their mom's head.
We're just...
Country bumpkins.
We are.
I know, but...
The wedding... will go well.
I'm looking forward to it.
Want to take their breath away.
You must feel hot in that dress.
Say it if you can't
stand it anymore.
I'm OK.
It's my most beautiful moment.
Wipe it.
Mitsuo.
Hanamura!
Congratulations!
Now it's just you and me.
You better drink up!
What a wedding feast!
Very luxurious!
I can't thank you enough.
Don't! Now we're relatives.
We are as one.
Never seen such a big feast.
Did it cost a lot?
At least 3 million?
Less than a million.
With the gifts,
I'll make a profit.
Profit!
Wait!
You did it!
Who do you want?
Me or her?
Congratulations.
You did great.
That's OK! Never mind!
Eat or you'll be very hungry.
This will go on all night.
"In heaven,
where the sun rises..."
Granny. Go watch TV.
Why are there so many people?
It's my wedding.
I invited them.
I thought Mitsuo's still a kid.
He's getting married?
Where's the girl from?
Everybody. Drink! Sake!
Granny, wait here.
I'll bring you some food.
Phone call.
- Phone call for Mitsuo!
- Coming!
Hello.
Where are you?
We're so worried.
It's my wedding.
They all say I've got
myself a good bride.
What about that woman?
What?
What did you do?
- Mitsuo, come drink.
- Coming.
What happened?
I'm coming. Don't go away.
Traditional clothes?
You look great in them.
Is it alright for you
to leave the banquet?
Where's the woman?
I killed her.
I strangled her.
She died so quickly that
I didn't feel a thing.
She just fainted?
You think I'm joking?
Of course. It's a joke.
I'm a murderer. Really.
She's a slut.
Where's she?
Snack bar.
Let's go to a snack
bar and drink.
Stop here!
It should be here.
Sorry. It's not here.
Further up.
Now I remember. Here!
It's here!
Koji! Koji!
You're all wet!
A walk in the rain.
Sorry.
You'll get a baby tonight.
It's like that in our house.
You did something good?
- Jealous?
- You young people.
Koji.
We went to the sea.
The sun was shining
on fish boats.
Woman's smooth skin
that makes you want to touch.
No matter how nice the view.
No matter where we went,
we did the same thing.
We walked around naked
in our room.
When hungry,
we went out to eat.
Gradually, it became less fun.
And frightening.
Kaede felt the same.
"I can't go back to him.
What will I do?"
She kept saying that.
Her uncle is a chief of police.
So she had to say
she was abducted.
When we passed by
the police box,
she yelled to let her out.
I stopped.
Then she became quiet.
"Actually I love you."
"Let's go to a place where no
one knows us and settle down."
At the next police box,
she thought of her child
and wept.
I felt very strange.
I got desperate and
bought a kitchen knife.
I gave it to her,
telling her to stab me anytime.
She sat beside me
when I drove.
She spread make-up cream on the
kitchen knife and enjoyed it.
And used it to
scratch my neck.
It was scary!
My cheeks were all wet.
I stopped at red lights.
I made a turn if I had to.
When I read the signs,
I saw places I knew.
I drove past my fields,
pretending I didn't know them.
Although I ignored them,
the rice still grows.
My eyes fill with tears
when I think about it.
At last, we went to a motel.
There's only one thing to do.
I expected to get
stabbed at daytime.
But she felt settled
once she got naked.
There were 2 cup-noodles
on top of the fridge.
There was hot water
in the thermos.
"We'll go to the police tomorrow
when we're out of money."
We decided to do that.
Once we made a decision,
it was a relief.
We bathed together.
Then we played in bed.
Then she started to talk.
"I have an ordinary family,
but without worries.
"How come I'm like
a cheap whore?"
She refused to
take responsibility.
I was exhausted.
I told her she's
responsible too.
"Die," I said to her.
"That's the graceful way out."
She sat up on bed.
All naked.
Her pubes were touching
the bed sheet.
When we choked each other,
unexpectedly,
she got very high.
She said,
"I'm sure I'm pregnant."
I said, "Does it matter now?"
"You haven't been a parent,
that's why you say that."
"Devil! Bastard!
Such grand talk!" I retorted.
"You're a nuisance."
"Die!" I sat on her chest.
While I was choking her,
she...
closed her eyes
as if she was enjoying it.
Honestly...
at that time...
I thought she was
so beautiful.
I wanted to do her
as much as I could.
I should have stopped then!
I should have put less
force in my fingers.
The force...
Was just unexpected.
Then, it was the end.
She wasn't moving anymore.
With her...
the first two, three
days were fun.
That's how she felt too,
I suppose.
The only way out is...
to turn myself in.
Come with me.
We're friends.
I'll do anything.
Let's go.
Please help us at harvest time.
Koji. Run away!
Take my car!
Tomorrow I'll take out
a million from my account.
You can live with that.
You'd be implicated.
You just got married!
Run away!
Hide in Tokyo!
If one million is not enough,
I'll give you five!
I made up my mind.
Sorry.
To do this...
on such a night.
It's not dry yet.
Take this.
Mitsuo.
The whole village is back.
When you came
and beat me up,
if she hadn't gone with you,
I might have been you.
The one who ran away with her,
and strangled her would be me.
No.
I'm serious.
You weren't.
Kaede fell in love with me.
It's true.
She was just playing with you.
Let's go.
Anybody?
Quiet!
Car crash? Your licence please.
I killed someone.
You've been drinking?
I'm turning myself in.
Mr. Yo! Mr. Yo!
A murder!
He killed someone.
He's turning himself in.
Bastard!
No! Not him!
I'm the killer!
Where have you been?
They came here for us.
When we were kids,
they used a blunt razor
to shave our heads.
She won't believe it.
It's true.
It's most painful
around the ears.
So unbearable that
we left in the middle of it.
Shya... Shya...
Dad sharpened his razor
with a grin.
Stop it!
Such painful memories!
Mitsuo. Come here and eat.
- I Miss My Ex!
- Ginza Love Story!
Love in Tochigi!
Ayako, sing with us.
Welcome! Kukukuku...
My blue bird.
Stays on my heart
that's in love.
With the wind...
Kukukuku...
Goes my message.
"I'm the happiest
person on Earth!"
Please...
Ayako, sing with me.
Help me out, my wife.
You're under arrest!
Welcome! Kukukuku...
My blue bird.
Stays on my heart
that's in love.
With the wind...
Kukukuku...
Goes my message.
"I'm the happiest
person on Earth!"
Please don't go.
Stay here.
'Cause my heart
is singing my happiness.
Singing it!
Kukukuku! Kukukuku!
Blue bird!
Please don't go.
Stay here.
'Cause my heart
is singing my happiness.
Singing it!
Kukukuku! Kukukuku!
Blue bird!
One more time!
Kukukuku! Kukukuku!
Blue bird!
One more time!
Kukukuku! Kukukuku!
Blue bird!
Will you friend get
the death sentence?
He turned himself in,
police said he'd get 10 years.
He'll be 33
when he gets out.
The baby inside me
will be 10.
Grade 3.
- Good afternoon.
- You've got time to talk?
Please hear me out.
Don't waste your time.
Hear me first.
This is our job,
or we don't get paid.
We'll give you the best deal.
Presents for you.
Ayako. Don't take it.
It's nothing.
Just to show our sincerity.
Go away!
- What are you doing?
- Go away!!
Go away! Cockroaches!
Soon you won't be able
to live here! Damn farmer!
Your face is black.
Looks funny? If it's funny
I'll wash my face.
That's OK. Peasants
don't powder their faces.
THE END