Every second, a human soul
enters this world.
A new light is lit.
A star that may burn
unusually bright.
One that has its own spectre,
never to be beheld.
A new being -
- that may sprinkle genius,
perhaps beauty, about it, -
- kisses Earth.
The never seen
becomes flesh and blood.
So the humans rejoice
for every newly lit soul.
They stand about him
with questioning eyes.
Do they wonder
what this newcomer will bring ?
No, man is no star -
- that you win renown
by discovering.
It's often a parasite
that steals into the world -
- through nine months
of Purgatory.
And it doesn't even have
its papers in order.
Here's the kid's birth certificate
for the teacher.
"Born out of wedlock."
Does it have to say that?
Yes, it's the law.
When the kid is illegitimate.
- And it'll be there forever?
- Yes.
- Goodbye.
Congratulations.
- Congratulations.
- Thanks.
Illegitimate.
You can't tell by looking at her.
I don't care what she is,
she has to eat.
- Where do I find the money?
- I have to take up fishing again.
Your back can't take that, Søren.
Nobody thinks about me.
What's to happen with me?
- The son from the Sandfarm?
- Yes.
He's the father?
Then he'll have to wed you.
- I'll go and talk to the farmer.
- Søren, you wouldn't dare.
Yes. I will go to
the Sandfarm tomorrow.
- Now the girl's got a kid.
- That's how it's supposed to be.
She says you're the father.
Can she prove it?
She can swear to it.
You'd better marry the girl.
- You laugh!
- Listen now.
The two of us should have
a sensible chat about these matters.
I don't think my son
will marry her.
I'll bloody well make him.
The only thing that can make him
is the law. And it won't.
But one might help the girl
find a proper match.
Look at this. You can have these.
Once and for all.
- I didn't come to get money.
- Be reasonable, Søren Man.
- Yes, those are big notes.
- Here.
I'll send you a note
and get your signature.
We'd better do this by the book.
The kid will bear the girl's name
and can make no demands from us.
Let it never be said
that our people -
- scale the neighbour's fence -
- without paying for
the damage they do.
- Goodbye, Søren.
- Goodbye.
Thank you. Goodbye.
I won't stay here
if I don't get a father for her.
The women look at me.
Talk about me.
Their eyes have been here
for months.
They're still there.
I can feel them.
They will probably accept you
on the Sandfarm.
Haven't I always said
you were a rich man's child?
Yes, not by birth
but by grace.
Children like that will always
bring their parents happiness.
Are you going sailing again?
Yes, if they'll let me tag along,
I'm going sailing again.
and if she for a tiny child
has wept such bitter tears
she'll sit upon a big pile
of pelts from minks and bears
now granny spins a yarn
for bed-ticks
and for cushions blue
so Ditte can sleep properly
alongside her prince so true
- Ditte doesn't like the trees.
- And why not?
- The trees are making wind.
- It's the Lord who makes the winds.
Then grandfather
won't have to row so hard.
What does the Lord look like?
The Lord, you say?
Well, he's got his hands full.
Yet it may seem to us -
- that he occasionally takes on
more than he can manage.
That's what he looks like.
What happened, Søren?
This will be the end of me.
Søren, come here.
Go to bed, Ditte child.
Granny will come.
I can undress by myself.
Yes, go to bed.
Granddad told you to.
No, you can't do it yourself.
Mother will do it.
This will be the end of me.
We've gone through
sickness and health, Maren.
And now it's all over.
Will you be faithful to me
for the days that you have left?
Yes.
There has never been
anyone else in my mind, -
- and there never will be
anyone else.
I will swear by our Lord
Jesus Christ.
Have faith in that, Søren.
Granny, aren't you coming?
Yes, I'll be right there,
Ditte love.
There's old Maren and Ditte,
they're begging.
Why isn't anyone coming?
There is no better way
of keeping people down -
- than keeping them waiting.
Just waiting.
ls that you? It’s freezing!
Hold on a minute.
God grant work and food
to each and every one of you.
For these are hard times,
and nothing comes for free.
They didn't have anything
they could spare.
There's wise Maren,
riding the storm.
It’s great weather
for a witch to be out in.
You just have to turn your bum to
the storm and let it have its way.
It’s a good thing
that you remembered the rock.
Granny's feet feel like ice.
It was a shame that we didn't get
any sugar, right, Ditte?
People are loath to give away
the things they like best.
Ditte? See if there isn't
a bit of sugar in that bag.
- There's nothing, granny.
- Let me have a look.
There's nothing.
Then it won't be real coffee.
Right or left?
You little rascal.
My dear girl, what have you saved
for your granny this time?
Left, of course.
It’s closer to the heart?
Exactly.
One, two, three.
The last one for granny's
second cup of coffee.
You see, I was psychic.
Here, granny.
Thanks. The cold doesn't do
granny's eyes much good.
Thank you.
- Did you get anything?
- Yes, I got some.
Granny, why don't I have a father
like all the other children?
If you'd had a real father, -
- someone worthwhile, -
- Sørine would sit as a married woman
on the Sandfarm.
And we ...
Starve and freeze,
that we wouldn't.
Let me help you, granny.
I'll show you.
- We're still doing alright.
- Yes, we are.
Sun, show yourself,
cloud, go away, -
- and sun ...
Granny, granny!
Granny, look what I found!
Let no one see that money.
They're the ones granddad got.
Save them until you get older.
Tell nobody about them.
Then they will take them from us.
It’s a fishmonger.
He's coming this way.
Am I not bringing you
some lovely weather?
Granny's eyes are failing her.
But I am your son-in-law.
Which girl are you married to?
The one who's the mother of that kid.
What's your name?
I am Ditte Love, Ditte Rascal
and Ditte Child of Man.
So Sørine has married?
It isn't quite official yet.
We haven't bothered
the priest yet.
- And what's your name?
- Lars Peter Hansen.
They call me the scavenger.
I hawk herrings, as you see, -
- and buy rags and bones
when people have any.
- That won't get you much.
- No.
People wear out their rags
and walk their bones to stumps.
But one has to sell something.
Yes, one has to eat.
Thank you.
Don't you need a bit of something?
Come here.
Tell the baker
that we have a visitor, -
- and that you need the bread
that we were having next week.
Can you keep her in check?
I have no one else
to support me, -
- but she's just a kid,
and I'm old and bothersome.
That's what I’ve
come to talk to you about.
You haven't come
to take away the girl?
No. It’s just that since
Sørine and I are getting married, -
- I’ve come to bring you
to the church.
That is, if you don't want to
move in with us.
- Sørine told you to say that?
- No. Well, yes ...
I could tell that you made that up
by yourself. I thank you.
Now I have a father
like all the other children.
He's at home with granny.
He has his own horse and a cart.
- Oh? And what's his name, then?
- He's called the scavenger.
- That means you're of fine blood.
- Yes, he's marrying my mother.
So you have
young ones at home?
Yes, Sørine is carrying one again.
- Thanks, Ditte.
- You are one skilled girl.
You deserve a kiss.
Have I hurt you?
The child has been looking forward
to getting a father.
And now it's come true,
although it's no big thing.
The two of us
will make great friends.
At Whitsun I will bring
you and granny to the wedding.
When the Whitsun bells are ringing,
I will come to you.
- You look so pretty, Ditte.
- Yes, I'm going to the church today.
- You are?
- My mum and dad are getting married.
Oh?
But it's Whitsun.
Don't you think
father will take us the wedding?
Dad will come. I know.
Shouldn't you be getting yourself
ready to come along?
I'll make it where I have to go.
The wedding is off for now.
Sørine wanted to wait a bit longer.
One has long known about
your business here.
You are expected.
Go and pack your clothes, Ditte.
It’s not my idea, but a mother
has a right to her child, -
- and Sørine finds that she's come
to long a tad for the girl.
I know that you've argued against it
as much as you could.
Well, everything will be
as it was meant to be.
Can't one of your children
come down here to help you?
A mother can feed eight kids, -
- but have you ever heard of
eight kids feeding a mother?
So, Ditte, did you
remember everything?
Yes, I did.
Well, then let's have
a look at the vehicle.
We are not going to forget you.
You're at the first end of things,
as Søren Man said.
You have much ahead of you,
young Ditte.
You can have this.
- Goodbye, Maren.
- Goodbye, granny.
Goodbye, Ditte love.
Ditte?
- Ditte?
Ditte? Ditte?
Get up, will you.
I'm up, mother.
Get the young ones up and dressed.
Dad will be here soon.
- Are we riding with Big Klavs?
- Yes.
I want Big Klavs.
Kristian, come here!
Else, don't run outside naked.
Kristian and Else!
Get over here.
- Kristian, wait for me.
- You need to wear your shirt.
Povl, let Ditte help.
Quiet, children.
Ditte, get them to calm down.
It’s dad!
Is the coffee done?
Good morning. I have a special
greeting to you from granny.
She thanks you for all the coffee
and sugar that we ...
- Is granny still bedridden?
- She always is, they say.
Blame yourself for that back.
You carry that big kid around.
Granny always said that ...
You talk a lot about your granny.
Any news from dad about my mum?
I guess she can't
keep it up much longer.
Don't make a fuss.
Old people can't live forever.
When granny dies,
we get a new house.
No, because granny says
that that money ...
What money?
Stupid girl.
I know you mean the money
that was paid for you.
What's it to be spent on?
Granny hid it.
Oh?
And where did she hide it?
In the duvet, of course!
- No.
- What a lovely smell of coffee.
- I have food for you.
- I have something for you.
And the kids.
- Come, dad.
- Let's see what you've got.
The porridge, Ditte!
That's fine, little wagtail.
Shouldn't Povl sit
in his seat and eat?
Aren't you going to show us?
I almost forgot.
I think this is
something for the neck.
Shouldn't we rather save the money
instead of buying worthless junk?
Take a good look at it.
Here's something for the nestlings.
Not until after breakfast.
Didn't you hear, Kristian?
I was just looking.
Can I go now?
- Have you fed the chickens?
- Yes.
- But the cow ...
- I'll do it.
Let her go,
or she'll be late for school.
Bring the sack,
so you can pick nettles for the pig.
She could be a bit faster.
She spends her time
telling tales about granny.
She longs for her.
I don't see
why she can't stay here.
You want us to sleep
in the stables?
Mum has always been
good at taking care of herself.
Can I give one to Povl now?
Get your beaks up, nestlings.
Loves me, loves me not.
Loves me.
- You're late again.
- I am? So are you.
- Aren't you going to school?
- We're ill.
Well, I have to hurry up.
Why don't your dad drive you
in your neat cart?
Dad is so busy.
Would you like a bonbon?
Yes.
Phew, they taste of herring.
Loves me, loves me not.
- Ditte, I can whistle.
- You can?
- Wanna hear?
- Yes.
That was neat.
- Now, lie down and go to sleep.
- Yes.
I don't know what you have to do
to get to school in time.
What can I do, Kristian?
Just turn the clock forward.
What are you doing?
You want to trick your mother?
Out of my way.
So you wanted to
trick your mother, you rascal!
Come here! I'm going to
teach you a thing or two!
Let go!
Come here, girl.
Come here, you dumb girl.
You rascal.
You can cry outside.
That'll teach you not to
play tricks on me again!
Granny ...
Granny?
What is it, Big Klavs?
What is it?
Ditte?
It’s late, Lars Peter.
Yes, you watch us.
There is a child here
who accuses you.
What are we to do about this?
You don't mind laying it on.
Now, let's see if you are
just as good at making it go away.
Come here.
Kiss Ditte where you hit her.
One kiss for each blow.
Well?
So you think your mouth
is too good for kissing -
- what your hand hit?
- No!
- Well?
Mum ...
My bloodline is not in high regard,
and we may not deserve it either, -
- but they never laid hand
on us children.
These hands have done much work -
- but never been turned against
the defenceless.
I'd advice you
to give that some thought.
Say, Lars Peter?
You know what?
I think my mother has sewn
the money into the duvet.
- What money?
- The money dad got from the farmer.
They're none of our business.
They were given to the girl
who is now a burden to us.
We could build for that money.
A new farmhouse.
Are you asleep?
Say, Lars Peter?
I have a feeling
that my mother will soon die.
Go and talk to her.
We probably have to
earn the money that we need.
What can we earn?
You toil and moil.
- And we get nowhere.
- Are you sure about this?
Do you know why people
call this the "magpie's nest"?
Because nothing go our way.
People consider us as nothing.
But I will show them.
If you won't talk to my mother,
I will go there.
And I won't be coming back
without the duvet.
Maybe Ditte
can tell us about that?
Yes?
You have to pay more attention.
Then Hans can tell us.
Where are you, Ditte?
Ditte?
Ditte, love?
I want that duvet!
I have a right to have it!
I won't let you have it, Sørine.
Now, leave me alone.
- Leave me alone!
- I'm taking it with me!
You have the money in it.
- What money?
- Don't you think I know?
Those are my money!
And I want it!
I'll cry out.
Sure, cry out.
No one will hear you.
They must be in there.
Be quiet, you thief.
Help!
What are you saying?
What are you saying?!
Granny!
Good evening, Sørine.
Good evening.
Granny, can't you hear me?
Granny, it's me. Ditte.
What happened? I heard
Maren knock, but I'm bedridden.
Oh, this is a fine mess.
Come, Ditte.
Who has been here?
What happened?
Poor Ditte.
Lars Peter!
Oh, this is a fine mess.
Now old Maren has died.
But it seems to me that it
didn't happen naturally.
Poor Ditte.
She was here.
Yes, and Sørine.
Hello?
- Ditte?
I'll run to the highway again
and look for her.
Bring the lantern.
Here, Else.
Do you want one, too, Povl?
Yes, a big one.
Sugared bread?
You're having an early Sunday.
They've been good
while mother was away.
- Goodnight, dad.
- Goodnight, kids.
Where is that girl?
You haven't had a row,
have you?
Nothing, Lars Peter.
Nothing.
- We're doing so well now.
- Sure we are.
And I'm happy about that.
I think it will be alright
if granny comes to live with us.
She probably ran down to her.
You really light up
when you smile, Sørine.
Did granny feel better?
Yes, much better.
- Did you give her any food?
- Yes, she slept alright when ...
There you are.
We've missed you so much.
Come, Ditte.
Dear me, girl.
Mum only wanted to ...
You're shaking.
Come, I have some food for you.
Give her a cup of coffee instead.
That's what she gave granny -
- when she was cold.
I ... I feel so queasy.
Ditte?
What's wrong with the girl?
It must be something she ate.
If I only knew ...
- If I only knew ...
- Knew what?
Nothing. Nothing.
You're tired after the trip.
Yes, I guess I am.
I think I'll clear the table.
Ditte?
Ditte, love.
Ditte? Where are you?
Ditte?
No! No!
Mum!
- Lars Peter! Lars Peter!
- Come on!
No, I won't! Let go!
- Ditte! Help me!
- Do you belong here?
Go and tell your siblings
not to be afraid.
- Shall we get going?
- Ditte! Ditte!
- There!
Lars Peter.
Mum! Mum!
- Mum!
- There's dad!
So, we've had visitors.
What's the matter, children?
The police came for Sørine.
For Sørine?
Came for her?
It must be some misunderstanding.
That can't be right.
You were there
when it happened.
You've got to know ...
You have to be able to
vouch for your mother.
Shall we go?
Do you need anything
honed, riveted or soldered?
I hone knives, scissors
and what have you.
I'll cut your corns
and suck up to your woman.
I'm the knife-grinder!
Where's the mistress?
- That's me.
- What?
- And how may I serve you?
- I have a dull pair of scissors.
- Where do you come from?
- From Spainland.
From Spainland?
That's what dad always answered.
Are you from Odsherred,
if I may ask?
Then maybe you could
tell me about an Arnst Hansen?
- Goes by the name of the scavenger.
- That I can.
Because that's my dad.
It is? Then I will have to
bid you welcome.
For then you are Johannes,
my brother.
I'm Lars Peter.
So, this is what you look like now.
I haven't seen you
since you ran away from home.
You look like mum.
Ditte, can you go inside
and make us something nice?
Come on in.
You're the spitting image of mum.
You're the first guest
in the Magpie's nest since ...
Well, since a long time ago, so ...
- Here, nestlings.
- Have some.
- We can take afterwards.
- Ditte? Come over here.
- Does your peat bog yield anything?
- Nothing more than we use ourselves.
We could sell a lot of peats.
If only you have something to sell.
Now I know how he does it.
Put your foot there, and I'll pull.
Go ahead.
she bumps into a little prince
in scarlet clad
That's it, right?
- Yes!
- One more time!
Give uncle some peace now
and go to bed.
This could become
one fine house -
- once we get to work.
And Ditte makes the best food.
- Cheers, fair maiden.
- Cheers.
And for the elderly gentleman.
There you go, uncle.
Cheers, brother.
And thank you
for helping us out.
Sørine will be in jail for
quite some time, -
- and I travel the roads so much.
Hawking herring and rags.
I know of another trade.
- Have you got money?
- A little. For mortgage.
Give it to me.
If you have money, then ...
I will make things happen.
Can you scrape guts?
- Uncle wants to slaughter?
- Certainly.
But we were supposed to
get the land into shape.
Have you forgotten your trade?
- Trade?
- Yes.
Those thick-headed farmers
don't use their carcasses.
I don't slaughter cadavers.
But I do. You just wait, -
- and I'll show you money.
Kristian, go and get dad.
He's in the peat bog. Hurry up!
Damned creature.
Dad? Have a look at Big Klavs.
I'll have a look at him.
He needs some love and affection.
Don't touch him.
- Are you mad?
- Go to hell.
Let go!
I suppose you understand
that you're through here.
People who hit animals
have no business here.
We saw something good in you.
We're not overrun by
family and friends, -
- so you could easily have found
your way in through good.
And what did you bring us?
Evil and filth.
Where are the money that you were
supposed to buy a peat cutter for?
- What's this?
- A dead rat.
- What are we to do with it?
- Give it to me.
Kristian.
I have something for you.
Here's some nice, fresh meat
for sausages.
Isn't it good enough for you?
- So you want to fight, you rascal?
- Don't you touch him!
Beware of the magpie.
Yes, she's learnt from her mother.
You forgot your shoe!
Cowardly kids.
Say hi from me in the magpie's nest.
- 1 .7 5.
- 2.00.
That's nothing for
a watch like that.
Wouldn't that be something
for the wife?
- Let's hear it.
- Three.
Three kroner.
Sold for that princely bid.
Three kroner bid by
Jens Peter Jensen.
And here is a fine comb.
Ten kroner?
- No, four.
- Four and a quarter.
Is it far to America?
I'd rather live there.
Nobody will know us there.
Or know about mum.
Is this also up for sale?
No, it's still too early.
Is nobody going to
make a bid on this?
One kroner.
- You will be paying cash, right?
- Yes.
He can get the money from me.
- Ten kroner.
- Four.
Four and a quarter.
It’s made from carcasses.
What's wrong?
They're not eating anything.
They can't be hungry.
They think it isn't edible.
That it's some of what uncle made.
- Dog's meat or something.
- Nonsense.
I'm looking forward to
moving some place with people.
- People?
- Yes, real people.
Like Kristian and Else and ...
And me.
What's this worth?
Ten kroner?
Now we'll rest a bit
and get something in our stomachs.
Let me do it.
Let me just say -
- that if the clerk
and the assistant would care, -
- there's food and beer
in the living room.
We can also offer you a schnapps.
Ditte has taken care of that.
To think that he invites
public authorities to his table.
And in the house of
the murderess, no less.
Thank you, but we brought
our own food.
And you and your little girl
have plenty to do already.
Yes.
Thank you.
Other people's food is always tasty.
And some schnapps for the food.
How about you?
- Come on in.
- Thanks.
I haven't had open-faced sandwiches
like this before.
You have a fine daughter,
Lars Peter Hansen.
- Would you like another one?
- Yes, please.
- Kristian, can you take Povl?
- Yes.
Here, Big Klavs.
Pers! Pers!
Yes, we almost forgot him.
Could you get him, Kristian?
Pers! Pers!
- Are you comfortable?
- Yes, Ditte.
One has started over a few times.
But this time ...
The kind innkeeper promised to
help you with the house and the boat.
We'll see how kind he is.
- I have him now, dad.
- Come on, Big Klavs.
Let's move out, Pers.
- It’s the innkeeper!
- The cannibal!
"And help me
to be dead while I'm alive."
"Dead while I'm alive"?
"From sin and shame and vice
that will ....
... that will for death suffice."
One managed to pay fare on
one of the innkeeper's boats.
It cost us everything
that remained from the auction.
I can't become confirmed.
What do you mean?
I won't have time to learn it all.
The priest says -
- that he won't dare
place me before the Lord.
Won't dare?
You could be the Lord's housekeeper
if you so desired.
I want to be confirmed.
I won't start over again and have
people sneer at me every day.
Maybe the priest can be greased.
But the innkeeper has all our money.
The innkeeper can fix it.
There's nothing in this village
that he can't fix.
Who says you can't
become confirmed, Ditte?
- The priest.
- Oh, him?
I'll take care of him.
And when you're done, I have an
opening for you on the Hillfarm.
- That is, if you want it.
- If you can get me an interview ...
We can't do without her.
You squander your sugar.
Those girls are too expensive -
- when they're not earning money.
You poor people ought to economize.
Be content with what you get.
We owe no one thanks
for what little we have.
We would be doomed without Ditte.
You don't have to
do without a housewife.
I have a mind to
getting you married again.
My wife is good enough for me.
But she is in prison.
And you have no obligation
to live with a convict.
There will be
no divorces in this home!
Sure, Lars Peter.
That's up to your conscience.
But the word of God says nothing
about sharing your bed or table -
- with a murderess.
I will never abandon Sørine!
- And now you know.
- Well, easy does it.
It’s agreed, then,
that Ditte starts at the Hillfarm -
- once she has been confirmed.
Confirmand, give us a coin.
Four øre.
And I wanted a pocket knife.
- Would you care to write in it?
- Of course. It’s a keepsake.
I’ve never had my picture taken.
Have you?
Yes, plenty of times.
- Here.
- Thanks.
- Bye.
- Congratulations, Ditte.
- Thank you.
Confirmand, give us a coin.
Each thing has its place.
That makes it much easier for you.
I have to fix this.
- We're going to miss you.
- Yes, you are.
Kristian, now you are the oldest.
Povl and Else only have you
to look up to now.
I'll bloody well take ...
I'll take care of them.
Is it from Sørine?
I can't quite read the last part.
- When is she getting out?
- In about a year from now.
- Do you long for her as well?
- Just read it, Kristian.
Do you think she's changed?
In regard to the little ones?
Privation is a good teacher.
You can always return to your home
if they chase you from the farm.
But don't you leave prematurely.
Accept the injustice done to you.
Ought one not
stand up for one's right?
Yes, I suppose one ought to.
But what is right?
The one who has the power
will also be right.
Here are the scissors.
Should I just tell them
that I'm the new girl?
First of all you should say "hello".
Otherwise they'll think
you're rude.
I wonder what the wife will say?
I suppose she'll say:
"Hello and welcome, Ditte."
Hello.
So you're the scavenger's daughter.
You look a bit stump-tailed.
You won't take up much room.
It’s for the rats.
Flour mixed with plaster.
Bring some of them to the barn.
- Is it very poisonous?
- No.
But as soon as the rats eat
that dry fare, they have to drink.
When plaster gets wet it hardens.
It’s like a rock in their stomach.
- That must me a terrible death.
- Why ever?
There are so many ways of dying.
They all lead down the same road.
By the way, when do you expect
your mum to get out?
That ... will probably be a while.
- Do you think she got the money?
- I don't know.
Shouldn't I go place the parcels?
Where were you last night?
You're certainly in heat,
aren't you?
I was with the church brothers.
That's my son.
He'll be managing this farm one day.
However he'll cope with that.
- Mother ...
- Hello.
Now get lost,
and call for the farm hand.
- He's taking a nap in the barn.
- I will.
You can't yell him awake.
You have to crawl up into the hay
with him and give him a shake.
Take care that he doesn't
tear off your angel wings.
It suits them well
to have their bud nipped in time.
One virgin helps another.
Those girls.
Ditte?
- Ditte?
- Yes, I'm right here.
- One of the cows was in the field.
- I'm sorry.
- I'll get it right away.
- I fixed it.
Thank you.
- It’s a good thing mum didn't see.
- You're afraid of your mum, right?
Did you like your dad?
Yes.
I liked him.
He was always in bed.
He was consumptive. He spat blood.
But mum sat on his bed
and smoked, -
- so the blood and the coughing
almost choked him.
I don't like my mum either.
But you're commanded
to love your parents.
Not if you can't like them.
You don't like your mother.
How will you do it, then?
I don't know,
but that's what the book says.
Is your mum cruel to
your dad as well?
No one can harm my dad.
He takes everything like the Lord.
In good spirits.
Don't compare a man to the Lord.
I will when it comes to dad.
And my granny.
You're no priest either.
Just be happy mum didn't
see that cow in the field.
- Won't you tell your mother?
- No, why would l?
No, indeed.
But you'll inherit the farm.
Sure.
- Would you like to have these?
- Yes.
- They're pigeon's feathers.
- Thank you.
Ditte? Ditte?
Kristian, dear,
you must have run all day.
- Did you shirk school?
- No.
How are they back home?
Does Povl ask for me?
- What's this?
- It’s my nest.
You should make
a hidden entrance instead.
- How is Else handling it at home?
- Fine. They're dove's feathers.
- Can I have that lapwing's egg?
- Yes. Is Povl eating properly?
Sure. Let's go to the lake.
That's much more exciting.
Those hillocks are islands.
If you had some poles,
we could build a bridge between them.
- This is so much fun.
- It’s more fun at home.
That's because you're a fool.
Does dad get his beer
when he returns from sea?
Sure.
- Did anyone have some little ones?
- Yes, Martha.
That can't be true.
You're lying.
- Then it's Marie.
- Marie isn't married.
She'll probably have a kid anyway.
There's a magpie.
Didn't anything happen
back home?
Yes, we got a new type of boat.
You have a cut on your heel.
We have to dress that.
I'll just tiptoe.
- Dinner time.
- Where do you eat?
- I run back home.
- Can I come?
No, then it'll seem as if
you just came here to eat.
But I did.
Stay here.
I'll bring something out for you.
- So, virgin ...
- I'm up.
Just leave the girl alone, now,
you old man.
It’s no good for her to sleep alone.
She might catch a cold.
I suppose you're still
as cold as a fish.
Colder!
My, now the girl
is off to sea again.
Well, let her.
It won't harm anyone.
She's homesick.
Why do you stand here
every morning?
That's dad's boat out there.
You have good eyes.
I just pick one out
that I imagine to be his.
We live behind that headland.
Would you like
to come to a meeting tonight?
Your church brothers
look so pious.
As if they swallowed Maundy Thursday
and are going for Good Friday.
They wanted to help you.
- Because of my mother.
- Yes.
What fault of mine is that?
I haven't got time
to be saved today, -
- because it's my day off.
Are you going home to your dad?
Yes, and my siblings.
I still believe that
the boat out there is my dad's.
- Now we're having visitors.
- Don't we get the day off, then?
We must have the day off.
Does anyone want to sell
beef calf, horses or sucklings?
Well, you hack.
You can't get off until tonight.
Your stock looks properly clean.
Well fed and well shaped
at both ends.
Like the mistress herself.
Except I'm not for sale.
I usually don't leave
without striking a deal.
But today I’ve got my mind set
on something extra.
We can go up and play
a game of cards over it.
And see who wins.
- What is it?
- I know him.
Indeed, so do I.
The worst of the hawkers.
They bring only misery.
The mistress seemed odd.
She's in the dangerous phase.
- Which is that, Sine?
- She longs for young meat.
Karen Hillfarm can become
almost dizzy when she ...
... when she has a visitor.
I sometimes feel sore all over
and becomes dizzy.
Is that when I'm in that ...
dangerous phase?
That's growing pains.
Don't you mind those.
They only mean that you're
becoming a grown woman.
Hurry up, before the mistress
puts us to more work.
I'm so rich. This is
the first money I’ve earned.
Let's just get going. This won't be
a nice place for us tonight.
I'm going to sleep at home.
I can buy everyone something.
Let's just get going.
Let me just fetch my things.
If she thinks of a reason
why you can't go, I'll help you.
- Thanks, Karl.
- Hurry, Ditte. Come on.
You can't leave. Our guests
are thirsty and want more food.
Their vocal chords got
well-oiled at dinner.
You'd better go on up
and get the guest room in order.
Is he sleeping here tonight?
Yes, if the heir doesn't have
anything against it.
- Today was our day off.
- Put my duvet in the gable room.
We're just so excited.
One gets so nervous.
That's what happens
when you don't find a man in time.
Karl, go and break the necks
on some of your pigeons.
Ditte, fill them with beer.
And don't spill.
Can't we please take chickens?
I asked for pigeons.
And take some
with some meat on them.
Can't someone else kill them?
What a sissy son I have.
Let me do it.
Come here, come here,
you innocent, immaculate pigeon.
you're so warm and soft
in a moment you are lost
Easy, now. Quiet.
There, now it expired.
Can you take its innocent attire?
You won't ever get to be
a proper man.
Let me do it.
- You're a coward.
- Yes, but I'm so scared of mum.
I wish I could go to
a classy ball someday.
Don't you wish for that.
They're so sinful.
You and your sin, you bore.
- Soon it'll be a sin to eat.
- Listen to them.
They take pride in their disgrace.
They're not touching at all.
They're not even kissing.
You wouldn't know.
- You're just a child.
- You always say that.
There are so many things,
and everything is loathsome.
Ditte, bring those glasses.
What's with the swaying?
Sorry, mistress,
I think I got dizzy. I'm sorry.
She couldn't cope with
the smell of liqueur.
Or perhaps it was your cigar.
Do I not bring lovely sunshine?
and Ditte walks upon the road
so red and round and sad
she bumps into a little prince
in scarlet clad
What's your name?
I'm Ditte Love and Ditte Rascal
and Ditte Child of Man.
She isn't very pretty.
No, because she carries the most
pretty on the inside. Her heart.
But it's not in high regard, -
- so it's tucked away safely.
Can I see it?
We'd rather not,
because it may easily get dusty.
But you're welcome to have her.
Is that you, Karl?
Now the hawkers have left.
That scum.
Don't you think about them anymore.
That won't make anything better.
She didn't walk them to the cart.
Maybe she couldn't even walk.
Why not?
She drinks along with them.
- Maybe she even ...
- Easy.
I will give you
the little help I can.
Karl, do you believe
that old maids go to Heaven?
That depends on
how they've lived.
It doesn't.
My granny is in Heaven.
I suppose one has to make room
for the Lord as well.
Yes, for granny's sake, that is.
If only I were like you.
Why are we whispering?
Why indeed?
What have you got there?
My shoulder blade.
I got that from carrying
the little ones so much.
Is it a sin
to pray for beauty, Karl?
I wish to be a good girl, -
- but it wouldn't harm
to be a bit pretty as well.