Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org
You say that vessel does not belong to the Meltran?
Correct. During our previous battles, we found numerous objects...
...of Micron size in the wreckage of the enemy ships.
I shall show you.
Micron size.
Indeed, it seems these do not belong to Meltran.
Furthermore...
A number of our soldiers received strange sound signals near the enemy vessel...
...and became confused and unable to fight.
Unable to fight?!
What kind of power could they have aboard that ship?
MACROSS: DO YOU REMEMBER LOVE?
Check your A.S.K. and adjust it to the proper coordinates.
Delta-1 to ARMD-01.
Skull, Angel, and Apollo squadrons: Start your engines and standby to launch.
Thank you.
It is a love sign.
I love you, you love me.
But he has a crush on his plane.
Zoom, zoom. Zoom, zoom.
My boyfriend is a pilot.
Good evening, everyone!
I'm Lynn Minmay!
Tonight's my first concert...
...and I'd like thank everyone here for supporting me!
MINMAY!
Thank you.
It's been five months since our Macross left Earth.
During that time, many unhappy incidents have occurred.
But tonight, let's forget such sad things and enjoy ourselves!
And now, I'll sing a medley from my soon-to-be-released first album!
Remember, The silver wings that dance in the great sky.
Little white dragon.
Remember, The burning eyes that tore apart the darkness.
That man who came to seek the diseased city.
Evirus the Slayer! Slayer! Slayer!
Little white dragon.
Delta-1 to Skull, Angel, and Apollo squadrons:
Make a course correction to 308 + A15.
Enemy will be within firing range in 30 seconds.
Prepare to intercept.
Skull Leader to Squadron: You heard the lady.
Assume intercept formation 17.
Got it?!
Roger!
Got them!
Don't celebrate so soon.
Match their speed before firing at them. Now break formation and reverse thrust!
Roger!
3 of them?
All right.
Oh no!
Take them, Max!
Roger!
3 down...
Wow!
He's a real genius!
I can do that too!
Got them!
This is Delta-1.
A battleship just de-folded in Area 108, heading directly towards us!
Scanners detect a large number of incoming enemy battle pods!
Return immediately to intercept.
These battle pods were only decoys!
Delta-1 to Skull-11:
What do you think you're doing? You should be attacking the enemy ship!
Go to the coordinates I gave you!
Are you kidding?
I just saved your life! Is that the way to thank me?
Is that the way to speak to your superiors?
Follow my orders, rookie, or you'll be in the brig!
But they were going to blast you! I had to do something!
Let Defense Group 2 handle it! There's nothing to attack there!
That's an order!
No time for that!
I'm going after the pods that went into the ship.
Hold it!
Damn. Who does he think gives the orders here?
I wonder if we'll live thru the day?
It's more violent than ever today.
Minmay! Run!
What?
Zentran and Meltran!
Zentran and Meltran?
Zentran and Meltran in same place!
Unbelievable!
This is... Disgusting!
Gravity system #11 is malfunctioning!
Subsystem is also non-operational!
Course confirmed. Target locked on.
Energy level increasing. Main Guns, stand by.
FIRE!
It can't be?
Is it the real thing?
You're the one...?
Yes.
You rescued me, didn't you?
I... I'm Valkyrie Skull Squadron Pilot, Hikaru Ichijo... Ensign.
Thank you, Mr. Ensign.
No problem at all. I'm a big fan of you.
I'm pleased to meet you. Do you listen to my songs?
Y...Yes... All the time.
I guess everyone is worried.
So, Mr. Ensign, do you know where we...
Uh... could I have your autograph please?
What...? Oh, sure.
Here you are.
Thanks.
We fell into the engine block.
Is there any way out?
I'll go for a look.
I don't think there's any.
Can't you break down the wall?
That's impossible. It's made of hyper-carbon.
Just a sec...
There's too much static.
Can you use the plane's radio?
That's also damaged.
Oh.
Anybody?!
Is anybody out there?!
I guess not.
Well, that's OK.
I was tired of my over-booked schedule anyway.
At least I can relax now.
What's going on, Mr. Ensign?
Macross must be leaving Titan's orbit.
What?
Really.
The artificial gravity system is malfunctioning.
W...Wait, Miss Minmay! Don't move around so much!
No!
It was an accident!
A mistake!
Never mind! Do something!
Swing your legs forward and stop them slowly!
Like this?
Yeah, just move slowly.
This is fun.
Miss Minmay! Watch where you're going!
H...Hey!
Miss Minmay. Wait.
Damn, I forgot... I broke the flashlight.
Look. Look.
What do you think? I had it made just for the concert!
There's tuna and some vegetables floating around.
They must have been trapped here too.
Look, there's even a doll of me here.
Zero-G love, zero-G love!
On my way home from school with my boyfriend.
At the usual corner where we part...
Seeing no one's around...
He kissed me without warning.
I pretended to get angry at him... but...
My head dimmed, my heart pounded.
Zero-G love, zero-G love!
Four, three, two, one, zero-G love.
My body went floating away on the wind.
Our invasion troops report the unbelievable.
Microns exist inside the enemy vessel, as suspected.
Wait! Increase the magnification!
Those are Microns of Zentran and Meltran!
Yes. There's more evidence showing Zentran and Meltran in coexistence.
Disgusting!
I have a terrible premonition.
Our ancient combat manual says...
..."Do not interfere with Microns. Those who do will perish."
Perish?! Zentran's fleet will perish?!
Absurd.
Is this a Micron of a Micron?
It moves!
Get back!
Terrible sound!
Sound weapon!
Disgusting!
There's still no proof that they're dead.
Yes sir.
Let's try searching the western block today.
All right, good idea.
Excuse us.
That kid still hasn't been found yet, huh?
Well, he has been missing for three days now.
Maybe he got scared and deserted?
Have you considered that possibility?
Impossible.
He isn't the military type.
A boy will be unhappy all his life if he chooses the wrong job.
Well, what I mean is that he would probably do a lot better...
...if he chose another line of work.
You're always so critical about everything.
If you keep this up...
..."No one will ever want to marry me"?
That's all right.
Since I was a little girl, I've devoted myself to the service.
Not that again. Stop talking like an old maid.
But don't worry...
And then my mom and dad said...
"Don't you know how hard your brother works to take care of you?"
"If you don't behave, I'll disown you!"
So, I thanked them for taking care of me...
...and told them that I was going to work very hard...
...and one day become a famous singing star.
And then?
Then I left home and came here.
That's great.
But...
I think I was too hard on them.
I just hope that mom and dad are all right.
Are they on Macross?
They're on Earth.
Earth, huh?
Do you know what's been happening on Earth?
The official word is heavy radio jamming prevents us from making contact.
I mean, the truth.
The Earth was bombarded so heavily...
...that I doubt anyone remained safe.
I see...
But don't worry.
We'll be back in Earth in only a month.
Oh.
By the way, could I ask you something?
What?
The other day, on TV...
TV?
Yes. The TV show "For Nights When You Want to Cry."
There're rumors floating around about you and that other actor.
Did you believe those rumors?
They're only stories made up by the magazine publisher.
But... Is that true?
That love scene seemed so real.
Oh, come on...
I was only acting. It's business, you know.
No way!
Want me to show you?
Show me?
Oh, Hikaru...
I've loved you all my life.
Tell me you love me.
But...
You don't love me, do you?
Yes...yes, I do love you.
Do you, really?
Y...Yes, I do.
I'm so glad.
What a scoop!
Because you rescued Miss Minmay...
...the PR department told me to pardon you.
But any further disobedience of orders will lead to strict punishments.
Remember that.
What, do you have a problem with that?
No.
From now on you had better watch your conduct. Clear?
Is that clear?
Yes Madam!
Geez, is she really a woman?
You did it... you did it, Hikaru!
What's that, Senior?
You pick-up artist!
Boy, you did pretty good!
So, how did you enjoy our idol, Minmay?
Huh?
I didn't know you were such an unscrupulous character.
So tell us what happened.
I didn't do anything.
Liar!
Don't you actually think that we'll believe that?
You will have to accept the responsibilities.
But, I really didn't do anything at all.
Geez...
You didn't do anything to her in the 3 days you were alone with her?
Nothing.
What? And you still call yourself a man?
IDIOT!
"What was she doing with Valkyrie pilot Ichijo?"
"Has she outgrown her innocent girl image?"
Let me see... "Her mate was a pilot... a filthy relation?"
Just like I told you.
You're right.
No one's innocent anymore these days.
These movie stars are all the same.
I wonder what number he was?
How despicable, changing lovers like that.
You're actually jealous, aren't you?
Yeah.
I knew it.
But the truth is she doesn't understand anything.
That's right.
Minmay and Ichijo could have gotten out of the area...
...if they really tried to.
But they didn't.
Here lies the suspicion.
So why didn't they?
Commander, I've brought the patrol schedule chart for tomorrow.
Thanks. Why don't you have a drink with us before you go?
Well er...
It's okay. Come on, have a seat!
But...
I think I'll be going now.
Huh?
I don't want to be a bother to you.
Come on Hikaru. Your superior's trying to make room for you.
Come on and sit down.
OK.
What's with this indifferent attitude, Hayase?
You should try to relax and act more like a woman when you're off duty.
A person's habits are not always easily changed.
You've got a point.
Look, Hayase...
...even though you graduated top of the class from the academy...
...you're also a woman.
Even if what a man does is wrong, it's sometimes important to pretend he's right.
Hey, Hikaru!
Yes sir!
You're a man, aren't you?
If you want a girl, you must be prepared to go after her.
Don't worry so much about hurting her feelings.
If you really love her... be aggressive. Make her your own.
Ok.
Uh, Roy. You've said enough.
I'll show you how a man and a woman are supposed to act.
Open your eyes and watch closely.
Roy!
See, they both look speechless.
Aww... that's all right.
Roy!
Claudia...
Excuse me...
There's a phone call for Mr. Ichijo.
For me?
From a member of your family.
Family?
Hello. This is Ichijo.
Really?
G...Got it.
I'll be right there.
Bye then...
What's up, Hikaru?
T...There's a sudden illness in my family.
Excuse me.
Family?
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Darn. You can recognize me?
I'd know you anywhere. I have all of your pictures.
And I tried so hard to disguise myself.
Is it OK for you to be doing this?
Don't you want to be with me?
All right!
Tonight I'll take you out on the town!
Yeah.
I'm tired of it.
What?
My present life.
I suppose, if your dream is to become a star, you must endure a little.
It's so beautiful.
I wish I could go there.
But are you sure we can do this without permission?
I'm going to show something wonderful!
What?
Ready to go?
You can open your eyes now.
OK.
It's great.
It's the rainbow of Saturn.
Fantastic.
Britai 7018
Sir!
Your report has been analyzed.
Capture an enemy Micron as a specimen.
Understood!
What is he going to do with a Micron specimen?
Supreme Commander Boldoza must have a plan.
Report sir!
Reconnaissance reports appearance of a single Meltran vessel...
...crossing the primary warning line.
What?
How shall we respond?
Reinforce our defenses.
Do not let the Meltran near us.
Understood!
If we do not act quickly...
...it is possible that Meltran will succeed before us.
Understood. Begin the Micron capture operation immediately.
You walk indifferently ahead.
I follow you with a sulking face.
The shiny white beach goes on forever.
You say I love him...
But I love you more.
Always together on Sunset Beach...
Ocean breeze, big wave.
The one who's starting to occupy my heart...
Jumps around merrily.
Surf, sun, pendant.
Sunset...
No use hiding, Miss Minmay.
I'm sorry...
Lieutenant...
I'm amazed!
Using a Valkyrie for a personal trip?
It isn't Hikaru's fault. I asked him to take me!
Minmay! Come back immediately!
Brother...!
Ichijo!
If the media ever find out about this, it would be the end of her career!
The senior officers aren't going to excuse your behavior this time.
I understand. I'll accept my punishment.
What a soldier.
Now hurry and get back to the ship!
Yes sir.
Let's go home.
OK.
Oh, No!
An enemy attack!
I know!
Do something!
This is Lieutenant Hayase. Relay an emergency message to Commander Fokker.
Hikaru...
Don't worry.
I'll take care of them.
Oh no, I forgot this is a training plane!
WHAT...?
That's strange...
I wonder why they don't fire?
Dammit, stop teasing us!
Hey, Hikaru!
In trouble again, eh?
Senior!
But you did the right thing...
...you need to be aggressive like this to win that girl, you know.
Senior! You're drunk!
Idiot!
How can you fight a war if you can't handle some booze?
Great!
Oh no.
Yahoooo!
Did you see that, Hikaru?!
Oh no.
This is really bad.
What are they?
Your language is being translated.
Answer our questions.
How can male and female Microns co-exist?
Male and female Microns...?
What's this...
I wonder what they're after?
We have already found that Men and Women coexist on your ship.
What's the use in finding that out?
It seems their culture is different from ours.
Why don't you fight? Why did you become Microns?
Just as you are born giants we are born this way.
It's not something we choose.
"Born"?
Does "born" mean manufactured?
Manufactured?
Is that not correct?
Sort of. Man and woman cooperate to create.
Man and Woman cooperate?
Unbelievable!
Why do you not fight?
Are you kidding?
It's far better to hug a woman than to fight her.
"Hug"?
Show us what "hug" is.
This is a hug.
What do you think you are doing?
Do Man and Woman of your kind always do such terrible things?
Yes.. with kisses and everything else included.
"Kiss"?
Show us what "kiss" is.
Well...That is...
Minmay!
What are you doing?!
Show us what "kiss" is.
I'll kiss her! Let her go.
Very well.
Quick, act it out, or they'll kill us.
"KISS"!
Minmay...
Hikaru...
Imagine that...they freaked out when they saw a kiss.
It would appear that their men fight against their women.
Now's our chance. Everyone OK?
Yes.
Barely!
A Meltran invasion!
3 Microns have escaped in the confusion!
Put the ship on full alert!
Annihilate the enemy and recapture the Microns.
Pardon, Britai...
We still have two Microns in detention.
We must take them to Supreme Commander Boldoza.
We found them!
Yeah.
Hikaru! Kiss her!
What? Oh yeah. Sorry.
So cruel.
Hurry! Start the engines!
I know.
I have to rescue Minmay.
Weaklings...
Disappointing. Can't anyone match my fighting skill?
Wow...
It's a woman.
Men and women are fighting!
What's going on?
Hikaru!
Now's our chance to get out of here.
Right.
You will not escape, Micron!
Oh yeah?
SENIOR!
Get out of here! Go rescue Minmay!
If you say so...?
Hikaru...
Tell Claudia goodbye for me...
SENIOR!
Don't go.
Don't waste the opportunity his death gave us.
What?! You cold-hearted...
Minmay has a homing device. Follow its signal.
Roger.
Energy level rising.
Flagship coordinates calculations complete.
Long-range fold, stand by.
Minmay!
Hikaru!
It's Hikaru! He's come for us!
This is the...
A Fold! This ship's going to fold!
Minmay!
Hikaru!
Hikaru.
Minmay...
Where are we?
How should I know?
And the enemy vessel?
No sign of it.
I see.
In any case, we're on a creepy planet.
That looks like an ocean! Can you fly us out that way?
What's the point?
What?
Going there won't reunite me with Minmay.
What are you saying?
Minmay will probably be killed.
Just like Senior was.
If I hadn't take her out, this never would have happened.
But it's our duty to find where we are.
Duty! Duty!
Is that all you ever think about?
I understand.
I'll do it myself.
W...Wait, Lieutenant...
That was extremely stupid!
This is...
United Navy...Pacific Fleet... Offensive Aircraft Carrier...
The Prometheus.
How could it be?
This...
This is our Earth!
When the bell tolls at the midnight hour...
...the magic will disappear.
At the top of the stairs...
...is a pair of glass slippers.
Like Cinderella's love affair...
...mine's all controlled by the clock.
Everything that can tell the time...
Please stop...
...until day breaks.
Protoculture.
Protoculture?
The Micron's Culture is called Protoculture.
"Culture"?
Even I do not know much, except that it means:
"Creative activity that is not fighting."
Our Creators did not teach me anything about "Culture"...
...except for our programming...
"Never become involved with Culture."
That terrible sound is "Culture"?
That is "Song".
"Song"?
I am a Mobile Fortress that has endured...
120,000 cycles since my Creation.
In my many battles, I have not learned much of the "Culture" of Protoculture.
Except that "culture" can be very powerful.
This "song" may have the power to bring Meltran and Zentran together.
Such power?
Power that deprives us of our will to fight?
Yes.
What's this?
A "Fragment of Culture" that was captured a long time ago.
"Fragment of Culture"?
The two Protocultures may know what this "Fragment of Culture" is.
Tokyo was also destroyed.
The United Forces HQ at Alaska Base was buried in lava.
We haven't found one single survivor in a whole week.
So, where to now, Lt. Hayase?
London? Or maybe Paris?
How about New York?
Just give me your orders.
Stop it!
Please stop.
Here, it's cooked.
You haven't eaten a thing in 3 days.
At least eat a little.
I would rather die before I eat that.
I put the anti-radiation drug in the recipe.
So, a little bite of this won't hurt.
Survival is also a soldier's duty.
It doesn't matter anymore.
But we finally made it back to Earth.
And if Macross is safe, it'll be here soon.
Here...
Don't you understand?
Macross can't do anything even if it does get here.
Why?
There is no one left on Earth!
The people on Macross are still alive.
Earth is totally lifeless...
10 billion people were annihilated in just a few seconds.
How pathetic...
To be an officer of an army whose defeat is obvious.
But you're much tougher than I.
Commander Fokker told me...
Senior...?
That you don't have a family.
Your mother died when you were very young...
...and your father died in an accident.
He screwed up during an acrobatic maneuver.
"Zoom - splat." See.
So, you've lived by yourself until now?
I've just been an air race prize hunter.
I've flown planes since I was small.
But that's why you're holding up.
But not me.
I thought I was a soldier...
...who'd struggle for survival even if I were the last one left.
But look at me now.
I'm sorry...I...
What's that column over there?
Let's check it out.
It looks like it sunk a very long time ago.
Yeah.
It seems deserted.
But it looks like some of the devices are still working.
They're made for our size.
If it doesn't belong to the giants, then who...?
This is...
A fold communications system...
A fold communication?
It still works!
Maybe we can contact Macross with it.
But it'll be bad if the enemy intercepts our call.
I know, but we have to give it a try.
If Macross hasn't been destroyed, they'll answer.
No response.
It's probably damaged.
Maybe we pushed the wrong buttons.
Let's try the other ones.
"We have been waiting"?
Waiting for us?
You can understand it?
Yes...a little.
Who are you?
"The colonization vessel's central computer"?
No, we are people of this planet.
Genetic manipulation?
It disappeared.
Wait!
I still have some more questions!
It's diverting it's energy...
What did it say?
It's using the last of it's energy to raise the city.
Raise the city?
Yes.
We're moving!
Long ago...
...there was an interstellar civilization called Protoculture.
They were advanced in genetic engineering. Eventually...
...the men and women were able to reproduce themselves on their own.
The males separated to become the Zentradi...
...and the females became the Meltrandi.
The two groups started wars against each other.
That's when they created the giants...
...who only knew how to fight?
But when the giants' fighting became too intense...
...and they realized at last, their mistake...
...sought to start over...
...with men and women in co-existence.
So, they took refuge here on Earth.
After they arrived on Earth, they manipulated the genes...
...of the indigenous creatures to create our ancestors.
They created our ancestors...?
Yes.
I see...
Where did the people of this city go?
20,000 years ago the giants' fighting reached this solar system.
They sunk this city to hide it...
...and temporarily left the Earth.
But they never returned?
Right.
So, the computer mistook the Zentradi attack 6 months ago as their return.
...and raised the city?
So that we could live here in this city.
But after waiting 20,000 years, we're the only ones to return.
True...
Everything seems to be in ruins.
Yeah.
This is...
I wonder what this could be?
Did you find something?
There appears to be some kind of writing on it.
"Remember..."
"...remembering..."
"...do you remember...?"
I can't understand it that well. The language is more complex than the giants'.
I see.
This looks like it's just an ordinary house.
Let's go look somewhere else.
Huh?
I don't really have a reason, but...
I just want to...
I see.
Well, I'll just go have a look around.
I'll be right back.
Some things never change.
No one's here, as you'd expect...
...and all the machines are useless.
Welcome home.
I...I'm back...
So, shall we eat?
OK.
Please sit down.
I want to go home.
Where everyone is...
Ichijo...
Is it starting to move again?
No, this sound is coming from the sky.
The sky?
Macross!
Our transmission did reach them!
Yeah.
Misa Hayase and Hikaru Ichijo, reporting for duty, sir!
It's good to have you back.
What's the situation on Earth?
Yes sir.
During the period of a month...
we searched 15,000 kilometers of ground and this alien city...
...but found no survivors.
I see.
I'll have a detailed report later.
For now, I suggest that you two get some well deserved rest.
Yes, sir.
Did Roy...die gloriously?
Yes.
Thank you.
That's all I wanted to know.
Minmay...
It's strange, isn't it?
Minmay is somewhere so far away...
...and yet we can still hear her songs.
...her songs.
As though she were still alive.
Yeah.
It's nostalgic.
Nostalgic...?
It's only been a month since the time I took Minmay out into space...
...but it seems as if it was such a long time ago.
True.
The night makes the Gypsy violin cry.
A wine bottle and two glasses.
But my burning passion has nowhere to go.
Tonight I toast myself, in my loneliness.
Miria 639
Yes, Moruk Lapramiz.
The "Fragment of Culture" must be in the Protoculture ruin.
For our victory, seize control of this ruin.
Madam...I swear by the pride of Meltran, I shall not fail.
Enemy fighters approaching at sea level, heading 027 degrees.
We believe they are the all-female Meltrandi.
Only women? That sounds good.
They may be women, but don't underestimate them!
They might even be tougher that the Zentradi!
That's interesting.
Interesting?
What's the matter, Junior Lieutenant Ichijo?
You're acting like a chicken.
What?
Commander Max is right.
Maybe it's because he has a woman now.
Kakizaki!
So much for Protoculture.
Damm!
Missed!
Impossible!
Oh no!
This is unbelievable!
I won't let you escape!
A battleship!
Dammit, at this rate...
Minmay...?
What is this...?
Where's that singing coming from?
How can it be...? Minmay...?
Beautiful.
Beautiful...?
Meltran's fighting efficiency is dropping!
What?! It's not possible!
Is this the "Power of Culture"?
It is a success. Meltran has retreated.
Good.
If we can augment this "Song" what Minmay calls thy "Lyrics"...
...then we will be able to make Meltran surrender.
Captain...
The Zentradi are proposing peace talks.
Peace talks?
Captain Gloval will now make his official announcement.
Effectively September 11, 11:00am, U.N. SPACY SDF-1 Macross...
...and the Zentradi 425th Bodol Fleet...
...have agreed to peace.
And now, as a result of investigating this alien city...
...we have found that the aliens who build it were the descendants...
...of a highly advanced interstellar civilization called Protoculture...
...that prospered over 500,000 years ago.
Originally, we humans, the Zentradi and their enemy the Meltrandi...
...all had the same genetic structure as the Protoculture's.
We were created by the protoculture's advanced genetic science.
Please observe.
By utilizing the Protoculture's genetic engineering techniques...
...it is possible to change Zentradi back into humans.
These three gentlemen sitting with us now...
...are the Zentradi soldiers you have just seen.
They are a warrior race that knows nothing of culture.
They are split into two forces, the males and the females...
...and have been fighting each other for over 500,000 years.
I thought we were forbidden to receive...
...the Protoculture's broadcasting until the operation succeeds.
What is it?
Can you see those three?
The three Microns we sent to make peace with the Earthlings?
What about them?
I, Britai, have never seen a Zentran so full of Culture.
I wish I could become a Micron.
That's disgusting!
I am just joking with you.
"Joking"?
Do you not know?
No, I don't.
Minmay, the Protoculture taught me.
I think it means "I am lying."
Unbelievable!
And now, may I introduce the Galaxy's greatest superstar...
Lynn Minmay!
This melody you hear now...
...comes from an ancient Zentradi memory plate we decoded.
Unfortunately their memory plate did not have the lyrics recorded.
So, our song-writers on Macross...
...are writing wonderful lyrics to this melody right now.
And I wish to broadcast this song to the universe...
...so that we can negotiate for peace with the Meltrandi...
...and establish a warless, peaceful world.
We can take this first step toward peace...
...because of countless sacrifices people have made in the past.
We have all suffered through many unhappy times.
All of a sudden, many of our young people were forced into this war.
Some became prisoners of war.
And many others have lost their lives.
Now, hoping for a reunion of joyful tears...
...Lynn Minmay waits for some special people.
Chief Operator of our Forces, Commander Hayase...
...and Valkyrie Skull Squadron pilot Lieutenant Ichijo.
Hikaru.
Minmay.
Hikaru!
Hikaru! Hikaru!
"Girl in love"? "Season for dreams"?
None are good.
"Do you remember..."
"...eye to eye..."
"When our eyes met..."
Could this be...?
Coming!
Minmay!
You're very busy now, I suppose.
By the way, is the melody to the song finished...
Minmay!
I love you.
I don't know what happened on that island between you and that woman...
...but...
...but still...
I still love you.
Minmay...
I...
Commander!
What's this?
What do you mean?
Do you remember this?
Uhh... Yes.
This is the plate I found in the ruined city.
I found out it contains the lyrics to that melody.
That song?
I wanted you to confirm it first, but...
Wait a minute.
It's not what you think. You've misunderstood.
"It's not what you think?"
A misunderstanding?
I can't stand it.
I can't stand it!
Minmay!
Hurry and go after her.
You two were just reunited. Don't hesitate because of me.
It's more miserable to be receiving sympathy from you.
Things are not like that!
That's not what I was thinking!
When the two of us wandered on the uninhabited Earth...
...and barely made it back on Macross...
...and heard Minmay's song in town...
...and saw her on the screen.
That's when I knew.
The one who I want by my side forever...
...is you.
I still feel the same way.
Honestly?
There's no telling when I might get killed.
But if you don't mind someone like me...
What's wrong with me?
Isn't it strange, Hikaru?
Tears won't stop flowing from my eyes.
Misa.
Hikaru!
It's a Red Alert, priority one!
Take these lyrics to Minmay.
What! The "Lyric" is not ready yet?
Also, Lynn Minmay is missing.
Unbelievable!
The Meltran are de-folding.
You have to get Minmay to sing this song now.
Lapramiz's fleet has now de-folded.
If the song is incomplete, we cannot make Meltran surrender.
Therefore, we must annihilate them.
Targets: across and Lapramiz's fleet.
All Zentran ships prepare for battle.
It was only a short peace, after all.
Lift off immediately! Let's get out of here!
It started.
Fools, Bodolza!
Hikaru...
Minmay...
You came...
You came for me, right?
I want you to sing this song.
What's that?
Why must I sing the song that that woman found?
Due to the damage in the stabilization circuit...
...we can only fire once.
Understood. Prepare to fire immediately.
But there are tens of thousands of our own ships in the path of our gun.
No need to worry about that! FIRE!
WHAT!?
Unbelievable!
Even if I sing that song...
...there's no possible way we could win with such a thing!
If we're going to die anyway, just stay here with me.
It's not just our problem.
It's for everyone on board Macross.
That has nothing to do with us at all.
Why can't we be the only two people in the world?
Except for you and me...
I don't care if everyone else dies.
Senior died.
Kakizaki died.
They all died.
They had left many dreams that they wanted to be completed.
You can still sing, can't you?
I'm sorry, Hikaru.
I don't know what got into me.
I chose a singing career for myself.
And if I don't sing, my mother and father won't be able to rest in peace.
Minmay!
I'll sing with all my heart!
I hear your voice now, saying "come here".
When sadness is about to overcome me.
Now I see your figure, walking toward me.
As I wait with my eyes closed.
As I wait with my eyes closed. [What's that...?]
As I wait with my eyes closed. [Minmay's song!]
Until yesterday became now. [Strange... This song...]
My heart that was clouded with tears. [I feel as if I heard it a long time ago.]
My heart that was clouded with tears. [Why?]
My heart that was clouded with tears.
Do you remember that moment...
...when our eyes first met?
...when our eyes first met? [I understand.]
Do you remember that moment... [The culture in our genes is being awakened.]
...when our hands first touched? [What?]
...when our hands first touched? [After an Interval of 500,000 cycles.]
It was the first glow of love between us. [Can Culture be brought back to us?]
I love you so.
Britai 7018 to the commander of Macross:
We will protect you from now on.
Protect us?
We cannot allow the Culture of Protoculture to be lost.
To all listening to Lynn Minmay's song:
We have only one enemy.
Defeat Gorg Bodolza!
Bring Culture back to us!
Now I can see your eyes...
...even if we're apart...
Making my body warm up. [So, this is Lynn Minmay's song?]
Now I believe in your love.
Although you are far away, please protect me.
Until yesterday...
...my world was clouded with tears.
Do you remember that moment...
...when our eyes first met?
...when our hands first touched?
That was the first glow of love between us.
I love you so.
I'm not alone anymore.
Because you are here.
Do you remember that moment...
...when our eyes first met?
...when our hands first touched?
That was the first glow of love between us.
I love you so.
I'm not alone anymore.
Because you are here. [Main target is at A-133 Z-165.]
Because you are here.
I'm not alone anymore.
Because you are here. [PROTOCULTURE...!!!]
Because you are here.
Skull-1 to Delta-1:
Mission accomplished.
I'm heading home.
This is Delta-1: Roger.
Now the real hardship starts.
In this galaxy alone, there are supposed to be over a thousand fleets...
...led by mobile fortresses of Bodolza and the Lapramiz-class.
Probably.
But a single song could bring all this change.
We can only believe in the power of Culture.
What was that song?
Just a popular song.
A popular song?
Just an ordinary song that was popular...
...in an alien city tens of thousands of years ago.
Of course it was... a love song.
Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org