That'll be 8 and 6.
8 and 6 what?
8 shillings and 6 pence, madam.
-Shilling?
-Penny.
Perhaps I could do it.
Just take what I need.
No, no. If I'm to live in London
I've got to learn the money.
You're quite right.
-Excuse me, I'm sorry.
-I beg your pardon.
That'll be one of these,
and one of these.
It would be two of these,
wouldn't it?
I beg your pardon but I am in a hurry.
Perhaps I could be of some help.
Look,
the lady is going to live in England,
she's gotta learn the money.
What's the trouble here?
Oh, there's no trouble, officer.
I'm just learning about 8 and 6.
Can I help you, madam?
She's going to live in England,
she's got to learn the money.
That's right.
Gentlemen, do you mind
if I try once alone?
Now, two of these
make 5 shillings.
No, madam.
The large ones.
Those are florins.
They are only worth 2 shillings.
It's half-pence, pence, trapence, sixpence,
shillings, florins, half crowns.
And we call a shilling a bob,
six pence a tenner, and a pound a nicker.
A nicker?
This is ridiculous.
Why can't we all use the same money?
We had intended to.
But your American Revolution, you know.
Well.
That's far too much.
Believe me, your bearing did.
Fine.
Send them over here to the company flat
and I'll sign them.
Like it? I love it.
I think I'll keep it
and make the company find another
apartment to entertain them.
Is that all, Miss Hackett?
A cable from the Paris man?
Read that.
Mike, I found it.
It's a beautiful house.
I want him at that meeting.
Now you call this Mr. Simmons
and make that clear __ .
It's not exactly in the heart of town.
It's in Kent.
But it's only 3 miles out.
This Mr. Pickering is a beaut too.
Was my memo that hard to understand?
I told him to find some designers
so we could see what our wool
looks like on a pretty back.
So it's new for Bert Woolens.
If I'm going to take over this company
I wanna make a few innovations.
I'll talk to you tomorrow.
Aren't you excited?
-About what?
-About the house.
-What house?
-The house I found.
And honey, our furniture
will fit perfectly.
Of course, we __ will need
some new things
but I always have a ball
shopping for antiques in England.
Wait a minute, Janet.
Where did you find a house
in this part of London?
You haven't heard a word
of what I said.
It's in Kent.
Darling, you'll adore it.
It's has a big yard
and a beautiful garden.
And a brook.
We have our own brook.
And the real estate man said
that the train service into London
is marvelous.
Where did all this come from?
You were supposed to find
an apartment.
On this block if possible.
I told you this morning at breakfast
that I was looking in the country.
-You told me?
-I told you and you said "good".
You were reading the paper at the time __
but that's what it sounded like to me.
I said "good".
Well, you didn't exactly say it,
you grunted it.
But it was your good grunt.
It's perfect for us.
You'll just fall madly in love
when you see it.
I hope I didn't smash anything.
I'm trying to get the knack of
driving on the right side.
I'd suggest that one,
Mr. Elborn, the red roses go
against the south wall.
They are a bit keen on sun.
And it's left side going,
right side coming.
Are you about ready?
I'm gonna get the 9:23.
I'm ready.
I've got to drive way downtown.
Good.
Take it all the way to the station.
You're Janet,
I'm Vanessa Courtwright.
Here's a hunting prince
you can hide __
You're Mike.
Put that down there, gaby.
Throw your arms around me,
I'm your landlady.
You've been here a week.
I thought it was time I popped in.
I say you're positively handsome,
I'm gonna like you.
Thank you, Mrs...
From now on you're Janet,
and Mike, I'm Vanessa.
That way you'll be less likely
to complain when the house falls in.
It's a marvelous house.
It's just what we've always wanted.
God knows I never wanted it.
It was in my husband's will.
You are such a pretty thing.
You were meant for Mayfair.
I can't possibly see why you want
to live out here in the woods.
Amen.
We just love it out here.
And I have a million ideas.
Would you excuse us?
Janet, the train station.
Are you ready?
I've been ready for hours.
I won't be long.
I'll be right back.
Mrs. Ordley, will you make some tea
for Mrs. Courtwright?
Don't bother, I'll look around
and have some sherry.
I think it's in
one of these boxes.
Janet, honey.
Go on, madam.
I'll see you later.
The gardener gave me a shortcut.
He said we go by way of Twombley
and cut down over a mile.
Sorry.
Pretty soon you'll have more shirts
at the office than you do at home.
I was gonna bring some handkerchiefs
but I couldn't find any.
I hide them.
I keep hoping you'll the sniffle
and you'll have to come home.
I'll be home tonight, early.
You wanna bet?
You tell me that
every morning.
And every night
I reheat your dinner.
Honey, I said I'll be home.
That's if I ever get to work.
That must be the Twombley turn
up ahead.
I sure wish the train stops
at Bramble Heath.
I'm sure the station is
right around this next bend.
I hope so.
It has to be.
We're down the last Twombley.
It has been an hour and a half
and we haven't even seen a station.
What's the matter now?
I'm terribly sorry
to have to ask you to stop.
But it's the first cuckoo
of the season.
I wonder if I might ask you
to wait a mo.
I'm very late.
The slightest distraction and...
It's nesting.
Can we look?
I've never seen a baby cuckoo.
Tomorrow I may walk.
Good paved road ahead.
Probably the Pennsylvania Turnpike.
Sir, would you mind backing up
just a little, please?
Darling, if you don't mind
my saying so,
I think we should stop at that house
and ask
Darling, if you don't mind
my saying so,
it won't do us much good,
that's our house!
Would like to take a taxi to the station,
now we had to take a tour of England.
I'm sorry.
It could happen to anybody.
-I'll get the right direction.
-Don't ask that gardener.
It got to be 11,
we were wondering
if something had gone wrong.
You're a lifesaver.
Mike, look.
Somebody's dog.
Honey, my secretary's here.
Don't be scared.
I'll take care of you.
Your heart is just pounding.
I'm going in with her.
What kind of a pup...
You're a fox!
No wonder you were scared.
You're hiding.
I said down!
You should certainly
be ashamed of yourselves.
Madam, may we please
have our fox there?
No, you may not.
And you ought to be
ashamed of yourselves too.
Chasing a poor defenseless
little thing like this.
It's absolutely inhuman.
That's what it is.
Why don't you go chase yourselves,
see how you like it.
Could we compromise?
Yeah, I'll compromise
with you.
I'll keep the fox
and you get off my property.
It's very difficult for us
providing a fox.
Did you ever see
anything like that?
Frankly, no.
Tell me,
why didn't you get to the station?
Station?
Where is Mike?
He left.
He's been collected
by a very pretty chauffeur.
What?
I don't pretend to know
all the answers.
__ first two weeks anyway.
and I cannot blame the product,
that's damn good wool.
What I am gonna find out
is why nobody in Europe buys us.
The buying season starts with
the Paris fabric fair next month.
We're gonna surprise our mill
and come back with a few contracts.
Congratulations.
If you'll excuse me
I'll get back to work.
Mr. Simmons,
could you and I have a little chat?
Yes.
Hello.
Of course they're merely
__ to give you and idea.
This McDorfin design is
for town and country.
It shows __ black and brown
__ tweed.
Another McDorfin.
In purple and black tweed.
Why do we drown
these pretty ladies in wool?
Sir, we sell woolens.
Yes, but couldn't we hint
that there's a beautiful woman
somewhere in the vicinity
of the garment?
Do you mind?
Mrs. Harper.
Hi.
Hi, honey.
I've got so much to tell you.
I spent the whole day with Vanessa.
And we've just been everywhere.
She knows everybody
there is to know.
By the way, we get our phone
first thing in the morning.
Good. you'll be able to call here
more often, dear.
Oh, Mike, Vanessa's been
so helpful.
She even arranged
to establish our credit at the market.
At the Armongers.
Do you know what that is?
It's a hardware store.
That's one of the reasons
why I called you.
To tell me a hardware store
is called Armongers?
No. I want you to bring
a 3-pronged plug.
Where am I gonna find
a 3-pronged plug?
There must be one
somewhere.
I'll try.
Goodbye, Janet.
Goodbye, darling.
9 pence?
I wish it were 8 and 6.
Wait a minute, operator.
That's three cabbage copper ones.
And one silver one.
Yes, I know, operator.
I know it's the size of an American dime,
but I just don't have one.
Can you take an American dime?
Tell me why we're so good
at not selling wool.
I'm a salesman,
and quite good.
I'm sure we don't have
any bad one.
Tell me why all these wonderful
salesmen are all avoiding our contract.
We were for Bert Woolens.
Willy Langsdorf
does not like Bert Woolens.
Willy Langsdorf?
Is he the only customer
on the continent?
He's the only one
that counts.
Ski pants Langsdorf.
Two million pairs a year.
He doesn't buy,
the others wonder,
they don't buy.
they follow him
like little ducks.
That narrows it down.
What does this Langsdorf have against us?
You.
And all the other men
that sat at that desk.
There's something about Bert general managers
that keep shutting us out of doors.
No man...
But a good salesman
should break doors.
Not in Europe.
It's bad taste.
They don't buy and sell in Europe.
They play it buying and selling.
And you must play harder
that anybody else.
You must make the name Bert
something to remember with a smile.
Thank you.
You really know your martinis.
I'm getting back into practice.
This recipe for doing business,
was a secret all these years?
No. But once they put it __
something always goes wrong with it.
Parsons, the man you replaced,
he went to Paris last year,
__ intentions,
and promptly died from a bowl of bouillabaisse.
McGregor before him
brought his wife to the Paris meeting.
Wait a minute.
You're losing me.
Something Langsdorf started.
If you want to be part of his crowd
you do not bring your wife.
If you're afraid of being alone
you can always bring a... friend.
But not your wife.
Make it sound like
an army reunion.
It's fun and games.
Absurd, ridiculous, childish?
Yes.
But it's also ski pants.
Two million a year.
__ even crack __ buy.
Not to be __ disregarded
the care and feeding of the __
In fact there's one in London
right now just for a few hours.
Culkos, a Greek manufacturer.
He should be entertained tonight.
Oh, no, wait a minute.
My wife's planning a quiet dinner tonight.
My first evening home
in four days.
There is an evening
tomorrow night.
That card table looks so silly.
It's the first thing on my list,
a Georgian dining set.
Perfect.
By the way, madam
the lamb's on.
Is it that late?
I better get dressed.
What are you doing
eating my plants again?
You'll never __ a goat, madam.
if you keep feeding him all the time.
I know.
Don't forget the candles.
Giving some sort of a holyday?
I hope so.
Oh, Wellington, what on earth!
Now, you go out.
It was a pleasure,
Miss Hackett.
You made my short stay in London
most enjoyable.
Thank you.
I'm seeing Langsdorf this weekend.
And I must tell him.
A man with Bert Woolens
who can order a wine.
Thank you. Have a nice flight.
I've put all the food away.
__
That's very sweet of you.
I want you to go,
you have your right.
Thank you, doctor.
we were simply fascinated
by your thrilling discussion
of the rock formations
in Central Peru.
Next week professor Smithers
will bring us an exciting lecture
on Babylonian writing utensils.
And now music for cogitating
with the Ochney highland bagpipes.
I guess I can just __
last train.
My car knows the way to Kent.
Mine doesn't even know
the way to the station.
Is a secretary of 2-weeks standing
allowed to be proud of her boss?
I'd like to tell __
You're a goat.
Mike, is that you?
It was me,
before I was electrocuted.
Are you hurt?
Half a million volts
never hurt anybody.
That's why I tortured you
to bring a 3-ponged plug.
And you certainly
took your time finding one.
The telegram explained.
What telegram?
I sent you a wire.
Well, where is it?
I haven't the faintest idea.
But I've got a better question.
Is there some reason
we have a goat in the living room?
His name is Wellington.
That explains why
he was in the living room.
I don't know why
he was in the living-room.
The last time I saw him
he was out in the back
nibbling an empty paint can.
I didn't have
very much to do this evening.
So I thought I would
touch up a few things.
Do you have to paint
everything inside?
I didn't paint
everything inside.
I painted the bread box, a __ table
and that chair you're sitting on.
Janet, look at that!
What else you got planned for tonight,
a flood maybe?
You had to pick __
house in the country.
What is wrong
with a house in the country?
Nothing if it's the same country
I live in.
A million apartments in town
and not many of them come with goats.
Does it make any difference
where we live?
I mean, really?
Janet, I'm tired.
You never wanna talk.
I don't feel like arguing.
Why not?
It'll be the first time in 3 years
that we communicated.
Even your telegrams
don't reach me.
I want to have an argument.
You have an argument,
I'll __ the bed.
I guess I'll have to face it.
All I am to you is a wife.
Of course you're my wife,
That was the general idea
when we got married.
It's been 5 years.
Is that a reason to take me
for granted?
You do, you know.
You don't even remember
our anniversary anymore.
It's today?
No, it's not today.
Then why do you bring it up?
Because it's typical,
that's why.
What happens to marriages
after 5 years?
We used to go shopping together,
do things together.
When I bought a new jersey
you admired it.
When I had my hair done
you told me it looked nice.
Okay, so you've got nice hair.
Just because I forget to say a few things
doesn't mean I take you for granted.
All I know is
the way things are with us now
I'd be rather
honeymooning __ alone.
Why not? You'd probably spend
the whole trip
painting the hotel room.
You know something?
You make it sound tempting.
And what does that mean?
Whatever you wanted to mean.
Are you suggesting a divorce?
Three o'clock in the morning
is no time to be telling your husband
you're drifting apart.
I'll get it.
It's another fox
looking for a place to stay.
That's very funny.
And don't do me any favors,
I'll get it.
You would, wouldn't you?
You would let me go down there
all by myself.
All right, we'll both go.
__
Let me tell you __ about life
Mrs. Ordley is sleeping.
Mrs. Ordley __ my words.
What about me?
Have you ever considered the fact
that I'm here in work?
Doesn't that bother you?
That's why we have this house.
So you can relax on weekends.
How do you relax in a warehouse?
While I am home I keep
dreaming of the plumber, the carpenter
the plasters...
We have more help than
__ hotel.
Maybe __
once in a while.
Telegram for Mrs. Harper.
Thank you.
Well?
It's from you.
It says you won't be home
for dinner tonight.
I am sorry I yelled.
I am sorry too.
You know something?
This house does look
like a warehouse.
Darling, I will try very hard
and maybe next weekend I'll be able to play
country squire.
You're panting.
You put on a little weight.
That's a terrible thing to say.
Put me down.
Who ever heard of a honeymoon alone?
I forgot, honey,
the door is __
The carpenter over here
first thing in the morning
take all the hinges off
__ down
I'll tell Mr. Belari that you were in.
He'll be devastated for not being here.
I've just got to get
that house in order.
Are there any other antique dealers
that we might visit today?
Paul Belari is the only one.
If he doesn't have it here
he'll have it in one his other shops.
I mean, he'll do your house
in half the time.
I hope so because my husband
is very uncomfortable.
Do you know that he stayed in town
two nights this week?
At the company flat.
And I must say
I just don't blame him.
I never used to let my Archie sleep out
except for 3 years during the war.
Then I didn't think it was proper
to make a fuss.
If we have nothing better to do,
we might as well have tea.
Yes, we might as well.
It's too early for martinis.
I've got a marvelous idea.
Why don't you drop in
on Mike?
Mrs. Harper?
I'm so sorry
to have kept you waiting.
That's all right.
I was just admiring
your lovely fabrics.
Mr. Harper is at the company flat.
I called. You'll be very welcome.
I don't think so.
Thank you, Ms. Hackett.
I'm Ms. Lynch.
What happened to Ms. Hackett?
-Ms. Hackett is his assistant now.
-I almost forgot about that.
-Everything all right?
-Excellent.
You are doing a marvellous job.
Thank you.
Excuse me, lady,
would you mind telling me why
we drove around the block one extra time?
I just want to get as close as possible
to 8 and 6.
8 and 6!
It's all I've learned,
8 and 6.
Thanks.
Thanks very much.
-I'm Mrs. Harper.
-I know, I'm Ms. Hackett.
-Oh, hello.
My husband asked me to come up.
__
I didn't think you really wanted to come.
It's a dull gathering.
It doesn't sound dull.
-It's so nice to see you again.
-Thank you.
The last time I saw you
you were holding a fox.
Do forgive me, Mr. Sharod
is looking for the vermuth.
May I have your coat?
Thank you.
Excuse me.
I've got a surprise visit.
-Darling.
-Hi!
The office said I should come up.
Sure it's okay.
-Mr. Harper, I have to leave.
-Oh, I'm sorry.
You go on, sweetie,
I'm fine.
Good afternoon.
Thank you very much.
-What is this?
-Smoked yak.
It is the favorite food of my people.
Mr. Harper knows how to please.
Yes, he does.
Marvelous.
Actually I think the smoked yak
is better than the regular yak.
You like our kind of food.
There is a cafe in soho.
Perhaps this evening
you and I could...
-Honey, you all right?
-I'm doing fine.
You and Mr. Harper are...
Too bad. I was going to suggest another place.
In Kensington.
Very romantic music.
It is the music of the desert...
-Sorry Mr. Harper.
-Don't worry about it.
Claire, honey, will you give me
a handkerchief?
Someone always has to spill a drink.
And poor Mike never has a handkerchief.
I bought him half a dozen.
I knew they'd come in handy.
Don't worry about it.
It's a very simple matter.
Simple?
Of course. Mike isn't the only
unfaithful husband in the world.
I bet there are plenty
running around London now.
They could elect their
own member of parliament.
I don't care about the others.
Naturally.
You have a fine husband, my dear.
I'd go for him myself.
We'll get it back.
Who shall we use for you,
Teddy or __
I don't want a lawyer.
You are not going to hire a lawyer.
We're going to find you a lover.
-A what?
-A lover.
Vanessa!
What would I do with a lover?
Among other things
use him to get your husband back.
-Good morning.
-Who sent the flowers?
-Vanessa.
What's the big occasion?
If you wanna know the truth
you're supposed to think
they are from a secret admirer
and become very jealous.
I asked her not to do it.
Thanks for telling me.
One of us should be honest
__ both bored, don't you think?
Janet, I've got the sneaky feeling
you are trying to communicate again.
Do you mind if I have
some coffee first?
Didn't you think I'd find out?
I mean, sometime?
-Find out what?
-About her.
I saw her clothes at the flat.
Whose clothes?
Claire Hackett's. That's whose.
A whole closet full!
Wait a minute.
You don't mean the six outfits
from the showing.
No, I don't mean...
What showing?
I'm in the wool business.
We have showings.
How suspicious can you get?
That's why you left the party
so suddenly.
When do you find time
to be suspicious?
One fashion show and then
you and your little grumbling buddy
are off and running.
If you'd examined the clothes more carefully
you would have seen the tags on them.
They looked like her size.
How __
Why didn't you ask me?
Oh, no, you had to run
after little Miss Dorothy __ of Mayfair.
They were her style too.
Here's a package for Mrs. Harper.
I'll tell you what I'm gonna do.
I'll Have a shower, shave, get dressed
and plan my lecturer's pursuits for the day.
And she doesn't have to buy
your handkerchiefs anymore either.
Elisabeth in love, poems.
Yesterday it was perfume,
the day before __
A real lover...
I mean, a real lover,
just wouldn't be this obvious.
You sound as furious.
I could get very angry
if I didn't know that
this was just also stupid.
Have you told Vanessa
that I'm going to Scotland?
She could take a __
She doesn't have to go through all this trouble
because I won't be here to be jealous.
Hello.
Hello!
That's a part of your little game?
What game?
Vanessa certainly
wouldn't go that far.
I could have driven you.
I'm getting very good at it now.
Hello.
Hello!
There must be something wrong
with that telephone.
Or one of us has
a very bashful friend.
I'll call you from Scotland.
Have a good flight, sweetie.
And don't eat anything
Remember you get __
Mr. Larson.
Good bye!
I'll take that.
She's getting bolder,
sending cards now, huh?
__ Paul Belari.
Mike!
You forget your bag!
Belari?
Cecil Graves.
May I help you, sir?
-Where's Belari?
-He's at an auction, sir.
You give him a message
from my card writer.
Tell him to stop pussyfooting around my wife
or he'll be taking up teeth
all over London, okay?
I may not see him
before I leave today.
Would it be all right
if I left him a note?
-What are you doing here?
-You forgot your bag.
I was gonna send someone for it.
You also forgot to read
the other side of the card
that came with the flowers.
What?
I have never met Paul Belari.
He was coming to the house
for the first time.
He couldn't keep his appointment
so he sent flowers.
I miss appointments
and I don't send flowers.
But he is different.
He is continental.
Well, I'm sorry.
Why didn't you tell me before?
I nearly __ with the little man
at Belari shop.
Oh, no. That nice Mr. Graves?
You didn't hurt him.
How can you hit a little man
who wears a wing collar?
The florist I got the __ from.
The florist too?
Let's forget him.
I made a fool of myself, okay.
What do you know?
Vanessa's game worked!
You really believed
those gifts were sent to me
from an admirer.
Why would I believe
a thing like that?
Well, you did.
And I think I'm glad.
I'm glad
you think you're glad.
Hello.
I'm Paul Belari.
-You are Mrs. Harper.
-Oh, yes. I'm Mrs. Harper.
I'm pleased to meet you.
-I thought that you were at an auction.
-I was.
I do wish you would have phoned.
I thought of it.
But after your husband's visit to my shop
I was very ques to see you.
But maybe you wouldn't have
wanted to see me.
To die at you husband's hands,
without really knowing why or for whom,
wouldn't be fair.
My husband is awfully sorry
about all that.
He just feels terrible.
I respect a man who fights __
Shall I get to work?
I don't know now
because of the circumstances and all..
The circumstances are past.
We can start with this room.
It seems to need a little help.
Or any room.
Some of the animals in the neighborhood
seem to have adapted to us.
This will be very interesting.
Fascinating
Look, it's a Georgian dining room set.
I recognize it from my
decorator's book.
A good copy.
It looks antique.
We could fix it up or...
Strip it and...
Do you want a copy?
All I want is to have
my anniversary dinner
on a table
that doesn't wobble.
With that you eat.
With true Georgian you dine.
We must find you
Georgian __
George, go through this list, will you?
-I'll get __ to the mill.
-Okay.
-Claire.
-Come in.
You got ready __ mill.
That's appropriate for a mill.
Well, we can't work 24 hours a day,
can we?
I thought the nights were cool
in Scotland.
A little higher, please.
This room looks so summery.
I just love it.
You deserve
an extra special lunch.
We'll have lunch in Paris.
In Paris?
-He said "Paris".
-He did, madam.
Charming city, Paris.
Some things I bought recently at the riviera
have arrived to my Paris shop.
There is a Georgian
dining room set.
-True Georgian?
-Of course.
For dining?
You can look at it
if it pleases you.
But I can't go to Paris.
Why not?
Paris is only an hour away.
We could be back by 6 or 7.
But it's another country!
-Isn't it?
-Oh, yes.
Ever since
William the Conqueror.
But you know that
when I go on my first trip to Paris
I have to go with Mike.
It is only a thought.
And I am expecting the plumber.
Good reason.
I mentioned it only
because of your anniversary.
Never mind.
For the next anniversary
you will have you dining set.
Mrs Ordley could take the plumber,
couldn't she?
I don't know.
I can't go.
Paris.
Why not!
To Paris.
__ if it tickles your nose.
It does tickle my nose.
This is very early in the day.
There are no hours for champagne.
Nor is there a limit.
Thank you.
Well, this is my street.
It's not the most fashionable street
in Paris.
Oh, I love it.
It's real.
Here we are.
Open Sesame.
-It didn't open.
-It's locked.
Ali Baba had a key.
He pretended not to, but he had one.
-Where are we going?
-To my concierge, to get the key.
Oh, monsieur Belari,
mais quel surprise.
Maman, j'ai fini.
Allez, dépechez vous.
Allez vite vous habiller.
Oú est Alfred?
Alfred must be the husband.
They are getting dressed
to go visit their grandmother
and Alfred is helping her
from the bistro across the street.
Hello.
Bonjour, ça va?
Bonjour, ça va.
-Madame Belari?
-Non, ma petite.
Votre fiancée?
Non, elle est Madame Harper.
Elle est américaine.
Américaine?
Oui.
Vous connaisez Rock Hudson?
Cary Grant?
Daniel Boone?
Elle est pas américaine.
Thank you.
Merci beacoup.
Est-ce que vous avez la clef?
What a family!
He wants to share it with you.
Thank you.
That's wine!
Of course, it's wine.
I thought he'd be drinking coke
or something.
No, wine!
It is a mother's best friend.
No, thank you.
To refuse is an insult.
Drink, drink.
Well, a little help
for our relations.
Au revoir!
I've got to admit
you made them very happy.
They made me happy.
Open.
Look at this bed.
It's an exact copy
of Josephine's bed.
Is it really?
How do I look?
-How do you feel?
-Like Josephine.
I'm so pleased.
Can we take on the plane
with this?
Perhaps we can put it
under the seat.
I don't even care
how much you cost.
It isn't too expensive, is it?
But for you...
Madame Harper,
the dinner was superb.
Now let's have lunch.
Oh, thank you.
I like this place.
Madame, enchanté.
What did he say?
You're a very good kicker.
Pick up your glass.
What are you doing?
I want to bring a toast. To you.
Your first trip to Paris.
-Bottoms up!
Are you hungry?
I am too.
The only word that I know
of that song is "au revoir"
I'm very glad
that's all you know.
Why?
It's a men's song.
__ gay.
Is it really?
Like what?
Come on, it can't be that bad.
__
When papa leaves maman
he just says
"au revoir for a while"
but she knows he'll return
so she waits wild
the home fire is burnt
au revoir is
good bye with a smile.
Is that it?
That's not as gay!
This is my version.
Now give me their version.
__ of new blueprints.
Would you like to initial them?
__ wrap it up.
Tomorrow is my wedding anniversary
and I may just surprise my wife
by remembering it.
Thank you, John.
Hello, Janet.
She's gone off to Paris, sir.
She said she'd be here about 6.
__
I'll leave a message.
Good bye.
All right, thanks.
What's she doing in Paris?
I can think quite a lot of things.
Thanks a lot, George.
Don't worry. She may have gone
to buy perfume, clothes...
She wants to look nice
for her anniversary.
Are you kidding?
Downtown __
There are two things my wife can't take:
downtown anywhere and a second drink.
♪ When papa
♪ leaves maman
♪ she just says
♪ "au revoir for a while"
♪ But she knows
♪ he'll return
I beg your pardon.
Where do they think they're going?
Home.
It's getting foggy out.
Home!
Just in time to get
to the airport.
I'm gonna get a taxi, Paul.
Taxi!
Janet, where are you?
I'm looking for a taxi.
Janet, you'll get lost.
Don't worry about me, Paul.
I can see perfectly.
You see?
You're not Paul.
My name is Alphonse, mademoiselle.
-Au revoir.
You're beautiful.
This isn't you either.
Keep on talking, I'll find you.
Would you like
to come home with me?
Wellington will love you.
He's a goat.
I should have known
you would end up with another pet.
Let's get back to the shop.
Wait a minute.
Au revoir, beautiful.
Give me your hand.
That was fun.
I will call the airport.
Watch the steps.
Four.
You wouldn't have found me so quickly
if it hadn't been for that horse.
Your trip to Paris
will be longer than you expected.
I will call a hotel for you.
Why do I need a hotel?
I spoke to the airport.
It will not be clear till morning.
They don't know
what they're talking.
The Ritz. You'll like that.
We're gonna leave
for the airport right now
and we'll get there
before it clears.
Janet, don't go outside.
I know all about fog.
It comes and goes.
Paul.
How did it happen?
Don't tell me it's locked.
My concierge must have __
while I was calling the airport.
Well, call him and tell him
to pull it up.
No, he doesn't have a telephone.
And it can only be opened
from the outside.
Well, that's simple.
Go outside and open it.
What are you laughing about?
I've never been locked in my shop
with a woman before.
With no way out.
You're not serious.
Yes, I am.
Because the shutter on the back door
is even thicker than that.
Don't you worry
about a thing.
Where is the telephone?
I remember that.
I'm gonna call Mike.
I'll tell him what happened.
He'll be laughing all over __
Hello, Mr. Harper.
I just come __ a warmer coat.
Did the missus get our note
all right?
No. It was a very nice note.
Is something wrong, sir?
Isn't she home yet?
Where is she?
I don't know
and you don't know.
She said she wanted
to be back by 6.
That's what she kept telling
the gentleman.
What gentleman?
Operator, are you sure
you checked out that hotel?
Maybe he's going home.
Will you try my home, please?
What?
You don't know my number.
Good evening.
Mike, what do we owe this visit to?
You know __
How do you do?
__ where I can find
your furniture buddy, Belari, in Paris?
Will you have a drink?
I don't want a drink.
I want to get to my wife.
You mean Janet is in Paris?
Janet is in Paris with that sex maniac
you dropped in our lap.
Please, Mike,
Paul Belari is a gentleman.
A sophisticated __ gentleman.
Do you think that's a drawback
if you're a sex maniac?
What's his address?
You are jumping to conclusions.
All right, Janet is in Paris.
Why do you think she went there?
For a loaf of French bread?
If you spent
a little more time with her
you'd know that Janet
could never do anything wrong.
That's why I wanna see her.
I wanna spend some time with her.
What's his address?
Excuse me, operator,
will you just keep ringing?
♪ For a while
Pardon me, op.
Will you just keep ringing?
Just keep on ringing.
It sure is hot.
Operator?
One more tingling?
What?
All right.
There's nobody home.
Paul! Let me out of here!
Where have you been?
I think I had enough.
Shall you forget where you are?
In Paris no one ever has enough
of champagne.
And do you know why?
Champagne is a drink of romance
and romance is
the soul of Paris.
That's really pretty.
To Paris.
To love.
It tickles.
To the Eiffel Tower.
One week ago
we had not even met
and here we are,
locked away from the rest
of the world.
It'll be a night to remember.
I think I'm gonna be sick.
Sick?
No, Janet.
You wanna bet?
We are in Paris!
Janet, you can't.
You're awake.
Good morning.
This will make you feel better.
I'll never drink anything
containing bubbles.
Don't be silly.
What happened last night?
You had too much champagne
and after the champagne...
Never mind, don't tell me.
If you just drink this,
it'll make you feel much better.
Nothing to be upset about.
Maybe a hot coffee.
Why did you let me...?
Mike!
Husband?
I will explain everything.
Happy anniversary.
Mike!
Monsieur Langsdorf, telefon.
Er hat gesagt "es is nichts neues".
C'est moi.
My wife from Viena.
She wishes to know
if I have arrived safely.
I'll be right back.
I've got meetings most of the __
__
Not a call for you.
Fine. I'm very positive.
I don't know what this is all about
but I think you ought to speak to her.
Listen, I've already wished her
a happy anniversary.
Langsdorf.
Mr. ski pants himself.
We want to be getting invitations to the party,
we'd sell some wool.
George, we shall be there.
Mr. Langsdorf,
you haven't met Mike Harper.
How are you doing?
We already know him
from our friend Culkos here.
He doesn't look like
__ full of bouillabaisse would kill him.
I can hold the bouillabaisse.
And just for desert
a little Sachertorte might be nice.
You know about our great Viennese desert.
I'm very big with deserts.
Alicia Petrova.
Something even better
than Sachertorte.
You must come to our party
this evening.
Thank you, I'll be there.
Perhaps I can help you
with a companion for the evening.
I don't really think
that'll be necessary.
If you'll excuse me,
I have a meeting.
He doesn't need a companion.
He must have his own
delicious little pastry.
I met her in London.
For a personal assistant
she is a pastry.
Huh, Simmons?
That she is. Excuse me.
We shall see it tonight.
__
You are right that he is different
for one of the Bert people.
London, Please.
I'd like to speak to Ms. Claire Hackett.
That's Mayfair, 3925.
Mr. Mike Harper's room?
I'll see you tonight. Bye.
I'm sorry, madam.
We do not give room numbers.
But you don't understand,
I'm...
-Mr. Simmons.
-Mrs. Harper.
So nice to see you.
Is Mike in his room?
I've got to talk to him.
Come with me.
We got a terrible misunderstanding.
Where are you taking me?
Mrs. Harper, I don't like
to __ people's personal lives.
But it would be best
if you returned to Kent.
Kent! I don't wanna go to Kent.
I'm going to talk to Mike.
He's not in the talking mood.
Then he'll just have to listen.
I'm gonna sit right here
and wait for him.
We can't have that.
You have met Ingrid.
She is the foreman of our Gothenburg plant.
And your friend?
This is she.
Excuse us, please,
we are very late.
Mr. Simmons, I don't know
what all this is about.
And what did you mean by
"this is she"?
It's difficult to explain.
I couldn't introduce you
because you are a... wife.
Of course I'm a wife.
It's a rather ridiculous thing
but men don't bring their wives
here to this free days.
What kind of nonsense is this?
It is nonsense.
It's also a fact.
I don't believe it.
They're all...
The plant foreman?
Yo no sabía cual vestido comprar.
Entonces compré todos.
-She?
-She is.
No, I don't think so.
That is not likely.
I don't know when you find time
to hold meetings.
Sometimes it is rather difficult
to get a quorum.
I have not met this jewel.
How would I forget her?
Mr. Langsdorf, this is...
Well, you met Mike Harper...
Oh, yes, the personal assistant.
You must come to my party tonight.
Don't disappoint me.
That was close.
Claire Hackett is in London.
Take the first plane back and see.
I just can't go home.
At least not until I talk to Mike
and I explain him what happened last night.
You don't know,
he's just furious with me.
Maybe the __ clerk will know
where he is.
He's not here.
He won't be back until the party.
Then I'll go to the party.
That's impossible.
It would absolutely ruin Mike
if they found out he was here with his wife.
Then they won't find out.
What?
Mr Simmons, leave everything to me.
__
-__ where is she?
-I haven't the slightest idea.
Wait a minute.
I didn't answer her calls this morning
but now I'm getting really worried.
I thought I __ you on the chin.
Where did you get the shiner?
After you cl __
me on the chin,
Janet insisted that
I ran after you and explain.
I refused and she...
Janet?
-You're kidding.
-No, I'm not kidding.
It's pretty funny.
You're right,
it is pretty funny.
What I've been through
only because your wife
wanted a dinning room set
for your wedding anniversary.
That's why she came here!
That's why she came here.
And she's probably on her way home.
Right now.
Wedding anniversary.
Come on.
Let's have lunch.
And I'll tell you all about
our glamorous night in Paris.
Ich und du
Müllers Kuh
Müllers Esel
der bist du
Pardon me,
is Mr. Harper __ yet?
I am sorry, mademoiselle,
His key is still here.
Thank you.
Which one is yours?
I beg your pardon?
Who is your man?
Mike Harper.
Nice.
Don't be surprised
if I steal him from you.
Room 207, please.
Operator, Simmons here.
Do you have a call for me?
Look, I'll call you back.
Thank you.
In the name of
Bert Woolens
I forbid you to go
to that party.
I am not leaving until
I've seen my husband.
Mr. Simmons, this is much more
difficult for me...
So good to see you.
I'm looking forward to
our meeting tomorrow.
I've seen some of your fabrics and
I'm really anxious to talk to you about them.
So am I.
This is monsieur Renard.
This is Claire Hackett.
How do you do?
Excuse me.
May I have your coat?
I am overjoyed
that you came to my party, Ms. Hackett.
Thank you.
That's what I call an assistant.
Mr. Langsdorf.
You are quite a salesboy
for Bert Woolens.
I think I'll switch to you.
That's wonderful!
I don't know how to thank you.
I do. Come to Vienna.
Be my assistant.
That's very nice
but I can't leave Mike.
I haven't met this lovely creature!
You had too much champagne tonight.
You met her in London,
Claire Hackett!
This Claire Hackett is not the personal assistant
that I met with Harper in London.
I know Harper. He probably calls
all his personal assistants
Claire Hackett.
It is very strange.
-May I?
-Two minutes.
-Mr. Langsdorf...
-Please, call me Willy.
Willy, I'm exhausted
and if you don't mind
I'd like to go to the powder room.
Of course.
After this is over
I'm giving a party in my own suite.
Just for very few people.
I don't know.
I won't let you go
until you say yes.
Yes.
Mike!
-Where have you been?
-What are you doing dressed like that?
__ with Paul, he told me everything.
-Just don't wait to hear my side of the story...
-Everything.
You don't know
what I've been through.
Yes, I do.
Tell me something.
It was a left hook or a right crossed.
A right crossed.
That's what I figured.
You know Belari's left eye
is glorious black and purple?
Well, the swelling
came down.
But the price of the dining room set
went up.
You bought it?
-Don't you love it?
-I love you.
I don't care what Langsdorf thinks
about wives.
Honey, Langsdorf doesn't think
that I'm your wife.
He thinks I'm your... you know.
No, I don't know.
They all think that
I'm your personal assistant,
Claire Hackett.
-Cut it now.
-They do.
Why would they think
a thing like that?
I don't know.
You mean you think Claire Hackett is here?
Honey, Claire Hackett is in London.
Would I lie to a woman
with a punch like yours?
Don't you think we better
get back to the party?
go up to the room
for a little glass of champagne?
Yes, I do.
But you should make an appearance.
Remember the ski pants.
Just for a minute.
-What is that?
-Just getting back into character.
Come back here.
-Mike, darling
-What is it, sweetheart?
Do you know what you can get me
for our anniversary?
-A divorce.
-Anything you like, darling.
The airport limousine
will be here in 15 minutes.
If you will be seated
I will call you when it arrives.
Your job will be
no more than a personal assistant.
My experience is Mike Harper
__ dull job.
You won't find it so dull
with Claude Renard.
It's about time I found someone
who really appreciates me.
You mean Harper never really
appreciated you?
There are only two things he appreciates:
his business and his wife.
Come, my dear.
I know a wonderful discotheque
that is open all night.
Ms. Hackett.
Excuse me.
We know each other.
By the way, Claire,
if you see Mr. Harper
will you tell him I just resigned?
What's his room number?
He is in room 203.
-Bonjour.
I want her found.
I don't care, check all the airline.
And you call me back on room 207.
Thanks.
Mr. Langsdorf, let go of me.
It's not what it looks like.
Mrs. Hackett, __
Wunderbar!
Help, police!
Help!
__ , sir.
Help, police!
Don't run so fast!
Hilf mir!
Meine Frau!
-Your what?
-My wife!
Meine Frau!
Help me!
Janet!
It's me!