(suspenseful orchestral music)
(feet stepping)
(monster growls)
(woman screams)
(audience yelling)
(bodies scuffling)
(audience cheers)
(audience cheering)
(bodies scuffling)
(audience shouts)
(audience cheers)
(bodies scuffling)
(audience applauds)
(Gloria exhales)
- For a moment there,
I thought you were going to lose tonight.
- I'd hate to be called a braggart,
but up to now, no woman has pinned me.
Let me take a short
shower, will you, honey?
And then we'll go out to supper.
- You know something, Gloria?
If I were you, I'd be afraid
of getting my arm broken.
- You never can tell. (laughs)
(woman laughs)
(ventilator breathing)
- All set.
We'll operate immediately.
- Right, Doctor.
You can bring her in.
(suspenseful orchestral music)
(electricity buzzing)
(sad orchestral music)
- Another failure.
And this makes the fourth one
For a moment, he fought to go on living.
Only one thing could have caused this.
The brain I transplanted
wasn't strong enough
to resist the shock.
- All of the brains that we've
tried to transplant up to now
have come from totally uneducated women.
They had no preparation whatsoever,
and their IQs were extremely low.
Don't you believe that
we'd achieve better results
from a superior brain, with a high IQ,
from a young and intelligent woman?
- I couldn't be absolutely sure about it,
but there is a strong
possibility that you're right.
Anyway, we're going to go on trying
until we overcome all the obstacles.
(creature growls)
Gomar is acting up again.
We better go look in on him.
(Gomar growling)
(suspenseful orchestral music)
(Gomar growls)
Quiet down, Gomar!
Quiet, I say!
This is my greatest achievement so far.
Half-man and half-beast.
- But doctor--
- Yes, I know.
I've done what no one
else has been able to do.
I've transplanted a gorilla's brain
into a living human being.
It's time he was fed.
Get back, Gomar!
Get back!
(Gomar growls)
Do as I say!
(meat thuds)
There you have the
results of our experiment.
This man has been going through a slow
but relentless transformation,
indicating that the animal instincts
and characteristics are
starting to predominate
in this symbiotic relationship.
In a little more time now,
the metamorphosis will be complete.
- Do you mean that he'll
eventually become a 100% gorilla?
(Gomar munching)
- Quiet down!
Quiet, Gomar!
Do as I say!
Quiet down!
(Gomar growls)
I'm not going to take that
to meat away from you.
Calm down now.
Calm down.
You can go on eating.
The only reason he obeys me now
is because I have him in a hypnotic state.
But sooner or later,
I'll undoubtedly lose
all control over him.
(Gomar growls)
Calm down.
Go on eating, Gomar.
Go on eating.
I must continue to make progress.
I can't stop here.
(door locking)
I must transplant a human
brain into another human being.
That's the goal that I've set for myself.
Unfortunately, the human
metabolism is quite weak
as compared to that of animals.
But in my opinion,
the female of our species
reacts more positively
in these experiments,
for many biological reasons.
- When will we make
another attempt, Doctor?
As soon as we find someone
that fills our needs.
- You mean an intellectual woman?
- Could be.
Perhaps one that selected
a professional career.
(door closes)
- Extra, extra!
Another woman murdered by the Mad Doctor!
Paper, sir?
Extra, extra!
Police say criminal still at large!
[Vendor] Extra, extra!
The Mad Doctor claims a fourth victim!
- Go out and get me a
paper, will you, please?
- Certainly, glad to.
- Good morning, Boris.
- Good morning, Professor.
- Good morning, how are you today?
- The things that are going on
in this city lately are hideous.
Hmm?
And did you go out last night, Alice?
- Yes, Professor.
I watched my sister wrestle a while
and we had supper together.
- Hmm.
- Have you ever watched a
wrestling match, professor?
- Hmm?
Oh, no.
You must know that I simply
abhor violence, Alice.
It disgusts me.
- It's really a fantastic sport, sir.
And I think you'd enjoy
it once you saw it.
- No, I couldn't bear it.
Did you two stay up late?
- Till midnight, I think.
- And did your fiance accompany
you to watch the wrestling?
- Well, there's a certain boy
that I've been out with on occasion.
But last night, he worked.
So I'm afraid no one took us home.
- But two women alone could be in danger.
Surely, you read all about that
criminal killer in the city,
we call the Mad Doctor.
- (laughs) And don't you
worry about it, Professor.
That animal can do me no harm.
- Oh, no?
And why not?
- (chuckles) I wear my little
rabbit's foot, you know?
I'm perfectly safe,
wearing this. (chuckles)
- It makes me so mad
when I hear a girl start
to joke about this.
It's just incredible, the
happenings in the city lately.
There's no protection.
There are no guarantees.
And yet you girls--
- Professor!
- Yes.
Run an analysis on this,
and I'll be back for it.
- I'll get to work on it, Professor.
- Fine, thank you.
- Professor, the medicine
you ordered a few weeks ago
finally got here.
Can you check it now?
- Oh, yes.
Yes, I'll go out and sign for it.
Thank you, Boris.
Thank you.
Alice, I'll say more about this later.
- Reports show that these
nocturnal acts are continuing
and the police are still accusing
that criminal who's caused
so much public discussion.
Due to his actions, he's
been named the Mad Doctor.
The woman he killed last
night is in the morgue.
She was found early this
morning, and as always happened,
police found marks showing
that the brain had been removed
from the unfortunate girl's body.
They admit that the
case is a mystery still,
but they'll work until
they run across a solution.
- Any news?
- No, there's still not a thing.
I questioned several persons
who went there to see the corpse,
but no one could give us any information.
- I only say that this particular
criminal is disconcerting.
He's an excellent surgeon,
and the proof lies in the perfection
of the operations that he carried out.
He certainly knows his job,
but just why is he doing it?
I'm at a loss to find any motivation.
Is he a sadist, some madman?
- Well, we investigated all the doctors
in the medical profession,
and we questioned several,
but got no results at all.
- And for as long as he's on the loose
it'll mean he's a threat to society.
This criminal has to be found,
otherwise these attacks will continue.
- What are you gonna do?
- I'm going to phone my
grandmother, make her stay home.
No use inviting bad luck.
Grandma can't hear.
Grandma, dear!
Don't go out tonight!
(ominous orchestral music)
- My experiment must not be held up,
so you're going to look for another woman.
- But, Chief, the police are
coming too close for comfort.
They might catch us.
- There are a lot of patrols out,
watching all the principal highways,
and they're searching all the cars.
- Silence.
You're going to do exactly as I order you,
and Gomar will go with you.
- So he goes.
You mean that he can't be hurt by bullets?
- Certainly he can,
but I've foreseen that possibility,
so he'll be wearing special equipment.
No one will be able to stop him,
so you men have nothing
at all to worry about.
Gomar,
those men are your
friends, your good friends.
You will obey them.
You will obey them,
because they are your friends.
Listen, Chief,
who is the next woman?
Do you want us to get
any one in particular?
- Yes.
This is her photograph.
(dramatic orchestral music)
(gate closes)
- Goodnight, Boris.
- Goodnight, Professor.
- Goodnight, Alice.
Hadn't you better go?
It's getting awfully late,
and no one told you to
stay here all night.
- I know, only I wanted to
get this experiment done.
- Ah, what an eager little girl.
Now, you remind me to raise your salary.
(Alice chuckles)
But I want you to go now.
And another thing, I'm
going to a accompany you.
- Oh, no, there's no need for that.
I'll just grab a cab, and
I'll be home in 10 minutes.
- Yes, Alice, but I think I should--
- Now, don't insist, Professor.
The night air is pretty cold,
and I don't want you to catch a cold.
See you tomorrow, sir.
- Goodnight, Alice.
Have a pleasant evening, Boris.
- Why, thank you, Alice.
Goodnight now.
(door shuts)
(light orchestral music)
(menacing orchestral music)
(Alice screams)
(ominous orchestral music)
(doors shutting)
(dramatic orchestral music)
- Gomar, those men are enemies!
Go after them, and hurry!
- Stop!
Who are you?
Answer me!
You all stop right there, or I'll fire!
(guns firing)
(policeman groans)
(fist punches)
(policeman grunts)
(body thuds)
- Gomar, Gomar!
Let's get outta here, pronto!
(body thuds)
(exciting orchestral music)
(buzzer buzzing)
- The boys have brought the woman in.
- Good.
Get everything ready to operate.
- Chief, Gomar really moves fast.
He battered those police around
like so many clay pigeons.
- You did a good job, Gomar.
You will go now.
Take him along.
(suspenseful orchestral music)
(oxygen pumping)
- She's not going to pull through.
She's dying.
- Hurry, get the Coramine.
(suspenseful orchestral music)
(oxygen hissing)
One failure after another, Boris.
- The operation is
tremendously difficult, Doctor.
- Isn't there any human being
that can stand the shock?
- Perhaps a stronger type
of woman, an athlete,
one that can take more
punishment than the average.
If we could find a
woman like that, Doctor,
she'd probably live through the operation.
- Four policemen torn to pieces
by strange beast.
Police completely confused.
- Chief, we identified
the girl he murdered.
- Perfect.
Only who is she?
- It's in my book.
Alice Fontaine.
- That name sounds French.
- Who asked you?
Was another girl living with her?
- No one else.
- Her family?
- A sister, whom she saw frequently.
Who's Gloria Venus?
- That's her, there.
- Thank you.
- Come on, girls!
- Gloria Venus?
- Yes?
- I'm from headquarters.
I'm sorry that it's my duty
to bring you this bad news, Miss.
- I don't understand.
- It's your sister.
- Is she sick?
- She suffered a very bad accident.
- (gasps) Alice was hurt?
- Would you accompany me, please?
- To the doctor?
- To identify her.
(Gloria gasps)
(dramatic orchestral music)
(suspenseful orchestral music)
(Gloria gasps)
(Gloria sobs)
- Last night, Alice left
much later than usual.
I offered to accompany her to her house,
but she said she'd go alone.
She said she would go in a taxi.
Oh, this thing is just horrible.
- Poor girl.
- It's too bad you don't have other things
to tell us, Professor.
There's no evidence to help us.
- We could find out whether
she took a taxi or not.
- It's obvious she didn't.
But anyway, Tommy, you
and I will check that.
- Just what is that maniac trying to do,
operating on all those women that way?
- I'd sure like to find
out why, Professor.
You see, we think this
surgery is behind it all.
- I just can't tell you
how sorry I feel, Gloria,
about Alice's death.
I adored her, as I would a daughter.
I want to help you if I can.
So please don't fail to call on me.
- Thank you, Professor.
And should you run across more facts,
I'd like for you to inform me.
- Oh yes, yes, yes, of course.
- I swear not to rest
until I find the one who
killed my poor sister.
I won't let the killer get away this time.
- Don't worry.
Have faith in the local police.
The thing is,
we don't have the smallest
bit of evidence to work on.
But sooner or later,
the man we're trying to hunt down
is going to commit an error.
And when he does, we'll get him.
- Yes, that's true.
- It's simply useless to go on
with the experiments in this way.
All the women have died
on the operating table.
- Let's say your right, Chief,
then what will you do?
- We've got to find women with
incredible physical stamina.
But at the moment, I must admit
that I don't know where
to start to look for them.
(bodies thumping)
- One moment!
Please, girls, one moment!
This is very important.
Now listen to me.
I'd like you to meet another young lady
who's spent many years
in the wrestling game.
She's come here today to join you.
This is Golden Ruby.
Ruby, I'd like to take this
opportunity to introduce you
to our star wrestler, Gloria Venus.
- It's a pleasure to know you.
- The pleasure is mine.
- Ruby came to start training.
She'll have a match very soon.
I hope you take time out to work with her
and show her all the things you know.
- I'd be glad to, Dick.
- Fine, and I'd like to thank you.
I must be going.
Good luck, Ruby.
- Thanks a lot.
- Shall we get to work?
- Whatever you say.
(body thuds)
- What are you doing here?
- I want those weights there.
- You can't have them, they're ours!
- Don't give me orders!
(body thuds)
(man groans)
(Ruby laughing)
(both laughing)
(phone rings)
- Inspector Rogers.
No, there's no more information as yet.
Call later.
These reporters are like locusts.
Anything new?
- Not one clue.
She could have climbed into a car,
only I know it wasn't a taxi.
We investigated the drivers and nothing.
- I only know that this case
would make a mad man sane, Chief.
There's no evidence, no motives, nothing.
No one knows who the man is either.
- The only thing we can do is wait.
- For another crime?
(Gloria sighs)
- There are really some
fine wrestlers here, Gloria.
I won't win easily, I know that.
- Hey, that's just modesty.
You know your business, I could see it.
- Know something?
I've watched you, and your
eyes have such a sad look.
Tell me, is anything wrong?
- No.
Well, all right.
My poor sister, it's just
something I can't forget.
They murdered her three nights ago.
- (gasps) I'm so sorry.
Forgive me, but I really--
- No, I don't want you
to feel bad about it.
- But, but if there's
anything I can do to help.
- Thank you.
You're a real swell girl.
Are you staying nearby here, Ruby?
- At the Splendid Hotel.
Why?
My new apartment is large,
and you must be lonely.
I thought maybe you'd like
to come and live there.
- I'd be delighted to.
But don't you think I'd turn
out to be a burden, Gloria?
- Course not.
And actually, you'd be doing me a favor,
'cause now more than ever,
I need someone else around me.
- Well, in that case, it's a deal.
(crowd chatters)
- Tonight, at two falls
with no time limits,
we present the American cyclone,
The Golden Ruby,
teaming with Gloria Venus,
fighting against The
Gazelle and Bertha Galindo!
(crowd chatters)
(audience shouting)
(body thuds)
(audience cheering)
(body thumps)
(body thuds)
(audience whistling)
(bodies thumping)
(audience cheers)
(fist thumps)
(body thumping)
(foot thumps)
(audience cheers)
- Why did you bring me here?
- Because we could run across some clues.
- Yeah, sure it could.
You wanted to watch Gloria wrestle.
- It could be.
- Well, well, you better watch out
and not get fresh with her,
because she'll put her
foot in your mouth, sonny.
And so long teeth.
You'd be pretty, talking
like this. (laughs)
- Quiet down, short stuff.
(audience cheering)
- Boo!
Boo!
(crowd cheering)
Well, join in!
Boo!
- Boo!
(crowd cheering)
(body thuds)
(audience claps)
(fist thumps)
(audience boos)
(body thumps)
(audience cheers)
(audience yelling)
(body thumps)
(audience clapping)
(audience applauds)
(audience yelling)
(bodies slamming)
(body crashing)
(bodies thudding)
(body thuds)
(audience yelling)
(body thumps)
(body thuds)
(audience yelling)
(audience cheers)
(body thuds)
- Get back there.
Go on!
(audience yelling)
- Boo!
(body slams)
(body thuds)
(audience yelling)
(body thumps)
(audience cheering)
(audience applauds)
(door knocks)
- Come in.
Oh, Professor Wright.
What a pleasant surprise
to have a visit from you.
I'd like you to meet my
teammate, The Golden Ruby.
- It's a pleasure indeed, young lady.
- Hello.
Did you like the fight, Professor?
I'm sorry to say it,
but I don't look such spectacles.
- May I come in?
- Sure.
- Thank you.
- Me too?
- Good evening, sir, how are you?
- Of course.
I'd like to introduce Mike Henderson
and his assistant here, Tommy Johnson.
The Golden Ruby.
- Hello there, how are you?
- Delighted.
- Not as delighted as I am, sweetheart.
(Tommy groans)
(knuckles cracking)
(group laughs)
- Who would have thought
that you'd like wrestling, Professor?
- I just can't bear it really.
It's more than I can take.
I only came here because
I wanted to tell you
certain facts that I
just remembered tonight.
- Really?
- About Alice, Professor?
- Uh, Yes.
I remember that she spoke about
a boy that she was seeing on occasion,
after work, I guess.
- Did she tell you his name, sir?
- Uh, no,
but I thought that
might help you a little.
- A little or a lot, it's still something.
- It's possible.
Many thanks, Professor.
I'll investigate this man tomorrow, sir.
- (chuckles) I'd like you to know
that I'm always ready to assist you.
You don't know how I itch
to get my hands on that fool maniac.
- I understand, sir.
- Well, I'll be saying goodnight now.
I must be going.
- Well, good night, Professor.
- Excuse me, please.
- Pleased to know you.
- Goodnight.
- Girls, Tommy wants to invite
you to supper and dancing.
- Who?
- How about it?
- I think that's great!
- What are we waiting for?
- Perfect.
- She has plans for me.
(suspenseful orchestral music)
(window rattling)
(body thumps)
(fist punches)
(exciting orchestral music)
(body thumps)
(fists punching)
(fist punches)
(body thumps)
(fists punching)
(fist punches)
- No, they might have more out there!
Stay right here.
- Are you all right?
They didn't hurt your arm, did they?
- No.
- But look, Chief,
why didn't you tell us that
those two girls were wrestlers?
You should've seen the
way they batted me around.
(thug moans)
- You two are a pair of useless fools!
At long last, I find a specimen
that is perfect for our work,
and you botch up the whole job.
Imbeciles!
- I'm absolutely certain
that those men will try to get you again.
Now then, if they do return,
I think it's best to
react in another manner.
That is, if you're interested
in helping the law.
- I think you can talk plainer.
- Look,
in this case, there's not
a scrap of solid evidence
to help us discover that insane murderer.
Alice's fiance came in,
and we questioned him too.
He's completely clean.
Besides, he's broken up about her murder.
It's a shame.
We'll have to begin at
the beginning once more,
with nothing.
- How can we help you solve the case?
- If my suspicions are based on fact,
and those men try to kidnap you again,
in that case, I want you
to let yourselves be taken.
Tommy and I will be
following close behind you.
Now, if you do that, the
men will lead us directly
to their hideout and to their boss.
- Maybe your idea will work.
All I need is a little
luck to avenge my sister.
- Now don't you worry, baby doll,
'cause I intend to watch out for you.
- Do you mean it, Tommy?
- Mm-hmm.
- I feel so safe and protected.
(body thuds)
(Tommy chuckles)
(throat clears)
(jazzy piano music)
- See you Wednesday night, Johnny.
(jazzy orchestral music)
(exciting orchestral music)
(man whistles)
- Did you hear that whistle?
- Yes.
- I've got a strong feeling
that we're about to be attacked.
Are you afraid?
- No, but I sure would feel a lot happier
if I knew that Mike were
out there in the shadows.
- I know why you say it and me too.
(Ruby gasps)
- Look there, that light!
- Do you think it's a signal?
- I don't know,
but be prepared just in case.
(jazzy orchestral music)
- X-4 to all cars.
Prepare your sectors to help
us when you get the command.
That is all.
(fists thumping)
We'll stop this right now.
- No.
You're trying to spoil things.
Let's follow their car.
(door shuts)
(car revving)
(tires squealing)
- You did an excellent job, Gomar.
(buzzer buzzing)
- That's the danger signal!
- You idiots!
You allowed yourself to be followed!.
(buzzer buzzing)
- There are two men, Chief,
and they look like cops.
(gun fires)
- Get your hands up!
(gun smacks)
(fists punching)
What a right!
Where are the others?
Let's get going!
Ghosty!
(fist punches)
(Tommy groans)
Oh, yeah?
(gun fires)
(thug groans)
(body thuds)
(fist strikes)
(boxes tumbling)
- Are you all right?
Then come on.
(bodies scuffling)
(fist punches)
- Tommy. Tommy, wake up!
Hold your fire!
It's me.
- You almost got it.
(sirens blaring)
(tires screeching)
- (gasps) So, it's you!
- Stay where you are, everyone!
Grab these men!
- Hold my gun.
- All right.
Get going!
- Come on.
After you, Chief.
- Police capture Mad Doctor and his gang.
(phone rings)
Hello?
He's interrogating the Mad Doctor.
- You might as well open up
and tell us everything you know.
A complete confession would
do a lot in your favor.
Answer me!
Are there other men in
this gang that got away?
Are these the only men
you had working for you?
Professor Wright,
is there anything that you want to ask?
- No, there isn't.
Oh, yes, just one thing.
It's all so confusing, you know,
but it's strange.
I still can't believe that
Boris is the Mad Doctor.
Don't you think he's playing with us,
covering up for the real Mad Doctor?
- That's possible.
We could give you
complete police protection
if you tell us the truth.
Are you the Mad Doctor, yes or no?
- No!
No!
No, another man killed those girls!
- Then where is he?
- He escaped.
When he suddenly realized
that you were just about
to break into the house,
he escaped, taking Gomar with him,
through a secret passageway.
- Gomar?
- Yes, the monster
that murdered those four
policemen that night.
And now the doctor will
try to murder me,
because I know too many facts.
I need protection!
Do you hear?
You've got to give me protection!
- Well, all you have to do
is cooperate with the law.
Tell us who the Mad Doctor is!
(suspenseful orchestral music)
- The man you're trying to find is...
- There's no danger.
Tell us!
Don't you know you're
surrounded by the police?
- The Mad Doctor is...
(Boris gasps)
(dramatic orchestral music)
- The man's gone.
I suppose that it was his heart.
- Anyone leaving here needs my permission!
The autopsy will tell us
if he died a natural death.
I can't rule out murder.
Someone in here could be the Mad Doctor.
These two small objects here
were responsible for Boris' death.
Inside this cylinder here,
there's a very powerful firing mechanism
that fired a tiny little poison needle.
And this morning,
the coroner located that
needle in the man's heart.
The killer had that little
weapon locked in his teeth,
and he had to bite down to fire it.
There's a spring in this.
It's silent and very powerful.
- Ah, then the killer lost this cylinder?
- He spit it out in the other room.
Anyone could have done
it without being noticed.
- Inspector, now that we know
where the needle came from,
we can locate exactly
where the killer stood
the instant he fired.
- That's not going to help us.
You see, the needle entered his
body at a fantastic velocity
but it wasn't the blow against the heart
that murdered the individual.
The poison took a second
to get to the brain.
He had sufficient time to turn around,
and that means he was in another position
when the needle struck.
- Are you trying to say
that among the person
standing there in that room
at least nine or 10 as I recall,
that you'll find the criminal?
- Exactly.
And I'm sure you're aware that I'm unable
to arrest the whole
group of suspects either.
- The Mad Doctor could be anyone, right?
You, Tommy, or some other detective.
One of those punks too.
Or you, Professor.
- That's right.
(The Mad Doctor laughs)
- Once again, I made the
police look like fools.
Boris tried to turn me in,
but he paid dearly for his treachery.
Did you kill him, Chief?
- Naturally, I did.
I reward my employees quite well,
as long as they're faithful to me.
On the other hand, the traitors
will pay with their lives.
Don't you forget that for one second.
- Don't you worry about me.
I'm no stool pigeon, Chief.
- No, no, of course you're not.
And now you are to go out
and locate three or four men
that I can confide in.
I'll explain why.
We've got to reorganize the group.
Once and for all, I've got
to get rid of that detective
and his stupid sidekick.
He's ruining my plans.
I'm going to make a good trap.
I'm sure his death is
not going to be pretty.
I swear.
And now listen, because there
are things that you are to do.
You will go to a certain house.
(bodies scuffling)
(body thuds)
(wrestlers clapping)
(Gloria claps)
- Gloria, that girl is
really a tremendous wrestler.
- She's extraordinary.
Bravo, you were great!
- Hey, look who's here!
- Any news?
- Not yet.
- How long will that
madman run around free,
killing other girls?
- Well, I know why you're impatient, but,
but he's going to be caught soon.
Don't worry.
- He sure is.
The Mad Doctor is going to be back soon,
but now we're prepared.
- Yeah, in what way?
- Well, look.
I'd like you to use these watches here.
- Hey, these are cute.
- Well, actually, they were
made to help the police.
They're not watches.
They're transmitting and receiving sets.
Now, you're not going
to forget to wear these.
- Yours are just like the
ones that we're wearing.
- They're useful little gadgets.
In case any of you find
yourselves up against it,
you only have to push this button.
(watch beeps)
That'll send a signal out.
Right?
Then I'll be able to find you.
- That's marvelous, really.
- You're the marvelous
one, you lovely redhead.
- I'd say the same thing about you,
you five-foot lightning bolt.
- Can the kidding around, you too.
We got lots of work.
- This woman loves me dearly.
- See you later.
Come on.
- Bye.
- Police station.
This is very urgent, please.
I'd like to speak to the detective bureau.
(phone rings)
- Detective bureau.
- I'd like to speak to the captain.
This matter is important.
- You say you want to talk to the captain?
Just a minute.
I don't think he's here.
- He came in just a second ago.
- Hold on, he just got in.
Captain, you're wanted on the telephone.
- Thank you.
Captain Henderson.
- This is Professor Wright, Captain.
I'm calling you because
my house was attacked
by the men of the Mad Doctor.
- The Mad Doctor, you say?
Are you sure you're all right?
- Yes, captain,
but could you come to
my house immediately?
Do me that favor.
- I'll be directly there, sir.
(tense percussive music)
(doorbell buzzes)
- Captain Henderson.
Come in, come in.
Won't you please, sir?
- Stay where you are!
- What is this, Professor?
- You don't know how sorry I am, Captain,
but they forced me to do this.
They threatened to kill me!
- Turn around, get your hands up.
(fists striking)
Grab them!
Let's go.
If you value your life, Professor,
don't move from this spot for 10 minutes.
- Yes, sir.
- Do you understand?
(door shuts)
(car revs)
(phone rings)
- Hello?
Oh, yes, just a moment.
She's right here.
Professor Wright is on the phone, Gloria.
- How are you, Professor?
You mean...
Why, that's terrible!
He insists that Mike and
Tommy have been kidnapped
by the men working for the Mad Doctor.
Okay, we'll be there in 20 minutes.
- Hey, no, just a minute.
Aren't you forgetting these?
- Gosh, you're right.
Thanks, Professor.
I'll talk to you about this later.
No, no, no, don't you do anything.
So long for now.
- Look, Gloria, if they find
they're in terrible danger,
they'll be calling us here.
Isn't that right?
So the only thing we can do is wait.
- Yes, only suppose they kill them
before they can use their radios.
(dramatic orchestral music)
- Good evening, gentlemen.
I hope that my men have not
mistreated you unnecessarily.
Due to the fact that you are continually
sticking your noses into my business,
I have decided to get rid
of you two permanently.
Once you are no longer in my way,
it will be simple to
capture the lady wrestlers.
Take them to the death chamber.
(suspenseful orchestral music)
(fist thumps)
(door slides)
- Have a nice trip.
Is this a ship they've thrown us into?
(Gomar growls)
(wall squeaking)
What's this?
(Gomar growls)
- Gloria, listen, can you hear me?
- Come in, come in, Mike!
- Can you hear?
Listen, we're in a trap, Gloria!
- Yes, I can, only where at?
- I don't know.
The doctor's men tied our hands,
and they blindfolded us also.
Now listen,
I'm going to turn on a constant sound wave
that you'll be able to receive.
If you follow it, you'll find us.
- You better hurry, honey,
or we're not going to walk
to the altar together!
- Don't say such things, small hero.
I'll be there like white lightning.
- We better hurry!
(signal beeps)
- I hope they're getting our signal.
- I think they are.
Don't worry about it.
- Don't worry about it!
There must be a hole around here.
(wall squeaks)
(car revs)
- There's gotta be some way out!
- But where?
- We'll find it!
- The harder we push against this thing,
the harder it pushes back!
(signal beeps)
- Go right straight ahead, Gloria.
The sound is coming in much
stronger in this direction.
(signal beeping)
- Look out!
Don't let him get his hands on you!
- Do you think I need your advice?
(Gomar growls)
(Tommy whimpering)
- Hang on, Tommy!
(Tommy whimpers)
Come on!
(Tommy screams)
- It's beginning to weaken Gloria.
(signal beeps)
You better take the next street.
Now the waves are coming in.
- Try not to fall!
You're doing fine!
(Tommy whimpers)
Hold on!
- The wave is coming in,
and it's getting much
stronger in this direction.
(signal beeps)
(Gomar growls)
- Hey, not so much noise!
- Try to hold on!
It's stopped now!
- Do you think I'm a machine?
- Try to stiffen your legs!
(signal beeps)
- But this is impossible.
This is the same place
where we captured Boris the other night.
(signal beeps)
- This is where the
sound is the strongest.
You can hear it.
(signal beeps)
- Any ideas?
- Let's go in.
(signal beeps)
- We're going to need the crowbar, Gloria.
(crowbar prying)
(crowbar rattling)
(signal beeps)
- Don't you think it's strange
that they returned to this house?
(signal beeps)
- Listen.
You don't think Boris has
come back to life, do you?
- Oh, don't talk nonsense.
(signal beeps)
(signal beeping)
- Here we are, boys!
- Tommy!
- Gloria!
- Ruby!
- Tom, where are you?
Can you hear us calling?
- Yes!
- Are you close to us?
- Yes, only behind the iron curtain!
(Gomar growls)
(fist strikes)
(exciting orchestral music)
(fists punching)
(fist punches)
(bodies scuffling)
(boxes crashing)
(fists punching)
(bodies scuffling)
(fist punches)
(fists punching)
(boxes crashing)
(body thuds)
(body crashing)
- Try to hold on!
They're coming in!
(fists punching)
[Mike] Gloria, Ruby!
- We can hear you!
How'd they get you in there?
- There's a button on the floor!
Step on it!
- It's underneath the lever!
(Tommy grunts)
(Gomar growls)
- Help me!
Help me get him down, girls!
(exciting orchestral music)
- Let's get out of here!
(Gomar growls)
- You take care of these guys here!
- Yes, sir!
- The Mad Doctor!
Come on!
(exciting orchestral music)
(fist punches)
(bodies scuffling)
(Mad Doctor screams)
(bottles breaking)
(machine exploding)
- The laboratory is going
to blow up very soon.
There's nothing we can do for this man.
- I guess this is the end
of the Mad Doctor then.
- It's a shame we couldn't
find out his real identity,
but he's paid for all these crimes now.
(fire crackling)
Tommy, this lab's gonna blow sky high!
- Too bad we can't stick
around for the fireworks!
Come on, you guys!
- Come on, move, get going!
(Gomar growls)
(fire crackles)
(boxes smashing)
(Gomar growls)
- Gomar, hurry!
Get me out of here!
(fire crackling)
- Gloria, Ruby!
- What happened, Dick?
- Have you girls seen Mary Carmichael?
- No, we haven't.
What happened to her?
- I don't know.
But two days ago, she left
her house and didn't return
and no one knows where she disappeared to.
- Is it possible?
- Harry, we're coming
to the end of the road,
a road that you and I
have traveled together.
I think it's time now that
you learned my true identity.
Nothing matters to me anymore.
My only desire is to make that girl pay
for what she did to me.
Look!
- It's you.
It's not possible.
- As I said, she didn't return.
I think something happened to her.
So I'll telephone the police immediately.
- Gloria, someone wants you on the phone.
- Oh, thanks.
Hello?
This is she.
Hello, Professor.
It's nice to hear your voice again.
- Thank you so much, Gloria.
Tell me, how are you feeling?
- Why, I feel fine, sir.
And you?
Hard at work the way you always are?
- Oh, there's nothing to it.
Gloria, I was thinking
that I'd like to watch your wrestle again.
Tell me, are you contracted
to wrestle abroad in the near future?
- No, no, I'll stay here
until at least March.
Listen, I'll send you
free tickets if you like.
- No, I'm grateful to
you, but don't bother to.
The truth is, that I still
don't know when I can get away.
But I promise you this,
I won't wait long,
and I'll see you very soon, Gloria.
- So long, Professor.
- I'll keep that promise
to you, young lady,
and then...
Vengeance.
(Gomar growls)
My vengeance!
And you two are going
to help me carry it out!
You, Gomar,
you that are part human and half beast,
that I created you.
I plan to use your physical strength
and transplant it into the
body of this woman here.
She's going to destroy Gloria Venus.
She'll blow her body to pieces.
Yes, a little killing in the ring,
for all the audience to see.
(Mad Doctor laughs)
You're going to help with the operation.
We'll start immediately.
(Gomar growls)
(suspenseful orchestral music)
(dramatic orchestral music)
She's alive.
She's alive!
She made it!
Your name is Vendetta.
Vendetta!
I created you for my own use.
Do you understand?
You are to obey me.
You are to do as I command you.
You inherited the strength
I had given to Gomar,
but now your new brain
is only a slave,
with which I'll make you act.
And now I'll transmit orders to you,
although I stay at a very great distance.
You will obey the commands I send.
You'll not protest.
You simply cannot.
Tremble, Gloria Venus.
Vendetta, who I created for my use,
is your destruction!
Get up now.
Destroy that table there!
Do as I say!
(table smashing)
(Mad Doctor laughs)
Tremble, Gloria Venus!
Tremble! (laughs)
- She's from Paris, and she uses a mask.
She hides her identity,
but her name is Vendetta.
And through her public relations man,
she has challenged our present
champion, Gloria Venus.
It is said that the winner gets 2,400,
and we would like to predict
that the crowds will pack the house.
Do you accept the challenge, Gloria?
- I have no objections,
and you can inform all the fans
that I'll accept a fighter,
because I like a good challenge.
I'll do my best to win this one also.
I know my fans want that.
- Fellas, here's Vendetta!
- I don't know why it is,
but when she entered,
I began to get this hideous feeling.
- Could you say why it is
your face behind that mask?
- It'll be very difficult
for her to understand you.
She doesn't speak English, I'm afraid.
Now here you have the
man who handles Vendetta.
- Oh, the lengths that people will go
to attract publicity for
themselves. (chuckles)
- Ah, Gloria, here's the
girl you'll be fighting.
- It's a pleasure to know you.
- Uh, excuse me, please.
Uh, I think it's time
we signed the contract.
Now everything is written out
according to the spoken agreement.
Miss Vendetta, would you be
kind enough to come over here
and sign the contract?
- Vendetta, you are to
go over to the desk.
Sit down.
Take the pen and sign your name, Vendetta.
- Tonight we present
the greatest wrestling match in history!
Fighting for a $25,000 purse,
Vendetta versus Gloria Venus.
And in the semi-finals,
the American cyclone, The
Golden Ruby versus The Gazelle.
(crowd chatters)
- Be careful tonight.
I don't know why,
but there's something
I don't like about her.
She has such a sinister look in her eye.
- (laughs) Don't worry about it.
I know I'll be all right.
- Okay, but you keep your wits about you
all through the fight.
(door knocking)
- You ready?
- Ready.
- Good luck.
- Thanks.
(audience cheering)
(audience applauding)
(crowd whistles)
(crowd boos)
(audience whistles)
(body thuds)
(audience yelling)
- A purse of $25,000 goes
to the winning wrestler!
They'll wrestle two falls out of three,
and the time is unlimited!
In this corner,
the champion of our country, Gloria Venus!
(audience cheers)
(audience applauds)
And in this corner,
is the mystery girl, Vendetta!
(crowd boos)
- Boo!
(crowd booing)
(bell dings)
- All right, these are the rules.
When I separate you, I'll count to 10,
and 20 on the floor
(audience screaming)
(whistle blows)
- Run.
Get back, get back.
Run faster.
(crowd shouting)
Now attack her.
(body thuds)
(fist punch)
- Break!
Break, I said!
- (indistinct)
Make her suffer, make her suffer.
Suffer Gloria Venus, suffer.
- One, two, three, four, five.
(body thuds)
(audience applauds)
(dramatic orchestral music)
- What are you doing in
this arena, you little rat?
Something is going on!
Now, is it a trap?
Tell me and hurry!
(body thumps)
(bodies thumping)
Just who is that woman
in the ring, do you hear?
(Harry groans)
What's happening around here?
Come on now!
(audience cheers)
- No, no! (groans)
I'll talk.
Vendetta used to wrestle with you all.
(Harry groans)
Her name is Carmichael.
The Mad Doctor gave her
tremendous strength.
He took a gorilla's brain
and transplanted it. (groans)
- Then she wasn't killed?
- (groans) No!
And Professor Wright (groans)
is working as her agent! (groans)
- Here, police!
Over here!
(audience shouting)
- No, no, no!
(body thumps)
(audience cheers)
(feet smacking)
(body thuds)
- Hold her.
Fight her quick.
Slowly, very slowly, squeeze down on her.
(crowd whistles)
(body thumps)
(audience shouts)
(body slams)
Something's wrong.
The other girl's going in.
Get the other girl.
Attack the other girl now.
(audience shouts)
Hurry, kill both of them.
(bodies thudding)
(body thuds)
(body slams)
(audience shouting)
(body thuds)
(sirens blaring)
(tires screeching)
- That's Professor Wright!
He is the Mad Doctor!
Now go get him and hurry!
(audience shouting)
(door shuts)
(body thuds)
- Come on!
- What's the matter?
- Tell me, have you
seen a masked man here?
- No, Captain.
- I want patrols right away.
We'll surround this building here.
Come on!
(door shuts)
- Vendetta, Vendetta.
- Listen well, I'm talking to you.
Leave the ring.
Come to me.
I need you.
Leave the ring.
(audience shouting)
(audience yelling)
Vendetta, get here as fast as you can.
Hurry!
Do as I tell you!
We've got to hurry, Vendetta!
(fist thumps)
(tires squealing)
(sirens blaring)
(crowd murmuring)
- I went out front, they're not there.
So that means they must
be around here somewhere.
- Up there on the lattice, sir!
- I knew they couldn't get far
Have them lend us a
spotlight from the arena.
And you, get this crowd outta here.
(crowd murmuring)
- Where are they?
Do you have them cornered?
(crowd murmuring)
- Here are the spotlights
you wanted, Captain.
- Thank you.
Turn them toward that water tower.
(crowd murmuring)
- Yes, yes, there they are!
- The problem is how they'll
be made to surrender.
They might decide to stay there.
- They're not coming down.
- No, you mustn't go up there!
(crowd murmuring)
Professor Wright!
You'll gain nothing by staying here!
Turn yourself in!
- No, no!
I know you're trying to get rid of us.
What you want to do is to kill Vendetta,
but I won't let you destroy my great work.
My work!
- Listen, professor--
- No!
(fists thumping)
Push him off the tower, Vendetta!
(fist punches)
(crowd screams)
(crowd murmuring)
(woman screams)
Destroy him!
[Mad Doctor] Destroy him!
(crowd murmuring)
- Vendetta will murder him.
Shoot!
(fist thumping)
(gun fires)
(Vendetta gasps)
(crowd screams)
(body thuds)
- No, you ruthless dogs!
You killed Vendetta!
You have destroyed my creation!
(gun fires)
(crowd screams)
(body thuds)
(crowd chatters)
(light orchestral music)
- It's all over now, don't worry.
And your sister's been avenged.
(sweeping orchestral music)
(upbeat synth music)