VERSION 1
Action!
We are a group of filmmakers.
We going to offer with our means
as actors, directors, technicians
a reconstruction of the
three official versions
the versions given by the judicial authorities
of the suicide, the ... alleged
suicide of the anarchist Pinelli.
This office represents the office
of Dott. Calabresi.
Dott. Calabresi, commissioner of the political
office at police HQ in Milan,
Collaborator at the official social-
democratic journal "La Giustizia"
and the newspaper "Momento Sera"
was for some months in America
where he is said to have
received a special training course.
In the circles of the left Milan
he is known as the "CIA Inspector".
The three versions we offer,
that is the official versions, confirmed
by the juridical authorities,
assume that Calabresi was not
in his office at this moment.
Present were instead
a lieutenant of the Carabinieri and
three officers of the political Police.
And Pinelli.
So, three officers of the political Police,
a lieutenant of the Carabinieri,
and Pinelli.
The Police say
The climate in the room
was very quiet at this moment,
since Calabresi was outside.
The interrogation was interrupted.
A break in the interrogation,
which lasted for?
It took three days and three nights.
Three days and three nights.
Has the anarchist Pinelli been
talking to someone?
On the morning of the last day
he has met his mother
He has spoken to her
He appeared calm, balanced
and sure to be set free again soon,
as no proves of his guilt were found.
It is necessary to emphasize something about the person Pinelli:
Pinelli was well known with the
political Police in Milan,
because for some twenty years
he was well known
Therefore, in the case
of ... social tensions,
special tensions, the anarchist Pinelli
was one of those persons
that were taken for questioning,
Sp he knew perfectly about the ...
... tricks of the political department
of Milan's Police.
This room represents the office
Dr. Calabresi.
We are ... What time is it?
It is about midnight
the 15th December 1969
Midnight of the 15th December 1969.
15th December in Milan.
The windows were ajar ...
so as to let in some air,
as the room ...
During the interrogation, all of them have smoked ...
The sergeant of the Carabinieri ...
May not have been ... here.
To close to the window.
Here neither.
Perhaps the officials ...
were here ...
It is known that Pinelli
at about 22:30 in the evening
phoned his wife
and asked her to search for his
labour-book as railway worker
which would provide a prove in his favor,
an entry about a trip by Pinelli
He told his wife,
that a policeman would drop by
to pick up the book.
That was the evening 22:30 to
the 15th December 1969
At this moment the police officers
were talking among themselves.
Of course, none of them
paid attention to Pinelli.
They say that I, the anarchist Pinelli,
had got up to stretch myself.
I had jumped with a cat-like leap
out the window.
The cat-like leap of
the Anarchist Pinelli.
"Cat-like jump" the precise wording
of the Chief of the Milan Police
to describe Pinelli's
jump into the yard.
Second VERSION, the Third
The second version,
the police has given of the
suicide of the anarchist Pinelli,
sees a different arrangement
than before of those
present in the office of Dr. Calabresi.
We cannot remain
like in the first version,
in which we were neither allowed to
hear nor see the anarchist Pinelli.
Now,on the other hand, we hear and see him.
So you go to the typewriter.
Two officers can be here.
You can sit down on where the
Anarchist Pinelli was sitting before.
They say that I, the anarchist Pinelli,
had gotten up to stretch myself.
And have turned slowly to the window ...
As if to get a little fresh air.
Eh! Stop!
Why he has thrown himself
out of the window?
He was not even suspected.
He was here for an conversation.
He was quiet.
A few months ago he has given
Dr. Allegra a book.
"A thousand million people"
That was the title of the book.
Why he has thrown himself
out of the window?
We have not done it.
Despite of the four officers
the anarchist Pinelli succeeded in
reaching the court.
Third VERSION, the first
We come to the third
and last version
the police has given about the suicide
of the anarchist Pinelli.
I, the anarchist Pinelli,
have got up to stretch myself.
I turned slowly to the window,
as if to catch a little fresh air.
Wait, wait! What are you doing?
I almost had him.
But only the shoe remained in my hand.
It is his escape by a whisker
and only the shoe remained in the
hands of Corporal Panessa.
The four officials have failed...
...and the anarchist Pinelli
managed to reach the court.
The body of the anarchist Pinelli was
found three meters away from the wall
with both shoes on his feet.
HEADLINES
"The massacre of the state"
"How died Giuseppe Pinelli?"
"Why died Giuseppe Pinelli?"
"Police and judicial authorities
side by side"
"The Testimony of Benito Bianchi,
theater technician'
"The Spy of March 22nd."
"The role of Mario Merlino
in the investigation."
"Who is Paolo Pecoriello?"
"Who is Bruno Giorgi?"
"Who is Giorgio Chiesa?"
"Who is Serafino di Luia?"
"Who is Giancarlo Cartocci?"
"Who is Antonio Sottosanti?"
"Italian and Greek fascists."
"The detainees were interrogated
by the window sill."
"The accidental death of Pinelli."
"Why it is allowed to doubt
the suicide of Pinelli."
"After three months the doctor was questioned, ...
... that offered the dying Pinelli first medical aid."
"We reconstructed the last hours
of Pinelli's life minute by minute."
"These are the famous words
of the Milan police chief
20 minutes after the tragedy
at a press conference:
'Pinelli was heavily suspected.
For me, his deed is a self-accusation.
I swear to you:
We have not killed him.
as soon as you get to know
the evidence... '
This evidence  remain at least so far
part of the fertile imagination
of Dr. Guida (chief of Milan Police)."
"Lieutenant Lograno of the Carabinieri,
one of four investigators,
was promoted to captain. "
Umanità nova (anarchist journal):
"So that the general public knows.
Letters from Italian prisons
This letter is from Paul Braschi,
an anarchist.
He writes: 'Here is much talk of windows
which is exactly the nickname
of Commendatore Calabresi,
and I must say, it fits perfectly.
I remember one interrogation
in that same office where Pinelli died.
This so-called
"Commendatore window"
on the last day I spent
in his office,
when he was happy to have
brought me to false confession
by extortion, violence,
insults and threats
together with his worthy companions,
he had me sit close to the open window.
And without approaching me,
he and the others
provoked me openly,
by asking me why I did not
throw me out of the window.
They repeated this several times
and tested my shattered nerves
after the treatment.
It would have been extremely easy,
and if they had wanted,
I absolutely could
not have prevented it. '"
VERSION Frezzi, the second!
"The bombing of Milan"
At the end of our work
we want to recall on an episode
from history of the labor movement.
Pino Pinelli, who grew up
with the anarchist myth
of social justice and freedom,
certainly knew the drama
of another anarchist:
Romeo Frezzi,
accomplice arrested in 1897
as assassin of Umberto I.
Frezzi was imprisoned as a victim
of delusional search for accomplices.
The police headquarters has
- after conflicting statements -
explained that the man had killed himself,
when he fell down from a
balcony, 6 meters high.
The autopsy, however,
that took place thanks to the courage of the physician Dr. Pardo
has shown that the man was killed.
For the police it was an accident.
He did not want to talk
and had absolutely nothing to say.
And representatives of public safety
have massacred him with blows.
The anarchist Frezzi.
Frezzi! Speech! Speech!
The Anarchists. The Anarchists.
The Anarchists.
We have killed him.
It was an accident.
He killed himself.
It's true. He killed himself.
Pino Pinelli,
last in a long line of anarchists,
who killed themselves.