- [Narrator] Somewhere in the
dark depths of the universe
far below the world
known as Earth,
is the ultimate destination,
all things evil.
Hell.
Here, all beings who have
committed atrocities in life
are tormented for eternity,
ruled over by the
fallen angel Lucifer.
A great war erupted when
the dark lord Desecrator
challenged Lucifer
for his crown.
The possession of the
key to Hell itself.
But Lord Desecrator's
own general, Dominator,
stole the key for himself.
Desecrator sent an army of
demons to pursue Dominator
and return the key,
but to no avail.
(growling and screaming)
(loud rumbling)
(intense electric guitar music)
In desperation, Lord Desecrator
sent three other warriors
to destroy Dominator.
Decimator, Extricator,
and Lady Violator.
But the real war
is just beginning.
("Carrion" by Cradle of Filth)
* Lurking in the shade
* Of dark and fragrant trees
* Shaking from the rage
* That tore the heavens free
* A vagrant Angel
* His with span to see
* The garden swell with terrors
* To banish man and Eve
* Another fall from grace
* Whiplashed from the gates
* Half-naked and insane
* Full-blooded, breasted
* Nerve ends tested
* To behests of pain
* A sombre lot to gain
* A storm slid in
* Borne by carnal winds
* The upper ether thinned
* And therein sat abominations
(bells ringing)
(electricity zapping)
- Demonica's fugid,
succubine on entere.
Demonica's fugid,
Oh well a few more Sidney,
then we call it a night.
(groaning)
Yeah I know it's a
hassle Sidney, but
someone's got to do it
or the world will be crawling
with the walking dead.
(lightening crashing)
(growling)
Still no point
bitching about it, eh?
(screaming)
It pays the bills right?
Oh shit.
(glass breaking)
(loud rumbling and crashing)
Oh, if only people knew what
we get up to on their behalf.
And how do we explain this
to the bereaved family?
(bells tinkling)
(heavy metal music)
- Tara, Fina, Dad and
Sidney are nearly done.
Maybe we should
forget all about this.
- You worry too
much little sister.
No sweat, I've got it.
Now let's rock.
(heavy guitar music)
- Now what?
(heavy metal music)
- Tara, Molly, Fina,
you idiots, stop!
You don't know what
you're messing with.
Stop now.
Oh no.
(electricity blasting)
- [Dominator] Up yours scumbag.
(electricity zapping)
What the fuck?
(screaming)
(grunting)
(giggling)
What's going on here then?
Start talking shit head.
- Um, he uh, he can't speak.
He's mute you see.
- [Dominator] I don't give a
damn, I'll kill him anyway.
- It's humping my leg.
Get it off, get it off.
- First time you've ever
turned down free sex.
(laughing)
(growling)
- [Dominator] I knew
this was a wind up.
(loud rumbling)
(electricity zapping)
- Ow, stop it, please.
(glass shattering)
- [Dominator] Play fragetar.
(screaming)
Strike.
Now is one of you dweebs
gonna give me an explanation?
Or do you wanna hear the chorus?
- Oh aren't you cute.
What's your name?
(growling)
- Just keep him off my legs.
(laughing)
(birds chirping)
- Oh what a dream.
This tall dark demon shows
up and oh was he tasty.
- Let me guess, he
made cool music,
smacked some other
demons around,
and smashed Dad's favorite
stained glass window?
Sorry Fina, that was for real.
(giggling)
- Look at Molly.
Hey I wonder what he
likes for breakfast?
- Deviled eggs?
- Nah, 10 shredded wheat.
- I think I know what happened
Mister, um, uh Dominator.
My daughters borrowed one
of my archold volumes.
Somehow playing the lost chord
opened up a gateway from Hell.
- [Dominator] Darkadia,
the sonic region of Hell.
- Uh yes, yes, quite.
And um, well, and
you popped through.
- [Dominator] Then pop me
right bloody back again then.
- Well uh, well I'm, I'm
sure there's a reversal spell
in here somewhere.
Oh yes, this might be it.
- [Dominator] Well?
(clearing throat)
- Well it seems there
isn't a reversal spell
for playing the lost
chord in this volume.
Perhaps it'll be in
one of the others.
- [Dominator] It had
fucking better be.
- Look it isn't my fault we
can't send you back immediately.
And we can't shut that
bloody gateway either.
God alone knows what
else might come through.
- [Dominator] Not
God, but maybe Ozzy.
Or maybe even Elvis,
if we're really lucky.
(metal tinkling)
- So, uh, do we have a deal?
I guarantee to find a way
to send you back home,
and in the meantime you can
stay with us and deal with
anything else that comes
through that gateway, hmm?
What's that?
- [Dominator] Uh nothing
that concerns you.
Just concentrate
on getting me home.
Unless of course
you want to throw
your daughters into the bargain.
- My daughters?
What do you take me for?
- [Dominator] Ah, don't worry.
I'll pay for them.
(electricity zapping)
- [Lady Violator]
Always the ladies man.
Hey my love.
- [Dominator] Lady Violator.
And I take it from the gorillas
that you're not here for a shag?
- Before you hand
over your women,
get him to tell you
how he betrayed me.
- Desecrator never said nothing
about no lovey dovey crap.
Right bro?
- Fraggin' A Decimator,
tank that wanker Dominator,
that swally sad.
- Quiet!
I'll deal with this.
Dominator
(speaking in foreign language)
Sonic Pits.
Lord Desecrator demands the
return of that which is his.
The key to Hell.
You will hand it over to me
and return with
us for punishment.
(electricity zapping)
- [Dominator] Clumsy.
- Don't dis the bro.
- They're killing him.
Can't you stop them?
- [Lady Violator] Of course.
But I can't think of a
good reason right now.
(electricity zapping)
- Bastard.
- After him you idiots.
(growling)
(motor cycle engine rumbling)
- [Dominator] Tell Lord
Desecrator to sit on this.
If you ever get back.
- Huh, you got lousy
taste in lovers Vi.
The creep's a coward.
- [Lady Violator]
No, he's clever.
Dominator knows he can't take
on the three of us at once.
- Then lets go get him.
(laughing)
- Dad what's going on?
- Where's Dominator?
- Well might you ask Fina.
It's all going rather
horribly wrong.
- It was awful wasn't it?
With the Lost Chord.
I'm sorry.
- Oh that's alright Tara.
I've a feeling the whole
world's going to be sorry.
The Prime Minster's
going to be livid.
I was supposed to keep
all this under wraps.
- Good grief girl.
Can't you even hold
a mirror straight?
- I'm trainee reporter Miss
Lynn, not a makeup girl.
- You are a dogs body
Lendra, just do as your told.
Good afternoon London, this
is Judith Lynn for XLN.
I'm on the the Thames
embankment speaking to some
of the less fortunate
who live in our capitol.
Uh, uh.
(gasping)
- This is Lendra Patel reporting
from the heart of London
where we are witnessing
an aerial battle between
what I can only
describe as monsters.
- What's the time Mr. Wolf?
- Who fragging cares.
(loud explosion)
- Big Ben's gone.
I don't believe it.
- Surrender and Desecrator
might go easy on you.
There's no reason why you and I
shouldn't get back
together again.
- [Dominator] You're pissing
in the wind Violator.
It's over between us.
Now get lost.
- [Lendra] One of the
creatures has crash landed.
I can see that it's a woman,
and boy is she pissed off.
- Two timing bastard.
(heavy metal music)
(scream singing)
* All for fire
* Keep it on fire
* Burn this noise
(loud rumbling)
* Buckle and break
* Drop it like you say
(yelling battle cry)
(sirens blaring)
- [Lendra] I can hear sirens.
I think the police
are on their way.
- Oh my God.
What the hell is
happening here Bishop?
(heavy metal music)
(loud rumbling)
* All for fire
* Keep it on fire
- We'll take him back to
Lord Desecrator, alive.
- Screw that.
Desecrator only wants the key.
Dominator is ours, right bro?
- Dead fucking A he is.
And the bastards
spraying some up.
(metal tinkling)
(electricity pulsing)
- What the fuck?
- He's using the key.
Look out.
(screaming)
- [Dominator] Cool.
- Excuse me, sir.
Could you tell me who you
are and what's going on here?
- [Dominator] Sure,
right after you take
your clothes off babe.
- Oh.
- [Police] You, halt.
Park or we fire.
You had your chance.
Open fire.
(metal clinging)
(engine rumbling)
Oh bugger.
- Geez.
- Get me Dr. Payne.
Now dammit.
- What the frag
happened there man?
- Dominator used the
key to teleport us away.
Devious wanker.
- Where's Lady Violator?
- Who gives a fuck.
- I don't.
- More to the point,
what are we gonna do?
- I dunno.
- Even if we do
get back to Hell,
Desecrator will kick
our asses for failing.
- Bastard.
Woah what's all this lot Mate?
There's a rook of ale here.
Smells good.
(gulping and burping)
Smooth.
- Hey um, a couple more
before we um, hit the road?
- Alright then piss head.
To Dominator, may he rot
in eternities back passage.
(liquid gurgling and burping)
(instruments tuning)
- Right, fuck 'em all, let's go.
(heavy metal music)
- What?
What uh?
You have to speak up I
can't, I can't hear you.
No I said I can't.
Hang on a minute.
Would you please shut up!
- [Tara] Nice end
to the song Dad.
(electricity sparking)
- What about those others?
- [Dominator] They
went somewhere else.
Forget 'em.
Let's say we make our own music.
(laughing)
- Uh that's quite enough
of that thank you.
Um, Dominator, um, could you
come with me for a moment?
There's some important people
who would like to meet you.
These past few years
an increasing number
of supernatural entities have
found their way to Earth.
We've even had to
start hexing corpses
so they can't be taken
over by the undead.
Don't suppose you know
anything about it?
- [Dominator] Something seems
familiar, I've got to admit.
Dunno know what though.
- Uh no, I don't know either.
I just feel as if
we're over looking
the blindingly
obvious in all this.
What, what?
What the hell are you doing?
- [Dominator] What
I promised I'd do.
Watch.
(cackling and growling)
Oy.
(speaking foreign language)
(metal clinging)
- Fool
Base metal cannot harm me.
- Oh yeah?
What about electricity then?
(screaming)
Hey don't touch that dial.
Bloody Goth's.
- Prime Minister, gentlemen,
this is Dominator.
He claims to be from
the sonic pits of hell.
And I regret to say I've
been unable to send him back,
and now a gateway
has been opened.
I have to warn you
that we can expect more
and possibly worse visitors.
- Sonic pits?
Hell?
- Gentlemen, please,
let's stay calm.
I'm sure Dr. Payne
wouldn't have brought, um,
Dominator here if he
posed as any threat.
- Indeed.
Dominator has agreed to deal
with any further intruders.
In return, I'm looking for
a way to send him back.
- [Dominator] Screw all that.
Just find a way to
get me back home.
'Cause if Lord
Desecrator himself comes
from Hell after me,
your little planet's in a
whole fucking heap of shit.
See ya.
- Now uh Dominator, wait.
- If this Dominator continues
to act as a free agent,
there'll be panic
in the streets.
And if he isn't with
us, he's against us.
I believe I know
someone who can help.
For a price.
(wind whistling)
- Guess who.
Hey, you okay?
- [Dominator] Bored.
Hey, wanna shag?
- Uh frankly yes.
But there are certain rituals
a girl likes, you know.
Talking, getting
to know someone.
So what's home like?
Motorhead album covers
immediately spring to mind.
- [Dominator] It's more like
Cradle of Filth actually.
- Can't blame you for
wanting to get back there.
- [Dominator] Hey I like it.
- You never said why those
others came after you.
- [Dominator] Lady
Violator and her stooges?
Ah, they were after this.
Most valuable thing
in all damnation.
The key to Hell itself.
- It's, it's.
- [Dominator] Powerful
is what it is.
Shred your soul
in seconds if you
don't know what you're doing.
And believe you me,
Lord Desecrator won't
give it up in a hurry.
It means too much to him.
- So, who's Desecrator?
And why steal it from
him in the first place?
- There's a war
going on in Hell.
A war for power.
The key, you see, gives its
owner almost limitless powers.
Lord Desecrator stole the
key first from Lucifer
'cause he fancies himself
as a new top dog in Hell.
So I stole the key from him
as I don't like the idea
of serving that wanker for
the next few thousand years.
So that's why he sent those
others to Earth after me.
- But why not use the
key yourself to get home?
- [Dominator] Nah.
I tried that
already, didn't work.
No idea why.
Sometimes it works for
me, sometimes not at all.
Guess I'm not evil
enough or something.
You're different
from your sisters.
- Same father, three
different mothers.
Cost Dad a fortune
in maintenance.
Molly's mother was a
teacher, Fina's was a witch,
and mine was a model.
- [Dominator] What's this?
Some kind of mating ritual?
- Something like that.
- Guys the cut is
smoking, I mean it.
- Oh get lost Fina,
I'll hear it later.
- Oh come on.
Molly's uploading it right now.
I've got a good
feeling about this.
Dom, you're gonna be a star.
- I'll upload a pic of you Dom.
Uh, strike a pose yeah.
Piss off Sidney.
(grunting)
You're only jealous.
- I'm here at Charing
Cross asking Londoners,
do you believe in
the supernatural?
(squealing)
(electricity sparking)
(heavy metal music)
* Stand and fight
(engine rumbling)
* You're the one
here to claim my soul
(electricity zapping)
(screaming)
(evil laughing)
(loud explosion)
(train wheels squeaking)
(gasping)
- [Dominator] Makes
you horny huh?
What are you doing after
the show then babe?
- Oh.
(ominous music)
(lasers shooting)
(laughing)
("Perfect" by Skith)
* When I go to sleep
* I lay my head
* Then all I can see
is you in front of me
* Why did you
* Creep into my head
* One day
* And you never went away
* Why did you do this
* I am scarred in the nicest
way but I want it to heal
* Feel so pathetic that I
can't control my emotions
* Why I am so hyper every day
* Because of you?
* And I wonder
where, what you are
* As I fall down
* Take my soul away from you
* And I wonder now
* If you weren't so perfect
* What you are as I fall
(loud explosions)
(upbeat music)
(loud crashing and
glass breaking)
- Just so they know what
to put on your gravestone,
it's fragged by the Hellkatt.
- [Dominator] Never
heard of you darling.
- Ditto, but I've been
hired to kill you, and.
- [Dominator] Hey wait
a minute, who are you?
- I'm half human, half
demon on my father's side.
Some big shot called Desecrator.
And when I find him, he's meat.
- [Dominator] It sounds like
we have a whole lot in common.
We should uh, get together.
You know, swap um, amongst
other things, details.
- [Hellkatt] Well
swap something anyway.
(groaning)
- [Dominator] Who hired you?
- Some politician.
Guy called Bishop.
Dunno why though.
- [Dominator] Who cares.
(phone ringing)
- What the hell?
- [Dominator] The Doc gave
it to me for emergencies.
Hey, this better be good.
What?
- It's me Dom, Tara.
The band sites are live man.
Over nine million hits.
We just called a press
conference at the Savoy.
Can you get there?
- [Dominator] Uh
give me a break.
I'm uh, I'm busy,
uh, saving the world.
- Look pal, I wanna be
famous even if you don't.
Please, can you
get to the Savoy?
- [Dominator] I'll definitely
be coming soon Tara.
(groaning)
(laughing)
- [Extricator] Hey
don't go light now.
- Listen, I've got one for you.
Now hey, do you remember when
the Kanakium dead rebelled?
Man we slaughtered those
decomposing bastards.
- We dazed the embattled
souls for weeks didn't we?
- We did.
- Holy shit, hallucinations.
Lord Desecrator.
- What the fuck
are you two doing?
- Um yeah, um sorry boss.
Dominator used that key he
stole off you against us
and he stumped our asses bad.
- Yeah and um, we're
just stocking up for
the rematch, yeah.
- And Lady Violator?
- Um, buggered off somewhere.
I dunno.
- Kill Dominator.
- Sure, yeah, no
problem, yeah we will.
But later.
- Now!
- Listen Desecrator, you're
a big shot in Hell, okay.
But here you're just
a fucking midget.
Copy.
- You will have all
eternity to regret that.
I'll be back.
- You know maybe that
wasn't so clever man.
- Oh who gives a frag.
A toast!
Fuck all fuckers.
- Good fucking toast.
A fucking men, man.
Bottoms up.
- [Lendra] What are they?
Where did they come from?
Why the hell are
they wrecking London?
- Dammit man, you told me we
were dealing with a few ghosts.
- Relax sir, and try to
get a good nights sleep.
Things always look
better in the morning.
I wish.
- What if your wish was
answered Mr. Bishop?
Indeed, what if I
were to offer you
the position of
King of the world?
- All girl rock group Crowcut
has set the music world ablaze.
Every celeb in town is out
tonight for their launch party.
I can see Miss Gurley, Howard
Volderman, and oh Dominator.
(applauding)
- [Dominator] Hey,
looking good kid.
(heavy techno music)
- Look I really like him.
And I know he
feels the same way.
- Yeah right.
- He's stringing you along
like a thunderbirds puppet.
- Not.
He took me into his confidence.
He showed me the key he
stole from Desecrator.
That's why those
others came after him.
(car horn honking)
- Where have you been?
People are getting impatient.
- Hey don't hustle
the main man Tara.
- Come on, it's play time.
(audience cheering
and applauding)
- Hi everyone.
We're Crowcut.
Sorry we're late.
This one's called
Die Goth's Die.
(heavy metal music)
- [Lady Violator] Relax.
Don't to fight me.
Traitor!
Pick this you bastard.
(electricity surging)
(screaming)
- Scum!
- [Dominator] Violator's
taken control of your mind.
You have to fight back Tara.
Fight back Tara!
Fight damn you!
- I, I.
It's alright, I've
got my head back.
Oops, I think I've
got her body as well.
Cool
And her powers.
Hey I can fly.
- [Dominator] Are you alright?
- I am now.
- Lucky cow.
- Why her?
Not even as if she's
the pretty one.
- Mind and get beer now Dave.
None of your cheap wine.
What's the big idea?
Put the fucking lights out.
- [Police] On your feet.
- [Homeless Man] Says
fucking who, James.
- [Police] Says
fucking me, asshole.
- Where are we going man?
- [Police] Somewhere warm.
Don't you worry.
- The beer was too expensive.
So I got some.
Oh shit.
- You caused havoc back there.
This can't go on.
- [Dominator] Then
send me back home.
- You think I haven't tried.
None of the usual spells work.
Like something on the other
side was counteracting them.
- [Dominator] Desecrator.
What's he up to?
(electricity zapping)
- Well?
- [Dominator] No ecto residue.
Whatever took those people,
it wasn't from my town.
- 200 homeless have vanished
in London over the last week.
Isn't there anyway you can
tell what happened here?
- [Dominator] Hey, I can try.
Lemme see.
(electricity sparking)
- Military.
It has to be.
And that means the government.
(liquid pouring)
- [Fina] Looks like
you could use this.
Good for the soul, they say.
To you sweetie.
Oh much better.
- [Dominator] Ah, to me.
Oh you're beautiful.
("Heroin" by Jezebel)
* Can't feel my skin
* Can't open my mouth
* Can't do anything
* No mind, no limbs
* My eyes have peeled
* Just let me lie here
* Free from fear
* Quiet on the floor
* For the first time the great
tales have something to adore
* Hell I feel so nice
(electricity zapping)
- [Fina] This is
what you wanted?
- [Dominator] Fina stop!
- You shouldn't interfere
in my plans Dominator.
It hurts me.
And soon I will hurt you.
- [Dominator] Not clever.
That key gives Lord Desecrator
a whole lot of power
he doesn't need.
- Oh shit, I'm
sorry, I didn't mean.
- You bastards.
- [Extricator] God, you dropped
one in a Hackney carriage?
- [Decimator] No.
(farting)
I am now.
Oh come on you daft
bastard, we're here.
Shift your fat ass.
- I haven't got an ass,
fat or otherwise, have I?
- Well just, well shift your
skull and tentacles then.
Come on, get out.
Come on you fat bastard.
- [Dominator] Don't
you two ever learn?
- No, not us man.
- [Dominator] What do you want?
- Eh we've left
Desecrator's employment.
We've gotten the sack,
drinking on the job.
- Okay short version.
We get home, Desecrator
wipes us out.
If he found his way,
then dit fucking oh.
- Right.
- Now, seeing as
he's after you too,
we figured we'd stand a
better chance together.
What do you say pal?
Let's all be heroes
and save the Earth.
- [Dominator] This hero
thing seems to be catching.
- Hey, we're starting
to like this mud ball.
It's fun.
We don't want Desecrator
up here spoiling it.
- You said it me man.
(somber music)
- Right, get her now.
- [Police] Open fire.
(electricity zapping)
- Hi.
We've got quite a
night ahead of us.
We're going to discover
all your secrets.
And an old friend of yours
might be dropping by as well.
Cool, huh?
- You mean Lord Desecrator?
You idiot.
You can't.
- Oh I can, I will.
And you're going to help me.
- But she can't have
just disappeared.
- [Dominator] Tara has Lady
Violator's body and powers now.
She can take care of herself.
- She's my daughter
for Christ sake.
- It's my fault she went.
Maybe I can find her.
- Fina, what are you doing?
- Mom was a witch remember?
She taught me a few things.
There, St. Paul's Cathedral.
- [Dominator] Oy you two,
let's go save the bitter skirt.
Oh yeah, if it's Desecrator,
we'll be needing help.
Call this number.
("10-4 Rocker" by V8 Pack)
* Last night you burned the sky
* Stay low 'cause
my wheels are high
* Rolling baby just fine
* Looking to rock
tonight, it's wild
* Zero gravity on my heels
* I'm flying that's all I can do
* To get rock around
* Screaming in my ear
* That 10-4 rocker
speeding like a jet
* Number seven all that rocking
* For the 10-4 rocker
* He's getting it in
(organ music)
(engine rumbling)
- [Dominator] You, dog collar,
we're looking for a girl.
About so-so.
Huh, be like that then.
- Oh bugger, ambush.
- [Dominator] Chill Decimator.
She's with me.
- Fuh, strike a
line, look at that.
Eh, you would, wouldn't ya?
- Well I would if I had any
discernible genitals, yeah.
- [Decimator] Well
what's that then?
I thought that was your nob.
- That's me gun.
(screaming)
- The chains will
keep her quiet while
the machine draws off
her energy and uses it
to feed to feed this
process you've set up.
Whatever it is.
- Official secret.
Need to know only.
Thank you.
(mumbling)
Everything's ready.
You got what you wanted?
- I possess the key once more.
My powers are at
optimum strength.
Start the transfer.
- The raw material for
your Earth body is ready.
But how do I know
you'll keep your word?
- Believe me, your
stature shall be
as no mortal has
ever known before.
(screaming)
(growling)
- [Police] Here it
comes, get ready.
Open fire.
- Honestly what kind
of a welcome is that?
- I think we're in
the right place.
(sirens blaring)
(screaming)
- [Man] We've got intruders sir.
- Stop them, by any
means necessary.
This won't take much longer.
- [Dominator] Having
fun Mr. Bishop?
- Fraggin' A.
- [Dominator] Gotcha babe.
- Oh thank you, you
two timing bastard.
It's your fault I'm here.
If you hadn't shagged that
sex starved sister of mine.
- [Dominator] Ah yeah,
sorry about that.
- Looks like we got
here just in time.
- Oh do you think so?
Huh, look.
(lasers shooting)
- I'll be, frag me with a
sharp stick, look at that.
- Now, the sacrifice of flesh.
(heavy breathing)
- Oh shit.
- And um, what now smart ass?
- I haven't got an ass,
either smart or otherwise.
You get stalking, you're
the big angry looking one.
- Bugger that.
- Well you're all mouth
and CGI trousers you.
- That's my father?
- [Dominator] Yeah,
that's him alright.
- Pucker up Daddy,
it's fragging time.
- You're no daughter of mine.
Burn bastard, burn.
- [Dominator] Leave
her alone bastard.
It's me you want.
(laughing)
- Nice one nob head.
You trying to get us all wiped?
- [Dominator]
Everybody outside, now.
- You're a beast of
your word Desecrator.
We can do business together.
- Insect.
You do what I tell you.
There is much I need to
know about this world,
and you will tell me.
I will suck your
soul's knowledge dry
like marrow from a bone.
- But, but you
said, wait a minute,
I built a new body for you.
- I lied.
This world shall
finally be mine.
All that I planned
has come to pass.
You and Dominator and the
others unwittingly paved the way
for me by weakening the
fabric between Hell and Earth.
Now it is time for me to
assume my rightful place
as ruler of all realities.
- Oh shit.
(screaming)
(heavy metal music)
- St. Paul's Cathedral
where something
very weird is going on.
The building itself
appears to be collapsing.
(glass shattering)
Oh my god, what
the hell is that?
- Here comes trouble.
- Hello London.
- Maybe not.
- Well go to the
foot of our stairs.
- What is that?
- Desecrator.
Oh bollocks, we're too late.
- Ow.
I'll never be mean
to a fucker again.
We safe yet?
- [Dominator] Uh no.
- Can we stop him?
- [Dominator] Maybe.
But I say we hit the bastard
with everything we've got.
(loud rumbling)
(intense heavy metal)
(loud explosions and
glass shattering)
- King of the
world, king of Hell,
king of every fragging where.
- Oh my god, he's
eaten the world.
- [Dominator] Yeah that's
one way of looking at it.
- We need a plan dammit.
- [Dominator] Yeah, such as?
- It's all your fault Tara.
You talked us into playing
the last chord in
the first place.
- Right bloody
mess we're in now.
- [Dominator] Come off it.
You gave Desecrator
his key back.
Without it, he
wouldn't have been able
to cross over to Earth.
- Hey.
- Hellkatt said Desecrator
raped her mother,
but then he returned to Hell.
How did that get arranged?
- A sacrifice I think.
- We need to find a sacrifice
bigger than all those poor
people that helped bring him
through in the first place.
Hey what if we get Desecrator
to sacrifice himself?
- Sounds good.
So what do we use as
the sacrificial knife.
- Look, what if we hit the
key with something so powerful
that it unlocks Desecrator
from his new body
and drags his
spirit back to hell?
Something like.
- [Dominator] The Lost
Chord played backwards.
- You do that, while
I perform an exorcism
and I think we may
get a serious result.
- It's as good a plan as any.
Shall we?
- [Dominator] Yeah, let's
go frag the bastard.
(intense heavy metal music)
Just make sure you
time it right Doc.
- Just you get on with it.
(growling singing)
(electricity zapping)
- [Dominator] Oy,
you lot, follow me.
Quick through there, we've
got to find his brain.
* Here we go, here
we go, here we go
- Down there, I can feel him.
Eat shit Daddy.
- Oops.
- You presume to challenge
the king of everything?
Then die!
- Oh bugger, the
power's gone down.
- Anybody got 10
pound for the meter.
Oy, Dom, we're in
big trouble here.
- [Dominator] The
rest of you fall back.
Leave the rest to me.
- Like hell.
I'm coming with you.
- [Dominator] Bullocks you are.
Hellkatt, get her out of here.
- No.
(intense metal music)
- Come to me little insect.
- [Dominator] Alright Doc, now!
- Exo demonicas, exo
malificarum, exo monsterous.
- What?
No, not me you
cannot sacrifice me.
(screaming singing)
(loud explosion)
- [Molly] What happened?
Where's Dominator?
- Still up there.
- I think it's over.
- Cool.
Hi Sis.
- You okay?
- I don't know.
Ask me later.
(engine rumbling)
You did it.
You got him.
- [Dominator] Huh,
it was nothing.
- Ugh.
- Thank God that's over.
- I wouldn't be
surprised if he gave us
a hand somewhere along the line.
Hey where are you two off to?
- We're gonna find
a bar and celebrate.
- Yeah alcohol's cool.
I need a new hobby now
that I'm stuck here.
- Fair enough.
Have one for me.
- [Dominator] Hey, they've
got the right idea.
Shall we?
- Does Keith
Richards play guitar?
- [Dominator] Only
when I let him.
Come on.
(engine rumbling)
- Aw, I was hoping
for a a threesome.
- Um, I have to explain
things to the Prime Minister.
Another time perhaps.
- That's alright.
But uh, see if he
fancies joining in.
(laughing)
- Oh that was a day and
a half wasn't it archaic?
- Unbelievable archy.
- [Extricator] I'll tell you
what, looking back on it.
- [Decimator] Yeah.
- [Extricator] I thought we
were a bit dirty to start with.
- [Decimator] We
were a bit yeah.
- [Extricator] And
for no good reason.
And then we got good
and we got nice.
- [Decimator] Yeah.
- [Extricator] And
we saved the world.
- [Decimator] Yeah.
- [Extricator] And
we developed a taste
for ale all in the same day.
- [Decimator] I tell you
what, being a good guy,
and liking beer, right,
is really something.
- [Extricator] Right okay.
And when you've
properly developed a
mature taste for ale,
I mean do you think you'll
be a lager or a bitter man?
- [Decimator] Oh a
bitter man definitely.
I'm a pile of Cripple
Dick for me, yeah.
- [Extricator] Oh really?
- [Decimator] Yeah,
why, what do you like?
- [Extricator] Oh I'm thinking
of going for lager top?
- [Decimator] Lager top?
No that's a southern
Jessie's drink.
- [Extricator] Oh is it?
- [Decimator] Yeah.
- [Extricator] I might go
on the Mumps Dong then.
- [Decimator] Alright fine yeah.
- [Extricator] I'll
tell you something else.
- [Decimator] What?
- [Extricator] I'm dead
pleased about this.
- [Decimator] What?
- [Extricator] Well
when we started off
we were just two
minor characters.
- [Decimator] Right.
- [Extricator] And
now here we are
in the end title sequence.
- [Decimator] Wow,
yeah, that's brilliant.
Hang on.
- [Extricator] What?
- [Decimator] We're not
getting paid anymore for this,
are we?
- [Extricator]
Right, shut up then.
("Psycho Sister" by Dominator X)
* Alright, get me
up, make me scream
* I got the answer
for these dark deeds
* I gotta run it,
gonna make it clear
* Stop me now, I
gotta taste your fear
* The devil take you ecstasy
* Burning inside me
* Devil take you, LSD, burning
* Wild and free
* Spit it out
* Twist my head, I'm
gonna make you shout
* See I kneel, between
your loving thighs
* So bite me now, I
wanna hear you sigh
* Devil take you, ecstasy
* Burning inside me
* Devil take you, fantasy
* Burning
* Hot and free
* Psycho sister
* Suck on this
* Know where I can find
someone's late night show
* Gags in a bottle,
gonna make you blow
* Gotta bring you down
* Gotta detonate
* Never blue or red
* 'Cause it's just to late
* Devil take you, fantasy
* Burning inside me
* Devil take you, ecstasy
* Burning hot and free
* I'm on TV, gotta make you see
* Video god's gotta a cameo free
* See my hand picking up the gun
* Say your prayers,
gonna make you run
* Psycho sister
* Suck on this