Subrip by DanDee
Your call has been forwarded
to an automatic
voice message system.
At the tone, please
record your message.
When you have finished
recording,
you may hang up
or press 1 for more options.
Hey, Robert. It's your dad.
Long time, no see.
Um, I've called you a few times.
You're a hard man to get
in contact with, these days.
Uh, do me a favor.
Call me when you get this.
Thanks.
What are you doin' here?
Your dad's
started calling me now.
Mm-hmm.
Make him stop.
I'm goin' to work.
What?
What year was that?
- '97. Yeah.
- Very good.
We've been comin' here
a long time.
- Hey.
- Oh, Robert.
- Hey, Sampson. How you doin'?
- Good seeing you.
- Hey. Good seeing you.
- You look good.
Oh, thank you. Hey.
Hey. Everything good?
Yeah. It's great.
Good.
You, uh,
thought about my offer?
Dad, I'm not gonna go
work for my parents.
I'm pickin' up jobs.
It's goin' all right.
You know,
it's just the beginning.
Okay.
Wouldn't have thought
photography
could pay the rent, but.
So, what's up?
Why all the messages?
Why don't we order, first?
Dad, what's going on?
Your mother is in Cabo.
You had an affair?
Again?
Jesus!
You know, midlife is
a very difficult time, Robert.
- Is it?
- Yeah. It is.
- Mm.
- And why can't you have
a civil conversation
about life, here?
So this is about me?
Robert, come on.
Hey, Robert, what are you doing?
Come on! Robert!
Robert, your father's habit
of having sex with girls half
of his age is getting old,
so, I'm gonna take off
for a while.
I'll be back in time
for your opening.
If you need money, take the job.
¶ Unh ¶
¶ unh ¶
You ready?
All right.
Hair's looking fine.
Thank you.
That's it.
What's up, dude?
- This is my friend, Robert.
- Hey.
Hey.
Oh, cool.
I know.
Time for the picture.
Oh, okay.
Nice one.
Ah!
Hey, Marc.
Morning, Roberto.
Pretty early for you, bud.
- A little bit.
- Uh-huh.
So?
What do you say, $500?
In your dreams.
I could probably swing $75.
7...? The frame
is worth more than $75.
$150. Ahem.
Thank you. Thank you.
Cups of coffee.
And I'm counting, this time.
All right.
Thank you.
- Deal?
- Deal.
All right.
Can I get two cups to go?
One with extra cream.
Put cream in the coffee,
you ruin the notes.
Agh. That's too much cream.
You gotta stay positive,
man, you know?
You're just about to blossom.
I feel it.
I might need one of my photos
back from you
to make rent this month.
Yeah, man.
Whatever you need. Hmm?
Well, I'm gonna go to work.
Call me if you have the urge
to, you know, end it.
Look at this hair.
Beautiful.
- It's fantastic. - Fantastic.
- Thank you
Who is here?
- Aaah!
- Oh, man. Yeah.
Oh, that stinks.
That's very...
I think you win.
- Robert. Attendance.
- I think you're...
- All right.
- All right, everybody,
please be neat.
Push in your seat
- and head over to the mat, okay?
- You can take that over there.
- It's time for attendance.
- Can I take this?
You can take those with you,
if you want.
Just bring 'em over there.
Let's do this.
After we do attendance
and reading, okay?
All right.
Let's start with Raymond.
Where are...?
Oh, there you are, Raymond.
- And then we we have Amanda.
- Alison.
Amanda. All right,
you gonna keep that
cash register with you?
Okay. So do...
Come over here for attendance.
Time for attendance.
You know what? I'll take over.
You go. Yeah. Thank you.
What is this?
This is for you.
All right?
She didn't paint it.
It was with her stamp.
I like it. I like the...
All right, you guys.
Why'd you put her in my class?
It's Alison's class,
not yours.
Why did you put her
in my class?
My dojo, my rules.
I thought
this wasn't gonna happen.
I thought th-this woman...
Sara Walsh.
You know her name.
Yeah. Sara Whatever.
She disappears years ago.
She's back now.
You're gonna float her?
It's a little more complicated
than that, Robert.
You don't even know
that she's your kid.
I'm 90% sure.
We're gonna go to a paternity
test to be 100% sure.
Great. So, when you're
100% sure, then what?
We try to work it out, Robert.
- What are you doing?
I am tryin' to work here.
What the hell are you doin'?
Hey, Mom.
What are you doing
in my office?
Seriously?
You need to get back here
before Dad ruins my life.
- Harry, stop hiding.
- I'm not hiding, dear.
Right.
So how's Mason adjusting?
You knew about this?
Robert, I have to support
your father.
This is a very difficult
time for all of us.
- Thank you, Miriam.
- If we're being supportive,
all of a sudden,
then why aren't you here?
Because your father's a prick.
Thanks, Miriam.
So, have you met
the mother yet?
No! No.
I'm not going to.
Why don't you just say
hello to her after school?
She could be the mother
of your sister, Robert.
- Half-sister.
- All right. Half-sister. Okay.
So, you gotta meet her.
I quit.
I'm serious.
You hear that?
It's good, right?
Yeah. What do you plan to do
to make money there,
Mapplethorpe? Hmm?
All right, honey.
I think that's it.
Come home soon.
I hate this.
Buh-bye.
Robert.
- We're gonna be 20 minutes late.
- Is this a setup?
No. It's not all about you,
Mr. Narcissist, okay?
This is about me inviting you
to a work friend's dinner party
because, I don't know,
you had a bad day.
So, then, it is about me.
Touché.
You didn't hear it?
It was tremendously loud.
Some nice notes.
Lenny, how long do you
cook that bird for?
You know like 45 minutes, 350°,
but then, the last 5 minutes,
you just blast it
in the broiler.
Golden-brown on top.
- It looks amazing.
- Thank you. Thank you.
- My mother's recipe.
- Wow.
Take the fork.
Just take the fork.
- Right, do you want me to cut it?
- No.
Why don't you just...?
I say just rip it.
Take it, oh.
- Yeah.
- Hey.
So, Robert, uh, Lenny tells us
that you just finished
an exhibition.
- I think it was photography.
- Photography. Yeah.
- Cool.
- Yeah.
That was a few years ago.
I'm currently working
on other things,
personal things.
- Anna
- Hmm?
- is an actress.
- Hmm.
Well, I work at a restaurant.
That's crazy 'cause I
also work at a restaurant.
- Yeah?
- Funny enough, I'm...
I'm actually a barista.
It's kind of, uh, you know,
it's a... it's a passion.
- Cool.
- Yeah. It's nice.
I work at a preschool.
Oh, cool.
Robert shot Jesse Singleton's
album cover.
Oh! I love that album!
We used to listen to that album
all the time, right?
We sure did.
A great record.
And, uh, which...
which part
did you actually shoot?
It was on the cover
of the album.
- Yeah.
- It was great stuff.
- It was in the alley.
- Yeah.
Well, so, what do you do
at the preschool?
I do like attendance.
I walk the kids from class
to class, you know?
That's great.
Creative environment for you
to make your art in.
No. Actually,
it's pretty miserable.
My parents run the school
and they're crazy.
And, to top it off, my dad just
enrolled a new student today,
who happens to be
his estranged daughter
from a woman
who is not my mother.
So it's a pretty dark time
in my life right now.
Thank you so much
for having us over.
- Our pleasure.
- Yeah. Dig in!
Fantastic.
New York City's a great place
to raise a child.
Dad, I thought about it
and I'm not gonna meet them.
If that means I'm gonna
lose my job, then...
Robert, speak of the devil.
- This is...
- I know you.
- You do?
- Sara-Beth!
Wh... where did you say
that we met before?
I shot Jesse's album
cover in the alley?
We hung out at the bar after.
- Oh!
- Yeah.
- Oh, wow. Okay.
Oh, my goodness.
So you're Harry's... s... son.
- Son, exactly. Yeah.
- Okay. Hi.
Wow. How nice.
I found your number.
I tried to call you
like a thousand times.
How's Jesse doin'?
He's doing...? He's good?
He's good. He's good.
He's workin' on a new album.
What are you doin' here?
I...
- Mommy!
- Hey, pretty girl.
Can you say hello to Robert?
Hi.
Robert, this is
Mason's mother, Sara.
Harry, Lynn Aldridge
would like to speak with you.
- About what?
- Naptime.
She thinks 30 minutes
is excessive.
I'll be there.
Give me a second.
- Okay. So did we...?
- What?
You don't think
he knows about...?
No.
I'm so sorry.
This is weird for me,
but it must be very
weird for you.
Yeah.
So we probably shouldn't
tell him that we...
No. I think...
I think we... we can omit...
So, small world, huh?
Question:
How did you two meet?
I went back to that bar where
you and your friends hang out.
- Ha.
- Wait. What bar? My bar?
I guess.
Why would you
go back there alone?
You're too old for that bar.
Uh, apparently not, Robert.
My fuckin' bar.
Jesus Christ.
Be careful, Easy Rider.
Hey. You ready to party?
Remember her?
Let's see here.
Yeah.
The eyes, the ass, the rack.
Yeah, of course.
I also remember you fuckin' her.
I was in the room next door.
My dad fucked her, too.
Uh, sorry, I thought you said
that your father actually
had sex with her.
Yeah.
Wow.
Oh, my god.
Uh, yeah. Oh, man.
All right.
Well, we gotta go.
Let's talk about it on the way.
Think my dad
is getting off on all this?
Yeah. It's possible.
I mean, it's negative thinking,
but it's possible.
You know, you could be
Mason's father.
No. That's impossible.
I've thought about it.
I'm not.
- When was she born?
- Uh, January 20-somethin'.
And when did you
shoot the album cover?
- May.
- No. It got released in May.
You shot it in April.
It's possible.
Think about it.
- What's up?
- Uh, nothin'. Uh...
Nothin'.
Do you remember Sara-Beth?
She was that blonde stylist
at your shoot.
We hung out with her
at our bar after.
- What bar?
- Uh...
Oh.
I can't believe it's you.
I haven't seen you
in months, man.
What have you been up to?
Anything new?
No. Just cruisin'.
Mm. Cruisin'. Nice.
- Are you done with that album?
- It's done.
- It's slated for spring, man.
- Cool.
We should do like another
album cover together.
- Really?
- Let's do something big. Yeah.
- You sure?
- Totally. I bet we can pay you,
- this time, too.
- All right.
- Aubrey. Hey.
- Hey.
Let's go, Jesse.
Robert, this is Aubrey.
Aubrey, this is Robert.
- Hi.
- We met.
- Oh.
- A couple of times, we met.
- Yeah.
- Hey. I'll call you, yeah?
Yeah. Cool.
Cruisin'.
Who says cruisin'?
Oh, hey. Excuse me.
Sorry.
- Was that Jesse Singleton?
- No.
Hmm.
- Hey, Robert.
- Hey, Anna.
Nice shirt.
'Cause we're...
we are wearing the same shirt.
Yep.
Small world.
I never knew you were
such a good conversationalist.
- Oh, my god.
- You okay?
April.
Kidding.
April. Yeah.
Okay.
Okay. So the evidence
is pretty overwhelming.
Mm-hmm.
But, you know, maybe neither
of you is the father.
I mean, she's in fashion.
I mean, I gotta tell him,
though, right?
Yeah.
I'm gonna come with you.
- I'm an uncle.
- Put your hand...
You're not my brother.
- You're not an uncle.
- Whoa whoa whoa. We've lived
together for 5 years.
We've grown together.
We've regressed together.
That makes me an uncle.
I can't.
I can't handle these
bizarre life calculations
right now.
All right. Furthermore,
I don't wanna be like
one of those pedophile,
bizarre like
take-the-kid-to-the-ballpark
uncles.
I wanna be, you know,
great uncle Lenny,
imparting wisdom.
- If you're comin', let's go.
- Are we going?
I'm ready. I'm ready.
I don't think he's here.
- What are you...?
- Oops!
Home, sweet home,
where father and son
once romped.
Shut up.
Come on, man. I'm trying
to create a loving context
for this announcement.
Stay positive.
Hey, do you still
have porn on this TV?
- Lenny.
- What?
Oh, come on.
Look, it's a scientific method.
Look.
Don't make me feel bad for
trying to better myself, man.
Ahem.
- Dad.
- I'm in here.
Agh!
So much for Mom's yoga studio.
Ah-ha.
Agggh!
From every difficulty
comes opportunity.
Who said that?
- Liberace.
- Close.
- Albert Einstein.
- Mm.
Dad, we need to talk.
Okay.
One more set.
You may have to spot me.
Uh!
A little red?
No, thank you.
Ah.
- So, tell me.
- Right. Ahem.
- Oh, hi, Harold.
- Oh. Hello, Lenny.
- Mind if I join you guys?
- Well...
FYI, your porn channels
are down.
I don't have
porn channels, Lenny, FYI.
- That's my point.
- What're you wastin'
my time for?
Why do you come into my house?
- You're attacking me.
- I'm attacking you 'cause
- I just came in here.
- You come and you wanna
- watch porn at my house?
- Well, yeah.
Don't do it.
Don't touch my stuff.
I don't understand
this hostility towards me.
Mason might be my daughter.
- What?
- We had unprotected sex.
We had... Me and Sara-Beth.
We. Me and Sara-Beth.
Congratulations, Grandpa.
Must be quite a relief.
Why are you here?
Dad, I had sex with her
at least a week before you did.
Wh... what is this?
Documentation.
Lenny took it.
He can vouch for the events
that followed.
Our walls are paper-thin.
And I watched.
Only for a minute.
- Please leave.
- Yeah. Right away.
- Dad, it might be...
- What... what... what is this?
Come on. What, is this
some kind of payback
for me cheatin' on your mom,
goin' to your bar.
- Just look at the date.
- April '09.
Yes. Okay. So that is 9 months
before Mason is born.
Think about it, Harry.
It checks out.
Get the fuck outta my house!
You can ask her!
I hate him.
- Are you sure?
- I'm pretty sure, yes.
Yes, I'm sure.
Wow.
Ha ha. Okay.
All right.
Did you tell Sara yet?
- No. Not yet.
- All right.
- Oh, my god. What are you doin'?
- What's it look like
- I'm doin', Robert?
- You're not gonna call her.
This is not a business call.
We have to tell her this
- in person.
- The DNA test is tomorrow.
You're coming and she needs
time to process this.
Why don't you guys
just have a three-way?
Oh, my...
Conference call,
like a hard line.
What?
No, Daddy,
we are fine on our own.
It doesn't matter where we are.
I am not telling...
Daddy, I gotta go.
I have another call. Okay?
- Hi, Harry.
- Hi! Hi, Sara.
- Uh, Robert's here too.
- I'm here. I'm here.
- Oh. Hi, Robert.
- Hi.
So, there's been
this whole...
development
in the fatherhood situation.
Uh, yeah, so there's, uh,
documentation that exists
that indicates that you and I
may have had...
Just get to it.
That we might both be
the father.
Okay. Um...
Well, will the test be able
to sort that kind of thing out
- or...?
- A- Absolutely.
- Are you okay?
- All right.
- Are you o...?
- Yeah. Yeah. No. I'm fine.
I'll see you...
both of you... tomorrow
at the doctor's, I guess.
- Okay.
- All right.
- Bye. Bye.
- Bye.
Ohhh.
"Both be the father,"
seriously?
- Yeah.
- That's what you came up with?
- Okay. All right.
- Guys. Guys, guys, guys, guys.
It's confusing.
- How's Miriam, Harry?
- Oh, she's great.
She's still on vacation.
Interesting time
to take a vacation.
Yeah.
May I ask how Daddy and Junior
ended up dipping
in the same well?
- Hey, guys!
- Hey.
How you doin'?
Sorry I'm a little late.
Mwah. Good to see you.
Hi. Sara-Beth Walsh.
- Nice to meet you.
- Very nice to meet you.
And this is
my daughter, Mason.
- Hi.
- Hi!
So, the process is simple.
We take a hair,
we draw some blood,
send it to the geneticist.
Should take about a week
to get a result.
- Great.
- Okay.
Thank you.
- How are you?
- Good! We're good.
- Is the blood draw necessary?
- Robert, man up, will ya?
- For God's sake.
- You know, you're the one
- having a midlife crisis.
- Oh.
Hi. I mean, who's
the 4-Year-old around here?
- Can we stop? Can we stop?
- Is it you, or is it her?
Enough. Enough.
Robert's afraid of blood,
so, he's scared.
- Oh, really?
- Take it easy. It's all right.
You'll live through this.
Ahem!
Who's first?
Sometimes I wish I hadn't
converted the building
into a preschool,
but, parents will always
- take care of their kids first.
- Right.
- That's the rule.
- That's true.
And kids?
Kids are very good business.
Sara-Beth, check this out.
Oh, I remember these.
They supposed
to be that grainy?
Yeah. You should look at 'em
with your glasses on
next time, Dad.
Aha ha ha.
Ahem. Let's go, kids.
Sara-Beth,
are you still in fashion?
- Guilty.
- Yeah. Now she's starting
her own clothing line, Robert,
branding herself
and everything like that.
It's kind of great.
A girl can dream, right?
- Ha ha.
- Yeah, I salvage
vintage dresses, jewelry,
that kind of stuff.
And why'd you leave New York?
You know, being in Knoxville
with my family
seemed like a much more
viable option.
They really helped out a lot.
They essentially raised her.
Well, it is good
to have you back.
- Thank...
- Yes, it is. Yes, it is.
Aw, thank you. Yeah.
It's... it's good to be back.
I... I love New York.
And, plus, I wanted Mason
to meet her father.
I think she thought
my dad was her dad,
so it was getting
a little confusing.
Yeah. I can't believe you
didn't know all that, Robert.
H... how would I know that?
She was living in Texas.
Actually, Tennessee.
Knoxville, Tennessee.
Heh. Had to leave him back
a year. He's a little slow.
Oh.
So, in the meantime,
I'm actually doing styling
for Tosh Wolfe?
Wow. That's...
I... I love him.
I... I have one of his books.
Cool. Good.
He's amazing.
He's a photographer, Dad.
I realize that, Robert.
I bought you that book.
Well, guys,
thank you so much
for dealing with me and...
- Hey.
- Staying with me
- throughout all of this.
- Don't worry about it.
- It's not a problem.
- All right, well, I guess
I'll see you both
at the end of the week.
- Mm-hmm.
- Hey, listen,
if Mason needs anything...
clothes, shoes,
I don't know, uh, toys...
take care of it.
And Joyce will be dropping
her off here after work.
- Thank you so much, Harry.
- I get paid next week,
so I can chip in.
Thank you.
Thank you both, so much.
Call me if you need
anything, okay?
- Yeah, I will.
- All right.
Hopefully, next week,
it won't be so weird, ha.
- Word.
- Okay.
- Yeah, word.
- Bye, guys.
- Ahem.
By the way, I saw the way
that you were looking at her.
Right. Right.
And you weren't.
Let me make something
clear, all right?
I am not interested in that kind
of relationship with Sara.
Wh... what kind of relationship
are you interested in?
Look, do us both a favor
and keep it in your pants
until we know what's what
and who's whose.
Got it.
By the way, her name is Mason
and I'm perfectly capable
of being a father.
Yeah, that's
some father figure,
living in a shithole with Lenny.
Have fun on your little
scooter, dear.
Dear.
Son of a fuck!
Heh.
Ahem.
Hi, honey. It's me.
Right.
Yeah, that's good.
I got good news.
You're being way
too grim about this.
Elaborate on how
I'm being too grim.
You're lucky
you can be a father.
You're lucky you have a father
who would support you,
if you are a father and,
chances are,
your father is the actual
father of said child.
That's pretty good advice,
coming from a guy
who never knew his father,
right?
I have no idea
what you're talking about.
Look, I'm just saying
that, you know,
I don't know.
It's complicated.
I don't know. Either way,
I think I gotta at least
kind of figure this out
with Sara-Beth.
- No. No.
- Right? At least.
No. No. No.
Stay away from her.
She might be fucking
your father.
- Lenny...
- You know, if you want to get
that image out of your head,
you can watch some porn.
Hey, Anna!
Hello.
Hey. How you been?
You know? I am good.
Good.
You guys just chillin'?
What?
We're good.
Um...
how is your... situation?
What?
Oh, I told her.
- Thanks, Lenny.
- Sure.
Um,
I'll probably figure it
out in a few days.
More like Connect Three, huh?
- Ha.
- Hmm? What?
Don't worry about it.
Do you... want a sandwich?
Hmm... no. No.
I was just walking by.
Cool.
Yeah.
You guys should meet up
next week.
- That works. That works for me.
- Sure. Works for me.
- Yeah?
- He can call you.
- That's great.
- That's a great idea.
- Right?
Great. I'll call you.
Goo-oo-d. Okay.
I'm gonna...
Ha!
- She great?
- You don't find it weird
that she just invites herself
to the table?
- Perfectly normal.
- Normal?
Oh, yeah.
Oh, my god. Look at this.
Connect four.
I didn't even realize.
Look at that.
You want to play again?
I love this place.
You excited?
Here we go.
Go on inside.
Why aren't you inside?
- Day off.
- Oh.
- Yeah.
- Cool.
You wanna grab some coffee
or something downtown?
Yeah.
Yeah, that would be great.
Do we just hop
on the Metro and go?
We could hop on the Metro,
but we call it the subway.
Well, then, why do they
call it a MetroCard?
We have three dogs at home.
One of them used to be mine,
until I had Mason.
How's she doing?
She's doing okay.
This is confusing for her.
Oh, yeah. I mean.
Um.
She seems happy.
Out-outwardly.
Yeah. Yeah, she is.
She's my baby girl.
Let me get a little bit more.
All right.
Do you smoke a lot of pot,
Robert?
Um, not really.
My... My roommate Lenny does.
Lenny the pothead.
So I have a question for you.
Mm-hmm.
If today was your day off,
then what were you doing
at the school?
I, uh,
I left my wallet there,
so I had to pick it up.
Oh.
Oh. This is gorgeous!
Isn't it?
- It's nice.
- Speaking of that,
why don't you
have your camera on you?
Actually, I haven't been
taking a lot of photos recently.
It's been less and less, anyway.
- Really?
- Yeah.
Everyone's a photographer now
and it takes a really long time
to get good at it
and really know
what you're doing.
It's complicated.
Well, maybe you just need
to rethink your approach,
you know.
For the longest time, I thought
I wanted to be a singer
or a dancer and dress up
and then I realized that
I just like to dress up.
Oh!
Hey, guys! Excuse me.
My friend can get a picture
of all of you guys together.
- Oh.
- He's a very talented
- photographer.
- Sara. Sara, no.
And he would love
to take a photo of you.
- Oh, god.
- Come on.
Thank you.
Works for us.
Mm.
Say, uh, "Diane Arbus."
Diane Arbus.
- There.
- Perfect.
You're welcome.
You're right. He is good.
Oh, good. Take care.
- Enjoy your stay.
- Thank you.
- Now, why was that so hard?
- I don't know.
You did good!
Hey, do you want
to walk me home?
Don't you have to
pick up Mason?
Whoops! Whoa.
Guess I totally forgot. Um.
Kind of new at this whole
single-mom thing.
Uh, listen, listen.
Just because they say
it's ecofriendly
doesn't mean it's ecofriendly.
Do I personally care?
Yes, I care a great deal.
But the information
that they're giving you
is only as reliable as the
person who's giving it to you
and what are you paying me for?
Look, it is
a free-standing structure.
It's not a building.
I can't tell you
how many times...
Hey, Daisy.
Oh, sorry.
You'll say hello one day.
- Robert!
- How you doing? You having fun?
- Yeah.
- You want a snack?
- All right. Let's get a snack.
Wait up, wait up.
You're gonna color
on the table, okay?
- I need help.
- Yeah?
Come over here and then
I'll help you, all right?
Oh, Isabella and Maya,
this is gorgeous.
So, ladies, if you can take it,
we're going to put it over
there, by the easel, okay?
- Okay.
- Hey, Mason.
You have one?
You can use that one, then.
That is a very nice painting.
It's Gram-gram
and Hooty's house.
- I miss Hooty.
- Yeah?
What kinds of things did you
and Hooty used to do together?
All kind of things.
Did Hooty teach you how
to paint like this?
No. Mommy did.
Who's Harry?
Harry is my dad.
And he might be my daddy?
He might be.
You want to see something?
You know how to use this?
No?
Ready?
You want to give it a try?
Put it up to your eye.
There you go.
And you point over at me.
You see this button up top?
Just press it as hard as you can
until you see the thing flash.
Ready?
There you go.
That was perfect.
That was really perfect.
Mommy, Robert said
Harry might be my dad.
I thought Hooty was my daddy.
It's complicated, baby.
Robert could be my daddy.
- He's cool.
- Maybe. We'll find out soon.
Mm-hmm.
I know you said a week,
Dr. Schnieder, but...
Ugh! All right.
Do we have a winner?
- Shouldn't you be at work?
- I'm hungover.
So, I think my dad
stole my moped.
He didn't.
But even if he did,
good riddance.
That thing literally
menstruates.
Hey, hey, hey.
Yeah. What's up?
About that Tosh Wolfe job.
Yeah. It's, um,
it's killing me.
Um, I was gonna ask you:
do you think that you could
pick up Mason after school?
Sure. Yeah. That's great.
Okay. All right.
All right. Bye.
Get dressed.
I'm babysitting.
Really? Yes!
Maybe we can take her
to the airport.
That's a good idea.
Kids like planes.
No. No. Not for the planes,
for the drama.
I mean, the arriving,
the leaving.
People hugging, people crying.
It's a tableau
of human emotion.
I don't think kids
are really into that stuff.
- Sure they are. I was.
- Yeah, like I said,
I don't think kids are
into that kind of stuff.
You're undermining
my uncle confidence, Robert.
- Can we go? Please. Let's go.
- I'm ready to go.
- Okay. Let's get up. Up!
All right.
Let's get some pants on
- and some shoes, all right?
- I have pants on.
- No. No. Like real pants.
- They are real pants.
- What you see is what you get.
- Shoes. All right?
Hey, Joyce.
We're here.
Okay. Okay.
She's gonna bring her out.
I look okay?
Relax. She's 4.
I don't know what that means.
Hey, Mason.
- Hi.
- Hi, Joyce.
I like that shirt, Mason.
Harry took us
to the planetarian.
To the what?
- The planetarian.
- The planetarium.
Oh, cool. Cool beans.
This is Lenny.
- Hi. I'm Mason.
- Hi, Mason.
Do you know Robert
might be my dad?
I did know that.
I was actually
in the adjacent room
when you were being conceived.
Oh, my god!
- Goodbye, Robert.
- Bye, Joyce.
Hey Mason, you have somewhere
safe you can put this?
You have a pocket in here?
Yeah? All right. Okay.
So put it in here
and don't let Joyce
take it from you, okay?
- Okay.
- So you want to go somewhere
way more fun than
that boring old planetarium?
- Yeah!
- How about the airport?
- Lenny.
- What?
All right. Let's go.
Go ahead.
Ah. C'mere.
Oh!
Dude.
Hey, Mason, no matter
what that light says,
don't go until you see
another person go first,
- all right?
- Yeah.
All right.
Let's do it. Let's go.
Uh, take my hand?
Get in there, kiddo.
Oh, good.
You asked out Anna.
What? No.
No, I didn't.
- Who is that? Who are you...?
- That was Brie.
- She heard it from Jack.
- No, I said we'd hang out.
- That's it.
- Stop being defensive.
- How am I being defensive?
- Hi!
Relax! Can't be
so negative around Mason.
- Hey, Sampson.
- So, when are you gonna
- bring back my favorite photo?
- Look, I'm sorry.
Next time, I'll bring it back.
Okay.
I don't like that actresses
can cry on command.
That freaks me out.
- Do you think she can do that?
- Probably.
- Can you find that out for me?
- Yeah.
- Okay.
- Go ahead.
I gotta admit,
she is kind of interesting.
You're our director,
so you get us started.
- Ready?
- Ready.
Ready.
Say "action."
Action!
¶ Ah do-do do-do do-do ¶
Here we are.
Thank you, Diane.
That is your lion friend?
What are you doin' here, Lion?
Is this supposed to be a joke?
No, I thought
it would be nice.
No, I don't think it's nice
that she's spending
this kind of time
in your apartment,
in your crappy neighborhood.
It's not good for her.
Jesus Christ.
Well, at least I know she's
not riding around with you
on that death trap of yours.
So you stole my moped?
- Really?
- Really.
You're potentially
about to be a father.
You're worried
about your little moped?
Hey.
Hey, Robert.
How you doin'?
Good. You busy at work?
Yeah.
I'm actually superbusy.
Would you... would you take
Mason home again for me?
Um, yeah, sure.
No problem.
Okay. Thank you again.
Okay, bye.
Listen,
if you're going to smoke,
can you point it
towards the window?
Just can we be done with this?
Yes. Please.
It's a process, guys.
- Can you relax?
- I remember you.
- Yeah.
- Relax.
- Hey, guys.
- Hey.
- Where's Mason?
- It's okay.
- She's asleep in Robert's room.
- Oh.
You okay?
How was she?
She was great.
We had a really good day.
- We went all around the city.
- No. No. No.
We went to the airport.
Incredible.
She had a great time.
So, by overloading your brain
with erotic material,
you're stripping away
every physical idea
that initially attracts you
to women,
thus creating a true,
meaningful relationship.
Exactly.
Isn't that comforting?
Don't let Mason
get into Tom Petty.
- Okay.
- She'll sell herself short
for like the rest of her life.
- Mommy!
- Ah!
What?
Okay. Okay. All right.
We're fine.
I think she saw my D.
Might be the first D
she's ever seen.
This might mean
something, right?
Yeah.
I'm gonna see you guys later.
Yeah. Take care.
Right?
It's getting late.
I'm gonna put Mason
- to bed here, okay?
- Sorry.
- What are you doing?
- Sleep on the couch.
So, there is exactly one egg
in this apartment.
Who wants it?
- Me!
- You want it? All right.
- I do. I do.
- Oh, what the...?
- There you go.
- There we go.
- How's that look?
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
- Good job.
- So how's your business going?
- Oh, um, it's just starting up.
Harry's sending me to his lawyer
to get incorporated.
Great.
I could help you with that.
Yeah.
Believe it or not, Lenny
probably knows that world
much better than my father,
in terms of legal jargon
and all that.
Really?
Well, that would be
really great, actually,
'cause Harry's already
doing so much.
- How is that?
- So, yeah.
How's Tosh?
Pretty terrible, but, you know.
You gotta work
to get work, right?
You know what I mean?
Are you gonna go get a job?
I think it's time
for you to get a job.
No-o-o.
No-o-o?
Mason, I can put you to work.
You can clean my room.
I'm serious.
You can come over.
It's up to you.
Robert.
- Yeah.
- Hi, Harry.
Hi, honey.
So, Sara-Beth spent the night
at your apartment again
last night?
Yeah, so?
- Did you sleep with her?
- What?
What kind of question is that?
A direct one. Answer it.
No! Of course not!
I helped her out with Mason.
Let me guess:
Mason's exposed
to pot smoking, pornography,
and shitty Chinese food?
Actually, we had
a really great day together.
Did I not ask you to wait
till we get the results?
- I understand.
- Did I ask you?
Really?
You two, just stop it.
Enough!
Hi, Miriam.
Hi, Mom. Ahem.
Welcome home.
Where is she?
Mason?
Right there.
Oh.
She's beautiful.
Hey, Mason.
Come over here.
- This is Miriam. Miriam's my mom.
- Hi.
Hi.
Well, I think I'm gonna be
a grandmother.
- Not necessarily.
- Hi.
Shut up, Harry.
Can I give you a hug?
Big hug?
- All right, um...
- The bickering is getting
very old, Harry.
That's just
the way it is, Miriam.
Maybe we should just not let him
work here anymore, okay?
- Because we're not helping him.
- Now, come on.
Robert might be a father
next week.
Yeah.
I think I'm depressed.
You're not depressed, Harry.
You're alone.
There's a difference.
Yeah. Okay.
Look, I know
I brought this on myself,
- but it is nothing to it that...
- Not my problem anymore, Harry.
Harry, Ms. Walsh
is here to see you.
Is that...?
Yeah, maybe we should
do this another time.
Just send her in, please.
You got it.
Oh, my god.
You motherfucker.
Hey, let's not have
name-calling.
- Oh, just blow it out your ass.
- Okay.
Hi. I'm Miriam.
- Harry's wife.
- Hi.
Sara-Beth.
Nice to meet you.
- I am very sorry. I...
- No. No. No. Nope. Nope.
Men are dogs. I did not
come here for an apology.
I came here to meet you
and your wonderful daughter.
I just wanted to say...
Thank you.
By the way, that one's
pretty wonderful, too.
Would you like
to get some dinner?
- I would love that.
- Sounds great. Let's go.
No, you're not invited, Harry.
- Really?
- Mm-hmm.
- Girls' night?
- Just like that?
- Yes.
Okay.
Robert, Mason, and I will
- do stuff that's fun.
- Good.
Is this man party
To this evil plot, Chipmunk?
Why are you not watching
the movie?
I have it on tape, so.
Aw, poor chipmunk.
Speechless in my presence.
What say you, sir?
Don't try my patience.
I... I don't know
what you're talking.
I seek a beautiful girl,
my other half, my one...
This is my kind of night:
beer and Chinese food.
Mm-hmm.
You like it?
I love it.
It's excellent.
We're longtime customers there.
Harry took me there
on our first date.
Me, too!
Okay! Got me.
It's been a while since I sat
through one of those.
There you go.
Under the covers.
Okay?
How about if I read you a book?
Here we go.
"Come see the amazing
diving horse."
No. I want both of you.
All right.
Okay.
"A long, long time ago,
in a city quite close,
the brave young horse
with a long brown nose.
His name was
Dale the Diving Horse
and he was quite famous,
of course.
So what if they took
your photos down?
Two weeks in a serious gallery.
Yeah, 3 years ago.
How are things with Sara-Beth?
It's okay to be worried.
I don't even...
I don't even know yet.
Oh.
- What?
- This is your new work?
Oh, you jerk. No.
No, those are Mason's.
Oh.
Sweet. I was wondering.
I was thinking
of teaching the kids
a class on photography.
That's a good idea.
- Really?
- Mm-hmm.
You're not just saying that?
You're sure?
No. I wouldn't just say that.
- All right.
- I mean it.
- I do.
- Let's go.
Let's get outta here.
I've seen enough.
- Where are we eatin'?
- I don't know.
You know the neighborhood,
right?
Okay, so this is your LLC,
okay? It allows for
pass-through taxation,
which is great,
'cause it's an easy thing.
- Okay.
- It protects you and Harry
from being personally liable,
you know,
- should the worst thing happen.
- Right.
This is your number
and that is his number.
- So we're separate?
- Yeah, totally.
- Okay.
- It's really just pretty basic.
Yeah, it's scaring me
'cause I actually think
- I understand it.
- Yeah, of course.
So maybe I don't,
entirely, but.
No, no, no.
I think you got it.
Okay. What do you do?
You're not an accountant.
Um, I raise capital to purchase
intellectual properties.
- Very fancy.
- Yeah, no no no,
it's very fancy.
Well, you will get
a free pair of cowboy boots
When it's all said and done.
- Right.
- Hey!
- Hey.
What's goin' on?
Oh, I was just talking with
Lenny about my new business.
Yeah.
Where's Mason?
Um, she stayed late at school
and then Harry took her.
Just hangin' out.
- Excuse me.
- Yeah, sure.
Hi.
Hey.
Are you mad at me?
No, you're working
all the angles, right?
Robert.
You know,
you get me to babysit,
have my dad give you money
and pay your rent.
You're gonna fuck one
of my friends.
Robert.
Come on, I was calling him
because I wanted
to ask him advice
on setting up my business.
I don't want to do everything
with your father.
Right, 'cause Lenny's
brilliant sexual theory
has nothing to do with this.
Are you serious?
Look...
I... I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. It's just there's
a lot going on at once.
I'm sorry.
Do you want to help me
tomorrow with Tosh?
Sure.
You can bring stuff over
to the shoot tomorrow
and I can introduce you to him.
I'm more interested
in just helping you.
Hey.
About last night.
What?
Fine.
Don't worry about it.
Okay. Good.
Just 'cause I feel like we,
you know,
have a real connection.
Furthermore, I think
she might be feeling smothered
- by you and Harry.
- Will you stop talking, Lenny?
What? I'm just saying
that there could be
some objectification at play,
some sort of nascent...
Robert.
Great.
Come down.
Stylist!
What is this, exactly?
Hey. You all right?
Hey. Yeah,
I cannot keep up with this.
Thank you so much
for bringing this.
Oh, shit! Oh, god.
These are all the wrong size.
They got me the wrong size.
- Oh, god.
- Stylist.
- Yes.
- Do you want me to...?
- I can take them 'em back.
- No, no, no. It's fine.
- It's fine.
- No, it's fine. I can just
- It's not a problem.
- Clamp it in the back
- or something.
- Hey, what's the holdup?
Oh, yes, I just
have to pin the underwear.
Mr. Wolfe, I just want to say
I really admire your work.
Let's go.
He's actually a really
talented photographer.
I only have it for 30 minutes.
Let's go.
- Now, now.
- Okay, that's my cue. Bye.
Talk to you later.
Okay, hurry.
- And you didn't tell me.
- Hmm?
- Dinner.
- Yes.
Sara. Did it
freak her out or...?
- Did...?
- What'd you do to her?
I didn't...
Did I freak her out?
- Yeah.
- No, she's in her 20s.
She's appropriately
freaked out, Harry.
Yeah. Yeah, well.
- Say, "cheese."
- Ohhh.
Cheese.
- And cereal is milk, right?
- Yeah.
Yes!
How many of you love milk?
- Oh, I'm so glad.
- Dr. Schnieder, please.
- Yes. Yes, yes.
- It's Robert.
So, give away these bowls,
first, and then...
Okay, okay.
So, so nothing. Yes.
- Thanks.
- Right?
Because too much milk,
what happens?
- Soggy.
- Yes!
And then, too little milk,
what happens?
- Dry.
- There you go.
Just enough cereal.
Very good.
You got a bowl?
Did you get cereal?
Hey.
Fancy a drink?
Sure.
You're not my boss.
- Um...
- My boss fired me today.
- Oh.
- So, that's what happened there.
It was a rough day?
Yeah, man. Tosh is...
I don't think I've met
a bigger jerk than that guy.
He's an idiot.
You haven't.
Unfortunately, that's
how it goes in my industry.
What better reason
to start your own line?
Yeah.
That is exactly
what your dad said.
Can we please not talk
about him today?
Robert. Be nice.
He's savin' my ass.
That's good.
My parents are really upset
that Mason and I left.
- They invested a lot in her.
- Uh-huh.
- And they helped me raise her.
- Yeah.
They really don't want either
of us to live in New York.
You... You're... you're an adult.
They can't...
Do they know
about Harry and me?
Um, no.
I mean,
- I just told them Harry Lang.
- Mm-hmm.
To parents.
I have a weird question
for you.
What?
Would you say that you
like my hair better now?
I don't. I...
Or did you like it
better before?
I don't know. I like it.
I liked it both ways.
It's nice. You know?
- No. No, no, no, no. No.
- Huh?
No.
Sara?
Sara!
No.
- What?
- Did we...?
No, no!
Well, I mean,
there was the cab, but.
- No memory.
- No.
Where's Mason?
Uhhh, at Harry's.
Relax!
Shit!
Nothing happened, okay?
- Hey. Hey, Miriam.
- Hi.
- Where's Mason?
- Joyce picked her up
and brought her to school.
Where have you two been?
Did you two
spend the night together?
Yeah. We...
Wow.
You know, every time I put
a little faith in you, Robert,
you do something
that makes me lose it.
All right, you know
what'd be good?
A life for Mason
without you in it.
Okay, that...
Just stop it, all right?
You know what? I have to...
I have to lie down.
I just can't.
Yeah, well,
the doctor appointment
is at 12:00 noon,
if anyone's interested.
Unbelievable.
Dad.
What? He's not here.
Oh, looks like a full house.
Oh, how was the, uh,
vacation, Miriam?
Fine.
- Good week, Robert?
- No.
Okay, so, we can get on
with this, right? Yeah.
Ahem!
So,
Mason's father is
Harry Lang.
Hey, listen.
I need to take a walk, so,
I will pick up dinner.
I will see you guys back
at the apartment.
What about Mason?
Well, Joyce is gonna
pick her up. It's covered.
Are you hungry?
We're starving.
Um, no.
You have to go,
talk to her, now.
Okay.
Hey, Mason.
Uh, Aunt Miriam's gonna look
after you for a second, okay?
- Aunt?
- You got something better?
You got something
better than aunt?
- Hey.
- Where you goin'?
- I'm goin' home to Tennessee.
I... I can't do this, okay?
This isn't gonna work out.
Can't do this.
You could just tell Mason
that we're all family.
But Harry doesn't even
wanna do this,
I can't keep letting Mason down,
I can't keep running away
from my parents,
and I don't belong here.
All right. I get it.
But you're wrong about Harry.
He's just scared.
I can talk to him.
We'll figure this out, okay?
Don't go anywhere yet.
All right?
Hey, Dad. Um,
hope you're all right.
So, Sara-Beth was saying
that she might be
heading back to Tennessee.
So, you know,
it might be a good time
to give her a call,
stop by the house, whatever.
Look, I'm sorry about Sara.
It's just we get along.
- She understands the process.
- It's okay.
Do you wanna get a coffee
and talk about it, or...?
Later, man.
I gotta talk to my dad.
I just feel like we have
something worth exploring.
- Dude.
- It's fine, Lenny.
We'll talk later.
There he is.
- Busted!
- A little bit.
Wow.
So, I guess the word is
I'm a big coward now, huh?
Never said that.
Robert, I judge people.
I judged you.
I still judge you and I don't
wanna do that to Mason.
Then don't. Don't.
Yeah, that's easy
for you to say.
Truth is, you would be
a better father to her.
- No, you don't know that.
- Sure I do.
- You don't.
- Yeah, I do.
I mean, you're a natural
with kids.
I grew up in a preschool.
- That's true.
- Yeah.
Dad, Dad, you're all right.
As a father, you are.
And all right's pretty good.
Just help me out
with this fathering thing.
- You got it.
- Sorry, we're closed.
- No, but thank you.
- Oh, no, no, no.
- Yes.
Lenny.
- Yes! Yes.
- What?
We need a bigger table.
- Why?
- Miriam!
- How are you?
- Good.
- Hi.
- Hello.
Sara-Beth.
Mason, throw some of those
noodles on top of there.
That is disgusting.
You're gonna start sweating and
the whole place is gonna stink.
- Are you done?
- I got a spicy thing before.
- Yeah, what was that?
- Yeah, what was that like?
- What?!
- Come on.
Hey, Robert.
- Did you show your dad?
- The, uh, the pictures?
- Yeah.
- Oh, no. Um.
I was telling Mom.
Look at these.
I was hoping to maybe
start a photography class
for the kids.
Wow, yeah.
It's, um, it's avant-garde.
- Yep.
- That's right.
They're Mason's,
you realize, right?
Yeah. It's not a bad idea,
actually. This is good work.
Good idea. I've never had
a bad idea, right?
Lenny.
Are... are you guys serious?
I don't mind. It's just
I... I don't see it.
- Harry, let it go.
- We're grownups.
Listen, I have to say
something. Uh...
You should make
an announcement, Harry.
This time around,
I'm going to be...
I'm going to be there.
I'm going to be present
for everyone in this family.
Mason and everybody.
All right,
take a step back, okay?
Don't cover the flash.
I'm not gonna cover the fl...
cover the flash.
All right, everybody,
get together.
- You ready?
- Okay, crew, smile.
C'mon, everybody. Ready.
- Is that a smile, Harry?
- Yeah.
All right. 1, 2, 3.
Got it.
- So I gotta go.
- Where you going?
I got things to do.
Why don't you
come back with us?
Nah, no.
Um, hey, Mason,
you gonna go home
with your old man?
- But I want you to be my dad.
- You've got a dad.
He's your dad.
- How about a brother?
- Yeah.
You want a brother?
Okay, deal.
¶ I traveled the world ¶
- See ya.
We have matching pants.
We have matching shirts.
¶ To get my ¶
- Yeah, I know.
That was funny.
Look at that.
¶ I guess it's the price
you have to pay ¶
¶ to collect what you're owed ¶
¶ I stare and think
as lovers pass ¶
Who's that?
Is it someone for you?
Harry Lang?
Who wants to know?
Hooty-y-y-y-y-y-y-y!
¶ To give part of my life
to you ¶
Hi, Mama.
¶ I am swimming ¶
¶ in the water ¶
¶ I am drinking ¶
¶ all the wine ¶
¶ I am moving ¶
¶ out of body ¶
¶ I am going ¶
¶ out of mind ¶
¶ When the crowds disappear ¶
¶ all the silence is left here ¶
¶ I am swimming ¶
¶ in the water ¶
¶ I am drinking ¶
¶ all the wine ¶
¶ I am moving ¶
¶ out of body ¶
¶ I am going ¶
¶ out of mind ¶
Subrip by DanDee