Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org
Coming! I'll get my bag.
It's that one.
Thanks.
Don't Worry, I'm Fine
Hi, my love.
Not too long?
And how. Almost 11 hours.
My parents... Léa.
Paris, August 25th
Thomas... Lili.
Her parents.
- Phone you tomorrow.
- Yes. And stop by!
Bye.
We're this way.
- I love that girl.
- She seems nice, yes.
I love that girl.
- She's older than you, no?
- She's 25.
Seen how cute she is?
She's in grad school. Doing her PhD.
- What's that?
- Comes after your Masters.
Beats my dumb diploma.
Your brother left.
- He came home? He enjoy his vac?
- I don't know.
Where did he go?
We don't know. It's been 5 days.
What happened?
We had a row.
He's mad at me.
Didn't he call you?
No. Yes, 2 weeks ago.
Why did you fight?
Over nothing.
Tell me!
Over nothing. Over his room.
- You don't know where he is?
- No.
Loïc, it's me.
I'm back.
Call me. Big hug.
What's that guy up to?
Traffic's backed up
all around Paris...
For 20 miles on the A6 freeway...
Things are also crawling on the A10,
all the way to the beltway...
Not having a shower?
He didn't leave me a note.
He just took off.
What's all the fuss
about his room? It's tidy.
I tidied it.
Stop it, Mom.
You know how Loïc is.
He's impulsive,
but it doesn't last.
Yeah.
- Dinner's ready.
- Coming.
Hi, it's Loïc. Leave a message.
It's me. Why haven't you called?
Dunno what happened,
but they're upset.
Call me. Big hug.
You spoke Spanish
with your girlfriend?
Sure I did. A month in Spain,
you speak Spanish.
Many French kids?
Lots. 2 Lyon girls,
a great guy from Brittany.
So you learned Breton!
You stayed in Barcelona?
No side trips?
To the coast, once.
But Barcelona's too much!
In Franco's day it was cop city.
Wasn't "too much" for us, huh?
Yes.
- Here.
- Thanks.
You didn't eat?
He took his guitar...
His accoustic.
Yes.
What really happened?
Can't be about his room,
it's been a mess for years.
It was...
Got ugly, I expected a fist-fight.
You know them. Want some tea?
Coming?
I'm going for a walk!
At this hour?
...Clouds over the English Channel,
and storms moving toward Italy.
- Was it nice?
- Fabulous!
I want to go right back.
- Seen Loïc?
- Is he back?
Yes, but he stormed back out.
Didn't he call you?
No.
He doesn't call every day.
So you didn't go with him?
No, Camille made me go hiking.
Wish I'd gone climbing with him.
Wanna hear what we did?
I mean, what he did.
No idea where he is?
He must've found a chick...
He wrote this one for you.
It's called "Lili".
Hi, girl!
- Things OK?
- And you?
Weird being here, huh?
What is it?
Boring stuff.
"Power politics in Mozambique".
Guess I like boring stuff.
- Miss?
- Same for me.
I just found a part-time job.
What is it?
Cashier in the local supermarket.
That's OK.
You here, Froggie?
Skies are blue, we can take it easy.
- "Froggie" means I'm a weatherman.
- I know.
Right.
After a month with her,
you know everything.
Nonsense.
I hate knowing the weather.
Me, too.
The fun is seeing it all
from up high:
Patagonia, Vladivostok.
But he just does local weather.
With satellites,
you can see the world.
The other day, we spent 2 hours
over the Azores watching whales.
I love whales!
What is it?
What's wrong, Lili?
Nothing.
It's just...
My brother split.
Your twin?
He'll be back,
but he hasn't called me,
and I don't know why.
Split, how?
He had a row with my dad.
When I got back,
he was gone.
Has he walked out before?
No, but they fight all time.
He can't stand all this...
This burb, Vigneux, our parents.
He's been gone 6 days.
He'll come back, don't worry.
You from Vigneux?
I'm from nearby, Draveil.
You went to Montgeron high school?
My brother, too.
I went there too,
up to my senior year.
Funny, huh?
Anyway...
Sorry.
He'll call you, don't worry.
Hi.
Commuter train was stifling.
You OK?
What did you do today?
What happened, Dad?
What do you mean?
You must know!
He didn't leave over his room!
What happened?
- Tell me, I want to know!
- Nothing happened.
Just what you were told.
I don't believe you, tell me!
I told you, Elise.
- I don't believe you!
- Stop it, Lili.
Loïc has vanished.
He may be in trouble!
You do nothing:
go to work, read your mail!
He left because of you!
What can I do, kid?
Go to the police! Isn't it time?
I already went.
- When?
- I forget, a week ago.
And?
Nothing. I said he'd left.
What did they say?
Answer, dammit!
Cool it! That an adult
does what he wants.
Will they look for him?
I left my number.
They'll call if need be.
Great!
Stop worrying. It's no use.
No use!
You're all a pain!
Coming to dinner?
No.
What are you doing?
Nothing.
You won't have a bite?
I'm not hungry.
You ate nothing last night.
Mom, leave me alone.
September 2nd
2 days ago, I was in Tunisia.
- Fun?
- Fabulous.
Greg, you seen Leo?
He's changed schools.
Why? You care?
Coming in?
Wrong room.
- Which one do you need?
- Room 17.
It's in F building.
Thanks.
So, on your schedules,
in addition to the classes,
you need two internships in a firm.
Start canvassing firms now.
That search
is part of your training.
Subway stalled for 15 minutes.
Who knows why!
So, how was your first day?
He wasn't there.
Want some?
Maybe he's dead.
Don't talk nonsense.
Or he'd have called.
If he's had a problem, we'd know.
If he was alive, he'd call me.
He'd call me!
I didn't fight with him!
He hasn't answered
any of my messages!
Now his voicemail's full!
We can't just do nothing.
It's not possible! I can't take it!
Get it?
I can't!
Why are you staring at me?
Shit!
Here we're dealing with damages...
and if a mistake was committed,
or if there's a causal link
between the mistake
and the damages.
If both conditions are present,
civil liability
means the wrongdoer
has an obligation.
Miss Tellier!
Tell us about the 3 conditions
for civil liability?
Or what this class is about?
About civil liability.
Sorry?
Stand up, please.
Speak loud and clear.
We all want to hear your answer.
Move aside!
Miss!
Can you hear me?
Anyone got some sugar?
Get a glass of water!
Miss... wake up!
Miss!
- How long haven't you eaten?
- 8 or 9 days.
I asked her, Madame.
I don't know.
Your blood pressure's way too low.
If you don't eat,
you'll soon get sick.
You must eat,
not much but regularly.
Don't let your stomach grow idle.
- Understand?
- Yes.
Meanwhile, stay in bed.
Know what it's about?
About her brother.
He left home, hasn't called.
I'll prescribe her
a mild tranquilizer.
For you too, if you want.
Thanks, no.
- And you, Madame?
- I'm already on one.
Her first name's Elise, right?
If she won't eat,
I'll put her in hospital.
We can't take any risks.
- Are you OK, love?
- Are you hurt?
Slowly... careful.
Gently.
- Can you move?
- Yes.
Settle down and get undressed.
Need any help?
No, thanks.
What are you doing?
Answer, what are you doing?
Forget this. Until you eat,
you keep nothing, it's the rule.
No phone. Give it to me.
Give it to me! I expect a call!
No calls. First eat, then we'll see.
Move aside.
Move, or I'll get someone.
Get in pajamas, I'll be back.
Often the causes
aren't what we think.
But here we're sure.
He's her twin. They're very close.
We're only sure
she's deeply depressed.
We must find out why.
You said her brother.
He may have set it off,
but there must be a deeper reason.
We'll look for it.
And we'll find it.
You must know
that visits are forbidden.
Even for you.
What do you mean?
It's rough, but that's
part of the treatment.
Once she's eating
and gaining weight, you can see her.
Evening, girls.
Let's try and eat a little...
Chew well.
You OK?
Tomorrow we'll weigh you.
Come on, give it a try.
Please, can't I have my phone?
First you have to eat.
Please, just the phone.
No, you must eat.
Go on, I'm waiting.
There you go.
Keep at it.
Can I have it?
I can't, I told you.
Eat! I'll be back in 10 minutes.
Unless you eat,
your stomach will shrink.
You'll grow even thinner,
develop disorders, miss your period,
lose your memory,
your hair and teeth,
get irreversible cardiac disorders.
The heart's a muscle:
your muscles are melting.
You don't want to die?
Françoise!
Now what is it?
Can't we spend one night in peace?
Françoise!
Léa, it's Lili.
I'm locked up in Evry hospital.
Who is it?
What?
- Where?
- Evry hospital...
Lili?
What's going on?
What's wrong with her?
September 15
Hello, doctor.
Mr and Mrs Tellier,
you shouldn't come.
I said, you can't see her.
Just call.
We've called for 3 days,
and get no news!
Then there are none. You must wait.
We've isolated her
for her own good.
That won't help!
Sir, don't question
50 years of psychiatry.
We know what we're doing.
She's still fighting us,
but we'll work it out, trust us.
- She's fighting you?
- A bit. It'll be fine.
So she heals fast,
abide by the rules.
It's the only way.
Don't worry. OK?
I'll keep you posted.
Keep us posted, you bet!
Hi.
Right, hi.
We didn't know she was here.
- Well?
- No visits.
Why?
Now, to cure people,
they stick 'em in the hole!
- Stop it!
- Why? To hear that idiot
say he's locked her up
because he knows?
Screw his 50 years of psychiatry!
What does he know? Shit!
Excuse me.
It's 411.
Don't!
Who is it?
Us.
Thanks for coming.
If they catch you...
You OK?
And you?
Is your job nice?
My job? At the mart?
Yes... sure.
We woke you up. Sorry.
We won't stay long.
What can we do, Lili?
Dunno.
I brought you this.
It's called: "Off To See The Sea".
Nice idea, right?
Can't you get me out?
I'll die here.
You OK?
I must get my phone back.
From where?
The room by the nurses' room.
In case Loïc calls me... Please.
It's locked up. Look for the key.
Please.
What are you doing here?
Who are you?
Jean!
What is it?
Over there.
Hurry!
Here, hold this.
Don't move!
I said, don't move!
What's all this? Who are you?
I want to leave.
Leave her alone! Look at her!
Give me that!
You won't get away with this!
Miss, go to your room!
Jean, take her back up!
- Don't you touch her!
- It's all over.
Let go of her.
Tolerating that soon leads to chaos.
It's a psychiatric ward,
with serious cases.
I'm sorry.
Sit down.
I'll be frank:
your daughter's health worries me.
She's in a precarious spiral.
She refuses to eat,
and to be drip fed.
She rips it off each time.
She says her brother has died,
and she wants to die, too.
I'm sorry to tell you this,
but it's a fact.
We had to strap her down.
What?
To keep the drip on.
Without glucose, she'll die.
We're going to force-feed her.
You're savages! That's torture!
- Paul!
- What, Paul?
Mr Tellier, your anger is justified.
That'll do, let us see her!
I can't.
It'll only drive her deeper
into her neurosis.
It could be fatal.
Stag-hunting to hounds is a rite.
Its call is "Tally Ho!"
Those words sum up
the pageant of the Hunt.
You're on horseback,
chasing your prey,
but the words "Tally Ho!"
summon the call
of the hunting horn...
You have an appointment?
No, but it's vital
to my daughter, Elise Tellier.
That's not possible.
- I want to see him now!
- You need an appointment.
She got a letter from her brother.
He wrote her.
Come in.
She must read it.
Come in, sit down.
We must snap her out of it.
That's impossible, you know that.
But it's from her brother!
After this, she'll eat again!
Things aren't that simple. Sit down.
Don't treat me like a moron!
I know what my daughter needs!
What does this letter say?
I didn't open it.
He wrote to her, not me!
If you won't give it to her, I will.
September 28th
Hi, darling.
You OK?
Don't you have TV?
No.
Here. Seems it's very good.
Thanks.
Where's your Diskman?
They still have it.
I'm only allowed books.
Then...
I'll bring you a book.
So you're eating now?
Yes.
Well?
He's in Rouen.
- I saw that.
- You saw it?
The postmark, on the envelope.
What does he say?
That he's fine.
That he flipped, lost his bearings,
had to clear out his head.
He's sorry he didn't contact me.
Is that all?
He gives you a big hug.
Lunch!
Sorry.
October 2nd
Leave it.
It's for you again.
Want some tea?
Yes, thanks.
Well?
"Lili, I just got to Rennes.
Nice town,
"think I'll stay here a bit,
"look for odd jobs, maybe
play guitar in a bar, who knows.
"It feels so good
"not seeing that creep,
"his wretched life and long face.
"Don't worry, I'm fine. Love you.
"Big hug, for Mom too. Loïc."
Milk or lemon?
Milk.
Mom, what happened between them?
Mom?
Just what he told you.
I don't get it either.
Shit!
Your mom
caught her foot in the wire.
She breaks everything now.
You go back to school Monday?
Dunno.
October 15th
Léa's not here.
I know, I need something.
That's not mine.
Sorry... I'm new here.
Mr Reynaud is wanted at checkout 3.
I need the key to cancel it.
I rang up an extra item.
Don't daydream!
This way, folks.
Concentrate, kid!
It's the rush hour.
27,50 please.
Thanks.
- Thanks.
- Sorry.
That all? You're a lousy customer.
Why? You get a cut?
Shall I buy more?
No need.
You're through at 7PM?
Yeah, when we've swept up.
A Perrier, please!
Léa's seeing her teacher tonight?
Yes.
Any news from your brother?
I got a card yesterday.
From Le Mans.
He moves around.
Yeah. Dunno what he's doing.
Doesn't he say?
Says he gets odd jobs,
sometimes he plays in bars.
He plays guitar
and sings really well.
He stays a few days,
sometimes a week.
From Rennes, he wrote me twice.
Then he's up and gone.
He doesn't want to see me.
Near my grandparents' home,
a young guy just split one day,
no one ever knew why.
Gave no news for years.
Not a letter.
Then one day, his parents
were 200 miles from home,
and saw him, lying on the sidewalk,
begging with a dog.
Why tell me that?
Dunno.
To show one can't
get inside people's heads.
Maybe he met someone and...
You should put an ad in the paper.
Ask for his phone number or address.
He doesn't want to see me.
I wanted to say...
When you came to the hospital...
That was great.
So was the book.
It's good, huh?
Ends badly, but it was good.
Ends well in a way,
badly in another, that's life.
It's that one.
With the blue door?
It's the Truman Show here.
Loïc says
it's like an Indian reservation.
And it's miles from anywhere.
You can't slog this every day.
Found a rental?
No. They're too pricey,
or already taken.
Our janitor's moving out soon.
Shall I ask?
Depends on the price.
It's the size of this car,
can't cost much.
Sure, yes.
Well... See you soon.
Can you find your way back?
Sure. Or I'll ask an Indian.
You OK?
Why did you come?
To say hi.
I'm going out.
They here?
Where else would they be?
I gotta go, I'm late.
Bye.
In the market,
I saw your old English teacher.
She said don't quit school,
go back next year.
I won't, I told you.
Be a cashier for life?
I'll find something.
With a high school diploma?
You had even less.
I had no choice.
And I went to night school.
Wish I could've gone to college!
Kids without a degree
aren't hired as filing clerks.
They'll be bums, pushers or whores.
So I'll end up a whore.
Well, what does Loïc say?
He's fine, in Angers.
It's not great, so he'll move on.
"But I'm free of that creep
"who says "Shush"
or "Tidy your room"!
"Now I'm rid of him, I feel alive.
"Hope you're well, kiss Mom.
"I love you. Big hug, Loïc."
I may have found a pad.
I'm splitting, too.
December 31
You look lost. Don't know anyone?
I'm with Léa and Thomas...
Léa, that black girl.
Lucille's friend. She's nice.
- Where did you meet her?
- We work together.
You in grad school?
No, in the local supermarket.
What else do you do?
Nothing. I'm a cashier.
What else?
I'm just a cashier.
Really?
Yes, really.
I'll grab a drink. Want one?
No, thanks.
Hi, what'll it be?
Some of that.
Thanks.
Not too bored?
I'm fine. I drink to forget.
You must eat, too.
There's fabulous salmon.
Don't stuff me like a Jewish mom!
Lili!
- Come meet someone.
- No, I'm fine.
Thomas!
Come over here.
You go. I'll have a smoke.
You came with Léa, right?
I tried out
for grad school with her.
But I didn't get in.
What do you do?
Senior in Business School.
And you?
Junior supermarket cashier.
What's that?
You memorize bar codes,
then they test you on prices.
That's for theory.
The practical test is
ringing up scads of items
in under 3 minutes,
and making change fast.
Sounds tough!
5... 4...
3...
2... 1...
Happy New Year!
Mind if I go home?
You sure?
You're right.
He's a bum now, ashamed to see me.
Love, health and money!
Chateau Beychevelle 1995.
Holy dust!
You should've let it breathe.
I forgot.
Well?
Yes, it's fine.
For a while it was a weird color.
Needs salt.
- Wait, I'll get it!
- No, eat!
On New Year's Day she tries
exotic menus. Foul, isn't it?
Not great.
She's made tons,
I'll eat it all week.
It's a new Alsatian recipe.
- Not having any?
- Sure.
How was the party last night?
- Fine. What did you do?
- Nothing.
You didn't see the Leducs?
Not this year.
He mailed it 2 days ago.
Says he just got there.
He must still be there.
I'll head there.
Reims is a city.
You won't find him.
Tomorrow's Sunday. It'll be dead.
I'll check out the hotels.
Downtown
there's 4 in his price range.
Really? What's his price range?
Got a better idea?
Beats sitting around on your ass.
Come with me?
Two of us will do better.
He trashes me,
he won't want to see me.
What does he say in that one?
Tell me.
- Stop it, Dad.
- Paul!
If it's about me, I can read it.
"Lili, I'm in Reims. It's a dump.
"Glad I got my guitar. My dumb dad
never listened to me sing!
"Feels good to be rid of his face
"and his wretched life.
"Happy New Year, Sis.
I think of you.
"Kiss Mom. Loïc."
He doesn't mean that...
Stop, Mom.
His wretched life. Wretched, how?
I enjoyed breaking
my butt for 25 years?
Who paid for this place,
his moped, guitar lessons,
rock-climbing course?
Stop it, Paul!
I know all that, Dad.
Bye.
True, I didn't relate to him. Right?
Dunno.
I do.
And I never listened to his songs.
I did nothing with him. Nothing.
Never kicked a soccer ball.
I've got a CD he made.
I can leave it for you.
I'd like that.
You'll see, it's great.
If I see him,
I'll say you listened to it.
He'll like that.
Hi.
I'm looking for someone.
Around 20. His name's Loïc.
Loïc Tellier. He too plays guitar.
Is he homeless?
I don't know.
What was that dude's name?
Wasn't Loïc, I reckon...
Forget it. Sorry. Thanks.
Where's the downtown area?
This is it.
Thanks.
Downtown! She's nuts!
No one by that name...
Try the St. André, on the right.
Thanks.
Hi.
I'm looking for someone.
The Hotel Monopole said...
What's the name?
Loïc Tellier.
Yes, Tellier slept here.
Is he here?
No, he paid and left.
When?
Last night and he left.
I got here at 8AM...
Say, 8.45AM.
That all?
Yes...
No. Sorry.
Did he look OK?
Were his clothes clean?
Seemed OK.
I don't sniff the customers.
He had his guitar?
In a blue canvas case?
Yes, a blue canvas case.
That it?
Thanks. Bye.
It's over.
What?
Thomas and me.
I'm leaving him.
I don't like
what's happening to us.
If we keep it up,
it'll end badly.
We never got beyond
what we always were.
2 shacked-up friends.
You won't meet?
Sure, as friends.
Hi, girls.
I'm renting a place with my sister.
Don't look so glum,
it's no big deal.
I hope so.
So!
A small birthday gift.
From me.
That's from me, from us.
That's for you.
It's not my birthday!
Don't fight it.
By the author of
"Off To See The Sea".
It's great. And this one ends well.
Don't tell her the ending.
I ran out of gift paper.
You're crazy!
It's fabulous,
but they cost a fortune!
We bought it together.
Thanks.
How can I thank you!
Happy Birthday!
What's this?
You swipe mine
so I figured you'd need one.
- Can I still?
- You bet!
I got this, too.
It's lovely.
From Loïc. His gift.
Sent to my parents' place.
Look, it's him.
You're so alike.
Aren't they?
Shall we eat?
First, we drink.
To you!
To your birthday. You're 20!
To you two.
To you.
To all three of us.
To him, too.
To Loïc.
...and her girlfriend says:
"They're not mouses, they're mice."
And the blonde says:
"They look so alike!"
At the office,
we get that crap all day.
I bet you do.
My dad taught me that.
At first, it's surprising.
Bye, hon.
Where you going?
To my sister's.
I got an 8AM class.
Bye, handsome.
Well, well!
That's how she is.
Makes up her mind fast.
Wasn't it a bit sudden?
Your split up.
Things had been tough for a while.
I didn't know.
It was my fault, not hers.
A fixation I couldn't get rid of.
Thanks, I'm not thirsty.
I know...
I need sleep.
Storm clouds are brewing.
Depression's in the air.
The atmospheric kind!
Good night.
July 10th
There...
Léa's leaving us, and in the fall
she's going to...
- Where?
- Mozambique.
I didn't know it existed!
To her! To you, kiddo!
To Mozambique! And to vacations!
Right to vacations!
The vac is being rid of him!
What'll you do there?
Finish my thesis.
How'll you survive?
Work and my scholarship.
You're paid to go there?
They'd have to pay me, too!
Where are you vacationing?
In the Creuse.
It's more exotic among the Zulus,
but count me out.
When are you leaving?
Saturday. You said
I couldn't leave tonight!
True, I'd only have
2 cashiers for 4 days.
Where in the Creuse?
I'm from there.
- Where's that again?
- Crozant.
Yes, Crozant's nice.
I'm joining her
in a house by a river.
I'll be going
with my new boyfriend!
Couldn't you fit me in?
Not a chance.
Why?
I'll be with my Zulu pals.
And we eat fat whiteys!
I'm not the janitor!
It's me!
Come in!
Not working?
I took 2 hours off.
- Packed your bag?
- Yes.
I rented a car,
and got the same one as you!
Going to the Creuse in a Smart?
It was the cheapest.
You won't come to Brittany with me?
No. Tonight, I'll sleep at my folks.
Tomorrow I go to Crozant,
to join Léa.
I'll quit thinking.
Just swim, sleep and eat.
Not thinking. That's your vac?
Yes.
You won't try something else?
Thomas, I adore you.
And I mean that.
But I want no part of all that.
I'll sleep for 2 weeks,
which suits me fine.
That's crap, Lili.
He won't come back, you know that.
No, I don't! Shut up!
He's moved on. It's been a year!
And would he like
what you've become?
How can you live this way?
The austere Queen of the Mart,
who never goes out?
What do you want?
Want us to make love, that it?
OK, go ahead.
Now. Let's get it over with.
Stop it!
I can't give you anything more.
Truly.
You'd have enjoyed seeing the sea.
- Hi, Mom.
- Hi, darling.
So you're on vacation?
I made lamb kebab.
We're coming. Come look...
Don't read it in front of him,
it upsets him.
You know, St. Aubin-On-Sea?
- In Normandy?
- Yeah.
What does he say?
He's on vacation, swimming.
He kisses us both.
And about your dad?
Same things.
Go on, read it.
Come and get it!
Main course coming up!
Almost done.
Smells good.
Caraway seed! With a good sauce,
you're a broiler champ.
Help yourself.
The lamb must stay pink.
Overcooked, it's wrecked.
Where you going in the Creuse?
Crozant.
Driving in that buggy?
It's a lovely spot.
No noisy neighbors.
Even in August, it's dead.
My office pals
are headed to Brittany.
It's the in-place now.
Nice spot, huh?
Alain and Myriam
bought a house in St. Malo.
Remember,
the little igloo tent we bought?
Know where it is?
In the garage.
You're not in a house?
There's a gang of us.
Might be too few beds.
You said overcooking wrecks it?
It's OK!
They're a bit charred, but OK!
About St. Malo...
that place gets to me!
I love it. I could end up there.
Guess they're charred.
We agreed to stay put, this year.
Not for a vacation.
To live there.
In St. Malo?
Now the kids are gone.
You could come visit us.
It's only 3 hours by train,
there's the sea...
What'd we do? And your job?
We'd open a pancake joint.
All St. Malo needs
is another pancake joint!
Something else, a steak house...
You want to leave your job,
Paris, the house?
We'll sell it.
But it has to suit you.
On the Net, I saw a lovely house,
big garden, flowers,
by the sea...
Ground floor's a pancake joint,
but we can change that.
Chef, they're blazing again!
So you came to see the sea?
What are you doing here?
How did you find me?
In the Creuse,
they said you were here.
You went there, then came here?
In a Smart?
Here, put this on...
Can we have some bread and butter?
How many slices?
Four!
And 6 croissants!
For once, you're eating.
What is it?
I'll be back.
Was that him?
You spoke to him?
Bastard never wrote me. Never!
It wasn't him,
it wasn't him...
We start with the fireworks display
Parisians saw last night.
Now you'll get to see it, too...
Who is it?
Me.
You were due back Saturday.
Got fed up. Came back last night.
You eaten?
Want a dessert?
No, thanks.
Was the Creuse nice?
Yes.
In 3 days you've seen it all.
You have a letter.
I saw it.
Not opening it?
Sure...
Want some ice-cream?
No, thanks.
- You're not chatty.
- She's just back. Don't bug her.
- Want some ice-cream?
- Thanks, no.
What does he say?
He's still in St Aubin,
he won't stay,
he's going overseas,
as far as he can.
"So I never see
that asshole again...
"in his suit and tie...
"his commuter train and TV set.
"Sis, don't let him talk you
into that life.
"Try to do something great.
"Dream on!"
Want to rest upstairs?
No.
I need some air.
How about a bike ride?
Now?
Yes.
You mom and I talked it over...
She's warming up to St. Malo.
What do you think?
This house
with the kids' rooms empty,
I can't take it.
I saw you in St. Aubin, Dad.
I saw you mail the letter.
You told your mom?
Tell her.
Now you know, tell her.
I'll put yours away.
So who won the Tour de France?
Dunno.
Sorry.
I guess you discussed St. Malo.
Yeah.
And?
What do you think?
I can't make up my mind.
He seems to want it so badly.
What is it?
Loïc didn't write
those letters, Mom.
What?
He never wrote.
It was Dad.
Imitated his handwriting,
and mailed them.
What's all this?
I didn't go to Crozant.
I saw him in St. Aubin.
He mailed the letters.
All of them.
From the start.
Don't be mad at him.
Without those letters, I'd be dead.
He saved me.
I wanted to say...
I've met someone.
You must meet him.
Sure.
You can both come on Sunday.
No, Sunday's Dad's birthday.
So what? On the contrary.
Come Sunday, it's fine.
July 20th
You, here?
Passing by.
On Sunday morning?
You could've called.
Who is it?
Thomas.
You remembered we exist?
Work going OK?
I see the weather report,
so I'm with you.
We're lunching at your aunt's.
Want to come?
- I can't.
- You got better things to do.
We'll be at grandma's first.
Can't you stop by?
- Where's Mathieu?
- With a pal.
Sure, pals come first!
What's she like? Is she cute?
Yes.
Grandma would've liked her.
At least she lunches
with her folks on Sunday!
You coming?
Hi.
You came to see Lili?
You're her friend!
She didn't tell us.
- That it was you.
- It's me, yes.
Come in.
She's not here yet,
won't be long.
Hope so,
or the roast'll be overdone.
Paul, it's Elise's friend.
Hi.
- Thomas.
- Right... Paul.
Let's have a drink.
Sit down.
Like what? Whisky? Port wine?
Port wine's fine.
What about your girlfriend?
Léa?
We're not together anymore.
That's weird.
You're still Lili's neighbor?
Yes.
But I'm from nearby Draveil.
I went to high school in Montgeron,
like her.
Really?
Funny. You grew up side by side,
without knowing it.
Yes.
My parents still live there.
I visited them before coming here.
We went to the cemetery,
to see my grandma's grave...
Draveil cemetery.
You know it?
What happened?
Rock-climbing.
During his rock-climbing course.
He fell.
While Lili was in Spain.
A year ago.
You won't tell her.
Right?
You're crazy.
Please don't.
There.
No need for introductions.
Hi, darling.
I'm coming.
You OK?
- Want a drink?
- No.
Some port, so we can toast.
To your birthday!
Cheers.
What's she doing?
Mom! Come raise your glass?
What is it?
The roast burned.
Doesn't matter.
Why are you so upset?
Doesn't matter,
we'll cook something else.
We'll make pasta.
Pasta's nice.
He doesn't mind.
Sure...
What if we ate out?
No, we'll eat here.
Let me take you to lunch.
Nearby, at "Jean's Place".
We can walk there.
Let us take you.
- I said I wanted to.
- He's right.
We'll be fine there.
I have something to tell you.
Me, too.
I love you.
Shall we go off somewhere?
Yes.
Where to?
Dunno, wherever you want.
Want to go back to see the sea?
Yes.
Subtitles: Sandy Whitelaw
Processed by C.M.C.
Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org