STUDIO 1 presents
DON'T CRY, PRETTY GIRLS
Starring
Written by PÉTER ZIMRE
Screenplay by YVETTE BÍRÓ
Cast
Bands starring
Music by
Lyrics by
Poem by
Chief Production Manager: OTTÓ FÖLD
Photography: JÁNOS KENDE
Directed by MÁRTA MÉSZÁROS
- Fetch me a white chair.
- A white one?
Otherwise I cannot play the cello.
I remember, it was so long ago
when the family still lived together
In the evenings,
my mother cooked supper for us
We, the children, just kept laughing
and enjoyed the warmth
Some of us asked for a second helping,
not having eaten enough
Vanishing smells took off towards the sky
Glittering stars fell down instead of them
- Hello.
- Hi.
It has been quite some time
since my good father stood up
This must have been a sign...
Hey!
Stop playing please.
Thank you.
Let's start the rehearsal.
Emese and my mother,
they sat at the piano
Let me welcome you
in the name of the performing band.
And in a moment they became lost
in the notes with enthusiasm
Then music started to play
Hey!
Boys!
Where are you going? Stop!
Come along, boys. The old man
is very cross. Stop fooling around.
Look. There she comes.
Count to twenty.
You're aces.
- Hi.
Hi.
Hello.
Come on, let's go.
- Your parents are here?
- Yes.
Come on.
- Good day.
- Hello, dear.
One, two, three...
four, five.
Thank you.
- The man with the rings is here.
- Where?
Outside.
We could arrange things as we agreed.
We'd pay for the wedding
and you for the rings.
In four weeks, we could have
the wedding at our house.
- Good day.
I've brought the rings.
Here they are.
- How much?
- Like I had said. Cheap.
Six hundred.
- No tricks?
- It's real gold.
My poor mother wore it.
- Here's her name engraved.
- It's a pity.
- Here you are.
- Thank you. Goodbye.
Goodbye.
- Thank you.
- Bye.
- Bye, son.
- Take care.
Hey, old man.
Are you seeing this?
Pull yourself together, grandpa.
It's your shift.
Hey, grandpa.
- Hey!
- He's had one too many again.
- Leave me alone.
- What will your wife say?
Put him under the shower.
Under the shower with him.
Come on, pretty face!
- Don't worry.
- Cold water will do him good.
Take off your jacket.
- Pull out your arm.
- Can you go to work?
- Yes...
- Like hell he could.
- Under the water.
- We'll see to it.
He's completely out of control.
He's done for.
Come on under the tap, old man.
Pull yourself together, old man.
Stand here.
Feels good, right?
This will do him good!
- Hold his head.
- Let him have it.
Close your eyes and do twenty squats.
- That will do.
- That's enough.
- Old man, was it good?
- No harm done.
- Was it good?
- He'll sober up. All right.
- Hey!
- What is it?
- Water!
- What's happening? Who did this?
- Is this a joke?
- Water!
- Or beer!
- Why do they always turn off the water?
- Was it you?
- I didn't turn it off. It wasn't me.
- Then who was it?
- It's the same every day.
- We're here all soaped up.
Let's kick up a row! To the office.
Comrade Szegedi?
The water's been turned off...
Hello, give us water.
It's been turned off.
No hot or cold water.
We want water!
Stars, don't shine
Stars, I am going blind
Time passes me by
Angels are creeping forth
Meteors falling into the depths
Beautiful girl, her face has disappeared
Perhaps she was only singing to me
I don't know where she went or who she was
I'm just doing drawings
of what I've dreamt
I put down what I'm thinking of
I'm just doing drawings
of what I've dreamt
I put down what I'm thinking of
I'm just doing drawings
A tiny man landed on my arm
He asked me what I was looking for
I couldn't tell him
Though I think it must have been something
The wicked dog catcher hid in a cloud
He is slyly peeping out from there
People are resting in the sunshine
It radiates its warmth on me
I'm just doing drawings
of what I've dreamt
I put down what I'm thinking of
I'm just doing drawings
of what I've dreamt
I put down what I'm thinking of
I'm just doing drawings
of what I've dreamt
I put down what I'm thinking of
I'm just doing drawings
of what I've dreamt
I put down what I'm thinking of
I'm just doing drawings
of what I've dreamt
No!
It's not me!
Not me!
This is not me! No, please!
Listen to me.
It is not me.
No!
It's not me!
It's not me! No!
It's... It's not me.
No!
It's not me!
At home, you're idle and feel bored
There's not one friend with you
We invite you to join us,
we're expecting you
Come along, you mustn't be afraid of us
Come with me, listen to the music
And do feel at ease
A shaky house, its big gate is open
Peep in, but don't expect
wonders to happen
You will be welcomed by
a smoky little room
Whoever you may be, no one will hurt you
Come with me, listen to the music
And do feel at ease
Some are standing there shocked
Some are waiting for lovely girls
Some are just sitting there in silence
Some are looking around
leaning against the wall
Come with me, listen to the music
And do feel at ease
Hey, here you are!
Down in the valley lived a girl
She wasn't what you'd call a beauty
She was an orphan and lonely
But her heart was as white as snow
After much wandering
A vagabond passed her by
His torn shirt and shoes
Were accompanied by the sound of a flute
We were going to spend the day together.
You know it.
Don't you want to?
Come along.
One afternoon, the vagabond
Arrived at the house of the girl
He was tired and weary
He asked for some food and drink
The girl told the boy to go inside
She made him sit at her table
And when evening came
She put him in her bed
Hello.
Kids, we've found some empty digs.
- Come on.
- It's a swell house. Let's go.
Ladies, come on.
The vagabond thanked the girl
Full of gratitude for the night
The girl said softly
"Stay with me forever"
We have solved so many problems
We have never been so well off
Still, sometimes you can feel it
It's annoying that you can't find digs
We said you can understand
Let's find a nice little place today
Where the neighbor endures us
And the caretaker won't rebuff us
So we, a big family, have found a home
It is the concern of all of us
We'd share it with anyone
And the caretaker won't rebuff us
Wild flowers grow up
the walls of the house
Happy to live, yes
There's a sign hanging
on the door of our house
Nobody disturbs us here
We're getting along with the girls
We leave things to them in the kitchen
And if they leave in the morning
Hey!
This is my room.
Not before we agree to it.
Stop making noises or I'll kick you.
Bye.
We'd share it with anyone
And the caretaker won't rebuff us
Don't bother us
for the next year or two.
Okay?
Wild flowers grow up
the walls of the house
Happy to live, yes
Then why did you come here with me?
Good afternoon.
- Afternoon.
- Strength and health.
- What are you doing here?
- We moved in.
What do you mean "We moved in"?
We found these swell digs.
Can't you speak like a normal person?
How many of you are there?
Nine.
One, two, three.
- And the rest?
- Up there.
Guys, a policeman's here!
Come outside.
Tell them to come out.
- I can't.
- Why?
I just can't.
- Open up. It's the police.
- Stop messing around, guys.
- In the name of the law, open up!
- Go to hell.
Open up!
- Afternoon.
What are you doing here?
Do you really want to know?
- Tell her to come outside.
- Juli.
She's my fiancée. Here's the ring.
Now listen. I'll give you one hour.
But if I find you here after that
you'll get into big trouble.
Understood?
Bye.
You have one hour to get out.
We said you can understand
Let's find a nice little place today
Where the neighbor endures us
One hour.
Understood?
Understood.
So we, a big family, have found a home
We're all in it together
We'd share it with anyone
Come on, the cop is back.
Great timing.
And the caretaker won't rebuff us.
Wild flowers grow up
the walls of the house
Happy to live, yes
There's a sign
hanging on the door of our house
Nobody disturbs us here
We are getting along well with the girls
Why are you still here?
What if we have no place to go?
People, use your brains.
What an idea to move into
a dangerous house like that!
Why? It's empty.
Another building
will be built in its place.
We'll be back then, remember this.
I gave you one hour.
If you don't leave at once,
I'll take you in.
I must report you. Understand?
That's not what you want.
Get your things and go.
Finished?
Yes.
This way, sir.
Pass the ball.
He comes from the right.
Jóska, son, fetch some beer.
Beer with beer, as usual.
- Hi.
What's up, girls?
So we, a big family, have found a home
We're all in it together
We'd share it with anyone
And the caretaker won't rebuff us
Wild flowers grow up
the walls of the house
Happy to live, yes
Guys,
I've read in the papers
that two girls went to the airport
and held up a sign that said
"a kiss for a dollar".
There was a long queue in no time.
- But the police came and drove them away.
- You wouldn't dare do this.
You think? Of course I would.
- You wouldn't.
- Do it right now.
Take my hat.
Let's see it, come on.
- She will do it!
- At least we'll have money for beer.
A kiss for a forint.
- A kiss for a forint.
- I only have fifty fillérs.
That's a good one.
She's pretty.
A kiss for a forint.
- A kiss for a forint.
- What? A forint?
Here's your forint.
Well, what do you say?
A kiss for a forint.
Here you are.
May I?
Oh, no! At just the right time.
Here's a twenty,
I buy your stock for today.
Wild flowers grow up
the walls of the house
Happy to live, yes
There's a sign
hanging on the door of our house
Nobody disturbs us here
We are getting along well with the girls
We leave things to them in the kitchen
And if they leave in the morning
- Good evening.
- Hello, girls.
- You can't come in.
- It's raining.
I don't care.
I'll get into trouble if I let you in.
You can't come in.
You're drunk, I can see it.
- Can't you understand?
- You're the one who's drunk, lady!
Go away and stop this hooliganism here.
Keep quiet!
Where have you been?
- Oh, my hair!
- They're soaking wet.
You're soaking wet, girls.
You're absolutely crazy.
- Your hair is totally wet.
- My shoes are all wet.
- You'll catch a cold.
- Come, Juli!
Get changed, quick!
- Come on.
- Water is running down my back.
We should have waited under a gutter.
- There's alcohol under the coat.
- Don't shout.
What do you mean?
The old lady told you not to shout.
It's terrible.
Even my sweater is soaking wet.
Hi.
- Watch out.
- Not so loud.
The old girl is asleep.
She'll wake up and kick up a row.
Stop joking.
Stop laughing. Don't you get it?
Hush!
- Kids, there's something wrong.
- Never mind.
- She's not asleep.
- Good evening.
We were celebrating an engagement.
Don't be cross with us.
Are you not ashamed of yourself?
- Of what you're doing?
- Why?
Four men with two women. Good Lord!
- Don't you recognize my sister?
- Anyone can say that. Get out of here.
- We're kicked out like dogs.
- Get out. Go!
All right, I'm going.
Don't let her overwhelm you.
- In we'll go and finish our beer.
- No.
You're already drunk. Go home at once.
- Get out.
- Next time then.
- Bye.
- Well, girls, it didn't work out.
Get out.
- Bye.
We liked her talk, though.
- Bye then.
Bye, good night!
Boo.
You filthy thing!
You try to knife your best pal?
No! Don't kill me! I beg you!
I'll do anything you want!
Murderer! Traitor!
You bastard! I'll kill you!
I'll trample you to death!
You bastard! You filthy thing!
You damn fag!
I'll tear you to pieces!
- I'll rip you apart!
- Don't do that to me, boys.
- I'll castrate you! I'll pickle you!
- What will people say?
- Don't do that to me.
- You cheat!
You'll pay for my sister...
For taking away her innocence!
For staining her sweet, pure life!
Don't move or I'll knife you!
What is it, Juli?
Hi.
Climb in.
Are you waiting to be asked?
You can wash our things...
since you're here.
Hurry up.
What are you thinking about?
The boy who was playing the cello
on the white chair.
That boy?
Yes.
What do you think of him?
He played beautifully.
I can play like that.
I was also thinking of you.
You'd better have been.
Where is the place where nobody asks you
We can start.
Why do you live the way you do
Is there a place like that?
Hi.
Stop there.
You, too.
You know you can't go in. You, too.
Where is the place
where there are no prejudices
And there are laws only in the hearts
All that suits me
doesn't hurt anybody else
There's only peace and no regulations
Where's that place?
Where's that fort?
Where meaning is more important
than appearances
Where's that place?
Where's that fort?
Where you are your own master
Girls, there's Géza!
Géza! Come over here!
Come over here!
- Hi, girls.
- Hi.
Come on, girls. Come on, hurry up!
Hurry up!
Excuse us.
Let them come in, they're with me.
- We're all with him.
- With Géza.
The guys are outside,
let them come in, too.
There they are.
- Guys, come up!
- Let the guys come in, too.
Where is that place?
Where's that fort?
Where meaning is more important
than appearances
Look, they were smuggled in
and we are just standing here.
Where is that place?
Where's that fort?
Where you are your own master
Where is the place where nobody asks you
Why do you live the way you do
Is there a place like that?
Good day. Where are you going?
You can't go in.
Let them in, they are with me.
- All of them?
- Yes.
I'd try to find it
Want to dance?
My coat is torn by the wind
The night is too cool for me
I pass slowly by them
Their warm voices overtake me laughing
I carry on my way, the wind follows me
Its chilly finger touches my back
And asks why it is good that many people
Think the same,
yet talk of something else?
Easy girls
You must never deny
That your dreams are woven from kisses
Words are the covers of thought
It isn't good to feel ashamed or cold
Intentions are wrapped up in word dresses
It isn't yet becoming walking around naked
Easy girls
I'm fond of you
Because you don't wear masks
The lyrics to the following two songs
were written by poets:
Miklós Radnóti and Attila József.
When beat music became popular,
we didn't sing much in Hungarian.
We just tried to translate the lyrics
of the most popular English songs.
The new Hungarian beat tries to adapt
folk songs and poems for a reason.
Metro's song is an adaptation
of Miklós Radnóti's poem written in 1937
entitled "Marginal note
to the Prophet Habakuk".
Kex' song is an adaptation of
Attila József's poem "With a Pure Heart".
Cities in flames
Villages exploded
Be strict with me, Habakuk
The ember's already cold and black
But within me,
the fiery bite is still burning
My food, my drink is bitter
Cover me with soot to my heels,
you, black anger
I have neither native sod,
nor a father, mother, god,
cradle gone, the shroud I miss,
lack a lover, lack a kiss.
Three days' hunger, not a bite:
nothing heavy, nothing light.
Just on twenty, strong and well,
twenty years I'll try to sell.
If a buyer can't be got,
let the devil take the lot.
Pure at heart, I surely will
break and enter, even kill.
They will catch me, I'll be hung,
blessed earth on me be flung,
deadly grasses will then start
growing on my splendid heart.
I have neither native sod,
nor a father, mother, god,
cradle gone, the shroud I miss,
lack a lover, lack a kiss.
Three days' hunger, not a bite:
nothing heavy, nothing light.
Just on twenty, strong and well,
twenty years I'll try to sell.
If a buyer can't be got,
let the devil take the lot.
Pure at heart, I surely will
break and enter, even kill.
They will catch me, I'll be hung,
blessed earth on me be flung,
deadly grasses will then start
growing on my splendid heart.
Come on.
I'll take you to a cool place.
Will you come with me?
I will.
She'd tell them to submerge
And watch the crabs making love
Hey.
I can't go alone.
Then tell them to come with us.
For what purpose she'd use
the many war devices?
She'd say: for any purpose
Well? Are you coming?
Come.
If Julia was asked
What is a soldier supposed to do then?
She'd say... But I won't tell you
If you want to know, go and ask Julia
I'm sure
Julia doesn't know much
about such complicated things
Still, if I could
I would realize all her ideas
Perhaps I am growing tired
Or the days have grown more burdensome
I miss you
I could stand more before
My strength is gone
I lived according to my beliefs
I was often disappointed
But nothing has changed
When there was encouragement
Oh, when you're with me
I don't get tired
I've become great for your sake
If that's what I am
Sorrow is measured by words
But their weight has been rubbed away
Still, he who understands
it can see into me
You're not angry, I hope.
Why should I be?
Why do you put up with it?
Come outside.
Come on.
Oh, you must tell me
Why I'm not good enough for you
Don't cry, boys
Don't cry, girls
Tears make me shiver
I regret being blue
Don't cry, girls
Don't cry, boys
You're a nice guy, good-looking, too,
but leave that girl alone
or you'll regret it.
She's his sister and his fiancée.
You'd better forget that chap.
It's we who are taking care of you.
Me and Sour.
You're his fiancée.
We got you a place, a job, you've got
everything, what else do you want?
- What's wrong?
- Nothing.
He who desires goodness for goodness
Will soon grow tired of it
There are only a few who'll understand
Why he feels sorry
And now here I am
A broken-down little boy
amongst the grown-ups
Don't cry, girls,
Don't cry, boys
Hi.
- Hi. Were you the one who asked for me?
- Yes.
I'm going to the country with the band.
- Will you come with me?
- I can't. I'm working.
You're scared, aren't you?
I'm not.
- Can't you get some time off?
- No.
Wait, I'll arrange it.
Don't cry, girls
Don't cry, boys
Oh, no, I didn't deserve it
Oh, no, don't cry, girls
Don't cry, boys
Don't cry, girls
Oh, no
Everything's been arranged, come on.
Don't cry, boys
Don't cry, girls
They're waiting for Julia
Oh all the boys
Who are reading poems
Will understand at last
Oh will understand
Pure love...
- Good afternoon.
- Hello, dear.
Come.
- Hi, girls.
- Hi.
- Hello.
- Going somewhere?
- Where are you going?
To the country with the band.
Juli is coming with me.
- This will cause trouble.
- Big trouble.
Is Juli going with you?
- She's going away with him.
- She's an idiot.
- Does she want to go?
- Of course.
She'll be beaten to death.
Don't be silly. Who'd do that?
- Juli is Sour's fiancée.
- So what?
You know what? Take me instead.
- Not now, but some other time, okay?
- Okay.
I'm ready to go.
- Bye, girls.
- Bye.
I've warned you.
A wanderer is strolling along the road
And keeps talking, talking of a girl
It was not long ago when he said goodbye
and he was asked
Will you come again next year, wanderer?
People are passing by
Birds are flying away
Clouds are blown away
Hearts are getting cured
Let's stop and give him a lift.
Where do you want to go?
- The next village over.
- Hop on, mate.
- Hello.
- Hi.
- Are you musicians?
- Wandering actors.
Wandering actors?
Where are you coming from?
We gave a concert nearby.
Are you hitch-hiking around the country?
- Yes.
- And what do you do?
Writing poems.
You? Poems?
Yes.
- Really?
- Really.
Here's one of my favorite ones.
You've placed a wafer-thin moon
in my window
It was white
as it climbed the yawning walls
It got stuck on the shadows of the trees
and is now hanging on the branches
It's late, don't go to the meadow,
Trouble is always bound to happen
Flower-tusks will hurt your feet
Grass and mud will be covered in blood
You'll be trampled to death
by the growling forest's herd
And the crazy whispering grass
will sting you
Wandering fires will set your hair on fire
Wild dogs will bite you
You, who are giving birth to dawns for me
And nobody will ever find out
That you've placed a wafer-thin moon
in my window
Once there lived a flower
Lonely, all alone
There lived a flower
In a pure, blue dress it lived
There came a girl
In a dress as white as snow
Lonely, all alone and said
Come with me, blue flower
Oh dear
How could I go with you?
In the ground
Under bushes I'm living
The lovely girl
Kept asking her for so long
Kept asking her so nicely
Come with me, blue flower
Come along, boys.
Come along.
- Good-bye.
- Goodbye.
- Bye.
Come again.
- Do come again.
- You're always welcome.
- Wait for me!
- Come on, Miki.
Though we might be
in some other place then.
Bye.
- Hi, guys.
Come on now. Hurry up.
A wanderer is strolling along the road
And keeps talking, talking of a girl
Bye. Hurry up! Bye.
Will you come again next year, wanderer?
People are passing by
Birds are flying away
Clouds are blown away
Hearts are getting cured
My heart overflows with you. Hi.
We will play three songs.
"Family", "With a Pure Heart" and "Stars".
I've heard you also do folk songs.
- Everything OK? Can I go?
- You can.
Yes.
- And why?
- Because we like folk songs.
I remember, it was so long ago
when the family still lived together
In the evenings,
my mother cooked supper for us
We, the children, just kept laughing
and enjoyed the warmth
Some of us asked for a second helping,
not having eaten enough
Vanishing smells took off towards the sky
Glittering stars fell down instead of them
It has been quite some time
since my good father stood up
This must have been the sign
to begin the music
My sister, Emese, and my mother
they sat at the piano
And in a moment they became lost
in the notes with enthusiasm
And the music chimed
I'd gladly fly with it today
Stars, don't shine
Stars, I am going blind
Time passes me by
Angels are creeping forth
Meteors falling into the depths
Beautiful girl, her face has disappeared
Perhaps she was only singing to me
I don't know where she went or who she was
I'm just doing drawings
of what I've dreamt
I'll tear you to pieces, you bastard!
What are you doing? Stop it!
Go away. You can't be here.
Run for your lives! No!
- Stop!
- It's not the right place.
Our dear leader!
- What are you doing?
- But gentlemen! This is a stage.
I'll beat you!
Jancsi, are you OK?
I'm OK, Miklós.
I'll tear your ears off!
When grass and leaves go home
Rivers become green
Fish swim there
We are flying on in peace
There's an open window
A red bird falling down, its wings tremble
Only the two of you feel sympathy for it
It has tripped over
It has fallen down
I can go to it
But you carry on running without it
Huge violin, green-cloud music
Always nearing and disappearing
With hands wet with tears
When you travel on alone
The train slowly stops
A red bird falling down, its wings tremble
Only the two of you feel sympathy for it
It has tripped over
It has fallen down
I can go to it
You can check for yourself.
The girl is here.
I'll skin the back of this bastard.
Don't do anything stupid.
This is so embarrassing.
Come on, boys, we're leaving.
- Ciao.
Have you gone mad, Sour?
We'll punch them twice and take Juli.
No, boys, we can't do that.
- Yes, we can. What are we waiting for?
- Why did we come here then?
- Listen to Kex.
- Don't kick up a row.
If I were you,
I'd have killed the whole gang long ago!
Don't kick up a row. Go home.
- Come on.
- Let's leave here.
He's helpless.
Things are getting bad, Sour.
This is my problem.
All right.
You're a shithead.
Shall I hit you?
Get lost.
Silence is getting tired,
it can't overcome the song
That brings back so many happy days
Welcome it with smiling faces
Girls, don't cry
I know there are vanished dreams
And misunderstood moments
But there are real joys awaiting you
Girls, don't cry
If a shiny promise withers
to become a cheat
This is no reason to shed tears
The flowers of the meadow
have withered a thousand times
And new flowers have grown
in their place a thousand times
If the sad moment draws to a close
It brings a cheerful day nearer
You are so lovely with smiling eyes
Girls, don't cry
If a shiny promise withers
to become a cheat
This is no reason to shed tears
The flowers of the meadow
have withered a thousand times
And new flowers have grown
in their place a thousand times
If the sad moment draws to a close
It brings a cheerful day nearer
You are so lovely with smiling eyes
Girls, don't cry
Are you angry with me?
I am not.
We'd better break up.
Such things can't be forced.
You're young and beautiful.
You should be free.
You're right.
Down in the valley lived a girl
She wasn't what you'd call a beauty
She was an orphan and lonely
But her heart was as white as snow
After long wandering
A vagabond passed by
His torn shirt and shoes
Were accompanied by the sound of a flute
One afternoon the vagabond
Arrived at the house of the girl
He was tired and weary
He asked for some food and drink
The girl told the boy to come in
She made him sit at her table
And when evening came
She put him in her bed
The vagabond thanked the girl
for the night
Full of gratitude
The girl said softly
"Stay with me forever"
Do you, Istvan Bencsik,
take Julia Keresztes
to be your lawfully wedded wife?
I do.
Do you, Julia Keresztes,
take Istvan Bencsik
to be your lawfully wedded husband?
I do.
But a day came
When the boy said:
"I'm being expected, I must go
It was nice with you, but I can't stand
This life any longer"
The girl only asked for another night
"You can leave tomorrow," she said
Oh and the boy remained in the valley
Buried forever
There were many people who loved truly
Oh, yes
But could never be happy
We're watching the TV
and going to the movies
Oh, yes
I can imagine what our life will be like
Don't cry, girls
Don't cry, boys
Life is beautiful
Don't cry, girls
Don't cry, boys
How beautiful life could be
The architect planned a big house
Oh, yes
Why it turned out to be bad,
he still can't understand
Oh, yes
Don't cry, girls
Don't cry, boys
Life is beautiful
Don't cry, girls
Don't cry, boys
How beautiful life could be
Don't cry, girls
Don't cry, boys
There is a big river somewhere
It's never navigable
An object submerged in its water
does not lose from its weight
And all the ships sink
Somewhere a little flower
Is smiling to see you again
It's being picked
and wanders into a vase
to adorn her home
We live and we die
So wish us lovely dreams
Somewhere an armchair
A bit old but still nice
Can't wait to surround its sweetheart
It hasn't seen for so long
Somewhere a grave
Has become so poor
It sorrowfully thinks of
Having given shelter to so many people
While it was still young
We live and we die
So wish us lovely dreams