Bye.
Bye, Mom.
I know it's frustrating.
But it's not easy at your age.
LAUNDRY WORKER
POSTMAN
-A subsidiary?
-Yes, in Toronto.
How long for?
Well, as long as it takes.
But a year at least.
A year at least?
You're going to live on the other side
of the world for a year at least?
I can image that…
You just casually drop that in
here on Boudewijn de Haas' couch
-a week and a half before you leave.
-I understand that…
Jesus! You can't just drop everything.
You've got two kids.
And you've got
all the time in the world. It's ideal.
Well… I… I think…
Let's try and…
They need to learn to fend for themselves,
Doris. It'll be good for them.
Otherwise they'll wind up
aged 45 with no job,
no money, no husband. Nothing.
-Hi.
-I'm not doing too great.
-Or rather with us.
-What happened?
Let's just says it was
some senseless violence.
Would you like to come in?
I was about to go to the market.
In that case, I'll come with you.
And I'll pop in
to the bicycle repair shop.
-One year?
-Yeah.
But he's got a business here:
The business
of looking after his son and daughter.
-It's a pretty big deal.
-But the worst thing about it is…
he's actually right.
I'm 45 and I'm a tragic case.
No job, no husband,
no money, no plan.
I'm a mess, aren't I?
I'm just like Sien's pet mouse.
I'm just running in circles.
Pointless little circles
and I'm getting nowhere.
Everyone I know has a purpose,
or they're actively doing something.
Sarah has a stream of interesting cases,
you've got a flashy career in TV,
Walter is moving to Canada,
and I'm the only one whose life
has come to a complete standstill,
who sits on the couch every night
like some sort of Big Lebowski
-watching Bake Off.
-Three million people watch that.
All you see on Instagram is photos
of all these super successful people
making something of themselves
with their witty hashtags
and their friends and their cleavages.
And it makes me wonder,
where did I go wrong?
Which turning did I miss?
I mean, this is nothing like
how I had imagined it would be.
-I feel…
-Take it easy, Doris.
I think you're hyperventilating.
Sorry.
You know, Door,
we're all walking in circles.
The people going for a run,
or taking their Rottweiler for a walk,
they're also walking in circles.
They walk to the bridge,
walk along the water and walk back home.
The stupid thing is the older I get,
the less I understand it.
-What?
-Everything. Life.
-Well, how had you pictured it then?
-What?
Your life. When you were younger
and you pictured the future.
-I'm not going to tell you.
-Oh, go on.
I always wanted to study in England.
In one of those beautiful old university
buildings like Oxford or Cambridge.
And it would have
a bright green lawn in the middle.
And there I'd meet a handsome,
well-dressed literature professor,
-of course.
-Can I have two of those, please?
And together we'd drink too much tea
and have highly intelligent conversations.
Sounds like you've been watching
too many BBC dramas.
-Wrapped together or separately?
-Separately.
-Do Sien and Willem know?
-About our financial situation?
No, about Walter.
He's telling them tonight.
-Thank you.
Here you go.
-What's wrong?
-Nothing.
-Don't you like daffodils?
-Oh, yes, very much. Thank you.
Sorry. Oh shit, I have to take this.
Hi, Lynn, sorry I didn't call you back.
Yes, OK, that's fine.
Email it to me and I'll give it a read.
OK. See you later, yeah? OK. Bye.
So, what are you doing for your birthday?
-Pretending like it's not happening.
-Sunday, right?
I'm not celebrating it. Can't afford it.
-What can I get you?
-A pound of green beans, please.
Maybe we could do something
with Sien and Willem?
Well it would have to be
a very budget-friendly activity.
-Anything else?
-A butterhead lettuce, please.
-We could go camping for the weekend.
-Camping?
It's the perfect antidote
to panic attacks and hyperventilation.
With Sien and Willem?
They'll think I've lost the plot!
It'll be fun.
Get out into the countryside.
And it means you won't have to worry
about throwing a party.
-Butterhead lettuce.
-And a pound of asparagus. That's it.
Hm, yeah, great. All of us camping
together, the great outdoors…
That'll be 8.50, please.
It'll be fine. The weather's going to be
lovely this weekend.
See?
HAVE YOU GOT A SLEEPING BAG
I CAN BORROW?
We'll be discussing the flooding
in Bangladesh in just a moment.
But before that, let's look at today's
parliamentary debate about tax increases.
Tim, you've been following the debate.
What can you tell us?
Emotions were running high,
even during the opening remarks.
It appears,
from the minister of finance's speech,
that his party, the Labor party
will need to retract
their earlier announcements
of tax increases for the highest earners.
The new measures proposed
by the minister are less far-reaching
than those announced
during the election campaign.
A notable change in policy…
Hi, sweetheart.
Listen, if you need some more money
to tide you over…
No, it's fine.
-I'm just gonna go and…
-OK.
Shall we just forget about
the responsible parent chat for tonight?
Yeah. Well, goodnight, then.
Oh, Tim asked if we want
to go camping with him this weekend.
-If you don't feel like it…
-If they've got Wi-Fi, I don't mind.
-Perhaps you'd like to invite Janne along?
-No.
Oh. OK.
Well, sleep well, then, eh?
Night.
I've decided to take some serious action.
Yeah, I can tell.
I've bought a book that tells you
exactly what you should and shouldn't eat.
I'm taking Friday mornings off,
and I've signed up for a half marathon.
-Jesus Christ.
-So now there's no backing out.
The kids are all grown up
and Daniel is never
not at the tennis club.
-So, I thought: now is the moment.
-Yes, you're absolutely right, sis.
"Be happy with the little things.
With the flowers, trees and bees."
"With the birds that sing,
and you'll always be at peace."
"From your sister Doris."
Not a bad philosophy for life.
Where are the damn things?
Saar?
Do you ever dream about someone else?
Someone other than Daniel, I mean.
Well, not very often, unfortunately. Why?
Lately, I keep dreaming about Tim.
Oh.
What kind of dreams?
Very kind of romantic,
costume drama type situations.
Yesterday, when I was at the market
with him, I suddenly thought…
What?
I'm going to give you a massive kiss.
-A massive one?
-Yeah. Massive.
Then he called Lynn.
You know, his colleague off the TV.
-They're together, right?
-They are?
-I thought I read it somewhere.
-Damn it.
I think I'm…
I think I'm jealous.
-It's very strange.
-Yes.
-Don't you think?
-Yes, it is a bit.
Generally speaking, I'm not
particularly inclined to kiss my friends.
-Even if I'm at the market.
-No, me neither.
-Does that mean that…?
-Yes, I think it does.
-But it's also kind of nice, isn't it?
-Nice? It makes it super complicated.
-Why?
-Because Tim is my best friend.
-So?
-He's always been there,
even when everything
is messed up and goes wrong.
He's just about
the only stable thing in my life.
So what?
-Well.
There's nothing to say
he has these 'massive kiss' feelings too.
-You don't know that.
-What's more,
you're telling me
there's something going on
between him and that mannequin
he sits next to every night
who never gets tongue-tied
and has 18,995 followers on Instagram?
It might not even be true. I thought…
If I bother him with this,
I might mess everything up
and it might never be fun
or nice between us ever again.
But if you say nothing at all,
it might turn into an even bigger mess.
Door, just tell him.
Just put two folding chairs by the tent
and say, "Sit down, Tim.
I've got something to tell you."
I really wanted to kiss you at the market.
Yeah. You'll be fine.
There you go. Have fun.
I'll call you later, all right? Bye.
-D.G. Dorenbos?
-Yes.
You need to sign for this.
Hi, Janne. How's things?
-Good.
Mom, the cheese is all gone.
And the ketchup too.
-Oh.
-The whole fridge is empty.
OK. I guess I'll go
and do some groceries, then.
WE BUY GOLD
Hey, listen, Tim,
there's something I wanted to…
something I wanted to talk to you about.
I've got something to tell you.
I've noticed…
Hi.
Let's sit down a moment.
There's something important
I want to talk to you about.
Would you mind
taking off all your clothes?
Sien, are you coming?
-What's this?
-A sky lantern.
A sky lantern. Of course.
-I think we've got everything.
-I hope so.
-Every summer with the scouts…
-I always wanted to do that.
Were you in the scouts?
Mom wouldn't let us. She thinks
the scouts are politically incorrect.
-That's right.
-I had the time of my life.
I looked forward to it all year.
We never went to a campsite.
No, we'd go wild camping.
Where did you shower?
No showers. We'd swim in a forest lake.
Nice and stinky.
Wonderful. Airing your manhood
in all that wonderful fresh air.
We'd dig a hole in the ground
and that was our toilet.
What did you do all day?
Look for tracks? Hunt foxes?
-Sing fascist songs, perhaps?
-We did nothing of the sort.
We were lovely little boys
with our short shorts and neckerchiefs
and badges that we were very proud of.
I promise to do my best
to be a good cub scout,
to help others whenever I can,
and to follow the cub scout code of honor.
-You can count on me.
-Where is Willem?
-Looking for a socket.
-Jesus, Mom.
-It's a classic tent.
-You know, the Albatross.
-Albatross?
Yes, with an awning and two rooms.
It's indestructible.
I've had it for 25 years.
-I'm going for a wee.
-You'd better be coming back!
After I undo this, it'll be up in no time.
We are the cubs,
And we love the forest
-You can have a run around--
-Give it a rest.
Listen, Mister…
it's the anniversary
of my father's death next week
and my mother has invited us all
to do
a sort of memorial ceremony type thing
-and she wondered if you'd like to come?
-I'd love to.
Really? Don't feel obliged to come.
-It'll probably be really boring.
-Of course I'll come.
Crikey, has it already been a year?
It's enough to make you crazy,
the way time just flies.
You make a couple of sandwiches,
take out the trash,
put up the Christmas decorations,
-and before you know it…
-And just like that you're 45.
Thanks so much for pointing that out.
-Perfect time for some mindfulness.
-Shove it!
It's very good for anxiety.
Pass.
It doesn't count
because you didn't say "last card."
-That's not fair.
-It's what we just agreed.
-I was finally going to win for once.
-Those are the rules.
Rules… Is that how it's going to be?
Is it going to be one of those weekends?
Stop whining, Mom.
The fascist boy scout comes crawling
out of his tent with his rules.
-You're just a bad loser.
-I am not.
-I'm going to open another bag of nuts.
-Hurrah!
-Have you ever been camping before?
-Sure. 33 years ago.
That's when…
That's when I went to England for a week
with my friend Marion and her parents.
We were camped next to
a young couple in a tiny little tent.
They spent the whole week,
and I mean the whole week, bonking.
-Bonking?
-Yes, bonking.
From early in the morning to late at night
with all the sound effects.
All the time there'd be an arm
or a leg pushing against the tent walls.
-Don't do that. You'll make the tent leak.
-Yeah, yeah.
The funny thing was
that for the whole week,
Marion's parents pretended
there was absolutely nothing going on.
Every now and then the zipper would open,
and out came two bright-red,
overheated, sticky 18 year olds.
I guess they were going
to get something to eat or do groceries.
And an hour later, off they went again.
Zipper open, tent closed, zipper closed…
-OK, Mom. We get it.
-Thanks. Can we go to sleep now?
Sorry. Sorry.
-Good night, guys.
-Good night.
-Good night, cub scouts.
-Sleep well.
-Are you warm enough?
-I think so.
-Scary dreams?
-No.
It's fine.
It's raining.
As it should be.
The ultimate camping experience.
-Sorry.
-Rubbish.
No, that was the wind.
It was the wind. It was.
Sorry.
Or a Biodanza workshop?
-Let loose a bit.
-Oh, wonderful.
What's happened here?
Has someone walked into it or something?
-That's odd.
-Yeah.
-Tim, I just wanted to…
-Mom.
Mom. They've got tandem bikes for rent.
-Oh!
-We should do it.
-I don't know, sweetie.
-That's a good idea.
-Is that at reception?
-Yes.
Great for middle-aged people like us.
Nice bit of cycling. I hope you brought
your functional windbreaker.
-Look! A squirrel.
-Ow. You yelled right in my ear.
Here's to a really lovely day.
Come on, then.
Tim, I…
Recently, I've…
Sometimes I think that I…
-You think you what?
-Well, that I…
Well, now I really want to know.
After the divorce,
I really thought I would never…
I mean, I had no desire
or inclination to… with anyone…
-To what…?
-I don't know.
At our age, we're so…
Well, who we are.
With an instruction manual as long
as your arm. And so stuck in our ways.
Especially with Willem and Sien in tow.
The three of us are this beautiful,
complex, fragile unit.
I always thought, how could we possibly
add anyone to that. It'd be impossible.
The whole structure would collapse.
-But?
-But…
Now, I'm starting to think
it might be possible.
With the right person.
For the first time,
I feel like that's what I really want.
Wait a minute. Are you saying…
Are you saying
you want to try and find someone?
-That's great.
-No.
Like on Tinder or something?
-No, no.
-Hi, Tim speaking. No. It's no problem.
Yes, I'm on a camp site near Kootwijk.
Yes, that's right. By the shifting sands.
What, really?
Oh, just with some friends.
-Mom, check it out. Mom.
-Door.
You have to make a wish, Mom.
Here it goes, Door.
For she's a jolly good fellow,
And so say all of us!
-Hip hip hurray!
-Hurray.
Well, Doris Dorenbos,
it's time for a little speech.
In every person's life,
there are good times…
-And bad times.
-…and bad times.
No, life will not spare us.
Thankfully,
there is such a thing as friendship.
Until death do us part,
in sickness and in health.
And when you know each other
as well as we do…
You know that I like apple sauce
with my pasta.
-Yuck!
-And I know you're not a very good singer,
and that you fancy men
in corduroy jackets.
-Is that your type?
-Yes.
When you know so many embarrassing,
call them intolerable things,
about each other,
then you can really speak
of a true friendship.
And to honor this heartfelt connection,
I would like to give you
this piece of jewelry. Please stand up.
Give me your arm.
Oh, that's so sweet.
-Took me a long time to save up for that.
-Very cool, Mom.
To my BFF, from Tim.
I had no idea what to get,
so this is a little joke.
Let me take you shopping
for something special.
Well, thank you very much.
-Another cup of coffee, Missus?
-Yes, please.
And then this birthday girl is going
to brave the creepy campsite showers.
-Hi, Lynn.
-Good morning, everyone.
-This is a surprise.
-Yes, I had some work things,
so I thought I'd bring them to you.
OK. Great. That's very kind of you.
-This is Willem and Sien.
-Hi.
And that is Doris Dorenbos.
It's her birthday today.
Yeah.
-Right, well, happy birthday.
-Thank you.
Would you like something to eat
or some coffee?
There's a cafe at the entrance.
Shall we go and sit there?
-It's probably quieter.
-Yes. Good plan. Let's do that.
-OK. See you later.
-Bye.
Bye.
Bit strange of her to visit, wasn't it?
-What do you mean?
-Well, I mean…
It's a bit odd for a colleague to turn up
out of the blue on a Sunday morning
on a campsite
an hour and a half's drive from Amsterdam.
Her parents live nearby.
But she could have just dropped those
papers in your mailbox, couldn't she?
Wim, could you give me a hand
with the washing up?
-Do I have to?
-Yes, you do.
Tim, can I ask you something?
I'm sick of it.
I'm behaving like a 13-year-old, Sarah.
Get rid of Sien and Willem for a bit
and then talk to him.
No, because I just don't know…
No, I just can't do…
See? As you can tell, I've taken on
some kind of totally incoherent form.
-I'm some sort of blob.
-Just talk to him, Door.
You'll feel much better for it.
How difficult can it be?
We are the cubs,
We love the forest
You can run around there,
And look for a fox
We swim and we cycle,
Lots of fun for you and me
There's nowhere in the world
I would rather be
-Bye, guys.
-I had a great time.
Me too.
Tim, could you sit down for a minute?
I want to tell you something.
It's important.
-Yes. I have something to tell you too.
-Oh.
I… Oh.
I had a really great time
with Willem and Sien.
I really enjoyed it.
And they absolutely adore you.
Well, the feeling's mutual.
What I wanted to say is, I…
I've noticed the past couple of months
that I've been longing for a family.
It's quite strange really,
after all these years of being a bachelor.
-I was always just busy with work.
-Do you mean…
Lynn is kind of in the same boat.
She's 36,
and she'd quite like to have children.
But…
But it's not something you can just…
It's… a huge decision.
Yeah. For sure. Totally.
-But this weekend…
-This weekend was really great.
Life isn't one long camping fest,
filled with pastries and ice cream.
It seems to me you have
a rather naive and romantic picture
of what it means to have a family.
-I don't think it's that bad.
-Sorry, but I don't think you realize
how demanding and tough it can
be to be responsible for children.
Well maybe it's high time I found out.
It's just that…
When you told me about your decision
to start looking for love,
I thought, yes, she's right.
I should be brave too and just go for it.
Wait a minute. You can't just
throw yourself into something
because you're in the same boat, Tim.
It's not exactly unexpected.
It's just I never
looked into it properly before.
But now suddenly you are?
Suddenly you're like,
it's Sunday May 17th, I'm going to start
a family with my colleague off the TV.
I'm not saying it's going to happen
immediately. All I'm saying
is that, like you, perhaps it's time
I got serious about it and…
Christ!
Why are you reacting so aggressively.
I understand that it would be nice
if I could be more enthusiastic.
I understand that.
But I just can't right now, OK?
I really like
how you've combined the chocolate
with the cookie dough and the nuts.
But the execution with the cream
is a bit greasy.
I like the idea,
but I'm not so keen on the result.
-A music cake.
-Fabulous.
-A Phantom of the Opera cake.
-I can see the logic.
Darling, you spent years
working for Walter.
You gave up your studies
to go and work in his first shop.
Don't you think I know that?
-So, it's perfectly normal to get alimony.
-I don't want to talk about it.
I'll find something.
I'm doing a trial shift
at a restaurant soon.
You never know, I might really enjoy it.
Here it is.
-Should I come and give you a hand?
-No, you've already got your hands full.
Look, it's from Tim. I found it
behind a cupboard. It's from 1987.
MY FATHER KEEPS DRIVING
ON THE WRONG SIDE OF THE ROAD,
SO I DOUBT I'LL SURVIVE THIS TRIP.
FAREWELL AND SEE YOU
ON THE OTHER SIDE. BEST WISHES, TIM
The thing is, Door,
this house is full of memories.
-But that's nice, though, isn't it?
-Yes, it's nice but also not nice.
What's this?
The rose bush out there
was a wedding present from my parents.
It used to be in the garden of the house
where you and Sarah were born.
When we moved house,
Dad dug it up and we took it with us.
But it's too big to move now.
It wouldn't survive that.
-So that's a cutting?
-Yes.
I want to plant it in my new garden
on Sunday when we're all together.
A kind of symbolic… Well…
I thought we could honor it in that way.
-Do you want a sandwich?
-Yes. Good plan.
-Peanut butter or roast beef?
-Roast beef with loads of salt.
There you go.
-I'd like to pay.
-I'll be right with you.
-Did you enjoy that?
-Yes.
-Sixteen fifty, please.
-Can I pay by card?
There you go.
Thank you.
Oh, it says "payment unsuccessful."
Have either of you got any money on you?
-There you go.
-Thank you.
I'll pay you back, love.
Do you mind if Janne comes
to Grandad's memorial thing?
-Of course not.
-Tim's coming too, isn't he?
-Well, I actually don't know.
-Why? What happened?
-I thought he promised?
-Maybe he has to--
-Have you fallen out?
-Thanks. I'm just going to the bathroom.
Guys, this is Doris. She's doing
a trial shift as a server this evening.
-Hi, I'm Ahmed.
-Hi, Doris, I'm Gijs.
Great, so if you just…
OK, so that's two beers and… and…
a glass of red wine…
and a glass of water.
-And a gin and tonic.
-Oh, of course, sorry. Gin and tonic.
OK. I'll bring that out to you.
Gin and tonic.
-Table four have been waiting 10 minutes.
-I'm going over there now.
-It's Doris, right?
-Yes, that's right.
-What would you like to drink?
-A glass of Chardonnay, please.
Char… don… nay.
-How are you?
-I don't think we have that.
-I'll have a beer.
-One beer.
Is this your restaurant?
No, I work here for 7.20 an hour,
including holiday allowance.
I'll go and get your drinks.
-Everything all right?
-Yeah.
Doris, table six can be cleared
and table eight wants coffee.
Would you like to look
at the dessert menu?
No. We do not want to look
at the dessert menu.
Where is the restroom?
Over there in the corner,
by the sign that says "restroom."
-Jesus, Door.
-Sorry, it's a very awkward situation.
Yes, but you don't need to take it out
on Lynn. It's not her fault.
I've got two cappuccinos
going cold over there.
Hey, Doris, fancy a gin and tonic?
Sure. Why not.
If you don't want to,
you don't want to. Right?
-Do you want another one?
-Yeah, but after that mo nore.
-No more.
-Mo nore. Come here.
What are we doing, Mr. Grey?
-Let's not get too acrobatic, eh?
-Darling? Gijsje, are you asleep?
I got you a surprise.
God damn it.
Calm down, darling.
But we'd agreed. I wanted to surprise you.
-It's all right, darling.
-I can't deal with this.
We weren't going to do this anymore.
You're going to ruin everything.
You know that as well as I do.
When you say you need space
and you're going to sleep in the studio
for a couple of nights,
I should be able to trust you.
Otherwise, you need to be honest
and say there's someone else
I'd like to try stuff out with,
and then I'll keep my distance.
Do you understand?
So I can protect myself.
But she's not really anyone, you know?
I mean…
Do you realize how shit it feels
to stand here like this?
-This is so humiliating.
-I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
I believe in us. I believe in this.
But if we're going
to allow each other that freedom,
that makes it a very fragile thing.
I know, darling. I don't know
what the hell I'm doing either.
I mean, look at me.
I bought a new bra.
I found a babysitter.
And I get here and…
Oh, jeez.
Oh, no.
Guys, have either of you seen my bracelet?
-No.
What's going on?
Why are you fully dressed
and eating breakfast
at nine on a Saturday morning?
Because Dad's expecting us
at quarter to ten.
Shit. Shit. Shit. Shit.
That's my girl.
You can always FaceTime me.
You need to get a haircut, son.
You look ridiculous.
Let's go.
Thank you so much.
I'll pay you back as soon as I can.
-How did it go at the restaurant?
-Not great.
What's next?
Tomorrow I'm going to apply
for a job as a postman.
I'm trying to convince myself
that it's a very romantic profession.
This one's for Willem.
And this one's for Grandma.
I think that's everyone.
-I thought Tim was going to come.
-No, he had to work.
-Have you guys got the cutting?
-Yes.
-Door?
-Hi.
-Hi, Tim.
-You came.
-I didn't know if you wanted me to…
-Come on.
-This is Janne.
-Hi, Tim.
Well…
Dear Dad…
I remember how you used to get up
really early in the morning
before our birthday parties
when we were little
to go and set up the treasure hunt.
And in the afternoon,
after we'd had soda and cake,
the whole gang of us
would go to the forest
to look for the clues you'd hung up
and hunt for the treasure, of course,
that was buried somewhere
deep in the dark, dark woods.
But one time, some little yobs had gone
and pinched almost all of the clues,
which meant we couldn't find the trail
and got completely lost.
It took quite a lot of lollies
to get us back in the mood for a party.
That's kind of how it feels
now that you're no longer here.
Life has become a treasure hunt,
but someone's taken away all the clues.
But luckily,
I've got some lovely people in my life
who lovingly push me
in the right direction from time to time.
Or they grab me by the collar
when I'm about to fall
into a deep pit of hyperventilation.
And it helps.
It really helps.
Other than that, I assume,
just like in the old days,
you'll be waiting for us
at the end of the treasure hunt
in your duffel coat
in the dark, dark woods by the tree
where the treasure's buried.
Well, that's it.
Sorry.
-I need to go.
I understand. It was wonderful,
really nice that you came,
on behalf of the others too.
I…
I think we should talk
about what's going on.
Because you were behaving
very strangely at the restaurant.
Yes.
It's good
that we're both moving on, isn't it?
Absolutely.
We can still be friends, right?
Otherwise, this whole treasure hunt
doesn't seem much fun anymore.
And we might as well forget
about the stupid treasure.
I don't think I can do it.
Do what?
Carry on the way it was.
I… I have to go.
I need to get to the studio.
Yeah, go.
This is it.
Well, for this season, anyway.
In the winter they'll give me
an equally practical,
slightly thicker weather-proof outfit.
Is it an option
for you not to work in our neighborhood,
but somewhere else instead?
-Have fun.
-Yeah. Good luck, Mom.
Do you need me to do it?
FRIENDS ARE SURE OF IT:
LYNN PREGNANT BY NEW COLLEAGUE
Hi, is your mom or dad at home?
-Mom.
-Coming.
Sorry.
I wanted to put this
through your mailbox,
but then it ripped.
-Who's that?
-No one, sweetie. Go and play.
I'm sorry about that,
and for…
-For the other thing.
-That and the other thing.
-Why are you angry with that lady?
-No reason, sweetie.
Well, I guess I'll be going then.
-Good idea. Kind regards.
-Mom…
Hang on a minute. That's my bracelet.
-Huh?
-Yes, that's my… That's my bracelet.
-Oh, really? Wow.
-Can I please have it back?
-It's mine, isn't it, Mom?
-No, it's mine.
My best friend gave it to me
and I'm very attached to it.
-Are you seriously going to cry now?
-It's mine.
Of course it's not yours.
Do you know what it says?
"From Tim, to my BFF."
Do you know anyone called Tim?
-It's mine.
-No, it's mine.
Get your hands off my child.
There, bitch. Take your damn bracelet.
Now get out of here.
-Cool outfit.
-I…
I'm not doing too great.
Well, actually, we're not doing great.
No.
Why didn't you call me back?
This new career opportunity
has been keeping me busy.
And to honest, I didn't feel like hearing
all your pink fluffy love child stories.
You don't believe all that stuff, do you?
I really think…
I really think
there are some things we need to discuss
if we want to stay friends…
-until death do us part, so to speak.
-Yes.
-But not right now.
-Why not?
It's not a good time.
Because…?
-Because I've got guests.
-Oh, OK.
Could we go and get a drink
round the corner instead then?
-Because I really wanted to…
-Now's not…
I just have to…
-I'll call you later, OK?
-Fine.
Whatever.com.
-Oh, you found it.
-Yes.
Darling, I don't feel very well.
Do you think
you could make dinner for you and Willem?
-Sure.
-I'm going to go lie down.
Mom, I'm home.
Mom. Mom.
Mom.
Mom?
She didn't wake up when I went in either.
Don't you think that's strange?
-Should I call Grandma? Or Tim?
-Yes. Call Tim.
Door?
Doortje?
I'm so cold.
-Could you fetch an extra blanket?
-Yeah.
-Dr. Schellekens is your doctor, right?
-Yes.
-There.
-I'll go.
Give her the first dose straight away.
You'll need to keep an eye on her tonight.
If something feels off, or her fever
gets worse, call an ambulance.
All the best.
Yeah?
How are you getting on
with your homework?
Not too bad.
OK. Well, sleep well.
Why are you and Mom fighting?
I…
Is it because you're having a baby
with Lynn?
We're not having a baby.
We barely know each other.
That's a relief.
I don't think you understand
how having kids works.
In what way?
Well, that it's strange
if to start with you're around a lot
for dinner and Saint Nicholas and stuff
and that it's really nice,
and then you have a great time
going camping together,
but then you suddenly disappear
and never get in touch anymore.
No…
I mean, yes.
I'm sorry.
OK.
Wim?
-Have you made a move yet?
-No.
My advice is, and it's probably best
you don't follow it,
because no one is better
at messing things up than me.
But in case you still want my advice,
then it would be this: Tell it like it is.
I think that's the least disastrous
of all the options.
-OK, sleep well.
-You too.
Sleep well, Door.
No.
Doortje?
Door.
Doortje.
I must look drop dead gorgeous right now.
Heidi Klum's got nothing on you.
-Did you sleep here?
-The doctor told me to keep an eye on you.
That's very sweet of you.
-I'm just keeping my cub scout's promise.
-You can…
You can count on me.
Willem was at my place
when you called round the other day.
That's why I couldn't let you in.
He wanted my advice.
He's in love with Janne
and he doesn't know
whether or not to tell her.
When he saw you at the door
he was worried you'd feel sidelined.
I'm just really happy
he talked to you about it.
Yeah.
I actually felt quite proud.
Tim, I…
Good morning, Ms. Dorenbos.
I've come to see how you're doing.
Hi, sweetheart.
-Quite a bit better, it would seem.
-Yes, much better.
Hi, love.
-Have you heard back yet?
-Yes. She didn't dare to say it either.
-What's going on?
-Nothing.
Thirty-seven point six. That's very good.
Make sure you finish the treatment
followed by a week of taking it very easy.
Understood?
I'll see you out.
My darlings. Eat your breakfast
and go to school. Chop, chop.
Off you go.
HOPEFULLY YOU LIKE THIS ONE TOO
-Hi.
-Hello, Mom.
-We'll try… We'll try…
-That's it.
To be honest, I miss print journalism.
I've got a meeting
with the newspaper next week.
I need to tell you something.
It's important.
I'm so sorry
I put off telling you for so long,
and that I totally overcomplicated it.
But I just didn't know how…
What I should…
And, honestly, I still don't know…
what the future looks like for us.
There's nothing I want more
than to make stupid jokes the whole time
and stay friends forever,
for Sien and Willem's sake too.
But I don't know how to anymore.
Because when I see you and Lynn together
or think about your being together
I turn into this great big,
green, humorless monster.
So, the children are going
to stay with Walter for a bit
and then I'm going camping
with them in England.
I hope that by the end of the summer,
I'll be able to behave normally to you,
and that we'll be able to have nice meals
together again like this evening.
But without having to suppress the urge
to press you up against the wall
and tear all your clothes off.
I'll see you in a couple of months, Tim.
Look after yourselves.
What now?
We're going to find a bus
to take us to the campsite.
FOLLOW THE RED RIBBONS
Follow the red ribbons.
I…
I'm not literature professor
and, if I'm being completely honest,
I'm not that keen on tea.
But I can't imagine anything better
than talking to you all day long
about daffodils and payment demands
and about savory snacks and Bake Off.
Because the thing is,
my dear, awkward best friend forever
that for a very long time, you have been,
and I'm talking about as far back
as when ABBA were still around,
you have been the greatest,
mail-delivering,
hyperventilating love of my life.
And all my tragic attempts
to get together with anyone else
or to throw myself into something
were desperate attempts
by this poor soul
to try to come to terms
with what I thought was
the bitter truth.
So, if you would be willing
in between all our civilized conversations
and all our attempts at creating
responsible parental structures
where I'm not trying
to be Willem and Sien's father,
but in which I make it clear to them
that I like them much more
than any love child…
If you would be prepared,
in between all of that,
to pin me against the wall
once in a while…
and tear the clothes of my body,
then I think I will have to be
very careful not to die of happiness.
I thought about arranging a horse
for us to climb onto and ride off on.
Maybe you should just shut your mouth.