Daniil? Hey, Daniil? Are there red horses?
When the sun sets on the earth,
it paints everything with its colour.
Then it makes not only horses red,
but people as well.
Our boys are clothed and fed, and what
will you clothe and feed them with?
They'll die of hunger with you.
Can you imagine what kind of a fate awaits them?
Children are our future, Father Nikolai.
It's too late to teach old men.
But we won't allow children to be
sent into some religious stupor.
That's how you see it.
By decision of the Regional Committee,
we will give your children an education.
We will teach them a profession.
If it were my decision,
I wouldn't give you the children.
These are dark times.
Are you afraid to go? Don't be afraid, Inokkenty.
You will see God's world, see the people in it.
You're probably tired of smelling incense?
Your felt boots have holes in them.
- Och!
Never mind, I'll get you new ones.
- And where will you get them?
They say you can find anything in the city.
M-yes!
With whom do I have the honour?
Chairman...
Of the People's Republic's Possessions, Kochi.
"Russia was created over centuries,
with sweat and blood...
Wherever we look, everywhere
we see the fruits of the hands of the working class.
The palaces of yesterday
have been returned to their rightful owners,
the victorious-revolutionary masses.
Every ancient monument, every work of art
with which the tsars and the rich
used to amuse themselves, has become ours.
We will not hand them over to anyone.
We will not hand them over to anybody,
and will preserve them for our descendants.
For the people who come
after us and want to know...
how and with what people lived before them.
The directive Committee of the
Soviet of Workers and Peasants' Deputies.
What's this, who's the lad...?
Intouriccio. If I'm not much mistaken.
It's the famous portrait of a boy
in blue from the Medici collection.
Prince Sergei acquired this
picture on his last trip to Italy
a year before the war.
A forgery?
My son didn't collect copies.
Well then, are you going to share
all this out between the proletariat and workers?
There's not enough for everyone, my friend!
- You shouldn't say things like that, old lady.
- Comrade Petrovych
Don't worry, Elena Konstantinovna.
We well understand
what artistic treasures we are dealing with.
Your son's collection will be transferred
intact to the Petrograd State Museum.
By decision of the Soviet of People's Commissars,
signed by Lenin.
His lmperial Majesty, hurray! Hurray! Hurray!
Hurray! Hurray!
- I'll tear your guts out!
- Hurray! Hurray!
It's lucky for you that you're a bird! If you
were a person, I'd give you a good kicking!
Lagutin's bandits! Bandits!
Stop! Stop!
Faster!
Go round her! Go round!
Heads down!
Comrades, run for it, I'll hold them back! I'll hold them!
Alyoshka! Shurka! Where are you going?
Guys, there's a station here, lots of trains!
Who's a counter-revolutionary?
I'm a counter-revolutionary?
I'm telling you, I'm taking the
Tikhvinskis' possessions to Petrograd!
- Hold him, guys,
- Bring him over here!
I'm telling you!
I'm taking the possessions of Prince Tikhvinski...
Which have been confiscated by the revolutionary forces.
Take him to Strunnik, to Strunnik!
Let's go!
I'll give you one, you counter-revolutionary scum!
- We've caught one!
- Who is it?
Here we are, defending the republic,
and this here lackey of some sort of prince...
is taking a load of golden knick-knacks to Petrograd!
- What's going on?
- Defending the rights of the aristocracy!
- Lackey!
- Me?
- You!
You!
- I - a sailor of the revolution in the Baltic
- A lackey?
Who are you, then?
Alright! Load his boxes, bring horses!
Let go! Read this!
Listen, sailor, the republic's in danger!
I have a stamp from the Soviet of People's
Deputies! Or can't you see?
Or perhaps you're illiterate?
"Russia was created over centuries,
with sweat and blood...
The palaces and mansions of the princes are now ours!
The rarity that I am transporting
in these boxes, art, is also ours!
- Hurray!
Well sailor, make sure it gets there
Could you tell me, Comrade Director...
the approximate price of this
collection in gold rubles?
I couldn't even give you an approximate estimate.
This collection, built up by the Tikhvinski Princes...
Over almost two centuries, has practically no price.
It is priceless!
For instance, number 67... Penturiccio, Boy in Blue.
Come along, come along, come along. Come!
Here's what I'm talking about.
Penturiccio, Boy in Blue.
In 1582, the Duke of Milan paid for it with gold coins...
placed two deep over the
entire surface of the painting.
Penturiccio, Boy in Blue.
Would you be so kind as to open the fifth box.
This one. Only carefully, for God's sake, carefully!
Now you will see this masterpiece... Penturiccio!
This is a mistake! This can't be! It can't be!
Open another!
Open it! Open it! Open it! Quickly and carefully!
Witness statements regarding the case of the
theft of the collection of art treasures...
requisitioned from the former Prince Tikhvinski.
Chairman of the People's Commissariat
for the Possessions of the Republic, Kochin:
I went to the front...
and assigned the sailor Petrovych
to transport the collection to Petrograd.
Sailor Petrovych of the Cruiser 'Onega'.
I packed the boxes with my own hands,
and transported them myself to the museum.
Kuzavlyova, companion of the old Princess.
The princess fell ill, and I did not leave her bedside.
I cannot testify anything in this case.
Former Estate Manager Tarakanov.
I helped pack the collection in the boxes.
From the estate, the collection
was sent intact and preserved.
Carpenter Yegor Dmitrievitch Buketov.
They told me to knock some
boxes together, and I did so.
That's all we know,
we weren't interested after that.
Inspection of the estate
and townhouse of Prince Tikhvinski...
has yielded no results.
The case is closed, it must be assumed...
that the collection has been lost
forever for Soviet Russia!
We will burn all the bourgeoisie in a global fire!
- Fan the flames!
- Hurray! Hurray!
What's this? Let me past! Let me past!
Let me past, I tell you! What is this?
Let me past! What are you doing?
What are you doing?
Give me that! Give me that!
Give me that, take my life, money, everything!
Thieves! Robbery!
This is a picture from the Tikhvinski collection!
Some hooligans stole it from a passer-by.
We detained them.
It would have been better
if you'd detained the passer-by.
They say he was a weasly type
in dark glasses, wearing a bowler-hat.
So the collection's not lost.
I can't even imagine who to assign this case to.
We're talking about priceless works of art...
which could turn out to be abroad.
If you fail to catch a profiteer or two...
it won't be as harmful to Russia
as the loss of these treasures...
belonging to the people.
Who to assign this case to?
I have one new recruit, he's just been demobilised.
Of course, he doesn't have
any experience of our work yet.
But he's conscientious and bright.
He's also looking for works of art just now.
Bronze candlesticks were stolen
from a famous artist.
I'll try assigning him.
Makar Ovchinnikov.
But we have to start...
with a thorough inspection of the
country mansion of this prince.
So! You've searched the attic?
Yes, we've looked everywhere.
You've tapped the walls, looked in the cellar?
Yes, I tell you, we looked everywhere.
- I even put guards on the doors.
- You didn't look well enough.
Boxes can't disappear into the ground.
They're here somewhere.
Nothing.
You should interrogate the carpenter, Dmitrich.
He put the boxes together.
Maybe he knows something.
- You Dmitrich isn't here.
- What do you mean, not here?
They killed Dmitrich!
- Ours?
- No
- The Whites?
- No.
- Who?
- Bandits, Lagutin's lot.
Well, have you seen the old woman, the princess?
Your old woman died of typhus last year.
Have you interrogated Tarakanov?
Tarakanov, Tarakanov!
Where will you find Tarakanov now?
False boxes arrive in Petrograd.
And the real collection was taken
from the estate and hidden in another place.
Are you sure it's not at the prince's estate?
Sure! I've searched every corner,
knocked every brick.
They've taken and hidden it so you'll never find it.
Who's hidden it?
The former manager of the
prince's estate, Tarakanov.
- Tarakanov?
- Well, yes.
Because the person who the muggers
stole the picture from...
is Tarakanov, according to their description.
Hi.
I have 13 Tarakanovs here.
If you please!
Right.
Bring him in.
Right, stand up. This one?
I told you, Comrade Boss. It was dark there.
We don't work during the day.
What are you saying? Boss, boss...
The third year of the revolution,
you should be free of this slavish mentality.
Sit. This one?
- Yes.
- Stand!
No. The other was a bit taller.
Wait, wait, you said he was a little weasly type?
You're the boss... you know best.
- This one?
- No, the other one
was wearing a cap and glasses.
- You said a hat?
- No, glasses, definitely glasses.
You know best, you're the boss.
What are you going on about. Boss, boss...
Right, next. This one? Stand! This one?
- No. It's him.
- Definitely?
- Definitely, it's him!
- What makes you think so?
The other one was also wearing galoshes.
Tsits!
Half of Petrograd wears galoshes,
every second person.
You're the boss, you know best.
That's all, take him away!
Right, Makar, enough playing the goat.
There is a man in Petrograd who can help us.
A renowned criminologist,
and a great art aficionado, to boot.
- You mean Dobrovo?
- Yes.
Prokofiy Filippovitch Dobrovo.
Prokofiy Filippovitch, we really, really beg you.
You beg in vain, Mister Makar.
Firstly!
Using your terminology, I am a police dog.
And to have dealings with you,
a representative of the revolutionary proletariat...
wouldn't be wise.
- Prokofiy Filippovitch!
- There you are.
Excuse me, Prokofiy Filippovitch,
but for me you are, let me say, ...
Secondly!
Who needs this collection now,
if Russia is going to the Tatars.
- How can you say that.
- And thirdly.
You expressed here, in plain words,
that I will receive a ration from you.
Remember this, Mister Ovchinnikov.
Dobrovo is not for sale, not even for a ration.
Prokofiy Filippovitch,
you are a renowned specialist in your field.
- You are an experienced detective.
- I am not a detective.
- I am a criminologist.
- That's what I meant.
The most respected lawyers
in Russia used to come to this study.
I was invited as a consultant to Paris,
Amsterdam, Venice.
- There you go!
- I see.
You mean to say that without
you we won't cope with this case.
Yes, you have experience, knowledge,
that's true. I don't have them.
But I give you my word, Mister Dobrovo.
I will find this collection, I'll find it even if devils took it.
I've received a letter from Paris.
Sergei Sanytch has indicated you as being a person...
who can transport some of his
possessions across the border.
I don't want to get into trouble
with the Soviet authorities.
And what is it that you want
to transport across the cordon?
- Some sculptures, pictures.
- Many?
No, a few boxes. Which will fit into one cart.
And the Bronze Horseman,
you're not going to send that to Paris?
No, we'll leave the Bronze Horseman where it is.
And if I refuse?
Don't refuse. You owe too much to the prince.
That's one.
Secondly, you won't be very pleased...
if the Bolshevik's find out that
the flight of the prince and his family...
was organised by you, Mister Shilovski.
No need. There's no need to frighten me,
llya Spiridonovitch.
I'm not afraid of anyone,
not you, not God, not the devil.
But... I'll help the prince.
I wouldn't like his treasures to be looted.
Citizens of Soviet Russia,
the revolution has liberated you.
From the tsar,
the landowners and the capitalists.
I will liberate you from the slavery of things.
What does a worker need with these objects of luxury?
Yesterday these things enriched your lives.
Today they have become stones
around the neck of the working person.
Bring these stones here,
and you will receive millions for them.
Oh! This piece of junk was made
in Belgium a hundred years ago.
May I?
What do you need it for?
I will liberate you from it.
- Be careful! I think it's loaded!
- Pardon!
Ah! A criminal, I'll show you!
Help me, he's stolen my new nightdress.
- Call the guard!
- Run! Run, I tell you.
- Achmed!
- There's the little imp!
- You won't get away now!
- Why are you feeling sorry for him?
A rotten criminal, box his ears.
Hold him tight, I'll give him a hiding.
Let the boy go.
Let me go, mister,
they're telling you to let me go!
- What do you mean, mister!
- Let me go!
I'll rip your ears off.
Let me go, let me go, let me go.
I'll shoot.
Little imp!
I told you it was loaded.
- Who are you?
- Me?
Just call me...
'the Marquis'.
The sword's ring is like the ring of a glass...
The sound has caressed me since childhood...
The sword has shown
a great many what it's all about!
Dzing, dzing, dzing - take away the old one...
Dzing, dzing, dzing... bring in a new one!
Come up closer, come up closer...
I'll teach you a thing or two...
I can see right through scoundrels...
When I run them right through.
Dzing, dzing, dzing - take away the old one...
Dzing, dzing, dzing... bring in a new one,
In dangerous situations it's as difficult as war...
And maybe someone soon will...
Say the last rites over me!
Dzing, dzing, dzing - take away the old one...
Dzing, dzing, dzing... bring in a new one!
- Uncle, do you have any felt boots?
- Felt boots? It's summer.
- Not for me, for Daniil!
- Yes he can have some felt boots.
Young friend, in open battle prepare to defend your honour.
And with a good old-fashioned weapon
take your sweet revenge!
Dzing, dzing, dzing - take away the old one...
Dzing, dzing, dzing... bring in a new one!
Ach, people these days are feeble,
why fight with such as they!
I'd be better testing my strength...
On the devil, damn it all.
Dzing, dzing, dzing - take away the old one...
Dzing, dzing, dzing... bring in a new one!
- Bravo!
- Hello there, llya Spiridonovitch!
- So it seems you've found a boy?
- Yes!
Meet Father Innokentiy!
- Get in!
- I won't!
Get in, I say.
Why do I have to get into a fireplace?
Well?
Find the wheel. No, to the side, to the side.
Found it?
- Found it.
- Turn it to the right.
A safe little place!
The whole house was rifled through,
but they never got in here. Go in!
You, get lost!
What!?
Right.
- There.
- What's that?
Pegasus... the winged horse of inspiration.
And all that's left of the collection
of Prince Tikhvinski.
Stop joking, Shilovski!
- Borzhomski!
- Yakov Nikolayevitch.
I've found you a groom.
Put him in a camisole, make him into an
African and put him on the footboard.
Right away.
Let's go.
Ilya Spiridonovitch, there's nothing
left for us to do in this house.
We're gawking at them shooting a film.
Isn't it a bit risky?
Don't worry, apart from filming,
they're not interested in anything.
How he stands, very convincing.
Borzhomski, put a camisole on him.
You. You in the bowler, you will open the door.
What right do you have?
Let's give a few instants
of our lives to the great Silents!
He'll be ready in just a second.
Oh my God, what is that!
Ready! Start the carriage! Camera!
Thank you everyone for a fine shot!
Shooting is over!
Come here. Come to the film studio tomorrow,
I'm shooting a new film.
'The Rubber Boy'.
You will play the main role, understand?
- Bye.
- Come.
- Here, take this.
- Let's go, step on it!
Please come. Goodbye!
Well, llya Spiridonovitch, c'est tout, I'm free.
No, Shilovski, not so fast.
- But all the leads have disappeared without a trace.
- Not all.
What do you intend to do?
Firstly, we will put your boy...
In the 'Paris Commune' orphanage.
No dawdling, hurry.
- Innokentiy, where are you going?
- I'll be right back.
Don't be late.
Uncle Marquis!
How are you? Hi!
How's things, Father Innokentiy?
Yes?!
At twelve on the dot, when everyone's asleep,
go down to the cellar. Here's the key.
Find a trapdoor. Climb down the ladder.
You'll see boxes there. Lots of boxes.
And at the top, under the ceiling, a door.
I'll be waiting behind it.
- Yes.
- Don't forget, twelve on the dot.
Uh-huh.
I'll be waiting.
'Amour and Psychia'... a picture from
the collection of the former Prince Tikhvinski.
Extraordinarily characteristic
of the master's painting style.
Notice the bold artistic modelling.
And the warm, rich colours.
And now let us proceed to the next room.
Where you will acquaint yourselves
with the art of the Great French Revolution.
Excuse me, if I detain you for a minute.
Are you sure this painting is the right one?
From the Tikhvinski collection?
Undoubtedly!
A whole range of things confirms its authenticity.
- The family coat-of-arms, for instance.
- I see. Excuse me.
Carry on, comrades, carry on!
The Tikhvinski coat-of-arms
is on the other side of the canvas.
Please show me the other side of the canvas.
That's impossible! It can only be done
with the permission of the director.
I'm from Criminal Investigations.
- My God!
- Right!
What are you doing?
Are you sure that this coat-of-arms
is that of the Tikhvinskis?
- Undoubtedly.
- Yeah.
It's high time to throw these pictures in the bin...
It's forbidden to work here at night.
You'll wake the children.
The children ran about so much today,
they wouldn't wake up them with a cannon.
And if you drop the bucket? There, you see.
Listen, why don't you go to sleep. Go on.
Could you speak a little
more politely with me.
- The children will hear. It sets a bad example.
- Go away.
Go away, dear lady, don't bother me.
- What's your name?
- Anna Sviridovna.
- I see, Nyura.
- Not Nyura, Anyuta.
I see, Nyusha.
Good night, Nyusha!
The monk? What's he doing here?
Who the hell knows?
What? Empty?
Not empty. Look, felt boots.
Felt boots?
Mister, mister! A ghost!
What? Where's a ghost?
In the cellar, the lower one.
Ssh! Sh! Enough. Let's go.
So, Father Innokentiy, you won't see me again.
Live in your home
'The Paris Commune' and be happy.
- Are you going away?
- No.
I'm just afraid you'll disappear with me.
Especially as I don't know
what will happen to me tomorrow.
- Where did you get to, Monk?
- What's it to you?
Lanky told us to tell you
to be at the cemetery tomorrow.
- What for?
- We've decided to scram to the Crimea.
Why the Crimea?
Lanky said it was warm there,
with apples. The good life!
- And why the cemetery?
- We need to lay in some grub for the journey.
Lanky says that if you rummage about in the crypts...
you can find a lot of good junk to sell.
- What kind of junk in the cemetery?
- What kind of junk?!
They say they only buried counts
and princes in our cemetery.
Very rich graves.
Hard-man, have a look at this! Come here!
Eagles, look!
Over here!
Wow!
Let's go to the fleamarket. Change it for bread.
Doughball, look at the picture I found!
Wow! Excellent!
Ya Beauty!
Shall we take it to the fleamarket?
A clock? We can take a clock!
They give a lot of bread for clocks.
- A knight!
- No! It's Yegoriy the Conqueror.
Unique jewel-encrusted clock,
by a 19th century Swiss master.
Claude. Claude Chefois.
Crutch mechanism with month hand.
- Well, it was worth us coming here, Alyona.
...Playing original music.
Valued at 7 million.
7 million once!
7 million twice!
7 million thrice! Taken from sale!
Disgraceful!
- Excuse me, madam.
- What is it?
- You are the owner of that clock?
- I am. What's the matter?
- Madam, the clock is stolen.
- I don't know, I bought it at the market!
Forgive my importunity, madam. From whom?
What, is it yours?
No, but I am acquainted with it,
I cannot lie, forty years.
Hm. Forty. Forty, forty years ago I wasn't even alive.
I bought them at the Haymarket!
From street-urchins! Pardon!
Gravy-boat.
Alyona, who now lives at the
former residence of the Tikhvinskis?
It's an orphanage.
Valued at 2 million rubles.
The collection was kept in a secret place,
behind the fireplace, in case of danger.
Mitrich had to take it to the prince's town-house.
- To that same cellar.
- Yes, but the cellar's empty.
And you must admit, llya Sviridonovitch...
the funeral march does sound a bit symbolic.
When did they kill this Mitrich of yours?
The devil only knows!
The last time he came to
Petrograd was to bury the old Princess.
Tell me, where did the Tikhvinskis bury their dead?
- I thought bandits had killed you.
- Alive, thank God!
Scoundrel.
Wait for me to catch up, Mitrich!
It was terrible on my own!
First from the estate to the cellar, and then
from the cellar on my hunched back.
Don't moan, you'll get your cut!
I endured such fear, God forbid!
Luckily no one asked.
And stiffs all around.
You, Monsieur Bouket, are ungrateful to the dead!
They happen to provide you with your daily bread.
- Come on, help me.
- Careful.
- Got it!
- That's that then.
Careful, gentlemen! Careful, careful!
These are valuable things!
- Gentlemen! Careful!
- Thanks!
Mitrich, you will stay here!
- Don't ruin me!
llya Sviridonovitch, take me with you!
You'll stay here...
so as not to alarm anyone by your disappearance.
Mitrich, my dear, be patient, for a few days.
I'm afraid, God, I'm afraid.
Never mind! You'll catch us up
in the village of Grand Pumps.
Come on, come on, come on!
More more, more, more!
Doughball! What's in the sack?
I asked you, what's in the sack?
Have you stolen something again?
What have you stolen, do you hear?
We didn't steal it, we bought it, we bought bread.
- Bread? What with?
- We flogged a clock.
- What, the clock from the second floor?
- No, from the tomb.
- The tomb?
- Oh Lord!
- A big clock, with knights.
- From what tomb?
The one with the Prince, general Ansher.
Anshev.
There's a coat-of-arms there, like on our house.
Who has come visiting here recently?
- Apart from boys, no one.
- Absolutely no one?
We live in the cemetery, sir.
So if anyone came visiting,
we wouldn't let them in.
You needn't do that, sir.
I've been paid up front for the maintenance.
Until March 1925.
- What was the cart that came past here?
- That was me, sir, bringing sand.
- Sand?
- Yes.
So, sir, if you need anything, we're always here.
Ask for Bouket, everyone knows me.
- Prokofiy Filippovitch, I've been thinking.
- I've also been thinking!
But you and I have been beaten, alas!
Only yesterday, the Tikhvinski collection was here.
You see these tracks,
perhaps they will lead you somewhere.
I suggest using diplomatic channels...
for the transfer of the cargo.
We have such a capability.
Diplomatic baggage is not subjected to scrutiny.
And will you also send me by
diplomatic post, in an envelope?
- I don't understand you.
- But I understand you perfectly.
You will receive money,
lots of money, hard currency!
I don't need you hard currency here,
I'll bring the collection myself.
You are putting yourself and a valuable cargo at risk.
But I will be sure that I won't be cheated.
- Out the way!
- What's all this?
What's all this? Why are you running?
Lads, where are you going?
- To the Crimea
- What for?
It's warm and there are apples.
Wait! Lads! Lads! Wait, let's talk!
Where's the governess?
Boys, boys! Please wait!
Boys, where are you going?
Oh, please, please help me!
lbeg you to stop them!
You couldn't even catch that little one,
and there are so many.
Goodbye, orphanage!
Spiridonovna, goodbye! Be healthy!
Step on it, brother, follow that tram!
Faster, brother, faster!
I'm not made for this work, I'm not made for it.
I was so kind to them,
and they run away to the Crimea!
It's warm there, there's apples!
- Faster!
- Careful!
Go on!
His lmperial Majesty! Hurray!
He'll be the ruin of us! Wring his neck!
One hundred years you've
been saying the same thing.
It's time to think up something new.
Say: "Tarakanov... hurray"!
- What are you teaching the bird?
- Tarakanov... hurray!
Don't worry!
lt'll take him another 200 years to learn your name.
- Tarakanov... hurray! Hurray... Tarakanov!
- Hurray!
Stop it!
His lmperial Majesty... hurray! Hurray!
Lord! Such an inhuman voice.
Not at all, it's very human.
Counter-revolutionaries sailing by.
- His lmperial Majesty... hurray! Hurray! Hurray!
- I should remember the number. 777.
Apart from the individuals you have named,
who else was present at the estate?
What are you on at me for? Who-who?
There was a parrot present there as well!
Stop acting the fool! What kind of parrot?
I'm telling you, there was a parrot.
The old dead princess said he was 200 years old.
And I just about gave him a kicking in!
What for?
For putting out monarchic propaganda!
His lmperial Majesty, may he rot...
hurray!! - Shouting like he's at meeting.
- You're not lying, Petrovych?
- My word of honour!
I'll remember that parrot 'til I die.
"His lmperial Majesty", he says, "Hurray!"
- Barge 777 is yours?
- Ours, Petrogartopskaya.
- What the hell do you need with it?
- Where is it?
What will be will be, Let fate be the judge.
In this gentle silence, All else is
fuss and noise, as tramp and a fighter...
I've travelled half the world, but I go
down on my knees before my city...
I don't know whether you've heard,
that I sing for the loveliest of ladies...
But I've died of boredom with them...
And this city is my sweetheart,
because I'm never bored with her...
And God forbid, God forbid we
should ever be parted.
I don't know whether you've heard,
that I've roamed from city to city...
And never had refuge or shelter,
But I always returned, as to my home,
to the beauty between the sky and the Neva.
And God forbid, God forbid I ever have other.
I don't know whether you've heard,
That I never complained when in trouble...
But sometimes in my hardest years...
This city looked after me, And to do her harm...
God forbid...
God forbid I ever do so.
Farewell, llya Sviridonovitch! I'm leaving you.
I'm sick of your jokes, Shilovski!
I'm not joking!
I'm staying in Petrograd, I'm out of the game.
What? You promised! You gave your word.
You said you'd transport my
boxes across the border.
- Your boxes?
- Yeah.
- Are they yours?
- Don't try to catch me out, Shilovski.
Hands off!
- You misunderstood me.
- I understood you correctly.
But you've convinced me, I'll stay.
I'll escort your boxes to the Prince.
I really wouldn't like them to stay with you. Let go!
You women, dressed in pearls and diamonds,
At the same time as our people struggle and suffer.
Be silent, you madman!
Who painted over the number?
There was a number when
the barge was berthed here.
What was the number?
- Vanka!
- What?
What was the number of the barge?
777! Can't you see for yourself?
There isn't a number, someone's covered it up.
Tarakanov... hurray!
Why have you gone quiet? Say something!
- Tarakanov... hurray!
- What?
Tarakanov... hurray!
Hurray Tarakanov. What a good goose.
And it didn't stop anywhere on the way?
Didn't stop anywhere?
Two people boarded in Mikhailovka
at night with a cargo.
- What kind of cargo? What kind of people?
- People, just people, that kind of people.
And the cargo... boxes, ordinary boxes.
See how I'm writing with a stump!
You're from Petrograd, why don't you
tell them we've nothing to write with.
Wait, the number of the train is 569, and then what?
Station of destination... Izgorsk, boxes to store 21.
- You see the paper we have...
- I see, I see!
- There's nothing to see...
- Wait, wait!
- What's this?
- You're from Petrograd! You should tell them there!
Oh come on, don't be like that.
- So, what else?
- Boxes!
- Right.
- Boxes all night.
- I see!
- Boxes all night! Just boxes!
And here, stations of destination
Kandalaksha and Gdov. What's that?
Boxes!
Inspection of boxes in Kandalaksha
and Gdov yielded no results.
- I didn't get it.
- No results.
Right. I personally permit
you to continue the search.
Leave immediately for lzgorsk.
- Go!
- I'm not going!
- I'm not going, I've got weak hands!
- Go, I say!
- I'm not going!
Alright, I'll go!
Guard, thieves!
Come here!
Let me go, mister, let me go! Let me go, I say!
Alright.
- Where are you from?
- From there.
- Outside.
- Alone?
Alone.
Smart.
Couldn't you get a lighter sack?
There you go.
Where are you going?
- Crimea.
- What for?
It's warm there, there's apples.
So, you're from Petrograd?
From the 'Paris Commune' Orphanage?
How do you know that, mister?
I know everything,
I've been watching you a long time.
Are you going to take me back to Petrograd?
lzgorsk!
Fire! We're on fire, brothers, we're on fire!
What are you waiting for?
Get buckets, pots, pans, follow me!
Let's get out of here, lads.
Citizens, what are you looking at? The treasures
of the Republic are burning before your eyes!
- Stationmaster!
- What the... what's wrong?
Where's the cargo from Mikhailovka stored?
From Mikhailovka? There, in the third sector.
Right. Comrades! There's sculptures,
paintings, our treasure.
Save them.
Bring water, quickly!
Feldsher! Feldsher!
Uncle Makar, Uncle Makar, are you alive?
It's all burnt. The collection is lost.
Alyona, is that face familiar to you?
I think he taught fencing
to Prince Tikhvinski's children.
If you would be so kind.
Cut off a few frames for me, please.
This one, this one, and this one.
No, Carl Genrikhovitch, you misunderstood me.
I'm not going to work for you.
I'm too old to start a new life.
It's simply that I don't want Russia...
to lose the unique collection of the Tikhvinskis.
It's lost, Prokofiy Filippovitch, it's been burnt.
Burnt?
In a fire at lzgorsk railway station, burnt to the ground.
- The evidence has been confirmed?
- Absolutely.
The warehouse burnt down, and everything in it.
- Hi.
- Still climbing through windows?
- They won't let me in the door.
- Where did you get that?
I won't eat stolen goods.
- Did you give me money?
- I don't need anything.
If you don't eat, you'll fade away.
- What did you do with my felt boots?
- Your felt boots are in the nurses cupboard.
- Are you really going to be a thief when you grow up?
- No, I'm going to be an icon painter.
- An icon painter.
- Yes, like Cross-eyed Daniil.
How many times do you have
to be told, God doesn't exist.
Yes, I've heard, but icons exist.
They gave Daniil Cross-eyed
a sack of potatoes for one icon.
- Eat a potato, go on.
- Thanks.
Uncle Makar, look outside, it's good.
Yes, beautiful! There's something to go back to.
We'll put an end to all the bad things...
and we'll build such things here, you can't imagine.
I can, Uncle Makar.
We need to build factories,
Innokentiy, and power-stations.
And we'll all ride on horses.
No, in airplanes, and steeds,
singing revolutionary songs.
Try some, try some. Get lost, you!
Oh, you little thief.
You little devil. Grab him!
- Get him, get him!
- Thief!
- Get a bit of your apple?
- Let me go, mister!
Uncle Marquis!
Hi!
- You recognise me, Father Innokentiy?
- Uh-huh.
Where are you heading? From Vologda to Kerch?
- No, Crimea.
- I see.
- And what haven't you seen there?
- Tit's warm there, there's apples.
Thanks.
You're not going to Crimea, you're coming with me.
- No, I'm not going to look for boxes.
- What boxes, there aren't any boxes.
They were burnt.
See that hut, that's where they burnt.
The collection wasn't in
the warehouse at the time.
But at the time of the fire, in so to speak,
a moment of emotion...
you may not have understood that.
If it had burnt in the warehouse, then...
Firstly, there would have
been some porcelain, marble objects.
So...
Yes.
Of course.
Secondly,
The bronze figure of Voltaire couldn't have burnt.
Yes, the work of the French sculptor Goudon.
A smaller version.
Oh, it appears you are a fine art scholar.
No, I just learned the
collection catalogue off by heart.
This work is listed as number 129 in it.
So, number 129 couldn't burn.
Yes, yes, yes, yes.
So just the warehouse burnt down.
They covered their tracks, the swine.
Well, we don't know that.
Perhaps they were just lucky.
And the warehouse really
was burnt down by Lagutin's gang.
What will we do now?
First of all, if your doctors permit...
They will...
This evening you will go to the
final performance of the circus.
I will keep you company.
Revolutionary pantomime.
The liberation of labour.
The red flag is flying, many songs and flowers,
The eyes of the sons of the
Republic are shining with joy.
The enigmatic mysteries of the East. Ali-bat.
Well? Ready!
The one-armed William Tell!
A death-defying act!
The management asks people with
a nervous disposition to leave the circus.
Lord have mercy, Lord have mercy!
What a guy! William, yeah? Give us a shot.
Granny, give me a blindfold.
Tie it, tie it, you'll get your
Scarf back.
Alright, let's say I go with you.
What part do I get to play?
Part? Will we take him?
Like today, you come out of the
audience in your own clothes.
- Why, why?
- What, then?
Alright, do you want to wear
a sailor's outfit for effect?
Alright, I agree.
Makar has gone off with the circus.
It's a dangerous situation, especially if we consider
that Lagutin's gang is armed.
Where's the circus headed?
I'll make inquiries.
So, if the circus is headed for the border,
then it can be assumed
that the collection is going with it.
Bulatov, leave for lgorsk tonight.
- Contact the military there.
- Yes, sir.
- Follow Makar.
- Yeah. I will.
Tarakanov locks his caravan very securely.
What's he got there? What's he hiding?
- What's he got? The money.
- Money. He gave out the money yesterday.
How come you notice everything, Makar?
I'll catch up with you in the village of 'Big Pumps'.
As we agreed with Mitich, he'll hide you until I arrive.
But don't you think about talking him...
into crossing the border without me.
- You still don't trust me, Shilovski.
- Come on, llya Spiridonovitch.
Until you can do without me, I trust you implicitly.
Leave the boy, your assistant.
No, no, I'm not leaving Innokentiy.
You take him with you.
I don't understand, what the
hell do you need with that puppy?
I love him.
You wouldn't understand that, Tarakanov.
- You're nervous?
- I'm cool as a cucumber.
So I see.
Makar, your proletarian instinct hasn't misled you.
Tarakanov really is a swindler.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
- You know what he's hiding?
- What?
Sunflower seeds.
- Sunflower seeds?
- Yeah.
Ten sacks of sunflower seeds.
- Ten sacks?
- Yup.
That's a lot.
But I don't see Tarakanov's caravan.
What's the matter, Makar?
Wait.
I don't want to! What are you doing,
llya Spiridonovitch!
I don't want to, let me go,
llya Spiridonovitch, I'll tell Makar!
Let me go, llya Spiridonovitch,
I don't want to, let me go I say!
Let me go llya Spiridonovitch,
let me go, I don't want to.
Let me go I say! Let me go,
llya Spiridonovitch! I'll tell Makar!
- What's the matter, Makar?
- I've decided to water the horses.
You can't water the horses in the road.
Be a good fellow, keep going.
Drop your weapon.
You're right, I'm too good a shot.
Go away.
Stop.
Stop!
Uncle Makar, Uncle Makar, I'm here.
Uncle Makar, I'm in the caravan.
I'm in the caravan, quickly.
Stop, Tarakanov, stop, or I'll shoot!
Stop, or I'll shoot!
Uncle Makar, my leg's stuck, my leg's stuck.
- My leg's stuck, Uncle Makar!
- Hold on.
You're alive!
Beautiful!
- You like it?
- Uh-huh.
This is number 67, Pinturiccio, 'Boy in Blue'.
He must be 500 years old, but it's as if he's alive.
Don't worry, gentlemen, you're coming with us.
- Trofimitch, let's ride! We're off!
- Get down.
Hide!
Let's go! Come on, come on, faster!
Take it to the Ataman, to Lagutin.
7, 74, 35.
Where, my good man, did you steal such treasures?
I didn't steal them.
They're treasures of the Republic.
69, 9, 77. What Republic would that be, hm?
The Soviet Republic of Workers and Peasants.
21, 15,
48, 31.
- You're a commissar?
- No.
A Bolshevik?
Uh-huh.
- Scum!
- 22!
59, 37...
5. Gentlemen... House!
Do you want to live?
Can you imagine, I don't.
I'm fed up.
I'm bored.
But what injustice there is in the world.
You want to live, but you won't.
And I don't want to, but I will.
I will strike you off the list of the living in this world...
As a member of the Communist Party.
You're lucky. I'll give you another 24 hours.
Take him to the church.
He'll have time to ponder his immortal soul there.
I answered her: "madam, what
is left you can have, don't be picky.
Arms and legs, as I said, all that's
left is my head, and that's tricky.
Luli-luli, oli-boli, without my
one and only, willy-nilly'.
I'll lie down here at last,
and tell you of my past, it's just silly.
- Close the gates!
- Hold him.
Get out of here fast, scumbag,
quickly, before they kill you.
Ballerina, semolina, oh it's such a shame,
Katerina or Marina,
I've forgotten my wife's name.
She said, he's vertically disabled
- But just one member's really needed.
- Get the legless cripple!
- You're not getting away!
- The gate's closed.
Jump down, come here, mate.
Show your documents.
The documents ran away with
the cashier and the money.
- Where's your William tell?
- He ran off with Tarakanov.
- Where to?
- He took a horse off me and rode off.
In what direction?
- The one with the caravan?
- Yes!
The Lagutin gang came and
took them to the monastery.
Right, bring all your performers to me.
I have a serious job for you.
Will you help me to beat the
bandits in the monastery?
- Father Innokentiy! Hello there!
- Uncle Marquis!
- How are you?
Bonjour, Monsieur Makar!
We're keeping each other company again!
- I don't keep scum company.
- Scum?
Let's not quarrel before death!
Until my death and after my death
I will call you scum.
Who are you fighting for?
You go down on your knees
for emigrants and the global bourgeoisie.
Enough!
I'll tell you the truth. I don't have
anything to do with the global bourgeoisie.
I simply want to preserve for our descendants...
All these knick-knacks that
you and I are fighting about.
You're lying! Who were you fighting for? For him?
There's our descendant, you were
fighting for him? No other moves?
Hey, who's there? Pass up my brush.
Daniil?
Daniil, I got hold of some felt boots for you.
- Innokentiy! Is it really you?
- It's me, it's me!
- The boots are almost new!
- Thank you, kind soul!
My legs, Innokentiy, don't want to go at all.
- You haven't forgotten how to grind colours?
- No?
Yes, it's funny how my life turned out.
I had a scholarship to the Academy of Arts.
They sent me to Italy on the public purse.
I was a hunter, a circus performer.
A chariot-driver at the hippodrome.
I was a pilot, and then an
educator of aristocrats, children.
Even a photographer, but never an artist!
You didn't have any real aims.
- And do you?
- I do!
I live for the revolution,
for the bright future of all mankind.
So that this lad here... ach!
If I escape the bullet, take my word for it.
Innokentiy will be a revolutionary artist.
- But you and I won't live to see it.
- We'll see, we'll see!
And I warn you, just in case,
you won't escape a revolutionary court.
I agree!
I trust that a proletarian court will
be more humane than Lagutin's.
Do you think there's a possibility, Makar...
That some of your lot know that you're here?
What's it to you?
Since the bandits are destroying,
looting and plundering everything.
- Are you coming round or pretending?
- Let's say I've come round.
The circus is coming! Open the gates!
Well then, you're ready, I hope?
My dear sir, my people say
that they saw you in the circus.
It seems you demonstrated fantastic marksmanship?
In a William Tell outfit.
That's right! ...He's the one!
Kolya, untie him.
I offer you a little amusement. In this
barrel there are seven bullets.
lf, with these seven bullets, you shoot
off the heads of these seven Terpsichores...
I will leave you on the list of the living in this world.
And even set you free wherever you wish to go.
I don't shoot women!
You're an educated man!
To destroy a work of art is barbaric, in my view!
You are mistaken, dear sir.
There is no sweeter pleasure for an intelligent man...
Than to destroy a world masterpiece!
To destroy, and I also know simple people.
Brothers! Do you need these stone women?
Or do you need healthy, hard-working, living girls?
Choose, dear sir, either you shoot, or I do.
Of course, I shoot worse than you do.
But all the same, I'm sure that
at least one of these seven bullets...
At this distance is enough for me to
splatter your brains all over.
I'll count to three. One! Two!
- Alright! I agree! You swine!
- It's the people's treasure!
A death-defying act!
Members of the audience with a nervous
disposition, please leave the circus!
Hands up! Come on!
Hey guys, he's out of ammo! Put down your gun!
Go to the door and unbolt it! I said to the door!
Unbolt it!!
Close the gates! The reds are coming!
Mister! They're going to kill Makar!
- Where?
- In the tower!
Take them! Take them, bandy-legs!
- Go away! Go away, damn you!
- Brothers, save the caravan!
Take the caravan to the forest!
Listen, you! You're not going anywhere without me!
Get out the way!
Stop! Stop!
My God! Ataman Lagutin!
Where's the collection?
Where's the treasure? Where?
Well, why have you gone silent,
Father Innokentiy?