A SOZOSHA Production
Producer: Masayuki NAKAJIMA
Script: Tsutomu TAMURA
Mamoru SASAKI and Nagisa OSHIMA
Camera: Yasuhiro YOSHIOKA
Sets: Shigemasa TODA
Lighting: Takeji SANO
Music: Hikaru HAYASHI
Sound: Hideo NISHIZAKI
Cut: Keiichi URAOKA
Starring:
Kei SATO
Keiko SAKURAI
Masakazu TAMURA
Rokko TOURA
Taiji TONOYAMA
Hosei KOMATSU
Hideo KANZE
Yoshikazu FUKUDA
Directed by
NAGISA OSHIMA
Japanese Summer - Double Suicide
JAPAN
Will it take long?
I just need a minute!
You delete it?
What a waste!
Je recommencerai ailleurs!
Just try to paint over me.
Putain! Bande de puceaux!#
I feel so relieved!
You've dropped something!
No problem!
I've thrown it away!
Why?
I've just broken up
with my boyfriend!
More men!
Japan's full of men!
I am going to die!
A whole group of them!
What's going on?
What's up?
What are you celebrating?
What party is this?
Is there something nice?
- How old are you?
- 20!
Isn't this boring for a
20year old guy?
Politics are interesting!
What are you doing?
Is this a funeral?
How old are you?
Aren't you young fellows bored here?
What's that? You get it?
Is it a man?
Or a woman?
- A human being.
- But you distinguish betwen mand and woman!
I got it!
How old are you?
- 100.
- 100?
Then I'll be 0 years old!
0 Years? Nice thought!
- Where are you from?
- Can't remember...
- And what are you doing here?
- Go into this form.
- For sleeping? Hooray!
- Not for sleeping!
- For what then?
- To fit into it.
Why would a man want to fit into
a human-form? Bullshit!
- Some will let me inside.
- Shall I?
Would you do that?
Sure! I'm a woman!
Let's find uns a cosy place!
- And this?
- I Don't need it.
I've got you now!
Let's go!
Nice mood!!
You're very good!
- Let's move into the middle!
- Here's the heart!
No way! In the middle!
Come on!
Hey!
Bust: 102.
Hips: 93.
I had my first period with 14.
Now I am 18.
Even after this advertisement you
don't want to be a real man, huh?
I'm still a man. I'm still alive.
Then come over here and proof it!
Don't disturb us!
Bastards!
My heart will be broken...
Stand up!
Let's find a real bed!
Come on! They are Yakuza!
They are dangerous!
Stop staring at me! Piss off!
How mean! Hands off my man!
You wanna be killed?
He is nuts!
Tell me! You don't prefer men, do you?
Stop following us!
- What's this?
- None of your business!
You kill people with that?
Do you belong to the other gang?
- You got rifles too?
- Of course!
Idiot!
Now they've seen it!
Let's take the girl and the maniac then!
I'm coming.
How sad!
Where are we going?
- To a place full of men.
- Wow!! Great!!
I've never seen him!
- Tidy up!
- Yes, Sir!
I wanna pee!
I'll pee here if you don't
let me go out!
Got it?
How long will we stay here?
Until tomorrow! You mustn't go
until the sun rises!
Until your war with the
rifles is over?
It's not a war! We're just
killing each other!
I tell you: I'm going to pee. OK?
Just do it!
Bullshit!
No Bullshit!
Bullshit! Nobody here can kill!
Huh? What are you talking about?
- "Pee..."
- Stop it!
You're not the type for it!
You can't kill!
- Bastard!
- "Pee..."
I'm not wearing a panty!
I'm just going to pee!
"Pee..."
Slut!
I can see it!
You guys can't kill!
Don't get it wrong!
- "Pee..."
- You can't kill!
You'll see! I cut you down!
Got it? I'll kill you!
You can't!
"Pee..."
- One more step and you're dead!
- "Pee..."
- Just go on!
- "Pee...!"
What's going on?
I wanna pee!
Come!
- Hello!
- You wanna watch? You're welcome!
- I want to ask you for something...
For a man I do everything!
- Can you hold it? I wanna come inside.
- You know what you want!
- Thank you.
- My pleasure!
Nobody else wanna do it.
I'ts hurting me.
- Are there any rifles?
- Rifles?
You didn't come for me?
- Bye bye.
- They won't allow kids!!
I wanna steal a rifle!
And why here?
Idiot! I've seen the backup!
Why backup?
Idiot! Because the gang's too small!
Then why are they fighting?
Idiot!! It's their job!
They could fight for women!
Idiot! It's for power
- Don't you know Yakuza-Films?
- Nope!
If I help you, will you
spend time with me?
Come on!
Woops! Sorry!
Pardon us!
Forget it! Why would you want
to shoot a rabbit anyway?
It's not about animals!
Whatever! Now about me ...!
- How old are you?
- 17.
Stop it! I'm going to find one!
Help me!
- Who are you?!
- Don't make such a face!
- I just went peeing...
- And the boy?
He wants to steal rifles!
- Which gang are you?!
- I'm just a student!
- Must be a lie!
- Look ... my student ID ...
Please! I want a rifle!
Something will happen tomorrow!
I wanna shoot somebody!
- You are nuts ...
- May I join you?
Bullshit! This is not a game!
What? Maybe there are no rifles?
You only got swords and daggers
like in the old times?
What kind of Yakuza are you?
You've already lost!
Stop!
You are going to stay! With the girl!
Nobody leaves until tomorrow!
Wow! This one is real!
It's a Thompson, right?
- May I hold it?
- Forget it!
- I just wanna hold it!
- Idiot!
There must be more, right?
I prefer other pistols!
Where are they?
Water pistols!
- Did you come to unbind me?
- Thank you coming...
- Where will we ...?
- When?
- The attack?
- Our leaders are...
- Does the enemy know?
- How about the strategy?
Ils souhaiteraient
que vous restiez group s#
et attendiez dans cette pi ce.#
- Where are you from?
- Himeji.
And you?
- Matsuyama, in Shikoku.
- Hiroshima.
What?
For your drive!
Please accept it.
- Nothing for me?
- Here!
You calculate everything?
How stupid!
- Bullshit!
- Shut up!
Just go on, you'll regret it!
Gentlemen! See you tomorrow!
Woooh!
We have to spend the night here?
One... Two... Three...
Four... Five... Six...
Seven.
Seven men and one woman.
Miss!
Here comes no.1!
Can you untie me?
What are you up to?
I've got some money!
You'll get half of it!
- I don't care about money...
- Stop it!
- Nice body! How old are you?
- Untie me!
Why are you tied up?
- He's killing without a reason!
- Without a ...?
- He just kills, no matter whom...
- Don't interefere!
- We are having a conversation!
- So will you untie me?
- Sure...
- Stop it! It tickles!
Will you spend the night with me,
if I untie you?
Yes!
You had a knife, right?
Give it to me!
Stop! You'll regret it!
Well? It's not dark yet but
you are in the mood already?
That was not what I thought about!
Shut up!
I'm not such kind of guy!
Just forget about that liar!
You are the best after all!
What are you doing?
You really kill everyone?
Without a special reason?
Bullshit!
Heart broken and
a headache on top of it...
Let's sleep until it becomes dark.
Good Night!
Tell me!
Are you a killer??
- Hey! I am first!
- There is a special order?
Looking for trouble?!
- Piss off!
- You really feel like killing!
Piss off!
Me! Now you want to kill me!
OK! I'll cut you down!
Stop!
Put the knife down! At once!
So much about killing...
- Just a toy.
- It must be real!
- A Mauser 712.
- A toy!
- Is it loaded?
- Yes. 6 bullets.
Wanna die?
Seem so.
Better die of sickness!
I don't want to.
You really want to be killed?
I think so.
- An accident would be better.
- Cars are no people.
- It's the same!
- No!
My murderer will look at me!
- I'll se myself in his eyes.
- "... in his eyes..."
- And?
- In this moment...
- ... I know who I am.
- "... who I am."
- But then you are dead!
- "... you are dead!"
No. In this moment...
- ... I know what I have to do.
- You know nothing! Shut up!
You mix something up!
Something is on your mind.
That's why the enemy wants to
kill you when he shows up.
Maybe.
- But I want to meet him.
- Just by hanging around...
- ... you won't.
- I will!
I think I'll meet him very soon.
That's why I started my journey.
I just took off, one morning.
Yes!
You'll meet him!
I'll kill you tomorrow!
- Just now you didn't.
- I've always! Until now...
"Until now"?
You've killed before?
- Yes. Very often!
- Bullshit! I don't believe it!
I used my knife 15 or 16 times.
Half of the men have died.
Liar! Someone like you
could never do that!
I've always carried a new
knife right here!
People understand the true
meaning of dead when having a weapon.
... when having a weapon.
Hold it!
The best is to put it in your
mouth, when shooting yourself!
Know how to shoot?
First you have to release it...
- You always have it with you?
- Yes.
- Why?
- Since I have it, ...
... I know what kind of
person I really am.
- Not like you ...
- Exactly!
Since I carry a knife...
... I want to kill people!
- But 15 or 16 times? Bullshit!
- Trust me!
After leaving the Marines...
... I became crazy for card games.
I came to Kamagasaki in 1960.
I had heard about a great casino.
But I found nothing.
I was so angry I bought a knife.
I stabbed a guy with it.
I interfered in
other peoples' fights ...
... just to cut down both men.
And you think you know me?
Bullshit!
You're crazy!
Once I start ...
... I kill 100s of people with
my rifle! That's it!
Just shoot at birds with
your air-gun, boy!
You'll never know how good it
feels stabbing someone.
Stop it!
I don't shoot people!
Who was that?
- I don't like him!
- Tie him up again!
All Japanese men should
be tied up!
- I went to a funeral.
- There was a funeral.
Boss told me to attend the funeral.
Sorry,
what's this?
- A TV.
- Show me!
Sure.
- Where are you going?
- Pee!
The enemy is ready.
Did the HQ send a message?
Yes, someone's at the air field.
The enemy is ready.
- Should we hand out the guns?
- Let's wait for the leaders.
They aren't coming!
Are the weapons ready?
You spied on us?!
Pig! Pervert! Bastard!
Hey!
I am going back! Don't worry!
Which gang are you?
Should I write "TV"?
- And the other one?
- "Companion".
Where am I?
- What does it mean?
- "Female".
This must be "male" then?
You are the "male".
So come on! Be a man!
It's going to start soon.
It's going to start!
- There are 30 rifles!
- Where?!
101 samurai swords!
And on top of it 60 pistols!
The enemy is ready!
Police is getting ready too.
- The killing will start soon!
- Do you know at which time?
Bang! Bang! Everybody's shooting!
Friend and foe,
you're going to die!
Flowers will bloom after your dead.
Your graves will be ...
... full of flowers!
Stupid cow! Stop it!
I am 18, but I am in full bloom!
I want to fight with a man!
It's going to start!
- And now ...
- Stop it!
Swords are not good...
- We must ask for rifles.
- I'm coming too!
Go!
That's the third victim.
The third victim of the
mysterious sniper!
Miss Sano was on her way
home from tailor class.
The bullets hit her without warning.
Just like the incident that
had happened 40 minutes before.
Nobody has seen the sniper.
Nobody knows, where he was hiding.
Meanwhile, office worker
T. Watanabe has told police ...
... that a foreigner with a
rifle took away his car.
Police assumes that his foreigner
must be the mysterious sniper.
His nationality is unknown.
The position of the car is unkown.
Should the foreigner be the sniper...
... he is able to move around
with the car and act everywhere.
The police is telling the public
not to leave the house.
Turn on TVs or radios for
further information!
Like a miracle the friend of
the first victims survived...
Is it far away to go to this guy?
When he comes with a car...
- ... one hour!
- Why is he doing that?
- No idea!
- A foreigner ...
No foreigner! A white man!
Three people in one hour!
He has a rifle with a
sighting telescope!
Lucky guy! Why don't you
let me have a rifle too?
There won't be any in
a room like this!
Please! A rifle! I'll join you!
I am very sorry about this.
Are you feeling alright?
Work will start very soon.
- Will we get our weapons?
- Yes.
- Rifles and pistols of course!
We are just calculating
how to distribute them.
Excuse me!
Not such a mood-killer-song!
Good Afternoon! Dear world!
That kills me!
Good afternoon!
Murder and suicide for love!
Good afternoon, dear Japan!
Good afternoon, in 1970!
Good afternoon! Good afternoon!
Idiot! Stupid!
Did it come from over there?
Sounded like an accident.
So they've got weapons already!
I want a rifle too! Please!
Have a look and get some!
But ... only me ...
Take him with you. That'll do.
Are you coming?
What do you need rifles for?
You are no true men after all!
Why do you need rifles?
You can't kill anyone!
- I can!
- Liar!
You did not even touch me!
You want to be a killer?
Very funny indeed?
You want me to show you? Where?
Here, in front of everyone!
Fine ...
Well? How about the rifles?
Later! I am first!
Shall I?
- You wanna die, right?
- Stop it!
He does not really
want to be killed!
I want to!
Try it! With your pistol!
Aren't you scared?
You really wanna die?
Better say it,
if you have any doubts!
I have nothing to say.
Fine ... can you see your face?
Not sure. It's not very clear.
You wanna fight?
Hey! What are you doing?!
Shut up!
Die!
Stoppage of gun!
It happens.
- What ...
- I can repair it.
Will you give it back?
- Yes.
- Really?
- It will take 30 minutes.
- I will wait.
There was this guy,
who decieved his friends.
He always played the honest one.
But then it was decided,
that he must die.
He stood up bravely
in front of the pistol.
Nothing he could do about it.
It was decided.
But ...
... he insisted on
not having decieved anybody.
I pulled the trigger,
but stoppage of gun!
I hoped he would run away
while I was reparing the gun.
We had been friends after all.
But he did not run away.
He waited two long hours,
until the gun was repaired.
And then - Bang! - he was dead.
That's a long time ago. There
were not so many guns then.
What do you say?
You!
30 minutes, right?
Will you give me your 30 minutes?
- That's okay, right?
- Yes, now I can.
I have not been wearing
underwear the whole time.
The police assumptions were right.
The foreigner is the
mysterious sniper.
Officer Hideo Jun was attacked
from a passing car...
... while being on patrol
on highway no.1.
It was the car which had
been stolen a short time before.
The sniper is fleeing towards
the east.
His looks and motives stay unclear.
He is shooting while driving which
complicates the whole situation.
The Police is trying to block ...
- What are you doing?!
- Repair it! Quick!
Let's go over there!
Just 20 minutes left!
- The foreigner is coming?
- He'll pass by.
I'll wait then.
I want to see him.
- I'll do it once the gun is ready.
- The foreigner will kill me!
- I can do it!
- Shut up! It's my job!
I'll have my knife soon,
just wait and see ...
Bullshite! Awww, my body hurts.
Bye bye!
Nobody's here!
What's wrong?
They are gone! Without you!
Serves you right!
That's the end, I guess.
- Nobody's there?
- No.
Poverty and hunger ...
... are the reason for everything.
Come! Let's go!
- I should kill him!
- But it's all over!
- The pistol will be fine soon.
- Who cares? He's my man!
Please don't go!
There's enough time left.
What's going on?
Nobody is here!
- The fight is cancelled.
- But why?
One of our leaders was
caught on the airfield.
- The cops?
- Yes. A crackdown!
They'll be here soon.
So I want to ask you ...
Out of my way!
- Shall we fight he police?
- No! Calm down!
- With the rifles? "Call down"?
- You want us to be arrested?
Out of my way!
I would take responsibility.
But only me? That would stink.
So I ask for your cooperation.
When the verdict was spoken...
What about the others?
They just ran away.
- And now we are the substitutes?
- Exactly.
When you are arrested, the
others will earn some time.
Is that a joke?!
We came to fight!
Not for going to jail!
Relax!
There's lots of time!
But let me tell you:
Not a word to the police!
You don't know anything anyway...
- How dare you?!
- Shut up!
Wanna die?
Or stand the bad food for
some days and go home?
Well?
Out of my way!
The big rock will break!
- I'll go for the bad food.
- Miss!
You should go home!
Will you join me?
Me as a young man ...
... committed many crimes.
Oh ...
Povert and hunger ...
... are the reasons for everything.
Poverty and hunger ...
... are the reason for everything.
Out of my way!
I hit you in pieces!
Big rock.
Out of my way!
I can't return to freedom yet.
Stop singing!
When the verdict was spoken ...
... the girl cried out loud.
Five years of penitientiary.
That was too much!
Out of my way! I hit you in pieces!
Big rock!
Out of my way! Out of my way!
I can't return to freedom yet.
Can't find a man
in this darkness.
What can I do but sleep?
Oh, I did not go peeing
since last evening.
It's me!
It's morning already!
- What's going on?
- Are the cops coming?
Nobody. Everything's quiet.
You know why I came back?
The TV's sound is working again.
The foreigenr is probably
hiding inside of the city.
Somewhere here in the city.
9 1/2 hours after
the first incident ...
... and 5 hours after the attack
on a police officer on the high way:
He did not show up at the
road barriers, ...
... so he must be in the city.
Damned! He's in the city?
Probably.
Just forget it!
It's working?
There are lots of toys in the box!
A rifle!
- For me too.
- I'll have two swords.
Two more rifles. Who takes them?
- What for?
- For killing of course.
Killing whom?
Now we have weapons.
But at whom shall we aim?
Nobody here to give orders.
So the fight is over?
- You won't do anything?
- Nothing we can do.
- No enemy!
- So we'll just go home?
That's why I am asking!
What shall we do?
Use your heads!
Don't you have any enemies?
Someone you really want to kill?
I'll go! Who cares whom I kill?
You don't think I can do it?
What a fine gang we are!
A white sniper and gang wars.
- Life is hard for the cops.
- Is nobody coming with me?
- Me!
- Where to?
- Doesn't matter!
- Me too.
87 persons were arrested
and 23 pistols were found, ...
... also 20 sowrds and 3 carabiners.
The investigations will be continued.
It's like Dallas!
We are like a Japanese Dallas!
The white sniper still hides
within the city.
At the same time armed gangs
are roaming through the streets.
About 200 gangsters!
All dangeous elements!
It's just like Dallas!
Repair the picture
until sunrise!
Hey ... Dallas?
Kennedy was killed there, right?
Sleep with me!
The night will be over soon ...
Dallas ...
In Dallas and still alive.
What about you, toy-man?
TV-Mann? How about it?
- I'll go!
- Me too. Everyone is okay for me!
Stop! Where are you going?
Go home!
It's dangerous!
What? Back already?
I got two.
It was boring!
Really?
I got three. But nothing
to be happy about.
Repaired!
Look who's there!
Arrested! Serves him right!
Leave us here to the police!
- Let's go!
- The news!
The American summer with
the race riots ...
"Long and hot American Summer".
How can we call this
Japanese summer?
No blackmen riots but a
white man is the cause of trouble.
Just look at the many victims!
Despite of the police order to
stay at home ...
... the area was full of people
heading for the factory.
After ten hours of silence the
sniper shoot many bullets again.
Nobody knows about his motives.
Our team is tryint to catch
a glance of him and report.
We don't know when we
will be shot at.
But it's our duty as journalists.
That's him! We found him!
That's him?
I'll go and face his rifle-
I'll fight with him!
- He just shot!
- How many will I get?
Arm yourself! Rifles or
sowrds! What ever!
- What are you doing!
- I'm leaving! It's over!
The other one too!
And you? Will you come?
How?
We have a car!
- What kind of?
- A small one.
For 5 person.
2 people too mich.
We are not going. Right?
You won't get it.
- But ...
- Shut up!
Leave me alone!
I had enough!
Then go!
Just five people!
The foreigner or the police?
Who's our enemy?
- Good bye!
- Bye bye, idiot!
Just die!
What was that about?
TV-man?
What was that?
Who fired?
He would have attacked
the foreigner!!
So there is one man less.
- Can I come too?
- No women!
Why?
I wanna sleep with the foreigner.
Poverty and hunger ...
... are the reason for everything.
The situation remains complicated.
A car is approaching!
The car has passed by the
barriers build by the police!
The car is approaching the sniper!
What's going on here?
You can see the car now.
There are 5 persons in the car!
They are Japanese!
They have rifles!
We cannot say what these
people are up to!
Will he shoot?
No idea.
I'm sure he'll be alarmed though.
I'll shoot at the police then!
Then he knows we are his friends.
- Why not?
- It's too early!
Mr foreigner!
We want to join you!
He won't understand that!
What? That's dangerous!
Such an idiot!
I'll shoot!
Don't!
What is he up to?
No police! No police!
Friend! Friend!
Did he understand?
He did not shoot.
Fine! I'll go too!
No police! Friend!
Friend! Darling!
Leave! It's dangerous!
Leave! Leave at once!
Leave!
It's dangerous! Leave!
Leave at once!
Friend! Friend!
Darling! Friend!
My friend?
Exactly! Friend!
Friend!
Let's shake hands!
- Alrigh! He's understood us
- Understood what?
That we are on his side!
- What are you doing?
- You!
- They are getting on my nerves.
- Leave!
- Shut up!
What is your plan?!
Who are you?!
Idiot!
Darling! Let's be friends!
You must be hungry! Here!
Don't worry! It's not poisened.
Who is that?!
Can't you seee it?
- A foreigner.
- But what kind of?
And why is he doing this?
Why? Why?
I'm twenty years old.
Oh, 20? I am 18.
20? I know how you feel.
- You understand him? Why?
- I just do.
What do you want?
I'll fight with him.
Me too!
Yes? Me: Eighteen!
- Me, eighteen.
- Eighteen?
You, twenty.
Me, eighteen.
Yes.
Me, seventeen.
Me, fifty-one!
Why did you come with us?
I know.
Huh? You know?
You want to kill the foreigner.
Right!
No!
- Let's get out of here!
- Tear gas!
Weapons down! Come out!
If you shoot again, ...
... we'll shoot back!
Weapons down and come out!
Drop the gun! And come out!
If you shoot again, we'll use our guns!
Drop the gun and surrender!
Just leave him!
Leave him! He's dead!
Hey, hurry up!
Come on! Come on, let's go!
Hurry up! Hurry up!
What are you doing?
C'mon! Let's go!
Drop your guns! Come out!
You are surrounded!
Drop your guns and surrender!
If you don't obey, ...
... we'll use our guns!
Drop the gun and come out!
We have you surrounded!
Come out!
With your hands up! If you don't ...
- Shit! Arrogant asshole!
- That's dangerous!
That's why I am shooting!
Drop your guns and come out!
You can't resist!
Drop your guns and surrender!
Drop the gun and come out!
It's useless to resist!
You don't have a chance!
Drop the gun! And surrender!
Will we do it? Bang! Bang!
What? You don't want to?
Then piss off!
I'll do it myself.
Hey, TV-man! How about you?
He said: People only understand
death when they have a weapon.
- Shoot me.
- Why me?
I'm nt sure ...
But I want you to.
Uff!
Time for decision!
I've been waiting for this!
Hey!
What's going on?
I shot the white guy!
I killed him!
What was that?!
You ...?
You!
"My murderer will look at me."
"I will se myself in his eyes."
"Then I will know who I am."
"I will know what I have to do."
"My murderer ..."
- What's your name?
- Nejiko.
"A woman with a loose screw (Neji)."
And you?
I don't have a name.
The man who will vaporize.
And now?
Nejiko!
Wonderful!
A love-double-suicide.
Not a voluntary one!