( hip-hop playing )
♪ The night is young
and we throw it down hard ♪
♪ Every time I raise my glass
all the girls were going wild ♪
♪ I ain't trippin',
what you sippin'? ♪
♪ I'm just trying
to have some fun ♪
♪ Why don't you bring it
over here, girl ♪
♪ And let me get some? ♪
( singing continues,
indistinct )
MAN:
Let's go, Lucas!
( cheering )
- Yeah, buddy!
- Whoo!
- Yeah! Connor,
you're up, man.
- No, dude...
- Connor!
- No, I'm thrashed already.
Hey, you are the head
of the house, and there
is no exceptions!
No! No exceptions!
Go!
( chanting )
Chug! Chug!
( chanting continues )
Chug! Chug! Chug!
Chug! Chug!
( chanting continues )
- Chug! Chug!
Chug! Chug!
- ( whooping )
( cell phone vibrates )
Amazing!
- It's Amanda!
- WOMAN: Amanda!
I love her!
CONNOR:
Hey.
Hey, you.
What's all the noise?
Oh, I just invited
a few guys over.
You know how it is.
Word got out.
I miss you.
I miss you too.
But I'm saving
a lot towards school.
So who's all there?
Just Lucas, Mya,
and a few other people.
I'd better go,
but I love you.
I can't wait for you
to get home.
I love you too.
So when does the wife
get back, huh?
The end of the month,
right before school starts.
- That's a long time to go
without gettin' something, bro.
- Nah.
- Whoa, whoa, whoa!
- Easy.
The host of the party
should always be
one drink behind.
That was nice.
( chuckling )
So, uh, who
invited the skank?
Uh, I don't even
know who that is.
Lucas friended her.
You are such
an Internet slut.
Oh, come on, Mya.
Give her a break.
She just moved here,
and she doesn't know anybody.
Look at her profile.
- MYA: Yeah, no thanks.
- Uh, we're almost
out of beer.
- I'll be right back.
- Okay.
( chuckling )
( groans )
- Need a hand?
- I'm okay.
Let me help you
with that.
( chuckles )
That's a nice Mercedes.
You know, I've always
wondered what these things
look like on the inside.
( giggles )
Can I?
Yeah.
Come here.
( groans )
God, look at this dash.
- What do all
these buttons do?
- What?
Come in. I want you to
show me what they do.
- Stop it. Come here.
You silly.
- ( chuckling )
Oh, man, that beer bong
is hitting me hard.
( groans )
( giggling )
( groaning )
Now I know
why you shouldn't
drink and drive.
- Everything's spinning.
- ( chuckles )
I can make it
stop spinning.
- What are you doing?
- Shh, shh, shh. Relax.
No tensing, remember?
We shouldn't do this.
( giggling )
( moaning )
( laughing )
♪ I part the gray skies,
let the sun rays shine ♪
♪ And every day fade away
in the daylight ♪
♪ Dang right,
need it just to stay alive ♪
♪ I get the same high
boosting every daylight ♪
Whoa!
Hey, did you get
your new schedule yet?
- First period, Mrs. Wolk.
- Awesome.
So I get to see you
first thing every morning.
Unless your parents
let me sleep over.
That is never
going to happen.
Why? We've been together
for, like, two years.
- I'm practically family.
- What about your parents?
My parents are still
barely talking to me.
Do you blame them?
I mean, you trashed
their house with that party.
I didn't plan it.
And I swear that's never
gonna happen again,
ever.
Hey, Connor.
Hey.
Uh, who's that?
Uh, just some new chick
Lucas friended.
You know how he is.
You gonna go in?
Okay.
WOMAN:
All right,
everyone.
- Good morning.
Welcome back.
I hope you all had
a fantastic
summer vacation,
relaxed, because
it's all over,
and the work is
really about to begin
because this is the year
that counts, right?
So, get out your
world history books.
Chapter five.
♪ Come on closer,
come and get it,
only halfway... ♪
Oh, here she is.
Heather Henderson.
What school
did she go to?
Doesn't say.
Oh, look, and other than
my dumb-ass boyfriend,
it looks like she doesn't
have very many friends.
What the hell is that?
Is that from the party?
Mm. Probably.
But, look, Connor
was so wasted,
he probably doesn't
even remember this photo.
Seriously, you have
nothing to worry about.
Yeah, it's just,
I'm late.
"Late"?
- Oh, you mean your...
- Yeah.
I was supposed to get
my period over a week ago.
- Have you told Connor?
- What? No.
And totally freak him out?
Absolutely not. No way.
( cell phone beeps )
That's my mom.
I got to go.
Okay. Well,
call me, okay?
Okay.
Oh, hey, look--
and don't worry.
I'm late all the time.
All the time.
( sobbing )
I just don't understand
why it has to happen.
It doesn't mean
anything's wrong.
- Uh...
- What's going on?
Um, your sister had
another miscarriage.
Oh, Kel,
I am so sorry.
Yeah, well,
I should be
used to it by now.
- Um, are you in
for the night?
- Yeah.
Okay. Look,
I really hate to do this,
but I have to go to work, okay?
Um, your dad will be
home later, okay?
( kisses )
I love you.
I love you too.
You know what?
It's gonna happen.
Thanks, Mom.
I know it.
Bye, guys.
( door shuts )
Greg and I swore
if the last one didn't take,
we'd try in vitro.
What does that mean?
It means I get to be
poked and basted
like a turkey.
( chuckles )
I just think it's funny
how in sex ed
they always warn you,
"Don't have unprotected sex.
You're sure to get pregnant."
And then when
you want to, you can't.
Yeah.
And how are you?
Everything okay
with you and Connor?
Yeah.
Yeah,
everything's great.
Are you sure?
Yeah, I don't know.
I just think
maybe I shouldn't have
left all summer.
Headin' out.
( toilet flushes )
- MAN: Hey, you in there?
- ( water rushes )
Hey, you hear me?
Yeah, Dad.
Whatever.
( door slams )
( shutter clicks )
( clicking )
- AMANDA:
Hey, Mrs. Walker.
- Hey.
- It's really good to
see you back, Amanda.
- Thank you.
- How was
the counseling job?
- It was good.
- I made a lot of money
for school, so...
- Well, that's good.
Well, I'm not gonna lie.
I wish you'd been here,
'cause then maybe my son
wouldn't have been so stupid
as to have a party.
Mom, are you ever
gonna forgive me
for that, for real?
Maybe, if I can
get that stain
out of my carpet.
Get back to
your homework.
- Come here.
- ( squeals, laughs )
- What are you doing?
- Making up for summer.
( phone buzzes, beeps )
What is it?
Nothing,
just this stupid
puppy video
Lucas sent me.
It's stupid.
( laughing )
♪ Yeah, baby,
you look like a superstar ♪
♪ I saw you walking
in them hills on
the boulevard ♪
♪ Yeah, baby, you need me ♪
♪ Just tell me all your dreams
and your fantasies ♪
We need to talk.
- Eh...
- ( sighs ) Okay.
You go deal with that,
Tom Sawyer.
( scoffs )
Nice.
( bell ringing )
- How do you know it's mine?
- Because I do.
No, there's no way.
I mean, it was,
like, one time.
I haven't been
with anybody else.
I just moved here,
like, two months ago.
I don't know anybody.
Except you.
So what do you
want to do?
I mean, it's not like
this was planned.
And I have a girlfriend.
Well, you should've
thought about that
before you slept with me.
- I barely even
remember what happened.
- ( door opens )
MAN:
Hey, you guys,
let's get to class, okay?
I'm keeping it.
Our baby.
( bell ringing )
Connor! Hey!
Hey! Where were you
this morning?
- Uh, I wasn't
feeling well.
- Oh.
Well, did you hear about
that new girl, Heather?
Apparently, she posted
a selfie of her positive
pregnancy test.
I mean,
that's crazy, right?
If she were
actually pregnant?
Yeah.
You know what?
I'm just gonna go home.
But I'll talk to you later.
( cell phone rings )
Hey.
MYA:
Yo, have you seen
Heather's Face page?
Yeah, she posted
her pee stick.
No, there's more, Amanda.
Look at it.
Are you looking?
Yeah, I got to go.
( chuckling )
Oh!
I've picked you
a good daddy.
- ( keyboard clacking )
- ( door shuts )
Shouldn't you be
at work?
Seriously?
- Are you picking up
where your mama left off?
- Yeah.
Looks like it.
Oh, and just like her,
I'll be out of here
soon enough.
( line ringing )
( ringing )
Why didn't you
call me back?
- Sorry. I was...
- What? Avoiding me?
What is this?
Hey, Connor.
Hey, I got
the blood results back.
I'm for-sure pregnant.
Is this real?
Look, Amanda,
I have no idea
what's going on.
You obviously slept with her.
Or is she just lying?
- I'm not lying.
- Shut up.
Look, I'm not
the one who cheated
on his girlfriend.
I didn't even know
he had a girlfriend.
Amanda, can we just
talk about this?
No, you have no idea
how bad you just screwed up.
( sobbing )
Amanda!
I can't believe this!
How could he?
I-I know, but maybe
it's not as bad
as it seems.
I mean, people make
mistakes, right?
You guys have been
together for two years.
- Maybe you can get
through this.
- I don't think so.
I'm pregnant too!
( sobbing )
♪ Nothing can change ♪
♪ The way you feel ♪
♪ There's a black hole
in my universe ♪
♪ A weight in my world ♪
- ( phone beeps )
- ♪ Now all of our yesterdays ♪
♪ Seem too far to touch ♪
♪ Ain't it funny
how one mistake ♪
- ♪ Can hurt so much? ♪
- Look, Amanda,
I don't even
know how to say
how sorry I am.
I mean, I don't know
what I was thinking.
To be honest,
I barely even remember
what happened.
- So you're gonna blame it
on being drunk?
- No.
No, it was totally
and completely my fault.
And now I just
hate myself
for all of it.
Especially what
it's done to you.
To us.
There is no more "us,"
Connor.
You took care of that
the night that you
got her pregnant.
♪ You just disappear ♪
You should eat,
sweetie.
You look pale.
I'm fine.
( bell ringing )
( retching )
( phone ringing )
CONNOR:
I'm not gonna
stop texting
or calling you,
Amanda.
Okay, I know we can
get through this.
Mr. Walker,
is there a problem?
Yes, Mrs. Wolk,
there is.
In fact, can I switch
seats, please?
- I'll switch with her.
- ( students exclaiming )
All right, all right.
Amanda, Heather,
switch seats.
But if I have
any more disturbances,
I'm gonna move you all.
"Ooh!"
She's all yours.
Amanda...
- Have you talked to
your parents yet?
- No.
- Why not?
I'm already eight weeks.
- Because they'll kill me.
Look, they'll get over it.
And then they'll meet
their grandchild,
and they'll be so happy,
just like we'll be.
Have you told
your parents?
My mom's not around.
She walked out on us,
like, four years ago.
I'm sorry.
I didn't know that.
And my dad...
he doesn't care
what I do.
And even if I did tell him,
he wouldn't help out.
He wouldn't buy me
any maternity clothes,
so what am I
supposed to wear?
I can't even see a doctor
because we don't
have insurance.
And I sure as hell
can't afford it
on my own.
And I didn't want
to say anything,
but I'm really worried
about this baby.
I'm trying to do
everything right,
but I have no one.
No one is there
to help me.
Look, I'll take care
of it, okay?
I have some money saved up.
You can use it for a doctor
so you and the baby
can get checked out.
Oh, thanks! I knew
you'd take care of us!
( sniffling )
Hey, Mom.
Hey, Dad.
Hey, sweetie.
Hey.
What?
Is there something
you want to tell us?
- No. Why?
- Oh, I don't know.
Maybe the fact that you
don't eat a lot these days,
you don't sleep very much,
you cry a lot.
I'm okay.
I just have been
really busy.
A little tired,
is all.
( drawer opens )
I thought we were
being safe. I swear.
I didn't mean
for this to happen.
Amanda,
do you have any idea
what this is gonna
do to your life,
to your future?
You're only 17.
You haven't even
finished high school.
And what about college?
Or did you just forget
about that?
I didn't do this
on purpose.
I don't even know
what I'm gonna do.
I mean, Mom's right.
If I keep the baby,
it changes everything.
No, no,
wait a second.
I did not mean to suggest
that you shouldn't
have this baby.
But you did make
a mistake, Amanda.
Look, you do need to take
some responsibility here.
She obviously can't
go to school and raise
the baby at the same time.
Okay.
No, she cannot.
But she also has
her parents.
Right?
You have both
of your parents here
to help you.
Do you know
that when I was 19,
your father and I had
to make the exact
same decision?
And do you know
how grateful I am
every single day
that I get to look into
your sister's smiling face...
and yours.
Dad?
( exhales sharply )
Obviously,
this is not what
I wanted, Amanda.
But your mother's right.
Come here.
Look, I'm sure
that you and Connor
are terrified,
but just know that
we will be there for you,
and we will get
through this together.
Connor doesn't know.
I haven't told him.
Why? Amanda,
this is his baby.
He deserves to know.
He cheated
on me, Mom.
And she's
pregnant too.
- What?
- ( sobbing )
Amanda,
your father and I
have decided to
go over to Connor's
and talk to his parents.
- Now?
- And we would like
for you to come with us.
You did talk to Connor, right?
Because his parents
didn't mention anything.
Yeah. He just probably
hasn't told them.
Okay. You might want to
give them a heads-up
that we're coming.
Okay.
( phone beeps )
( doorbell rings )
We had the greatest summer,
as I said, but we missed you.
- The vineyard was spectacular.
You have to come next time.
- FATHER: We'd love to.
And this pinot is phenomenal.
I mean, wait till you taste it.
But anyway, enough about us.
So, uh, how are things?
MOTHER:
Well, actually,
that's why we're here.
Amanda and Connor have
something they want to
discuss with us.
Oh, what is it?
Amanda.
I'm pregnant.
MR. WALKER:
Unbelievable.
Connor, you didn't think
that maybe you should've
told us?
I didn't know about it
until just before
they came over.
tt?
- AMANDA: It's true.
- I don't understand this.
Weren't you being safe?
- Yeah, we were.
At least,
I thought we were.
- Well, one of you wasn't.
- MOTHER: Wait a second.
In all fairness,
even if they were
taking precautions,
we all know something
like this can still happen.
Okay, okay, let's not
all get worked up
about this, okay?
I mean, there is
a way to handle this.
Right?
I'm keeping the baby,
if that's what you mean.
And there's more.
There's a girl at school
who's also claiming
she's pregnant
with Connor's baby.
What is this, a joke?
Is this some kind
of damn joke?
It's true.
Connor, I don't
understand any of it.
- How could this happen?
- I'll tell you how
it could happen.
This is some kind
of sick game
these girls are playing.
Now, wait a second.
It's your son who
screwed around here.
- It does take two, Peter.
- MRS. WALKER: Connor,
I don't understand this.
Who is this girl?
What's her name?
Her name's Heather.
I don't even know her.
I met her--
Whoa, wait a second!
What do you mean,
you don't know her?
It doesn't sound like it.
MRS. WALKER:
You know what?
What if you just calm down?
PETER:
You still think we shouldn't
have sent him to private school?
- Away from these--
- What, Peter?
Away from what?
Hey, look.
My son's life
is ruined, Jeff.
- You know, this is not
just about Connor.
- Amanda, she's right.
I mean, have you thought
about this, what this means
for both of your futures?
Yes. I have.
And I want to do
what's right for the baby.
What about this other girl?
Is she gonna do
the right thing?
- Yeah.
- PETER: That's great.
And guess who gets
to pay for all of it.
- Us, that's who.
- JEFF: Really, Peter?
You know, I've had
enough of this.
Come on, Amanda,
let's go.
MOTHER:
You know,
we will contribute as much
as we possibly can.
But I thought that you
knew that about us already.
Amanda, wait.
Why didn't you tell me?
I was gonna tell you.
You were too busy
fondling Heather.
- I don't want anything
to with her.
- Exactly, Connor.
If it was just us,
I could talk to you.
But it's not.
- Amanda, please...
- MRS. WALKER: Connor.
Look, I don't care
what my parents say.
I'm gonna be here for you
whether you want me to or not.
Come on.
( shutter clicking )
( clicking
continues )
♪ I was awake
when you were asleep ♪
♪ And I laid at your side
like a bird's little wing ♪
♪ Formed in the image
of the king, where ♪
♪ Love knew no shame ♪
♪ I heard you praying
in the garden for me ♪
♪ Said you wanted me
with you ♪
♪ You always believe that ♪
♪ Love is so much
stronger than the ♪
♪ Grave ♪
♪ Oh, no,
there's someone else ♪
♪ In the garden ♪
♪ Oh, no,
there's someone else ♪
♪ In the garden ♪
Dylan Walker.
Dylan... David.
Little Dylan's
starting Little League
in two weeks.
Yeah, Connor's so excited.
He's so proud of him.
♪ Oh, no,
there's someone else ♪
♪ In the garden ♪
♪ You were the master
and I was your queen ♪
- ♪ And we reigned in the garden
before there was pain ♪
- Ryan Walker.
- ♪ Our love became
a violent thing ♪
- I think that's a perfect name.
- ♪ That took our breath away ♪
- We're gonna be so happy.
♪ You were firm like a soldier,
make ends meet ♪
♪ With a manmade grace ♪
Mrs. Heather Walker.
That's me.
Thank you.
Mrs. Walker.
Mrs. Heather Walker.
( knock on door )
What do you want?
That's no way to
treat your boyfriend.
Your dad got
any beers?
No.
I said "no."
And you're not staying.
- Come here.
- ( gasps )
Come on.
Dad's not home,
you're looking great.
It's been a month since
I've been in your pants.
You know that?
I don't want to see you
anymore, Trent.
Why do you think
I haven't called?
What,
you got some new,
rich boyfriend?
Seeing as the last time
you tried to swindle somebody,
it didn't work out
so good.
We're done, Trent.
I'm getting tired of
of getting jerked around
by you
every time
one of your plans
doesn't work out.
- Hey.
I just thought you
should know that this
isn't the first time
- that Heather
has done this.
- What do you mean?
- She's faking, Connor.
- Faking what?
- You know what
I'm talking about.
- No. No, I don't.
What do you want,
Heather? Money?
The attention?
Or are you just some
pathological liar?
- Hey, come on, Amanda,
just forget it.
- No, you're lying, Heather.
You're not pregnant.
Just like you lied
at your last high school.
Burkin High.
I mean, seriously,
how long did you
think you could
get away with this?
I bet you're lying
to me about Connor
sleeping with you.
Oh, trust me,
I did not make that up.
You're just jealous
because I'm having
your boyfriend's baby.
Or is it "ex-boyfriend"?
Oh, I have nothing
to be jealous about,
because
I'm pregnant too.
Bet that wasn't part
of your twisted plan,
was it?
Connor was so drunk
at that party, he barely
remembers anything.
For all he knows,
you're making
everything up.
You just can't
deal with the fact
that your boyfriend
cheated on you, can you?
Let me paint a little
picture for you:
me and Connor
in the front seat
of his daddy's Mercedes.
- Amanda...
- Just don't!
You know, the one
with the soft
leather interior
with me on top
and your boyfriend
underneath me.
- You're lying!
- ( clamoring )
- Oh! Connor!
- Whoa, whoa.
What's going on here?
( groans )
Amanda, she pushed me!
- Oh, my God!
- Back to class!
- ( coughing, groaning )
Okay. All right.
( gasping, groaning )
MRS. WOLK:
Call 911.
It's okay. Breathe.
I just can't believe
she would do that, Connor.
She could've hurt
our baby.
I mean, what about when
the baby actually comes?
I'm just afraid of
what she might do.
She wouldn't hurt
the baby, Heather.
I'm in the hospital,
Connor,
because of her.
Look, I'm not gonna
let anything happen.
All right?
- Mom.
- What happened?
Nothing.
The baby's fine.
Nothing's fine.
Amanda pushed me.
I take it
you're Heather.
Connor, will you
make sure I don't
get a ticket where I'm parked
in front of the entrance?
So, you're the one
planning to be carrying
my son's baby.
I am carrying
your son's baby.
- Have you had
a paternity test?
- No.
I won't endanger
my baby.
Besides, Connor knows
I haven't been with
anyone else.
( chuckles )
Connor knows you haven't
been with anyone else. Sure.
Connor doesn't
know anything,
but I have
a pretty good idea
of what you're
all about.
Just so you know.
Oh, and don't sweat it.
It's just a blood test.
You can't make me
do it.
We'll see about that.
( ringing )
Hey.
Hey. How is everything
with Heather?
Uh, the doctor said
she and the baby
should be fine.
Look, I didn't mean
to hurt her.
I just...
I'm sorry.
Amanda, I get that
this is my mess,
okay, but we're all
just going to have to
try to get along.
I'm not gonna be friends
with her, if that's
what you think, Connor.
I get that.
So just leave her alone.
All right?
Fine.
I'll do that.
- Are you kidding me?
- Kelly, it is hard enough
on your sister without you--
She can't have a baby.
She's not even married.
Or do you and your
high-school sweetheart Connor
plan on getting hitched?
- You know what, Kelly?
That is enough.
- No, I mean it.
How do they plan on raising
a baby between home room
and soccer practice?
You know, if there was
ever a time that Amanda
needed a big sister,
now would be it.
Wait, just...
I'll go.
Look, I'm really sorry,
all right?
I've been trying for
over a year, Amanda.
I want a family
more than anything
in the world.
- And then you
just go and...
- I know.
It's not fair.
Fair or not,
I'm still your sister,
and I'm here
for you, okay?
I mean it.
( chuckles )
Oh! I know you'll
take care of us.
( shutter clicking )
( chuckles )
( phone beeps )
♪ Butcher in the sky
gonna find out why ♪
♪ Butcher in the sky ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ Used to live forever,
now I just don't know ♪
♪ You been gone so long
I suppose ♪
♪ Honey in the pantry
drips like blood ♪
♪ Butcher in the sky ♪
I don't even know how much
longer I can go without
wearing maternity wear.
I mean, everything I wear
is so uncomfortable.
What are you
doing here?
He called and asked
if he could be here
for the ultrasound.
I'll just
meet you in the car.
Actually, Mrs. Cohen,
I would prefer to take
Amanda home myself,
if that's okay
with you.
Of course.
Good luck, you guys.
♪ Sing me to sleep ♪
♪ Through the winter ♪
- ♪ And your lips are
strawberry red ♪
- Okay.
- Fine.
- ♪ It takes all I have... ♪
WOMAN:
All righty. Well,
unless it's hiding,
it looks like you're
going to have a girl.
Really?
I'm having a girl?
- It's pretty safe to
paint your nursery pink.
- ( laughs )
And everything else
looks okay?
Everything looks fine.
Do you want to hear
the heartbeat?
- Yes.
- Yeah, for sure.
( beeps )
( whooshing sound )
That is crazy!
That's weird.
( laughs )
( giggles )
Thank you, baby daddy.
Ooh!
( giggles )
Oh, Connor's gonna
love me in this.
Ah!
( giggling )
Hmm. ( giggling )
- ( door opens )
- You left your keys
in the door again.
Seriously?
You got to be
kidding me.
( scoffs )
Jeez...
It's not
your problem, Dad.
Yeah, you're damn right
that ain't my problem.
Well, I wouldn't expect
anything to change now.
Well, I hope you got it
all figured out, then.
Of course I do.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
I'm not that much
like Mom. I was smart.
- I didn't pick a loser.
- Hmm.
Well, he must be
some kind of
lucky boy, then.
Don't lose them again.
Clean all that up.
( door shuts )
CONNOR:
That's incredible.
- It's like in 3-D
and everything.
- ( chuckles )
- You can clean up now.
- Okay.
( phone ringing )
I heard your mom
was making her take
a paternity test.
Yeah. We should hear back
from the lab today.
She's driving me
crazy, Amanda,
calling and texting
all the time,
needing stuff.
And when I talked to you
that day at the hospital,
I was stressed out.
Okay? She got me thinking
something bad could've
happened to the baby,
and just didn't want
to deal with any more drama.
But I never meant
to push you away.
( phone beeps )
( beeping )
See what I mean?
- Well, is
everything okay?
- Yeah.
I'll just tell her
I'm at your ultrasound.
I mean, she's got to understand
that it's not just about her.
Besides,
I want to be here...
with you.
Connor, hi, this is me.
I need you to call me right now.
I don't know why you're not
answering your phone.
Please call me.
Connor, hi, this is me.
I need you to call me back.
Baby, I'm sorry, I need you
to call me back right now.
This is really important.
Please, you have to
call me back right now, okay?
- ( phone beeps )
- ( sighs )
That bitch!
( coughs )
So has Heather been
to her ultrasound?
Not yet, but I'm sure
she'll let me know,
seeing as my parents
have to pay for it.
( laughs )
Thanks for letting me
be there today.
( phone beeps )
- Is it her again?
- Yeah.
She says she's taken
some pill to calm her down,
and now she feels sick.
Better go.
Amanda, she doesn't
have anyone else.
I get it. Go.
I'm sorry.
CONNOR:
All right,
I'll tell her. Thanks.
So the doctor said
you and the baby
should be fine,
but to never take
any medication again
until you talk to him first.
I'm sorry, Connor.
It's okay.
You need anything?
I'd love something
to drink.
( sighs )
( buzzes, beeps )
( refrigerator door shuts )
( shudders, sobs )
( door shuts )
- Here.
- Thanks.
- So, where's the baby
going to sleep?
- My room. Want to see?
I was thinking maybe
I could put the baby bed
right here next to mine.
I want to fix it up
a little bit.
And some new furniture
and curtains
and a new heater
and maybe patch up some
of the holes on the wall.
Do you think maybe
your parents could help out?
'Cause I'd really hate for
our baby to be sleeping
in here like it is.
I'll talk to them.
- Do you want to come in?
- No, thanks.
I'd better get going.
Well, do you want to just
stay, just for a little bit?
'Cause it kind of gets
lonely here lately,
and my dad's
never around,
and my mom hasn't called
in over a year, so...
- ( vehicle approaches )
- Sounds like
your dad's home now.
- We should talk to him.
- Okay.
( vehicle door
opens, shuts )
FATHER:
Hey, kid.
Come here.
Come on.
Are you the one?
I'm sorry?
The one who put my girl
in her condition.
Is that you?
That's what she says.
You poor little
son of a bitch.
( chuckling )
MOTHER:
Hey. Feel any better?
- Not really.
- You know,
when Connor called
and said he wanted to
go to the ultrasound,
he said he really wanted
to be there for you.
Yeah, well, he can't be
in two places at once, can he?
He loves you, Amanda,
not her.
Try to remember that,
okay?
( line ringing )
Hey, it's me, Amanda.
Leave me a message.
( beeps )
So I just got off
the phone with the lab.
Heather's baby is yours.
Are you all right?
Yeah.
Look,
I was just over
at her house, Mom.
It's a mess.
She showed me where the baby
was supposed to sleep,
and it was disgusting.
She asked if we could
help fix it up.
- Now that we know
the baby's mine--
- So she wants money for this?
She doesn't have any
herself, Mom.
I'm well aware
of that, Connor.
God, don't worry about it.
I'll take care of everything.
( kisses )
I'll take care of it.
social media that
the baby's Connor's.
She even posted
a picture of the test.
Hey, I was
calling, and...
( whispering ) I was calling
and texting you all night.
The results came back.
I heard. Is that why you went
and stayed at Heather's house?
To celebrate?
What are you
talking about?
I came home.
Connor, you texted me
saying that you were
staying there.
No, I didn't.
You can stop with
the stupid little
games, Heather.
I mean, really. Texting me
that Connor stayed over?
Pathetic.
What's pathetic
is you believing
everything
Connor tells you,
or doesn't.
In case you forget,
he never told you that
he slept with me before,
so why would he
tell you the truth now?
♪ She welcomed me
with open arms ♪
♪ She gave me coffee,
chips and charms ♪
♪ And that's love ♪
♪ She gave me life
and she gave me friends ♪
♪ But whisper tells me
it's all pretend ♪
♪ And that's love ♪
♪ That's love ♪
- Are you
Heather's father?
- Yeah. Who are you?
I'm Diane Walker.
My son is the father
of your daughter's child.
Okay, I get it.
No, no, I don't think
you do get it,
Mr. Henderson.
You see, my son
has a very, very
bright future,
and, well, quite frankly,
a baby isn't part
of his plan.
Okay, so what
you're saying is that
your son knocks up
my daughter,
- and now he ain't
gonna step up?
- I'm saying,
my son made
a mistake,
one which
I'm pretty sure
your daughter planned.
Which is
why I'm here--
to make good
on that plan.
That should help
raise the child
for the next seven
or eight years,
and after that,
we can make other
arrangements, but only
if Heather stays
away from my son.
- Are we clear?
- Oh, yeah.
Then if we have a deal,
I need you to sign these.
Cool.
Wouldn't you like
your copy?
You want to come inside
and have a drink or something?
Bein' neighborly.
Ha!
MYA:
Hey, check this out.
I'm sure these will
piss Heather off,
since I bet nobody decided
to throw her a baby shower.
- What?
- It's not a game, Mya.
I know that.
But she's playing like
it is, so you have to too.
I mean, you believe
she's the one who
texted you, right?
She's messing with you,
Amanda.
Look, you've got to give
Connor a chance here.
He's been
texting me today.
Wants to know
if he can see me.
Then forget the crazy bitch
and go.
- ( phone beeps )
- ( gasps ) Look at that.
One "like" already.
( chuckles )
I'm so not surprised
we're having a boy.
I mean, I've been
dreaming about this.
You and me
taking him
to his first
ball game.
( giggling )
Oh, by the way,
did you talk to your mom
about getting money
for the "renos"?
Yep. She said she'd
help take care of it.
Good!
- You want to come in?
- ( phone beeps )
Ah, I can't.
I got to be somewhere.
( exclaims )
Fine!
Dad?
( phone beeps )
( exclaims )
Look, I know
things are really
messed up right now,
and you have every
reason to doubt me,
but you got to know...
it's you.
I mean, it has
always been you.
I love you, Amanda,
and I will do
everything I have to
to win your trust back.
( laughing )
Not so fast!
( clears throat )
What's going on?
It appears Heather's
father has left.
Uh, he left because
your mom tried
to pay him off.
And now I don't even
have a dad.
So this is the only place
I could think of to go.
Is this true?
- I was trying to
help you, Connor.
- How is that helping, Mom?
She's pregnant with my kid.
she can't just be living
in the streets.
Amanda!
Hey, Amanda, wait.
This doesn't change
anything, all right?
What do you mean,
it doesn't change
anything, Connor?
It's obvious where
she's gonna be staying--
with you.
And that...
that changes everything.
( car door opens, shuts )
( engine starts )
( car drives away )
( sobbing )
Hey.
What's wrong?
Are you okay?
I don't think
I can do this.
This... is amazing.
In the past couple weeks,
I really feel like
I've been eating for two.
Oh, by the way,
there's a school
field trip next week,
and I was hoping
maybe you could sign
the permission form.
It's, like,
20 bucks to go.
So, um, Heather,
have you started
thinking about a plan
- for you, for the baby?
- Yeah, I have.
I was thinking maybe
we could set up a room here,
like a nursery,
and Connor and I
could live here,
unless, of course,
you wanted us to
live somewhere else,
and I'm sure you guys would
help us out with
a down payment.
PETER:
Well, Connor needs
to finish school.
And by "school"
I mean college.
Whittendale.
Actually,
I've decided to stay.
Go to community college.
That way I can still get
my degree and at least
be here, you know,
for everything.
But that doesn't mean
I'm moving out.
Amanda and I still
haven't talked about
our plan yet.
( line ringing )
( ringing )
Hey, it's me, Amanda.
Leave me a message.
CONNOR:
Hey, Amanda.
Listen, I meant it when
I said nothing's changed.
Trust me.
Let me pick you up
for breakfast tomorrow,
and then I'll take you
to Lamaze. Please.
I love you.
Uh, are you lost?
Would you like me
to show you back
to your room
on the other side
of the house?
( wry chuckle )
Good night.
Brought you
something to eat.
Look, Amanda,
I understand it must be
so hard knowing that
Heather's over at Connor's,
but he's just trying
to do the right thing.
I know.
It's just,
so much has happened,
and the babies
haven't even come yet.
Connor's not ready
to be a dad.
Not to two kids.
Maybe keeping the baby
isn't the best decision.
What are you saying?
Maybe Kelly and Greg
are better parents.
Oh, Amanda, sweetie.
Look,
giving up a child
is one of the most
difficult things
a mother can do.
- Have you talked
to Connor about this?
- No.
You need to,
because this is a decision
that you need to make
together, okay?
( beeps )
- Hey, sleepyhead.
You slept in.
- Where's my mom?
Oh, she had
a hair appointment
or some stupid errand.
I don't know.
( giggles )
I made you
ham and eggs.
- My dad already left
for his trip?
- Yeah.
He was gone by the time
I got up this morning.
Left a hot new Mercedes
in the garage.
What's the deal?
Does he get a new one
every year or something?
Yeah, it's a company car.
They lease it to him.
Mm, nice.
We should break in
to that one too.
( giggles )
- Where are you going?
- Just out.
Well, I thought
that we could spend
the day together,
look at cribs
and stuff.
Heather, you're not due
for another six weeks.
- Are you going to
see Amanda?
- ( scoffs )
- Connor!
- ( door shuts )
( car engine starts )
( car drives away )
( garage door opens )
- What nice wheels.
- What the hell are
you doing here?
I came to see
how much swag
you ditched me for.
Where are you going?
Hey.
It's not bad.
I could use one of these,
seeing as they took my truck.
They wouldn't repossess it
if you got a job.
That's a great idea.
Oh, you know
what's a better idea?
I was thinking about this
on my ride over here.
Seeing as
one of your plans
finally seems
to have worked out,
I figure that you...
you can start paying me.
- Screw you, Trent.
- Yeah, you did that
already.
Remember?
Now it's my turn
to screw you.
Look, if you don't start
throwing a little
something my way,
I'm gonna make things...
I'm gonna make things
really uncomfortable
for you here.
You forget that
I know you.
I know who
you really are.
You tell that kid about
the other rich dude you
tried to hook up with?
You tell him about
your miscarriages?
There's a ball of secrets.
So I recommend
you just pay me.
Where's their jewelry?
Hmm?
I can tell by
that belly of yours
you've been
putting in some work.
You're such
a little slut.
( exclaiming )
( Heather grunting )
WOMAN:
All righty, everyone.
Today, we are going
to practice
breathing.
So, now,
let's take
a deep, cleansing
breath in...
( inhaling )
and out.
- ( exhaling )
- And now I want
all the partners
breathing as well, okay?
And breathe in...
( inhaling )
Now, partners,
I want you to wrap
your arms
around the mother
as she leans back
into you.
Excellent. Okay.
Oh! Did you feel that?
Yeah, she's always active
during this time.
- Did you feel that?
- Yeah. That's incredible.
I know.
WOMAN:
All righty, everybody,
I want you to
continue practicing
your breathing
techniques,
and we will see
you next week.
( engine starts )
Look, Connor,
I know you've been
trying, but...
I've been thinking a lot
about you being a dad
not to just one
but to two babies.
I mean,
you're only 17.
And trust me, I know
that you would give up
anything for our baby,
just like I would,
but what if
there's another way?
A way that we could
give our baby
the best life possible
and make someone
very, very happy?
I just want you
to think about
what I'm about to say.
What are you
talking about?
I'm talking about
giving our baby
to my sister.
I mean, she's been
trying everything,
and nothing's working,
and it's breaking her heart.
And here I am, pregnant,
and I didn't plan for this.
So it made me wonder that
maybe this is a sign.
Maybe I was supposed
to get pregnant,
and she's meant
to have the baby.
So this is what
you want to do?
If you do.
I-I don't know.
I really don't know.
And that's why
I love you.
( screaming )
( gasps )
( tapping glass )
Get out of the car.
Get out of the car!
What the hell do you
think you're doing?
I called the police
'cause I thought somebody
had stolen the car.
What made you think
you could take Peter's car
without even asking, huh?
Really?
That's it?
No apology?
You listen to me.
You know you're not a part
of this family, Heather.
You're only here
because of my grandchild.
So don't make yourself
so damned comfortable.
Because Connor won't
have you, ever!
I am just so sick of you,
you meddling bitch!
You just can't
leave us alone, can you?
I mean, don't you get it?
I am having your son's baby.
Me. That's right.
The girl from the wrong side
of the tracks.
Is that what's
so horrifying to you?
That I'm not good enough?
What's so horrifying to me
is what kind of person you are.
Manipulative,
conniving.
In fact, I'm now
really worried
whether you're
even a fit mother
for my grandchild.
- ( exclaims )
-Are you insane?
- What is wrong with you?
- Don't you mess with me
or my baby, Diane,
because you will be
so sorry!
What's up, buddy?
So, how'd you sleep
last night?
Fine.
Did you get any?
No, hey, hey, hey,
how is it to hook up
with a pregnant chick?
- Dude, what are you
talking about?
- Oh, okay.
You're not gonna
tell me? Bro...
Look.
( phone beeps )
You're a freak, bro.
You're a freak.
( door shuts )
What happened?
The mother of
your child, Heather,
just went crazy.
Look, Connor, she can't
stay here anymore.
That's it. I won't have it.
I will pay to have her
put up somewhere,
but she is not staying
in this house.
I am not going to be
assaulted in my own home.
That's it.
She hurt you?
I got it.
- Get out.
- Look.
I thought I'd use this photo
until we get a real photo
of the three of us together.
You have crossed
the line.
I mean, taking
pictures of us
sleeping together
is bad enough,
but when you hurt
my mom, that's it.
- I want you out!
- Really? And why do you think
I'm here in the first place?
Or did you forget
what your mother did?
I don't care, Heather.
Okay?
I am done being the good guy
because you are crazy!
Okay? It doesn't matter
how many pictures you take
of us together,
we are not a couple!
Because I love Amanda.
And you?
I don't even like you.
Wait. Wait!
Connor! I didn't mean
to hurt your mom!
Connor, I'm sorry!
Connor! Connor!
Connor!
Have you thought at all
about what we talked about?
Kelly and the baby?
Yeah.
And I'm starting to think
maybe you're right.
Maybe there is a reason
you got pregnant.
( screams )
JEFF:
Okay, it's ready.
Dad, will you hand me
a hot dog, please?
- Yes, sweetie.
- Thank you.
- Remember I like
my burgers rare.
- Yes, sir.
Kelly, Greg, uh,
Connor and I have
something we want
to ask you.
We've been talking,
and of course we want
what's best for
our little girl,
and we've agreed that
the best is you two.
I'm not following.
We want to know if
you'd adopt our baby.
Are you serious?
I mean, you guys
have wanted this
for so long,
and you would just be
amazing parents.
( voice quavering )
Amanda, are you sure?
We're sure.
I don't know what to say.
- Say yes.
- ( laughing, sobbing )
Thank you, thank you!
- Congratulations.
- I'm assuming that
that's a yes.
Yes, of course it is.
You guys are
gonna be great.
Thank you.
- JEFF:
I want to do a toast.
- Yes.
- To family.
- ALL: To family.
We're gonna
have a baby!
It's okay.
( beeping )
( chuckles )
.
If you haven't
handed me
a signed permission form
to go on this field trip,
you can't go.
- Does everyone
understand that?
- ALL: Yes.
All right? Okay.
Line up.
- Is Heather coming?
- I think so.
My mom signed her form.
( gasps, groans )
( bus engine starts )
( groans )
MRS. WOLK:
All right, everybody,
buckle up. Let's go.
( students chattering )
Yay! We're here!
All right, we're going to
break up into two groups.
Group A goes into
the conservation center
with Gray Eagle,
and group B will
join me in the park.
- Are you gonna be okay?
- Yeah. I'll be fine.
All right, everyone,
let's go.
MAN:
Have a wonderful day.
Follow me.
( groans )
Hey, check this out.
- ( chattering )
- Dude, look at this in here.
Mrs. Wolk, I have to
use the restroom.
Oh. Okay, there's one back
in the conservation center.
Take the shortcut,
but stay on the trail.
- I will.
- Okay.
( birds chirping )
( insects buzzing,
birds warbling )
( suspenseful music )
( gasps )
God, Heather!
What are you doing here?
Just making sure
you don't get lost.
You know, we were
planning on getting
our own place together
to raise our baby.
That's actually the reason
why his parents put me up
in an apartment--
because they just
couldn't handle the fact
that their precious Connor
wasn't theirs anymore.
- You're lying, Heather.
That was never going to happen.
- No?
You know that picture
of you two next to his bed?
He actually put that away
and replaced it with
a picture of our ultrasound.
And I never asked him to.
He just did it.
And he just loves
my pregnant body.
And the best part is,
we don't have to use
any protection.
It's just so awesome.
It's so intimate.
It's just me, him,
and his baby.
Just stop, Heather!
He'd never sleep with you,
all right?
He doesn't love you,
and he's said so himself.
I mean, God, when are
you gonna get it
through that twisted
head of yours
that you're just
a mistake that he made?
Your little plan to
trap him or whatever
obviously backfired,
'cause where are you now?
You're alone
in some apartment,
and soon you're gonna
be alone with a baby
to take care of.
Is that what you wanted?
'Cause if it is,
congratulations--
you got it.
You stupid bitch!
Why?
Why did you have to
get pregnant?
He didn't want you!
He wanted me!
And he still does!
Because he promised that
he will take care of me!
Of us! And you?
Why are you trying
to ruin this? Why?
You already have
a family!
And what do I have?
I have nothing!
Everyone in my life
has left me. Do you
know what that's like?
No, of course you don't,
because you have everything
that you want,
you stupid, spoiled,
selfish little bitch!
Miss Wolk.
Where's Amanda?
I thought she came back
to use the restroom.
I didn't see her.
- Let me go check.
- Okay.
Have you guys
seen Amanda?
Ladies, have you
HEATHER:
Amanda!
( gasping )
( gasps )
( screams )
( groaning )
She's not there.
Okay, I want everyone
inside, and stay there
until the next lecture.
( moaning softly )
( groaning )
Amanda!
The baby's coming!
Amanda, please help!
Come back, please!
The baby's coming!
I need your help!
( screaming )
Amanda!
The baby's coming!
Help!
Amanda, help!
- We have to get you back.
- No, I can't!
- I don't know. Um...
- Oh, do something!
Okay, give me your shirt.
Give me your shirt.
Amanda!
Okay, I need you
to push.
- I can't!
- Heather,
I need you to push!
- ( cries out )
- Push!
- I can't!
- Breathe!
- ( panting )
- Heather, do you want
to have this baby?
- Yes!
- Then push!
( groaning, screams )
( screaming )
- ( baby crying )
- ( Heather gasps )
( groans, laughs )
Amanda! Amanda!
It's our baby, Connor.
It's our baby!
AMANDA:
Oh, my gosh.
She's so adorable.
CONNOR:
Look at that.
Look at her smile.
Hi, little girl.
I have just been
dying to meet you.
( sniffles )
This is your daddy.
He loves you
very much.
We both do.
That's why
it was so hard
to do what's best
for you right now.
( sniffles )
But don't you worry.
We'll always
be here for you.
And one day,
you will have
a little cousin
that you can
play with.
( whispering )
I love you, baby girl.
With all of my heart.
Are you ready?
KELLY:
Hey.
How are you both doing?
- Okay.
- She's beautiful,
just like you.
I mean,
look at that nose.
( chuckles )
There's no doubt
she's your baby.
She's yours, Amanda.
Yours and Connor's.
You're her parents.
It wouldn't be
right for us to
take her from you.
But you've wanted
a family for so long,
and you were so happy.
There's still
time for me.
Don't worry.
I'll be just fine.
Besides,
I am going to be
the coolest aunt
in the world.
I love you.
I love you too.
Knock, knock.
How's my little girl
and my granddaughter?
- Hi!
- Perfect.
Oh!
- Oh, there's my boy.
- There he is.
- How's he doing?
- Oh, he's doing great. He's
gaining a pound a day, I bet.
This kid, he has
an iron grip.
He grabs a hold
of your finger,
and he never lets go.
He's gonna be a bruiser
like his dad.
We just wanted to
come by and say hi.
We want to give
you guys your privacy.
We'll come back
a little later.
Hold on. I want to
get a picture first.
Connor, you're there
next to Amanda.
You and Ryan.
This is gonna be
our first family portrait.
All right, now,
just hold that pose
and say "cheese."
All right, now, everyone,
a selfie. Let's do it.
- Selfie!
- AMANDA: Mom, did you
just say "selfie"?
- Yes.
- Parents aren't allowed
to say "selfie."
- Yeah, we are.
- No, you're not.
- We old folks get
to do it too!
- She loves these.
Cheese!
Say "selfie."
Well, they found Trent's body
in your basement.
Your dad was out of town,
so all the evidence
points to you.
If you don't take the plea,
it's life in prison,
no parole.
Take the plea, you might
be out in 20 or less
with good behavior.
Whatever.
Can I get some water?
Sure.
( buzzer sounds )
( beeps )
♪ All I need ♪
♪ Is some sunshine ♪
Don't worry.
We'll be together soon.
( chuckles )
♪ All I need ♪
♪ All I need is ♪
♪ Some sunshine ♪
( chuckling )
- ♪ All I need ♪
- ( shutter clicking )
( clicking continues )
♪ Yo! ♪