-= ***** =-
Created by CyberBlade
no matter how busy he got, he
always find time for his animals
my name is Brandy
I am an astray?
that's ok. We're all astray
I know the first's gonna take you time
one part a time
never ever give up hope
not just Brandy, and all you dogs
listen to me
every dog in here is gonna find a
family and be somebody's best friend
let me hear you say that
say I'm somebody's best friend
I'm somebody's best friend
one more time again
that's right
there's also at the north beach
who's trying to find a good watchdog
to prevent housebreaking
and great with kids
you guys got a background in security?
that'll be Rusty
he wants to be a watchdog
who's Rusty
Rusty, oh no
it's better be important
I say must learn to lick ass
every zoo in the country got
a job for the doc
how long ago did you guys
make a little turtle?
not that long, maybe 20 years
gonna be 40 years next Monday
I see what the problem is
I'm gonna give you this pill
I want you to crush it up
and put it in as food
what did they do?
you're looking fine
I'm coming at you
there we give an international celebrity
traveling from Alaska to Australia
I'm here with the world famous Dr. Dolittle
who actually speaks with animals
what're we gonna do?
we sneak up on this unsuspected alligator
we better be quiet or he'll know we're here
the trick to catch it is to wear
teeth this big
when he catches me
I'm gonna bite his hands off
I think he knows. . .
it seems every wants to be a
patient of a good doctor
his family understood
most families did
right now I gotta answer the door
who's there?
it's me . I forgot my key, open up
I guess you gotta beg
come on boy, beg
role reversal
usually it's human
you better open up
just open the door
since you're the one who feeds me
I'm gonna let you in this time
guess who's back from France
I got you from Paris
it's for me
I can enjoy this present as well
you know what'll be a really nice present?
it's you keep that flock off
I got you a present from Mexico
can I see it?
don't shake . 91 1
don't shake
it's a camellia. lt can change colors
the black master is in the house
I'm gonna disappear for a while
now you see me . Now you don't
am I gone? Am I not invisible?
you remember Cherry's birthday?
sure I do . You remember to get
the cake from Stancy?
actually Cherry doesn't wanna have a family party
we always celebrate together
get this thing off
she got a date
a date with who?
I didn't ask. She is a big girl now
we'll see a out this dating
where's the birthday anyway?
she is unreachable
what do you mean? Where is she?
she is her room with the dog
and the earphones on
you can try paging her
she is unreachable in my house
and I have to page her?
see who am I gonna page?
be careful doc
she is 1 6
open the door
can you believe it?
try your cell
I'm not trying to call her on the cell phone
while she in her bedroom
open the door
ok alright
doesn't I teenager get the right
to drive and drink?
what're you drinking?
give it to me
Gaedali make wine now?
you better slow down
which one is Dolittle
what now?
I have a message from the boss
from the who?
the boss
save the question
come with me
you guys know the rules
don't just come up here
without an appointment
make an appointment
now go tell the beaver make an appointment
just like everyboby else
I can't turn there . I'm not with the fishes
how's going to look in the paper?
doctor Dolittle go past the roof
that's not right
now leave cos I'll
watch your tone buddy
talk
this is your daddy. How are you?
I got a question for you
why am I on the outside talking
to you on the cell phone?
what am I doing?
it's the only way to reach you
what are you doing here?
what's all this about?
dance of course
that's not dance that's advertise
you don't wanna spend your
birthday with your family?
I had to have dinner when I was younger
now I'm turning 1 6
besides I have a date
you can bring him here
cos you're having dinner here
my parents and my little sister
are gonna join us on our date?
you're joining us. We have it every year
what's this?
that's private
I can see why it's private
it's embarrassing
since you got 2 Cs and a D on here
you should be the last person
talking about being embarrassing
what are you talking about?
what is it supposed to mean
you mean I should my work and everything
is it what you mean being embarrassing?
it's not going to happen
that's right. You're going to dinner
no cell phone for a week
what am I supposed to do
without my cell phone?
you cab learn to write some letters
look at me don't I look like care?
this is unbelievable
she has 50 numbers
none of them is mine
you shouldn't be looking at it
why not?
who the hell is biggie Mac?
I don't know
I'm gonna find out
I don't like that name
what the hell kinda name is that?
what is that?
max's cell phone?
when did he get a cell phone?
I'm asking a question, punk
it's none of your damn business
it's my business to find out
how old you are
are you threatening me?
no but I'm coming to you whenever. . .
I'm so sorry that's a wrong number
that was an old man on the cell phone
I wish I could say the same thing about you
the door
go get the door
doctor D, what's up? lt's me
me who is me? Back off me
you don't know me?
doctor D, what is going on?
you deliver pizza?
I forgot to give you a tip I'm sorry
it's cool you do don't have to give a petty tip
this is your date?
this is Eric
Eric this is my dad
my man, what's up?
we need to stay to have family dinner
this is cool with me
don't be like that
you're gonna ruin the dinner for everybody
don't worry
I know how to take of it
pup?
Charliz always has a mind of her own
a year and a half
she decided not to wear diapers
anymore, remember that?
then she started to make
messes around the house
it's cool I can actually learn something
you're really something?
cos you've never to take off
your hat at the dinner table
is your head being hot or what?
1 6
just think in 2 years she is out of the
house and on her way to college
one year and 1 0 months 1 6 days
Berkeley is a close college
if you go there, you can live
at home and save some money
that's a good idea
but I already reserved a college
when I graduate from high school
you reserved already?
someone to see you
excuse me darling
I love you too
you down here
what do you want?
first of all let me beaver wants to
sent a birthday greeting
to your loving daughter
that's very nice
you go tell beaver start getting
out of my nerves
he only wants some moment of your time
what if I say no
I think you need to go in that room
you go tell the beaver
be in my office 8 o'clock tomorrow
he knows you're busy
but this is really a matter
of life or death situation
in my car, 7 am . Alright?
this is good news
the beaver likes good news
Jimmy, get the car
blow the candles and make a wish
surprise
give me that
I'm gonna eat that
you lick my fat bump
don't be a pig
we're trying to do something nice
to your daughter
you're not 2 little cute kitties
you're just 2 disgusting rats
no, we are not
you just ruined the birthday cake
if you write backward of rats
it's stars
I'm your star
you know hospital backward?
yes it is
diapers!
my favorite, chocolate
say miya
what do you think you're doing?
I think he's about to say something
bring me a bone
bring me a large plate of flies
super size
you'll bring me ham
can I talk to Charliz a second?
I'm sorry about tonight
I'm thinking about cutting a little work
and spend more time with you guys
great more animals will be here
what if we don't stay here
what about a big vacation in Europe
the whole family?
are you serious?
we're going to Paris, Rome, Greeks
just do it
what do you think?
is it a bribe?
yes, it's a bribe
it's working
yo doc, one more thing I forgot to tell you
tomorrow
tomorrow, we're going to Europe
so the raccoon and the parcel
take the road trip to meet the beaver
nice wheel, what do you call this thing?
this is a mustang
any car that's named after me?
I'm gonna be go over a couple of rules
rule number 1, no sudden movement
number 2, do not stare at his teeth
he's got a little rodent bite
I think he needs bracing
but I'm not a dentist
number 3 to 1 0
show with respect he deserves
we're talking about the beaver, right?
how're you doing?
how's the hanging?
back away
show some respect to it
the raccoon got a doctor
it's a miracle
doctor Dolittle I presume
welcome to my bed
do you like a fish
on, I've eaten already
when the beaver offers you a fish
you just take the fish
shut up
sorry boss
I read some of the good things
of your bay area family
bay area family
what are you guys
some Mafia or something?
we don't know anything about Mafia
I've never heard of it
that's myth
I'm just a simple fisherman
I'll only be blessed to make friends
you'd be one
what you guys from me?
I'm losing my territory
are other animals moving in
on you or something?
the human kind . They're cutting
down our homes
busting our families
we hear they're cutting down the whole forest
you're talking to the wrong person
you gotta contact the nature groups like
that has to be you
you are the only one who know
how to speak human
we can't fight humans on my own
they got guns, knives and pull out couches
sure I got rabies, I can bite
but I really can't do so much
you guys have no idea what I'm
talking about, do you?
it's human against nature
but with you on our side that'd be nice
me on your side, I didn't say
I was gonna help you
I didn't say it
before you say no
I'd like you to see what we're talking about
it's gone
everything gone
how do you save the forest anyway?
it's not gonna be easy
I assume the lumber companies
have a lot of crowd
but I do know a few endangered
species living in the forest
who definitely have lost the protective
how am I gonna find how many endangered
animals living in the forest
you can ask Eugine
we find the endangered species
the females killed by the poachers
it's the only western Pacific bear
at least one bear has to be protected, right?
let the lawyer of the logging
company argue this
since she is the only up there
there's no chance for survival anyway
there had to be a male too
so we get a male up there
and let them together
let nature take its course
the only male western Pacific bear
we can find is raised in captivity
never has a bear raised in captivity
been successfully reintroduced to the wild
they never have a world famous doctor
make an introduction
your man left the button open
something wrong?
I hope he didn't see it
I know you're really disappointed
disappointed?
about not going to Europe?
why'd I be disappointed?
I made you a promise
and I'm gonna stick to it
you don't want me to it
I understand
if I say no . I'll regret for the rest of my life
when do we leave?
as soon as we get the court order
to stop the tree cutting
who is going to argue the case?
why are you looking around?
me?
not me, you
for the animals
I don't do the animals
you are a speciest
we're asking for an injunction
so that we might the chance
to save the species
this is a delaying tactic a publicity stunt
I have an afidavit signed a range
of experts who'll take them
a bear raised in captivity is
reintroduced to the wild
it's dangerous and irresponsible
simply raised by a circus who
don't know how to feed
let alone let it through its first winter
it 'll certainly succumb to Darwin's law of nature
survival of the fittest
but Darwin never met my dad
young lady, that's inappropriate behavior
who's your father?
it's me . I'm her father
my name is Dolittle
doctor Dolittle
do you feel you can rehabilitate
and make it in the wild for the female?
yes I do
in that case I'll delay one month
one month, that's it
if that bear is capsized in this month
I'll dismiss the order
I understand completely
thank you your honor
you can speak with the wild animals
and the circus bears?
I don't know much about it
I only know it's living in captivity
I bet they'll be happy to return to the wild
so much for a family vacation
can doctor figure how much it's gonna be?
that's before he met Acher
you know what I'm talking about?
no, listen .you'll be lucky
winning somebody like her
I've had so many girlfriends
I never have a girlfriend
just bring her by on Monday
I can't her here
you have to go to her
go to her, where?
she is in the forest
I don't play in the forest
do you what kind of beer you are?
I'm a singer, dancer
you're an endangered species
is that a threat? Cos my lawyer. . .
you're a very rare bear. You're
called the western Pacific bear
I know I can play any bears
western, polar
I'm freezing
your ancestors came from the
mountain of California
when you were 6 months they
took you from your mother
they taught how to dance
according to a hound dog
I taught myself that
cos I'm a panda bear
yes funny stuff
what I'm proposing to you is
I'd like you back to your ancestors' room
and teach you to be a real bear
I like the bear I'm... I'm famous
do you have a gift shop?
I have my own baby
you do this I promise you'll
be the most famous bear in the world
famous that pooh
are you kidding me?
you pull this off and you're saying
Winnie the who?
you got yourself a bear?
and what's the most unusual
story of the year
doctor Dolittle is going to
rewrite the law of nature
by tempting to reintroduce a
performing bear into the wild
and in doing do hoped to save an
entire force from destruction
it's Darwin versus Dolittle
get over yourself
I got 2 lumber millers waiting for that wood
I understand but it's complicated
especially if that bear survives
you're the one who's going to be endangered
that bear is bound to screw up
when he does, have yourselves a little toy
I have just the place to put it
so we're going to the forest
waiting for Acher to arrive
when the family's settled
I'm starting to look for mount number one
looks like a good place
simple pleasure
that woof is a fox
you like that
there's more where I came from
what is that?
some kinda secret lady dog's code
you like me?
this is called back scratching
where are you going?
call me
so the big day finally came
I have a feeling
the fur is gonna fly
you all know why we're here
we're about to do something
we've never done before
everyone thinks we can't pull this off
they got their blaze sharpened
truck ready to roll
we're going to prove them wrong, right?
I want everybody to put their claw together
how about an applause for the bear
who is going to leave?
are you going to save the forest?
reach further
is it some kinda joke?
I wanna go serious on you for a second
I got my work cut out
but with your help I know. . .
one thing
the show is over
you got your work cut out for you pal
ok I'm done . Turn it off
it's so dirty
yes, it's a shit hole
is that her?
she is a babe
look at the way she walks
I love her wet
I'm going over to introduce you
you just wait here
tell her I really her fat pouch
but don't be cruel
I'll try to work that
are you coming over here?
I'm real busy foraging
my name is John
I'm Eva
that's a pretty name
nice to meet you
a quick question
how would you like to meet your man of dream?
you're real cute
but I don't go for the other species
I'm not talking about man
I'm talking about a male bear
how would you like to meet the
big magnificent male over there
I don't think I see him
is he standing behind that tree?
let me explain what's going on
there's a logging company that's
trying to tear down this forest
the only I can stop is
I bring 2 western Pacific bear together
you're a western Pacific bear so is he
if I can the 2 of you together
and you make a little western Pacific bear
you see where I'm going?
hey Acher come over here
I think we can work it out
what do I say to her?
tell her a little more about yourself
I like walking on the beach
and sharing pop corns with someone
and also the sound of back street boys
you're weird
weird? Isn't sexy
why don't you let me take it from here
what do you think of Acher, cute?
don't make me eat you
I know he's a little uncomfortable
with female around
that's not even the point
I need a real bear
someone who can hunt and provide for me
I'm already involved with someone
you have a bear friend already
are you in love with this bear
my cousin married for love but she
know her husband has another in the north
so you're not in love
so let's make a deal
in one month's time, I'm going to
turn that bear into someone
you'll be proud to have little baby bears of
perfect night
so you're just breathing the country air
and listening to the crickets chirping?
you know what the crickets are saying?
I don't know. You're the one who
speaks to the animals
a monkey don't come to me asking
for malt of 40 ounce
I can't do that I stay in the room
you ever seen me talk to an animal?
slow down a little
the crickets are the human temperature
you can tell how colder it is
the faster they're chirping
it seems a little colder
what's up baby?
maybe you should tell me what's up
I'm gonna stay a couple of days if it is cool
what is that you don't understand?
his bag
he's staying for a couple of nights
mama said so
you're gonna sleep on the
sleeping bag on the floor
by the way I'm watching you
not just me I got all the eyes all around the woods
you know I talk to birds, right?
you watch your back
I'm watching you
can we see what else is on?
no you gotta watch this and learn
how to survive in the winter
what's he doing? Digging?
you don't even know what sharp
claws are for?
bears're excellent swimmers
not this bear
you're not just sitting there telling
me you can't swim
haven't you ever heard there is a
new invention called boat
tomorrow we're gonna get up at the crack of dawn
I'm gonna teach you how to fish
and so began the bearathon
the training is so unbearable
so hairy. Ok, that's all
this might be full of fish . Let's go
so are lobsters
look at the water
that's where the fish is
there's one touched me
I want you to put your head
down and grab a fish
I want you to do just like what you saw on TV
put your head under the water and catch a fish
I'm here with you . Go under water
I'm trying
that's Achder
what's up?
you get one
I can't breathe
tell me how smart you can be to
lift your head out of the water
when you can't breathe?
I saw a light
it was beautiful
let me take you for a swim
that'll sharpen you up
we're gonna find something you can catch
I saw my grandmum
come on eat
am I close?
cold
and the force
colder? Warmer
attic
how is going?
it's going great. We bare need 3 weeks
he's already foraging grapes
I can't see why he's walking away
he's circling the grapes
why? Are they dangerous grapes?
grapes are not dangerous?
he's doing great. We're right on schedule
explain it to me again
I'm going to crawl into a dark space
and sleep for 6 months
it's called hyphenation
it sounds depressing
how do I eat?
you eat a lotta enough and last the whole winter
where is the bathroom?
a week before you start hyphenating
you eat dirt, moss, hair and green glass
it blocks my butt?
you want me to sleep for 6 months
with a big cork in my butt
come back here see ya
I'll leak the gas and sleep in
the back with the kids
this isn't gonna work
I almost drowned
Evy doesn't like me
I'm sick and tired of your complaints
look up at the tree, what do you see?
a bird
a bird and its home
and below is a squirrel
down is a little rabbit in his home
all these animals are depending on you
you can do it. Just listen to your inner bear
just trust him
he'll tell you what to do
is it really necessary?
go in there
why?
there're a couple of bears inside
who want to meet you
do I hear someone talking
these kids today have no respect
I think he needs us to teach him a lesson
get over here I'm gonna give you a bear hug
actaully it's going quite well
looks like everybody like music
while the cats are away, the mouse will play
I mean teenagers
you gotta a cover
there is something I've been
meaning to do since I gotta here
what is that?
your plan worked out
the drink is on me
mean while the doc's giving Acher a lesson
could you leave a little for me
cos technically it belongs. . .
just a thought
what's going here?
you don't have to put up
with that, get out of here
that's one hot fox
don't you know every female is looking
for the strongest female
what about personality?
I'd rather die a virgin
alpha male is the boss. lt is the boss male
alpha male should learn how to walk
like an alpha male
walk the walk
it's about power
unchecked, uncompromise
didn't I ask you to line the garbage pales
you line them you damn self
what?
I was talking with the animals
I'm on my way. I'm going to
get food right here
go I'm going?
where're you going?
talk the talk. shut up
you telling me to shut up?
I am talking to the animals
I'm going to get the food
sure you don't want this thing?
I have a question
you say you'll spend your
whole life in show business
when is it gonna be a big finish?
I mean in life
who do you share your success with?
your hopes, dreams, fear and failure
sometimes I'm lonely
I've never been in love
this is your chance
I think Evy really likes you
did she say something?
you gotta read between the line
she loves me? I knew it
you shouldn't be carried away
I think it's the mushroom cos
you've eaten a whole bag
tomorrow you're gonna see a brand new bear
I think I'll call it a night
it's a little scary out here
can you stay until I fall asleep
I'll wait until you fall asleep
can you leave a light on?
the light stays on
keep this here
it's a new Acher in town
feel windy
feel the muscle cramp
don't quit
my butt stinks
can you rub my butt, please
doc finally realized he wasn't able to make
Acher fast enough to impress Evy
maybe he can make him sweater
how can anybody be so beautiful
why don't you go over and tell her?
that's Sunny, her little bear friend
don't get discouraged
you can win her over
you just figure out what she likes
let's take my wife . .
I'm sorry
she likes to be surprised
like jumping out of the bushes and sreaming?
do something romantic
say I'm thinking about you all the time
you're always on my mind
you say that all the time?
I used to
lately I'm caught up in this
I think I need a little practice
what are you doing?
it's all about you tonight
I sent the children up to the movies
and the bears camping in the woods
you can see me
I'm blending, getting interwoven . . .
I can give you some pointer
where were we?
you were thinking about the candles
and some wine would up make for
annoying me for the last few days
I know something that'll be able to resist
is it our wedding song?
that's not fair
show is about to start
what show?
he is good
he scratched my belly the other day
what's going on?
he is truly in love with her
give her some garbage
chicks like garbage
get out of here all of you
this is really helpful
I'm learning a lot, truly
we'll discuss tomorrow
you're gonna discuss what tomorrow?
why don't you sit on the couch?
what she said doc?
she said she loves me so much that
I can sleep on the couch
I'm a man on the couch
Romeo is on the move
there he goes
I was only going to the bathroom
you can hold it
what's wrong with your voice?
why don't you put some sugar in . . .
is that our song?
you should learn to climb trees
that's a bruise
come on out of there never
I'm sure it wasn't that bad
I understand . We can fix it
we just need to work a little harder
we're staying here we'll make
our own bear suit
cos we were wondering it'd be alright
if every animal in the entire forest
is going to stay with you next week?
I want you to come out right now
who are you calling a coward?
you're a big coward for a quit like this
my wife and my daughters are mad at me
I'm spending my vacation with a pizza boy
now listening to you furry cry baby telling me
it's too hard
Evy laughed at me
she is even better than a coward like you
I didn't poke a bear
I'm warning
I'm poking you
stop it
that was good, bear like
you just take your ass back to the circus
I'm an alpha bear
there was love in the air
be a man
now you listen to me
you're in my house now
you wanna go out with me tonight?
what you think you're doing?
I'm not doing anything
you marked my tree
I don't even know what those words mean
I drink a lot of water
it smells like lemonade
it smells like anomia
I'm getting dizzy
let's beat it
what're you doing?
we're having fun
you make a very handsome couple
I hate myself
if you want it I'll go up
don't even think about it
I'm gonna go get it for you
it's too dangerous. Promise me
I like you too
what're you girls doing over here?
beat it, circus boy
your charm is matched only by your odor
what's he saying? I'm confused
you think you get used to it?
maybe you'll be better being with me
don't do worse
you'll only be a city bear I need more than that
shall we put our cards on the table?
this bear you brought up here
is much likely to have little bear babies
it ain't gonna happen
here's my offer
I'll set aside 1 0 acres turning it into a sanctuary
you can bring your animal buddies there
that's the offer
the dead line is Wednesday 1 2 noon
let me be clear it's 1 2:01
we'll be sending every piece of equipment
we got. By Friday there won't be
a tree standing there
I need to run this by my wife
there's a pay phone in the back
phone the wife
always a sign of weakness
I know what to do I got my thing finished
I gotta tell you this thing is over
sorry to drag you in all of this
might as well give you an audition in Vegas
cos these guys offered me a deal
this is the best I can do
the best you can do is not give up on me
you told me, listen to your inner bear
I know how I can win Evy
I know I'm dumb or something
I'm giving you one more chance
the ice cream is acting up
I got depressed by Sunny and Eva
I realized I'm in love with Eva
don't you dare throw up on me
it's gonna come out
you gotta sit down on the toilet
you gotta lift it up first
I'm gonna keep guard you just sit there
I'll meet you one second
I gotta take care of some business
what are you talking in there?
I was talking to myself
I gotta. . .
sometimes I gotta coax it down
you must have some little pet talk
let me get the window open
it's worse than I thought
you just ate ice cream?
that's not ice cream
no deal . Thanks for your time
was that me?
I'm trying to blend
your mother is little worried
I knew something was bothering you
tell me
daughter to daddy
you wanna cry, we cry together
nothing stop
it must be the mountain messing me up I'm fine
you sure you're alright
take your time I'm in the house
talking time's done
it's time to be bold
he's going up to the high
this cliff is higher than I remember
you come back here . Get back
I'm doing it or die
what are you doing here?
I'm not gonna win Eva by
eating a bunch of worms
I need to show her how much
she means to me
if you fall you're just stupid
circus boy got a little trick
it's not gonna hold
I'll buy you the honey
break
I want you to come down
I'm fine
there're bees
don't move
they're sting me
protect the hive
jump circus boy
go eat the salmon
why'd you do something like that
are you crazy?
I could have got that hive if I wanted it
we're not working out
take a hike
I mean would you like more honey?
you're ready to talk about presuming the species
we could talk or you count to a
hundred and cone to get me
focus
I should really in the open
pace yourself not so fast
daddy is back
what happened?
it's Acher
folks we got a wild animal coming through
I'm doctor Dolittle
what happened?
he broke down the back door
we found him ransacking in the kitten
let's move up show is over
it's me what happened?
I was so close
they came out of no where
are you ready to save the forest?
we're setting aside 1 0 acres of the forest
we cal it doctor wild life sanctuary
speak of the devil
you think you've won but you haven't
thanks very much . That's all for today
we only have an eyewitness
did anybody see what happened?
we got one problem
it's a freaking weasel
what did he do?
weasel, the doctor is here
did you see what happen to the bear?
you give me your watch I'll
tell you what you need to know
you're such a weasel
an animal? You can't offer them evidence
you got a better idea?
I'll stall the trial maybe we hire
a private investigator
they're going to take Acher to Mexico
if you go on the witness stand
Riley is going to tear you to shreds
what do I have to lose?
your reputation
I'm not giving up these animals easy
we admit it was a setback
but we'd like one more week
to rehabitate the bear
what if I could prove the entire
thing is a setup?
that'd be a very serious allegation
do you intend to present the evidence?
we have an eyewitness
can I address to the court just a minute?
we have an eyewitness who can testify
he heard the gunshot and a truck
back to the area
is that witness here in the court?
it's not in the court cos he's. . .
he's a weasel
I know this seems very unreasonable
I can talk to animals
this did come forward
I have no problem doctor Dolittle
to question the witness
I'd like a brief recess so that I'll have
an opportunity to get a camera
to have a snapshot
if he needs immunity we can provide
animal protection
I'd not allow you to make a mockery
in my courtroom
the deadline has passed
the motion to delay is denied
that's a shame
could you tell us what the weasel
wanted to say?
you come to get me out?
what do you mean sort of?
I couldn't prove your story
they what?
they think you'd be too dangerous
to be set free
they sold you to a Mexican circus
everything . I dragged you out and
put you through all this stuff
like I've ruined your life
you gave me a life
you even taught me about love
no one can ever take that away from me
mama wanted me to tell you that
the appeal's been denied
you're back to your show business
I just want eva
maybe I wasn't meant to be loved
everybody is meant to be loved
since when?
a couple of weeks ago
at first I was kinda fuzzy
now I'm really clear
this is what you've been keeping from us right?
don't say anything cos I don't want to be a freak
you're not gonna be a freak
when it started to happen to me
I got scared too
this is a good thing
now I know what I've been missing
a family. I guess it's something I'll never have
you gotta help him
isn't there something that we can do?
not just him I mean all the animal
so many of them
there are so many of them
you guys have given up haven't you?
what am I gonna do, I'm 6 years old
I am not a young beaver no more
beside, we've been living
in this forest how long?
about 1 00 years we've been
shacking in the forest
I can't do this by myself
you guys wanna save your home
you gotta help me
whether you'll believe it
you guys have untapped power
you got a heart of the lion
or just strong like an ox
eyes like an eagle
movement swift like a gazette
or you stink like a skunk
sorry, I'm trying to make my point here
what I'm trying to say is
we can do this
just don't do it without a fight
listen don't stall with me
everybody take your position
roll them up
I have never seen anything like this before
none of them're having milk
what's wrong?
strike
go get the fribee
all the animals are working together
you'll be out of here in no time
animals can't organize
you may want to take a look at this yourself
maybe you should talk to Dolittle
giving in to a bunch of beasts
lowering our life form?
I can take democrats
I can take animals
retreat
organized
I heard something
don't make any move
you locked the door
I think you should run
I'm an attorney. I'm not with him
I'm sure we can work something out
I'm gonna call doctor Dolittle
no sudden move or I'm gonna bite you
Mr, Potter, how are you sir?
I'm here with a couple of your friends
I don't think you believe animals'd organize
I don't know what to think anymore
I'll be happy to set up a meeting
with you and the animals
so that we can work out our problem
it's the only way for you to admit
so you won't look like an idiot
just call them off
put the raccoon on the phone
he wants to speak to you
make it short
I got it all under control
I'll call you back
I'm here only a mediator
this negotiation is between Mr Potter
the representatives of the local wildlife
this is my new proposal
what kind of territory we're looking at
only 1 2 acres here
they like it
I'll give you something you like
like this
meanwhile the strike kept rolling
even the pros're getting in on the act
no, no . we won't go
you try running a mile
I don't feel like jumping any hoops today
hope you'll fill in there
give me a bear hug
you're not leaving here
until you get a bear hug
just a little one
you crushed my spine
drive safe now
are you in there?
I just stopped by to say hello
thanks for everything
Acher, I'm ready
she is in heat
gotta go save the species
it's quite a summer
what are you doing here?
Charliz and the doc were closer than ever
you'll blend trust me
look at me I'm blending again
right you're invisible
good job
they doubt the black master is back
I'm king of the third world
but the best news of all came
the following spring
step, step turn kick step
I thought it was step kick turn step, step
I thought you've retired.
ok, from the chorus