DR Goldfoot BIKINI MACHINE AND
It's going, Miss?
Here we are.
My speciality.
Cheese sandwiches.
Oh, I'm hungry!
You too, I hope.
A banquet fit for a queen ...
Your Majesty.
Her Majesty was not amused, stingy of Species!
A cheese sandwich in a cafeteria?
You call that a dinner?
But Louise is cheese of ?? import.
This is the famous ...
Louise tomorrow I have my pay.
We go out and we will have fun! Come back!
Milk.
You are fine?
I am doing very well.
And you?
Do not sit there, it's all dirty.
Put yourself out there preferably
You'll be much more comfortable.
Good thank you.
Thank you, thank you, sir.
You do not want mustard?
It's very kind of you, sir.
Taking care of a poor girl like me.
Oh, it's nothing.
I take the mustard and you could take too
since you eat my sandwich.
You are nice!
I'll tell you that there is something in you ...
That makes my poor little c ?? ur ...
pounding.
It's weird.
And you're weird.
I can sit?
I should be flattered.
M. Armstrong.
No, I'm Gamble.
Craig Gamble.
Oh, you laugh at me.
I know you are Todd Armstrong.
No, I tell you, my name is Craig Gamble.
I work in the headquarters of the secret services.
What is your name, my lovely?
Diane.
Something in your eye?
Old rascal.
I'll take care of you from now on.
I already have a mom.
Moron.
Not like a mother.
A sister?
Shut up.
Who Does else?
You have reached the voting age,
and you have no idea?
Yes, what I mean ...
How would you like to kiss me?
I love that embraces me.
In fact, I'm insatiable.
What is a girl like you rotten
done in a nice area like this?
Why do not we go with you to talk about ...
sweetie?
Chou?
Let's go.
Here we are.
This is not really classy, ​​but comfortable.
I like living a dream.
I just take your coat here, and ...
Put on your coat...
But my heart, I very hot without.
But you'll catch cold and die.
It is horribly hot here.
How can you sleep in such a small bed?
You see, I have a very good sleep.
I do not move a lot at night.
By cons, you move now.
You want something to drink?
To do what?
I thought maybe, finally ...
You would drink because ...
Come here, beautiful tiger.
Tiger?
they will never believe ..
HQ Secret Service!
Oh, calm down, baby!
Kiss Me!
I remember now!
You're part of the team Derby.
Old rascal.
I love you!
You are-and coco!
Igor!
Yes, Dr. Goldfoot?
Species of slouch!
I have done something wrong?
Something bad?
You did not bring the right man.
I love you!
I believe you!
Really?
Yes, it's Craig Gamble.
it does not have a penny.
But Dr. Goldfoot, I thought ...
You thought...
That's the problem!
Let me think, and everything will be better.
Create a creature as lovely ...
and spoil his ...
ammunition on a poor guy.
Honni be you!
You idiot.
Call at number 11.
You hear me, Number 11?
Number 11, you're on the wrong track.
Little chip...
Tu es ...
Is this a way to treat a lady?
Go away!
I trust you and you try to enjoy it.
Pig!
Oh, a wolf in sheep!
More Diane ...
Non!
Take your dirty hands off me!
Scoundrel!
More Diane ...
Sale type!
Help!
Get me out of here!
What have I done wrong?
You know, Igor, I begin to regret
to have you back to life.
Why?
You're foolish, blunt, rude,
Illiterate, ungrateful, uncooperative, rude ...
You say rude, Dr. Goldfoot.
And unnecessary.
This is the price for having unearthed a gravedigger.
Well, we'll go somewhere.
He is the future husband that my computer has selected ...
for Diane.
And their paths will cross now.
Ah yes.
Well, I was wrong, it can happen.
Igor...
Yes, Dr. Goldfoot?
Ferme-in.
Number 11.
Yes, Dr. Goldfoot.
I correct the stupid blunder of my so-called wizard.
Give me your adress.
Sloan, near Nesbitt.
Fancher is on street and away from her.
Igor, you like to do something constructive,
For change?
Yes sir.
So, get the numbers 1 to 9.
I want them to see that.
Yes sir.
Trotting pace!
1 to 9, is calling you!
Hurry up!
Roars!
OK, girls.
Gathering.
Now, pay attention.
Look at the monitor to learn something.
Number 11.
Hits the front tire.
Lean forward, and verifies it.
God be praised!
You came, darling.
I completely flat.
I would not say that.
The tire, my dear, the tire.
Oh, oh, pardon...
I have a jack in the trunk,
Do not let him get out, honey.
Three, it's the world.
Especially in a time like this.
Anyway, I have no alternative.
What I'd really like, this is an angel.
To drop me to the garage.
Oh, well, uh ...
Touch my wings and sail.
When people are nice to me, I'm nice to them.
Todd Armstrong.
Todd Armstrong, euh...
Do not break the spell.
Whoever you are, darling,
I could eat you!
What took you so long?
I knew the moment I saw you.
Can I see your license?
You see, I was struck as never before.
Do you believe in destiny?
I believe in what brought us together, something that is.
Kiss Me.
Will you sign this, please?
You're an angel.
An angel, what an angel!
Oh hi ...
Health.
Do me a favor and Will in, okay?
Yes sir, right away.
And thus, the convertible luxurious Mr. Armstrong ...
disappeared in the darkness of his single life,
Say goodbye.
My dear, this is how it goes ...
when you're an expert.
Incidentally, my darlings ...
in case your promised married ...
or, if you will pardon the expression,
he has a relationship,
this little bauble easily arrange the problem.
Simply present your rival ...
one of these elegant pair of binoculars,
the first thing she will, of course,
this is to put over her eyes to adjust.
Here, look!
The blades are poisoned.
In the space of a few seconds ...
a rival.
Silence.
Okay, follow me.
No. 6 ...
Number 6, this computer will provide you all what you need ...
to talk intelligently with your rich surgeon ...
in Denmark.
10 years of medicine in a single floppy disk.
Oh, you're wonderful!
Yes.
Ah, number 8.
Number 8 it will instruct you in State Affairs ...
for your rich Italian diplomat.
Oh, you're amazing!
You can say it!
Number 9.
What is she doing here?
Urgent work, sir.
Number 10 will make his musical education.
She was assigned to the English composer ...
Sir Benton Bixby Brillwater.
That, I know, stupid!
It is I who have chosen!
Well, disconnect it, and see what she has learned.
Yes sir.
Stop!
Stop, all of you, stop it!
Come on, she must be registered ...
in one of the directories.
You tried Sausalito?
A San Jose?
But I do not know his last name.
All I have is Diane.
Come on, you can find it.
Look, how many girls To call Diane ...
Yes, Uncle Donald?
Oh I am sorry.
Come to my office, I have to talk to you.
Immediately, Uncle Donald.
What is happening...
Yes, Uncle Donald?
I am sorry.
Leave it alone!
While the world is madly,
why sigh in this office ...
for a girl with a cafeteria?
I am outraged that you call a girl.
It's a lovely girl, very well, with character.
You had said nothing about his character yesterday.
Everything you spoke, it was her legs.
Uncle Donald is really serious.
Your career is serious,
and thou strikes is what you make it!
Sometimes I think you forget ...
you are a member of the headquarters of the Secret Service.
You are sick!
Yes, Uncle Donald.
'' Yes, Uncle Donald. ''
Oh, come here.
Leave it alone!
Now you see all these red flags?
Eventful areas.
South East Asia.
The Caribbean, Congo ...
So trying to figure out who is responsible?
Me?
I'm not talking Mickey!
The Abernathy inspector can not stand us.
there is a red flag for him.
-Now ... -Attention!
This is all your fault, Craig.
What is your code?
Double O and a half.
Double O and a half!
And you claim to be a secret agent!
they will never allow you to carry a weapon ...
as you will not have a figure instead of a fraction.
And how do you accomplish that?
You'll forget the girls.
You're going to change all these red flags ...
by blue flags.
Joyous flags, OO and a quarter.
And a half, sir.
A quarter, sir.
Yes sir.
'' Hey, you all! ''
'' We'll dance, we'll dance ''
You know, it's funny.
Never before has something like this had happened to me.
Bingo!
I can not believe it.
You drink, I hope.
You want to know my opinion ...
in international oil stocks?
Oh, that number 11 ...
I would like to have it as 12.
You're as happy as me, love?
I'm on a cloud ... gives.
You can always count on me, honey.
Tchin-tchin !
Hey, you do not drink too much?
Oh my God no.
I have not even started.
Tchin-tchin !
Do not you think it begins ...
to be a little busy here?
If you went home?
I fear that you do not find that very romantic ...
in a laboratory.
A laboratory?
I'm assistant laboratory ..
a dingo scientist.
N ?? This is not your type.
You think I'm kidding?
Yes.
I will show you.
it is there, near ...
Shut up, Number 11.
Now I know you've drunk too much.
We're going home.
Oh, but it is impossible for me to go ...
the apartment of a gentleman,
unless we are married.
This is the first thing I learned ...
my school of good family, and I learned well.
A good reason to come to me and explain it to me.
I have not attended school good family.
Tchin-tchin !
Its good.
The approach of the denouement.
This finger is horribly exposed.
it needs a ring.
A big, big ring.
But of course I'll marry you.
A second server!
She succeeded!
More ice, please.
Boy?
You.
I immediately removed.
One minute, ma'am.
You just touch the bottom.
The papers, please.
Thank you.
Diane!
Diane, how dare you?
-What? -Nothing.
A client can flip, but it must be done on site.
Thank you.
Good good good.
3 other debutantes ready ...
to test their wings.
Well let's see.
Number 3 ...
The king of Brazilian coffee, Senor Ortega.
Number 7 ...
The Dutch tanker, Herr van der Veer.
it's about your waist,
I am sure you will make a beautiful couple.
No. 9 ...
Swiss banker Webber.
Now you know all Exactly how?
Yes, Dr. Goldfoot.
Follow the good example of the number 11.
And you'll be all brides ...
rich wives.
That's it.
You almost forget your opera glasses,
in case of competition.
Number 3.
Number 7.
And number 9.
Well, that's it for now.
See you before you leave.
Right!
Forward, march!
Dr Goldfoot.
Number 12 back!
Number 12.
This one must be exceptional.
It is for this Spanish painter Perez Pardo.
What is that?
Well, I played the role,
Where is the action, Doc?
T'as gaffé.
Go back to your box!
I'd be dead again.
Hello dear.
Did you sleep well?
I have not slept at all.
Oh, that's horrible!
I hoped so you'd better mood.
I'm in the same mood, and it's terrible.
I'm sorry.
You can be, having spent our wedding night ...
with a screen between us.
But honey ...
My batteries were not charged.
'' Batteries were not charged? ''
What wedding night!
In fact, I did not feel ...
we had really married ...
because thou hast not offered my wedding gift.
Your wedding gift?
Good heavens, it can not wait?
Here, honey.
You are not happy?
You do not even have to go buy it.
My actions.
General Chemistry, Gas Transmission and South Central.
How did you get access to my safe?
Listen, darling, all you have to do is sign.
But I do not have a pen.
Oh, if you got one.
But I have nothing to sign it.
That's quite a honeymoon!
Oh, and do not forget the Arapahoe shares.
The Arapahoe shares.
And if you want to be especially ...
Particularly generous,
how about this building 28-story ...
You possess on East Poplard?
Sorry, but there is that I have not on me.
Oh, but you're going to get, is not it?
What are your plans now?
I have groceries to do.
So why do not you stand up like a good little frame,
and make even more money?
I do not know why fate is attacking me.
I'm a good guy.
Finally, I try to be.
I never forget Mother's Day.
I do not think we have met.
A moins...
Tell me you were not one of these vendors ...
passing to my house in Upper Bloomsbuy?
The pharmacist?
The son of the butcher, perhaps?
The son of the butcher?
What happens to you, Diane?
It's me, Craig Gamble.
Do you remember?
Honestly, no,
but you know, I have a bad memory for faces.
Especially from ordinary ones.
Come on, stop, would you, Diane?
What are you trying to do to me?
Come on ...
Now, let me!
But, Diane, I have my car here.
Stopped!
Igor, I think he's your friend, Mr. Gamble.
Pull over to the curb.
I feel that the number 11 has problems.
I say this is disgusting on your part!
But Diane, I love you.
lout kind!
Diane, I need you.
Number 11, come with me.
Oh no, not that!
Oh, do not worry about ?? t hand.
I have two full ridges members.
Let me see, let me see.
That's wonderful.
27.OOO shares of General Chemical Corporation.
45.OOO shares of G & T South Central.
And 60.OOO Arapahoe shares.
All of the first order of values.
Beware the road!
You're getting along brilliantly,
Brilliantly, number 11.
I do not know.
Suddenly, I have a migraine.
I think I forgot something.
This is probably nervous tension,
after struggling with that slob on the sidewalk.
That's all?
That's all, Doctor.
In fact, I think you forgot something.
Where is the proxy of the notary supposed to put everything in your name?
Oh, I knew there was something!
After the briefing that I made you, number 11 ...
is inexcusable.
I will never forget, Doctor.
No, I'm sure, once you have been punished ...
by the chair!
Oh, no, Doctor.
Oh, you.
Beware the road!
Now let me get this straight.
-His hand fell. -That's right.
With a top alliance, I see.
His hand is detached, Uncle Donald.
And in the cafeteria, she vomited milk.
Exact.
In fact, I could go right ....
to tell you.
No, not about you to come talk to me about that.
Because I do not want to listen.
Okay, so give me your opinion at least.
Alright I'll do it.
You're crazy!
I thought I told you not to ...
Abernathy ...
The inspector Abernathy Washington?
Himself.
Forgive my cries ...
- I'm coming to see you. -What do you mean?
I want to know what happens.
You intend to come here on the coast?
Indeed, I come here and I want ...
I would like to see you.
A damn good job.
My office is an open book.
Very good.
I will give you food later, Rasputin.
Good good good.
Let's see how the number 12 is doing,
as I created without your damned interference.
Now that's more like it.
Silhouette, complexion, posture.
Turn my dear.
Yes, this time I surpassed myself, Igor.
The perfect companion for Perez Pardo.
Yes, the artist in him will react, I'm sure.
And it will take everything he owns.
Take off your hands merchandise.
The computer will brief the number 4 in art.
-Mets-the duplex. -Yes sir.
Buddy, buddy.
Well, girls, ready to go?
Well, let's see now.
Number 4, designated as thee marry Greek tycoon ...
navigation, Triombos.
And you, 5, King of the South African Diamond, Peter Labomba.
Very good.
Only it turns out that these two gentlemen ...
are already married.
But with my latest system ...
to liquidate the wives,
I think you should have no problem ?? n.
What woman could resist
a beautiful lipstick.
Attractive, sweet, creamy, and shimmering.
But when she will bring to her lips ...
You see?
It will disintegrate completely,
and you will have free rein.
Well, Igor takes you later at the airport.
Well, good luck!
And remember ...
Goldfoot's eyes watch over you.
Right!
Forward, march!
Igor, how often ...
About the number 11 ...
I know that was not my business,
but I think it is sufficiently punished.
Finally, more could cause permanent damage ...
its circuits and transistors,
and it would no longer serve you for anything.
You're probably right, but I hate to admit it.
One.
Well, I hope it made you understand ...
the mistake you've made ...
by not bringing the proxy.
Yes, Dr. Goldfoot.
Okay, I'm glad you take it that way.
You think you can get me the paper now?
Well, Igor is going to give you another hand and will arrange
for you to be presentable.
and I hope for your sake that you do not disappoint me.
Promised.
What makes this body, lying there?
I do not know sir.
-Who is it? -I do not know.
This is Wittlauffer Eustache.
And then what Eustache Wittlauffer doing here?
it will be embalmed.
Our special funeral Deluxe 9895.
So what?
Someone had to show neglect
and allow the carriage slide down the ramp.
You're going to go right away to the embalming room.
Then you will take 4 and 5 at the airport.
it is late, and you have enough time.
I'll take care of the number 11.
Trot, trot!
That's all he can say, '' trot ''.
Oncle Donald!
C'est un robot, Uncle Donald!
It's a robot!
This must be one of the songwriters next door.
Do not worry.
he shall not come here.
C'est un robot, Uncle Donald!
It's a robot!
You see?
Oh, oncle Donald!
Leave me, kind of moron!
Ah, this is my nephew, Craig Gamble.
Abernathy inspector.
How are you?
It's him.
That's Igor!
The assistant to Dr. robots!
Mr. Pevney, this idiot is not your nephew!
You see, he works too hard.
I repeat, I saw with Dr. Goldfoot!
It's him...
Craig, attends, attends.
It's you.
Oh, by Jove, you are dangerous!
Why not go straight to your desk ...
and take a handful of aspirin?
Take an entire bottle.
Dr. Goldfoot has magical powers!
I know!
they could destroy the world!
And you have your hand in it.
No wait!
Get out of here.
I hope you will not hold against me in, Inspector.
I hired because of my sister widow.
I could not...
Inspector?
Oh, no.
Oh, no!
Stop!
Sit there!
Quick.
Lower your hands.
Who are you?
I'm Todd Armstrong.
And you what are you doing in my apartment?
Oh, let me introduce myself.
I put it in the small ...
I am a sick man.
I wish to believe.
You want to get to the point?
Mr. Armstrong, I have news for you.
Yes?
I'd be better to buy you a drink.
That is very kind of you.
Take one good sip.
Of course.
I will soon go the way.
I hope.
But bluntly.
Mr. Armstrong, you are married to a robot.
You are sick!
I assure you and I will prove it.
Would you recognize the covenant of your wife ...
If you saw her?
Of course. Obviously.
Here.
Do not go, Mr. Armstrong.
That's not very nice.
Come back, Mr. Armstrong.
Dear Todd, you promise not to sign anything.
After what you've told me, do not be ridiculous.
You take it well.
You take it well, man.
I know this is hard to accept,
but why you would make Dr. Goldfoot richer?
Exactly.
This is the elevator that stops?
Yes that's it.
Climb it.
Remember, call me as soon as you tend the pen.
And stay quiet until my signal.
Okay.
Attention is dangerous, clever and sexy.
Calm down, I can manage.
Prepare a few good glasses.
Good evening darling.
Good evening.
It's good to come home.
I'll put on something more comfortable.
You saw what I saw?
I saw.
Hi Angel.
Good evening!
I missed you, sweetie?
Yes!
If you missed me?
It will give you an idea.
I hear something...
What are you doing?
I do the inventory to see if anything is missing.
You missed me so much!
I counted the minutes until our reunion.
My ears are playing a trick on me, or I hear a noise?
No, but you're not far away.
Wait, love, what is it?
But nothing.
Just another piece of paper that you forgot to sign.
Oh, for what?
I suspected you'd react like this.
You're the sweetest, sweetest, most wonderful ...
husband a woman ever had.
Me?
Sign down there.
Perfect.
Now come back here ...
as fast as you can.
Diane, attends.
Where you gonna go like that?
Hey, come back!
It is fantastic, Igor.
Simply fantastic.
Would not it be wonderful if they were all like that?
It was my idea to let the machine ...
turn half an hour.
Now we have all the actions Mr. Armstrong ...
titles, apartments and office buildings.
Not to mention his ranch and yachts!
This is a great day for us, Iggy.
You can tell.
You let yourself go.
Pardon, Dr Goldfoot.
I am really sorry.
And believe me, it will not be repeated.
Dr Goldfoot?
Yes?
How would you like to see a diabolical trick I invented?
You invented something you want to show me?
Yes sir.
-I can not wait to see it. -Stay here.
You invented it?
Sit there.
A briefcase.
But this is no ordinary briefcase.
This is something that you will really love it.
Now wait.
there are tricks to open.
Yes I see.
This stuff is really strong!
If ever you can open!
Let me do it!
Awesome.
I hope he has not broken.
Who are you?
Todd Armstrong
You are in my apartment, you remember?
Oh, Todd.
Diane.
I knew she was there.
You signed?
Yes, I signed.
Oh, no ...
Not after what you promised me.
Why you did not call me?
What has changed would have had I done?
You told me to prepare myself some good glasses ...
Do not worry, I had many.
What did you mean by that?
I signed the power of attorney notary of your name.
Oh, excellent!
You are awesome!
Why am I laughing?
No, this is your punishment for bringing me ...
this signature worthless.
What carelessness, inefficiency, stupidity!
The kind of things I will not tolerate.
Ruining my most brilliant stroke.
Give it back to him.
Let Me In, Uncle Donald
I'm with a guy who can confirm to you ...
everything I have told you.
Surely!
Tell him.
C'est un robot, Uncle Donald!
I know.
Follow me.
Help!
Uncle Donald, I would like to introduce you to a friend of mine,
Todd Armstrong.
How are you?
Mr. Armstrong will tell you, Uncle Donald.
This girl, Diane, is really a robot.
And he had to know because he married her.
I do not want to hear about it.
he told you the truth, Mr. Pevney.
It is a diabolical plan to sting me my money.
This maniacal Dr. Goldfoot is a genius.
I refuse to listen to you both.
And now out both!
Outside!
-M. Pevney-- -Dehors!
Okay, but before leaving, take a look at that.
M. Pevney?
I hope you feel better.
The amount of the sale of Mr. Armstrong Securities.
Good!
It compensates, at least in part, my disappointment.
Now, next step: find Mr. Armstrong.
The liquid estimated how much before?
It does not concern you.
Leave me alone.
Now, get out, you idiot, before I get angry.
Yes sir.
Oh, do not be afraid.
I am not afraid.
Where passer par là.
Okay.
What are you doing?
What shall we do now?
Why not try the main door?
It is an excellent idea!
I agree.
Visitors.
It may be Mr. Gamble and Mr. Armstrong?
Perhaps.
Everything comes to those who wait, Igor.
Lets go see.
Welcome, gentlemen.
It's nice to be passed.
I'm Dr. Goldfoot.
and this is my assistant, Igor.
And I know who you are,
vous, M. Gamble, M. Armstrong.
I came to see Diana.
I was wondering if you'd be kind enough ...
to sign my guestbook.
Thank you very much.
Goodbye!
L'arc!
Please, do not go, gentlemen.
I would be offended if you do not give me a chance ...
to offer hospitality.
Oh, ma machine.
Maybe you would like.
Follow me.
Here is my bikini machine.
What I told you?
That's who created Diana.
And all the others, too.
And you see this magazine?
It is between these pages that I choose ...
all husbands for my robots.
Only the richest men in the world.
And that's when you found me!
Yes!
Follow me.
You see these computers?
Well, it is with these machines That I prepare my ladies.
Lovely, is not it?
Once they are programmed,
they go in search of their prey.
Where is Diana, where are my actions?
And where is the proxy of the notary with my name on it?
But you know it has no value.
Ah yes?
Do not forget that I am in the headquarters of the secret services.
Not according to your uncle.
Oh, come, gentlemen.
I never discuss business before dinner,
and I insist that you are my guests.
Oh, is that you were talking about?
Diane!
I was looking for you...
Diane, but where are you going?
Wait, I want to talk to you.
After you, Mr. Gamble.
Do not you remember me?
I am your husband!
Please, gentlemen, take a seat.
I make great case of fresh fruit and gentlemen.
They are grown especially for me ...
in distant corners.
Des Papayes Samoa ...
Poison!
Do not eat. It's poison.
Oh, come, gentlemen ...
You disappoint me.
He never occur to me the idea of ​​contamination
this wonderful fruit with poison.
Well, I have enough of that.
May I ask a few questions?
After all, it's my wife.
Please, my dear, do so!
Thank you.
Diane...
Of course, you should talk to him in Japanese.
In Japanese?
That's all she has now.
My little Todd ...
Petit Todd?
I will say at number 14 not to giggle like that.
Especially during dinner.
Gentlemen, your wine.
Chateau Frontenac, 1947.
Excellent grown, do not you think?
Cheers!
If you still have it tomorrow.
Oh, that miserable Igor!
he forgot the knives.
Forgot knives ...
Whatever.
Let's go from here.
Idiot!
The parts that I will show you ...
are the most interesting of my studio.
A propos ...
Here are some of my ancestors.
This is my Great-grandfather ...
The most bloodthirsty pirate,
which was never hanged, drowned and quartered.
This triggered the terror of the Inquisition ...
in the peaceful village of Carpathians.
I like it.
He's the boorish Sandor, a Slav.
he learned to Attila, King of the Huns, all he knew.
An extraordinary character.
Great family resemblance, do not you think?
This was my first experience.
Coupons short all this nonsense.
Nonsense?
Excellent, hein, Igor?
I prefer it better when he did not laugh.
Gentlemen!
After you.
I must warn you not to try to escape,
otherwise I will be forced to use this laser.
Attention.
Look around you, gentlemen.
Here come the disobedient and hesitant.
It is called '' the barbershop ''.
That you made a hairstyle just at the shoulders.
For your manicure,
And that, of course, to your shampoo.
You will never need another.
It is not possible.
But you'll like it.
Why me?
Why me all the time?
Go ahead.
And here is the medieval bridge, the stretcher that converts ...
Instantly the little men in very large.
And now I would like to give you a demonstration ...
the most ingenious of the Inquisition.
Let me see.
Non.
Gamble, it will not work.
But you will do just the job, Mr. Armstrong.
You allow?
Thank you.
It is not going good, no?
It!
What? It!
It is not going good, no?
Have said.
Well, Mr. Armstrong is the time we expected ...
to finally stop all this nonsense ...
and back to business.
So would you please sign the proxy of the notary,
or would you wait for things to fester?
And if you return crawling with insects?
Well answered, my friend!
In fact, he's bluffing!
Your friend does not know me very well.
Igor!
Yes, Dr. Goldfoot?
See if you can persuade him to sign.
Should he show obstinate, I will prepare the ...
how to say...
the ultimate means of persuasion?
Yes, Dr. Goldfoot.
I really have no desire to use these things on you.
You know, I think you're a nice guy, right?
-Yes? -No.
If this does not clean better than you ?? ... ??
I'll buy another ?? ... ??
-Yes? -I said no.
This will make you change your mind ...
the Borgia thigh compressor.
simply put it down, like this, on your thigh,
you turn, and again, and finally,
you are so bad that one go ...
You are fine?
Oh, it hurts.
Bravo, Todd !
Stay with my friend.
Do not sign!
he will sign, my friend.
You'll see.
Mr. Armstrong, you will be the first victim ...
My new separator.
You will love it. Have his head in the air ...
and the rest of your body down, right?
You are sick?
You'll see.
I think you have stuck up.
Dr Goldfoot!
Please, release me!
Oh, Igor, Igor!
moron!
Why, oh why I always leave you alone?
Up, up!
Farms!
Wail of pity when I show you ...
what I have in store for you now.
Removes the necklace that is, Mr. Armstrong.
I'll make you a moron patented ...
unless you do not sign it.
For the last time...
Non!
Very good.
Working!
Come on!
Let's move!
Okay, it stirs!
The CIA will pay you what you're doing, you bastard!
I will hunt you myself ....
even if it lasts a lifetime!
If I am still part of the organization.
Well, Mr. Armstrong, this is your last chance,
unless you change your mind.
We'll begin.
So let's go.
Now...
I warned you, Mr. Armstrong.
Do not waste time!
he left you very little.
It will help you to come back ...
to reason before it's too late.
Bring the other speed.
Yes sir.
Okay, Craig, we go.
What am I doing here?
It is you who should be inside.
Come on, you think you crafty?
I still have the key.
And I have these things?
They are not cool?
They are really very cool.
They are not beautiful?
They are beautiful.
You know, it's used everywhere here, all the time.
So you will not need that.
No, in fact, no need.
Come back here!
Hurry, Igor!
there are only a few seconds!
Hey, stop the ax!
What?
The ax!
Stop the ax!
The lever!
Oh, the lever!
Comment?
Remove it.
Quick!
Go.
Slowly...
Let's go from here.
Wait!
And Diane?
Diane Forget!
Come on!
Igor!
You will have big problems.
Close the doors ...
locked and do not let them escape!
Go.
Let's go from here!
Igor!
Hello, Doctor.
I should have known!
Right, I should pierce ...
tone skeleton worthless with this beam,
and let you rot ...
My empire, everything I created is threatened.
-No. -Yes.
we need to stop them before ...
they prevent the police.
I will do my best.
No, not that.
they arrive! Supports it!
there's stuff on the dashboard.
Maybe we can lose them in the smoke screen.
The button!
Igor faster!
Faster!
I can maybe find something.
Concentrate on the road. I'll find something.
Y is tired of the game of cat and mouse, Doctor.
We have to catch up them!
On y va!
Hey, Todd, where loss!
Perfect, continues.
Excellent idea.
It happens from time to time.
Deserter!
Igor, where have you been?
Dr. Goldfoot, I looked for you everywhere.
It's a pleasure to see you.
Now, after leading them!
It was what street is that?
Wait!
Hurry up! They are close!
Turn right!
Igor, idiot!
Why are you listening to me when I'm wrong?
they are again behind us!
Accelerate! Faster!
We can not go faster!
Forward!
they arrive!
Let's get out of here!
I think we lost them.
Continue, continue!
they arrive!
-Who? -Them!
they come back!
We will pay you back!
they are always behind us?
Yeah!
It is gaining ground.
Stop ringing that bell!
Stopped!
Run after them!
Keep quiet and keep going!
Attention !
I can not see!
My secret weapon.
I kept it for an emergency.
So attack them!
Great, we succeeded.
And now?
file is here.
You and your secret weapon ...
AREA MISSILE EXPLOSION HAZARD
What shall we do now?
I have an idea.
Come.
Dr Goldfoot! On y est!
Igor, idiot!
he did not even know what had hit him.
Craig, we had quite a hard week.
How about a short break in Paris?
I do not think so...
-I invite you. -Yes!
Goodbye, Dr. Goldfoot,
where you are!
After all we just endure,
it feels good to relax.
That's for sure.
Diane?
Sweetheart!
Coffee, tea, or cuddling.
What do you think?
The minute I saw this little Austrian ...
it was love at first sight.
I am so happy that I could fly away.
Is love.
THE END?