Miss Ryan?
- Yes.
Berlin Police department, Rudnick.
How do you feel?
- I'm OK.
What is this?
Your brother had this on him: Wallet,
keys, cigarettes.
Please, sign here.
There.
I've also put the death
certificate inside.
His body has been cleared by the
district attorney this morning.
Why did it have to be cleared?
Bureaucracy.
The autopsy showed that your brother
definitely committed suicide.
When can I take my brother home?
You have to show this
paper to your embassy.
There you will get a paper called
"consular mortuary certificate"
and then you can
organize the transport.
My flight leaves on Thursday.
If there is anything I can do for you,
call me.
Der Aufzug funktioniert nicht.
I'm sorry, I don't understand German.
The elevator is out of order.
You must be Michael's sister, Marian.
You two were pretty close, weren't you?
He was my brother!
Of course we were close!
So he would have confided in you if
something was wrong in his life?
What about his friends? His work?
Excuse me, I would like to
go up to the apartment now.
Oh please, let me help.
Thank you. Just follow me.
This way please.
There are not that many
people living here anymore.
They all moved out.
This is a very quiet house.
Do you really think he jumped?
Can I have my bags, please!?
Police have been known
to make mistakes.
Listen, this is really
none of your business.
OK. If you need anything,
I'm just down the hall.
Thank you.
Do you really think he jumped?
Excuse me.
You're Michael's sister, right?
I saw some photos of you once.
He talked a lot about you.
You're a friend of his?
Something like that.
What's that supposed to mean?
Nothing. Never mind.
I'm Eric, by the way.
Marian.
Look, I'm gonna go,
but if you ever need to talk
or need anything, just let me know...
No, thank you. I'm leaving
in a few days anyway.
Sure.
Listen, I'm really sorry about your brother.
He was a good guy.
Thank you.
You have a good trip back, ok?
- Bye.
Bye.
Puh!
Fuck you!
No, fuck you!
Well, I ask you to do one thing one time
and you can't fucking do it.
What do you want me to fucking tell them?
Richard?
Oh... hi Mom...
I don't know, Mom.
Camera equipment, furniture,
personal stuff.
It's got to be worth
a small fortune, though...
I'm going to pack it up and
have it shipped back home...
No. Absolutely not.
I'm gonna go through it there...
Well, at least I made
the effort to come here, Mom.
What's your excuse?
No. I have to be back...
...by Friday at the latest...
I've got an important auction coming up.
Why's that suddenly so important?
You had absolutely no interest
for Michael when he was alive,
why should you care now?
Sorry, but this form is wrong.
What's wrong about it?
That it is not the right one...
So?
So I'm afraid you have to
go back to the mortuary
and get it there.
When? Now?
Sure, if you can make it in time.
They close in ten minutes.
OK, I get it tomorrow.
Do you know what time they open?
They are not open tomorrow.
You have to go there on Monday.
Listen, Mr. Jemison.
I have a flight on Thursday!
...sorry.
What are you saying?
That I can't take my brother home
because I don't have a fucking piece of paper?
Without that "fucking piece of paper"
I can't give you the consular certificate.
No!
It's sad that it has to be something
like this that brings us back together.
You never really hung out with
Michael when he lived here, did you?
No. We talked on the phone
a few times. Wanted to meet,
but somehow always something
came in between. I mean...
Hey.
Sorry.
OK, my flight's on Thursday.
But I made out a schedule on the plane.
We should be able to sort
out Michael's affairs.
It's your brother we're
talking about here.
I could spend four years here
and it wouldn't bring him back.
So much is riding on this auction...
I just can't afford to be away
for longer than a few days.
I mean, you're talking about a bunch
of paintings with frames around them.
What have you done,
some kind of cost benefit analysis?
I'm sorry. Hey, I'm sorry. Come here.
I need a hot bath and a bed.
Thank you so much for coming
here and helping me today.
No problem.
Do you think you might have some time
to come by tomorrow and help me again?
Well, I have got to be at the university at ten,
I got a couple of classes and...
Please!
Sure.
Thanks.
Are you gonna be alright?
Yeah.
Fuck!
OK.
You gotta auction it all off on Ebay.
I bet you'd make a fortune.
No time. I just want to get rid of it.
All that camera equipment, the prints...
Listen, if it means that much to you,
you take care of it and we'll split the earnings.
OK! Cool.
Alright, we're done.
The rest goes to the dump.
Do you really know the way out of here?
Sure. We're almost there.
Is this where we came from?
Right.
We're lost.
No, we're not. We just took a wrong turn.
Hi.
A person can really get lost
here if they don't know the way.
We're not lost.
- We know our way, thank you.
Please... Let me help
you with those boxes.
Shit.
Wow! Take a look at this!
This must really be worth a lot.
It's a comic book, it's not worth anything.
It's not just a comic book.
It's a first edition volume of "Cycle of Pain"
and it is worth more than you think!
You know, the more time that I think
about it, the lesser sense it makes.
I talked to Michael
three hours before he jumped
and there was no indication
that he was thinking of...
I've gone through the conversation
a thousand times in my head.
We all have our demons.
Only some can hide them
better than others.
Where did you get that deep wisdom?
A fucking comic book?
Let's see...
One beautiful spring day Michael Ryan,
a handsome young man with
the world at his feet,
earning a good living in a city he loves,
just says: You know what?
Fuck this!
I'm getting off the fucking world!
Hello? Richard,
where have you been?
I've been trying to call you for days.
So what's up with the deal,
did you talk to them?
What? Why not?
Richard, I'm telling you,
we're going to lose this.
Well, they're getting cold feet
at the last second, can't you see that?
No, don't talk to him,
talk to the other guy,
what's his name again... Yeah, right.
Listen, I need you to talk to them personally.
Tell them exactly what I told you.
Is that so hard to understand?
I can't. I'm not there!
Why not? Why can't you just get
down there and talk to them?
Don't mess this up, Richard!
Yes, right. Whatever. Bye.
Did you enjoy the view last night?
Goodbye!
Oh, hi Mom...
No, not much, I'm just cleaning up,
throwing things away...
I also talked to one of
Michael's clients today...
...no, somebody else.
Well, they told me that Michael
stopped working for them in December.
No, in December two years ago.
What do you mean, if he was fired?
Mom. He was a free-lancer...
he can't be fired.
Well, that he was irresponsible,
hard to work with, yada yada yada...
Yes, I went to the bank.
Yes, Mom, I cancelled his accounts.
No, nothing special.
Just the usual: rent, utilities...
Yes, the weather is nice.
...yes, I'm still here.
Go, go.
Mom, listen, I gotta go.
Yeah, you know what,
I'll talk to you later.
Yes, you too. OK, bye Mom, bye.
Berta 27 bitte melden.
Berta 27 hört.
Verkehrsunfall, Uhlandstraße.
Wahrscheinlich drei Verletzte.
So, you're saying this box full of cash
is somehow connected to
your brother's death.
The man in these photos
lives right across the yard.
So?
Maybe my brother was
blackmailing this guy.
Would your brother do
something like that?
No, but maybe he had no choice.
Right. No choice.
That argument never fails in court.
And that comic painter, Eric...
- McKeen...
Eric McKeen.
Did he tell you that your
brother was blackmailing him?
No, of course not...
...so, what has he
have to do with all this?
I don't know. You tell me,
you're the Detective.
Let me see...
Maybe your brother was blackmailing
that Eric McKeen and maybe
he was tired of
making the payments
so he put an end to it by
putting an end to your brother.
Is that what you think happened?
You don't believe me, do you?
Listen,
I know it's hard to accept,
but your brother committed suicide.
He jumped
and there's absolutely no evidence
of aggravated assault... nothing.
And that's not going to change
just because you found some money
in a box and some nasty pictures.
Aren't you at least
gonna question this guy?
No.
Why not?
Under which charge, Miss Ryan?
Hi.
- Hi.
Can I get a white wine?
Just half a glass. Small.
Quite the showman, huh?
How much?
- Three Euros.
Hey, you know that song?
He coulda been an actor but
he ended up here. I want... No?
Thank you.
They probably singing it about Eric.
I mean, that's one talented
son of a bitch. I give him that.
I mean,
he could be anything he wants.
He could paint like a Dutch master,
he could probably race motorcycles...
He could work as a gigolo.
He could even work as a gigolo, you're right.
Are you a friend of his?
Partner is more like it.
Look,
see this bit
"Artwork by Eric McKeen"...
the Eric McKeen.
And now see this bit,
you need a magnifying glass to read it
but it says "Written by Steve Briggs".
I guess that would be you.
That would be yes.
That must be the "Downtrodden writer
that don't get no respect" pickup ploy.
Haha.
Eric, this is...
Yeah, yeah, we've met.
You know, I have this love-hate
relationship thing kind of going.
Eric creates all the beautiful,
sadistic pictures and colors them in,
and I write the story that
gives it all meaning.
He gets the glory and I pay my rent.
Yo Dagger!
Yo.
- Yo Dagger.
Well, it looks like Dagger's
scoped out his next victim.
Have you been following me?
Dream on.
Can I get you a drink?
- Yeah.
Can I have that Tequila please?
Thank you.
You're one tough guy, huh?
What?
Do you always get what you want?
Always.
How far are you willing to go?
As far as it takes.
So, Don Juan.
What's up with the photos?
Sorry?
What photos?
I hate to say it, but your
brother was a peeping Tom.
What are you talking about?
You think I'm gonna invite him over so
that he can photograph me having sex?
Well, it's pretty obvious, isn't it?
Why would I do that?
I don't know,
maybe you're a sick pervert?
Fuck you!
Look you don't come here...
Who are you accusing me?
You don't even know me...
I am sorry about Michael, OK,
and it's perfectly normal
that you're trying to find
an excuse for his suicide...
...he didn't commit suicide.
- I don't know.
Listen, I talked to him every day.
All the time.
I was there for him
when he really needed me.
I am sure you were.
Listen, I think you start
chasing windmills.
It's like Freud said,
sometimes a cigar is just a cigar.
And you haven't seen
him in how long?
I'm not trying to lay a guilt trip
on you or anything like that.
But it's pretty hard to tell
what's going on in somebody's head
from five thousand miles away.
Maybe you're right.
Nightcap?
That's not that bad.
Who painted it?
Me.
Sorry. It's not bad at all.
You're a connoisseur.
Actually I just see dollar signs.
I work for an auctioning house.
I'm not the creative type.
I doubt that.
Listen,
you're gonna have to do
a bit better than that.
Just getting started. C'mon.
You know what... It's late.
I'm gonna go home.
Have a good night.
You don't really think
I killed your brother, do you?
Who is this?
Nobody.
Do you think he has a girlfriend?
I know her.
What do you mean, you know her?
She's a friend of
yours or something?
She is an actress.
She's famous.
She's on TV all the time.
She sucks.
That's her car.
You sure you wanna do this?
... yes, I am.
- OK.
Was machen Sie hier?
You must be Mrs. Reinhardt...
Who are you?
I'm sorry. I was hoping
that you could help me...
Where did you get this?
Greetings from our mutual artist friend.
Since when does Eric send women?
Is he too frightened to do
the dirty work himself?
You tell Eric and his photographer
friend they'd better be careful.
Sybille, kommst du bitte noch mal,
wir wollen weitermachen.
Ich komm gleich.
Tell Eric, if he thinks he can get
more money he can forget it.
And you can also tell him
if even one of these photos
will be in a newspaper, ever,
I will kill him.
Do you understand me?
Yes, Ma'm.
And now get off the property.
Let's go.
Who does he think I am?
I can't believe he just lied
to me. Like... just...
Listen, I told you everything, right.
Now, I go there,
he lies to me completely. Oh God,
he's not gonna get away with this.
Who does he think I am?
Some little country girl
or what the hell?
Hi.
You blackmailed her!
Come on in.
Hello, there!
- Hi.
You guys have met, right?
- Yeah.
Yeah.
Would you like something to drink?
- No.
How is it going?
- Good.
Steve's just telling me about
his idea for the next volume.
Right, and then this particularly young
woman, she decides to take a bubble bath.
And she's lying there in the water,
she's all soapy and sexy
and very slim...
...and she's lying in the hot water
and she's got her eyes closed
and she's dreaming and it's all still
and then the Dagger breaks in,
and he slashes her up,
and he rips her to pieces,
and then he has sex with her
corpse on the bathroom floor.
Pretty evil, ha?
That's not evil, that's sick.
Well, c'mon, think about it.
Think how many issues we'd sell.
Way more than we've
ever sold before.
What. Why you're
looking at me like that?
Can I talk to you...?
Yeah. Go ahead.
...in private!
Steve,
could you take a little walk please.
I'm not. C'mon.
Just fucking do it!
Fine.
Yo Dagger.
So, what's the story
with Frau Reinhardt?
She actually volunteered to pay.
Money is not a big
problem for her.
You are a fucking liar.
Believe it or not,
she seduced me.
She was bored stiff,
so we were hanging out for a while
and your brother snapped the photos.
Then it was just a
matter of negotiations.
The tabloids would offer
10.000 Euro for a photo...
and Sybille was willing
to pay one cent more.
And was she the only one?
You lured him into this!
It was his idea, not mine.
You already lied to me once.
Why should I believe you?
Look, your brother was desperate, OK?
He wanted to put on a big exhibit of all
of his work. He needed to get backing.
I had seen he was a
talented son of a bitch.
I gave him the money.
He got great reviews.
But nobody was buying,
it was a disaster.
And there we were, broke.
So?
So Michael came to my apartment
one day with his idea.
A simple plan for simple people.
If I would have said no, he wouldn't have
gone through with it. But I said yes.
End of story.
What if they blackmailed
the wrong woman.
What if somebody put out
a contract on Michael.
What do you think?
You really want to
know what I think?
Sign this!
Äh, wie lange dauert das ungefähr noch?
Puh, das kommt jetzt
erst mal ins Fach und dann...
Can you ask her how long it will take?
She doesn't know.
Danke.
When is your flight again?
I'm extending my stay.
Just a couple more days.
Yess! OK, let's do some
serious partying tonight.
I'm talking about some drinks,
some clubbing...
and some hot looking guys
to squeeze the orange
juice out of for breakfast.
Just like old times.
- Yeah.
Hi.
Oh hello.
- Hi.
How are you doing?
Good, good, how are you?
Hey, hon,
I want you to meet somebody.
Steve, I want you to meet
a good friend of mine, Susann.
Hi.
- Hi, Steve Briggs.
Susann, Steve makes comics.
Wait a second.
The "Cycle of Pain" Steve Briggs?
The very same.
That comic is totally sick!
I'll take that as a compliment then.
Can I ask you a question?
- Sure.
In issue number seven, when Dagger
is behind that big oak tree?
You're a big fan?
Can I have your babies, please?
Oh, right now?
Or do you want to dance first?
The Chinese masters used to say
that when they were gonna die they
were gonna inhabit their artwork.
Yeah?
But... cool, he?
And the Dagger he has tattoos in
places that defy imagination.
But I don't expect that you are the kind
of people that go looking for them.
Well, I'm gonna go looking for them...
Hey, where are you going?
Honey, I'm so tired,
I'm gonna go home.
I'm coming with you.
- No, no, no. You stay here.
Have a good time.
Thanks. See you tomorrow.
Bye.
Yo Dagger.
Do you need any help?
"We came at the agreed
time but no answer.
"Please call. Urgent."
Any friends of yours?
No. It's the moving company.
I'll call them.
Your brother did not have many friends.
But he was a nice neighbor.
Thank you.
I hate to intrude, but...
haven't you found anything strange...
I mean... didn't you find it
strange that Michael...
I mean why the window?
Let's face it, the height is critical
if you're a jumper.
We're pretty high on this floor
but it's still not a sure thing.
He could have jumped from the roof,
no problem.
You mean... you don't
think that is was a...
Suicide?
No way.
No way. No way.
Nightcap?
Still hot on the killer's trail?
No, I'm taking the night off.
That's a nice dress.
Well, thank you.
I'm glad you like it.
Haven't had a chance to wear it yet.
So what's the special occasion?
Oh, nothing...
I just saw you... working over here.
So I thought I'd just
come over and say Hi.
Hi.
- Hi.
Hey guys, how's it going?
No problem. We have
everything under control.
Right...
So, comic book groupie. How was it?
Mezzo-mezzo.
Oh come on, out with it.
He's a writer. What do you think?
Well, I had sex with the artist...
No way.
Way...
I mean, when, where?
Well, last night obviously,
after you and that Chinese master
were making out on that couch.
How was it?
This is ridiculous.
You are the one with all
the conspiracy theories.
Here is some more.
Cool.
Listen, I trade you all of these
if you'll give me back the Frank Miller
I sold you last month.
Hmm, how do I say this delicately?
No!
- Ok, that's all.
You collect this crap?
I bet my comic collection
has increased its value more since
9-11 than your stock portfolio.
Ehm? What does that say again?
"29-year-old Hungarian
stewardess murdered"...
Here.
So what's that supposed to prove?
Wouldn't you say this is just a little
bit more than a coincidence?
C'mon, you don't really think that
Eric killed this woman, do you?
I mean, inspiration, sure,
but these are just drawings.
To tell you the truth,
this scares the shit out of me.
I mean, I thought you were a bit out
of it with Michael's death and everything.
But now I think we
should talk to the cops.
So who is she?
I don't know.
Do you know that she's dead?
Yes.
So who was she?
Another one of the women
that you were blackmailing?
She was a stewardess I met on a flight.
Did you go to the police?
Why not?
Because if I go to the police...
...they will start asking you questions
about all the women you blackmailed.
Yes. All the women I blackmailed.
Me and your brother.
Look. I didn't kill Michael
and I didn't kill this girl.
I might be a sick bastard,
but I am not a killer.
Do you have any idea who's doing this?
I don't know. Some copycat killer?
She's missing, too.
Since when?
Since the night your brother died.
Nacht.
- Nacht.
What if Michael photographs Eric with that
red-haired popstar to blackmail her?
Maybe Eric gets a bit too rough.
He kills Maria.
Eric sees Michael taking pictures and
realizes he has to kill your brother, too.
Wait a second, she's not dead.
She is just missing!
"Missing", right.
Michael died the same day
this Maria disappeared.
What more do you want?
Eric has slept with these women.
Now they're dead.
Not me.
You didn't go and fall
in love with him, did you?
What about that weird guy next door?
What's his name again... Bergen.
He's strange enough.
What you're doing is called
breaking and entering.
I just want to find out whether
he has anything to do with this.
If he's got nothing to hide,
he's got nothing to worry about, right?
You know what?
I've been studying psychology
for seven years now.
And I don't have the foggiest idea
what kind of problem this guy has.
Oh my God.
Give me the flashlight.
I wanna check something out.
The window. See if anyone's coming.
Are you nuts? He could see that.
Marian.
He's coming!
Give me another minute!
Marian!
- I'm almost done.
Let's go.
C'mon.
Does that say what I think it does?
She's dead.
It's time to talk to Rudnick.
Ich will Ihnen das erklären...
Bergen's the one.
Bergen? You mean Michael's neighbor?
- Yes.
He's a loser! He's not capable.
Listen, he's a copycat killer, just like you said.
He's obsessed with your comics
and he's been acting out the stories.
He's a total psychopath.
I think you've been reading
too many comic books.
And I think if you weren't so hot
on showing pictures of girls
getting shredded to death,
because it sells more comics,
maybe a couple of your one-night
stands might still be alive.
It's not about selling more comic books.
But maybe you're right. Maybe I just
didn't realize the consequences.
What are you talking about?
That I should have stopped the moment
I realized that they were dying
after they appeared in the comic books.
So why didn't you?
I don't know.
Maybe I just didn't want
to give up the thing that
I had worked for my entire life just because
I had a little bit of blood on my hands?
Maybe I realized that I was never
gonna be a real painter?
I'm stuck in a rut?
Or... I just want everybody to like me
in the end? I don't know. You tell me.
Who said you are not a real painter?
Whatever.
The thing is I have to
still fulfill my contract.
But... Steve's not gonna like it...
This is the last issue.
You remember the story he was telling...
The one about the girl getting
slashed to death in a bathtub?
Yes.
- Yes.
I changed it.
In the end there is a twist of fate...
It's called redemption.
What?
I can't hear you.
Berta 27 bitte kommen.
Mr. Bergen?
An alle Einheiten.
I found your note.
Berta 31 verstanden.
Müssen wir die Straße sperren?
Berta 31 ist unterwegs.
Wir schauen uns das an.
Berta 31. Ende.
Mr. Bergen?
Berta 10 an Berta 31.
You wanted to talk to me.
Berta 31 hört.
Verkehrsunfall mit drei Fahrzeugen.
Wahrscheinlich Verletzte.
Mr. Bergen?
Oh my God!
Miss Ryan, are you there? It's Rudnick.
Well, how long is "not very long".
Two minutes? A half hour? A whole century?
I don't know,
long enough to run home, lock the door,
call you guys and wait
for you to get here.
And when we arrived everything
was magically back to normal.
Thank you Miss Ryan, that will be all.
No more questions.
Listen, don't patronize me.
Bergen was here.
I saw him, and he was dead.
And there's somebody running around
pretending to be a serial killer!
A serial killer, wow?
I know what I saw.
I had a meeting this morning with Bergen
at the station. He didn't show up.
He's an investigative journalist.
He's been in every shithole in
this world and ended up in Berlin.
Wait a second. He's a journalist?
He said he knew your brother.
I think I'll ask him next time I see him.
You're not gonna see
him again, he's dead.
Look, Eric has slept with these women.
He's used them as illustrations
and now they're dead.
You didn't go and fall
in love with him, did you?
I think you might be
right about the comics.
Well, I found some photos that Michael
must have taken right before he died.
Listen, I need to go down to the
basement and check something out.
I don't wanna go by myself.
Thank you. OK. See you!
Are you really sure you wanna do this?
Yes, I am.
Are you coming, or what?
Let's get the hell out of here right now.
I'm right behind you.
Entschuldigung.
Miss Ryan, can you come
with me to the station?
We have to clear up some questions.
Yeah, it's not a problem.
Just give me a minute.
They want me to go to the station.
Hey, come on...
The storeroom belongs to him, right?
That's right.
He says it was just rough sex.
Afterwards, she asked if
she could spend the night.
He left for an appointment
and when he got back she was gone.
He says he hasn't been down
to his cellar in two years.
Did he tell you about the blackmail?
Miss Ryan.
Thank you.
He's free to go?
Hey. I'm just a cop.
I'm the one who puts em behind bars.
It's the judges who let them go.
And he's got a very good lawyer.
Can I get police protection?
If you want to sleep here at the station, sure.
Otherwise....I have no manpower.
What's this?
The certificate. They sent it over
from the embassy this morning.
You can take your brother home.
I'm sorry.
Listen, I'm getting out of the apartment.
Wait, wait, wait. What do you mean
you're getting out of the apartment?
That's not a great idea, honey.
- I got a flight for tomorrow morning
and I'm not staying here another second.
You can stay at my place.
I'll pick you up, OK?
No, no, honey,
you don't have to do that.
Marian...
- I can stay at a hotel, really.
Listen to me.
Just stay where you are.
Don't move until I get there.
I'm gonna pick you up
in ten minutes, just stay!
Alright. OK, I'll see you soon. Bye.
Marian?
Marian, what happened?
Hey, it's me, Susann.
Open the door.
Hey, open up. Come on.
No.
- Hey...
Susann?
Susann!!
Come on, come on.
Come on...
Marian, Marian, Marian. Hey....
What are you doing?
Why don't you kill me now?
What are you talking about?
- Get off me...
Hey...
Just c'mon...
Shit!
Are you ready?
Ok, Eric, this is the part
where life imitates art.
Are you ready to
become immortal, Eric?
That's what this is about,
you crazy fuck.
If you touch her,
I'm gonna kill you.
Oh, don't worry.
You won't survive this either.
But if you don't mind,
I'm gonna start with her first.
You and me, we still got
a lot to talk about.
Shit!
Why do you take the shit you
write so personally, huh?
You're a joke, Steve!
Every kid can understand
the shit you scribble.
It's all teenage masturbation
fantasies and power trips
so they can get the kicks.
It's only comic, Steve, it's only comic.
Don't you get it, Eric?
Even you, don't you get it?
God, get a life...
Yeah, just give me a minute.
You fuck. Fucking asshole!
Marian, he's coming!
Hello there.
I know what you're thinking, Marian:
"This guy ever written a book?
"A newspaper article?
"Published a poem?"
No, you're right. I haven't.
And maybe I was just lucky
that I met this Eric Mc-Artsy-Fartsy.
This great guy who can
draw this beautiful characters
with such passion and flair.
A "true artist".
I'd be nothing without him, right?
Anyone else can do it just as well.
You know what? You're wrong!
And even if you were right, even if,
I wouldn't give a shit,
because you'll be dead in a minute.
By the way.
I'm sorry about your brother.
Well, as sorry as anyone can be
for someone who's really fucked up.
It's not really my fault that he's dead.
I mean, if you want someone
to blame, blame the redhead!
I mean, I went through all the trouble
of calling up Eric and
making some lame excuse
and getting him to leave the house
and she... stayed!
I mean, what kind of a guest stays,
once the host has left? Hm?
That's just fucking rude!
It's rude, Marian. Rude!
Oh, c'mon, Marian.
Are you hiding in here?
Marian?
Marian, where are you?
Fuck, I'm looking forward to killing you!