[anticipatory music]
[narrator]
The greatest players in football
are defined by their triumphs
signature styles
and the footprint
they leave behind
once they depart
the beloved game.
[music continues]
They are the superstars
who have left
a unique mark on the game
an impact so profound
it is woven into
the very foundation
of the sport today.
[music continues]
[explosion]
[reflective music]
They are the players responsible
for the evolution of the game.
They are the visionary icons
who push themselves
and the sport to new heights.
[music continues]
From the streets
of Latin America
glorious talents such as Neymar
Chicharito, James and
the phenomenal Lionel Messi
have emerged.
They are
the successors to legends
who have long since
hung up their cleats.
Heirs that will seek to emulate
and surpass
the players before them.
[fast-paced music]
The athletes that
paved the roads to glory
with their dazzling skills
and mesmerizing
control of the ball.
Names like Pele
Hugo Sanchez
El Pibe Valderrama
and Diego Armando Maradona.
[music continues]
In the next hour
we will compare and celebrate
these generational talents
see why they are
considered one of
if not the best,
to ever step on the pitch.
[music continues]
This is, DRAW.
[explosion]
[theme music]
[music fades]
[fast-paced music]
When the world mentions football
all eyes turn to Brazil.
A nation with a unique fusion
of various cultures.
Brazilians didn't
invent the sport
but they were able
to make it their own.
They adopted its foundations
and now it's become
part of their DNA.
Two of the sport's
greatest players were born here
Edson Arantes Do Nascimento.
'Pele' is considered to be
the most important
player to have ever lived.
And Neymar stands as Brazil's
most exciting prodigy today.
[fast-paced music]
Both began, like many in Brazil
by playing on dirt,
or rugged concrete surfaces.
And as fate would have it
neither
the pavement in the favelas
nor the indoor wooden pitches
could contain the grandiosity
of these two
rare-breed individuals.
They overcame
every single adversity
that crossed their path
on the road
to becoming national heroes.
[electronic music]
Pele was born in 1940
just south of Minas Gerais.
And Neymar was born in 1992
east of Sao Paulo.
Both stars born decades apart
began their journey
in Santos Football Club.
Even though the playing
field looked very different
on the dates of their arrival
the sentiment in the air
and passion for
the game remained unchanged.
Pele joined Santos in 1956
after being scouted
by former player
Waldemar de Brito.
Conversely, Neymar
was discovered during his time
practicing with the Portuguesa
Santista Futsal Academy.
[fast-paced music]
The 1940s and 1950s were years
of political tension in Brazil.
The nation was
finally able to rid itself
of a military dictatorship
that had deprived its people
of their freedoms
for many years.
The country's
economy began to boom
and the economic growth
seemed to spread everywhere
throughout the country,
except the favelas.
[reflective music]
Sao Paulo.
Estadio Urbano Caldeira
popularly known as Villa Belmiro
was where
these two remarkable players
began developing
their skills and their swagger.
[electronic music]
[explosion]
After a brief spell
in the Youth League
Pele joined Santos'
first team at the age of 15.
Pele's talent was undeniable.
His skills were so impressive
that at the mere age of 17
he was chosen
to form part of the team
that would represent Brazil in
the 1958 World Cup in Sweden.
But it was not
an entirely smooth experience.
Upon his arrival
with the national team
Pele was labeled as young
naive and inexperienced,
by the team psychologist.
However, Vicente Feola
coach of
the Scratch du Oro at the time
completely disregarded
the psychologist's diagnosis
and allowed the Brazilian star
to travel with the team.
Pele witnessed
Brazil's first game
of the tournament
from the bench.
His debut came later
during a match
against the Soviet Union.
Pele scored his first
World Cup goal against Wales.
That match did more
than Pele could fathom.
It instantly let the world know
that he was a force
to be reckoned with.
[fast-paced music]
Brazil's team reached
the tournament's final
where they faced
the hosts, Sweden.
This encounter
confirmed everything
that had been
predicted about Pele.
He scored two goals
that ultimately led Brazil
to their first
World Cup in history.
At 17 years old
Edson Arantes do Nascimento
became
an international celebrity.
At the same age
Neymar Junior debuted
in Brazil's First Division.
He was included in
Santos' first team in 2009.
Ney scored more than
40 goals in 60 games
and with his cheeky approach
he became a vital factor
in Santos' Campeonata Paulista
and the Copa do Brasil's
victorious campaigns.
Despite his
incredible accomplishments
Neymar was not
included in the 23-man roster
that would represent Brazil
during the World Cup
in South Africa.
Like Pele, Ney was labeled
as 'inexperienced' by Dunga
the national team's coach.
Dunga was later fired
for the team's poor
results during the tournament.
[fast-paced music]
Months later,
with no obstacles in the way
Neymar had the opportunity
to make his first appearance
with the national team.
This took place
during a friendly match
versus the United States.
In 2010, Neymar's
exceptional achievements
earned him an invite
to the annual FIFA Gala
There, he received
the Puskas award
for scoring
the best goal of the year
and was also recognized as
the best South American
player of the year.
In 1962, at only 21 years of age
Pele was already considered
the best football
player on the planet.
He was indispensable for Brazil
and a fundamental part
of Santos' mid-field.
He made history with both teams
creating unforgettable moments
that would live on
in the sport forever.
[cheering]
[explosion]
[fast-paced music]
To this day,
Pele has been the only player
to have won the World Cup
on three occasions
and with Santos, he was able
to break the predominance
that the Argentine teams had
over the Brazilian squads.
They were able to defeat Boca
and lift their second
Copa Libertadores
in the mythical Bombonera
something that has
never been replicated.
Pele played most of
his career in his home country
but the same
cannot be said for Neymar
whose chapter in Brazil
was cut short by modern times.
[electronic music]
The tempting offer
to play for Barcelona
one of the world's
most dominant teams
led the Brazilian sensation
to depart Santos
and sign a lavish contract
with the Catalan club in 2013.
But Ney's
new-found glory in Europe
did not side-track his
commitment
with the national team.
He put his talent on display
alongside
the rest of the Selecao
at the Confederations Cup
the 2014 World Cup,
and the Rio Olympics.
[cheering]
[fast-paced music]
Pele also experienced
a short international stint.
He packed his bags
and traveled north of Brazil
to the United States
where he joined
the New York Cosmos.
In 1977
after two years with the Cosmos
the King played
his last professional match.
The game was
between his beloved Santos
and his current
home, the Cosmos.
The match was
the perfect farewell
for this iconic player.
[rhythmic modern music]
Today, Neymar is considered
one of the best
players in the world
and carrying
such a coveted title
has opened many doors
for the young athlete.
In 2017, he departed
from Barcelona's Camp Nou
and joined Paris Saint-Germaine
who offered
the star-boy a contract
that broke
several transfer records.
[fast-paced music]
For years,
Brazil has been represented
by world-class talent.
It has become
impossible not to compare
new generations to
the nation's permanent hero
Pele.
With so many eyes upon him
Will Neymar Junior
live up to the King?
It is difficult
to draw a conclusion
based on leadership
and achievements at this time
as Ney is still very young.
And although they are
both extraordinary players
they have each taken on
two very different
roles on the pitch.
Pele played most of his career
as a withdrawn forward
or a center-attacking mid.
Neymar excels when he's
coming in from the left wing
but has also taken on
roles as a second striker
and as center forward
for Brazil.
He is extremely efficient
at destabilizing
the opponents' defense
making him extremely dangerous
just like his predecessor.
[electronic music]
Neymar currently
holds more than 50 goals
in a little more
than 80 appearances
with the national team
which places him very close
to matching Pele's record
of 72 goals in 92 matches.
On a larger scale,
it is unlikely for Neymar
to break Pele's grand record
of 1,000 goals by the age of 29.
Ney currently holds slightly
over a quarter of that number
at the age of 26.
[fast-paced music]
Ney and the King can be compared
on various characteristics
such as their vision, agility
ability to outwit defenders
and the ginga they brewed up
while playing as kids
on the streets of Brazil.
Both are
undeniable trick masters
perfecting everything
from 'magical sombrero' flicks
to impressive elasticos.
[fast-paced music]
When Pele retired,
he became the image
for a number of
different commercial brands.
He also participated
in several films and TV shows.
Pele has worked tirelessly
to defend human rights
and was appointed
a UNESCO goodwill ambassador
as a result of his initiatives.
As far as his personal life goes
Pele is father to seven children
and has been
married three times.
Most recently
he eloped with his
current partner, Marcia Aoki
in 2016.
Neymar has also found
love in his personal life.
He is currently dating
the Brazilian actress
Bruna Marquezine.
[fast-paced music]
Football is experienced
differently in every country.
In Mexico, the passion
fueled by football is intense.
Here, football
is more than just a sport
It's a religion,
and the players are the gods.
This melting pot
of rich cultural history
in the northern-most
part of Latin America.
It is also the birthplace
of two of
the game's brightest stars
Hugo Sanchez Marquez
and Javier Hernandez Balcazar
El Chicharito.
Hugo Sanchez Marquez was
born in Mexico City in 1958.
Javier Hernandez Balcazar
was born
29 years later in Guadalajara.
Both players came into the world
with remarkable pedigrees.
Sanchez' father
played for Atlante in Cancun
while Javier's
father and grandfather
were both Mexican football
idols during their time.
[music continues]
Both were exposed to
the game at a very early age
Hugo Sanchez at 14 years old
and Javier Hernandez
at nine years old.
The pair developed
an appetite for goals
that set them
apart from the rest.
[explosion]
[anticipatory music]
In 1974
Sanchez took his first steps
in professional football
with the youth system at
the National Autonomous
University of Mexico.
That marks the beginning
of a 21-year career
filled with pages
of unforgettable
football artistry.
[cheering]
Chicharito began
his journey to the top
at the Club Deportivo
Guadalajara Youth Academy.
Hugo's career developed quickly.
In 1976
in addition to his debut
with Puma's first team
he also represented his country
at the Montreal Olympics.
At the age of 18
he was already
demonstrating his talents
with the senior national team.
His efforts earned
Mexico their qualification
to the 1978
World Cup held in Argentina.
[fast-paced music]
That same year, he demonstrated
his skills on the pitch
by finishing off his
third season with Pumas
with more than 25 goals.
In 1980, he was an instrumental
part on the path
to winning the Mexican League
the CONCACAF Club Championship
and the Inter-American Cup.
His spectacular performance
throughout the season
attracted the attention
of a European giant
and at the age of 23
Sanchez embarked
on a journey overseas.
[music continues]
[explosion]
Chicharito began to
write his own history
at the young age of 15
when his youth club Chivas
offered him his first
professional contract.
[electronic music]
In 2009
Chicharito's talent
exploded exponentially
as he began to play
at his full potential.
He finished the year
as the top scorer
with 11 goals and as
the Champion of the Interliga.
The following year,
his triumphs earned him
a spot on the senior team
that would represent Mexico
during the World
Cup in South Africa.
In the tournament, he
scored his first World Cup goal
against France.
Back home, he found himself
leading the top scorer
list once again.
His phenomenal
performances for Chivas
caught the eye
of Manchester United
and at 22 years of age
Javier Hernandez signed
with the Red Devils.
[fast-paced music]
Hugo Sanchez
was just one year older
when he arrived in Europe
and joined Atletico Madrid
Sanchez had a tough time
adapting to the Spanish
team's rough ways of playing.
This was obvious
in his performance.
This incited a wave of criticism
from the Spanish press
who labeled the Mexican player
a total failure.
Sanchez remained driven.
He was not going
to let these obstacles
stand in the way
of him fulfilling his goal.
He was determined to succeed
outside of
his country's domestic league
and in the 1984 to 1985 season
the world began
to witness his grandiosity.
That year he was
a fundamental part
of the colchonero's triumph
in the Copa del Rey
and in the Spanish Super Cup
all while securing his place
as Pichichi of the league.
These successes
caught the attention
of Spanish super-club
and neighboring rival
Real Madrid.
[exciting music]
In 1985, 27-year old Sanchez
took the definitive step
that united him with
the victorious merengue side.
A fantastic group of players
known as La Quinta del Buitre
led by Emilio Butragueno
were waiting for Hugo's arrival
at the Santiago Bernabeu.
The lethal combination
of Hugol and La Quinta
established an unbeatable
dynasty in the Spanish League
that lasted for five years.
In four of them, Hugo was
named Pichichi of the league
and thus, the legend of
the PentaPichichi was born.
[explosion]
Chicharito's first year
in Europe was remarkable.
With the help of
his effectiveness
in crucial situations
Manchester United managed to win
the Premier League
and the Community Shield.
This earned him
the respect of his teammates
and above all, of
his coach, Sir Alex Ferguson.
[fast-paced music]
After four years at Manchester
Chicharito's stay
came to an end.
That summer, his nation
reached the round of 16
at the World Cup in Brazil
and subsequently, he became
the fourth Mexican in history
to sign with Real Madrid.
[music continues]
In 1992
Hugo Sanchez
departed Real Madrid
and embarked
on a four-year journey
through the leagues in Austria
the United States,
Spain, and Mexico.
In 1997, at the age of 39
he retired from
football in his homeland.
[electronic music]
Chicharito's fate
is very similar
to that of his predecessor.
When he departed Real Madrid
he took on a new
challenge in the Bundesliga.
During his two years
with Bayern Leverkusen
he scored a total of 39 goals.
In 2017
he made a return
to the Premier League
and joined his current club
West Ham United.
Hugo Sanchez and Javier
'el Chicharito' Hernandez
have become
legacies in their own right
but one thing sets them apart
the number of
goals each has scored.
During his 21-year career
Sanchez reached
the 500 goal milestone.
That number could
possibly outshine
Chicharito's accomplishments
as he has only scored around
190 goals at the age of 29.
Those numbers don't
dim Hernandez' talents
who has scored almost
50 goals for the Tri
making him Mexico's top scorer.
During his time,
Sanchez was only able
to score 29 goals
for the national team.
Hugo amazed the masses
with his bicycle kicks, volleys
and of course his
signature celebrations
that defied gravity.
[music continues]
Hernandez has been a quieter
and more reserved player
throughout his career.
Javier is used to defining
the final moments of every game
and has become
the last-minute hero
on multiple occasions.
Chicharito's weaknesses
were Sanchez' strengths.
His long-distance shots
gave him a clear advantage.
He was dangerous inside,
outside, and around the box
while Chicharito shines best
when he's receiving passes
from outside the penalty area.
Despite their differences
they are both considered
two of the best players
in Mexican history.
Although their
careers took similar paths
the lives of these two athletes
could not have been
any more different.
Hugo Sanchez was one
of the first Mexican players
to market himself as an athlete.
He made appearances
in several commercials
talk shows
and advertizing campaigns
in Mexico and in Spain.
Sanchez embraced fame
and lived for the crowds.
There's even
a street named after him
in the Mexican city of Puebla.
Football continues to hold
an important role in his life.
He currently works as
a sports commentator in Mexico.
Chicharito, on the other hand,
is less of a protagonist
and prefers to use his fame
to support humanitarian causes.
In 2012, Hernandez was appointed
as a UNICEF ambassador.
He utilizes his fame to
support initiatives in Mexico
that's aimed to help
children living in poverty.
[reflective music]
Colombia is a nation rich
in coffee, countryside and sea.
A nation reborn from decades
of conflict and heartbreak.
Its people turn to music
art and football to find joy.
[fast-paced music]
Two of their
greatest football legends
share something
that makes them great.
The number ten.
[fast-paced music]
Carlos 'El Pibe' Valderrama
was born in 1961
in the coastal city
of Santa Marta.
And 29 years later
in the city of Cucuta
his successor,
James Rodriquez, was born.
Carlos Valderrama
was born into a humble family.
He played football
whenever he could
with his brothers and cousins.
But his natural talent quickly
set him apart from the rest.
[explosion]
[fast-paced music]
Football was also
a fundamental part
of James Rodriquez' early life.
Everything in his life
revolved around a football.
Between the ages
of four and five
he joined
the Tolimense Youth Academy
and the course of
his life was transformed.
El Pibe signed his
first professional contract
with Union Magdalena
at the age of 19.
This marks
the beginning of the road
that would lead him
to become part of
the Milionarios de Bogota
and Deportivo Cali
the clubs where he demonstrated
his one-of-a-kind talent.
In 1987, he led the team
during their third-place finish
at the Copa America
where he was recognized as
the best player
of the tournament.
[fast-paced music]
In 1988, his amazing skills and
intelligence as a mid-fielder
earned him a move
to the French League
playing for Montpellier.
James Rodriquez' encounter
with international football
arrived before
his 20th birthday.
He had already excelled
in Colombia's Primera B
and at just 15 years old
he became the youngest
player in Colombia's Under 17.
In 2005,
he was presented the opportunity
to show off his techniques
with the first team
at Envigado Futbol Club.
Three years later
James' impressive performance
allowed him to
demonstrate his skills
at Banfield in Buenos Aires.
Eight months later,
the Colombian superstar
became the youngest
foreign debutante
in the Argentine First Division.
[electronic music]
With this
string of accomplishments
Rodriquez caught the attention
of the old continent
especially of one of
the fiercest clubs in Portugal
Porto.
In 2010, at the age of 18
the Colombian mid-fielder
finalized his move to Europe.
[music continues]
[explosion]
[fast-paced music]
Unlike James, Valderrama's
consecration as a player
did not come until
after his 27th birthday.
In 1990, he was the strength
of Montpellier's mid-field
and a key player
in the French Cup victory.
But it was at that
year's World Cup in Italy
that Valderrama played
the best tournament of his life.
He led Colombia
to the round of 16
for the first time
in the country's history.
[exciting music]
After the World Cup
Valderrama searched
for new challenges
and he briefly
took his talents to Spain
where he joined Valladolid.
He returned home and helped
strengthen the national team
as they made their way
to the second World Cup.
[anticipatory music]
Colombia's
demonstration of skill
during their five-nil victory
against Maradona's Argentina
in River Plate's
Estadio Monumental
was historic.
The road to
the tournament was impressive
but Colombia's World Cup dream
rapidly turned into a nightmare.
The team did not live up to
their expectations
in the group stage.
They lost their
first match against Romania
and the second
to the United States
due to an own goal carried out
by defender Andres Escobar.
Despite having achieved
victory during the third match
fate was set,
and Colombia was sent home.
[reflective music]
The defeat was heart-breaking
and coincided
with some of the hardest times
in Colombian history
as the guerrillas
and drug traffickers
terrorized
the country's citizens.
Only 11 days after
the arrival of the national team
Andres Escobar was assassinated.
[explosion]
[fast-paced music]
The news tarnished and stained
the national team's success.
Valderrama retired from
international football in 1998
after playing in
the World Cup in France
and in 2002
he officially
retired from football
leaving behind
the memories he created
during his 21-year career.
Although
Valderrama's achievements
fill important chapters in
the history of
Colombian football
James continues
writing his own story.
[music continues]
His first year in Europe
was a total success.
In 2010,
Porto won the Europa League
and the Taca de Portugal.
In 2012, he was recognized
as the best player in the league
with the Bola de Ouro.
In 2013,
he was acquired by Monaco
in a deal worth 45 million euros
and his development as a player
came at a crucial time
for Colombian football.
With his leadership
and technical input
the Cafeteros
returned to the World Cup
following a 16-year absence.
In Brazil 2014,
Colombia fascinated millions
with their vibrant style
and James with
his spectacular goals.
He was honored
with a Golden Boot
three Man of the Match
recognitions
and his name began
to appear on the radar
of Europe's biggest clubs.
It was quite a year for James.
By the third quarter of 2014
Spanish giants Real Madrid
had signed Rodriquez
for 90 million euros.
During his time in Madrid
he won the European Super Cup
and the Club World Cup
scoring more than
15 phenomenal goals.
In 2017
Rodriquez departed
the Spanish capital
and joined his
current team, Bayern Munich.
[explosion]
[fast-paced music]
Comparing these two
Colombian football stars
has become inevitable.
James and El Pibe Valderrama
have defended
the Colombian colors with honor
and have carried
the number ten with pride.
Rodriquez' speed
and vision are things
Valderrama did not possess
but Valderrama
compensated his weaknesses
with his intelligent
anticipation
and defensive tactics.
James is a bit more versatile
and can be placed
in different positions.
He has lined up as a winger,
or attacking mid-fielder.
Carlos played further back
a play-maker during
the majority of his career
and only toward
the end of his career
as an attacking mid-fielder.
Although Rodriquez
is primarily left-footed
these two sensational
assist machines
share the incredible ability
to play well with both feet.
They also share the
mental capacity to prioritize
making crucial passes
to team-mates,
despite having to sacrifice
scoring opportunities.
Valderrama
scored almost 90 goals
throughout his 21-year career
while James with
a long way to go in his career
has already surpassed
the 100th goal mark.
Carlos Valderrama
is known for his eccentric
behavior and charisma.
He is idolized as a symbol
of football in his nation.
In 2014 he was inducted
into the Football
Hall of Fame in Mexico.
He has been married twice,
and has six children.
[explosion]
James Rodriquez is one of
the most popular footballers
in the world today.
He was married to Daniela Ospina
sister of his
teammate David Ospina
with whom he has a daughter
named Salome Rodriquez.
According to Forbes Magazine
Rodriquez was one of the
top-earning athletes of 2017.
[explosion]
It's impossible
not to mention Argentina
when discussing football.
This two-time
World Cup-winning nation
has without a doubt
made its name
in the world of football.
Two of its most beloved
and legendary players
are Diego Armando Maradona
and Lionel Andres Messi.
Maradona is considered
the best player of
the late 20th century by many
and Messi is one of
the most important figures
in the modern-day game.
Maradona was born
on October 30th, 1960
in Via Fiorito
a suburb in Buenos Aires.
Twenty-six years later,
in the city of Rosario
Lionel Messi was born.
Like most Argentine children
Maradona's
first love was football.
Those who saw
Diego play as a child
knew he was built differently.
The same
could be said about Lionel.
Since childhood, he was
a force to be reckoned with.
At the age of eight, Diego
was discovered by a neighbor
who took him to train
with Argentinos Juniors.
Messi was four years old
when he played for Grandoli
a small local club in his city
where he would average
six to seven goals per game.
It was obvious that they were
both destined for greatness.
In 1976, a week
before his 16th birthday
Diego Maradona
debuted with Argentinos Juniors
and during his
five years with the club
he managed to score
a total of 115 goals.
His skills on
the pitch amazed everyone
and his potential
did not go unnoticed.
One of the country's
greatest teams, Boca Juniors
did not hesitate
to offer Diego a contract.
Maradona reached
the Bombonera in 1981
and he played
with one of the most
popular teams in the capital
before his 21st birthday
but his stay with
the Argentine giants was brief.
When the 1982 World Cup arrived
Diego formed part of the team
that would be
traveling to Spain.
Maradona's debut was not enough
to take the Albiceleste
past the first round.
After the tournament he did not
return home with
the national team.
The youngster had been purchased
by football club Barcelona
for seven
point seven million dollars
a record-breaking
amount at the time.
[explosion]
Messi's rise in Europe
happened under completely
different circumstances.
At the age of 11,
he was diagnosed
with a growth
hormone deficiency.
This almost changed
the course of his life
but his family was persistent
in finding Leo a sponsor that
would pay for his treatments.
Representatives
of football club Barcelona
had the opportunity
to witness la pulga practice
and as soon as they saw him play
they decided to cover the entire
cost of his treatment.
In 2004, after four years
with the Youth Academy
he made his first-team debut.
Maradona played in Barcelona
for only two seasons.
In 1984, he was
transferred to Napoli.
He arrived at the San Paolo
during the prime of his career
ready to make history.
[cheering]
In 1986, at the age of 25
Maradona was
ready to participate
in his second World Cup.
[fast-paced music]
During this tournament
in the quarter-final
match versus England
Diego was involved
in one of the most
controversial
moments of his career
and also one of
the most memorable plays
in football history.
A ball that was
disputed between him
and English
goal-keeper Peter Shilton
ended up in the net.
The goal was validated
and the polemical
controversy began.
Diego had scored
the goal with his hand.
The play was baptized
as 'The Hand of God'
and it is still
remembered and discussed
in football pitches
across the globe today.
Within minutes, Maradona
went from villain to hero.
He scored one of the most
incredible goals of his career
so grandiose and spectacular
that it was named
'The Goal of the Century.'
Eventually, Diego
reached football supremacy
by crowning Argentina
World Cup champions
for the second time in history.
[fast-paced music]
Back in Italy, he continued
to astound the fans.
In 1989, he led Napoli
to their first league title
and UEFA Cup victory.
Then, in 1990
they achieved
their second Serie A title.
His image has been
immortalized in Italy.
His contributions
and leadership in Napoli
have left
a permanent mark on its people.
Murals and shrines
throughout the city
are dedicated to him,
and to this day
Diego is remembered
as a god in the city of Naples.
Despite having
achieved glory in Italy
Maradona began to struggle.
[unsettling music]
He tested positive for cocaine
and was consequently
suspended from the sport
for 15 months.
In 1992
he left the Italian club
and his number ten
shirt was retired.
But the giant's real downfall
did not come until
the 1994 World Cup
Following the second match
he tested positive during
an anti-doping inspection.
He was expelled
from the tournament
and Argentina
was eventually eliminated.
Diego Armando Maradona
officially retired in 1997
sporting his beloved
Boca Juniors jersey.
[explosion]
[fast-paced music]
Lionel Messi made
his World Cup debut
at the 2006
World Cup in Germany.
He was part of the action
during their second game
versus Serbia and Montenegro
where he scored
his very first World Cup goal.
By 2009
La pulga was the star of a team
that was built to succeed.
That year,
Barcelona broke the record
for most trophies won
in a competitive year.
Messi impressed
during every single match
and his incredible
season won him his first
of four consecutive Ballon d'Or.
But his peak had yet to come.
In 2012, he broke
another world record
this time for
the highest number of goals
scored in a calendar year.
Ninety-one goals between
his club and national team
earned him that achievement.
With three Champions League,
four Ballon d'Or
and five Spanish Leagues
conquered by the age of 25
the world began to
understand that Lionel Messi
was from another dimension.
In the 2014-15 season
he won his third Copa del Rey
fourth Champions League
and seventh Spanish League
as well as individually,
his fifth Ballon D'Or.
[electronic music]
On the pitch, both Diego and Leo
fluctuate between
the right wing and the middle
playing as
center-attacking mids.
Throughout his career,
Maradona played with more grit
always demonstrating
an almost warrior-like
style on the pitch.
He efficiently combined
his skill with strength.
Messi, on the other hand resorts
more towards his ingenuity
vision, and
creativity on the field.
Leo has scored more
than 600 goals to date.
While El Diego
scored just over 300 goals
during his 21-year career.
Both are avid dribblers
due to the combination of
their small size and agility.
Their similar playing styles
categorizes them as
the legends they are today.
They are recognized as
true technical geniuses
distinguished by their mastery
and creativity on the field
which they use
to build memorable
indescribable
and effective plays.
The way these two athletes
place themselves on the pitch
have many striking similarities
but the way these two
have led their private lives
could not be more different.
Diego Maradona has been
involved in numerous scandals
while Lionel Messi
has led a quieter
and more private lifestyle.
Maradona married
Claudia Villafane in 1989.
The couple had two daughters
Dalma and Giannina.
After 14 years together
the couple
announced their separation.
During his time in Naples
he had an extramarital son
named Diego Sinagra
who is now also
a professional football player.
Diego has struggled with
alcohol and drug addiction
for many years.
In 2001
he was
hospitalized in Buenos Aires
due to
a life-threatening overdose.
In 2004
he stated that he had fully
recovered from his addictions.
Maradona has also been very bold
with his political decisions.
His support for
leftist ideologies
have even found
a place on his body.
Diego currently lives in Dubai
and enjoys the benefits
that his multi-million
dollar career left him.
[explosion]
[fast-paced music]
Lionel Messi is the opposite.
He stays as far away
from controversy as possible.
In 2017, he married
his childhood girlfriend
Antonella Roccuzzo
in her hometown Rosario.
Together,
they have three children
Thiago, Mateo, and Ciro.
Today, Messi is one of
the best-paid
athletes in the world.
The riches have not changed him.
The Argentine
has remained humble
and is known for
his introverted demeanor.
[explosion]
[reflective music]
The legends of the game
are those who broke
the paradigms of the sport.
They are those who feel the game
run through their veins
and come alive as soon
as that whistle blows.
They are those who imagine
create, visualize,
and play football
as if it were magic.
The lives of
these eight personalities
have shaped them
into iconic individuals.
These football players
traverse through the sport
over the last 50 years.
They have experienced obstacles
triumphs, and different
versions of the game.
[fast-paced music]
They dare
to challenge the impossible
and pave the way
to football glory.
This is DRAW.
[ending theme music]