Well.
It would be slow.
Gentle as a dream.
An object thrown
into the unknown.
It could be called...
It would be called...
Dreaming Films
Some films are silent
and some films speak,
some films act
and some films watch.
There are films of memories
and memories of films.
Some films have shut eyes,
others open them.
Some films say goodbye,
others say farewell.
Some films tell no story,
others tell a story.
Some films laugh,
and others cry.
Some films take the gods'
point of view,
some take man's point of view.
Some films travel,
others stay put.
Some films remember,
others forget.
Finally, there are
the films I dreamed
then made...
and the films I dreamed
but never made.
These are the dream films.
It would be the story of a film
that starts in a cabin
and ends with a storm,
a sand storm,
or a wind storm,
or a sea storm,
but a real storm.
One day...
One day, a man...
One day, a man, a filmmaker...
One day, a man, a filmmaker
had a dream.
He dreamed of making a film
that would contain all the films
he had dreamed of making.
Imaginary Map
of Dream Film Territories.
It is the dream of a child
who was told the story of Ulysses,
that fragile man,
who was clever, who lied,
who travelled so far
from his loved ones.
Ulysses,
this is the first journey.
It would all start in Troy,
for it was there,
under the great walls,
that the great hero Achilles died,
and from there that Ulysses
left on his great odyssey,
preferring the sea and adventure
over the heroism of battle.
The film would show his journey,
the strange islands he passes,
beautiful and unsettling,
like the Island of the Sirens.
But above all,
there would be the island
where he washes up alone,
that of the beautiful Calypso,
the goddess
who falls in love with him
and keeps him seven long years
by her side.
She promises him immortality,
paradise,
but Ulysses leaves,
because to journey is to leave
and to return,
because he loves the passing of time.
And he returns to Ithaca,
where his wife and son await him,
where his dog, Argos,
also awaits
and who will be
the first to recognize him.
Then there is Rouch, the traveller,
the filmmaker, the master,
for whom films
are about sharing,
a 'potlatch', as he used to say.
A few years ago,
Rouch came to my home
and Boris, another filmmaker
had come to film him,
get him to talk about cinema.
What we do is improvise,
which means being able to move around,
get up and go to look at an insect,
whatever.
All the rest...
the image doesn't matter a bit.
The image will be good
if it means something.
But focusing and all that,
I don't believe in it.
So that's what it is
and the only one capable
of filming and understanding
is that little dog.
He has his camera in his nose.
He looks with his nose,
his sense of smell.
Filming is like playing with a dog.
You throw something he likes
that he can bring back to you.
That's cinema.
Thank you.
Great sequence.
Great sequence!
Because you too thought of
the cinema, a film,
as a strange object
flung into the unknown,
which comes back to you later.
Could you define 'potlatch'?
Potlatch means sharing surplus.
We all have a surplus of dreams,
of means, of food, etc.,
that we must share.
One thing I feel is essential
is necessary waste.
One must waste one's energy
and one's riches,
on one condition,
that you do so with people
who will do the same in their turn.
Then one day, by phone,
a friend told me of his death
in an accident,
one night on a road in Niger.
I didn't know what to say.
I grabbed my camera and filmed,
dreamed these images for him.
When Jean Rouch died,
a legend was born:
Mahatma the spirit,
Mahatma the Touareg,
had snatched his soul.
And I dream of seeking it out.
But how do you seek,
how do you show a soul?
In Polynesia, the soul
is represented by the ray.
One day,
a traveller came, with
a portrait by Raphael.
When he showed it
to four old men on an island,
where the art of portrait painting
was unknown,
they all said: "Magnificent.
Yes, we recognize it."
Intrigued, the traveller
asked what they saw.
They all replied: "A ray!"
I dream of going to place
this covvry on Jean's tomb
and I dream of seeking his soul.
Legend has it that Arrako Gikko,
the river spirit,
Mahatma the Touareg's mother,
took back Jean's soul.
Legend has it that his soul has
become the guardian spirit of the river,
in this loop of the Niger
where hippopotamuses swim,
where he lived,
worked and filmed all his life.
This is where Rouch
made his first film.
When he shared it,
screening it for the locals,
the Sorko fishermen
asked him to take out the music,
so as not to frighten
the hippopotamuses.
One day, Stany came to visit,
before leaving to sail around the world.
He left,
promising to bring back images
for me to dream on.
Look,
it's the little blue tortoise
I found on the beach that day.
It was just before I left
to sail around the world.
Remember?
You asked me to set him free
in the land of the tortoises.
There's a film
I've always wanted to make,
something lodged within me
like the trace of a gaze.
I remember an adolescent
sitting at the table of a night club
astray in a foreign land.
I remember the sonata, her body,
the first woman's body
I ever saw.
I remember the atmosphere,
the smoke,
and what her gaze
said about the gaze of men.
We should evoke the travellers,
the sailors,
speak of those who left first,
of their leap into the unknown.
When a man like Columbus
leaves to discover America,
even those condemned to death
refuse a pardon
to leave with him.
But those sailors were the first
to sail far from land,
losing sight of it,
surrounded by water only.
And they knew
that whatever happened,
nobody would come to save them.
Those sailors made songs
about their fears
and their solitude.
Weeks, surrounded by the ocean,
believing they saw mermaids
rise from the water...
until the first signs of land.
The first thing they truly saw
of the new world
was this...
It was dark
and without realizing it,
they had come close
to the first island.
This is what they saw.
The next day,
they realized it was
the lights of the Indians
coming outside at night,
to relieve themselves.
The Indians believed the sailors
had come from the sky,
the sailors were certain
they had found paradise.
The mixed waters,
of different colours,
all around them,
proved them right,
they were indeed in paradise.
The world was thought to be
the shape of a pear.
Paradise was right at the top.
From this spring flowed
the four rivers known at the time.
It was therefore normal
that around paradise,
the waters be of mixed colours.
All this can be found
in Las Casas.
If a film were to be made
about one of the first travellers,
it would be him,
the churchman,
Bartholomew de las Casas.
He was Columbus's companion,
went on the first journeys
and told it all in his
amazing "History of the Indies".
Las Casas is wonderful.
When he pondered
the production of pearls,
which the sailors saw
for the first time,
he recounted that oysters
came onto the beach at night
and walked,
opening and closing their valve,
until they reached
the first blades of grass.
There, they lay down
and opened wide,
awaiting the first drop of morning dew,
which would later
become the pearl.
Then, the oysters would
quickly return to the sea.
When he reached Cuba,
the first big island
they discovered,
Las Casas wrote:
"They saw nightingales
singing very softly,
and it is good to think there's a land
where nightingales sing in November."
But Cuba
was also the first experiment
in enslavement,
for wherever the white man
thought he had found heaven,
he turned it into a hell.
Las Casas tells stories
from another point of view,
as with the first Indian rebellion.
The Spanish had just arrived
on the island of Cuba
and went on land to celebrate.
They left 8 crew members on board,
to guard the Indians
they had taken prisoner.
But the latter rebelled,
killed their guards,
raised the anchors
and left with the ship.
From the shore,
the Spaniards watched them
disappear into the horizon.
Cuba brought the discovery
of tobacco.
The first to bring it back to Europe
were excommunicated.
Las Casas talks of "pipes of smells",
of "
it comets, full of scented herbs
that intoxicate
and lull the body to sleep."
Later, it was in these places,
while tobacco was rolled,
that Alexander Dumas'
"Count of Monte Cristo"
was read out loud, for years.
I read it as a child,
looking at the picture of Danton,
trapped in the hell of his prison.
Dreaming a film based on blue.
The blue of the sea
and the blue of the sky.
Blue, the color of eternity,
of paradise,
the world of before, where men and
animals spoke the same language
and lived in peace.
In Ulysses' era,
the Masters of Time wore blue.
And finding near this little town
at the "edge of the world",
as Ulysses called it,
the island of Calypso,
whence he set off to join his family.
He returns and Argos awaits him.
Home at last,
but one day,
Ulysses would leave once more.
The first man to go to paradise
and come back
was Lucian of Samosata.
Around 180 A.D.,
Lucian made the first trip
to the moon.
On his way back,
he stopped off in paradise.
He saw cities of gold and rubies,
temples of emeralds and diamonds
bathed in an eternal dawn.
The ears of corn
bore little loaves,
there were fountains of honey,
milk and wine.
Here, souls once again
took on a human shape
and Lucian described
his meeting with Ulysses,
who gave him a letter
for Calypso.
In the story, in ancient Greek,
Lucian repeats Ulysses' words:
"Now that I am in paradise,
I miss the pleasures
we had together.
I wish I had always stayed
by your side,
and accepted your offer
of immortality.
If I can escape, rest assured,
you will see me again.
Farewell, Ulysses."
Then there's the paradise
my mother described,
the paradise she saw as a child
and wanted to return to.
Sometimes, we spent the afternoon
at my grandparents'...
at my grandparents',
not far from our home.
Their red brick house
was surrounded
by a magnificent garden
containing all sorts of flowers,
fruit trees, redcurrants,
and raspberries.
I imagined I was in
the Garden of Eden.
And under the apple tree,
I saw Eve hold out the apple
to Adam,
the snake that curled around the tree,
then the Good Lord chasing them
out of the Garden of Eden
into the big wasteland
just opposite my grandparents' place.
A friend sends me a postcard
from Las Casas in Mexico.
Bartholomew de las Casas
stayed here for years.
The Indians named the city after him
because he was the first
to defend them,
to say they had a soul,
just as he was the first
to question the role
of the White man,
the first to say
you must not dream for others.
It would be the story of a man,
a traveller,
who spent his life
filming railway tracks,
endlessly fleeing,
all over the world.
In the 16th century,
the Mughal Emperor Babar wrote:
"If paradise on earth exists,
it is here, in Kashmir."
Across these Himalayan landscapes,
the Frenchman, Bonin, set off.
After several attempts,
in 1900, he finally became
the first Westerner to reach Tibet.
After a crazy journey,
he neared Koko Nor,
the Great Blue Lake.
In his notes,
ever more enthusiastic,
he described the mad night winds,
the rooftop of the world,
the tribes of nomadic Mongols
and Tibetans
travelling in thousands
to visit Genghis Khan's tomb,
to pay tribute to him.
But today,
all researchers agree
that there is not,
nor ever has been,
neither there, nor anywhere else,
a tomb to Genghis Khan.
Could his whole journey
have been but a dream?
There's a film to be made
about Magellan,
about the man and his crazy project
to be the first to travel around the world.
The world was known to be round
and much bigger than first thought,
but no one was sure
a passage existed
south of South America,
to go all the way round.
No one knew.
Magellan, without knowing
if he'd ever return
charters a fleet and sets off.
Five ships leave
the European continent
on September 20th, 1519.
After three years of travelling,
only one ship
would return to Spain.
All along South America,
ever more doubtful,
Magellan seeks the passage.
The fleet weathers storm after storm,
suffers a mutiny,
one boat founders on a reef,
another deserts
and returns to Europe,
but Magellan perseveres.
It took him over a year
to reach the passage,
which would later be named
the Strait of Magellan.
There,
after months without seeing
a living soul,
they spotted the Patagonian Indians
on the shore,
clothed in animal pelts.
But they fled
when they approached.
At night, they saw their fires
and called the desolate shore,
Land of Fire.
The Patagonian Indians
were the last ones
to travel down South America
in their migration
to the end of the earth,
carrying with them
the dream culture
common to all Amerindian peoples.
The lnextiua celebration
is the rite when
one seeks one's destiny.
Here is what a 16th century monk
had to say about it:
"During this feast,
they said all the gods were dancing,
so all those dancing
dressed up as various characters,
some as birds, others as animals
and some metamorphosed
into butterflies,
others into bees or beetles.
Still others carried a sleeping man
on their back,
saying it was the Dream..."
For Magellan's crew,
the ordeal of the Pacific
was awful.
Three months of sailing
with no sight of land.
Many died of hunger
before reaching the heavenly islands.
They were welcomed like gods.
But everywhere they went,
despite Magellan's orders,
the sailors couldn't resist
the island girls
and sowed discord
wherever they went.
He who wrote the tale
of the journey,
tells us:
"In exchange for one knife,
you get two or three girls,
whose only clothing is their hair,
and this for a lifetime."
In the Philippines, Magellan was killed
in an expedition against a local lord.
The ship then sailed on,
and set course for Europe.
Months later, only one ship
and 18 sailors made it to Spain.
But none of them
was the first to sail around the world,
as History would have it.
The first man to sail around the world,
of whom no portrait exists,
was Enrique, Magellan's slave,
companion, and shadow.
A native of Malaysia,
Enrique had followed his master all over,
even on his trip around the world.
But in the Sunda Islands,
Enrique's mother tongue is spoken
and he acts as interpreter,
Magellan is killed
and Enrique disappears.
I imagine Enrique
back on his island,
grown old,
far from the history of the world.
He dreams of the story of Serrao,
whom he knew so well...
Many reasons have been given
to explain Magellan's attempted world tour.
Perhaps Serrao is the explanation.
Ferdinand de Magellan
and Francisco Serrao
had been close friends for years.
In 1512, Serrao leaves
for the Maluku Islands via the Indies.
On his way back, his ship
founders on a reef
but he survives and returns
to the Maluku Islands.
There, forgetting Portugal
and the spice trade,
Serrao and his crew desert
and stay in this endless paradise.
Serrao will not be remembered
as a great conquistador,
but perhaps this Ulysses,
enamored of his Calypso,
was the wisest
and happiest of captains.
Serrao remained there 9 years
and had three children
before dying the same year
as Magellan,
and not so very far from him.
For years, Serrao
on his far-off island
corresponded with Magellan
as he prepared his trip.
Yes, his friend
described the delights of paradise
and invited him
to come and join him there.
Meanwhile,
Stany continues his voyage.
He has passed
the Strait of Magellan
and is heading towards
Easter Island.
Every day, he notes
his latitude and longitude.
Every day, he draws the sky and the sea
at that moment.
With his filmed images of the sea,
he sends me these drawings.
It's the most isolated land
on the planet,
the last land to be colonized
by humanity.
The Polynesians,
coming from the Marquesas Islands,
travelled thousands of kilometers,
following migratory birds,
and stopped on this island.
After the longest known
maritime odyssey,
they felt they had found paradise,
the belly button of the world,
a land for the spirits
of the ancestors.
But in the 17th century,
all the island's trees died of drought
and the inhabitants,
no longer having ships,
were prisoners
of their paradise,
a tiny dot in the ocean.
Stany sets sail
for the Galapagos Islands
to drop off the blue tortoise
in the land of tortoises.
A swallow signals
that land is close.
The swallow
is the bird of paradise,
a symbol of migration
and the return of the soul.
There are so many
images of journeys
and so few of those
who stay behind.
So few of those who stay behind
and dream their journeys.
Trying to capture the invisible,
that which is archaic
in a mother's relationship with her child.
Filming the imperceptible mirror.
Jean-Marie,
neighbour and friend.
His balcony overlooks my garden.
From one institution to another,
Jean-Marie's life has not been easy.
He never travels.
He often stays home,
in his little apartment,
he whose heart
is as big as a house.
He comes around
to chat of this and that,
of you and me,
of this film that's sprouting
and growing like a plant,
like a tree.
We dream and we film.
We dream and record sound.
And one day we say: "Ah,
there's the film I desire."
Jean-Marie is part of the waking dreams,
of the dream films.
Is the image OK, like that?
- Yes.
Like this I've just got your head.
Don't you think you should
do it properly,
the whole thing?
- Like that, yes.
It's much better.
You mustn't change the image.
You must leave the image
the way you filmed it.
Otherwise,
your image of the person filmed
will break his heart
and that of the person
who filmed.
I think lots of people
no longer have respect for that,
for that profession.
They lack respect
for themselves,
because they want
the person to change,
to show something other
than what they really are.
And that's impossible.
Is this OK?
- Yes, that's fine.
I wondered if you
believe in paradise
and above all,
how you imagine it to be.
Well, imagining paradise!
Everyone has their own take
on paradise.
It's just that
we get the wrong impression
sometimes.
Sometimes, we're even disappointed.
And if it's a disappointment,
it's not worth it.
That's why giving an image
of paradise
is beyond any person.
On the map, I show Jean-Marie
James Bruce's journey in Abyssinia.
In the 18th century,
Bruce, a noble Scot,
also called the "Marco Polo of Africa",
decided to go looking for
the petrified town of Ras Sem.
Legend has it that
the inhabitants have been frozen
for centuries, like statues,
in the position they were in
when God's wrath fell on them.
He wrote down his adventures
and illustrated them himself.
Bruce crossing a waterfall
in search of the source of the Blue Nile.
Bruce dressed as an Arab,
bowing to the Emperor of Abyssinia.
Bruce pays tribute to the
favourite wife of the King of Sennam.
After an incredible journey
of four years,
braving death countless times,
grown rich,
then robbed by bandits,
he finally returned to Cairo,
in rags, a mere ghost.
Many claimed his tale
was pure invention,
that he had never set foot
in Africa.
But the truth was never known.
One of the most extraordinary
travel tales is that of Rougemont.
Louis de Rougemont, a Frenchman,
is shipwrecked with pearl hunters
in the 19th century,
off the coast of Australia.
He finds himself alone
in an unknown land
where he will spend 30 eventful years
in the Australian outback.
He is miraculously saved
during the shipwreck,
helped by his dog,
now his sole companion.
He tames turtles.
He finds an Aborigine partner
who takes care of him.
He becomes chief of a cannibal tribe
that he leads into war
against his enemies.
He saves two young English girls
from the clutches of the natives.
But everyone dies
and alone he finds his way back
to civilization.
He becomes famous and his book
is translated all over the world.
But gradually, as the episodes
of his story appear,
month by month, his story
is called into question.
It seems this incredible
30-year crossing of Australia
had been invented.
Even his identity
was apparently fake.
Rumour had it that
he had invented his tales
in the reading room of the British Museum,
surrounded by the travel stories he loved.
Rougemont disappeared
as mysteriously as he had appeared.
A sole witness later claimed
he had seen a bearded tramp
selling matchsticks
in the streets of London.
It seems his whole story was fake...
Perhaps. For here, another man
enters the picture". Lander,
the Englishman, Savage Landor,
the man who went three times
around the world.
He discovers Tibet
around the same time as Bonin,
crosses frozen peaks alone,
and, pursued by an army of 2000,
climbs the Himalayas
without equipment.
Then he continues
to travel the world.
He crosses the African jungle
from west to east,
journeys down South America,
travels all over North America,
and sets sail for Japan,
where he disappears
into 6000 km of dense forest.
Many of his trips
were called into question
and doubt was cast
over his extravagant adventures,
but publishers fought for his manuscripts
and Landor became famous.
He was a good drawer
and he sketched landscapes,
and portraits of people
he met on his travels.
After Japan,
he set sail for Korea
and crossed China
before arriving in Australia.
And there,
at the end of his journey,
it would appear that
Rougemont's extraordinary adventure
crossed Landor's path.
Landor met and made a portrait
of an Australian adventurer
whose face strongly resembles
that of Rougemont.
If this really is Rougemont,
as is supposed,
and if Landor really did go there
and met him,
then Rougemont's whole story
could also be true...
Then there's the story
of the forger, Van Megeren.
All his life, he painted Vermeers,
fakes, of course,
but not copies,
paintings one could imagine
Vermeer might have done.
Everyone was dupe.
He even sold a canvas
to Marshall Goering,
a great art lover.
When the Americans found the painting
at the end of the war,
they traced it back to Van Megeren.
He was tried
and risked the death penalty
for having sold a Vermeer
to the enemy.
Van Megeren denied the charge,
claiming he had conned Goering
by selling him a fake.
But the experts were unanimous,
this, and the other Vermeers,
were genuine.
So, to prove the truth
and save his life
Van Megeren painted a fake Vermeer
in his prison cell,
and was set free.
Long ago,
in the beginning,
in paradise,
men and animals lived together
and spoke the same language.
There are many animals in the garden,
but mostly, there are frogs.
They're the only ones I know,
but they're incredibly curious.
In all cultures, everywhere,
stories tell of the breakdown
of equality between
animals and humans.
Ours is that of Noah
and the story of the flood.
When the floods came,
Noah saved those animals he could.
But when he got back to land
after his journey,
for no good reason,
he became a carnivore,
thus breaking his pact.
It brings to mind a story
my granda told me when I was little.
When God at last finished creating
the world and all things,
he created heaven.
But one day, the animals,
all the animals,
came together, because they too
wanted to go to heaven.
So, they sent representatives
to God.
And God said perhaps they were right
since He had created them,
but that He would not tolerate
dirt in His home.
Time passed, heaven
was starting to fill up,
and now
all sorts of animals were there.
But one day,
the inevitable happened.
God walked in some poop.
Furious,
he gathered everyone together
and asked:
"Who pooped in my Heaven?"
As no one replied,
God repeated loudly:
"I'm warning you,
I know about droppings.
This was clearly done by a dog.
May that dog come forward,
or I'll throw all the dogs
out of heaven, forever!"
But the dogs all
glared at each other
and none of them came forward.
So God banished them
from heaven, once and for all.
"That is why,"
my grandfather said,
"When one dog meets another,
he sniffs his backside and asks:
'Surely you're not the one,
who pooped in paradise?"'
I don't know if animals
have a soul,
or the extent of their awareness,
but I know they dream.
We are surrounded
by strange animals
and we all pick our own.
Ulysses was pursued
by bird-mermaids.
But there are all sorts
of mermaids.
When I sang that,
I dressed up as a mermaid.
I don't know why I went to dance
In St. Jean,
At the popular dances.
But all it took was one kiss,
For my heart
To be taken prisoner.
How could I not lose my mind,
Wrapped in those daring arms?
For we always believe,
Those sweet words of love
When they're spoken
With the eyes.
I, who loved him so,
Thought him the most handsome
In St. Jean.
I was drunk,
Powerless before his kisses.
Then there's Jacobson's mermaid,
in Denmark.
Jacobson was the youngest member
of a family of brewers, the Jacobsons.
From a young age,
he had a rebellious nature.
As soon as he could,
he founded his own brewery,
Carlsberg beer,
and made a fortune.
In the final years of his life,
he went to the theatre
to see a ballet,
The Little Mermaid,
based on a fairy tale
where a young mermaid
wants to marry a man
and become a human being
because her mermaid grandmother
had told her
that men live shorter lives,
but have an eternal soul.
Old Jacobson fell in love with
the young performer, Ellen Price.
It was to her memory
that he commissioned the statue
that now stands
at the entrance to Copenhagen port.
Regarding animals,
there is one story,
a true one,
that I would like to film.
It's about a pigeon.
Well, in the beginning,
it's about a man,
somewhere in England,
who loved pigeons,
loved to watch them fly,
and sent them on journeys.
One day, he sent a young pigeon
off on a journey.
Then awaited its return.
He waited four years.
One day, he got a phone call
from China.
His pigeon had got lost.
It was found 10,000 km from home,
in the Sichuan mountains.
In the end, after much discussion,
the Chinese decided
to let it leave...
by plane.
A Chinese air company
took charge of getting it home.
There, that was the tale
of the homing pigeon,
also known as
"the Ulysses of birds".
When William Winchester,
inventor of the Winchester rifle,
died in California,
he was busy building a new home
for himself and his wife, Sarah.
Soon, a legend was born:
as soon as the building
was finished,
it would be haunted by the souls
of the thousands of Indians
killed by the Winchester rifle.
Sarah, the widow,
believed the tale
and for 38 years, she did not stop
building the house
night and day,
which grew bigger and bigger.
In 1922, when she died,
the residence contained
over 950 doors,
leading to 160 rooms,
including 40 bedrooms
and 6 kitchens.
There should be a film
about the life of Curtis.
For over 35 years,
he photographed
the Indians of North America,
travelling from tribe to tribe.
His work includes
thousands of plates.
When White men, foreigners
who were building a railway
on Indian territory,
asked him
if they could hire some
young Indians of his tribe,
Smohalla, Indian chief, replied:
"My young men will never work.
Men who work cannot dream
and wisdom comes to us
through dreams."
In Canada, among the Kwakiutl tribe,
Curtis shot
one of the very first films
in the history of the cinema:
magical images of the return
of the animal masks.
The word 'potlatch'
comes from the Kwakiutls:
sharing, giving to another
who will later give back more.
Monarch butterflies
leave from Canada
and migrate 5000 km to Mexico.
I dream of following them
to the Huichol Indians.
It is the most mysterious
of all animal migrations.
Each butterfly,
which has never flown the route,
leaves alone.
Gradually,
it is joined by the others.
They arrive by millions
in the Mexican mountains.
Dreaming of going with
the Huichol Indians,
across the desert
in search of the sacred cactus.
A pilgrimage in search of peyote,
the hallucinogenic cactus
that guides their dreams
and imaginary journeys.
But there are times when
the strength of a dream,
of a desire, wakes you up,
and reality takes over...
Then you must get up and leave.
End of Part 1
Dreaming Films Part 2
There are times when
the strength of a dream,
of a desire, wakes you up
and reality takes over.
Then you must get up and leave.
There are imaginary places
one tries to mark on a map
to make them real.
And there are real,
terribly real places,
that one cannot forget
if one has been there,
and which figure on no maps,
so great is the shame.
The penal colony of Tazmamart
is not shown on any map
of Morocco.
Salah Hachad spent 18 years
in Tazmamart
in the Moroccan desert, freezing
in winter, stifling in summer,
wrongly accused for participating
in a coup against the king.
For 18 years, Salah Hachad
did not see the blue of the sky.
When I read his story,
I wanted to meet and film him.
If there was only one film,
it would be that one,
to tell the crumbling of time
and the resistance of human beings.
Filming this man
to speak of all men.
And I would get up
and go to see him.
He would show me
the cell he has recreated.
how he managed to survive,
without going mad, or blind.
It took Salah Hachad 10 months
to make what the prisoners
codenamed the "Kabazal":
a little mirror set on the top
of palm stems fixed end to end.
Pushed through the air hole
in the ceiling,
the Kabazal,
in the total darkness of the cell,
saved his life.
Then, all of a sudden, barn!
Light came inside,
a small, bright white spot.
I was euphoric.
I shouted and jumped, I cried.
It was pure joy.
Ah, I see my hand!
It's hard to describe the emotion.
You're in the dark
for 10 months,
and all of a sudden,
you see a patch of light.
Salah Hachad resisted,
struggled, for 18 years,
but other prisoners
didn't have his strength
and dreamed their escape.
He started by telling me:
"You know, Captain,
it's easy to get out of Tazmamart.
All you have to do
is hang yourself,
they'll get you
and take you outside,
and then at night, you escape."
I understood then that he was...
He was no longer normal.
I told him: "If you carry on
talking like that, it's over between us!"
He said: "No, I'm only joking."
But in the end,
he carried out his plan.
He escaped.
- Yes, he escaped. It's true.
For him, it was an escape.
"I'll hang myself,
they'll put me outside
with the others."
For him, the others who had died
had escaped.
What struck me
was the power of the dream,
of the imagination.
At one point you say:
"I travel to my wife..."
It's not just the sexual aspect,
but even life itself.
Sometimes I would
wrap myself up in my blanket,
like a Mexican,
and I'd close my eyes
and hup, I'd go outside
and start
to live outside,
on a farm, making plans...
For years, he planned
his imaginary farm:
the various buildings,
the electrical circuits,
the animals in the yard,
the number of milk cows,
the number of fruit trees,
where they'd be planted.
One fine day, a little pigeon,
fresh out of its egg,
fell into the corridor.
And it was our friend, Marzouki...
The bird fell in front of his cell
just when they opened the door
for him to get his food.
He saw the pigeon and picked it up.
And that was it,
for months afterwards,
we lived for 'Mr. Farrach'.
Farrach means...
We chose the name Farrach
because it means 'liberty.
But his color...
Because there was no light,
he lived inside with us,
there was no sunlight,
he didn't go pigeon-coloured.
He stayed a weird color
due to lack of sunlight.
In the end, he grew strong.
We would open the little hatches
and Marzouki
would let Farrach go.
He would whizz up and down
the corridor at great speed,
from one comer to another.
We loved it!
When he passed, one after another
we'd put our hands
out of the hatch, and he'd come
and sit on them.
We'd stroke him and talk to him,
then he'd fly off again.
We had a great time with Farrach.
Then one day, we thought:
"Well, really,
we should let him go,
give him his liberty,
Farrach has grown."
So
It took almost
a whole day of debate,
serious debate. Some wanted
to keep him, others said:
"No, nothing is more
precious than liberty,
we must set him free."
Then Marzouki came
and passed him through...
Above the corridor between
the cells there was wire netting
made of barbed wire.
He pushed him through
and let him go.
But the terrible thing was
that the other pigeons
wanted nothing to do with him.
Because he didn't look like them.
Maybe it was his color.
They attacked him!
So he came back to us.
Two days later, we tried again.
This time it worked
and he flew away.
Then, and this is truly wonderful,
one day, after about a month,
maybe 20 days,
he came back,
accompanied by another pigeon.
He had married! And he came back
and landed
just above Marzouki's cell
where he sat cooing with his lady love.
We were so happy.
"Ah, he's married,
he's come to bid us farewell."
Some even cried.
It was really moving,
that little pigeon...
Before we parted,
as he was driving me back,
he suddenly said to me,
at a crossroad:
"You know, I feel as if
everything here,
this street, that man,
those trees,
you and me... that all this
is just a dream
and I will soon wake up
in Tazmamart.
All he had told me
about hell was so present within me
that for a brief moment,
I felt I was part of his dream.
Then he added:
"When I got back my freedom,
for weeks and months
I had this awful feeling:
'All this isn't real,
I'm still dreaming,
I'll soon wake up in Tazmamart.'
Surviving.
Surviving so that words never die.
We had to survive,
to speak for those who were buried
along the walls of Tazmamart.
At least one of us must survive
the savagery, lest memory forget.
Lest History forget.
Lest stone forget.
Lest blood forge
One day, a man, a filmmaker,
has a dream.
It is the dream of a little boy
who was told the story of Ulysses,
the man who lived happily
with his family, then left one day.
It's the story of a man
who went to Africa
to film men and spirits,
whose soul became
the guardian of the river.
It's the story of a man who dreamed
of finding the Garden of Eden,
that fabulous place
from mythical times
where men and animals
lived in the same world.
It's the story of a man,
an unknown slave,
who, without realizing it,
was the first to go around the world.
It's the story of a man,
unjustly imprisoned,
who waited like a beast
for 18 years
before he saw the blue sky
once more.
It's the story of a man
who sailed around the world
and who sent his filmmaker friend
images from all over the world.
I remember this man.
At his home, I saw this photo:
a young woman and a sequoia.
Then he took me into his garden
and showed me the sequoia
he'd brought back from Canada:
a baby.
And for the first time,
I saw a man taller than a sequoia.
The Japanese say a garden
is the portrait of a soul.
Since then, Andre has left us
and the sequoia continues to grow.
Stany continues his sea journey.
I hope all is well with you,
my journey continues...
He reaches Hiva-Oa,
in the Marquesas Islands.
I don't know how to describe it.
It's splendid, magnificent.
I'm in paradise.
I'm sending you my latest images.
I hope they'll be useful for your film.
As for me,
I'm heading for new horizons.
He sends me these images for my film
about the final days of Gauguin,
the painter who went
to live in paradise,
the painter who
worked on dreams.
For my part,
I'm doing portraits of young women
that Gauguin might have painted.
It was on Hiva-Oa that Gauguin
spent the final years of his life.
It has been 8 years since
he left Europe,
where his reputation as
"island painter" is now established.
But Gauguin begins to feel lonely.
He is tired and ill
and can think of only one thing:
returning to France,
leaving this paradise
that has become a hell.
He writes to his friends back home
but they all advise him
not to come home.
One of them writes:
"You are now a great artist,
a legend,
who, from the depths of Oceania,
sends back unparalleled works
by a great man who has,
so to speak, disappeared from the world.
You must not come back."
But Gauguin insists. He even proposes
to come back to Europe and hide.
Perhaps he could live in Barcelona
and send his paintings to France
from there.
He is told he will be found out
and ridiculed.
So, prisoner to the dreams
of others, he stays
as his health gradually deteriorates.
When he died,
his final painting was found,
a Brittany village under the snow.
A few days later, the painting
was sold in an auction,
upside down, with the title:
View of Niagara Falls.
My daughter Lola, in India,
at the time of our great journeys.
She could play the beautiful Draupadi
in the film I want to make.
I dream of making a film
telling the Mahabharata,
the whole story of the Mahabharata,
the longest story ever written.
The Mahabharata is a story
told by a hermit to a child
when they meet in the
mythical world of Ancient India.
As the elephant Ganesh was there,
he broke off one of his tusks
and wrote the story,
that's how we know it.
Here, I show only
the beginning and the end,
and you must imagine
everything that happens in between.
In the beginning, there's a face-off
between Yudhishtira,
eldest of the five Pandavas brothers,
the goodies,
and Shakuni, uncle of
the hundred bad Kauravas,
who want to conquer
the universe.
Yudhishtira has but one fault,
he likes to gamble and he's
about to bet his family
his wife, his brothers,
his palace and the whole universe.
Shakuni, sitting opposite,
is a professional cheat.
This all takes place
under the eyes of the beautiful Draupadi,
Yudhishtira's wife, perhaps
the main stake of the game.
Let's play!
But promise you won't cheat.
Not cheat?
You ask a professional gambler,
not to cheat?
Would you ask the most beautiful woman
to make herself ugly
so as not to hurt others' feelings?
Would you silence an intelligent man
so as not to offend the idiots?
Yudhishtira, life isn't like that.
Then let's play!
Thus began the epic tale
of the Mahabharata,
the terrible war during which
Yudhishtira and his brothers
had to win back the universe.
And this is the end.
Only Yudhishtira remains,
and he climbs the Himalayas
to get to heaven.
But it is so cold
that he would have died
if a dog had not come and warmed him up.
Have I arrived?
- Yes, Yudhishtira.
You have arrived at last.
You have finally reached
the gates of heaven.
Your mother, your brothers,
your wife, Drapaudi,
are all waiting for you.
Come, Yudhishtira, follow me.
No, Yudhishtira,
you may enter paradise,
but not the dog.
- If the dog doesn't come, neither do I!
Here you are at last
You, for whom I have been waiting
So long
Jewel of my heart
The doors of heaven are open
They are the doors of happiness
For eternal happiness awaits us
Come, my love
In heaven the river
of endless happiness flows
Leave the dog
and come join us, my love
Come, my love Come, my love
Leave him
You will see
what happens to the dog
and everything that happens
between the beginning and the end
the day the film is finished.
I dream of filming
a romantic epic,
a tragic love story
like that of John Nicol.
Here is the story.
In July 1789,
a ship of the royal fleet
leaves the port of London
carrying 245 women
and bound for Australia.
Cook has just
discovered the continent
and the fleshly needs
of the settlers must be met
and the new colony populated.
Mainly thieves and prostitutes,
the government had taken them out of prison
to deport them to Australia.
Among them
is a young girl of 18,
Sarah Whitelam.
The crew, led by
His Majesty's officers,
counts all sorts of sailors
including a 34-year old Scotsman,
John Nicol.
They hug the coast of Africa
and cross the Indian Ocean
on a voyage
that will last 10 months.
John Nicol falls madly in love
with Sarah Whitelam,
and their love
grows stronger over the journey.
Sarah is one of the 50 women
to give birth
during the voyage.
On arriving in Australia,
John Nicol has to leave Sarah
and return to England,
according to the terms of his contract.
He swears he will return
as soon as he can, and sails away.
Years pass before he returns.
But when he does, Sarah
is no longer there.
He makes enquiries
and discovers she has left
on a ship heading for Bombay.
What no one dares tell him,
and what he would never find out,
is that she is married
to a settler,
mother of two children.
John Nicol leaves for Bombay
and searches everywhere for her.
He searches in the countryside,
he searches in the city,
but finds her nowhere.
He looks for her all over,
but finds nothing.
So he leaves and travels
to all the ports in the world.
Cape Town, Buenos Aires,
London, Rio de Janeiro,
Santa Cruz, Batavia,
Zanzibar, Bombay,
Sidney, Canton,
Macau, Tangier,
Lisbon, Recife,
Salvador de Bahia, Havana,
Valparaiso, Bilbao
and Port-Louis,
La Rochelle and Porto Ribeira...
For over 25 years,
John Nicol travelled the world
going all the way round, twice.
He landed on six continents,
fought with pirates
and Napoleon's fleet,
made friends in China,
Jamaica and Hawaii.
But he never found Sarah Whitelam.
At the beginning of the 19th century,
exhausted, he returned home,
to Scotland.
He wrote: "By then I was too old
to look for her further,
and I didn't know
where in the world she was,
or even if she was still alive."
For in 1822,
a publisher in Edinburgh
asked to publish his memoirs.
Having no money to live on,
John Nicol accepted.
But he was old now,
and had forgotten the dates
and places of his journeys.
All he now remembered
was the name of the woman
he had loved all his life,
Sarah Whitelam.
Victor Hugo used to come here.
It's one of the places
where he liked to write.
But when you go back
over the writer's path,
it becomes clear that the dates
and places of his manuscripts
do not always correspond
to reality.
Many of his texts
served him as an alibi
to be elsewhere,
a place where he met
his love dreams.
One of these loves,
the strongest, was Juliette Drouet.
A young orphan,
fresh from the convent,
and turned actress.
She met Victor Hugo
and they became lovers.
She left everything for him,
following him like a shadow
for 50 years.
Over the years, she wrote him
over 20,000 love letters.
There are so many images,
everywhere.
So many images of the other,
the elsewhere,
that you think:
"Why go out anymore,
out there, into the landscapes,
the horizons we've already seen,
already shown?"
Might as well stay home,
with oneself
and imagine the other,
the elsewhere,
and tell stories.
For though there are
too many images,
points of view are lacking,
and there are still
stories to be told.
I'd like to film the story,
or rather the journey, of Lobera,
a Spanish aristocrat
from the 13th century.
He vowed to go to Jerusalem
with the fourth crusade.
But, after much thought,
the length of the journey
and his fear of the Saracens
made him change his mind.
He then undertook,
on his estate,
a long imaginary journey.
For over a year,
he toured his estate
four times a day
until he had covered
the same distance as that
between his castle and Jerusalem.
In the 18th century,
Bougainville also leaves
on a trip around the world.
A certain Commerson is chosen
as naturalist for the expedition
and boards ship with his
young domestic, Jean Baret,
who is in fact his servant
and mistress, Jeanne Baret.
Women are not allowed on board
His Majesty's ships
and Jeanne is disguised as a man.
She manages to fool the crew
for over a year.
They reach the coasts of Brazil,
hug the coast of South America
and enter the Pacific Ocean.
They arrive in Polynesia and
Bougainville is in seventh heaven.
But as they disembark,
the naked natives
rush towards Jeanne Bare!
Shouting:  A woman, a woman!
and start to undress her.
Unmasked,
Bougainville questions her
and she lies to protect her lover,
saying that Commerson
is aware of nothing.
Generously, Bougainville
drops them off on Mauritius
on the home journey
to avoid them being punished.
Commerson lived another 5 years,
before falling ill and dying,
but not before he named a flower
after his young mistress:
the Baretia.
Later, Jeanne married
a French soldier
and returned to Europe with him,
thus ending her trip around the world.
Of Jeanne Baret, the first woman
to sail around the world,
there is not a single image.
Unless it be
the image of a flower.
Today, the immensity of space
leads to other journeys,
ever further.
And we look at the universe
like the frogs watch the cabin,
with the same curiosity.
And we send out signals.
The space probe Voyager
has long since left our galaxy.
It will outlast the solar system
and all life on earth.
It carries sounds, voices,
music from our planet.
Worlds appear and disappear...
This is the last moment
of the Ubykh language.
This man from Anatolia is dead
and with him died the Ubykh language,
which he was the last to speak.
The last sounds of this strange language
were a set of lies.
"For," he said, "There are no words
without lies."
The police have just arrested
a cinema student
who was prostituting herself
to pay for her studies.
Under the streetlamp,
she was reading Kant.
She told them
the parable of the pigeon.
"When the pigeon flies, it struggles
against the resistance of the air,
and imagines it would be easier
to fly in empty space.
But if it flew in empty space,
it would fall.
In order not to fall,
one must learn to resist,"
she told them.
It would be the tale of
a young filmmaker, just starting out.
He wants to film rebellion,
resistance,
rejection of the world
the way it is.
First, he writes a script
and gets together a big team.
There's music
and professional actors.
Ready? Action!
It could be the tale
of this young woman, in England,
in the fifties.
Maybe she's a spy.
She could be a Russian spy,
supporting the revolutionary cause.
Or an Indian terrorist, fighting
for her country's independence.
But something's wrong,
it's all too heavy.
So he writes a simpler fiction
and films it near home.
The actress is the same,
now a Maoist militant
in the sixties,
but the mother and father
are not professional actors.
Careful, silence,
we're filming.
But something's wrong,
because reality doesn't follow
his script.
So, he stops writing
and plunges his actress into
the social fringe of the eighties.
OK for the sound.
But something is still wrong,
is not synchronous with reality.
So he drops the whole team
and makes portraits of the rebels,
the marginals of his time.
But he still feels
that something is wrong.
He feels the gap
between them and him,
and realizes it's just an image.
So, he sets off alone
realizing he must stop expressing
his rebellion through others' eyes.
He starts to film the world:
water,
stones,
clouds.
Yes, that's how it could end:
he films the clouds,
over and over...
Then he understands
that he simply has to watch them,
that he must stop
wanting to reproduce the world...
Is this OK?
- Yes, that's fine.
Look at me.
I'd like to film all the places
all the things in the world
called "I don't know'
or "I don't understand"
because of the surprising encounters
between travellers and natives.
When Captain Cook
arrived in Australia,
he pointed to an animal
and asked what it was called.
The aborigine answered:
"I don't understand":
kangourou.
Cook actually died due to
a misunderstanding in Hawaii.
The natives, thinking he was a god,
ate him and
were awaiting his return.
When Cook's companions
explained that he was human,
that he was now dead
and would not return,
the natives apologized
and gave back the bits
they had not eaten.
My story box
is a reservoir of dream films.
An Italian woman
in a hospital in Lugo, Italy,
who fell into
a deep coma six months ago,
a few weeks
after falling pregnant,
shed a tear on Thursday
as she gave birth to her baby.
All these amazing stories
come from everyday life.
Like the one
of the old Polish lady
whose portrait I'd like to do.
She's 113 years old.
When asked what it was like
to be so old
she said she was afraid
she might never die.
So I raise my glass
to those who are dead, the ancestors,
to you, Jean Rouch, who I often saw
make this gesture of offering,
a salute to the ancestors.
To you, who watched
the dancing Dogon masks
that you brought over to Paris,
the masks from
the cliffs of Bandiagara
that Germaine Dieterlen
had taught you about.
Hail to the ancestors, to those
who are drunk with adventure,
to those for whom drunkenness
represents the disorder
at the origin of the world,
for the souls of the dead are thirsty,
as you used to say, Jean.
Rouch, who filmed the Dogons
for years,
often spoke to me of the
Bandiagara cliffs where they live.
He spoke of it as
a mythical, magical place,
an apparition
in a Chirico landscape.
But since Rouch,
so many others have been there,
so many other images
of these cliffs have been made,
that I wanted to dream my own.
There was...
There was a dream...
There was the dream
of a film with Jan.
Jan was a mechanic
and a musician.
I remember filming him
one evening.
My name is Jan
and I like mechanics.
Could you move closer to the light?
- Yes.
Could you move your face
closer to the light. OK.
The film never got made
because Jan left for Africa,
to do aid work.
Months later, I received
a letter from him,
on December 6th,
a letter from Africa,
on Saint Nicolas Day.
I read Jan's words
and watched what I had just filmed.
I got lost between
here and there,
between my images
and what I was reading.
Jan wrote about their inability
to contain a starving crowd.
He described the disorder,
the pushing,
the crush to grab some food,
to survive.
Then he said that he
and the others on the mission
went back to their camp,
shocked at what they had seen.
Then he, like the others,
broke down and cried.
He wrote: "A
the men
break down and cry.
But the women hold up."
He told me how fascinated he was
by their resistance.
Between the beginning and the end
of the Mahabharata,
right in the middle of the tale,
there is a pond,
a magic pond,
and if Yudhishtira
wants to pass,
he must answer these questions:
What is swifter than the wind?
Thought.
Give me an example of sorrow.
Ignorance.
An example of defeat.
Victory.
Which is the most cunning animal?
The one man has not yet
managed to know.
What causes the world?
Love.
What is your opposite?
Myself.
What about rebellion?
Why do men rebel?
To find beauty,
in life, or in death.
What is inevitable for all of us?
Happiness.
Happiness is inevitable.
Now tell me,
what is the greatest marvel?
The greatest marvel
is that each day, death strikes
all around us
yet we live as if we were immortal.
That is the greatest marvel.
There's a film to be made
about Bernard Moitessier.
In 1968,
the Golden Globe was organized,
the first round-the-world race,
solo and without stopovers.
Moitessier was one of nine
to take up the challenge.
He left on his yacht
with no help,
no radio equipment,
taking only a little tape recorder.
After ten months of sailing,
he was in the lead
and was preparing to sail up
the Atlantic towards England
where the Golden Globe
awaited him,
along with a reward
of 5000 sterling pounds
and, naturally, fame.
He would be the first sailor ever
to sail single-handed
around the world
without stopovers.
But, on April 18th,
he catapulted a message
onto the deck of a passing ship:
"I am sailing on
to the Pacific Islands,
because I am happy at sea,
and perhaps also,
to save my soul."
Turning his back on glory,
he sailed on to Polynesia.
I am truly happy at sea.
You can't imagine how good
I feel, alone, peaceful.
It's not always easy,
but when things go well, it's...
It's fantastic,
all the things I have felt.
It's something that...
So I don't want to stop now.
It would be stupid to return to Europe.
I was always on the go there.
I could never live a whole month
- what I call living -
really living...
Letting the sun inside you,
finding a deep sense of peace.
I never found that in France,
I never did,
not for a whole month.
There were small joys,
snatched from time to time.
I cannot go back to France,
truly, I cannot."
Moitessier is the man who could
have equalled Achilles' glory,
but rejected it to become
Ulysses, the traveller.
By his death before
the ramparts of Troy
Achilles answered the question:
"Why die?"
But Ulysses,
who sailed the seas,
then returned to his family,
only to leave again,
was seeking the answer
to the question:
"How to live?"
There's a film I dream of making
but which I never will, because
I'll no longer be of this world.
One day, after 2060,
the world population
will stop growing
and start to decrease.
I would like to film
the headlines
announcing this unique news
in the history of humanity.
And I would like to film
the slow disruption
it would cause to man's relationship
with the world,
with animals,
with himself.
It's winter.
The dog is sleeping.
Far from everything and everyone,
the film hibernates.
I listen to the radio
and I travel...
A moment of the world...
To sit alone at a terrace
and watch the world.
For years,
when I saw a pile of ashes,
I imagined lovers,
awaiting their beloved,
hour after hour, smoking
one cigarette after another.
Then one day, sitting at a terrace,
I saw a car draw up
and a door open...
A moment of the world.
Yes, I'd like to film
a moment of the world.
I'd watch the young women pass,
and think of Baudelaire's poem,
To a Passerby.
Baudelaire is sitting there,
at the terrace of a cafe,
he is alone, drinking.
Suddenly a woman passes
and glances at him
for a brief moment.
In that instant, he knows
he'll never see her again,
that he knows nothing about her,
that she is disappearing into the void.
And his poem, addressed to her,
ends with these words:
"Oh you, whom I would have loved,
Oh you, who knew it."
I dream of filming the gaze
of the women who pass.
And I dream
of filming friendly faces.
And I dream of filming
the vastness of the cosmos
where, perhaps,
all the souls of the universe meet.
I dream of filming
the face of an old lady
and finding there
the infancy of the world.
And I dream of filming
the desire of children.
the desire of lovers.
And I dream of filming desire...
I dream that it's summer,
that I offer Jean-Marie
a small role in a dream film.
It would be the film of a man
who, all his life, had done but one thing:
portraits of his dog.
But some dream films
are impossible to make.
For years, the same photo appeared
in the obituaries of a daily paper.
Every 27th of September,
the photo of lmgard and the words:
1982 - 1989 Already 7 years
Always close to you, Uncle.
But some films
must be kept silent,
some films will never be made,
some films are impossible to make.
Jean-Marie fell,
then entered a coma...
His heart, as big as a house,
beat on for a long while.
Then he left.
Jean-Marie's story,
like Ulysses' story,
like all stories,
tells us:
we cannot live without dreams,
without lies,
without illusions.
A film by Eric Pauwels
Subtitling: Tongues Untied