♪ Switch
It's sold out because
it's obviously really amazing.
This is the end of an era.
♪ Slipping on the stilies
and the really tight dress
♪ Pouting out your glossy lips
and learning how to kiss
♪ Madness, passion...
Hi, I'm Jonny Woo.
I suppose you could say
I'm the ringmaster
of this big old glittery circus.
♪ Go out tonight
dressed as a girl
Some say the word drag
comes from Shakespeare's notes
when he wanted boys
to dress as a girl.
Some say it doesn't. Who cares?
I just think drag is an excuse
to put on women's clothes
and set yourself free.
We're part
of a big extended community.
- Flawless maquillage.
- Look at that, ooh!
Scottee's
the youngest of the group
and definitely
the most ambitious.
He sets out to shock and shock
is what he usually does.
What can we say about Holestar?
She calls herself
a tranny with a fanny.
That's her shtick.
She looks like a man in drag.
She acts like a man in drag.
And she has something to say.
Cos I'm a woman
trying to enter
that world of being a tranny,
people still seem
a bit wary of me.
I associate
as not being male or female.
They say
that still waters run deep.
But Pia is like a torrent.
And who knows what lies beneath
those troubled waters?
There is actually a third sex.
There is a set of people
genetically predisposed
to be different
than everybody else.
Amber Swallows is outrageous.
If anyone knows where the booze
and the boys are, she does.
Amber,
show us your she-male powers.
- She-male powers.
And then there's our
DJ extraordinaire, John Sizzle.
You can bet your life
there's a drag superstar
just waiting
to get out of that one.
The whole world tells you
you can't wear a skirt.
It's about going "fuck you"
to everyone else.
♪ We're going out,
we're going out tonight
♪ Dressed as a girl
If all the world were a stage
and we were merely players,
we were about
to put on one hell of a show.
Material's very thin today.
But, hey, so am I!
About ten years ago,
we were doing some parties.
And then we came up
with the idea
of doing a night
called Gay Bingo.
How many ways can you call out
numbers? I will show you.
I went to the bun seller.
She was selling 74 fairy cakes.
I went, "I want some of them."
She was selling them
for 56 pence each.
"56 pence each?"
Gay Bingo's fabulous.
It's a magnet, almost,
for the scene.
It wasn't so much
about playing bingo, though.
It was more about being
as outrageous as possible.
Pushing things
as far as we possibly could.
Oh, look, everybody, Ma
Butcher's coming up on a pill.
What made Gay Bingo special
was anarchy.
She's coming up,
she's coming up!
Let's give a big round...
The format is
we're gonna play bingo
and we're gonna fuck you up.
We were outrageous.
It was provocative.
It wasn't about being cool.
It was about being
completely and utterly insane.
I think Gay Bingo was messy.
It was about
getting off your nut.
It was anarchic in a way. Kind
of bingo turned on its head.
A springboard
for doing other stuff.
It's mainstream,
it's accessible.
You don't
have to be gay to play.
You wouldn't play.
69!
What it was all about
at the end of the day
was the number 69.
Who wants to do the 69? Come on.
Oh my God, you're gonna have
to get all those clothes off.
If the number 69 pops up
on the number cruncher,
- Jonny starts dry humping.
- Yeah, dry humping.
Dry humping someone.
OK, do you wanna
see a slot machine? It's time!
You sit on their face and stick
my head down their pants.
Much to the excitement
of the baying crowd.
69!
It celebrated the east, and it
celebrated the alternative.
And the fashion and the art
and the weird and the music
and this collaboration
just ignited something.
OK, we are now
going for a full house.
In the early days of Gay Bingo,
we were either
on a massive comedown of drugs
from the weekend
and to counteract your,
you know,
the kind of massive insecurities
you get on a comedown off drugs,
obviously there'd be a lot
of booze being consumed.
And so that became
a fixed thing with everyone.
We're on, we're pissed
and the audience are pissed
and for a long time it worked.
But there got to a point
where it stopped working.
My drinking is linked in
to being in social situations
and partying and also if I have
one drink I have the lot.
I don't know when to stop.
I don't stop.
You know, there is no stop.
There has never been a stop.
Beep, beep went the nurse
to the doctor one day
There's a drag queen in
emergency and I just wanna say
Her wig's on backward,
she thinks she's a catch
Her liver's in her handbag
and her kidneys don't match
Beep, beep went the doctor
when he found the nurse
The drag queen in emergency
is getting worse
She shallow fried her liver
and swallowed it whole
And the blood in her veins
is alcohol
Coo-ee!
We're being filmed. How are you?
- Nice to see you.
- I'm fine.
My mum told me once, and this
was quite recently actually,
she said, "I was always worried
that you were always kind of..."
Not so much scared of failure,
really,
but I think she was worried
that if I felt I hadn't done
well enough, I'd commit suicide.
Listen, he looks his best
anyway cos he's my son.
- There you go.
- He's our son, you see.
I always worried about Jonathan.
- Well, yeah.
- Cos he nearly died.
- Nearly died when he was born.
- When he was born.
Three times
you've been rushed to hospital
with life-threatening things.
Well, it's a recurring theme
in my life, isn't it, clearly.
I hope you've only had three.
I don't want any more.
I was in hospital
with multiple organ failure
as a result
of drinking and taking drugs.
I was in hospital
for about five and a half weeks.
On death's door.
Dialysis, the lot.
♪ In the darkest night
I didn't know
Jonny as a performer
before
he came into intensive care.
He was critically ill.
His liver wasn't working.
His kidneys
were starting to fail.
I had multiple organ
failure after party central.
And then I wake up
two and a half weeks later
in intensive care.
When we had this phone call to
say he was rushed into hospital,
it was awful.
Erm... It was awful.
You know, we all hide
behind various masks,
and alcohol or drugs are a mask.
The route to survival in this
is that you've got
to set yourself some rules.
And if you don't set yourself
some rules,
life will become very difficult.
You have to nip it in the bud
and the sooner you can do that,
the better, you know.
Performers
are all insecure creatures.
We entertain, we're fabulous.
Inside we're screaming.
Don't do drugs, stick to drag.
Well, here's to another 40 then.
Here's to another 40 years.
Cheers.
I think he appreciates
his family more.
- Yeah.
- But it was something
I'd never want to ever, ever
have to go through again.
No.
It was the worst time
of my life.
When I came out of hospital, I
needed to make up for lost time.
Nothing
was gonna stand in my way.
I started kind of pulling
various people together
and got really excited
about seeing something new
and really community blossoming.
There was also this, you know,
thrill at kind of working
with loads of different people.
- Morning, Woo-Woos.
- Hi, trans.
It's Amber Swallows, look.
She's trans.
Welcome!
I consider myself
to be a straight woman
but I've also been a gay man.
Morning!
When I first
met Amber as she is now,
she was Dean.
Every time I see her
she's had some more work done.
This is it, we're getting on.
Document it.
I used to have a skinhead,
have tattoos all up my neck,
which I am just kind of
like getting rid of.
My whole dressing-up side has
gradually kind of taken over.
We are the trannies
doing a gay tent at Glastonbury,
which has
never been done before.
Have you seen the hotel sign?
Have you seen all this shit?
We have our role to play.
It's a zone,
it's the trans zone.
It's about being colourful.
So what if our balls
are hanging out of our bikinis?
I love working
with loads of other people.
I love seeing people get excited
about being part of the scene.
I love new faces coming on
and trying out mad looks
for the first time and being
part of the dance troupes.
♪ Move a little closer,
you can see it in my eyes
There aren't any more.
We need them.
♪ To hell and back and that's
something I can't disguise
♪ How does it make you feel
It's camaraderie.
It's part of it all.
This is the fucking work
getting done.
Jonny will probably
be naked in a field.
And Amber Swallows
will be fabulous. Where is she?
Hey, hey!
Welcome to Glastonburg!
I've come
as a representation of Aids.
People died,
this is a symbol of death.
It's very glamorous.
In drag!
It might not look glamorous
but inside,
we're feeling glamorous.
It's pissing with rain
out there.
Not happy!
- This is nice.
- Just something I picked up.
In a brothel!
Make some noise!
Lousy fucking bitches!
It's always very mixed.
Yeah, I'll be getting my kit off
and if they don't like it,
fuck 'em.
Who cares? They're all
off their tits on acid anyway.
Are you ready for a show?
This is a crew
who were so on fire.
It was a crest of a wave.
Good evening,
ladies and gentlemen!
My name is Scottee
and we are here to entertain!
It was that feeling
of, oh my God,
I belong somewhere.
Got this sense
of like community.
It was completely
and utterly bonkers.
Everyone was
completely off their tits.
Stand clear.
We're coming through.
Holestar!
My God, tranny injury.
Holestar has been hurt.
She's not dead, that's all
we have at the moment.
I slipped over.
All I know is my knee went
one way, I went the other way.
It fucking kills.
This is absolutely live.
Holestar being carted off
to the Priory.
Holestar, we've heard
you were pushed. Is this true?
That's nasty!
She pushed you. She pushed you.
All the drag queens
thought it was hilarious.
She's off to Hollywood
to have her fanny stitched up
or something.
In memory of Holestar,
we are renaming tonight's number
not Rapture but Fracture.
Yeah!
♪ Whoa-oh-oh
After, what is it now, 15 weeks,
I've finally got
the results back.
Something's degenerated
below my kneecap.
I'll have JPS, actually.
Menthols, please.
Yeah, thank you.
It's quite upsetting,
especially when people think
you're doing it for sympathy.
I've not actually received
any sympathy
so I wouldn't
be doing it for those reasons.
Julie. Julie Holestar.
Apparently she twisted her toe
or something. I can't think.
People just
didn't seem to give a shit.
I feel like I don't exist.
Because you're an animal
that's been injured
and packs of animals,
when one is wounded,
when one is lame, they leave it.
And when I was first diagnosed
with hypermobility syndrome,
erm, I was 20.
The doctor
that diagnosed me initially,
said that I would probably
be in a wheelchair
by the time I was 30.
This accident pre-empted
what life could be like.
But I eventually will have to be
in a wheelchair permanently.
Which is really upsetting.
- I assume she's quite well.
- Fair to middling.
Yeah.
After Glastonbury,
Time Out asked me to throw a
party at the Royal Opera House
to show off the best of
east London's drag superstars.
It was a showcase for Jonny
to do something with a
bigger budget in a bigger space.
I don't want to jinx it,
I am kind of like
the drag queen of choice.
Hopefully I'm making
hay while the sun shines.
I don't know if it's brave
of them getting Jonny,
but it's definitely something
quite edgy that they're doing.
Stop. Stop.
I don't feel too nervous,
actually.
I will be a bit later.
Jonny's talented,
he's got
the vision, the direction.
I see my sort of job working
with him as a kind of enabler.
Be ready. This show is gonna
start, ready or not.
I've only given myself a job so
I can hang around and be part of
that sort
of level of creativity.
♪ I I-I-love it
♪ I want it
Ladies and gentlemen,
welcome to Jonny Woo's
Phallo in the Sky.
♪ Fistful of fairies
make a hell of a balloon
♪ How to rock and roll party
♪ And he went to the kitchen
for his fairy cake
Jonny Woo's a superstar now.
He's busting it out.
You got some lipstick for Jonny?
Quickly.
Everyone, calm down.
I've got lipstick for Jonny.
Jonny needs lipstick.
Jonny, I've got some somewhere.
♪ There are no fairies
♪ Fistful of fairies
lie around the floor
♪ In a flat downtown
on the 52nd floor
Audience are great.
There's not many of them.
You standing there
in your girly poofy outfits.
I'm more of a man
than you could ever be.
More of a woman
you could ever want.
Bend over,
spread 'em and start praying.
All of those things
that Jonny's really good at,
I thought he was bigger
than he ever has been.
Although I've spent all week
having weird dreams,
being really anxious.
I couldn't stop looking
at myself in the mirror.
♪ We are the glamorous,
we are the golden kids
♪ We make the world shine
because of what we did
♪ We are the glamorous,
we are the golden kids
♪ We make the world shine
because of what we did
♪ We are the glamorous
Please welcome to the stage
the one and only Scottee!
I wanted to get as many
people involved as possible.
And they loved it!
Holestar was out
of the wheelchair.
It was fab to see her
with a stick.
This is the best thing ever.
And I really mean it.
Like, I'm sweating.
The whole time
I was just like...
When we did
the Royal Opera House
there was a sense
of togetherness.
It's sad that we don't have
that togetherness any more.
My background
is a little bit twisted.
I did a show about this
last year.
This story's about my mum.
She's damaged.
It's about my dad.
He's also quite damaged.
It's about me.
My mum was an alcoholic
and an over eater.
And my dad was a drug user
and an alcoholic.
♪ They say there's nothing
like a mother's love
I've got lots of early memories
of finding drugs on my dad
and my mum stopping off
before taking me to hospital,
cos I was having
an asthma attack,
to buy bottles of whisky.
♪ Will anyone feed me love
♪ And rid me of this...
And they used to
beat each other up quite a lot.
And lots
of failed suicide attempts.
And so that kind of did
build me into the person
I suppose who I am today.
♪ Everyone needs a mother's hand
But when I was 18
I had a nervous breakdown.
And that kind of
really affected me
and I thought, right,
I need to take control of this.
♪ That I want my mum
to fade away
On my 18th birthday
I stopped all contact
with my parents and my family.
And I haven't
spoke to them since.
♪ All the time I wanted
♪ I...
By the time I was eight
I already knew
that I wanted to be a woman,
or at least not a boy.
You start to see everybody
turning into men around you.
And you're fucking terrified.
There are people as young
as eight years old
killing themselves.
Cos normality says
that I have to be like you.
You are born this way.
It isn't a nurture thing.
It's nature.
You don't really get a handbook
of how to parent.
And if your child is a bit weird
then you do the best you can.
My mum and dad
did the best they could.
First time that I really knew
I was a transsexual man
was when I was 13.
My favourite T-Girl,
Miss Amber Swallows!
Amber's on the road
to transition now.
Yeah, it's a big step to take.
Ladies and gentlemen,
this is evening wear.
Putting the wig back in the box
and keeping the wig on
all the time
are two different things.
You do get a lot of girls
that you get your first bit
of surgery or whatever,
or you get a nice pair of tits
and it turns into
more of an addiction.
You end up looking like
a cartoon character
of what you really want to be.
She's absolutely wonderful.
Wearing all of last year's
fashions at the same time!
I'm having a big
major operation tomorrow.
A little treat for myself.
Tomorrow, that is what
I'm having done tomorrow.
So... So, Amber,
you look a little bit different.
Pretty much, yes,
I've just come out of hospital.
Apparently
I was a real heavy bleeder.
So I'm kind of used to that
with all the tampons
I go through anyway!
So next ingredients
into the fucking fruitcake
are a pair of tits!
Everybody keeps asking me
about downstairs.
Keep the peace.
You know what they say?
Keep the peace, babe.
That's what I am in life. A
three-legged girl with a secret.
I used to be really good friends
with my dad at one point
but I think I've messed
the relationship up
because of a situation
that happened a few years ago.
My phone had gone missing.
And then I realised, oh my God,
it's my naughty phone
that went missing.
It's literally got pictures
of the insides of my fanny
so that kind of gives you
an idea of what's in the phone!
So my dad has gone
through the phone,
obviously seen
all these text messages.
"Amber, when am I gonna get to
kind of like fucking slip you
one up your tranny fanny?"
I opened the front door
to my daddy.
And he threw the phone
at my head and spat in my face!
He was like, "You're a fucking
disgrace, you, Amber."
There's a big difference
between Holestar
and Julie Hole day wear.
And Julie Hole day wear
in the past
could have had a tendency
to not always look
on the brighter side of life.
But...
But then we can all be
a bit like that.
♪ Vashanka, Vashanka
♪ You're a fashion wanker
There's a frustration
in me where I think
why don't I deserve...
I deserve, I think I deserve
to have a little bit more
recognition.
Just have a little bit more
acceptance, perhaps.
I see other people's shows
and I think
why are they getting
those opportunities and I'm not?
And I'm better than some
of the shit out there.
Tell me what's going on today.
I'm doing a drag queen workshop.
Cos I guess
they're expecting a man.
I presume.
Cos that's what people
usually expect, erm... is a man.
Calling myself
a tranny with a fanny,
it still jars
with a lot of people.
I've got a feeling
they might be outside.
- Hello.
- Hi.
I'm not ignoring you.
I'll be back in a moment.
Anyone for drag? No drag?
Anyone for drag? Drag?
Anyone here for drag?
Anyone for drag?
No? Let's just go back in
and sod it.
Why do you think people
might not want to do it?
Because they're scared.
Can't teach it with two people.
A grumpy young boy
and a lesbian.
Ooh, the drama!
Ooh, pull, push.
Pull? Pull!
- Holestar is amazing.
- Private Hole!
There's no one else coming.
Sod them.
She's a rose between 15
transvestite thorns, isn't she?
She's even more funny
when she doesn't mean to be.
Come forward, come forward,
come closer, come closer.
So...
If you haven't noticed already,
I'm not actually a man.
I'm actually a lady.
And I call myself
the tranny with a fanny.
And that's my kind of shtick,
really.
You may be thinking
why is a woman doing drag
or what qualifications
does a woman have to do drag?
Well, I've been doing this now
for seven years.
Used to do it in Europe.
In Vienna,
all round central Europe.
She's got a lot to say
about gender
and what you're allowed to do
cos she was in the army.
She went through
the whole trying to be normal.
And then realised what the fuck
was I doing in the army?
She left the army
and ran away
to become a drag superstar.
Erm... Yeah. Just looking
at those pictures.
My song was out yesterday.
Got a new song out.
Which we'll talk about later.
So that's me.
Tell me a bit more about you.
I've recently
become a Christian.
Erm... That's quite a big part
of my life.
You're gonna be Teresa Green
just for now.
There we go! We're getting it,
we're working it.
Keep going, honey, keep going.
Work, work, work. Ooh!
At the end of the week
there's a performance
that I'll do
in front of everyone else.
And they're gonna be
doing my song!
Teresa Green, who is Jules,
was all up for doing today.
And mincing around in his heels.
Her heels.
And can't seem to find her,
she's missing in action.
♪ Don't try to fit me
into your heart
♪ Cos there's too much of me
Part of the feeling
that I felt today
from either being God
or the Holy Spirit
saying I shouldn't do it,
that it just told me
not to do it.
♪ Yeah-hey, yeah-hey
♪ Yeah-hey, ah ah
That was... You saw the show.
Was it good?
Yeah.
- Do you wish you'd done it?
- In a way.
Well, I saw him in the tent
and I thought he's just
got scared, what have you.
But he just pointed
to the ceiling and he said,
"I was told not to do it."
And it took me a minute.
Ah, God.
Makes me sad that we live
in a world in the 21st century
where people
still persecute people.
Putting a dress on
in a western little village
at a performing arts school,
you'd think that's normal,
par for the course.
But it's still something
that people
still find quite shocking
and wrong.
And that disturbs me
a little bit.
All I'm trying to do in life
is just make a go of things.
Open a really nice shop,
do my thing.
It's not rocket science.
The whole idea of the shop,
really, is to kind of like,
you know,
to cut out the middle man
in terms of buying high-end
luxury stuff.
So the stuff that we get here,
we get all the cream stuff
from the catwalk.
So much hot trade goes past
this shop every day.
Builders, scaffolders,
all day long.
Amber in the window! Hi!
My main problem is as soon
as I open my gob, you know,
people are on it straightaway.
They're like,
she's got a bit of a secret
she ain't telling us.
But I look pretty good
from behind.
I reckon I could pass
looking this way like that.
Soon as I turn around,
I'm fucked.
I'd only get straight gays,
only. I mean, come on.
Who wouldn't have a slice
of the honey pot?
I think it's the intrigue
and the mystery.
It kind of makes people
want to discover a bit more.
What else can she have down her
knickers apart from a big cock?
Maybe she's got three tits
as well, you know.
I went shopping this morning
at the surgery.
And I picked myself
a nice pair of...
34G silicone breasts.
Tried them on, had a little
whiz around the surgery.
They looked great.
They're really, really big,
though.
So I don't know
what they're gonna look like.
Do you like big tits, Tony?
I like any tits, to tell the
truth, as long as they're nice.
I'll bring them in a plastic bag
and show you!
It's almost like what I'm doing
here. I'm decorating the shop.
It's pretty much what it is.
To be honest, I don't know
where I'm gonna get the money
from to pay for my boobies.
I don't know where she gets
her money from.
She might sue me.
That's probably what she does.
She waits for someone
to hypothesise
about where
she gets her money from
and then she sues them
for slander.
That's where she gets
her money from.
I need to get six grand
by April. £6,000.
I'm gonna have to get that.
Cos I know who it is.
Oh, it's nonstop.
So where are you?
Highbury?
So you wanna come over
and see me?
OK, so tell me about your dick,
how big is it?
Really?
What do you wanna do with it?
What? OK, call me when you're at
the station, alright?
Alright, babes, bye.
I can't believe the time.
It's nine o'clock.
Right, I'm out of here.
I have to say,
I've done my research
and I think this is the world's
first ever boobathon.
Definitely tranny boobathon
anyway.
We're trying to get our sister
some titties.
OK, yeah, you know,
everyone's out for themselves,
but I actually consider myself
part of like a little
tranny meerkat clan.
It's a matter of no tits
or tits. We need tits.
We are raising money
for Amber's new tits.
We wanna see all of you
there now. Over to Ma Butcher.
Hard cock.
Boobathon!
Yes! It's a boobathon!
We love Amber!
It's very important cos she's
a very good friend of ours.
And we know
it'll make her very happy.
Because she doesn't get enough
action as it is.
The girl needs a rack!
We're gonna raise that dollar
one way or another.
She'll have those titties
and we as a family have bought
our sister Amber her tits.
And thank God for that.
I had my sex change
six months ago.
My hair transplant was 2,500.
My nose was 2,000.
This was 5,000.
Er... My boobs were 3,000.
My hips were 4,000.
And my vagina I did on the NHS.
I just went bankrupt.
At night I was escorting
to pay off
the loans for my surgery,
which most of us have to do.
And anyone who thinks
that this is a choice
is absolutely insane.
Now it is eight o'clock
in the evening.
The place is hammered.
I'm talking about...
How much was that worth?
This is a bum print, remember.
Ooh ooh ooh! Ooh ooh ooh!
♪ London's getting dirty
on the dance floor
Amber's tits?
No, I haven't seen 'em.
But I will see them.
Everyone will see them.
There's no rush.
Here he comes.
Oh my God! £20! £20! Yes!
♪ See you do it, see you do it,
see you do it
You don't choose your
family, you choose your friends.
And I look around the room
tonight and I think, thank you.
Thank you, you. Thank you, you.
Thank you, you.
It's called a community.
If somebody wanted a cock
enlargement, I'd be there.
Amber Swallows, how much money
have we made tonight?
The total amount is...
£4,260!
I like to think that I own like
a little piece of her nipple.
It belongs to me.
- What about Africa?
- Kids in Africa.
Somalian droughts!
OK,
this is trans community spirit.
This is people that give a shit
about other people.
Amber! Amber! Amber!
-  She didn't!
- She did!
I thought she was taking
the piss.
I've just had
my life-changing operation,
which is my boobies.
Bearing in mind
that this is the first time
that I've seen them as well,
so let's see...
..what's happened,
and where that boobathon money
has been spent.
Ta-da!
Amber's new girls.
Hello, babies. How are you?
In a way I kind of feel
a bit pissed off
that I've had to pay for them.
Cos really they should have been
here when I was born.
Some people don't like
my kind of people.
And sometimes
you need to take a stand.
Adolf Hitler
was a Roman Catholic.
When the Pope came over,
a lot of people were talking
about wanting to protest
against it.
And so I'd written this rap
called "Pope Benny"
where I made the Pope a Scouser.
- Get your nun's outfit on.
- Alright, alright!
Hi, kids!
I'm dressing up
as the Pope today.
I'm promoting my new hit single,
Rapping at the Vatican.
Can you get in the car?
We are going
to Hyde Park Corner,
where the protest against
the Pope is happening today.
They're killing all the gays in
Africa, aren't they? They are.
Killing all the bears?
- Killing the gays in Africa.
- Oh God, yeah.
♪ Listen, kids,
my name is the Pope
♪ I'm slipperier
than a soap on a rope
♪ I'm a pimped-up
kind of religious man
♪ I'm a geezer
rapping at the Vatican
♪ I'm the Pope
so don't abbreviate
♪ With "what's up, chuck?"
or "hey there, mate"
♪ The cardinals think I am it
♪ My bezzies call me Benedict
♪ My name is Benny
♪ I'm Benny the Bible basher
The Pope was saying
that gays and transsexuals
were a bigger threat to mankind
than deforestation.
Right-wing evangelistic
Christian culture
would happily see us
not on the map at all.
And that needs to be addressed.
What I really
like about people like that
is that they talk such utter
massive bullshit
that it's quite obvious
that they're being
completely twattish.
♪ I'm a blinged-up
kind of religious man
♪ I'm a geezer
rapping at the Vatican
♪ My name is Benny
I'm saving arseholes tonight.
Non-believers, fuck off!
Everybody else, do the cross!
Whoo!
On one side of the page
there was a banner that says
"suffer little children"
and on the other side,
there was Jonny.
Jonny doesn't actually
say anything.
♪ My name is Benny
♪ I'm doing the Bible bash
I would expect more to be said
about the hideous crimes
that have been committed
by the Catholic Church,
and less about his performance
as a pop star.
There is a cut-off, isn't there?
In clubland.
What's the cut-off?
It's 45, isn't it?
I've got literally 1,000 days
left of clubbing left in me.
Come on. Let's go, kids.
This is Gay Bingo!
I think John Sizzle
is the party queen de jour.
He's the grande dame
at the moment.
Snuffing up all the DJ gigs.
John Sizzle, look at that.
Primark's finest, she is.
Let's read some palms.
You are all gonna have
bloody shits tomorrow.
Why do you you pretend
you're a psychic?
I don't believe a word.
I need a career. A new career.
I sense someone behind me.
I do not like having my tits,
my arse or my mangina goosed
by drunk twats in nightclubs.
You're the shaky drunk.
Obviously. What's your name?
I just want to go home to bed.
I want to forget all about this.
Put it down to experience.
Happens to all the greats.
The thing with John,
John always battles
with this idea that he shouldn't
be a drag queen.
We've got this wonderful DJ
booth. It's crystal encrusted.
So he's always kind of pretended
not to really like
being a drag queen.
She didn't want it. She wanted
to be on full display.
Between you and me,
I have got quite a gash.
I think
drag's got a shelf life, right?
Eyes down for a line,
come on, let's go.
I need
some methadrone immediately.
You ask most drag queens.
I don't think they wanna do this
in their mid to late 40s.
I am looking for an escape.
Should I be taking this down
to here?
So I'm doing upholstery. This is
going back to what I used to do.
I always used to make stuff.
Looking good.
Bit of shabby chic.
Just nice, isn't it?
Just the idea of pottering
around in a dusty old shed.
Like, you know,
stuffing old pouffes.
What's my name again? Ofrah.
Oh God.
The things we do for 50 quid.
Lovebox is really... It's good
because I feel like
it's a culmination
of lots of things I've been
doing over the past few years.
So from a personal level,
that's very kind of gratifying.
We're performing to thousands
and thousands of people.
So in the back of your mind
you're hoping that exposure's
gonna lead on to something
bigger and better.
Jonny, he still should cross
over into the mainstream.
Out of all the things I've done,
this is probably
the biggest thing I've done.
And this one hopefully
is going to be to 15,000.
♪ Get your raggedy ass up
and sit the fuck down
My titties are freezing cold.
My Spandex is wet.
And, yes, do you know what?
I've always been
a bit of a show-off.
- Have a brilliant show, dears.
- Thank you.
Welcome!
Scissor Sisters!
Whoo!
I'm having quite a fun day.
You know,
get to run out on stage.
Whup whup!
Please welcome
the amazing Miss Beth Ditto!
Whoa! Go, baby!
- It's all about Jonny.
- Jonny Woo!
♪ What you gonna do,
what you gonna do
♪ When the party's over?
♪ What you gonna do,
what you gonna do
♪ When the party's over?
♪ What you gonna do,
what you gonna do
♪ When the party's over?
I didn't see Jonny on stage
cos I was doing my own job
at the time.
Some of us have got to work,
you know.
What's happening?
Amber and cohorts
were grabbing cock
wherever they could.
- Watch the hair!
- Amber Swallows.
Watch the hair!
Everybody's trying
to steal my gum.
Basically I missed everything
because I was
tossing some guy off.
We're getting out of here.
We belong in a different place.
I wanna go
and fuck a chav to death.
I am just about to introduce
Blondie onto the stage.
It's my biggest audience,
isn't it?
She is the one!
- Blondie!
- Blondie! Blondie!
Blondie! Blondie!
The wonderful, the sensational
Miss Debbie Harry!
Blondie!
Whoo!
It's good that I got to
introduce people this year.
It'd be nice if people came
in thousands to see me one day.
But maybe they have.
Have they? No.
But they might have.
Do you like my entourage?
Can we see my entourage?
Hi!
That is success!
Whoo!
I thought I'd show you
a little sexy Sizzle secret.
Part of the woods
where I used
to procure married men
and relieve them
of their dignity.
Everybody knew
that John was gay except me.
I was the last one to know.
His dad knew, his sister knew.
I never seen him
wearing my clothes.
I can see the exact tree
where I lost my virginity.
I mean, the thing is, like,
you know,
people don't understand
the idea of cottaging.
Heterosexual people
don't understand
the idea of cottaging.
And they see it as like...
like dirty homosexuals
and their lust
for cheap and nasty sex
in parks and places
where there are hedgehogs.
It was the love
that dare not speak its name
because you got into trouble.
You couldn't walk around
holding hands.
I remember in the '90s
and my boyfriend
and getting stopped
by the police
for kissing him in the snow
outside a theatre in town.
It was really romantic.
I mean, nobody could ask
for a better son, actually.
I think a lot of people
would be jealous
if they had a son like mine.
There was no way
for me to meet gay men.
And so you met people furtively
and I think even though
we were having sex,
a lot of the time
it was just about contact.
It wasn't just about
getting your rocks off
with some 70-year-old
who looks like Rod Stewart.
He came out with it
and said, "I'm gay."
And I said, "If you promise me
you don't go near the parks,
you know,
these seedy type things,
cos you get beaten up,
I'm quite happy."
I think I slept with
about 1,000 people in two years
when I first started.
I was addicted.
Nothing like a bit of cheap sex.
Hello, tree! Remember me?
I remember you!
This, like, middle-aged guy,
like, blond hair and a mac
whisked me up here
and then he fucked me
up against this very tree.
It didn't even hurt,
I was loving it.
I was literally like a cat
clawing at the bark.
I think about a month later,
I was going to work on the tube,
and opposite me was him,
his wife and two kids.
He was still wearing
the same mac.
I realised the first time that
men are quite possibly shit.
And the gay scene is going to be
really dicey.
It didn't put me off though.
Goodbye, tree.
♪ I'm a big daddy tom
with a big daddy cock
♪ And daddy
is looking for his boy
Pia, really,
of all the clan, she's the one
that's the most,
I suppose, invisible now.
Pia, I haven't seen Pia
for donkey's.
I've stopped taking hormones
because erm...
My intention this year
is to get castrated.
She's one of these people
that doesn't wanna conform
and be a woman.
She wants to be this amazing
trans creation that she is.
I just started to get hairy
again, which is really horrible.
My boobs are less full
and I'm losing my ass.
I've lost two inches off my ass
which is sort of quite alarming.
It was a vote against vanity.
She had to do her own thing.
Speaking to a few people,
it sounded
like that was for the best.
I'm clearing the decks
for the dissolution of mankind
to all intents and purpose.
There are huge changes afoot
with the actual earth
possibly will turn end to end.
You could be on top of Everest
with two miles of water
on your head.
Everything that we know
as physics is wrong.
There is a very interesting
radio transmitter called Harp.
Point this thing at the earth,
you can create a huge bass note
which makes the earth vibrate.
To be honest, I think a lot
of Pia's conspiracy theories
are drug related.
It's a shame.
I don't think
the world's gonna end this year.
It's gonna drag on.
I'll say when it's gonna end.
I haven't
really broached the subject
with a lot of the performers.
Generally people on the street
tend to raise an eyebrow.
She could be right. She'll
be there on her narrowboat,
drifting away with her cats,
going, "Fuck you, you ignorant
twats, you didn't listen to me."
People have been walking around
with boards on
saying the end is nigh
for bloody years.
There's nothing new, darling.
Yeah,
I'm quite looking forward to it.
We are party
to the world changing.
We are very privileged
to possibly all die horribly
but they will know that
I was right. Sorry.
Check this out.
♪ It's my hormones,
they're ripping into my bone
♪ Taking over my waist
and slipping into a zone
♪ It's my wild side,
I've always been so denied
♪ When I see you I just knew
that I just wanted a ride
Every time I come in the park
I always seem to get erm...
trade.
I think everyone's horny in this
park, it's a horny kind of park.
There's one just right behind me
staring at me now.
Here goes.
Yeah, I take myself seriously.
I've lost nearly three stone.
Yeah, I feel
a whole lot more positive.
She's got her
shit together, hasn't she?
She's stopped being
a complete bladder on a stick.
According to some
transgender prophets,
it's gonna be the end
of the world this year
so I hope I get in contact
with my dad before then.
I'm gonna invite him down
to London
to maybe come and stay with me
for the weekend.
Hopefully try to bring him
into my life.
At the end of the day
he's my dad
and I'd like to be his friend.
- Hello?
- Dad?
Hello?
Hi, it's me, Amber.
Hello, you OK?
Yeah.
Ah. I've not spoken to you
for a long time.
- It's my birthday tomorrow.
- Tomorrow? I know.
So if you want,
maybe we can meet up?
Go and have a bite to eat? Yeah.
OK. You're not gonna
get freaked out, are you?
Huh?
I said, you're not gonna get
freaked out, are you?
I look a little bit different
from the last time you seen me.
Huh?
- You'll have to put up with it?
- Hello?
You'll have to put up with it?
Yeah, I think you will.
You'll have to just
put up with me, I'm afraid.
There's a lot of sadness
just to think, you know,
of all the shit
that happened here.
And then he starts to rub
himself up against me.
And so I start to rub myself up
against him.
And I'm not touching him cos
I remember thinking to myself,
if I touch him, that's
the thing that makes me gay.
A lot of my sexual experiences
happened around about
the age of 12 to 15.
And they happened in these sheds
that are kind of
around the estate.
And the local boys would do
what they wanted with me.
It's interesting that woman just
looked back and laughed at me.
I went to school with her son.
I don't say anything
cos I've never spoken
to a policeman before
so I'm petrified.
"We're arresting you on
suspicion of buggery and rape."
I'm 13 years old.
On an estate,
news travels quick, very quick.
Erm...
And it got out here
that I'd had sex with a guy
when I was 13.
And then that got warped into
"he's a rapist".
And then to be a gay rapist
was the worst thing.
Like the worst thing
that you could possibly be.
They ask me to stand up
and so I do.
And they say to me,
"You're free to go."
I was free to go.
I was never allowed
to go back into education
because I was a risk
to the other students.
My mum had to deal with
death threats on my life
and I was branded a rapist
on my estate.
But I was free to go.
And with this show, you know,
I've toured it round the world.
It's won awards,
it's got great reviews.
And then I brought it to London
and I brought it
to the Roundhouse,
which is literally
on the edge of the estate.
And I guess
I feel that weird fear again.
Like maybe
they're gonna tell me off. Who?
What's this weird thing
that I'm worried about?
I constantly worry.
I don't want to carry around
any form of shame any more.
I need to let this shit go.
There's a fat girl in the corner
And she's the office clown
The life and soul of parties,
never easy to weigh down
She can count her friends
on one hand
She knows who to trust
The plump girl in HR,
the boys at school cussed
There's a fat girl in the corner
She's been like it
since her teens
She blames her mum's side
for the obese gene
Hair is always pristine,
flawless maquillage
Underneath the war paint,
a broken facade
There's a fat girl in the corner
And for once she's had enough
Things have gone pear shaped
She wants someone to love
Overworked, overeaten,
and overweight
A 20-something fat cat
who never got her bait
There's a fat girl in the corner
and now she's deceased
Went down the wrong hole,
her midnight feast
She ate a box of doughnuts
She shoved them down her throat
The thing that killed her was
The thing she loved the most
Does anybody want a flyer
for my show?
Would anybody like a flyer
That is about as involved
as my pitch is.
Hello, would you like to come
and see my show?
Hello! No, another no.
I'm not fulfilling my potential.
I've kind of sold myself short.
That is when
I get really depressed.
There's been a lot of boys
with their pants down
to get attention.
Hello, darling, how are you?
- Very well, how are you?
- I'm very good.
I hate it.
Stars, stars, stars, stars.
That's what everyone wants,
stars.
Desperate for reviews.
For the stars.
Roll up, roll up, ladies
and gentlemen, don't be shy.
Am I lying in the gutter
looking at the stars?
No, I'm face down in the gutter.
With my ass in the air.
New show, twisted drama
set in an abattoir.
Slaughterhouse comedy.
New play.
How did you end up
coming here anyway?
For the last year we've been
developing the show
and it's been touring.
You're planning your world tour.
Last night was alright.
The night before
I had nine people in.
- Soul destroying, isn't it?
- I just didn't need it.
- Soul destroying.
- I slit my wrists the next day.
I think if I want to push myself
to be at the top of what
I see as being top of my game,
this isn't the top of my game.
It's the last day, anyway,
I don't care.
I am over it!
Let's get out of here.
♪ So you ask me
♪ Are you happy with your life?
So I'm sitting at the estuary
of the River Medway,
and just slightly to the north
is the village where I grew up.
Being here actually it feels
very, very comforting.
I feel like
I could stay here forever.
It's quite peculiar.
You could literally just
leave me here and I could become
like one of these boats.
I feel like
I should be more successful.
I've wasted a lot of time.
I think I've done myself
a lot of damage.
And I have to deal with that
and I have to take
responsibility for that.
I could have been more
successful but I made choices.
I spent a lot of time
doing lots of ecstasy.
My memory's shot.
My memory's fucked up.
I can't remember shit.
I'm fairly happy. I haven't
fulfilled the potential
that I think that I have.
And the ability that I have.
I really feel like
I've got to pull my finger out.
Oh, my God.
I was diagnosed HIV positive
I think
seven or eight years ago.
I can't remember which. Erm...
Oh God, it was awful.
It was the single worst thing
that's ever happened to me
in my whole life.
And I've buried a parent.
So it was worse,
a lot worse than that.
Erm...
It was shock. It was just
complete and utter shock.
And I think you hear people
use the word "devastated" a lot.
They don't know
what they're talking about.
Yeah. They don't know
"I was devastated.
Oh my God. I was devastated."
You know. No, you weren't.
When you have your whole...
When it feels like your whole...
Everything you've understood
about yourself and your life
has been removed from you,
that's basically how I felt.
It was really shocking.
I joke about it
as much as possible.
I think probably too much.
I think bit of gallows humour.
It disarms people, I think.
What percentage of people
do I know are HIV?
Of my close friends...
God. Probably 40 or 50 per cent.
And counting.
There's a good chance
that you'll get it.
If you've been doing your job
properly, you should get it.
Come on.
My father and my uncle
are five minutes away.
One second,
I need to pull my all-in-one
fucking body shape up.
It's falling down.
Just what you wear
to meet your dad
when you've not seen him
for years,
when you've actually
changed sex.
This is the outfit
that you wear. Oh!
See you soon. Bye. Bye.
That's my uncle.
He called me Amber.
So not only have I got my dad
to deal with,
I've got my uncle as well who
again I have not seen for years.
I think he might be embarrassed
to be with me in the street.
Oh, my God!
Oh, my God.
They're gonna knock in a second.
They're gonna knock on the door
in a second.
Come on.
Hi! You OK? Come on.
Come on in. Come on in.
Hi, you OK?
No, not much, no.
How are you both?
Are you alright?
- Very good.
- Come on in. Come on.
- Have you been here before?
- Have I heck been here before.
You've not been here before.
It was Amber's father's idea
to come down and... and stay.
And I think it was
a little window of opportunity
to break the ice myself.
- So this is the kitchen?
- This is the bathroom, yeah.
My dad is so nervous.
I thought I was nervous,
but he's more nervous than me.
Just came in and started talking
about my boiler straightaway.
- And what's this here?
- A toilet.
I'm making eye contact with him.
He looks...
I'm really happy. Really,
really pleased that he's here.
Where does your television go?
Well, it can go on there.
Be alright, won't it?
Oh, aye, yeah.
It's going to be a shock,
you know.
It was Dean, now it's Amber,
and he's got to get used to it.
You can take a man
out of Manchester
but not Manchester
out of the man.
£30? It was a tenner, that.
You bought it off a shoplifter.
What do you do, drink it with
the alarm still on it?
Shall I show that to the police?
It's a joke.
Seriously, you want me to speak,
proper?
- What I've got to say?
- Yeah.
That's it. Alright.
Mirror, mirror, on the wall
Will I always
look this beautiful?
♪ Grab your stilettos,
love to do it
♪ In the Dolphin,
the murder mile
♪ In the hot tub, at the shed
♪ In the Dolphin,
the murder mile
♪ In the hot tub, at the shed
♪ In the Dolphin,
the murder mile
Hello, darling.
How's it going in there?
-  45.
- Shut up!
- 45, still alive.
- Fuck you. Fuck you.
Fuck yourself.
Give me some prosecco.
♪ In the Dolphin,
the murder mile
My body's falling apart.
Drag is giving me rickets.
We're here for John Sizzle's
45th birthday.
John Sizzle
shouldn't give up drag
because otherwise there would be
nowhere for all
that bitterness to go.
He'll say
he's doing it for money.
I think he's enjoying it.
Sizzle has paved the way for us.
That's fucking cava.
So, John Sizzle, you're 45.
- Ish.
- Apparently.
- Are you giving up drag?
- Fuck you all.
- No!
- D'you know what...
Yes! Yes!
Do I have a choice?
No!
Cheers.
To tights! To tights!
Just about to perform my
brand-new track
for the birthday boy
called Ten Star Hotel.
He's gonna get a fresh insight
into my new body.
So there is no more
keep the peace any more.
It is about to be
World War Three.
They don't call it a transition
for no reason.
♪ Yeah, you were cruising
down the street
♪ As I was working my heat
♪ Strapped into my Herve,
hair scraped back
♪ Yeah, I was clipping it neat
♪ It was just one of those days
♪ Sending boys
into total sex craze
♪ That's when
you pulled on up to me
♪ And wound down
your window to see
♪ What all the other girls
wanna be
♪ That's a bitch
with a back-door pussy
♪ You cried,
hello, there, pretty lady
♪ Those legs are fine, yeah,
really shapely
♪ I wanna slide my tongue along
♪ Pull back your thong
and hit you strong
♪ I said, excuse me, Mr Boy
♪ What's there is warm
and it'll bring you joy
♪ Why don't you
pull my thighs aside
♪ Squeeze up your fist
and try to make me cry
♪ I only wear fake Chanel
♪ Only do anal with Cristal
♪ And when I'm in the mood
for fucking you
♪ Better get a ten-star hotel
♪ And if you shoot,
this bitch gonna yell
♪ Take your gun,
send you right back to hell
♪ Hit your boys
and tell 'em you're not so L
♪ Call the paps
and exclusive this and sell
Happy birthday, John Sizzle.
Allegedly, I said
I was giving up drag today.
By today. And I haven't.
And here I am at 45 doing
what I swore I wouldn't do.
I'm gonna do a gig, Saturday
night, and earn some money.
But ultimately
it is a young person's game.
I think Jonny Woo's also in a
transitional moment in his life.
You need to be glamorous.
I don't mind the fact that
I'm 45 and doing it so much
because ultimately
I'm a show-off.
45 and still alive.
And the gigs
have actually freed me up
to do what I wanna do.
Upholstery
and all this sort of stuff.
Everyone else
works their tits off.
Spending their whole life typing
for their pensions.
And here I am expressing myself,
basically.
Sexsational. Relevant.
Challenging.
Mwah.
Fab.
Whoops. I think
I might be a transvestite.
So what I'm doing is...
my ten years of drag show
called Sorry I'm A Lady.
Rather than just do it
in a cabaret space,
I thought this would be a more
interesting place to do it
because I can sit here and do
my make-up before the show
and be a kind of
art installation.
Woo-ee! Hey!
The idea being
every time I put my make-up on
it's kind of sculptural.
I'm sculpting right now.
I'm painting.
Trying to create a masterpiece.
There's something I've got
Depression
I was different
An eccentric child.
Not pretty, sporty or popular.
I didn't know that
Thought I was normal
Singled out for being different
I have depression and I've
had depression for a long time.
We don't talk about it.
Everything's fabulous.
The world of drag, everyone's
fabulous and no one's ill.
No one gets hurt or injured.
It's all fabulous.
It's like, well, no,
we're human.
You do it
because you love to show off.
The bullying got worse
The depression got worse
Until at the age of 15
I...
attempted...
suicide
I might be in therapy and on
pills for the rest of my life.
I've accepted that. It's shit.
I have my moments
when I'm catatonic
and I don't want
to speak to anybody.
And they're horrible times
and they're dark times.
I'm on the verge of suicide
and it's awful.
However, there's this.
I'm actually quite suicidal
most days.
I honestly don't think people
would care.
People would go "Oh" for a week.
On Facebook. "Oh, she's dead."
And that would be it.
There's not much to live for,
really.
I try and make my life
as colourful as possible
while I'm still here.
Cos one day I will go.
Simple as that.
And that's that.
Cut.
♪ Vacuous and vicious,
words you can't spell
♪ Your vocabulary's
limited to me
♪ You're so ambitious
♪ What do you do
♪ Is it anything
that matters in this world
♪ Flying high
♪ It must be
all the air you're piercing
♪ Driving by
♪ The regal wave
is all that's missing
♪ So stop
♪ Who made you
♪ Whoa
♪ The queen
of fucking everything
♪ Who made you
♪ Whoa
♪ The queen
of fucking everything
I guess a good place to start
is where we left off last.
The last kind of time I met you
I think I was a bit mental!
And since then
I got in contact with my family.
My mum's six months in AA
and my dad's four months in AA.
And their life
has completely changed.
Good evening,
ladies and gentlemen!
Welcome to Burger Queen!
Scottee's just working,
isn't he?
He's just doing
more and more shows.
He works very hard.
He's being very prolific
and has become a very competent,
charming performer.
Yes, well, we have,
of course, Lisa Stansfield.
Don't piss on my parade, bitch.
I've stopped partying
and I've really focused
on my work, I guess.
I feel like life is kind of
finally settling down.
Yeah, I do.
It's good. I can say that.
We are all the outsiders.
Everybody in this room
is an outsider.
We are all fat
and we all are quite fantastic.
Lisa Stansfield, you are fat.
And welcome to the fat club.
You know, growing up here,
coming out was never an option.
You become the runt. You become
the runt of the litter.
Well, I was.
The reason why I do what I do
and why I'm such a show-off
and why I'm so determined
to be seen
and to be outlandish and outré
is because I wasn't able to...
I wasn't able to be that
when I was growing up.
I was always the faggot.
If we look into the psychology,
we're all, all of us,
we're desperate for attention.
And we're desperate
to articulate ourselves
now that we know we can't
be fucking bullied any more.
You know, I'm gonna get on stage
and wear a sequin outfit.
Nobody's gonna call me fat and
nobody's gonna call me queer.
If they do,
they're gonna get chucked out
and get a lot of hassle from me.
Because now I'm in control
and I think that's what
it's about. It's about control.
A friend of mine has had
it done. 175 for three areas.
She did mine
and this bad frown line
just didn't go, did it?
I didn't like our Cher
with Botox.
Like surprised looking.
She looks Chinesefied.
Can't she? Chinesefied.
My family are not strangers to
a little bit of a nip and tuck.
I think there's a competition
who's got the biggest tits
at the moment!
And I seem to be winning.
Have you seen my boobs?
I'll show you how big there are.
- God!
- They're gorgeous.
- What size?
- 36F.
36F. I want to go 34DD,
what I used to be.
Are you two gonna have
a joint boob job together?
- Do you get a discount?
- Yeah.
It's gonna be on the sale
of the property.
That's what Cher's boob job
is done. When we've sold this.
She's getting hers done.
You know the person who did your
surgery when I come to see you.
I wouldn't mind using...
- Him for your facelift?
- Yes.
This is only three months.
He did a fantastic job on you.
Yeah, you can see it.
I can see my mum in you
a little bit there.
I'm up in Manchester for a while
to be closer to my family.
It's going to be more easy
for them and more easy for me
if I've got more connection
with them.
I've got friends of mine
going through transitions
and their families
have disowned them.
Alright, I'll see you
in about 45 minutes.
Don't be too long, Dean.
Er, Amber.
Alright.
My dad. Just slipped up again.
This is the reason
for kind of like being up here.
It takes time, you know.
All's I ever do
is bloody put make-up on.
Right, go on.
What have you made?
There's some chips an' that.
Asparagus, peas,
chips, carrots, pork.
The dog and everything.
- Her dog, Ruby.
- That's her dog.
So how's everything been?
Alright?
Yeah, I've just got
a new place in Manchester.
I want to be back
near my family, you know.
Cos I'm having my operation
soon, aren't I? In March.
Yep, biggest operation
of my life.
Can't do anything. Can't have
sex for six months.
- You can't what?
- Can't have sex for six months.
Right. Don't be picking at that.
I want you to eat it proper.
Not like a bit here,
a bit there.
It's massive.
I don't give a damn. Get it ate.
- Is this chicken or pork?
- Pork, that.
To me, you look the same, to me.
What, exactly the same person?
Yes. Always the same person.
Oh, well, that's nice.
Physically she looks
very different from Dean,
doesn't she?
No, I don't think so. No.
What do you mean?
I look exactly the same
as what I used to look like?
A little bit better?
I look completely different.
Yeah. OK, fine,
if that's how you perceive me.
Of course I've not disappeared.
I'm still the same person.
Of course you are.
Obviously I've moved on in life.
I've transcended and you know...
Are you embarrassed?
You'd stick up for me?
That doesn't happen.
I hugged him today
so that's a breakthrough.
He gave me a kiss on the cheek.
Dean, Amber,
having the operation
wouldn't make
any difference to me whatsoever.
To me, she's a girl. Obviously
she's changed that way.
But to me,
it's still my flesh and blood
and that's all there is to it.
So it makes no difference,
the operation, whatsoever.
It's immaterial.
It takes time but gets easier
and easier, you know.
That's how it should go.
Erm... I bought a boat.
It was a kneejerk reaction
to me thinking they were gonna
blow the Olympics up.
-  Who's they?
- The Archons.
Shape-shifting evil wrongdoers
that are trying
to enslave the human race.
They didn't blow the Olympics up
which was very nice
and pleasing.
But, you know,
I don't know any more.
I'm just sounding more and more
mad as time goes by.
But I don't really mind.
I stopped taking my hormones
even though they were making me
very happy.
I didn't feel happy
being content,
which sounds really stupid
but the reason that everybody's
sad at the moment
is because half the planet
are starving.
And me glossing over that
with medication
doesn't really seem to be
the answer to my problems.
If I'm screaming from
the rooftops to feed everybody,
then maybe that's more helpful
than me grinning away inanely
being happy with tits.
Do you miss tits
and things like that?
Greatly. I miss running around
without my clothes on
and dancing a lot.
I really miss dancing.
I miss that terribly.
You can still do that.
I don't feel like I can
any more.
-  Why's that?
- Because I'm too sad.
Erm... Give us a minute.
Is that because
of the state of the world?
Because of the state of me.
Erm...
What I desperately want
is for everything
to be like it was
five years ago.
Because I was a lot happier.
It was great fun.
You know?
I need to make more of an effort
with my life.
I can't talk about anybody
in their life and what they do.
I'm no fucking angel.
I'm...
..lost.
It's only now in hindsight
having made the decision
to stop drinking,
that I can now look back
and see that the behaviour
after a massive hospitalisation
that risked my life
and tore my family to pieces
and kind of shocked
all my friends
was the behaviour of someone
who was desperately in need
of help for their drinking.
For me now the party's over.
Do I choose the booze
and the drugs and death?
And I'm not exaggerating.
Do I choose that
or do I choose a career?
Do I choose friends,
do I choose relationships
and do I choose
a really great future?
You've done the Winter Olympics.
The sledge.
Then you've got to go off.
You've got to get changed
quickly.
We have sold 1,200 tickets.
They've opened parts
of the theatre
that normally would not be open
for any other kind of event.
They've only opened them
because we told them
we have to make
some bloody money.
We're not making
a fucking penny.
I don't know
how these shows work.
- OK, that's it.
- Whoo!
Arms outstretched.
Keep straight.
And then turn on the spot.
I've got a feeling
this is probably it.
It can't get bigger than this,
can it?
I feel stronger.
I feel much more capable
of delivering the show
that's coming up.
I haven't seen a lot
of the other queens
for a very long time.
I think it's sad, yeah.
I think it's sad.
So Mike Leigh's popping down
at some point to see the show.
I've become a broadcaster.
BBC Radio 4, nonetheless.
I think the scene is a little
fucked up at the moment.
Everyone has got
this weird feeling
that there's one golden ticket.
And like only one drag queen
can make it.
But with that it kind of breeds
this weird competitive vileness
where everyone's fighting
for the same limelight.
Yeah, my ideals are now all
based around happiness.
Just want to be happy.
It's completely sold out.
It's a huge moment.
Moment in gay culture
in east London.
Jackie, I'm your biggest fan.
I'm here to interview
the poor people
who they cannot come in
because they didn't have money
to buy a ticket before.
This is the Hackney Empire!
How are we doing tonight?
Are we there?
Yeah!
They're not gonna stop.
They're gonna be like Cher.
They'll keep going.
And they ain't done yet.
Good luck, everybody!
This is the final night of Gay
Bingo. Ten years of Gay Bingo.
We are in the principal
cast members' dressing room.
John Sizzle. Ma Butcher.
The lovely Holestar.
I hear Chris Stein's
gonna turn up apparently.
It's a scary gig tonight.
It's nerve-racking, isn't it?
Gay Bingo, yeah.
Everyone's on this gig.
And the audience like that,
don't they?
They perceive us as individuals
that, together,
make a bigger whole.
How are we doing, east London?
♪ Love will always be the end
♪ I feel this, I feel this
♪
This is the Hackney Empire!
I'm really enjoying it.
I can see my mum and my sister.
My mum's looking a bit bemused.
I think she's upset that we're
not playing proper bingo.
London was ready
for someone to go,
this is what I'm going to do.
I'm going to put myself
right out there at the front
and say, come on, everyone,
look at me.
OK, let's play bingo.
Let's go.
I've no idea where Amber is.
Wouldn't like to comment
where Amber could be.
She's been louche,
she's gone shopping with Pia.
She's gone to see a friend.
Oh, a special friend. Right.
- Amber's here? No!
- How are you?
Didn't Mr Surgeon do well
for Auntie Amber? I think so.
♪ Love will always be the end
It's not about giving it up.
I can't just stop.
I need the money.
Who leaves their job and goes,
"I am going to be this"?
I know who.
Fucking Middleton bitch.
Is Pia not coming tonight?
Unfortunately Pia's
a bit of a mess these days,
God bless her.
Last time I saw Pia she didn't
look the best she's looked.
But that's her life,
she can do what she wants.
I try to... No, I'm not saying
more on that. It's not fair.
There's nothing you can do about
it. The show must go on.
Pia!
Oh! Wahey!
Community, it's a bit
of a dry word, isn't it?
Mates.
I prefer just saying mates.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the gorgeous Pia!
Still got three legs, honey.
Still got three legs
but not for long.
I know the journey
of how I got to where I am.
I know the route.
It's just I wear
kind of slightly less clothing
and higher heels than I thought
I would have done.
Ten years in the East End!
One more song! One more song!
One more song!
If we mortals have offended
Say but this and all is mended
That you have but slumbered here
Whilst we drag queens did appear
♪ I can't get the glitter
out of the groove
♪ No matter how hard I try
♪ There'll still be a sparkle
where the sun don't shine
♪ And I can't get the glitter
out of the groove
♪ A leather case full of secrets
♪ I leave no trace behind
♪ But there are some things
that won't go
To all those
gender dysfunctional children
around the world...
- Gay, lesbian...
- Dress as a girl!
♪ I can't get
the glitter out of the groove
♪ No matter how hard I try
♪ There'll still be a sparkle
where the sun don't shine
♪ And I can't get the glitter
out of the groove
♪ I can't get the glitter
♪ No matter how hard I try
♪ There'll still be a sparkle
where the sun don't shine
♪ And I can't get the glitter
out of the groove
♪ I can't get the glitter
♪ Oh no, I can't get the glitter
out of the groove
♪ No matter how hard I try
♪ There'll still be a sparkle
where the sun don't shine
♪ And I can't get the glitter
out of the groove
♪ I can't get the glitter
♪ Oh no, I can't get the glitter
out of the groove
♪ No matter how hard I try
♪ There'll still be a sparkle
where the sun don't shine
♪ And I can't get the glitter
out of the groove
♪ I can't get the glitter
♪ No matter how hard I try
♪ There'll still be a sparkle
where the sun don't shine
♪ And I can't get the glitter
out of the groove
♪ Can't seem to find
those honey coloured floorboards
♪ Any more
♪ A leather chair
says take me, please
♪ By the door
♪ Pictures of friends in boxes
♪ All of those books
that I'll never read
♪ And a nail on the wall
where I used to hang a dress
♪ That you gave to me
♪ Lying in the bed
that my old poppa made for me
♪ Gotta go
♪ A poster
screwed up in the trash
♪ From a show
♪ All of the films
that I'll never see
♪ A newspaper article
said I was good
♪ And if I could talk
to my shoes
♪ About the nights together
♪ If I could talk to my shoes
♪ Words in lipstick
smeared on the mirror
♪ What they say they say
♪ Don't think I'll shed a tear
♪ If you go away
♪ Fingerprints by the windowpane
♪ Why are they there?
♪ The dream of yesterday blowing
♪ As if I really care
♪ A leather case full of secrets
♪ I'll leave no trace behind
♪ But there are some things...