- How did I not see that?
- Hey, I'm not here to protect your drink.
While you were gone,
this guy drank it.
- Gimme another.
- I'm sorry, mister,
I thought it was free drink.
- Nothing's free anymore.
- I will pay.
I have no money.
- Forget it.
- But I would like to buy you drink.
- I'll buy you one.
What are you having?
- Tequila.
- Can we get a shot of Titanium, please?
- Thank you, mister, uh-
- Monroe.
Would you like to see my friends?
- No time, gotta meet someone.
- I will make fast.
- How long you had those guys?
- This one is not guy.
This one is girl.
His girl.
Usually, Putin waits
until Gorbachev is eating.
And then when his back is turned,
he has his way with Ana.
Maybe you can see when you have more time.
Would you like to kiss Ana?
- No thanks.
- Make sure you take your
friends with you when you leave.
- Da, Yelena.
I like you, Mr. Monroe.
One more before you go.
- Think I need to take a leak.
Think I'll take it outside.
Thought that you said bye to me.
- Next train arriving at Midtown Station
in four minutes.
- [C.O.N.T.A.G.] 4-1-1-2, standby.
Good evening, Harry.
You have six priority messages
from Chief Inspector Carter.
- Call Carter.
- Harrison?
- Yeah.
- Where have you been?
- Off the grid.
Call it a vacation.
- Next time you go on vacation,
do me a favor and let me know.
- Not my job to anymore.
Besides-
- Monroe was hit.
- How bad?
Carter?
- He didn't make it.
Taft wants to meet.
- When?
- I'll forward you the location and time.
- Monroe's data scan,
came back with traces of Dropa DNA.
- So what brought it out?
- Oh what the hell
are you asking me for?
I mean, survival instincts, I guess.
They're damn flesh pods, Harry.
Who the hell knows why
they do what they do?
- You got a tracker on this Dropa?
- Not yet.
- So what do you need from me?
- Well...
Monroe had this on him.
It's a cell number, untraceable.
So, I want you to go back to the Dry Dock.
Bartender may know something.
Poke around, ask some questions, dig.
It's what you're good at.
That's your gift.
- So...
I'm your tracker?
I'm not even sure I
have that gift anymore.
- If that thing can find Monroe,
it can sure as hell find any one of us.
And you better pray it's working alone,
otherwise we are all
in for a world of hurt.
Now, there is one more thing.
I want you to go see Dr. Glenka
at the Leeland Institute.
- A psych test?
- Yeah.
Well, I gotta know if
my dog can still hunt.
You're no good to me otherwise.
- Let us move past the war.
We are going to need to
start the sequence again
if you don't focus.
Please, concentrate.
- Give me a second.
- Your childhood again?
- Yeah.
- Was this a good day?
- It was a day.
- How are you feeling in that moment?
- Safe, maybe.
Protected.
- Come on, stay with the machine.
You were born into a military family, no?
- You already know this.
- Why are you going back to her?
Focus.
- I'm tired of this.
- We are almost done.
- We're done.
Well?
- Solid nerves.
- No rust?
- Not exactly.
Your motivation rate is lower
than in your previous tests.
- Well,
it has been eight years
since my last test.
So what does that mean?
- Your mind kept wandering
and that bothers me.
- Uh-huh.
- Considering the nature of your visit,
it could be....
- What?
- Unhealthy.
Today is your birthday.
You haven't put in to leave?
- Nope.
- You're going to be over the age limit.
- Look, I could make an
infinite list of complaints
about living in this city,
on this planet too,
but I'd still much rather
be here than up there.
- Are you so sure about that?
- Why didn't you go?
- My husband was too weak for the trip.
He's a virus survivor.
- But if you could?
- The Moon Colony, no.
My job is down here.
Mr. Harrison,
when this is done,
whatever it is,
my advice is for you to leave the city.
- I need employment profile verification
for bartenders at the Dry Dock Bar.
Employer ID registration,
1-9-8-6-4-3-bravo.
- [C.O.N.T.A.G.] One owner, ten employees.
Three are bartenders,
no illegals reported.
- How many female bartenders?
- [C.O.N.T.A.G.] Two.
- Process.
- [C.O.N.T.A.G.] Based on
the crime scene report,
we are looking for Helen Adamov,
age 28, Soviet immigrant.
Address, 1-3-0-7 Baton Street.
Employed nine months and four days.
- I need her education
and employment history,
her cell records for the last 48 hours,
and RFID log.
Well?
- [C.O.N.T.A.G.] Interesting.
- What?
- [C.O.N.T.A.G.] Classified
clearance level A12 required.
No additional data available.
Attempting to access.
- Hold up, bro.
Yeah, you're good.
- I'm looking for the bartender
who worked last night.
- Yelena?
- Helen Adamov.
- What?
- Helen, Yelena.
- Where is she?
- Is she in some kind of trouble?
In dressing room four.
- I'd like to have a word with you.
- That's more than a word, genius.
- I'm looking for someone.
He knows a friend of mine.
- Go on.
- He was here last night.
Big Russian guy.
- Hmm, I know a lot of big Russian guys.
- Well, how many were here last night?
- None that I remember.
I think it's time for you to go.
Unless you can think of
another reason to stick around.
Hmm, pretty.
Goodbye, mister-
- Harrison.
Your name's Helen Adamov.
Born to Russian immigrant
parents Yuri and Kira Kosov.
Both killed in a train
wreck outside Boston.
Your father's sister,
Dasha Adamov, raised you.
She was assistant
to the Minister of
Socialist American Affairs.
At age fifteen,
you were enrolled in the
Military Intelligence Academy,
and excelled academically.
Eight years later,
you were part of the Moon
Colony's Project Horizon Two.
Then, nine months ago,
you became a bartender in
a dive in the East Sector.
Should I keep going?
- If you know me the way you claim,
then you know it's best to leave me alone.
- October 7th, you left
the city for two weeks,
just disappeared.
There's no record of your transport pass
or RFID being scanned anywhere.
How is that possible?
You know what happened here last night,
so one more time,
where is this man?
I need to find him.
- Who are you?
- I'm the guy that's gonna
find the Dropa flesh bag
that killed my friend.
- The Dropas are dead,
just like your friend.
- It's a simple question.
- Things aren't always what they seem.
- I need to find him.
- Who are you?
- I'm the guy that's
gonna find the Dropa flesh bag
that killed my friend.
- The Dropas are dead,
just like your friend.
- It's a simple question.
- Things aren't always what they seem.
Did your research happen to mention
that I've had four years
of combat training?
- Eleven years of real combat.
I've killed for a lot less reason.
- This is bigger than us, Mr. Harrison.
Your friend was a part of The Legion.
And my guess is, you were too.
Murders stack up down here
and no one investigates,
unless it was someone that mattered.
How could any of you expect to
walk away from what you did?
- Their cocoons carried the virus spores
that nearly wiped us out.
The only thing that stopped them,
was The Legion.
- Mr. Harrison,
do you know what it's
like to lose everything,
your home, the people you love?
- I don't care about your moral cause.
Where is it?
- I don't know.
- This is not a negotiation.
If you can't help me,
I have other options.
You don't.
- He has a room at the Grand
Hotel in the Lower Quarter.
- I know the place.
- Room 832, name's Mikhail.
No last name, just Mikhail.
- Why did you go there?
- He asked me to contact Mr.
Monroe to leave him a message.
- What message?
- A note with a number.
I left it at his apartment.
- What did the note say?
- There's a traitor in The Legion.
- A traitor?
More!
- That's it I swear.
My father fought for the Dropa's
rights when they came here.
Then The Party killed him for it.
My mother too.
He would tell me that
people were so afraid
that the world was going to end
that they were actually
hoping that it would.
You know, it's easier to
give up, to live in fear.
That's what those in
control want you to feel,
powerless, insignificant.
But the Dropas came here
and they made us realize
that there's more out
there in the universe.
They gave us hope.
What do you believe in?
- If the hotel doesn't
check out I'm coming back.
And trust me, you don't
want me to come back.
- You won't be back.
Mikhail just may find you
first if he hasn't already.
- That would make my job easier.
- Was it easy before?
- [C.O.N.T.A.G.] Welcome home, Harry.
Daily status, one missed VidFon call,
eleven unread email transmissions.
Fusion energy bill, 19 days past due.
- Enough already, C.O.N.T.A.G.
Can I just have a few minutes?
Alone?
- [C.O.N.T.A.G.] Harry, I
have something else to say.
- What?
- Happy Birthday.
- Happy Birthday, baby.
- Make a wish.
- I make it every day.
- Sometime between 10 and 12.
- DNA sweep?
- Clean.
- Clean?
- Nothing, only established samples.
We're scanning the staff and patrons again
to make sure we didn't overlook anything.
- This is professional.
- Does this remind you of something?
- Inspector Carter.
- You wanna tell me what
happened last night?
The woman you questioned
last night is dead.
Her eye sockets were crushed in.
I've seen a few Dropas you
finished off look the same way.
- She was breathing when I left.
- Can you explain this?
Well?
- She must have removed it
when I was questioning her.
- And?
- She was trying to
manipulate the situation.
She was very, persuasive.
- I've got eyewitnesses
that put you at the Dry Dock
at the same time as the murder.
- What are you implying?
- Implying?
Nothing, except that I
just covered your ass.
Taft can't end up with a trail of bodies,
leading back to this Dropa.
- Yeah, that wouldn't
look good, now would it?
- We're on our own out here.
It's about survival now, ours!
We let these Dropas walk away.
Now they're back to finish us.
- Can you blame 'em?
- I've done some pretty
bad things, Harrison,
things that I can't take back.
- You did them to protect the cause,
like all of us.
- That's The Party's line.
We did it because we had no other choice.
You do what you're ordered to do
and don't ask questions.
- You chose the lesser of two evils.
Just learn to live with it.
I did.
- You're no saint in all of this.
- I know.
- [C.O.N.T.A.G.] Warning,
two rounds of plasma ammunition loaded.
Restricted use due to potential
thermal burns to civilians.
- Coming, I'm coming.
What do you want?
- Come on, Jin, play nice.
- I'll play nice up your fucking asshole!
You wrecked my place pretty bad last time.
- It was a long time ago.
- Come on, get out!
What gives you the right to barge in huh?
Just like that?
Geez.
You have no respect for
other people's property!
- You're my eyes down here, Jin.
You always have been.
The Legion needs your help.
- The Legion no more.
Those days are gone.
Uh, I don't owe Legion
for nothing, no more.
- Well, consider it a favor then.
- No, your kind of favor,
bad news, bad news.
- I'm looking for the tenant in room 832.
- Don't know nothing.
What number?
- 832.
- Hm, nobody lives there.
- Catch your breath.
I just need a minute of your time.
- No, no minute for you.
- Make time.
- Ah, now I remember.
A big man, a big man, name Mikhail.
What do you want with him?
- It's personal.
Gimme the key.
- Personal?
Everything's personal with you,
means big trouble.
- The key, Jin!
- Are you gonna bust
up my place again, huh?
Listen, he's a good tenant, model tenant.
Always pays the rent.
- Your model tenant is a Dropa.
- What?
- And I'm taking him out of
here with or without the key.
You understand?
- I believe you have something
that does not belong to you.
- Come and get it.
- You know a little known fact,
can become a well known fact.
And part of our job, Harry,
is to make sure that don't happen.
Now, how in the hell are we gonna do that
if you start trying to blow away Dropas
in front of a damn audience
in the Lower Quarter?
Well?
- Got something for ya.
Found that in the Russian's
room at the Grand Hotel.
- Now, why in the hell are you showing me
half a damn cockroach?
This is cybernetic.
That's pretty advanced
technology for a Dropa.
Kinda like them bug bots we
used to use back in the day.
- Yeah, I thought it might
be a surveillance tool
or a weapon but it's not.
Took me a moment to figure it out.
- Figure what out?
- It's a decoy, an elaborate decoy,
but decoy nonetheless.
- I'm not following this.
- The Dropas have a
different magnetic makeup
than anything else on this planet.
The magnetic field around them,
throws the compass cells in roaches crazy.
- All right, all right,
professor, please, plain English.
- They spin around, get lost.
350 million years of
navigating gone haywire.
Monroe knew this.
He tracked with bugs.
- Okay, so why cybernetic?
- Somehow this Dropa figured this out.
He knew Monroe's methods.
He found a way to throw
him off long enough
to let his guard down.
- So, this Dropa is hunting us?
- Monroe anyway.
And maybe all of us.
There's one other thing.
The Adamov girl,
said something odd to me last night.
She said the Russian had
a message for Monroe.
- Yeah?
- Said there was a
traitor among The Legion.
Any idea what it's talking about?
- Look, why don't you go home,
get some rest,
take some aspirin.
Hell, take a whole lotta aspirin.
This Dropa knows we're onto it.
- [Madison] Give up that easily?
You've become soft in your retirement.
- What are you doing here?
It's been five years, Madison.
- I came back because someone
killed a member of our team.
Judging by the looks
of you, I'm glad I did.
What happened?
- Retribution.
- You look terrible.
- I thought you might have left.
- Someone's gotta keep an eye on you.
- I'm fine.
- What's the next move?
- Heading out to the
country in the morning.
- What's out there?
- Hopefully answers.
Wanna come along?
You could stay the night.
No strings.
- There never were with you.
- So tell me what you've been
up to the last five years.
- I'm gonna go.
- Look, I...
I just wanna talk.
I could really use that right now.
- You better dry off first.
- Eva?
I wonder where she could be?
Oh, I must have spent too
long at the shipyards.
My beautiful little
girl must have grown up
and moved away.
What am I going to do?
If only she had come to say goodbye.
I miss her so much.
Oh!
You are hiding the whole time.
I knew it.
- So, what happened?
- Well,
after The Party disbanded The Legion,
what else was there?
You know we were nothing more
than an embarrassing secret
that just needed to go away.
Taft, Carter, Monroe stayed.
I was out, moving on and you were a wreck.
Guess if I was living in
your skin at the same time
I'd be the same way.
Arthur took off to the colony.
It was his time and he wanted
to leave everything behind.
- So what happened to Jackson out there?
- I guess she just
couldn't handle it anymore.
I don't know.
She was on cleanup with me.
It was either us or them
with the Dropa Resistance.
We understood that but the families,
that was different.
A few months later,
Monroe brought in Jackson
to head up the final sweep
of the containment camps.
The Party wanted it finished,
fast and clean.
They poisoned the Dropa water
supply with a DDT derivative.
It only killed the children.
Two months later, I...
I found her dead in a
motel room outside of Waco,
gun still in her mouth.
- Jackson may have been the only one of us
with a conscience.
- Yeah.
And look where that got her.
Still not over her?
Out of all of us,
you had the most reason to
hate 'em after what she did.
- That's enough.
- She betrayed you.
- I said that's enough.
Kate's in the past.
- Do you really wanna
know what I've been doing
for the past five years?
Trying to find reasons to stay away.
I never lost faith in you, Harry.
- Faith is for the weak.
- Thank you, mister-
- Monroe.
- Come back to me.
- Over seven million
hits on the CityCam network.
I thought you said it was cleared.
- We cut the feed as quick as we could.
I told you not to get Harrison involved.
He's dangerous.
- There's no one better for this job.
- Maybe, but he changed
since the accident.
I'm not sure where his
loyalties lie anymore.
- Listen, Harry moves fast.
He'll find this Dropa.
- He's unpredictable.
- You're not alone.
Death is not the end.
Death is just another road,
the road in life.
And your soul is the guide.
This is not over, Monroe.
- Arthur?
- Want some?
- What made you come back?
- It's quieter here, less
distractions, you know.
- I don't know about that, Arthur.
You wanted outta here pretty bad
after your time in The Legion.
- That's what I thought, too.
But it's worse up there.
You know they're considering
complete isolationism.
No, the Colony's no place
for someone like me.
- Seems kinda isolated here.
- It's simpler.
- Yeah, I can see that.
- So, I take it this isn't a social visit.
- No.
- Good.
Let's keep it that way.
Business then?
- Dropa hunt.
- [Arthur] Who dragged you into this?
- Taft.
- You just can't say no to that sumbitch.
- It could've been any of us in that bar,
couple of nights ago.
- But it wasn't.
- Yeah, maybe so,
but that doesn't change things.
- Your loyalty's gonna
put you in a body bag.
- This Dropa is not like the others.
They're usually runners not killers.
- We knew this was gonna come back on us.
We should've finished 'em
off when we had the chance.
- There were other
options for dealing with them
but The Party chose the easiest way out.
- There's a lot you still don't know.
- Maybe it's time you told me.
- Let's go out back.
- Why did it come after you?
We really did it, didn't we Monroe?
We took it all back from
those greedy bastards.
Everybody thought we were heroes then.
- Back in 2004,
we found a stone disc
washed ashore near Rockport
along with several cocoons.
The discs told the story of
the Dropas in hieroglyphics.
And then there was this one.
You see any pattern in all that?
- Not really.
- There are recognizable forms.
- Recognizable?
- Symbolic.
Very stylized.
This first one, the oval, is a cocoon.
And this?
- I suppose it's...
First phase Dropa metamorphosis?
- Yes.
And next a human form.
And then this.
- What's that?
- It's what your hunting.
- Who else knew?
- Other than the need-to-know
personnel in The Party,
only Taft, Carter, and me.
I suspect Monroe would've
found out sometime later.
It was tight-lipped.
You have no idea
how much worldwide hysteria
it would've caused.
Even more than the virus.
- What do you mean even
more than the virus?
- It was all a cover, Harry.
The virus was spread
through the atmosphere
in small, controlled amounts,
in geographically specific locations.
The same pattern as the Dropa migration.
The virus was nothing more
than a mutated strain of
a viral hemorrhagic fever.
There was nothing alien about it.
We manufactured the bug to
create just enough fear to-
- Just enough fear?
I knew people who died from that virus.
- We all did.
Calculated risk, unfortunately.
If one of those things got out-
- It would've killed over 20
million people like the virus?
That's controllable, measurable?
Who decides who lives and who dies?
- The Dropas were a potential threat.
We just had to disguise the reason why
and use it to create unity,
unity in The Party.
- We committed genocide.
- No.
Genocide is for humans.
I preferred...
Extinction.
It was them or us.
Now, I don't know about you,
but I prefer to be on the
us side of the equation.
- I was referring to humans.
- We're just pawns.
It's always been that way.
You've been around long
enough to know that.
- It's time things changed.
- It's not so easy when
the prey fights back,
is it, old man?
- How's that for easy?
- What are you doing?
- Why did you come back?
Or maybe you didn't.
- Wakey, wakey.
- Oh, no.
- Oh, yes.
- Well, this is embarrassing.
- Where's Arthur?
- It's still me, Harry.
It's just a synth body, an android.
We're bio-linked.
I wasn't safe down there.
I'm better off in the Colony,
least for the time being.
I hope you understand.
- I don't know what to believe.
- You still don't realize what
we were dealing with here.
The longer it's out there,
the less chance you'll be able to stop it.
- How am I supposed to kill something
that constantly evolves?
- Taft picked you for a reason.
You understand the Dropas.
- If that's an off-handed
reference to Kate
then leave her out of this.
- Oh, I didn't mean it like that.
No one blames you.
She fooled all of us.
I've never seen a Dropa
with such complete
human genetic synthesis.
Kate was unique.
She had a great ass too.
- Don't mention her again.
- A little levity is needed
here, don't you think?
Helps us keep a level head.
Besides, this thing is
much bigger than you or me.
- The girl I questioned about Monroe,
said the exact same thing.
- Sure she did.
- What are you telling me?
- Yelena Adamov.
The Party had me work an
angle on her for six months.
She didn't know what her
real role was anyway.
She just kept on fighting the good fight.
- She was a part of all this?
- Wakey, wakey.
- And you set up Monroe!
- A miscalculation.
- Miscalculation?
- The Dropa was the target.
Just didn't go as planned.
Didn't know what we were dealing
with until it was too late.
Shame too.
I always liked Monroe.
- Yeah, I can tell you're
all broken up about it.
- More than you know.
It took us six months
to set this thing up.
You have no idea how to
make things so covert.
We had to keep quiet.
Even Taft was kept in the
dark about most of it.
- And you played both of us.
- I had no intention of bringing you in.
That was Taft.
- And Yelena?
- I had to uh...
Quiet her.
- If the Dropas presented
this much of a threat,
why didn't we just finish them off?
- If it were up to me,
I would've finished what we started.
But, the females didn't pose a threat.
It was the two bull males.
We needed their genetic codes.
Stepwise Evolution.
That's what the scientists
back East called it.
- Stepwise Evolution?
- Well, something
about adding additional Dropa amino acids
to the human genetic code.
- Jesus.
- Dropas have incredible
regenerative qualities.
- Where is the other male?
- Tagged.
He's dormant.
- Dormant?
Was this one dormant?
- Yes.
Until he figured out how
to remove his tracer.
But the other male is not a threat.
- Yet.
- Harry.
What do you remember after the accident?
What about all those months you spent
at the clinic with Kate?
- Leave Kate out of this.
What's that?
- It's what you're hunting.
- I wish Mommy was still with us.
- Oh, my solnyshko.
We will be fine.
And I will never let
anything happen to you.
- Where have you been?
- Working a lead.
- Taft's dead.
This thing knows how to find us.
The coroner's report from Monroe's attack
found small traces of liquid dysprosium.
- Dysprosium?
- It's an element that was
used in fusion reactors,
prior to balthorium.
Outdated now and rarely used.
The data scan found one regional
location where it's stored.
It's a warehouse in the ship channel.
I'm gonna check it out.
- I'll go with you.
- I'm on it.
- Just wait until I get there.
- No time for that.
- You don't know what you're dealing with.
This could get ugly real fast.
- I know what I'm dealing with, Harrison.
The question is, do you?
- Oh.
- You okay?
- What's wrong?
- Taft's dead.
I was worried.
C.O.N.T.A.G. tried to locate you on RFID.
- I know how to handle myself.
I removed the sensor years ago Harry.
- It's not safe here.
You need to get outta the city.
I have to find Carter.
She has a lead on this Dropa.
- I'm gonna go with you.
- Not this time.
Things are different.
- No!
You don't need to do this.
Okay, just walk away.
Let Carter deal with it.
- Taft brought me into this for a reason.
- You have no loyalty to him.
- He's the reason I'm still breathing.
- You're alive because you didn't give up.
- Not giving up didn't save me.
Between Taft and Kate,
I owe them.
- You owe them nothing.
You gave everything to The Legion
and Taft repaid you by what,
putting you back out there?
And Kate?
Really?
You need to understand who
really cares about you.
Open your eyes.
What are you so afraid of?
- Nothing.
- [C.O.N.T.A.G.] Harry, she's gone.
- C.O.N.T.A.G.,
give me a report on warehouses
in the ship channel,
reference dysprosium.
- [C.O.N.T.A.G.] One warehouse
matching export records
for dysprosium.
Location in Fallout Zone 12.
Potential for rad absorption levels,
200 to 300 units.
- What kind of man are you?
- The killing kind.
- Come back to me.
- What scares you?
Perhaps, not knowing who you are.
- You don't know me.
- You were trained for war.
Mankind's gift to the universe.
And you're fighting for what?
Nothing.
But you,
you might be different now.
- Different?
- Yes.
I am different.
Would you like to see?
Now, do you see?
The Legion has taken everything from me.
And now all that is left is this hate.
Just like a human.
- You're not human.
- No.
I am so much more.
Have you ever lost someone?
Then you know what it's like.
- What? Pain?
- No.
Pain is easy to control,
to hide.
Revenge, that is not so easy.
You are here to kill me
to avenge their deaths.
But part of you does not want to do it.
Why?
Perhaps it is because I am more like you
and you are more like...
That's it, little man.
Become that which you hunt.
- That's it.
Keep coming.
Come on.
- You cannot run away from who you are.
- Who's running?
- Told you someone's
gonna keep an eye on you.
- What do you remember after the accident?
What about all those months you spent
at the clinic with Kate?
- When this is done,
whatever it is,
my advice is for you to leave the city.
- There's a traitor in The Legion.
- What scares you?
Perhaps, not knowing who you are.
- Open your eyes.