"Near Bistritz,
"the road turns towards
the heart of the Carpathians,
"one of the most barren
and least known places in Europe."
Allow me.
Thank you very much.
What was that, Sara?
"...one of the most barren
and least known places in Europe."
Keep reading.
"Crumbling castles are
scattered among the rugged summits.
"They belong to a remote era..."
Coachman, you should go a little slower!
No! No! We must get to the inn
before nightfall.
Why?
Today is Walpurgisnacht, a night of evil.
Nosferatu...
The dead come out from their tombs
and suck the blood of the living.
(SCREAMS)
Nonsense!
You would not laugh if you lived here.
Tonight, all doors will be locked
and we shall pray to the Virgin.
(PRAYING)
MAN: How was the trip?
WOMAN: Very good, thank you.
MAN: I'm glad to hear it.
Lad, don't take my luggage down.
I must continue on to Borgo Pass.
(CONFERRING QUIETLY)
I must warn you
that today is St. Walpurga's day,
which is considered
a bad omen around here.
And the coachman, who is a good man,
wishes to know whether you wouldn't mind
continuing the journey after sunrise.
I'm very sorry, but at midnight,
a carriage will be waiting
for me at the Borgo Pass.
Whose carriage?
Count Dracula's.
From Dracula's castle?
Right. That is my destination.
WOMAN: Look, he wants to travel
on to Borgo Pass tonight.
I beg you to stay the night here.
But all of this is mere superstition.
I mean, in a mountainous area like this one,
I don't understand how...
Anyway, what I mean to say
is that I'm not afraid.
I told him already, this is a business affair.
I must go there, really.
Wait.
Since you mean to leave, put this on.
Put it on, for God's sake.
It will protect you.
Thanks.
You are very welcome.
Good night.
Good night, and I wish you a good journey.
Good night and good luck.
DRIVER: Giddy-up! Giddy-up!
Tell me,
do you really believe there are vampires
who come out of their tombs
and roam about looking for blood?
I have seen the victims!
Nonsense!
Come, Sara.
Count Dracula's carriage?
(COACH DOOR CREAKS)
(WOLF HOWLS
(CREAKING AND GROANING)
(DOOR CREAKS CLOSED)
(BAT CHIRPS)
I am Dracula.
You couldn't have appeared at a better time.
I have no idea what
happened to the coachman and my luggage.
With all that, I thought
I had come to the wrong place.
The walls of my castle are cracked
and there are shadows everywhere.
But come in. Make yourself at home.
(WOLF HOWLS)
(WOLVES HOWLING)
Listen to them.
They are the children of the night.
What beautiful music they make!
(HOWLING CONTINUES)
DRACULA: The eternal struggle for survival.
Every living creature
needs blood to keep on living.
The spider weaves its web
to catch the unwary fly.
Blood is life, Mr. Renfield.
(DOOR CREAKS OPEN)
(DOOR CREAKS CLOSED)
I think you will
find this part of the castle more appealing.
I certainly do.
I thought you might be hungry.
You are very kind, Count Dracula.
Sit down.
Thanks.
I trust no one knows of your visit.
Absolutely no one,
just as you recommended.
I assume you burned all our correspondence.
I followed all your instructions to the letter.
Excellent, Mr. Renfield. Excellent.
It was nothing. Just a scratch.
Won't you have some?
I never drink
wine.
And now, if you're feeling refreshed...
I would like to talk about
the lease of Carfax Abbey.
But all the documents are in my briefcase.
I took the liberty
of sending for your luggage.
Everything is in order.
You just need to sign it.
I hope there are
enough tags here for all your bags.
I am only taking three boxes.
We shall leave tomorrow night.
Everything will be ready.
DRACULA: I hope you find it comfortable.
RENFIELD: Thanks.
It looks appealing.
Now I shall leave you alone.
DRACULA: I may be occupied
during the day tomorrow.
In that case, we shall meet here at dusk.
(DOOR CREAKS OPEN)
Good night, Mr. Renfield.
(DOOR CREAKS CLOSED)
(GASPING FOR AIR)
(HOWLING WIND)
(THUNDER)
(MANIACAL LAUGHTER)
(MANIACAL LAUGHTER CONTINUES)
(THUNDER)
(SILENCE)
MAN: Look!
Fingers frozen stiff on the helm.
He must have died of fright.
What a terrible tragedy!
Not even a shred of the sails is left.
It must have been a terrible storm.
MAN 2: What about the sailors?
What became of them?
Master! Master!
We've arrived!
Can't you hear me, Master? Master!
MAN 1: What's that?
MAN 2: It's coming from that hatchway.
(MANIACAL LAUGHTER)
(ORCHESTRA PLAYING)
You will tell Dr. Seward,
who is sitting in the next box,
that there is a phone call for him.
Once you have given him this message,
you will remember nothing.
(ORCHESTRA CONTINUES)
Dr. Seward, there's a phone call for you.
Excuse me.
Pardon me.
Yes?
I happened to overhear your name.
Are you the Dr. Seward
who has a sanatorium in Whitby?
That's right.
I am Count Dracula.
I have just rented Carfax Abbey.
I understand it's next
to the gardens of your sanatorium.
Correct. It lies next to my property.
It's a great pleasure to meet you, Count.
Would you like to join us?
Count, allow me
to introduce my daughter Eva.
Miss Weston.
Mr. Harker.
Count Dracula has just rented Carfax Abbey.
It will be a joy
to see those dark windows lit up again.
Count, I beg you to excuse me.
There's a phone call for me.
In the meantime, please be seated.
My pleasure.
(ORCHESTRA CONTINUES)
A very nice house
could be built out of those Carfax ruins.
Of course, it would take a lot of money.
I shall barely touch them.
They remind me of the crumbling walls
of my own castle in Transylvania.
What they remind me of is that old toast.
"Lofty beams upon deserted walls
"beat with the echo of our laughter
"as if the dead whispered through them."
(CHUCKLES) How nice!
WESTON: Wait.
The next part's even nicer.
"For those who are already dead,
let us empty our glasses
"and let us cheer
for him among us who must die first."
You can keep the rest to yourself, Lucía.
DRACULA: To really die...
To be really dead
must be sublime.
But, Count...
DRACULA: Something worse than death
awaits the living.
(ORCHESTRA CONTINUES)
(LAUGHS)
Laugh all you like.
I find him fascinating.
Lucía the romantic. That explains it.
That part about crumbling walls...
I prefer someone a little more normal.
Like Juan?
Yes, my dear.
Like Juan.
Well, Countess, I'm very tired.
I leave you with your count
and his crumbling abbey.
May you have sweet dreams.
Good night.
- The fog is getting thicker.
- Yes.
(BAT CHIRPING)
(WINGS FLAPPING)
Another death.
When was the last transfusion
performed on Miss Weston?
About four hours before her death.
Identical symptoms in each case.
A baffling loss of blood
that we've been unable to prevent.
Give me the magnifying glass.
And these same two marks were found
on each victim's neck.
Gentlemen,
we're dealing here with vampires.
Vampires?
Nosferatu?
Yes, the vampire of Transylvania.
That's right. Nosferatu the vampire.
The vampire attacks his victim's neck
and leaves two tiny white wounds
with a red dot in the center.
But, Professor Van Helsing,
that theory is implausible.
Medical science nowadays does not accept
the existence of such a creature.
That's just a myth.
A superstition.
Dr. Seward's patient, Renfield,
whose blood I have just analyzed,
is obsessed with the idea
that he must eat other living creatures
in order to sustain his own life.
I am going to England
with Dr. Seward to study Renfield's case.
And perhaps I will prove to you
that the superstition of yesterday
can become the scientific reality of today.
Look.
(MANIACAL LAUGHTER)
(RENFIELD SCREAMING)
No, don't take it away, Martín!
Don't take it away!
You're a good man. Don't!
Aren't you ashamed of yourself?
Now you're interested in spiders. Spiders!
You're no longer happy with flies.
Flies?
Tiny wretched flies!
Who could be happy with them?
You! A raving lunatic!
When nice plump spiders aren't available,
perhaps.
All right, do as you please.
But now come with me.
The professor wants to speak with you again.
Let's go!
It's a very strange case.
Nevertheless, the only thing
Renfield has craved so far
are small bugs.
Not human beings.
That's what we think, Doctor.
But you say that
he slips away from his room.
That he's gone for hours.
Where does he go?
- (KNOCK ON DOOR)
- Come in.
Well, Mr. Renfield.
You look much better now
than when I arrived this morning.
Thank you, Professor. I feel much better.
Martín.
They tell me you studied
at Oxford University.
That's correct.
I graduated from the school of law in 1927.
I was accepted by the bar in 1928.
After that...
Excuse me.
An inferior organism.
Unworthy of my attention.
What would you have done with that fly
had we not been here?
He'd have gobbled it up.
VAN HELSING: Tell me,
Mr. Renfield,
what makes you eat flies?
The wings of flies, sir,
represent the aerial power
of the psychic faculties.
There's more to this fellow
than meets the eye, Doctor.
I've never seen you like this, Eva.
What's wrong?
Are you worried about something?
Have I done something to hurt you?
You haven't done anything, Juan.
Don't worry.
But there is something wrong. Tell me.
I don't know what it could be.
I've been feeling frightened lately.
When night begins to fall,
I get this feeling,
as if something were tightening around me.
Oh, Juan.
Get your filthy hands off me!
Come on, Renfield.
(RENFIELD CRYING)
You must let me out of here!
Why is it so important to you?
Because I scream at night.
I might bother Miss Eva
and even cause her nightmares.
Nightmares?
Yes, Doctor. Yes.
Nightmares.
(WOLF HOWLING)
It sounds like a wolf howling.
Yes, it does.
But I hardly think
there are wolves so near London.
He thinks there are
and I've heard howling at night.
He says they're talking to him
and he screams back at the top of his voice.
He's crazy.
I should have known.
You know very well why the wolves talk.
Isn't that true, Mr. Renfield?
And you also know how to make them stop.
(SCREAMING)
You know too much to go on living!
We won't get another word
out of him for the time being.
You can take him away, Martín.
Get up, flycatcher.
I'm warning you once more, Doctor.
If you don't let me go, you'll be responsible
for whatever happens to your daughter.
What is that herb that made him so upset?
Wolfsbane.
Peasants in Central Europe
use it to drive vampires away.
Renfield reacted as soon as he smelled it.
Yes.
He must be watched closely day and night.
Especially at night.
Yes.
You were saying you had gone to bed.
Yes. I was reading and I fell asleep.
I began to dream. A dog barked.
And it looked
as if the whole room filled up with mist.
It was so thick
that I could hardly see
the light by my bedside.
It looked like a tiny spark lost amidst the fog.
EVA: I saw two red eyes
staring at me
and a livid, white face through the fog.
He came closer and closer.
I could feel his breath on my face.
And his lips...
(GASPS)
But, Eva, it was just a dream.
The next morning,
I felt very weak,
as if all life had been drained out of me.
When did you have this dream, Miss Eva?
The night
that Father left for Switzerland.
In other words,
the night after Lucía was buried.
Let's see. Think for a moment.
Do you remember anything
that might have caused this nightmare?
Nothing.
There's something troubling Eva, Doctor.
Something she doesn't want to tell us.
And the face you saw in your dream,
you say it came closer and closer?
That the lips touched you?
Where?
Eva.
No, Father. Please!
What do you have on your neck?
Please, Father.
How long have you
had those marks on your neck?
Marks?
Since the day after that dream.
MAID: Count Dracula is here.
It's a pleasure to see you again, Doctor.
I was sure you were back.
Miss Seward.
SEWARD: Excuse me, Count Dracula.
This is Professor Van Helsing.
DRACULA: Van Helsing,
the distinguished man of science
whose fame is known
even in the mountains of Transylvania.
VAN HELSING: Doctor,
I beg you to excuse me,
but your daughter
had better go to her room immediately.
Aren't you feeling well?
I hope it's nothing serious.
I had a terrible dream a few nights ago
and I haven't been able
to get it out of my mind.
Could it be you've taken
my stories too seriously?
Stories?
I made a humble effort
to entertain your fiancée
by telling her a few of the legends,
somewhat gloomy ones,
about my distant motherland.
Daughter,
I'm sure Count Dracula will excuse you.
You must go your room
as Professor Van Helsing
has advised you to do.
But, Father, I tell you I'm feeling fine now.
You'd better do as your father says.
Very well, then.
SEWARD: Good night,
my dear daughter.
I must go, Doctor.
Professor Van Helsing,
I hope I shall
have the pleasure of seeing you again.
EVA: Good night.
Good night, Juan.
DRACULA: Mr. Harker.
DRACULA: I shall come by later
to enquire how you're feeling.
Thank you.
Good night, Miss Seward.
EVA: Good night.
I'm very sorry that my visit was so untimely.
SEWARD: Not at all.
VAN HELSING: On the contrary,
it may turn out to be of great importance.
Moreover, before you leave,
you could be helpful to us.
It will be a pleasure to do whatever I can.
Just a moment ago,
I discovered an amazing phenomenon.
Something so incredible
that I do not trust my own eyes
and I'd like you to help me prove it.
Look.
Dr. Seward, please accept my apologies.
I couldn't help it.
Considering that you have not yet lived
even one entire lifetime,
you are a wise man, Professor.
Did you see the expression on his face?
He looked like an enraged beast.
Dracula is our vampire.
Vampire?
For God's sake, Professor!
Vampires cast no reflection in a mirror.
That is why Dracula shattered that mirror.
Look, Professor,
this makes no sense whatsoever.
Dracula is the monster
who killed Lucía Weston.
The same one who left
those marks on Miss Eva's neck.
Him?
Well, please understand
that I mean no offense
but that's more like something
one of the patients here might say.
Yes! And that's exactly
what physicians in this country
and the police will think.
What gives vampires their power
is the fact that people
refuse to believe in them.
But, Professor,
according to your own theory,
the vampire must
return to his grave before dawn.
He must return to his native land,
which is where he was buried.
Now, Count Dracula's
native land is Transylvania.
Then he must have
brought some of his native soil with him.
Perhaps in boxes big enough
to serve as his bed.
(MANIACAL LAUGHTER)
SEWARD: Come on, come on.
Come on.
Renfield, what were you doing out there?
Come on. Come with me.
Renfield, did you hear what we were saying?
Pay attention to what he's telling you.
That is your only salvation.
And the same is true for her.
Save me! Save my soul!
Save me! Save me!
I am weak. You are strong.
I am crazy. You are sane.
I shall save you.
But you must tell us everything you know.
Everything.
(LAUGHS)
Fool! Fool!
And I thought you were a wise man.
What do I stand to gain
by telling you everything?
That physician keeps me
locked up here all day.
And when I behave nicely,
he gives me a bit of sugar
so that I can catch flies.
But if I serve the Master...
An intelligent madman would rather serve
the one who can grant him life.
Him? Who are you talking about?
Why mention names
among friends, Professor?
What ties do you have with Dracula?
Dracula?
I've never even heard that name before.
You're lying!
Crazy people, Professor,
do not have the ability to distinguish
between what is true and false.
For that reason, I take no offense.
I begged you to let me out
but you wouldn't do it.
Now it's too late. It has already happened.
What has happened?
I dare not say it. I dare not.
I would die in torment if I tried.
And you shall die in torment
if you let innocent blood stain your soul.
No!
God will not condemn
the soul of a poor madman.
He knows very well that the power of evil
is too great for those of us with weak minds
to resist.
Then, Renfield, trust me.
Tell me what I want to know.
What do you want to know?
VAN HELSING: The name of the creature
that has deranged your mind.
The one you call "Master."
No!
Don't ask me that!
No! Don't ask me that!
SEWARD: You must tell us!
You must tell us!
Leave me alone! Leave me alone!
VAN HELSING: Renfield,
tell us before it's too late.
Before your soul is damned forever.
I shall tell you.
(SCREAMS)
Master! Master!
I wasn't going to tell them anything!
I haven't told them anything!
I'm faithful to you, Master!
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
MAID: Dr. Seward! Dr. Seward!
Miss Eva... Over there... Dead!
(RENFIELD LAUGHS MANIACALLY)
Thank God, she's still alive.
She's alive, but she's at great risk.
She's under his influence.
That would be terrible.
I can't believe it.
Nevertheless, it's true.
We must put an end to it.
We must confront it.
Is Dr. Seward around?
No. What do you need?
That flycatcher has escaped again
and he could try something foolish.
Dr. Seward and his famous scholar
are in the abbey
chasing vampires.
Vampires. Flycatchers.
Look, Mr. Harker,
if there's a brave man
after my job, he can have it.
I'm going to look for work at another asylum
where the crazy people
are nice and reasonable.
Let them think they're Napoleon or royalty.
Something worthy of my time.
"The mysterious lady in white,
"that merciless scourge of childhood,
"played another of her tricks last night
"a little after nightfall.
"The testimony given by two girls,
"both confirm it's a beautiful lady
dressed in white
"whose modus operandi is to offer
"candy to her victim.
"She then lures the victim
to a deserted corner
"where she delicately bites
the victim's neck."
What would she know
about the lady in white?
Why would she know anything about it?
She shouldn't have read that.
For God's sake, Mr. Harker!
When did you see
Lucía again after she was buried?
Once when I was on the terrace.
She came out of the shadows.
She came towards me.
She stopped and stared at me.
I began to speak to her.
And then
I remembered
that she was dead.
Her face took on a horrible expression
like that of a hungry beast.
Like a wolf.
She turned
and disappeared into the fog again.
So the lady dressed in white was...
Lucía.
Miss, I promise you that from this day on,
Lucía will rest in peace.
Her soul will be forever freed
of that awful appetite.
Since you can save
Lucía's soul after her death,
promise me you'll save mine too.
You're not going to die, my love.
You will go on living.
No, Juan, you mustn't touch me.
And you mustn't kiss me ever again.
What are you saying?
Professor, explain it to him.
Tell him.
I can't.
Eva.
Juan, it's over between us.
Our love, our wedding plans.
Please, Juan, don't look at me like that.
I love you.
I love you more than life itself.
But this terrible thing...
He wants it to be this way
and I must obey.
HARKER: You know what you're doing?
You're driving her crazy.
Mr. Harker, you should be worried
about what's out there.
The last rays of the sun are gone.
Night hovers over us again.
We've put wolfsbane in this room
and in your bedroom
to free you from Dracula,
in case he comes back.
She'll be free of him, all right,
because either she returns with me
to London or I call the police.
VAN HELSING: Seward, my friend,
I must be in charge here
or whatever I do will be useless.
Miss Eva must keep
this branch of wolfsbane in her bed.
Be careful that
she doesn't drop it while she sleeps.
Under no circumstances must those
windows be opened during the night.
I understand, Professor.
Come, my daughter.
(WINGS FLAPPING)
Yes, Master.
You've come back, Master.
Are you angry with me?
No, Master!
Please!
Not her!
Never again!
No, Master!
No! Not her!
No!
No! No!
Please!
No, Master, please!
(RENFIELD HYPERVENTILATING)
Mr. Harker,
though I have devoted my life to
the study of the strangest things,
little known facts that the world
is perhaps better off not knowing,
a world content to busy itself
instead with mundane affairs.
Dracula's name is associated with a legend
still told among his fellow countrymen.
The legend tells of an ancient family
that disappeared over five centuries ago
and was said to be made up of vampires.
Since I discovered, by chance,
that Dracula cast no reflection in the mirror
and that in addition,
that three large boxes
had been sent to Carfax Abbey,
and since I also knew that
a vampire must sleep during the day
in his native earth,
I quickly realized
that Dracula had to be the person
whom Renfield calls "Master."
One of the undead who has been able
to prolong his life beyond its natural limits
by feeding on the blood
of other living creatures.
The only way we can save Eva
is by finding the place
where the living corpse of the vampire rests
and driving a stake through its heart.
What a strange conversation
for men who are not crazy!
Renfield, you will force me
to put you in a straitjacket.
I'm afraid that would be
of no use at this point.
What? What's that, Doctor?
Again?
I'm on my way, sir.
Right away, Doctor.
The doctor's favorite lunatic is at large again.
Well, I'll be!
That madman must be Hercules himself.
- What's he done now?
- Come and see for yourself.
DRACULA: From now on
any mental suggestion you receive from me
must be carried out.
Whenever I want you to do something,
it must be done.
It must be done.
When you come out of this state,
you will remember nothing
of what I am telling you now.
Do you understand?
I understand.
I have already told you what you must do.
Now,
obey.
Renfield, you know where those boxes are.
Tell us and we shall protect you.
But I no longer need your protection.
The Master is not angry with me.
On the contrary, he's pleased.
He came to my window
in the moonlight and promised me things.
Not to say them, but to do them.
- VAN HELSING: Do them?
- Yes!
To make them happen.
A red mist spread over the lawn
and came towards me like a raging fire.
Then the Master parted the mist
and revealed before my eyes
thousands of rats,
their eyes inflamed like his own, but smaller.
He raised his hand and they all stopped.
I felt he was telling me,
"Rats! Rats! Rats!
"Thousands, millions of rats!
"And in each one of them,
"a life full of red blood
"promising many years of life.
"I shall give you all those beings!
"Yes! And many more!
"For countless generations!
"But you must obey."
VAN HELSING: What did he want you to do?
What has already been done.
Dracula is in this house!
Where else did you expect him to be?
He won't be able to cause any harm.
We've placed wolfsbane in every room.
MARTIN: So here you are!
For God's sake!
This man is going to drive me crazy.
He broke through those iron bars
as if they were toothpicks.
Come with me, Martín.
Let me show you somewhere
he'll never escape from.
Let's go.
You may be right,
but I still say what St. Thomas said.
DRACULA: Van Helsing.
Now that you've learned what you've learned,
it would be wise to return to your country.
I intend to stay and protect those
you seek to destroy.
You're too late.
Dracula's blood
is already flowing in Miss Seward's veins.
She will live for all eternity
as I myself have.
Should you escape, Dracula,
we know how to save Miss Eva's soul,
if not her life.
Of course I'm all right.
I've never felt better in my whole life.
Tell me, why are you staring at me like that?
You're so...
I can hardly believe it!
You look like a different woman.
Darling, you look terrific!
And I feel terrific.
But it's stuffy in here.
And that smell.
It's the wreath of flowers
the professor wanted me to...
Marta!
Yes, miss?
Throw away those awful flowers, will you?
And please open the windows
and let some fresh air in.
But, miss, the professor won't approve.
HARKER: Don't worry about him.
It's much nicer out here.
I'm happy to see you like this.
I was really worried about you.
I don't know
what was wrong with me.
It's as if
I'm waking from a nightmare.
Juan, the moonlight is beautiful, isn't it?
Look. Have you ever seen so many stars?
Millions and millions.
And they seem to be so close,
as if you could reach out and touch them.
Would you like me
to offer you a handful of them?
Do not forget, Van Helsing,
that over the years
those who crossed my path
paid for it with their lives
and some in very unpleasant ways.
Come
here!
Stop!
You shall not move your hand
unless I tell you to.
Take out whatever
you have in there and put it in this box.
DRACULA: Hurry up!
DRACULA: Did you obey?
VAN HELSING: Yes.
(SCREAMS)
- Yes, that's what you said.
- No, I didn't, Juan.
What do you mean?
I could have never told you
such a foolish thing.
You made it up.
No, you told me
that the night frightened you.
And what is there
about the night to frighten me?
I love the night.
It's the only time when I feel truly alive.
(WINGS FLAPPING)
Careful, a bat!
It could get tangled in your hair.
Yes, I will.
I will.
You'll what?
Me? I didn't say anything.
I thought you did.
God, that bat was huge.
Juan,
I want you to promise me something.
Whatever you want, my love.
Whatever you ask.
EVA: That strange professor and his herbs...
I can't stand them any longer.
Will you do me a favor
and take them away from him?
And the crucifix. Take it away from him too.
He'll say he wants to protect me again.
From the night, from Count Dracula,
from everything.
I don't know what to believe.
But he might be right.
He told me some terrible things
about that Count Dracula.
(LAUGHS)
What is it? What's wrong with you?
Why?
Your eyes.
They look at me in such a strange way!
HARKER: Oh! Eva!
(EVA SCREAMS)
SEWARD: Eva, my daughter!
HARKER: It's all right, Eva, my love.
The cross. Juan!
After what's happened, I can't look at it.
But... What's happened?
I can't tell you! I can't!
You must tell me. I have a right to know.
Dracula.
He came.
He opened a vein in his arm
and forced me
to drink.
(GUNSHOTS)
VAN HELSING: What is it?
Who is it, Martín?
MARTIN: A bat, Professor.
Very big and black.
Don't waste your pellets. It's no use.
You'll never harm that bat.
What can we do?
He's crazy.
They're all crazy.
All of them, except you and me.
And sometimes
I even have my doubts about you.
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
It was a good deed,
driving a stake
through the heart of that poor girl.
Now her soul will rest in peace.
Let's go to the abbey.
Look! An opening in the wall.
RENFIELD: Master!
Master, here I am!
Here I am!
HARKER: Eva! Eva!
Eva! Eva!
He went in this way!
I didn't bring them here, Master! I swear!
I didn't know, Master!
Wait!
Master! Master! I've always been faithful!
I am your slave. I did not betray you!
Don't kill me, Master!
Punish me! Torture me! But let me live!
I cannot go before God
with so many deaths on my conscience
and so much blood on my hands!
(SCREAMS)
(GASPING)
HARKER: He came in through here!
Eva! Eva!
Use this pole, Harker!
(BANGING AT DOOR)
(BANGING CONTINUES)
(BANGING STOPS)
(EVA SCREAMS)
HARKER: I've got it.
Eva, we're here!
Eva! Eva!
Eva!
VAN HELSING: Harker! Harker!
I found them.
Look.
His life as a vampire
is coming to an end.
What about Eva?
You must be brave.
Find me a stone.
Something
that I can use to drive a stake
through his heart.
What about Eva? Is she...
She's not here.
Then she's still alive!
HARKER: Where are you?
(BANGING, DRACULA GROANING)
(SILENCE)
HARKER: Eva! Eva! Where are you?
Eva! Eva! Eva!
You're safe, Eva!
(EVA CRYING)
You're safe!
Juan!
You should have seen
the horrible look on his face
when he saw the sunlight.
There is nothing to fear now.
Dracula is dead forever.
Aren't you coming?
I'm staying behind.
I shall make good on my promise to Renfield.