It was when summer
was almost over.
It was rainin'
a hell of a lot.
Do you also fix
broken things?
I can fix anythin' except
makin' a hag into a maiden.
Then could you
fix this, too?
Oh my, you must pack
a big punch down there.
How hard could
you have peed
to break that steel
bedpan into pieces?
When I arrived at her home
to bring the fixed bedpan,
the rain suddenly stopped.
Hello?
Anybody home?
Who's there?
Yes, it's me, the blacksmith
you visited down below.
How much did you
say it cost?
Man, I'm so darn coldafter
gettin' drenched out there.
A drink is better than
any money if you
got any booze.
Don't know if a young maiden living
alone like me would have any.
I did buy some raw rice wine
to make vinegar two days ago.
But where could it be?
Could it be there?
Where could it be?
Here?
There?
Or here?
Where could it be?
Where is it?
Oh boy, her tight butt looked
like it was gonna burst.
I just wanted to sink
my teeth into it.
- What?
- What the hell?
What happened next?
- Hurry up.
- Quickly.
Tell us!
- Then she...
- Shut up!
You low class bastards.
I can't concentrate, damn it!
What? "Low class bastards"?
What? And they aren't?
You low class bastards.
Try some taffy! Taffy!
I got taffy a young widow likes
to eat on a lonely night!
Taffy that's as white
as a baby's thigh.
If you have taffy white
as a baby's thigh...
Then got one as big as
my pecker?
I got all sizes, some even
big as a palace crossbeam.
The sun's falling over the mountain,
and this taffy is running out fast
This booze isn't just booze
Drink!
It's a potion to make
you live forever.
Now, come and drink.
- Try out a few sips.
- Can I use my two nuts as tab?
Depending on the nuts.
If the piece is solid,
drink for free.
Thief!
Catch him!
- Taffy! Come buy some taffy!
- Watch where you put your hand!
Don't just salivate,
come buy some taffy now.
I'm gonna break your wrists!
Lady, have some taffy.
Test it out.
Come here.
Hey, you have to pay first!
- What the hell?
- Oh my, I'm sorry.
- What are you looking at?
- You little...
I oughta...
Let's go.
You're lucky
I'm a busy man today.
Money!
Protect the wagon!
Protect the money!
I'm a police officer!
Freeze!
Do or die.
I mean, if you surrender,
I'll let you alive!
So put that thing down fast
and be a good boy.
I knew you'd do that.
I knew!
Don't let a single sack go!
That way!
Gross!
Ouch, that hurt.
What blockhead bumped into me?
Who the hell?
Me? I'm nothin' special.
I'm just Detective Namsoon!
Now you're completely surrounded.
What's a crazy bitch
like you doin' here?
Go.
I said go.
I said go!
- Where is he?
- Yes?
I said where is he?
Where's who?
Want a taste of a bitch
who's really lost her mind?
Where is he?
The bald guy with
an eye patch.
The short, fast-walking one.
He's the one you're
looking for, right?
You know him, too. Right?
Pardon?
See?
Now he puts his tail down since
we're talking nice to him.
Use your mouth not your
fist next time.
He's human, not a beast.
So beating him won't
make him listen!
Oh my! How could you do
this to him?
Anyway,
he came this way,
so where could he have gone?
In the toilet? In the well?
On the roof?
Well, mind if I ask you
who you are?
Come on, don't need to
be scared!
We're not out to check IDs
for prostitutes,
nor or we out to find liquor
illegally stashed away.
So don't be scared.
Just quickly tell us
where he is.
We'll go quietly
like a silent fart,
without you asking us to.
All I know is that
his name is Eel.
That's right.
That bastard is so fast he slips
away like an eel all the time.
Well, his real name can't be Eel,
so what is it?
You should know already that
Ma is one vicious guy.
If I open my mouth, he'll stab me!
So I can't tell you!
Hey, you're trying to send
me to Hell, too?
I'd like to settle
things if we can.
So what's his name?
Ma the Lizard?
So he must run
as fast as a lizard.
Where does he live?
Where he eats and shits
all the time.
Right, okay.
And from there?
I know the rest.
I've seen a lot of
fast fighters,
but I haven't seen anyone
as fast as him.
There's a saying that
someone poked a thorn
out of a speeding tiger's paw.
I guess that kind of person
really exists.
Unfortunately, we haven't
found any clues
to the counterfeit incident
that erupted today.
All probable suspects
were killed by that masked man
who popped up and vanished.
Since not a single person
was able to
get a good look at his face,
it's currently difficult to draw
his picture montage.
This was picked up in the market
during the day.
Take a good look at them.
At first glance,
they look like real money.
If you take a closer look,
the engraving is very rough.
That can happen if the
heating is not right.
Although it's a hunch,
I think...
It's really strange.
They're not just a few coins...
But there are tons...
Of fake money circulating...
In the capital city...
So something's up.
First, make sure that none
of this leaks out and causes havoc.
Make a montage of at least
half of that
masked man's face, spread it,
and probe around in secret.
Then something will
eventually come up.
Who the hell,
and for what reason
did this person fake
so many coins?
There's a shitload of fake
money goin' around.
Prices are gonna
reach sky-high.
I had a bulk of money,
but all I could buy
were some eggs.
But I heard the money
looks real.
My money-lovin' big brother
can't even tell if it's
real or not anymore.
can I even do business
if I don't know
what money's real?
Fake money's all over the place,
even in my Choonchung Province.
Think that's all? Haejoo,
Kaesung, Anhdong, Namwon.
They're all over the country.
If this keeps up,
this damn country
will go belly up.
I still have the right to
speak my mind.
Son of a bitch,
what's he staring at?
Oh my, leaving already?
Was it tasty?
Hey, this money is fake!
How dare you accuse me!
I just got this money
after selling something.
Take a good look at it.
Can't you read
the official seal?
You can't even read at all.
Yeah, I can't read, so what?
Anyway, I can't take
this money!
Can I take a quick look at it?
Oh my, how can a young boy
like you be so darn pretty?
If only you weren't a boy,
I'd have some great fun with you.
Oh my, how could
your hands be so soft?
Oh, how wonderful.
If you were younger than me,
you'd already be dead.
Scram!
And your voice is even pretty.
I'm gonna crush your balls!
Oh no!
Namsoon!
The money's real!
I can never leave you
alone for even a minute!
I bet it hurts a lot.
Let me take a look.
Ouch!
Each person died from
a single strike.
I also found out that
the dead prosecutors are fakes.
Oh boy, fake money circulates,
and now fake
prosecutors are in it.
Goodness, the whole world is
filled with fakes.
You're not fake so
don't worry.
Hermit Gongan...
Remember?
Only Hermit Gongan
could make a fake
prosecutor's seal like that.
Isn't he in Surin Jail?
As far as I know,
someone paid big money
to bail him out.
Is that so?
Are you absolutely sure
you can protect me?
We'll even cover the money
for your paintings.
Is he the one who visited you
at Surin Jail a month ago?
Yes, sir.
His eyes looked quite sad.
You sure you got
a good look at him?
That Sad Eyes
or whatever guy?
I did! This is where
he vanished.
There's nowhere else to go.
But you know where we are,
don't you?
The powerful Defense Minister,
who can even stop
a bird from flyin'.
That Minister Song
whatever's home.
Why'd a powerful official like
him hang around those rotten crooks?
That's so you.
You don't have much of a brain.
That's why you were
never promoted.
What did you bring that up for?
That's complete nonsense.
I just like to sweat
on the job.
It means that I like
being out on the scene.
Well, sometimes you
can be right.
But I still don't buy
what you said.
It's really iffy.
Corvina fish and
Ambrosia casserole!
Oh my, it looks so tasty!
But nothin' exciting
is happening.
Is that Sad Eyes?
Don't get too close to him.
It's not time yet.
Oh goodness, my belly!
Where are you hurt?
Stomachaches...
Sir, are you following me
because you like me?
Are you chasing after me?
Don't know what you're saying.
Or...
Are you tailing me?
Oh goodness!
Where've you been
all this time?
Trailed the fallen
leaves to here?
Or were you drunken
by the perfume?
Or were you possessed
by the night?
No one saw us, right?
- Yes, sir!
- Let's go.
I swear it was the Defense Minister's
old assistant, Gu Jang-gon.
I clearly remember
because I served
under Minister Song
in the last war.
They're smarter
than I thought.
They installed bellows
in the boat,
made the fake coins while
riding in the canal,
and also distribute them.
The Defense Minister's
assistant, you say.
These are the fake coins gathered
in Pyongyang and Hamheung.
Money is also useless there,
and prices have skyrocketed.
Sir, shall we bring
in Gu Jang-gon first?
You scared the hell out of me!
Where the hell have you been?
Anyway, are you alright?
Sir,
it's impossible to produce the
counterfeits in huge sums
without aid from
the dignitaries.
Since Defense Minister Song
controls the entire military
and has no rivals,
I'm sure he's
behind everything.
Who are you to shoot off
your mouth like that?
Please let Detective Ahn
and me go into Minister Song's home.
We will definitely
find evidence.
You have good intentions,
but we could fall first
if we're too hasty.
But sir!
Why aren't you sleeping?
Are you trying to put me
on a skewer or something?
You know that you're done for
if you weaken before a fight, right?
A fight only comes
one time around.
There's no second chance.
That's Minister Song's
old assistant, Gu Jang-gon.
Your Excellency,
I wish you a happy birthday.
This a famous sword brought
over from Japan.
It was made for the Prime Minister
during the Muromachi era.
They also say that a curse
comes with this sword.
According to its curse,
the sword's maker was executed.
The Prime Minister,
who held this sword,
was eventually assassinated
by his men.
The sword disappeared for
centuries and was then found
at the Prime Minister's grave.
Strangely, it wasn't rusted
and was perfectly in tact.
Quite an interesting sword.
A sword like
that suits the
Minister perfectly!
Yes indeed!
They say those
kinds of swords become
a lucky sword to powerful men.
Of course.
Nazukusa.
Zuwamonodomoka Yumenoato.
The summer grass, traces of
a vanished warrior's dream.
Jeez, I guess this
ain't the toilet.
Oh boy, this place is
as big as a palace.
I was told the way,
but I can't find the toilet.
Oh my, I peed on myself.
You all scared me to death.
Your Excellency,
could we see an example
of the sword's power here?
Great idea!
Yes, please show us!
Strike me if you like.
If you don't trust me.
Your Excellency!
How about giving him
this girl as a prize?
That's a great idea!
Your loyal henchman
seems to be very interested
in this girl.
Hurry and pour him a drink!
Drinks aren't important now!
She better go wash up first!
Oh no!
What is your name?
Nam! Namsoon...
I mean, Sweet Flower Moon.
Then what's your name?
Sir...
Well...
What?