Oh, Mr. Parker'.
Oh, Mr. Parker.
Oh, whatever happened?
Are you all right?
Did you hurt yourself?
Oh!
Oh shush, Arnold.
That's it, you stay there.
Oh, careful, Mr. Parker.
Hello?
Here, you come and sit
over here, Mr. Parker.
That's it, I'll make you a cup of tea.
You haven't got much to say, have you?
You let your stuff get into
a rare mess, Mr. Parker.
Don't you have no one to come in
and clean the place for you?
It's about time somebody did.
If I get time tomorrow,
I'll come and give the place a bit
of a cleanup for you.
Oh, that does hurt?
You feeling better now, Mr. Parker?
You wanna take care of yourself
or you'll be killing
yourself one of these days.
Here's your hat, Mr. Parker.
You dropped it outside.
You've been gone a long time, Dulcima.
I'm sorry, Ma.
Children, children, shh!
Rowena, Abigail, stop that noise!
Your father's having a rest.
Go on, get some water in for me,
there's a good girl.
Oh yeah, all right, Ma.
Be, quiet, Abigail, Rowena, now go on.
Go on play, go on.
Go on down the field.
Dulce!
Get me some more tea.
I've let this get cold.
Dulcima, someone here waiting.
Dulce!
Dulce, get me a cup of tea!
Put some water on, Dulce,
I wanna have a wash.
And I want some new shoes!
I've been walking about on bare feet
for a week now!
I won't be treated like a dog!
Hey Dulce, do this Dulce, do that Dulce.
I'll Dulce myself out of here one day!
Whatever's gotten into Dulcima?
How do you feel today, Mr. Parker?
Ain't so bad.
Does your head hurt?
That's all right.
I said I'd come up and give your place
a bit of a cleanup.
Yeah.
You pick up my hat yesterday?
I picked it up, I put it in the kitchen.
You didn't lose nothing, did you?
No, not that I know of.
You did not give that henhouse a wallop.
Shoo!
Oh, hello, Mr. Parker.
I haven't had much time
but it's a bit better.
Yeah.
Oh.
I don't know what you want for your supper
but this is all I could find.
You'll have to get
yourself some new curtains.
I ain't got money for curtains.
Well you have to.
Those others won't stand another wash.
Well I ain't made of money.
I've got a living to get.
What's your name?
Gaskain.
One of George Gaskain's lot, right?
Yes.
Which one are you?
Dulcima.
Ah, that's a funny name innit?
What they call you?
Dulce or else Dulcie.
It's worse than Dulcima.
Well I better be off now.
They say that curtain
material's going up, you know?
Well you could save
yourself 12 or 13 shillings
if you bought it now.
Ah.
I ain't had no new curtains
since the missus died.
But it's about time you did.
You let me get 'em, I'll fix 'em up.
All right you get 'em.
Hello, Mr. Parker.
I suppose I must owe you a bob or two.
Soon as I get the hand done
I'll settle up with you.
Oh, Mr. Parker.
You'll have to get yourself
some new shirts and underwear.
I don't think these'll stand another wash.
That'll be all right.
That's good ventilation.
I shall need some soap.
Ah.
Dulce?
Dulce, you up there?
Hello, Mr. Parker.
Isn't it hot today?
Oh it's fair tired me
up walking up that hill.
I'm sorry I couldn't come up yesterday.
That's why I come up early today.
Oh, I gotta go and get myself a drink.
Oh, Mr. Parker.
Do you want something?
No, love, no.
Do you want a cup of tea?
No, thanks, no, no.
How about you coming up here for good?
What?
Yeah, that's right,
like you know, keep house for me.
I couldn't!
But why not?
Why not eh?
I'm willing to pay.
I've been meaning to ask
you for some time now.
I'm very satisfied with the way you work.
Yeah, I mean you like
it up here, don't you?
It's not that.
I just couldn't.
Well why not?
Why not, I'm willing to pay.
I don't know, I mean what'll you pay?
You keep saying you'll
pay but how do I know?
Three pound ten a week and your keep,
now how's that?
I could get more than that
working down at the supermarket.
Four pound.
And I wouldn't have to traipse
all the way up here.
Anyway, you keep saying you'll pay me,
but there's all that
what you owe me already.
Oh!
You didn't think I was gonna
forget that, Dulce, did you eh?
Tell you no,
you didn't think I was
gonna forget to pay?
No, I've been a bit busy.
I know you'll pay, Mr. Parker.
Yeah.
Well that's right then innit, eh?
And the three pound 10 a week you,
four pound a week and your keep.
I don't know.
I'll have to think about it.
'Cause there's other people
I got to think about.
Other things.
Ah.
Yeah, right, right.
You think think about it.
How much longer
you gonna sit there?
I can't sleep with the light on.
I just got this
bit and ending to finish.
You shouldn't have to
sit up all hours doing that.
Why can't Dulce do it?
She's got enough to do as it is.
Don't you think she works hard enough?
Yeah but clackers,
this is her place here
working in this house.
- Dad--
- Yeah but clackers.
Anyway you don't pay her for it.
Pay her?
No you hear when I said
- put the light out!
- Don't make so much noise,
you'll wake the children.
Put the light out!
Dulce?
You think about what I said?
A bit.
Ah, that'll be all right then eh?
I mean it ain't bad up here is it, eh?
You like it here, don't you?
Yeah but what am I gonna
do with myself all day?
There's nobody to talk to.
There's nobody up here.
Well I'll take you to
town Saturdays, market days.
There's no need to be lonely.
It ain't that.
It ain't only what I think.
Well who else is it then?
Is it your dad?
I don't care what he thinks.
I don't care about him.
Who else then?
Well there is somebody else.
Well who, who?
My boyfriend.
My young man.
Boyfriend?
Well I never knew you had one.
Well who is he?
What's his name?
Albert.
Well you don't think he'd like it?
It ain't only that.
He gives me money.
You know, a few shillings
saving every week
so we can get things ready,
so we can get married someday.
Marry?
You're gonna get married?
Well I hope so.
Four pound 10 a week.
Now if I give you that, will you come?
I'll ask Albert tonight.
I should think he'll probably murder me.
I'll stomp you
if I get hold of you.
You stupid useless bitch.
I hope we don't bump into Albert.
I had to tell him all kinds of
tales about you, Mr. Parker.
Ah.
Well what'd he say?
Well he said I could give it a trial.
He said I could come up here for a week.
Ah.
What else?
Oh he was a bit jealous.
But I said it would be all right.
Well never you mind about Albert.
Now you keep along with me.
I got a few fly deals on today.
Oh.
Right then, here we go.
Lot one, four nice Friesians,
the property of Mr. Bamberg.
What can I see for 'em?
Who's got me a 40?
Well a 35 then, 35, thank you sir.
35, 35, 36.
37, a 38, a 38, a 39, thank you sir.
Waiting, 40, 41, a 41.
A 42, 43, a 44.
45, 45, 46, 46.
A 47, thank you, a 47.
A 48, 48, 48.
49, 49, 49.
A 50, a 50, thank you sir.
50, 51.
Mr. Parker.
Who's doing the bidding?
I mean how does he know?
Ah, he knows all right.
See that man smoking a pipe?
That's a bid.
See that man over there
scratching his nose
with a stick?
That's another.
Him there flicking his thumb.
That's a bid.
Old Charlie Sawkins there,
changing his stick from
one hand to another.
Don't you move your hand about
or it'll be knocked down to you.
If you're all done,
have a nice sale to Mr. Reeves.
Come along with me.
Hello, Symes.
What's on today?
What you got?
Four Galloways.
Good 'uns?
Fair.
Another bloke's got Galloways.
Good 'uns.
When is his lot up?
Oh, about half an hour or so.
Reckon the bidding should be tasty.
Apart from your own,
there's no other Galloways.
Ah.
I better take a look.
Come along with me.
They your own?
That's right.
Ah well I like 'em.
How much will you take for 'em?
Well they're up for auction.
Well you can sell them
prior to an auction.
You've been here before?
Couple of times.
I used to go to Rolie market.
Well, like anywhere else, you
can sell them as you please.
How much would you take for 'em?
I reckon they'd pull in 60 pound apiece.
Good strain, see for yourself.
I'm in a hurry, I'll
give you 60 pound apiece.
Well.
Take it or leave it.
I'll take it, Mister?
Parker.
Harris.
It's a deal.
You know that popup on the hill there?
Where, up there?
Yeah, that's right.
Now you wait for me there,
I'll be along with my
partner in half an hour.
I'll give you cash.
You want cash?
That'll be fine.
I'll see you there.
Thank you.
Come along with me.
All right, let's try
and sell these, shall we?
Lot E.
Four nice Shirley cross Galloways,
the property of Mr. Parker.
These hefers, the only ones today
due to the last minute
withdrawal of the other lot,
are as you can see our superior stock.
Now what can I say for 'em?
70 apiece?
65 then?
60.
Thank you sir.
60 pounds on bid.
61, 62?
62, a 63, a 63?
64, thank you sir, a 64.
65, 65, 65, 65, 65.
A 66, thank you sir.
66, waiting, waiting, a 66.
66, 66, 66.
67, 67, 67.
A 68, a 68, a 68
and a 69, a 69.
One thing for you.
Stick with it, sir.
A 69.
A 69 if you're all done.
Stick your hand up.
Anyway if you're all done.
What me?
Come on, stick your hand up.
No, I can't, Mr. Parker.
69.
A 70, a 70.
70 have you, a 71.
71, 71.
A 72, a 72, a 72.
If you're all done.
Last time now sell at 72 to Mr. Blake.
I told you I had a few
fly ideas on the day.
Come along with me.
That's a jolly good price
I'm paying you, Mr. Parker.
They're worth more than that.
I don't want no checks.
I don't go about with
300 pounds on me, you know?
I don't want no checks.
Make it out to cash.
I'll give you your cut later.
Well, why don't you make
it out to us, Mr. Blake?
And then I can give Mr.
Parker here the money.
And deduct our commission
at the same time.
How does that suit you, Mr. Parker?
Right.
283.15.
273 pounds 12.
Let you down?
My partner won't give me the money.
Won't give you the money?
Gimme a pint.
But we made a deal.
We'll have to break it.
What do you say your name is?
Mr. Parker.
Look, Mr. Parker.
You have put me through
considerable trouble.
I'm sorry, I can't help it, can I?
My partner's let me down.
I don't think you're as
sorry as you'd have me believe.
Mr. Parker.
I'm hungry.
There's a cafe just a
few doors down the road.
That's a nice place.
Are you coming?
Mm-mm.
I'll be here.
I only got three shillings.
You can get a good feed down there
for three shillings.
Mr. Parker.
I just seen Albert.
I don't know whether he's seen me or not.
But I'm scared of what he might do.
We better get home.
That's what I think.
Right this way.
All right.
He lives right here, does he, Albert?
Not too far from here.
Ah.
Come on, Mr. Parker.
What's his work?
Oh he's got a good job.
Well what is it?
Well he
works at a building site.
Construction work.
Ah.
Well how long you known him?
Oh, going on two years.
Two years,
oh that's a long time.
You get to know a person real well
out of two years though.
Yes, sometimes
a bit too well, Mr. Parker.
Ah.
Come on with me.
All right.
Ah, there you are.
Had a bit of a bath?
I was wondering if you'd
care for a glass of beer
in the front room?
I was just off to bed, Mr. Parker.
I'm fair worn out by everything today.
Ah.
Tomorrow night.
Good night.
Night.
Albert.
Miss Parker?
No.
Oh, sorry.
You must want Mr. Parker.
I don't know where he is right now.
Can I help?
Please, my name's Ashby.
I'm Mr. Morton's new gamekeeper.
I have some young pheasants
that have a bad habit
of straying onto your land.
I wondered if it'll be all right
for me to come and round
them up once in a while.
You mean come on to Mr. Parker's land?
Yes.
Oh, I don't know.
He's very funny like that.
He don't like strangers
prowling around his land.
I know.
Mr. Morton told me he'd had
a few bad words with him
a couple of years ago.
I wasn't sure if Mr. Parker had forgotten.
He gave me explicit instructions
to ask first, you see.
You let me ask him.
'Cause he's very funny like that.
Why he'd very likely blow your brains out.
Really?
Well I'll keep out of his way then.
That's it, you keep out of his way.
Right, well the
next time I see you, I'll ask.
I see you quite often.
You do, how?
Oh around the farm.
I live just over there.
Where?
In Compton Wood.
What, you live in that old house?
You know it?
Yeah.
We used to play in it when we were kids.
You must get ever so lonely.
Not really.
I have plenty to do of an evening.
Anyway, I like being on my own.
I'd better be off.
Look, I'll ask Mr. Parker
about the pheasants
to tell you later.
Thank you.
Goodbye.
Bye.
Dulce?
How many in your family down there?
10.
That's including Ma and Pa.
Huh.
That's a lot of mouths to feed, innit?
Does Albert ever come to your house?
Albert?
Why'd you ask?
Oh, no reason, no.
Except I saw a stranger in
the hayfield this morning.
He had a gun.
A gun?
Yeah.
Tall fellow, dark haired,
brown jersey with a sort of pattern on it.
Is that him?
That sounds like him.
Yeah, he's got a jersey like that.
He's jealous of you, Mr. Parker.
He's very jealous of you.
Is he there now?
No, no, no, no, no.
He shot off when he saw me.
Yeah.
Yeah, he shot off when he saw me.
Ah.
I was wondering where you was.
Hey, what's this?
You aren't going anywhere's are you?
Oh, I don't know.
I get worried.
Worried, what about?
It's Albert.
I mean when people start
prowling about with guns,
it's time I went back home.
No, no, no, don't do that, Dulce, no.
For God's sake don't do that, no.
You can't do that.
I can if Albert says so.
Dulce.
Hey, Mr. Parker.
I don't want you to go.
Yeah, but when people start
prowling about with guns,
besides, you haven't paid me yet.
I know.
I know, I'll pay you.
You keep saying that.
That's all I've heard
since I came up here.
Well how much is it?
Hey, for God's sake, now how much is it?
How much is it Dulce, how much is it?
I don't know, I've got
it written down somewhere.
Right.
20 pounds 17.
And about time too.
20 pounds 17 shillings.
22 pounds.
23 pounds five.
Oh.
Oh, Dulce.
Hey.
We won't get the money paid like this.
I want you so bad, Dulce.
I can't get on without you.
I can't get on.
Yeah, mind my dress.
What?
Well you're sitting on my dress.
I thought you came to pay me the money.
Hmm?
Oh yeah, that's right.
Yes I, I got it here.
Well put it on the table then.
Hmm?
Go on.
How much is it?
40 pound.
Well I bought a shilling or two.
Put it in the drawer, it'd be safe there.
Hey.
How about Albert?
You don't think I ever
wanted Albert, do you?
Did Albert ever?
Does it matter if he did?
Oh!
Oh, Mr. Parker.
I'll give him 15 pounds.
Mr. Parker?
Hmm?
Your tea is ready.
Ooh.
That's the money you gave me.
I did say 14, didn't I?
Yeah, yeah, that's right yeah.
Well you gave me too much.
You gave me 15.
Oh.
Did I?
That means I gotta
give you a pound back.
I mean we wanna keep
things right, don't we?
No, no, no, no.
You keep it, eh?
Yeah.
That's for a little extras.
You like the little extras, do you?
Oh, what are you doing to me?
There's a time and place
for that sort of thing.
No you don't!
Oh no you don't!
- Oh yeah.
- No.
- It's my day!
- No, stop!
Dulce, Dulce!
Stop it!
Hey!
Oh!
Oh no, no!
Ah!
Mr. Parker, yoohoo!
Wait, Dulce, come here!
No!
Yoohoo, Mr. Parker!
Oh, Mr. Parker!
Ah, I seen you!
Banks?
No, you don't want to have
nothing to do with banks.
Banks ain't no good.
No?
No, no, they know all your business.
They get to know too much.
Then the income tax get to know.
I ain't paying no bleeding tax,
not if I know it.
No, they ain't getting
nothing away from me.
Well I'll put it in
the post office then,
I'll get interest on it.
No, you don't want
to do nothing with it.
No, you keep it.
Keep it where nobody can't
touch it, that's all.
Well I'll have to see.
I forgot.
Albert came around again today.
Albert?
Well what does he want with you now?
I don't know.
I can't think why he won't leave us alone.
I told him.
Told him?
Told him what?
I told him about us.
About how we were.
About us being on our own
and all that, it's over.
Cool.
Oh cool, Dulce.
Oh cool.
Oh Mr. Parker,
what are you doing to me,
that tickles!
Hello.
What's that?
Oh it's a polecat with
a bit of ferret in him.
There's something wrong with his leg.
Oh I suppose you'll have to kill it.
No, I'll put a cast on it.
He'll be all right in a
couple of weeks or so.
Oh I didn't know you was a vet.
I'm not, but
I used to work for one.
Poor little thing.
What a shame.
Did you speak to Mr. Parker
about the pheasants yet?
Well I did mention it to him.
He didn't like the idea very much
but he said it would be all right
as long as he didn't see you.
I see.
Oh it's not you he don't like.
It's Mr. Morton.
But as long as he doesn't see you
it'll be all right.
Right, thank you.
Well I better be off.
Bye.
I hope the polecat gets better.
Thank you.
Morning.
Hello, Mr. Parker.
Ah, cha!
Hey Dulce, hey what's this?
What's up now?
I can't find that money you gave me.
Well you must have mislaid it somewhere.
I've looked high and low.
Well when did you last see it?
That day when Albert
came prowling about.
Albert.
We got to put a stop to this.
I'll get the police onto him!
Oh no, don't do that.
We don't want no trouble.
Now, now, don't cry
Dulce, don't cry, don't cry.
That won't do no good, won't do no good.
Yeah but what have I got now,
I ain't got nothing.
I paid all that out for the
hours and now it's gone!
All right, I'll make it up to you.
I'll make it up, I'll make
it right, I'll make it right.
Oh.
I made a mistake.
I added it up wrong.
You put me off that night
when you came into the bedroom.
It's 24 pounds 10 to me, right?
Well it's only a little bit extra.
It ain't much.
You can't have all the little extras
for nothing, can you?
Ooh.
Mmm!
I like the way you've
had your hair styled.
Do you?
Yes.
It's about time I had it done.
Oh, it's very becoming.
I don't think you can carry any more.
Are you sure you can manage?
Yes.
I'll carry them up the
house for you if you like.
Oh no, don't bother.
I can manage.
Don't you want none for yourself?
Oh they grow all around my house.
I just can't imagine
you living up there.
I can't imagine it.
You should see it now.
I'd like to.
Anytime you like.
I'll make tea for you.
I will then, thank you.
Goodbye.
That you Dulce?
Yes.
Where you been all this?
Oh my God.
Hah, what you done all that for?
I had my hair done, that's all.
Ah.
Yeah I like it, yeah.
It makes you look different but
yeah I like it.
But what made you do it?
I had it done with
that money you gave me.
Sure, oh.
God, what a sight for sore eyes, eh?
Cool.
You look good, Dulce.
You put some new pictures up?
What?
No, no, no they're old ones.
I'd come across some
old things in the shed.
I thought they might
look good up there, huh?
Did you like 'em?
Yes.
I've been thinking now.
I reckon the place could do with
an extra set of furniture
specially after you fixed it up so good.
Yeah, pictures and flowers
will make the place
sort of homely.
Course, I could go for a television.
Eh Dulce, eh?
Watch the television huh?
How about it?
- Mmm.
- Yeah.
Yeah, don't cost nothing
now that you bought it.
I've been doing quite a
bit of thinking lately.
I mean, you know how people are,
they start talking.
Well, I reckon,
reckon you and I all get married.
Eh Dulce, eh?
Eh, get married.
How about it, Dulce?
I don't know.
I'll have to think about it.
Well what's there to think about, eh?
You know me, you enjoy the place.
Hey, it ain't Albert, is it?
Good heavens, no.
I mean I'd like to.
I wouldn't mind.
But I'll have to think about it.
Ah.
Of course, you might have to marry me.
Well I wouldn't mind that.
I should think not.
I'm the one that should worry
about a thing like that.
Ah.
Let me think it over.
All right, all right, you think it over.
I'll put a few more of these pictures up.
Yeah, that'll look nice.
All right.
Hello Mr. Smith, how's things with you?
Oh, can't complain.
That's right.
Too nice a day to complain.
You sure, Mr. Parker?
Yes, right, two sacks will do.
That's three pounds 10 please sir.
Here's four pounds, keep the change.
Thanks very much,
- Mr. Parker.
- Thanks Mr. Parker.
Will that be your truck here?
Yeah
that's right over there.
Hello?
Hello.
I hope you didn't mind me coming in.
The door was open.
You did ask me.
No, I'm glad you're here.
Sit down.
How about a cup of tea?
Thank you.
You never told me your name.
It's Dulcima.
That's Dulcima Parker, isn't it?
Dulcima Gaskain.
- First I thought Mr.
- Parker was your father.
What, him, my father?
Oh no, I only housekeep for him.
Oh I see.
Do you stay up there?
Not likely, no.
I go up every night.
I couldn't face living up there.
I mean, there's nobody to talk to,
nobody to see.
Do you live in the village?
No, Bristol.
Oh, that's a long way off.
I like it here, though.
I like the life.
My father wanted me to go
into the family business
along with my brothers.
But I wanted to be a vet so I left.
I suppose I've cut myself off a bit but
at least I'm free to do what I want.
And I can talk to people
who are interested
in the same things as me.
How's you're tea?
It's nice.
45, 46?
47, 47, come along now.
47, 48, thank you.
48, 48, you done?
48, 48, and 48, are you done?
49, thank you sir.
49, 49, 49, 49.
50, thank you.
50, 50, 51.
52, 52.
What a shot for Rangers
and what a pity that it was out
against Storm tactics.
I told you I'd get us a television.
It's good, innit?
The Rangers worked hard
to make up their deficit
but Celtic were quick to clear
and retaliate positively.
Yeah.
That's just what we need for the winter.
I know winters are bad here,
you couldn't get out of the place
for a month or more.
Hey, we can sit and watch the telly.
Yeah.
Did you think any
more about what I said?
Well I haven't had time really.
What's there to think about so long?
I mean, you enjoy it here, don't you?
Yeah.
Yeah, course you do.
I mean you've got the run of the place.
You've been getting a full pound 10 a week
and your keep.
I mean, that's a lot for a girl.
I mean that's too much really
and we could both all better live on that.
Of course you get a bit more
when you're married, now.
Yeah you get a bit more, Dulce.
Yeah.
I'd been fly now.
Yeah, I been fly.
I got quite a bit.
You think about that, Dulce, eh?
I am thinking about it.
Ah.
Well I'll give you something
to hurry up your mind.
You come along with me.
Sit down there, sit down there.
Look at that, Dulce, look at it.
There's money for you ain't it, eh?
Ain't you surprised?
Look at it!
You don't want more than that, do you?
I don't want it.
See how fly I be?
More than I know what to do with.
I wanna wait a bit.
All right, all right, all right.
You wait.
Here, here, take a pound
or two for yourself.
Buy something just for yourself hmm?
Dulce, how long do you wanna wait?
I don't know, Mr. Parker.
I just wanna wait a bit.
45.
Okay how about 40?
35 then.
Thank you sir, 35, and 35.
And 35, and 36.
And 36, now 37.
37, now 38.
38, thank you sir.
38, 39, thank you sir.
Waiting, 40, 40, thank you sir, 40.
What you got on today?
What?
Are you buying or selling today?
I don't know, William.
I don't know.
Hello, Dulcima.
You look nice today.
It's my day off.
You've never seen me on my day off.
I wish it were my day off.
You busy, then?
No, not really.
Oh I was just going down the hill.
Well I'll walk with you if you like.
Hey, look at my shoes,
they're all dirty.
Here, I'll clean it for you.
Oh, that's all right.
We'll do it when we get off the road.
Why don't we walk by the stream?
There's a path through there.
It's very pretty.
It leads to the main road.
All right.
Mhmm.
Oh.
Dulcie!
Dulcima!
Dulce!
Thank you.
Mr. Parker, I thought you were at market.
I came back.
Where you been, eh?
Where'd you get them things?
I bought them.
Well you gave me the
money, you gave it me.
Ah that's right, yeah.
Yeah I did, didn't I?
Course.
You look good.
Hey, you look so good, Dulce.
Been out by yourself?
By myself?
Course.
Who else is there for me to go out with?
Do you want a bite to eat?
No, no, no, I ain't hungry.
Oh I am.
Walking up and down that hill.
I better go and take these things off.
I got some work to do.
No, no, don't take them off, no.
Keep them on, they're nice.
But I got work to do.
I ain't working in these.
Well don't do it now, leave it.
I tell you what.
I'll get dressed up and
we'll go out tonight, eh?
Have a meal out.
Oh not tonight, Mr. Parker.
Why not?
Well I got to go down to me Ma's.
Your Ma's?
Well I ain't seen them
since I been working up here.
Oh.
Well I can come to, can't I?
Oh no.
I mean I wanna see me sisters.
Show off me new things.
I'll only be gone a couple of hours.
That dress in the
window, how much is it?
Which one?
The white one.
18 pounds.
18 pound?
I ain't trying to buy the bloody shop.
It's a special design.
Ah.
Ah well get it out.
I wanna have a look at it.
Can you come back in the morning?
We're closing now.
No I can't, I gotta have it now.
Oh all right.
Ah, that's lovely.
Yeah it is.
That's really lovely.
She'll look lovely in that, huh?
Yeah.
Any girl would wanna get married in that.
Wouldn't they?
Not
yet, just a few months.
You ask, sweet Susan.
Getting to know you has been wonderful.
Oh darling,
please don't go without me.
Take me with you please.
I won't be long, Mr. Parker.
Just a minute, Dulce.
I got something to show you.
Oh.
You bought a new suit.
I like it.
And you got some new shoes.
Oh you do look smart.
Hey Dulce, you ain't gonna
walk down there, are you?
Yes.
Well you can't do that.
It'll be dark before long.
You'll fall in them potholes.
No I won't, I'll be careful.
Well
I'll run you down there.
Oh no, don't do that.
No, I'll be all right.
You stay and watch the television.
And don't wait up for
me if you don't want to.
Hello, Mr. Parker.
You're still up.
Yeah.
How's your Ma?
Oh, well enough.
She was pleased to see me.
Yeah?
What she think of your new things?
She thought I looked grand.
Grand?
She thought I looked nice.
Well I better go upstairs.
My dress has got creased
and I wanna hang it up.
Just a minute.
I ain't had a good look at
you myself yet, have I, hmm?
I mean after all, I,
I got a right to, haven't I eh?
Why, new gloves.
New underwear.
New shoes.
New dress, huh.
After all, you did get
them for me didn't you?
Well didn't you?
No!
No?
Oh, I see.
Ah, well then.
Well who the hell did
you get them for, eh?
Nobody.
Nobody?
No, you must have got yourself
dressed up for somebody, huh?
Who was it?
Who was it!?
It's Albert, isn't it?
It's Albert!
There ain't no Albert,
that's somebody I made up!
- There never was no Albert!
- No, there wasn't
no Albert, wasn't they?
There ain't no Albert, I made it up!
I'd seen you!
I'd seen you, I'd seen you down there!
I'd seen you plain as daylight!
You never think I did see you, did you,
you bitch!
Open this door, you bitch,
I'll take a bloody stick to you!
Never was an Albert, eh?
You lying bitch!
There ain't no Albert.
There never was no Albert.
That's somebody I made up.
No?
Well who the hell have you been with?
With, with,
With Albert, that's who,
with Albert!
Yeah, I've seen him.
I've seen him this morning!
I've seen him tonight!
I see him all the bloody time!
That's who you got yourself
codded up for, wasn't it?!
It was Albert, Albert, Albert!
You ain't got nothing
to say now, are you, eh?
Oh don't go on so, Mr. Parker, please.
I was gonna tell you, honest I was.
Tell me what?
I'm leaving in the morning.
Leaving?!
Yes.
My young man's coming to
fetch me in the morning.
You're
not leaving this house!
I'm going home.
Home?
For how long?
For good.
Forever!
Oh, you bitch.
You bitch.
I bet you've both had a bloody good laugh
over me, eh, eh?
I bet you both had a bloody good laugh!
Dulce?
I'm sorry for what I said.
I'm sorry.
Don't go, Dulce.
Don't go.
I don't know what I'd do if you left me.
I can't.
I can't bear to think of
you with anybody else.
I can't bear it.
Dulce?
Dulce, let me in please.
I wouldn't hurt you, you know that.
Dulce?
I love you, Dulce.
I love you.
Mr. Parker?
Hello, Dulcima.
Hello.
Am I too early?
No.
I can't come now.
You see, it's Mr. Parker.
He's very upset about me leaving.
I don't know where he is.
And I just can't go.
I just can't go.
Ah, well.
You better stay then.
Albert!