§§§§ Subs fixed by Djilik & PenileDemon §§§§
DUPLICITY
I'll count to 10.
If you do not wake before 10,
there will be...
big trouble.
One...
...two...
...three...
...four...
...five...
...six...
...seven...
...eight...
...nine...
Ten.
Pierre ! Pierre !
What are you doing?
It's all wet.
Look, it's all wet.
Come on, get out.
Come on, get out of the tub.
- There. Did you wash your hair?
- Yes.
Good.
- Let's play, Dad?
- Later..
First pass through the dryer.
You're hurting me !
Ah, I'm sorry.
- We dress to see Mom ?
- Yes.
Easy, son !
You scared me !
We must be careful
with the baby.
Come out, little baby.
Soon it will come out of hiding.
Come near, my loves.
Did you see what has drawn Pierre ?
My mom is dead.
My mom is dead
Here, now.
- Was she alive?
- Look.
- Please.
- Thank you.
Morning.
Come in.
Thomas Dussart, Matyas Hebert.
Please have a seat.
I understand your commmotion.
But...
let's get to the facts.
Before dying,
your mother revealed your existence...
to Thomas Dussart,
your brother here present.
When she died,
I did a search for heirs.
It took a few months to find you,
reason was your name change
and custody of Child Services.
At death, Mrs. Depierpont-Dussart
was the proprietor of two bank accounts ...
I then urge you to sign
the tax return succession.
- I wish good luck to you both.
- Thank you.
How is it possible?
Shortly before her death,
mom told me you were alive.
It was a great shock.
They always told me you died
in a car accident, at age 6.
I don't know why they lied.
- I thought they were dead.
- You mean...
You don't remember anything?
No.
Don't you remember me ?
What about us, the house ?
- Don't you remember anything ?
- Nothing.
Listen, I...
I have to go pick up my wife
at the airport.
I would like to stay, but I can't.
She is very fragile right now...
- Wait. You can't leave me like this.
- Hey...
I can't do anything else.
Now that we've found each other,
we will not separate, I promised.
But I really must go.
I'll call around.
- Did you know I exist ?
- I'll call you back, promise.
If she was alive,
why did she leave me alone ?
I don't know !
I don't know.
They never spoke about you.
- I promise I'll call you.
- I don't even know where to find you !
- Wait, you can not walk away.
- I'll call you, trust me.
- We need to talk.
- I swear I'll call you. I swear.
Matyas!
Been so long !
How are you doing ?
Why did'nt you tell me
my mother was alive ?
How funny you should ask me that now.
Usually everyone else wanted to know,
but you never asked anything.
- So you knew it ?
- No, I didn't.
- That can't be. You must have known it.
- I never know anything.
- If you knew something, you'd tell me ?
- Matyas, I know the same as you, I promise.
I have no access to records.
A social worker brought you here,
that's all, I'm sorry.
- Just tell the truth.
- Matyas !
Don't worry,
he said he'd call you.
You tried to call the notary again ?
Always the answering machine,
and there's no Thomas Dussart on the list.
You maybe remember, now.
After a concussion,
some say memory returns.
Claire, I don't even
remember my dreams.
- You may not want to remember.
-  Dad !
Dad !
- Dad !
- I'm here, what's wrong ?
- Why'd you yell, son ?
- I saw you down there, Dad.
- Thomas ?
- No.
No. It's me.
I can't sleep.
TWINS DISORDERS
IN FAMILY RELATIONSHIPS
FRAGILE BALANCE OF THE FATHER-MOTHER -
PAIR OF "TWIN" FAMILY
Easy.
I feel like doing it.
- Wait.
- Easy.
Not now.
Here we go.
Thank you, Sylvain.
Next.
Children, please.
Jeanne, I would like you to smile, please.
Try to improve, will you?
Hush kids, I need quiet
or there won't be enough time for all.
Try to smile, come on.
I only ask you to smile.
It is important for the picture.
- I'm glad to see you.
- So am I.
- Can I come in?
- Sure. How'd you find me ?
I called your wife.
She gave me the lab's address.
- Have you changed your hairstyle ?
- Yeah I like this one.
Come in.
I make a living photographing
children. Well, for now.
- Me too.
- Is that true ?
Actually, I work in a hospital
I do scans.
- How funny.
- Yes.
- Is this your son?
That's awesome !
There's a resemblance.
Look.
You're there.
- Can I keep it?
- Sure you can.
It's yours.
- Is this your wife?
- Yes.
She's nice.
My wife's like us:
She has a twin sister.
Unfortunately, Elina can't have children.
- How are you both doing ?
- Good.
I mean in the sexual aspect.
It must be difficult right now, right ?
Matyas,
you and I feel the same things.
You gotta get used to it .
We are the same.
I'm sure that you like it
as much as I do.
The first time I saw Elina
in the hospital, I was attracted.
She has an amazing body.
And she always wants to do it.
- Don't you want to sit a minute ?
- Whatever.
Shit !
Matyas ! Matyas !
What is it ?
Are you okay ?
- I can't stand the sight of blood.
- Let me see.
Don't look.
- Do I bleed a lot ?
- Don't worry, it's nothing.
It's just a piece of glass.
There, it was nothing.
Take it easy.
That's it.
Matyas !
Sit down.
Are you okay ?
I'm dizzy.
Relax.
That will be okay
Breathe slowly.
How will you do with childbirth ?
I promised Claire I would try,
but I don't know if I'll make it.
I understand.
The smell of blood ...
Cries ...
I think I wouldn't make it either.
Thomas.
You have to help me
understand what happened.
That's why I'm here.
- Do you remember us before ?
- Of course.
We were very close.
Inseparable.
And one day, you disappeared.
it was just like removing
a part of myself.
A cut-off.
I'd like you to come to my place
this afternoon, around five.
I want to show you some of our
childhood pictures.
Okay.
From now on, we won't separate.
Thomas ?
MRS. DEPIERPONT-DUSSART.
BEGUINAGES REST HOME
CANAL STREET, 12 A - 1000 BRUSSELS
Thomas ?
Is that you ?
Thomas !
Don't go, please.
Wait a second.
You're wrong,
I'm Thomas's brother.
It was open, I came in.
I'm so sorry.
- God, what've I done !
- Sorry, my fault.
I thought it was Thomas.
I didn't mean to...
Go away, if Thomas see us,
he'll get irritated
- We agreed to see !
- Go, hurry !
I should have meet him now !
Morning.
- Permit. Why are you here?
- Good afternoon. I...
I'm looking for...
Mrs. Dussart's room.
I was told it was on this floor.
- You know she's dead ?
- Yes, but I wonder if...
by chance there was some object left...
Mrs. Dussart's daughter
took everything.
- Her step-daughter, you mean.
- Yes, Mrs Elina.
Excuse the question:
do you recognize me ?
I'm Mrs. Dussart's son.
- Don't you recognize me ?
- No.
Thank you.
- Bye.
- Daddy !
- Have you seen my plane ?
- Later, sonny.
Your brother came to see us.
What did he want ?
To apologize for failing
to attend the appointment.
He liked that you had met his wife
He's invited you to his place tonight.
- How is she ?
- Who ?
His wife.
Barely saw her.
- Is everything all right ?
- Yeah.
- What about him ?
- Your brother ?
He's very nice.
But he is less handsome,
smart and charming as you are.
- How could you recognize him ?
- There was no need.
- He immediately asked for you.
- So you knew it was not me?
How could you doubt ?
I'm sure to recognize you, first sight.
I'd never confuse. I feel for you.
It is not because he looks like you that...
- Did he touch you ?
- Why do you ask ?
- Did I asked if you touched his wife?
- Sorry.
You haven't even told me
what she looks like.
She's less pretty, smart and sweet
than you are. Now, did he touch you ?
Matyas, leave.
He was playing with Pierre an hour.
You can see he likes children.
He's a very sweet person.
That's good.
What is that ?
Did I already prohibit you
to play with guns?
- What is this ?
- Calm, Matyas. It's a plastic toy.
It's a weapon.
- We shouldn't give weapons to children.
- It ain't me.
But your brother.
Matyas !
Where are you going?
Wait, Matyas!
Stay with me, please.
Stay !
Matyas!
I don't like when you go to
my place when I'm not.
You came as well.
But I did not pretend to be you.
Doesn't matter.
Come.
Come in.
- Why didn't you ever visit mom ?
- What for ? She'd never recognize me.
Come in, I've prepared a surprise.
Come.
Come in, don't be shy.
Please.
I want to introduce my brother Matyas,
who honors us by being present tonight.
Since some time ago,
we met to share our experiences.
I am very happy to have you with us.
Come, let me introduce.
Celine, Carine,
this is my brother Matyas.
- Hello, Matyas.
- Thomas talks much about you.
Shall we go on ?
These are Fabrice and Patrice...
Laurence and Florence...
Marc and Luc, Marie and Sophie...
Arnaud and Benjamin,
Pierre-François and François-Louis...
and Jean-Pierre,
who has spent several years
looking for his brother.
Well, I've introduced everyone.
Matyas ?
Matyas wait.
You can't deny this moment.
I have prepared a surprise
that could...
that could help you to remember.
Okay.
Jean-Paul, would you help me?
Dear friends !
I hope you enjoy the movie.
It's a movie about...
developing a very interesting
theory regarding the twinship.
I'll let you watch it.
Some experiences were conducted
with "mirror-twins".
We name monozygotic twins that way
because they're perfectly symmetrical,
just like in a mirror.
Case of twins Lionel and Jonathan
that suffer identity troubles,
was analyzed by sicentists..
Jonathan incorporated
his brother's image as himself.
When seeing his brother,
he feels like he's seeing himself.
So, while looking in a mirror,
he thinks he sees his brother.
In order to understand the
melting intensity between twins,
researchers focused on
their intrauterine life.
- They discovered that 80 %...
- I was like you.
I lost my brother.
You're lucky, you know.
You'll never have anyone
so close to you.
...just like being soaked up
by his brother.
From the lost twin,
remains only a shadow fetus,
a dry paper.
Some scientists argue that
fetuses struggle for their own life.
If twins are born,
this means they survived the battle...
and their strength
is absolutely equal.
We can consider them
as a perfect couple, although...
Matyas, if you look for Elina
she's not there.
These meetings make her sad.
She rarely sees her twin sister.
Good !
So you found dad's picture ?
Keep it if you wish.
I have more recent ones.
- You mean he's still alive ?
- Sure, it's not because mom died...
- Why didn't you tell me?
- Matyas...
To him, you died at age of 6.
Thomas, stop playing with me.
I play no games.
- I need to know where he is.
- I don't know where he is.
I don't know, I swear.
Anyway, I haven't seen him for years.
Okay.
Wait, Matyas.
I wanted to say, about that delivery...
- It seems very important to Claire.
- Claire told you about that ?
I just want you to know that...
if it's too hard for you,
I can go in your place.
You can't be serious.
No.
What are you doing ?
- Why are you looking at me that way ?
- Nothing.
I was worried.
Sorry.
Put your hand on my belly, please.
- Matyas ?
- I've been thinking.
I decided to attend the delivery.
- Really ?
- Yes.
Sir ?
- Yes ?
- Where are you going?
Looking for a girl who just entered.
It's important, I need  to talk to her.
Her name is Elina Dussart.
- About what ?
- Private.
She's my wife.
Elina ?
Your husband is at the reception desk
She's waiting for you. Room 22.
- Middle of hall, left.
- Thank you.
Thomas ?
No, this isn't Thomas.
Matyas ?
Come in.
Elina...
Why do you hide ?
Oh my God !
Thomas did that ?
I hit the closet door. Stupid.
Don't be ashamed, Elina.
You can't accept that.
He's jealous of you.
- Why ?
- He said you've done him a lot of damage.
Damage ? I don't understand.
What I've done to him ?
- I did nothing to him.
- I don't know, I don't know.
Since he found you out,
he's changed. He became mad.
- Why are you still with him ?
- I got him under my skin,
within my blood. Before him,
I didn't know what love was.
Can I trust you ?
Yes.
I need my father's address.
Can you tell me where he lives ?
Yes.
You're dead.
Don't you remember ?
You're dead. Dead !
Shit !
- Matyas.
- What are you doing here?
Pierre, what are you afraid of?
Pierre, is your dad.
I already explained that Uncle Thomas's
twin brother is dad.
- I thought it'd be good to meet all.
- You're right. A great idea.
- Your wife didn't come ?
- She couldn't.
She apologizes.
Things right now are quite....rough.
Anyway, she's quite shy.
Almost never goes out.
- Does'nt she have friends?
- Yes, one.
Well, two now.
- I had better go.
- There's no reason why. Stay.
You lied to me.
- You knew where he lived.
- I knew he didn't want to see you.
Can you tell me what you're talking about ?
- About our father.
- He's still alive?
- Place was filled with your wife's pictures.
Did he let you come in ?
Damn, Thomas !
Place was filled with your wife's pictures !
Dad cherished Elina.
Maybe too much.
Thank you, Claire,
thank you so much.
- I gotta go, kid.
- Don't you want to stay and play with me ?
Of course he stays.
Matyas, tell him to stay.
You stay, I'm leaving.
- Where are you going ?
- For a walk.
- I'll come with you.
- Impossible. I run.
So do I.
- You plan to go dressed this way ?
- Lend him a sweatsuit.
You've got a wonderful woman.
I envy you, you know.
Elina is so complicated.
- Wanna stop?
- Why ? You tired ?
Matyas ?
Won't you help me?
You don't play with me anymore ?
You don't play with me anymore...
Are you okay ?
He's dying !
We have to revive him, quick !
No, he breathes  !
He breathes !
He's alive ! Alive !
He laughs ! He's alive !
Come, Matyas.
- What about arm wrestling ?
- Okay  !
Let's go !!
He's too strong !
- I won !
- You're the strongest.
Wanna do arm wrestling with me ?
No, thanks.
You owe me that.
You owe me a return match.
I don't feel like it.
What do you think about, Pierre ?
Anyway, your dad's the strongest, right ?
Come on, Dad !
Don't worry, Claire.
He always was the best.
I don't think it's a good idea.
And Matyas doesn't like playing.
Okay.
You loved fighting with me,
remember ?
- Can we start ?
- Yes.
Stop it, it's not funny.
Bravo !
Bravo who ?
Enough.
Come to bed.
- Say good night.
- Goodnight.
Good evening, Pierre.
Sleep well.
Don't worry,
he'll always know who his father is.
Matyas ?
What are you afraid of ?
Excuse me ?
- Can I say goodnight to Pierre ?
- Sure.
It's not that simple
for your father nowadays, you know ?
He's kind of lost.
Maybe I'm wrong,
but I think he's afraid...
...I usurp his place.
But there's one thing I'm sure:
He'll always love you.
- You'll come again to play with me ?
- Sure.
- If your mother will let us.
- Of course.
Tell me again the story
of Elina and Regina.
No, no. I can see your intents.
It's bedtime now.
You need to sleep.
Baby's also need to sleep.
He needs to rest.
You've got to be sweet with the baby.
You've got to be sweet with your mom.
She needs it right now.
Come and say goodnight to your child.
Claire, this is what I'm doing
the last five minutes.
- I'm sorry.
- It's not your fault.
I never could have done such a thing...
Good evening, Claire.
Thank you.
Matyas, open.
I want to talk with you.
Busy.
What did you play ?
What you did was horrible.
- I did what you let me do.
- How can you say that ?
Matyas, stop running away.
You thought I was him.
You're not able to recognize me.
Of course I am ! You've played with me !
You betrayed me !
- It was the only way to know.
- Know what ?
- He stroked your belly, and you liked it.
- The baby ! He stroked the baby !
- But you liked it.
- Naturally !
Of course, I wish you'd behave
this way with me and Pierre.
See?
That's all you want
me to be with you.
You don't understand anything.
I wish you could be like this.
You could, if you would.
You can also if you wanted,
ask him to attend
the delivery in my place.
How can you say that ?
How cruel !
- Now stop it.
- Now you stop it.
- Matyas, have you gone mad ?
- Stop laughing at me all of you !
- The baby, stop !.
- Mom ! Mom !
- Mom !
- It's all right, dear.
Go back to your room. It's over.
Dad won't be angry anymore.
I'm going to talk a minute
with him and I'll go see you.
- How could you raise your hand ?
- I didn't.
- Don't do it ever again.
- Claire, you know me.
I never could.
- You almost did.
- But I didn't.
I did nothing.
How did you find me ?
Claire.
- Did you see her ?
- She just told me where to find you.
- He hit you again..
- He was crazy.
I could escape with his car.
I'm afraid he'll find me.
I don't know where to go.
Help me, please.
- If you wish, you can stay here.
- Hold me.
I know how to help you
recover your memory.
- You must return to the house you raised in.
- You know where it is ?
I can give you the address,
if you want.
Here it is.
Take me in your arms.
No I can't.
I can't do this.
But your body wants it.
Be bad.
It'll be fine...
It'll be fine...don't worry.
- It will pass me.
- I'm sorry.
Let me do it.
No...
No, I don't want...
- What happened ?
- I had a nightmare.
- You made much noise.
- Sorry.
Matyas ?
What are you doing there ?
I need help.
Come on.
Come with me, kid.
Can I ask you a question?
You always said you loved your life before.
Before everything.
Yes, of course.
I love Claire, my son,
I like my job...
- Never felt the need to remember ?
- No.
- But you were happy ?
- I think so.
Are you happy today ?
Don't you see what you're doing ?
Open your eyes, damn it.
It's no time to worry about the past. Wake up.
Claire needs you now.
Go back home, take care of her.
I'm sure you're expected.
Pierre ?
What happened ?
Pierre !
What is happening ?
- Claire ?
- Leave us alone.
Claire, what happened ?
Open !
- What happened ?
- Go away.
Thomas did that, right ?
Thomas did that ?
And that too ?
You think it was me ?
You think I did it?
No, no...
I was in the lab,
with his wife.
- She called you, you gave him the address.
- I never spoke to her.
- But yes !
- Never.
Impossible !
Bad !
No.
- It was him. He's crazy.
- You make me afraid, Matyas.
- Claire, please believe me.
- Don't touch me !
- I was with his wife in the lab ...
- Stop it.
I'll call a doctor,
You can't stay like this.
I've already called one.
Go away.
I'll find this out,
and I'll come back.
Thomas !
Thomas ?.
Cover up !
Aren't you ashamed ?
Cover up ! To me you're dead.
I don't want to see you, ever.
Mom !
Thomas !
Matyas !
Hello, brother.
Thomas ?
- Mom !
- Thomas !
- Thomas ! My baby !
- Mom !
- My baby !
Do you remember now ?
Don't look at me like that.
You know waht ?
I never felt as good as when
I decided to be a woman.
Until the day that I found you.
I want you to know that you've got
an adorable child and a wonderful woman.
I'm sure she'll have a girl.
Pierre will be happy.
He told me he wanted a sister.
Girls are much nicer children.
You don't know how lucky you are.
You don't deserve them.
You don't even know what love is.
Have you thought about Claire ?
She'll be hurt when she knows
what you've done to Elina.
You're a monster.
Now you sleep.
To take to the lead.
But when you wake up, rush.
Otherwise,
there will be great trouble.
I'll count to 10.
One..
Two...
Three...
Four...
Five...
Breathe slowly.
Claire !
His wife has contractions.
She's gone to the hospital.
No, no...
Please, I'm looking for Claire Hebert.
She's giving birth.
- And you're...?
- Her husband.
One moment, please.
- Any problem ?
- Not at all. Just a moment.
Sir !
Claire ?
Claire, it's me, Matyas.
Claire, are you okay ?
How did it go ?
How is the baby ?
He almost died, Matyas,
because of punches.
No.
Where is Pierre ?
Tell me where Pierre is.
In a safe place.
Six...
Claire,
didn't you entrust him to Thomas ?
Claire, tell me you didn't intrust
him to Thomas ?
It's important.
Where are they?
What for ?
So you can hurt them again ?
Sir.
- Tell me where they are.
- Sir, come with us.
- Claire, where are they ?
- Come on, sir.
Claire !
Let me !
Let me go !
Thomas !
My little girl...
Why are you still getting
dressed like that?
Aren't you well ?
You want to talk ?
Is that why you called me ?
You want to talk, finally ?
Thomas ?
You made the best choice, you know
Girls are nicer than boys.
You were so quiet. You played for hours
with your dolls in your bedroom
Seven...
Thomas ?
Thomas,
give me back my son.
Give him back to me.
- Don't worry, he's okay.
- He has nothing to do with this.
I just wanted him
to know who you really are.
I swear, if you've done anything...
Pierre !
Eight...
Pierre, can you hear me ?
Are you okay, son ?
It's over, now.
Do you understand ? It's over.
I'll be right back. Don't go.
I'll be right back. Everything will be fine.
Nine...
Sweetheart.
Matyas couldn't find you ?
No.
I would never forgive him.
Uncle Thomas...
- You come to play ?
- I'm coming, kid.
How are you doing?
You're doing well.
I'll show you how to curve it.
Look.
Ten.