BACK IN THE FIRST TIMES,
IN THE TIME
OF THE RED LIGHT,
THE DESERT WIND--
SOO-OOP-WA--
WAS A MAN LIKE US,
UNTIL BY MISCHANCE
HE GREW WINGS...
AND FLEW...
LIKE A BIRD.
HE BECAME A HUNTER,
AND LIKE A HAWK,
HE FLEW TO SEEK HIS PREY,
TAKING REFUGE IN THOSE
FAR CORNERS OF THE WORLD
WHERE MAGIC STILL
LINGERS IN THE EARTH.
BUT HAVING
ONCE BEEN A MAN,
SO DOES HE STILL SUFFER
THE PASSIONS OF A MAN.
THE PEOPLE
OF THE GREAT NAMIB--
ME AND MY ANCESTORS
BEFORE ME--
WE HAVE ANOTHER NAME
FOR THOSE VIOLENT WINDS
THAT BLOW FROM NOWHERE.
WE CALL THEM
"DUST DEVILS."
[FLOCK OF BIRDS FLIES]
LIKE MOTHS
INTO THE FLAME,
THE DUST DEVIL DRAWS THEM
INTO HIS FATAL AURA.
HYPNOTIZED BY HIS
RAZOR GLARE, THEY COME--
THE FAITHLESS,
THE GRIEVING,
THE LOST.
SAARTJIE.
YOU'RE ALMOST THERE.
[WOMAN
BREATHING HEAVILY]
[NECK SNAPS]
[TELEPHONE RINGS]
[RING]
HELLO?
ROBINSON HOUSE.
WHO IS THIS?
[FAINT GASP]
[HANGS UP PHONE]
WHO WAS THAT?
NO ONE.
JUST A CROSSED LINE.
GO BACK TO SLEEP.
WHAT TIME
DID YOU GET IN?
THEIR DEATH...
IS GIFT TO THEM.
THEIR BLOOD...
THE TRIBUTE HE TAKES
TO PAINT HIS WAY OUT OF
THE CIRCLE OF INCARNATION.
LORD, WE PRAY FOR
RELEASE FROM THIS DROUGHT.
SEND US THE SOFT RAINS
OF YOUR MERCY!
THE EARTH
CRIES OUT TO YOU!
THE CATTLE DIE
IN THE FIELDS!
THE CROPS WITHER
IN THE SPRINGTIME!
FORGIVE US, LORD,
AND SEND US
THE POWER TO FORGIVE.
SEND US PEACE FROM
THESE TROUBLED TIMES.
SEND US THE PEACE
OF YOUR RAIN
AGAINST OUR BROWS.
WATCH FOR THE EVIL
AND DRIVE IT
FROM OUR HEARTS
AND FROM OUR LANDS.
LOOK TO THE WEST
INTO THE WASTELAND,
FOR FROM THENCE
COMETH THE EVIL.
HIS SHADOW FOLLOWS ACROSS
THE WAYS OF THE RIGHTEOUS
AND MAKETH THEM
AS COLD DUST.
EVEN THE INNOCENT
AND THE BABE AT ARMS--
THE SUN HAS GONE OUT
FROM THEIR PASTURES
AND A SHADOW HAS
BLIGHTED THEIR BEING--
THE SHADOW OF
THAT OLD SERPENT
WHO DECEIVETH THE WORLD
AND LEAD IT INTO DAMNATION
AND NOW CONTROLS
EVERLASTING FIRE!
YOU'RE LYING
TO ME, WENDY!
WHERE WERE YOU?
GET OUT
OF MY HOUSE! OUT!
YOUR HOUSE?
YOUR HOUSE,
YOU BASTARD!
I'M NOT CHANGING MY MIND,
NOT THIS TIME.
NO! WAIT!
WHAT DO YOU THINK
YOU'RE DOING?
MARK, I'M LEAVING YOU!
RUNNING TO HIM
WILL FIX THINGS?
TALK TO ME!
JUST LET ME GO.
NO.
WAIT!
WENDY, PLEASE.
I'M SORRY.
WENDY, DON'T DO THIS!
YOU KNOW YOU'LL BE BACK!
AW, SHIT!
[POLICE RADIO]
TAKE CASTS OF
THE FOOTPRINTS.
SEAL OFF OUTGOING ROADS.
ANY INDICATION THAT
IT'S POLITICALLY MOTIVATED?
IT'S FAR TOO EARLY
TO EVEN CONSIDER IT.
WE SHOULD PROCEED
WITH THE INVESTIGATION
AS A LOCAL INCIDENT
UNTIL WE SEE
WHAT EVIDENCE ARISES.
I'VE PUT
MY BEST MAN ON THIS.
AS LONG
AS IT'S NOT YOU.
YES, SIR.
I'LL GET BACK TO YOU.
HELL OF A WAY TO
START THE DAY, HUH?
FUCKING NIGHTMARE.
WHOLE PLACE
HAS BEEN GUTTED.
HOUSE IS FULL
OF BODY PARTS.
LOOKS LIKE IT'S BEEN
HIT BY A COMMANDO UNIT.
I THINK WE'RE DEALING
WITH TERRORISTS.
THERE ARE NO TERRORISTS
THESE DAYS--CEASE FIRE.
IT'S A FREE COUNTRY.
ACH!
ACH, MAN!
THE VICTIM WAS WHITE?
PROBABLY--HARD TO TELL
FROM WHAT'S LEFT.
THE HOUSE WAS OWNED
BY THE HAARHOFF FAMILY.
THE KIDS ARE
GROWN UP AND GONE AWAY.
MR. HAARHOFF WORKS
AS A SITE FOREMAN
FOR A COPPER MINE
ACROSS THE BORDER
IN SOUTH AFRICA.
WE'RE TRYING
TO CONTACT HIM.
MRS. HAARHOFF?
MY BET IS THAT'S HER
IN THE HOUSE.
SIR!
AT EASE.
THESE LOST ISRAELIS
LYING IN THE SAND DYING
WHEN JUST
ACROSS THE DESERT,
COMES THIS P.L.O. GUY
TO SHOOT THEM.
HE CRIES OUT, "WHAT
WAS THAT, A VACANCY?"
"NO," SAYS THE P.L.O. GUY,
"IT WAS AN AMBUSH."
[TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWS]
THE THINGS I'VE SEEN--
THE THINGS I'VE SEEN,
YOU WON'T BELIEVE.
YOU BEEN IN A WAR?
HOW FAR
IS THIS TRAIN GOING?
IT GOES ALL THE WAY
TO THE SEA.
WHAT'S THE NEXT STOP?
BETHANY--
SOME SHITHOLE LIKE THAT.
ANYBODY EVER
GET OFF THERE?
NAH. TRAIN TANKS UP
WITH WATER.
PEOPLE GET ON
AT BETHANY.
NOBODY GETS OFF.
[RADIO]
THE LITTLE TOWN
OF BETHANY,
JUST INSIDE NAMIBIA'S
SOUTHERN BORDER, IS DOOMED.
THE RECORD
SEVEN-YEAR DROUGHT
HAS ALREADY DEVASTATED
CATTLE HERDS,
AND WITH THE CLOSURE
OF THE LOCAL URANIUM MINE
BROUGHT ON
BY THE WITHDRAWAL OF
SOUTH AFRICAN INVESTMENT,
BETHANY'S LAST SOURCE
OF REVENUE AND FRESH WATER
WILL FINALLY DRY UP.
[CROSSING BELL RINGS]
[CROSSING
BELL RINGS]
HE HAS BEEN HERE
SINCE THE FIRST TIMES,
PASSING FROM ONE
HUMAN HOST TO ANOTHER.
SEARCHING OUT THE DAMNED,
HE WALKS THIS WORLD
DRAWN TO HIS PREY
AS THEY ARE DRAWN TO HIM.
HE SMELLS BETHANY DYING,
AND NOW HE'S COME
FOR THE SOULS HE NEEDS,
SOULS TO EMPOWER
HIS RETURN
TO THE REALM
OF THE SPIRIT.
[GUNSHOTS]
HE HAS KIN...
THOUGH
HIS PEOPLE ARE FEW.
FIRE!
[GUNSHOTS]
THEY SEE EACH OTHER,
BEHIND
THEIR MASKS OF FLESH.
BUT LIKE THE HAWK,
THEY HUNT ALONE.
LOAD.
EYES FRONT.
FIRE!
[GUNSHOT]
HELLO, OPERATOR.
I'D LIKE TO MAKE
A COLLECT CALL.
YES. PRETORIA
885-82.
[OPERATOR]
PLEASE HOLD THE LINE.
[TELEPHONE RINGS]
[BEEP]
[WENDY]
WENDY AND MARK ARE OUT.
TO LEAVE A MESSAGE,
SPEAK AFTER THE TONE.
[BEEP]
THIS IS
THE BETHANY OPERATOR
CALLING SOUTH AFRICA
FROM NAMIBIA.
WILL YOU
ACCEPT THE CHARGES?
HELLO?
BETHANY OPERATOR.
I'M SORRY. THERE'S
NO ONE ANSWERING.
THANK YOU.
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
[MEOW]
* KILLERS AND SWINDLERS
AND THIEVES *
* IT'S HARDER
TO GROW ROSES *
* THAN ROCKS
AND TUMBLEWEEDS *
* WHEN HE WALKED
IN THE BARROOM *
* EERIE SILENCE FELL
* THE SIGHT OF
THE BLOOD-RED COLORS *
* OF THE ROSE
IN HIS LAPEL *
* A PURE,
ENCHANTING PERFUME *
* OF THE ROSE
IN HIS LAPEL *
DEAR MARK, I'M GOING
ON A LONG HOLIDAY
AND DON'T WANT
TO SEE YOU AGAIN
UNTIL I GET
MY HEAD STRAIGHT.
I KNOW I STILL NEED YOU,
BUT I CAN NEVER BE
THE WIFE YOU WANT.
GO ON, GIVE ME...
[ANSWERING MACHINE
BEEPS]
[BEEP]
THIS IS
THE BETHANY OPERATOR
CALLING SOUTH AFRICA
FROM NAMIBIA.
WILL YOU
ACCEPT THE CHARGES?
[MUSIC AND
PINBALL MACHINE NOISE]
HELLO?
BETHANY OPERATOR.
I'M SORRY. THERE'S
NO ONE ANSWERING.
[WENDY]
THANK YOU.
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
[DIAL TONE]
[BEEP]
UHH...
HE HEARS THE SILENT CALL
OF THE DAMNED,
THE FAITHLESS,
AND NEVER FAILS TO ANSWER.
BUT ONLY WHEN
THEY ARE TRULY READY
WILL HE DRAW THEM
INTO HIS DARK EMBRACE.
WHO'S THERE?
[BIRD CHIRPS]
[AWWK]
OHH...
[CAR
WON'T START]
UGH!
WHAT'S SPECIAL
ABOUT YOUR WOMAN
APART FROM
HER BEING WHITE?
SHE DIED NEAR
BETHANY, DOCTOR.
HE DIDN'T
DO HER ANY FAVORS.
WE'VE JUST GOT
ABOUT EVERYTHING HERE--
EVISCERATION,
PARTIAL CREMATION,
SEXUAL MUTILATION,
AND POSSIBLY
EVEN CANNIBALISM.
WE FOUND THE...
REMAINS OF A CLOCK
WEDGED INSIDE HER,
FOR GOD'S SAKE.
WHAT'S YOUR THEORY
ON ACTUAL CAUSE--
I MEAN,
JUST OFF THE RECORD?
SHE WASN'T TIED DOWN.
I'D SAY SHE MAY HAVE
BEEN STRANGLED FIRST.
HER NECK'S DISLOCATED,
AND...
THE SPINAL CORD'S SEVERED
BETWEEN THE ATLAS
AND AXIAL VERTEBRAE.
WE KNOW THAT MUCH.
GOD KNOWS...
MAYBE SHE LET HIM
DO IT TO HER.
THE ONLY REALLY
INTERESTING STUFF
WE'VE GOT SO FAR
IS IN THE SCRAPINGS
FROM THE MURAL.
BUT WE'LL
NEED SPECIALIST HELP
IF WE ARE GOING TO GET
ANY FURTHER WITH IT.
GO AHEAD.
WHAT AM I MEANT
TO BE LOOKING AT?
HE HAD TO MIX OTHER
MATERIALS WITH HER BLOOD
TO BRING OUT
THOSE COLORS.
WE FOUND TRACES
OF IRON OXIDE
AND HEMATITE.
THE WHITES
AND LIGHTER SHADES
WERE ACHIEVED BY MIXING
THE VICTIM'S FAT
WITH KAOLIN AND...
SEA GULL GUANO.
THE MAN'S AN ARTIST.
HE LEFT NO PRINTS.
THIS STUFF'S CLOSELY
RELATED TO WITCHCRAFT.
ARE YOU SERIOUS?
PERFECTLY.
HUMAN BODY PARTS
ALL HAVE THEIR USES
IN RITUAL MAGIC.
A WITCH OR SANGOMA
COULD TELL FROM
THE MISSING PIECES
WHAT OUR MAN WAS AFTER.
YOU MUST HAVE
A LOCAL SANGOMA.
WHY DON'T YOU
ASK HIM ABOUT IT?
HI. JOE?
I'VE BEEN TALKING
TO HIM, BEN.
HE SAID...
HE'S GOING TO END
THE WORLD REAL QUICK NOW.
THE EARTH'S
GOING TO DRY UP...
CRACK.
I DON'T WANT
TO HEAR THAT, JOE.
I WANT TO KNOW...
WHO DID THIS?
SHEESH!
I SEE YOUR PROBLEM.
ONE LAST NIGHT.
YOU KNOW ANYTHING
ABOUT IT?
THIS...
I WOULD SAY THIS...
IS A CLUE...
FOR OFFICER MUKUROB.
IT'S A SHAME THAT
HE DOESN'T BELIEVE
IN THIS BULLSHIT, HUH?
IT DOESN'T
MATTER WHETHER
I BELIEVE IN IT.
I NEED TO KNOW
WHAT IT MEANS.
MY FRIEND, THIS STUFF--
TO KNOW IT,
YOU HAVE TO BELIEVE IT.
IT'S GOING
TO BE DIFFICULT
FOR A MAN
IN YOUR POSITION
WHO'S TAKEN
THE CHOICES YOU HAVE
TO UNDERSTAND
THIS MAGIC.
HE TOOK HER FINGERS.
WHY DID HE DO THAT?
THERE'S A WHOLE LOT
OF POWER...
IN FINGERS--
KNOTS AND KNUCKLES
AND SUCH.
IF YOU WANT
TO WIN A WAR,
YOU NEED A WHOLE
FISTFUL OF KNUCKLES.
YOU, UH...
YOU SMOKE TOO MUCH.
MAYBE YOU SHOULD
HELP ME LAY SOME ROCKS.
IT MIGHT BE EASIER
FOR YOU TO UNDERSTAND.
YOU'VE GOT TO KEEP
YOUR EYES WIDE OPEN
WHEN YOU DEAL WITH MAGIC.
YEAH, JOE.
THERE'S, UH...
MAGIC ALL AROUND US.
YEAH, YOU BET.
ALL AROUND YOU,
FRIEND.
HELLO?
IS ANYONE THERE?
ANYONE AWAKE?
HELLO?
ARE YOU THE DRIVER?
DO YOU DRIVE?
NO. NO, I DON'T DRIVE.
UH, NOT THIS.
MY CAR IS OVER THERE.
I THINK I'M STUCK
IN THE SAND.
COULD YOU HELP?
WHERE YOU HEADING FOR?
NOWHERE.
I JUST CAME FROM THERE.
ANYPLACE ELSE I'M GOOD FOR.
CLIMB ABOARD.
I SAW YOU AT
THE ROADHOUSE YESTERDAY.
FIGURED WE WERE
ON THE SAME ROAD.
I COULD SEE
YOU NEEDED A RIDE.
THE NAME'S WENDY.
PLEASED TO MEET YOU.
ARE YOU
A SERVICEMAN?
I'M A TOURIST.
ARE YOU FROM THE STATES?
TEXAS, MAYBE?
I TRAVEL A LOT.
GREW UP ON THE ROAD.
IT'S THE ONLY PLACE
I FEEL AT HOME.
WHERE WAS IT
YOU WERE HEADING TO?
WHY? HOW FAR
ARE YOU GOING?
STRAIGHT THROUGH
ALL THE WAY
TO THE SEA.
YOU'RE NOT RUNNING
FROM SOMETHING, ARE YOU?
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
I DON'T KNOW.
YOU JUST LOOK LIKE
YOU MIGHT BE RUNNING
FROM SOMETHING.
THAT'S ALL.
LIKE MAYBE YOU
COMMITTED A MURDER,
AND THE POLICE
WERE AFTER YOU.
NO. I WISH!
YOU WANT TO TALK
ABOUT IT?
NO.
THAT'S O.K.
WE'VE GOT NOTHING
BUT TIME.
HEY, JOHANN...
GO CALL BEN
ON THE RADIO.
TELL HIM WE FOUND
SOMETHING HERE, MAN.
[VOMITING]
YOU MUST BELIEVE
IN SOMETHING.
GOD?
THE DEVIL?
THE SOUL, AT LEAST.
DON'T BE SILLY.
I DON'T BELIEVE IN THAT
ANY MORE THAN I BELIEVE
IN MAGIC OR PETER PAN.
SURELY YOU'D
HAVE TO ADMIT
SOME SUPERIOR FORCE
GUIDES YOUR HAND.
FUCK SUPERIOR FORCES.
WHEN YOU'RE DEAD,
YOU'RE DEAD. THAT'S IT.
KEEP YOUR EYE
ON THE ROAD.
YOU DON'T WANT
TO FALL ASLEEP.
HEY, THAT LOOKS--
DON'T STOP.
DRIVE ON.
WHAT THE HELL
WAS THAT?
OH, GOD.
JESUS CHRIST.
HEY, TEXAS!
TEXAS!
OOH!
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
STOP IT, MAN!
WHAT'D YOU DO
THAT FOR?
FOR CHRIST'S SAKE,
WHAT HAVE YOU DONE?
NOTHING WORSE THAN
WHAT THE BOYS DID
TO SAARTJIE,
OR WHAT HE
WOULD DO TO US
GIVEN THE CHANCE.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN US?
I'M NOT ONE OF YOU.
HE WOULD'VE TALKED TO ME.
SO WE GOT
HEAVY WITH HIM.
SO WHAT?
AT LEAST WE'VE
GOT SOMETHING
TO GO ON NOW.
SHE'S A WHITE GIRL...
IN HER LATE 20s
OR EARLY 30s.
SHE WAS RIGHT THERE
AT THE SCENE OF THE CRIME.
HE SAYS HE HELPED HER
PUSH-START HER CAR.
A RED VOLKSY
WITH CITY PLATES.
SHOULD BE PISS-EASY
TO PULL IN, MAN.
IT'S A BREAK, MAN.
THE FIRST REAL BREAK
WE'VE HAD.
RELEASE THIS MAN.
HE'S A MATERIAL WITNESS.
I DON'T CARE!
RELEASE HIM!
KATIE.
THE HAARHOFF WOMAN
IS HERE, SIR.
SHE'S IN HERE, SIR.
SHE'S BEEN WAITING
FOR YOU, SIR.
I'M AFRAID YOU'LL HAVE
TO EXPLAIN IT TO HER.
SAARTJIE...
I'M SORRY.
I'M DOING
EVERYTHING I CAN.
I...
I WAS DREAMING.
THAT WAS NO DREAM.
AAH!
YOU IN A LOT
OF TROUBLE, PAL.
AM I...AWAKE?
NO, MY FRIEND.
NOW YOU DREAMING.
I'M SORRY.
I DIDN'T MEAN
TO FRIGHTEN YOU.
WHO THE HELL ARE YOU?
HOW DID YOU GET
INTO MY CAR?
OUT OF IT LAST NIGHT?
YOU FELL ASLEEP.
I THOUGHT
I WAS GOING CRAZY.
WE SHOULD BE GOING.
YOU'RE STILL GOING
TO THE SEA, AREN'T YOU?
WHAT MAKES YOU SO SURE
I STILL WANT
TO GIVE YOU A RIDE?
* TRAVEL ALONE
* ON THE JERICHO ROAD
* I'M GONNA TRAVEL
WITH MY JESUS *
* OH, YES, I'M GONNA
* TRAVEL ALONE
* ON THE JERICHO ROAD
* OH, YES, I'M GONNA
* TRAVEL ALONE
* ON THE JERICHO ROAD
* OH, YES, I'M GONNA
* TRAVEL ALONE
* ON THE JERICHO ROAD
* YES, I'M GONNA
* I'M GOIN' TO TRAVEL
WITH MY JESUS... *
PUT THE TOP ON.
GIVE IT A TWIST.
KORNELIUS,
YOUR MAN IS HERE.
AH.
BEN. AT LAST.
GLAD YOU MADE IT.
I'D ALMOST
GIVEN UP ON YOU.
I WAS AT
A FUNERAL.
COME ON.
WE'D BETTER GO
IN THE HOUSE.
KORNELIUS, YOU SAID
YOU WERE READY.
WAIT IN THE CAR.
I'LL JUST BE A MOMENT.
I BROUGHT EVERYTHING
I COULD FIND.
I DIDN'T EXPECT
THIS MANY.
HERE, BEN.
LOOK AT THE DATE.
CHRIST, THIS IS FROM 1952.
THEY GO ALL THE WAY
BACK TO THE WAR.
I EVEN FOUND ONE
FROM 1908.
SOME HOOKER
GOT HERSELF STABBED
IN KLEIN KARIB STATION.
THEY FOUND
A POCKET WATCH
UP HER PUSS.
THAT COULDN'T
HAVE BEEN HIM.
THAT WAS
BEFORE HE WAS BORN.
DO YOU EVER ASK YOURSELF
HOW MANY MURDERERS
ARE STRUCK BY LIGHTNING
EVERY YEAR...
DIE IN CAR ACCIDENTS
OR OTHER ACTS OF GOD?
A GREAT MANY,
PROBABLY.
IT WOULD MAKE
AN INTERESTING STATISTIC.
KORNELIUS!
[HONKS HORN]
[SHOUTING]
HURRY UP!
I'D BETTER NOT
KEEP HER WAITING.
NO, I SUPPOSE NOT.
THIS IS ALL
I CAN DO.
YOU HAVE TO LOOK
AFTER YOURSELF
NOW, BEN.
I SAW MR. HAARHOFF'S EYES
AT THE FUNERAL.
HE DIDN'T LOVE HER.
NOBODY LOVED HER.
NOBODY CARED ABOUT HER.
YEAH, BEN.
REMEMBER TO LOCK UP.
YOU'VE DONE IT.
MADE IT ALL THE WAY
TO THE EDGE
OF THE WORLD.
OH, MY GOD!
THIS IS AMAZING.
THIS IS THE HOME
OF THE GREAT SNAKE FATHER
KOUTEIGN KOUROO.
IN THE DAWN OF THINGS,
HE MADE THIS PLACE
FROM THE LASHING
OF HIS COILS.
DON'T...DON'T SPOIL IT.
BUT YOU DON'T
UNDERSTAND.
Shh.
[PLAYING MUSIC]
AH!
WHAT'S THAT?
PROBABLY JUST SOME
BORED SOLDIER MESSING AROUND.
* I CAN SETTLE DOWN
* AND BE DOING
JUST FINE *
* TILL I HEAR
THOSE TRAINS *
* ROLLING DOWN THE LINE
* THEN I HEAR
HIS BRAKES *
* ON THE TRACK
* AND IF I DID...
CARE TO DANCE?
* I'D LEAVE,
I'D BLOW MY STACK *
* I LOVE YOU, BABY
* BUT YOU GOTTA
UNDERSTAND *
* WHEN THE LORD MADE ME
* HE MADE
A RAMBLING MAN *
* SOME FOLKS MIGHT SAY
* THAT I'M NO GOOD
* THAT
I WOULDN'T SETTLE *
* DOWN IF I COULD
* BUT WHEN
THAT OPEN ROAD *
* STARTS TO CALLIN' ME
* THERE'S SOMETHIN'
O'ER THE HILL *
* THAT I GOTTA SEE...
[REGGAE MUSIC PLAYS]
EXCUSE ME.
I WONDER
IF YOU CAN HELP ME.
I'M LOOKING FOR SOMEONE.
SORRY?
A WHITE LADY.
HER NAME'S WENDY.
WENDY ROBINSON.
I'VE GOT A PHOTOGRAPH.
SORRY.
I DIDN'T KNOW HER.
SHE CAME IN HERE
TWO DAYS AGO AND
USED THE TELEPHONE.
JUST PASS IT AROUND.
YOU MUST HAVE
COME THROUGH
THE WRONG DOOR.
I BEG YOUR PARDON?
YOU MUST GO
TO THE OTHER SIDE.
THE WHITE BAR.
JUST BECAUSE SHE'S WHITE
DOESN'T MEAN
YOU COULDN'T SEE HER.
NO ONE HERE HAS SEEN
SUCH A PERSON.
PLEASE, MAN. I'M LOOKING
FOR MY WIFE.
HEY, YOU.
HEY, YOU RECOGNIZE HER,
DON'T YOU?
NO ONE HAS SEEN
ANYTHING HERE.
THERE'S NOTHING
FOR YOU HERE.
STOP PLAYING BLOODY GAMES
WITH ME, O.K.?
THAT'S THE PINBALL MACHINE
I HEARD WHEN SHE CALLED ME!
WHO ARE YOU?
MY NAME IS MARK ROBINSON.
I'M HER HUSBAND.
WE'RE MARRIED!
YOU'RE A POLICEMAN,
I THINK.
WHAT? LOOK, MAN, I RUN
A SPORTS SHOP, O.K.?
WHAT FOR YOU
WEARING A UNIFORM?
I WAS IN THE ARMY!
COMPULSORY
MILITARY TRAINING!
SOUTH AFRICA!
GIVE ME BACK
MY PASSPORT.
DO YOU BELIEVE IN GOD,
SOUTH AFRICA?
OF COURSE I DO!
THEN I HOPE
GOD CAN HELP YOU.
AAH! FUCK!
GET THE FUCK--
YOU'RE NO ONE'S
HUSBAND NOW,
SOUTH AFRICA.
I WANT MY WIFE BACK.
AHH.
OHH...
OHH!
THIS IS THE WORK
OF A DUST DEVIL.
BLACK MAGICIAN.
A SHAPE SHIFTER.
HE GAINS POWER
IN THIS WORLD
THROUGH THE RITUAL
ECSTASY OF MURDER.
HE'S AS TRAPPED
AS HIS VICTIMS.
THE KILLINGS ARE
A MEANS TO AN END,
AND THAT END IS
HIS TRANSFORMATION,
HIS
TRANSCENDENCE...
HIS ESCAPE.
UHH!
CUFF HIM, BOTES.
CUFF HIM!
ONE WRONG MOVE
AND I'LL SKIN
YOUR FAT, WHITE NECK.
NO!
YOU'VE BEEN WATCHING
TOO MANY DRIVE-IN MOVIES.
MY FRIEND, YOU...
YOU GOT TO STOP
THINKING LIKE
A WHITE MAN...
AND START THINKING
LIKE A MAN INSTEAD.
OTHERWISE,
YOU'RE GOING TO BE
IN BIG TROUBLE
WITH THIS.
HE'S FLESH AND BLOOD
LIKE US.
HE MUST BE.
YOU CAN'T HUNT
A DUST DEVIL
LIKE A ORDINARY
CRIMINAL.
HE'S OF THE SPIRIT.
WE'RE NOTHING
TO HIM.
WE ARE HERE
JUST TO USE AND DISCARD.
HIS WORLD
IS OLDER THAN OURS.
HE HAS BEEN HERE
SINCE THE FIRST TIMES,
HE AND HIS KIN,
WALKING IN OUR SHADOWS,
THEIR HEARTS AS DRY
AS THE DESERT SANDS.
LEECHES...GROWING FAT
ON THE WORLD'S PAIN.
Fill the bowl.
[VOICES WHISPER]
UNTIL THIS RITUAL
IS COMPLETED,
HE IS TRAPPED...
LIKE US IN
THE MATERIAL WORLD,
BOUND BY THE FLESH.
THERE'S ONLY ONE WAY
TO RUB OUT
A DUST DEVIL.
HE MUST WORK
THROUGH HUMAN FORM
WHILE HE'S
IN THIS WORLD...
SO HE'S VULNERABLE
TO HUMAN FAILINGS.
ONLY THROUGH RITUAL...
THROUGH GAINING POWER
OVER THE FLESH...
CAN SPIRIT AWAKE
TO FULLER CONSCIOUSNESS.
TO WORK THE RITUAL,
HE MUST KEEP MOVING.
MOVING.
BUT IF HE CAN
BE TRICKED...
TO STEP ACROSS
THIS KIERIE...
HE CAN BE ROOTED
TO THE SPOT
AND STRIPPED
OF HIS POWER.
I DON'T KNOW
ABOUT THIS, JOE.
YOU...
YOU MUST BIND HIM
WITH A STICK.
STRIKE A BLOW.
IT'S THE ONLY WAY.
BIND HIM
WITH THE STICK...
AND BURN THE ROOT.
DRIVE AWAY
HIS SHADOW.
FAIL IN THIS, AND
HE WILL TAKE YOU,
HIS MURDERER,
TO BE HIS NEW HOST.
TAKE THE STICK.
YOU MUST COMPLETE
THE RITUAL.
BURN THE ROOT.
YOU MUST GO NOW,
BEN MUKUROB,
BUT GO CAREFUL.
DEATH HUNTS YOU
JUST AS YOU HUNT...
THE DUST DEVIL.
[WATER RUNS]
DON'T TOUCH THAT!
WHY?
WHY, FOR GOD'S SAKE?
I SWEAR TO GOD, WENDY,
I NEVER HAD ANY CHOICE.
THEY WANTED TO DIE.
I JUST PUT THEM
OUT OF THEIR MISERY.
YOU'RE OUT
OF YOUR FUCKING MIND.
DON'T YOU SEE THAT?
NO. YOU'RE THE ONE
WHO DOESN'T UNDERSTAND.
IT WAS THEIR CHOICE.
THEY CAME TO ME.
I CAN TELL WHEN
SOMEONE'S TIME IS UP.
WHO THE HELL ARE YOU?
YOU KNOW WHO I AM.
GOD, YOU'RE NOT FROM TEXAS.
I'M FROM THE OTHER SIDE
OF THE MIRROR.
I COME FROM YOU.
WHY--WHY--
BECAUSE YOU NEED HELP.
ANYBODY CAN SEE THAT.
YOU'RE RIGHT ON THE EDGE...
LIKE THE DESERT SKY...
AT NIGHT...
JUST AFTER SUNSET...
OR MAYBE JUST
BEFORE THE DAWN.
YOU HAVE A CHOICE TO MAKE.
DAY OR NIGHT?
AAH!
YOU HAVE A SPARK
OF LIGHT INSIDE OF YOU.
I'M JUST A MIDWIFE.
ALL I HAVE TO DO...
IS MAKE
A SMALL INCISION
AND LET IT OUT...
RELAX.
IT'S ALL RIGHT NOW.
EVERYTHING'S ALL RIGHT.
I'M RIGHT HERE.
I SHOULD'VE
DONE THIS DAYS AGO,
BUT I GET LONELY SOMETIMES.
FORGIVE ME.
I WON'T KEEP YOU
WAITING ANY LONGER.
THERE'S NO GOOD OR EVIL...
ONLY SPIRIT AND MATTER.
ONLY MOVEMENT
TOWARD THE LIGHT...
AND AWAY FROM IT.
IT'S ALL ALIKE.
ALL OF IT.
AAH!
OH, PLEASE.
YOU PICKED THE WRONG GIRL,
YOU SON OF A BITCH!
GRR!
[AIR HORN SOUNDS]
[ARGUING]
[EERIE SCREAMING]
[WOMAN]
OH, MY GOD.
I'M DYING,
YOU BLOODY FOOL!
[SCREAMING
IN AFRIKAANS]
CALM DOWN, ANDRE.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
[SWEARING IN AFRIKAANS]
ANDRE, QUICK, COME AWAY.
RUN, CHILDREN!
RUN! RUN!
AAH!
YA-HOO!
[CELL DOOR SLAMS]
IS THIS YOUR WIFE?
IT'S FOR YOU.
YOU ARE A GOOD MAN,
AND I DON'T
WANT TO HURT YOU,
NOR DO I WANT
TO SEE YOU HURT YOURSELF,
BUT I MUST LEAVE YOU
AND SOUTH AFRICA FOR GOOD.
DON'T BLAME YOURSELF,
AND DON'T LOOK FOR ME
OR TRY TO FOLLOW ME.
YOU MUST BE STRONG NOW
AND TRY TO BE KIND
TO YOURSELF.
LOVE, WENDY.
HER TRACKS LED
STRAIGHT ON
TO OPEN DESERT.
VULTURE CITY.
I WOULDN'T RATE ANYONE'S
CHANCES IN IT ON FOOT.
CAN'T YOU
CALL IN AIR SUPPORT
OR SOMETHING?
GET A COUPLE
OF HELICOPTERS
TO COMB THE AREA.
NO CHOPPERS.
NOT HERE.
WE'RE NOT GOING TO
FIND HER LIKE THIS.
AT LEAST CALL
SOME EXTRA COPS
TO HELP US.
WHAT KIND OF FUCKED-UP
THIRD WORLD COUNTRY
IS THIS?
THERE ARE NO MORE POLICE,
JUST YOU AND ME...
NO COUNTRIES, JUST THIS...
JUST THE HUNTING GROUND.
DO YOU THINK
I FUCKING CARE
WHAT HAPPENS
TO YOU AND YOUR WIFE?
THAT'S FUCKING
OPEN DESERT OUT THERE!
LISTEN, RAMBO,
IF IT WAS YOUR WIFE,
YOU'D FEEL THE SAME.
MY WIFE
LEFT ME 15 YEARS AGO
WHEN OUR SON
GOT KILLED ON THE BORDER,
SO DON'T
TELL ME THIS SHIT!
WHAT DO YOU KNOW
ABOUT GRIEF?
AT LEAST
I STILL STAND
A CHANCE WITH MINE.
LET'S GET THE FUCK
OUT OF HERE!
[COUGHING]
KEEP THE WINDOWS CLOSED!
I CAN'T BLOODY WELL
BREATHE IN HERE, MAN!
WHAT ARE YOU
BURNING THIS THING FOR?
TO KEEP IT OUT.
NO! AAH!
[GUNSHOTS]
[GUN COCKS]
[GUNSHOT]
WHAT THE FUCK
IS GOING ON?
GET OUT OF THE WAY!
GOD!
STOP SHOOTING!
THERE'S NOTHING
OUT THERE!
LISTEN!
PUT DOWN YOUR GUN,
OR I SWEAR TO GOD
I'LL BLOW
YOUR FUCKING HEAD OFF!
I MEAN IT!
I TOOK OUT THE BULLETS.
AFTER 15 YEARS,
DO YOU THINK I'D
LET SOMEONE LIKE YOU
FUCK IT UP FOR ME?
PUT THEM ON!
ONE ON THE WRIST
AND ONE ON THE BUMPER.
DON'T LEAVE ME LIKE THIS!
YEAH, THERE YOU STILL
HAVE A CHANCE.
HE ONLY TAKES THOSE
WHO'VE GOT NOTHING.
COME BACK HERE!
PLEASE, MAN!
SHE HAS STEPPED
THROUGH THE MIRROR NOW,
AND SHE AND HE ARE ONE--
PARTNERS
IN A DANCE OF DEATH
FROM WHICH NEITHER
CAN WITHDRAW
UNTIL THE CIRCLE
IS COMPLETED.
WENDY.
YOU'RE ALMOST THERE.
[GASPS]
WENDY.
OH...OH, GOD!
NO!
NO, PLEASE, NO.
THERE MUST
BE SOMEBODY HERE!
[CROW CAWS]
[FLIES AWAY]
[BEN]
MRS. ROBINSON?
WHO ARE YOU?
[HINGE CREAKS]
DO YOU HEAR IT?
TAKE THIS.
KEEP YOUR EYES OPEN.
STAY HERE
UNTIL I CALL YOU.
[LAUGHTER]
[RAGTIME
PIANO MUSIC PLAYS]
[LAUGHTER]
JOE?
WHO'S THERE?
WHO'S THAT?
KATIE.
YOU'RE ALMOST THERE.
ALMOST THERE.
[LAUGHTER AND APPLAUSE]
[COUGHING]
[HINGE CREAKS]
[GASPS]
CAN'T FIX THIS.
IT'S ON SAFETY.
IT'S THE LITTLE LEVER
NEXT TO THE BREECH.
BACK OFF!
HANDS IN THE AIR!
I MEAN IT!
WHAT ARE YOU
GOING TO DO, SHOOT ME?
FUCK YES!
THERE'S A STORM COMING.
I THINK
IT'S GOING TO RAIN.
[THUNDER]
LOOK AT MY HAND.
ALL FIVE BEAMS
WILL STAY WITH YOU.
YOU HAVE TO
TRUST ME, WENDY.
I THOUGHT YOU WERE
GOING TO SHOOT ME.
[DEEP, SLOW VOICE]
I LOVE YOU, WENDY.
[VOICES ON POLICE RADIO]
WENDY?
WENDY!
I--I'VE COME
TO TAKE YOU HOME.
WAIT FOR ME!
WENDY!
AGGH!
[VOICES ON POLICE RADIO]
THE DESERT
KNOWS HER NAME NOW.
THE DEVIL HAS
TAKEN HER HAND.
HE HAS STOLEN
BOTH HER EYES.
WHEN SHE LOOKS
INTO A MIRROR,
SHE WILL SEE HIS SHADOW.
THE DUST DEVIL MUST
KEEP MOVING TO SURVIVE,
BLOWN BY THE DESERT WIND,
ON AND ON
THROUGHOUT ETERNITY,
WITHOUT REST OR PITY.
CAPTIONING MADE POSSIBLE BY
PARAMOUNT PICTURES CORPORATION
CAPTIONING PERFORMED BY
THE NATIONAL CAPTIONING
INSTITUTE, INC.
CAPTIONS COPYRIGHT 1993
PARAMOUNT PICTURES CORPORATION