- Scellinc...
- Sir.
How is the girl?
Everything is well, sir.
She sleeps soundly,
her appetite is good.
All is as it should be.
And the teeth?
Everything is well, sir.
The month's remittance
has been sent.
- Do you require anything else?
- No, sir.
There will be
no further payments.
Sir?
You must start preparing
the girl to leave.
Leave?
You will bring her to us
on the 6th of next month,
in 13 days' time.
In the meantime,
you must teach her
how to behave outside.
Do you understand, Scellinc?
Yes, sir.
You must get used
to being outside.
Mia!
Stop it!
Stop.
- What can I get you?
- A tripel.
May I?
I'm a traveller, sir,
a stranger to this city.
I live far away...
in the shadow
of a great cathedral.
No matter.
I think I shall join you.
Thank you.
And now, sir...
What's your name?
Albert Scellinc.
Albert...
We've met before,
I'm sure of it.
Although for the moment,
I can't quite recall where.
On the field
of conflict, perhaps...
covered in mud, blood and shit.
Or was it long before
at the orphanage?
No...
No, in fact, I believe
it was after the war,
when you had a wife.
Wife?
Didn't you take a wife
after the war?
I don't...
I don't have a wife!
Marie is dead...
it's true...
But then there's the other one.
She's waking.
I don't have a wife!
A child, then.
An abandoned child.
It's on the house.
Thank you, Celeste.
Have you never wondered
what it would be like
to be someone else?
Hmm?
Her,
for example?
Please, stop!
No?
Then perhaps the lovely Celeste?
So, it's her.
I thought so.
Marie...
How is the girl?
Everything is well, sir.
She sleeps soundly,
her appetite is good.
Everything is as it should be.
I know, I know.
I'm here.
Who are you?
Don't try to talk.
Go back to sleep.
My name is Laurence.
I'm going to take care
of everything.
I want her moved
to a private room.
I will cover the costs.
What matters above all
is that she receives
the very best care.
If I might...
Come on, Celeste.
You need to get well.
Good. Good, good, good, good.
You will find these
satisfactory.
We need your help
with the teeth.
You must ask the masters
for help.
Masters?
Yes, our masters.
I have to leave soon.
On the 6th.
The house has been empty
since my mother died.
It's too big for one person.
The gardens will be lovely
in winter.
I would be honoured
if you would agree
to come with me...
as my guest.
For as long as you need.
Is there really anything
keeping you here?
Mr Scellinc?
Have you informed our masters?
Have you informed our masters
that I need assistance?
I don't understand.
Have you informed our masters
that I need assistance?
What's the matter?
Dirty, sneaking bitch!
- My God...
- What are you doing?
I will...
I will go with you.
Do you not recognise me?
I know who you are.
Go and fetch the girl.
Come.
Mia...
Put that thing away.
On the table.
Lie down on the table.
This will take some time.
Please leave us alone.
Open.
Wider.
It's a different system now.
The glass implants
are permanent.
You must attend scrupulously
to the girl's hygiene
in the days to come.
Saltwater will keep her mouth
free of infection.
If you can manage that,
there'll be no need
for me to return
before your departure.
Argh!
Not long now.
It hurts.
Laurence, please.
I'm sure
that in our life together,
you will no longer feel
such need of it.
May I help you, madam?
It's on the house.
Mmm.
I have brought the child,
as I was asked.
I am Albert Scellinc.
Please wait in the hall.
She has been well cared for.
So I can see.
Everything is as it should be.
You mustn't be afraid.
Perfect!
No doubt you have
papers for me to sign.
They are waiting
for you at reception.
Will you be leaving
anything with her?
Your daughter.
Will you be leaving anything
with her?
She's not my daughter.
But you're signing for her.
I am just her keeper.
Look.
It's a lie.
Marie.