Subtitles by Renatinha Tankinha
Tonight the universe is
no bigger than my head.
It's time to make room
for some visitors.
So, dio they talk to you?
What, in their own voice
you mean? No.
Well, they...they talk through me.
They speak inside my mind
We're on target.
I can feel them.
Steady...
Sorry about the build up.
I could feel them.
I could...I could hear them inside.
Pretty much on me.
They had this...meeting.
and then they left.
Stay alert.
See if you can get it.
And that was it?
No, that wasn't it.
They left something behind.
Something inside of me that's
been there ever since.
Approaching the house. Stay tight.
When I'm awake, it hurts.
But when I'm...
When I'm not, it
floods me with these
nightmares.
Nightmares, no. Nightmares, it's
not nightmares.
It...it's not a thing, it...
it's a feeling.
It...it's not pain, it's not...
it's not fear.
It...it's something else. It's
something much, much worse.
Go, go. Move.
Go. You hit.
Why don't you take
a few painkillers
before bed, just
knock yourself out?
I've tried everything.
Everything.
Everything?
And it just never works.
No fatigue. Stroke.
Got you.
Please stay tight. Stay tight!
Fuck! What the fuck!
You should get some help.
Oh, I've...
I've seen doctors.
And they say I'm in
peak of physical health.
All I need is a little more sleep.
-What the hell did you do?
-Something was there.
What are you doing?
I saw it, sir. It was
right behind Stevenson.
What the fuck?
So, did you try it?
No.
All I allow myself is a few
hours of sleep every few days.
Go ahead, move! Bring it in!
Target's on you.
Take it! Take it!
Target's on you! Go, go, go!
Pull out! Pull out!
If a doctor tells you to sleep,
maybe you should sleep.
-You don't understand.
There is something inside of
me that...
a comfortable pillow
will not fix!
-Will! I believe you, I do.
I'm making this
film so that other
people will believe you,too.
I don't care if people
believe me or not.
Yes, you do. We've been
discussing it for years.
If you don't care what
other people think,
then what do you want?
I just want someone to
tell me how to make it stop!
How to pull it out
of my head!
I cannot...cannot close
my eyes
for them to tear them out!
Alright, men!
Put a bullet through my head!
I fear that...
that...
The...the...anticipation...
of...of...this feeling...
eats away at my life.
Hold your fire!
I need that man alive,
do you hear me?
Put your goddam gun away, rookie.
Bullets through and through.
But he's alive.
Do you understand?
Tell me what it feels like.
Does it hurt?
It hurts! OK?
It...it hurts.
Do you know how
to follow orders, soldier?
to follow orders?
You almost killed one of
my men in my target.
Copy that.
Don't worry about it, soldier.
This is how we follow orders, soldier.
No!
I've always found it strange
that humans even bother
to
try and imagine the end of the world.
Staging areas,
ships to flee on,
lotteries for tickets
off the planet.
We're all so stupid.
The beginning of the end
as they say.
But that's long
begun by now.
Truth is when it hits,
You will simply cease
to do the stupid little things
that you do.
Just like that.
Ten month...
if it's the big one...
like the sun storm of 1859,
the carrying event
as it's called,
Then there's no
such thing as tomorrow.
She lifts up the sun
like a fiery wing.
It whips back and snaps.
She breaks loose.
Cosmic inferno like a
moveable hell
sprays millions and millions of miles
as if it were nothing.
A cough. A sneeze.
And then, it hits us.
Yes indeed.
It's going to hit us.
And when it hits us,
When it comes crashing through
our flimsy atmosphere,
the good will collapse,
the magnetic poles reverse,
And you know what that means?
The entire surface of the planet
heaves. Its molten heart bursts!
And we all drown in
a lake of eternal fire!
Then we go to Jesus!
Maybe we could just get a
little lecture.
That's all for now, folks.
I have a scar. I'm telling you.
Just show it off and
bang! There it was on the radar.
I don't know, man.
I wouldn't get too excited.
Seen him before.
Ha, ha, ha. As was our cliche.
Opened his eyes. Almost
blew over our head.
Never seen him so
sure of himself.
Sir?
Are you okay?
Can we get you something?
Who are you?
We're the good guys.
We're here to help.
Whose blood is that on your shirt?
Mine.
They shot me.
They shot you because you ran.
Bad things happen when you disobey.
It's best if you
learn that now.
Let me go.
Sit still and let's talk.
We lost a rookie tonight.
He was a good kid.
I don't know about you,
but we want to end
the bloodshed.
-And you can help us
by giving us some answers.
-I don't know anything.
Oh, come now,
that's not true.
What about...
the planets in our solar system?
I'm sure you know those.
-Mars...
-Saturn. Thank you, agent.
I have a feeling he's aware. Now.
I'm curious
what he knows about
things from
a little further away.
Let me go!
-Let me go!
-You need to calm down!
Just...relax.
I told you...
to sit still, old man.
And you don't listen very well, do you
spider Nevi?
Please have Heather
prep the prep helmet.
Now! Please and thank you.
William Cassidy. I
must apologize.
William Cassidy is our guest...
He's part of our team.
You know, you look a little bit rough.
I have to admit. But I
I did not expect that you
would look quite so old.
Might be time to update the
profile picture on your website.
William, I would like
you and I
to hit the reset button right now.
I want to like you and
I want you to like me.
I'm a firm believer in
straightforward conversation.
If you and I would have
a straightforward conversation
between friends,
then we'll have a
wonderful outcome today.
It's so easy.
Don't you agree?
I will assume that you agree,
and that you're not
being difficult right now
So, let's start with
a very easy question.
What happened last night?
I'm going to ask you
a few questions on camera, OK?
Is that all?
Yeah.
OK? Yeah.
So sorry about the confusion
before, but
Can I ask you
if my name rings a bell
at all?
Why? What is it again?
Joe.
Joe Sullivan?
I got an email
from you the other night.
No.
I never give out...
personal information online ever.
OK.
I'm here with...
Bill Cassidy.
Let me just say that
I have been following
your story for years.
And I'm doing a documentary.
Extra-Terrestrial activity.
Things...beyond our atmosphere.
So, it's obviously
a pleasure to meet you.
Yeah...Uh...
So the first question is:
You were abducted by
aliens thirty-nine years ago?
I never said abducted.
Something came to me.
OK, good, That's what I want.
I want to hear what
happened in your own words.
My own words?
I met
an advanced
life
form...from somewhere else.
You met them. What
does that mean?
They came here
through the front door,
just like you.
And you just let them in?
No.
I didn't have much choice.
They threatened you?
No.
They control me.
So, what did they look like?
Hit William hard.
Please.
That's it, agent.
Thank you!
I'm sorry, William.
Sometimes you really have
to hit that reset button.
Now that you are clear
on what our expectations are,
you should accept them.
On the one hand,
you could disclose the
events of the twelve
hours or so,
And on the other hand,
just not really hand at all, it's
more of a toolbox
of devices
that you really never
want to have to see.
Tell me everything
you know, William.
I know all of you people.
Strange, William.
Very, very strange
you with your
history.
You've been staring
at the sky
for decades now.
Posting your theories online?
Unbelievable ideas,
some would say.
We've had our eye on you
most of your life, now.
Sorry. No autographs today.
Last night, there was a
coronal mass injection.
You know about it. You were
a part of it. Historic.
Bigger than the Carrington event.
This is kidnapping.
It knocked something
out of the sky. Didn't it, William?
Do you want to know what I
can't get my head around?
There are so many
people out there just like yourself,
Colorful folks, just like you,
who have knowledge of
or had experience with visitors.
Yours was what?
Thirty-nine years ago?
How wonderfully vindicating
it must be for you...
to have one crash in
your backyard just last night!
Or is that just too
much coincidence
for your weak little
story to pair?
It's separate.
You find it funny
they're hitting me.
Squaring with the enemy.
Over the years it's
gotten more drastic.
Usually I just wake
up in bed screaming.
Sometimes, I wake up
in other places.
Yeah? Like where?
In front of the computer, staring
at sites I've never heard of.
Sometimes outside.
I've woken up walking
down the highway.
I've woken up floating on water.
No shorts...I...
I woke up two states over.
Two weeks had passed.
I had no idea how I got there.
It had been erased from my memory.
Once, I woke up in a field
fifteen miles from here.
I was covered in blood.
There was a horse
on the ground in front of me.
It...it...had...been cut
down the center.
Its insides
removed and laid out
and displayed in the grass
like an internal...road map.
Why don't we talk
about something else for a second?
Like...
tonight's mass ejection.
Yeah, it should...should
be interesting.
Yeah...
Solar flares in.
traveled millions of miles here and burst
through our atmosphere tonight.
Yeah.
There's nothing else here
that should be interesting on the ship.
They say it's going to
interfere with the whole grid.
World-wide blackout.
Grounded all the flights.
Systems...
...might get knocked out
of the sky.
All the transit's been shut down.
I look forward to it.
Nature has a way of
mixing things up.
Humans really are
not in control.
We'd like you to hook
up the platform.
Let's put a couple of
holes into William's head.
And see what we see.
You want to know
more about it?
No?
Well, it's too bad.
It's less destructive if
you know what to expect.
Is that comfortable?
-Heather!
Please don't do that.
It's just...when our subjects
are more comfortable,
we actually get better results.
Just...stop talking.
And finish.
Yes, Doctor.
Doctor, we got something.
It's about time!
What I got here?
equals square circle.
It appears we have an abandoned truck.
The back of the truck is clear.
The truck is clear.
-Copy that.
Some blood.
Something else.
Protecting...
You know what we're
looking at here, William?
I've made this truck.
Hey, your insides seem valuable.
Must be your pest
helmet, doc.
I'm seeing a bunch of blood.
Doctor?
You're gonna want
to see this.
OK, bring it in.
Copy that.
There's a substance here.
What is it?
Definitely foreign.
Sir?
It's not human.
Care to tell me what
you know about this truck, Bill?
No.
So, you might feel a
little sting here.
That's not really a sting.
Kind of...kind of like a
hot blade slowly digging around
in your head.
What is this thing?
Oh! So now you're interested.
It pulls your thoughts
out of your mind.
No, we don't really know
how it actually works,
we usually get the results
we're looking for.
Unfortunately,there's some
undesirable side effects
for the subjects.
You know, it took a
hundred years before
anybody could figure out
how to turn it on.
Isn't that interesting?
What happened last night, Bill?
That's a funny one.
Can I have some more, please?
Did I tell you that we
have figured out
how it pulls your mind out
of your head
but we have no idea
how to put it back in?
They're so...
Give me some more juice.
Keep at it, girl!
Turn it up!
Turn it off!
Check her!
What the fuck
just happened here?
Take that off.
You crazy?
Good?
Please take that device
off of your friend's head.
Now.
I order you.
Get rid of her!
Is that the camera, soldier?
Bring it in.
Put it on the monitor.
Thank you, soldier.
Hey, everybody.
Joe Sullivan here.
Sully_5433
I just got the most
amazing email last night.
While I was sleeping,
I got contacted by a god.
OK? Hello Joe Sullivan.
I would like you to come
meet me at the address below tomorrow.
Spider Nevi. Spider Nevi...
He's the whale of astronomy.
People have been trying to
find this guy for years.
But he doesn't want
to be found.
He's off the radar, he's off
the grid,
not even the government
knows where he is.
He contacted me.
Maybe...maybe he wants
me to film him.
Maybe he wants to talk about
the mass ejections tonight.
I mean, There are some crazy
shit going on in the atmosphere
and he decides to contact me?
I mean, this guy's been blogging
about an alien
experience for years,
the things that he's
writing about, the
concepts and the ideas,
they're just so...
Anyway...I'm backed up.
I'm going to need the help. Let's go.
That's where we're going.
Right over that ridge.
I've got zero idea if
this is anywhere close
to real or a total scam.
All we know is what
this guy looks
like and that he
goes by Spider-man
Fuck. That sounds made up.
Not sure what to make of this.
What the hell?
Jesus...the tanks...?
I wonder if we can get closer?
Howdy.
Hi sir.
My name is Joe Sullivan.
Hi, Joe. Is that a camera?
Uh? -Yeah.
Are you filming me right now?
-No sir.
-I don't believe you.
You're a liar. Why
you got a camera
sitting there pointing at me?
-I'm making a film. Uh...
-Oh, you're making a movie.
I am, sir.
You think there are
some interesting
people up here, aren't there?
Go fuck yourself today.
What about tomorrow?
Hi. Hi there.
My name is...Joe.
Hey! I'm Joe Sullivan.
How you doin'?
Hello.
My name is Joseph Sullivan.
Filmmaker.
Astronomer.
It's really stupid.
Alright. Here we go.
This is perfect.
Hello?
Hello!
Anybody here?
He's coming...Jesus!
Oh.
Hey. Ha.
You...just...
snuck up on me there.
Hi, I'm...I'm Joe.
It's...
Uh...
Joe Sullivan. You...
You sent me an...
...email last night?
Uh...you're Spider Nevy?
Um...
Listen, I...I just...
want to talk to you
for a few minutes
on camera if...if...
Uh, I'm not going to
take up too much of
your time, I just...
I assume you want
to tell your story.
You know, I'm a filmmaker, I'm not
I'm not some weirdo.
I have read everything you've written...
...I've watched everything you
have posted online...
...And I believe your story
and I
and I'm not here to debunk
I'm not here to make fun
of you or
eh...you know.
Um...I'm here to...
listen...that's...that's all
I'm here to do.
I mean,hey...if this isn't
a good time, I can always
I can always come back or...
you know, we can just...
you can give me one of
those beers and...
We don't even have
to talk on camera or
anything like that. I can
just put it down and
just talk.
Oh...
No...no...no...
No...no...
Aah!
Fascinating.
Completely.
I have put that
on hundreds of people.
And there is never
anything left, any, nothing.
But William...
There's still plenty
of you in there isn't there?
Something's different.
It is? What? What's different?
It's changed.
It's stronger.
More vicious.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. I don't
want to see you in pain.
You and I, Bill,
we share a mission.
I'm not going to have a mission.
-Yeah.
Yes, you do.
Oh, but you do have a mission.
That same creature that contacted you
contacted us. Do you know when, Bill?
One thousand three hundred
and sixty-five years ago.
And we have been trying
to return the call ever since.
We can help each other.
Then...
we can help you
find the proof that you need.
I don't need anybody to find proof.
I just want it to stop.
I know, I know,
I understand. We
can help you.
Where is it, Bill?
Is it with Joe Sullivan?
It's not with anybody.
OK.
Come on. Come
on, William.
I feel like I'm being
much more honest
with you than you are
with me right now.
He'll hurt anybody.
Erase anybody.
So, Bill, what are we
going to see out here tonight?
Fluctuations in the sky.
Colors are ripples as it
bursts through the sky's atmosphere.
This energy is traveling
1,500 miles a second.
and almost 500 million
miles to get to us, and when it hits,
Ugh. Ugh..
Bill?
Ugh.
Bill, are you alright?
Ugh,- there is something
out there. -Ugh,
I think it...
Oh, my God, Bill, look.
Oh! Look. Look at it, Bill.
Look. Seriously.
What's happening, Bill?
What's happened?
-They're here. I can feel them.
Who's here?
Bill, who's here?
They found me. And
they've come back.
What are you saying?
-Look. Look. You see?
Don't you see?
-Please, just tell me.
Tell me what I'm
looking at here.
Look...I told you.
They didn't believe me.
Platoon. It's coming.
Look. Come on.
Up there. It's...It's...
Follow, follow me, follow.
Look.
No.
No! Bill, don't.
Bill.
-Bill...
-Shh!
Bill, wait!
Wait!
Wait. Wait.
Bill, I don't know where I'm going.
Bill...
Shit!
Joe!
Over here!
Hang on, Bill.
My God!
Look at this!
Oh...
Look! Over here, too.
My God!
Oh...
Oh, my God!
Don't get too close, Bill.
Oh...
Bill!
Run.
Run!
Bill! Bill!
Shit!
Bill, I need you to tell me
what it is we are
looking at here.
What do you think
you are looking at?
William, I'm going to
ask you one more time.
Tell me what it is
that you found there.
Is this some sort of
game you're playing
to get people to
believe your story?
Spray paint, cardboard,
camera tricks, and
post on-line for your
conspiracy buddies.
is that what this is?
Or are we looking at something
significant here?
Yeah.
It's significant.
If you are fucking with me
I will make sure you
leave this building
cut up into a thousand pieces,
burned and pissed on.
I haven't much option
here. Sounds like I'm losing.
All units...
we have significant evidence
to indicate that
an unidentified flying object has
split apart in our atmosphere and
crashed onto Cassidy's property.
A small pod has landed in the
forest and the main
unit is in the pod.
Find me this ship.
We're going to fucking die
out here.
Shut your mouth, soldier.
Move quickly and quietly.
Appears to be a...substance
similar to what we saw at the truck.
-OK, sample it for the lab.
We got something.
The impact is obvious.
Seven touchdown.
So that's it? That's the
second crash site.
Find the pod.
-Surrounding area is burnt.
There's nothing left.
There's no ship.
No pod. Nothing.
You see what we see? There's nothing
here. I repeat, nothing is here.
We need to move on.
No, that's...that's the right site.
Doctor, there is no fucking ship.
Something must have come and gone.
Open your god damned eyes.
Ah!
Bill?
Bill!
Oh,Jesus!
No yelling.
Oh, God. Sorry.
Oh, let's see whats happening
There's something out there.
You're fucking...what?
I see...I see it.
What is it, Bill?
Bill?
Bill, what is it?
Look!
Shh...Bill!
Wait!
Bill!
It's erased.
Bill...
No...No...
What the fuck is that?
I'm gonna shit my pants, man.
What the fuck was that?
Did you see it?
I don't know, Joe.
Bill, Bill, wait!
Wait, wait!
-I knew you had a
goddamned camera.
Bill?
Ah!
Bill!
Move...fucking move. Shit!
Oh, fuck. Move!
I don't want to die.
Fuck! Oh, shit!
Oh...Ah...
Where...where am
I going?
Where am I going? Fuck.
What the...?
Ow!
Shit! The light!
Oh, oh, fuck.
What is this?
What the...what the fuck?
Things are about to get
very nasty right now.
We don't really know
what they were originally designed for
All I know, is that they
cause immense pain.
And shut off your body's
coping mechanism.
Your body's designed
to shut off.
But with the D-83 shackles,
It keeps the pain switch
turned on.
It's your last chance.
Where is that ship?
Turn it on!
Yeah, you want to
tell me where the ship is now, Bill?
You had enough now?
Hey, you want more?
Come on, Agent! Turn it
up! Give him more!
Ahh! Ahh! Ahhh!
Ahhh! Ahhhhh! Ahhhhh
You're gonna need more
power than that!
Hey!
Bill?
Bill, come on.
Is it out there?
Oh, please don't be out there.
Oh, fuck.
Oh, shit.
Weird. Oh. Oh.
I'll just...I'll just...
OK, OK, OK. OK. Ok.
That's just me.
It's fine.
Oh, fuck! Oh, God!
Why are running?
You running away?
Gotta get way back to the cam.
Up the stairs.
Shit! get the door!
That's not enough!
Oh, shit.
Bill? Bill!
Take the camera!
-Look!
-The shelf!
The noise.
Bill, what's that on
the fucking roof?
Bill, how did they get on
the roof?
Oh, fuck!
Son of a bitch!
It's back. At the car site.
Back up, back up!
Ahhhhhh!
Ah! Ah!
You can do it.
Stevens!
Ok, what happened, soldier?
I lost my feed.
Something grabbed Stevens
at the grid.
Stevens!!!!
Anybody got eyes on him?
Go ahead into his last location.
Did he say what he saw?
Negative. All we heard was
too fucked up sound, then silence.
It ain't human. It's got to
be extra-terrestrial.
Stevens!!
Stay close. keep your
eyes open.
Stevens! Stevens.
Stevens. Stevens!
Got a bunch of them live.
Stevens is gone.
Fuck!
Tracks.
That side...
Both of you.
Ok, keep following. I want
you to find something,
Find some answers here.
Nothing for a while.
It's been about an hour.
I was thinking...I think
he's gone.
Nothing's moved out there.
I don't know.
What are we gonna do?
I just want to be backing
off that truck and
getting the fuck out of here.
Yeah, well, just stay put.
I'll haunt after daylight.
Huh..
We got a gun.
If we could see it,
we can shoot it.
It's just you and
me in the end of the world.
Uh...
Yeah.
Let's get out of here.
Ok.
It's a fucking light!
Jesus freaking Christ.
Clear.
Yeah.
Where is the truck keys?
What? Wait a minute, truck keys?
What the hell does it look like?
Ahh!
Jesus, fuckin bullshit!
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
Where's the gun?
It...it...it  bounced out of my hand.
I don't know.
Did you forget?
Maybe...I don't know.
What about the roof?
Bill!
Here!
Here, over here!
Can that thing get through
that fucking bed?
Ok! Move! hey!
One...two...three...
Fuck it!
3...2...1! The door!
We can't stay here.
Where else are we gonna go?
It's gone.
Bill!
I fucked my ankle.
No, no, no,no...move...
Got them...?
Not on one key
What does it look like?
I'm gonna get the gun.
No! No!
Don't do that. Bill, don't, don't...
No, Bill. Don't leave me with
that thing .
Bill, Bill! please!
Please! Please!
Fuck!
Shit!
Bill, Bill.
-Shh!
Bill!
Where did it go?
It was crawling right there.
Ok, let's get out of here!
Hold on...
-No. Let's go!
I think it's dead.
Dead?
What? What?
It was bleeding very loud
and it collapsed though there.
It stopped.
Ok, great.
That's fucking cool.
Wait there.
No.
No. No, fuck you.
Uh! Ah!
We have confirmation of contact.
Yes.
A video recording, sir.
I'm going to see it now.
You have my full
understanding, sir.
I will be waiting your arrival.
Fuck, come on, Bill!
Bill, Bill, where are you?
Fuck, fuck, fuck, fuck, fuck.
Oh....
Ah! Ah!
Bill!
Oh! Bill, Bill!!
You've got to see this!
What? What?
Who's in your camera?
What are you doing?
Come here.
My god!
Hello?
Who are you?
I knew it was you!
I've been waiting.
Please, I...I'm needing help.
Destroy them. I'm...
I'm nothing.
I'm nothing!
Ahhhh!
Ahhh! Ahhh!
Enough with the screaming already.
It doesn't matter now.
I've contacted council.
They will be here
in a matter of hours.
You'll be in their hands now
and let me tell you, Bill,
their hands are a lot
rougher than mine.
We're moving...we've got some sound...
It's here.
creature is here.
No! Hold your fire!
Hold your fire, god damn it!
Fucking idiots!
You fucking chicken
shit morons!
Don't just stand there
staring! Go get them.
Toggle that.
Fuck me.
There's a man.
He's pretty fucked up.
He's gotten the same substance
as the crash site.
Oh, my God, I don't
believe it. That's...
That's Joe Sullivan.
Repeat. Same substance from the truck.
And at the crash sight.
Is he alive?
He'll survive.
Bring him to me now.
Copy.
Did you hear that, William?
We're going to have a guest.
You sure it's dead?
It's not breathing.
Uh, Bill...
We should...We should
call someone.
You focus on what you're doing.
Listen...What is that?
Whoa! Oh!
Get the tape! Run!
Bill.
Hey Bill.
Why don't we call the cops?
No,we should...
We call the cops
and they can come
and then they can
call whenever and
We can call the army and the national guard
This isn't right. I need
we need  the new suppliers.
Wow...
Shit. I don't feel good.
I wanna go home.
Yeah...I wanna go home.
Bill, there's something wrong.
Can you focus for a goddamned second?
Good.
-I saw that.
-I'm sorry.
Will you clean that
shit up?
What?
What are you talking about?
- Clean that shit up!
-I'm sorry, Bill.
Bill. Bill!
Joe, Joe, Joe, Joe. Joe. Joe.
Shit!
-Fuck...
-I'm sorry about that.
Before...the police...the camera.
Is all in here. Cassidy, Bill.
Shh...
This is his.
It's so important.
You're going to get the camera.
And then you are gonna operate it.
And I want you to see this. Are
you ready?
Come. Come closer.
Over here. Come on.
Look.
Look at this. Look.
See?
Isn't it lovable?
It's good.
The same thing that's
inside of here
is inside of me
There's something bigger
controlling us both.
And I've got you.
What's that?
What?
What's that? What's going on?
We gotta go!
Look.
I got a visual! There he is!
Target's on me. Take them!
take them!
Target's on you. Go! Go!
Pull out! Pull out!
in time, men.
It's on you!
My name is Joseph Sullivan.
What you've just seen is 100
That's not exactly how you
thought it would end, huh?
Don't worry, William.
That's not the end for you.
It's just the start of a long life.
Locked up in a cage...
squealing like a dog
while they stuff you like a pig.
I'm not afraid of you.
What do you want?
You!
do...suffer!
We will find you!
No you won't.
We are in a heavily
guarded facility here.
You brought us!
Listen to me, you
cocky fuck!
We ripped apart your
granddaddy in the sixties
We'll rip apart you
just the same!
You will suffer
most!
You will suffer most!!!
We're approaching the facility
with Joe Sullivan.
He's not conscious.
I hope you're ready for this.
Aboart!
Aboart! Do not bring
Joe Sullivan here!
Kill subject immediately.
Do not bring him here!
Kill him!
There's been a breach!
Officer! Let him locked out!
What happened?
They're here.
Please...let me go...
Help me.
What do I do? Tell me.
Please, I don't want to die.
They won't let you die.
Please tell me something.
Something that you know.
Please.
I know they're like me.
They may be something more
than is humanly possible.
I can't imagine what
they'll do to you.
I guess it's over.
Please...
Take it up.
Make it stop.
Make it end.
I'm begging you.
Well...
Congratulations, internet.
You win.
You deep dulled Sully.
I drove for fourteen hours
To an address
that did not have Spider Nevy
I didn't even see the abducter. So...
All in all, it ends to an epic fail.
I promised you guys a white whale and...
I give you nothing. All I've got to
show for is this headache. So...
I'm going to try and get some sleep.
I'll get back after it tomorrow.
Hello everybody. My name
is Ashley Winnington-Ball
and today we're going to
look directly at the sun.
mass coronal ejection.
Sounds odd, huh?
As a matter of fact it is.