Well? Have the four of you
brought a treasure vault?
Can't you see?
lt's a cupboard
Your master placed an order yesterday.
We're here to deliver it
But my master has already left
for his vacations today
Anyway, bring it in.
- Move it, guys
Come on in
One and one...
makes eleven
one and one...
makes eleven...
my friend
One and one... is eleven
One, two, three, four, five,
six, seven, eight, nine, ten...
and one... is eleven
One and one is never two
Those who laugh,
never cry
Those who keep awake,
never fall asleep
Their identities,
they never lose
Wherever they find an enemy...
they deliver the punch...
my friend
One and one make eleven,
They are Tara and Sitara
Homeless orphans, driven
by poverty and despair...
they have formed a team together
They have taken the words of their
foster mother very seriously
They believe that should
one and one come together...
they possess the power of eleven.
They then set out...
on the path of thievery and fraud.
They think they will...
win over this world and
carve a place of their own
Little did they know that there are
the worst of thieves in the world...
who are not just enemies
of society...
but of the nation
and humanity at large
An instance of this kind became the
biggest lesson for Tara and Sitara...
when they met the dreaded criminals,
Cobra and Panther
Sir, our soldiers are ready
to take the guns to the base
Load the guns quickly.
We've got to leave
But you have an appointment
with Mr Subramaniam at 12
Plans have changed.
For security reasons
As you know, sir, no one except you
has the permission to go inside
He's on official work
for our department
He's responsible for delivery
of the gun at the base
But orders are orders, sir
Major, the Captain is doing
his duty. Orders are orders
You can go ahead.
l'll wait here, okay?
What is the matter?
- This is Dr Subramaniam's cabin, sir
While l meet Dr Subramaniam in
privacy, you will wait here
We need proper security
for this gun
We have toiled for years
to develop this gun
Come, let me give you
a demonstration
lt has an inbuilt sensor which detects
movements within a 10-kilometer range
Our soldiers will be greatly benefitted
in dealing with infiltrators
Because we don't want the gun to
fall in wrong hands...
each gun has been given
a different code-number
Without the code-number,
this gun will not function
What is the code-number
to operate the gun?
Ml2 3853713
Thank you. Can we take the gun now?
First sign the documents
You've signed the document...
but you haven't entered
the password of this operation?
You know very well, Ram Singh
Without the password,
you cannot take this gun away
This gun... l am surely taking away
You're here, sir?
- Where else? This is my base
You were in there a little while ago,
and this is the only entry-point
l've arrived just now.
ln your presence
ln my presence, you've
already passed through sir
You also had an officer of
your department with you
My brother has left with the gun.
You can do what you wish
He has only left with the gun.
Not the code
Without the code,
that gun is worthless
And l'll get the gun back...
because you're with me
You can't do a thing!
Greetings, sir.
- Welcome, Bahadur Singh
What brings you to my place today?
- l've come with a reason, sir
l've come to warn you, sir.
- Warn me...?
A pair of thieves has struck terror.
- Terror...?
They hit upon such novel ideas
for robbery...
the police are left stunned.
- Don't tell me!
A few days ago, they got into
a cupboard and robbed the whole house
The whole house...?
They rent a house for a few days...
and sell the place,
as if they own it
Sell it away?
- They pose as servants and...
Sir...
- Milk, or the yogurt-shake?
The two of them... at your place?
The way they've taken care of me,
even my children haven't
After they've taken care of you,
they'll vanish with the loot!
What do you mean?
- They're conning you!
They're the twosome
l've been warning you about
One is Tara...
- The other is Sitara. l know
l say...
you've ruined all our efforts
Even if a criminal
wants to reform...
people like you
won't let him turn a new leaf
l say... have you forgotten?
- lt might hurt
We had sworn it on your head
that we'd work hard for a living
That we'd never steal again
That's just what we were doing,
but you've told our employer about us
You've snatched our livelihood.
Where to...?
l got a kick on the waist
Sir, l wish to
tell you something today
lf these guardians of the law
keep harping on cliches...
people like us will keep
going to the jails
No, l'm not letting you guys
become thieves
You're staying here with me.
- Sir, l will leave now
But you'd better
remain alert with them
A fire...
- he has started
No, he hasn't
l know you guys are reformed
But tell me of your modus operandi
as thieves...
so l will remain alert
with cheats in the future
We first survey a locality.
- Then?
Then we get into the household
which is most innocent and wealthy
Then?
- Then...
we serve the master as his servants.
- Like you've been serving me?
And when we've won the confidence
of our master...
we lace his milk or yogurt-shake
with a bit of sedative and...
Such foolish people! Their
yogurt-shake is laced with sedatives
And they don't even get to know...
Did he... get to know?
The moron
Ruined
This man was out to
reform those thieves
But those thieves have
put him to sleep
l told you to remain alert
But you will continue to sleep
C'mon
Tara and Sitara...
your game is up
Don't even try to escape.
Else, l'll let you have it
He's getting dramatic.
- Looks like he wants to die
Tell me something, Bahadur Singh
Why're you always hounding
us innocent guys?
Because of you guys,
l haven't had a wash in a week
But l'm taking you to
the cleaners. Nicely so!
No more jokes, lnspector.
Else, an innocent man will die
That's Cobra, isn't it?
- Yes, sir
You guys know who you're messing with?
Shut up! Else, l'll pluck
your eye-balls out
You speak as if you've got a
reward of millions on your head!
You're right.
- Can't you see...?
the cops and the thieves
are making a deal?
Go ahead and kill him. That's Cobra.
The dreaded criminal
There's a reward of 100,000
for catching him, dead or alive
Landed us in trouble, haven't you?
- You ought to carry a signboard...
that you're Cobra.
How would we know?
There's a reward of
100,000 on his head
Will we get it?
- Sure
lf l let you live
to claim the reward
Arrest all three of them
Before l turn cold,
let me take his blessings
lt's Mr Cobra who's being
presented in court
And why're we going there?
- That's the new style
Hammer a nail into a block of wood,
it'll sail with it in the waters
Like Mr Cobra here.
He's the engine...
and we're the trailers.
lf he runs, we run. For no reason
For how many years do you think
Mr Cobra will be sent away?
Going by the way he looks
and behaves, l think...
you tell me how many years
you're likely to get
He's scowling at me.
- ls he?
Let me see, Brother Cobra
Sure he's scowling
l think there's a terrible storm
lurking behind his silence
Brother...
don't be angry, we're kids.
Give us a smile
You guys are free
Move it
Lovely weather...
- Shut up. l've had enough
C'mon
There's a car parked down there.
lt'll take you to the highway
Mike will...
We don't utter names
in the presence of strangers
He was revealing our gameplan
What's with him, brother?
Why's he fallen down?
My bullet got him.
- We didn't even hear it
When did it happen?
- You fired yesterday, did you?
Today. Want to hear it again?
Don't move... l'll shoot
Drop the guns,
or l'll shoot
Well? We call you brother
and you turn out to be a snob?
What have you been up to?
What...?
Are you going to talk
or undo these chains?
What's with the chains?
l say, who's screaming?
ls it the chains?
- No, it's a leg actually
The bullet hit him a little
below the chains in the leg
What the hell have you done?
Cobra... forgive us!
Was it a mistake?
- What if it struck him 4 inches up?
No one has survived.
- Let me undo these chains
Why're you shooting at me?
- Not you, l blew the chains away
So what do we do?
- Run
Where's my brother... where?
Get up, sir. Police!
Congratulations, sir.
Cobra has been captured
That's all right. But where have
Tara and Sitara disappeared...?
My job's on the line!
And you...
you call yourself a big criminal
and you couldn't stop those guys?
Get up
How will he get up? He's got
a bullet-injury in his leg
Carry him on your shoulders
and take him to the hospital
Where will l go looking for them
in this wilderness? Tara! Sitara!
Lots of stuff they've collected
Where are Tara and Sitara?
- Don't you read the newspapers?
Don't you watch TV...?
Has there been a robbery in town?
Has anyone robbed anyone...?
There's peace and calm in the city
What does that mean...? What?
lt means my sons are at their
in-laws (read jail). Tihar Jail
Your sons have run away from jail
and left me in a spot of bother
What...? My sons have run away?
Scoundrels! When you can't take
care of my sons...
why do you take them away
for six months?
They weren't guests! We took
them away because they were thieves!
And there l was... with a heavy heart
l gave my darling sons to you!
And you make them run away!
Am l crazy to make
the prisoners run away?
They ran away on their own
There must surely have been something
lacking in your hospitality
Else, why would my sons run away?
They're my support in life
Tara and Sitara.
Now listen carefully, you ass
lf my sons are not returned to me,
l'm going to curse you
You're going to fall
to a criminal's bullets
Even if you escape that,
you'll lose your job
That's enough!
When l find your precious sons...
l'll leave them here on my own.
This woman is a tyrant!
Tara, Sitara...
he has left
Darling mother...
you were amazing
Enough. You boys ought to
read the writing on the wall...
and slip cross the border.
Do telephone me
And don't come back,
till l tell you to
Here's some money.
l collected it for bad times
You're so sweet...
you're so innocent...
you're lovable...
dear mother... our mother
Mother, you've done so much for us.
Know what...?
Even if our real mother was here...
- What did you say?
Have l given you any less love
than a real mother?
Had your real mother been here, she'd
have handed you over to the police...
to prove her greatness. She wouldn't
have shielded you, like l did
But you boys always say such things
to hurt my feelings
No, mother... don't misunderstand us.
What we meant to say was that...
had it not been for you,
we wouldn't even have been alive
We know, the one who rears is far
greater than the one who gives birth
And you have brought us up.
So please don't misunderstand us!
All right. Run away
as quickly as you can
You only had the cops
after you earlier
But even Cobra's hunting for you now.
He wants to have your legs broken
Big deal! We're the ones
who shot at his leg!
Of course. But before he
gets into another game...
we'll start a new one.
- By cutting ourselves down to size
l say, hold this...
l'll make enquiries about the train
Relax
What's happening?
Posters for a circus...?
A magician in town?
Or is it a new movie?
Right now, it's these two thieves
who are making waves
They've made lives miserable for the
cops and the citizens in the city
Want to take a look?
- All right, let me see
There's a reward for their capture.
lf you catch them, you keep some...
and give me some
Sitara, l can hear
the band being played for me!
l say...
- Look here
l say, sir...
is that your daughter?
No, not my daughter.
But you sure are my son-in-law
Your blessings.
- Bless you
l have another son-in-law...
where is he?
l'm not telling you.
- Don't tell me. But l know
You can't live without each other.
lf one of you is caught...
the other comes forward
to court arrest. Right?
Let's go
Wait there, Sitara...
else, l'll shoot
l say, praise the Lord!
- Tara...
You took such a huge risk
to save me?
No big risk, Sitara...
we share a great relationship
The world knows. Tara and Sitara
are two bodies and one soul
lf something happened to you...?
- What's happening to me?
Tell me, what would you have done
if you were in my shoes?
What's a jeep?
l'd have hijacked a train for you!
There you are, aren't you?
- On the dot
Sitara, let me tell you
something today
l respect you a lot, my friend.
- Watch the jeep
When we got to be friends...
we spawned a thousand stories
of friendship
Friendship was a precious gift
Every season was lovely
They know...
- They know...
the whole world knows that...
my friend...
One and one...
adds up to eleven...
my friend
one and one...
is eleven
lf you see someone trying
to cross the fence...
go ahead and shoot them
Who's in that jeep,
could you explain?
Major Ram Singh
l'm Raju Nepali
Only two men can help you
cross the border
One is Major Ram Singh,
who won't do it
The other is me...
l do it only for money
That's a new one.
- How much money will you take?
200,000 for two guys.
- We aren't asking the price...
of this place. We want to know
the price for crossing over
That's the price for
crossing over
Come over, when you have the money.
You'll find Raju Nepali right here
He won't even say bye...
rude man
How are we going to raise
200,000 in this area?
Not a soul to rob
They found no dear ones, but they picked
on Apna Bank to fulfill their needs
You think we can manage to
squeeze 200,000 out of them?
Greetings, sir.
- Greetings
You want to open an account?
- No, we're planning a robbery
Robbery...?
- Foolish man!
What will two top businessmen do
if not open an account!
We have a lot of money.
- l see
Ten million
Ten...
He's stuck on ten,
as if he hasn't seen it at all
We hardly have 2 million
in our bank at any given time
lt's a very small bank.
- Not small...
Listen
That's 10 million lost!
Something amazing happened
at the bank today
There were these customers who
wanted to open an account
Of... 10 million
Like an idiot, l told them that
we never have more than 2 million
And they walked away
ls manager in?
-Who could it be so late in the night?
Give in the name of God!
ls this any time to beg
for alms...? Go away
We are not beggars, we're here
to make a beggar out of you
Who are you?
Look here. l have one too
Recognise us? He's the elder brother,
l'm the younger one
Brothers with six bullets each.
- Six...?
Recognise us?
Junior... that's a beautiful girl.
- Where?
What insolence is this...?
Dad, call the police immediately
Your telephone's already dead.
- Your dad could be dead too
Don't be sad. The look of you
has already driven me mad
See? Your daughter has
robbed my elder brother
l'm going to do some robbing now.
ln your bank
We'll go to sleep right here
You'll take us to the bank
tomorrow morning...
and personally have your bank robbed.
You'll then see us out...
and then will follow the police,
the questions, the answers...
the news channels...
you'll become famous
Keep eating
Brother! There's porridge!
Potato and cauliflower pancakes!
Let me have some porridge
in peace
l've made it...
would you like some?
Let me eat it in peace
Will you have some...?
- l'm already eating some. You have it
l see. That's non-fattening,
this is fattening
Very intelligent
What are you doing here?
Go and fetch a bag...
we've got to rob a bank!
You got to understand
ls he laughing or crying?
l can't tell
Hurry up, son.
You know who l am
The brothers with six bullets each.
- Hurry up, l hate delays
Hurry
Are you laughing or crying?
l can't make out
Just run away with me
l have so much of money,
l'll keep you happy
You've robbed all the money and you
want to run away with my daughter?
The cops will get us, brother.
- Why?
We're bandits, that's why.
Let's go
Let's go, l say!
- Let's go
They've taken away all the money!
Brother... what bad times
We used to run away with
the money earlier
Now we give money and run away.
- Don't you think...
that rather than pay this guy
200,000...
we could've struck a deal
with Ram Singh himself?
He'd have shot you
He's been shot!
l see Ram Singh clearly!
Ram Singh's house
Tara and Sitara would never find
a better place to evade the police
Well, they could effortlessly
gain entry into any house
Let's see how they trick
their way into Ram Singh's house
A hundred-rupee note!
God, if You had to cure
the itch in my hand...
You could've given me
a 500-rupee note!
500 rupees...?
Which side of the bed did
l get off this morning?
God, let me find a wallet stuffed
with money since You're so kind!
A wallet stuffed with notes!
Scoundrel!
- Cur!
We're going to cure your itch today!
- You steal our wallet!
l didn't steal it...
it was lying here
Not lying there.
lt was kept there safely
Take him to the police station.
- Let's go
No, sir! Please don't
take me to the police station
l'm a very poor man!
l've got a mother, two brothers
and three sisters
All sisters have got
to be married
You can marry two of them,
l'll find a better guy for the third
Will you find anyone
better than us, you ass?
Look at this personality
Check out my looks...
better than us, you say?
Listen...
You tell him
We aren't marrying your sisters,
but we can help in their marriage
How?
- Here you are
Help with a hundred bucks?
- All right, you have a big quota
For the money, you'll have to
extend some help to us
What help?
- Ask my senior
Ask junior.
- Ask senior
Just tell me... stop teasing me
Are you scolding us?
- No, please tell me
Madam, look!
Your wedding necklace
How did you get it?
- A thief was running away with it
This is the last memento of
my husband. lt's so dear to me
l'm glad you caught
the thief, Chhotu
Not me, it was these decent gentlemen.
Tara and Sitara
They're the ones
who caught the thief
l say, Sitara... a familiar sight.
Our house hasn't changed at all!
The same house, the same windows
and the same doors
The same curtains too
Have you been
in this house earlier?
Been here? This is where
we were born, what say?
This is the place where we
were christened and initiated
l'm Tara.
- l'm Sitara
Our father's was going through
a lean patch in those days
He had to sell this bungalow.
- Ever since, to this day...
we brothers miss our parents
so much!
Mother!
- No, son... calm down
That's just what mother used to say
Don't...
- Mother!
l really miss my mother!
- You are great
A kid...
- Kid?
He's a big kid
Remember when we were children?
l used to bring a chocolate like him
And l used to snatch it from you.
- l used to snatch it back
Know what?
l love eating things l snatch
Really? You'll make it big some day!
Sister-in-law... mother...
Gotcha!
- Gotcha what?
He has found his room.
- Not my room... my bedroom
l've found my bedroom
The same texture,
the same air...
Come to your senses.
- l've just come to my senses!
l've gone crazy looking
at this house today!
Tara, if you're so attached
to this house...
let's hire a room in a hotel
and you can keep looking at it
Must we live in a hotel?
- Yes
Stay here for a few days, son.
This is like your own house
Mother!
Tara, don't...
l can't get up, you see.
l was only taking her blessing
Brother Sitara...
- Go on
Does it remind you of something?
- What?
Didn't our daddy look like him
in his younger days?
Oh yes, the same height,
the same moustache...
and a stern disposition.
There's no difference at all
Who are they?
This bungalow used to belong to them
They're here for a few days,
we asked them to stay over
l don't allow strangers
to stay in my house
This house isn't ours anymore
So how can the folks here
feel any sense of belonging?
You are not going anywhere.
You're staying here
You don't know what a big favour
you have done to me
l know my son very well.
He'll never disobey me
He's a soldier, you see.
He can't trust people easily
Chhotu...
- Yes, madam?
Take their luggage to the out-house.
- Sure. Please give it to me
Mother, even God wouldn't
look any different from you
We haven't ever seen You...
Every saint and Prophet
has said...
in this world...
love is the greatest feeling
End my agony...
O Lord...
heed the cry of Radha...
Lord Krishna
Help it sail across...
the boat of my dreams...
heed the cry of Radha...
Lord Krishna
You sing very well, son.
lt gives me so much of peace
Sitara and l have
always been like this
We've always wanted to
sing melodious songs
But alas! we've always
had a terrible chorus
Where's Sitara?
- l say the prayers in the morning...
he performs the rituals
in the evening
That's very nice.
Let me take you out
Take her blessings
l can drive the wheelchair
on my own
Chhotu, why've you come in
with my luggage and footwear?
l sent for him.
- You...?
We were comfortable in the out-house.
Why call us into the house?
Neither are you staying in the house,
nor in the out-house
You can win over my family with
your sentimental crap... not me
You haven't driven Sitara out,
have you?
He's waiting for you at the gate.
- You've already driven him out?
Come on, Chhotu
Don't you think we have
been humiliated?
Brother...
- You're here too?
l was singing a hymn and he
very respectfully saw me out
But l'm told he didn't even
let you change?
What's changing? He didn't even
let me go to the loo
Listen, get a can for my brother.
- Shut up!
You know, when l lose my temper,
l always give someone a thrashing
l've lost my temper too!
But we can't beat up Ram Singh.
- So?
l'm a very poor man! l have a mother,
two brothers and three sisters!
After him
The bullet mustn't hit Ram Singh's
son. We want him alive
Help!
Tara, please help!
- Not to worry
The kid has won the race,
you guys have lost
Get going.
- Going...? Me?
Brother...
the jungle's already green.
Come over
What happened?
- We have thugs here!
You handle them.
- l'm on a pedal...
how can l handle them? Get it!
- l'm busy with my own handle!
Your handle's busy, my pedal's busy...
it's no so easy
These guys are pointing guns...
swap your handle!
Get him
Not so late... they'll lay me out
What are you here for? Run away!
- Run
Scram!
Dad, come to
the club house immediately
They tried to kidnap me...
the driver has been killed
ln the streams of time,
we do not flow
We don't talk too much...
but we don't remain
silent either
Atrocities, we do not tolerate
This world...
has conceded defeat to us...
buddy-boy...
one and one make eleven
Ram Singh's here.
- Sit in your vehicle
Brother, do l look decent enough?
- Wear a sad look
Are you all right?
- Yes
Had they not arrived on time,
they'd have kidnapped me today
Bansi...
How will l ever thank you?
You're not supposed to
thank children. Only bless them
We must leave now.
Good bye
You're not going anywhere.
You can stay at the outhouse...
for as long as you wish.
- Brother!
Brother!
l have travelled a long distance,
with my love
Tell me something, sir.
Do you plan on buying this bungalow?
You've made yourself comfortable.
- That's like us brothers, you see
Even when we buy a pair of slippers,
we properly check it out
Can't say when we might use it.
- One thing, sir
Whenever you buy the bungalow,
let me be your servant
l'm very poor. l have a mother,
two brothers and three sisters
You've got to get them married?
- Right, sir
He's eyeing the bungalow.
- Listen, arrange for some breakfast
You won't forget, will you?
- No way!
l know you've got 3 mothers,
300 brothers, 3500 sisters!
No, one mother, two brothers...
- Get lost!
Brother Tara...
- Brother Sitara?
We have a place to hide.
- Right
Till Cobra dies,
let's hide in this hole
You see something?
- Great danger
Ram Singh has not adopted us to
take care of us till we're old
We're his guests for a few days!
- We aren't his guests, brother!
You've seen only Ram Singh,
not his sister
She's so beautiful,
and they're such a nice family
l wonder why l mustn't marry her
and live with them
Live with them?
What do you think?
ls he the potter Chandan Seth to
give his daughter's hand in yours?
lt's Ram Singh!
- Big deal!
Just as we've got into his house,
we'll get into his heart too
Really?
Know what Pinki?
l'm very happy with your brother
lt was great of him to let
Tara and Sitara stay in your house
For what Tara and Sitara have done,
the house is nothing
They deserve a place
in our hearts
Sitara's such a he-man.
He's so brave
Bunty wasn't saved by Sitara alone
Even Tara risked his life
to save him
He's so brave. l'm surprised how he
beat them up, even in a wheelchair
With a brother like Sitara,
what's a wheelchair...
you can deliver the punch
even from a bed!
Why're you giving Sitara
all the credit?
l'm talking about both of them.
- But l could hear only about one
Because you've been talking
about the other
Oh yes!
l forgot, l must leave now.
l'm getting late for the college
l've got to meet the doctor
and ask him about Tara's legs
But you stay here. You never know.
Sitara might spring here
My love...
my beloved...
my love...
l'm your beloved...
l'm a lover...
l've given you my heart
Give my beloved to me...
l've pleaded with God,
l've wept on every shoulder
l have wept so much
My love, l have
given my heart to you
Give me my beloved...
l've pleaded with God,
l've wept on every shoulder
My beloved, l seek...
at every beautiful twist
love takes
To my house she shall come some day,
leaving everything behind
You're the one
who lingers in my breath
l always think about
l'm crazy about her...
l'd tell her, if l met her...
l'm your beloved
Your beloved
You're my lover...
you're the one
l have given my heart to
Sweetheart...
O beloved...
my love...
Where has is gone?
What are you doing?
Obviously, l can't swim
in a bathtub
l've been trying to commit suicide.
- What?
Yes, there must be a hilltop
in your city?
There is. Why?
- So take me there...
and give me a gentle kick,
l'll fall off
What are you talking about?
- l have another idea
Hold my face like this...
and shove it in the tub.
Hold it down firmly, with your foot
Till l stop breathing,
don't take your foot off
l've made a lot of unsuccessful
attempts at suicide
Look at this book. lt has 250 ways
of overcoming your disability
You will be able to walk again,
run again...
and maybe even dance with me too.
- Dance?
Will l be able to walk again?
- Certainly
You mean, l can run...?
l can take your hand and run?!
Pinki's dress...?
Why's it here?
The lame-duck hasn't
jumped her, or has he?
Sitara... you're back early.
- Early?
l think l'm too late.
- Not at all
Give me an explanation.
- Explain what...?
She was here to cure a cripple!
- Cure...? There you go!
You're the elder brother
and you push your kid brother?
lt isn't two days since we got here,
and you've gone so far ahead!
l planned on going deeper...
right to the altar
Come to your senses!
We're here to escape,
not to play grooms!
lf only Ram Singh saw what l did, he'd
have made a real cripple out of you!
What will Ram Singh do?
l'm not entering his sister's life
His sister's coming into my life!
- Really?
l smile to myself when l think
how tickled l'll be...
when his sister massages my legs.
l can laugh already
Tara, did you feel any pain?
l felt something,
but it wasn't pain
No? You will now
Did you feel any pain now?
- lt wasn't pain
And why're you smiling?
- l smile because l see...
how concerned you are
about my cure
You're putting your heart into it.
You're leaving nothing to chance
l think this stick is a fake
With a little stick
you're out to cure me, Pinki
And so many big ones
are broken already
Look at that.
- What?
Sister, throw away that little stick.
l'll use this whip on Tara's legs...
and make him feel the pain!
Out of my way!
Brother, why's the whole family
bent on curing me?
Why's this guy charging at me?
Ask him to hold on
l can't. When Ram Singh
can't control him, how can l?
l've never taken
such a huge stick!
This is a well-oiled stick!
lt has squeezed the life
out of several men!
One blow with this stick and...
- Handle him, brother
He's mad
He's a monkey!
There goes
My leg...
Why're you hitting me?
l was only curing you!
l was curing you too
Give him a banana.
- Yes. For extra energy
Here you are
No one can cure him!
- Hush. You mustn't say such things
l'll surely be cured...
with love
l say, Pinki...
Sitara? How are you?
- Wonderful
l say, what are you doing
with such fat books?
l'm trying to find a new cure
for Tara
A new cure for Tara?
- Because he can't walk
l'm trying to find a cure
that will help him move around
Listen to me.
Tara's actually hungry for love
No amount of beating
can ever cure him
So what am l to do?
Could you suggest something?
You ought to produce
the heat in him
lgnite a fire in his body.
So that he burns in the fire...
runs helter skelter,
cries, howls, jumps around...
you get me, don't you?
- Yes
Tea
Tell me something, Chhotu.
How do you start a fire?
With petrol
Start the fire with petrol,
and he'll race around like a car
All right
That's the shock-therapy!
There's mischief
in the air today...
it's terribly mischievous today...
A storm is coming
That's my line... stop singing
Pinki... why're you watering
the place around me?
lt isn't water. lt's petrol
l use my hands on the wheelchair,
why use petrol?
lt isn't to run your wheelchair,
it's to make you run
Me...?
- This is shock therapy
They find a new therapy
for me every day
l wonder what she'll do...
she won't start a fire, l hope
The dark clouds
move in the skies...
every bud...
casts a suspicious
glance at me
My God!
Escaped!
Escaped, finally!
You ran away even before
the cure could work!
l couldn't help it...
you don't understand
Where do you get such
great ideas from?
As if it was my idea.
- Whose was it?
lt was your brother Sitara's
So he's the brains
behind this sight?
Where's the genius?
Where's he?
Sitara, l feel great love
for you today
So, embrace me.
- Let me complete my line
This is Pinki's book.
lt has 250 cures for my impairment
And you gave her
an extra tip!
l merely told her to produce
the heat of love in your body
The heat of love is something...
and setting the body on fire
is yet something else
She was setting my body on fire.
- On fire...?
Hide me somewhere...
she seems to have found another cure
Hold on. Let me bowl her out.
- No... l'm bowling her out
Can't l at least hold her?
- Go ahead
Maintain the distance
My enemy...
this is a beautiful moment
My foe... a beauty stands
for your love
Take me in your embrace...
think of nothing else
You're a woman,
a mischievous girl...
l'm an innocent boy
l'm a priest's son,
related to those who worship
You're a big name...
Me, an enemy...?
No way
l will keep awake.
l'll keep you awake too...
all night
Let my pining be sated...
do something about it
My heart beats
in loneliness...
there's no one else
at home, my love
So come into my arms
Listen, lady...
listen, Goddess!
Someone tell her...
the lndian woman is most beautiful
and talented
But l don't want to be captured
My patience is breaking,
l'm slipping...
stop, stop, stop
The curtains are drawn
All windows are shut
For a while...
have all the fun you want to
My pining is soaring...
how can l remain
in my senses?
don't stop me anymore, my love
O enemy...
it's a beautiful moment
This youth craves
for your love
Take me in your arms...
don't think of anything else
Think of nothing else
Tara's jumping on his feet!
Let me watch!
Tara, you're on your feet...?
Are you out of your mind?
What have l done?
Tara! You're standing on your feet!
l have cured you!
Shake hands!
Tara has recovered!
l guess, you guys
have gone blind
He's standing on his feet!
Congratulations!
Heed my prayer now, sirs!
l'm very poor man...
with a mother, two brothers
and three sisters
Get your mother married,
find jobs for your sisters...
and get your brothers wedded.
- l can't get my mother married
l'll deal with that. Go away.
- l can't get her married
Get lost.
- Move it
l'm feeling great love for you.
- Don't tell me
l wrote about fifty or sixty
duets for you
And you stand up in a single duet?
- l'm a Punjabi, you know!
l can't hold! That's why
the girl's clean bowled!
Mr Cobra, your wound has healed,
the fracture has been set right too
l've been asking you
to try and walk around
You don't respond to anything l say.
- l can't walk, doctor
At this rate, you'll never
be able to walk all your life
You were hurt only in one leg...
- Watch it
l've read about a patient
in a medical journal
He was crippled in both legs.
Only because of his will power...
he can walk and move around today.
Read it
l don't want to read it...
- For inspiration. Read it
This is amazing inspiration
Had you shown it to me earlier, l'd
have been running at the Asian Games
l'd have won a medal for lndia.
- Good!
l want to sit up.
- Certainly
Open that.
- Of course
l want to sit
l can... sit up.
- Of course
Let him keep lying, doctor.
Else, we'll be put to sleep
Hush... this is the treatment.
- Doctor... can l stand?
Of course!
Help me to my feet, doctor.
l want to stand
Easy...
- l can stand!
Let him sit, doctor.
- Shut up. He's being treated
Can l walk, doctor?
- Oh yes
Carefully
You don't know him, doctor. ln a
little while, he'll ask if he can run!
l think l can run, doctor.
- Of course you can run
Let him run... it's the cure.
- l can run
Slowly
He'll run away!
- Exactly! l want him to run
Let me go! l can run.
You are great, doctor
Watch it... there's a glass-pane ahead.
- Stop him!
Where has he gone?
- He has run away!
l told you and you said
it was a cure!
After him! Get him!
Wait there... shoot him
in the leg!
Not his legs, l've just
treated his leg
Don't you think our life has changed,
ever since we've come here?
lt has changed, no doubt.
We haven't committed any robbery...
nor theft, nor picked a pocket.
- That's not what l'm talking about
l'm talking about the moonlike beauty.
About Pinki, that is
She picked me up from the wheelchair
and transported me to her heart
l say, Tara. Priti's made a place
for herself in my heart
Why don't we live here then?
Don't you think this is a much better
life than the one we led earlier?
What did we have anyway?
Running away from the cops...
and Cobra?
- Don't even talk about Cobra!
He's bitten us black and blue.
- l say, brother
We'll swim across
this river of love
Let's kick this wheelchair
together!
124...
125...
126...
127...
128...
What news have you brought
from Ram Singh?
Have you had enough of the cells...
that you've called me out
for a thrashing today?
Even if you change the location,
you'll ask the same old questions
Your first question: Where is the
ammunition you stole from the army?
Your second question: Whom have
you sold the ammunition to?
Third question:
Where is your hideout?
Right...?
- You forgot my fourth question
Where are your friends hiding?
- That question, l'll surely answer
My friends are close by
Plans to rescue me are also in place
The day l'm free...
you'll be finished, Ram Singh
l'll give you the opportunity
right now
Run away from here
and finish me
You think you're very brave?
Try crossing the main gate
and prove it
l'm the only one standing
between you and your freedom
No one will interfere
With the handcuffs?
- Release him
But remember something. lf l catch
you in the first attempt...
you're getting ten blows.
The second time... five
ln the third attempt, you won't be
able to take even one blow
Go on
Soldiers...
this is Ram Singh.
Nobody will stop Panther
Let him go anywhere he wants to
Traitor! You threaten
a soldier with death?
That was four blows, Ram Singh.
Just one to go, okay?
Hit me.
- The final blow, eh?
Ladies, listen...
l'm a very poor man
l have a mother, three sisters
and two brothers
All three have got to be married.
How would Tara and Sitara be...
for two of my sisters?
- Not good at all
What's wrong with them?
- Go and find other suitors
l'll do that if l can leave the house.
You won't let me go anywhere
By the way, why did you
say that, Priti?
Obviously! He spoke of getting my
Sitara married to one of his sisters!
Have you noticed his personality?
He's so handsome
With the glitter of gold...
with the sparkle of silver...
it was when the juice
of roses was extracted...
my beauty, my love...
was created
Those who look at me,
keep looking...
l'm the one they always
think about
Take me in your arms, my love...
make love to me
A bit concealed...
the mischief of your beauty...
it was when the juice
of roses was extracted...
your beauty, my love...
was crafted
Psst to you!
Back again!
This is Cobra speaking.
- Lovely voice. Call for you
Lovely voice...?
Must be my girlfriend
Listen to the romantic chat
l have with her
Where are you, darling?
- This is Cobra
Which cobra is this?
ls it the one we defanged...
and made a public mockery of?
- This is Cobra, your father!
lt was Cobra calling.
- l know
Why did you give it to me then?
- l was scared
l understand. l'm scared too.
- Let's sit down
Could he still be on the line?
Still holding
Tara, Sitara...
please come and sit down
Have something to eat,
why're you standing there?
lf you're not hungry, could l have
some juice served to you?
What's the matter, son?
You boys look worried
No worry...
it's just a bit of tension
Actually, both of us had
the same nightmare last night
A nightmare...? What was it about?
- We saw a snake... a cobra
A venomous cobra.
- That's a very bad omen
When you have a nightmare like that,
it means your enemy's after you
But you needn't worry. Just find
a small snake and feed it some milk
How about feeding Chhotu instead?
- Good idea
The headlines: The dreaded terrorist
Cobra has escaped from police custody
Cobra has escaped from jail
on several occasions earlier...
and the police are looking for him
Know when a terrorist breaks jail?
- When?
When he wants to extract revenge
from his enemies
l saw it in Sholay
Gabbar runs away from jail...
and takes revenge from his enemy.
Cobra's taking revenge too
What's wrong with him...?
He hasn't even had any lunch
He swallowed fear at breakfast
But why are you trembling?
- As if l'd be afraid!
Brother! Cobra is here!
- Hit him!
What are you doing here
so early in the morning?
That's my question. Why are you
sleeping here, instead of the bedroom?
Moron! We are guests and
guests can sleep anywhere
What are you doing here?
- Mr Ram Singh is leaving...
for the outpost for a couple of days.
l came to clean the jeep
And these guys sleep just anywhere
Cobra wouldn't have come here,
for fear of confronting Ram Singh
But if Ram Singh himself leaves,
what happens of our safety?
Say something.
- Know what?
l have an idea.
- Shoot
Why don't we go to the border
with Ram Singh...
and cross the fence
when we get the opportunity?
What made you plan a trip
to the border with me?
We wanted to ask you something
about our character
You ask him, brother.
- Me...? No, you ask him
Go ahead and ask... what is it?
Move it! Move!
Freeze!
Get in!
Here they are
Two more guys are coming
Here you are
lt won't go off.
- Try again
lt went off,
but it didn't hit him
The bullet hit his leg!
From your face...
take off the mask...
dear sir
Let the veil be,
do not take it off
lf the veil is taken off...
- Big deal?
You've got a bullet in the leg
and you're singing songs?
What's so special about him?
You've shot me in the leg!
You shot him in the leg again!
- lt's his mistake actually
His face has value in police circles
and the public
But how will the public know
what's behind the mask?
Let me drop the curtains
on your life!
You don't even know...
your days are getting over
The impossible is
about to happen...
start counting your days
One, two, three, four...
- Five, six, seven, eight...
add it up to eleven,
buddy boy
One and one is eleven...
my friend
l say...
- Tell me
Why has Ram Singh brought us here?
Looks like we're getting the
huge reward on Cobra's head
l've always thought that
the two of us are great men
But time has always
prevented our success
With times changing...
- Ram Singh will change too
Welcome, Ram Singh.
What do you want to ask now?
Not ask, l've come to
tell you something
What?
Your brother Cobra, who wanted
to kidnap me and have you freed...
has been killed
l want to tell you something more
lt wasn't me or
a soldier who killed him
He was slain by a couple
of brave civilians
l've brought them with me,
so you can see...
our civilians are no less
than soldiers
ls this a death sentence for us?
- l don't know
We always find happiness
to protect sorrow
l don't know. l'm fed up
Brother Panther, please don't pay
attention to what Ram Singh says
Whatever happened was an accident.
- lt sure was
You could say brother Cobra
was destined to die
And isn't God kind? He snatched
one brother from you...
and gave you two brothers instead.
- Brothers. Buy one, get one free
Brother Panther,
please be patient
l will be patient
But your brother wasn't patient.
No wonder the scoundrel died!
The poor guy.
- Oh yes
The day l escape from here...
l'll dig your graves
We're talking of patience
and he's talking of graves
Hold it. You might puke on his face
Why're you so sad?
Give me a smile
What do you think of that car?
Let me take you for a drive.
- Where?
Wherever destiny takes us
Let's think it over again. Will we be
able to live without Pinki and Priti?
No, brother don't!
We don't want to listen to the
tinkle of Pinki and Priti's bangles
We must heed the threat of Panther
Panther, who is caged...
he's baying for our blood
Turned your mind, didn't l?
- lf l say something...
you'll lose your mind too
- What?
The car is gone
We've lost the dough,
but the goddesses are here
Let's forget what is gone and
appreciate what's coming our way
For beauty, we burn
in the fires of passion
Like wax, we melt
We're crazy, we sway
We slip up
and steady ourselves
There's no one
quite like us...
my love...
One and one make eleven...
my love
Tara! Sitara!
Come on out!
What was that? Lightning? Thunder?
Or, has the roof come off?
What's up, son? What happened?
- l'm going to decide this today
Decide what?
- About Tara and Sitara's lives
You guys think l don't know
anything about you?
l know every thing. And today,
l've discovered your secret too
l say, Tara...
looks like the lid has been blown
off our bank robbery
Stand right here
What are you girls doing there?
Come here
Hurry up
Lovely couples
You think no one saw you
dancing and singing?
Every time l left for the border,
l always worried...
what would happen of my family,
if something happened to me
But l'm not worried anymore.
Even if something happens to me...
l know Tara and Sitara
will look after my family
l can't believe my luck that
l find such boys right at home
l'm so happy that you've finalised
a match for Priti and Pinki
Shouldn't you ask
Priti's parents too?
What's the problem? Take mother
and go over to their place
They won't find boys like these,
will they?
l'm so happy. lf Ram Singh
has sent the proposal...
it must be from a decent
and high ranking family
That's all right. But won't you
introduce the boys to us?
At once. Tara, Sitara...
don't feel shy
Come here
l say...
greetings
The brothers with
six bullets each
The same height and looks...
they'd look the same with beards
There were these scoundrels
who robbed my bank
These boys bear a striking
resemblance to those fellows
We look like scoundrels and criminals
to him, although we're well dressed
lmagine what he'd say if were
were dressed in kurta-pajama!
l can't tolerate this...
- But l can tolerate it
We don't want a proposal like this one!
- Let me go ahead, if you don't want it
Listen sons...
l was talking about
those two scoundrels
One of those scoundrels
looked just like you
He was talking of running
away with my daughter
Why're you calling us names
again and again?
l told you we must leave.
- l'm abusing those two chaps
But we're offended.
- Why?
Obviously. We look alike.
- l see
Now tell me, which one of you
is the thief?
Both, in fact
l want to know who's the thief
who stole my daughter's heart?
Who's my son-in-law?
l'm the one Mr Ram Singh sent.
- l see
Let's hurry up. l'm getting late.
- This is my watch!
lt's mine! With a T for Tara!
- No, T stands for Tiku
lt's Tara!
You'll now say this S is yours
This S is my wife's !
- S stands for Sitara
Tara and Sitara.
- Strange coincidence
We bought them.
We got the receipts too
Come, let's sweeten our tongue.
- After bitterness comes sweet
Come, my boys
We know, you make very
good porridge, don't you?
Also cauliflower pancakes!
- How did you get to know? How...?
How many times will you ask...?
We know everything
This is the hall, there's the bedroom,
and a bathroom with a commode
The safe's over there.
- And a table, on which...
Hold it!
Let's discuss it with Mr Ram Singh
and finalise a date for the wedding
Your car keys, sir
Brother...
- l say?
lt's a surprise!
Found it!
Why's he rolling over the bonnet?
Found it! The car!
Get the stuff out, l say.
lt's going to make our lives
One moment
Who...?
Your stuff is here
l'm getting it out.
- Your permanent stuff is here
You take care of her...
l'll attend to this
What happened?
- Carry on
What's happened to him?
- l'm feeling shy... Carry on
Why've you come to meet me
so late in the night?
l couldn't help it.
l've found my heart after ages
Get a hold on your heart...
it's only for a few days
No way. l've spent
so many days without it
l'm not letting it
slip out of my hands today
Go away, before someone comes here.
- Wide open
What?
- Doors... here and there
Who's that...?
Who is it? Tara and Sitara!
What are you doing here?
- This bag fell down.
We're putting it in
This is the bag in which those
thieves stuffed the loot!
You boys have found my money!
You've found the bag!
You're like Gods to me!
Tara, Sitara...
the two of you are great!
Give us the bag.
- You are great guys! You're angels!
Every Romeo has left
Every lover-boy has left
This isn't love...
it isn't about lovers...
you're no friend...
your love...
is treacherous love
Every Romeo has left
Every lover-boy has left
Let's not talk
about those crazy lovers
Those fireflies
are better forgotten
lt wasn't love...
it wasn't about lovers...
your love...
is treacherous love
Where's the show
of modesty anymore?
Where's the innocence
of yore?
The veil slips...
and nothing matters anymore
Nothing is sacred anymore,
the promises don't matter
Devastation is about to strike
Every Juliet has left...
every lover-girl has gone
into oblivion
Let's not talk
about those women...
it isn't love,
it isn't about lovers...
your love...
is full of deceit
Call the lover boy
Call lover-girl
Call Romeo
Call Juliet over
Summon Sohni,
call Mahiwal
Bring Paro
and Devdas here
How many of them
will you bring...?
This is love only in name
What good is this joy?
When you're heart-broken,
left in the lurch
When your trust is betrayed...
The love in your eyes
is make believe
Every drunken lover has gone
Those special people
are no more
Don't even talk of
folk singers...
nor those who set
examples in true love
lt isn't about love,
or the beloved...
your love is treacherous
Love...
Brother, l don't believe it.
He looked like Cobra
Was he Cobra himself?
What a shameless man!
We threw you off the cliff...
and you still climb up?
- There was water down there...?
There was nothing.
God saved me
And now, you guys will do
just as l ask you to
Why would God save him?
- Ask Him
Why would we listen to you?
We have always done the bidding
of only one person
Our mother!
- Your mother? Talk to her
Let me talk
Mother...? Why are you crying?
My son, these scoundrels have
kidnapped me and brought me here
Where are the two of you?
- Brother, Mother's crying
Mother... are you all right?
These scoundrels have given me
nothing to eat... the rascals
Mother!
- Just you listen!
We're going to ruin your life,
you filthy...
Chhotu, you've brought uncle today?
- He wanted to see the regiment
Go ahead and show him around.
Go on
This way, Uncle... this way
See the clout l wield?
l'm no lesser than Mr Ram Singh
Had you come alone, they've have
turned you away from the gate
They wouldn't have let you in, even
though you're Tara and Sitara's uncle
Chhotu's the one they respect!
Nothing's happening to you
till you're with me
Come straight after me.
Don't turn anywhere...
Don't shoot! l'm not an enemy...
l'm Major Ram Singh's relative
Major Ram Singh's relative
l'm glad you've arrived...
or your guys would've shot me
Yes, they would.
This is restricted area
We have orders to shoot
at strangers
Major, you have very tight
security here. What's up?
We're holding a very dangerous
criminal here. Panther
Panther, did you say?
He's the criminal whose brother
my nephews have killed!
He has threatened to
come out of jail and...
Not to worry, Uncle.
He can never escape
Not only do we have
very tight security...
the keys to the cell in which he's
locked is always in my custody
lt's safely kept
in my safe at home
Caught you, didn't l?
- What do you mean?
l know why you're secretly
moving around at this moment
What for?
- To steal
Steal...?
- Afraid, aren't you?
But you won't find anything there.
- Where ?
ln the kitchen.
You're hungry, aren't you?
You're hungry, right?
- Yes
l'll go and cook something.
- Hush!
All are sleeping.
- May l go and cook something for you?
My hunger has vanished
Go on. Go
Dad! Mom!
What happened?
Let them sleep
l've got to leave early for school.
lf l don't carry my fees...
my teacher's going to kill me.
- So take the money from Mummy's purse
But let them sleep. Go ahead
Where does Mummy
keep her purse?
She leaves the cupboard open!
Moron, you can't see anything.
- The purse is in the cupboard
lt's not there!
You take a look
lf l find the purse,
l'm going to fix you good
lt's right here
What's this ?
- l couldn't see it
Can you ever see anything
except food?
You'll find the rossogollas,
wherever they are
Tara...
- Yes, Sitara
Cobra's disappeared.
- He must be in the loo
He's not there.
- He's dark-skinned...
switch on the lights,
you'll find him
Get up, will you?
- What rubbish is this?
Let me sleep.
- l'm feeling scared!
Scared...? Scared of what?
- Cobra's not gone...
to free Panther, has he?
- lf he goes to free Panther...
it's good news for us.
He'll fall to the security's bullets
The bloody...
- Rat!
Not rat, the bloody...
Yes... rat!
- No, my boys
lf l die, who'll give you
the whereabouts of your mother?
Tell us something... where did you
disappear in the middle of the night?
To have this key made.
- lsn't that a key we heard of?
You mean we saw it earlier.
- We've broken so many locks
Must be the key to one of them.
- This is the key to Panther's freedom
Why has he thrown
the key in our face?
Explain this... why have you
thrown the key in our face?
l'll tell you. Because...
why did you throw it?
With that key, you're going to
free my brother Panther tonight
Why will the two of us
free your brother?
Because if you refuse to do that,
the Sun will rise tomorrow...
but your poor mother will
not see the new dawn
You're a bloody...
- Rat!
We'll do it for you...
let's shake paws!
Lower the beam.
- Tara?
Can't be you in both places, can you?
The officer's here, open up quickly
Raise the barrier. Quick
Mr Ram Singh's car?
- He has just arrived
At this hour?
Must l awaken him?
- With love
Shall l?
l say, brother!
Brother Panther...
He's not reacting,
he's not dead, is he?
Say nice things...
let me try
Brother Panther...
you're not dead, are you?
You're the ones who are
going to die. At my hands
You can't escape
Tara and Sitara?
We're helpless
Open the handcuff
l've found a truck driver.
We've got to leave in an hour
Where are we going?
- Wherever the truck takes us
You know, we have no place of our own.
- But...
we've ended up doing
something very horrible
What happened?
What is it, Mother?
What happened, Mother?
- l'm responsible for what you did
To save my life, the two of you
have risked your lives
Even my own children
wouldn't love me so much
Why are you harping on that?
You're hurting our feelings
Have we loved her any less
than our own mother?
Listen to me, Mother.
What's one lifetime...
we could sacrifice
ten lifetimes for you
What is the matter?
- We have some questions for you, sir
l'm sorry, l can't
talk to you
We're told you've been suspended
Two wanted thieves lived in your
house and you didn't even suspect...
their mission was to rescue Panther?
You're such a big officer...
you hold such an important post...
how could you be deceived, sir?
Apart from being an officer,
l'm also an lndian
We lndians have a huge weakness
We're very emotional
When a poor man comes to our door,
we share our food with him...
without even finding out
whether he's hungry or not
When someone comes seeking shelter...
we give him shelter in our house,
without finding out...
what lies in his heart
l was blind to have
wished to marry Tara
How was l to know that the man
l wanted as my life-companion...
would ruin my brother's
life some day
To save their mother's life, Tara
and Sitara had Panther released...
but it was poor Ram Singh
who had to bear the punishment
As someone truly said, he paid for
the sins the boys had committed
What are you doing...?
What?
You were the one who
always lent us courage
And we stand by you today.
We are with you
Dad, whenever l didn't
do well at my studies...
or was found lacking
in sports and games...
you were the one who always told me,
A soldier's son must never give up
lf the one who gave me hope
himself gives up...
what will happen of us?
- My son...
your father never gave up,
nor will he ever
No enemy has ever escaped
my eyes
What l regret is that those two
enemies lived in my own house...
and escaped my scrutiny
No, sir...
l'm the guilty one!
They made me tell them
everything about the family
l'd rather you shoot me, sir!
- Chhotu!
l'll kill those who have
betrayed all of us
Bastards!
Whom did the bullet hit?
- Not me
Tara, we came here to explain
our situation to him
But he's shooting at us
even before we can speak
l think this crisis that goes on
and on in our lives...
Mr Ram Singh, if you could hear
us out before you shoot at us?
l want to listen to nothing!
Nobody moves! Else, l'll shoot
Madam, you step here...
it's a request
You come here, brother
You're kidnapping me...?
- l swear it on God!
Nobody moves!
Else, l'll shoot the old lady!
Dad! Save Grandma!
- Have patience
Fatso, not even your father
can save your grandma!
You know what that means?
Not a word against Dad!
- Patience
Sir, even if l die,
l'm going to fix these guys!
Cut that bloody crap!
You have a mother, two brothers
and three sisters
You're going to die without
getting them married?
Not my Mother...
- Your sisters will remain unmarried
l'll see how you don't
get your mother married!
No tricks, please.
- No smartness... no
l'm not playing any tricks.
l'll do just as you say
Only let my mother go
See? lt kills you, doesn't it?
That's how mothers are
Just as your love for your mother
makes you helpless...
the two of us were helpless too.
- True
Cobra had kidnapped our mother.
He asked us to have Panther freed
Had we not had Panther freed,
the scoundrel...
The bastard!
- The sonofagun...
the bloody owl...
- The ape!
Come to the point.
- He'd have killed our mother
How could we give death to the
mother who gave us our lives?
Don't cry, Tara...
Give me the gun.
- What's the problem?
Mr Ram Singh, we enacted this drama
to make you see the truth
lf you still don't trust us,
take this gun...
and shoot us!
- What are you doing?
lf you must give the gun to someone,
give it to the mother...
she has a mother's heart!
And Ram Singh is only her son
Mr Ram Singh, please forgive us
Circumstances have driven us
to commit these bad deeds
But we're not bad human beings.
- Mr Ram Singh...
we've never wanted to
ruin anyone's family
Give us just one chance
We're the ones who set Panther free.
We'll be the ones to bring him back
That's not all.
Let me tell you, Mr Ram Singh
The respect and the happiness your
family has lost because of us...
we brothers will restore to you.
- That's not all
Just give us one more opportunity.
That's all there is to it
l see truth in what you say
Go on. l give you an opportunity
Pinki, l saw your interview
on television
You said that you're blind
Had you been blind, where would you
have found a handsome man like me?
l have a request...
please accept me
No?
She's willing, because she's shy.
- Don't tell me!
Please telephone Priti and tell her
that Sitara has turned a new leaf
And do tell yourself too, that
your Tara has also turned a new leaf
One moment
l called you a fatso.
- But he is a fatso
Brother, we made tall claims and
spoke impressive lines in there
But where are we going
to look for Panther?
You played the lion
from Punjab in there
You spoke of restoring the family's
happiness and honour
Can't help it. lt's the Punjabi blood
which is forever on the boil
But what are we going to do now?
- Brother...
that was the way mother showed us
A way out of this,
mother will show us too
Mother!
Tara, Sitara... the two scoundrels...
- What are you saying, Mother?
This is the place those two
scoundrels brought me to
Amazing! She has brought us
to the enemy's den!
That's how a mother is.
- Enough
This is no time for emotions,
it's action time
Go and keep your promise
Go and inform Ram Singh.
ln the meantime, we'll fix these guys
Watch it!
Mother! You've learnt to drive?
Mother has learnt to drive, brother.
- That's how a mother is
Right
l'm leaving your country, so l thought
l'd say bye to you one last time
You did throw your weight around
in that uniform
You will now bow your head
out of shame all your life
You asked me many questions
in custody
But Panther has the last word
Have you set the landmines?
- Yes
And the bombs?
- Yes sir
Not a trace of evidence
we leave behind
We've loaded the stuff.
So let's move
Stop the van!
Chase!
l'm so happy today
Without any bloodshed,
or doing anything wrong...
we've done something great
for the country
l'm so happy!
- Drive the van!
l feel like crying.
- Concentrate, will you?
Overtake the van!
Hold it!
Right or left? Where do we go?
- This is the first time...
we've done something right,
so take a right
That guy's gonna fall
l'm very excited today.
- Why?
Ram Singh will happily get us married.
After that...
we'll have kids from Pinki and Priti.
- Concentrate on the wheels!
What do l take now?
Right or left?
l'm even more excited.
- No excitement. Drive the van!
Listen...
- No, drive the van
l say... have we returned
to the same place?
You kept saying right and
brought us to the wrong place
When the time is right,
you come to the right place
Your time isn't right.
Ours is
Get the clowns
Strange story...
it begins and ends
What destination...
- You can't sing! Not you!
Who told you to suggest
so many rights!
You were the one who was driving.
- And who asked me to take right?
He couldn't understand,
nor could l...
What destination...?
- Not you! You can't sing!
Skip the nonsense.
- No nonsense, you don't know
This chap creates the trouble
and lands me in the soup
l create the trouble?
- Oh yes
Brother Panther, ask brother Cobra
who shot him in the leg
lt was him!
- One moment
Where was the need to say that?
Landed me in trouble again
Even if l shot at you,
who gave the gun to me?
lt was him!
- One moment!
Where was the need to say that?
All right, never mind
Ask him who gave him those kicks
and took him to the corner?
lt was him!
- One moment...
l forgot what l had to say...
where was the need to say that?
Oh yes, even if l pushed you around...
who was the one who
gave him the final kick
Who was it?
Who kicked you?
Both of us had kicked him.
Both of them had kicked me.
- l'm not sparing them!
Get them!
Where has the grenade disappeared?
- Why didn't it explode?
lt hasn't gone into a coma, has it?
There... gotcha!
Kick it. lt's been years
since we played soccer
l'm David Beckham!
- No, l'm David Beckham!
lt's me!
- Me!
What are they up to?
- They're playing with the bomb!
All right, l'm Ronaldo
Kick it
l'm Ronaldo!
How can you be Ronaldo and
David Beckham? That's not happening
They're coming for us...
- Let go!
Tara and Sitara...
scored a goal.
C'mon!
Find them!
Find them! Move it!
We're hiding in the tank, no doubt.
But can you drive it ?
l can't even ride a bicycle
and you talk about a tank?
l'm only talking out of tension,
don't get worked up
l once pushed a handcart,
but l can't even do that now
They're in the tank!
What's happening here?
- What's going on?
The headphone...
listen to the news
Kill them!
What happened?
- They say they're going to kill us
Brother! l'm so scared
Numbers... ever played roulette?
- Yes
Try a lucky number.
- One moment
What's happening here?
Those guys are kidding us
out there!
Know what?
Try one and one... it's eleven
Explosion, brother!
Shiva!
Remember what Mother used to say?
When nothing else works...
a prayer yields fruit.
So let's pray
God's gift!
We played football with it, remember?
- Let's play catching the ball
lf you remember, when we gave it
a hard kick, it simply blew up
ls it the same one...? You take it!
- You take!
Toss it out... Go on!
Let's try some more noises?
- What noises?
Press these buttons,
something will give way
Something blew up out there!
Kasim, l'm not in the car...
You said you couldn't
even ride a bicycle
So how're you driving a tank?
A bicycle needs to be balanced...
this is balanced on its own
l don't get this. Can you explain?
Our bag of tricks...
the world will see
We're different...
there's no one
quite like us
There hasn't been anyone like us...
nor will there ever be...
buddy-boy
One, two, three, four, five, six,
seven, eight, nine, ten and one...
one and one makes eleven...
buddy-boy
You don't even know...
your death is soon arriving
Stop!
The impossible
is about to happen...
so start counting
your days
One, two, three, four...
- Five, six, seven, eight...
ten and eleven...
Where have they gone? And who did
this all this? Mr Ram Singh?
There's Cobra!
Here you are.
- You use it
l have a bad aim. You shoot at him.
- l can't shoot at all
Let's try together.
- Suits me
We hit his leg again!
You shoot me in the leg again!
Brother...
Die, you swine! How long
am l going to carry you?
No one can tie Panther down
l'm not sparing you!
- Panther's running away
Like the other day,
won't you wager a bet today?
No more blows?
Today... you get only one blow
One? For Panther?
What is the story of Tara and Sitara?
Can you explain it?
You know l can't explain.
Still, l will try
Although Tara and Sitara
stay in darkness...
they give light to the whole world.
- My word!
For the first time, you've
explained it without any hiccups!
Also for the first time,
we have done something good
But there's something
piercing my heart
What?
- Ram Singh's family...
made no attempt to stop us!
You're leaving without telling me?
- As if you'd have stopped us
l could've dropped you
at the station in my jeep
We don't need any jeep.
- We can walk also
He's offering us a lift!
l've arranged a mare for you
For the first time ever
Tara and Sitara realised...
that good company could
reform the worst of them
When the power of one and one
helped humanity and the nation...
they had found their wives,
a family and a comfortable life
But old habits die hard.
They wouldn't guarantee otherwise