Yes, those are his victims.
All of them died under
his cruel claws.
And many more will be added
to the funeral procession,
if you don't stop that
insatiable  murderer.
These coffins oppress your heart,
Juan Carlos,
as if it were your duty
to carry all of them...
with what little strength you have.
So be it, then, until you discover
the murderer...
and annihilate him!
Rest not, Juan Carlos,
rest not.
Search for him in the world,
find him and kill him
with your bare hands!
Behold!
The time has come!
There's the murderer!
He's in your hands!
Kill him!
Finally, you'll see his face.
What's his face look like,
how's the look in his eyes?
Oh, poor boy.
You'll never see that face.
You'll never break,
because the murderer has no face.
He doesn't even have
the face of death.
He is nothing but
a faceless man.
" T H E   F A C E L E S S
M A N "
Directed by
Juan Bustillo Oro
Oh Lord, please have
mercy on us,
those who carry death
in our very own souls.
Those who didn't know how to chain
the bloodthirsty beast that dwells in our hearts.
Those who released the monster
who ended up tearing us apart from the inside.
Have mercy, oh Lord.
Have mercy on us.
Hey, my friend!
where are you headed for in such a hurry?
Do you want to die, or kill someone?
- Did you hear me?
- No.
- Papers, please.
- Uh?
- Documents, please.
- Oh, you're Doctor Britel,
from the police?
Sorry to have stopped you, doctor;
Please moderate your speed.
Drive safe.
- Are you sick?
- No. I'm fine.
I'm a murderer, I've killed,
and remorse overwhelms me.
I must write a confession to
avoid choking in anguish.
This is the most terrible punishment,
but my crime has an explanation.
I must tell all, in order to be understood.
Everything! I must start with the
events of that tragic night,
back last December.
" Another crime by the mysterious
murderer of women "
No doubt, this is the same murderer.
Yeah, same method of operation
and the same ruthless brutality.
Has maimed the body
just like the other ones.
The work of a beast,
but with surgical precision.
And the same for our inability
to stop that filthy monster.
What kind of idiots are we,
what kind of incompetent is the commissioner?
- This isn't an easy case.
- Those aren't experts, they're useless!
Come with me doctor,
those useless people should listen to us!
Find that idiot Lozano
as soon as possible!
I want to talk to him right now!
Dumb ass!
Stupid!
You're a bit harsh with Juan Carlos.
Harsh? For how many months
has he led this investigation?
Where are the results?
In the mass graves, where the mutilated
bodies of these women are rotting!
Juan Carlos is a great officer,
and has resolved very complicated cases.
- When he was working!
- You know, he had a lot of trouble
with this case.
So, what's wrong with him?
You know he's clueless,
banging away at emptiness,
even though he used to solve
the most difficult crimes.
He must take into account many factors;
as to whether or not there was a prior relationship with the victim,
and once he finds the right track,
that will lead him to the truth.
- Yeah, but...
- In this case, the murderer
didn't know the victims.
This savage kills any woman
who crosses his path.
- He must have a reason.
- Yeah, a reason within himself.
His only reason seems to
be that they're women,
ugly, beautiful, young or old,
no matter, just women.
Certainly this a monstrous
indulgence of instinct,
and it's clear the investigator
isn't a psychic.
Go on!
- Hello.
- Hi, Juan Carlos.
- Good morning, Chief.
- Lozano, my friend,
I want to warmly congratulate you...
Cut the irony and
tell me clearly what you want.
- You should already have an idea.
- Naturally.
"Naturally"? Is that all you can say?
Nothing more about your utter failure?
No, but it crossed my mind that
you'd accept my resignation.
- Your resignation?
- Yes.
Even if you hadn't called me here,
I would have resigned anyway.
- Excuse me.
- Wait a minute, Lozano!
- What do you want?
- I have four things to say.
- Go ahead, I deserve it.
- Sure you do!
The problem is not your inefficiency,
but your cowardice!
I've failed.
I have totally failed!
On this matter!
Precisely, the very case I asked about furiously!
This case was my pride,
even my conscience.
Look Lozano, this is no
time to flinch!
I know the case is difficult,
but you've solved greater mysteries.
I can't! Don't you
see that I can't!
Take it easy, Juan Carlos.
Take it easy.
Obstacles shoulf be our greatest
encouragement!
You need a drink,
and think things over.
No, what I need...
I just don't know.
Let's think about this issue over
a whiskey, you'll see.
It's useless, Eugenio,
please don't insist.
I can't go on with the case.
Didn't you say that your
conscience is at stake?
You know it is.
- So?
- I don't know.
I don't know what's wrong
with me.
It's possible my own anxiety
is interfering with my abilities.
Also there may be something more serious.
Something more serious?
Like what, Juan Carlos?
I don't know...
Look, this sounds foolish,
but I'm almost certain...
that I'm the reason
the murderer...
mutilates his victims, he
actually wants to break me!
Break you?
How come?
Maybe by leading me to make errors.
From failure to failure.
No, Eugenio! I don't
want to fail again!
- I'm sick of my failures.
- Yeah, you just pointed out the problem!
- Why?
- You're suffering, not because of
your failing,
yeah, not because of your failing,
but by your fear of failure.
You've always had a
pathological fear of failure.
No, you're wrong.
Then why did you leave your surgical career, just when
you were about to become a doctor with honors?
- That wasn't my way!
- And why did you abandon so
many other things!?
So you became a police officer,
and now you want to give up yet again.
Do you really want to know?
Because I'm useless!
Do you hear me?!
I'm good for absolutely nothing!
Stop being a coward, Juan Carlos.
If you want to heal your soul,
confront your fears with courage,
and don't turn your back
on responsibility.
- What do you mean?
- Act like a man. Finish your work!
I can't.
I tell you, I can't!
Why not?
Would you feel less of a loser
if you quit?
You see?
If you give up your duty, each new victim
of that sadist will weigh on your conscience.
And your confusion will increase!
Don't hesitate; it's not
the triumph that'll set you free,
but to stay in the game until the end.
And if by the end,
you're defeated,
at least attain peace within yourself.
Don't you see?
Maybe you're right.
- Just "maybe"?
- No! You're right!
It's true; the murderer
can't escape so easily!
Sure.
It must be I who catches him
and puts him in the hands of the law.
And if I have a chance,
I'll kill him like a mad dog,
as viciously as he's
done to his victims!
Self-control,
self-control.
Don't be discouraged as you were before,
or reckless as you are now.
I'd rather see you as well,
don't give up!
- Don't give up.
- I won't! On the contrary,
I'll be more cunning!
That's the spirit!
I'll take the first step now.
I guarantee you that I'll succeed!
Every day the lousy life of
this loser becomes more interesting.
If he manages to get to where I think,
he may resist the terrible test,
and let us see how he reacts
to the next murder.
Another victim, Eugenio.
Yes, another one.
That devil is laughing at me
and all of us!
He's as cunning as a beast.
His instinct is cunning and bestial.
- These crimes are instinctive.
- Disgusting is what they are!
You don't know how I despise myself
for not being able to stop this.
You know for an investigation like this,
you must have a bulletproof patience.
Yeah, and lose one's dignity.
- One should be lowered to
snooping in landfills!
- Why?
- Do you have any clue?
- None.
What else can I do?
It's not just a lunatic who kills for
some (sexual) impulse.
For some (sexual) impulse.
- It could be.
- It might be!
Well, we must go to where
criminals gather...
and wait for a telltale word,
a gesture, anything that would
betray the murderer.
That sounds like an exciting endeavor.
For me it's exciting.
I've always been fascinated by
the depths of the human soul.
I should go with you sometime.
Want to make sure I'm not doubting myself,
and doing my duty?
- Not for that reason.
- You can come anytime.
- How about tonight?
Okay. Tonight.
- Where will we go?
- You'll find out.
Is everything ready?
We must wait; we can't do
anything with damn Lozano here.
It disgusts me to come to
these filthy holes.
- It fills me with nausea.
- You don't come for pleasure?
Hear that dirty music.
It speaks to the lowest of men.
Look around; everything is
just vice and shadows.
Thick, smelly smoke;
drunkenness and lust.
- Especially lust.
- So what? You've business to attend to.
- Enough! I can't take any more of this!
- Juan Carlos!
- That guy is drunk.
- What's wrong with him?
Now that you're calm,
can you explain your absurd behavior?
I can't; I can't
understand it myself.
There's something wrong with you,
something serious.
What is it?
Why you don't say?
I just don't know.
Except that every day, I lose even more.
I feel like I'm losing my my mind.
I'm about to fall into the abyss.
Then, I feel a deep fear.
Cold, thoughtless!
But I can't define what it is.
I'm your friend, also a doctor.
I can help you, trust me.
We must dig into the depths of your soul.
- Dig into my soul?
- The idea scares you, right?
And rightly so; we all carry an inner demon,
who doesn't want to faced.
There are many aspects
about ourselves that we ignore.
Things that have been buried deep inside,
that hurt even more.
That must be it: this destroying fear
is within my own soul.
Haunting me in the back,
from my inner darkness.
- You see?
- Help me, Eugenio. Save my soul,
if we have time.
It depends on yourself,
on your courage.
I will be your guide,
but you have to do the hard work.
It's a difficult task,
one impossible for a coward.
You'll reach the darkest part of your conscience,
and confront your more horrific creatures.
I have the will to do it.
Considers that very brave souls have
gone back to confront their uncleanness;
and having once receded, are lost forever.
I won't. I'll be doing as you will me to.
Then, let us begin with the
formal treatment now.
Come with me.
Lie down on the couch.
Lie down, feel comfortable.
Try to calm down.
And now, let your imagination
freely overflow.
Let the thoughts come to your
mind, without resisting.
And if any thought disgusts you,
don't try to push it away.
Usually, we defend ourselves against thoughts
that bring us a lot of harm.
We'll have a quiet conversation.
I'll ask questions, not look for answers.
Answer quickly what first come to mind.
Ask me.
What comes to your mind,
just remembering your sense of fear?
The faceless man!
Don't get up,
rest.
Who is the faceless man?
- The murderer.
- Why is he faceless?
- Because of my dreams.
- Your dreams? Tell me about them.
Dreams hold secrets,
even though we refuse to acknowledge that.
What are you dreaming about?
There is one specific dream,
a recurring one, like an obsession.
I want to hear about it.
There's a woman in the mist,
a woman who orders me to
go behind the murderer...
she says not until I unmask that man,
will I achieve my rest.
Then, I saw him.
He leaves, but without haste.
I go after him, with anger.
Sometimes I kill him,
at other times,
I can only stop him.
But at every opportunity,
when I crave to see that unknown face,
I find that he is... faceless.
So I'm overcome by this fear
that eats at my soul.
Then, the lady laughs at me,
and mocks my failure.
Juan Carlos, are you afraid
to see the face of the murderer?
Fear? On the contrary,
it's my greatest wish.
Right. Now tell me,
do you know who that lady is?
My mother... I mean,
no! I don't know her.
It's very important to tell me the truth.
- Yes, my mother.
- Why did you deny it before?
Because I wasn't aware of it.
Only until now was I sure.
We keep forgetting the
cruelest aspects of our dreams.
- This is the most cruel.
- Leave it for now.
- There's another dream.
- Oppressive as well?
Very oppressive, and fairly recent.
I had it, just last night.
I entered the foyer of my own home,
but walked in the shadows,
hopeless, unable to recognize
anything in my environment.
Suddenly, some grotesque inanimate
forms surrounded me,
statues, reminiscent of vague human shapes,
blurred, asexual.
Especially, asexual.
However, I knew that those ghosts
were cheap sluts.
I wanted to buy them with all my heart,
but the offer was disgusting to me.
I tried not to look at them anymore,
and continued on my way.
I steadily returned to the dark.
I knew my fate:
I would go to an undue place,
in a hurry.
Yes! I finally faced the feared and desired
forbidden door.
I could not miss that opportunity.
I entered, even though I knew
I shouldn't.
Now, I had to descend to
the depths of my own home,
down without hesitation,
everything underneath where one
can get, in a vacuum.
So, my feet reached the
bottom of the abyss.
And after wandering wearily,
I stopped. I stopped with
deep anguish!
Because I had just entered
the realm of my biggest fear.
There, the monster was chained,
content in a prison which
he should never leave.
Moaning in sadness
for his old enclosure,
He cried for his chain,
as old as antiquity itself.
My soul was full of sorrow,
I decided to release the monster,
at any price.
Just saw it off, and I knew
that with this rash act,
my soul was lost forever!
He did it, Eugenio.
He accepted the offer,
bought them to destroy them,
to shred them to death...
in a vicious attack!
Then, he started out again
on the streets.
No rush,
absurdly quiet.
Suddenly, he stopped and
turned to look me in the eyes!
My blood ran cold.
My God, the faceless murderer!
Released by my own hand!
That damn spectre,
during the days
I go after him,
and during the nights
he comes after me.
What you've told me
is very interesting,
that the faceless man isn't the
murderer.
Dreams never say
what they really mean,
they're expressed symbolically.
For example, the statues
of women for sale,
represent prostitutes,
which are the target
of the murderer.
It's true. I can see
that clearly now.
No doubt, your obsession with the murderer,
has a deep connection with
a sexual symbol,
so we must explore that avenue.
- What avenue?
- Your love life.
My love life?
What is this, Eugenio?
I never loved any woman
but my mother.
This is the second time you've
mentioned her, there's a reason behind it.
Besides love, what else
do you associate with her? Speak quickly.
Failure.
The story of my life.
What failure?
A broken heart, perhaps?
Yeah, In some way that
ended up with a broken heart.
- How can you know that?
- Talk me about your broken heart.
It's of no importance.
Even so, I want to hear about it.
What for? Actually, it didn't have
much effect on my life.
- I didn't love her.
- Even so, talk about it.
I was about to get married,
some years ago,
in my hometown.
It happened during one of my vacations...
in Guadalajara. My girlfriend
Ana Maria was an orphan...
my mother gave her refuge
as a child,
and treated her like a daughter.
So, she lived at home,
always near to me.
We confused our feelings,
due to our constant companionship.
We believed we shared
a deep love.
I wanted to marry her,
at a date fast approaching.
Then, an obstacle that we had almost
forgotten appeared,
that filled us with fear.
- Juan Carlos!
- Everything's ready,
Ana Maria...
our wedding's next month.
It's too soon, we must wait.
Why? Don't you love me?
You know I love you, but don't you think
your mom should know about our plans?
- Of course.
- Aren't you afraid of her reaction?
I do. She's going to hate me.
She keeps saying that the woman you love
will be the thief who'll take you away from her.
And that you belong only to her.
And she would consider your wife
as an intruder,
and she would never be forgiven!
My mother was very kind,
but way too possessive,
she was terrified to share
my love with someone else.
she always tried to control me,
forgetting that I was no longer a child.
I thought that satisfying her desires
was my main duty.
My biggest satisfaction.
But I wasn't going to give her the opportunity
to speak about my wedding.
So I told that to Ana Maria.
I don't mind if your mother objects,
even if she hates me.
I respect her, love her.
But I love you even more.
- Ana Maria...
- Juan Carlos...
I wasn't sure that you loved me enough
to have such an independent will.
I know it's a big load for you,
So I'll be your wife at any time.
No regrets.
However, she never became my wife.
Because of my mother, in some way.
Fortunately, I had a head's up.
I discovered my mistake.
One afternoon, after returning home,
I heard a cry, and a
hysterical voice in the room.
Thankless, ungrateful!
This is the love of a "mother"?
This is my reward for the love
and care that I've given to you?
I saved you from misery,
picked you up from the street!
So this is my reward?
My son... is mine!
Mine, you hear?
My son will not be in the arms of another woman,
not while I'm alive!
That was too much for me!
For the first time, I felt a furious
rebellion against mom!
I rebelled against her authority,
against my slavery!
against everything that had
represented the essence of my life.
No, Ana Maria, he will never
be yours.
Enough!
Shut up! Say no more.
- Juan Carlos!
- You've shocked me!
- Your selfishness is monstrous!
- My son.
Don't "son" me. I don't need
a dubious love.
- Juan Carlos...
- Leave me, let me free myself.
I don't want this woman
to continue enslaving me.
My happiness lies with Ana Maria,
don't you get it?!
- My life belongs to you, Juan Carlos.
- I don't care about your life!
It seemed as if I had physically injured her,
in a mortal way.
I, her very own son!
She paled, turned away,
and when she was going out,
faded away.
My words were so harmful,
she fell ill.
She was slowly dying,
and I was filled with regret.
I felt like her murderer,
as if I had stabbed her.
I was filled with a grudge
against Ana Maria, the culprit.
That tense situation ended up
in a deep crisis.
The night my mother was dying.
When she called me,
I came in fear and shame.
I didn't know how to handle the situation.
Ana Maria was there,
I think I looked at her with hatred!
She looked away, no longer
with those loving eyes I knew.
Juan Carlos, my son, come closer.
I want you to hear me,
maybe for the last time.
I will die soon.
No mother! Don't even
say that!
I'll die, and as all I've ever wanted
is your happiness,
marry her, Juan Carlos.
Marry Ana Maria, if that is
your desire.
Marry her, even if it costs
me my life.
No mother, you won't die,
I'm not going to marry her.
Live! Don't leave me alone
with this terrible remorse!
I swear I will not marry while you live.
- Don't you love her?
- I... hate her.
I deeply hate her for the
damage she did to you!
So we must be this way.
I will live, perhaps forever!
Since then, Ana Maria and I were strangers.
- We weren't able to forgive her.
- But your mother regained her health?
Completely healed.
- How did you know?
- It's logical,
the cause of it disappeared,
and so the disease ceased.
She had gotten away with it.
- Away with it?
- Leave that, for good.
The important thing is that we begin
to discover the source of your anxiety.
Is it not your fear, a desire to fail?
- Who wants to fail?
- So many! Maybe even you.
Since you were a child, you learned to curb
your desires, to please your mother,
and you maintained that habit.
But as an adult, your impulses
have become too large to restrain,
you let them manifest,
but only for a time,
and at the end, you've chosen
to abandon those urges.
Maybe...
And your crush has been the same.
You're wrong! I didn't actually
love Ana Maria!
You've never wanted
to be free from your mother.
You lie! My mother passed away
two years ago; I haven't changed.
The saying "the dead speak out"
is true, Juan Carlos.
Don't say that.
If someone controls us too much,
even if it is out of love,
they become an object of hatred.
Sometimes, unwittingly,
we wish the death of that person.
- That's a lie!
- Your life is full of remorse.
Because until today, you think you've
killed your mother, because of your desires.
That's a lie! It's not true!
Your loving failure may be
related to the murderer,
who commits crimes of a sexual nature.
Enough! Shut up!
- You must enjoy increasing my confusion!
-Courage, courage.
No time to step back.
Don't lose heart!
- You're trying to scare me.
- On the contrary!
I want to rest for today,
I feel exhausted.
I'm sick, I have no strength
to continue.
Okay, we must revisit this
another day.
Perhaps we worked too hard
in the first session.
Remember that your salvation depends
on your perseverance.
My salvation?
Or perhaps my ultimate downfall.
Finally, I just dragged him
in the direction I wanted.
He's already in my hands!
Juan Carlos...
Why would you never talk to me?
I have nothing to say.
For several days now you've returned,
even told me that you were
glad to see me.
I've been looking forward to your return,
as if God only gave me life
to see you again.
Since your mother died,
I've been here,
waiting, with my heart full
of love for you, as always.
Dreaming to be yours.
Yes, I know this is just a dream,
an absurd dream,
but nothing's changed by your absence,
or this silence, which is even worse!
Hope is in me.
You're very wrong.
My mother didn't separate us,
but my own will.
Alive or dead, mom has nothing
to do with this.
I didn't love you, Ana Maria.
That broke our engagement, forever.
Got it!?
Forever...
Coward...! Coward!
You're a Coward, Juan Carlos!
You lie,
you know you're lying,
You love me as I love you,
but you deny it out of cowardice!
By denying your weakness,
by not escaping your authoritarian mother.
You stand by your lie now,
as you will, forever.
Coward, indeed!
Coward!
Your mother continues to exert
her ghostly will on you!
She is still a barrier between us.
She may as well be still alive.
As she said... forever.
What happens, Juan Carlos?
Who's that slut that smooches
with a thug, at the door of my house!?
That may be Rosa, the maid.
She is not a slut, and
her boyfriend is not a thug.
He is a decent guy, they're getting
married next month.
He comes to town on Sunday,
and comes here to greet Rosa.
- Tell her to come.
- What for?
- Tell her to come!
- Rosa!
- Go. See you tomorrow!
I'm coming, dear!
- Yes, miss.
- He wants to talk to you.
- Pick up your stuff and leave.
- You're fired.
- Fired? Why?
This is a decent house.
Beat it.
- Don't you hear me, get out!
- How is she going to leave at this hour?
- It's close to midnight.
Where can she go?
- That's her business.
Don't worry miss, I can take
care of myself and I've got a place to go.
I'll get my things.
Good bye, miss. Thanks for
being nice to me.
Nice? I couldn't help
your dismissal.
Don't worry, The decision
was made by the Master.
I'll stop by here to say hello.
- I'll send the promised wedding gift.
- Thank you, miss!
- Take care.
Bye.
- What do you want?
- I'm a police officer.
- A cop?
- I need to know if Rosa Martinez
worked here.
- Yes, why do you ask?
- Why did she leave home at
midnight with her stuff?
Well, the homeowner fired her.
I want to have a word with him.
Wait a moment.
I just fired her. I have the right
to make that decision, don't I?
- Certainly.
- So, I have nothing more to say.
Why this question?
Has something happened to that woman?
Yes, and in a way, you are responsible
for sending her into the street at that hour.
What happened to her?
Say it.
- Please give me your name.
- Juan Carlos Lozano.
Juan Carlos Lozano? From
the police?
The city police, yes.
Ah, you're here to
track the mutilator.
The mutilator?
Why do you ask?!
Because the mutilator was here.
Your maid has been his
latest victim.
She was slaughtered just a few
steps away from here.
And I think he chose that victim only
to mock you, and the police.
Go to police headquarters,
there you'll find our collaboration.
I'm at your service, unconditionally.
- Excuse me. So long, miss.
- Good evening.
- What's wrong, Juan Carlos?
- I'm lost, Ana Maria...
- I'm lost.
- Why?
My intuition didn't fail,
it was not just my imagination.
- The murderer is after me.
- What are you saying?
You can't imagine the horror
of my situation, Ana Maria.
Eugenio.
- You, here in town.
- What's up, why are you looking
at me like that?
- What do you want here?
- I came for duty.
- I came for an important assignment.
- Liar!
Liar?
- When did you arrive?
- Yesterday at morning.
- Why didn't you come to me right away?
- Because... I don't know.
I do know.
Follow me. We need to talk.
What happened to Juan Carlos?
I don't know, the news of a crime
that happened near his house made him angry.
Put him in my hands. I'm a doctor,
and a close friend of his.
Dr. Eugenio Britel, at your service.
And you, you're Ana Maria, right?
Yes, how do you know?
- Juan Carlos talked about me?
- A lot.
- Eugenio!
I told you to come.
I need to talk you.
There will be time for us
to talk, Ana Maria.
Excuse me.
Here I am, Juan Carlos.
I'm listening.
- Do you know that the mutilator
is here, in Guadalajara?
- Yes.
- How do you know?
- I work for the
police, too, you know.
- I know even more about you.
- Like what?
That you're the murderer!
You are!
You always have been;
you're here to play with my mind!
What do you want from me?
I don't understand you!
You want to experiment with me,
like I was a lab rat,
and ruin my mind!
Do you want to get back to something?
If so, say it now.
Put an end to this.
Stop torturing me!
Come on, Juan Carlos;
take it easy.
Are you so deranged
as to say that nonsense?
Forgive me... I don't know
what I'm saying.
The murderer is near,
it drives me crazy!
That shouldn't be more
than a coincidence.
That should not affect you this way.
- I can't help it.
- Yes, you can.
Why did you abandon the treatment?
- It hurt me.
- What hurts is being brought out of you.
Look, you don't even take care of
your personal hygiene.
I don't care about my looks.
This is further evidence of your
morbid abandonment.
Look at that bag,
It's been here for several days,
and you haven't even unpacked it.
I haven't had time.
What about Ana Maria?
Ana Maria...?
I don't let her touch my stuff.
What are you doing here,
Juan Carlos?
What?
What are you looking for?
That...
what's that?
The knife, don't you see?
- A scalpel.
- A scalpel?
- Where was it stored?
- Here.
- I didn't put it there.
- That's not important.
This is your stuff from when
you were a medical student.
I got rid of it all.
But if that scalpel was mine,
I would know if I'd put it there.
It wouldn't be strange to forget
something like this. You're too deranged.
No, I would remember.
I would remember, I say.
- Eugenio.
- What?
- Not yours, right?
- Juan Carlos!
You are in an absurd nervous state.
You shouldn't give such importance
to everything that happens around you.
Stop babbling and get out of here!
I need to be alone.
Get some rest.
You're right.
I'll come back when you're rested,
and I can be of further assistance.
- If you need me...
- Why would I?
I don't know. In case you need me,
I'll leave you my phone number.
Give it to Ana Maria.
Yes, that would be better.
Ana Maria!
Call doctor Britel!
Yes? Yeah, put her on the line.
I accept the charge, this is Dr. Britel.
Ana Maria... what do you want?
What's happening?
I'm on my way.
Right now.
Doctor... I thought you'd never come!
Something terrible must be
happening to him; he called for me loudly.
Horrible cries, but he won't
let me go into his room.
- That's fine.
- He says that only you can enter.
Don't worry; he's only had
a nervous breakdown.
Wait up here, Ana Maria.
- Ana Maria?
- This is me, Eugenio!
- You... by yourself?
- Yes. Open up.
Come in.
- What's up?
- Something terrible...
- Something awful.
- What?
Look at my hands.
There's nothing wrong with them.
A few moments ago,
my hands were bleeding.
Endlessly bleeding.
I couldn't stop the bleeding.
How is that possible?
I streaked the walls with that blood.
And the towel that
I wanted to clean up with.
This one?
That's the one.
- This is clean, now.
- See for yourself.
The prints are also gone.
What's wrong with me, Eugenio?
- I'm losing my mind.
- Take it easy.
It's due to your nervous breakdown. An hallucination
doesn't indicate anything serious.
Perhaps it's nothing but a dream.
No, not a dream.
But the actual projection
of one of my anxiety dreams.
I slept in that chair,
and found myself wandering
into the path of the mist, lost.
I heard a voice that was guiding
me through the fog.
I didn't see the face.
Just saw a hand, calling me.
It kept calling me.
Inviting.
There were mysterious voices
calling me, softly and ominously,
completely irresistible to me.
So when I got to the lake of Dark Waters,
I stopped, terrified.
An irresistible force threw
me to the shore,
and my hands sank into the waters.
I immediately knew what
it was, warm and viscous,
it was blood!
Human blood.
The blood of the victims.
The murderer was laughing at me,
running away once again.
The next day, as it was my
eternal doom,
the monster turned to look at me,
so I stopped, drowning.
I was once again about to behold
that blurred spot, his face,
and thought I couldn't see that face,
without falling hopelessly dead!
However, I couldn't
help staring at it.
Hallucinating, waiting for a hint of a face
to sprout in that fuzzy cloth!
He turned to me,
but the light didn't reach his face.
Then, he headed toward the street light,
so I could see him clearly.
Oh, Lord!
It was my mother!
The murderer was my mother...!
Then I woke up.
But my delirium continued.
My hands bled,
until you came here.
I know I'm losing my mind.
I know that only you can
help me in this trance.
Here I am, defeated.
Hopelessly defeated.
Willing to obey you.
For the moment, you have to rest
and calm your spirit.
You need to rest.
Deep, restful sleep.
I'll give you an injection so you can
sleep more easily.
Anything you say.
I put my life in your hands.
And while I prepared the
powerful narcotic,
to avoid tormenting dreams,
I faced the awful truth,
grief and horror
simultaneously assailed me.
Yes, I possessed the diabolical secret
of Juan Carlos.
My hands were shaking,
and I refused to accept it.
But I knew...
Oh, poor friend of mine.
I gave him a shot,
and let him sleep in peace,
for the first time in who knows how long.
But I decided to stay at home,
to watch him.
I asked for a room from Ana Maria.
On a sleepless night, I discovered
that my duty was to let her know.
So I did the next morning...
Juan Carlos is facing a terrible
danger, Ana Maria;
we have to help him, but I
don't know how.
Doctor, you're scaring me.
He's sleeping soundly, and will
for a few hours more,
under the influence of the drug.
But when he wakes,
you and I must make a decision,
and any option will be very painful.
Doctor, you're scaring me more and more!
Ana Maria,
Yes, doctor.
- Do you still love him?
- I do, with my soul.
Beware of commiting so easily.
So easily?
So easily, yeah; your love for him will
soon be put to a severe test.
Speak clearly, please.
I beg you...
Take a seat.
Yet I doubt whether it's good or bad
to go further,
but I feel obliged that you know
the whole truth.
I'm listening...
Juan Carlos suffers from a terrible
sickness of the mind.
A split personality.
Within him, there are two beings,
each acting on their own.
We have the conscious and selfless
Juan Carlos, who sacrificed his life to a maternal whim.
On the other hand, one who lives by the instincts
he privately suppressed,
and the latter are in violent rebellion.
I don't get it, doctor,
I can't understand.
Any repression, as any excess,
implies punishment.
The punishment of Juan Carlos
has been enormous.
When the man kills the love of his heart,
he unleashes the fury of hell.
It gives a spiritual imbalance,
and can only survive
by finding shelter.
Some find solace in drinking,
others in suicide,
and others in madness.
Do you understand me?
Doctor...
Is Juan Carlos...
crazy?
I would say that he's
only crazy at certain times.
But he doesn't recognize, and ignores
the savage who dwells within him.
When the savage is released,
through unconscious delusions by him,
- It makes him a...
- A crazy man.
Something worse, Ana Maria,
A murderer.
Juan Carlos is the mutilator,
Ana Maria.
The mutilator...?
You lie!
I wish I was lying.
- How did you know?
- At first, it was almost a wild guess.
Because he has confirmed it, gradually
and without realizing it.
In each of the dreams he's
told me, the truth was laid bare.
First, he released a monster
which became the murderer.
Then he blamed himself
in his delirium about bloody hands,
which represented the blood of his victims.
And he accused his mother of being
to blame for everything.
And then, his deep fear to discover
the identity of the murderer.
- But that doesn't prove anything!
- Abandon all hope, Ana Maria.
There is sufficient evidence.
I have also seen the weapon.
In his room.
We stayed silent,
dismayed,
wondering what to do, how to help him?
What to do, oh Lord?
A friend so dear, so innocent,
but monstrously guilty.
The shadows of the night, as
the shadows of my discoveries,
fell upon us.
We didn't know how to
face our horrible duty.
That restless night...
I heard a loud noise,
towards the room of Juan Carlos.
My heart trembled,
I'd given him another shot,
so that he slept in peace.
Something serious must be going on,
if, despite that, he was still awake.
I woke up with the desire that the
noise had nothing to do with his inner demon.
I heard new noises.
I decided to deal with that,
and I went to his room.
As a precaution,
I left him locked up,
so he would have to break
the lock to get out.
Oh, Lord. Is that Juan Carlos,
or his monster?
He abandoned the attempt, and left.
I heard his troubled footsteps,
that for the time being,
remained quiet.
That lack of a human voice,
filled me with horror!
What unspeakable situation
may be happening in those shadows?
Doctor... Doctor!!
Precaution acted against us.
Having heard my warning,
she had locked herself inside.
Juan Carlos...
This is me, Ana Maria.
Juan Carlos... Juan Carlos...
Juan Carlos!
There lay my poor,
dear friend.
At my feet, bleeding from
a deadly wound.
Dying from the bullet that I shot at him.
He opened his eyes; his gaze
again became tender, human.
- Ana Maria...
- I felt as if a claw was squeezing my heart.
The devil had finally left his soul.
Ana Maria...
Eugenio!
Eugenio.
The murderer was here tonight?
I heard him coming...
Assaulting Ana Maria...
Right?
But I came to defend her.
Yes, Juan Carlos, you
defended her courageously.
You fought with the murderer
and managed to kill him.
Praise God!
But you're seriously injured.
I saved Ana Maria,
I don't care if I die.
Forgive me, Ana Maria,
what a coward I was.
Kiss me... Give me the
kiss I hadn't the guts to ask for.
He didn't know where he was,
or how he got there.
It must have been like a dream to him.
The last of his dreams.
He smiled,
leaning his head,
and left his passions
and place out of this mortal world.
And so I,
I became a murderer.
Police Headquarters?
This is Dr. Britel.
At house number 503,
lies a murderer, waiting for
the arrival of justice.
Hello...?
Who is this?
Subtitled exclusively for Cinemageddon.
March 2013.
Translation and timing:
Spinal
Proofed:
Antonio
We hope you enjoyed.