"New York is the city of tall tales."
"It is the city of
strange contradictions."
"Of unending variations."
"Some of us know it as
the city of steel and stone."
"A staggering mast upended into space."
"But whether we look up or down."
"New York cannot
adequately be described."
"It can only be felt."
"Sensed. Experienced."
"And those who have been caught
up by New York's swirling life .."
"Have their own stories to tell."
"For out of the city's best and worst."
"The people live and love
in a search for happiness."
"This is one story about a boy and a
girl who had a rendezvous with fate."
"And to tell it,
Warner Brothers present .."
Let's get the show on the road.
What you want to do, stick around?
Get going, stupid.
Somebody go in there and call a doctor.
Call an ambulance will you.
Someone call an ambulance.
She's hurt.
Somebody will be here in
a minute to take care of you.
Is she hurt bad?
- I don't know.
Relax, kid.
You forget where you picked
me up. I forget I saw you hit her.
Where have you been?
- Hotel Royale.
Get anything?
- He's dead.
Very dead. Shot with a 0.45
by the size of the holes.
Name.
Buzz Sorenson. Occupation: gambler.
Seems it was a fight over cards.
It could be anybody he ever played with.
Which means half of New York.
The dame upstairs heard the
shots around a quarter after eight.
Said she knew exactly what time it was
as she had a date with a guy for 8:15.
And men don't keep her waiting.
Naturally, she didn't tell anybody.
And?
- That's all.
That's a busy little street.
The night watch turned this in.
Didn't run, huh. At the corner.
Hey. 8:25.
It could be. There was a getaway car.
It could be a coincidence.
It's worth a little spade work.
Give it a run-through.
Bronislavski.
- Yes, sir?
You're the conservative type.
You handle the routine work.
Yes, sir.
What were they playing?
- Poker.
Who was winning?
The guy with his own deck of course.
The corpse.
Should I heat it up for you?
[ Telephone ]
Yes?
I am coming.
Hello?
Who?
Smiley.
Telephone.
For the rent he pays me I should
take messages like a secretary?
Yeah.
Wait, the man said ..
Ballet Girl across the board.
Ballet girl? Maybe.
Forget the horses, Sammy.
Stick to milkshakes.
Ballet Girl.
Yes or no?
No.
Yes?
Is Miss Willens on this floor?
They told me the 3rd.
Are you her brother?
No. I just wanted to
find out how she is.
I am glad you've come.
She hasn't had any visitors.
We haven't been able to reach
her brother. Do you know him?
I've met him.
Right this way.
Are you from Milwaukee?
No.
That's where he is but
we can't reach him.
That's where I knew him but
I haven't heard from him lately.
I read about this in the
papers and thought I ..
This is her room.
Try and cheer her up. She needs it.
[ Door knocks ]
Come in.
Who is it?
I'm a friend of your brother's.
I read about you in the paper and I ..
I thought I would kinda look you up.
You're a friend of Jerry's?
Yeah.
You're from Milwaukee?
That is, not exactly.
But that's where I knew Jerry.
How do you feel?
Terrible.
I have shock and internal injuries.
They're real worried about me.
They had three doctors in here
to see me this morning.
Maybe I ..
I'd better go and let you sleep.
I can't sleep.
But I'm supposed to rest.
May I can come back
and see you sometime?
What's your name?
- Eddie Novok.
Oh, you.
You can go outside again and knock.
Did your company make you feel better?
Never mind how I feel.
Did you catch the guy who hit me?
Not yet.
- Not yet?
We're doing the best we can
for you, honey. But it isn't easy.
Sure, I know.
You're all too busy hoisting
your feet up on to your desks.
It could only happen to me.
Ten morons standing
around keening over me.
And not one with the brains
to get the license number.
There's a kid who said he
saw the car but that's all.
It isn't only a matter of catching him.
We also have to prove he did it.
Who is your boyfriend?
Eddie Novak, A friend of my brother's.
Swell. Then they found your brother?
Nah, he hasn't seen him for ages.
That's too bad.
I think maybe he works for
an insurance company.
Why?
He's not a friend of my brother's.
I haven't got a brother.
But you said that ..
- Well ..
They kept asking me
questions about my family.
Who were they?
Who was my nearest relative?
Who should I notify?
I just felt so funny, like I was
a lost soul or something.
So I said I had a brother.
Then I said Milwaukee
because it was far away.
What do you think?
Well, maybe he read
about you in the papers.
Then why are you so interested in him?
Hey, I'm not.
I just want to see you get your kicks.
That's all, honey.
Hello, doctor.
- Hello.
I just saw our patient.
She looks pretty good.
Yes, she does. But watch this chair.
What do you mean, something wrong?
She's not the usual case.
Got a minute?
- Sure.
A complication has developed.
Come in and read it for yourself.
In plain English it means she's in a
critical condition. We can't operate.
She doesn't know?
- Uhuh.
I'll tell her she's alright
and release her.
Release her?
- What else can I do?
She isn't even supposed
to have a private room.
I can't keep her here without treatment.
Not if there isn't any treatment.
You're sure about this?
A couple of specialists
looked at her this morning.
Sometimes I don't like myself.
Me and my cop's mind.
I thought she was faking. You know,
working up a case for the insurance.
She is.
Now wait a minute, Doc.
She can't have it both ways.
That's what she's trying to do.
She is pretending to be in pain.
Actually there's no pain and there won't
be until she begins to have attacks.
She feels fine.
Can I use your phone?
- Sure.
Sorry.
Hello. Records.
- Ferris. Homicide squad.
Have them get me a make on Eddie Novok.
N-o-v-o-c?
- That's right.
Just some juvenile delinquency charges.
No convictions?
- No.
No other record, huh?
No. Did he kill anybody?
Well.
If he didn't, somebody did.
Thank you, nurse.
That bad?
I feel weak. Everything hurts.
No it doesn't, Marie.
I know when I hurt.
- I'm the doctor.
Now listen to me.
I understand what you're trying to do.
There is no use.
There's nobody to collect from.
Maybe if there were I'd stretch
a point and help you build it up.
But there isn't.
You really do feel better, don't you?
That's a good girl.
We're going to send you home soon.
Maybe the day after tomorrow.
Then everything will look different.
Sure.
Everything is going to be wonderful.
But I haven't got any home.
That's how it all happened.
They'd locked me out of my room.
I was walking around
driving myself crazy.
Trying to think of a way to
get my hands on some money.
Come on, now.
Maybe we'll find your brother.
Or something else will turn up.
Not with my luck.
I haven't had a job in two months.
Then it was dancing in some
crummy little dive in Brooklyn.
Then it folded and I didn't
get my last week's pay.
It's not fair.
There was a girl at the Geddes theater
who broke her leg and got $5,000 for it.
I can't even have a good accident.
Eddie, please.
What's the matter with you?
Nothing.
For the first time you are
hanging here all day long.
There's no important business in
the pool room with the big-shots?
All quiet.
Sammy, you think the Greek down the
way can give me a break on some roses?
Oh .. a girl?
No, it isn't a girl.
For boys he buys roses?
They're beautiful.
Goodbye, Miss Willens.
- Marie.
Marie.
Must you go?
Yep.
I've got some important
business to take care of.
I'm glad you're feeling better, Marie.
- Thanks.
Thanks for being so nice to me.
It's nothing.
I'm ..
I'm glad you feel better, Marie.
You already said that.
Well.
Goodbye, Mr Novok.
- Eddie.
Goodbye, Eddie.
I'll be here until 4 o'clock tomorrow.
The doctor wants to see you.
Who, me?
You're Mr Novok, aren't you?
- Yeah but ..
Come right this way.
Go right in.
Hello, Mr Novok.
I'm Doctor Wirth.
Have a cigarette.
Sit down.
I want to talk to you
about Miss Willens.
You've no idea where we
can reach her brother?
No.
I thought he was in Milwaukee.
How well do you know Miss Willens?
I don't know her at all.
I mean I ..
I thought I'd come to see
her because I knew Jerry.
That's her brother.
I don't know him very well.
Why?
Because she is liable to die.
But I just saw her.
She's fine. She told me so.
She doesn't know.
That's a mistake.
She feels good. She looks good.
- I'm sorry. It's not a mistake.
She has an aneurysm.
An inoperable aneurysm.
What's that?
It's a blood tumour in an artery.
Like a bruise inside.
Caused by the accident.
She'll be alright for a while.
Then, possibly in a month
or so a blood clot will form.
When it reaches her heart ..
You're sending her home.
She told me you're sending her home.
- That's why I wanted to talk to you.
I'd keep her here if I
could but it's impossible.
And she has no place to go.
I thought, since you're
her only friend ..
You might want to help her.
Why me?
Why should I help her?
You can't put it on me.
Sorry, Mr Novok. I asked you
because there was no-one else.
Yeah.
Sure I understand. You had to ask me.
We'll see what we can do with
one of the charitable agencies.
Did you ask any other doctors?
Did you take an X-Ray?
Quite a few.
Hello Eddie.
Been waiting to see you.
I want to ask you something.
How does it feel to find out
that you're a murderer?
Maybe you know what you're
talking about but I don't.
I got no interest in finding out.
- Don't go.
I got things to say to you.
When I look at you I
get sick to my stomach.
Everything you get,
you've been asking for.
If you've something to say, say it.
Otherwise peddle it elsewhere.
I've been watching kids
like you all my life.
The same story. You're so smart.
Hanging around the big-shots.
Playing the angles.
Only thing is you never
figure out any good angles.
You never get next to anyone really big.
Something like this happens
and you're a scared rabbit.
Praying for out.
I told you before.
I don't know what you're talking about.
When were you in Milwaukee?
Is there any law that says I
had to be in Milwaukee?
There is no law about this.
You're in trouble, kid.
In trouble with the cops.
I can't take you in. I know
you hit her but I can't prove it.
But I know what you and
Ketch did before you hit her.
What do you mean?
Read the evening papers.
You'll find out what trouble is.
Where was I? Oh yes.
I was telling you what I know.
What I can't prove.
Yet.
Now I'm going to tell you
what this adds up to.
It means you do what I
tell you the way I tell you.
Otherwise I'll make you
my personal pigeon.
If you walk down the street just once
without money in your pocket and no job.
I'll pick you up for vagrancy.
If you sit in on a game.
The game gets raided.
If you put a slug in a telephone I'll
run you down like you robbed a bank.
What do you want?
- The doctor told you, didn't he?
Yes.
Did he tell you she has no place to go?
Yeah.
- Get her a place.
Sonny.
Me?
- You.
Take care of her. Treat her right.
Buy her presents.
See she has a little
fun before she dies.
But I can't.
How can I?
I ain't got no dough.
- Get some.
You're a smart boy.
Find yourself an angle.
Don't forget to read the evening papers.
Like I seem to have said
before, don't you knock?
How do you feel?
- Swell.
You will.
Your problems are all over, honey.
You're going to have a place to stay.
Eddie Novok is going
to take care of you.
I don't get it.
- You don't have to.
Take all you can get.
You're entitled to it.
Just don't be a dope, baby.
Not that I think you'll be a dope.
Why, Mr Ferris.
How you do go on.
Hey, Sammy. Two scoops.
Yes, two scoops.
Did I ever cheat you?
Money, money, money.
They were here. Asking for you.
Who?
The police were.
What did you tell them?
- What could I tell them?
What cream and sugar
you put in your coffee?
You are in trouble.
Nothing a couple of grand
wouldn't straighten out.
Can you spare it?
Before I answer your proposition.
I should look up my financial holdings.
Oh.
USD went down three points.
Eddie.
Hey, where are you going?
I want to see Ketch.
He ain't in.
I've got to see him.
- He ain't in.
Give me a beer.
I'll catch you later.
You said he wasn't in.
Don't get yourself in an uproar.
He isn't.
Yeah?
I'm going to wait.
Suit yourself, friend. It's your time.
I'm getting myself a case of beer.
Hi.
Hello Bernie.
What plays?
I got to talk to Ketch.
I don't think he wants to see you.
He got me into this.
I'm in trouble.
Right now, kid.
He has troubles of his own.
He thinks you should
stay away from here.
But he has to help me.
I need dough and the
cops are on my tail.
He told me to tell you to stay away.
He told me to make sure you stayed away.
You know Eddie, I like you.
But I'd do what he tells me.
Be a good boy.
Don't make me trouble.
Alright, you hate it.
Now let's get down to business.
Who needs it? Who wants it?
'Honest Peterson', it says.
'Will buy anything'.
You'd have to pay them to take it away.
You must have had it pushed in here.
Six hundred and fifty.
- Six hundred and fifty?
Who said you were crazy? It says:
'Get more money from Honest Peterson'.
I need new signs. I can't afford them.
Seven.
I gotta have more dough or I can't
do business. Come on, Peterson.
What am I running here,
a charity bazaar?
Seven fifty and I'm being good to you.
Nine.
Drive it away.
- Eight.
Sign here.
Any messages?
Well.
And what can I do for
you mister .. mister ..?
Novok.
I want an apartment.
I don't have a single thing.
Not a thing.
If you'd been here half an hour ago.
I took a young couple up to a place.
Charming people. A dentist and his wife.
They snapped it right up.
Look, skip the double talk.
I want an apartment today.
This afternoon.
I don't think I understand, Mr Novok.
Sure you do. I want an apartment
and I'm ready to pay for it.
That's a very bad philosophy, Mr Novok.
We don't do business that way.
We're not a fly-by-night concern.
We've been here at the
same old stand since 1945.
Well.
It just occurs to me.
There might just be ..
Of course, this may not suit you.
How much?
A yard and a half a month.
Three months in advance and ..
Three hundred for the janitor.
That's seven-fifty.
Wrap it up.
You're going to be very
happy there, Mr Novok.
Not as happy as the janitor.
It's lovely.
The best thing is the fireplace.
It works.
It winks.
Just think. If I hadn't had my
accident we never would have met.
Yeah.
Here. I'd better give you
this and get out of here.
Aren't you going to show me around?
There are more rooms, aren't there?
Sure. There's a kitchen, bedroom.
A kitchen and a bedroom?
Come on.
I insist on a complete tour.
- Hey.
You ought to rest.
Yes, I should.
But .. please.
Eddie, it's stunning.
I don't know how to thank you.
I'd better run along.
When are you coming back to see me?
I'll drop around.
Hello?
Who?
Marie.
Marie Willens.
Don't you remember me
from the Spade Club?
Yes. How are you, honey?
Where have you been?
Oh, around.
Have I got stuff to tell you.
Tell me all. Who is he?
An apartment?
I don't get it.
To tell you the truth, neither do I.
But it's gorgeous.
Now if I could only get myself a job.
Everything would be perfect.
I think something can
be done about that.
I'm going to see my agent tomorrow.
If you hear of anything,
will you call me?
Sure, of course I will.
Give me your number.
We'll make a date anyway, huh?
2-2-6-2.
Okay.
Bye.
And don't trip over any
of those pink clouds.
I won't. Goodbye.
Yeah?
Miss Dennis is here.
Send her in please.
Don't forget, dear. A week from Tuesday.
Alright, you character.
Don't forget your appointment this time.
Don't worry, honey. I won't.
And.
Keep in touch.
Libby, darling.
Matt, my love.
What can I do for you?
What have you ever done for me?
Things are tough all over.
Why don't you drop in
more often.? Sort of ..
Keep up my personal interest.
Give me .. enthusiasm for my work.
You've got plenty
of enthusiasm, brother.
How about tonight?
I'll invest a dinner in you.
I can't tonight. I'm going
to a housewarming.
Do you remember Marie?
No.
Marie Willens.
- Oh yes.
You know, I just can't believe it.
She's found a rich friend.
He sets her up in a gorgeous apartment.
I have to go there tonight
and make like I'm not jealous.
Why should you be?
You can have the same  anytime you want.
All you got to do is ask.
But don't change the subject, Matt.
You know, up to now Marie
has had some very bad luck.
I always thought she was a pretty girl.
What's she doing these days?
Still dancing.
- Is she working?
I don't think so. Why?
I might find a spot for her somewhere.
Send her in tomorrow. I'll talk to her.
Not tomorrow.
You see, she's had an accident.
Give her two or three days, huh?
- Okay.
But.
Let's talk about ..
You.
You do that, Matty.
Let me know how it turns out.
Bye now.
Miss Willens.
- Good.
Hello. Glad to see you.
Mr Hethron - Mr Novok.
- Hello.
You really threw me with
this job talk, Mr Hethron.
First we have to sell you.
I've got my piano player in there.
You can run through that
speciality of yours?
Sure.
- Good.
I should have my costume.
It's a tap number you know.
That's alright.
But Mr Hethron.
I wear a leotard. A silver leotard.
And a top hat and black
stockings and carry a cane.
Miss Willens does the tap routine with
a silver leotard a hat and a cane.
Yeah, that's my tempo.
Now, start from the top please.
Eddie.
That was my big break.
Wouldn't you know I'd do that to it.
You had an accident.
Mr Hethron knows it.
He'll give you another chance.
What does the doctor say?
He said you were still weak. That's all.
But it ..
It hurt, Eddie.
It really hurt.
Sure.
It's like a charley horse.
I'm a dope.
I got so scared.
Do something for me will you, Eddie?
Sure.
Don't go away.
I'm scared.
Stay with me.
Sure.
Sure, Marie.
Hello Eddie.
What you trying to do?
Finish her off quick?
I thought I made myself clear.
I thought I told you to fix it so she
won't kill herself trying to find a job.
You told me alright.
But you didn't say how.
What do you think I'm doing,
saving up for her funeral?
Look.
That's all I've got left. Three bucks.
- I'm bleeding for you.
Why don't you get a job?
What kind of a job can I get?
I never had one in my life that
paid more than coffee and cake.
Seen Ketch?
You are a cop.
You think like a cop. You haven't
got what it takes to understand.
I am going to take care of her but it
hasn't got anything to do with you.
Right now, anything you'd do
with me would be a pleasure.
It isn't hot. I paid three bills for it.
A hundred down and 2 bucks
a week for 2 years.
You were robbed.
75 dollars is the best I can do.
Seventy-five?
Well?
I'll take it.
I want to see you, Ketch.
Sure, kid.
I want to see you alone.
Sure.
What is it? Money or the cops?
Money.
How much?
A grand.
You got a gall, I'll say that for you.
Now why should I give you a grand?
I'll pay you back.
I swear I'll pay you back.
I'll make it up to you.
I'll work for you.
You'll work for me? You'll pay me back.
How much, two bits a week?
You'll do me favors.
Right now I got 50 guys like you to do
me favors and I don't have to pay them.
You forget something, Ketch.
There is one favor I can do
you that nobody else can.
And I've been doing it.
I made a mistake about that guy.
Yeah, I did.
I don't like it the way it is.
You guys may have to fix it.
No, no Matt.
Come on baby. It's like I told you.
If you want me to behave why not
marry me? Then I'll be a good boy.
I have a picture of that.
You being a good boy with
those blondes around.
Honey, give me a chance. I'll prove it.
There won't be any blondes.
I won't handle them.
Just acrobats and jugglers.
So funny.
Waiter.
No, Eddie. Give me the check.
Wait a minute. This is my party.
It was my idea.
It might be pretty steep.
Just my left arm. That's all.
I feel good.
Very good.
More wine, brandy, cordial anybody?
On me.
Darling, after that dinner?
We'll have to diet for a week.
Let's not stay here all night.
What will we do?
Go where we can dance.
I want you children to put
yourselves in my hands.
I know the spot. The show will kill you.
I've got an act there. It's a honey.
The most beautiful ..
Comic, dear.
- Yes.
Take a taxi or walk?
We'll walk. It's only two blocks. Okay?
Okay.
Please Eddie, let's dance.
Pardon us.
- Yes. Marie.
Hello Eddie.
I want you to meet Miss Willens.
This is Mr Bernie Sallin.
- How do you do.
See, I said I wasn't too tired to dance.
Honey, do you think ..
- Don't spoil it.
I'm having so much fun.
What is it?
Nothing.
I just felt dizzy for a minute.
You alright?
- Yeah.
I'm alright.
Here, sit down.
No Eddie, it's nothing.
Honest, I'm alright.
Look, I'm going to find a taxi.
You sit there and wait for me.
I'm going to take you right home.
- But Eddie, I ..
I just got a little dizzy
for a minute and he ..
So he thinks you're made of glass?
Is that bad?
Sometimes.
I got a cab waiting right here.
Come on, Marie.
I don't want to go home.
Please honey.
- It isn't nice.
You're spoiling it for
Libby and Matt too.
Hi.
It looks like you go where I go.
Yeah. It seems that way, doesn't it.
You're the one that was in a hurry.
Try using the motor, Jack.
When we get to your home I
want you to go right upstairs.
You do? That does it.
You got some nerve treating
me like I was a kid.
Or an invalid.
Why did you get so scared?
I'm not scared.
Will you do what I tell you please?
Don't worry.
I don't want to be with you
any more than you with me.
Look, it's not like that.
It's a thing I can't explain right now.
- Don't bother.
"Bus leaving for Trenton,
Philadelphia and Baltimore."
How much is the bus fare to Chicago?
- $39.50.
"Bus leaving for Trenton,
Philadelphia and Baltimore."
"Bus leaving for Harrisburg,
Pittsburgh and Columbus."
"Bus leaving for Cleveland,
Chicago and St Louis."
How did you come, by dog-sled?
- You have something to tell me?
Let's get some coffee.
"Bus leaving for Cleveland,
Chicago and St Louis."
You said you had a deal.
What is it?
I gotta get out of town.
I got to take her with me.
I want you to help us.
Later, when she ..
You get yourself a killer.
And a hit-and-run driver for a bonus.
How do I know you won't run out on me?
If I could I'd be on a
bus now, wouldn't I?
You got enough dough to take care of it?
How did you get it?
I told you I had to leave town.
You figure it out.
What's your problem?
They've been tailing me all night.
I wasn't sure of it but when I got to my
place one of them was waiting for me.
I lost him but they'll be at
her house waiting for her now.
I got to get her.
But I got to have some
place to take her.
Wait here.
"Bus now leaving for Trenton,
Camden, Philadelphia."
Hey.
Come here.
You were wrong calling me a cop.
I've a friend who has a
place in the country.
Ask what time the bus leaves for Harmon.
Where it stops along the
way and how long. Get it?
And call her. Tell her to get ready,
to trust you and not get scared.
What will you do?
Dr Wirth doesn't know it
but he's going to help too.
Here they come now. Let's get rolling.
How dumb can you get.
- But, boss ..
Don't give me the 'But' routine.
Hoist up onto your feet and find him.
How can we find him ..
I said, find him.
Just find him.
Leave the rest of it to me.
Hello?
Smiley.
Telephone.
Yeah?
He paid 483.60 and 220.
Want a soda?
- Nah.
You came in here.
You must have wanted something.
I want to know where Eddie is.
Sammy will tell you. Won't you, Sammy?
I don't know.
He didn't come in for ..
For three days.
You think he knows but won't tell us?
- Maybe.
Maybe he needs a little
of the treatment.
I .. I told you I don't know.
No. He doesn't know.
He would tell you.
He knows what's going to happen
to him if we found out he knew.
And wouldn't tell us.
Hoodlums.
Yeah. I heard him.
I wouldn't tell them.
If they killed me I wouldn't tell.
I bet you got a sore neck.
I guess you think I'm silly lying
here like this all afternoon.
All my life I wanted to fall
asleep in front of a fireplace.
Now I did it.
Still mad?
I wasn't mad.
It's only I thought maybe you
wanted to tell me things.
But if you can't ..
It hasn't anything to do with you.
It's my own troubles that
make me act the way I did.
But at the club you were
so careful of me and ..
You would tell me if there was something
wrong with me, wouldn't you, Eddie?
Sure.
Like it here?
Oh, yes.
I thought the apartment was
something but this is even better.
I've never seen such a beautiful place.
You must have an awfully nice friend.
Only ..
- Only what?
I'm hungry.
That was practically breakfast
we had and not lunch.
I know. I was going
to fix you something.
There's stuff in the kitchen but ..
There is a gasoline
stove and I'm afraid of it.
It might explode.
Come on.
Let's go find some place to eat.
This is an occasion.
I ought to put my face on.
I like it the way it is.
Come on.
How do you like these apple-knockers?
You think they'd have sense to turn
the lights off when the joint is closed.
Wait a minute.
Maybe there is someplace else.
- Sure. About ten miles down the road.
Come on.
- Somebody's coming.
Want something, folks?
- Eats.
Sorry. We're closed.
But we'll be open again in
October when deer season starts.
That's fine. We'll wait.
Are you hungry?
That's a fine question.
It's just that we don't have
a car and it's a long walk.
Well, come on in.
- Thanks.
It won't be much but I'll
rustle up something for you.
A ham sandwich maybe
and .. a cup of coffee.
Got some eggs too, come to think of it.
It will take about ten minutes.
Now don't starve on me.
You see, all you have to
do is use your charm.
I would if I had some like yours.
Well, be charming.
Go on. Try it.
Charming.
[ Radio music ]
Flowers, music, soft lights.
No-one can say I don't take
you to the best places.
And exclusive too.
May I have this dance?
You can have all of them.
Unless somebody cuts in.
Look at me. I'm a wood chopper.
Woodsman, woodsman, spare that tree.
Touch not a ..
I can't walk, Eddie.
Does it hurt?
No. It did but now.
But I can't walk.
I've tried. I can't.
Where are you going?
I'm going down the
road to call Dr Wirth.
No. I don't want you to go.
I want you to stay with me.
Honey, I've got to.
Look, just lie here.
It's going to be alright.
No, Eddie. Don't go.
Don't leave me alone.
Honey, I must call him.
It won't take long.
Eddie, please.
- I'll be right back.
I'll run both ways.
I'll be right back.
I'll get up and see you again.
Now you be a good
girl and sleep tonight.
Goodbye.
Wait a minute.
Better tell me the truth for a change.
I have told you the truth, Marie.
- No you haven't.
Neither has he.
You've been lying to me all along.
I'm sick. He wouldn't be so
worried about me if I wasn't.
You are lying to me.
I know you are lying to me.
No. I'm not lying to you.
I'm telling you the truth.
I don't believe it.
You mean I am ..
Going to die?
No. No you're not.
You're going to get better.
- Don't, Eddie.
It's no use.
Why did you tell her?
You didn't have to tell her.
- I didn't really. She sensed it.
It's far better this way.
I've seen it so many times.
They make an adjustment and it
is easier than the uncertainty.
When do you think ..
I mean, how long?
That's hard to judge.
A month. Perhaps more.
Or she may outlive both of us.
Thanks.
Thanks a lot.
Eddie, will you do something for me?
Sure.
Will you marry me?
But maybe you never
wanted to get married.
Some men feel like they are caught.
That has nothing to do with it.
I don't feel like that.
But this is different. It wouldn't ..
- I can't.
I can't explain it.
Do you love me, Eddie?
You know I do.
Then ..?
- I can't.
And I know why it is.
It's because you were
the one who hit me.
Don't feel so bad.
You did everything you could.
Eddie, you mustn't go
on blaming yourself.
Nobody is blameless.
The first day you came
to the hospital ..
I thought you were from
the insurance company.
If you only knew how I was ..
Trying to work you and get
everything I could out of you.
Then you'd ..
- Don't say that.
Please, Eddie.
I didn't care before but ..
Now it's different.
What's that?
Nothing. Nothing.
A regular Beau Brummell.
Going somewhere?
To see my relative in ..
In Bensonhurst.
I got relatives in Bensonhurst
myself but I never go to see them.
And if I did I wouldn't
get that dressed up.
Yes, Miss?
Do you sell me jelly beans?
Yes. Jelly beans.
Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Let me talk to Ketch.
I'll be right with you.
Okay, mister.
Thank you, sir.
You're new here. Huh?
Yeah. The guy that used
to work here is sick.
I ought to charge you extra.
What makes your big feet so large?
Any excitement?
No.
It's been so quiet I'm kinda
worried about the business.
What about Ketch?
He went inside. He hasn't come out yet.
Call that a shine?
Look at all the territory
I had to cover.
It reminds me of the beat I pounded
before they made me a detective.
Don't cry.
Women always cry at weddings.
But not at mine.
I could never be as
brave as you are, Marie.
You're not as happy as I am.
Where's the Justice of the Peace?
Hasn't he come yet?
What time is it?
Ten after two.
But relax. He's only ten minutes late.
He may be lost. I'll run down to
the back road and look for him.
No Eddie. I'll go.
- I'll do it.
When a man is going to
marry, keep him busy.
And after the wedding, leave him alone.
You get it?
Wait a minute!
Hold it. Hold it!
Surprise.
Turn around.
Ketch, you can't.
- Turn around.
Walk until I tell you to stop.
There's people in the house.
They'll hear you.
They'll think somebody is
shooting a rabbit. Keep moving.
Alright.
Listen, Ketch.
I got a girl.
- I got a lot of girls. So what?
But she needs me. She's sick.
She's going to die.
You can keep her company.
Turn around.
- Ketch, listen please. Please.
Please. Just give me a little time.
Just a couple of days. Today, we ..
- Shut up.
Turn around.
Start walking.
[ Gunshot! ]
Been hanging around here all afternoon.
Aren't you going to say thank you?
I'm sorry kid. I'm afraid this
means I've got to take you in.
Come on.
How is Marie?
She had another attack.
She can't walk.
We were going to get
married this afternoon.
She is going to die.
The doctor said it might only be a week.
Please.
Give me a little time with her.
I can't. I can't.
I've got to report this right away.
If you want to make a
statement about Ketch ..
I think you'll get off easy
on the hit-and-run charge.
What do I care about that?
Afterwards, they can hang me.
I want to marry her.
I don't want her to be alone.
You said it yourself once. I am a cop.
There are some things
I just can't do, kid.
Look.
Look, what am I asking you for?
You shot Ketch because
he tried to plug you.
You got what you were after.
All you have is a hit and run.
You let it go. Let it go a bit longer.
I've a lot of explaining to do as it is.
If I try to stall this long enough to do
any good the coroner will figure it out.
Come on.
You helped me before.
It wasn't just because you wanted Ketch.
It was because you saw what
was going on with me and Marie.
You know what I was before this
happened, Where I was heading.
I guess she wasn't much better.
But it's different now.
We got something we never
would have had otherwise.
I can't talk about it good.
But we got it.
I know we've got it.
And I want her to have
it as long as she lives.
Afterwards.
I'm willing to pay for it,
no matter what it costs.
It must be the Justice of the Peace.
Sorry.
I'm afraid you're going to
be late for your wedding.
I've got a little straightening
out to do. I can't come.
Beat it.
I, Edward Novok.
Take this woman for my lawful wife.
To have and to hold
from this day forward.
For better, for worse.
For richer, for poorer.
In sickness and in health.
Until death do us part.
I, Marie Willens.
I, Marie Willens take this
man for my lawful husband.
To have and to hold
from this day forward.
For better, for worse.
For richer, for poorer.
In sickness and in health
until death do us part.
The ring, please.
Now, will you put that
on her finger please.
And now by the authority invested in me.
I pronounce you man and wife.
Eddie.
Well.
Good luck.
Marie, we have to go.
Matt.
Must you?
Yes.
We got to get along.
Sammy, you coming?
Just a minute.
There is something my
people do at weddings.
Maybe I could if you don't mind?
Sure, Sammy.
God's blessing.
I wish you.
Also. Broken glass brings luck.
If it is broken by somebody who ..
Who loves you.
You know, Eddie.
Once, I myself was two times married.
The minister was there. I was there.
But the bride never showed up.
Enjoy this happiness.
Thanks.
We forgot the cake.
We can eat it for breakfast tomorrow.
It's funny.
It was just like it is in stories.
Were you scared?
How do you feel?
I do feel fine.
Maybe.
How does the doctor know?
He could be wrong.
Well.
Sometimes doctors make mistakes too.
Like everybody else.
Sure.
Sure they do.
Eddie.
Huh?
Let's make believe.
Make believe what?
That it is for ever.
It is forever.
..s-d..