.
Alfred, are you also going to
the auction in Backhorva?
Yes. We'll be on our way soon.
This day there was
an auction in Backhorva,
and everyone wanted to go.
Auctions were popular in
Lönneberga and in Smaland.
The Katthulters also
wanted to participate.
Let Emil go too.
Let him out, Ida. He has
been in the shed long enough.
I don't know what Emil
should do at an auction.
Also, if we don't take him,
there'll be enough excitement.
When Emil wants to come
to the auction, he will come.
Just let him come, then.
Take better care of your behavior
and don't fool around as usual.
Emil! You can come out.
Father? Will you buy me
something at the auction?
Buy and purchase.
I never hear anything else.
Didn't I buy you
candy for ten øre?
For your birthday in January.
Already forgotten?
Emil, are you coming with me?
Drive ahead.
I'm following on Lukas.
What is he up to?
You probably best stay at home.
And come home safely.
Goodbye!
I hope that Alfred has a thick skull
that holds when they fight.
If you don't, you
shouldn't go to an auction.
Emil needed money.
You can't go to an
auction without money.
Asking dad was pointless.
So he had to get money.
But how?
If you had been a child
in Smaland at that time,
you would have known how blessed
many gates there were on all roads.
This was a good thing for the children,
because they earned money
by opening the gates.
Well Emil? Are you
now also a gate boy?
Uh-huh.
Thank you.
You will get rich, Emil.
Here you go.
Do you have time for this?
So who's pulling the pranks?
Right now, no one.
Hey! Why are you closing the gate?
How can I open it if I
don't close it first.
Oh, open it!
Why don't you leave
it open on a day like this?
I would be crazy.
When I can make such pocket
money for the auction.
Then you should get
gate money from me too.
- Is that my pedestal?
- Yes...
At an auction the auctioneer
sets the minimum price.
If somebody wants an item,
he must offer more.
Whoever offers the
most, gets the object.
Now we'll begin the auction.
First we auction
hammer and pliers.
Who offers 25 øre for both?
- Ten øre.
- That's too little.
- 15 øre.
- Not enough either. 20.
25. Who offers more than 25?
- 32!
- 35.
35. A bid of 40.
40 øre. Going once,
going twice, sold!
Hammer and tongs go
to you for 40 øre.
If Emil from Katthult-Farm is
coming, we better go home.
(Auctioneer)... a pendulum clock.
A wall clock, which has been the
pride and joy of a wealthy household.
Who bids?
23 are bid and awarded.
The pendulum clock goes
to Kalle for 23 kroner.
Then we have a very
comfortable sofa.
What's your bid?
- 3.50.
- Four!
- Four are offered here.
4.50.
Does anyone offer more?
- Five.
5.50. Because I want that sofa.
Yes, yes. 5.50.
A tenacious bidder.
And you? Even more?
No? Then the lot goes
to the old lady for 5.50.
Well, I am lucky. What would I
have done with that old sofa?
What do we have here?
A bread shovel.
Who bids?
Nobody? Nobody bids anything?
Does nobody bake at home anymore?
For the bread shovel I
only want twenty-five øre.
My bid.
For 25 øre to Emil
from Katthult farm...
goes this beautiful bread shovel.
And now...
Emil, are you going
to start baking bread?
A bread shovel is always good to have.
What do you need the box for?
I want to give it to Ida.
It's nice. This is velvet.
Oh, well. That old thing
has never been nice.
What do I have here?
A fire engine.
Who is bidding a crown?
Then 50 øre.
What if a fire breaks
out in your house?
Twenty-five then. Who bids?
I bid 25 øre.
25 øre!
Going once, going twice, sold!
Uh-oh. I didn't
want to have that.
Always in for a joke, Emil.
Now you can extinguish fires.
Alfred! Alfred!
- Where's the farmer?
- Up at the barn.
25 øre. In cash.
Well, then we have a pair of skis.
- Who bids?
- Ten øre.
Ten øre are bid.
Farmer!
Yes, what is it?
- Farmer!
- Yes?
Emil is buying a fire engine.
Can he do that?
What? A fire engine?
He must have lost his mind.
Yes, he probably did.
Say, fire engine owner Emil Svensson.
What do you want to
do with that thing?
When lightning strikes
and starts a fire...
Just wait! I will help you.
You darn rascal!
What do you want to
do with this fire engine?
And who's paying for it?
I paid for it from my own money.
Oh?
Darn rascal! Now tell me
where you got the money!
I have earned it
as a gate boy.
Well, really.
Well, where's the money?
All right. I don't want involvement
with such transactions.
Did you buy anything else?
Naughty boy! A bread shovel!
You know that we have
a bread shovel at home.
What's this? A shell box.
The hideous thing is
totally worthless.
How often did I tell
you to only buy things,
which are really
necessary, dear Emil.
What a naughty
little boy you are.
5.20. 5.20!
5.30 is bid.
- 5.35 in the back.
- One beer.
5.35. 5.40.
- 5.45. Who's bidding more than 5.45?
- I'd like to have one more.
This is almost for free.
Who's bidding more?
This is a unique opportunity.
- And another bottle.
- Who's bidding more than 5.45?
Just wait! Do you want to
put the money in lemonade,
after earning a few crowns?
If I don't have money,
I can't buy lemonade,
and if I have some,
then I can't buy any.
I want to know when
I can buy lemonade.
Naughty boy.
It will be the shed for you
when we get home.
You'll be locked in the shed, Emil.
Please another lemonade.
The lemonade is excellent.
I've never drunk
anything like that.
An auction is the most
beautiful thing there is.
At least as beautiful as
the market in Vimmerby.
And the most beautiful thing is that
you get away from work for a while.
It's nice to have enough work.
Yes, but the work never
ends for a farm hand.
It never stops.
- But I'll help you, Alfred.
- Yes, you do.
How good to have you, Emil.
Oh, the wine.
Come sit down.
I'll help you up here.
Now look at Lina
and Krakstorparn!
Let's marry our stupid Lina
with this Krakstorparn.
Then you are rid of
her for all time.
Oh, that would be a good thing.
Actually Lina wanted to
get engaged with Alfred,
but Alfred didn't want to marry.
Now Alfred and Emil
were thinking,
that Lina should marry Krakstorparn.
Perhaps he was too old for Lina,
but he had a little farm,
and Lina would surely
like to be a farmer's wife.
We should make sure that
no one disturbs them.
Will I get 20 crowns
for this fat sow?
- 20!
- 20?
20 crowns are bid.
Who's bidding more?
- 21!
- 21. Who's bidding more?
- 22.
- 22 over there.
- Who's bidding?
- 23.
23. Who bids more than 23 crowns?
Going once...
I'm bidding 25 crowns
and no one crown more.
A bid of 25.
25 going once,
25 going second,
and sold.
You'll feel good
at Katthult farm.
Because Emil lives there.
You've certainly heard of him before.
Do you hear how happy she is?
Bulten I Bo was the worst drunkard
and the biggest ruffian in Lönneberga.
That there were fights at the
auctions were mostly Bulten's fault.
If he had drunk a few schnapps,
he didn't know what to
do with the wildness,
which bubbled out of him.
Yes, unfortunately not
everyone drank lemonade,
and especially Bulten I Bo didn't.
Aren't you ashamed, Lina! What
do you want with that old rabbit?
He's too old for you.
Wait. Say that again if you dare!
No! Stay put!
I can manage Bulten on my own.
Leave people alone if they're
having a nice time together.
You lout!
Let the boy be, otherwise you'll carry
your arms and legs home in a bundle!
Just try if you're suicidal!
Come on! I'll hit you green and blue.
I'll show you.
You bloody dung-heap!
I'll get you for this! Ouch!
You bastard!
I'll break all your bones.
Everyone had been waiting for this.
They came from everywhere
wanting to join the fight.
Do I have a say?
Get lost! This is
not your brawl!
Oh! They are all fighting over me.
That would suit you, Lina.
Now come here, you!
Where are you, Alfred? Where are you?
- Are you down there?
- Yes, Emil. I'm right at the bottom.
Break up! We want to
do some more bidding.
Yes, save some blood for later.
Stop!
Stop it!
Does it hurt bad, Alfred?
Oh no, it doesn't.
Though someone
almost tore off my nose.
My dear friend, I
really got him good.
Even when my pants are torn,
and my nose got quite a hit.
My ear is damaged as well.
There's an auction in
Knasholt next week.
There we can carry on.
No way. No fighting at my auction.
Oh, I wouldn't
give a guarantee.
I think so too.
You may need a fire
engine for your auction.
It's for sale.
I bought the fire engine for 25 øre...
and I sold it for 50.
So I made 25 profit.
You're not stupid.
You'll certainly become
a good business man.
There's a bid of 74 crowns.
Who's bidding more for a cow in
her best years? 74 crowns.
Who's bidding more?
Now check your pockets!
A bid for 75.
Who's bidding more?
76.
76 from there.
You bought six cows yesterday.
I want this last cow.
76 crowns and 50 øre.
76.50 is bid.
- 77.
- 77 crowns is bid.
Do you bid more?
77, going once,
going twice, and...
- 80 crowns and no more.
- 80 crowns. Anyone bids more?
You have her.
Going once, going twice and sold.
The cow goes to
Svensson for 80 crowns.
And now I have a whole
bunch of chickens to offer.
15 laying hens. What do you pay
for this unique opportunity?
- I bid ten.
- Ten crowns being bid.
Ten crowns.
Ten crowns. Ten crowns.
For ten crowns to Bastefallarn.
I don't want the limping hen.
You can slaughter it.
He's stupid. Limping Lotte
is our best laying hen.
I bid 25 øre for limping Lotte.
Come! Come!
Stop! Where are you going?
Stop! Wait!
Will you stand still!
Come on!
The beast is crazy.
Give me a gun.
I'll shoot her.
Emil's father
was sorry for the cow.
But there's no use
for a crazy cow.
Everybody understood.
- Here you have a rifle.
- Is it loaded?
Of course it is.
- So...
- But Anton...
Do you really want
to shoot the cow?
Stop, father!
If you're going to shoot the poor
cow, you'd better give it to me.
What do you want the cow for?
You've done enough
crazy business today.
Can't you give
the poor cow to me?
You should really
give her to Emil.
Well, if you can get her
home, you can have her.
But this monster will
knock over everything
or demolish the barn.
Mr. Bastefallarn, if I drive
your cows to Katthult,
what would you pay for it?
Well, to me it would
be worth 25 øre.
It's a deal!
Now guess what Emil did.
He tied the six cows that
Bastefallarn had bought,
and drove them to the crazy
cow he had called Rolla.
Rolla became calm and docile
in company with the other cows.
For Emil had been the
only one to understand,
that Rolla was that stubborn...
because she couldn't be
together with other cows.
Help me, Alfred.
I'll just get Lukas.
Now I'll be the laughing stock
of Lönneberga for ever and ever.
Go, cows. Go!
We want to go home to Katthult.
Life stock owner Emil Svensson,
now you have a horse,
a limping chicken
and a crazy cow.
Anything else that you want?
In time I'll get a lot more.
- Mother?
- Yes?
- Now they're coming!
- Ah! Do they?
No... God have mercy...
What is this?
Now the father of Katthult
might be in over his head.
- Seven cows! He has gone mad.
- Yes.
Hello! Where do you want to go?
Seven cows! That's crazy.
Yes.
Seven cows! Is it you or
me gone mad, Anton?
The cows are.
No, they are not my cows.
They're Bastefallarn's.
The cow I bought
is no longer mine.
And I don't want her back.
Yes, but Anton,
what are Bastefallarns
cows doing here with us?
Hm!
It took some explanations,
before Emil's mother understood,
what the matter was
with the cows.
God bless you, Emil.
What a clever boy you are.
- Without you, our cow would still be there.
- It's my cow now.
- Yes.
- And don't you forget.
- This is for you, Ida.
- That's sweet, Emil.
Yes.
- Wait! I take her.
- She's already laid an egg.
Now this is a very good
laying hen, Emil.
But Alfred, what in the world
did happen to your nose?
In Backhorva at the auction.
And next week, this will
be repeated in Knasholt.
What's with you, Lina?
What's that face for?
- Toothache.
- Our poor Lina.
Krakstorparn has probably
given you too many candies?
What is it, Emil?
Do you want to milk now?
I can't help that Bastefallarn
isn't yet here to milk his cows.
Here you go.
This one is from limping Lotte.
And this is from Rolla.
This is a nice bread shovel.
How could you know that
my old one was broken?
- Yes, it is.
- The old one is for firewood.
Anton, it was very
clever from Emil,
to buy a bread shovel for me.
Lina held a hot potato
against the tooth.
And then it hurt seven times more.
Darn. Now it really hurts.
It was careless of Krakstorparn
to offer you sweets.
- You should marry him, Lina.
- Ouch! That old man?
He's already 50 and I'm only 25.
I don't marry someone
twice as old.
That doesn't matter.
He can still be nice.
Oh, now it wouldn't be so bad,
but... when I'm 50...
he's already 100.
Lord, what trouble would that bring?
You're counting as
if you have no brain.
Crazy business.
Old fart.
Emil! I can't open the box.
Now that's good.
When I have to write letters,
I already have some in stock.
Ida loved the
box with the shells.
She put her hymnbook,
her thimble,
her scissors, beautiful
colorful glitter...
and her red hair loop inside.
Well, father?
What about the shed?
You don't deserve to
be imprisoned today.
If I really think it over,
you have only done good.
That's true, of course,
but what's said is said.
- Bloody hell.
- Once again.
Pooh devil!
Pooh devil.
Wait.
You can also say: To hell.
- Pooh devil.
- No! To hell!
To hell.
- You can also say devil be damned.
- Devil be damned?
- Devil be damned.
- Good.
And the worst is:
Go to hell.
- What did you say?
- Go to hell.
Go to hell.
The devil should get you.
Damn and blast it.
Ida, shut up!
Darn rascal!
Should you teach
your sister to swear?
I didn't do that!
I just told her that she
can't say son of a bitch.
And then I told her
which other words are bad,
and to watch out for
which other words.
Yes, you should as well, Emil.
You should also watch out.
What a darn rascal!
To teach his little
sister to swear. Ha!
It was a Saturday, on which
the auction had taken place,
and now Emil was sleeping,
happy with his clever deals.
A short June night
came and went.
A new day began.
Sunday. But the cows had to
be milked Sundays and weekdays.
My goodness! Now how do I look?
How terrible.
I can't show myself like this.
What should I do?
Yes, Ida, I think
it's nice of Emil,
that he has given you the
box, even if it is worthless.
And everybody makes
a few crazy deals in life.
You shouldn't blame anyone.
But Lina!
- Emil!
- There's no reason to laugh.
Oh dear!
Poor Lina, the way you look!
You can't show yourself like this.
No, just today, when there's
Sunday coffee after church.
Emil, go and ask Krösa-Maja if
she can help with the coffee.
Yes. I don't want to make
a spectacle of myself.
That's terrible.
It must hurt a lot.
Yes, and how!
My head is about to burst.
Then put some snuff
into the hollow tooth.
- That'll surely help.
- Do you think?
Guaranteed.
Snuff is a drastic cure.
Oh!
- Well? Any better?
- No!
Then I rather
keep the toothache.
Lina, we are all very sorry.
But we must hurry now, Alma,
otherwise we'll be
late for worship.
I'm ready.
Set the table, Lina.
Take the flowered cups.
Emil, get on your way.
If you were ever in a forest in Smaland
on an early Sunday morning in June,
then you will surely
remember how it is.
The cuckoo calling and
the blackbird chirping,
you feel how soft the grass
is under your bare feet,
and how the sun warms your neck.
Yes? Yes?
God help us, Emil.
Typhus has come to Jönköping.
- Oh yeah?
- There, read it.
"Two people in Jönköping"
"are, as we have just heard,
infected with typhus."
What is typhus? Like the plague?
That people just die from it?
Yes, like the plague.
I don't know either.
I think at first they're
all blue in the face,
and then they die.
Shall we try the snuff again?
No thanks. I'd rather die.
Then you should go to the blacksmith.
Sme-Pelle was the blacksmith who
pulled out teeth with his dreadful pliers.
But you can't run around with
this toothache all the time.
No, I really can't.
How much does Sme-Pelle
charge for pulling teeth?
15 øre per hour.
I could pull the tooth much faster
and cheaper than Sme-Pelle.
Don't you understand?
I gallop off, and tally-ho,
the tooth is already out.
Tally-ho? No way.
You won't gallop off with me.
The only thing you
know are pranks.
Oh, we should try it.
Now all that's left is wait for the yank.
Yo!
Now she has to run.
Stop!
Stay put, Lina. Or you'll
never get rid of the tooth.
I'll be darned if I don't
get the tooth out.
- Run, Lukas!
- Help!
- Hop, Lukas!
Stop! I don't want to hear
about your yanks anymore.
Emil!
Your yank didn't work.
Poor Lina.
Yes, my little one.
I know I blew it myself.
Oh, I was so scared.
All right. Then I'll try
to find something else.
Yes, but not with
a jerk or a yank.
Certainly one can pull a tooth
with a bit more feeling.
There must be a
more gentle method.
Now you're making
a sour face again.
Do you want to get
rid of the tooth?
- Uh-huh.
- Okay.
Now there's no yank.
I'll pull the tooth with "Drr".
Slowly and with feeling,
as you wanted.
It's about to do "Drr".
No! I don't want that either!
Leave me alone with
your silly tooth.
I've done what I could.
Yes, thank you, Emil.
I know that.
Perhaps you'll find
something else we can do.
Somehow I have to
get rid of that tooth.
Do you really want that, Lina?
Yes, you must understand.
But I believe the fastest
method is still the best.
Do you think?
How about jumping into
the hay from up there?
When you're half way, the
tooth flies out. Boom!
Boom.
Come here.
This will get me killed.
Jump!
No. I don't dare to jump.
If you want to keep your old
tooth, you don't need to jump.
- What are you waiting for?
- Dear Lord!
Come on, Lina!
Now jump!
I'll help out a
bit, if you want.
Yikes!
Now look at this, Emil.
You can pull pranks,
but you can't pull a tooth.
So here I am.
Yes I see that.
And it's about time.
He's doing it with a wham.
Open your mouth!
What is that?
That doesn't look good, child.
Cough!
What disease do I have?
You have typhus, a bad disease.
First you'll get a blue face,
and then you are dead,
says Krösa-Maja.
But I'm not blue in the face.
No?
Emil had an idea.
How could he give Ida the facial
color of a typhoid patient?
Don't waste the ink.
Mother needs that to
write down your pranks.
Yes, I know that.
What's that?
"You're friendly invited to
the church coffee on Sunday,"
"Alma and Anton Svensson,
Katthult, Lönneberga."
This was the draft
letter of the invitation.
But it was no longer needed.
Emil had good use for it.
Now I'll show you
what typhus is.
Well? How are you, Lina?
Does the tooth still hurt?
- I don't know.
- You don't know?
What do you mean?
Sme-Pelle threw the tooth
on the rubbish heap.
Hopefully, the tooth
still screams in pain.
Look! The tooth is out!
What's happening?
Was it bad?
Yes, it hurt very much.
- Are you in there, Ida?
- Yes.
- Don't you want to get out?
- I can't. I'm sick.
What? For God's sake.
What's the matter?
What's wrong with you?
It's typhus.
Welcome!
If you please, Pastor?
Good day!
A coffee will do us good.
Get out!
We have typhus on the farm.
- What?
- Typhus? That's impossible.
What are you talking about?
Who has typhus?
Who? Me!
Oh, Ida!
I don't understand.
Don't you have typhus?
No, Krösa-Maja, it
just looks like that.
Surely you know who
painted my typhus.
Emil!
Where are you?
Thanks, thank you.
Just take it. Take
another piece of cake.
- More coffee, Mr. Pastor?
- Yes, please.
- Krösa-Maja.
- Ugh.
It's always Emil pulling
pranks on the farm.
But don't worry.
If the real typhus had come,
it would be even worse.
Well. One of my old confirmands.
How are you, Lina?
But what is it?
Do you have a toothache?
Poor thing.
But the tooth is already out!
Don't be so sad.
We all make mistakes.
This Emil! He should never
be let out of the shed again.
What is this?
What's this?
Where do these letters come from?
That's part of Emil's stuff.
He leaves everything lying around.
They belong to Emil?
I've been searching for
this stamp for years.
- They don't have any at the post office?
- Certainly. But this is a rare one.
Could I buy them
for my collection?
Yes. You can have it.
That's just some old stuff.
This isn't a joke. I'll pay you
40 crowns for the stamp.
What? 40 crowns for
a small piece of paper?
God forbid!
What? 40 crowns?
I can buy almost half a cow for that.
Half a cow?
Which end do you want to buy?
Do you want the mooing front,
or the tail wagging back?
Go straight to the shed, Emil.
Hello, dear Emil.
Tell me, where did you
get these letters from?
I bought them at the auction.
You know what I think, daddy?
I should go to
auctions more often.
You're going to the shed
and nowhere else.
Pastor, look at this! Aahh!
Uh... wait, Emil. Wait. Wait!
Emil was sitting in the
shed all evening carving.
Suddenly it occurred to
him that it was Sunday.
To use a knife on a Sunday
seemed a sin to him.
So as he was standing at
the window of the shed,
he was thinking about his sins.
Surely one couldn't pull teeth
on a Sunday or paint people blue,
and he came to the decision
to start a better life.
That's why he asked God
to make a good boy of him.
Help me, dear God.
I want to be good in the future.
I want to stop with the pranks.
Emil Svensson,
Katthult, Lönneberga.
Look how far I can jump, daddy.
Oh yes, a big casserole in the
stomach let's you really jump.
Do you dare to jump too?
Yes, I sure do.
Well, you see? Hop!
I still excel in
jumping and running.
Can you also jump from here?
Yes, I could jump from there.
But I... I don't want
people to see me.
I've ridiculed myself
often enough.
I dare anyway.
You'll soon see
that I dare too.
Watch out.
There I go!
I dare to jump from here as well.
When I jump, you have
to catch me too.
So, my dear friends, if
you see me here now,
you will surely
believe I am crazy.
Now, however, we
have jumped enough.
And, Emil? We don't tell mother.
No.
Emil tried to have as
much fun as possible.
For soon a new wind would blow.
School would start for Emil.
Surely you will like it.
Yes.
Beware of Emil.
He'll just teach you nonsense.
- Can you really read?
- Yes.
Then read something.
"The bear growled
fearously and..."
No, Emil.
Fearously!
Emil could read, even though
he sometimes made mistakes.
And the teacher was
not the first to suspect...
that they had a future community-
chairman in the classroom.
- So hear and wonder...
- Sit down!
Emil became top of his class.
Now, who are Jacob's sons?
Emil?
Ruben, Simeon, Levi,
Judah, Dan, Naftali, Gad,
Ascher, Issachar,
Zebulun, Joseph, and Benjamin.
Right, Emil.
Of course he still pulled pranks.
But always the kind the
teacher liked to forgive.
One day, however, he planned
something that no one had dared to do.
At least not at this school.
In Lönneberga it was talked
about long afterward.
And it was like this:
Good, Emil.
Now you can sit down again.
But Emil, now why
did you do that?
I've done this out
of my great goodness.
This answer became a
popular quotation in Lönneberga.
"I've done this out
of my great goodness",
he said after kissing
the teacher.
You kissed the teacher!
Yes, and if you want,
I'll do it again.
But he did not. There was
only this once and never again.
The teacher was not angry
because of the kiss.
No. Not at all.
The first snow fell,
and the women were
busy with the laundry.
Because at Christmas
everything should be clean.
On the day of Christmas Eve,
Alfred and Emil went into the forest...
and fetched the most beautiful
fir that they could find.
On a spring night something
terrible happened:
Emil had a stomachache
and had to get out,
but that was not the
terrible thing.
On the contrary, it was fortunate,
because the toilet was near the pigsty,
and there the terrible
had thing happened.
You poor little piglet.
Hey! Daddy!
Daddy, wake up! Quick!
Daddy! Daddy!
Darn! What have you done now?
Something terrible has happened.
Yes, that's how it was.
The sow that Emil's father
had bought at the auction,
had given birth that night and
killed ten of the piglets.
Something like this sometimes happens.
She would have killed the eleventh,
if Emil had not
passed by and saved it.
You poor little piglet.
What a bad mother you have.
There seems to be only
wickedness in Backhorva.
There's certainly a
curse on the cattle.
I'll look after the piglet.
I don't care if it's cursed.
You always want to
have everything.
The father was to be pitied.
A few days later the sow
was afflicted by a disease.
- Now the sow is also dead.
- God shall protect us from evil.
We shouldn't have gone to
this unfortunate auction.
What did we get from it?
A single, small, miserable piglet.
And that may also die.
How is the piglet?
It's restive.
It doesn't want to eat either.
Well...
Why doesn't it eat?
No idea. There has to be a
curse on him, daddy said.
The poor piglet will
surely be dead soon.
No, it won't die.
The piglet stays alive.
I'll take care of that.
I just want to see
that before I believe it.
It won't die.
Because I said so.
Yeah, yeah.
The days passed.
The small piglet grew and
became bigger and stronger.
On a beautiful Sunday, the
shooting team of Hultsfred had...
a morning meeting on the
cow pasture of Katthult.
Just this morning, Emil
had read in the newspaper...
about the Smalander Hussars.
And he wanted to
become a hussar as well.
Hussars, ride an attack!
Lukas, run as fast as you can!
God protect our King
and our Fatherland!
A powerful hurray for our
beloved royal house!
- Long lives!
- Hurray! Hurray! Hurray! Hurray!
- Help!
Hurray! Smaland together!
An attack!
- Pang! Pang!
- Quick! Seek shelter.
(Woman) Oskar!
Oskar!
Emil!
Griseknoen! Come here!
Emil wasn't sitting
alone in the shed this summer.
Where Emil was, you could
be sure Griseknoen was too.
Come on!
Come here!
Come.
Lukas!
And there is something for you.
Piggy!
I have something for you.
But not so wild.
Sit!
Sit! Come on, sit!
Sit, piggy.
Emil!
Sit! Sit!
Instead of carving figures,
Emil tried to teach the
piglet all sorts of tricks...
that nobody in Smaland thought
possible for an ordinary pig to learn.
Watch it, piggy.
Sit. Sit.
Yes, sit.
Take it.
Sit.
Sit, now take it.
Good piggy, sit.
The piglet can't catch me!
Hey, piglet, catch her!
Come, piglet.
What's going on here?
Jumping around with a piglet!
But the piglet finds it funny.
A piglet isn't there
to have fun.
There should be a
good Christmas ham.
But when you jump around
with it, it becomes skinny.
This is utter nonsense.
Christmas ham!
Emil did not like that.
You now know what you have to do.
You just have to remain skinny.
Then you'll always be happy.
Jump!
Jump, piggy!
Now jump, piggy.
Jump, piggy. Well done.
Jump!
What madness.
Do you see, Ida?
Now he can do it.
And again!
The piglet realized more and
more how beautiful life could be.
Just wind up in a place
where there is an Emil.
Emil sat there and thought about
how much he liked the piglet...
and who else he liked.
Well... first of course Alfred,
and then Lukas and then Ida.
And after the three...
the piglet.
Oh, I forgot my mum!
Of course mum...
But otherwise it is
Alfred, Lukas, Ida...
and the piglet.
And then we have
Father and Lina.
Oh yes, I like daddy
on most days.
But not on some other days.
And Lina?
I really don't know.
I don't like her,
nor dislike her.
She belongs to us
just like the cat.
So piggy? So far
you made it all right.
It makes a lively impression
and has a good appetite.
Yes, you did a
good thing, Emil.
This way you saved
your piglet twice.
How many times will I have to
save his life before he's mine?
Now, don't pester
dad about it.
You have Rolla and limping
Lotte since the auction.
Let your father at
least have the piglet.
What's that supposed to mean?
There comes Mrs. Petrell!
So?
What is the reason
for your visit?
I want to go to the pastorate,
but then I thought:
Take a detour to Katthult.
- How nice.
- You're welcome.
Alma, what can we
offer Mrs. Petrell?
No thanks.
I'm in a hurry.
Can we give you some cherries?
We have so many.
- Anton, go get some.
- Yes. Right away.
Yes, you could
make wine from it.
Make cherry wine?
No way.
Anton would be against it.
He's teetotaler.
Oh?
- He never drinks a glass of wine?
- No.
I'd pay good money
for a bit of wine.
- He does not need to know.
- Oh no!
I would never do
it behind his back.
But I could ask him.
Cherry wine?
No. Not for anything in the world.
All right.
Do as you think best.
Has she already said how much
she wants to pay? Not to little.
See you when the wine is ready.
Careful you don't
get a stomach ache.
The piglet follows him like a dog.
Come here!
You can taste strawberries.
No thanks.
I want to know how you
managed to do that.
There's nothing to it.
With a bit of cleverness
and a few potatoes...
you can teach a piglet
almost everything.
Sit! Sit!
Sit! Very good!
So, that's good.
And now...
Paw. Very good.
Oh, isn't that cute?
Indeed. I find it quite
peculiar for a piglet.
Paw. Good piggy.
Isn't our piggy sweet, Emil?
And jump!
Well done, piggy.
There's only one piglet
like him in Lönneberga.
And there won't ever be
someone as crazy like you.
I hope so.
Every day Ida and Emil brought...
the afternoon coffee
to the harvest helpers.
For it was drunk in the fields.
This was everywhere,
and everywhere the
children brought the coffee.
When you touch the
ground, you're dead.
But you too.
The cherry wine for Mrs.
Petrell was fermented,
and since Emil's father was
in the field during the day,
the mother took the opportunity
to put the wine in bottles.
Thus the father didn't
need to feel a sinner,
for wine being made at his place.
I'll be glad when I finally
get the stuff out of the house.
Good you are back.
Emil, be so kind and bury
the residues of the fruit there,
where we always put the garbage.
Did they enjoye the coffee?
Yes, especially daddy.
Yes?
Our daddy.
Hey, piggy!
Are you thinking I'll give
you something to eat?
That's not for you.
This is to throw away.
But why should I bury it?
I might as well give it to you.
Because you are so
crazy about cherries.
Well? Do you like it?
The cock liked cherries
just as much as the piglet.
But the hens weren't
allowed to taste.
But suddenly...
What is wrong with you?
Why do you lie down
at this time of the day?
Suddenly, the cock
behaved like a madman.
What's got in to our cock?
And our piglet has
also lost his mind.
Poor hens.
Bad enough that their
cock behaved strangely,
but that a wild pig was running
after them was too much.
Yes, that was really too much.
Emil knew you can
be scared to death.
What will mother say?
All chickens are dead.
Poor Lotte.
It was over with limping
Lotte and her many eggs.
The only thing Emil
could do for her was,
to bury her decently.
He already knew what should
be written on her tombstone.
"Here rests limping Lotte."
"She was scared
to death by a piglet."
You should be ashamed of yourself!
First you scared
the hens to death...
and then you continue eating
as if nothing has happened.
Why are you swinging back and forth?
And you, cock, suddenly
got rid of all your wives.
Aren't you sad?
Aren't you ashamed?
Well! That's no reason
to keep over.
What's wrong with you?
Maybe something was wrong
with the cherries? Could be.
No. They taste good.
How did Mother get the
idea of burying them?
- Here you go.
- Thank you.
Now stop!
Sing to Alfred another time.
Now where is Emil?
Where can he be?
Please take a look where he is.
Isn't he in the shed as usual?
No, he isn't there today.
- Come on!
- Yes.
Not hungry, Krösa-Maja?
I've had enough.
I notice that I am getting old.
Also my back hurts
more and more.
"Behind the stove sits a mouse.
You have to get out."
When we step it up, we'll be finished
with the rye harvest tomorrow.
Yes. If it doesn't rain.
So it would seem.
So what's going on?
Why do you stand there?
Did something happen?
Yes. Something did happen.
Um... it's just hard to
say what happened.
Yes...
In any case, our hens are dead.
- What? Our hens are dead?
- Dead?
And... uh...
the cock is drunk.
- Drunk?
- And... uh...
The piglet is also... drunk.
And as for Emil, he is also...
Yes?
Emil is...
Yes, what about our Emil?
He's also drunk.
- Emil!
- No!
- What did I say?
How is that possible? What
knocked the poor boy over like that?
- He smells of alcohol.
- Yes.
- Oh, my boy!
- Such a misery!
- I'll take him.
- My Emil!
Can I help?
- I'll help you.
- I'd better carry him alone.
Maybe water helps.
- We'll find something.
- No, no water.
Krösa-Maja ran straight
away and told everyone,
what bad things had happened.
Oh, my boy. My poor boy.
Alma, everything will be all right.
Come on, Alfred.
Carry him up into the room.
No, fresh air is better
for him. Believe me.
- No.
- Better leave this to Alfred.
He knows better than you and me.
Well, come, Emil.
Yes. That's right, Emil.
Alfred sat all evening
on the bench...
and had Emil on his lap.
He helped him, when
he had to throw up,
and consoled him when he
wept over his wickedness.
Emil had heard
that he was drunk,
but he didn't know
how it had happened.
He didn't know that
cherries, when they ferment,
are full of the stuff that
can make you drunk.
Listen! Let me tell
you something.
The Svenssons in Katthult.
Emil, the villain, got drunk...
and slaughtered all the hens.
Such misery. Such misery!
The sun went
down, it was dark.
The moon looked down
at Katthult farm,
and Alfred still
had Emil in his arm.
So how are you, Emil?
I'm still alive.
But if I die, you'll get Lukas.
Oh. Nobody died of it yet.
You can believe me, Emil.
Listen! Listen! Hey!
Emil from Katthult...
He got drunk. I know!
Did you hear?
Emil got drunk.
- Yes.
- And killed all the hens.
Come here! Come here!
Emil from Katthult
farm got drunk...
and slaughtered all the hens.
You poor limping Lotte.
Oh, goodness gracious!
Ida didn't know what to think.
Perhaps she had magic hands.
Yes, perhaps she could bring
back the dead with her hands.
Hocus-pocus...
now you're no longer dead.
The hens had
only fainted with fright,
when the piglet ran after them.
That's something hens do.
Hocus-pocus...
Just imagine: I've brought
all the hens back to life.
The next morning everyone
was on their feet again:
Emil and the cock
and the piglet.
But the cock couldn't
crow for three days,
although he tried again and again.
The hens looked so reproachful,
that he disappeared in
the high grass ashamed.
You can walk normal again.
To get drunk with
the piglet and lay down.
You are a real drunkard!
Emil's mother wrote in
the blue notebook:
"God help me with this poor boy."
"Today he was at least sober."
But that's not the
end of the story yet.
In the afternoon a car
came to Katthult.
There were three
serious-looking gentlemen.
Three Good-Templars from
Lönneberga, who came to visit Emil.
Now you certainly don't
know what Good-Templars are.
But I can tell you that there used
to be such people in Lönneberga...
and were very
necessary in Smaland.
The Good-Templars
were determined,
the stop the horrible drinking,
which used to make so
many people unhappy...
and certainly still does so today.
It has come to our attention that
not everything is in order here.
- What do you mean, please?
- We are thinking of Emil.
Did Emil do something? Hm?
They say he was drunk yesterday.
Well, listen.
That is exaggerated!
Surely you have been told
that it came to this,
because he has tasted cherries
from which I made wine.
Yes, and it wouldn't hurt,
when he would listen to a
sermon about soberness.
Today is a meeting.
After he got to the taste, it
would only be for his best.
Well, okay.
Then I'll go with him.
No way. If necessary,
I'll go with you.
I made the wine, Anton.
You shall not suffer because of this.
I will attend your campaign
against the alcohol.
And I could bring Emil,
should you consider it necessary.
Come, Anton.
Yes.
Goodbye.
See you.
Emil didn't mind.
It could be quite nice
to be among people.
No, Griseknoen, you're not coming!
Go home!
Go home, I said.
First of all, you didn't
drink one glass...
and secondly, it was my fault.
We have seen how alcohol...
has ruined people's prospects.
How it turns youthful innocence
into vice and shamelessness...
and how it lets the power
of manhood vanish.
So I ask you:
Will you, Emil Svensson,
for the rest of your life,
take the vow of sobriety?
Yes, I could do that.
Our mission is to warn
people for the consequences...
Piggy! You shouldn't be here.
Impossible. What is that?
This is our piglet.
Take it out.
A pig doesn't belong here.
Actually, it must
also take a vow.
After all, it ate more cherries
than I did. Sit, piggy!
Yes, good.
You have to be a good piggy.
Sit... paw.
Yes. Good.
- Here. Because you are so obedient.
- This can't be true!
Everybody was just
looking at the piglet...
and they were almost
forgetting about the vow.
So what about the vow?
Or shall we just forget it?
...to renounce alcoholic
beverages for all times...
and to help our
fellow human beings...
- that they too become sober.
Griseknoen, this also
applies to you.
Well, Emil?
There you are again.
I've taken a vow.
I have vowed to be sober
throughout my whole life.
Then I'll tell you
something, Emil.
If you do, you'll get
the damn piglet.
For real?
Yes.
Besides, I don't think
there won't be any good ham.
Oh, thank you, father.
I would never have drunk
alcohol without the piglet.
The next day, Mrs. Petrell
came to pick up the wine,
and Emil's mother was glad,
that his father was
now on the rye field.
- Hello, Alma!
- Welcome!
Welcome.
- Is the wine ready?
- Yes, it is.
But what are you doing, Emil?
I'm supposed to
ensure sobriety.
And so I thought I'd
start with Mrs. Petrell.
♪ Do you know what's good?
That there are no more like him ♪
♪ What if another dreadful little
boy came up like that? ♪
♪ Like well, doing mischief
every now and then ♪
♪ In a way, it would be good
if there was one more ♪
♪ One more like him, oh how
much fun we could have ♪
♪ Oh how cool, he and me,
doing mischief all day ♪
♪ Well then there's two thinking
what mischief we could do next ♪
♪ If there were two of us,
what would daddy say then? ♪
Subtitles by Subransu