There once was a story-teller
from Nantucket.
Who kept all his tales in bucket.
Instead of that guy,
Now I'll be your guide.
The coolest dragon
in the whole wide world.
It doesn't really rhyme, does it?
There you are.
Very well then.
I will tell you a story
that might have never happened.
But I swear all of it is true.
After all, I, too, had my paw
in that pie, so to speak.
All right.
A long, long time ago...
...in a kingdom
far far away there lived a king.
And his name was Allein III.
Voila.
It was during the 25th summer
since the Great Drought...
...that I bravely challenged...
...a fire-breathing dragon
to a fight,...
...single-handedly slaying
the beast...
...and saving my people.
"A fire-breathing dragon,
and saving my people." Got it.
Your Majesty, do you think
one dragon is enough?
It doesn't sound that impressive.
Make it five.
And each one had three heads.
You know what?
Let's make it a nice round number
worthy of a king.
Ten sounds much better.
You're right, Your Majesty.
Ten it'll be.
Ten five-headed dragons then?
That's right.
How could I forget that, huh?
ENCHANTED PRINCESS
His Majesty Allein III
had three sons.
His youngest son, Evan,...
...was always busy
inventing something,...
...from spring-loaded stilts
to a hot air balloon.
At times, you wouldn't even guess
what he was fiddling with.
Great.
Hey, you.
-What is it you invented...
-There you go.
...this time, Evan, huh?
Oh, I made a present.
It's for you, my brothers.
A one-of-a-kind goatcycle.
It won't move an inch.
And you call yourself
an inventor?
Trust me,
you couldn't be more wrong.
Hold on, I'll put my gear on.
Two older brothers, however,
led the life of a royalty.
Day and night, they seemed
to be busy as a bee.
-Giddy up
-In other words,...
...they were
true public officials.
Would you look at that?
Help us!
Don't twist the horns.
Evan, save us.
I got you.
Or maybe not.
That is just great.
Thanks for the present, brother.
You know, I kind of liked it.
Let's do it again tomorrow,
all right?
Meanwhile,
the neighboring kingdom...
...was ruled by another king,
Arrian IV.
And he had a daughter,
Princess Barbara,...
...who was known
for her unrivaled beauty.
As well as
for her unrivaled willfulness.
In a word,
she was a true princess.
Barbara.
Daughter, where are you going?
We have a guest
from the Tulip Kingdom.
Prince George Frederick...
Van...Van...Van...
Luther Beethoven something.
Another one?
Well, he will have to wait then.
I'm testing new fuel
for my balloon.
Don't go. What if you crash?
Oh, please, Daddy. Trust me,
I know exactly what I'm doing.
Oh, dear.
What was I thinking when I bought
this stupid balloon for you...
...in the Faraway Kingdom?
Don't you worry, Daddy.
Everything will be fine.
What am I to do?
How can I restrain her?
Even as a little girl
she was nothing but trouble.
She'd be looking
for fern flower...
...or trying to find out
how deep the sea is.
And now this.
A hot air balloon, huh?
I just want to see her
get married.
I...
I want grandchildren.
Your Majesty,
it can't be that bad.
All you need to do
is find a good match for her.
You know,
but where will I find one?
She brushes them all off.
You should use your authority.
Put your foot down.
What do you mean?
Put my foot down?
Like this.
Oh, no, no, I cannot do that.
What?
Stop, hang on.
Hello there.
Would you please help me
unhook my balloon?
Hello?
I...
I'm coming.
You should have dropped
the ballast.
Whoa, thank you,
it's all my fault.
I lost control.
And forgot
about the power increase.
But it flies
a lot faster right now.
-Faster?
-Yes.
I used straw and wool as a fuel.
If you use wet straw,
hot air becomes humid,...
...and it has
a better lifting capacity.
I got to say that's a great idea.
But I was thinking
of filling my balloon...
...with marsh gas.
That could be even better,
you know?
You are quite an interesting man.
How do you know
about ballast or about marsh gas?
Who are you?
Well, I am...
I am Evan, prince Evan.
And I'm Barbara,...
...the princess
from the neighboring kingdom.
That's great.
I thought you were different.
No, you're all the same.
Bye, Evan.
Thanks for your help.
What a girl.
We were destined to meet.
After all, I was the one
who made that balloon.
And it brought her to me.
Into my arms.
Breaking news.
Princess Barbara
turned down yet another suitor.
Rejected prince is heartbroken.
Princess Barbara turned down...
I am no match for her.
I mean, even a foreign prince
wasn't good enough.
What is going on, my child?
You've turned down
at least a hundred princes.
Don't exaggerate, daddy.
It was not a hundred.
A couple of dozens, maybe.
Or three dozens.
Why are you like this?
All other princesses long
for their Prince Charming,...
...and when he shows up,
they live happily ever after.
Well, I'm not like
other princesses.
None of them loves me, daddy.
They just like the way I look.
And when I smile, they
fall head over heels in love.
There you go. See?
Please, daddy, I just want
to be loved the way I am,...
...for my mind, for my soul,...
...for my thoughts and my dreams.
But, pumpkin,...
...you have to get married first,
and then, slowly but surely,...
...your husband
might take interest...
...in your thoughts and dreams,
and all those things.
Daddy. I'm done talking about it.
Look, the princess wants
to be loved the way she is?
She wants to be loved
for her thoughts and dreams?
Her wish is my command.
Wind, you're powerful and strong.
-You command the clouds along.
-Dragosha.
Are you messing up my bed again?
Yeah, I was just warming it up
for you.
So, I heard
you turned down another suitor?
Was he really all that bad?
Are you not going to love anyone
in your life?
End up an old cat-lady?
I don't know.
I met one guy today.
He seemed to like me as a person.
Not just my looks.
But it turned out
to be the same old story.
Same old story?
Eyes wide open
and just stands there drooling.
Just like every other prince.
I swear, sometimes
I just hate my own beauty.
What are you talking about?
Go look in the mirror,...
...you've got mud
all over your face.
Oh, you are right.
This is odd.
What was wrong with him then?
Yes. You may come in.
Your Highness, I have something
very important...
...to talk to you about.
What is it?
I was afraid to tell you, but...
...I can no longer hide
my feelings.
Your Highness,...
...I am in love with you.
No, not because of your beauty.
Your looks are not
important to me...
...as I'm quite handsome myself.
And I can't help but admire
your thoughts and dreams.
Your mind, and your soul.
We are so much alike.
Your Highness.
Will you do me the honor
of being my wife?
You and me?
So much alike, huh?
Well, I would beg to differ.
How dare you laugh at me?
I'm sorry, advisor, but I...
I am not planning
on marrying anyone,...
...least of all, marrying you.
You foolish insolent girl.
I'm warning you...
...if you dare to reject me,
I will turn you into...
I will turn you...
Into what?
A dragon.
Dragosha.
This is one of
my most powerful spells.
It can only be lifted by someone
who can love you as a dragon.
And give you a true love's kiss.
But you can't tell anyone,
not even your father,...
...who you really are.
Or you will turn into ashes.
Oh, no. This is a nightmare.
What did he turn me into?
What am I going to do now?
I'm so hungry.
What's that?
Wait, who is that?
A mighty beast.
See the little birch
In the meadow
See the green birch
Growing in the meadow
And this is how
my unparalleled valor...
...put an end
to the despicable enemy.
Have mercy, Your Majesty.
We come bearing terrible news.
Our kingdom
is facing a great threat.
There is no escape.
A certain death
is coming for us all.
We are all doomed, Your Majesty.
Stop banging
your heads against the floor.
You'll knock a hole in it.
Who will fix it then?
You won't, will you?
You've already broken
my door down.
Have mercy, Your Majesty.
Stop it, stop it. What is it?
Like we said,
we are all doomed.
Get to the point.
-We bear bad news.
-Just spill it anyway.
Your Royal Majesty,...
...a huge dragon
has been sighted at our borders.
It is enormous in size
and spits fire all around.
It has burned down
five acres of forest.
And now it set
its eyes our lands.
Sound the alarm.
Quiet!
Where are my sons?
I want them here immediately.
The time has come for them
to protect our kingdom.
There you are.
All right then,
here's my royal decree.
You all will,
without further delay...
You got all that?
Without further delay.
...ride to our kingdom
borders,...
...locate the wicked beast
and slay it.
We need this selfless act...
...to bring further glory
to our royal kingdom.
You got that?
My dear father, I am always
ready to serve our kingdom.
And I solemnly swear I will find
and slay the wicked beast.
Good.
And what about the rest of you?
Your Majesty,...
...we think Evan will manage
to bring further glory...
...to our royal name on his own.
Yeah.
It's just not a good time for us.
We got so much stuff to do.
-Like, you know...
-No inheritance for you.
Fire.
See the little birch
In the meadow
See the green birch growing
In the meadow.
This beast couldn't pick
the worst time to show up.
We've got better things to do.
I couldn't agree more.
We have to risk our lives,
and for what? It's not fair.
Well, I think it's wonderful.
A perfect chance
to prove our worth.
Yeah, right.
We have the chance,
we just don't have the time.
We're there.
Okay, Evan, you volunteered,
so you will have to go first.
Now go and guard the bridge.
Yeah, while we take a nap.
That's exactly right.
I'm so tired I can barely stand.
BORDER OUTPOST
OF THE FARAWAY KINGDOM
It's so beautiful.
Sometimes I wish I could fly.
I see the brilliance of the moon
The flame inside my chest
Is burning
You came to me in the balloon
And now I rush to you, my darling
Please, dad.
Just one more minute.
Why, you little...
Come here, you...
That's it. You're dead.
Are they here for you?
No worries.
It's just like bowling.
I didn't mean it, actually.
Maybe you didn't.
But who cares anyway?
They are trespassers, and bam.
You stopped them.
You saved your kingdom.
Oh, yeah?
Who are you again?
The wicked beast?
Well, yeah.
I guess so.
-And who are you?
-I'm Evan.
-Prince Evan.
-Oh, that's right.
So why did you burn down
half our kingdom?
I didn't burn anything.
Well, I did, just one tree,...
...but it was not
in your kingdom anyway.
It was there.
-Honest, I swear.
-Yeah?
And I thought you were...
The princess is missing.
What a tragedy.
What a nightmare.
The Neighboring Kingdom News.
Princess Barbara
has gone missing.
To whomever finds her,...
...the heartbroken king
has promised her...
...hand in marriage
and half the kingdom, as well.
The princess is missing.
If he fell in love with me
when I was a princess,...
...maybe he can love me
as a dragon, too?
Anything is possible, right?
Hey, Evan.
Where are you going?
To search for the princess?
Why don't you take me with you?
I promise,
I can help you find her.
Take me with you.
I will die here
without your help.
Let our fool of a brother...
...and that overgrown lizard
find the princess.
-We will follow them and...
-Wham, bam.
...then we'll see who gets
the princess...
...and who gets the kingdom.
You are right
as always my brother.
Evan?
-Evan?
-Yeah?
So where are we going
to look for her?
You are right.
Where should we start?
I'll tell you.
Where was she last seen?
In her kingdom?
I think so.
Well, that means
that's where we should start.
You're right. They have a fair
going on right now.
A lot of people out there.
Maybe someone heard something.
FAIR. SALE. EVERYTHING MUST GO.
NEIGHBORING KINGDOM.
Look at that.
Everyone's wearing costumes.
That's perfect.
They'll think you're
one of the actors...
...and won't get scared.
-Yeah, perfect.
-Lucky charms, love spells,...
...curses, and fortune-telling.
Princess-locating magic.
Excuse me.
What were you saying
about a princess?
Why? Are you interested?
-Sure.
-Well, just for you.
A handmade map, one of a kind.
It will help you
find your princess.
It's not just a map, it's magic.
We are here.
And here's the tower where
the princess is locked up,...
-...waiting to be rescued.
-Let's go.
Hold on a second.
But it won't be easy
to get there.
No pavement for miles.
I can give you a nice discount.
Are we going or not?
I said, hold on.
Just for you
special, five gold coins.
But I don't have any money.
How about you give me the map,
and I'll pay you later, huh?
You're kidding me, right?
That was hilarious.
Well, do as you please.
It's a unique item,
it won't last long.
Ladies and gentlemen.
Boys and girls.
Only one performance.
Try and beat
our invincible champion.
Don't even think about it.
You will never defeat him.
He will beat you to a pulp.
-We'll see about that.
-The winner gets five gold coins.
-Come on.
-No way. Hey, hold on.
Ladies and gentlemen.
Our invincible champion
has won another fight.
Okay.
Is there anyone else...
...who'd like to challenge
our champion?
I would.
Okay, welcome.
Evan.
Ladies and gentlemen.
We have a winner.
Five gold coins
go to this young man.
You are
the new invincible champion.
I offer you a one-year contract.
For sure you'll be a millionaire.
No time for that.
I need to find the princess.
One, two, three, four, five.
Now, this is
what I'm talking about.
Here's your
one-of-a-kind the map.
Good luck finding the princess.
Lucky charms,
love spells, and curses.
Seasonal discounts
all year round.
Now, where's the map?
Whoa, what map?
What are you talking about?
Lucky charms, fortune telling.
Where's the princess map?
Oh, this..
That's a one-of-a-kind,
handmade item.
Just for you, five gold...
Get lost, you fool.
As you please.
Sure, sure.
Where could she be?
Dragosha is missing, too.
Have you searched the cellar?
Have you searched
the secret passage, as well?
I wonder
if it was something I said.
Maybe I was too hard on her.
I mean, she is so young,
after all.
She has plenty of time
to settle down.
And as for grandchildren.
Well, I will wait
as long as it takes.
I just want to know where she is.
Until they finally found
themselves who knows where.
Meanwhile, Evan and the princess
were crossing wide fields...
Butterflies.
...and climbing
the highest mountains...
Well done.
...and making their way
through the thickest woods.
Are we there yet?
I'm so tired,
and my feet hurt,...
-...my tail hurts.
-Stop whining, will you?
I have blisters on my feet.
So, where are we?
Wait. We'll see now.
Yep. We're who knows where.
-That's where.
-I should have guessed.
Where now?
We'll go straight ahead.
We'll make it
somewhere eventually.
Yeah, right.
So much for male logic.
Fantastic.
Evan.
Slow down.
-Will you slow down already.
-What now?
I'm so tired. I'm so hungry.
I'm thirsty too. I'm sleepy.
Sleepy, thirsty, hungry.
Maybe you could make up
your mind.
You're acting
like a spoiled princess.
Hey, hey, you mister.
Hey, you, excuse me, hello there.
I'm sorry,...
-...but where are you taking us?
-To my house for the dinner.
The warrior will be
my first course,...
...and you, lizard, will make
the second one.
Why don't you wait here for now?
First, I need
to take a nap, all right?
To work up some appetite.
Hey, that rhymes.
That's a good one,
I need to remember that.
See, Evan?
Your map led us into trouble.
Why didn't you listen to me?
Now we'll be eaten
by some ugly ogre.
Stop pacing.
I can't think straight.
Do you even have
anything to think with?
Okay.
There must be a way out.
Hey, here's the idea,
you can breathe fire, can't you?
The bars will melt down,...
...we'll break them
and get out of here.
Breathe fire? No way.
-I get sick every time I do it.
-Oh, yeah?
So sick, you'd rather
be eaten alive by an ogre?
Quiet.
Well, hello there.
It's not my fault.
I told you,
breathing fire makes me sick.
It's okay.
At least we tried, right?
So was it worth, huh?
No one ever escaped from my cave.
Don't you understand,
you're doing it all wrong?
What? What do you mean?
You're breaking
the law of all ogres.
You have no right
to eat us just like that.
The law states, you have
to ask us three riddles first.
If we can't answer right,...
...then you can swallow us
right away.
But if we do,
you have to let us go.
And how do you know
about the law of all ogres?
I read it in a book once.
Well, you are right.
Okay, let's get it over with.
To answer, you have 30 seconds.
Riddle number one.
I am round, but...
...nothing can roll off me.
What am I?
The clock is ticking.
What can be round?
Tree stumps?
You are dumb as a stump.
What else?
-Barrels, apple pies?
-And nothing can roll off those?
Come on, think, Evan, think.
-Planets are round, too.
-That's right.
I have the answer.
It's our planet.
The Earth.
It's round,
but nothing ever rolls off it.
All right, you guessed that one.
Here's another riddle for you.
I am very easy to pick up.
But I am hard to throw far.
What am I?
You'll never guess that one.
Something easy to pick up.
Yeah, yeah, and hard to throw.
But why is it hard to throw?
-Because of the air resistance?
-Of course.
You time is up.
What is easy to pick up
but too hard to throw?
Feather. It's way too light,
so it just floats in the air.
Great, out of all people,
I get two highbrows.
All right then.
Here's my last
and my hardest riddle.
There are all kinds of stones
on the bottom of the sea.
Rubies, I don't know,
diamonds, emeralds, sapphires.
But what kind of stone
can never be found down there?
It doesn't make any sense.
All kinds of stones
can be found there.
All kinds of minerals.
Yeah, this one
is truly difficult.
-There must be a catch.
-Well, think fast.
Or he'll have us for dinner.
Just a second.
I got it.
It's not about the stones,
it's about the sea.
There are all kinds of stones
on the bottom of the sea,...
...but you will never ever find
any dry stones down there,...
...am I right?
Fine then, you won.
Okay then, time to go.
-So long, ogre.
-Stop right there.
You're not going anywhere.
Even though the code of laws
of all ogres...
...says that I have
to let you go,...
...however...
...it does not say when.
I like the way
you cracked all my riddles.
You'll be
my personal entertainers now.
All right.
But this time we'll be the ones
asking you riddles.
Believe me, I know
all the riddles in the world.
Really? All right, then listen.
Two men come up to a river.
There's a boat by the bank
that can carry only one person.
But both of them
successfully get across.
The question is, how?
Wait a second.
Wait a second, I know this one.
-Lets go, let's go.
-Hold on.
I swear I know this one.
-We have to hurry up.
-Don't worry so much.
It'll take him at least two days
to find an answer.
I got it!
Go, go, go.
-Run, quick.
-Where are you going?
-I will kill you both!
-Run, quick.
Just hear once.
Come back!
You won't get away!
I'll show you!
Stop right there!
I can't see anything,
but I will find you all the same.
I know the answer.
They were on the opposite banks.
That's how they got across.
One after the other.
Well?
I am listening to you.
My Royal Yourjesty!
I mean, your Royal Majesty!
Anyway.
Your sons have disappeared
and are nowhere to be found!
Disappeared how?
I would say, without a trace.
Meaning, they are gone.
-All three of them?
-Affirmative.
How could you let this happen?
Executioner!
Requesting permission
to be executed.
Stop!
We will immediately...
...form and send out
a search party!
I will personally be
in charge of the operation!
From here, from my office.
Well? What are you
waiting for? Scribe.
You stay here.
I got to have someone
to write down my strategic plan.
Well, where are we going?
There's nothing but trees here.
According to the map,...
...we just need
to follow this trail.
You rely on this map too much.
There's this rule, you know,...
...when in doubt,
read the friendly manual.
Does your manual say
how to save princesses too?
Evan! Wait!
What's wrong?
I just have a bad feeling.
What are you talking about?
Hello, kids.
I've been waiting for you.
Got you, dearies.
Welcome back.
You've got some pretty rad
whistling skills...
...for an old lady.
I am no old lady to you, boy!
I am the Witch of the Forest!
All of these woodlands
belong to me!
That's right.
Hey. Where's the dragon?
Over there.
It's one of my exhibits now.
Excuse me?
Come, I'll show you.
Here it is.
My collection.
Magic sword.
Flying carpet.
Why would you hide these gems
from the world?
They just make me happy.
And I don't care
about the world, dear.
Here it is, my brand new item
on display.
A wild fire-breathing dragon.
Please, do not feed.
Set it free, witch.
And don't make me
say it twice. Now.
Whoa, take it easy, my boy.
Why would you need
this beast anyway?
You need to be on your way.
The princess
is not going to rescue herself.
I will not leave my friend.
Why do you have
to be so stubborn?
Well, I'm offering you
a deal then.
If you can get three magic items
for my collection,...
...I'll let you both go.
Otherwise, you both rot here.
And what kind of items
are we talking about?
Well, for starters,...
...bring me
the seven-league boots?
You'll find them on top
of the world's tallest pine,...
...unreachable for anyone.
Including you.
You know,
it's not as bad as I thought.
You know how to play?
Poker? Bridge?
What about dominoes?
Let's go play then,
while our hero's on his quest.
Okay, here we go.
Here we go.
Hey, get off me.
Annoying critter.
I won.
Sure did.
This is starting to get old.
You don't think
I can win it back?
Your boots,
just like you ordered.
Look at that, you got them.
Sure did.
-Please, save me.
-Don't cry.
-Don't cry you poor thing.
-I can't take it anymore.
Don't get excited too soon.
Your second task,
Evan, is even harder.
This time, you will have to go,
who knows where.
And then bring you
who knows what?
Not at all.
I want you to find
and bring me the Helper.
And who's that?
What does he look like?
No one knows.
No one has seen him before.
But he helps everyone
who needs it.
Well, here I am. Who knows where.
Now, where do I find this Helper?
Oh, I got it.
Greetings to the one whom
they call the Helper.
I don't know who you are,
but if you help people,...
...you must be a kind person.
If you are anywhere around here,
please break the bread with me.
Thank you.
It's been a while
since I had any bread.
So you are the Helper?
-Yes, I am. I am. I am.
-Could you be a little less loud?
Like this?
That's better.
Will you follow me
to the Witch of the Forest?
Well, since you helped me,
I'll help you, too. Let's go.
That was easy.
-Are you still here, Helper?
-Yes.
Help me. Someone, help.
I'm right here, Evan.
What's with you?
Is it raining outside?
Or just windy?
Neither. I've been looking
for your Helper.
-So? Did you find him?
-Of course.
Of course. Of course.
Of course.
What took you so long?
All right.
Here's your final challenge.
The Sea King
has a wonderful magic comb.
Whoever uses it,...
...immediately becomes
young and beautiful.
If you bring me the comb,
I'll let your dragon go.
Otherwise, I'll eat you both.
But the King lives
at the bottom of the sea.
How do I get there?
What?
If I knew that,
I would have visited him myself.
Why do you think
I'm asking you? You get it?
I get it.
All right.
If I can't go to the Sea King,
he'll have to come to me.
Hey! Who are you and
why are you muddying my waters?
Hello, Your Marine Majesty.
I am Evan, prince Evan.
I'm sorry I had
to disturb you, but...
...could you please let me
borrow your magic comb?
It's for a friend, you know?
Well, well.
Did the Witch
of the Forest send you?
That's right.
She's such a pesky old lady,
isn't she?
-Hey, Evan.
-Yeah?
You're not by any chance
tech-savvy, are you, my boy?
-Actually, I kind of do.
-Maybe you can help me out then.
I used to have
a unique music machine.
But it broke down.
Oh, wait. Wait, wait a second.
I have an idea.
I have a really awesome idea.
Now, give me the beat.
I had a cool music machine
Real groovy
You know what I mean
It was entrancing
To watch my mermaids dancing
Now there's no one
On the dance floor
We can't party anymore
Yep. That's pretty much it.
I got so bored, I even
started sinking ships again.
If you can fix my machine,
you can have the comb.
I'm sure I can fix it, but...
...how do I get to the sea bottom
without drowning?
Well, suit yourself.
All right, here goes nothing.
Great.
Okay.
What's up, Evan?
Something wrong?
Don't worry.
I can handle it.
No way. Here I am the king.
And spin you go.
They had it coming.
-Hey!
-The coast is clear.
Keep in touch, Evan.
In case my music machine
breaks down again.
Hasta la vista, baby.
What am I going to do with you?
Catch the rope, guys.
It's getting dark already.
Where is your friend, I wonder?
-Checkmate.
-What? Where?
Oh, you sneaky little lizard,
it really is a checkmate.
You know what?
Don't get excited too soon.
Where is your hero?
He's gone. Perished at sea.
Trust me, you will
never see him again.
Yay, Evan.
We've been waiting for you.
Oh yes, we have.
-So do you have it?
-I do.
Here you are, my magic comb.
You have to let
the dragon go now.
I have to, although
I really don't feel like it.
I like the creature,
it's fun to play with.
Don't you worry.
I'll be visiting you.
-I doubt that.
-Goodbye.
Maybe you should stay the night
and leave in the morning?
Don't worry.
We can sleep in the forest.
We don't have much time.
We need to rescue the princess.
Well, off you go.
-One more thing, Evan.
-Yeah?
If you are ever in trouble,
turn the ring on your finger.
It's all right.
You will understand.
Tell me, Balthazar.
Where is my daughter?
We are still looking for her,
Your Majesty.
Our agents
leave no stone unturned.
I don't care about your agents!
I need my daughter!
I'll give you another day,...
...then..
...heads...
...will roll.
Trapped behind bars
In dampness I dwell
I am a young-hearted dragon
Brought up in a cell
Well? Dance.
Entertain me.
In your dreams.
Sit there for a while then.
And when your princess is tired
of wandering around,...
...she will get back to me.
No one will ever lift that spell.
So tell me, what
will you say to the princess,...
-...when you find her?
-What?
I guess I would say,
"Hey there, princess.
I am here to rescue you."
-And that's it?
-What else is there to say?
What about your feelings?
If you rescue her, it means
you got to propose to her.
What are you talking about?
I don't have feelings for her.
Why don't you wait here?
I'll take a look at what's ahead.
I see a tower.
Princess.
Hey, princess?
Princess?
Evan! What are you
doing up there?
You know, just...
...hanging.
We don't have time for this.
-Where's the princess?
-She's not here!
Who could have thought...?
Okay. I'll be down...
...in a minute.
Oh, no.
You know what?
You're not very gentleman-like.
That was crazy.
I didn't know you could fly.
Well, it kind of just happened.
Honestly, I was about to die.
My whole life
flashed before my eyes.
So thank you.
Oh, come on. You're welcome.
Run!
What?
Thinking about the princess?
Yeah.
Maybe someone else
already rescued her.
Come on, there's plenty
of fish in the sea.
What's so special about her?
I'm in love with her.
You're in love?
But you said
you had no feelings for her.
And how do you know?
You've only met her once. Oops.
But she...
She's just so...
...amazing.
Can you imagine?
She made my hot air balloon
flies so much faster...
...using wet straw as fuel.
I've never met such a smart girl.
But...
What about me?
Don't you care about me?
Nobody will ever love me!
Nobody will care for me!
I'm just a stupid dragon!
Hey, come on, stop crying.
Don't you know that
you are my best friend...
...forever and ever?
I will never leave your side.
As for me and the princess,...
...she may never
so much as look at me again.
But you and I,
we've been through so much.
The spell can only be lifted
by someone...
...who can love you
as a dragon.
And give you a true love's kiss.
Princess?
Princess!
Look, brother. It's the princess.
I can see.
Let's get them both.
Balthazar the Sorcerer
put a spell on me,...
...and you, you rescued me.
Hey! Who are you?
What are you doing?
What's got into you?
We are brothers.
I'm sorry, brother,
but we've had enough of you.
We've been chasing you
on that stupid goat for too long.
So true, bro. Let's get her.
Let me go!
I'll tell my dad all about you!
Go ahead, tell him,...
...don't forget the part
where you were a dragon.
And we'll tell him
we found you in the woods.
And you were so scared
you lost your mind.
What are we going to do
about Evan?
-One, two, three!
Bye-bye, Evan!
Goodbye, brother.
No hard feelings.
Now, this is a sticky situation.
And I didn't rescue the princess.
And now I never will.
Not you again.
Over there! Over there!
Okay.
Prepare for landing.
Oh, just wait
till I get to you two.
Well...
...I was just wondering...
...why there was
a thunder and lightning...
...on such a splendid clear day.
Your evil plan
has failed, Balthazar!
Evan has lifted the spell.
And he really loves me
the way I am.
Yes. That's unfortunate.
Who are you, anyway?
-It's time to get lost, grandpa.
-Or else.
Hey, what are you doing?
Now, what should I do with you?
All right.
I'll think of something.
So that's him,
Balthazar the sorcerer.
Looks like his ring
is the source of his magic.
If I take the ring away,
he should become powerless.
Hang on, Barbara, I'm on my way.
Who are you?
It's all just a dream.
My ring.
Give it back.
No way.
Who are you?
I'm Evan, prince Evan.
And you, Balthazar, are done for.
Take that.
-Helper, Helper, Helper.
-Give me the ring.
I'm here, Evan!
What's going on?
-Who are you?
-Hurry up.
Thank you.
I can't hold him much longer.
I'll show you.
Why isn't it working?
What's wrong, Evan?
Can't make it work?
-Can't figure out the ring?
-If you are ever in trouble,...
...turn the ring on your finger.
What? Wait. What?
Stop it, I feel dizzy.
Please, stop it right now.
No! I'm afraid of heights!
-Dragosha!
-My princess!
-My little girl!
-Daddy!
-I missed you.
-Our princess is back.
-She's home at last.
Everyone, come.
Now it's time to celebrate!
You'd better
get out of here, brothers.
Or I'll...
...turn you into toads.
-Evan!
-What?
Where do you think you're going?
You want to leave me
just like that?
I thought I was your best friend.
I thought
you'd never leave my side.
I'm not sure
if it was a good kiss.
It's hard to tell
since it's my first one.
But you know what?
Now you, being an honest prince,
just have to marry me.
Will you marry me?
Yeah.
Breaking news! Breaking news!
Princess Barbara
is getting married!
The day when I became
An awful dragon girl
You did not know
You would be my best friend
Even though I'm breathing fire
From my mouth
We are walking
Through the troubles hand by hand
The world appeared to us
And it became a dream
We have found the happiness
The joy and love in it
Even though it seemed
There was a hopeless time
We followed to the answer
With the loving light
The Ogre was overcome
All money for the map
You figured out the puzzles
Of the Giant my friend
And he rescued me
From the evil's way
My hero's getting close to me
From day to day
You were running
Like a vortex trough my life
I did not believe
In a power of love
And it doesn't matter
You were dragon girl
I felt the dragon turns
Into the angel wow
You can find the magic world
Is full of miracles at all
You can feel the kindliness
From the beaver on this land
Let the fairytales come true
The whole wide world
And it fills the towns, the seas
The mountains and the fields
Let the fairytales come true
The whole wide world
And it fills the towns, the seas
The mountains and the fields
We wish you to travel far away
In the world of fairytales
Well, I am...
Please, daddy, I just want to be
loved the way I am.
Oh, no.
This is a nightmare.
What did he turn me into?
Your looks
are not important to me...
...as I'm quite handsome myself.
Great, out of all people,
I get two highbrows.
I am the old lady, to you boy?
I am the Witch of the Forest.
How could you let this happen?
Executioner!
Trapped behind bars
In dampness I dwell
I am a young-hearted dragon
Brought up in a cell
That's just great.
Thanks for the present, brother.
I kind of liked it.
Fire!
How long do we have to dig here?
Dad said our punishment
is to dig a tunnel...
...until we get to
the other end of the Earth,...
...you know.
Hey, look, I think
I found something strange here.
What is it?
Looks like a chest or something.
All chained up.
But what do you think is inside?
There's a bear inside that chest.
In that bear, there is a hare.
In that hare, there's a duck.
In that duck, there's an egg.
In that egg, there's a needle.
In that needle, there's death.
And whose death is it? Huh?
Don't you know? Everyone knows.
But I don't remember.
-Oh, great! Just great!
-Stop.
I remember.
There's no way.
What? Beavers?
What's up?
What do you want from me?
Leave me alone!