[WAVES LAPPING]
[ENGINE SPUTTERING]
[FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING]
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
[FRENCH ACCENT] Oh, heh. Sorry, dude.
We didn't mean to sneak up on you.
It's just that we can't get
to where we want to go.
- Oh, where do you wanna go?
- We're looking for Pike's Trail.
- Pike's Trail?
- Yeah.
This map we got at the docks
is no good.
Yeah.
Well, north is up. That might help.
You might wanna think about
staying close to the shoreline here.
There's no cell reception
in case you get lost.
Just head up the trail about three clicks.
You'll see a big oak tree. Hook a left.
Another half click,
it should be in front of you.
- Thanks.
- Thank you.
Also, hey, a couple house rules here
on Kings Island.
You gotta go by dark,
don't leave any trash and...
...no drinking.
0K8)'-
So unload the beer.
Come on, dude.
- Have a nice day.
- Bye.
By the way,
don't let anyone see that flask.
HENRY:
How's your day going? Okay?
You know that this is the river
that leads down to the lake?
We had to put this...
[INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE]
--We have of the island.
It's the biggest one...
...but there's also a list of things
on here.
HENRY:
Oh, there's no cell service up here.
I'm afraid you'll just have to look
at the lake.
Hey, Mr. Sanderson. Are you home?
I know that you're around because I
saw smoke coming out of the chimney.
Are you cooking something?
Are you cooking, like, a stew?
It smells really good.
It smells like good stew.
You wanna invite me in for some?
- Hey.
- Go away. I'm fine.
I know, I know. I'm just doing my job.
You're the only other guy on this island.
What would people think if I didn't check?
Exactly what part of "I'm fine"
don't you understand?
I-- I...
Thanks for checking in on me, Henry.
Hey, no problem, Mr. Sanderson.
Wanna come in for dinner?
Oh, wouldn't want to impose.
AGENT 1:
The radius is too big.
AGENT 2: Shit, we should've hit
these guys before takeoff.
Little thing called probable cause.
We didn't have it. Fucking Constitution.
- We could also use some more men.
- We could use a lot of things.
We got 4000 miles of border here.
Only problem is
we're looking at Canada.
The Canadians
don't wanna sneak in here.
That's why we don't get squat.
All anyone cares about
is Mexicans sneaking in...
...and we happen to be facing
the wrong fucking way.
Hang up. Now.
Where are we with the GPS modulator?
AGENT 1: Nothing pinpointed yet.
- What about Border Patrol?
AGENT 1: Plane was flying
too low for them to track it.
Only one reason a plane flies
without a transponder...
...and low enough to avoid radar...
...and that's because they're carrying
a load of some very naughty shit.
We're gonna have to trawl the waterways,
boys and girls. That could take all night.
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
Open it.
[HORSE NEIGHS]
[FRENCH ACCENT]
Pardon our intrusion.
We are with the RCMP,
patrolling the area.
We heard you needed help...
...in locating a suspected drug delivery...
...that went down a couple of hours ago
along the border.
We have knowledge of the island
and would like to offer you our assistance.
You're a bit out of your jurisdiction,
aren't you?
And, uh, we don't use horses.
See, we drive cars.
What Mr. Johnson meant to say
is thanks, but no thanks.
Shitload of red tape
to team up with the Mounties.
Much obliged. We'll keep you posted.
Pardon me,
but we can be really helpful.
We have HMI lights, we have generator,
we have trawling gear.
If we don't find the drugs
before the runners...
...it will be picked up, shipped out
and chopped down by morning.
Time is of the essence.
LEADER: I appreciate your concern,
but not interested.
There's no leads
that we can share at this time.
Well, giddyup.
[IN FRENCH]
Hey, what the fuck, Frenchy?
I told your boys we didn't need any help.
Is this some sort of joke?
[IN ENGLISH]
Do I look funny to you?
Uh, yeah, as a matter of fact, you do.
- Is it my shoes?
- Well, kind of.
You see, I don't wear leather.
I'm a vegan. It's for the environment.
I'm helping the planet.
Oh.
Do you know that cow farts...
...are responsible for one-quarter
of the methane pollution in the world?
[AGENTS CHUCKLING]
That's right.
What?
[ALL LAUGHING]
What the--?
AGENT 1:
Hey, man! Hey!
Come on, come on, come on!
Freeze!
Drop the gun.
AGENT 3: Shoot him!
- I can't get a shot.
- We can do this one of two ways.
- Hey, I'm the guy with the gun.
And I'm the guy with the guy.
You can turn over the GPS location
of the crash...
...and I spare you a painful death.
Or we can keep on playing games.
[BOTH GRUNTING]
[YELLS]
[IN FRENCH]
[GASPING]
[IN ENGLISH]
I hate guns.
[BEEPING]
I have it.
XANDER:
Good. How close?
Middle of the lake,
few kilometers from shore.
No read on depth,
but easily reachable by boat.
- You're sure?
FRANCOIS: Yes.
Let's hope it's wrapped tight.
It was not supposed to be underwater.
Let's move.
We'll find out about the ranger.
We won't have any unknowns.
Get the horses en route to the dock.
Four hours
before replacements show up.
Better get the Humvee. It will be faster.
Think about our carbon footprint, hmm?
[NECK SNAPS]
Think about the children.
Hello?
Is anybody here?
WOMAN:
Hello?
Down here.
Oh, heh. Thank goodness.
I have been here hours.
I got tired of yelling for help.
Could you come down here, please?
I'm-- I'm kind of stuck.
Yeah, hold on. I'll be right there.
- Hi there.
- Hi.
So you got yourself lodged in here
pretty good?
Yeah. It's, uh-- It's kind of stupid.
I, um-- I saw a blackberry.
Can you believe that? Heh.
Twisted my ankle reaching for it,
and I slipped.
I'm-- I'm pinned in here.
All right. It doesn't seem so bad.
Hold on, wait. Let's just, uh...
[BOTH GRUNT]
How's that?
- How's the leg?
-It's, uh, sore.
- Is it?
- Yeah.
- Let's get you up on the path, okay?
I'll stay here. Turn around and I'll push.
All right? So you--
You just, uh--
I'll stay back here and push you.
- Just-- Actually, let me get up next to you.
- Okay.
HENRY: All right. Ready?
- Yeah.
HENRY: Okay. Just hold on to me.
- Okay.
HENRY: Can you put any weight on it?
- Uh, some.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
Here. I'm just gonna carry you, okay?
I'm gonna lose my feminist card for this.
Oh. Well, I won't tell anyone if you don't.
[BOTH CHUCKLE]
[COMPUTER BEEPING]
Hey, guys, the cell tower is down and--
Holy shit!
No cell, radio's busted. A GPS signal
from the water near Kings Island.
That's where they're headed.
To the dock.
HENRY:
It doesn't look too bad.
We'll just keep it elevated.
I could tie it tighter.
- Keep the swelling down.
- Okay.
- Okay. You ready?
- Mm-hm.
I'll pull on three.
- One, two...
- Unh.
...three.
You tricked me.
[BOTH CHUCKLE]
So are you a military guy?
Yeah. How did you know?
You got the look.
Also, you know,
the photographs over there, heh.
Ah, yeah, I was a diver.
They used to call us "frogmen."
Wow, that sounds exciting.
Well, I mean, I guess it depends
on the level of danger.
Right. I mean,
I didn't mean it sounded fun.
Just, you know,
it's not your normal 9-to-5.
Mm-hm.
So you never get lonely being out here
all by yourself?
Couple hundred people
come through here every weekend.
Yeah, but there's being around people
and there's being with people.
Could I have sounded more of a bitch?
I'm sorry.
No, no, no. I understand.
It must look pretty weird.
I just, uh, heh...
I just needed to be by myself, so...
Had to clear my head of some stuff.
Right, so how long you been here?
- Three years.
- Three years?
Heh. Well, it must be pretty clear
by now.
Clearer. It's getting better.
Still a bit murky.
Well, clear or murky, it's a--
it's a nice head.
Oh. Thanks, ma'am.
[KAYLA & HENRY CHUCKLE]
Hey, um, how's the ankle feeling?
- Better.
- Good.
It's gonna get dark soon. We don't
wanna lose the light on the water.
- I could get you to your canoe.
- Okay.
HENRY: Ready?
- Yeah.
Hey, it would be no problem
to quickly shuttle you across the water.
That's kind, but I'll be fine.
Besides, I don't wanna
leave my canoe here.
0K8)'-
We should exchange info, though.
So you know I made it back safely.
Oh, yeah. Yeah, that's great.
Okay. Ahem.
I, uh-- I stole a map from your office.
I hope you don't mind.
- Those things are worth, like, thousands.
- Huh.
Well, use this hundred dollars' worth
to write down your number.
- Hmm.
- And I can call you before dinner.
Dinner?
Yeah. Dinner.
You know,
eating a meal at night together.
Speaking in between bites
to get to know someone.
HENRY:
Uh-huh. Um...
Next week sometime?
I was thinking more like tonight.
My address is on the back.
I'll expect you around 9?
We could eat a picnic under the stars.
You saved me today.
Let me say thank you. Please.
I don't know.
I've got a lot of stuff to do up at the lodge.
- Yeah, I noticed. It's a real hub of activity.
- Heh.
Come on. I'm so grateful to you.
It's dinner, for God's sake.
I will see you tonight.
- I'll see you there.
- Bye.
- Eenie...
MAN: Ha-ha-ha.
XANDER:
...meenie...
...minie...
[CONTINUES LAUGHING]
...mo.
Get the equipment.
We're leaving in five.
He shoots, he scores. Ha-ha-ha.
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
[KNOCKING CONTINUES]
HENRY:
Coming.
Oh, thank God.
I was starting to think nobody was home.
I'm here.
What are you doing on the island so late?
Oh, I, um-- I beached my boat,
like, way on the other side of the island.
I started hiking, got lost. Sun went down,
I couldn't find my way back to the trail.
Yours was the only light I saw for miles.
Glad you found me.
Come on in. Get you warmed up.
- Sorry about the mess.
- Right.
- Can I get you anything?
- Water would be great.
All right, come on right back here.
Not a lot of residents around here,
I take it'?
No, it's just me. There's another guy...
...had his cabin grandfathered in
before they declared this a state park.
Feel like an idiot getting lost like I did.
Don't be.
Kings Island, it's not easy to navigate.
It's why we got all the signs saying
"Leave before the sun hits the horizon."
Thanks for that.
Sure.
So, what are we gonna do
with you, mister...?
Clay. Everybody call me Clay.
I guess you'll have to spend the night...
...if you don't mind sleeping on the floor.
Got extra blankets and a pillow.
And in the morning,
we'll look for your boat.
Cool.
So you work up near here
or down in the city?
Not working at all right now.
Was a construction worker...
...but that turns into day laborer
when people stop building.
Yeah, I hear that. Though the economy
seems to bring people to the outdoors.
We've been pretty busy up here.
Silver lining, so to speak?
So is that what this job is all about?
Getting in touch with nature?
So to speak. I guess you could say I came
up here for a little bit of perspective.
But it's hard to explain.
Well, I'll get the blankets and the pillow.
I'm actually going out tonight,
and I won't be back until late.
Going out? This late at night?
Looks like you brought a knife
to a gunfight.
I've gotta give it to you, Henry,
you're kind of perceptive.
Must be that,
what you call, military training.
Duck and cover, enemy approaching.
Sit.
If you want money, I don't have any.
If that's what I was after,
you think I'd come to a place like this?
It's a fucking gold mine, right?
What do you want'?
It's not about what I want,
it's about what's right...
...it's about what's just.
Whatever you think I did,
I can assure you I didn't do it.
See, that's where you're wrong, Henry.
You can't assure nobody of nothing.
I will always place the mission first.
I will never accept defeat.
I will never leave
a fallen comrade behind.
That sound familiar?
I'm telling you this so you'll understand.
I always knew I was gonna be a fuckup
like my old man...
...and I did not disappoint.
No, sir.
So I had to make sure
my baby brother was the opposite.
In school, he get a B, I'd belt him one...
...make sure he raised it to an A.
He was everything I wasn't.
He was a fucking all-star at everything.
He enlisted so he could go to college.
And I told him,
"if you're gonna be a soldier...
...you're gonna be the best soldier."
I pushed him...
...the way I wish
somebody had pushed me.
When he made Special Forces,
it was the proudest day of my life.
Few months later, I got picked up
on a bullshit assault charge.
That's where I got the letter...
...telling me Decker had been killed
in a firefight in Afghanistan.
Decker. You're Decker's brother.
I said, shut the fuck up.
Now, that's a hard pill to swallow...
...finding out your baby brother's
been killed.
But what made it even harder...
...was learning he had been abandoned
by his commanding officer...
...and left to die at enemy hands.
They sent us in
without knowing the risks.
It wasn't my fault.
It wasn't anyone's fault.
So why did you resign, hmm?
The military acted on bad intel.
They gave the order, it went crazy.
I don't know. I...
- I guess I just couldn't take it any more.
- That is fucking bullshit.
Admit it.
Admit you got my brother killed.
Confess it right now...
...and I will make sure
your death is quick.
But you keep lying to me...
...and I promise you...
...it will be anything but.
They ordered us into a shitstorm...
...your brother got separated, and if we'd
gone in, we'd all have been shredded.
I had to protect my team.
You had to protect yourself!
You're a fucking coward.
You should've been leading the charge,
Henry...
...not falling behind it.
[PHONE RINGS]
[MACHINE BEEPS]
KAYLA [ON MACHINE]:
Hey, Henry, it's Kayla.
Um, I just wanted to tell you
that I'm running a few minutes late, but I--
You don't have to do this.
We can work this out.
No. We can't.
[GRUNTING]
[YELLS]
XANDER:
Oh, you guys.
Now, that's good, pure, crisp air.
Eto, are you ready to dive?
Just about.
- Francois.
- We're getting close.
And how are we on time?
Next shift arrives in three hours,
20 minutes.
We are clear till then.
XANDER:
I want to be gone in two.
We have to retrieve 5O pounds
of pure white uncut heroin...
...and pound for pound,
it's worth more than each of you.
So make yourselves worth a lot.
CLAY:
You awake, huh?
You awake?
Get up. I'm tired of carrying your ass.
I said, get up!
You had me there for a second,
didn't you?
Good thing I over prepared.
Nothing could have stopped this day.
You hear me?
You won't feel better when it's over.
I might.
Stop.
Take this.
What are you doing?
It's got a bullet in the chamber.
You put it to your head,
you pull the trigger.
Do the honorable thing.
Did you learn about honor in prison?
Maybe I did.
I did my time.
Now it's time for you to pay for your sins.
Go ahead.
Put it to your head and pull the trigger...
...because if you're not man enough
to do it...
...I promise you, I will.
You know, for a long time
I wanted to do this.
Every goddamn day.
You think I didn't blame myself? Do you?
I couldn't send any more men in.
He wouldn't have let that happen.
No soldier would.
And he was a soldier.
I still think I could have done more...
...except I don't know what the more is.
I lost my career. I drank.
I have a son.
I haven't seen him
since my wife threw me out.
So I got as far away from everything
as I could, and here I am.
After a while,
I stopped feeling like I killed him.
A little bit at a time.
So I guess you're just too late.
A while ago, I would have done it, gladly.
Now...
...you're just gonna have to do it yourself.
Sorry.
[WATER SPLASHES]
Very well, then.
Don't you say a word.
XANDER: This is Immigration
and Customs Enforcement.
That's not ICE.
They don't patrol at night.
- At least, not without contacting me.
XANDER: You there.
- Let me see your hands.
-Sure, my bad. We just, uh...
...out here night fishing. Trout.
XANDER:
You need to leave the beach. Now.
No problem.
We ain't caught nothing all night anyway.
XANDER: Who's there with you?
- I'm the park ranger.
XANDER:
What's going on here?
Just caught him night fishing like he said.
XANDER:
Looks like he caught you.
Gentlemen, mind stepping forward?
Get down!
XANDER:
Now fire!
[GUNFIRE]
[GUNFIRE IN DISTANCE]
Was that gunfire?
Well, it ain't the Fourth of July.
Eto's down.
[SPEAKS IN FRENCH]
Shit.
Fuck.
[ENGINE STOPS]
[IN FRENCH]
No.
[SHOUTS IN FRENCH]
[IN ENGLISH]
Eh. Shit happens.
[IN FRENCH]
Eto.
[SPEAKS IN FRENCH]
[IN ENGLISH]
Close your eyes.
[XANDER GRUNTS]
What the hell was that?
Who was that guy with the shotgun,
and why was the ranger there?
I thought he was accounted for.
I don't know. We had tabs on him.
How do you not know?
Oh. You don't know how close you came.
So let's get to the landing strip.
We don't know
if anyone heard those shots.
No one lives here except the ranger.
We can work with this.
We complete the mission with the ranger.
He has training. He can make the dive.
We hunt the ranger.
We kill the other guy.
No mistake. No hesitation.
Let's go.
SAUL: Ranger's place is empty.
Signs of struggle.
The phone is shattered.
XANDER [OVER RADIO]:
That must be our new friend.
Sink all the canoes.
No one gets off of this place except us.
There is a boat tied up outside.
The engine's still warm.
Sink it.
JEAN:
Oi.
[GUN COCKS]
No one asked you to leave.
Put the kayak down.
Now start walking.
Whatever you guys are up to,
go ahead and do it.
Just don't litter my park.
Oh, park-ranger humor? Very funny.
- Where is the other guy?
- I don't know and I don't wanna know.
He led me down here at gunpoint.
He wanted to kill me.
Well, then, you won't be sorry
when we kill him.
JEAN [IN FRENCH OVER RADIO]:
[IN FRENCH]
[GUN COCKS]
[BOTH GRUNTING]
Oops.
Hey, hey, he)'-
I don't want you dead, okay? They do.
In the next few hours, we're gonna have
to work together if we wanna survive.
Work together?
Have you lost your goddamn mind?
Listen, in the service, they paired us up
with Pakistani special forces.
These incompetent assholes
who wanted us dead.
And we didn't like them either,
but we worked together...
...knowing that at some point,
either later that same day...
...or 20 years from now
when politics changed...
...we'd be trying to kill each other again.
You understand what I'm saying?
CLAY:
Let's go.
[IN ENGLISH]
Jean?
Jean, report.
Saul, we've lost Jean.
Be prepared for heavy resistance.
Understood. When we were
in the visitors center, I took a map.
I'm looking at it now...
...and it shows another cabin...
...further inland.
Take care of it. I'm on my way.
CLAY:
So who the fuck are they?
Military-trained.
French-Canadian by the sound of it.
Probably mercenaries,
either working the drug routes...
...or picking off the leftovers.
A lot of drama for some weed.
They got too much firepower.
Gotta be something more lucrative.
Okay, makes sense.
So, what's our next move?
We gotta call for help.
You destroyed my phone,
so we need another one...
...and there's an old man who lives
this way. That's where we're headed.
Hey, stop.
You sure he's got a phone?
I don't know. But he's our only option.
No visual on the park ranger...
...but there's a body on the ground.
I think it's Jean.
Okay, stay on the trail. Minimal comms.
Radio compromised.
[IN FRENCH]
CLAY:
I guess that's that.
He already knew. This guy's pretty smart.
What?
Your brother knew what he was doing...
...and he never would've let us
sacrifice ourselves for him.
If this little truce of ours is gonna hold...
...let's not talk about my brother, okay?
I just think you should know
the whole story before you kill a person.
If I were you...
...I wouldn't talk to me about my brother
while I'm holding a gun.
Good point.
Let's go.
Unh. Shit.
SAUL [IN FRENCH OVER RADIO]:
AGENT [WHISPERING]:
Did you hear that?
[WHISPERING]
Hear what?
If you have to ask, then you didn't hear it.
[ALL GRUNTING]
[GRUNTS]
Fragaria ananassa.
[IN ENGLISH]
The wild strawberry.
I wasn't aware you grew in these parts.
They'll smell that a mile away.
CLAY:
So how did you know about me?
HENRY:
Your tattoo.
And just intuition, really.
You get a feel for someone
who wants you dead.
Time?
Two and a half hours.
Gentlemen, good evening.
I would like to speak
to whoever has the walkie.
[OVER RADIO]
We are under time constraint.
We want to finish our work.
End this now and no one else gets hurt.
That's the wrong move.
We have a conversation,
find out what they want.
We know what they want.
They're drug dealers.
They want their drugs.
XANDER:
Allow me to be direct.
I simply want the park ranger.
The other guy...
you can go.
This don't mean I trust you.
Move.
XANDER: If you change your mind,
you know how to reach me.
I'm in the book.
[IN FRENCH]
- How much further?
- We're close. We should see it soon.
[KNOCKING]
Mr. Sanderson.
- Break it down.
- No, it's not a home invasion.
I don't want to involve the guy. I just want
to get in, make the call and get out.
Forget the window.
No, this is our best chance.
- No, we go in this door.
- We don't have time for this.
I'll go, then you go.
I've got nowhere to run once I'm inside.
You make one wrong move, you're
gonna have a new asshole. You hear me?
[GRUNTS]
HENRY:
Now we do this my way.
What happened to trust?
I trust you to go pick up that phone
and dial out.
- What?
-It's dead.
- Give it to me.
- What, you think I'm lying?
Oh, shit.
Just what do you think this is,
a goddamn hotel?
Put the gun down right there on the box.
- Mr. Sanderson--
- Do as I say, boy!
Huff)'-
Okay, okay.
- I thought you said you knew this guy.
- I do. Mr. Sanderson, it's me, Henry.
Don't you recognize me?
I've not gone dumb up here.
You broke into my house.
I got a right to defend it.
CLAY:
Look, we ain't here for you, old man.
We got drug dealers out there
hunting us, trying to kill us.
Seems like you are trying
to kill each other.
- Well, it's complicated.
- Always is.
We just need to use your phone,
call the authorities...
...and get off this island
before anybody gets killed.
Phone don't work.
I had it cut off a couple of years back.
- Why the fuck is it sitting on the table?
- It looks nice.
[IN ENGLISH]
Hello again.
It's a nice house.
Do me a favor.
Can you please send me the park ranger?
He's not here.
We gotta get out of here. Now.
I ain't going nowhere.
This has nothing to do with you.
These fellas want a bite.
I'll give them a mouthful.
[CHUCKLES]
Morris, cover the back.
Nobody gets out.
Shh.
Piss off my land!
This guy's kind of cranky.
Hey, you people inside, I hate guns.
They are very bad...
...for the environment.
However, I'm not stupid.
Gentlemen, a little help.
Get down!
[GUNFIRE]
I get hikers here from time to time
trying to run me out of my home.
Hikers?
You seriously think those are hikers?
Sir, we gotta leave this house.
We're sitting ducks here and you know it.
SANDERSON: Take that.
- What, am I invisible?
- Why him and not me'?
- I don't know you.
I do know fellas like those assholes.
Couple shots...
...they'll run off like squealing pigs.
You'll see.
I don't think you understand
the situation we're in.
We appreciate your help,
but for the last time, this doesn't seem--
[GUNFIRE]
XANDER".
Give us the ranger...
...and we'll go away like a bad dream
you won't remember in the morning.
Fellas, I don't know what's gone on
between you. You gotta get past it.
Old saying goes,
"Hang together or hang separately."
A knife? What the fuck
am I gonna do with a knife?
Man can do a lot with a knife.
That's how much I trust you.
Now just stay low.
You're gonna have to fall back
before they get us surrounded.
Fine by me.
No. Not fine. You're coming with us.
I've got my ways of getting through this.
Just go.
[GUNFIRE]
SANDERSON:
You boys get out of here.
Go out the back. Head east.
- Oh, hell, Henry, you know the route.
- No!
Go before I shoot you myself.
This ain't a negotiation.
You got the rest of your life to be a hero.
I just got this one time.
I brought this to you.
You stay, I stay.
Well...
...okay, then.
I guess that settles it.
“No!
He is gone. He's gone.
And I'll be happy to let you go with him...
...but I need you to get off this island.
You mean sometimes,
you have to leave a guy in trouble?
- Any more shells?
- I didn't think I would need any.
Well, that's just perfect.
Like the old guy said,
"A man can do a lot with a knife."
They're gone.
Morris, come in.
MORRIS [OVER RADIO]:
I'm hit. They are gone.
- You're hit where?
- Shoulder.
Use the other one. Move your ass.
Hey. Where did they go?
Kiss my geriatric ass!
[SANDERSON GROANS]
[SANDERSON COUGHING]
FRANCOIS:
Are you sure about that, huh?
XANDER:
Wait, wait, wait.
Stand him up.
[GRUNTS]
Organic. Good man.
When I was a little boy
at my grandmama's place...
...she had a lovely goose.
I named her Edith,
after the French singer Edith Piaf.
I truly loved that goose.
Everybody thought it was funny.
Then one night when we were at dinner...
...my grandmama said to me,
"Edith tastes good, no?"
I ran out of that table...
...I puke up...
...I cry like a child.
Ever since, I became a vegan.
Mm.
I'm telling you...
...I had to kill her.
[GROANS]
We're losing time. I need my diver.
My patience is losing weight.
No, no, that's not what they say.
They say, "I'm getting real pissed."
Let's go.
Gotta get to the other side of the island,
where your boat is.
Yeah, I kind of lied about that.
I paid a guy to bring me here.
Supposed to come back in the morning.
You got a plan B?
You hide till morning
and make it through the night.
You want me to hide?
What are you gonna do?
I'm gonna lead them away from here.
Now, they track one of us, they catch both.
I'm gonna take the fight to this maniac.
- With what?
- Whatever I got.
All we got is this.
I got some matches...
...a spool of fishing line and some rope.
Well, that'll scare the shit out of them.
Look, man, I came prepared for one night.
I didn't come prepared for war.
Yeah, well, this war came to us.
Listen, if we both survive this,
let's talk, okay?
[LAUGHING]
HENRY:
Your brother was a wonderful soldier.
He had to be, in Special Forces.
Always had to be the first man
through the door.
I wonder what or who
made him that way, huh?
Always pushing.
Maybe you think about that too.
I'll bet you do.
Not a day goes by I don't wish
it wasn't me instead of him.
Not a day.
I'm gonna be needing this.
Gentlemen, I'll put it simply.
Henry, I know you.
Henry, I know a lot about you.
I also know you are trained
in deep-sea rescue and retrieval.
Which makes you worth a lot to me.
Now, if you don't help me
to get what I came for...
...I will have to go...
...after your family...
...and kill them, one by one.
And I will start with your son first.
Henry, please, it's your final chance.
I take it by your silence...
...that you've made the wrong decision.
All right, it's time to hunt.
Let's go.
[IN FRENCH]
SAUL [OVER RADIO]:
Fuck me.
You!
[BOTH GRUNTING]
I thought you wanted the ranger dead.
I did.
[JEAN CHUCKLES]
What changed?
My mind.
[GASPS]
Aah! Fuck! Help!
[BOTH GRUNTING]
[IN ENGLISH]
Come on.
Pass the fuck out.
Come on. Unh!
Pass out.
Pass the fuck out.
[GASPING]
Hey.
Hey. Come on. Wake up.
You can't die yet. I won't get to kill you.
Yeah, that'd be a shame.
[CLAY CHUCKLES]
Look what your friend dropped.
Look, man, I got a lot of questions to ask.
Well, I've got answers.
Maybe even some you don't want.
But I'll always tell you the truth.
Let's get out of here.
I located a canoe
in case you don't feel like swimming.
I'll do you one better.
[SCREAMING]
Fuck. Aah! Agh. No, no, no!
You-- You're so fucked.
By my count,
that's three of you down so far.
Fuck off.
[GRUNTING]
Okay, let's go.
No, no. We gotta see what's what.
- How many of you are left?
- Eat a dick.
[CLAY CHUCKLES]
[GROANS]
You know, when I was in the yard,
when we wanted somebody to talk...
...we'd carve one of their eyes out.
Though I notice you've got two of them.
You wouldn't. Heh.
- You've got 30 seconds.
FRANCOIS: You gotta stop him.
Oh, yeah, he's really gonna listen to me.
One...
Okay. Okay, okay.
Xander. Okay, his name is Xander.
He wants you to make a dive.
For the drugs.
Told you it was drugs.
- Don't brag.
- You assholes, you killed our diver.
Xander knew, he knew you were trained.
So when you killed Eto,
we needed you to make the dive.
- How did he know that I could dive?
- He knows things.
The drugs are in the lake?
It's a shipment of heroin.
It went down in one of the lakes.
- How many of you are left?
- Just Xander.
- Just one guy?
FRANCOIS: Yeah.
Good. Knock him out.
- Let's get the hell out of Dodge.
- Let's go.
XANDER [IN ENGLISH]:
Leaving so soon, Mr. Taylor?
[XANDER HOOTING]
Over here.
I'll make this simple.
Half a million for 10 minutes of work.
You have no one left.
We know that you're the last one
standing on your side of the equation.
Your best bet is to get back on your boat
and travel on out of here.
If you leave now
without hurting anybody else...
...I'll let the police handle you.
If you don't...
...I'll come for you myself.
Trust me, you'd prefer the police.
[SHUDDERS]
Bring that fire.
I like this side of you, Henry.
I know what you want...
...and I'm not operating any dive.
You've lost your mind. You've left nothing
but bodies behind you tonight.
Then you'll want to listen closely...
...when I tell you I have someone
you want to keep safe.
There's somebody else on this island?
- What color was that canoe you found?
- Canoe?
- Yeah, what color was it?
- Silver and blue.
XANDER: Yes, I have a woman
who would like to speak to you.
KAYLA:
Henry?
- Kayla?
KAYLA: You didn't show up...
...for our date, so I came down here.
This man's got a gun.
He's got a gun, Henry.
XANDER:
It's true. Even though I hate them.
Kayla, hang on.
I'm coming for you.
After you do your job,
you can leave with the young lady.
You have 10 minutes.
If you don't come, well...
...let's not talk about negative.
CLAY:
You're in no shape to take this guy.
Come after me, but keep your distance.
If you see an opportunity to move in,
take it.
Otherwise, keep your eyes on Kayla
no matter what, okay?
Forget that, man. I say we take this boat
and get out of here.
What about Kayla?
It's my fault that she's even here.
Another person you wanna leave behind.
What is with you?
I just wanna make a trade with this guy.
Hopefully, he'll let her go, you get her...
...you find anything that floats,
and you get out of here. Okay?
Straight to the mainland, don't look back.
Find the police, tell them everything.
Well, not everything.
Okay, go, come on.
- This guy will kill you.
- Well, I guess you should thank him.
Good luck.
You know, these beans are fair trade
from Colombia.
No slash-and-burn agriculture.
But you could care less, I'm sure.
Where is she?
- Where's your friend?
HENRY: He left.
He took Kayla's canoe to get help.
But by the time he gets there,
we'll be done and you'll be gone.
Why do I doubt that?
Show me Kayla or I turn around.
Mm, that's good. But you forget...
...you're not the one
who's calling the shot here.
You need me to get what you want.
You spent the last two hours proving it.
[SIGHS]
Very true. Okay.
Outside, girl, now.
There she is.
Let her go first.
I can threaten her, you can say,
"Let her go."
You can threaten me,
and I can put my, uh...
...on her throat.
It's all one big circle, you know.
And I don't have the time.
She waits here, or she die.
You're the only one left.
We're gonna do this my way.
[FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING]
FRANCOIS:
You lose, park ranger. Put the gun down.
That's right.
You know...
...you should learn to tie better knots
next time.
Now, then, shall we?
Get on.
I'm making the dive. Let her go.
Or the girl stay here.
You know, you finish the job...
...and then both of you will drive
to the sunset.
Let him think about what I'll do to her
if he fucks with us.
Francois, be a gentleman.
Just hang in there. I'm gonna get you out
of this, okay? I'm not going anywhere.
He promise. Come on, inside.
[SPEAKS IN FRENCH]
You know, Mr. Taylor, I'm not a bad guy.
I was in the service like yourself.
Oh, yeah? Which side?
That's not very nice.
Well, now you deal drugs and kill people.
It's so true.
Where did I go wrong, huh?
[BOTH GRUNTING]
[GRUNTS]
I should've killed you
when I had the chance.
- You okay?
- Yeah. What's going on here?
What's going on?
We're getting the hell out of here.
We can't just leave Henry.
Henry can handle himself, trust me.
That man will kill him.
Look, he will not hurt him
until he gets the drugs.
We've got time to go get the cops
and get back here.
Now let's go.
KAYLA:
Stop.
Put your hands up,
turn around slowly and face me.
What are you doing?
No police, Mr. Shotgun.
- Fuck me.
- I'd rather not.
So how are we doing?
The suit's a bit tight.
He must've been kind of short, your diver.
Don't insult Eto.
Clock's ticking.
So you can see.
- Thank you.
- Attach this to the bag, tug twice.
You have eight minutes.
In nine minutes,
your lady friend will be dead.
Okay? Don't be late.
Give me 30 seconds to clear out
of the way before you pull it up.
Oh, Mr. Taylor.
Be careful.
So, what are we doing here?
Shut up.
I see it in your eyes, you're not a killer.
You can't see shit in my eyes
except my eyes.
Look, tonight's been hard on all of us...
...except Xander quite often has me
do a lot more to distract people.
A lot more. So it may have been difficult
for you people...
...except for me, it's kind of been a breeze.
- So you're just a hooker?
- I'm so hurt.
If you're gonna shoot me, shoot me.
0Kay.
Shit.
[couemwe]
I can tell you're in pretty rough shape.
Why don't you just come on out...
...and we'll--
And we'll work this out.
Xander,
a speedboat's approaching the dock.
It's two police officers.
What should I do?
Be normal. Tell them you're fishing.
Agree to pay the fine.
And be quick.
[SIREN WAILS]
Good morning, officers.
What can I do for you?
You haven't seen the park ranger,
have you?
No, I just got on the island
a couple minutes ago.
Been doing some late-night fishing.
Is it season already? I don't think it's--
Uh, no, okay, you caught me.
I just-- I wanted to get a head start.
I'll pay the fine.
Ma'am, we got a report
of a loud noise coming from the island.
We tried to reach the ranger
but couldn't get through.
I don't know. I haven't seen anybody yet.
CLAY:
Hey!
Shoot her! Shoot her!
- Shoot her!
- What the hell?
- Fuck yourself.
CLAY: Shoot her!
[BOTH GRUNTING]
Fuck.
Kayla, meet me at the pickup site.
I've got the package.
Be convincing.
Sounds good. I, uh, took care of our friend.
Let's get out of here.
Very nice.
- Good. Good work.
- Oh.
I'm not done yet.
This is a Magpul ACR.
It works after being submerged in water
hours, days, even weeks.
- You're great.
- Come on. We're done here.
You're gonna turn the key, drive to shore.
I'm gonna get Kayla,
and we're getting out of here.
You look at me funny and you die.
Oh, you're the boss.
XANDER:
So remind me, what are we doing here?
The cops are here.
We're gonna hand over the drugs,
and you're going to jail. You got it?
[BOAT CREAKING]
You mean those cops?
All right, move it.
KAYLA: Henry? Henry!
- Hey, shut up!
- Thank God, Henry, you have to help me.
- Henry, she's with him.
- No, I'm not!
- She is with Xander.
- Keep moving. Keep going.
CLAY: Shut up!
- Clay, what are you doing?
KAYLA: He's gonna kill me!
CLAY: Shut up!
KAYLA: You have to help me, Henry!
- He's crazy! He's crazy!
CLAY: Shut up! I am not lying to you.
- Do not point that gun at me.
KAYLA: Don't let him hurt me!
- Don't let him hurt me, Henry, please!
CLAY: Listen, do not point that gun at me.
- Listen to me, okay?
KAYLA: He's crazy! He's crazy!
She-
[ALL GRUNTING]
Hey! You want this, huh?
You want this?
Come on.
You fuck up, baby.
That's not good.
Henry.
[XANDER COUGHS]
You know, Mr. Taylor...
...most people never use
all five senses at once.
Me? I use everything I've got.
That's why I'm better.
That's my edge.
Oh, we get to play in trees.
I'm coming, Mr. Taylor.
[GRUNTING]
There's no shame in defeat.
Sleep, my child.
Sleep.
[BRANCH CRACKS]
[GRUNTS]
[ENGINE STARTS]
You gotta be kidding me.
[GRUNTING]
A man has got to know his limitations.
Well, Mr. Taylor,
you can always say "almost."
Bye, Mr. Taylor.
Almost.
Fucking gasoline.
I knew it would ruin everything.
[LAUGHS]
- Unh!
- Come on. Come on.
Thanks.
Not a fucking word.
Oh, my lips are sealed.