Your wife,
your daughter,
your son.
Behind you, your parents.
The emotional circle's closed.
What are you feeling now?
I feel vile. Guilty.
I want to get out of here.
Ms Jarczyk?
I'm happy, when he's unhappy.
Kaim?
My sisters beside me.
Why did she want tn die?
You committed suicide.
Why?
I wanted to unburden my father.
What do you want to do now?
I'd like to hug him.
Go ahead!
No,
it's impossible,
I don't want to hear this.
Back ever there, please.
Your wife?
I don't love him.
I want him out of here.
But I haven't... there's nothing...
And your son?
My heart hurts.
I'd like mother tn stop hating father.
It's your fault
my daughter died.
And now my son's sick.
Leave me alone! All of you!
It's not my fault!
I don't even feel hatred.
Just contempt...
We'll finish up
tomorrow morning.
It's too bad we broke oh?
Please go to your rooms.
Don't talk to each other,
please.
And no television.
We'll meet for breakfast
at 8.00 tomorrow.
He's still not here.
And it's already 8.15.
I'll go see what's up with him.
Mr Telak left us yesterday.
Please, don't take it personally.
What now? Is that it?
Patients tend to react forcefully
after such intensive therapy.
What about us?
No, come on, that's lust wrong!
But I can't force anyone!
The therapy's voluntary,
I barely persuaded him
to do it anyway.
Isn't it weird? The whole
family starts with an a.
Agata, Agnieszka and Antoni.
You'd rather we all began
with a b?
Bronislaw for me
and brigitte for you.
- Bonaventura for me...
- That's a man's name.
Nope, it ends in an a,
ergo, a woman's!
I wouldn't want to start
with a b.
Not to mention grandpa Andrzej.
I saw one bacteria
that was lust so like you...
Give me a break!
Mummy, he's suffocating!
He'll die!
Oh, Jesus!
30 degrees in the shade...
And they didn't even
crack open a window for him.
- We need to call the police.
- There's no time for that!
Agnieszka! Stand back!
Careful...
- All right... here, boy, here!
- I've got some water.
Gut it?
There you are.
What's going on here?
Some imbecile shut
their dog in a car in this heat.
And you've gone one better!
- What was I supposed to do?
- The dog was suffocating!
You've destroyed the car.
Your id, please.
Here you are. Excuse me.
- Hello? Yes, what?
- They were all tight shut and...
Ok, fine, I'll be there asap.
If I must"...
I'll be happy tn cover the cost,
but as you can see, I'm a prosecutor
and that very same day,
I'll have the owner in court for
ill-treating an animal. Ok?
- Where are you going asap?
- I have to go to work...
But it's Sunday!
- I do know it's not Tuesday!
- I was meant to go into the lab...
So, work at home!
I'll be back soon.
- Who's in charge here?
- Lieutenant Smolar.
That's not Slawek Smolar,
by any chance?
I don't know! Smolar.
Thank you, you can go.
"Only mountains never meet..."
You became a prosecutor?
Well, we had to meet
sooner or later.
Later would have been
fine by me.
Sure...
Fingerprints?
None on the instrument itself.
And what's that in his eye?
A skewer.
There was a set in the dining room.
He died around midnight.
There was nobody in this wing.
It's closed oh' from the hotel.
Theoretically, it'd be possible
to break in, but why bother?
So we have four suspects.
A psychologist and
the people in therapy.
On the face of it,
there's no motive.
On the face of it?
Yeah. I mean someone had to
drive that skewer into his eye.
You don't do something like that
without a reason.
The widow's arrived, lieutenant.
Please accept my condolences.
How did it happen?
In all probability,
assault and robbery.
An accidental death.
He must have run into the burglar.
He received a fatal blow to
the head from a sharp instrument.
He died at once.
The doctor says...
He wouldn't even have felt
any pain.
May I see him?
That might not be the best idea...
I want tn say my farewells.
Evidence is still being collected.
Besides,
it's not a pleasant sight.
As you wish.
- May I go now?
- Of course.
But we'll have to talk.
Would you come and see me, please?
How about tomorrow?
Around noon?
And the body?
There'll have to be an autopsy.
But the funeral home will be able
to collect him on Thursday.
Here's the number
to a support center...
For the families of crime victims.
It might help.
- Will they bring back my husband?
- Knwnacki, drive Mrs. Telak...
No, thank you.
I've got the spare keys.
Odd... as if she really
hasn't taken it in.
My wife wouldn't take it in either.
She was laughing even
at the divorce hearing.
So why did you marry her?
For her sense of humor.
And you... did you get married?
- Hi! Got anything for me?
- Nothing for the jackals.
No politicians
and no celebrities involved.
You're not nice.
And in front of the ladies, too.
- Prosecutor zieleniecka...
- Szacka.
- Are you new in town, ma'am?
- I am.
Tip me oh' when you get anything.
Szacka?
Get on with interviewing
the witnesses, ok?
- Want to arrest someone?
- Right now, I don't have cause, do I?
Put them through the wringer.
Find the killer, I'll lock him up.
They can't like you much
at the prosecutor's office.
Not if they land you with
a case like this.
Is this going to take long,
lieutenant?
It's rather inconvenient.
We've already been here 3 hours.
I understand your irritation.
If it's any consolation,
you're still in a better situation
than the deceased.
Bad joke.
It's not a joke,
it's the truth, doctor.
I have to question you.
And then we'll decide what next.
What next? You're not going
to arrest us, are you?
Now that, I'm afraid,
I can't promise.
You're not going to believe
who I met today.
Who?
It doesn't mailer_.
I love this. First of all
you want to tell me something,
then you decide you don't want
to talk about it.
It'd be better
if you didn't start at all.
Who did you meet?
I think I'll put Agnieszka
down for ice-skating.
She's got such inborn grace...
Agata, are you finally going
to tell me who you met today?
You don't tell me everything,
ehher.
And you're surprised?
You're a prosecutor, after all...
Watch.
Belt.
How about my shoelaces, too?
Shoes.
And what've I got there?
A kalashnikov?
I don't know. We'll see.
- Can't you hurry it up?
- I'm sure we can.
Yes? Hello?
Ifs Igor.
- Go on.
- I have some bad news, sir.
- Hen/yk's dead.
- What happened to him?
I'm afraid it was
an unfortunate accident.
Come to the airport.
- We're going back.
- What?
Grab all that, honey, grab it.
- Just what are you doing, sir?
- Can't you see? I'm through.
If this is how you treat
passengers,
nubudy'll bother tn fly at all!
The weather's breaking,
mr chairman.
I just don't get it.
Why've we come back...
Take it easy, babe.
Go with the driver.
Maybe it's a good thing
you turned us back.
A week with her and
I'd probably have gone crazy.
Tell me what happened.
Henryk was murdered...
Nn Saturday night.
At przegurzaly castle.
- What the fuck was he doing there?
- Group therapy.
One of the others in the
group could have killed him,
or someone who knew he was
going to be there.
Or a burglar,
like the police are claiming.
Bullshit, not burglars.
They always say when they want
to get the press oh their backs.
What should we do?
The initial procedure's already
been set in motion.
- That'll do for now.
- Are you sure, sir?
The person who killed him
won't get far.
Who's running the investigation?
Smolar at police hq and Szacka
at the d_a_ 's oh'ice_.
Smolar___.
- And who's this Szacka?
- New. No experience.
That shouldn't be a problem then.
Well?
Nothing.
Nothing?
- Nothing's also something.
- What am I supposed to make of that?
Nobody saw anything,
nobody knows anything,
nobody has any suspicions.
The whole group had been
in therapy for a week.
Before that,
they didn't know each other.
They say that Telak
was deeply depressed...
And they're so convincing I almost
believe he committed suicide.
And your impression?
Nice. Nice.
Nobody was unnaturally
composed. Or agitated.
None of them gave anything
away about themselves.
Henryk Telak was the first
of the group to be the subject...
Of the family
constellation method.
And what's that?
Look it up on the Internet.
Hellinger's method is lust a way...
Of bullshihing people out
of their money.
Interview everyone
who was around.
Someone might have
seen something.
The windows and the door
are barred.
The Porter could have dozed oh?
I really can't lock
all four of them up.
Prohibit them from leaving
the fold.
- Pardon?
- Take their passports.
These days, one travels
on one's id, you know?
In your opinion, what kind of man
was henryk Telak?
Well,
very unhappy.
Anyone who goes into psychotherapy
is kinda' nuts,
but he'd had exceptionally
bad luck.
You know,
his daughter committed suicide.
And six months after her funeral,
he found out about his son's illness.
A congenital defect.
You found the body, right?
It was before nine.
I ran oh' the terrace
into the dining room...
I found the body there,
with that skewer in its eye.
That's it. I started screaming.
Who arrived first?
Ms jarczyk_ then dr rudzki...
And finally, Kaim.
The doctor yelled that nobody
should touch anything...
Until police arrives...
And to get out because we were
trampling on the evidence.
Which one of your group
could have murdered Telak?
I don't know. I have no idea.
I see.
But if you had to take a guess,
name one person, ___
- then who would it be?
- Kaim, perhaps.
He played the role
of lvlrtelak's son in the session.
You could see that his father
had wronged him badly. So...
I thought perhaps it was he...
Out of revenge on his father...
That he'd had no love,
well, and generally...
Yes, I felt hatred toward him.
And did you kill him?
- No.
- And did you want to?
No. Honest to God, no.
And what do you think?
Who killed him?
How would I know that?
The papers said it was a burglar.
An adult guy's supposed to kill...
Some other guy...
Because during a session...
He pretended
to be his unloved son, right?
I don't know.
I did say that I don't know.
I was taking part in a constellation
for the first time...
And it's an experience
close to losing consciousness.
The longerl stood there,
the worse I felt and the less
like myself.
Ok, so now you're looking at me
as if I've lost the plot,
but I'll finish anyway.
I wasn't pretending
to be his son.
I was clearly becoming him.
And please don't ask me
how that's possible.
Which one of your group
murdered Telak?
Nobody, of course.
You surely can't be thinking
that one of us is a murderer?
You'll vouch for people
you've only lust met?
Well, no...
But, I mean, they're normal people,
I've heard their life stories.
It must've been some thug.
Since they're normal, how come
they're having psychotherapy?
No, that's not fair.
All of us have problems
of some kind,
but not everyone can cope
with them on their own.
- Hania?
- Why?
The daughter commihed
suicide at the age of filleen___
I'll bet my life he molested her
when she was a kid.
Hania sensed that and
she could have killed him.
Like, in some kind of sleepwalking
state, for example.
No, it's not right to
throw accusations around.
It also came out
during the therapy that...
Lvlrtelak's wife hated him...
And ivis Jarczyk played that hatred
so evocativelym
I don't know myself.
And what did you feel
when you saw mr Telak's body?
First of all I was terrified.
And when I calmed down,
I felt a sense of relief.
I've never met anyone
as wretched as him.
So I thought that perhaps somebody
had done him a kindness.
There couldn't be any world
where he'd be worse oh'___
than he was here...
Lvly apologies.
But in my current state...
I couldn't make it tn your office.
At least
I didn't miss the view.
Impressive, isn't it? You should come
and visit me once it's dark.
Let's begin, otherwise I really
will be here till nighh'all_.
Seme coffee er tea?
A glass of water will be fine,
thank you.
When did you meet mr Telak?
I was organizing an international
psychotherapists' conference.
Looking for a printer for the
publication of the papers,
I came across his company,
polgrafex_.
He was intrigued by the contents
of the publication.
I told him that
I try to help people...
For whom life's lost its meaning.
That was when he told me
about his daughter's suicide,
his troubled relationship
with his wife ____
I asked if perhaps he'd like
to meet with me.
He wasn't sure, but a week later,
he phoned.
We met once a week.
Then I decided to use
systemic family constellations.
And they are___?
Bert hellinger's family
constellation method.
Other patients embody the subjects
family members.
We build a model
of the emotional relationships...
To discover hidden dependencies.
But why do you limit it
lust to the family?
Aren't emotional relationships
between people who aren't related...
Often the most powerful?
We're concerned
with the archetypal love...
Which is not
of our own choosing.
Love for our children,
our parents and our grandparents...
Is thrust upon us
by the law of nature.
If you'd like to read up on it...
During therapy, did Telak
tell you that he had enemies?
Telak was a broken man, withdrawn,
closed in on himself.
I don't think anyone in his circle
paid him any attention.
Please set up
your immediate family.
Barbara will be your wife.
Yes.
Kaim will be your son.
And hania, your daughter.
But I...
My daughters dead.
Put her in place, please.
We 'll place
your dead parents here.
Your primary family.
So, this is how it looks,
henryk.
You can see your family.
What are you feeling?
I feel vile.
- Gui/ly.
- Breathe, please, breathe deeph/.
Sit down.
But what kind of theater's this?
Do they receive a script
beforehand?
No, and whats more, they know
almost nothing about henryk.
They don't know that he ran away
from home as a teenager,
orthat his parents died tragically.
Did you see
what's happening there?
Try and draw some conclusions
from the way he placed them.
Telak is lonely.
His wife isn't standing beside him,
his children aren't looking at him.
Think about what the children say.
They want to be together.
And they want to go to their grandparents.
What does that mean?
They want to die. But why?
Out of love for their father.
He failed to give due reverence
to his parents before their death.
He disturbed the systemic balance.
That means that someone must
take atonement upon themselves...
And it's most often a child,
who enters as new into the system.
The child takes on the burden
of restoring the equilibrium,
takes on the guilt, anxiety and anger.
Watch what happens, please.
The son.
My heart hurts.
I'd like things to be better for Dad.
For mother to stop hating him.
It's your fault my daughter died.
And now my son's sick.
Leave me alone!
All of you!
It's not my fault!
I don't__.
Come on, how's it possible
for Kaim's heart to be huding?
I mean, how can he feel
physical pain?
The morphogenic field theory...
Is used to explain hellinger's
therapy.
According to the theory, what
we are doesn't only depend on genes,
but also on an electromagnetic field.
Hellinger maintains that our spirit
resonates with everything...
That happens within the given
family and is connected...
Not only with the living,
but also with the dead.
While the constellation
is being put in place,
a stranger can enter
that resonance.
And you believe this?
Belief is meaningless,
as far as I'm concerned.
What's important is whether
it's eh'ective or not.
I myself have witnessed how family
secrets of which the patient...
Had no idea at all have emerged
during the constellation.
Interesting.
It could provide a new
investigation method.
Establishing the guilty...
Party on the basis
of family constellations.
- A sense of humor, too...
- I'm not joking.
If you'd tell me more about
the other patients' case history,
it could prove immensely helpful
to the investigation.
I can't reveal my patients
secrets...
Very well then. Please give me
all your recordings.
There's bound to be a clue
in there somewhere.
I rather fear that they,
too, are a professional secret.
May I remind you of the law?
And may I remind you that a murder
has been committed and that I,
as a prosecutor,
am investigating the case?
- I thought it was a police matter.
- You thought wrong.
Now, sir, you're one of the
chief suspects.
I could write out
an arrest warrant...
Right here and now
and call the police.
And then write
out search warrant...
And take all the recordings
for myself.
Would you prefer
to deal with it that way?
[ - You're ]Oking_
- by no means. So?
As you please.
Thank you very much.
Is this your first
criminal investigation?
It is.
- And what did you work on in tarnow?
- Economic frauds.
They have economic frauds
in tarnow?
No. Which is why they
closed down the department.
Sit down, please.
The investigation will be
tedious and laborious.
That's probably why I was
assigned to it.
Don't be too hasty
to pronounce judgment.
It's a fundamental sin
for a prosecutor.
I read it your file that your
maiden name's zieleniecka.
- Is Professor zielenieeki any relation?
- My father.
Daddy.
Thanks to him we have
our modern criminal law.
The police made a note...
That Telak's wallet
was found among his things.
Take a look at that wallet.
A wallet can speak volumes
about its owner.
His wallet. Of course.
Hello? Yup, he's here.
Oh, it's you. Hi.
Things? Sure. Personal.
Toothbrush, razor,
that kind of stuff. Pajamas.
Sure, there was a wallet.
Nothing interesting.
Look, I'm telling you,
nothing interesting.
Ok, I'll send it over.
New lady friend, huh?
The prosecutor, idiot.
Supervising the investigation.
Prosecutor? Which one?
- Not that sperm whale gaiewska?
- She's new. You don't know her.
New? Pretty?
Depends en your taste.
A new prosecutor and you're going
"oh, it's you"?
Keep your fucking nose out of it.
Curiosity killed the cat.
Whadd'ya want?
We're investigators, right?
She's a friend.
We studied law together.
Jablonski?
Sling Telak's wallet in an envelope...
And take it over
tn the d_a_ 's office.
- Prosecutor... Szacka, it seems...
- Tell him to call me.
And wolniak wants to talk to you,
so call him.
He's fallen in love, I reckon!
Look. Where's the city police?
They'll be copulating here in
broad daylight before long.
Do they have
any interests at all?
Dope, fucking and computer games.
How's this country supposed
to develop?
Who's going to pay our pensions?
You're not intending to live
on a pension, mr chairman?
Me, nu.
Unfortunately, I have to work.
But all those people
in Poland who fucking
sweated for decades
for a few cents,
they're going to be kept
by that lot?
What a generation.
They did a survey recently
in primary schools.
Fihy-five percent of them
didn't know...
What the warsaw uprising was.
Can you imagine that?
No. But young people have
always been like that.
They don't read books.
They watch the school reading
list on DVD. On fast forward.
In 2009,67% of poles hadn't read
so much as one book a year.
When I was in high school,
you fucking discussed books
during breaks.
Kafka, salinger, gombrowicz
and James Joyce.
“Ulysses“_a sensation
when they published it here.
Sold like hot cakes.
And is this the price we have
to pay for democracy?
The complete dumbing down
of the nation.
Well? Does it look as if the
henryk matter will be all right?
It looks like it'll be all right.
The prosecutor's drawing up
the investigation schedule...
And then we'll know more.
- When will we get it?
- This evening.
Yes?
Listen, I've remembered...
Hat he had some lottery tickets
in his wallet.
Could you check and see,
in case he won something?
The widow would find it handy.
Couldn't this have waited
till the morning, lieutenant?
I have no means of checking
at this precise moment.
Good night.
Come and loin us. Dorota says
she's not angry with you.
So what's her problem and
how come it's with me?
Seems you left her in a club.
Alone. In the middle nf the night.
What the fuck? Alone in a club,
when there were at least
a hundred of her friends there?
Come and tell her yourself.
I'm going home.
I'm not in the mood.
I'm sorry I phoned during
the night,
but I'd had a couple of drinks and...
No problem.
I can't talk now. Yes?
- The police just sent this over.
- Thank you.
Seven, eight, nine, seventeen,
twelve, twenty-two.
I checked. He didn't win anything
with the numbers he picked.
You're asking me what's going on?
You had the idea
that if he'd won the lottery,
his wife would gain by his death.
I just told you,
he didn't win a thing.
Was it you,
who told us to check whether...
The deceased stabbed himseli
in the eye?
Yes. We have to be certain.
No bruising, cuts, stab wounds,
signs of struggle...
Or bullet wounds
ascertained on the limbs ortorso.
The left eye is missing,
multiple fractures
tn the left orbital bone.
Perhaps you'd like us to chop
oh' his member,
put it in formaline and leave it
on your desk for you, ma'am?
I imagine you're aware
that the law contains a clause...
Regarding the profanation
of remains.
I'll be waiting for the
full autopsy details.
How do you all get to be
such boring pen-pushers?
You gut a special school
fur that?
Your client vomited before
his death.
- Get toxicology tests done.
- Sure.
Even though the cause
of death seems obvious.
Lesion to the brain brought about
by a sharp instrument.
It was a fairly strong blow,
though not
sufficient tn Pierce the skull.
Could a woman
have delivered the blow?
Easily. The orbital bone is thin,
doesn't take much force
to Pierce it.
And could he have done
it himself?
It'd be the first time someone
killed himself...
Like that as far as I know.
But I can't rule it out
one hundred percent.
You read the interview records?
- Zilch_ nothing to go oh.
- And have you been to his ohices?
An inspector went. Conducted
routine questioning. Another zero.
He vomited before he died.
He was on medication.
Trankiloxil_ sedatives_.
There were two sets
of prints on the bottle.
Telak's and Barbara Jarczyk's_.
Excuse me.
- Hi, what's up?
- Can you pick Agnieszka up?
I'm caught up in something
at the lab.
But I tuck the car in fur service.
Hey, are you on the old square?
I can hear the bugle_.
Just passing by. Ok, listen,
I'll pick her up. I can't talk now.
I have to pick my daughter
up from school.
- I'll run you there.
- If I go now, I can still make it.
It's no problem.
I've called Jarczyk
back for further questioning.
Her fingerprints en that bottle
need explaining.
And we have to interview
Telak's wife and the son.
Have a look at the video
of the therapy.
You believe that stuff?
Give me a break...
The hellinger method was
banned in Germany...
- Alter a girl in leipzig killed herself.
- It could be the same here,
if it turns out that Telak stabbed
himself in the eye with that skewer.
Remember when kashpirovsky
was doing...
His psychic healing thing
on television?
This grandma in poznan...
Was watching the program.
She was alone in the apartment,
five locks on the door,
all locked, windows tight shut.
The program finished and...
It turns out her gold watch
was gone.
Hi!
That's not daddy.
I'm slawek_ your Mom's driver.
Daddy said he couldn't make it.
I had tn come from the office...
But daddy promised we'd gn
fur cream puffs after school.
No problem.
We'll go for cream puh's_.
Well, ok then, I guess.
Thanks.
You didn't have to do that.
You've got a great daughter.
Thanks.
For your mercy is boundless.
Give us always to remember
that our life is but short..
And the hour of our death
hidden from us.
May the holy spirit
guide us through this world...
In sanctity and righteousness,
that we may serve you
in the community of your church,
steadfast in faith,
and with the full solace of hope...
That we may come at last in joy
tn your kingdom.
Through Jesus Christ our lord,
amen.
Let's get out of here.
Wolniak's taking photos.
Maybe we could head out
of town for a while?
It's Saturday.
I know this great new bar
out in lanckoroni_.
For Saturday downtime, I have a family.
And friends, if need be.
We'll stick tn a working
relationship.
Please accept
my sincere condolences.
You have no respect for the dead.
Have some self-respect,
at least.
- Take it easy. I'm police.
- Such are the police today.
- Gimme the card.
- Back off...
Gimme the card.
My husband was depressed.
I knew he was in treatment,
but he never shared
the details with me.
I never met dr rudzki or any
of the patients, either.
Why did your daughter
commit suicide?
Do I have to talk about that?
This interview concerns
a homicide.
Why does a fiiieen-year-old decide
to swallow a bottle of pills?
Even God wouldn't be able
to answerthat question.
We thought it was a heart attack.
But we found a letter.
"Lvly Darling parents, don't be upset
I love you all,
and you, daddy, most of all."
'You, daddy'
was in capital letters.
How did your husband take it?
He as good as died.
Ended up in hospital.
Did he feel guilty?
I know I'm being questioned
in a homicide case,
but could you possibly curb
the number...
Of foolish questions, lieutenant?
Of course he felt guilty.
I felt guilty, too.
I feel guilty all the time.
Did you blame your husband
for your daughter's death?
- I don't understand the question.
- It's a simple one.
In her letter, she wrote that
she especially loved her father.
Maybe their relations
were closer?
What the fuck are you insinuating,
lieutenant?
What have you concocted in that...
Fucking twisted policeman's
head of yours?
Answer the question, please.
She loved her father more than
anyone else in the family.
When she killed herself,
the greater part of henryk died.
The murderer didn't so much kill
him as deliverthe final blow.
Good morning.
I'm sorry, but we're not taking
new orders at the moment.
I'm a prosecutor.
I'm investigating mr Telak's case.
Yeah, right.
It's landed on my plate
and I only started here six months ago.
The police have already been.
I told them I don't know who could
have killed lvlrtelak_.
- He was such a quiet man.
- And yet...
I'd like to see your recent orders.
Did he leave any private notes?
No, no.
Mr Telak never made notes.
- He recorded everything en his mp3.
- Ah. And where is it, this ivip3?
Not here.
He always kept it with him.
What did it look like?
Kind of small and black,
with a silver control disk.
Thank you very much.
The police already searched here.
They took all
the gentleman's things.
- He had a recorder.
- Say what?
Like a tiny tape recorder.
There wereh't no tape recorder here.
I'd have noticed.
The police would've found it.
Sure, but he must have had
it with him.
Maybe it's in a diiferent room?
Like, I don't know what
a tape recorder looks like?
The cleaner found a hearing aid...
When she was cleaning
under the bed,
but that had to be the previous
occupant's_.
Where is it?
Actually, I was meant to phone
the gentleman from the police,
only I mislaid___
- the phone number.
- Excuse me.
May 23rd_
p00/grafex meeting with...
Printers' inks wholesaler;
Poffarb_
Saturday June 4th,
time: 11 pm.
I have to check.
Am I dreaming this?
Daddy. Daddy.
Is that you, princess?
Daddy.
What's that? More of the therapy?
Whose voice is that?
No. It was recorded at night,
in his room.
Listen to the final recording.
Sunday, June 5th,
time: Five after midnight.
To my wife, jadwiga.
I apologize for talking to you
like this
/t'd be easier to write a letter
I've nothing left to /ive for.
You don? Love me.
Maybe even hate me.
I found out today...
That I'm to blame for kasia's death
and bartek's illness.
Don't worry about money.
Igor runs a trust fund for me.
You're authorized to use
the account.
They've also got my policy.
We have a kind of mutual
insurance society.
The money'// he/p
with bartek's operation...
If the chance comes up
for a transplant abroad.
Bye, Darling.
I always loved you more
than you thought.
I don't believe it was suicide.
Can you picture it?
A guy records a letter of farewell,
then swallows some tablets,
but gives up on the idea a moment
later and vomits his guts up.
Gets dressed, packs, leaves.
But then changes his mind again,
and sticks a skewer in his eye.
Have forensics run a phonoscopic
analysis.
We need to know who was pretending
to be his daughter.
And I'll find out who Igor is.
- And the investigation's version?
- As I predicted, boss.
Henryk was murdered
by one of the patients...
Under the influence of emotions
related to the therapy.
People kill because they're drunk,
or for money, or under orders,
or out of political necessity.
And the prosecutor?
Routine blah, blah, blah.
I wouldn't worry about it.
- Why?
They're questioning the family,
the patients, his customers.
I don't think that poses
any dangerto us.
We'll keep ourfinger
on the pulse.
All right. You can go.
Do you know what a
phonoscopic analysis is?
Kind of like fingerprints?
Right? Something with the voice?
Telak had a habit of
recording everything.
He recorded something crucial
to the investigation.
I wouldn't want to hear it.
It seemed to him that
he was hallucinating_.
He recorded it.
A conversation between Telak
and his dead daughter.
We sent the material for analysis.
The results are unequivocal.
The person who stood
outside Telak's door...
Pretending to be his daughter
was you.
Is this some kind of a joke?
No. It's impossible.
I don't believe it.
This isn't a matter
of what you believe.
You stand outside Telak's door
pretending to be his daughter,
pleading with him to come to you.
Telak's driven to such despair
that he records a suicide leiler___
and then swallows
a boitleful of sedatives.
The facts suggest...
That since you failed to induce
him to commit suicide,
you decided to kill him yourself.
If you do nothing to clear this up,
you'll be leaving here to be
detained.
This is some kind of bad dream.
It can't be true,
no, it lust can't be.
Daddy. Daddy.
Is that you, princess?
/miss you, daddy.
/miss you too, princess.
I have to go now.
Well?
I'm listening.
It's my voice...
But they're not my words.
I just remember that...
That evening...
I brushed my teeth with my finger...
Because I'd forgotten
my toothbrush.
And then I went to bed.
I mean, I'm not a somnambulist
I don't walk in my sleep.
I don't know
how to explain this.
This is an arrest warrant
I shan't sign it yet.
But you are the chief suspect.
Please don't leave the city
and don't talk to anyone.
The slightest shadow of suspicion...
That you're hampering
the investigation...
And you'll be detained
that very same day.
Yes. I understand.
I won't hamper anything.
I'm as anxious as anyone fur this
tn be cleared up.
You can go now.
Give her a guardian angel.
Just a moment.
You can go in.
The prosecutor's waiting.
They won't let you out
without this.
Sit down, please.
I have two questions.
Do you use sedatives?
I don't understand.
Yes, I use them.
But doesn't everyone over the age
of fihy these days?
Often?
Rarely, now.
I took some yesterday, though.
But there was a time when I had
to take a pill every night.
Which is one of the reasons
I ended up with dr rudzki_.
- What do you take?
- Trankiloxil_
it's a French medication.
- Do you know why I'm asking?
- No.
An empty trankilnxil bottle
was found in mr Telak's Mum.
The pathologist has ascertained
that mr telak___
took a large dose shortly
before his death.
Yourfingerprints are on that bottle.
Dear God.
Now I remember.
But surely you don't think
thatl could have...
Well, I have to confess that
such a thought did enter my head.
Dear God,
how can one take it all in?
The therapy, that corpse,
the police and everything,
this interview...
What was it you forgot
to tell us?
On Saturday, after supper,
I ran into lvlrtelak in the corridor.
He said he was very tense
and asked if...
I had anything
that would help him sleep.
So, well,
- I gave him that bottle.
- How many pills were there?
- Over half. There are thirty to a bottle.
- And you weren't afraid that,
in the state he was in,
he'd take the lot?
It would never have entered
my head.
“So I thought that perhaps
someone had done him a kindness.
Well, because
there couldn't be any world...
"Where he'd be worse 011
than he was here."
Those are your words.
Tell me,
"did you give mr Telak
more tablets than he needed-"
in order tn transport him
tn a better world?
- What you're saying is despicable.
- Really?
In any case, why did you
conceal the maher of the tablets...
When you were being
questioned before?
It would have stuck
in my memory...
- Are you through?
- Yes, in point of fact.
You are the chief suspect.
I shan't arrest you today,
but please don't leave the city
and don't talk to anyone.
The slightest shadow of suspicion...
That you're hampering
the investigation...
And I'll lock you
up without hesitating.
I understand and I won't
hamperthe investigation.
Well,
we've put the cat
among the pigeons.
Now for some discreet
surveillance.
And bug their mobiles.
It's done.
What're you thinking about?
About you.
- Something's happened?
- No.
So? What, specifically?
That it'd be good
if you won the lottery.
I'd have to play it.
Come up with a system,
invest some money.
My deceased... he played.
He had the coupons in his wallet.
The same numbers every week.
- And he didn't win.
- No.
That's how people bet.
The date of their wedding
ortheir kid's birthday.
Utterly moronic.
Why would a machine pick out
the exact date of someone's wedding.
7,8,9,17,19.
It can't be a birthday...
- Goto sleep.
- Adds up to 82.8 and 2 is 10.
1 plus zero is 1.
It's meaningless...
Hello?
Hi, Agata.
I'm sure those numbers
stand for a date. I can sense it!
I checked all the dates on file...
And only one matches up
with some of the numbers.
The date on his daughters
suicide leiler_.
Only, I don't know, could a guy
be crazy enough to choose...
The date of his own child's suicide
as lucky numbers for the lottery?
I never ran an investigation
with a woman before.
I'll have to get used to it.
It opens up a whole
new bunch of possibilities.