The throat, Señora.
Oh, your voice.
It's like a bell tonight.
Thank you, Dottore.
Then don't wash it all away.
The wig. Quick. Yes, hurry.
Have you fixed it?
In the first act it looked
like a bird's nest.
Excuse me Madame Della Robbia.
Good evening, good evening.
Good evening, Farnham.
What a house we got out there tonight.
They come see my Tosca.
The most beautiful Tosca in the world.
Hey, that good-looking American
is out front again tonight.
Who is that?
You know. The fellow that sits in the
right-hand box every time you sing.
Don't tell me you hadn't noticed him.
Goodnight, Madame Della Robbia.
I do not care about some
silly stage-door Jackie.
Johnny.
Whatever you want to call
him. I'm not interested.
Is he good-looking?
Fond of opera, aren't you?
- Huh?
Especially if Miss
Della Robbia sings it.
What do you mean?
You come to hear her often, don't you?
- Every time she sings.
Why you silly boy.
Don't you like her?
Oh, of course she's handsome.
But I've certainly heard better voices.
I haven't.
Gerald, don't do that.
You look so conspicuous.
Shut up, Flora.
- What?
Shut up Flora. This is her big scene.
What's it about?
Look.
This man, has tortured Tosca's
lover and put him in prison.
Now, he's agreed to let him
go if she'll yield to his ..
Unholy demands.
Oh.
Madame.
Help him someone. Dottore!
Get my Doctor.
- Dottore!
Open the mouth.
No, no, no.
Bring the stretcher.
Uno momenta Señora, uno momenta.
Dottore, you take him.
- Uno momento Señora, uno momento.
Will nobody get me a stretcher?
I've come for the gentleman who's
hurt, Mr Fitzgerald. You know ..
Gerald.
Would the hospital be better perhaps?
- No, no. The villa.
We must nurse him with our own hands.
Gerald .. speak to me.
- He is unconscious.
We must get him to the hotel.
- But you are his wife?
No.
He's a friend, then?
- Yes.
No .. not what you mean. Not at all.
Good.
I will take him to my villa.
You will do nothing of the kind.
Madame, why do you keep interfering?
What exactly is it with you?
He's an old friend of my husband.
- Where then is your husband?
My husband is dead but
I've known him all my life.
Madame, you do not make
sense. Please go away.
Please Madame, you must go away.
You leave me alone.
- You take care of her.
Uno momento. He's coming round.
My wonderful rescuer.
Are you alright?
I am yes .. but you .. are you alright?
Yes. Sure .. I ..
Oh, my head.
- Your poor head.
Gently .. gently.
I know Madame Della Robbia
is here. But who is with her?
We are not permitted to give out any
such information about our guests.
Look here.
I'm her brother.
- Indeed?
You don't believe me?
The family resemblance is not marked.
Wait.
Besides which, the Señora
looks more like an American.
I'm her half-brother.
We have different mothers.
Mine lived in Indianapolis.
Now will you please let me ..
Hello? You want to talk to her
on her room-phone perhaps?
Thank you very much.
Hello? Well, hello Bice.
This is Mr Johnny.
I'm coming right up.
Don't say anything to my sister.
Boy.
Take this gentleman up to room 68.
I am sorry, sir. I did not know
Madame came from Indianapolis.
My father travelled a good deal.
Señor Johnny.
- Hello, Bice.
And Señor Giovanni.
Hello.
Where's my sister?
- On the balcony.
I thought so.
Johnny.
Lisa .. just exactly what is
going on around here?
This is my little American brother.
- Oh, I've heard about you.
I've heard about you, too.
The moment I got off the boat.
It's a public scandal.
You took him to live at your villa?
- Yes, Johnny dear.
Is that all you have to say?
Carrying on like this at your age.
- At my age?
You're twenty-five years old.
You ought to know better.
Wait a minute, son.
As for you? You're an American.
You know better too.
Let Lisa withdraw and we'll
settle this man-to-man.
How ..
How old are you, Johnny?
That's irrelevant.
Señora .. Farnham is at
the door. What can I do?
Your manager?
He'll be angry. He'll be furious.
He'll talk about my contract.
That's alright, sweetheart.
Hello, Farnham.
Oh, it's true.
- Yes, I love him.
It is not your business, Farnham.
I have my own life.
Now, now, Señora. Relax.
I'm glad you've come.
- Oh, are you?
Yes sir. You've got to save my sister.
- Save your ..?
This is Johnny? Sit down.
Sit down, Johnny. Sit down.
As a matter of fact, I'm in favor of a
little romance now and again. It's ..
It helps you sing.
Never have I sung so well.
My whole heart is in my throat.
Oh, by the way, my name is Fitzgerald.
Howdy.
- How are you?
Hey, you two ought to
be a little more careful.
After all, there are other places than
the most prominent hotel in Venice.
I'll kick him out if I have to
do it with my own hands.
We are going to have trouble with him.
Yes, well.
Perhaps I'd better explain.
You see .. uh ..
Lisa and I are .. married.
Married?
- Yes, three days ago.
Is that true?
- My new bride.
Show me the marriage certificate.
Johnny, you nasty boy. How dare you.
Where is it?
Bice has it. Go and ask Bice.
You bet I will.
Married, eh?
Well, that is different.
Sit down.
- Thank you, Farnham.
Do you think you can take it?
- What do you mean?
I mean have you any idea what it is
like being married to an opera singer?
Sure. I think I'm the
luckiest man in the world.
You'll have to be.
Farnham. What a horrible thing to say.
It's not talking against you,
Madame. It's your job.
Well, I suppose I'd better catch some
more bookings for a month or so.
We want to make this last
through the honeymoon.
You'll do nothing of the kind.
It's going to be a swell honeymoon,
going from city to city as Lisa sings.
Alright, tag along.
After you've heard those opera songs six
times you'll wish you had taken vanilla.
That's a nice thing to say .. vanilla?
Never mind darling. You know
it isn't true. I don't like vanilla.
The pooch.
Have you uh .. have you met Toto?
Yes, why?
Nothing. I expect from now on you ..
You two will see a lot of each other.
- Farnham.
I'm sorry to have been a "gloom".
Next time I flutter in I'll
be scattering rosebuds.
You sure there is nothing I can do?
- Yes. You can take Johnny away.
Oh yes, and get him just a little bit
drunk. I think it will do him good.
I've had jobs I liked better.
Have a cigarette.
American.
Thanks.
Hey. Such a nice guy too.
Can you read Italian?
Is this thing legal?
Sure it's legal. Look at the seal.
You're coming with me, kid.
We're going to paint the town pink.
Why pink?
- Well ..
Pink is for little boys
and blue is for little girls.
Personally, I prefer little girls.
That Farnham. He spoils everything.
No he hasn't.
If you think it's true what he says ..
I will give you a divorce tomorrow.
I think he's crazy.
And I think you're beautiful ..
I wouldn't change places with
anybody in the whole world.
Oh, if my career should come
in the way of our love.
It couldn't.
- I'd give it up.
It never will.
It will turn to dust, in my hands.
I'd never let you.
You come first .. always.
Lisa .. whatever you like.
That's what I like.
Always.
Listen.
Come on, come on. Come on, Toto.
Happy?
Ecstatic.
Lisa, what was Mr Farnham
saying about a concert tour?
I don't know.
He's not allowed to talk business
with me during a performance.
Darling.
You won't let him persuade
you to put off our trip, will you?
Oh my sweet, didn't I promise?
You certainly did.
Tomorrow we sail for America. Your home.
And for one long year.
Well, for six months anyway.
I'll be just your wife.
Just my wife.
Darling, I had the hotel give us the
same rooms we had on our wedding night.
Oh you .. darling.
And I've ordered supper just for
us two on the same little balcony.
The same supper?
And the same wine.
The same moon.
I think we can do business. I hope so.
Cigar?
- Thank you.
Ah, Madame. Great news.
Hello Farnham, what are you doing here?
Madame, these gentlemen ..
- No, no business tonight.
But Madame, Mr Bjorgenson
and Mr Carlson have ..
Come all the way from
Copenhagen just to see you.
Not tonight.
They have Catharina under contract.
But you see Madame, she lost her voice.
She never had one.
I tell you. A Scandinavian tour. The
finest cities and the highest prices.
No, no, no.
What?
- May I come in?
Thank you.
Yes, I know you're tired and I
know you want to go to America.
But this is a chance you
may never have again.
Cities that never heard of you. You'll
have the whole Scandinavian peninsula ..
In the hollow of your hand.
The whole of Scandinavia?
Yes, Catharina there, is the favorite.
And now you can be, Madame.
No, no, no.
Well, at least there's no harm in
talking about it. Sit down gentlemen.
Thank you, Farnham.
Take a look at that list of engagements.
Where's the list, Carlson?
- Bjorgenson borrowed it.
Looks like a pretty good route.
I cannot.
There will be a Triumph waiting
for you in every city, Madame.
Madame, Denmark needs you.
And Sweden and Norway.
That makes 75,000 kroner.
And in Oslo Madame,
you will break their record.
I didn't know there was
so many cities up there.
Copenhagen, Oslo, Stockholm, Bergen.
And the Royal Family have asked for me?
The whole Royal Family will
be there for your Premier.
Yes, Madame. They have asked for you.
We stay only for Copenhagen.
Not for Oslo?
No.
Steward.
Check.
Let's see how many drinks the Señor had.
One for Copenhagen.
One for Oslo.
Stockholm, Bergen, and .. let me see.
You don't mind?
Oh no, dear. I'll need
you in a few moments.
Flora.
Gerald.
I thought you were in Paris.
- Surprise.
Come in. Come in.
Where's your wife?
We must get a table together
in the dining-room.
My wife .. couldn't sail .. just yet.
Really?
Yes.
Waiter.
What will you have to drink?
I've been drinking one for each
of the Scandinavian cities.
A Manhattan.
- Two.
Si Señor.
For Manhattan.
Ahh!
Impossible.
Bad news?
He wants ..
He wants to leave me.
Are you thoroughly convinced
of your incompatibility?
Well, he wouldn't be here
otherwise, would you darling?
Hardly.
Well, we won't have any difficulty
about getting a divorce.
That was the stock question of mine.
Sort-of last chance to reconsider.
No, no, I don't want to reconsider.
I'm glad it's over.
Too unwieldy.
It was a ..
Well, sort of a charming nightmare.
Say, have you any conception of what
my married life has been, Mr Massey?
Perpetually bustling across
the face of the earth.
Spending all your waking
hours in hotel lobbies.
Or in the babble of the
backstage at an opera house.
Never free, even in your own hotel
room, from the trillings and tootings ..
Of the Prima donna's friends and ..
Her musical entourage.
Press agents and admirers.
You ever had your picture taken sitting
on a truck with a dog and a parrot?
No.
Half the time, in the newspapers I was
referred to as "Mr Gerald Della Robbia".
Are you taking this down, Miss Stone?
Yes, sir.
Perhaps the bell is out of order.
It's open. We'll just walk in.
Do you think we'd better?
- Sure. Come on.
Highball?
No thanks dear, but you have one.
- Right.
Hmm, this is nice.
I'll make you happy, Gerald.
Oh, I know you will Flora.
We are ideally mated, we two.
We want the same things.
Permanence .. stability .. comfort.
Yes, and peace of mind.
You never had that with her, did you?
To Lisa, our marriage was a game she
played when she had nothing else to do.
To me, it wasn't a game.
It was solitaire.
Poor darling.
Well.
What on earth?
Does this sort of thing
go on all the time?
Look here, you impossible young ..
- You always kiss people, don't you.
You always pop up in places unexpectedly
and always jumping to wrong conclusions.
There's only one conclusion.
You and this woman.
- Gerald, explain to him immediately.
This is Mrs Preston, my future wife.
I thought my sister was your wife.
Yeah, well, I'm divorcing your sister.
What?
What are you doing here anyway?
And who is this young lady?
Miss Aline Chalmers.
How do you do.
- How do you do.
Don't speak to him.
She's my future wife.
Nice of you to drop in.
I brought her here to meet Lisa.
Here?
Aline's family think it's bad enough
that my sister is on the stage.
What will they say when they
find out she's being divorced?
I don't know. What will they say?
They won't care really.
That's just Johnny's idea.
You don't know life the way I do.
Where is Lisa?
The last I heard she was in London.
What made you suppose she'd be here?
Lisa sent me a wireless this morning.
She arrives on the Berengaria today.
Today?
Yes, I got in from Newhaven too
late to meet her at the dock.
I expected she'd be here by this
time. Instead, I find her here.
Really?
That will do Johnny. Show me the cable.
Tamamoto.
Well, this does sound
as if she's coming here.
You didn't know?
No, she hasn't found time to
answer my cablegrams.
Sir?
Madame is coming. Get things ready.
- Yes, sir.
You don't mind if we wait here for her?
- No. Sit down some place. Here.
I'll run along.
Yes, yes darling.
Well, I guess you'd better.
And Tamamoto, put some flowers around
the place. You know, plenty of flowers.
Oh yes, sir.
Well, I think I'd better move to the
club. Lisa will take this place over.
Perhaps I should send some flowers too?
There's an Italian florist downstairs.
He has such lovely, clever ideas.
Oh swell, sure. We might as well
keep the thing as friendly as possible.
Friendly?
Judas.
That's what he is. A cut-rate Judas.
Come on, come on.
- Hello, Bice.
Well, we did arrive quick. Ha.
Hello Archimedes.
Mama-mia, I have forgot the bird.
Was it always like this?
- Always.
Goodbye darling. Call me when
you get settled at the club.
Alright sweet. Bye-bye.
How was Monte Carlo?
We have a little trouble with
the Customs Inspector.
And Mr Farnham is our guru.
This is Bice .. Aline.
No, no, no. This stay here.
You open them on the floor. Quick.
No understand.
- Presto, presto.
Tamamoto, you have to
do what Bice tells you.
But of course, you can take
the pillows and the scarf.
I will arrange.
Where do the pictures go, Bice?
- On the table.
Madame, she likes to have
her friends all about her.
And her flowers.
Presto. I will arrange.
You come with me. Get the basket.
And clear all the things from the table.
Hey.
Go quick.
Bice, where do these go?
- In Madame's room.
All these smoking things
is bad for her voice.
Bice, have a heart.
There you go.
- Yes, there I go.
They came for Madame.
Holy Moses. Who's responsible for that?
Don't let her see that. She will scream.
It appears like a funeral.
- Perhaps it was made for one.
Flora Preston.
Who's that?
Oh, a friend, Bice.
Put it on the mantle.
On the?
- On the mantle.
Oh .. oh.
Ah .. a little dead bird in the middle.
That's bad luck.
Ah. .. I forgot.
Well, what's the matter with him?
Now what?
Wait a minute. What's going on here?
Where are my cook? Where are
my table-boys? I want to know.
Put down that knife.
- I am cook. My kitchen here.
You too. Put down that knife.
He come in my kitchen,
he push me around.
Shut up! Shut up! One at a time.
You see.
Without me .. Madame, she die.
She cannot eat the mess of
this foreign gentleman here.
And yet, he has the machine.
How can we cook together?
- I am cook in this place.
Don't come in kitchen.
But Madame, she cannot
eat you. She want me, me.
Look in heaven. Do I cook in my hat?
Yes. Well, Tamamoto, during the
stay of Madame Della Robbia ..
Her chef will do the cooking.
I do not like noise.
Yes, well. I'm terribly sorry Tamamoto.
But I guess we'll have
to put up with it.
No can do.
No!
Oh .. heaven bless our happy home.
Enter Madame.
Archimedes .. she come.
Johnny.
Lisa.
Gee Lisa, you look slick.
Doesn't she, Aline?
This is Aline.
You know. Aline Chalmers.
Ah .. first love.
Young love .. isn't it sweet.
Sweet child, I want to hear
the timbre of you voice.
I hardly know what to say.
A very light soprano.
Perhaps it will grow.
Gerald.
How are you, Lisa?
Are you surprised that I came?
Well, you might have let me know.
I might have done many things.
But the sound of my own voice
singing silly little tunes ..
It deafens me to the rush of life.
Passing by me like a sweet stream.
Of course, I forgot.
This is America.
Here, when the heart
speaks, the lips say ..
"Fine weather we are having."
I imagine that's just
what your life is like.
A swift wind.
They were only silly words.
It was charming of you to greet me.
I think we'll be going Lisa.
May I come again, please?
Of course. Goodbye.
Goodbye Lisa. I'll call you.
- Au revoir, mes enfants.
Bice.
Where are my servants, Bice?
For hours you leave me with
my hat and furs. Here, take it.
Hold it, boys. Hold it.
Farnham.
- Pardon me, boys.
Pardon me. Here are those
few trifles you left me with.
Thank you, Farnham.
Well boys, I guess ..
- Hello.
Oh hello, Mr Fitzgerald.
- Hello Farnham. How are you?
Merry and bright. Merry and bright.
And uh .. and you?
Oh uh, fine. Fine thanks.
Have a cigarette .. American.
Thanks .. I'm just out.
Now, if you'll show me where
to put these little knick-knacks.
Okay, follow me.
Ah Señora, please.
You must drink this at once.
I command it.
And then, completely you must
rest two or three hours. Si?
Ah Dottore, life demands
that I be strong.
With rest comes strength.
Yes, you must be tired, Lisa.
I'll run along.
Si si.
I hope the place is comfortable for you.
- Where are you going?
I'm staying over at the club.
Oh yes, yes.
Oh, my head.
But this tonic always helps you.
There is so much I have to do.
Later I am quiet. But now I
must speak with my husband.
Oh no, Lisa. There is
plenty of time for that.
Alright, Dottore. I take the medicine.
Subito.
- I take it.
I promise.
Faithfully.
Mama-mia, Gerald.
Did you bring that thing for my grave?
Well, no Lisa, Mrs Preston
of whom I wrote to you ..
Ah .. I see.
She sends a peace offering.
The little dove.
She's subtle, this lady.
Oh you will twist things your own way.
She did it to be kind, to welcome you.
That sort of thing.
Oh Gerald, it's wonderful
to have it here in the room.
So that's her view.
Oh, nothing of the sort.
She left it to the florist.
Probably.
I doubt it .. never mind.
I understand. I am a woman of the world.
We shall talk this over quietly.
Yeah, that's more like it.
Good luck. Mon ami. More, bon ami.
Shake hands en Anglais.
I am your friend, Lisa.
To me, you're still the most
fascinating woman in the world.
Oh, thank you.
That makes it easier for me
to tell you my little story.
The real reason for my coming.
What now?
Your letter arrived at the
most opportune moment.
I also have met someone.
Ha?
He's marvellous.
Not yet twenty but a great poet.
No money he have.
No jewels to bring to me.
Just his heart, and his
poems he lay at my feet.
When you write me about
the American lady ..
I say: "All is well.
Soon, I too can marry."
A poet?
- Uhuh.
Oh Lisa, I don't believe a word of it.
You don't believe it?
- No.
You then are the only one
who has "yearnings".
You are tired of romance.
You long for peace,
for quiet, for old slippers.
What am I to do with these
things? You leave me all alone.
I leave you alone?
I am Lisa Della Robbia.
I starve for romance, for poetry.
You come here to watch over
your business. Your business.
Very well. When I find these
romantic things, I take them.
Don't be such a fool, Lisa.
I Lisa Della Robbia is to be
cast aside like an old shoe?
To live alone. To die alone.
All of a sudden, a pressure for romance.
This melodrama about dying alone.
I begged you to settle down
and what did you answer me?
Can I help it if I love someone else?
I am Della Robbia. Love is
my master and my slave.
Oh stop it, Lisa. Stop acting!
You've been the baby-wonder of the opera
for a long time. Now you listen to me.
You've been petted and spoiled.
You've done as you pleased.
I always catered to your whims, but I'll
not see you making a fool of yourself.
Oh.
A poet .. a new plaything.
You're a conceited child and it's time
you grew up. You're old enough.
Am I then so very old, Gerald?
Too old for you to love.
And to love you?
No, Lisa, I do love you.
And I'm grateful to you.
Why you've been exquisite,
magnificent, ideal.
To play with.
Gerald.
Have you the faintest idea
what it means to be a wife?
Gerald!
I mean it, from the bottom of my heart.
I'll never forgive you for saying
that the longest day I live.
Very well then .. divorce!
Divorce. You shall have it.
I wish I had it here now, that I might
throw it in your sneering face!
Thank you.
Ahh!
This broth will give
you strength, Madame.
This will make you sleep.
Look Madame. Look what I get for you.
Isn't it beautiful.
No!
Now, now Madame, if you'll
only let me talk business ..
No.
Would you?
Get me my kneeling pad.
What you need is to get
your mind off these things.
New surroundings, hard work.
Now, I've got a South
American tour up my sleeve.
Oh, Madame.
- No.
And before we sail.
I think I can arrange for one guest
performance here at the opera.
Oh bellissimo.
How would you like it?
No.
I will never sing again.
Well, of course.
If you're going to let
this thing lick you.
Who said I would?
Why regret? Just because
another dame steals your husband.
She hasn't stolen him yet.
And she won't.
Wait and see.
What are you going to do now?
This is war. And I have not quit.
I have only begun to fight.
Okay, Gerald.
First thing, we move.
- Move?
Not one night will I
spend under his roof.
But Madame ..
- My things. Pack them.
Quick. To work everyone. Quick.
Archimedes.
- Si, Señora.
Pack everything.
Leave nothing that is mine.
But Señora ..
The preliminary decree.
Then she is divorced?
The decree becomes
absolute in six months.
Then .. she is not divorced?
Just a formality.
Then she is divorced.
Certainly, they're divorced.
Only it isn't .. quite right.
Who will tell her?
Not me.
Ah .. I have it .. you tell her.
Now let's see.
Spirit of ammonia.
And perhaps I will even go so far
as a mild injection of morphine.
Very mild.
I will cook her risotto.
That will be better.
I will cook her.
Oh, you all.
You don't know her as I know.
Every night she cries herself
to sleep, on my breast.
"Bice", she say.
"When I leave this house,
I think you follow me."
Every night she say:
"Perhaps he comes tomorrow."
And I said: "but Madame, why don't
you speak to him when he calls?"
And she said:
"Well, perhaps he comes anyway."
"Perhaps he break in the door."
Break in the door?
She would not open the door
to him. After what he do.
But she wanted him to
break it in, and say:
"Lisa, you are like the sun in my life."
"I cannot live in this great darkness."
But he never comes.
Now it is too late.
Now she comes.
Oh, it's alright. The sun
is shining this morning.
Once again, positive?
Good morning.
- Good morning, Señora.
All is well with my little family?
All is fine ..
- Alright, Madame.
What is wrong with all of you?
No matter what has happened,
never look like that. Never.
Come out. Out with it.
Well ..
Madame, the preliminary
decree has been granted.
He did not break in the door.
My dears .. my friends.
I'm so worried about me.
How lucky I am to be so blessed.
Thank you.
There .. there, that's enough.
All is not over, no.
Archimedes, open a bottle of wine.
Drink my health.
- Si Señora.
I will be alone with Farnham.
- Si, Señora.
Well.
You are an amazing woman, Madame.
You never do what is expected of you.
No one ever does what is expected
of them. It is such a puzzle.
They say there are great, pitch-black
spaces between the stars.
I think they are between people too.
Like pitch.
Pitch-black.
Pitch .. very pitch.
I must dress.
Go and make a speech to them,
Farnham. Make them laugh.
Make them laugh.
She cries. What we do?
There is one thing you can
do, but you won't do it.
What's that?
- Pretend you don't hear it.
Oh Giovanni.
Johnny, Johnny, she
cries out her heartache.
What's the matter?
Preliminary decree blues.
Oh ..
Don't let it worry you, Sis'.
You oughtn't to come
when I look like this.
That's what brothers are for.
If only I could have seen
him once more. Just once.
I guess Mrs Preston fixed that?
- Yes.
It is full of cold, ugly words.
What does that mean?
When the decree is final?
Well, you see, you're
not quite divorced yet.
No?
No. The law requires both
parties to wait six months.
Just in case you change your mind.
Well, Gerald will not change his mind.
You love him a lot, don't you Sis'?
How else can I sing of love?
Probably doesn't do Gerald much good
if you sing to him and he's not there.
I don't know, I don't know.
I only know that I am unhappy.
What am I to do?
What can I do?
I've thought of many ways to win him
back but Gerald is not like other men.
He pricks my little bubbles.
He says: "Come on Lisa,
come on. Don't act."
What am I to do?
Here ..
Blow your nose.
What is it?
Your husband's lawyer is on the phone.
Gerald is there.
They wonder if you can come down for
some sort of a financial conference.
I guess I can cancel if you want me to.
Gerald is there?
- That is what they said.
Bice. .. Bicenza.
Bicenza, quick.
I'll tell them you're coming.
Si Señora?
Mr Fitzgerald is upset over your refusal
to accept any financial settlement.
Oh really?
So I asked you to meet him here.
Thank you.
You didn't answer my phone calls.
Well, I'll leave you to
discuss things alone.
Isn't Flora here?
Why should she be here?
She is your future wife. She should be
interested in your financial affairs.
Really, it's no business of Flora's.
- Oh but Gerald, it is.
Every wife should be interested in what
her husband does with his money.
I know I wasn't .. but I was a failure.
Now look Lisa, why do you
always make things so difficult?
I've always helped you out with
your bills. I want to keep doing it.
I like to do it. Heaven knows, you
could never manage them alone.
No. I will not listen to a word of this.
Not here.
- Where then?
And not without Flora.
- Now look, Lisa.
I know.
You bring Flora to
supper tomorrow night.
At first, you come to hear
me sing. For the last time.
After, I send you a note.
- I don't know whether Flora would ..
Flora? Flora is a modern woman.
Of course she will come, rather than
let you come by yourself. You ask her.
Well.
Alright then. Tomorrow night.
Goodbye.
I wish I'd read the libretto.
What is she singing?
She's praying.
For her husband to come back?
Oh, I mean in the acting.
Look here, Flora.
It is alright to go to Lisa's
for supper tonight, isn't it?
I wouldn't miss it for the world.
No. I mean, there won't
be any unpleasantness?
Not on my part.
Naturally, I asked you.
You belong to the family now.
I do not know yet just what relation
we are to be to one another.
But something, surely.
My English is so shaky.
"Wives-in-law", is it not?
I couldn't say.
What an idea.
At any rate, we should not be strangers.
We have so much in common now.
Oh, my doctor.
- Señora.
My Bice .. my Archimedes.
Of course, you are
acquainted with the children.
Yes, today it all happened.
Good evening.
- Hello dear.
She's so sweet.
May I congratulate you on
your success this evening.
Or would it only bore you?
You've had so many.
One is rarely bored with the success
for which one has worked and planned.
Don't you find that is
true, Mrs Preston?
Well, aren't you going to
say hello to me, Lisa?
Standing there so big and solemn ..
I quite forgot that you're no longer
part of the furniture of my life.
Good evening, Gerald.
I am glad you are here.
You're looking radiant.
- Thank you Gerald.
Bice. Bicenza. Bicenza.
Si Señora?
Call the Dottore.
Call Archimedes. Quick.
Tell them to move the table
right in there. But quickly.
Si Señora .. Archimedes.
Why are they doing that?
It's easier than moving
the piano in there.
They never do anything very
far away from the piano.
How amazing.
They're really a lot of fun.
Well, here we are.
Ah, just look at those truffles Flora.
Those truffles have come
from my farm in Tuscany.
Rigoletto and I hunted
for them last June.
He with his nose, and I with my stick.
To hit him on the head
when he find the truffle.
He love a truffle, that Rigoletto.
Archimedes, who is Rigoletto? Your son?
No. My pig Madame.
A great hunter of truffles is Rigoletto.
What a strange name for a pig.
Why not Madame?
He enjoys it poor fellow.
It gives him some style
before the other pigs.
My cow, I name Aida.
My ox, Don Giovanni.
Oh, they are all very pleased.
Yes, Archimedes is going to retire to
his farm when he gets old, and ..
The doctor here, to a
little practice in Cannes.
Oh yes.
Two years ago, I tried to leave Madame.
I had the rheumatism and
a little homesickness.
So my sister, she say: "why you run all
around the whole world with rheumatism?"
"Stay here, and I cook for you."
So I tried to stay.
Why didn't you?
- Well.
I tell you.
An opera company come to Cannes
and they give La Forte Del Simio.
I go .. the Soprano,
she sings like a cow.
I think she might never ..
[ Italian language ]
And I run out.
Tell me doctor, where did
you run? Back to Madame?
Yes .. and here I am.
The music is in the blood,
worse than the rheumatism.
It makes me suffer more.
And the memories.
Grab my heart a hundred times a day.
And pictures of the past come
up quickly to my mind at night.
And I am alone.
Ah, it is a great life of pictures
we live with Madame.
Imagine.
All about the laundry?
Oh of course, she does not
compare with Madame.
She's a very good dramatic.
[ Italian language ]
As a matter of fact, I've
heard there are lots of things.
Hear Señor Geraldo.
He say so too and he is a connoisseur.
In the Aria with the tenor.
Oh, what a beauty.
Ah poo!
I will play it for you.
- I'll get my flute.
Yes, Archimedes, get your flute.
What I say?
So sentimental and sickly it
makes your stocking's fall down.
Bice.
Oh, Mama-mia.
Oh .. Bice. Pass the salad.
Have some salad, Flora?
- No thanks. Not anymore.
Well, Señor Geraldo, this is
the last of our suppers together.
Your health, Doctor.
We have drink the health
together in many places.
Cairo, Milano, Vienna.
Yes, it was fun while it lasted.
Madame Della Robbia.
I hear you're to be married again.
What?
What's this, Lisa?
You never told me.
Now that Gerald has gone, I think you
ought to talk these things over with me.
Hey, look here.
Don't talk as though I were dead.
I don't know what you're talking about.
Sometimes, I get confused.
All the English words ..
[ Telephone ]
I'll answer it.
Hello?
Oh. Hello.
Are you tight?
Who is it?
It's Farnham.
Yeah.
Yes .. wait a minute.
He says an impresario from Buenos Aires
was in the audience tonight, and ..
He's crazy about you.
Yes?
Yeah.
Hold on.
He's willing to pay you twice your
salary if you open the season there.
I go. Of course I will go.
Trouble is, you'll have
to sail tomorrow.
Then we sail tomorrow.
You mean it, Lisa?
Of course I mean it.
Go ahead and close the deal.
Tomorrow?
A toast .. to life.
To life without chance
and love and death.
To life .. the winner of the race.
To my husband .. and his wife.
To my wonderful sister.
Bravo.
Ah, thank you, Bice.
Hey, let's get Archimedes and sing
the amber chorus for the last time.
Dear me .. I feel as if I were at a
funeral with all these last rites.
Archimedes.
You come and sing the soprano.
- Subito.
Ah, here she is. You should hear Bice.
Bice has a fine voice, haven't you?
The amber chorus then.
Pronto.
Bravo.
Pianissimo.
Stop, stop, stop.
We're uh .. without voice tonight.
I always suffer from catarrh
in this country of yours.
Now Madame, I hope you will excuse me.
It is getting late. And as we are to
leave tomorrow, there is much I must do.
Buenas noches.
- Buenas noches, Señora.
Goodnight, goodnight.
- Goodnight, Doctor.
We must all be going.
It's very late.
And Madame must be tired.
No.
If you must.
Your car is waiting I suppose Flora?
Yes, but I'm nervous travelling home at
night. You'll ride with me, won't you?
I still have business to discuss with
Lisa and if she's leaves tomorrow ..
I'm sure Madame can find
time for you in the morning.
Oh, Mrs Preston.
Johnny and I will ride home with you.
I go your way .. and we
have no car here and ..
May we?
Thanks. That would be charming.
You sweet, thoughtful child.
These pearls .. perhaps
they seem a little dull.
That is because I'm not always
happy. Pearls are like that.
On your throat, they
will soon shine again.
My present for your
engagement to Johnny.
Oh Lisa.
- Thank you.
There, there, there.
- Goodnight.
Oh, they're awfully young, Lisa.
Too soon to talk about engagement.
Perhaps they will grow together.
Like a tree with one strong stem.
They cannot be divided.
At least a tree can't pick up its roots
and sail on a steamer to South America.
Or the first place that
comes into its head.
Goodnight, Madame Della Robbia.
Such an unusual evening.
Quite extraordinary.
Really?
I suppose you have to be like this.
If you weren't, people wouldn't pay so
much money to see you on the stage.
To myself, I seem quite simple.
Perhaps it comes from throwing
yourself into every part you do.
You ..
Throw yourself out of joint, as it were.
And with him, not knowing
how to behave at all.
However, I am delighted to have met you.
I understand Gerald much better now.
And you have behaved most
becomingly on the whole.
Really, amazingly well.
Oh, thank you so much.
Don't let Gerald tire you.
Send him home soon.
Goodnight.
Here we are, Mrs Preston.
There you are, Flora. Goodnight.
Gerald, will you ..?
Down?
Goodnight.
- Goodnight.
Bice .. Bice.
Call Archimedes and tell
him to clear away later.
Or in the morning. Hmm?
Oh.
Well, perhaps I'm intruding Lisa.
Taking up your time?
Dear me, no.
I'm a girl of the night.
A nightingale.
You know Gerald, I have
not forgotten what you said.
That I was never a wife to you.
Oh yes.
I'd give anything to wipe out the
words I said to you that day, but ..
I don't know. I've always said
things to you I didn't mean.
The trouble is there is always
just enough truth in them.
No truth at all. It was just that ..
That young poet of yours set me off.
Silly, wasn't it?
- Yes.
By the way, what ever
became of him, Lisa?
There is no-one.
There never has been anyone.
[ Telephone ]
Shall I?
- No, no. I will do it.
Hello, hello?
Oh Flora.
Yes. He is still here.
You want him? At once,
you shall have him.
Yes, Flora?
You aren't home already?
No, I'm downstairs.
Call me when you get home, will you?
Say, a quarter of an hour?
Well, these things take time you know.
Well, get plenty of sleep.
Yes Flora. Goodnight. Goodnight.
I uh ..
I must go now Lisa.
Of course.
Thank you for coming.
Well.
I hardly know you in this mood.
No tricks, no sorry speeches, no poetry.
Ah, perhaps you are
glad to get rid of me.
Haven't you anything to say?
No.
Goodbye then.
Oh Lisa, I wish you had cared for me.
I wish you just hadn't been emotion
without any heart behind it.
How can you say such things to me?
I know I haven't the right to
say them, but .. they're true.
Emotion without any heart?
How do you think I learnt to sing
as I have never sung before?
Do you think I sang to the fat little
tenor, with food in his eyes?
I'm glad I was good for
your career, at least.
Oh.
I thought we both wanted
the world to be richer.
In music .. for our love.
If you had a better wish ..
Why didn't you make me listen?
Oh Lisa, I wish I had.
[ Telephone ]
Oh, stop that noise!
Hello.
Hello. May I speak with
Mr Fitzgerald please?
Hello. Hello. Where are you now?
I'm in a drug-store.
What?
I know you're not deaf, Flora.
I beg your pardon.
I know it ain't far but after all,
I'm alone with my own wife.
By jolly, I had forgotten.
Yes, yes, honest I am.
I think you had better call me
when you get back to the club.
I will, I will.
Well, I can't go until you
hang up the receiver, can I.
Oh rubbish. Goodnight.
Poor Flora.
Oh Lisa, I love you.
I'll always love you.
[ Telephone ]
Hello.
Yes. Good morning, operator. Did you ..?
What?
You called his club all night long,
and he hasn't been in yet?
Are you sure?
Hello.
Get me a taxi .. right away.
Good morning, good morning.
Buongiorno, Geraldo.
Very happy to see you again.
Thank you, Bice.
Good morning, Archimedes.
Very happy. Very happy.
Buongiorno, Bice.
- Buongiorno, Señora.
My dear, have you gone musical?
Why not, darling. You look lovely enough
to drag the heart out of a catfish.
Good morning, Toto. Come, come, come.
Well Bice, how would you like
settling down in America, huh?
What is?
- Yes, Bice. No more opera.
From today, we raise chickens,
the most beautiful chickens.
Yes, you remember Bice? I showed you
pictures of my house in the country.
We don't go to South America?
Of course not.
Certainly not. Never heard of the place.
I love.
Oh you darling, you darling. Promise
me that you'll never leave me again.
Promise me that or you
won't get any breakfast.
Henceforward, I will be like
a shadow cast by the sun.
Now to the East, now to the West.
But always close beside you.
Eat your grapefruit.
Of course, I won't mind if you sing
a performance now and again ..
At the metropolitan.
Oh, you darling.
And at Covent Garden.
Just once in a while.
Well, alright.
Just once in a great while.
Oh Toto!
Toto darling.
Toto will finally bark.
Yes, but ..
Is there something else, my Gerald?
Just .. Toto.
Oh .. never again will I ask
you to take care of Toto.
I swear.
Will you forgive your mother, darling?
What are you trying to do?
- Madame is not up yet.
It doesn't matter. That will do.
- But you cannot come in.
I'd like to know who's
going to keep me out.
Good .. good morning, Flora.
I simply wanted to make sure.
You didn't answer the
telephone last night.
Oh, I answered it three or four times.
You know what I mean perfectly well.
I called you for hours.
Finally, the operator said
the receiver was off.
It must have fallen off.
- Do you take me for a fool?
If you think ..
If you think I'll let myself
be humiliated like this ..
For a common opera singer.
Oh.
Now, Mrs Preston.
Don't imagine you've broken my heart.
I happen to be rather hard up.
And I need a solvent husband.
What do you suppose this woman wants
of you? Except to pay her debts?
And cover up her affairs with
Dukes and Princes and whatnot.
Will you please confine
your remarks to me.
I'll confine them to my lawyer.
You. .. you libertine!
You'll make a good settlement,
or I'll know the reason why.
Good day to you both.
What a woman.
How dare she?
How dare she come into
my own house and talk so.
It isn't as if she is the wife. I should
have said to her "are you the wife?".
Darling, darling .. you forget.
We are practically divorced, you and I.
Oh yes. And whose fault is it? Hers.
Oh, I should have said to her ..
- Hey, wait a minute.
It's alright. I'll pay her off.
We don't want any more trouble.
Opera singers are just like
actors, only more so.
Oh, I beg your pardon
but isn't this Mrs Preston?
Yes.
- Fine.
We're just going to interview
Madame Della Robbia.
You have called on her,
haven't you, Mrs Preston?
Will you excuse me please.
Just a minute.
When is the wedding going to be?
There isn't going to be any wedding.
Oh.
How do you do Mrs Preston.
Do you know where Gerald is?
Nothing could interest me less.
Well, what do you make of that?
Hey, I smell a mouse.
You go phone our city desk, Trixie.
Joe and I are going upstairs.
Lisa.
Hey, hey. Get rid of him.
Get rid of him.
He mustn't see me in these clothes.
Johnny and Aline.
- Hello, Lisa.
Hello.
Having breakfast? Gerald here already?
Oh .. no ..
Yes. He's not here.
What?
I thought I might help
you pack or something.
Say, we saw Mrs Preston
downstairs, talking with some men.
Reporters, I think.
- Who?
Yes. One of them had a camera.
So.
May I go in your bedroom
to powder my nose?
Oh .. you mean .. in the ..
In the bedroom.
May I?
No, my dear. Wait. Wait my dear.
[ Telephone ]
You see?
I will answer. I had better answer.
Hello?
- What are you doing?
Why don't you answer?
They can't hear you Lisa.
The phone isn't plugged in.
Oh Bice, plug in the plug.
I always like to telephone down here.
I can hear better by the window.
Hello, yes it's me .. who you want?
No, I cannot receive at this hour.
Bice ..
Everybody is telephoning all the time.
The papers?
No.
Is this Madame Della Robbia's apartment?
Gerald.
Gerald, what are you doing here?
I can't get out. I mean I just came in.
Don't let them in. They're reporters.
How dare you pound on my door!
Gerald, what are you doing
here in your evening clothes?
I wear them all the time now.
They're more becoming.
Meaning what?
- Mind your own business.
No, don't answer it Lisa.
I had better go.
They phone all the time.
I plug in the plug.
- Never mind Bice. Don't answer it.
But why are they telephoning,
and why are they knocking?
And why are you in evening clothes
at this hour of the morning?
Well, I ..
Oh.
Oh!
Oh .. oh.
Oh? Keep still.
Keep still and let me think.
Oh, gracious.
Bice, Bice .. oh shut up.
Tell Archimedes to answer the door
and make those men go away.
Lisa, you had better
go in the dining room.
Oh.
You idiot! Stop saying "Oh"
and make yourself useful.
Oh!
Take care of Aline. Hide her somewhere.
Where?
- Anywhere. I don't care.
Oh, this is a nice piece of work.
Oh.
Shut up!
Hey what is this? Hey. Open up.
- Come on, open up.
Nobody is in this flat.
Vacant!
Hey, what is this, anyway?
Now, you get out of here.
To meet hat mob in these clothes?
- You have no business here.
She's my sister and I ..
- Johnny, they're married.
Oh, are they? What about
that interlocutory decree?
Oh yes. I have forgot. We both forgot.
Well, those reporters won't forget.
Yeah, that's right. Well, move over.
Help, help! Help.
Help!
What is it now?
The dumb-waiter.
- The dumb-waiter?
Someone hide in the dumb-waiter.
I hold. Come quick.
What is going on?
I see the top of his head.
I pull the rope. Down he go.
Come on Archimedes, we'll fix him.
He has come up again.
Get you down, or I pour.
Get you down.
Keep your shirt on, Bice.
It's me.
Señor Farnham.
And I almost poured.
Well, well.
- Farnham.
Is this that peace-and-quiet
you were talking about?
Oh, Flora turned the
whole press loose on us.
You're telling me. The lobby
is knee-deep with them.
Farnham .. go out.
Send them away.
So that you can go to that
potato-patch, or whatever it is?
Oh Farnham, as my friend ..
Please.
Nobody on earth can do that.
- Well, what can we do then?
How about running away?
- In that thing?
I can't recommend it.
We'll elope to South America.
Farnham, go outside and
stall the reporters. Get going.
Okay, Gerald.
Bice, you get a coat for Madame.
Hurry. Come on.
Archimedes, you get the doctor and take
our luggage to the boat. Now quickly.
You'll have to travel light for once.
Wait a minute.
Now if you boys will just be patient
for five about five minutes ..
I'll give you a real good story.
Quiet!
Five minutes.
Hey, we won't need that.
Move over, Lisa.
Now, down we go.
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
Don't forget Toto.
- 0h yes.
Here Gerald.
- What?
Goodbye.
Now see here, Lisa.
I'm letting you sing again, and I'm
even going to South America with you.
But there's one thing
I'll never do again.
Be nursemaid to that dog.
Gee-whizz.
Gerald. Never, you have
spoken to me like this before.
I like it.
Huh?
Exit, Madame.
-(s-d)-