Welcome to Disneyland, U.S.A.
This was all a Disney dream
a dozen years ago.
A far off project
that was totally unproved.
Today, 60 million people
have come here
from every state in America.
And from almost every nation
around the world.
In Town Square on Main Street,
many have paused to read
the dedication plaque
that symbolizes
the warm and friendly spirit
of Walt Disney's Magic Kingdom.
"To all who come to
this happy place, welcome.
"Disneyland is your land.
"Here, age relives
fond memories of the past.
"And here youth may savor
the challenge and promise
"of the future.
"Disneyland is dedicated
to the ideals, the dreams
"and the hard facts
that have created America.
"With the hope that it will be
a source ofjoy and inspiration
"to all the world."
Disneyland grew out of
Walt Disney's own feeling
that an amusement park
should offer more
to the entire family.
Here was no mere amusement park.
Here was a whole new concept
in entertainment,
where parents and children
could have fun, together.
The touchstone of Disneyland's success
has been its concern for people.
A wholehearted dedication
to the happiness of the people
who visit here.
Today, Disneyland has established
standards of performance unsurpassed
in all the world.
Yet in the planning and building,
there were no standards to follow.
Whatever worked became the code.
Whatever failed
to meet the public need
was changed, replaced
by a better idea.
People and vehicles are constantly
in motion at Disneyland.
Here, people travel aboard
almost every method
of transportation
man has ever designed.
Provocative, new ideas
like the first monorail system
in the Western hemisphere,
have demonstrated their potential
in this practical proving ground.
Disneyland vehicles have carried
340 million passengers
in comfort and speed,
and have traveled
more than 19 million miles
in unequaled safety.
To plan Disneyland, Walt Disney
long ago established
a design organization
called WED Enterprises.
Today, the staff at WED
includes designers, architects
and engineers skilled in the Disney way,
and also fine craftsmen and technicians
skilled in the arts of the space age.
What WED does
is called imagineering.
A blending of creative imagination
with technical know-how.
The talents of WED have gone
to work outside Disneyland too.
At the New York World's Fair,
four of the most popular attractions
were Disney shows
and corporate exhibits
that skillfully
welcomed and entertained
more than 150,000 people every day.
Tribute to the achievements
of the Disney design staff
has been paid by
many highly respected
planners and builders.
Among them, James W. Rouse,
developer of the new town of Columbia.
In his keynote speech
before the 1963
Urban Design Conference
of Harvard University,
Mr. Rouse said in part,
"I hold a view that
may be somewhat shocking
"to an audience
as sophisticated as this:
"That the greatest piece
of urban design
"in the United States today
is Disneyland.
"If you think about Disneyland
and think of its performance
"in relation to its purpose,
its meaning to people,
"more than that, its meaning
to the process of development,
"you will find it the outstanding
piece of urban design
"in the United States.
"It took an area of activity,
the amusement park,
"and lifted it to a standard
so high in its performance,
"in its respect for people,
in its functioning for people,
"that it really has become
a brand new thing.
"It fulfills all the functions
it set out to accomplish.
"Unselfconsciously, usefully,
"and profitably to
its owners and developers.
"I find more to learn
in the standards
"that have been set
and in the goals
"that have been achieved in
the development of Disneyland,
"than in any other single piece
of physical development
"in the country."
Yesterday, Disneyland and
the New York World's Fair.
Tomorrow, a project so vast
it has already been called
a whole new Disney World.
And now, here is Walt Disney.
Welcome to a little bit
of Florida here in California.
This is where the early planning
is taking place for our so-called
Disney World project.
Now the purpose of this film
is to bring you up to date
about some of the plans
for Disney World.
But before I go into
any of the details,
I want to say just a word
about the site of our Florida project.
As you can see on this map,
we have a perfect location
in Florida.
Almost in the very center
of the state.
In fact, we selected this site
because it's so easy for
tourists and Florida residents
to get here by automobile.
Now in larger scale on this map,
our Florida land is located
partly in Orange County
and Osceola County,
between the cities
of Orlando and Kissimmee.
And the important thing is
that the Disney World is located
just a few miles
from the crossing point
of Interstate 4
and Sunshine State Parkway.
Florida's major highways
carrying motorists east and west,
north and south,
to the center of the state.
The sketches and plans
you will see today
are simply a starting point.
Our first overall thinking
about Disney World.
Everything in this room
may change time and time again,
as we move ahead.
But the basic philosophy of what
we're planning for Disney World
is going to remain very much
as it is right now.
We know what our goals are.
We know what we hope
to accomplish.
And believe me,
it's the most exciting
and challenging assignment
we've ever tackled
at Walt Disney Productions.
Today, I want to share with you
some of our ideas for Disney World.
Now the prologue to this film
told you some of the philosophy
that made Disneyland
in California what it is today.
Of course, there'll be
another amusement theme park
in Florida, similar to the one in California.
We're now developing a master plan
that encompasses the theme park
and all the facilities around it
that will serve the tourists.
Hotels, motels and a variety
of recreation activities.
In fact, just this little area alone
is five times the size
of Disneyland in California.
But as you can see
on this master plan,
the theme park and all
the other tourist facilities
fill just one small area
of our enormous Florida project.
According to this scale,
I am six miles tall.
Now it's 12 miles
from here, up to here,
and the whole area
encompasses 27,400 acres.
That is 43 square miles.
Twice the size
of the island of Manhattan.
Now the area
we propose to develop
is between the Reedy Creek swamp
and the Bonnet Creek Swamp.
So one thing we don't need
is a fence to protect us
from trespassers.
Here in Florida
we have something special
we never enjoyed at Disneyland:
The blessing of size.
There's enough land here
to hold all the ideas and plans
we could possibly imagine.
Right now, our plans include
an airport of the future,
down here in Osceola County.
An entrance complex where all visitors
will enter Disney World.
An industrial park area
covering about 1,000 acres,
and of course, the theme park area
way up here.
And all these varied activities
around the Disney World
will be tied together
by a high speed rapid transit system
running almost the full length
of the property.
But the most exciting,
and by far the most important
part of our Florida project,
in fact, the heart of everything
we'll be doing in Disney World,
will be our experimental
prototype city of tomorrow.
We call it EPCOT.
Spelled E-P-C-O-T.
Experimental Prototype
Community of Tomorrow.
Here it is, in larger scale.
EPCOT will take its cue
from the new ideas
and new technologies
that are now emerging
from the creative centers
of American industry.
It will be a community of tomorrow
that will never be completed,
but will always be introducing
and testing and demonstrating
new materials and new systems.
EPCOT will always be
a showcase to the world
for the ingenuity and imagination
of American free enterprise.
I don't believe there's a challenge
anywhere in the world
that's more important
to people everywhere,
than finding solutions
to the problems of our cities.
But where do we begin?
How do we start answering
this great challenge?
We're convinced we must start
with the public need.
And the need is not just
for curing the old ills of old cities.
We think the need is
for starting from scratch
on virgin land and building
a special kind of new community.
So that's what EPCOT is.
An experimental prototype community
that will always be
in a state of becoming.
It will never cease to be
a living blueprint of the future.
Where people actually live a life
they can't find anywhere else in the world.
Everything at EPCOT will be dedicated
to the happiness of the people
who live, work and play here,
and those who come here
from all around the world
to visit our living showcase.
We don't presume
to know all the answers.
In fact, we're counting
on the cooperation
of American industry to provide
their very best thinking
during the planning and the creation
of our experimental prototype
community of tomorrow.
And most important of all,
when EPCOT has become a reality,
and we find the need
for technologies
that don't even exist today,
it's our hope that EPCOT
will stimulate American industry
to develop new solutions that
will meet the needs of people
expressed right here
in this experimental community.
Well, that's our basic
philosophy for EPCOT.
By now, I'm sure you're wondering
how people will actually
live and work and move around
in our community of tomorrow.
So in the next few minutes,
we'll go into detail
about some of our preliminary
sketches and layouts.
"Remember those," I said earlier.
"This is just the beginning."
With that thought in mind,
let's have a look.
No city of today
will serve as the guide
for the city of tomorrow.
EPCOT will be
a planned environment,
demonstrating to the world
what American communities
can accomplish through proper
control of planning and design.
EPCOT begins with an idea
new among cities
built since the birth of the automobile.
We call it "the radial plan."
Picture a wheel.
Like the spokes of the wheel,
the city fans out
along a series of radials
from a bustling hub
at the center of EPCOT.
A network
of transportation systems
radiate from this central hub,
carrying people to and from
the heart of the city.
These transportation systems
circulate to and through
four primary spheres of activity
surrounding the central core.
First, the area
of business and commerce.
Next, the high density
apartment housing.
Then, the broad green belt
and recreation lands.
And finally,
the low density neighborhood
residential streets.
EPCOT's dynamic urban center
will offer the excitement
and variety of activities
found only in metropolitan cities.
Cultural, social, business
and entertainment.
Among its major features will be:
A cosmopolitan hotel
and convention center,
towering 30 or more stories.
Shopping areas, where stores
and whole streets
recreate the character
and adventure of places round the world.
Theaters for dramatic
and musical productions.
Restaurants and a variety
of nightlife attractions.
And a wide range
of office buildings.
Some containing services
required by EPCOT's residents,
but most of them designed especially
to suit the local and regional
needs of major corporations.
But most important,
this entire 50 acres
of city streets and buildings
will be completely enclosed.
In this climate-controlled environment,
shoppers and theatergoers and
people just out for a stroll
will enjoy ideal weather conditions.
Protected day and night
from rain, heat and cold and humidity.
Here, the pedestrian will be king.
Free to walk and browse
without fear of motorized vehicles.
Only electric powered vehicles
will travel above the streets
of EPCOT's central city.
This towering hotel
is the visual center of EPCOT.
The shining jewel
at the center of the city.
It will offer tourists
and vacationers not only
the most modern guest rooms
and convention facilities,
but also a seven-acre recreation deck,
located high above the pedestrian
and shopping areas of the city.
But hidden from view,
directly beneath the hotel
is another kind of vital center.
EPCOT'S transportation lobby.
Although out of sight to hotel guests,
this transportation terminal
will play a key role
in the city of tomorrow's
ability to meet the needs
of both visitor and resident.
Two separate but interconnecting
transit systems will move people
into and out of EPCOT
in speed, safety and comfort
through this central terminal.
Both are electrically powered.
The high speed monorail for rapid transit
over longer distances,
and a concept new to the American city
for shorter travel distances,
the WEDWAY People Mover.
Automobiles and trucks
will not be barred from EPCOT.
In fact, a vast armada of vehicles
will continuously flow through
the heart of the community
traveling below the pedestrian level
on roadways reserved
for specific types of vehicles.
Let's look at another view
of EPCOT's transportation hub,
and see how traffic flows
through the heart of the city
on three separate levels.
At the bottom of the stack
is the truck route,
reserved for supply vehicles.
Trucks will have easy access
to all loading docks
and service elevators
for the delivery of commercial goods.
The middle level
is the automobile thruway,
exclusively for cars.
Adjacent to the roadway
are parking areas
for the convenience of hotel guests.
For the motorist just driving through,
no stoplight will ever slow
the constant flow of traffic
through the center of EPCOT.
But automobiles and freeways
will not be EPCOT's major way
of entering and leaving the city.
The transportation heartbeat of EPCOT
will be the two electric powered systems:
Monorail and WEDWAY,
that radiate to and from
the transportation lobby.
And the key system
in this coordinated network
will be the WEDWAY People Mover.
The first People Mover installation is
already in daily operation at Disneyland.
On peak days, it carries
nearly 40,000 passengers.
The cars you see here are approximately
5/8ths scale, considerably smaller
than full size passenger cars
would be for city use.
EPCOT's People Mover is a silent,
all electric system
that never stops running.
These cars continue to move
even while passengers
are disembarking or stepping aboard.
Power is supplied from a series
of motors embedded in the track,
completely independent of the cars.
No single car can ever break down,
and cause a rush hour
traffic jam in EPCOT.
Because the cars run continuously,
there will be no waiting in stations
for a WEDWAY People Mover.
The next car is always ready.
Now let's go back to
the transportation lobby,
and see how the WEDWAY
will travel along one radial
between the center of EPCOT,
and a typical residential area.
Leaving the transportation lobby,
the WEDWAY trains travel
above the downtown streets.
Within minutes,
the WEDWAYpasses through
the first station.
Many people who work
in the offices and stores
of EPCOT city center
board the WEDWAY here
for their trip home.
Some people leave
the WEDWAY here, too.
They live in EPCOT's
high density apartments,
surrounding the metropolitan center.
Most passengers who ride the WEDWAY
live beyond the apartments and
stay aboard the People Mover
as it crosses EPCOT's
sheltering green belt.
EPCOT's green belt is more
than just a broad expanse
of beautiful lawns
and walks and trees.
Here too are the community's
varied recreational facilities.
Its playgrounds for children,
its churches and its schools.
Beyond the green belt are
EPCOT's neighborhood areas
of single family homes.
This is one radial neighborhood.
Here, and throughout the community,
residents returning from work or shopping
will disembark from the WEDWAY
at stations located just a few steps
from where they live.
The homes are located
in a wide green area
that provides light recreation
activities for adults,
and play areas for children.
Circulating through this area
are footpaths reserved for pedestrians,
electric carts and bicycles.
Children going to and from
schools and playgrounds
will use these paths.
Always completely safe and separated
from the automobile.
The resident leaving home
in his automobile
will drive down a street
reserved for motor vehicles.
He then enters a one-way road
that circles the city center.
This road carries the motorist
onto the main thruway,
connecting EPCOT with
other points in Disney World
and with Florida's nearby
network of major highways.
But most EPCOT residents
will drive their automobiles
only on weekend pleasure trips.
From all over the community,
residents going to theirjobs
converge by WEDWAY on the center city.
Many work downtown in offices,
stores and shops.
But most employees go beyond
the city core to theirjobs.
From the transportation lobby,
monorail trains carry employees
either to the theme park,
or to EPCOT's 1,000-acre industrial park.
At this central station
in the industrial complex
passengers disembark from the monorail
and again board WEDWAY cars
that radiate to each facility.
This industrial complex
will provide employment
for many people who live in EPCOT.
But it will mean much more,
not only for this community
but also for American industry.
Here, the Disney staff will
work with individual companies
to create a showcase of industry at work.
In attractive park-like settings,
the six million people
who visit Disney World each year
will look behind the scenes
at experimental prototype plants,
research and development laboratories,
and computer centers
for major corporations.
So this is EPCOT,
the heart of Disney World.
In other parts of the country,
a community the size of this prototype
could become part
of an entire city complex,
composed of many such communities,
planned and built a few miles apart.
In Disney World, about 20,000 people
will actually live in EPCOT.
Their homes will be built in ways
that permit ease of change,
so that new products may
continuously be demonstrated.
Their schools will welcome new ideas,
so that everyone who grows up in EPCOT
will have skills in pace
with today's world.
EPCOT will be a working community,
with employment for all.
And everyone who lives here
will have a responsibility
to help keep this community
an exciting, living blueprint of the future.
And now, here again,
is Walt Disney.
That's the starting point
for our experimental prototype
community of tomorrow.
Now, where do we go from these
preliminary plans and sketches?
Well, a project like this
is so vast in scope
that no one company alone
can make it a reality.
But if we can bring together
the technical know-how
of American industry
and the creative imagination
of the Disney organization,
I'm confident we can create
right here in Disney World
a showcase to the world
of the American free enterprise system.
I believe we can build a community
that more people will talk about
and come to look at
than any other area in the world.
And with your cooperation,
I'm sure this experimental
prototype community of tomorrow
can influence the future of city living
for generations to come.
It's an exciting challenge.
A once in a lifetime opportunity
for everyone who participates.
Speaking for myself and
the entire Disney organization,
we're ready to go right now.