Bucharest Film Studios
present
in
The Eruption
A film made in honor of the centenary
celebrating the petroleum industry in Romania.
Screenplay
Music
Set Design
Costume Design
Sound
Editing
Make-up
Camera Effects
Second Unit Director
Camera Operators
Assistant directors
Secretary on Set
Assistant Camera
Gaffer
Film made with the support of the Ministry
of Oil and Chemical Industry
Symphonic Orchestra for Cinematography
Jazz Music by
Production Manager
Cinematography
Director
The film is dedicated
to our well-drillers who,
through their heroic work, provide our
homeland with incomparable riches.
Damned be this region!
They say elephants go to their
graveyard when they're ready to die.
Cars come here, to Ursei.
May this one rest in peace!
I'm sorry, you'll have to continue on foot.
But the trust is not that far from here.
About 3 kilometers.
On foot?
All alone?
I might get a lift.
It's useless to wait,
cars seldom pass by here.
Go across the hill!
It's shorter.
When you get there, tell the center
that we got a flat by the cemetery.
- They know where exactly.
- I will call them.
Good day!
A strange creature
appeared in front of me.
A ghost of these abandoned oil wells,
that are decades old.
I've been here for 50 years.
And so's Marioara...
This is Marioara.
But she's almost out of use,
she barely drips.
That one over there is Rodica.
Over here, oil wells have names.
That one there
is V. Stoinescu.
V...
That silent one is number 106.
A rotten well
only has a number.
And not a drop of oil, either.
Not even enough to light a lamp.
Haven't they retired you, old man?
You'd think I'd accept retirement?
I'll die along with them.
Very soon.
Is the city close?
Walk up to the monument,
and then go past the train station.
The station looked abandoned.
A goat, a lamb and two kids
playing on the rails.
- Why are you playing on the rails?
- Why not?
- The train might hit you!
- It won't, we've never seen one here.
- Come on! Play the train game!
- Leave me alone!
Look! Just like I told you...
Look at them leaving...
in high numbers!
- The oil workers?
- Yes. Since there is no more oil...
It's the death of this place.
Like in '33.
What happened in '33?
Ursei 1 burned down.
It blew up because of the gas.
There's a gas layer here...
The drillers call it "Hell's Gates".
I know it well.
It's a gas layer of 320 atmospheres.
Even cities have their own lives.
They're born, they live and die.
This town was dying.
Oil was its blood.
But it had been drained of it.
Keep the change!
Goodbye, thief!
If we don't show up at Ursei tonight,
they won't reassign us.
Any idea where the trust is?
- For you, I have an idea.
- Where I should go, then?
Allow me to take you there!
Gore.
Gore...
Gore!
Just a moment!
Buddy,
please put the bottles on the table.
Thank you, buddy.
Good day, Mrs. Stanila!
From what I see, the city is dead.
If they don't find any oil at Ursei 2,
everything will close down.
Who are you looking for, here?
I came for training.
Well, that is a weird idea.
No, thank you.
Wait here, Petrica!
I urge you to stay!
Why? So I can dry up like the oil wells?
Can't you see
everything is rotten around here?
Why don't you wanna go to your folks?
Oltenia is pretty close to here.
- While here..
- There's a lot of oil here too.
You're mad, like the engineer at Ursei.
The trust will close down,
I'm telling you.
They don't trust him any longer.
Let's go, Petrica!
Careful not to fall!
So you're staying for Ursei?
The trust was old and non-functional.
On the road,
my new acquaintance told me:
The second crucial moment
in the life of the trust.
I told him I didn't understand.
And he explained:
A trust has two big moments in its life.
The first is its creation.
- And the second one?
- Its closing down.
Make way for the inspector
coming from Bucharest!
Make way, comrades!
She's from Bucharest, comrades!
I am busy now!
I was assigned to Ursei.
Comrade, we've been assigned to Ursei.
I don't have time!
Be patient!
CHIEF ENGINEER
Ursei 2
is a pointless venture.
It might be,
but without oil we cannot survive.
We've been drilling in vain
for a year.
We confirmed in the report
that in 1933 at Ursei 1
there was nothing but
a gas layer which was...
exhausted at the moment
of the explosion.
What about you?
- What are you doing here?
- I've been assigned to Ursei.
We've been assigned to Ursei.
Is this the site of Ursei 1?
The old man...
The explosion catapulted him here.
Are you comrade Anca?
How come you know me?
Comrade engineer Emil Oprisan from
General Management told me to wait for you.
I wasn't expecting such a present!
How are you, my little dove?
Follow me!
Do you know her?
Tell me about it, buddy!
These are for you.
Everything seemed so strange!
This day was so different,
compared to yesterday.
It was my last day of vacation.
I was not alone.
Emil was really sweet.
But sometimes I disliked his humour.
Anca...
this is your last day of vacation.
How about going dancing tonight?
You know dad will never approve.
My life is a bit too sweet, he says.
We'll pass by the General Management.
I'm looking for the General Manager.
I'm his daughter.
- Yes. First floor, on the right.
- Thank you.
- I don't think we can find seats.
- Let's try anyway.
Emil!
A fellow student.
My fiancée, Anca Banu.
Engineer Nina Manoliu.
Your fiancée?
I'm happy for you.
Get yourself a chair!
- I shouldn't have...
- He'll manage, don't worry.
I'll see what it's like
when I become a husband.
He's not my husband.
You don't know anything
about me anymore.
We haven't met for a million years!
For 4 years.
Actually 5...
Oh, how time flies!
What do you do now, Nina?
Nothing.
But what did you try to attain
back then at the Institute?
An oil engineer diploma?
No, a husband.
I drilled for one, but he didn't
make it through the refining process.
Let's just say...
he wasn't good quality.
I prefer the smell of Chanel,
rather than gas.
Don't you agree?
No. I'm leaving for training tomorrow.
At a drilling rig? Where?
I'm assigned to Ursei.
The Ursei 2 rig?
How strange!
- Tonight the ghosts are swarming.
- I don't understand.
We even have the perfect music
for ghost stories.
My ex-husband is at Ursei.
He stayed there.
Engineer Barbu.
Who?
- Barbu Andrei?
- Yeah.
The world is so small,
yet we know so little about it.
I didn't know
you had been married to him.
I made him choose between me
and the rig, and he preferred Ursei.
But Ursei surely is not beautiful.
But you should go dance!
That's why you came here.
If I were in your shoes,
I wouldn't let her leave.
Ursei is an ugly place.
Only mud...
and men.
Yes, Emil. It's me, Nina.
So Anca eventually left...
I'm very sorry.
I wouldn't have let her leave.
A woman, all alone, among so many men!
Anca...
Ok, Emil...
Call me if you go see her.
I'd like to know how things are there.
Good night, Emil!
Showing off...
What do you say, lon?
She's quite a pretty girl, isn't she?
You're all real chatterboxes!
Careful not to fall.
What do you mean by that?
Got some matches, buddy?
Go buy yourself some matches... buddy.
Is that heavy?
It is!
No pain, no supper, buddy.
- Who's that?
- Who?
Good day, comrade engineer!
Are you on leave?
Then you might...
Understood, comrade engineer.
Try one here, buddy!
I see you'll get some supper.
- Where's the engineer?
- On the rig platform.
Unscrew that!
Come in!
Why are you staring at me?
- Have you worked on a rig before?
- No, I haven't.
This is my first one.
There are so many rigs in the country.
Here's my advice, young lady:
A truck is leaving
for the trust in 15 minutes.
Don't miss this wonderful
opportunity and go home.
That's all.
What if I don't want to leave?
- Still here?
- Yes, comrade engineer.
What are you doing there?
Studying the mud.
- Don't fall in the tank!
- I won't.
- That plank won't stand.
- It will!
Fine, then...
Won't you give me the blackberries?
I'll give you 20 lei for them.
Take them, I'm full anyway.
Where are you going?
To get blackberries.
They sell well. Wanna join?
Did I scare you?
You again? What do you want?
- I picked some berries for you.
- When did you pick them?
I heard you like them.
I'll trade them for a kiss.
Where were you, buddy?
Want to become a chemist, huh?
Dobre, I got you some blackberries.
The mud tank!
Quick! Quick!
Wanted to study mud up-close?
He's a horrible man.
Apart from that, nothing.
Mud,
noise...
boredom.
I'd like to leave this place.
Call me every night, Emil.
Who wants to lose some money?
Nobody?
It's worse than jail in here.
Found anything?
My ass!
We will all rot out here.
You've been rotting already.
They just forgot to bury you.
Hello, comrade engineer!
Coming to the shower?
After sunbathing.
It's my special pastime.
When I set my eyes on one,
I'm determined to get her.
- So you like her too?
- I do. She's a strong woman.
She is beautiful.
Playing the innocent
since she got a lab job.
Don't worry, I have my tricks.
What tricks?
I'll tell you my method.
Leave her alone!
Why?
She's got enough for all of us.
She's like a cigarette butt.
If you enjoy smoking butts...
What are you doing here?
- Looking for the beauty of Ursei.
- Get out!
Your hair has grown quite fast.
It suits you better.
I couldn't stand your shorter hair.
I'm a delicate man and...
Leave me alone!
Get out of here!
I don't like it when you scream.
I have a sensitive ear.
You might offend me and...
it would make the situation worse.
I came for the mud analysis.
- Am I intruding?
- No, comrade Gore.
Please, stay!
This room is pretty small.
Yeah, pretty small.
- So?
- There's no room for 3 people.
I think you heard me well.
You said had a sensitive ear.
Get out!
Now you go too!
What happened?
The cart wheel broke.
Are you alone?
The driver went back
to the city for help.
All this because of lon.
Who's lon?
lon lon, my husband.
He stayed in Ursei.
An engineer talked him into it.
He knows there isn't a drop of oil,
but he keeps digging.
They're digging like
they're digging their own graves.
Can I be of any help?
What are you doing here?
Studying.
I'm completing my notebook.
Why don't you go to bed?
It's late.
I'm not tired.
You're stubborn.
- Stubborn and...
- And?
Nothing.
Now I understand
why Nina left this place.
You know Nina?
That's not your business, anyway.
You could mind your words.
You should be more careful!
Listen, young lady:
you should be more careful.
Come in!
Emil!
My dearest!
- You've come right on time.
- Unfortunately, I can't stay long.
Let me look at you, Anca! You're the
most beautiful girl-driller in the world.
Emil...
Why are you so silent?
Want me to sing?
You know very well I don't.
We've drilled over 2800 meters and...
nothing.
Why are you telling me this?
You're right.
I'm saying this to myself, not to you.
2800 meters...
Mr. Dobre, how do you
get a girl to like you?
- Bring here some berries!
- Doesn't work.
I think I know how!
I read a novel about a driver
who seduced his lover
with some poppy flowers.
With flowers!
He brought her flowers.
Mr. Dobre...
Have you really read that or...?
Comrade Emil Oprisan,
the Chief engineer
from the Head Office, is here.
He's awful.
- Nina told me.
- You can't imagine how he treats me!
He's just awful.
- Am I interrupting?
- No, not at all.
I haven't seen you in a year.
Since we started drilling here.
- And how's it going?
- !Still drilling.
- I have even worse news.
- I thought so.
The General Management is preparing
the order of liquidation for this oil well.
Close it down?
There are tons of crude oil
under this gas layer.
- And the idiots want to shut it down.
- Yet, where is that layer?
You're almost at 3000 meters.
Where's the layer...?
- Right here, under your feet.
- I hope so.
The management wants to know how long
it will take you to get to the oil layer.
Or it might be better to abandon it.
I need three weeks.
Fine, I will inform the management.
- Do you still need me?
- No.
- Why? Got work to do?
- Yes, I do.
Good night!
What are you looking at?
What do you want?
You can stay if you want.
I'm leaving! You hear me?
- Who's gonna' take your place, Panait?
- I don't care.
There's no oil, I tell you.
Only gases.
The inspector said that.
The engineer is lying!
We'll all burn, like they did in '33.
There's no oil! There is no oil!
Shut up or I'll kill you.
After you finish this training,
would you like to...
Actually, I'll ask you some other time.
Goodbye!
I forgot to tell you.
There's a crashed cart
at about 43 km from here,
carrying the luggage
of one of your drillers.
Is that an allusion to the rats
leaving the sinking ship?
The wife of a certain lon lon.
lon lon's wife.
- At 43 km.
- Close to the tarmac.
Good morning!
- Get her things in the truck
and bring them back to the city! - Yes.
Get her something to eat too!
Understood, comrade engineer.
And I don't want lon finding out.
I trusted you.
- Do you know what I did for Ursei?
- I do.
You left your family.
I didn't know that this land was so dry.
I thought I could bathe in oil.
Without oil...
Listen, lon:
I still believe in my calculations.
Understand?
There is oil here.
There must be oil.
Oil? Here?
Like Burca said,
"When the pigs fly and hell freezes... "
Keep working!
And stop following Burca!
He's a bad lot.
Dinu! Dinu!
See if engineer Oprisan has arrived.
Hello, Emil?
Yes, it's Nina.
Got any news?
Don't you want to come over?
Are they for me?
What do you think?
I think you're an idiot.
Take it easy...
dude.
It's not worth fighting for a whore.
- What did you say?
- What you heard.
Good thing you got rid of the flowers.
For her, money is more valuable
than the flowers.
- Get it?
- You're lying!
I seldom lie.
Why do you think her hair is so short?
Because it's stylish?
No, my friend.
It's because her hair hasn't grown yet.
She had been shaved bald recently.
Know what that means?
How do you know?
I just know, my friend.
I saw her on the job.
I was on a two-month holiday back then.
At Berision.
If you're lying...
- Want me to prove it?
- No. I'll find out for myself.
I don't think you'll succeed.
I will still visit her tonight.
Convicted for PROSTITUTION
You're the one bringing me
flowers every day?
I used to...
Then why are you here?
I want to speak to you.
What's the use?
I want to know the truth.
I'm an honest man.
Everybody says that about themselves.
Even myself.
Do you really say that about yourself?
I do. But who believes me?
I do.
I do, Bica.
I want to believe you.
Do you understand?
Fine.
Sit down and hear me out!
And don't interrupt me,
since this is our last talk.
- Bica!
- I told you not to interrupt me!
I used to be a telephone operator.
I was in love with a student.
He left me when he took his medical degree.
I was engaged to a tailor last year.
He had a little workshop.
I once asked him why
he was delaying the wedding.
He didn't answer.
I asked him again.
We got in a quarrel.
I ran from his place immediately.
I ran up the street like a lunatic.
I didn't know what to do.
It was late.
I went to a park
and sat on a bench.
After a while,
a man approached me.
He asked for my I.D.
I didn't have it on me.
The tailor told them
he didn't know me.
I was sent for moral rehabilitation.
They shaved my head
and sentenced me
to 6 months for prostitution.
They also sentenced Burca
for theft around that time.
That's what you wanted to know.
Are you satisfied now?
Tell me!
Go away!
Good evening, my little bird.
How are you?
I hope that Gore
hasn't raised the prices.
- Be quiet or I'll hit you!
- Don't touch me!
Leave me alone!
- What the hell do you want?
- To kill you.
Just try!
Listen to me!
Bica is mine.
If you don't leave the rig now,
I'll kill you like an animal.
What happened to you?
Who hit you?
Gore!
For that whore!
He killed me, comrade engineer.
- What did you want with her?
- She asked for money.
I didn't give her any,
so Gore tried to kill me.
He's lying.
Shut up!
Tell Bica to come see me tomorrow!
Got something to tell me?
There's enough dirt on our boots.
Just leave!
There's no place for you here.
It's about Bica.
- Bica needs to leave.
- Why?
Thing aren't that simple.
- I know her past.
- I know it too.
Then everything is clear.
Do you know what I think of you?
You don't know how people are.
And you don't know Bica.
You're just a broken piece of metal
from this dried-up rig.
You've never loved anyone
in your life.
Maybe only these oily rig engines.
I hate you, you hear me?
I hate you!
Bica!
He's going to fall!
Dobre, activate the hook!
Leave me alone!
Stop crying, Bica!
You know...
I have a house in the city.
I have no parents,
I only have you.
Leave me, Gore!
Leave me alone!
- When's the truck coming, uncle Dobre?
- Are you leaving?
Because of the engineer?
Yeah.
He's made a mistake about Bica.
But...
He's hard and stiff like a walnut.
He works here, in slime and rain.
People come and go,
but he remains and drills on.
But it's in vain,
there's not a drop of oil here.
You're right.
Then why is he digging?
Because there NEEDS to be oil here.
The people are waiting for it
and the ground needs to provide it.
Without oil, we are nothing.
And he knows it.
That's why he goes on drilling.
Drilling silently, like a mole.
Hello, comrade Bica!
We're stuck on a crosswords puzzle.
"What turns litmus paper red?"
4 letters.
Acid.
Acid!
Comrade...
I'm waiting for the mud analysis.
We planned to talk
on the phone every night at 9.
And it's the third time
she's not answering.
I don't know what to believe.
You don't want to believe
what you already know.
I didn't stand a chance
against the rig either.
It's a rival I can't be proud of.
But your current rival is beautiful.
Anca?
You're being mean, Emil.
I'm being mean with myself.
No, Nina.
Give me a cigarette, please.
And light, please.
Light for two disheartened folks.
I haven't given up yet.
There's nothing you can do, Emil.
But there is.
I can shut down the well.
Comrade engineer Andrei Barbu
will have a surprise.
I'm reporting to the Ministry tomorrow
about his futile project.
But you supported it.
They'll question your professionalism.
- And that's exactly what they should do.
- Emil, control yourself!
I can't.
I can just see them walking
like two lovers, holding hands.
And then I thought of abandoning it,
like most people abandoned their houses.
Gore!
How is lon?
This is my house.
If we find oil,
you'll make it beautiful.
Follow me!
Come on, move it, move it!
What are you waiting for?
Come on, move it!
"I didn't want to just drill an oil well. "
"I took responsibility"
"in giving life to this region. "
Continue!
"In bringing back to normal
the lives of some people,"
"lives which were full of misfortunes. "
"People whom I know and who
do not deserve these misfortunes. "
"And I acted accordingly. "
"Signed: Andrei Barbu"
- Put me through Ursei 2!
- Can I take those?
Take that too!
Come on!
Hello?
Ursei 2?
Who is this?
Yeah.
Please tell comrade Barbu that...
- They're shutting it down!
- Who told you that?
- The driver.
- He just came from the trust.
- Just ask him, he's outside.
- Is it true?
So you lied to me, comrade engineer.
Comrade engineer,
they're coming to shut it down!
So you came to close the rig, lon?
Yes, comrade engineer.
Then do it, it's yours anyway.
Let's go!
The Chief Engineer informs us
that the trust has been disbanded.
How about the rig?
Informs us to continue working
only on a single shift.
What depth are we at?
3150 meters.
Increase the drilling speed
from 6 to 9.
Understood, comrade engineer.
8, Gore.
And with you, 9.
We can manage two shifts.
Gore at the bridge on the first shift.
Vasile can take over the night shift.
You at the winch, for the night shift.
- And Comrade Anca can take your place
during the day. - She is leaving.
Comrade Emil Oprisan said
he'd come to take her tomorrow.
Her training is over.
Comrade Anca?
Yeah...
Then...
lon can do the winch day shift.
He's leaving...
lon?
Fine, we'll continue working.
Consequent to the decision
of the General Management,
after the report-analysis of the
Technical Service Department,
the drilling works are suspended
at the Ursei 2, Trust 3 Muntenia.
The mud at the tank is rising!
The mud is rising!
Comrade engineer!
Where is Comrade engineer?
Hey, Mr. Dobre!
To the mud volcanoes!
Comrade engineer!
The mud's density is decreasing.
The mud tank is boiling.
Comrade engineer!
Bica, did she say anything before she left?
No, she didn't.
- How much has it decreased?
- To 1.6.
Mud Density
The Gates of Hell.
1000 revs.
Speed up the engines! 1000 revs!
Driller, take care of the tank!
- Anca!
- Going right now, comrade engineer.
Dobre, call the trust!
Maybe the truck hasn't left
and our people are still there.
Who the hell could that be?
Wait a minute.
Just wait.
Hello? The trust?
- Who's there?
- It's me.
- "Me" who?
- The trust.
- Who exactly?
- Now the trust is only me, the guard.
This is Ursei 2.
- Hasn't the truck with our drillers
passed by there? - It did.
Yes, it has just left for Ploiesti.
The truck has left for Ploiesti.
There's no one there.
- Who did you talk to?
- The guard.
We need men and barite supplies
from the General Management.
In three hours they could be here.
We have to talk through the trust.
Tell the guard to connect you!
I'll try, comrade engineer.
I used to be a telephone operator.
Nina!
How did you get in?
I knew you were coming back alone, Emil.
Emil, don't be a fool!
Hello!
Ursei 2 here.
The rig!
We hit the gas layer, we need help!
My child...
I'm alone here, but I'm coming.
Listen to me!
You don't need to come.
You need to connect me
with the General Management.
We need barite supplies and men.
Do you have the keys
to the telephone exchange?
But I don't know how to use it.
Go and open it!
- I need to get the keys first.
- Hurry up!
Which one is it?
Gas!
Hello?
Come on, uncle!
Hello? Ursei?
Ursei?
It erupted!
It's an eruption!
Eruption?
Tell me how to make the connection.
Insert the fifth plug.
Wait...
The fifth plug in the first hole
of the second row.
In the first hole...
And ask for Bucharest.
Bucharest!
Increase!
- Hello?
- Bucharest!
Hello!
Increase!
Open the second pump!
Open the second pump...
Close the blowout preventer!
It's useless, it's broken.
The hooks won't tighten up.
I don't want to die.
I don't want to die!
To comrade engineer!
- The preventer doesn't hold.
- Put the emergency one!
Bucharest! The trust speaking.
Which one?
Wait, let me tell you!
Ursei 2 has erupted.
Erupted!
Send men and barite!
Who am I?
I am... the driller...
I mean the guard...
the old man.
What do you need?
It's comrade engineer.
Hello? Don't interrupt me!
Has comrade engineer been
connected to the Minister's office?
The second oil well has erupted.
Alarm at the Ursei 2 oil well!
- Don't answer, Emil!
- I have to.
Yes.
Engineer Oprisan.
Fine.
I'll come right over.
I'll give the order.
I'll do everything necessary.
Nina,
I'm a wretched man.
Don't use such harsh words, Emil!
I told them to shut the well down.
And?
Ursei has erupted.
You'll be criticized.
I hope they'll be harsh.
We're leaving.
I have to give the order.
Yeah.
I've never felt so...
Let's go!
We're losing pressure.
It's leaking at the flange.
Someone needs to climb and repair it.
Don't! You have your family.
I haven't opened... the valve.
Bring the stretcher!
Water!
Comrade...
Anca...
Bica...
Don't tell her!
I won't. Don't worry.
Water...
Gore needs to be sent to the hospital,
otherwise he'll die in a few hours.
I want to, but how?
We don't have men to spare.
There are three at the well rim
and one in the engine room.
We need four men for the stretcher.
- How will we do it?
- We don't have a choice.
We have to shut it down.
Shut the rig down?!
When we're so close to the oil?
Never!
You will shut it down, comrade Barbu.
Are you giving me orders,
comrade brigadier?
It's not an order.
It's a task from the Party.
A man was born here and
we don't have the right to kill him.
Not even for 1.000 oil wells!
Shut down the well!
Gore!
Andrei!
Gore vanished!
He fled.
Gore?
Gore!
Lower the drill pipe!
Oil! Oil!
God bless you, lon!
Come on in!
Come on, watch your step!
Good job!
Like it?
You can laugh too.
Get in there too!
Come on!
- Do it yourself!
- Go on, go on!
Go on!
Buddy...
Ursei 2
The oil well.
Mud, noise, boredom.
It meant so much more for me!
It means so much for
the people I learnt to know here...
Now we are leaving them.
My husband and I.
Another Ursei is waiting for us.
My life yesterday was so different
compared to my life today
and my life tomorrow.
THE END
Corrections
Bogdan Movileanu