Subtitles by explosiveskull
www.OpenSubtitles.org
Friendships in
New York are like encounters
on a bus.
You might hit it off right away,
but only if you're lucky,
you also get off
at the same stop.
New York,
the famous melting pot.
Here are some of the
young and beautiful
that found their
way to the city.
Posting their saturated
Brooklyn lives on Instagram,
attracting even more
from all over the world.
All looking for love,
happiness and success.
Just like the two women
we're about to meet,
Maria and Lena.
I just don't know.
This whole new development,
every single guy
I hang out with,
they just want to have
kids like immediately.
Well, take it as a compliment.
I mean they see this big
pile of amazing genes
bundled up in this cute
little package of yours
and they wanna snatch it away.
Haha, but it's
actually very frustrating
because I don't even think
it's about me, you know?
It's about them.
I mean look at
James, he adores you,
and not the idea of you being
with him, know what I mean?
Well, adore us as
much as you like.
I don't know, maybe
he's just too old.
Oh, yeah, we don't do old.
They're wrinkly and
smelly and they go like
Yeah, tell me about it.
Should we get going?
Yeah, yeah, yeah,
I think we should.
- Yeah, let's get...
- Oh my God,
the guy's already sitting
in front of your door.
Well, maybe.
No, no, it's on me.
Come on.
No, no, no, my treat.
That's a really cute
bracelet, it really suits you.
Yes, you like it?
- Yeah.
- Wanna try it on?
Thank you.
- It's very nice.
- You can keep it.
- No, come on.
- Yes, my treat.
This is very expensive.
I have like five
of them, it's yours.
Thank you.
Did you ever see this
picture on Facebook
that looks like a roschach
but also like an old lady?
Oh, yeah, yeah,
yeah, that like thing
that if you squint your eyes,
you might see an old lady
or a princess or something?
Or, yeah, or a chichi.
A chichi, that's
your word for it?
Chichi or hooha.
- Well, I don't know...
- Come on, check it out.
- I wanna show you.
- Okay, I'm gonna pull it up.
There, there, you see?
- Oh my God!
- Totally.
Oh my God, you're so right!
It's totally a chichi,
well that's good to know.
Why?
Well, next time a
guy goes down on you
and he squints his eyes, he
might discover a princess?
Yeah, speaking of which,
I gotta go.
Alright, bye, have fun.
- Bye.
Lena and
Maria were best friends,
that kind of close
friendship in your early 30's
when all your real best friends
have become childhood memories.
They met at a charity event
where Maria was part
of the catering group.
Realizing that they
were both European
was a great
conversation starter.
Unfortunately, it
also got Maria fired.
Hey.
You're home early.
Yeah.
Did you guys have fun?
Looks like you had fun, huh?
What?
Oh, yeah, they just left.
They?
I just,
I just saw her.
What?
I just saw that
woman leave our house.
No, remember, I
told you about this.
I was having a friend
over for a drink?
You know, it's just a
colleague from work.
We talked about this, remember?
Hey, it's fine, hey, come here.
Oh my God, you
even smell like her.
Oh shit, oh shit!
- Shit, shit, shit, shit, shit.
- What are you doing?
I'm looking!
Looking for what?
I don't know!
Lena, you're
being ridiculous!
So, is this like
a one time thing
or has this been
going on for a while?
What?
Listen, you are really
stressed out, Lena, okay?
Don't put this on me.
No, listen, I'm not
trying to put it on you.
All I'm trying to say is
that we're both working
through a lot of problems
right now and just...
That's not an excuse!
Listen, let's just, can
we please sit down and talk?
Please?
- Please, can we just...
- Don't fucking touch me!
Okay, fine.
I'm leaving.
Fine.
Go.
Lena!
Fuck.
- Strawberry?
- Nm-nm.
Come on.
- Just one.
- No, no.
Just a strawberry.
Can't you see I'm smoking?
Yes, I can see that.
Didn't you say you
wanted to quit anyway?
Well, I've changed my mind.
Again, and again, and again,
always changing your mind.
That's what I'm talking about.
You can't commit to anything.
Man, what's your problem?
We're having great
sex, we're having fun,
I don't want anything of
you, you should be happy.
Yes, but I'm not happy.
Why?
Look,
- you're 30 years old...
- I'm 29.
Okay, almost 30.
Do you know what that means, hm?
You're on your best years,
don't waste them around.
You should have a baby.
- A baby?
- Yeah.
No.
Don't you want to
have a baby with me?
No, I don't want
a baby, no babies.
Wow, women of your generation.
What is wrong
with my generation?
The problem is you
can't commit to anything.
Okay, in a perfect world,
what's an ideal woman for you?
- You're asking?
- Mm-hm.
Okay.
I would like a woman that
bakes a strawberry pie
in the morning, gives me
a blowjob in the night.
You're disgusting,
- that's absolutely disgusting.
- Come on, I was kidding.
- Come on, I was joking!
- No, you're disgusting,
- that's not even funny.
- I was joking about
- the strawberry pie.
- No, you know what?
Just leave, okay?
- What's wrong?
- Just leave, go away.
- No, I want you out.
- Come on, come on.
No, no, leave, leave,
I want you to leave.
- Are you serious?
- Go, leave,
yes, I'm serious, leave.
- Go!
- Okay, I'm going.
As much
as Maria had enough
of men explaining her life,
Lena had enough of her marriage.
She wasn't sure
what she had seen
or if she had seen
anything at all.
Her decision to leave made
her sad, but not sad enough.
This
is Kings Highway.
And her confusion
lead her to Maria's place.
Do you think this has been
going on for a long time?
I mean, I don't know.
I had a strange feeling lately,
we had some problems, but...
I don't know.
I am so sorry.
I mean, James, who
would have thought?
He was always so
concerned about you.
But then again, I've only met
him a couple of times anyway.
What an ass.
Wanna sleep over tonight?
No, thank you, I don't
think I can sleep right now.
Do you want some wine?
I could use a glass of wine.
I had a pretty fucked up
date myself, actually.
Oh my God, you, I totally
forgot, your guy was here.
- I'm sorry, I can, I can...
- Why are you sorry?
No, no, no, stop it.
Relax, you know
what we're gonna do?
We're gonna have a party.
That's it, we're
gonna have a party,
my roommates are not here, so,
we could have some booze
and something to smoke,
- we could have fun.
- I don't know.
That's what we're gonna
do, and it's gonna be great.
I'll take care of it.
This was
Maria's typical way
of handling a crisis.
And Lena, Lena
didn't mind at all.
Morning.
Good morning.
Fuck.
Shoes.
Let's go.
So, what are you gonna do now?
I don't know, I mean,
right now I feel really hungover
so I don't really wanna
wrap my head around it.
Are you getting a divorce?
Wow, um...
I don't even know what
happens to my visa then, so.
Oh shit, yeah, that's true,
you can't get a divorce.
At least you can keep the house.
No, he can stay
at the apartment,
- I don't care about it.
- What, are you crazy?
First of all, it's
an awesome apartment,
and second of all, darling,
you know I love you
but you can't stay
in my shit hole forever,
you gotta get the apartment.
You know, I know it
sounds strange, but,
the apartment, all of
it, never made me happy.
That's bullshit,
we can redecorate.
He's the one who cheated on you,
he has to give
you the apartment.
You gotta conquer that castle!
What?
Conquer the castle.
Maria, I don't think that's
an expression.
Doesn't matter, this
asshole has to go.
I'm gonna conquer
that castle, watch me.
Oh my God, Maria,
you're crazy.
Where were you?
I was worried all night.
I don't think you care.
Lena, of course I care.
You shitbag!
What is she doing here?
We conquered the castle!
What?
Well, I think it's better
if you leave for a while.
For a while?
Better forever, you
fucking cheater.
Lena, can we talk
about this in private?
I don't think I can
talk to you right now.
See?
Just pack your shit and go.
I already packed my
bags, you can shut up.
Listen,
maybe we both need just some
time to figure this out.
I also need a break.
Okay.
So, I'm gonna leave if
that's what you want.
Okay.
See you in a week.
Wow, that was easy.
What now?
What are you doing?
I'm gonna burn
his fucking clothes!
Fuck, fuck.
Come on, come on,
come on, come on.
- Yes, there we go.
- That's not gonna work.
Yeah, it's gonna
work, you see?
There you go, there
you go, oh, oh!
Fuck, fuck!
Fuck, oh my God.
Just leave them here.
Okay.
The pathetic
attempt of burning
her husband's clothes
didn't satisfy Lena's need
of destruction.
James' decision to leave even
caused a brief
flickering or doubt.
As the cold water
ran over her body,
doubt became fear.
Lena?
Yeah?
Can I wear this dress?
Sure, just give me two
minutes, I'll be there.
Okay.
Maria
suggested a night out
and Lena gladly tagged along.
Maria had always
considered the attention
of men to be reassuring.
As long as she had her youth,
and her presence and her beauty,
she would always get by.
Lena was more reserved
in that matter,
but tried to follow her lead.
What are you doing?
You're still wearing
your wedding ring?
Yeah.
I thought you wanted
to have fun tonight.
I'm having fun, I'm dancing!
Take it off.
I, I don't wanna
lose it, come on.
I thought you didn't
care about money.
I don't.
Come on, I'll fix it.
One,
this would work.
- Alright, another round?
- Sure.
Maria and Lena
felt closer than ever before.
Hours went by, lost.
But all that seemed
to matter now
were the possibilities
of the moment.
"Follow your heart,
and you may shine."
What the fuck
does it even mean?
I have no idea,
what does yours say?
"The path to
everything is love."
Oh, God!
Well, yeah, right.
By the way, I had this really
weird dream last night.
I dreamt like either I
was wearing a wig, or,
I had just black
hair, I don't know.
Well, I think...
I was you, if that
makes any sense.
That's a very
interesting dream.
Yeah.
Oh, shit, I gotta go.
- I'm late for work.
- No!
- Yeah.
- No, don't leave me.
Don't, no, quit your job and
stay with me here, please.
Shut up.
Guys, where's my steak frites?
Enjoy.
Maria, a word, please?
Of course.
Listen, when you're on the
floor, you need to smile.
We sell food here, good
makes people happy, right?
- Yeah, okay.
- Do you like working here?
Yeah, I do, I do.
From what I understand,
you need this job.
No other fine dining
establishment is gonna hire you,
so please, adjust your attitude.
- Okay.
- So, let me see it.
Alright.
While
Maria was dealing
with an irrational boss and
the stress of making a living,
Lena sat at home
wondering about mortality.
She had always been fascinated
about life's vulnerability.
A fascination that could
quickly turn into obsession.
Especially when there's
not much else to do.
Bones.
Skin, and bones.
Blood.
White blood cells.
Inflammation.
Hives, pox?
Chicken pox.
Meningitis.
Castleman disease.
Crest disease, lyme disease.
Poems syndrome.
Liver failure.
Kidney failure.
Congenital heart block.
Lina?
Lina!
Um, it's actually Leh-na.
The doctor's
ready for you now.
The doctor will
be right with you.
Lena had seen
Dr. Hollis for a while now.
He was kind and patient,
and didn't seem to mind
that she visited him often.
Especially after
last year's incident
of bleeding out a
cluster of cells
that had formed a
fetus inside of her.
Hi, Lena.
- Hi, Doctor Hollis.
- What's going on?
Um,
I just feel all
drained of energy.
I have these headaches,
like right here
and sometimes up here.
I just don't feel that good.
How long has that
been happening?
Um, maybe two months?
Yeah.
Okay, let's take
a look at you.
That looks good.
Look to your left,
let's see.
Well,
you look good to me, I mean,
we can have the nurse
draw some blood,
see if there's any deficiencies,
but other than
that, you look fine.
Okay, yeah, yeah,
let's do that.
Okay.
Their
new living situation
has soon enough provided
a consoling pattern
which tightened
their friendship.
Waking up together
in the morning
and going out together at night.
Today, it was Maria whose
emotions were in turmoil.
Not only was her boss
a pain in the ass,
but her ex-lover had also tried
to call her several times.
My boss, he's so
sleazy, he's so annoying,
he gets on my
nerves all the time.
Ugh, I wish I could do
something about it, but,
he's gonna have me deported.
I'm sorry.
Yeah.
Maybe I should marry an
American just like you did.
Well, we saw how that goes.
Come on, I bet he's
calling you all the time.
This city's just so beautiful.
Is it though?
I remember when I was
a kid and I came here
for the first time on vacation.
I just thought the
city is so sterile,
it doesn't even smell.
Are you crazy?
New York stinks, everywhere.
Must have been a winter holiday.
Christmas shopping.
You spoiled bitch.
Ow!
Come with me, I
have an idea, come.
- Where are you going?
- Just come.
Are you ready?
- Yes.
- One,
- Two, three.
- Two three!
One more!
Enjoy, ladies.
Thank you.
Cheers!
- Another round?
- Sure.
Two more.
- Fuck.
- What?
The guy you're
hooking up with,
he's right over there.
- Where?
- There.
Just ignore him.
He's right there,
he just saw you.
I wanna know more about you.
Did you ever have a proper job?
Are you serious right now?
Yeah, like a proper
job, not advertising...
- Are we really doing this?
- Mm-hm.
Oh, um...
Actually, um, yeah, I once
worked on an assembly line.
One summer, when I was 16,
my dad wanted my sister and me
to experience "the real world,"
which is hilarious
'cause he's spending
all his life in
conference rooms.
Actually, he wanted us
to be lawyers like him,
but yeah, so.
I wanna know more
about the assembly line.
Of course.
It was not that bad, I
mean, the actual labor.
The worst part was that
they were listening
to the same radio
station all day long
and there were only so many pop
songs they played, you know?
That, and they talked
about soap operas a lot.
Poor you.
You were once in a
soap opera, weren't you?
Yes, yes, I was.
What was that name again?
- And that means?
- Heart On Fire.
- Oh my God.
- Yeah.
Oh, fuck they're coming over.
Good evening, ladies.
Hi.
Hello.
Would it be cool
if we joined you?
Sure, hi, my name is Lena.
- Rick.
- Nice to meet you.
Hi, I'm Palo.
- Hi, Lena.
- I'm Maria.
- Maria.
- Maria, nice to meet you.
What are you guys drinking?
We had shots.
Yeah, you care
for another one?
- Sure.
- Yeah.
What are you drinking?
- Vodka?
- Sure, alright.
Could we have four more please?
Lena woke up alone.
Neither James nor
Maria were there.
The apartment was awfully quiet
and she felt rather
small and unimportant.
When she closed on eye,
and then the other,
per perspective would shift.
At least one thing
offered her some comfort.
Lena thought of her childhood
and how things were
a little better then.
Lina?
Lina!
It's still Leh-na.
Okay.
- Hi, Lena.
- Hi, Dr. Hollis.
Your blood work is not in yet,
is there anything
else I can do for you?
Um...
Uh, yeah, okay, um...
Maria had
a stressful morning.
Her ex-lover, Palo, had
left her several angry
and condescending
messages the night before.
And even though she
liked his passion,
she disliked the ownership
he took over her.
Can I get you anything else?
- Maria, what's up?
- Hi.
How are you?
That's a cute outfit
today, I love it.
- Thank you.
- Is this 100% cotton,
because myself,
I'm a cotton man,
I love 100% cotton,
that's all I wear,
- you know?
- Okay, I'm really busy, Bill,
- bye.
- Alright, see ya.
Hello, may I take your order?
Surprise.
What are you doing here?
- Quit your job.
- I can't.
Yes, you gotta quit your job.
Shut up, I told you, I can't.
What do you want?
Well then, I'll have
the lobster salad, please.
- Are you serious?
- Chop, chop.
I'm gonna spit in your salad.
Both feeling
rather unhappy by themselves
and only happy together,
Maria and Lena decided to
make Lena's dream come true.
They decided to become
the other person.
At least for one night.
"Content is happiness.
Happiness is content."
Okay.
That's interesting.
"What's meant to be
will always find a way."
Hm.
And it's interesting
I get that today.
Why?
I have an audition tomorrow.
Oh my God, that's great!
Yeah, yeah, I know.
What is it for?
It's for a space film.
- Cool!
- Yeah.
Congratulations.
Thank you, I mean, I
didn't get it yet, but,
you know, it'll work out.
Cool, I'm happy for you.
But you promised, you
promised you would stay
with me forever, fuck.
Maria
had the feeling
that this was finally
the opportunity
she had been waiting for.
There was a better version
of herself out there,
and she was close
to becoming it,
if she could only find a
way to calm her nerves.
But you promised.
You promised you
would never leave me.
You promised you would
stay with me forever
in the outer realm space...
Fuck!
Space station.
Space station, space station.
No, no, no, outer
realm space station.
But you promised, you promised
you would never leave me.
You promised you would
stay with me forever
in the outer realm
space station,
this is, who the
fuck wrote this?
But you promised, you
promised you would never
leave me.
Fuck.
Lena!
I've got nothing to wear!
I mean, look,
this could work, no?
Wow.
It's futuristic and feminine.
What was the role
description again?
A space steward
determined, by sensual.
Well, this is totally
determined but sensual.
I know, but, you know,
it's too expensive, I can't.
Oh, no, I want you to wear it.
Come on, you can even
keep it if you want.
Thank you.
And do you need any
accessories, any jewelry?
Yeah, but that's,
you know, too much
Not at all, just have
a look, I got plenty.
Okay, thank you!
Wow, this is, this is perfect!
And there's like
this necklace, maybe?
Oh, sure.
Yep!
While Lena was happy
to have helped Maria,
she had her own
business to tend to.
Lina?
Hm...
Your blood work came
back, it looks great.
It's normal,
everything is wonderful.
You're healthy,
just keep trying.
Maybe I'm not the
right doctor for you.
Oh, really?
You know what?
Forget about this, fuck this.
That evening,
both Lena and Maria
seemed awfully tense.
Want more wine?
Who are you texting with?
Don't worry, it's
not your husband.
- Ouch.
- I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry, it's
just this audition,
I'm so stressed about it
and the lines are so bad.
If you want, I can't
rehearse with you.
No, no, actually, I'd
rather go to bed, I'm sorry.
Good night.
Hm, "Fall in love
with your life."
Gotta go, gotta
go to my audition.
Okay, good luck,
break a leg, huh?
See ya later.
Maria,
we're ready for you.
Okay, let's
start with the slate,
what's your name?
My name is Maria Kalitsi.
Hi,
Maria, how tall are you?
I'm five foot six.
Okay, I'd
like to see your profile,
can you turn to
the left, please?
Lovely, and to the right?
Okay, fantastic, let's jump
right in, are you ready?
I'm ready.
And action.
But, you promised me.
You promised you
would stay forever
with me in the outer
realm space station.
But that was
before everything happened.
I don't think I
love you anymore.
Okay, thank you.
Maria, there's one more thing.
You know this love scene,
the one where you're
supposed to be giving the BJ?
Yeah?
The director
would like to know
if you could show him
what you would do.
So, here's a prop.
What do you mean?
Uh,
just, you know,
if you could like show us with
the bottle what you would do.
Are you serious?
Just hold
it up towards your mouth.
While
Maria was auditioning,
Lena had time to think.
Lena felt that they
were both drifting apart
and that she wanted to have
an honest conversation
with Maria.
Lena also wanted to come clean,
and tell Maria what really
happened with James.
Hey.
Hey!
- How did it go?
- Shit.
- Are you sure?
- Yes, I'm sure!
What happened?
Maria!
Hi.
Oh, fuck.
Um, Maria,
um, that's my sister.
I am so sorry!
In English: Are you two lesbian?
You and my sister,
are you lovers?
Julia!
I'm sorry.
Okay, you know what, guys?
I better leave you two alone.
Maria, you don't have
to go, I'm sorry, Maria?
Mhm.
I am so sorry.
While Lena
was still contemplating
her complicated relationship
with her sister,
Maria felt like
burning down a house
or destroying an
expensive Chinese vase.
Anything would do that
could lighten the anger
and disappointment she
felt growing inside her.
So, she first turned to
alcohol, and then to sex,
two things that had worked
out for her in the past.
Another round?
It's on the house.
Sounds tempting, but um...
I think I shouldn't.
Yeah, I know that feeling.
I do serve more than
drinks though, you know.
Maria
stopped at a playground,
trying to remember how easy
it was when she was a child.
But she couldn't.
My ball.
What, you're not
gonna apologize?
You just hit me.
Where are you manners?
You know what?
Here's your ball, bye now.
Bitch.
When they
woke up the next morning,
they were both still so
absorbed in their own troubles
that they could not
even face each other.
Maria, what's up?
- Hi.
- How you doing?
- Good.
- You look so great today.
I love your hair, are you doing
something different with it?
- You look fantastic.
- Mm-hm, I'm really busy,
- I'm so sorry, Bill.
- Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah,
well, you know, alright, see ya.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
You know, you look
so familiar to me.
Yeah?
Yeah, do I know
you from somewhere?
Um, no, no I don't think so.
Are you Greek?
Yes, yes, I'm Greek, yeah.
Okay, um...
You're on that TV show!
Yeah, right?
Yeah, I used to watch it
every summer in Greece
with my grandparents, my
grandparents are from Kefalonia.
Yeah, what are you doing here?
Um, I'm working here.
Yeah, why are
you waiting tables?
I moved to New York.
- Maria?
- Yes?
For the last time,
you need to be friendly.
I am friendly.
No, you're a pretty girl.
This city is filled
with pretty girls.
Girls who would
love the opportunity
to work at my restaurant.
Girls who would personally
thank me for the opportunity.
Personally thank me
for the opportunity.
Okay, that's it.
Come on, Maria,
you don't need to...
- I quit.
- You don't have to do this.
Fuck you.
Maria, come back, Maria!
Hey.
Hi.
Can I buy you a drink?
Sure.
No,
please, please.
- What?
- Stop.
Did I do
something wrong?
No, I'm sorry.
Please, I can't.
What?
I'm sorry,
I just can't, I can't.
Can I at least jerk off on you?
Lena!
Lena, I quit my job!
Lena, Lena!
I quit my job!
- What?
- I quit my...
Hi.
Oh, are we having a party now?
Uh, sorry, I didn't
know you had company.
Well, actually, he
was just about to leave.
- Oh.
- Okay.
Know what?
I think we should
go to the Hamptons.
- Now?
- Yes, now.
I know this guy, he has a house.
Let's go.
Hm.
Come on, we need
to get out of the city.
Okay.
That's disgusting,
you're disgusting.
- Here.
- No, no, no!
No, show me.
Oh, I can't, it'd be like,
- no, no, no, I don't...
- Are you cold?
That's a man horse.
No?
Come on.
I'll do a turtle.
- Wait.
- Okay, I'm waiting.
Maria!
Okay, this is it.
Maria, what are you doing?
- Come on, get up.
- What if someone's home?
There's no one home,
he has like five houses,
that's why he used to
bring me here all the time.
- Are you kidding me?
- Come on, it's gonna be fine.
- Trust me.
- Oh my God.
What's going on?
Come on.
Fuck, the keys, he
always leaves the keys.
Okay.
Maria!
Fuck, fuck.
Shit, shit, shit.
What?
Fuck.
Shit, shit,
shit, shit, shit, ugh!
What?
Tada!
Did you just break in?
Uh, not exactly.
Are you bleeding?
Eh, not really,
come on, come in.
Shit.
No, I mean, I totally get it,
my sister and I, we're just
very different, you know?
I mean, she likes
to please my father
and loves her conservative
way of life, and...
I totally respect that.
No, you don't.
No, I don't, I'm an asshole.
You know what?
I actually think she
has a crush on James.
Perfect timing.
I mean, now that her
sister is a lesbian.
Yeah.
Good for her.
No, I mean it, maybe
we should consider.
I mean, I'm having a
great time with you,
and you're having
fun with me, right?
Always.
See?
So...
should we, should we,
should we do this?
Yeah, yeah, let's do it.
Let's do it.
- Let's do it.
- Oh, okay.
Let's do it.
You're very pretty.
You're very pretty also.
Thank you.
- No.
- No, I'm sorry.
I'm, yeah, I'm
definitely into guys.
Being out
in the Hamptons seemed
to make everything
so much easier.
Lena swam in the cold water
for hours, clearing her head,
while Maria was lying in the
hot sun thinking of nothing.
Oh, it's cold.
It's nice, no?
Ugh, teenagers.
I know.
- I hate them.
- I get it.
They always feel
so, invincible.
"Remisuri"
What?
It's an old Bavarian word,
meaning the
exuberance of children
and the absence of parents.
That's one word?
Yeah, it's pretty
good, isn't it?
Okay, remi...
"Remisuri"
"Suri" like the
daughter of Tom Cruise.
Well, in that case,
I'm pretty "remisuri" myself.
I think our whole
generation is.
Yeah, you know,
when I was born,
my mother named me Maria
after Maria Callas.
No shit.
Yeah, she actually did that.
She used to say I was
the prettiest girl
in the neighborhood.
Once my mom told me my
beauty's a currency,
and that I could actually
pay with my beauty.
Wow.
Yeah, she's amazing.
When I was 14, there was
this boy that fancied me,
and he followed me home.
My mom was at work,
so, when we got in,
he said I was the prettiest
girl he had ever seen.
He was so nice, so I
gave him a blowjob.
In the kitchen.
My mom was pretty as well,
but she got knocked up.
She was so proud of me when
I got that shitty soap opera.
But I wanted to
be a real actress,
I want to be a real actress,
that's why I came to New York.
But now, karma fires back.
Now, I have to give
blowjobs in audition rooms.
God, I prefer the
one in my kitchen.
You know, I was
pregnant last year.
I lost it.
Lena, I'm sorry.
I don't even know if
I want to put children
into this world anyway.
I'm so sorry.
Oh man, you know
what your problem is?
What is my problem?
Tell me.
You have to say that
you are an actress
before you can be an actress.
But, that's not true.
No, I mean, you have to say,
"Hi, my name is Maria,
I'm an actress."
But, that's not true, I...
I've never been paid
for anything I've done,
and I haven't worked
in such a long time.
Oh come on,
money's so overrated.
That's easy for you to say.
But, I'm gonna tell
you a little secret.
You actually need money
to survive in this world,
like pay your rent...
Really?
And go shopping.
Shocker, I kind of knew that.
That's progress.
No, I mean I'm serious,
you can't have money
define who you are.
I mean, listen to me,
you can't have money
define who you are.
'Cause money...
Money makes you lazy.
The whole fucking world
can crumble around you
and you still don't make a move
because of all your
comfortable money.
It's like...
It's like comfortable glue.
Hm.
I used to sniff glue
in kindergarten.
Well, that explains a lot.
Yeah, it probably does.
I'm hungry.
These are really good.
- Mm-hm, more wine?
- Yes, please.
- Another oyster?
- Yeah, thank you.
Hey, did you see the
captain over there?
Yeah, nice hat.
Do you think he's peacocking?
Well, actually, I think
he might be old school.
He might come over here
and pay for our lunch.
Okay.
Hi there, Captain,
how are you?
Oh, well, hello.
Hi, you wanna join us?
I'd love to, may
I buy you lunch?
Oh, that would be
lovely, thank you.
And maybe after lunch,
we could have a drink.
On my boat.
- Oh, you have a boat!
- Sure.
- Yeah, that would be great.
Alright.
Bubbly.
Thank you.
- Top it off a little bit?
- Sure.
Why not?
Thanks.
Cheers.
Should I put on some music?
You know, why don't
we just get naked?
Alright,
- yeah.
- Yeah.
Wow.
Nice.
Close your eyes.
Mm.
Keep your eyes closed,
count from 10 to one
and imagine your wildest
dreams coming true.
Mm.
10,
nine...
Seven...
Sex...
Uh, I mean six.
Five, four...
Hey, hey!
My hat!
Where are you going?
Hey!
My hat!
Lena,
Please, come home now.
I know you don't wanna
talk to me but just...
Please, come home
After the
episode with the captain,
Lena developed an inkling
that their forlornness
was coming to and end.
She realized that
nothing had changed
and that she didn't
want change after all.
Meanwhile, Maria
was absorbing nature
and nature seemed to absorb her.
Life had always felt like
an abundance of opportunity,
too overwhelming
to make a choice.
Now, nothing seemed
to matter anymore.
The wide space made Lena
feel small and insignificant.
She longed for the city
where everything had a system
and she knew her place.
Maria, however, felt
at ease with herself.
She felt like a part
of something bigger.
And for the first
time in a long while,
she was happy and hopeful.
Don't look.
No, I'm not looking.
Don't look, no cheating.
Don't look.
Okay, here we go, here we go,
- just one more step.
- Alright, here?
There you go, and tada!
You made fire!
- I made fire!
- Wow!
But that's not why we're here.
- Why?
- We are here to do
a little burning ritual
so you can free yourself.
Okay, you ready?
One, two, three.
Yay!
Okay, so free yourself, come on.
Burn it, burn it,
burn it, burn it, burn it,
you have to free yourself,
free yourself, come on!
Burn it, burn it,
burn it, burn it!
Do it, do it, burn it, burn it!
Yay!
Okay, there's more, okay.
No, stop, stop!
- One, two...
- Stop!
What?
What the fuck is wrong with you?
What's wrong with you?
He never cheated on me.
What?
He never cheated on me, okay?
I made it up.
He never has, he never will
be, it's just not who he is.
Why would you do that?
I don't know.
You don't know.
I know why.
Because you're so
fucking ungrateful.
You just like to play around
with people's feelings.
You're so wise and you know
everything, you have everything.
I fucking quit my
job because of you!
Oh, don't put this on
me, you hated your job!
What a dreamer you are.
Always dream big and
then you get cold feet.
What a rebel.
You can never
commit to anything.
Always on your fucking
phone, always withdrawn.
You're so afraid.
No, actually worse...
You're a coward.
I'm a coward?
You're worse, you know why?
Because you destroy everything,
you just like to destroy
everything because you're bored.
You have everything, you
have the perfect life,
the perfect husband,
the perfect marriage!
You don't even know what
you're talking about, okay?
You're just jealous.
You wanna know how I feel?
You wanna know
how I really feel?
Fucking lost.
Lost in this apartment, in
my marriage, in this world
where people are killing each
other for religion, whatever.
And all of my shit?
I can't do anything with it.
Can I be a mother?
No. Can I make a difference?
No. And it doesn't even matter
because people will
still kill each other
and starve, and drown in oceans.
And you know what?
No one,
no one expects
anything of me anyway.
So, it's all about you again.
You are such an asshole.
You really are a
fucking spoiled bitch.
- Fuck you.
- Maria,
Maria!
Maria was
upset and confused.
She couldn't believe
how naive she had been.
At the same time, she felt
a strange sense of relief.
Lena had the feeling
that this week
actually had helped
them after all.
That they had found
something together.
A possibility of honesty,
a chance to accept.
She was wondering
if Maria would agree
and forgive her after all.
Maybe, if she explained
herself one more time.
Subtitles by explosiveskull
www.OpenSubtitles.org