(DOG BARKING IN DISTANCE)
(BARKING CONTINUES)
Oh, shut up, Murphy.
(GARAGE DOOR CLOSING)
(DOOR SQUEAKS)
(BARKING STOPS)
Is someone there?
(HEAVY BREATHING)
(BREATHING GROWS LOUDER)
(MUFFLED SCREAMING)
(LABOURED BREATHING)
I'm not going to hurt you.
No, no, no, no.
I don't want to hurt you.
I just want to talk to you.
(GASPING BREATHS)
(MUFFLED)
Your hand is...
(GASPING)
Now, nothing's going to happen...
unless you do something foolish.
Then I'll kill you.
I've already killed twice, so I
won't hesitate to do it again.
Do we understand each other?
Good.
You've got a small waist.
Measurements...
34...
22...
(WHIMPERING)
35. Right?
(WHEEZING LAUGHTER)
Oh, I know a lot about you,
Miss Sherwood.
What do you want?
You.
I'll scream. Somebody will hear me.
This is a dead-end street...
You won't scream.
And I know what kind
of a street this is.
(GASPING)
Why...
Why don't we go in the house?
- There's nobody home.
- Yes, I know.
Your sister's staying with a friend.
Louella Hendricks.
206 Palo Alto Street.
She left at 7:23.
And you left for
your party at 7:32.
You see?
I do know a good deal about you,
just about everything
there is to know.
I think that we'd be more
comfortable in the house.
And you could see
what I look like.
No. No.
If you could identify me,
you might be tempted.
That way, we'd both lose out.
You'd be dead,
and I'd be out a hundred
thousand dollars.
A hundred thousand dollars?
That's the figure.
If you know so much about me,
you know I don't have any money.
Of course you have.
You've got a whole bank full of it.
You've got me...
pretty well cased.
Isn't that the word?
That's the word.
Now, your 16-year-old sister Toby
goes to the George Washington
High School.
Her present boyfriend,
a lad named David,
picks her up for school
just before you leave for work.
She has lunch at the school
or at a place called the Hangout...
with some of her friends.
She's done at 3:15.
If Dave can't bring her back,
she comes home by bus.
In any case, she's home by 4 o'clock.
Now, that's an hour and
a half she's by herself.
All by herself.
Your sister's a very
attractive little girl.
What do you want me to do?
That's better.
It's very simple. When the time's
right, you're going to rob a bank.
- That's impossible.
- Not at all.
Now, I just wanted to meet you
at close range tonight, so to speak.
But I'll be with you again.
And then I'll explain just
what you're gonna do...
and how you're gonna do it.
If everything works out right
and you don't cause any trouble,
I'll even cut you in for 20%.
Oh, you're very generous.
Don't provoke me, Kelly.
Don't provoke me!
If you don't want the money,
that's your affair.
But you've got no choice in this.
You're gonna do as I say.
If you try to tell anybody or...
notify the police,
I'll know it.
I'm not the only one
watching you.
Is that clear?
All right.
(WHIMPERING)
All right, Kelly.
Get in the car.
(CAR DOOR OPENING)
Look straight ahead, Kelly,
and don't turn around.
Close the door.
Straight ahead, Kelly.
I haven't hurt you this time because
I think you're going to cooperate.
But remember, one false move...
and I'll kill you.
Or I'll kill your sister.
Stay where you are
for ten minutes.
(GARAGE DOOR SQUEAKING OPEN)
Goodnight, Kelly.
You'll hear from me again.
(GARAGE DOOR SQUEAKING SHUT)
Oh!
(SOBBING)
Oh, God!
(SWITCHBOARD BUZZING)
F.B.I.
I'll connect you with an agent.
(PHONE BUZZING)
Yes? Yes, put her on.
This is Ripley speaking.
May I have your name, please?
- Your phone number?
- (PHONE CLATTERING)
Hello? Miss Sherwood?
(DIAL TONE BUZZING)
(HANDSET SETTLING IN CRADLE)
(HEAVY BREATHING)
(MOANING)
Oh.
(GROANING)
I knew you'd try to
call the police, Kelly.
(WHEEZING BREATH)
Now, I allowed you this one mistake
because I wanted to teach you a lesson.
(WHEEZING BREATH)
I hope you've learned
that lesson, Kelly.
Because, next time,
I'll kill you for sure.
(GASPING)
You understand?
(WHIMPERING)
(GROANING)
(DOOR OPENING)
(DOOR CLOSING)
All right, we'll phone
all the Sherwood's in the book.
Here, you take San Francisco.
You take Marin County.
- I'll take Oakland.
- What do we tell them?
Tell them we were talking to a
Miss Sherwood and we got cut off.
Don't tell them who you are.
If you don't get a lead, hang up fast.
Right.
She said someone
was going to kill her?
Yeah. You know, she seemed to know
what she was talking about.
(DOG BARKING)
(BARKING CONTINUES)
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
MAN:
Hello? Miss Sherwood?
Hello.
Hold it. Rip, got your party.
- Sorry, I must have the wrong number.
- Mr. Ripley wants to talk to you.
Miss Sherwood?
No, I...
No, I haven't gone to bed yet.
I... I was just doing some
things around the house.
Is somebody listening?
Well, I don't know.
I'm not sure.
- Inside the house?
- No.
Outside?
Well, I...
I honestly don't know, but it...
it's certainly possible.
All right.
You answer as best you can.
You say a man's going to kill you?
Yes, that's right.
He was there when
the phone went dead?
Mm-hmm.
I see.
Did he do anything to you?
Well, you...
You certainly...
certainly know all the answers.
- Are you hurt?
- No, not really.
I'm used to those long
hours at the bank.
She lives in Twin Peaks.
Street's a dead end.
Is the address there
100 St. Germain Street?
Yes.
We'd like to come out there.
No!
Er, no, Dick.
Er, er...
I tell you what, if you...
If you find the lighter,
why don't you bring it
to the bank tomorrow?
Is the bank in the downtown area?
Yes.
I found it, erm,
around the corner on Post Street,
around the corner from the bank.
- Crocker-Anglo Bank?
- That's right.
All right, you're doing fine now.
Is anything going to happen
to you or at the bank tonight?
Er, no, I don't think so.
I still think we'd
better come out there.
No! Absolutely not, Dick.
It... It really isn't necessary.
You mean it might be putting you
in some kind of danger, huh?
I knew you'd understand.
All right, I tell you what you do.
Leave the phone off the hook.
I'll arrange to keep the
connection open all night.
Oh, that would be wonderful.
Thank you, Dick.
Goodnight.
Oh, Janie, get me
the special agent
and Captain Moreno
of Bureau of Inspectors.
She says if we go out there,
we might put her in danger.
It's a dead-end street, and if he's
watching the house, then...
All right, let's stake out the bank
as soon as we can.
Get me Sillenga,
get me Ryan, get me Taylor.
Send a car out to St. Germain.
This spot right here.
Tell them to just take it easy
and keep outta sight.
Are you there?
Yes, ma'am.
Car ten in, please.
POLICE RADIO:
Car 10 in, please.
Car ten.
Nothing here. Just wanted
to know if you're stationary
We're stationary, all right.
- How's it going?
- Everything's quiet.
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
(CAR RADIO PLAYING LIGHT JAZZ)
(HORN HONKING)
Oh, come on, Lou,
why don't you come by the pool?
- Who's gonna be there?
- Oh, you know. Everybody. All the kids.
- It'll be kicks. Come on.
- Hi, Sis.
RADIO D.J.: It's a beautiful
day in San Francisco.
The high will be
around 72 degrees
with a bit of fog
expected tonight.
♪ Now, how about a little music? ♪
(CAR RADIO PLAYING POP MUSIC)
(SCHOOL BELL RINGING)
Toby.
Er, what are you doing
after school today?
- Why?
- I just want to know.
- You want me to do something?
- No. I just want to know.
Uh-huh.
Now, Toby...
Sis, is something wrong?
No, I... I just didn't get
much sleep last night.
Well, Dave said something
about going over to the park.
- And he'll bring you home?
- Sure.
- Sis?
- What?
Look, I thought
we had a deal, huh?
No secrets.
Tell each other everything.
Well, I'll tell you all about it tonight.
But now, Toby, I want you
to promise me something.
I don't want you to be by yourself
at any time today.
Do you understand that?
Sounds pretty serious.
Well, it's not serious yet.
But it could be
unless you do exactly as I say.
Now, if Dave gets you home
before I get there,
I want you to sit in the car
and wait with him, all right?
Gee, Sis.
Now, Toby, I'm going to be late.
Now just trust me
and do as I say,
and I'll explain it all
to you when I get home.
All right.
Bye-bye.
Let's put a surveillance
on the sister at the high school.
If he's threatening the older one,
he may use the younger one as a lever.
Better keep it loose.
- Yes.
We can't run the risk of
having the subject spot us.
But tell the agents to keep a close
watch for a counter-surveillance.
You never know, he may be
expecting something like this.
Right.
- What's the bank manager like?
- Fellow by the name of Burkhardt.
He's reliable.
We've already checked him out.
All right. Let's take him
into our confidence
when we get all the
information from the victim.
But no one else in the bank.
All right.
I'll get over there right now.
- Oh, Mr. Ripley.
- Yes?
There's a Miss Nancy Ashton
waiting in the conference.
- Nancy Ashton?
- Yes, she asked to see an agent.
I see. All right, thank you.
Miss Ashton?
I'm John Ripley.
How do you do, Mr. Ripley?
Won't you sit down?
Well, now what can I do for you?
Well, I...
Oh, I really...
Really, I shouldn't
be taking up your time.
I have a very dear friend
who's in trouble.
Thank you.
- Oh, would you like one?
- No, thank you.
I, erm...
I told my friend that I would
do whatever I could to help.
And I said I was coming
down here to F.B.I. to...
ask some questions.
I hope this isn't too much
of an inconvenience for you.
I can't be too specific.
Suppose you tell me what you can.
Well,
she's gotten involved with a man,
and he's not...
He's a pretty terrible man really.
He's caused her a lot of trouble.
And I told her if she came down
here and talked with you people...
Well, I mean...
Would she be prosecuted
for something she couldn't help?
What kind of a crime, Miss Ashton?
It's a serious one.
Embezzlement?
Extortion? Blackmail?
We're an investigative agency
only, Miss Ashton.
We turn our facts over to
the United States Attorney.
It's for him to decide.
You mean...
- you couldn't...
- Make a deal?
No, Miss Ashton,
we don't make deals.
No promises.
But I would suggest, if your friend really
wants to make a break with this man,
she do it now before
she becomes more involved.
If she has committed a crime,
she'll be prosecuted, of course.
But then the jury will take into
consideration any mitigating circumstances.
Thank you.
You've been very kind, Mr. Ripley.
I'll tell my friend.
I'd like to buy you a drink
some evening.
I'll survive if you say "no".
No, I'm very flattered.
Mm.
But you're a very busy man
and you don't have much time.
I understand.
Goodbye.
Goodbye, Miss Ashton.
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
WOMAN: This little chick comes
on like a registered nurse.
We get about a block away
from the house, and... Whammo!
Penny, I almost didn't
get to work tonight.
Wow, what a miserable night.
You don't believe this baby-sitter.
I mean, you don't believe her.
- Hi, Kelly.
- Morning.
You look a little ragged
around the edges.
I didn't get much sleep last night.
Miss Sherwood.
Yes, Mr. Burkhardt?
Would you please go
into the conference room?
Yes, of course.
Miss Sherwood?
My name's Ripley.
I'm the agent who spoke to you
on the phone last night.
Oh, yes, I'm glad to see you.
Why don't we sit down, hmm?
Is there something wrong?
No. It's just that every time
I speak to somebody on the phone,
I get this sort of mental image
of what they're supposed to look like.
Usually I'm wrong.
Your case is no exception.
- I guess everybody does that.
- Yeah, I guess they do.
Well, now about your problem.
Yes.
You know,
I... I just can't believe it.
It's hard to adjust.
I can't think.
Well, I'd be surprised
if you reacted any other way.
You know, I didn't think
he'd do anything violent.
I mean,
he scared the wits out of me.
But for some reason, I didn't
believe he was completely serious.
And then he comes in the house
and catches me phoning you.
Now the first thing we need
is a description of this man.
I don't know what he looks like.
I never saw him.
That's going to make
things a little difficult.
- But I'd certainly recognise his voice.
- Yeah, what else?
Well, there's something
wrong with his breathing.
What do you mean by that?
Well, it...
It sounded like, erm,
like asthmatic breathing.
My sister, Toby, had a kind of
mild asthmatic condition for about a year.
And it sounded like that.
Sort of... laboured and wheezing.
What did he say?
That he wanted me to steal a hundred
thousand dollars from the bank.
And that if I didn't...
he'd kill me and my sister.
He said he'd killed twice before, and
he wouldn't hesitate to do it again.
He said that he's not
the only one watching me,
that he would know my every move.
And...
And that...
if I contacted the police...
Did you drive your sister
to school this morning?
Yes.
Tell her about this?
No, but...
You see, Toby and I are very close,
and she's a very intuitive young lady.
She guessed something was wrong,
and I'm afraid I didn't manage
to carry it off very well.
She knows it's serious, or it could be.
She doesn't know what it is.
But I promised I'd tell her tonight.
No. No, I don't think you'd better.
Suppose you let me tell her.
Besides, I want to give her
some instructions.
All right.
Do... Do you think
that it's... it's possible he...
that he knows you're involved?
No, I doubt it.
You see, we really can't tell
until he tries to contact you.
If he does try to contact you,
then he doesn't know.
And if he doesn't contact me?
You will be well protected.
It's not gonna be easy.
No, it's not.
As a matter of fact,
it's going to get a lot tougher.
He's going to work on you
and your sister
until you just may decide to go
along with him rather than us.
Oh no. If I do this thing,
I'll do it all the way.
You don't have to worry
about anything like that.
Fine. But just remember this.
If he knows as much about you
as he obviously does,
and he has a very definite plan,
he's probably very clever.
And he knows it's going to take a
lot to make you steal $100,000.
Now, he may institute
a reign of terror...
that will make you agree
to do almost anything.
You mean he'll try.
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
Good morning.
Morning.
See you next week.
Miss Sherwood.
You have a phone call,
a police lieutenant.
A police lieutenant?
He says it's important.
Take it on your phone.
This is Miss Sherwood.
Hello, Miss Sherwood.
Yes?
You made a serious mistake, Kelly.
You talked with the police.
No. No, I didn't.
Shut up!
What do you think,
this is some kind of a game?
I'm going to teach you a lesson.
I think Toby would be
interested in a man like me.
Oh, no!
Please, please.
(SCREAMING)
Rat fink!
Whoo!
Wow!
I don't like you.
- You love me.
- Oh, I hate you!
Oh, come on.
Come on now.
Come on, Dave.
I love you, too.
Come on.
Oh.
Are you ready for this hair?
What's the matter with it?
It's wet. That's what's
the matter with it.
So what?
So you haven't got any.
It doesn't make any difference.
I feel like a Coke.
I'm broke.
I'm not.
Crazy.
"Kelly, meet me at the Roaring 20's
tomorrow night, 11 o'clock."
Why didn't he just
call her on the phone?
Well, he wanted her to know
how close he was to her sister.
You know, if we just knew
what we were looking for.
Tall? Short? Seventeen?
Seventy?
A lot of people around
that swimming pool.
Any one of them
could have left that note.
Well, I'll get this off.
Maybe they can identify
the type, the paper,
the ink, something.
I'll call Bill Varney
over at the Roaring 20's.
(SWITCHBOARD BUZZING)
F.B.I.
One moment.
(PHONE BUZZES)
Yes?
OPERATOR: I've got a
Nancy Ashton on the line.
All right, put her on.
Hello, Mr. Ripley?
About that matter...
my friend.
It's important that I see you,
but I can't come to the office.
Er, well, look, I'm quite busy right now.
Do you mind if I send another agent?
I'd prefer if it were you.
And believe me, Mr. Ripley,
it's important.
It's just possible that...
my friend's life is at stake.
All right.
What's the address there?
2632 Larkin.
And, please...
Come as soon as possible.
I can't help it.
I'm frightened.
Be there in an hour.
Wonderful.
Oh...
Don't be shocked.
I work in my apartment, and I have
a rather unusual occupation.
I'm fairly well conditioned
to shock, Miss Ashton.
I'll see you in an hour.
Goodbye.
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
- Yes?
- This is Ripley, Miss Sherwood
Oh, yes, hello.
We're just getting ready
to go to bed.
Everything all right?
Yeah, everything's fine.
I just talked to our agents
up at your neighbours'.
Now, you get a good night's sleep.
Don't worry.
- Thank you.
- Goodnight
Goodnight.
Who was that?
- That was Mr. Ripley.
- Oh.
- He's pretty interesting.
- You think so, huh?
- Well, don't you?
- Mmm, yes, he is.
- Er, Kel.
- Hmm?
Do you think this phantom
asthmatic really means it?
I mean, if you cross him,
do you think he'll do something?
Yes, I think he really means it.
But Mr. Ripley and his men aren't
going to let anything happen.
Well, what if they don't
find out who the guy is?
Oh, they'll find out.
The F.B.I.'s a very
efficient organisation.
Yeah, but in time, I mean.
Suppose you meet the guy
tomorrow night, and he says,
"Okay, Kelly. Tomorrow morning
you steal that hundred thousand dollars."
I said the F.B.I.'s an efficient
organisation, not Kelly Sherwood.
I just follow instructions
and do what they tell me.
Just like you're gonna do.
Sure.
That's why you can't forget
for one minute.
I mean, one mistake, one slip...
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
Hello?
(HEAVY BREATHING)
Hello? Hello?
- Who was it?
- I don't know.
- It was him.
- Well, what did he say?
- He didn't say anything.
We just had a phone call.
I guess you heard it.
We're going to bed now.
I left the porch light on
like you told me.
Control, this is unit two.
Victim just checked in,
going to bed.
She just got a call.
Might have been suspect.
Otherwise, everything okay here.
(DOORBELL BUZZING)
Miss Ashton.
Miss Ashton?
(SCOFFING)
What kind of a place is this?
She said she had
an unusual occupation.
I guess she repairs or makes
mannequins or something.
Well, look, old friend,
if she decided to break the date,
I think we'd better get the...
There's nobody here.
I think you're wrong.
- Is that Nancy Ashton?
- Yes.
Then, I'll call
the Bureau of Inspectors.
- What's going on here?
- Who are you?
I happen to own this building.
Who are you?
BRADLEY:
Captain Moreno, please.
- F.B.I.
- F.B.I.?
Hello, Frank. This is Owen Bradley.
I'm with Ripley.
Listen,
we've got a homicide for you.
Homicide?
That's right.
(SIREN WAILING)
I don't know.
I... I don't know.
I was coming home
and I saw the door was open,
and the man was here and
the other one on the phone,
and... I don't know.
All right, Mr. Cutter.
You'd better go to your
apartment and take it easy.
Yes.
She was obviously strangled
before she was hanged.
Dead about an hour.
That's all I can tell you right now.
Excuse me.
There obviously
wasn't any girlfriend.
She was probably gonna
tell me that tonight.
She made up her mind too late.
This got anything to do
with the Sherwood case?
No, I don't think so.
Why?
Just wondered.
I got a call last night.
We've got an informant
named Jim Durger.
Everybody calls him 'Popcorn'.
I don't guess you can really
call him a stool pigeon.
He considers himself
a newspaperman.
Circulates around the crumb joints,
picks up a little news here and there.
He'll sell it to us
for five or ten bucks.
You mean he knows
about the Sherwood case?
Mm-hmm.
And I just wondered,
one thing right after the other,
there might be some connection.
BRADLEY: Rip?
- Hmm?
This was in one of her purses.
RIPLEY: Well, I was wrong.
There is a connection.
(CHARLESTON MUSIC PLAYING)
(AUDIENCE LAUGHING)
(LAUGHTER CONTINUES)
Evening, Captain.
I've got a new partner.
This is Mr. Ripley.
I'm glad to know you, Mr. Ripley.
You're new, aren't you?
Nah, he's been at it quite a while.
I hear you haven't
been feeling too good.
Oh.
Doctor says if I was a building,
he'd condemn me.
What have you got on the bank job?
Oh, about fifteen dollars' worth.
All right.
Well, I don't know who the guy
is that's gonna pull the job,
but he's got a friend, and this friend
uses a phone that I got staked out.
Where is the phone?
I'd rather not say, sir.
Go on.
The guy wanted his friend to do
something. I don't know what.
And the friend asked
if there's gonna be a killin',
and the guy said there might be.
Near as I could get the name,
the victim was Sherwood.
Miss Sherwood,
the friend called her.
And sure enough, he was
going to do away with her.
Not now, but later.
- How much later?
- It was all very vague, sir.
This friend,
what does he look like?
Oh, I just got a spot where
I can listen. I never see him.
Look, I want to know
where that phone is.
- Well, the captain and I...
- Don't give me any of that...
The captain and I
have an agreement.
I just supply the information,
not the source, right, Captain?
That's the agreement.
All right, if there is a killing,
it's gonna to be right on your head.
- I know that, sir.
- Yeah.
You think you'll hear any more?
Yeah, I think so.
You be sure to call me?
Soon as I hear anything.
Thanks.
Nice meeting you, Mr. Ripley.
'Night, gentlemen.
(DOOR OPENING)
(DOOR CLOSING)
Think we ought
to put a tail on him?
He'd spot it.
I've tried it before.
He spots it every time.
A very unique character.
- Has kind of a built-in radar.
- Yeah.
Has his own peculiar set of rules.
You play the game his way,
or you don't play it at all.
And, in this case,
I think it would be better for
Miss Sherwood if we kept the faith.
Yeah, I guess so.
(CLOCK TICKING)
(HEAVY BREATHING)
(ALARM RINGING)
(WHEEZING)
(GASPING BREATHS)
(DEEP BREATHING)
(DIALING)
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
- Hello?
- Good morning, Kelly.
- Did I wake you up?
- Yes. What do you want?
I don't like the way
you're talking, Kelly.
I'm giving you 20% of
a hundred thousand dollars.
You can afford
to talk a little nicer.
- I'm not awake yet.
- That's better.
I'm calling to reconfirm
our appointment tonight.
11 o'clock.
I'll be there.
I hope so.
Because if you're not,
I'll just have to contact
your little sister.
You understand?
Now one word of warning.
We've got a woman's life
in jeopardy tonight.
We hope there won't
be any shooting.
But if there is,
think before you make a move.
I know these things
move awfully fast sometimes,
but we can't afford any mistakes.
Well, that's about it,
except for the layout.
It's all yours, Rip.
Right, now, we're placing
four men in the club.
There'll be two on the upper floor,
two on the lower floor.
Now, of course, we don't know if
he'll contact you on the lower floor
or, perhaps, the upper floor.
Matter of fact,
you might not even see him.
He may send somebody
with instructions about the money,
telling you to meet him
somewhere else.
But there's one thing
you must remember now.
If you do contact him,
we will not move in and take him
until you're a safe
distance away, okay?
You know, I had another
phone call this morning.
Yes, I know.
Do you think he really might
try something with Toby?
Well, you know,
I'd like to say "no",
but there's no way of telling
until we know the man.
You know, I really believe he knows
I've been talking to you.
Nah, he's just guessing.
He took a calculated risk
that you'd come to the police.
So he figures if he says he does know,
you might panic and you might admit it.
That's all.
- I hope you're right.
- Yeah.
You know something? I don't think it
matters whether I'm right or wrong.
This fellow figures that
he's got a plan so clever
that it doesn't make
any difference what you do.
You know?
Damn!
Miss Sherwood,
I wish there was something
I could do to make things easy.
You're doing everything you can.
I'm just scared.
Please, just don't worry, huh?
We'll be close by all the time.
And everything
is going to be all right.
Yeah.
(ALARM RINGING)
♪ CAMPTOWN RACES ♪
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
Victim is parking car at gas station.
Subject's entering the club now.
(MUSIC CONTINUES)
May I take your coat?
Oh, no, thank you.
I'm just waiting for someone.
- (MUSIC ENDING)
- (APPLAUSE)
♪ WHEN THE SAINTS GO MARCHING IN ♪
Can I help you?
Oh, well, I'm supposed
to meet someone.
Well, I think there's
some room at the bar.
Well, is there a table?
No, I'm sorry.
We're all filled up right now.
Oh, well, then I guess
I'll wait at the bar.
Oh, just ginger ale, please.
Scotch.
(AIR RIFLE SHOOTING)
(METAL TARGET CLANGS)
(TARGETS CLANGING)
(TYRES SCREECHING)
The yellow convertible, please.
Hello.
Are you looking for someone?
Yes.
Well, I could be that someone.
Well, are you?
Yes.
Come on.
My car's parked just over there.
Can't we talk right here?
Here?
All right.
- (CAR DOOR CLOSING)
- (ENGINE STARTING)
It's a blue '59 Ford.
License number, RCD 022.
Where are we going?
We'll drive somewhere
down by the ocean.
What are you sitting
way over there for?
Come on over here.
- Well, come on.
- No!
What do you mean "no"?
I thought this was
supposed to be business.
Okay.
If that's the way you want it.
The way I want it?
Look, what is it with you?
You did call me?
Call you?
Honey, I don't know what gives
with you, but I didn't call you.
You mean this wasn't prearranged?
Nobody told you to meet me?
No.
I just walked into that club,
and...
there you were.
Oh, my God!
Oh, there... there's been a mistake.
I was supposed to meet someone else.
Oh?
- Please, let me out.
- Someone else, huh?
- Yes, I give you my word.
- All right, honey.
So you met me instead.
What's the difference?
Come on.
- No!
- Look out!
(TRUCK HORN BLASTING)
(BRAKES SQUEALING)
Let me go!
Hold it! Hold it!
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
KELLY:
Hello?
You dirty little double-crossing bitch...
Now you shut up and listen to me.
I didn't know that man.
I never saw him before in my life.
How was I supposed to know
it wasn't you? I've never seen you.
He picked me up because
I was standing around,
looking like I wanted
to be picked up.
You're a lying little...
Why didn't you come out
of your hole and get me?
Why did you let me stand
around and... and...
and get picked up
like a prostitute?
Now, I did exactly
what you told me to do.
I said I'd work with you and I will, but
only if you keep your part of the bargain.
I was nearly killed tonight!
It wasn't my fault.
So now what do we do?
Hello? Hello?
You know what I think, Kelly?
I think that man
you met tonight was a cop.
A cop? That makes
a lot of sense, doesn't it?
- (HANGING UP)
- Hello?
Oh, Kel.
Oh!
RIPLEY: Now, you remember
we recorded the phone conversations
between the subject and the victim.
We sent those tapes to Washington,
and they kept going through
the backgrounds of wanted men
until they found one
with an asthmatic history.
His name is Garland Lynch.
Has an alias of 'Red' Lynch.
We'll pass out I.O.s
to all of you.
You'll note that he has convictions
for statutory rape, forgery,
criminal assault,
armed robbery and murder.
He's wanted now for the slaying
of an Oklahoma City bank teller.
Bertha Meyers, aged 24,
who was murdered in her apartment.
Since she was a bank teller,
it might be reasonable to assume
that the subject was trying
to force her to work with him
in a crime similar to the one
he's attempting to perpetrate here.
And, when she refused,
or something went wrong,
he murdered her.
Washington reports
Garland Humphrey Lynch
is fond of movies, nightclubs,
fishing, amusement parks,
and he frequently establishes liaisons
with women of Oriental descent.
We'll divide all these phases
up between us
and cover every nightclub and movie
theatre and so on in the Bay area.
(TROLLEY BELL CLANGING)
(JAZZ MUSIC PLAYING)
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
(SHIP HORN BLOWING)
(DINERS CHATTERING)
- That's good food you have here.
- Thank you, sir.
Did you ever see this man before?
No, sir.
I don't recognise him.
- May I see the manager, please?
- Certainly.
Now, you're not gonna
find him in there.
(CHUCKLING)
(GRUNTING)
I wonder if you'd ask the others
if they've seen this man?
I'll be glad to.
(GRUNTING)
(BELL TOLLING)
(TOLLING CONTINUES)
Good afternoon.
Father, my name is Ripley.
I'm with the F.B.I.
I wonder if you could help us.
Have you ever seen
this man before?
Yes. I've seen him many times
with one of my parishioners,
Lisa Soong.
- Miss Soong?
- Yes?
We're from the F.B.I.
This is Agent Bradley, I'm Ripley.
Come in, please.
Thank you.
Please sit down.
Now, Miss Soong,
I must ask that you keep this visit
of ours in the strictest of confidence.
Yes, of course.
I understand you know a man
by the name of Red Lynch.
Do you?
No.
Perhaps you know him
under a different name.
No.
We're looking for this man
on a murder charge.
He killed a woman
just about your age.
She had a year-old baby.
I want to talk to my lawyer.
Of course.
He's a neighbour.
He lives across the street.
We'll wait, if you don't mind.
Please do.
Benson? Lisa.
(SPEAKING CHINESE)
He's coming up.
Now I'll prepare tea,
if I may leave the room.
(SPEAKING CHINESE)
You're not involved in
anything wrong, are you, Lisa?
No, Benson.
If you are, even innocently,
I'd advise you not to talk.
I am telling the truth.
Then you must cooperate
with these gentlemen.
- I'll take that.
- Thank you.
I'm sorry,
I was terribly frightened.
That's all right.
We understand.
- Then you do now him?
- Yes.
Then perhaps you can tell us where
he lives, where we can find him.
- I don't know.
- Lisa.
I don't.
You'll just have to believe me.
We dated a few times.
That's all.
When was the last time
you saw him?
A week ago Saturday.
We had dinner
and went to a movie.
You haven't heard
from him since?
No.
Sometimes I don't
for a month or so.
He's out of town a great deal.
How did you first meet him?
Where?
It was at the drugstore.
He used to come in,
and we'd talk.
He seemed all right,
so I went out to dinner with him.
That was about two years ago.
You dated him only a
few times in two years?
That's right.
- BRADLEY: He tell you where he lived?
- No.
- RIPLEY: He didn't even mention it?
- He never mentioned.
Miss Soong,
if your relationship with this
man was as casual as you say,
I don't understand
your apparent hostility.
I've told you everything I know.
Thank you.
You know, this man
has killed three people,
and he's going to go on
killing until we find him.
Goodnight.
(DOOR CLOSING)
Lisa, if you do know
something you're not telling,
you'll be guilty of
being an accessory.
I'll be talking with you.
(DOOR CLOSING)
Mm-hmm. All right, thanks,
Captain. I'll pass it on to Rip.
(DOOR OPENING)
Chuck.
- I was just talking to Moreno.
- Yeah?
They showed the subject's photograph
to Nancy's Ashton's landlord.
He recognised Lynch.
Said he'd seen him visiting
Nancy Ashton on a couple of occasions.
Did he say anything else?
No, he only saw him,
never talked to him.
Didn't know who he was
until he saw the photograph.
You know, judging from this guy's
women, he's quite an operator.
Obviously, what has happened is
he's involved Nancy Ashton
in the Sherwood case.
She got frightened, and then
he killed her just like that.
Besides, he probably knows
she tried to contact us.
I'll make a bet Miss Soong
tells him we been around.
Stupid woman. How can she protect
a man like that? Will you tell me?
Well, she could be scared.
You'll admit Mr. Lynch is a very capable
fellow when it comes to scaring people.
All right, so she's scared.
There's more to it than that.
Maybe the lady's in love.
What are you talking about?
"In love"?
How can anybody be in love with a
man that's just killed three women?
Now he's threatening
to do it again.
If she is in love with him,
she didn't know about him.
- Ah...
- Now she knows.
It's not easy being
in love one minute,
and the next find out
the man's a murderer.
It's a pretty big adjustment.
All right, I'll make a bet with you.
I'll bet she's not just in love with him.
And I'll bet she's not just scared.
(BUS DEPARTING)
Subject just entered
the Kaiser Foundation.
(BELL PINGING)
- Hello, Joey.
- Hello.
- Where's your mother?
- She went to phone.
I'll go see if I can find her.
There's a phone in the visitors'
room at the end of the hall.
Thank you.
Joey, this is Mr. Ripley.
- Hello, son.
- Hello.
Joey was born without a hip socket,
so we gave him one.
Other boys have ordinary,
old-fashioned ones,
but Joey's is brand-new plastic.
Well, now, isn't that something, huh?
Well, I have to get back to work.
I'll leave you two men alone.
Are you a doctor?
No. No, I'm from the F.B.I., son.
Here, I'll show you.
See this?
- Are you a G-man?
- That's right.
You don't look like a G-man.
Oh, I don't? Well.
Well, I am one.
Honest?
Honest.
Uh, you been in the
hospital long, Joey?
- I don't know.
- Huh.
Well, I suppose you have
a whole lot of visitors, huh?
My mommy comes to see me.
My mommy comes to
see me every night.
You have a gun?
Er, yes.
Yeah, I have a gun.
Can I see it?
Oh, I can't. You see, we're not
supposed to show the gun, Joey.
It's loaded, and loaded guns
are very dangerous.
I know, but couldn't
I just see it, please?
Well, I don't suppose it'll
do any harm to show you.
Okay?
Does your father come
to see you, Joey?
I don't have a father.
- Did you ever shoot anybody?
- Oh, no.
How come?
Oh, never had any reason to.
Erm, who else comes
to see you, Joey?
Only Uncle Red.
- Do you know Uncle Red?
- Yeah, I know him.
Mommy, he's a G-man!
Yes, I know, dear.
He's got a gun and everything,
but he's never shot anybody.
I have to talk with Mr. Ripley.
Then I'll be right back.
Now, it's late, and you've got
to try and get some sleep.
Would you mind coming
out to the hall?
JOEY:
Will you come back?
Yes, I'll be back, son.
You get some sleep now, huh?
Okay.
(ELEVATOR BELL PINGING)
Now, you get out of here.
I don't ever want to see
you around my son again.
- I'm sorry, but I have a job to do.
- A job?
What kind of a job when
you have to sneak around
and interrogate a
six-year-old child?
Look, I have to catch a man
who's killed three women.
That is not true.
It is true, and you know it.
Now, in order to catch Red Lynch,
if I have to interrogate Joey,
I'll do it anytime it's necessary.
Did you know he paid the bills?
Thousands and thousands of dollars.
Did you know that?
Yes, Red Lynch,
the man you said is a killer.
Why, I can't even begin to tell you
the things he's done for my son.
The kindness, the affection.
He's like a father to Joey.
Oh, come on, now...
No! You can go straight to hell.
Now look, we can't let a murderer go loose
just because he's been kind to your son.
Well, you'll get no help from me.
All right.
But you think about this.
If you don't help
us find Red Lynch,
somewhere, sometime, a woman
is going to die because of you.
Now, how do you think your
Joey's gonna feel about that?
I don't know who she was calling.
She hung up just as I got there.
(SOBBING)
Why are you crying, Mommy?
It's nothing, dear.
Go to sleep.
(WINDING)
(TINKLING LULLABY)
(DOOR CLOSING)
(CUSTOMERS CHATTERING)
(PAPER TOWELS RUSTLING)
(HEAVY BREATHING)
Hello, Kelly.
(WHIMPERING)
(GASPING)
I don't have much time.
You take the money
Friday afternoon,
put it in your purse
and just walk out.
Go straight home,
and I'll get in touch with you.
Is that clear?
And... And you'll call me
as soon as I get home?
I didn't say when.
You just stay put.
And don't get any ideas,
or you'll regret it.
(GASPING)
Excuse me.
Do you feel all right?
Oh, sure.
He knows this bank.
Knows she'd have access to this
kind of money only on Fridays
when the big commercial accounts
bring their deposits in
so they won't be caught with a
lot of cash over the weekend.
Does the bank ever examine purses?
What's the point?
If somebody wanted to embezzle,
he could find a way.
Miss Sherwood.
I was just telling Mr. Ripley,
I was talking to the trustees,
and they appreciate your
cooperation in this matter.
And, when it's over,
they'll see you get a promotion.
That'll be nice.
Now...
about the money.
I'd let her have it
if I were handling the matter,
but I'm not.
And a hundred thousand!
If it got away from us...
No. No, I wouldn't want
that responsibility.
Could we make up
a dummy package?
Yeah, we'll take care of that
situation when we get to it.
Look, I know you don't want
to say it, but I know very well
he's going to keep me
until he examines that money.
And if it's fake...
But even if it's real,
he's not gonna let me go.
Well, that's not necessarily so.
Look, we've got 28 hours
before the bank closes tomorrow.
In the meantime,
we'll just wait for a break, huh?
Well, if there's nothing else
you want me for?
RIPLEY:
No. Thank you very much.
If there's anything, Miss Sherwood.
Anything at all.
Thank you, Mr. Burkhardt.
Well, as I always say, you meet the
strangest people in the ladies' room.
Yeah, I guess so.
You'll have to brief me
about tomorrow.
Well, suppose we wait
until tomorrow, hmm?
Do you think we have a chance?
Yes.
Now, I want you
to do something for me.
I want you to take Toby
swimming today after work.
If she wants to bring her boyfriend
along, fine, that's all right.
Whatever you say.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
(WATER SPLASHING)
(POP MUSIC PLAYING OVER P.A.)
Afternoon, Mr. Ripley.
Well, I'm glad you could make it.
- Come here. I want to show you something.
- All right.
Captain Moreno says you
might have a big story tonight.
That's right.
Yes, sir.
He also said that you
might not sell it to us.
Well, you do have
a little competition.
- Hmm. The newspapers, huh?
- Well, I'd rather not say, sir.
There are certain ethics involved.
- You understand.
- Yes.
But you know something, Popcorn?
I've known a lot of newspapermen
in my time... good ones, bad ones.
The good ones,
they're the ones with ethics.
Yes, sir.
I've yet to meet a good reporter whose
only concern was getting a story
and keeping that source secret.
Well, what else would
he be concerned with?
Well, the people involved
in the story,
the effect that story
might have on their lives.
Oh.
Now, take a look over there,
Popcorn.
See at the end of the pool,
that girl in the green bathing suit?
The attractive one.
The one with the brown hair.
- Yes, sir.
- Well, that's Kelly Sherwood.
That girl with her,
that's her younger sister, Toby.
And by this time Saturday,
Kelly Sherwood may be dead.
That is, if Red Lynch's
plans work out.
As a matter of fact, she might
be dead before Saturday
if the story gets to the newspapers and
he figures that she's double-crossed him.
And if he doesn't get her,
he'll go after the sister.
I just wanted you to see what
they look like. That's all.
You're asking me
to suppress a news story.
I'm not asking you
to do anything.
(BUZZING)
F.B.I.
One moment.
(BUZZING)
Yes?
I've got a call.
Says he wants to talk to an agent.
All right, I'll take it.
This is Agent Ripley speaking.
I've got some information
to give you about
one of your cases.
(SNAPPING FINGERS)
- Trace Ripley's call.
- RIPLEY: What's your name, please?
My name won't help you.
This doesn't concern me.
Well, er, what's it about, then?
It's the, er, Sherwood matter.
- Sherwood?
- Yes, that's right.
Well, I'm afraid
I don't know the name.
Er, what sort of case is it?
She's being threatened.
Miss Kelly Sherwood.
I don't think I know
anything about it. Perhaps, erm...
I tell you, if you give me
some more information...
Well, maybe I was wrong.
I tell you, if we were
handling the case,
I'm quite sure
that I'd know the name.
- Er, I tell you...
- (RECEIVER CLICKS)
Yeah?
Thanks.
Not enough time.
I knew it was him
the minute I heard his voice.
And if I could've just
kept him talking. Just...
We just got a report.
There's a heavy fog rolling in
on Glenbrook Avenue.
Now it's getting so thick down here,
I can hardly see the front of the house.
Hold it.
There's a car in the vicinity.
It's stopping in front
of the victim's house now.
All right, who are you?
Who am I?
I'm Smokey the Bear.
Who the hell are you?
- (BUZZING)
- Control, this is Colby.
Yeah, Colby, come in.
We have a drunk up here.
Can you send the local police up?
(LAUGHING)
Roger.
Evening, Mr. Ripley.
Hello, Popcorn.
I'm afraid I'm not
a very good newspaper man.
I've been doin' some thinking.
This one's on the house.
Costs you nothing.
It's for the girls.
I'm going to show you
where the phone is.
The phone that Lynch uses?
Oh, no, a friend of his.
I don't know who he is.
I don't know his name.
But, he's making arrangements
to get Mr. Lynch out of the country.
Air tickets, forged passports,
health certificates, all that.
Every night at midnight,
Mr. Lynch calls him.
Follow me.
(PHONE RINGING)
(DOOR OPENING)
(FOOTSTEPS ON STAIRS)
Don Shoemaker.
He's a runner.
Was a runner.
Errand boy for anyone
who had the price of a fix.
Too bad he's dead.
RIPLEY:
Well, I had no other choice.
And it's too bad about Popcorn.
MORENO:
Bound to happen.
Can't be that kind of businessman
and expect to live forever.
RIPLEY:
Hiya, Joey.
- How are you doing there, boy?
- Swell.
Miss Soong.
I'd like to talk to him.
And I don't have
anything to say about it?
Oh, on the contrary.
I'd much rather talk to you.
I said everything
I had to say last night.
All right.
Joey, I'd like to talk
to your Uncle Red.
JOEY:
You want to see him?
RIPLEY: Yes. Do you
know where I might find him?
Where does he live, Mama?
I've told Mr. Ripley I don't know.
Joey, does he ever send you toys?
He sent me a big tiger.
When was that?
- On my birthday.
- When is your birthday, Joey?
July 26. I'm six years' old.
RIPLEY: Well, now,
you're quite a fella, aren't you?
When was the last time
Uncle Red came to see you?
On my birthday.
Did he say when he'd be back?
Did he ever
write you a letter, Joey?
Why doesn't he write me, Mama?
I asked him special, last time.
He's busy.
See you tonight, pumpkin.
I've got a surprise for you.
- So long, Joey. I'll be seeing you.
- So long.
(YOUTHS CHATTERING)
(POP MUSIC PLAYING OVER P.A.)
Hey. Why don't you get that seat.
(PHONE RINGING)
- Hangout.
- LYNCH: Is Toby Sherwood there?
- Who?
- Toby Sherwood
Just a minute and I'll see.
Toby Sherwood!
That's me. Yeah.
Hello?
This is a friend of your sister's.
We've got a business deal together.
Did she tell you?
- What?
- A friend of yours sister's.
- She's been shot.
- She's been what?!
She's been shot.
It was an accident,
but she's bleeding badly.
Somebody's got to get her
to a hospital, so you better hurry.
I'll be at the corner of 25th
and Clement in my car.
Come by yourself.
Go out the back door right now
and don't say anything to anybody.
Anybody at all.
If you do,
I'll let her die.
- Tobe?
- Get outta here! Get outta my kitchen.
Tobe!
(CAR HORN HONKING)
DRIVER:
Hey, look out!
I don't know. She just got a phone
call and ran out the back door.
Toby!
Get in.
Come on, come on.
- Thank you.
(WIND GUSTING)
(WHEEZING COUGH)
Your sister's all right.
You said she was dying.
I had to find some way
to get you here.
Take off your clothes.
You want me to take
'em off for you?
Then take 'em off.
(SOBBING)
The sweater, too.
(CRYING)
Toss 'em over.
Sit down.
(HEAVY BREATHING)
Miss Sherwood, please.
- Hello?
- Now listen carefully Kelly.
When you get off,
drive down to Fisherman's Wharf.
Park at the open market.
Now, you walk to the telephone booths
across the street at the gas station.
I'll call you at exactly 7:30
and give you instructions
where to go.
- You understand?
- Yes.
Oh, and one more thing.
In case you're considering
anything foolish,
I've got Toby.
Oh, she's all right now.
And, if I get the money,
I'll let her go.
But, if anything goes wrong,
I'll kill her.
(SOBBING)
And if I'm not around to do it,
I've got a friend
who's going to babysit.
Oh, wait a minute.
Tell her you're all right.
(CRYING)
Sis? He said you were shot.
That's enough.
(SOBBING)
Oh, no! Please don't!
- (SOBBING)
- (LABOURED BREATHING)
All right.
Come on.
Over there.
In there.
Go on.
(LOCK TURNING)
We checked for miles around.
Nobody remembers seeing the subject's
car, though we had a good description.
Police put out an all points,
so we're covered there.
On the toy tiger, Cronin's men are
still checking out the stores.
Agents running a tail on Miss Soong
report in the negative.
Subject has made no attempt
to contact her, nor has she him.
That's about it.
What about Miss Sherwood?
How is she doing?
She'll probably have a nervous
breakdown after it's over,
but I think she'll make it.
Let's go.
One thousand.
- There you are, Mr. Murchison.
- Thank you.
How about a movie tonight?
No, I'm sorry, Dick,
but I promised Toby...
I'm gonna drown that kid.
Tomorrow night?
Yeah, tomorrow.
What time?
- Oh, why don't you call?
- Okay.
Have a nice weekend.
(CASH BOXES CLATTERING)
(HONKY-TONK PIANO MUSIC PLAYING)
(SHIP HORN BLASTING)
(PHONE RINGING)
She's in the phone booth.
We'll follow.
(HELICOPTER BLADES ROARING)
I'm running an emergency check.
You got a cab with
license plates Y64 728?
MAN ON SPEAKER:
Yeah, that's our cab.
Made a pickup at Taylor
and Jefferson. A woman.
And we got her checked out
for, er, Candlestick Park.
The guy who told me to pick
you up said to give you this.
(HELICOPTER WHIRRING)
(MUFFLED CHEERING)
ANNOUNCER: Now batting
for San Francisco, number seven,
right fielder, Harvey Kuenn.
(CROWD CHEERING)
Now batting for San Francisco,
- number 23, left fielder...
- All right, come on!
...Felipe Alou.
All right.
He has two ways to go.
Either he can contact
the victim himself
or he can send somebody else
to pick up the money,
like one of the news boys
or one of the vendors.
I'm posting men at each of the
tunnels and all of the 28 exits, too.
Fine. I don't have to tell you
fellas how important it is
not to put any lives
in jeopardy tonight.
But we're gonna get this man.
All right, let's go.
WOMAN:
Oh, I remember him very well.
He's purchased a number of things
here in the past year or so.
Did he always take
the toys with him?
Oh, no.
No, not always.
Erm, here.
Here's the sales slip on the tiger.
It was delivered to this address:
The, er, Budget Fur Shop
on Vista Street.
All right, out there! Let's get a
little more action going! Come on!
That's my team!
That's it, baby!
Hey, buster, how about a beer down here!
ANNOUNCER:
The pitcher, number 44...
A beer, little lady?
No.
- One?
- Yeah.
All right, come on. Come on, you guys.
Let's get a few runs!
Er, pardon me, could I borrow
your binoculars a minute?
Yeah, sure.
ANNOUNCER: Your attention,
please, ladies and gentlemen.
The same two teams play here
again tomorrow evening at 8:15.
Advance tickets may be purchased
at the Advance Ticket windows
in the lobby
as you leave the Park.
Thank you.
(CROWD CHATTERING)
(APPLAUDING)
Have your camera sweep
the area again, huh?
DIRECTOR:
Camera one, pan Section 'E' again.
ANNOUNCER:
Pagan into it, backhands the ball.
A long throw to first base is
not in time!
And, oh, are the Giants mad.
There's McCovey and Amalfitano.
Mike McCormick comes over,
along with catcher Ed Bailey,
and they are really in a
rhubarb at first play.
Wally Moon just did leg out
the long throw by Pagan.
(HELICOPTER BLADES ROARING)
(RHYTHMIC CLAPPING)
UMPIRE:
Strike two!
We've got the sister.
She's all right.
Had her locked
in a fur-storage vault.
- No accomplice?
- Nope.
Looks like our hunch was right.
He's working this alone.
Toby Sherwood found safe.
Repeat.
Plan B now in operation.
(CROWD CLAPPING)
You're out!
(ORGAN MUSIC PLAYING OVER P.A.)
ANNOUNCER:
Your attention, please.
Spectators are requested
to not go on the playing field.
Please leave by the nearest
exits. Thank you.
All agents, move in.
Maintain surveillance as
victim leaves or makes meet.
(CROWD HUBBUB)
MAN: Hey!
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
(PEOPLE SHOUTING)
(LYNCH SHOUTING)
All right, move!
Get either side! Come on.
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
WOMAN:
Help! Help! Help!
(SIREN WAILING)
(HELICOPTER WHIRRING)
(WHEEZING)
SUBTITLES BY POWERHOUSE FILMS LTD.