Here we go.
You don't gotta see him.
But you will.
I won't.
The guy I met on the app is married.
Cheating's cool.
Not at all!
Jesus. Masahide said he
wants to see me again.
Guy's 80. How much drive can he have?
He gave you 16 million
yen so don't complain.
Tell him you're at a funeral.
I did that already.
You have other relatives.
Just keep it going.
True.
Well, I've done in 90 people so far.
Awesome. A serial killer!
Maybe I'll pull in 20 million this time.
20 mill? I'll do that in a year.
Really?
Probably in half a year.
For sure.
Wanna bet?
On what?
I can take a vacation.
Take me!
I wanna go.
Let's go!
Where'll you take us?
How about abroad?
Thanks. I'll be back.
Extraneous Matter
It gets kinda confusing.
Don't screw it up and send
it to the wrong person again.
Even so, Adone is good at sidestepping.
Adone here!
She knows every trick in the book.
She's a smooth operator.
Fancy work should reflect on sales more.
Alright, I got 100,000 points!
Yes!
Thank you!
Thanks.
I'll be back.
It can't be that bad.
It's disgusting!
He can't be that bad.
But he's so utterly hot!
See! He's irresistible!
Today, like any other day,
has been so damn unremarkable.
Welcome.
Long time no see.
Yeah.
Hi, we're serving dinner menu...
Coffee, please.
Sure thing.
What's up?
How are you?
Not too bad, how'bout you?
Same.
I see. Are you working?
Yep.
Same place?
Which one?
The record shop.
Yeah.
Oh yeah?
Here is your coffee, Sir.
- So, what's up?
- I've moved.
To where?
Higashi-Kitazawa.
One station further, huh?
Yep.
You could've gone a lot further.
But I really like the area.
I know.
Got a bidet toilet, too.
Have you?
- So, what's up?
- One night,
I came home and found it.
What is it?
Put it away.
What's that thing?
Dunno.
It was there when I came home.
Just like that?
Just like that.
Well, that's...
I was scared.
I almost wet myself.
Can I see it again?
Sure.
Stop it.
You don't touch there.
Does it bite?
Nope.
Good.
It's pretty gentle.
One parfait.
That's random.
It's not for me,
for this little fella.
What, parfait?
It has a sweet tooth.
Loves strawberries.
Sure thing.
Don't do that.
You and your prudishness.
So?
You haven't changed a bit.
You know, when I first saw it
I found it utterly disgusting.
But it grew on me and
now I find it charming.
I don't know how to put it,
but I think I can look after it
if I'm with you.
I know I was a jerk back then.
Here you are,
your...parfait.
Wait.
Open wide.
You're right!
Is it nice?
Look, how happy it looks!
It's kind of cute.
Right?
Do you want more?
Relax, will you?
Can I feed it?
Don't spill it.
Isn't it adorable?
Cutest thing ever.
Do you want more?
Alright, little one, you win.
Stop that!
Yummy, isn't it?
My little pumpkin.
Coexistence
Propagation
What are you doing?
It's just said “Help me.”
Where are you taking it?
I can't do that job anymore.
I know what you mean, it's gross.
But if we refuse,
the factory won't...
IS that still alive?
Yes.
"I want to live."
He's saying: "I want to live"
So you understand him?
Yes.
You think he'll eat?
Open wide.
“I don’t like spicy food.”
H...hey, stop that, will you?
"Looks yummy." he said.
He said what? That's crazy!
No eating! All right?
No way! You hear me?
Oh my god,
don't eat it! Hands off, you!
You can let him go.
What if we get caught?
We'll be arrested.
But wouldn't we hate it
if we were him?
To be squashed alive, right?
Thank you, sir.
He's saying "Oh shit!"
How did they find out?
I called them.
What for?
It's against the law.
Isn't it?
They're coming!
We're done for.
What the...
Huh?
He's vanished.
What did he say then?
I bet he said...
something so awesome.
Actually...
I never understood him.
Thanks for the food.
Next up,
"Where have those 'matters' gone?"
Since those 'matters', which infested
the whole world, all vanished that day,
with a flash of light and screaming,
none have been found anywhere.
The reason for the infestation and
the disappearance remain a mystery.
What's your opinion on this?
I'm baffled...
Things always occur suddenly
without any warning, then
they go away suddenly.
Life consistently remains
impartially absurd.
What's significant about that?
I don't know.
When something starts to flow
and you're in it,
you may try fight against it.
Or you may go with the flow.
When people see you struggle,
some would cry for you,
and some would laugh at you.
Welcome.
A beer.
- A beer.
- It's five dollars.
Welcome.
- A beer.
- Sure. It's five dollars.
See you, then.
Excuse me!
You take care.
Disappearance