- ♪ Well, I woke up
this morning ♪
♪ With my mind ♪
all: ♪ Stayed on freedom ♪
- ♪ Halellu ♪
chorus: ♪ Halelu ♪
- ♪ Halelu ♪
all: ♪ Hallelujah ♪
- Many people are gonna think
they know what this story
is about.
[echoing]
But they do not.
[dynamic bass music builds]
- ♪ Whoa, whoa ♪
♪ We goin' make a scene ♪
- This morning,
we look to America's
civil rights struggle
of the '60s and late '50s.
Sadly, it's now estimated
that one
if not two generations
of Americans
are too young to have
direct recollection
of those years.
Now, thankfully, the years
are dramatically reconstructed
in a six-part
documentary series
which begins on PBS next week.
It's called
"Eyes on the Prize."
Henry Hampton
is executive producer
of the series,
and he joins us now
from our newsroom in Burbank.
Good morning.
- Good morning, Bryant.
- What is it you wanted to
achieve with it?
- Well, I wanted
to capture the miracle.
You had an extraordinary group
of leaders
who emerged who literally
changed the course
of the country's history.
- Camera roll 1032,
sound roll 114.
- Mark it.
[clapperboard clacks]
- Copy that.
- Team K.
- The purpose of this series
is really to put the cameras
on those unknown individuals,
those little-known people
from the backwater counties
of Georgia and Alabama
and Mississippi
who really made this movement.
- ♪ I know the one thing ♪
♪ We did right ♪
all: Hey!
♪ Was the day
we started to fight ♪
[dynamic bass music]
♪ ♪
- ♪ Whoo! This that kerosene ♪
♪ Whoa ♪
♪ ♪
♪ Bitch tryin' to say
it was me ♪
♪ ♪
♪ Fire ♪
♪ There go we gon' see what ♪
♪ Eyes, prize ♪
♪ Eyes, prize, eyes, prize ♪
♪ Whoo! ♪
♪ See ♪
♪ ♪
- Have you seen the original
"Eyes on Prize," Prentis?
- Yeah, of course.
- Okay.
- I mean, not in a long time,
but yes.
- ♪ Keep your eyes
on the prize ♪
- The first time I saw "Eyes"
I must've been a teenager.
My former high school teachers
had all these cassette tapes.
It had such an impact on me.
I don't know if I would
be doing what I'm doing now
if it weren't
for "Eyes on the Prize,"
if I didn't
have representation,
have a place to see,
you know, what was possible.
- I always remember
being inspired
but very traumatized.
I was traumatized by looking
at the water, the dogs,
these people dressed up
in this beautiful style
having coffee poured on them,
not moving.
I'm just enamored
and terrorized
and inspired at the same time.
So it was like this tender rage
and this beauty and terror.
- I watched
"Eyes on the Prize"
on the south side of Chicago
in my community center.
I was like 14, 15.
A bunch of Howard College kids
came to talk to us
about their organizing
campaigns on campus.
And then we watched
"Eyes on the Prize"
for, like, three days.
[tense music builds]
- "Eyes on the Prize" kept us--
it was like a bridge
that kept us connected
to this history long enough
for us to understand
how important it was.
- When you really watch it
and look closely,
it's like a record of...
- ♪ Keep your eyes
on the prize ♪
- Of just Black brilliance.
Absolute Black brilliance,
and all that
we brought to movement--
our spirit,
our love, our strategy,
all of it
in there for the record.
♪ ♪
- We have gone
in our own past...
♪ ♪
And in the past of others
to look
for alternative visions.
- The archive ain't there
to be enclosed in amber.
It ain't there to be
just dusted off
every now and again.
It's a tangible, living thing.
And now it's like
technology'll put things
in the hands of people
that you--
that wasn't supposed
to have it,
and now they get
to tell the story,
and they get to shift
the narrative.
Like, never before
could you see
these things happen
in real time.
- This country
teaches you to forget.
We are supposed to forget.
That is America.
If it doesn't run on anything,
it runs on forgetting.
You forget
what happened to you.
Move on.
That is the past, right?
You walk it off,
but we must remember.
[echoing] Remember...
[water flows gently]
[static crackles]
- My first memory of
civil rights really revolves
around the story
of a 14-year-old boy.
It became--
for many of us,
it was a time
that we understood
our vulnerability
in this society.
- In the summer of 1955,
Emmett Louis Till,
a junior high school student
from Chicago,
came down to the Delta
to visit his mother's uncle,
Moses Wright.
- When I opened the door,
there was a man standing
with a pistol in one hand
and flashlight in the other
and wanted to know,
did I have two boys
from Chicago.
I told him I did,
and said they wanted
the boy that didn't talk.
[static crackles]
- It's all yours, Kelly.
- Okay.
How did you hear about
the Emmett Till case,
Ms. Parks?
- Well, it was on the news.
- Would you start that again?
Tell me what was on the news.
Remember, people
won't hear my voice.
- [softly] Oh, I'm sorry.
[normal voice]
The murder of Emmett Till--
I believe he was
about 14 years old
who was visiting his relatives.
[melancholic choral music]
His home was in Chicago,
and the...
news came that he had been
brutally murdered
and put into the river.
His body was removed
from the river
after it had been
weighted down
and he was so badly mutilated
he was unrecognizable.
- I believe
that the whole United States
is mourning with me.
For him to have died a hero
would mean more to me
than for him just to have died,
and I hope that his death will
certainly start a movement
in these United States
to clean up
our own back alleys.
[dynamic choral music]
Emmett was not just mine.
He was a universal child.
♪ ♪
- I'm never gonna
get my son back.
He's never gonna come back.
So I'm gonna use my time
and my energy
to help somebody else's son,
to make a difference
in somebody else's life.
- I believed in all
of the stories of America.
You know, I thought
I could be the exceptional one.
And very quickly
over those years,
those Obama years specifically,
I think, for a lot of us,
the veneer of what the U.S.
has told us we could be
and what we could do snapped.
- When Trayvon happened,
it echoed to Emmett Till,
but it also echoed
to the people in my own life
whose names
we all didn't get to know.
♪ ♪
- This exists.
The country, no matter who
is the leader of the country,
the steward of the empire,
it's gonna remain the same,
gonna be recalcitrant,
gonna be evil, gonna murder.
- For them, I feel committed
to creating
new possibilities for us.
That feels like the honoring.
That feels like the listening.
Understanding what's created it
and making it less possible
each time
for that to happen
to any more of us.
That that is how
we create a monument for them.
- What kind of impact
did his death have
on you personally?
- Well, just like
any person murdered,
I couldn't be any way than...
Very upset,
very...devastated
by the...
fact that in...
The United States of America,
that a child could be
just taken out and killed.
[dynamic music]
- Listen to me!
They'll pretend
that I'm crazy!
Let me tell you
something right here.
♪ ♪
Listen to me!
[chorus vocalizing hauntingly]
- So you go ahead and vote.
So what?
♪ ♪
- How you gonna tell me
to love
this property that has
flaunted me every day?
- Anger inside me night
after night!
- I wanna get your-your-your
feelings-feelings
specifically towards
white people at that time.
- At the time he was killed?
- Mm-hmm.
- When Medgar was felled
by that shot,
and I rushed out
and saw him lying there,
and people
from the neighborhood
began to gather,
there were also
some whose color
happened to have been white.
I don't think I have ever
hated as much in my life
as I did
at that particular moment
with anyone who had white skin.
I screamed at the neighbors,
and when the police
finally got there,
I told them
that they had killed Medgar,
and I can recall wanting
so much to have
a machine gun or something
in my hands
and just stand there
and mow them all down.
I was just--
I can't explain the depth
of my hatred at that point.
♪ ♪
[melancholic jazz music]
- On the day
that Medgar was--funeral.
I mean, there was violence.
I mean, there was no way
to predict it.
There was a different element,
the people
who had never participated
in the movement before.
♪ ♪
[people shouting]
[sirens wail]
The police department
and others came there.
They actually antagonized
the people.
They were there
in full battalion gear
with the riot armor on
and guns,
and they were being
pretty rough
with the people
on the street.
And the people just said,
"We're not going to take that.
"This is a funeral
of our leader.
"And here they are,
you know, harassing us,
and the white folk
killed him."
[people chanting] Don't shoot!
Hands up!
Don't shoot!
We're still here!
- When I think about...
The times I have felt
ancestral rage,
it has been in moments
where Black dignity
was stripped away.
[soft dramatic music]
♪ ♪
I remember everything
about August 9th--
where I was, what I wore.
I understood the interaction.
Police officer stops
Black person.
Harasses them.
I understood that.
Every Black person
in St. Louis understood that.
What I didn't understand
was how that stop
turned into Mike Brown
being killed.
♪ ♪
[car horn blaring]
- Your child's in my heart.
- Thank you.
- And when I went,
and I saw...
I saw all these Black people
holding space.
I knew what that was, right?
This, like--this mourning,
this public funeral,
this grieving out loud.
And then I saw police come in
to attack that.
Black mourning out loud
was a threat,
and they reacted
as if though it was a threat.
Black people being together
in public was a threat.
[distant sirens wail]
To try to suppress
our mourning,
I had a visceral response
to that,
that there are mothers
who were crying,
that there were
people's children out there,
and they drove
down that street,
and they got out those cars,
and they had these dogs,
and they had these
aerosol cans of mace.
And I just remember thinking,
"This is violence.
"You killed somebody.
"And then you get to come in
and tell us
how to mourn what you did?"
- You are in the streets
blocking the roadway.
You are unlawfully assembled.
You need
to disperse immediately,
or you will be
subject to arrest.
Do it now.
- I was mad because
Black people couldn't be.
Mike Brown couldn't be,
and then the people who came
to mourn Mike Brown
couldn't be.
♪ ♪
And that felt deep in my body
like something
I had never felt before,
that level of anger.
- I think that was
the most fearless
I've ever been in my life.
I was so out of body.
It felt like
all spirit, all heart.
[distant shouting]
Those long nights in Ferguson.
The boots, the cop boots,
the baton sticks
that they use,
the shields, the weapons.
♪ ♪
It's like I have never
heard coldness, right?
But...
In that moment,
at that time, I did.
It felt and it sounded
just cold.
♪ ♪
It just felt dangerous,
and it felt
like a loveless place,
and time felt still.
♪ ♪
I would be out in Ferguson
from as early as 6:00 p.m.
until about 4:00
in the morning.
No concept of time.
I wasn't even on my own time.
♪ ♪
It wasn't until one day--
I was doing my rotation
at a children's hospital,
and I had to draw up
some medication.
And my hands were shaking.
That was the day
I went home from clinical...
♪ ♪
I made a phone call,
and I said, "I'm dropping out."
♪ ♪
If I have to choose,
I have to choose the community.
That's where my heart is at...
♪ ♪
And I'm glad I did
because Michael Brown
changed this world...
♪ ♪
And the people
who fought for him
changed this entire world.
♪ ♪
- I believed in all
of the stories of America.
It's gonna be recalcitrant,
gonna be evil,
gonna murder.
- Makani Themba
caused 2020 a rupture.
- Taylor, a 26-year-old
former EMT
was shot and killed by police
in March.
- Justified
in their use of force.
- Have not been fired.
- Protesters demanding
swift justice.
- The death of George Floyd.
- And the police officer
has not been charged.
- Violence and protests.
- You couldn't situate
the encounter George Floyd had
with those officers
without understanding
the larger pandemic
and the economic devastation
Black folks
were going through.
You couldn't separate
the fact that Breonna Taylor
was a frontline worker
surviving COVID
killed by police.
All of that came
to a head at that moment.
In the face of a virus
that was literally
killing people,
folks felt
that it was still important
to be in the street.
So I understood it
as a rupture.
That's how I understand it.
[people shouting indistinctly]
- What we're trying to do
has never been done
in the history on Earth!
- Our lives matter.
Black lives matter.
[people shouting]
[whistle blowing]
- Our streets!
- That uprising is so large
because everyone was suffering.
- Human life, let it marinate.
So many people
have reached out to me
telling me they're sorry
that this happened
to my family.
Well, don't be sorry
'cause this has been happening
to my family for a long time.
Emmett Till is my family.
Philando, Mike Brown, Sandra.
This has been happening
to my family.
- And so by the time
George Floyd come around,
I'm not surprised.
- Unarmed.
- Black teenager.
- 18-year-old.
- 26-year-old.
- 17.
- African American man.
- Chicago woman.
- Shot and killed by police.
- Having any kind of
conversation around this
with anybody that ain't Black
is a chore in itself.
- This is nothing new.
I'm not sad.
I'm not sorry.
I'm angry.
And I'm tired.
I haven't cried one time.
I stopped crying years ago.
I am numb.
I have been watching
police murder people
that look like me for years.
[soft dramatic music]
- The dream of Black people
in the United States
necessitates the destruction
of this country
from its roots.
- They don't give
two damns about us,
and a lot of us
always turn around
worrying about what's good
for America, what's good--
later for America.
What's good for Black people?
- We must arm ourselves,
that we are in imminent danger.
- Am I under arrest?
Am I under arrest?
- Why don't you place him
under arrest?
- Liberation is not
about being killed.
We are not interested
in those suicides.
- We must continue to push
for all of our demands.
- We want a new life.
- All power to the people.
- ♪ Say, "Freedom got
a shotgun!" ♪
[people singing indistinctly]
- We want a life
that we remember vaguely
sometimes
in the back of our heads
as a liberated African people.
[smooth music]
- I think it's
generally agreed
that if we are to solve
our problems,
we've got to transform
our powerlessness
into causative
and creative power.
- Then you talk
about Black power.
I wanna know
what's wrong with it.
- We believe
that Black power
is not only legitimate,
it is necessary
because we feel it.
- We want Black power.
- Black power!
We want Black power!
- A lot of people
call a revolution
a confrontation.
Really what you and I meant
by revolution
was a need to revolve
more political power
and economic power back
into the hands of the people.
That's really
what revolution is.
- Power is always being used
against us, right?
Power has been used
as a force to oppress us,
and so we naturally grow up
feeling like power
is inherently negative and bad,
but power is neutral, right?
Power can absolutely be shared.
Power can be broken up.
Power can be used.
Power should not be hidden.
Power should be discussed
and talked about.
And when Black people
have power,
we have the opportunity
to show what life looks like
when people use their power
for the betterment
of other people.
- What the Black Panther Party
has done and was able to do
and where they emphasized
their work or effort,
you know, absolutely
hitting the streets,
absolutely talking to people,
and they're also organizing
but also caring
for their communities too.
♪ ♪
- The idea
was obviously twofold
for the specific purpose
of serving those people
who were directly benefited
by our programs,
but also secondarily
to influence
the minds of people
to understand
not only
that the Black Panther Party
was providing them this,
but more importantly,
that if they could get food,
that maybe
they would want clothing,
and maybe they want housing,
and maybe they'd want land,
and maybe they would ultimately
want some abstract thing
called freedom.
- Power is who gets
to set the choices,
who gets to set the options.
I want Black people
to have more choices.
I want them to define
what those choices are,
not just respond to what
has been given to them
as the options.
- Affirmative action
is not reverse discrimination.
It is rather the recognition
of the fact
that, for over 200 years,
Black persons in these
United States of America
have been excluded
from the economic, social,
and political milieu
of this great country.
- We got to be
in every arena
where they have power.
We got to be willing
to go contest for it.
- Tonight we show the world
that working people
are united.
- We want teachers
who understand our community.
- We will not compromise
on any term.
- We are reclaiming this house
from a billion-dollar
corporation.
- The Black Panther Party
talked about the police
as an occupying force
in the community,
but we had not really
understood the extent
to which the whole
criminal justice system,
the police, the courts,
the prison system
is very much intertwined
with the economic oppression
of Black people.
- The carceral system,
it's a whole pie, right?
It's a whole thing.
It has many slices.
Many different things
that come into it.
We got cut somewhere.
We give our permission
to cage our folks.
We take the resources
from this jail,
our folks will be better off
because that money
can go to our people,
and people can go home.
- So when we say
"defund the police,"
we mean take their money
and invest it in the things
that actually create
safe communities.
We mean
reimagine public safety.
When we defund the police,
we have the capacity
to reimagine public safety
and invest those dollars
in what actually
makes safe communities.
- When you have power,
you have the ability
to make your tomorrows
look like you wanted
them to look like.
- I was talking about time.
It's so hard for me
to believe in it.
Some things go pass on.
Some things just stay.
I used to think
it was my rememory.
chorus: ♪ Keep your eyes
on the prize ♪
♪ Hold on, hold on ♪
♪ Keep your eyes ♪--
- Who told you
to buy a brownstone
on my block in my neighborhood
on my side of the street?
- And our new Miss America
is Vanessa Williams,
Miss New York!
- ...This happen just because
you were walking
down the street
in a neighborhood where people
thought you didn't belong?
- Stop worrying
about integrating
and being accepted
and start thinking
about building for yourself,
for our people
so that we can provide
a future for our children.
- ♪ I want money,
lots and lots of money ♪
- Liftoff.
- If we were up in space,
I would be floating around.
[alarms blaring]
[explosion]
- Lift me!
- You've seen
these young children.
- What is it, a crime
to be Black in this country?
- [screams]
- I felt that I had
to tell the truth.
I could not keep silent.
- You know,
the end of the '80s, early '90s
was very similar
to this moment in history
where there was
a lot of uprising,
a lot of, you know, people
who were doing movement work.
- We will picket.
We will sit in.
- Corrupt creatures--
- We will march.
- Do you think age
is a problem
in your community?
- You will be hunted
no matter what you do.
- They said
we did not have name.
- Where is the justice?
- Things like this still
exist in America.
- I feel like the movement
of the '80s and '90s is lost.
I came up in that.
There are young people--
I met a young person
from Ferguson
who was part
of the Ferguson uprising
and stuff
who was--beautiful spirit,
but he was telling me like,
"We finally got, you know,
people pushing back
against police brutality."
And I was like, "Are you--
are you--
what are you talking about?"
- What was happening
to me was happening
to virtually everyone
whom you could identify
in that community
who was of color.
- Today we're willing
to get arrested
just so Giuliani knows
that we're really serious
and that the police shootings
must stop.
- What happened today
with Rodney King was unjust.
- Why'd they have to beat
the mess out of him like that?
- Movement has to continue
or it's not movement.
And so it may be lulls in it,
but it never stops.
So many people jump
from the '60s to 2013.
Yusef Hawkins,
Amadou Diallo,
Abner Louima.
I was in the streets
for all of that.
Million Youth March
was, like, '98.
That was huge.
We were protesting.
We were marching.
We were organizing,
but a lot of that is lost.
[people chanting]
Guilty, guilty, guilty!
- The documentation
of movements,
they're essential.
And...
where would I be
without that information?
[birds chirping]
I may have learned it
a little late,
but I needed it.
I needed to know the truth.
What happens when we isolate,
when we single-story
a systemic issue?
If we only see
Martin Luther King Jr.
for example.
- We are depending
on moral and spiritual forces.
using the method
of passive resistance.
- If we see him
without the administration,
without all the Black women
that made it possible,
without Malcolm,
without understanding
the story of the nation.
- By any means necessary.
[crowd applauds]
- Sure, I learned
about Bayard.
- My point is that
all the police,
all the curfews,
all the bully clubs,
all the guns
will not stop rioting.
- But where were the other
queer and trans people?
But the truth is,
there were more of us
than I could even know about
because I'm here,
and I'm not so unique.
I'm not so special.
- We had to find things,
uncover things.
So much was hidden.
So much was untold.
So much stuff
was not even given a space
to be able to exist, right?
So there are many lost stories,
stories that
weren't told at all.
- I do mourn for those stories,
that nuance, those details
that inevitably
get lost in time.
- I truly believe
from the bottom of my heart
that Black trans women are
the architects of resilience.
I think about ancestors
like Francis Thompson.
Many of us
were taught in schools
that Elizabeth Cady Stanton
was the first woman to testify
before
a congressional committee,
but in reality,
it was Francis Thompson,
a formerly enslaved
Black disabled trans woman.
That testimony
about the atrocities
that happened
during the Memphis riots
was the reason
why the 14th amendment
was ratified,
which afforded Black Americans
equal protection
under the law.
A Black trans woman's legacy
is forever engraved
in the United States
Constitution.
The reason why she was robbed
of her historical
acknowledgment
is because years later
there started to be rumors
that she was
assigned male at birth.
Francis Thompson's story
is not an uncommon one.
♪ ♪
- Darling, I want
my gay rights now.
I think it's about time
the gay brothers and sisters
got their rights.
- You know, when I was a kid,
I couldn't see
far into the future.
I didn't see myself
very far into the future.
There was so much richness,
so much joy in my life,
but I grew up queer,
and I didn't know
many queer people
who were the age
that I am now.
So many people
didn't make it that far.
- You need to begin
with a movement
which is what Black Power
and the Civil Rights
Movement was.
Then immediately within it,
you are going to get
those people
whose differences
are not being articulated.
- For me, it's a discovery
to be this age.
Life or God is out here
creating
just so many different ways
of being.
[soft wondrous music]
What if I looked at the world
with reverence
and not control?
What would I see?
- Those balls and all that,
that's like our fantasy
of being a superstar.
- What if I looked at myself
with curiosity
and not control?
[people chanting indistinctly]
- It helps out
when somebody else
is there in your corner.
- 'Cause with y'all
vicious mother [...],
it do take nerve.
- And allowed myself
to discover myself,
to unfold in front of myself.
That's what my experience
as a queer person
is really about.
- I know how you watch
as you grow older--literally,
that is not
a figure of speech--
the corpses of your brothers
and your sisters
pile up around you
and not for anything
they have done.
They were too young
to have done anything.
In any case, too helpless.
- Also just the wonder
of creation, you know,
that I am, that we are.
That's really been the teacher
of queerness for me.
♪ ♪
- I don't want there
to ever be a moment
in which someone else
can tell us
what was true for us,
and we not have
the proof,
the material,
the documentation
to show otherwise.
We know what
erasure can do to us.
[static crackles]
- What movement does each time
and what we are seeing happen
is that we're starting
to even tease apart
the things that our movement
has not done right, right?
The things that have been
unseen that we made unseen.
And the thing that I think
about the most
is how this iteration
of movement centers
and lifts up
the voices of people
who are often silenced
in previous moments, right?
That, like,
our labor has been unseen.
Our contributions
have been unseen.
What does it mean
for Black queer women
to be at the forefront
of a movement?
What does it mean
for trans folks
to be leading in this time?
- Ours didn't really
cover women
as strongly as it should have,
you know, but at least
we got to see them.
- It is staggering when you
look at the history books
and get a sense
that this period
was basically males
because nothing
could be further
than the true.
- Black women were playing
extremely important roles.
The Civil Rights Movement
would not have been what it was
without the roles
of Fannie Lou Hamer
and Daisy Bates
and Ella Baker
and Ruby Doris Robinson
and Joanne Robinson,
and we can go
on and on and on.
- We're not taught
about Ida B. Wells, Ella Baker,
Fannie Lou Hamer, right?
And it's not just about
the work that they did.
I think it's also
who they are as people.
I know who I want to be,
and it's informed
by a lot of these Black women
that I've seen, like,
in movement spaces.
- When we think about the ways
in which Black women
put our bodies on the line,
our health on the line,
and our safety on the line
for the rights and dignity
that everyone benefits from,
but yet we're the last ones
to reap the reward.
- Black women
have carried the labor
of cultivating this country
and this world
on their shoulders
in a particular way,
and a particular experience.
To navigate anti-Blackness,
white supremacy,
and then on top of it,
navigate patriarchy,
heteronormativity, transphobia,
and all of these other levels
of oppression
creates
this particular experience.
- I have literally,
since 14 years old,
dedicated my life
to Black people.
I don't--there's nothing
I love more than Black people.
That includes Black men.
I have stood by,
worked with, held up,
held down Black men
my whole life.
But the minute I talk about
violence against Black women,
I suddenly have become
the enemy of Black men.
There was this whole uprising
around police brutality.
Right?
For the last several years,
definitely.
This new wave of people
being outraged
about police brutality.
What people said to me is
this is not the time
for that "me too" stuff.
We gotta deal with Black lives.
[chuckles]
And I'm incredulous, all right?
I'm like, "So you think,
you believe with all your heart
"that Black lives matter,
"and you don't think
about the Black lives
that are ruined
by sexual violence?"
[soft music]
[birds chirping]
♪ ♪
Black women experience
the second-highest rate
of sexual violence
in this country,
and a lot of that violence
happens at the hands
of Black men.
It's a truth that does not mean
that Black men
are bad, immoral, evil,
but it does mean that we have
to talk about something.
There's a conversation
to be had
internally in our community.
♪ ♪
I need somewhere
for this truth to live.
This is a truth
that Black women are holding.
♪ ♪
- Last year...
- Okay.
- Do you remember
the young woman
Oluwatoyin Salau?
- Of course, Toyin, yeah.
I didn't know
you was gonna ask about that.
It still makes me emotional.
♪ ♪
She was 19, you know?
And she looked like
one of my daughter's friends.
- Our lives matter.
Black lives matter.
Black trans lives matter.
- Yes!
- Trans lives matter!
♪ ♪
[clicking]
You cannot take my Blackness
away from me.
My Blackness is not
for your consumption!
It is not!
[notification chiming]
- There's no way
that you should be able to
go to a action...
not have a place to stay,
and sitting on a bus stop
on your way
to try to figure out
your housing,
be taken and killed.
♪ ♪
- That video is haunting.
She's just
dancing and laughing
and twerking in the mirror
and just being regular
like what she should be--
free and feeling good
about herself,
and somebody took
that away from her.
♪ ♪
[birds sing,
windchime twinkling]
She was running
from sexual violence
and ended up being vulnerable,
and there's
just not enough spaces
for vulnerable Black girls
to be safe.
- She loved it so much...
and she deserves to be here.
[thunder rumbles]
♪ ♪
I see so many Black women
in her.
I think about what could have
been possible in her life.
Who loved her?
You know,
what was important to her?
Was she loved?
Just her power
and her dignity.
♪ ♪
When she told her story
about what happened
to her publicly,
and I think about,
"What if just someone
would have listened,
"would've been there,
would have intervened
in some kind of way?"
♪ ♪
- I don't know
if we have solutions--
the necessary solutions
to patriarchal violence yet.
I want Black women
particularly
to be able to live out
their wildest dreams,
and so I hope that we can
put more intention
into asking Black women
and girls,
"What does it look like
to feel safe?
"What would need to happen here
for you to feel safe,
and how can we embody that?"
♪ ♪
- So many of our girls
don't have
a soft place to land.
[camera shutter clicks]
[laughter]
- Yer.
- What?
What is "yer"?
[laughter]
- My dream sacred space
involves a lot
of trees around,
to being close to nature
and feeling around it.
[laughs]
I would say
that my sacred space
will also have my dog Dream
'cause she's like--
- Puppy!
- Yes.
She's like--
she gives me--
like, you know, like,
when I'm feeling sad
or when I'm, like, depressed
and laying in my bed,
like if Dream comes and, like,
licks my face or something,
it's like everything to me.
I would want a room that has--
that holds, like, a lot
of emotional space for me
to be vulnerable.
And I think for me really
to be okay
with being vulnerable
and not being like,
"Well, you have
to suck it up,"
or "You have to stop"
because there's like
all this other stuff going on.
If I didn't have to worry
about, like,
all of this other
outside stuff,
there would be nothing
holding me back,
but I think the fear
of, like, not being settled
and not being like--
like it's not,
like, necessarily,
I guess, a safe space,
but you know
that your ends are gonna meet,
and you're gonna, like--
you're gonna survive.
And I think sometimes we choose
survival over safe space.
♪ ♪
That's the ultimate goal.
To just, like, be.
- Yeah.
- To be, and we've been
talking about that all day.
Like, no matter
what we're gonna do,
being a Black girl, like,
there's always
gonna be something,
and sometimes
you just want to be.
♪ ♪
- To me, building a home
is like having
my own sacred space where
I think like, "You're safe.
You're taken care of."
Like, yes, life is difficult,
but you're still growing
every single day
and everything is temporary.
♪ ♪
[low rumbling]
- A sacredness
is a respect of the divine,
even in places
of trauma and terror.
[gospel music]
- ♪ Paul and Silas ♪
♪ Thought they were alone ♪
♪ That dungeon shook
and the chains came off ♪
♪ ♪
♪ Keep your eyes ♪
♪ On the prize ♪
♪ Oh, mm-no ♪
♪ Heh ♪
[vocalizing]
♪ ♪
[soft dramatic music]
- These children unoffending,
innocent, and beautiful...
[static crackles]
Were the victims of one
of the most vicious
and tragic crimes
ever perpetrated
against humanity.
- 18 days after
the March on Washington,
Birmingham, Alabama,
a bomb exploded in
the 16th Street Baptist church
just before
a Sunday morning service.
15 people were injured.
Four children were killed.
♪ ♪
- They are
the martyred heroines
of a holy crusade
for freedom and human dignity.
We must be concerned
not merely
about who murdered them,
but about the system,
the way of life,
the philosophy
which produced the murderers.
♪ ♪
[people singing]
♪ Someday ♪
♪ Oh ♪
- Good night,
sweet princesses.
- ♪ Deep in my heart ♪
- May the flight of angels
take thee to thy eternal rest.
- ♪ Oh, we shall overcome ♪
♪ Someday ♪
♪ ♪
- Places like
Ferguson and Baltimore
where these uprisings
took place
after these
state-sanctioned killings
are hallow ground, right?
And so seven years almost
after Mike Brown is killed,
I can't go on Canfield Drive
and not feel immense energy,
like, coming from the concrete.
♪ ♪
- A sacredness is
a respect of the divine,
even in places
of trauma and terror,
that there's this idea
and understanding
that there is something
more to this,
that there is
a spiritual dimension,
that there's always
something happening
behind the scenes
that we can't see.
♪ ♪
I also I wanna uplift that
anywhere
where Black people are
is a sacred space.
[chuckles] You know?
♪ ♪
- What then is Black
that it should be redefined?
♪ ♪
Black is the form of forms,
the womb of infinity
out of which all things come
and to which
they in time return.
♪ ♪
It contains all things
without distinction.
In its deep pitch,
the seed of life begins.
From its dark down
comes healing sleep.
To its merciful ink,
consciousness flees pain.
From its infinite reach
comes the light of day.
♪ ♪
Black plagued, blacklist,
Black Sunday,
black market
notwithstanding.
♪ ♪
- Roll 428.
Marker.
- And I'm gonna ask you
one more time.
You go--all Mississippi people
go through,
the violence, the struggles,
the...
Why--
why do you stay in Mississippi?
- We put a lot in it.
People like myself
was born on this river.
I love the land.
It's the Delta.
And to me it's now a challenge.
It's history.
It's everything of what
Black people is all about.
We came up out of slavery.
And this is where
we acted it out,
I suppose, all of the work,
all of the hard work,
and all that.
But we put in
our blood, sweat, and tears,
and we love the land.
- It's only fitting
that--and inevitable
that Vincent Harding
would be our first speaker.
He was without doubt
the spiritual father
in many ways
of "Eyes" and led us
from the very beginning.
- In this period,
I think that the major part
of our experience
has been the search
for alternative visions.
And we have gone
in our own past...
and in the past of others
to look for
those alternative visions.
[insects chirp]
[wind howls softly]
[engine starts, rumbles]
- If you're only looking
at what's in front of you,
you can't look up.
[echoing]
[upbeat electronic music
building]
- Matter cannot be created
nor destroyed.
I existed from
the beginning of time.
I just didn't exist
in this form.
All the particles
and atoms in me
were somewhere.
They just weren't together
yet to form me.
And so I've been here.
[chuckles]
I have pride that I'm related
in some form or fashion
to whatever heritage
that I, unfortunately,
I don't know about.
I share their blood.
They live inside me
in some form or fashion,
and their energy
has traveled with me too.
And I feel like they will
always continue to guide us.
They will always live in us.
- My dreams are a space
of radical imagination.
They are not restricted
and confined to a world
in which white supremacy
has dominated.
They allow for creativity
and exploration.
[soft music]
Sometimes
what we are fighting for
is right in front of us.
It's a safe house
along the way
to the North Star.
Getting people safe,
improving their conditions
gives them opportunity
to think about the North Star
because if you're only looking
at what's in front of you,
you can't look up.
♪ ♪
- If we're gonna talk
about a Black dream,
a Black African American dream,
a Black diasporic dream,
it has to start
at the radical root.
Who are we when we are not
the benefactors
of the exploitation of women,
the exploitation of people
in so-called
third world nations,
the exploitation
of domestic colonies
within the United States?
Who are we when we reach
that self-actualization,
that community actualization
where we can just be?
Be who we're supposed to be?
- This work
is about bringing people
back to their true nature,
to what you were
before the terror
of white supremacy,
to what you were
before the lies,
the terror of capitalism.
♪ ♪
- Healing is the work
of getting
other people's stories
out of your system,
other people's shame
out of your body.
♪ ♪
- When I think about
how our ancestors lived
and I think about
African indigeneity,
in particular,
there wasn't "time."
There was space.
There was us.
There was place.
There was community.
There was sustenance.
And that so much
of what we operated by
was based off of the land.
♪ ♪
All of us may not be free yet,
but we can create
freedom portals,
and we can create
these experiences of freedom.
♪ ♪
- And we're talking
about Black futures.
You can't get to a Black future
without Black dreaming.
- Well, you know,
the title of the series
is "Eyes on the Prize," and--
- And the prize
remains elusive,
the prize being freedom.
- I think the prize
remains well-defined
for many Americans,
many Black Americans,
many women, many people
out of the mainstream.
The prize
still remains elusive.
But I think that those of us
who came
out of that experience
continue to try
and focus on those areas
where total dream
of the movement
hasn't been realized.
♪ ♪
- If I had a legacy to leave,
there's very little else
I could ask of it,
but, of course, I will,
that maybe those countries
that haven't seen it will
and maybe it'll be there
for generations yet born.
- And then
I'm gonna do my last one.
I want to know
what the prize is.
- Hm.
- You know?
What does that mean to you?
What is the prize
that your eyes are on?
- Hmm. Wow.
Ooh, ain't that
a question, huh?
♪ ♪
- Mary Hooks says
that the mandate
for Black people in this time
is to honor our ancestors,
earn the respect
of future generations,
and to be willing
to be transformed
in the service of the work.
That willingness
and that transformation
is the prize.
- I don't think
I've ever really sat down
and thought
what does a world without me,
like, having to fight
for something look like.
I don't think
we've ever historically
have had just, like,
a moment of rest.
♪ ♪
- The prize for me
is that folks
should have
the fundamental necessities
of what it means
to be a human being,
that folks can live
into their dreams.
♪ ♪
- Most people would say
the prize is freedom.
And I think we define freedom
in different ways,
and think about freedom
but, you know, prize
is always our liberation.
♪ ♪
- Just an equitable society
that yields
dignity, safety,
and access for all of us.
- The prize is abolition.
The prize is our ability
to determine our own destinies.
♪ ♪
- The prize is we win.
And I know you want to ask,
"What is winning?"
You know, what is the victory?
♪ ♪
I think it's just
hundreds of thousands
if not millions of people
who are completely transformed
and know who they are,
know whose they are.
They love each other.
They feel powerful
in the presence of one another.
♪ ♪
- Self-determination...
it's...it's...
♪ ♪
Creation.
It's becoming all over again.
♪ ♪
It's taking everything
that has happened
and remaking the world
in a new way.
It's Black children
that imagine futures
that I can't conceive of yet.
♪ ♪
- Any and every part
of my journey
has had ancestral guidance.
- ♪ I ♪
♪ Know I've been changed ♪
♪ Good Lord now ♪
♪ I ♪
♪ Know I've been changed ♪
♪ Come on
and help me tonight, Church ♪
♪ I ♪
♪ I know ♪
- ♪ Know I've been changed ♪
- Come on, now, rock with me.
♪ You know that I ♪
- ♪ I ♪
- ♪ I know ♪
- ♪ Know I've been changed ♪
- ♪ Know, know, know, I ♪
- ♪ I ♪
- ♪ You sound good to me ♪
♪ I know I've been changed ♪
- ♪ Know I've been changed ♪
- ♪ Yes, I did ♪
♪ The angels ♪
♪ The angels in heaven ♪
♪ Done signed ♪
♪ ♪
[continues over car radio]
♪ My name ♪
[engine rumbles]
- ♪ Know, love, one thing
we did right ♪
♪ Was the day we started
to fight ♪
♪ So keep your eyes
on the prize ♪
♪ Come hold on ♪
♪ Hold on ♪
♪ Keep your eyes
on the prize ♪
♪ Hold on ♪
♪ I got my hands
on the gospel plow ♪
♪ I wouldn't take nothing
to stop me now ♪
♪ Keep your eyes
on the prize ♪
♪ Hold on ♪
chorus: ♪ Hold on ♪
- ♪ Hold on ♪
- ♪ Keep your eyes ♪
chorus: ♪ On the prize ♪
- ♪ On the prize, oh no ♪
chorus: ♪ Hold on ♪