In the year 1988,
the Counter-Terrorism Committee...
...of NATO resolved
for the isolation and...
...rehabilitation of
political prisoners.
This resolution was reiterated
by IMF delegations...
...whenever they visited
Turkey...
The aim is to eradicate
the fight for revolution and...
...socialism from the prisons
and therefore, from the world.
They are trying to defeat and
dissolve the political identity...
...of the revolutionist prisoners
by oppression.
For this, the ideal solution
is a prison of cells...
After this resolution,
governments attempted for...
...many a time to
implement a cell system.
The most comprehensive and
strategic of these attempts...
...is the implementation of
F-Type Prisons.
This film is dedicated to
122 revolutionists who passed away...
...in their struggle
against the Isolation.
What's going on here?
Calm down. You are in a cell.
You were in death fast (hunger strike).
They intervened.
You do not remember anything.
Every time you sleep, all day's
experience vanishes from your memory.
Breakfast is coming.
That's why you woke up.
Give me your plate. Guards will
come for counting procedure soon.
Breakfast! Pass your plate.
Calm down. Pass your plate.
Guards will come for counting
procedure soon. Remaing stood.
Put the note in your pocket,
hide it.
Ladies, counting!
Calm down. You are in a cell.
You were in death fast.
They intervened.
You do not remember anything.
Every time you sleep, all day's
experience vanishes from your memory.
Breakfast is coming.
That's why you woke up.
Pass your plate. Guards will
come for counting procedure soon.
Remaing stood. Put the note
in your pocket, hide it.
Counting time!
Good morning Çigdem.
Calm down. You are in a cell.
You were in death fast.
Every time you sleep, all day's
experience vanishes from your memory.
Breakfast is coming. Guards will
come for counting procedure soon.
Remain stood! This is important!
Ayse is staying in the adjacent cell.
You know her since a long time ago,
but you do not remember.
Her name is Ayse.
With black hairs.
She tells everything to you.
Good morning Çigdem!
Yes. How is it going?
Can you remember anything today?
Anyway, ok.
I will explain to you all over again.
My friend Çigdem, we are in prison...
...since five years. One year ago,
we started death fast for protesting...
...F Type Prisons.
They brought us here
with an operation on December 19.
Previously, we used to be
in Bayrampasa.
You started death fast 8 months ago,
but five months ago...
...they made a medical intervention.
Because it was a forced intervention...
...you do not remember the last 4 years.
You forget everything you did
in daytime when you sleep at night.
That's why I'm telling you
every morning...
Here is some tea.
You remember anything Çigdem?
If we are not in Bayrampasa.
Then where are we?
You remember me?
My friends.
Who died?
It has been a year since
we came here from Bayrampasa.
Here things are somehow different.
There are certain rules.
Do you remember that? Look, we are
finding a way tocommunicate with each other.
Look, if you remember anything
of what I've told you...
...please tell it to me, OK?
Bookshelves are forbidden.
Writing on the walls, forbidden.
Computers, typewriters, cassette
players, all kinds of color pens...
...fountain pens, ink...
all prohibited.
Look here it writes: C10.
They sent this from that cell.
And we will send it back to C10.
Here is A3. Okay, don't forget.
Here is A3. We're staying in A3.
To sing songs, folk songs,
hitting on doors... all forbidden.
One thing more, go and write
down all these on your notebook.
You have a notebook inside.
Every day you jow down things in it.
If a ball comes,
you must inform me.
It is also written on your notebook.
There are diagrams also.
When you get it, you'll take it,
look at the diagram, and...
...then throw it. Got it?
Zeynep. Where is Zeynep?
Calm down. You are in...
You are in a cell.
You do not remember anything.
Guards will come for counting...
Never let them see the note.
Ayse stays in the adjacent cell
Gib diese Notiz in deine
Hosentasche. Sie dürfen diese Notiz...
Ayse, no Ayse. No Ayse.
My dear friend Çigdem!
Hello! I'm Zeynep.
They separated us during the operation.
Ayse is no longer with you.
She is punished,
she is in a cell confinement.
She'll come soon. I'm fine.
I'm fine. Resistance is holding.
They carried out a forced medical
intervention on you.
Don't be sad, you did everything
you could.
Now your only purpose is
to get better. Only thing I saved...
...from Bayrampasa operation
is this music box. Do you remember?
You used to play it all the night
and drive us mad.
Don't worry, write everything.
We'll see each other soon.
If you get the message throw
the ball back.
I'm at D5. Don't forget!
Write it down! Zeynep.
Get it! Get it!
Hey! Hey! It is forbidden to
throw balls from the yard.
Why, are you going to blast it?
Give it to me.
Come on, take it, take it.
Damn it, enough, give it.
Here.
Hey man, Vahap,
do not make fun of Ramazan...
...you will give us a headache.
Ramazan, what happened?
I got the ball, chief.
They didn't see the flower, right?
Well done man!
Don't! Fuck...
Fuck...
What's up, Ramazan?
Well chief, how are you?
I'm fine, thank you.
Stop calling me as chief.
Why do you say that?
What can I do,
you look like a chief.
Oh my God.
They are throwing balls
from one yard to another.
Give them a break, they are
communicating with each other.
It will be bad for that guy.
He will be banned from the yard.
Two more people are coming
tomorrow, you will be taken to...
...the three-person ward
together with them.
Finally you are free
from loneliness.
Two more? Three-person ward huh?
Aren't you glad?
No, it's not that. I'm trying to
finish this book.
Anyway, things happen.
Goodbye chief.
Wow is it 5 now?
Yes, it is.
Could you please take it.
Let me remove these.
They, the others...
They want a ward.
They are carrying out actions,
writing petitions.
You're so alone...
You are alone.
I'm not. Thanks to my friends
who write me letters.
I am fine if my doors stay
open during the daytime and...
...if I can go out to the yard with
my friends who are not banned...
...from the yard.
What else can a man do if he
cannot do these? He will take action.
Ramazan are you married?
I could not. Fortune.
Fortune.
Are you single, Chef?
Didn't I tell you not
to call me chief?
I'm married.
They are not allowed visits for
unmarried guards.
It's hard to write a book. Hard.
Did you write me as well? s
Would you like that? s
It's very bad to be lonely, Chief.
Right.
Guardians are in the prison as well, Chief.
Write me too.
Ramazan, manager is coming.
Close it up.
Thanks Chief.
Ma chérie, Ma Ayse,
Today, I'm in the same cell with
new arriving comrades.
I'm getting my flower in front of the
window, ready for the obsticles.
It's a yellow flower.
You'd like it.
Whenever I look at this flower...
...I feel a leaking paing in my soul,
like a bad feeling during a beautiful dream.
This flower seems to remember his friends
in the forrest with a little fear.
It must be forgotton.
It wants to be remembered.
Prison gave it a new meaning,
new feature.
It looks like the prisoners.
Because the prison...
...never leaves anyone entered the same.
Whenever I look at this flower, I understand
what they have done to me.
In here, it is like they are casting
your soul into the mould of the walls.
The mould of the silence,
the mould of humanlessness.
There's no movement that you can
observe from somebody else...
...and repeat with pleasure.
Every movement you do is
something that you don't want to.
Here, loneliness is waiting for you,
before you come here my darling.
I have spent a lot of time in prisons,
but I have never seen...
...any place so frigthening.
To be known diminishes the feeling
of loneliness, but not the loneliness.
One could still be afraid from here,
even if he were a prison guard.
But my biggest fear is
not to be in prison...
...it is to not to be known
while I am inside.
Please director... Get ready!
Attention!
Mr. Director is inspecting!
Mr. Director, there are
four wards in this corridor.
Who is in here?
He is political, death fasting.
Death fasting?
How is his health, doctor?
Mr. Director, the prisoners
has entered the critical phase...
...but our eyes are on him.
- We have to pay attention to that.
- Yes sir, of course.
Everything is okay, ordered,
regular. Who is in?
A political journalist.
Propagating terrorism.
This journalist, activist.
We are now beyond
the European standards...
...everything is fine, our food is
great, but look what do...
...we have to deal with.
Am I right Mr. Doctor?
Unfortunately sir.
Who is in there?
Not a political,
but an ordinary criminal.
Is he comfortable?
He is certainly comfortable,
that is why he is called...
...Detergent Orhan.
Detergent Orhan?
Detergent Orhan. He is extremely
hygienic and he was complaining...
...because of the dirt
in the former prison.
- Very well, let's visit him.
- Open!
Orhan! Come Orhan come.
Hello Orhan!
Hello.
Detergent Orhan. How are you?
Fine, I am surviving.
Are you OK?
Not bad.
Is there anything that
you want from us?
Thanks.
Can you see Mr. Doctor?
He is comfortable, clean, neat, tidy.
Meet all his demands.
Of course sir.
Please pay a particular attention
to disinfect against the bugs...
...painting, and against all
kinds of possible problems.
Allah Beschütze Orhan. Sie sehen
es, nicht wahr Herr Doktor.
May god save you Orhan.
Attention! Ball is coming!
I got it.
Stand up, up! Stand up!
Yard time is up. Are you mad!
Go in there, go, go! Come on!
Yard.
Ball for the C10!
It didn't come!
Yard is okay!
Okay bro, okay I'm in.
Well done, you are learning.
Hey! Hey hey! There is
no room for you here.
Okay, calm down.
You are disgusting!
Do you have any other friends
man? Or are you alone?
I see, you are going to the C10!
Are you alone?
Alone? Any news for C10?
Bow your head, now
you are a prisoner like me.
Do you need fresh air?
I can take you to the yard.
But promise me that you
will not escape. All right?
Okay I have your word.
It is few, but don't escape...
...I am opening. Don't escape!
No escape.
Well done.
You are a good
guy, huh? Hey hey hey!
Stop, don't escape
where are you going?
Are you there? Where did you
go, god damn where are you?
You are mine now.
Come on. You promised me.
Come now, be quiet and sleep.
Come on now. Come on.
Come on, don't be obstinate.
Come on now.
Well done, no escaping.
Come here.
Come on. Well done,
you are learning.
Come on, don't escape.
Yard!
Let's see what is
Mr. Detergent doing?
Come, come. Have a
look, what is he doing?
What is he doing man?
Playing with the bugs.
He is totally gone mad.
I bet he will be worse.
Take this, take it. Eat it,
what happened, didn't you like it?
What happened, didn't you like it?
Detergent! We came to disinfect!
What disinfection! Man,
I don't want any disinfection.
I said I don't want disinfection.
Come here!
I don't want disinfection!
Don't! Don't!
- Shut up.
- I don't want.
Don't spray it over the table,
I am eating there.
Keep your mouse shut, come here.
He was friends with a bug,
how do you become a friend...
...with a bug man!
Why are you doing this?
Yard!
Ball for C10!
We got it.
Yard!
Go! Suicide in C4! Go on!
It has nothing to do with us.
They are already depressive
and suicidal.
You are right sir.
A new day was born, We woke up
and Charged upon the trenches
We were soaked in blood
For the sake of independence.
Come sisters and brothers,
Ours is the way to revolution
Our country is full of fascists,
Strike brothers and sisters,
Take off your shoes, your shoes.
You too. Take off the shoes.
No to arbitrary search!
Guard! We have an
injured person here guard.
Guard! We have an injured
comrade.
Munir Eröz, you have a package.
The human dignity
will beat torture!
Why didn't you tidy up here?
- There's no rush.
- I'll teach you where there's rush...
- Shall I help you?
- Why?
- If you want to tidy up...
- Ah, no, thanks!
Ah! My shoulder...
Shall I throw it?
Can you?
It's not the first time I'll throw.
Thanks.
In any case, they will
mess up everything again.
Where they will mess up?
The room. Won't they make
a search again? They will.
What about if we don't
clean it up, from pure spite?
How? All right.
We can do they too.
It is a sort of resistance as well,
but we should do it together...
...you get it?
You can suggest this.
They won't accept it, I think.
Maybe not. At the end of
the day, it is something...
...demoralizing.
Like a hoarder's house.
- Have you ever lived
in a hoarder's house? -No.
I had. It's not so bad.
Better than a neat and tidy cell.
That's right. But we are in a cell,
and this is reality.
Why do you think they are
making so much searches.
For the are pure assholes.
For annihilating us.
For making our will collapse
and drive us into submission.
They are trying everything
for breaking only one of us away from us.
To collapse one person means
to pluck out a strand of our hair.
Good morning.
Sirma, you know what.
Let's take you to the ward
of independent prisoners, huh?
No need to file a petition or like.
I'll speak it with the manager.
And you're an artist, you'll be
more comfortable there.
Your disciplinary penalties will also
be deleted, what do you say, huh?
Think about it.
Let me think about it.
This is for you.
Won't you come out today?
I've things to do.
Okay.
Hi Sirma! How are you?
You know. Isolation is a tool for
making you alone, to put you...
...inside the prison of your soul.
And we are trying to break it up...
...pull it to peaces. And you, with
your all strength and dynamics...
should smash the wall of solitude.
Good morning.
It is April 27th today.
Only three days later,
it is May the 1st
Really it is, so few days before...
- What does this mean?
- It means we are so near to it.
Sirma is experiencing
the effects of isolation intensively.
However, she is one of our friends
having strong revolutionary dynamics.
Always be with her and
never leave her alone.
We, from all prisons,
will write letters to her.
We will raise Sirma and all friends
similar to her...
...by means of our resistance.
Best!
Come on Sirma!
- Name, surname?
- Hayriye Ersoy.
- For whom you are here?
- Hasan Ersoy.
- What is your degree of relationship?
- I'm his mother.
What is the number of his cell?
C-8
Okay, now go in.
Take off that thing.
Shake.
Yes. Go on...
Come on, go ahead. Take off.
Quick, go go.
Shake. Shake it well, let me see.
Show me. All right.
Come on woman, go on.
Don't you want to see your son
woman?
Come on! Remove your clothes...
Remove!
Okay, put them on. We won't
make it. Come on, wear.
Get out.
Woman don't you get it, get out.
I'm gonna kick you out
if you don't remove your clothes.
Get out, get out.
Go on. That's it...
Let me see. Show me.
All right.
Remove the undershirt.
Come on, woman,
take off the undershirt.
Come on!
Remove it!
I'm gonna kick you out now...
Come on!
C'mon.
Get out. Get out. Go...
Come on... Remove
your undershirt woman!
Okay, okay.
Go on...
Shake it so that I can see.
All right.
Unhook the bra.
Remove the straplets, come on.
Take off. Unhook it.
Remove the straplets...
Even the sun is forbidden.
But inside I am yellow and warm.
The ember of my love
Is powerful enough to pierce the walls.
Güleycan, güleycan...
Güleycan, Güleycan.
You have guests, Muharrem.
Here you are sir.
- Hello.
What's up, Muharrem?
Were you escaping off the chair?
Nope, I am not Mr Director,
but the sun was trying to sneak in...
...so I thought I should catch and
hand it over to the management.
Hello, Mr Muharrem, hello.
We are coming from
the human rights commission.
If you allow us in Mr director,
can we speak in private?
Of course, sir. I will be in
my room if you need anything.
- Thank you.
- We are leaving.
Don't worry, whatever we talk
will remain confidential.
You can relax.
I feel even more uncomfortable now,
because I was hoping that...
...you would get out and
tell a few people about the isolation.
You are very funny Mr Muharrem.
We are already here to investigate...
...the isolation and
the bad treatment claims.
Are you? Well, what did you find out
about these isolation and...
...bad treatment claims?
Well it is not that there aren't
any problems, of course there are.
Now we are writing them
down one by one.
If you have a complaint,
please tell.
What complaint are you talking about?
Why do you think
I am on a death-fast.
I understand you very well
Mr Muharrem.
So what you are saying is
that, these rooms are too small.
Cells.
Whatever it is, a room or a cell.
You are saying there are bad treatments
from time to time.
Tortures.
I mean that you are saying
they happen quite often.
You are also saying that you can't
communicate and you stay alone.
We are saying that
we are being isolated.
Well, do you think these are
worth killing yoursef?
So you are thinking that
I am trying to kill myself.
Well, hunger is a way of kil...
You are wrong. You are wrong.
I am not trying to kill myself,
I am striving for the liberation of people...
...who are being tortured in these cells
as long as these prisons exist. That's it.
Well, now... with death.
That never works.
You need to look at it as the life is
sacred. The life you have?
Isn't it the life the god has given to you?
How can I take it away? That is a sin.
How old are you?
55. What does this have to do
with that?
Since you are 55, can you please
tell me why a person would die?
Errr, Allah bless all of us.
May Allah save us from that.
Well, fate would be
the most normal one.
I mean fate yes fate would
be the most normal one.
Besides this you can also die
for your country or for your flag.
Fighting for your religion...
You can die for your religion, well
cihad I mean, for the sake of martrydom.
For such a long list you
have lived too long...
here I am thinking that I am even
too late for my list with two items only.
Two items? What, what are they?
Two items; Honour and justice.
Pull his sleeves up, pull them up.
You are such a good person, you
don't torture but still you witness it.
Look, how amazing it is.
No, no, no I strongly reject this.
I can't even look at it,
let alone watching it happen.
Me, too.
Here I am standing right in front of
your face. Look, look, look at my arms.
They burst my veins trying to
give me a serum.
Look, look, can you see
the bruises here?
They are from the kicks I got when
they tried to put me on a strectcher.
Don't you think that's torture?
Isn't the isolation a torture proper?
No, no you are right, this is
not acceptable at all.
But think that Muharrem, well,
we have completed a report...
...on ward types. You need to see it,
people are jammed...
...packed like sardines. They don't
have anything; No hygiene...
...no air conditioning,
no heating, nothing.
Do you solve the unhealty conditions
in the wards by prisoning people in cells?
Well the only problem is
not that people are packed.
We have seen Bayrampasa prison
the other day.
We visited the wards of the criminals.
The mafia owns that place.
Well now, the criminals are
very disturbed by this.
If there are individual rooms, the
pressure factor automatically disappears.
Why did you cast us in these
cells then, you could bring mafia.
But you have the issue of
pressure by the organisation.
I have been here on my own
for years. Ok?
I exercise every morning, read,
write a letter. I am on death-fast.
Go, look under the bunk,
maybe the organisation is there.
Muharrem, Muharrem
someone came for you, is that right?
Who are they Muharrem? Who came?
What's that?
Telefon.
Can you use phones
in the rooms freely?
- It is an extension line.
- What?
We use this because
it is cheaper to talk that way.
Anyway I should tell them not to
bother us much during our consultation.
It is the committee,
the committee from the assembly!
Say 'hello' to the friends
for me and talk to you later.
Good, nice, very smart. Maybe,
you are not totally isolated here.
How can you say that?
All of these conditions mean that
there is isolation not there isn't any.
Haven't all these creative methods
been discovered in such...
...harsh circumtances
throughout the human history?
Yes, we will assess
what you have told us, Muharrem.
We have noted them all, right.
We are leaving now but I ask you,
please don't kill yourself, ok?
Pleease!
Are you still stuck in that topic?
Anyway, let me enlighten some of...
...the problems with my action and
you do focus on these problems...
...not on me.
- Have a good day.
Have a good day my friend.
The human dignity will defeat torture!
Open! Open!
Cover his mouth.
Come on! Can't you do it?
...seine Arme zu öffnen!
Los ausstrecken!
- Pull them up.
- Where are his vessels? Hold his wrist.
My dear comrades! They are
trying to stop me with forced intervention.
I won't allow it. When I started off,
I said that I will sing the lyrics of...
...'My generation, I am at the climax
of dying with my honour now'...
...by Kahraman on my last breath.
Now is the time.
I would like you to know I will sing
"My Generation" before I light the lighter.
We have seen enough.
We have shared enough.
The beauty of shared values lies
in the prices you pay for them.
Now is my time for me to sacrifice
and die for those beauties. Goodbye!
Goodbye!
Muharrem Karademir is immortal.
- Muharrem's mother wants to come as well.
- To have the coffin made?
She should better stay at home...
Our friends are with her.
I mean, she can't stand
staying at home.
Where are we going to
have the coffin made?
Osman will do it.
Seyfi, just take down all,
pile them up there. Properly...
- Where is Osman?
- He has a patient.
Go and bring him here,
quick. Hurry!
Come on, mother. Mother Sakine
you can sit here if you like.
Hold on, we will be arriving shortly,
okay? Let's go...
Isn't Master Osman here?
We are waiting for him as well.
He was supposed to come...
- Did you have an order?
- We will have...
Look. There is no problem about
his craftsmanship, he is great.
But why don't you mind your own
bussiness, just care about...
...your profits, am I right?
Look. He will build the same set,
that's for sure.
Should the owner of this brand
come, he cannot differentiate it...
...from the original. He is that good;
But give him the money before...
...he finishes the work, and
you are lucky if you can see...
...Master Osman's face again.
Just win the race for once.
I swear I will nicker like a horse.
Master, that man who asked
for a dining table came.
Just grab some sweets and
pastries from the pastry shop...
...hurry. Run, man, run!
Hey! He came with whom?
- With his wife or alone?
- His wife wasn't here.
They have carried some
wood blocks with porters inside.
Run, man, run!
Look at this wood,
a meter cube of this...
...can buy this workshop completely.
Recently, he asked me
for an advance payment.
So he would go and buy it with
cash for himself, you see?
I said okay. How many meter cubes
do you need?
He just multiplied, divided and
said this much...
I asked what his other costs
are going to be.
I mean, altogether it is two hundred
or three hundred liras.
When he comes, I will say
here take this four hundred...
you see I have brought the lumbers.
And here is the advance payment.
Am I wrong?
Oh for goodness sake. Do not give him any
money before you have your work done.
- What kind of piece do you want?
- Coffin.
Welcome brother...
You are welcome... Welcome...
Welcome.
Okay, you help these friends.
Was it burnt? Do you need
galvanization again?
Yes.
- My condolences.
- Thank you.
- Thank you
Unfortunately I don't have pine tree.
The worst thing is that
there is no galvanization.
Okay, then umm, let's use
linoleum instead of galvanization.
Can not we find any another tree?
- When do you need it?
- Tomorrow morning.
- Where will it go?
- To the Gazi Neighborhood.
No, the money is not
a problem mother.
Well, brother, it is not
possible to deliver it tomorrow.
I mean, if we think of buying
any other kind of wood...
...it will only arrive by tomorrow.
I suggest that you hire a funeral
transport vehicle, they will do the rest.
Okay, bye.
Who are they?
That's none of your business, asshole.
Are you a policeman or a prosecutor?
I know nothing about
the organization and anything else...
Damn, they have burnt the man
for not eating the food and...
...this asshole is worried about
his dinner table.
Moreover he is fake. If you are
rich enough, go and buy...
...a genuine table asshole...
Ah this money thing, you can
grease all the wheels with it.
Take this. Look, I wrote
the dimensions here...
...make the cuts accordingly and
you can leave when you are finished.
Take this as well,
that pimp may arrive.
If he comes, you can say I left
to buy some polish. All right?
Okay then, good luck.
Thanks very much.
It is very good.
How much do we owe?
This time, this is from us.
Let's unload it.
Here is a grave.
There is nobody. No sound.
Where am I?
Anybody? Anybody?
Human dignity will defeat torture!
Anybody?
End to the isolation!
They thought that we could fit
in here, but they were wrong.
We don't fit in here,
we've started to overflow
We've started to flow,
just to spite the silence
The F-Type prisons opened
in December 19, 2000...
...with the bloodiest prison
operation in history.
8.335 soldiers in 8 battalions and
37 companies were...
...involved in the operation.
Chemical gas, flame throwers...
...hand grenades and
more than 20.000 shots of...
...gas bomb were used.
During the operation,
28 prisoners were killed...
...while hundreds of them
became permanently disabled.
Survivors were sent to
F-Type prisons.
Revolutionary prisoners
who rejected surrendering...
...to the F-Type and
the isolation resisted...
...with the death fasting campaign.
7 years, which makes 25 seasons...
...or 79 months or 2280 days,
passed in hunger.
Some died because of death
fasting while some were...
...massacred in the operations.
With the interventions in death...
...fasting by force,
some were disabled.
Still resisting against these,
some of the other Death...
...Fasting Resistance Fighters
had to burn themselves.
Today, the resistance against
the F-Type prisons and...
...Isolation is being sustained
in and outside the prisons.