English Subs Yavass and Laurent Szabo
April 2017
Al Hajj - The Beginning of the Journey
(Also: the Pilgrimage to Mecca)
Maryam!
Salam!
You want fire?
- You saw Arzu today?
- Yes.
- Did you take the drug kit ?
- You still wanna go in ?
- Of course!
- She asked how much?
- 50.
You can't get in
Come back when you have
hair on your pussy.
I am Turkish. We
invented pussy hair...
Show it to me.
Watch out!
Did you see this ?
He hit me.
- I did not !
-You hit women?
He hits women!
Call the police. I'm in pain...
1-1-0. Done !
Asshole!
- Tired?
- Yes, really.
Watch out, asshole!
You're disabled or something?
- You bumped into me
- My fish is ruined.
Calm down!
Sinan, it was not on purpose.
He should be a little more careful!
Stop.
Tell your boyfriend to pay attention.
People want to work here.
Asshole!
Dirty fag!
Sinan, your father
sells fish, eh?
You're Turkish.
Why not sell kebab meat?
- Shut up! Don't talk about my family.
- You should drink less.
Sinan, stop!
Stop! Calm down.
You're lucky he's here.
I would have smacked you !!
Don't look at me like that!
You could not just shut up ?
Why?
You are here to protect me.
I'm not always here.
(song lyrics) You must fully understand
No, I must not !!
You must adapt yourself
You have to march with us
No, I must not !!
All I have to do
is sleep, drink, breathe, fuck !!
And live by my own rules
All I have to do
is sleep, drink, breathe, fuck !!
And eat a hamburger
at 4 o'clock in the morning
Careful !
Get lost !
Don't you wanna go to the hospital ?
Spread your legs!
Push !!
Maryam !
Stop!
Police! Stop!
Do not move!
Leave him alone !
I'm a cop.
Shut up !
Police.
Maryam ?
It's me. Open the door !
Did you have one too many tonight ?
Shut up, you dirty Gypsy! Shut up!
I told you to shut up, asshole!
Go home !
Tell your whore mother
to go home !
Bitch!
Your mother is a bitch !
You OK ?
I don't think he was Gypsy.
He's still an idiot.
Are you gonna be fine ?
Well, we'll take a taxi.
What are you doing?
No!
Stop!
Want to take it with you?
How long have you been
in Germany?
35 years
Ah! You come from Nigeria.
Yes, but we've been here 8 years now
Can I see your papers please ?
Well. You can leave.
Idiot! Idiots!
I doesn't matter where you live !
In my country or yours,
it is always the police.
Speak German !
Rainer!
If their papers are in order,
let them go. She's right.
Your papers have expired....
Everything is OK.
You can go now
You may leave !
Al Salat - Devotion - Prayer
Good morning.
Come on, put your jacket on.
- What time is it?
- 9:30 am.
I have to go to work.
I'll take him to school.
You sleep in the living room now?
Kinay, go put your shoes on
Listen.
I saw her again
Whom ?
Leyla Imamovic.
A routine police check for
illegal foreigners....
Her papers had expired.
I let her go.
You what?
Don't worry.
Nobody has seen anything.
But why?
Why did you do that?
You do not owe her anything.
- It's not that.
- What then?
I do not want to relive that.
I cannot stand it.
We finally have managed...
...to have a normal life.
Yes.
You're right.
I just wanted to tell you.
It happened.
It will not happen again.
It's over !!
Mom?
I promise....
Missed.
Try to focus more on the left.
Is everything okay?
This is not your day, eh?
You're right, it's not my day.
Bull's eye !!
Daniel, why are you still here ?
Don't you have school later ?
Yes, this is life and
life is my school !
What do you know about life?
Come and help my Sammi
Let Daniel do that ! This is not halal
(halal=Moslem dietary laws)
Do you really want to come tomorrow ?
Don't you want me to ?
- But you have school !
- I'm interested in the mosque.
Do not move!
Shut up!
You should invite Daniel for dinner.
I do not know, Mom.
But he's a nice boy.
You should invite him.
Maybe.
I'm not sure.
May I interrupt ?
Sammi.
- Salam Aleikum !
- Aleikum Assalam !
- How is your mother?
- Good.
Good.
This is Daniel, a friend.
He wants to attend Quran courses.
Is he circumcised?
Well....
You can join us.
The course is in German.
You can attend
as a non-Muslim.
Sinan!
Could you translate this for our guest?
There is no god but Allah
and Muhammad is His Prophet.
Good !
This is the Shahada.
Our proclamation of faith.
By pronouncing the sentence
before a Muslim witness....
one becomes a Muslim.
What does that mean?
What you just recited ?
Allah, make me
repentant and pure.
Pure? What does that mean?
Being righteous, that
you act in loving your neighbor...
...you're honest, you ...
Honest?
Yes.
What does the Quran say
about people like us?
People like us?
Will you be OK ?
(speaks turkish)
Where were you?
At Renan's
Renan again !
- Papa ...
- I do not want to know.
Go to bed.
Close my door, please !
Yes, Dad.
- Oh no!
- Maryam !
Your breakfast is ready.
Dad?
You're not going to school
today?
The first two classes
are canceled.
That's why
I came home late yesterday.
Do you still see doctor Olmaz?
Dad, it's been years !
He was my pediatrician....
when mom ...
....when mom was still alive.
Your breakfast will get cold.
Excuse me. Where is
the gynecology clinic?
End of the corridor, right,
then the elevator, 3rd floor.
Is something wrong ?
Can I help you?
Is there someone ?
- What happened?
- I had a car accident.
Arzu ?
Come in !
(in turkish)
What are you doing here?
I told you never to come here.
I was very clear.
I work here !!
I need you.
There is a problem.
Is it out yet ?
Yes.
You bleed, like
when you have your period?
- Pain and cramps?
- Yeah
You have the pills
I gave you?
- Yes.
- Take them !!
Yes, but ...
All is well, Maryam.
It does like this !
I cannot do anything more.
Shit !
My God!
My God, make it stop!
Shit!
Al Zakat - Sacrifice, Offering
(from ancient Greek "Dhekati", offering
of 1/10 of one's wealth for the poor)
He moaned all night
He would not eat,
nor brushing teeth.
I tried to call you a thousand times.
I thought..
I had to find a way
to calm him...
...because I was exhausted.
He finally ended up falling asleep.
I look at him, thinking...
...he is so beautiful,
I could cry.
Today, there was a woman
in the Emergencies...
...with her baby boy
She had a car accident.
I could not look at her
or talk to her
I continued what I was doing.
I wanted to hold her hand.
But I was so ashamed ...
..because my son was
in bed, in good health.
And so, so beautiful.
Then I got home...
and our son moans.....
He groaned and you're not there ...
Where have you been?
It's not fair, I know.
I had a difficult day.
I do not know ...
I get ideas that
you met this woman.
- She needs help.
- Yes, of course she does....
I could help her
You're the last to be able to help.
It was me,
the guy with the gun.
It was an accident.
It was not an accident.
I see such things every day.
Accidents do happen !
It happened to her !!
I killed her child.
Dad?
You have awakened Kinay.
Go back to sleep.
Who is looking for work ?
I need four people
One ..
two ...
three ...
four. This way.
Amen.
- Are these dates?
- Yes.
-Go and get him a fork !
-No. it's ok !
- Are you sure?
- Yes.
Is this banana ?
Well...?
Not this way !
Get dressed already !!
Speak to her.
I'm really worried.
- Call her.
- Yes, I will call.
Yo, man. How are you?
- Alright ?
- Yeah man.
Renan, Sammi. Sammi, Renan.
Samuel Jackson !
- This is is Daniel.
- Hi !
How do you know each other ?
- From a darkroom.
- What?
From work.
- The meat market ?
- That's it.
He came shortly after us.
I'll take a look around
Excuse me.
- A coca.
- Wine with soda
Thank you.
My favorite song.
No, no! We will dance later.
We just got here
Your Coke?
- You don't drink alcohol?
- No, I am a Muslim.
Yes, it's true. So am I.
I have to go to the bathroom.
Back in a sec !
Maryam, pick up !!
I must speak to you.
Answer the phone, bitch!
Hey, man! You follow me or what?
Hands off!
Where is our black boyfriend,
wanker, eh?
It comes from me, this
smell of fish, or from you ?
It gives you a boner ? Excites you?
It excites you?
It gives you a boner ?
You want to touch my dick, eh?
Do you ?
Wanna look at it?
Wanker!
Sinan! Stop it !
What's gotten into you, man ?
He pissed his pants, that queer !
Come here, you !
Daniel, it is useless.
It's no good.
Listen to me.
He just wants to provoke you.
Calm down.
''We have warned you
of such punishment.
''This is the day of truth.''
Papa!
- What are you doing here?
- You have a fever
You should see a doctor.
I don't know if you will understand ...
It has to do with Renan ?
I have my period, that's all.
I'm sorry.
I just wanted ...
I worry for you.
Your mother ...
I do not have cancer.
And I'm in the hands
of God, right?
..... right...
It's always the same with Orhan.
He almost beat me ...
Are you leaving ?
We live in Germany.
I work at Starbucks ...
- Shall I come with you ?
- You don't have to
My husband came ...
We need a German teacher....
Especially for the children...
but also for other members
of our community ...
Hello?
- I do not wish to disturb you
- You don't !
What can we do for you?
May I join you?
Of course.
Thank you.
Sit down.
Speak, Cemre.
He almost beat me
in front of customers.
So I told him that ...
....I had my period
...and that it was sinful to fast
for the Ramadan
So, he calmed down.
You have sinned twice:
you ate and lied.
May Allah forgive me, Defne !!
It was just a glass of water.
He deserved the lie !
He's checking up on me at work....
...as if he has nothing
better to do.
Aren't you afraid that he will punish you?
Who ? Orhan ?
No, God.
God is so busy
with the sins of our men...
..that he turns a blind eye
on the women.
There were bedbugs.
And they bite....
After that, you look like a pizza.
She slept at her friend's....
There is a problem.
There is something wrong.
I think so too.
Your boss has no taste. Where did he
get these from ? Afghanistan?
I have a problem.
This medication ...
It will pass.
I have weird dreams.
- What?
- Stop!
- It's not right.
- You're hurting me!
You have made a decision !!
Íot to destroy your life
and to get rid of the child.
And you asked me to help you.
So, no complaints!
What do you want?
Talk to you.
Can we have a coffee together ?
I work here and I'm
having a break right now
So, you have time to talk
I have nothing to say.
I want you to leave.
I talked to Renan.
I don't know what you mean
Yes you do !
She told me what you did.
You should have told me.
I could help you.
It does not concern you.
Surely it does
This totally destroyed me !
Do you understand?
I cannot eat...
I cannot sleep.
I have nightmares.
How could you kill my child?
Say something.
Was it really my child?
- Sorry.
- Get out ! Get lost !
Out!
My God! Make it stop!
My God, make it stop !
I'll do anything.....
I renounce evil.
Make it stop !!
"Al Sawm" - Self-denial - Fasting
(the word derives from hebrew: "tzom" fasting)
"God is great"
What?
The pendant..... it is written:
''God is great'' (Allahu Akbar)
Why did you ... ?
(Daniel calling)
Say something !!
Are you leaving ?
Gimme a kiss ?
Why?
Because I need it.
Careful, it's hot.
- Be careful!
- It's Ramadan.
Yes, it is
Why did you tell Sinan?
I am worried about you
Everyone is worried about me.
- Goo see a doctor.
- I don't need to !!
- The pain stopped ?
- I feel fine !
Has the pain stopped ?
The bleeding ?
You should talk to your father.
Or you will talk to him ?
Everything happens for a reason !
Leave me in peace !
Do not talk about me to anyone !!
Do you understand?
You're changing your style?
Why? Don't you like it ?
I do actually
The school called.
You were absent the last few days
I was not feeling well.
Feeling better now ?
Fasting has helped me.
Fasting?
I feel lucid, clear and pure.
Hunger can make one discern
between dreams and reality.
Watch where you're going, man !
That was not Daniel's fault.
I saw you, you pushed him !
Clean this now !
Leave me alone !
I said, leave me alone!
Why did you do that?
God is testing you,
These are not your ideas !
That Daniel !!
You stay away from him !!
Don't let him...
It's not about Daniel !
It's not about God ! It's me !!
I don't want to hear anymore about it.
It is haram, haram !! Forbidden !!
- Let us pray !
- Mom !!
Enough!
Come !
We will pray to God...
and then everything will be OK !
''I seek refuge with Allah,
against Satan, the accursed.''
Pray with me, Sammi.
Glad to see you again.
What are you doing here?
Stop following me.
ÏÊ ?
É'll stop !!
I promise
I'm leaving....
...and I will not come back
Just tell me this once....
....that you liked it too ?
Can't you understand ?
Or won't you ?
You did like it !!
What we did was wrong.
It was simply wrong. Ok?
Did you like it ?
- It was bad.
- You liked it !
My religion forbids me.
You liked it !!
Why did you leave the mosque ?
I don't belong there.
I'm not like you.
- I cannot find ...
- But you are a Muslim !
I saw they were looking
for a German teacher.
You are a teacher....
I was....
.....for evening classes.
And afterwards, I met you !!
I like Angelina Jolie.
She takes care of poor children....
...even though she's a star.
And she's with Brad Pitt.
Are you serious ?
She knows nothing about life.
Why ? Do you ?
Me, I like Khadija, the first wife
of the Prophet, peace be upon her !
She's a good example.
She was a business woman.
She married Muhammad who
was 15 years younger than her....
She was very modern.
She did not care
about people's gossip
What you call gossip, is important
for the community.
Yes, that's why everybody knows
everything about everybody else !
What would you do, if it was
otherwise ?
I could have some fun!
God is not interested in
your fun !
- You know that for sure ?
- Yes, I do !
God wants us to obey His laws.
Perhaps He does not want you
to be our guardian !!
Yes, He does want that !
He judges people by their actions.
Maryam, only Allah decides
which side the scale will lean !
This is between you and Him.
You have no idea what
you're talking about !
- And you have ?
- Yes !
I know the corner-stones
of Islam
''Whoever does not believe in God,
His Angels, His Sages, His Scriptures...
''And in the Judgement Day ...
It is up to each individual to decide
how to live his faith.
''... Those who wander off, far astray.''
It is in the Koran.
Maryam, wait!
I know I screwed up.
What happened?
I'm sorry about
what I said at the store.
When did you come to the store ?
Listen, I misbehaved
because ...
...of the story with the child....
What child ?
What are you talking about ?
You were right to have
the abortion
What are you talking about ?
Are you kidding me now ?
Be careful !
Don't tell such stories about me !
What stories?
You OK ?
Very few people
understand that...
...the Koran is a book about love.
But do you speak
of love or lust ?
I'm talking about...... a friend of mine...
A friend who is confused.
He does not know how he feels,
or whether it's good.
It is forbidden love ...
right?
It's wrong.
Allah prohibits this
kind of love....
because ...
I'm sorry.
Sammi, it is the Koran that says....
what is correct and what is wrong,
what is good and what is evil.
The Koran wants to guide us
and comfort us, but ...
it does not tell us
who we are.
As a friend
and not as your Imam,
I can say this to your friend ...
In the eyes of Allah,
all forms Love are good !
This love makes us better men than those
who still have not understood this !
Are you doing well with
your Koran studies ?
Well.
This is not the right direction.
Mecca is that way.
Why did you fight
with the women?
Everybody is talking about this
I already have enough
fundamentalists, as it is
Maybe you need more.
So ...
you are angry at me.
''Oh, my father ...
"I have received an enlightment
that has not reached you yet"
''Follow me and I will guide you''
Stop! Stop reciting verses....
All is well !
I am in God's hands.
He guides me with  steady hands
on His way.
You sound like an old man!
You don't like it that they'd rather
listen to me and not their imam !
Listen to you ? You speak of the girls
that you fought with ?
You are so tolerant that
you forgot to be a Muslim !
You should have done this sooner.
You'll get out of here when
you'll make sense again !!
Give me the key!
I like the old Maryam better !
Open the door!
Fuck !
''And a third of the stars
disappear.''
Is it here that my bullet hit you ?
Yes.
I'm really sorry.
I don't need your pity.
I didn't want this to happen !
Neither did I.....
The baby...
I did not want it
I prayed to God
to rid me of it
I did not want the child
of that man.
I did not want it inside of me
I did not want it
to grow up in me.
I prayed, begged God
to make it disappear.
What?
And then you came.
My dark angel.
You had heard
my terrible, terrible wish....
Nonsense !
And you removed the child.
Do you believe that God sent me ?
God has nothing to do with this !
Your God was just a poor,
little car thief !
Blasphemy!
That man had stolen a car stereo.
And I was chasing him....
Every day, I wish that
it did not happen...
...that I did not move
and I let him go.
This was an act of God !
God ...
It was a car radio...
..that looked like a gun !
He turned around...
And I see something shiny
in the dark. The car radio...
- ..shines like a gun..
- Shut up !
I told him to drop the gun...
I shoot !!
Shut up !
I shoot without thinking ...
- Shut up!
- I hear you scream.
Shut up !
I hear your cries every day.
Every day.
Is that why you're here ?
I wish I could make everything right
There is nothing to make right
I'm terribly sorry.
If you feel so bad...
...be consistent....
Shoot yourself !!
You haven't done anything that I
hadn't already asked God for !
God ...
- Shoot !
- What are you doing?
If indeed God sent me, then
nothing can happen ! Shoot me !
No.
Shoot  me !
If I am your dark angel, shoot !
- No !!
- Shoot !
"Al Shahada" - Choosing a path
What is Islam?
What is a good Muslim ?
When the children that I teach
or the adults that I give counsel to....
...ask me such questions.....
I always talk
of the Muslim community.
I think that being a good Muslim...
....it means being a good person !
In this great community....
...it pleases Allah to see....
... a good man,
an obedient son, a good brother,
...a good father that helps his child
in everyday problems....
...here and now....
...who understands the World
and the Times that his child lives in...
...a father who does not sin by
depriving the child of possibilities....
....available to the child
For these small sins
Today we ask
forgiveness from Allah.
Let us raise our hands to heaven
and say...
''I have only one Lord"
"Allah'',
''And no other Lord than Allah"
''Allah, forgive us.''
And Allah will say:
''I've forgiven you''
That's not true !
God sees and punishes.
Do you really think that this is
so easy ? We sin and he forgives us ?
You lie to these people !
You sin before God,
if you listen to this mam.
God cannot stand this any longer !!
Don't you see the signs ?
The first angel sounded the trumpet already
- Maryam, stop.
- Hail mixed with blood !
Stop!
The second angel sounded the trumpet,
water mixed with blood.
Have you not seen this ?
Are you blind ?
The Day of Judgement is coming !
Have you not seen the plagues ?
The stars disappear !
A sign appeared in heaven.
''A woman clothed with the sun,
the moon under her feet.
''She is pregnant
and she cries out ...''
- Was she partying all night at the disco ?
- What do you know of my daughter ?
- Control her or....
- Or what ?
What?
For heaven's sake !
Have you  lost your mind ?
I mean ...
Surely, I hear something...
It's like the voice of an angel
who says ...
No, I know that
we need to change our ways !
God will not forgive us
if we do not change.
Immediately !
Maryam, let's pray ...
''In the name of Allah
the Almighty"
''Allah the Merciful"
"Allah the Merciful
forgive us.''
No.
Father, listen to me !
I'm your daughter
Look at you. Look at me.
What has befallen upon us....
He does forgive me !
He gives me no comfort !
What happened ?
What did you do to believe
that Allah punishes you?
Vedat!
Speak up !
The worst !
I did the worst thing !
And Allah punishes me !
We need to talk !
- Sammi, how are you?
- Good.
You're on break?
- Yes. You too?
- Yes.
Let's go further down !
Calm down, man.
Hey, bro ! How are ya ?
Come join us !
- Sinan, leave him alone !
- Calm down. We're all friends here
We're all friends.
So, how are you ?
I hate this job. You know why
Allah does not give us any money?
...'cause he knows what
we'd do with that money !
You've got it?
What's that?
A hickey or what?
From your lover, huh?
Your lover ?
What is this lingering look ?
You fancy him ?
He likes you !
What are you looking at?
- Are you in love?
- Stop looking, man !
Stop looking!
Fuck him, yeah !!
I'll make you a Muslim.
Recite the profession of faith.
And then you'll be over
with your faggoty life
Awesome, man!
Repeat after me.
There is no god but Allah
and Muhammad is His prophet.
Repeat : there is no god but Allah
Go on, dirty fag ! Repeat it !
Say it just once !
Go on wanker !
- Faggot, speak up !
- Shut it !
What are you doing, man ?
You have him pinned down !
He's down !!
No! No!
Maryam, wait.
What? I want to go home !
I must speak to you.
Listen girl. It took us years
....to build this community.
We had to fight prejudices...
Now, it's time for us to unite
If you continue, you will destroy
the community of your father.
I do not destroy anything.
It's the community that needs help !
We must open the eyes of the young people.
You forget that young people
must respect their elders.
Our parents want us
to obey them
But their lives and their faith
are false.
My dad
is the best example.
Ather the death of my mother,
he left me do as I please...
It's all his fault!
How can you say that
about your father ?
The Quran says:
"If they force you to associate yourself
with what you do not know...."
''Obey them not''
My child, it takes a lifetime
to understand the Koran.
Leave me alone.
Swear to Allah that you will stop !
My daughter !
What happened?
(in turkish)
Your children
are not your children
They are the son and daughters
of your desire for life
They come through you,
but not from you
And though they are with you
they do not belong to you
You can give them
only your love
but not your thoughts
We found in the handbag of your daughter
the pamphlet of a drug....
...that is used to terminate a pregnancy
Your daughter had an illegal abortion
She should had come to us to receive
immediate care
She's almost empty of blood.
All is well, my child.
All is well.
Can't you sleep either ?
You know what helps me?
Praying, 'cause it's so boring!
Shall I try ?
''I'm tired, I go to bed.
''And soon, my eyes are closed.
''Father, I beg you,
watch over my sleep"
"If I have misbehaved today,
please don't hold it against me"
''Your goodness makes us stronger
and repairs all the damage"
''Please protect all those
that are dear to me"
''All people, young or old
must obey your Laws"
"Let the sick hearts rest"
''Close our tired eyes"
''Let the moon, from heaven,
shine over the silent world''
Good night, Dad.
English Subs Yavass and Laurent Szabo
April 2017