Father, our neighbour
has brought a girl home.
The poor thing is hurt.
He is carrying her.
Look at that. Yusuf says
both those men are smugglers.
- They earn a lot of money.
- That is bad, son.
Death is preferable to this.
Why don't people thrash
those who do bad deeds?
Such people wield
influence with rich people.
Let's go.
Who is it? Foolish jerk!
What is it?
This storm you have raised for
months of smuggling and promiscuity...
End it right now.
Throw that whore out.
Don't tempt fate.
Sit at home quietly.
If we change our views,
you'll die a terrible death.
If you must stay here, live
decently. Or we won't let you stay!
Why do you want to spoil
our mood? Get out of here!
Take a look at where
the master is going.
Do you think he's going
to our foe, the police?
- Hello.
- Yes, go on.
There's trouble brewing
in warehouse number 28.
There's a master close by.
He has reported to the cops.
You ass! Why don't you send him to
his Maker before he reaches the cops?
We got the news quite late.
What do we do now?
I'll check from the boss.
These rascals had to
think of me at this moment!
Who is it?
Why did you disturb me at this hour?
Burn the warehouse!
Forget about the loss!
Tell those idiots to erase all
evidence before the cops arrive!
Rescue my mother! She's inside!
My mother will be burnt!
Uncle! Help my mother!
Who will lunge into this fire?
Father! Mother is trapped inside!
You wanted to be a leader. You've
destroyed us as well as yourself!
- Let go!
- Now where will we stay?
- First answer me!
- Move away!
No!
Let go!
Doctor uncle, will
mother get well?
Everything is in God's hands.
Buy this medicine.
Administer it to her every two
hours. I'll see her tomorrow.
You stay with mother.
I'll get the medicines.
Don't go anywhere, my brother.
Uncle! I need money for
my mother's medicines.
Has your father left
money with me? Get lost!
Why are you shooing the boy off?
You want money? Come here.
Take this.
Want it for free?
The young one of the snake
won't be given milk for nothing!
The son has to pay for
the sins of the father.
You'll get a buck for a slap.
Do you want the cash?
Look at this.
Answer.
- Shall I slap you?
- What are you thinking?
So?
Yes.
Mother!
- Want more?
- Yes.
Now 4 slaps for one buck?
Why are they beating you?
I need money for mother's medicines.
Beat me mover, sir. I need at least
10 bucks for mother's medicines.
You'll get twenty not just ten.
Ten for your mother
and ten for you.
- Don't beat him sir!
- Why not?
- Will you take his share?
- Yes sir. Beat me instead.
No, my mother is unwell!
I'll take the thrashing!
Stop. Come here, son.
Take this.
Mother! I've got your medicines!
Now you will get well!
Mother!
What is this I see?
Tears in my son's eyes?
Have you forgotten
all that I taught you?
Sing that song for me.
Won't you fulfill your
mother's dying wish?
Sing it fast, my son. Fast.
The master is no more!
He wanted to oppose us!
What a fool!
The gold is in the car
and the boss awaits us.
Let's go.
Beat him up!
You!
I'm dead!
- What are you doing?
- You devils!!
You devils! What are you doing?
Let's get away! Hurry!
He's running away with the gold!
What? Catch him!
- He's running ahead!
- You chase him.
You little devil!
Hurry! Catch him!
Look at this! He's removed
the air from the tyre!
The devil's younger
brother must be around.
Vijay, did you find Munna?
Don't cry, Vijay.
Consider me Munna.
From today I'm your
brother not only friend!
Are you and Nilam ready?
Yes, boss. Absolutely.
- I am going.
- Hey, where are you going?
I won't go with you!
- Are you deaf?
- Your Pop maybe deaf!
Inspector sir!
- I'm glad you came...
- Take your cart off the road.
My cart never took off
on the right track!
She's not leaving her parental
home for her husband's home.
Unless she goes home, how
can a baby play in my arms?
Unless I have a baby, who will
carry my family name forward?
To Hell with your family!
Sir, I won't go with
this dwarfed man!
She called me a dwarf!
If not with this dwarf,
will you go with him?
- Move the cart fast.
- How can I do that?
If I move the cart,
she will run for it.
I'll be darned. For 6 months I've
been waiting to consummate our union.
What crazy fools! What are you
doing there sitting like monarchs?
Come here and move the cart.
Hurry up!
Stop the jeep!
Don't leave me here!
My mynah...
Never encourages me
Be sweet to me too.
Is it for free?
I feel like shooting all of you!
You all sit idle while Fakira
inflicts defeat upon us.
What can we do?
We don't know who he is.
Where he lives. Like the
devil he swoops down on us.
Try to find out.
If this state continues,
someday we'll be beggars!
No doubt about it.
Give us another chance.
We will dig him out.
You always say that but
don't prove anything!
Go and find that scoundrel!
Sir, an idea!
If you don't shut your mouth,
I'll have you skinned alive!
Such excellent ideas being
wasted on the unappreciative!
Hey! Where are you
going with the bag?
- Who are you? - A gentleman
asked me to give this bag to you.
- Who gave it to you?
- I swear I don't know.
He brought me here, gave me 10 bucks
Said, give this to the commissioner.
Catch anybody who is seen outside.
Greetings to the Police
Commissioner from Fakira.
Sometimes people like me have
to get up to serve the nation.
I proffer the amount
stolen from the bank to you.
It is all there except for my
service charge of 10000 rupees.
This amount maybe recovered
from the police charity.
Your well wisher, Fakira.
Gently... you're hurting my wrist.
- Quiet!
- Good day, sir.
Only he was outside.
She, not he!
What were you doing here?
May your stars shine bright.
I was out on a business tour.
To check if some policeman
has been blessed with a baby.
He arrested me and got me here.
What is my crime?
- Let her go. Him too.
- Come on.
Thanks to me, you too
are safe. Good day sir.
Set the CID on her.
Baby... sweet babies...
See you later. Go on.
You are strange. You returned
such a large sum of money!
This money belonged neither
to smuggler nor businessman.
It's public money.
How can we keep it?
Don't forget it's very difficult
to digest an honest man's money.
- It bursts forth like acid.
- I give up, Vijay.
Long live our Fakira.
Your Fakira has made me a pauper.
What are you doing?
- Feeling sleepy.
- Feeling sleepy?
- The bed is there.
- Join me.
I'll sing you a lullaby
and put you to sleep.
Have you ever looked at yourself?
Often. 20 times
better than Vijay.
22 not 20.
Believe me now and come to me.
Would you like to be spanked?
I'd like dinner.
Dinner? I'm hungry.
- Shall I eat you?
- Should I take off my shoe?
No, you're welcome to eat that.
I'll set you right today!
It's not right to
get angry over a joke.
You are great, boss!
What a trick!
The police must be
searching the ship, Indiana.
And you got the goodies
in the middle of the sea!
- You're great!
- That's why I've never been jailed.
Turn these diamonds into
a necklace and overnight...
Exhibit it in our
Honesty Jewelry shop.
Excuse me, where can
I find Kunwar Dilip Singh?
Strange man. Doesn't answer.
Excuse me...
Good God! He's flat out!
Murder! Murder!
No!
My brother has left me alone!
My mother!
Screaming is not allowed here!
What else do I do?
Blow the trumpet?
Can't you see what has
happened to my brother?
Nothing is wrong with him, this
is the art of holding your breath.
Man can hold his breath for a
long period with his will power.
He can only hold his
breath for 30 minutes.
Look at him! He's
coming back to consciousness.
Brother Vijay!
Live long.
Why did you come here?
The news is that the diamonds
that the smugglers had brought in...
...have been turned into a necklace
to be sold through Honesty Jewelers.
- Where is Neelam?
- She is waiting.
Yes sir?
What do I say? Peer out and see
a car swaying like an elephant.
Your life is made.
Nawab Jhumritalaiya has graced
your shop with his presence and family
I'll bring him in You quickly ask
the manager to greet him at the door.
- In a minute.
- Hurry!
Sir, our destiny is looking up!
The Nawab of Jhumritalaiya is here!
- Nawab?
- Yes, he'll buy in millions!
Hurry and get some sweets,
cold drink, flowers, garlands...
- Greet him.
- Good day, sire...
Little master.
Please be seated here.
I am pleased. Reward.
No need for that, sire.
Not accepting the reward
is tantamount to insulting sire.
Thanks you.
As long as sire is in your shop,
no stranger should step in.
Your will is our command.
Stand at the gate.
Don't let anyone in.
- Is that better sire?
- I'm much pleased by your obedience.
Another reward.
Sir...
- Sire, a garland...
- Here's the bouquet.
Little master.
Sweetmeats.
- Fruits.
- Prince...
What are you doing?
Garland...
These aren't made of butter.
Don't over eat or you'll catch cold.
Let him eat, sire. The little
master is a child. He'll digest it.
I wish to buy a diamond
necklace for my queen.
- Diamonds?
- Yes.
I'll pay for it in cash.
But I won't ask for a receipt.
Do you understand or not?
I've understood.
I'll present it in a flash.
Spare a glance at this necklace.
It costs 4000000.
- Only 40 lakhs.
- This gladdens my heart!
Get me a cigarette!
Please tell my wife to come and
have a look at this necklace.
Your madam slipped on a
banana peel this morning.
She's been sneezing since then.
Look at her.
Why didn't you tell me so? Stepping
on a bitter gourd would remedy it.
- I beg apologies.
- Doesn't matter.
I'll put it round her neck
and see for myself.
- But sire...
- Do you mind?
No, sir! Absolutely not.
This entire shop is yours.
Go right ahead.
I understand that.
- Go right ahead.
- Take care of my prince.
- Yes, sire.
- Don't eat too much, you hog.
And we are proud that at
the hands of Chimanbhai...
- This hospital is being inaugurated
- Applause!
Here you are.
Sir, call for you.
I'll be back soon.
What? 4000000 in black?
Reduce a couple of lakh
and sell it to him.
I'll reward you with 25000.
All right. Fine.
- Here you are.
- 100 bucks? - Your reward.
Those two are looking at the
prince. They look like kidnappers.
- Throw the beggars out.
- No, they are not beggars.
- They are my Mom and Dad.
- Mom and Dad?
And the Nawab?
He gave me good clothes.
I want to stay with him.
I see... what??
Locate the Nawab's car!
- He has gone.
- Gone!!
Nitwits! Why didn't you stop him?
He sat in the car in your
presence and gave us 100 bucks.
100 bucks!! His rewards
were our undoing!
- Leave this! Stop eating.
- No, I want to eat more.
I'll feed you venom! Let go!
Get out! Out!
My child! Did he harm you?
- What has he done?
- Crooks! I'll have you arrested!
- Why did you give him the child?
- He gave us 100 rupees for it.
Another 100 rupees!
He paid 400 rupees and
swindled us of 40000!
I'll open 10 such hospitals
for my poor brethren.
I'll beg for charity
with out stretched arms!
If need be, I'll auction
the shirt off my back!
Hurry!
- Swindled the Nawab?
- He swindled us.
What rubbish?
Boss, we've been duped.
If was Fakira in
the guise of a Nawab!
And he has turned us into paupers!
Thank you oh Lord!
If these miracles continue,
my salary will grow to 1000!
You are quite an ass and an imbecile!
He conned you in bright daylight.
And you sat twiddling your thumbs!
I've caught the child and its' parents
Will you ask them
to dig your grave?
Throw them out.
Here he comes.
I want to speak to you about my salary
Fools! Got fooled so easily.
They've been conned so bad that
they will curse each other for ages.
Good, they got conned.
What's wrong?
We're carrying extra baggage.
Get out.
Who are you?
A helpless girl.
Tell us the truth or
we'll bury you right here.
Honestly, it's the truth.
My parents are no more.
My uncle wants to kill me
for my inheritance.
I was alone at home.
A hood came to kill me.
I jumped out of the window
and ran but he chased me.
I reached the market
where your car was parked.
Escaping the eyes of the
hood, I hid in the boot.
This girl acts very well.
You think my desperation is acting.
Don't help me if you don't want to.
Where is the exit?
Nobody who comes here
leaves without my permission.
You could be innocent or
a conspiracy of our enemies.
If there is truth in your
words, we will help you.
You'll get back your right.
But... if you are cheating us...
Keep in mind... who you are...
where you came from...
...where you went...
Nobody will have a clue.
I swear by my deceased parents...
- I speak the truth.
- What's the proof?
That we'll find out. Your name?
If your name is Geeta, the
Mahabharat is bound to follow.
I hope she won't turn
our Krishna into Duryodhana.
I had no clue you'd
hate my name so much.
Or I'd give another name.
We still don't know whether
you're telling us a false name.
How long will it take to find
if she's telling the truth?
What's your uncle's name?
There are full chances of
our Lanka getting burnt.
Get rid of this poison girl.
How can she harm us?
These girls have destroyed
the saints of yonder.
You and I hardly matter.
- I too am a girl.
- You too create problems.
When we have a downfall
you will be the cause for it.
Tell him to shut up or
I'll smash his teeth in!
Quiet, both of you.
Where do you stay?
We're really destroyed.
Till we find out all about you,
you can't leave this place.
- Take her to the room downstairs.
- Follow me.
Always scolding me!
And you come up with me
to the room upstairs.
Neelam, I've often told you...
We are only business partners.
Get the thought of becoming my
life partner out of your heart.
Where is the heart?
You've taken that away.
Come inside.
- Where is the light switch?
- In your hands and mine.
I don't understand.
Try for yourself.
A bed to sleep in.
Clothes in that cupboard
should you require them.
If you try to leave this
place without permission...
My pigeons will start twittering.
They may look tiny but
if they get after somebody...
The person might lose his life.
Do you still doubt me?
I don't spare my Pop!
How dare you send my young
daughter to such a risky place?
Why didn't you ask me?
If any harm befalls Neeta,
I'll consume poison and die!
You worry for no reason.
She can handle 10 gangsters.
Nobody can beat her at
judo, karate and gun firing.
I've raised my daughter like a son.
She can protect herself.
Besides, she's a
responsible CID officer.
Even the devil not just men
would run at sighting her.
Blow your own trumpet!
Never pay heed to me!
Are the cops in the police force
women that you had to send my baby?
Chimanbhai here.
What about Fakira?
We are on his tail.
We'll arrest him very soon.
Why haven't you arrested him
so far? What is the police doing?
When the time comes you
will know what we're doing.
Like Hell we'll know!
I'm a servant of the public.
The public demands to know who'll
safeguard their lives and property.
I have a request...
If you won't do anything
I'll stage a protest march.
Take out a procession.
Go on a fast in front of
your office. Shout slogans.
If no action is forthcoming,
you are aware of my power.
As for you... I thought you
were the lion of the forest.
But you turned out to be the
paper lion children play with.
And tears it to shreds
whenever he feels like it.
I want a credible lion.
Who will cleave the
vultures and the jackals!
I want a ferocious
beast in human form!
Mankind should fear him.
Have you heard of Toofan?
Yes. All the gangsters fear him.
Name like Toofan (Storm)
But the form of an ant.
I swear by the Maker...
I've never seen a
donkey greater than you.
What???
Worm! An ant can kill an elephant.
And you're just an ass!
Hey ant! I'll crush you to death!
First drink some water.
You're perspiring away.
I've been released from prison after
2 years. Do you want me to go back?
What do we have in common?
Two rulers can't live in one kingdom.
To blazes with your monarchs.
Why get hot under the collar?
- What are you watching? A drink.
- Here you are.
He won't drink this.
Swear by the Maker, you've
invited your own doom!
Now tell me, which
kingdom you rule.
- Punch your brains out?
- Let him go, son!
- He doesn't know you.
- He'll bark again!
Forgive him.
You're fortunate, bald man
that uncle is here.
Else you would return in
a coffin not your own feet!
I don't approve of anyone
carrying guns in my presence.
But I am your friend not foe.
I've come for a job.
Look at this.
Now talk...
You've returned from prison only today
So you'll really need this.
I swear by the Maker,
you're really smart.
- What's the job?
- Job?
You have to bump off somebody.
- Why?
- Somebody who is not my foe...
I don't kill him.
You can't kill him but
you can bring him to us?
That's much better.
- Who is he?
- Don't know.
Suddenly you've turned
from smart guy to fool.
How would I know if you don't?
He has always appeared in disguise.
- Any address?
- Don't know that either.
He has one special style.
He throws away the front half of
the cigarette before smoking it.
Did what she said turn out
to be the truth or lies?
It's true. The house does exist
and it bears her uncle's name.
My jewelry and papers of
inheritance are in the vault.
I'll be grateful to you
if I can get them back.
It's our duty to help the weak.
You'll get your things tonight.
Take her back home.
Meet me near her house at midnight
after fixing the vault business.
Fine. Let's go.
From where did he land up?
I'll have to order new furniture.
Is this a hotel or a cemetery?
Why are you quiet? Play on!
Waiter, get sir another peg.
Swear by the Maker,
you're quite something.
Swear by the Destroyer,
you too are intense.
- Introduce yourself.
- Praise the Lord who made the earth.
What am I compared to him?
Tell me something about
yourself if you wish.
Don't you know me?
Petty things miss my eyes.
You have a long tongue.
Hands longer than that.
Nobody dares to chatter
like this in my presence!
I am Toofan!
Anything that comes in my path
is blown away like straw!
And I'm the mountain that the storm
encounters only to flee in return.
There goes my furniture!
My Lords, it would be great
if you would talk with love.
Reputed men come to my bar.
Do you mean we're not respectable?
- You're better than the best!
- What do you think of me?
May God smile at you.
You're our King!
- Recognise me?
- I can forget my father not you.
As soon as I saw you enter,
I told the waiter to...
...present anything that
you 'd like to eat or drink.
And not present the bill
even if you demand it.
I'm pleased.
Pleased to meet you too.
- The reason for that?
- The heart knows that.
But what's the point in
telling before a drink?
Get the bottle. Today
we'll drink hard to our meeting.
I drink gently not hard.
Have a double on me.
This man is slipping away.
Than God the bottle and
the furniture is safe!
- What do you want?
- Try to understand.
Want a lift?
Hearing my words from your lips.
Some relation of a previous birth.
How would you like us to have
some relation in this birth too?
- I don't understand.
- I'll explain on the way.
You didn't tell me
where you want to go.
This time you're losing touch.
Swear by the Maker, you can't
guess what's in my heart.
Anyway, I'm illiterate.
I can't read.
You read this.
- I don't understand, dear brother.
- Adorable brother...
I've accepted Rs. 10000
advance from them to nab you.
I'll get another 10
once you reach them.
Doesn't that bind us in a relation?
I earned 20000 from you.
- If I refuse to go?
- Same amount for the corpse.
But take the pistol
away from my temple.
I'll shoot your brains out
if you make any funny moves.
Sonny be my disciple and learn
something. Then become a hood!
This is the first jerk. If we meet
again, you'll forget your ancestors!
You used a machine to show me down!
But I trust my arms!
I swear I'll kill you in a place
where you'll pine for water!
Fool! Nitwit!
I'll shoot you if you move!
You wanted to kill me
with the help of this hood!
I'll show you!
This is Hanuman Singh
from 12 Love Lane.
A thief is here. Come immediately.
He'll go to prison.
Then I'll set you straight.
Throw down your pistol.
This is the muzzle of
a pistol not a finger!
Throw it or the bullet will be
in you and your life winging away.
Throw it!
Stop or I'll shoot!
Vijay! Hurry!
You have very good aim.
So... how are you sir?
A fool by name and acts smart.
Give me an opportunity real fast
to handcuff you and the other hoods.
When you find the truth,
your head will be reeling.
The earth will slip out
from under your feet.
Darling, you're so cruel.
I wish I were the photograph.
Why have you come here?
You thought of me
and I came attracted.
- Like bees to honey.
- Somebody might come!
God's will be done.
Now you must go!
You love the photograph but
are so curt with the person.
The picture is silent but you speak.
Then I'll be quiet.
Love me too.
How would I know if
your love is true?
My love is true not false.
Where shall I take Her Majesty?
The oars of my boat are in your
hands. Take me wherever you wish.
Fine. I'll take you to the wedding.
- Wedding?
- Of the daughter of a poor man.
If you desire, we too
could get married there.
Mother! My mother will be burnt!
Why did you leave?
That fire reminded me of the
fire that destroyed my world.
But there's such a difference
between the two fires.
This fire unites two strangers.
And that fire left me alone
to live tormented in this world.
I don't understand.
Do you want to understand?
Come, I'll show you the
festering wound of my life.
Hey, that's Kunwar Dilip Singh!
Hurry!
The Prince is here!
Come on!
This school of my father and this
temple stand witness to our ruin.
Once I relished life to the hilt
in the portals of this temple.
Then I held these walls and wept.
This heart is a graveyard of memories.
I can't tell you how many incidents
and tragedies lie buried in it.
Life has been very cruel to you.
But you faced it without bowing.
You have been the support of count
less poverty stricken families.
You constructed a school for children.
This portrait of your
life is so beautiful.
All said and done, he is a criminal.
What is the meaning of
praising him to the skies?
Definitely not what you think.
I know my duty.
He is in my hand.
If I wish I can have
him arrested today.
He should be arrested.
But there's no point
in arresting him alone.
We can get to the other smugglers
and their leaders through him.
We can arrest Fakira any
time once they are nabbed.
I'm always worried about you.
Take care.
Inform me whenever you need help.
- Shall I leave?
- Won't you meet mother?
I've already met her. Okay?
- You?
- Where are you coming from?
- From the bathroom.
- From out?
Out? I went with Vijay.
Where did you go
after dropping Vijay?
Talk to me with respect so
I can answer you with respect.
You witch! I know the real you.
You want to ensnare Vijay
and land him in prison!
You have tortured me.
Made me jealous! I'll kill you!
What is going on? Let go!
What madness is this?
- Aren't you ashamed? Fighting!
- Shoot this bitch!
What nonsense is this!
You rejected my love for this witch!
But I warn you she will
leave you in pain for life!
- Are you mad?
- It's you who is mad!
Do you know who she is?
She is a spy!
She... she is lying!
She's lying! I saw her getting out
of the police commissioner's office!
I have never gone there!
She is jealous of me! So
she's doing this to break us up!
Is it not true that your
name is Neeta not Geeta?
Is it a lie that you are the
police commissioners' daughter?
I swear I am Geeta.
The orphan Geeta whom
you encouraged to live.
Every word she utters is a lie!
She is your enemy and mine!
Kill her!!!
This is my personal matter.
Let me handle it.
You may leave.
Honestly, she is wrongly accusing me!
I completely believe you.
...that you are alone and
have nobody in this world.
Yes.
You are my life.
And I mean the world to you.
Isn't it?
Don't you trust my love?
I do.
And after today I won't
ask you this question.
You... why have you brought me here?
To make him the witness to my love.
Lord, in your presence I accept...
This woman is my world.
I love her from the depths of my soul.
If I die before her,
it is my desire...
Her face be in front of my eyes.
What have you done?
This is the last wish of lovers.
I have accepted you as my
wife in the presence of God.
No!
This can't be true!
Why did you do this...
without asking me?
So that you can go
and tell your Dad...
Fakira is your husband!
Now if I am shot, the commissioner's
son-in-law dies, not Fakira!
I considered you my life.
And you made fun of my love.
I will pine for you all my life
but not alone! You too will pine!
Even if you wash off this vermilion...
You won't be able to forget it.
No other man will be able to
adorn this hair with vermilion!
You will have to turn him down
and not give any reasons.
You will be tortured! All your life!
No! Forgive me!
I was what I was earlier.
But now I am not what I was then.
Forgive me.
Forgive me! Please!
Should I address you
as Geeta or Neeta?
No, call me Geeta.
Somebody is at the door.
You'll be shot if
you make a run for it!
Come on!
What are you doing here?
Anything special?
You're acting innocent!
I don't get it.
Why did you have Vijay arrested?
Who is Vijay?
I gave no such orders.
But why are you so worried for him?
Why are you so annoyed?
Is this drama or reality?
Answer me. Why do you have
vermilion in your hair?
Vermilion? What???
- Where is it?
- In my hair.
- Do you know what it implies?
- Now I know.
What is his name?
What does he do?
Who are his parents?
Why don't you answer?
What can she say? We're
left with no face to answer.
You asked who he is.
I'll tell you.
He is a cheat! He commits thefts!
Such scoundrels have neither
family nor background!
They are a blot on the name
of the nation and society!
He is not as you describe him!
He is a decent human being!
He is like the lotus that
flowers even in the muck!
- Quiet!
- Send her out on jobs!
Turn your daughter into a son!
She's really ruined our name!
The son-in-law of the police
commissioner is a thief!
Print your picture with
your son-in-law in the papers!
Wouldn't I shoot him before that?
I don't accept this marriage!
Wipe off the vermilion!
- That's not possible!
- Shut up!
You will have to remove
him from your heart!
- Before that I'll leave this house!
- What did you say?
Don't you dare step out of this house!
You can leave this house
only after you are married!
- I am already married!
- I said I don't accept it!
What difference does that make?
So... you set out to beat me.
Got the fight out of you?
Stop! Bravo!
- Surprised?
- No.
Seeing the real you has saddened me.
This sorrow can still turn to joy.
If you promise to do as I say.
Would I dance to the tune of one
whose blood is tainted with treachery?
The fight hasn't gone out of you.
Stop! Don't beat him!
If I don't beat him,
should I welcome him?
- I'll set him right!
- You've done all you had to.
You mustn't beat a decent man so much.
Hope you're not hurt too much.
Hurts less than the wound
you're stabbing the nation with.
Do you know me?
How would I recognise the man
the Lord Almighty couldn't!
But I have caught a glimpse today.
Move aside. I'll show him the sights.
No. Anger is not good.
I'm burning in the fire of revenge!
I swear nobody has
humiliated me and survived!
I will kill him!
If you have the courage and are
your mother's son, uncuff me!
Then we'll see how kills whom!
Undo his bonds!
Fakira looks good in chains.
- No jokes, I give tit for tat.
- No.
Never poison a man who
can die with honey.
Love reforms the worst crooks.
And this poor unfortunate
soul is a mere human being.
We're brothers. He's a thief like us.
- Isn't it, son?
- No, son Chimanlal.
Though we're thieves, we're different.
Really? What difference?
You steal from the public and the
government and I steal from you!
What difference does that make?
Every man steals from one
who is less smart than him.
I am worthy of the public and the
government so I cheat both of them.
You are smarter than me
so you make a fool of me.
But when I came to my senses,
you're handcuffed in front of me.
It's her treachery not your
intelligence that brought me here!
It is smart to divide and rule.
I can annihilate you if I wish.
But I won't do so.
Because I appreciate intelligence.
You have brains.
I have the power. Wealth.
If we join forces, we can ruin
the government and the public!
- What do you say?
- My doubts were right.
- What?
- Just this...
...that you are not your father's son!
Only a pervert can betray his nation!
Take him to the torture chamber
and torment him till he dies!
You had promised
you wouldn't kill him!
I haven't killed him
I haven't even touched him.
You are a filthy dog
who can't keep his promise!
Are you a picture of loyalty?
You are disloyal and
expect loyalty from others?
And in what way is that
scoundrel better that me?
I wouldn't give you a second glance!
You won't spit at me, my love
you'll lick my heels!
Take her to my room!
- Come...
- Boss...
Square up my account.
Your account will be
squared up tomorrow.
I'll draw the money from the bank by
morning. You can collect in by noon.
Fine. I'll take leave.
Join me for a drink.
- To toast Fakira's death.
- Sure.
Quiet. It's time for you to stop
laughing and him to start weeping.
Swear by the Maker
take action fast!
Or he'll butcher everybody!
What a jump!
- Kill him!
- Just a minute.
God will kill him not us.
- How? - Tie bricks of cement to
each leg and throw him in the sea.
No police inquiries nor
difficulties to hide the corpse.
Throw him in.
Let's go back.
All four of you guard
this place for 24 hours.
So that nobody can rescue the body.
Spare me! Let me
bring his dead body out!
You killed Fakira?
That's a terrible sin!
You were in prison so you don't
know how much he helps the poor.
He is the saviour of the poor.
That's terrible. But why
didn't you tell me earlier?
Well, he was Kunwar... Lots of cash...
- Uncle...
- Yes?
Take a look at this. It seems
to be a picture of my childhood
Absolutely.
Then who is the other?
Your brother, Vijay.
My brother?
Could Fakira be my brother Vijay?
Ouch! Help!
Police! Help!
Help! It bit me!
- Are you Fakira's friend?
- Yes.
Kill me! I won't
say a word in protest!
Fakira is not yet dead.
My Fakira is alive!
- My Vijay is alive!
- Was Vijay, Fakira?
He was my real brother!
My flesh and blood!
- Your brother?
- Yes!
Do you remember me? I'm Popat!
I killed my own brother with
these very hands! Kill me!
This is not the time to argue.
First try to save Vijay!
- Only 7 minutes left.
- What does that mean? - Come with me!
- Hurry up!
- Don't worry.
Our brother does yoga.
He can hold his breath for 30 minutes.
I plead with you to hurry!
Stop! This is the spot!
Lord, I never asked you for anything.
For the first time in life I
beseech you to save my brother!
Found anything?
Can't find anything.
Just two minutes remain!
Brother... brother!
- He's not breathing.
- Everything will be fine.
If something happens to him...
Brother has regained consciousness!
God heard my prayers!
Forgive me, brother!
- Brother? - Yes, look at him.
Try to recognise. He's our Munna.
For whom you would cry,
for whom you'd ache!
Yes, I am that unfortunate
brother of yours.
Here, this is our childhood picture.
You were so close to me
yet you remained so far.
I have committed many
blunders out of ignorance.
I hit my elder brother!
Beat me, brother! Punish me!
Your punishment is that now
you will never leave me.
Had Laxman left Rama
that I would leave you?
My heart is at peace
now that now I've found you.
But the childhood fire that
burned out father to death...
It still rages in my heart.
- Those people...
- who were they?
Have you forgotten?
You too had hit them!
I... don't recall anything.
You were younger so you forgot.
But I won't forget those killers.
Those scoundrels were smugglers!
And that is why I hate all smugglers!
I searched for them high and low.
But they were not to be found.
Till I avenge the
death of my parents...
- I won't rest in peace!
- You're not alone.
Both of us will join hands
to find those murderers!
- Two? Why not three?
- Sure.
Your wife will be very
glad to hear about Ajay.
Your wife? Where is she?
The thighs I have to do for you!
This stupid thief has ruined my plan!
Let him enter. I'll teach him
a lesson that he'll forget his past!
- Talk softly!
- How can I talk softly.
You hit me so hard! Had you
hit my head, I would be dumb!
- How did you escape the police?
- They were hoodlums not cops.
- Why did you come here?
- Ban on visiting in-laws?
Not here!
Where else? Fine, on the bed.
What sound was that?
I was sleeping.
I was dreaming...
- What about the voice?
- That's what I'm saying.
Why are you holding the blanket?
This too is related to the dream.
- Funny dream.
- Absolutely.
I dreamt that a thief is entering
the house through the balcony.
He jumped in. I hit
him hard on his head.
He screamed. Then I turned
and saw it was Vijay!
- Where is he?
- In the dream.
I met him. Then you came
and I pulled up the blanket!
- Why are you holding it?
- You asked me that in the dream!
I hurriedly told Vijay, Run!
- Put the blanket down.
- Pardon?
Even in the dream, you
yanked the blanket away!
Move away!
What's the matter?
Nothing.
- I'm going.
- Okay.
Go to bed.
What's going on?
She's singing because she
can't fall asleep. Go to bed.
But...
What sound was that?
Whatever it be!
You go to sleep!
What's going on?
Whatever is happening is right.
It's daylight!
Now what?
Get up.
Let me sleep.
- It's bright day!
- Shut your eyes, it will turn dark.
If your father-in-law finds out,
he'll send you to prison!
And also thrash you.
Nobody can thrash the
one you have blasted.
Just get me some hot tea.
Tea? If I call anyone up here...
- What?
- Shut up and get up!
I'll get up but I'm not leaving.
I'll spend my honeymoon in this room.
- I'll get out after 8 days.
- 8 days!
Not enough? We'll make it a fortnight
- You don't know my Dad!
- Go on!
When the couple are willing
the commissioner can't interfere.
Quickly arrange for some breakfast
or I'll yell for the commissioner.
- Shall I call him?
- Don't yell!
Go into the bathroom.
They got married.
Neeta was living with him.
What must have happened then...
Do you think any decent
boy will marry her now?
Don't irritate me. We'll cross
that bridge when we come to it.
Just do as I say.
- Yes sir?
- Where are you taking this?
Your daughter has asked for breakfast.
Do you see that?
She's come to her senses.
- But so much?
- She's ordered for double!
What's so surprising?
She hasn't eaten anything for days.
Go ahead.
- I'll go and see her.
- No, she's hungry.
If you go up, another scene will ensue
- Don't bother her.
- Okay, I'm going out.
Ensure that she doesn't go out.
Smells of clarified butter.
Does the commissioner accept bribes?
My Daddy is a principled
and honest officer.
Impossible! An honest man
can't afford oil these days.
My grandfather was a landlord.
After him my Daddy owns the land.
If you inherit your Daddy's wealth,
for the peace of our ancestors...
Distribute it among the poor.
God Almighty... just a minute...
Okay, I'll do as you please.
Now eat and make a move.
I'm not leaving!
Won't Ajay and Popat be worried?
Are they little infants
to cry for their mother?
They know the lover has gone to
his beloved with heart in hand...
The exchange of hearts takes time.
- What is the matter?
- He winked at me!
My brother after all!
Meaning you are a family of loafers.
Now I'm just your chauffeur,
It must be urgent if Ajay has come.
I must leave.
- Good day, sir.
- Good day.
Hey! Listen...
Where is the idol?
This idol is 4000 years old.
We risked our lives to steal it.
In return you're getting
your price. Give me the box.
No, not in this manner.
First give me 50000 bucks.
- How did he come to life?
- To kill you!
I don't understand anything.
How did that twerp escape?
You destroyed me.
He will destroy you.
Shut up!
If they don't pay in
Hong Kong for the idol...
I will be ruined!
My last idea sir.
My brain is turning stale.
Use it to your advantage.
All right! What is it?
You are a social worker,
the servant of the rich.
That I am! But how does it help?
Everything, my sir.
Your private secretary will
inform all the newspapers...
All the social workers
will present their...
...leader Chimanbhai with a cake
made of gold on his 50th birthday.
It will be adorned with
50 candles made of gold.
Apart from the candles,
they will have 50 diamonds!
We offer it to him.
The total worth will be 5 crores!
What does that achieve?
Don't you see? Fakira will
start drooling at this news.
That's a large sum. He will
be drawn into our trap easily.
Great! Bravo, my tiger!
I'm sorry I didn't
identify a gem like you!
Inform the press.
Arrange for the celebration.
Wear it!
Fakira will definitely
come for the gold and diamonds.
Set the CID all around.
Surround the hall.
He must not escape
the eyes of the police!
You will stay with us.
But not in uniform.
In the disguise of a signer.
But there'll be lots of people!
Yes but there will be singers
to entertain the public.
I've fixed everything!
I just have to fit things in!
If that is fit, here goes!
Indication, the matter is a hit!
The honour my brothers
have showered on me...
For that I am very...
- Grateful.
- I'm grateful.
Brothers and sisters...
Chimanbhai is our great leader.
He has been serving us for 30 years.
I hope he performs
his duties for ages.
On the 50th birthday of this great
man, my brothers and all of us...
...want to bestow a gift on him.
And there is the gift!
Bring it here.
Gently... carefully...
Brothers, this precious
treasure costing 5 crores...
We present it to our leader!
This guy seems to be Toofan.
Shall I pull off his beard?
We want Fakira, not Toofan!
- Shall I grab his beard?
- Watch the drama.
I'll catch Fakira red handed.
Our men are spread all around.
Swear by the Maker,
they are all policemen!
Fear not. When his daughter
is ours, he is no match.
My chest expands with joy!
The love and honour
my town has bestowed on me...
I can never forget it!
I will spend all this money
for the welfare of my brethren!
- Chimanbhai!
- Long live!
You won't get a better
opportunity to fool the wealthy.
- What the?
- Brothers!
Seeing your pathetic condition,
my great leader's heart bleeds.
So he will auction his clothes!
He will spend the money
collected on the poor fellow men.
No, praise yourselves not me.
What humility! What love!
I'm floored by this love!
I bid a thousand for this cap!
- Is that all?
- Two thousand!
Nobody can cross me. 3000!
5000!
The fools swallowed the bait!
Pay the money there and take the cap.
And this is the shawl that our
leader wore in 1948 for his wedding!
- 5000!
- 5000??
How stupid! It costs
much more. Go beyond that.
If it's a matter of whom
the cap fits, I quote 15000.
Our bags will be full!
I underestimated a gem like you!
Let me carry on.
Brothers! Bid for the shawl!
20000 diamond rings!
- 20000!!
- The shawl is yours!
- Sir
- What is it?
- Your shirt.
- No!
Observe his spirit of service.
He's giving the shirt off his back!
Shame on me! Why didn't I
stand for elections all this while?
It's never too late.
The shirt goes for 40000!
Will anyone go beyond it?
This jewelry worth 50000!
I won't disappoint my fans.
- Give it to him.
- I want the dhoti!
What... Oh, sure!
Don't you dare touch it!
Your name will go down in history!
- I will be nude!
- But you're wearing your underwear!
- Yes.
- Then take this off!
Your great leader has taken
his pants off for your welfare!
- 20000.
- What nonsense! I'll pay 25000!
This will go only to Rajasthan!
Write down a lakh from my wife!
A lakh! It is yours!
- Sir!
- Now what?
- Take off the underwear.
- No! - I say, take it off!
- No way!
- Take it off!
What a loss for an underwear!
Brothers and sisters,
to entertain you...
We present famous singers,
Sherali and Babbarali.
In opposition with them are...
Ustad Bhole and Bambhole!
Feeling very cold!
Sir, you have to face minor
difficulties in public service.
Shut up!
Nobody will leave!
Check the electricity!
Quietly be seated.
Where is my cake!
My candles! My diamonds!
The cash and jewelry of the auction...
All gone! Fakira has taken it!
The scoundrel made me nude in public!
But sir, I gave the idea
for your advantage.
To my advantage or so that
everybody could focus on me.
And Fakira could steal everything!
I thought you were smart!
You have ruined me!
Forgive me!
Put him in the pool all night.
He'll die of cold by morning.
Take him away! Stop!
- Take off my ring!
- That's the only thing left!
- Let it be.
- Take him away!
Sir!
I'll see how that rascal
Fakira escapes my clutches!
- Who is speaking?
- Neeta here.
I'm calling on behalf of
Vijay. He has said...
Reach Tulsi Lake at 5 in the evening
I'll be there.
Let me lay my hands on him,
Then I'll see...
I wish I had thought of this earlier.
Every dog has his day.
We have the upper hand now.
Your beloved is in our custody.
To set accounts right,
be at the old airport at 3.
If you act smart,
you won't find her corpse.
Have you brought all the loot?
You can count it after
you hand Neeta over to me.
- I trust you.
- But I don't trust you.
How can you trust me?
The ache of separation hurts.
It's only a question of 15 minutes.
Then it will be her
beautiful arms and you.
It must be great to
hold her in your arms.
Wrestlers like you can't know that.
Hurry! Faster!
We're close to the place.
Look down there!
Neeta is with my men!
Turn the plane and
bring it back to this spot.
If you harm my brother,
I'll kill you!
- Why did he enter the plane?
- Even I don't understand that!
Where is the plane gone?
- Turn right. - Why?
- The needle says so!
Tie this parachute and jump down.
- My loot...
- First the parachute.
Listen. As soon as Fakira jumps...
Be alert.
His body should hit the ground.
- Come on, hurry!
- Hail Lord Hanuman!
Help! Help!
- Let go of me!
- Should I? No!
Don't let go of me!
Boss is with him? Don't fire!
Where's my bag? Yes, it's here!
Don't let go of this dog!
Else they will shoot you!
Stop!
Throw down your guns!
Or I'll shoot out his brains!
Throw your guns.
Now tell me, where Neeta is.
- She is inside.
- He's lying! She's not in.
She doesn't know. I'll
locked her in the dungeon!
He's playing a trick!
Answer me truthfully
or I'll have to kill you!
- Answer!
- All right.
I've tied her inside the effigy
of Ravana in the Ramleela ground.
So that she gets burnt with it.
Burnt? You are the devil incarnate!
I'll kill you before she dies!
Don't kill me. There are two
hours before Ravana is set aflame.
We can reach in an hour.
- Come on.
- Get the car.
Drive the car.
- Vijay!
- Stop the car!
Get the bag.
Got the loot and the enemy is no more.
Full of stones!
Got the loot? Want to
square up the account?
I'll settle scores in such a way
that your soul will shudder!
If you don't tell me
where the loot is...
You'll die here and
she'll die there!
All arrangements fine?
There's still time.
Tell me where my loot is!
Never will I tell you!
You won't give in
so easily. Wrestler!
Dance!
Your steps will take him
closer to death!
Don't just watch. Beat her
till she starts dancing!
Look there!
What have you done!
Forget it. I've been
punished for my sins.
Time is short.
Go and save Neeta.
Hands up!
I've been released from
prison after 20 years.
But I've come just in time.
No! You won't escape alive!
The murderer of my father!
You ruined my family!
I won't spare you alive!
My father died in the fire he lit!
He slapped me hard to give me
money for my mother's medicines!
He's the one who stole our joys!
Kill him! I'm burning in the
flames set by him years ago!
Let go! You rascal!
Let go of my leg and hold my hand.
Baldie! What's wrong?
What's the matter?
So you're the children of that master?
Good. You were all fated
to die at my hands!
You dog! Had I known you were
responsible for our ruin...
I wouldn't have let you live!
I won't commit the same mistake.
Kill this rogue!
You dog! You will die not him!
I'm returning the money you
gave for my mother's medication!
Take this money!
Take this!
And this!
Isn't this how you killed my Dad?
I'll make mincemeat of you! Brother!
You look after him.
I'll ruin you!
Here is that ungrateful wretch!
Catch them! Let none escape!
Now if you raise your head,
I'll snap your neck!
They are going to light
the effigies. Hurry up.
Hail Lord Rama!
Stop! Who is this fool?
Arrest him!
Neeta! My child!
- Move out, sir!
- Get out!
I have come!
Don't worry. I'm on my way!
Don't be scared. I'm almost there.
I... I am bound by the law.
Chimanlal is the real
culprit, not him!
- What? - See for yourself
if you don't trust me.
He is lying unconscious in the car.
If anyone comes towards me,
I'll kill them!
Stop!
Handcuff him.
Swear by the Maker,
our young one is here!
No, brother. I'll hold him
while you may hold her.
I don't think I should
break Popat's heart.
Sweet little baby.
Grandpa is here!
Grandpa is here! Good day sir.
Live long, son.
What's wrong?
What happened to Munna?
What's wrong with him?
- How's that?
- Good.
He'll be one up on you.
My Junior Fakira!