What's the time?
02:23 and 10 seconds. Beep!
Christ, you'll have to leave. Bye.
John, dear. Come!
-Come and lie with me.
-No, don't pull me. I can't.
Please, just leave.
What the hell's gotten into you?
I'm sleeping here!
No, you're not. Get lost, go!
You're hurting me!
I don't feel well.
-Please.
-Okay, I'm going!
-Good.
-Shit!
I live out in Angered.
It's damned cold!
Then you must take a taxi. Here.
200 kronor should be enough.
If I'd known what a fucking...
You regret this, little man?
Take another hundred.
Reception will order a taxi for you.
You're a...
Hello, it's me.
Yes,
I know it's almost 02:30, but I must...
I need the telephone number
of George Mezinski in Los Angeles.
It on the notepad by the telephone.
Yes, I have to call tonight.
I'm sorry, Anna. No, I'm not drunk...
Is someone there with you?
The radio's on?
I see, Tina is still up.
Yes, thanks. Los Angeles, yeah...
Yes, one, two. Thanks.
When I called yesterday evening,
no one answered.
No, damn...
Shit!
Is anybody home?
Don't shout.
John Jr's asleep with a fever.
-Hi.
-Hope it's nothing serious, then.
-No, it's just a cold.
Yeah...
-How was Gothenburg?
-Zandor got drunk as usual.
But we sold the new novel well anyway.
The booksellers think he's so colorful.
-Have you started smoking?
-No. Why?
Why? There's a butt here, a slim More.
The same that Carl smokes.
Really? I don't know.
-It must be Tina.
-So, she's started smoking again?
Sorry, I have to go to the store.
I haven't bought dinner.
-I called earlier, but no one answered.
-No, I was at the pharmacy.
-You weren't going to work at all.
-Inger got sick.
But I answered when you called
at 02:30 the other night.
Yeah, but I had to call George.
Los Angeles, six hours.
It's very strange you don't
have his number in your phone book.
-You wrote it when he was here last fall.
-I forgot it at the office.
At Hasse's place, they have a video,
and we saw a horrible film
about a guy who shot another guy
in the foot so it exploded.
There was another guy
who threw a fox trap over his head...
A gun! Is it real?
It's a water pistol.
But you can't shoot it inside.
But at the country house this summer,
we can shoot.
-Did you miss your dad?
-Not much.
I've been at Hasse's for two days.
I got the cold from him.
Was Tina at Sophie's Saturday and Sunday?
No, not indoors I said!
What a dumb gift that was.
-So Mom's been alone for a few days?
-No.
A stranger was here Saturday
and Fia and Jens were here after.
-You have a hickey on your neck, Dad.
-Hi. What's that?
-What the hell are you saying?
-Just kidding.
Do you have a bad conscience?
Such silliness!
Stop it, you horrible brat! Cut it out!
Calm down.
Give him the gun. Not like that!
You can't shoot indoors.
Remember, he's sick.
-What about me? Don't I get anything?
-Yes, you get Zandor's new novel.
-I get it for free anyway.
-Mom said you'd started smoking again.
What's she talking about?
I'm actually 18
and I do what I like!
You're nuts, John.
There's no way Anna's having an affair.
But she was quite hot for you in Italy,
for instance.
That was 14 years ago!
And it was just a bit of fun.
Pull yourself together, John.
That damn Italian party
is nothing to get hung up on.
No. Alright, then.
You're feeling guilty
about that broad in Gothenburg.
It's not so odd.
Napoleon said that infidelity occurs
when there's a sofa nearby.
I was at Eberman's home in Frankfurt.
His wife's a bit... You know.
He went out to buy cigarettes.
-She pulled me into the bedroom and...
-Clara Fallgren is here.
And Stig Svensson.
I came along to make sure
everything goes by the book.
-We want a big goddamn advance.
-Yeah, okay.
-Have you read...?
-Welcome, Clara.
Great you could come.
You know how much I like your poems.
-Please, take a seat.
-Thanks.
-It's the best writing in years.
-This century.
-Hello.
-Yes, this is John. Clara.
I thought you were a lot... older.
I read the manuscript yesterday.
It moved me.
It's as if you have
so much experience of life.
-Anyone have a beer?
-Sorry.
No, but we have Cognac. Of course
we're going to celebrate our new poet.
With a glass of Renault Carte Noire.
That okay?
That's good. Make mine a large one.
“And the key turns in my heart
as I lock my summer house.”
You've read it, I hear.
Only, it's not her summer house.
No, it was Stig's father's.
But he sold it.
Hi.
-Sorry we're late.
-Where's Stig?
-He's in a bad mood.
-No, he couldn't come. He's working.
-He has to write an article.
-Bullshit. He's just sulking.
Hello.
I'm Anna. John's other half.
What a wonderful day. Is it far?
No, it's on that little island.
It's called Askholmen.
Jesus, it's cold!
Go, Dad, go!
Hi! Anyone want a ride?
Me!
-Wait for me!
-How exciting! Where do I sit?
Sit up front and hold the mast.
-We'll take it easy.
-Be really careful, Clara!
-John's lethal.
-Geronimo!
We're coming about. Hold on!
Goddamn madman!
Watch out!
-What the hell are you doing?
-Stig!
Hi. I changed my mind.
You're fucking nuts!
Come on!
Food's ready.
Well...
You're welcome.
-You could have killed us.
-Wishful thinking.
Give Mom a kiss!
Let's have a sauna!
I put on the sauna out there.
Yes, let's get those pants off!
Oh, yeah. You just want
to see Tina naked. Small girls...
-That's all that turns him on.
-Let's strip off!
-Yeah, let's strip.
-Is this a damn orgy, or what?
Sure, hygiene's important, Stig!
Jerk! Forget it... Come on, let's go home.
I don't want to. Let me go!
Come on, you little hussy.
Let's calm down.
We'll forget about the sauna.
Let's have herring
and a drink in the kitchen.
-Publisher asshole, who you think you are?
-Damn nutso!
Go to hell! You know, I paid for all this.
Not only me, but other writers.
They've written all this with their blood.
-So you could buy all this.
-You're a real black pudding!
What the fuck are you doing?
Check out the cocktail sausage!
What's that for? Come on.
I'm staying.
Come on.
Come on! Do I have to carry you?
If you move, I'll shoot.
Here's some ink, so you can write
a few more summer houses for us!
Jesus, you're assholes.
Aren't you coming, Clara?
-Where's my jacket?
-Stay!
-If you stay you'll go back to Beckis!
-Stay, Stig!
-You can't drive. You've been drinking!
-It's fine.
There's no traffic on the ice in winter.
-Bye, you murderer!
-You're all nuts.
-What are you doing here?
-Why can't I have my own bed?
You know Carl wouldn't leave Clara alone
if they slept in the big room.
I want you now.
-Why do you always...?
-Always?
It's never!
-You detest me.
-You can love in other ways.
Clara can sleep in the big room...
Okay, do it against the sink. But be
quick, I have to give Fia and Jens towels.
"In this fucking truth...
And when he'd thanked the Devil for
the meal, there was no light in his eyes.
He stamped on the chest of his companion
and tied a knot in the swan's neck."
We thank Clara Fallgren for her reading.
Now I'd like to present Carl-Magnus von
Seth who'll read some of his latest poems.
I've brought with me some local poetry
from the village where I live.
I'll read a few poems.
"The outer helps up the inner
a little bit.
If you enter our bedroom
you'll see that our bodies
float above the treetops.
It's a chestnut and two cherry trees."
Thanks for the dinner.
For everything.
You've been so very kind.
Considerate.
To read for all these people...
-Could you see my hands shaking?
-No.
You were good.
Listen...
How are things with Stig?
-And you?
-Not good.
He's so...
Well, he's unhappy.
-Does he hit you?
-No, but...
He's in a dead-end.
Yeah. Life isn't tripping
the light elastic as Kate Rolfsen said.
No.
-You feel like a whisky?
-No, thanks.
I have to look a bit fresh tomorrow.
In the bookstore when I'm signing books.
If anyone comes.
And I'm going to see my dad.
I'd love to stay, but I have
to catch a plane in the morning.
There's been some mix-up with Zandor.
And the Book of the Month.
Good night.
God, you scared me!
You weren't due back until tonight.
You drinking stereo coffee?
There are two cups.
-No, Carl was here. Didn't you meet him?
-Yes.
-Does he live here now?
-Stop it!
He came half an hour ago to leave some
papers. You know he's off to London.
You moved the painting
from the fireplace to the sofa?
-Yes, I think the light's better there.
-Yeah, it looks good there.
We must get rid of that English hunting
thing. Where the hell will we hang it?
In the toilet. I'm so tired of it.
So Carl was so charmed by you
he forgot to leave the papers?
No. Here you are.
-Suffocating.
-What?
What?
-What did you say?
-Nothing.
I just think it's suffocatingly hot here.
Well, then turn down the heat.
-How was Ystad?
-It was as usual.
Is there any coffee left over for me?
The train stops at the station.
Three men get off.
It's me, the deaf and the blind. He sees,
the other one hears - I stand beside them.
-Do you want...?
-No thanks.
I just want quiet!
Must you eat crispbread?
You're being silly. I'm going out
as soon as I've had my coffee.
Leave your damn silence here.
How can I work when you walk around
in silence all the time?
I do everything I can not to disturb you.
I'm out all day.
I can't turn into a gas.
You're like a damn gas
because you suffocate me.
How can I work when you tell me
"Must you? Must you write
when you can help with the dishes?
"Must you write when we can go
to the movies, talk or watch Dallas?
"Must you write
when the sun shines, when it rains?"
And me?
I have to write when you sleep, at night.
Your fucking poems...
You'd go crazy if I wrote
in the bedroom while you worked here.
-Go and sleep. Go to bed.
-No, I'm going out.
-Go to bed!
-To sea, to sea...
I hate you! You get it?
Hello. Hello...
Ladies and gentlemen.
A warm welcome to
Olovsson and Hjortfelt's 10th anniversary!
We've put on
a smorgasbord in the basement.
Eat, drink and be merry,
for tomorrow is another gray day.
Cheers!
I got a refusal on deductions for my
workspace from that damn tax inspector.
-I've had it four years, he didn't care!
-That's how they are.
I've got an Alfa Romeo.
It's a damned good car.
-I always had a thing for Citroens.
-Also very good.
I wonder where that blonde went?
Fucking leeches!
You know, I asked him
if I could have a small goddamn advance.
The sonofabitch just looked at me,
as though he thought I was nuts.
Which, by the way, is a misunderstanding.
I usually take payment in whisky.
It's much better for both parties.
Especially at readings.
You know that girl from the radio?
That worked out just fine.
-The dark-haired continuity girl?
-No, the blonde.
-But she lived out in Tensta.
-Oh, God.
-You're really putting it away.
-You must seize the day on company dime.
Of course,
it's healthiest and best to eat at home.
Home-made. Mom's meatballs...
What if you don't get much at home?
I often go to bed very hungry.
Then you have the right
to eat somewhere else.
Maybe you could offer me
something tasty sometime?
Oh yes. At home I try and come
up with all kinds of variations, but...
Jens doesn't eat that much.
John? Jan Myrdal is looking for you.
-You can't only chat with your secretary.
-We were talking about Mom's meatballs.
Jan Myrdal? Right.
My goodness! The accountant
peeping at the toilets again?
Helena Lagerborg is in there with Acke
Zandor! And Lars-Åke Jansson...
They're doing a bit of...
What are you up to?
Hey! Leif or whatever
your name is.
-You have any more wine?
-You've had enough.
You've had enough...
You don't fucking decide, you gay asshole!
Stop it, Stig. Let's join the others.
Who the fuck does he think he is?
Stig!
Let go of me!
I'm leaving. I'll go with Carl.
-Are we going or what?
-I must stay to make sure people get home.
-He's right!
-You're stuck in the whipping cream!
-Let's go!
-Goodbye.
-Bye.
-See you at the barricades tomorrow.
-Turn the lights out. Okay?
-Bye. Come on Jens, let's go.
-No!
There's loads of wine left.
I'm going to take a couple of bottles.
I'm leaving now anyway.
The taxi has been waiting for ages.
Stig? Stig! Come on, get up!
You won't be able to wake him now.
No? Well, he'll have
to lie there until tomorrow.
Can he?
Thanks.
Oh, water is so good!
Yeah, water is good when you're...
Please Clara, don't cry.
Clara.
Don't cry. Clara, don't cry. Clara?
Hi! I thought you could come home
with me. We finished early today.
You didn't yesterday.
You didn't come home.
No, it got late yesterday.
It was hard to find a taxi.
-I slept on the sofa in my room.
-Really?
Stig passed out on the floor in the
basement. He threw up on the carpet!
Pig...
I have some errands in town.
Go home and sleep.
You can pick up John Jr from school
on the way. He'll be happy.
-Sure. Bye.
-Bye.
Dad's very special. He loves boats and has
an echo sounder to measure depth with.
When he sails he looks at it and says,
"Wow, it's deep here!"
Then he sails a bit more and says,
"Wow, it's not that deep here!”
I have to find somewhere to live.
I can always go home to Dad.
I can write there.
In Skåne? No, then we won't get to meet!
-Well, I may have an idea.
-Really? What?
It's not much to look at, but...
-Do you know someone with an apartment?
-Yes. I have an apartment.
-Where?
-I inherited some buildings in Södermalm.
There's a one room apartment in one
of them. It's not modern or anything.
It doesn't matter.
So, you're a real capitalist?
That's great!
There's no elevator,
but there's a corner store.
-I love Södermalm.
-A used car salesman lived there before.
The stairs are tough...
Everyone I know who lives in buildings
without elevators lives on the top floor!
There's a law for that.
Step in, to paradise.
Not much of a view. But the room is big.
Big...
There's a bathtub!
-A stove.
-Yes, you can light a fire in it.
-We'll buy new furniture on Monday.
-No!
What for? It's fine the way it is.
I think that you're good.
I think that you're very good.
But I can't, Stig.
No, I'm not. But I can't anymore.
Listen to me...
Listen, I just called
to say my stuff, the old guitar,
the dictionary
or whatever else, you can keep them.
Or throw them away, do whatever you like.
Yeah...
You could tell me where you are.
No. Yeah...
Be seeing you, Clara. Take it easy.
Yeah, yeah...
I'm working like hell, you know.
The Greenery is almost finished.
I have to fry a pork chop,
so I can't talk.
Bye, take it easy. Bye.
Totally professional!
Now you can be here without throwing up.
It's really nice in here now.
-Let's forget this now and go for a swim.
-Yeah.
What's this? No...!
Look at this!
My panties have been cut to bits.
All of them.
What the hell?
I didn't notice
when I took them off the line.
Fucking kids!
Let's get going.
We'll pick up new ones on the way.
I have to buy typewriter ribbon as well.
This is crazy!
-Tina!
-I'm full. Anyway, I'm off to town.
-I'll take the little boat.
-What are you going to do?
-All kinds of things.
I'm going to a movie tonight.
I'll sleep at Lena's.
Okay, is that his name now? Lennart?
John Jr and I
will go to my mother's for a week.
I guess you're working?
-Yes, I'm off to Malmö for a few days.
-Good. Then you won't miss us.
So what shall I say to Richter?
Tell him I'm away until Monday,
but that he can come then.
Hi. Yes, I'm off to Malmö now.
That means, to you.
We'll have a little crayfish party.
I have some in the freezer at home.
Then a Dopff Dry
and a really smelly cheese.
No, she's gone
to her mother's with John Jr.
Four days. Just us...
Anna.
-What is it, John?
-Nothing.
-Where are the crayfish?
-Screw the crayfish!
-You're hurting me.
-I love you.
I love you like hell! Do you hear?
Everything's finished.
No!
It starts now. Life starts now!
God, John.
If only you knew what you mean to me.
I've found a kind of peace
these past few months.
I've never written so much. Look.
-Can I read it?
-No...!
Later. I have to rewrite and rewrite.
Turn the words and chew them over.
Do you think it could always be like this?
Come.
-Does Stig know where you live now?
-No.
I don't think so.
I'll sleep in the study from now on
so you won't have my snoring.
That's very good.
You're seldom here, anyway.
And when you are,
you're just irritated when I read in bed.
Well, you don't like being woken up
when I come home late.
Exactly.
I can have the window open
without you going crazy.
Yup.
And I can have the sheets all to myself.
What do you mean?
I mean exactly what I say.
Is anyone there?
...the latest election.
Postal votes could decide, but the Green
Party will hold the balance of power.
"We've won a great victory,"
said Prime Minister Olof Palme last night,
who, visibly relieved...
Now we're going to have an orgy
of champagne and omelet!
And if you get a splash of champagne
then everything becomes intoxicating...
It's nice being in the rain with you.
Such warm rain! Are we in Hawaii?
-No, we're in Hönefoss.
-Hönefoss!
Yeah!
What is it?
I feel weird.
I can't explain it.
No! What's up with you?
-It's as if someone was watching us.
-There's not even a window.
I've felt it all day.
It felt like someone was following me
in the park yesterday.
-You're just imagining it.
-Yes...
-I haven't heard from Stig.
-He doesn't know where you live.
-He could have called the publisher.
-It's good he's dropped it.
I don't want to be in here.
Let's go into the room.
I'm sorry I have things to do.
I have to have Mankiewicz
to dinner at home
and go with him to London tomorrow.
Yes, I know.
Goodbye, John.
What is it?
I think you're good.
I think you're very good.
I know what you're doing!
You don't fool me! I have contacts!
Watch out, you assholes. Watch out!
-You're a hussy!
-What?
-You're nervous, you're imagining things.
-But I heard it.
And someone's after me on the street.
That building's creepy.
Your damn building!
No, it's not true!
-You don't believe me?
-No.
I just called him.
Yes, and...
Like that. And he said...
WHY DO YOU EAT SO MANY ORANGES?
-You want any?
-No thanks.
It must be some kid who wrote that.
You don't believe me.
You think I made it up?
-No...
-Yes, you do.
No, seriously, I think it's
some young guy who's...
...got the hots for you. He follows
you around and scribbles stuff like that.
There are no young guys in the building.
Just that horrible old man one floor down.
-I haven't seen anyone on the first floor.
-A Volvo director, lives in Gothenburg.
He's very rarely here.
The other apartments are empty.
There's a pimply-faced guy
in the grocery store sometimes.
Then it's him! The oranges!
Solved.
There is someone. There's someone...
John? Someone's been here.
Yes, I'm sure. My manuscript. It was in
the drawer and I found it on the highboy.
It was me.
I looked at it last night
and forgot to put it back.
I know you didn't want me to read it,
but I couldn't help it.
Don't worry.
I'll see you this evening at seven.
Yeah. Bye.
-Is the poetess acting up?
-No.
It was nothing. So, where were we?
-We were going through remainders.
-Yes.
No...
Help!
Open! Help!
I know who you are. I know everything.
Instruments are recording it.
You won't fool me!
Cla... Clara!
Clara!
How are you? Clara? Clara!
-Shouldn't I take you to the hospital?
-No, I'm okay now.
John? Someone must have been here.
The window was closed.
Clara. They blew shut.
They weren't hooked open.
You had them open to air.
The door over there also blew shut. Look.
When I shut the door,
this thing falls down.
-What about the window catch?
-It's so worn out.
It's lucky you came!
We have to change the lock. Promise me?
Stay with me.
John?
What are you doing here at this time?
What are you doing in here?
Hasse and I are doing a paper called
"Stockholm's Blood Broadsheet."
I'm writing a story about a guy
called Peter who meets a werewolf...
How many times have I told you
not to touch Dad's things?
-But I just...
-Why can't...? I'm sorry!
I'm sorry, John. I'm sorry.
I got upset. Don't cry. I didn't mean it.
John, you know what?
At work I have a machine
that can photograph and copy papers.
When your paper is ready
I could make several copies for you.
My darling John.
I like you so much...
A packet of crispbread, please.
-Crispbread... No oranges today?
-No!
-No, thanks.
-Orange juice is healthy.
But the lady is one of them that only
drinks Champagne wine, right? I know.
It's a crappy novel
he's written this time.
On the contrary, it's his best book.
You lost your nose, John?
Is your little poetess
sucking the juice out of you?
-Fucking asshole! Shut up!
-Are you crazy? What are you doing?
-Think I don't know? I don't give a shit!
-What? I don't understand.
Maybe I'm naive, but I love Clara.
I live at home only for the kids.
Anna is nothing to me!
I didn't mean what I said, John.
I was kidding. It was a joke.
You have a fucking annoying
sense of humor!
I was home
when you thought I was in Malmö.
I saw your clothes and I saw you with...
Oh, shit. You saw us?
I love her. I know she loves me.
I'm really careful.
It disgusts me!
-And you disgust me!
-Just listen!
-We're two adults!
-We're old friends! Fucking hell!
John...
Okay, I'll end it with her today.
If you say so, I'll end it with her. Okay?
That's the sleaziest thing I ever heard.
Get out!
I don't give a shit what you both do.
Okay. I'll go to the Frankfurt Book Fair
so you won't see me for a week.
If only it was forever!
Clara is here. She seems very upset.
-Do you want me to...
-Yeah.
-What is it?
-I can't stay there. I can't.
-Calm down, Calm down...
-I can't, I can't.
-I've made an important decision.
-What?
I'm moving in with you. For good.
-What about Anna? The kids?
-Well, it is what it is.
-It's not working. I'm getting a divorce.
-Are you sure?
Yes, because... Because...
Because you are very good.
So, here's a little kissing party...
Sorry, barging in to
the lovefest like this. But..
-I heard Clara was here so I...
-Yes, what is it?
Well, good news.
Your poetry collection sold out.
Not bad! We've printed
a new edition of 6,000 copies.
It's more than we've done for years
for a little book of poems.
-That's great. I'd never have believed it.
-But I did. I knew it!
-And Clara's almost finished a new one.
-Good to hear!
8,000 copies for the first edition.
-Take it easy. We have to see it first.
-You've read it.
-A little bit, anyway.
-Yeah...
Yes, it seems exciting.
Well, then maybe
I should leave the young lovers.
Yeah. Sure.
-Tonight we'll have an engagement party!
-Oh, you're so good!
Go and change into your best dress
and I'll pick you up at 7:30.
Cheers.
-To our young happiness.
-Cheers.
-Have you spoken to your wife?
-Yes, I've spoken to her.
She took it very coolly. She just said,
"That's good John."
"I won't have to wash
your underwear anymore."
It feels terrible. I like her a lot.
I have loved her.
I don't anymore.
I've started looking for a proper
apartment. I've spoken to an agent.
A three-room apartment on Östermalm.
I think I'm going to make it a five-room.
-We have to live respectably.
-It costs money.
Yes it does, but there are the means here.
I'm going to have you,
just for your means.
Wait! Wait, I know her!
-I know her! It's my...
-Yes it is! It's your fault!
You poisoned my eggs.
There are spots on all of them!
-Go to hell. I know you!
-Lie down!
He's going.
Now we're alone in the whole building.
He was creepy.
It must have been him all along.
Let's say so. If it was anyone.
Of course it was him who wrote
on the door. About oranges.
-I bought you some oranges.
-I hate oranges!
Oh, it's perfect, perfect!
Far removed from all those powder sauces!
Taste.
I have to resort to French.
It tastes magnifique.
When we were at Askholmen in winter
and were iceboating, Stig said,
"If you stay you'll go back to Beckis."
What did he mean?
He meant what he said.
We met there. At Beckomberga.
-The nuthouse.
-You never told me.
You know, my mother was very beautiful.
Extremely beautiful.
And extremely tired. And Dad...
A farming bastard. Square.
Very sad.
And...
When I was 12, a bookseller turned up.
Slicked back hair.
He walked so damned beautifully.
So Mom left with him.
But he sold two books to Dad:
Character Building by H. I. Fosdick
and Marriage is Ordained by God
by Emil Löfstedt.
Marriage isn't ordained
by Emil Löfstedt, but by God.
-Don't kid around, go on.
-Yeah.
But he's a very good father.
Not Emil Löfstedt, but God... No, Dad!
So, I was out there on the farm with him.
Nothing happened.
Then we had a fight one day
because I wanted to learn to ride
a motorbike and he didn't want me to.
So I threw a wooden clog at his head.
And I took the train to the city
to stay with Mom.
You look nuts
with that sauce on your nose!
It's written: "It starts with a pin and
ends with a silver bowl." But it's wrong.
I started with a silver bowl,
an antique from 1755.
That belonged to the book peddler.
So Mom reported me to the police.
That was impossible for me.
She just didn't care.
You understand?
There was a guy that...
...cared a little bit about me.
Jan-Erik Johansson was his name.
He was what you'd call an addict
of stimulating neurological substances.
Well...
I swallowed 100 tablets.
Ended up in the nuthouse.
That's where I met Stig.
Then I wrote a thousand poems...
...and was rejected.
And rejected. And rejected.
And I'm here now.
It's no more remarkable than that.
Sorry, I didn't mean to interrogate you.
I love you.
You're very good, you mean.
Promise me we'll never marry.
Because marriage
is only ordained by Emil Löfstedt.
Everyone is unhappy. Besides you and me.
James?
Here kitty...
Did James get out
when you left this morning?
Well, you know how he is.
He could be gone for days.
No, I don't want anything, thanks.
I'm sure. Eat before you come.
No, I'm fine.
See you. Bye.
Fallgren.
What?
Leave John Hjortfelt the fuck alone!
You've broken up a happy marriage
that lasted almost 20 years.
Get out of town. Go to hell!
DAYS OF ASHES
NIGHTS OF IRON
I thought the title was so good, I asked
Folke to put a cover together now.
-Huh?
-Yeah.
I don't know. Maybe she'll never...
A weirdo called Silt or something
called and said you must come.
I don't know any damn Silt!
It was about Clara.
He says he works at the grocery store.
Really? I'm sorry, Jens.
I have to go there.
It's been a bit tough lately. I'm sorry.
Clara?
Oh, good God!
Hello, anyone here? Hello, Mr. Silt?
My name's not Silt.
It's Schüllt! S-C-H-Ü-L-L-T!
-You called about a woman...?
-Miss Fallgren is here.
What's happened?
Totally nuts. Dumb!
How are you? I'm here...
It's probably this.
The bag was hanging on her doorknob.
It smells of almonds. That's prussic acid.
I worked on boats, we used that for rats.
Okay, calm down.
She went crazy. Screaming and running
around so the windows almost broke.
-Sit up a bit.
-I won't go up there again!
I promise, we'll never go again.
Could you please call a taxi?
Sure. Completely screwed up, right?
She's not suffering from any
acute psychosis. I wouldn't say that.
It's more a psychic trauma in conjunction
with heavy alcohol consumption.
De-escalating is what she probably needs.
Calm it down.
We've identified some elements
of paranoid delusions that...
...of course allude to a persecution mania
somewhere at the heart of this.
However, I don't think it should evolve
into a palpable psychosis this time.
She'll rest here, maybe medicate and
gain strength. There are good chances...
I want to leave.
You just rest, take it easy,
go for long walks and listen to music.
It's so nice down there now.
But I'll get fat. Dad stuffs me with food.
I'll come and see you next weekend.
I'll take at least four days off.
Do you still think I'm good, though?
You're very good.
Next month
we'll get the apartment on Karlavägen.
You're very, very good.
-Are there two places free here?
-Yeah, sure.
-Go ahead.
-Thank you.
Hjortfelt?
Yes, Hjortfelt.
Clara, hi...
It's so nice to hear your voice.
You sound good.
I'm milking. Yeah... The cows.
And I feed them.
I help Agnes with the cooking
and I cuddle up to Dad.
The hell you do.
I shop and I take walks by the sea.
Everything here is so simple.
Yeah.
There's no one here following you.
You still think I imagined everything?
-I'm just reassuring you.
-You can't deny someone killed James.
-Or that they called and threatened me.
-No, that's true.
But it must have been a lunatic.
But you're well now. I can see that.
I think I'll stay here for Christmas.
But we get the new apartment next week.
We have to get furniture and everything.
I have to, John. I can't.
-You are coming back to me?
-Yes.
I think so.
You have to!
We'll see.
One helluva partner! He's never here!
He's been away for 14 days
with that one.
Shit, I hate that fucking damn poet!
She's hypnotized John!
Destroyed his marriage.
Let me tell you, Fia...
I could break that fucking bitch's neck!
Olovsson and Hjortfelt. Hello!
No. No, he's not here.
He hasn't been here for a while.
Last Thursday already?
That's weird.
Yes, I promise to get in touch
as soon as I have any news. Bye.
John left Skåne on the 7th.
John?
Are you there?
John Halvar Hjortfelt, book publisher.
It seems to be suicide
with prussic acid or...
potassium cyanide.
But there's no bottle or vial.
He could have
flushed them down the toilet.
Yeah, I guess that's possible.
There are no other fingerprints here
apart from his and a woman's.
Clara. Clara Fallgren.
She lives here, but...
She's in Skåne now. She's in Skåne.
I got the keys
from John before he went there.
Could she have written this?
It's an unusual style. I think
only electrical typewriters have it.
NO MORE ICEBOATING!
Was Mr. Hjortfelt
very depressed when you parted?
No.
He...
He was a bit sad.
-He wasn't like that.
-Sit down, Miss.
So many strange things happened in that
building. Someone was following me.
It's quite sad
when something like this happens.
But...
-You'd ended your relationship, had you?
-No.
I just said I wanted to stay home
with my father for a while. It's Stig's.
NO MORE ICEBOATING!
Sorry?
No, nothing.
Yeah. Yes, it's me.
Yes, I know.
No, I'm busy. Can I call you back?
-No, no.
-I understand you better than you think.
-If it's too much, you can come out to us.
-Yeah.
Bye.
I'm very sorry. You weren't
meant to meet like this. This way.
That was unnecessary. Unpleasant.
Mrs. Hjortfelt
wasn't meant to come in like this.
It doesn't matter.
We know each other well.
-Can I leave?
-Sure.
Yeah?
-Is Stig at home?
-Stig?
Yes, Stig.
Doesn't Stig Svensson live here?
No, he's dead. He hanged himself
last summer. When his girlfriend left him.
Taxi!
-Yes, where do you want to go?
-I don't really know.
-Yes, go to Lidingö.
-Lidingö?
-15 Sigtrygsvägen.
-15 Sigtrygsvägen. Off we go.
Hello.
Hello, Clara. You've come to see us?
Yes. I have no one.
I don't know who to talk to.
I just dropped
the kids off at my mother's.
I'm going to Askholmen until Sunday.
-You could come with.
-Something awful has happened.
You can tell me. Jump in.
It's weird that you and I are here. Yes...
The Lord works in mysterious ways.
But we have something in common.
John's dead body.
I can't take
that tough line of talk you have.
You know that John thought
I was unfaithful with his partner Carl?
Of all the men on this earth.
-He never told me.
-Do you know your Othello?
"She was false as water.
"Thou art rash as fire,
to say that she was false.
"Oh, she was heavenly true!"
-Anna, you don't have to...
-Oh, yes I do.
I was heavenly true.
But it's true.
The relationship between us was quite cool
sexually speaking the past few years.
But still...
I loved him.
Can you understand that?
We lived together for almost 20 years.
A marriage
isn't only carried through the bed.
And children.
And we knew exactly who wanted
what piece of chocolate in a mixed box!
It was stupid of me to come out here.
I'm sorry, Clara, that I got so worked up.
I'm not really like that. Hey...
Let's play some happy music! Huh?
Do you like Offenbach?
John loved Offenbach!
You don't want to dance? Okay, forget it!
Let's have a drink.
You wait here and listen quietly.
And I'll go and mix a martini.
There's no way I'm drinking that.
Don't you long to see your lover again?
-You cheap hussy.
-You must be crazy.
You're staying here.
Help me, godammit! I can't get free!
Help me!
Help! Can't anyone help me?
You fucker! Get back here!
Fuck!
Get back here!
Help me! Stop!
Stop! For God's sake, stop!
Help!
Help! Stop! Help me!
Help! Stop!
Subtitle translation by Alexander Keiller