MONASTERY OF THE MATHILENES
Wait down here.
Please...
We're a peaceful people. You've taken
everything we have.
- Everything?
Not yet.
Go on.
Stop! Reveal your identity!
Meow!
The Green Eye!
The most valuable emerald on earth.
- Please...
You can't do this.
Who's going to stop us?
Me!
You're not a thief?
- No.
I'm here to help you.
Who are you?
They call me the Black Cat.
Please, hide it for us.
Return it when the time is right.
I give you my word of honor.
You lost this during the fight.
THE FAMOUS FIVE 2
PRESENT, 102 KM
SOUTHWEST OF KIRRIN COTTAGE
Our first parent-free outing!
- Brilliant!
Yes, wonderful.
And finally together again.
Not the worst of things.
These are the Gaffenstone Rocks.
The Gaffenstone Rocks?
Never heard of them. - Come on!
It's not far now.
Welcome to the Cat Gorge.
Cat Gorge? - As long as
we stick to the roads, we're safe.
So? Have I promised too much?
- Cool!
Come on, let's fix us something to eat.
So, Dick, watch your step.
What's that supposed to mean?
Do you think I'm stupid?
- If you put it like that... Dick!
Oh man!
Didn't I just warn you?
Alright. No harm done.
Timmy, come on.
Timmy seems to
actually like aunt Fanny's food.
A mystery.
Dick, want one?
- No thanks, I've still got
this pizza.
What's on it?
Tuna, pineapple, spinach,
egg, salami and garlic.
My favorite combination!
Anyone want some?
- No, thanks!
Anne, it was only a toad.
An old legend surrounds this area.
Which one?
Ever heard of the Black Cat?
No, Timmy, it's not a real cat.
- He was a kind of Robin Hood.
He saved the Green Eye
for the tribe of the Mathilenes.
The Green Eye?
- The largest emerald on earth.
To the Mathilenes
it was a symbol of peace and happiness.
Yes, thank you, Dick.
Pleasure.
Ever since the stone disappeared
the Mathilenes have been cursed.
Why didn't the Black Cat return
the Green Eye? - It's presumed
the Black Cat hid the stone
in a secret place and then died
before he could tell the Mathilenes.
What's it to do with this area?
The Black Cat's said to have lived here.
That's really scary!
Does that mean
the stone could be hidden here?
Hey, show yourself!
What are you doing here?
And you?
Are you vagrants, or something?
Do we look like vagrants?
Oh Dick!
Never mind.
I'm Hardy.
- I'm Julian.
They're Dick and Anne.
- That's Timmy,
and I'm George.
- George? But you're not a boy!
After all, I'm not called...
Harriette!
Pity. It'd suit you a lot better.
Someone's very touchy!
So what do we do now?
"We"? How do you mean?
Let's go to my place.
I could show you... - Not interested.
We want to camp out here.
- Camp!
You're a bunch of freaks!
Why?
There's a huge thunderstorm on its way.
- Really?
So what? We're not made of sugar.
In case you change your minds...
I'm getting into safety.
I'll check up on you tomorrow.
Please don't!
Strange sort of guy.
- Kind of, yes.
Nice of him to invite us over.
He could be right
about the thunderstorm.
It'll pass over.
I guarantee it.
Not a word!
It smells funny here.
Did you know
the human scent attracts midges?
This smell renders us invisible to them.
Give it to me!
They were as good as new!
- Quiet. I want to sleep.
Good night.
- Night...
Wasn't it to your liking, Hardy?
It was. Excellent, Gisbert!
Thank you.
Hello, my boy!
Sorry for not calling before.
- That's okay, Dad.
I'm glad. How's work?
Fine. Unfortunately I have to stay here
a little longer. The deal's dragging on.
I understand.
- I'll bring you something marvelous.
How's Roby?
He's right beside me.
- I am Roby!
The things you teach him!
I have to go.
Don't get up to any nonsense, okay?
- Of course not.
See you...
... soon, Dad.
You can hear
the sunshine in every note!
This is Coastal Radio One
with an important message:
police report the escape of the criminal
Rookey Burns.
He broke out of jail last night.
Burns is 1.86 meters tall
and has short-cropped, dark blonde hair.
If you see the fugitive,
please report it to the police at once.
Burns managed to steal a service
weapon and is considered most dangerous.
The fledgling is leaving the nest!
Roger that!
So when's this Hardy coming?
I meant him, weirdo!
Oh yeah.
We'll meet up at the rail bridge.
You pushed me under six times!
- You squirted water at me.
No, I didn't.
- You did.
No!
Morning, freaks!
- Hello.
Morning.
- Let me introduce:
that's Roby.
Cool, right?
My father brought it from Singapore.
You can't even buy it here yet.
Roby, your friend.
Hey, dog, he's delicate.
He's called Timmy.
- Sit!
Doesn't he know "sit"?
He doesn't listen to just anyone.
He's a clever dog.
If he's that clever, what can he do?
Timmy's the greatest dog in the world.
He can do anything. - Yeah?
Like what?
Play dead?
What good is that?
Look at what Roby can do!
I am Roby,
your friend.
That's got you rattled.
Now Timmy'll chicken out. Wanna bet?
What're you doing?
- Friend...
That settles that.
Let's pack up. - You're leaving?
- Yes, we have to move on.
Awesome!
Cool, right?
- Is it an XP5?
No, an XP7. Straight from Japan.
You can't even get it here yet.
Wanna take it for a spin? - Yeah,
but don't you have to be 16 to drive it?
Not if you're on your own land.
All this belongs to my family.
No, Dick.
- Why not? - It's much too dangerous.
You've never driven one of those!
It's very easy.
- I don't know...
But I do. I'll do it.
Oh man!
Man, what an idiot!
I'd better put this in quarantine.
What's keeping Dick?
I want to get going.
Maybe I'll come with you.
We've got him.
I'm starting to get really worried.
I hope nothing's happened to him.
We'd better go and check it out.
- Okay.
Dick!
Man, my quad!
Why can't he listen to me just once?
- Where is he?
The quad's alright.
You're not serious?
My brother's had an accident,
and all you care about is your quad?
But...
- This is all your fault!
Bugger off!
And leave us alone.
DICK CALLING
It's Dick!
What's happened?
I'm not Hardy!
I'm Dick Kirrin!
- What's going on?
Yeah, yeah, I get it.
And I'm Santa Claus.
Where are you taking me?
To a safe place.
My friends will call the police.
And they'll come looking for me.
I'm really scared now!
At the slightest whiff of the police...
... we're gone!
We'll leave you behind all by yourself.
Where no one'll find you!
We're almost there. This hideout...
Why?
I'm your brother and I say so!
Stop talking so much.
What's that?
Are you jerking us around?
DISCONNECTED
Dick's been kidnapped! - They think
he's Hardy. - He drove his quad.
And wore his stuff.
Now what?
- We have to find Dick.
How? Without any clues?
What's that?
A button. Maybe Dick
tore it off one of the kidnappers.
What's that symbol?
I don't know. But I do know who might.
You have visitors.
It's alright.
What do you want?
- Dick's been kidnapped!
Why would anyone kidnap him? Ridiculous.
They thought he was you, that's why.
He was wearing your stuff.
What? I was going to be kidnapped?
Unbelievable.
What would they want with you?
- No idea.
Ransom money?
It might not look like it,
but we're very wealthy.
I'm calling the police.
- Wait!
If the kidnappers find out,
we'll never find Dick.
You heard what those villains said.
We have to find Dick ourselves.
Man, that's totally dangerous.
So what? We're talking about Dick here.
Have you ever seen this symbol?
Sorry. Never seen it before.
Hardy...
You know something.
I don't want anything to do with it.
- You won't tell us?
Never mind. Let's go.
Have fun with that Roby of yours.
We'll manage without you.
Come on!
Roby, your friend.
Hardy need friend.
So what do we do now?
Take it slow, for a start.
So he can catch up with us.
- You think he'll come? - Sure.
Who else is he going to brag to?
Wait!
See?
I can't let you freaks down.
Maybe I have seen the symbol before.
Where?
Okay, Hardy...
Now spit it out.
- I...
am not Hardy.
Good one.
Nice try.
We have the map.
What map?
The one leading us to the Green Eye.
It'll make us stinking rich.
You're after the Green Eye?
- What else?
But what's Hardy got to do with it?
- Stop playing dumb. We need the song.
Once more: there's been a mix up.
- How stupid do you think I am?
We've dealt with tougher guys than you.
Yeah.
Like who, for instance?
Well, for instance with...
Never mind, it doesn't matter.
I'll get you talking yet.
I even know how.
I was right. See that?
- It's the symbol of the circus.
If we find a man with a button missing
from his coat... - He'll lead us to Dick.
If we want to find Dick, we have to
stay one step ahead of the kidnappers.
Yeah.
Sounds like a plan.
- Here's the best part!
I've got more stuff.
Oh God.
Mega cool, right? You won't believe
the punch this baby packs.
Cut the crap, okay?
I'll take that.
- So what do we do now?
Anyone got an idea?
Except for Hardy?
Good boy.
Not bad.
Great!
Good boy.
- Wow!
Not bad at all, but for a circus act...
I don't know...
- Pity.
Could we have a look around anyway?
My friends and I
all want to join the circus one day.
Yeah.
Sure you can have a look around.
But don't get up to anything, okay?
- Of course not.
Thank you.
- Okay.
Why would I want a hammer?
- I know vintage cars.
Just hit the engine block once,
and it'll run smoothly again.
How nice of you to help me.
My pleasure.
Nice... jackets.
Do you make them yourself?
Most of them, yes.
Did you see a boy with a cap?
Yes, he went that way...
into the circus tent. - Thanks.
You no longer have a will of your own.
You'll do everything we tell you.
Yes, everything we tell you.
- Yeah. Everything
we tell you.
So?
What's the tune?
Go on, birdie, sing!
0-3-4-9 and the pizza's mine.
Brilliant!
And what is it?
What?
- This "0-3-4-9 and the pizza's mine"?
The "Maxi Pizza" commercial?
Damn.
Stop jerking us around!
Sorry. I'm hungry.
All I can think about is pizza.
Okay... Get him one.
A what?
A trumpet.
Why a trumpet?
I thought you wanted him to sing.
A pizza, of course, you idiot!
Why me?
Because I'm telling you!
And return the car to the circus.
I have to make a call.
"And return the car to the circus."
Yes, older brothers think
they own the world. Believe me,
I know what I'm talking about.
You do?
Yes.
Did you know that
80 percent of all younger brothers
are more intelligent
than their older brothers and sisters?
I knew it!
But wait a minute...
I'm the older one.
You're the better-looking one.
What kind of pizza d'you want me to get?
Hey, great make-up. Going somewhere?
Is Peppino going somewhere?
- The button!
Come on!
Hello, kids.
Have you tried Gerda's
wonderful almonds? They're famous.
Maybe later.
Damn.
Damn, where's he gone?
- He must be in one of the trailers.
Come on.
Where are the others? We've checked
everyone out. - No idea.
Here you are, they're on the house.
- Thank you. - My pleasure.
Enjoy them.
- Thank you.
Careful, it doesn't look very stable.
- Yeah, yeah.
Yes, hello?
So tell me,
do you and your butler live all alone
in that house? - Most of the time.
How about your parents?
- There's only my dad.
And he's away a lot.
On business trips and stuff.
I'm sorry.
No need.
Let me have a look.
- You don't wanna see that.
Want one, too?
- No, thanks.
They're my favorite candy.
No joke. A pizza with tuna, pineapple,
egg, salami and spinach.
Oh, and garlic, too.
It's not my thing, either,
but please, Gerda. - Okay.
Who'd eat something like that?
- Dick. Watch him. I'll get the others.
What?
- Just do as I tell you!
Women!
It's him.
There's a button missing.
- What?
Damn! How did that happen?
Julian!
Come down! Our man's over there!
No, he's in here...
What?
I know! Fil must've mixed up our
jackets when he brought me the car key.
Sorry.
Carry on.
Come on!
To the bicycles, quick!
Come back at once!
It's not funny!
What is this place? - The Owls' Nest.
It belongs to old Count Hamingham.
But he goes salmon fishing
in Alaska every summer.
So the house is empty?
An ideal place to hide someone.
Now!
Come on, this way!
It's really scary here.
You could say that again.
Not a trace of a signal.
Do you think there are ghosts here?
- There's no such thing as ghosts.
Scientists don't agree on that.
Did you know that many paranormal
activities have never been...
Come on.
So?
Will you sing now?
I'd like to, but it just
doesn't come to me. I need dessert.
Something sweet
to activate my brain areas.
Right, you little runt...
If you think you can play for time,
you've got another think coming.
Your good old friend Rookey
will show up in the morning.
Then you'll sing like a canary.
I guarantee it.
Rookey? Who's Rookey?
He still has a score to settle with you.
Let me go first.
What was that?
Oh man.
- Sorry...
No idea.
I'll check it out.
Want to see something funny?
Not so loud.
Bugger off, you fleabag!
Careful.
Quiet!
- Wait, let me.
After him!
Come on, Timmy!
Dick must be held here somewhere.
- Let's have a look, but be quiet.
Come on.
Hello, hello!
That's very good.
- Right? Look, there's no window pane.
Thank you.
But I've got another one. Watch this.
Smell those.
Very funny.
- Right?
I always wanted to be a clown, but...
my brother said it wasn't a real job.
And criminal is?
Your brother's really been
putting the screws on me.
Yeah, that's right.
Got a cold?
- No, it's my allergy.
I just came across
one of Hamingham's cats.
But you're only allergic to dogs.
Yes, that's what I always thought.
Timmy!
What did you just say?
Nothing, I...
I meant, Tim...
...buktu.
Did you know Timbuktu's an oasis town
with a population of 54,453,
and that the name
means "Well of Buktu"?
Listen to all the things the runt knows.
The only thing he's forgotten
is the song!
Where was I?
Oh yeah, over there by the door.
Thanks.
Timmy...
Now what?
We must've been everywhere by now.
Timmy!
He would've found him ages ago. If only
we had something that smells of Dick.
Oh no.
Please, no. - What's wrong with you?
It's only a... Oh my God!
I'm dying!
- Timmy,
you have to be very brave now.
Smell that, Timmy.
Find him, Timmy. Go on.
Good boy, find him!
Yes, go on.
They came from upstairs.
- We've been there. - So we missed it.
Okay, go on, Timmy.
Why open the window?
The way you fart all night?
Ridiculous.
You do. You fart in your sleep.
You just don't notice.
So sleep somewhere else.
You sleep somewhere else!
Now don't be cheeky.
It goes on here.
How long's this stuff been hanging here?
- At least a hundred years.
It must lead somewhere.
It's alright, Timmy.
The dog's only in the painting.
Now what?
Someone's knocking.
They're ancient pipes.
They tend to make noise.
Pipes don't know SOS.
It's Dick!
Great, Timmy!
We must be able to open it.
There has to be something.
Bingo!
Not bad.
Come on.
Dick?
- Yes.
Everything okay?
- Yes, I'm alright.
I'm so glad you're here.
- So are we.
We'll never get it open.
- We need the key. - Dick,
what do they want from you?
They keep asking about a song
that leads to the Green Eye.
The Green Eye?
- What's the Green Eye to you?
My great-great-great-grandfather
Archibald Kent was said to have been
the Black Cat and to have hidden
the Green Eye. - What?
The Black Cat was your ancestor?
Hardy,
what song could it be?
- I've no idea.
I really don't know what they mean.
Honestly.
- Okay.
We'll settle that later.
Let's find the key first.
But hurry! Tomorrow morning
a certain Rookey is going to show up.
Rookey...
- He has a score to settle with Hardy.
Hey, Dick...
we'll get you out of here.
- Promise? - Sure.
I won't let my favorite brother down.
Thanks, Julian.
Goes without saying. Let's go.
I can't sleep.
No wonder, if you keep talking.
Just shut up.
Listen...
- What?
They're awake.
Night.
Good night.
So who is this Rookey?
A former business partner
of my father's.
He was always in and out of our house.
One day I caught him red-handed.
He was stealing from us.
I called the police at once, of course.
And Rookey was arrested.
Turned out he was a wanted criminal.
Oh man.
Now I know what he'd been searching for.
- The Green Eye.
I thought Rookey
was a friend.
I haven't trusted anyone since.
You can trust us.
Does that mean...
we're something like friends?
Sure.
Okay, let's go.
Okay,
we'll have to go through the window.
Sure, great plan! We just abseil from
above and climb in through the window!
Great.
- Okay, let's go.
Oh man, I was joking!
Quite a drop.
I'll do it.
Too low.
Okay, he's in.
I know another one. Another one.
See?
- What?
Man, you farted.
Stop blabbing.
Go to sleep!
Everything you can do, I can do better.
What's keeping Julian?
Smell that?
Oh man.
That was a good one.
Pull him up!
Alright. Come on, let's go save Dick.
Come on, Hardy.
Everything alright, Brother?
- Yes, everything's alright.
We have to go, the sun's coming up.
Come on, hurry up!
What's going on here? Stop! Don't move!
What's all this?
Shut up!
- Run away!
Stay calm.
What are you doing? Save yourself!
The gate's open!
What does the mutt want?
- Leave them alone.
What?
It's me you want.
Rookey!
- You could've run, but you came back?
Why?
It's what friends do.
Oh, how nice!
Little Hardy's found some friends!
But this is Hardy!
Nonsense!
- This is him!
This little runt and me go way back,
right? You idiots!
What are all these brats doing here?
- No idea where they all came from.
Let the others go. It's nothing to do
with them. - So they can rat on us?
Go on.
- Come here.
Timmy, no!
Let me go. Timmy!
No! Timmy!
Let me go!
What's he done?
Don't make such a fuss, man.
It was an accident.
No, Timmy!
Come on.
Go on!
- Let me go. Timmy!
Cut the dramatics, will you?
It was only a dog.
- The cleverest dog on earth! - Oh, sure.
Stupid enough to get himself shot.
Surprise!
This is the old map
that belonged to your brilliant
great-great-
great-great-great-grandfather,
the Black Cat.
"I do not tend to joke.
Listen to this rhyme.
A lullaby straight from the heart,
add an N
and it will lead you to the stone."
I'm pretty sure
you can sing us this song.
Start singing, I'm losing my patience.
Leave him alone. It's obvious
he doesn't know. - What's this?
An heirloom from my granddad
who got it from his granddad.
- A worthless trinket.
A lullaby...
"A lullaby straight from the heart,
add an N
and it will lead you to the stone."
That's it.
You're trying to tell me you didn't know?
- I didn't!
I didn't know it could be opened.
A likely story!
Timmy only played dead.
- What?
The solution must lie
within the notes of this lullaby.
Rookey, you're brilliant.
You...
Which of you can play the piano?
You?
I think... you can.
Play.
Which notes are they?
G, C, D,
C, B,
A, E, C, E.
"Gcdcbaece."
Brilliant!
Now play it again.
Stop.
Just the left hand.
Which notes are those?
G, A, F, F, E.
G, A, F, F, E? Gaffe!
"Add an N..."
Gaffen!
"It will lead you to the stone."
Gaffenstone!
The Gaffenstone Rocks!
That's where the Green Eye's hidden.
Then let's get going.
He's coming, too.
He could be of use to us.
- Come along.
Take care.
- That's enough, come on.
Stop it, cut it out!
Timmy.
Come on.
Come here, quick!
Good boy.
Bite the rope.
He can't even drive a car!
He can't do anything.
- Seems to run in the family.
Man, oh man.
You okay, Anne?
- Yes, I'm alright.
Come on, let's save this freak.
- To the Gaffenstone Rocks! - Timmy!
Come on, give it to me.
This way!
Now this way.
There's the car!
- Yeah!
There's no way in here.
Maybe someplace else.
Then why park the car here?
- Dick's right.
Let's have a look here first.
- Timmy?
Timmy's found something.
- A mint candy?
Hardy always eats them.
- He probably wanted to give us a clue.
We have to move this thing.
Awesome!
Not bad!
Come on.
Ten, eleven,
twelve, thirteen...
This way.
And stay right behind me, get it?
What did I say?
Who'd do such a thing?
- The Black Cat, you moron,
who else?
To protect the stone
from people like you!
Luckily we've got the map. Come on.
Let's move on.
One,
two,
three...
- Hello?
Four...
- Move!
Five...
Hello?
Watch out.
Careful. It's going downhill here.
It's an old rope trap.
Pretty clever.
We'd better go that way.
Let's go.
No, those brats again!
Everything okay?
- Yes. I'm alright.
I thought you tied them up?
- We did.
They're getting on my nerves, just like
you two. Can't you do anything right?
Never mind.
They won't get anywhere without the map.
Right...
We have to go...
this way. Come on.
Get going.
What's this?
Did you think
you could trick us?
You thought wrong.
Not with me.
Don't take the right...
- Quiet!
Move!
Go on.
A candy!
So that must be the right way.
- I'll go first.
Alright.
Come on, Timmy.
We have to hurry.
Timmy, come on!
No, Timmy, this way. Come on.
Hurry up!
What's keeping you?
Slippery, careful.
It's really scary here.
Wait a minute.
If they'd come this way,
the spider's web would've been damaged.
Damn. You mean...
We went the wrong way?
- Yes, it's a trap! - Get down!
God, you gave me a fright.
Bad luck, I'd say.
They're my friends!
- I believe...
they were your friends.
Come on.
Move.
Hot, hot!
Move it!
Sometimes it ain't bad...
to have a big brother.
Let's go back.
In one of these holes
the Green Eye is hidden.
Which one?
We'll find out in a minute.
Ocu...
Oculus.
Rookey, you're brilliant.
- Shut up!
Oculus...
Viridis.
"The Green Eye".
At last!
How long have I been waiting for this!
What are you laughing at?
Nothing.
Nothing at all.
You know something, smarty-pants?
You take it out.
Go on!
Do it!
And what if it's a trap?
- In that case...
you're out of luck.
Okay.
Shut up!
Put it out!
Is your hand okay?
- Yes, fine.
But I've got something here...
Mega cool!
Come on!
I can't see a thing.
- Come on!
Come on, you morons!
- I can't see a thing! - Stupid jerks.
I don't believe it.
Hurry up!
Not the bikes. They'll catch up with us.
- Then where to?
Up the hill, come on!
They're up there.
Come on, you dickheads, I'll drive.
Up there!
Come on!
Hurry up!
Hurry!
- Come on, hurry!
Damn.
- Back up!
Back up!
You hotshot!
There they are!
Stop! - Damn it!
- Faster! - Run, Timmy!
To the circus!
To the circus. I know a short cut.
What's that I see?
Whipped cream.
Go on, hurry up.
I have to go to the stables.
To the stables? To do what?
What do you think? Horse around!
Don't you like it?
- It's boring.
Faster!
- Come on.
Over there!
- Anne! - Hurry up!
Watch out!
- Hurry!
Ladies and Gentlemen,
and now,
to conclude our show, here's...
the Flying Peppino!
Call the police!
Out of the way!
That does it!
There, it's off! Let's hear a big...
Go! Go! Go!
They're criminals. Arrest them!
Call the police!
- What did you say?
They kidnapped my brother!
- They tried to steal this stone.
Yeah, yeah, it's alright.
Where's Rookey?
Give me that stone.
Catch!
Hey, it belongs to me!
Out of my way!
No more fun and games.
Just you wait...
What's she doing?
- George!
Oh my god!
George! - Be careful.
- Are you crazy? - I'll get you!
Just you wait!
Watch out!
Stay calm, George.
- You can do it.
Watch out, he's stepped onto the rope!
- Oh yeah.
Careful!
You can do it.
- Slowly.
What?
- She can't get down.
Wait!
Quick, hurry!
Good idea.
George, catch this.
Quick!
What are you doing?
Pull it hard!
- Come on!
Quick, the bathtub.
- Hurry, hurry!
Come on.
It's the coolest show I've ever seen.
Okay.
- Get back!
These damned brats!
That was all for today,
Ladies and Gentlemen!
We're really glad you liked...
our show.
Come back soon.
Pair of losers.
Last stop jail.
- You're a loser yourself.
But I'm a clown!
Bravo!
Kids, you did a really good job.
We thought
we'd lost every trail of Rookey Burns.
They didn't reckon with the Famous Five!
Nor with me.
Sorry. Pronto?
In that case...
- Let's get this over with.
Alright.
I owe you a great deal of gratitude.
Don't thank me, thank the children.
You kept the Black Cat's promise.
We'll never forget this.
Thank you.
The pleasure was all ours.
Is there anything I can do for you?
No.
How a about a photograph as a keepsake?
FAMOUS FIVE CAUSE SENSATION
GREEN EYE RETURNED - PEOPLE SAVED
ROOKEY BURNS BEHIND BARS AGAIN
FOLEY BROTHERS ALSO ARRESTED
MILLIONAIRE WITHDRAWS FROM COMPANY
TO SPEND MORE TIME WITH SON
Subtitles
Adrian Byrne
Film und Video Untertitelung GmbH