there is no light in old world
but we human created the fire
then power
make the modren world
our eyes wild open
but
the more we want
the more we greed
why r u so hurry
wanna die
he is a funny guy
why we here
to catch the bad guy
really
why you still watching tv
i pay u 100 every month
and give u all you want
hello
if some kind of god come form this jar
to give u 3 wishs
what u want
i wanna food
great
me too
i wanna pee
again
wanna fire you
u was so lazy
two X rice
hello
don't come form the front door
use the back door
wanna thief going in
in fact he was there
death to you are
to die
how stupidy u r to be thieves
means we
we
you 2
how could you get in
tell me
what
die die so easily
why
if u die who will pay my loss
i wanna marry my sister
i hope too
i wanna be strong“
give me
i wanna be rich guy
this move
just
throw it away
hello…
aunt
u u cray
I was graduate form famous school
but my sister was silly
he live nea my home
she was sick
i don't wanna know
american
have money
i can swim
don't go with me
can i go by air
too less
u earn too less
what is this
where u got all this money
i storage for my wife
give it to me
no
tell you—
sister
coming
sorry boss
there are 1969 people out there
for this job
c
congratulation
i'm the god
harry Butt
u can call me butt
you tought the jar
so i come
i was a god
u have 3 wish
listen clear
any wish
i will help you
but
don't be too greed
sure
but don't wish too small
a hint
money women ets
clear
who tough it
make your wish here
i wanna have a spaceship
too big for you
I wanna Ling
Who is Ling
your brother was there
you still can—
get there
hurry
but he was there
him?
he was so smart
but i wann tell u
sorry my call
hello
here
yhis fish
you wanna
doing?
see
who tough me?
make your wish
let her go
how
sorry
find your brother
he like radio
come here
you don't wanna wish?
really?
on't waste your chance
and don't be afraid
I came in
ome here
i love science
really?
hello
this is harry butt
number 7654321
i in bag trouble
freeze
hijack
c
let's move
watch what
take off your clothes
Please
i was female
give me your chopsticks
brother
how good you are
6 chicken
5 for stolen
really?
how dare you
you can mug
shut up
boss
only
you…
do youever watch your hair
last month
lay down
your call
hello
hello…
it's harry
hello
hello butt
we have checked
you r ok
but i can't proform mricle
hang up it
i have a trouble things
they don't wanna wish
really
you fool
people like me
how can we back to school
can
no completed wish
no back
how
rob
she said rob
hang up it
hello
hijack
sorry
anything
just left here
even your stock
hello…
no
boss
he have nothing
hello
miss
where you wanna we sting
you r so
eat this
l/r?
what?
left hit or right hit
turn—
l or r
i will choice
let's go
where's my chopsticks
anyone see my chopsticks
no
chopsticks
find your self
boss
i forget my food
hello
u…
what happen to your feet
i was shotted
what r u looking at
sister
aunt?
my sister
sit down
we have decter
c
i talk to Ge
ok
what she looks like
chopsticks
really
she can make a large money
our money was
no money
if she was suck be bad guy
she will be silly
so i can't move
you can take me
make a wish
just leave us alone
shit
i can't tell my aunt
second floor
really
let me fly
i was god
come down
you wanna stay wish me
she was creazy
please come down“
first eish
come here—
take her
she was our friends
stay here
we don't have money
use my money
can't
please
no
she can bite
ya
we need a dog
can we?
please
don't move
rob
hello
miss
how dare your 2
catch me?
ok
drive
i as good guy
i'm chopsticks
K0W[00n?KoW[oonHongKong
WenkeHongKong
thatp[aCeforme
K0W[00n?KoW[oonHongKong
WenkeHongKong
thatp[aCeforyou
wake up
wake up doggy
morning
for everyone
our breakfirst
boss
it's sunday
we can learn kongu
time to beat Bruce li
hello
play majiang
we hae she
change
milk
food—
we take the konfu lesson
cool
can beat anyone
clean you room
win
auto
i was in trouble
can't do any thing good
brother
do you listen to me?
stay here
look at you
please forgive me
brother
don't play with me anymore
go down
how could you
scary me
brother
i hate you
no way
i wanna many me
7654321 harry don't move
rubb
anyone can hear me
here are guest
stay here。
more faster
show me
any more
take all your cloth off
hurry
sorry
sorry what?
faster
sorry
let's go
die
asshole
beat him
i win
max
just bullshit
lik shit
i win
just win
we must find a way
to win
it's gonna morining
when will you finish
little brother
don't
be
too aggressive
can't we say
what i have done?
more pocket
hahahah
how can we take this money away
ou like shit
play
xiang
you cheat?
really
sure he was
you cheat
you be dead
play card
it's my fault
use girl to rubb
so
i can play card with you
but
i meet
thsi cheater
i never cheat
i win buy my skill
but yu wanna kill me
i wouldn't dare
ok
don't lie to me
you be dead
brother
play
win
my first time to win
hello
play ok?
look at you
wanna cheat
xiangli
what he say
he say
you wanna cheat
carefully
your turn
take it
hurry
r u win?
enough
you wanna me know
you have this one?
must have promble
let me see
i have a good card
but you
i have a max  score
i call
what
wanna se if he was cheater
hungry
dong't eat
my magic was slow
clean—
what you doing here
what happen to your hand?
hijacked?
clean this place
he will leave you
it's fine
my magic still here
just a little slow down
what
let me show you
hello…
change“
see
why youchange to a shit
why not flower?
shit was good for flower
it will never down on it
he always shit on my phone
your brother
he was really a bad guy
too dirty
too handsome
girls like him
he was your boyfriend
i wanna him be normal
what
see dead people
be clean
why it still not change
help me
wait
funny
we seek for the brench killer
it's 10
funny
kill fly
really funny
daughter
recive
over
no
maybe we was too strong
only 3 guns
few knife
but they have 1000 people
can't take them
daddy
let'stry
let's go
sister
what么
where is she
what you looking for>
hello dear over
what dear
you 2 little sweet
broke my arm
too bad
please help us
how bad
none of your busniess
father
mother
help me
shere is she
overthere
sister
help them
we bad
how bad?
father mother
sister help me
she was really bad
sclience
i was talking
who r u
you are my star sunshine
close it
sailmoon
hello
what
find you out
do it
0Ver
you scare me
what?
for?
just point it out“
see things
daddy
what you mean
why you stop
porformce what
rub
rise your hand
thx everyone
now rub
give your money to me
listen to me
i will kill those hide their money form me
search
any thing rich
just hit him
Thx
and i wanna full corperate
i wanna find
some one who use the phone
sclince
get out
Sail moon
come here
i said i will find you
no
it's
i was gamble
start
3 fitst
4 5 follow
i buy
10.4.
what?
but i know the rule of horse race
you cheat me
i know you
you cheater
wanna lie to me
ok
eat this
l or r
go away
no help
let me handle him
Boss
sister help us
father
mother
let's go
come here
what boss
no boss
you 2
they was our sister
they was good for us
chopsticks
just 2 of you
change to chopsticks
we can't
really
wanna lie to me
what
who hate me
our brother
brother
sorry boss
we won't do it again
let's go
you 2
you be dead
how can you do this to him
let her go
what if...
i will let you choice whatever you want
go after her
look at him
it's
it's really
can we run
what?
give me another
brother
it's hurt
ok
she was good to her
it's for her good
i
i'm really sorry
but i was a good guy
ok
let's live together
i like your ass
i will treat her like a queen
thanks
try my new bed
feel good
but i don't like it
when you leave
my chicken will come here
for fun
if you have time
you
coming in
thank god
before i was born
i have nothing but
now i have many
i talk to much
i feel uneasy
ya
why everynight
you like shake
like shake
if you like shit
she will be yazheng
right
Big hongkong
see my brother b4
wish?
fist money
second women
third no hint
but you can keep it
don't be hurry
just you 2
it's too rush
what r u
wish 1
think hard
i wanna
food
again
u 2
1 wish
understand
which one?
what we here
sorry
i am looking for
where is this place
where an i
why i am here
who an i
i c
you was my creation
name harry butt
i turn you
your master
i win the gamble
i change you form empty
not really
really
you master?
boss?
if i was really
morning master
you
just care too much
taste good?
stop
time for story
time for old time
time for knowledge
let's start
xxing
question 1
rocket
how fast it need
4km
A
no
what for a nuke bomb
u 235
[all about the question]
what you have done
she looks wired
give her some drug?
dont disturb her
daddy
sweet
don't trust your dream
it's all nothing
sister
time to say goodbye
be strong
no dream
sweet
sweet where r u
no rocket
don't scare me
sweet
boss
let's go
a rocket
i can made it
no
he tranform it
i am god
send her to the hospital
like a dream
you 2
we will tough moon 2020
scilence
i trust you
was watching tv somewhere on earth
can't find her
don't when
we can tough the moon
tomotrrow of 2020
you know this?
i was god
if i really what i am
my first wish
to be the first people who get to moon
take a pic wiht me
send it to my sister
boss
u  u wanna againest me?
sorry
his sweet was in hospital now
she got mad
poor
that girl can run fast than wind
can speak many language
and strong
just like me
no
she was your sister
you created her
really?
she was born form hospital
dance with the
why you here
dance with me
hello
it's my faulty
i change her
my wish
Boss still like now
and kill him
her mother born her
why
let me see
shit
i'm afraid
maybe next time
today
i wanna teel you
brother
answer me
whatever
don't eat him
i'm afraid
but
i love her
I know it's not good but...
i can't help myself
it's unfare for u
sorry
but i give you my word
i never let her down
sorry brother
please
brother
i was big enough
to me
you was too cool
to our space hero
our flag on moon
wht you feel
groly
more
proud
great
myself
was honored
shit
something attack our hero
what
太空英路
where is god
go to space
he gain 3 wish
why him not me
shit
my wish not come truth
he will come and kill boss
slow down
where u go
wherer ever you go
how long yougo
his wish with you
so  don't blame me
i will kill him
but it's his wish
u who r u indeed
calm down
find fish
you hide somewhere
under the table
shit
ok
find fish
it's ok
i'm cool
to moon
why you wanna kill me
i gonna kill you
wh o take my fish
police!
take this
my sweet tell me
3 wish
your sister for her
he miss her much
what?
i don't afraid of her anymore
return my sister
other wishs?
no
u
you 2
who got wish
we have 3
you lie
only
1 wish can come true
who's wish
don't know
you wish
no kill
i hate lie
just kill him
you drive
i don't know how
follow my order
B boss
get off the car
show
you can kill both eachother
and
10987654321
no
time is up
i'm sorry
u bad asshole
shit
return my sweet
let's go
who is first
i choise
u first
i wann go first
you call
hello
hello butt
just cancel it
ok
yes
your wish
youcan have 2 new wish
don't be hurry
sorry
i wanna
i can sent first people on moon
just 50 years left
byebye
if his
i'm back
never see you again
me 2
my 3 wish
is…
nothing needed to say with me even you are leaving now?
what is the wish you made?
i just hope everybody can have one more wish
i am the headmaster of a magic school
everyone can have a wish
u say first
headmaster right?
I sure want to become a rich
wanna be kind of a rich with  nothing done or with much much diligence and hard work?
thats perfect with nothing needed to do
then also wanna be healthy after becoming a rich?
sure
wanna healthy and wealth more
just want to have both of them ok?
only one of them
um.......then i just hope that i can have a happy and simple life
throughout a happy live also wanna to have sad issue?
no!
boss
next
it is chicken foam
chicken..
principal i wanna learn magic
next
i wanna learn magic
i wanna find back ball ball
next
principal
i have no any wish
is it possible to learn magic
then you guy all go to learn magic
also include me please
principal
he just learn from you
hey guys you learn
Yes
then i accomplish all wishes of the monkeY
welcome to the school of magic
hope all of your wishes become real
actually people should not just do for themselves and their own wishes?
and become self-centered and only hope to be a rich in one day
wishful thinking
it may come to loss more than gain at the end
people should be euthsiastic and realistic
only that can offer people real fortune and happiness
human should continue seeking for their smart and intelligence
after the invention of electricity
contributive things..
maKing this world more nice
and more enjoyable