(Calm instrumental music)
(Ocean waves)
(Children playing)
[Rey] Hey.
[Hazel] (foreign language)
(Crowd talking loudly)
[Man without cap]
(foreign language)
[Man with blue cap]
(People speaking far away)
(Crowd speaking
foreign language)
(Audrey screams)
(Crowd speaking
foreign language)
[Audrey] What do you want?
(Crowd speaking
foreign language)
[Hazel] Excuse me, excuse me.
Hey, hey.
What's your name?
My name is...
Audrey.
I'm here on vacation,
I'm visiting.
(Ballad music playing far away)
So, I landed right here
And I've been hitchhiking
for about two days.
I want to get here,
so where am I now?
Damn!
I'm gonna need a guide,
Somebody who is bilingual.
[Hazel] I know
someone that...???
How about you?
No, I can't.
But I know someone who
would be perfect.
(Ballad music)
(Ocean waves)
[Hazel] Hey, Nick!
[Nick] Nick is listening.
[Hazel] This is Audrey.
Hello, Audrey.
She's looking for someone
to go on a trip with her.
That's terrific.
As a guide,
And I recommended you.
[Nick] Um, no.
I'm writing something
very important
And it's due yesterday.
Nick!
Why don't you
ask Tomas, Hazel?
I don't speak to him anymore
And she also needs a guide
that speaks English.
It's kind of the
clincher, actually.
She seems to speak it
pretty well herself.
Nick, turn around.
[Nick] Oh, fuck no.
What's wrong?
I don't bite.
Keep on walking, people.
My mom will have
dinner in an hour, Nick.
[Nick] Hazel.
You say that she needs a guide.
Yeah.
So she'll be leaving soon.
Good.
(Ocean waves)
(Luggage being pulled)
[Rey] Hey, Nick.
What is that?
[Nick] Oh, it's heavy.
(Mumbling)
[Hazel's mom]
(foreign language)
[Nick] What are
you doing here?
[Hazel's mom] Audrey.
[Audrey] What am I doing here?
[Hazel's mom] This is Nick.
Our other guest.
[Audrey] Oh, great. We've met.
Good, good.
Now you two can talk
about America things.
We can talk about
American things.
Cheeseburgers, capitalism.
I'm glad we had
this conversation.
[Hazel's mom] You can stay
as long as you need to.
You are a good house guest.
Like Nick.
We have two good house guest.
How is work going, Nick?
Brilliantly.
(Audrey laughs)
I'd say I'm back on top
If it weren't for the fact
that it was due yesterday.
You said that, yesterday.
I'm dating Rey Aquino.
[Hazel's mom]
(foreign language)
I can't take it
back, it's true.
(Foreign language)
[Hazel] Oh mom, really?
[Nick] You know,
Hazel's a big girl.
I think she can make
decisions on her own.
And Rey's not a...
[Hazel's mom] Audrey.
Nick.
Leave the table now.
(Instrumental music)
(Window knocking)
[Nick] What do you want?
[Audrey] Can I
come in for a bit?
I'm writing right now
And it's very important
And I'm supposed to
send it in yesterday.
[Audrey] Rey just came
in through Hazel's window.
It's kinda awkward.
Come in.
(Book pages turning)
So, are you on vacation?
Why?
Come to see the exotic sights?
Shouldn't you be writing?
I should, but it's not
that easy, you know.
I can't just turn it on and off.
Come with me.
Oh, not this again.
[Audrey] I can tell
you're not happy.
I could have told you that.
Have you heard the
legend of the Diwata?
I don't listen to death metal.
[Audrey] It's about
the race of Diwata
Which are legendary
fairy beings,
Who wrote stories which
became the lives of men.
There was an unruly
Prince who was born...
Oh!
(Hopeful instrumental music)
(Foreign language)
(Soaring instrumental music)
(Footsteps)
[Audrey] And as the
daughter started to write
Her first mortal life story,
The royal family
descended on her.
And then her family eats her.
Yum, yum.
The story is probably
a primitive explanation
For how some people
become rich or powerful,
And others become
short-order cooks.
But this legend has a
grain of truth to it.
I believe there really is some
sort of royal Diwata tribe
With a small kingdom which
is never even been found.
I'm gonna find whatever's
left of the place.
While I'm at it,
Maybe help myself to some
Of the untold golden
riches of their kingdom.
I wish you luck.
(Calm instrumental music)
(Hazel and her mom discussing
in foreign language)
[Nick] What is that?
(Hazel and her mom discussing
in foreign language)
Let's get a move on.
What?
[Nick] Your stupid adventure.
I'm in.
Um, what?
I just lost my job,
My agent dumped me.
I venture it has something to do
With the fact my script
was two months late.
So let's go get ourselves
killed in the jungle.
Hop to it!
[Audrey] Ok!
Before I change my mind!
[Audrey] You can't
take all that.
[Nick] Well, speak
for yourself.
[Audrey] Alright.
(Hopeful instrumental music)
[Nick] I changed my mind.
[Audrey] Come on.
[Nick] How are
we gonna travel?
I don't know,
I'll figure it out.
[Nick] Do you have any money?
[Audrey] No.
[Nick] Well, we're not
gonna make it past the pier.
[Audrey] Would just...
Shh, (mumbling)
(Car engine starts)
(Heavy metal music)
[Nick] No...!
(Car engine)
(Heavy metal music)
So are you really
a movie writer?
Yes, I am.
Was.
Ok.
What do you mean ok?
I mean, yeah.
[Nick] What?
You don't think I'm the kind
of guy that can be a writer?
You don't believe that
I house the power
Behind these fingertips to turn emotions into words?
No, no.
I see it.
I'm glad to hear that.
So why are you here?
Well, imagine that I had a
gourmet pizza place back in
California,
Not popular, but big
and up-and-coming,
Take-out only with a
few regular customers.
And then those few regular
customers refused to pay me,
Steal my recipes,
Arbitrate me out of the credits
And then fucked my residuals.
So I get a new place, far away,
Delivery only this time,
But I have no customers.
But that's ok,
'Cause I get to keep those
Piping-hot pepperoni
pizzas all to myself.
By the way, what is
pepperoni pizza like?
Would you describe it?
It's been so long.
I don't know, depends.
Details, specifics.
When's the last time you had a
Savory pepperoni pizza?
They'd never even heard about...
Before my dad died.
Two months ago.
Hawaiian.
How was it?
Tangy, not sweet
like here, right?
Tangy.
Oh, well you hang on to that!
And you relish that
memory, 'cause your
Little quest has taken
you far from home.
You're gonna have to let go
that old pizza-loving you
And embrace a new you.
A you that's ok
with fried chicken
And rice with every meal.
A Philippines you.
That's why I'm here.
(No-lyric chants)
(Motorcycle engine)
(Heavy metal music)
(Heavy metal music
getting louder)
[Audrey] Oh, my god!
[Car driver]
(foreign language)
[Nick] Come on.
(Car engine getting closer)
[Audrey] Alright, let's go.
[Nick] Wait.
Wait.
Wait, wait, wait.
You've had your
little adventure-
(Car engine drowns
out Nick voice)
There's no way in hell
That we're gonna get across
half this fucking country.
Hey, guys!
We had to get away
from my parents,
So I made Rey steal the jeepney.
I'm hoping if we
can come with you,
If that's alright.
Yeah, I guess.
Can this thing make
all the way to Leyte?
Sure, easy.
This is gonna a
burden on all of us.
The question really is,
Are you two sure you wanna come?
I guess.
I just want you
to understand me,
If you two come you're
in for the long haul.
Got it?
- [Hazel] Got it.
- [Rey] Get it.
[Audrey] Ok, good.
Alright, so how far
can we make it...
Oh, relax.
It is going to be easy.
You have a car now.
(Instrumental music)
(Moves to adventurous
instrumental music)
(Adventurous instrumental music)
It's just a story for kids.
Audrey said the place
is real, that's all.
You can be such an idiot.
Let me drive.
No way.
I got this thing
and it's my right.
Oh, rightfully stolen, huh?
You can't even drive!
It was driving on
the parking break
The whole time until
I got in the car.
[Audrey] Hey, maybe you
should let him drive.
Slowly!
Let off the clutch slowly, Rey!
[Audrey] Ok, stop.
Stop!
Switch back!
[Rey] It's not my fault.
The clutch has always
been jerky on this thing.
Freak.
We're breaking up.
Here's the thing you've
got to learn about women:
They're a lot like people
in a lot of ways, but...
I was kidding.
(Adventurous instrumental music)
[Audrey] Ok, crew.
It looks like we've
gotten pretty far today,
So, I think we've earned
ourselves a little break.
The next town is a day's drive,
So everyone is free to
take in the sights.
The guide book says
we're in Calbayog city.
There's the Mapaso Springs.
Best beer in the province,
so there's that I guess.
[Nick] But we can't afford
to imbibe at the moment,
We have places to be.
So everyone: no
drinking, agreed?
- [Hazel] Agreed.
- [Rey] Agree.
Okay.
(Loud dance music)
[Audrey] ...do you
have anything like, a-
I'd like one of these.
How much?
[Shop owner] One at 20 pesos.
[Audrey] And this one?
Ok.
Thank you.
Rey?
Rey, what are you doing?
No, Rey.
[Audrey] Rey, get up now.
Come on, we gotta go.
I'm sorry buddy, we gotta go.
Alright, get up.
[Hazel] Sorry.
Sorry, sorry.
[Audrey] Can you bring her...
[Audrey] Thank you.
Where the hell is Nick
when you need him?
(Car engine starts)
(Car engine)
(Hazel, Nick and Rey
laughing out loud)
[Hazel] Audrey
is so responsible.
[Nick] Yeah, she's like
our mom or something.
(Hazel, Nick and Rey
laughing out loud)
[Hazel] Mom, we're hungry!
[Nick] Hey, mom!
Mom, I'm sleepy.
Can I sleep now?
(Hazel, Nick and Rey
laughing out loud)
[Hazel] (foreign language)
[Rey] (foreign language)
(Hazel, Nick and Rey
laughing out loud)
[Hazel] (foreign language)
(Hazel, Nick and Rey laughing)
(Foreign language)
[Nick] (foreign language)
(Hazel, Nick and Rey
laughing out loud)
[Audrey] Hey, say
whatever you're gonna say.
Drunken natives-(laughs
drowns out Audrey's voice)
(Hazel, Nick and Rey
laughing out loud)
You guys don't like
the way I do things,
I can go it alone, you know.
(Hazel, Nick and Rey
laughing out loud)
[Nick] Hey, white girl.
Us natives and honorary
natives aren't mad.
We're coming with
you all the way.
Just like you said, ok?
So stop crying and
come out of there.
[Audrey] I'm not crying.
I know, I know.
[Audrey] I'm Filipino
too, actually.
[Nick] No kidding?
[Audrey] Yeah, half.
Just buried under all the white.
(Melancholic instrumental music)
(Moves to mysterious
instrumental music)
(Moves to vibrant
[Nick] Wake up,
wake up, wake up.
Hazel, wake up, get in
the front and drive.
[Audrey] What?
[Hazel] (foreign language)
[Nick] Shh! Calm down,
calm down! Remain calm!
[Hazel] (speaking
foreign language loudly)
[Nick] Listen, there
are motorcycles-
Get in the back, get in the...
[Nick] Remain calm!
Everybody needs to stay calm!
There's not going
to be any... any-
- [Audrey] Nick,
what's going on?
(Audrey screams)
(Car engine)
[Bandit] Oh, shit!
[Rey] Who was that?
I don't know.
All I know is they pulled
off the side of the road
And turned off their headlights.
[Hazel] What
were they driving?
Motorcycles.
(Vibrant instrumental music)
They're following.
[Hazel] I think
we missed our turn.
Nick, get the map!
(Vibrant instrumental music)
Ok, which way?
I don't know, um, left!
(Vibrant instrumental music)
I meant right.
But left is ok too, I was...
You're so stupid!
Whatever! Fuck!
We're lost.
(Vibrant instrumental music)
There, go into that
town, right there.
(Foreign language)
Whatever they want with us,
They're not gonna try
anything in town.
But, what would
they want with us?
They're probably just bandits
Looking for an easy mark.
[Nick] You think
we'll see them again?
[Audrey] Doubt it.
(Blissful instrumental music)
(Moves to suspense
instrumental music)
[Yellow shirt bandit]
(foreign language)
[Shop owner]
[Nick] Give me one of those.
Buenas tardes, mi angel.
[Hazel] Finally!
[Audrey] Don't leave until
we get back, alright?
Stay awake, keep an eye
on all of our stuff.
Oh, and try not to write
any shitty screenplays.
(Nick laughs sarcastically)
[Audrey] I think
it's his fault.
He saw them coming first,
Because he just happened
to be on the roof.
How do you figure?
Well, when he into town,
To buy all that booze,
He probably told everyone and
anyone what we were doing.
Probably before he
was even drunk,
With that big mouth of his.
[Hazel] Are you
gonna get mad at him?
[Audrey] As soon as I stop
being glad-I'm-not-dead,
I'm gonna chew his ass out.
[Hazel] I think you're
really mean to Nick.
What?
It's getting to be like
he's your pathetic screw-up
Of puppy dog who barks and
breaks all the furniture-
- and you just have always a
newspaper beside his face-
Ready to smack even
if he doesn't...
Ok, that's really
overreaching...
And then I'm just completely
going to be honest with you,
I think it's my fault.
Don't be mad.
You know, I'm a lot less mad
Knowing that was you
instead of Nick.
See what I mean?
Puppy-dog-newspaper...
(Hazel screaming)
(Tense instrumental music)
[Joey] (foreign language)
[Hazel] He says he's
not going to hit you.
[Joey] (foreign language)
HE'S going to hit you.
If you won't tell him
where we're going.
Tell him that we're
just on vacation.
(Foreign language)
If they don't believe us-
Well then,
Just keep trying to lie to them.
(Foreign language)
Excuse me!
I'm sorry, my (foreign
language) is an Americana.
Yeah, yeah.
Her, right there.
[Joey] So, the truth,
You know where is the money.
Tell the location
or we'll all die.
[Nick] Audrey, everything
is going to be okay,
Just tell them where
the stupid place is
And we can have an adventure
some other time, okay?
^- [Joey] (foreign language)
(Tense instrumental music)
(Bandits screaming
in foreign language)
(Vibrant instrumental music)
Rey!
[Joey] (foreign language)
[Audrey] Stop it, stop it!
Hit me!
Come on, hit me!
He doesn't know anything!
[Joey] (foreign language)
[Hazel] Rey!
Rey!
[Joey] (Slowly) Will
you tell? Your friend
Wants you to. He
doesn't want you hurt-
-But you are okay if he is hurt!
[Audrey] Let me go!
Get off of me!
Ah, then it is your turn!
(Vibrant instrumental music)
(Moves to tense
instrumental music)
(Motorcycle engine)
(Bandits screaming)
[Rey] (screaming
in foreign language)
I can't, I cant!
(Vibrant instrumental music)
[Audrey] Go, let's
go, let's go!
(Adventurous instrumental music)
[Nick] Hurry!
Go, go, go!
I'm going!
I'm going, I'm going.
(Vibrant instrumental music)
(Joey complains of pain)
(Foreign language)
(Adventurous instrumental music)
Nick, good idea
wtih the bikes.
[Nick] There's a lot more
That needs healing if
you're interested.
You know, your
cowardly escape attempt
Is what got us out of this mess.
I don't know if I
should thank you
Or toss you out and let those
bandits slap you around-
- [Nick] Oh, no.
We know which one you'll
get more of a kick out of.
Excuse me?
[Nick] Maybe they were right.
Maybe you don't care
how much I get hurt
So long as your
secrets are kept.
I suppose that goes for
all the rest of us.
Oh!
As long as I can help it,
I won't let anybody
else hurt you,
Or anyone here.
[Nick] What about that?
You needed it.
(Adventurous instrumental music)
You'll come out filthier
than you went in.
(Joyful instrumental music)
(Moves to adventurous
instrumental music)
Another city, another adventure.
You don't think I'm gonna get
Beaten up again do you?
Because that would really
bring down my mood a notch.
[Audrey] Dry up, we're safe.
It's not hard to figure
out where we're going,
It's either here or Cebu.
If they still care
about catching us.
They probably care more
Now that we've embarrassed them.
Doesn't matter
anyways, we're here.
Okay, you're gonna
have to tell me
Where exactly we're going now.
Okay.
Um, Diwata Falls, Kapinyahan.
English, English.
Why didn't you
tell me earlier?
I was keeping it secret,
So no one might drunkenly
spread it around.
Why does it matter?
You told me to take
you to Calubian,
Which is indeed near
Kapinyahan Bay,
But there are no
waterfalls around here,
All of the waterfalls are
at Kapinyahan Island.
[Audrey] Kapinyahan Island?
[Audrey] What?
What?
So I didn't know,
What's so bad about that?
I've never been here.
That's why I have you around.
Well you don't anymore.
Okay, this again.
Oh! This again!
You don't wanna hear it again?
I'll tell you something new,
Whatever fairy tale
adventures that you've
Got playing your
head are just that:
In your head!
Feel better now?
You've got those two
So wrapped up in
your little fantasy
That Rey stole his family's car.
[Audrey] You're a coward.
I know that, I'm
not delusional.
You need to stop.
This isn't about me right now.
How are you going to get home?
[Nick] I can take
care of myself.
Yeah, okay.
I said I can take
care of myself!
(Nick cries)
[Nick] No, no. Put away that
iPhone! (Discussing in foreign
language)
I don't know what that is.
(Reggae music)
(Bandits speaking in
foreign language)
(Reggae music)
[Rey] Is Nick leaving-?
Sorry.
[Hazel] We need
to get him back
We can't just leave him here.
Why not?
That's what he wants.
We won't get five
feet without him.
We need him as a guide.
Hazel, the only thing he's
useful for is translating,
Which you can do.
Well then, why did you need
him so bad in the first place?
That's my point!
You weren't coming before,
Now that you are, fuck that guy.
[Audrey] Do we have this?
(Ballad music)
(Hazel and Audrey laughing)
Don't worry, just work
off your debt tonight
And we'll come get you
in the morning, okay?
We won't leave you.
Well, she won't leave you.
(Steps getting far away)
(Ballad music)
(Bandits speaking
foreign language)
[Nick] Okay, hit.
(Bandits laughing)
[Female waiter] Oh, my God!
(Rock music)
Look, he fucking
left his screenplay.
"The last days of Danny Anderson"
Were standing cold and lonely,
"But not half as lonely
as the days prior"
(Rock music)
[Nick] Money.
[Nick] No.
(Rock music)
(Tense instrumental music)
(Bandit snoring)
[Brown shirt bandit]
(foreign language)
(Vibrant instrumental music)
[Nick] I'm coming Audrey!
(Bandit screaming)
(Big hit in the ground)
(Surprised instrumental music)
(Moves to tense
instrumental music)
[Blue shirt bandit]
(foreign language)
(Tense instrumental music)
(Moves to vibrant
instrumental music)
(Resolution instrumental music)
(Moves to distracted
instrumental music)
[Nick] Audrey,
wake up, wake up.
Hey, look, look!
I got it from the bandits,
I showed up at night
And stole all this money.
We can fill 'er up now, baby!
[Audrey] I don't... mm...
(Mumbling)
[Audrey] Shit... Hazel!
Hazel, wake up!
Nick's back.
[Hazel] Rey, what
are you doing?
[Rey] Working?
[Audrey] While you
were wasting time,
Nick got us some money.
So, come on!
We're leaving.
We have to go!
Okay, you punks I'm
back for more...
(Tense instrumental music)
[Hazel] Okay, we're filled.
Go, go!
[Audrey] No! What about Nick?
(Tense instrumental music)
(Moves to surprised
instrumental music)
(Moves to tense
He's coming, he's coming!
Go, go, go!
[Audrey] Come on, Nick!
(Vibrant instrumental music)
(Screaming in foreign language)
No!
I'm going!
[Audrey] Come on, Nick!
Let's go, let's go,
let's go! Come on!
(Vibrant instrumental music)
(Motorcycle crashing)
[Green shirt bandit]
(foreign language)
(Vibrant instrumental music)
(Tires screeching)
Okay, I've got a couple
questions for you guys.
Rey, did you make
any extra money?
No.
Nick,
Where did you get this?
I took it from the
bandits hideout.
[Audrey] Okay.
I did!
See, look at the money.
Yeah, it is money...
And I escaped from their
clutches all by my lonesome.
I'm like a hero.
Wait a sec...
[Audrey] Okay,
cut the bullshit,
Did you steal this?
Yes, I did!
From the bandits.
Notice how they were chasing me.
They were chasing us.
I was...
Hold on a second, Rey.
No, they were chasing me.
They didn't see you until after
I jumped in the jeepney.
At which point you became
their main target.
(Rejoicing instrumental music)
(Moves to tense
instrumental music)
Oh!
(Vibrant instrumental music)
[Nick] Get 'em, Rey!
Oh!
I got you!
(Vibrant instrumental music)
Stop the jeep, stop the jeep!
Okay, okay!
(Vibrant instrumental music)
(Tires screeching)
Stop the jeep, stop it!
(Vibrant instrumental music)
(Moves to triumphant
instrumental music)
(Moves to vibrant
(Hazel screams)
[Rey] Stop the car!
[Hazel] Stop, go
Go, stop... Goddamit!
(Nick screams)
[Audrey] Nick!
[Nick] Oh, you broke,
you broke my fall.
[Bandit] (screaming
in foreign language)
Shhh.
(Screaming in
foreign language)
[Rey] (screaming in foreign
language) - [Audrey] Stop, stop.
What are you doing?
[Rey] (foreign language)
[Audrey] What do
you people want?
[Rey] (foreign language)
[Nick] Oh, he runs
away for you...
[Audrey] Come on.
[Nick] Did you see that?
You drive!
[Audrey] Why?
That was kind of
heroic, what you did.
Continue.
Getting away from capture,
Stealing the money,
Fighting that man.
[Nick] I was just saving
my own ass, it's all.
Ours too.
Keep it up, troop.
Glad I made you come.
(Adventurous instrumental music)
[Nick] Come on,
we all have to go.
When we get gas, we'll stop.
(Adventurous instrumental music)
[Rey] Aw, aw, aw.
[Nick] This gas station.
[Rey] Yeah.
(Adventurous instrumental music)
Oh, no!
There's a town a
few miles back,
Nick and I will go,
we'll find help
And get the jeepney going again.
I don't wanna be stuck here.
We won't be.
(Wondering instrumental music)
[Nick] So where is this
whole journey taking us?
Diwata Falls, where
the legend comes from.
Yes, and?
And what?
Tell me, you need
to be honest here.
You're losing Hazel and Rey
And a little honesty
will go a long way.
Why is that?
Hazel thinks we're
going some temple,
Rey believes we're
actually gonna visit
The magical fairy beings
And sample their sweet
honey dumplings.
They're not questioning things
now, but they will soon.
How about you?
I want to believe you.
And you don't?
You make it very difficult.
Also there is the unexplained...
Oh, my God! Look!
There's the town!
We don't have to
small-talk anymore.
[Nick] That town
is like a mile away.
This looks like it.
Hey Audrey, why don't
you go in there
And ask him how
much it's gonna be
And how long it'll take?
Oh, that's right!
You can't do any of those
things without me, can you?
(Tense instrumental music)
He said they do indeed
do Jeepneys and-
(Tense instrumental music)
[Biker] (speaking
foreign language)
Not everybody on a
motorbike is out to get you.
You should probably
get over yourself.
Come on, lets go.
So, sir, we want
to get going soon.
He says he can take us.
[Repairman] (foreign language)
(Motorcycle engine)
I need to talk to
the beautiful one.
[Nick] Well, since you
are already talking to me
You must mean the
butch, manly one.
Sure.
(Joyful instrumental music)
[Audrey] What?
My friends are
still following you.
And we won't show ourselves.
We know you will always fight,
And if you fight you won't tell.
So I guess that's that then.
[Black cap repairman] But
your friends are getting tired.
They won't be on
your side for long.
If you value them, tell
me where you're going.
We'll share. We like
you, you're funny.
If you decide, I'll always
be here a step behind you.
Why are you doing this?
There's probably not
a single dollar
Or diamond, or peso
on that island.
We believe you, we
have to believe you.
We need the wealth
so desperately.
And you have no right
to take it from us,
The people of this land.
There is no money!
We will see.
[Nick] You know I've been
watching the mechanic,
And things seem a little fishy.
He's been working
for eight hours
And all he's managed to
do is stare at screws.
Stare at a screw,
tighten, untighten.
I think it would be faster
if we all just walked.
In fact, that's what
I'm going to do.
[Hazel] Yeah right.
Ten minute rule.
[Nick] What you
mean ten minute rule?
A joke we made about you.
[Nick] A joke? What
do you mean joke?
What kind of joke?
What are you talking
about a joke?
Well, you have your
knee-jerk reaction.
You say, "Fuck no,
I'm not doing that".
I don't talk like that.
And then about ten minutes
later you come back
With a completely
reversed opinion,
As if you never felt any
different in the first place.
Name one example...
Like when I asked
you to be my guide,
Like when the truck driver
chased us down the road,
Like when the shopkeep
told us about the island,
Or like when...
Okay, whatever. I get it.
But a man has the right
to changes his opinions.
That's the difference between
us and the fascists.
"And the fascists".
[Hazel] Yeah!
(Car engine)
[Rey] Wait, wait!
Hey!
[Nick] I can see all
the way down this road,
I have eyesight like a carrot. -
I can see all the way too, I see
dark.
What do you think Audrey-
(Car engine failing)
(Car engine not starting)
(Crickets chirping)
[Hazel] (foreign language)
Yeah, yeah. Cheap-ass job.
We're going into the jungle.
What?
Well, to drive there
We'd have to go all
the way around this.
But if we go straight through,
we'll go right into town.
Well, we can do
that at day break,
But I don't think any earlier.
No, right now.
Grab what you need, we'll get
the jeepney on the way back.
[Hazel] But the
jungle is no place
For us in the middle
of the night!
We have plenty of flashlights,
And this is just a thin
stretch of jungle.
[Nick] You don't know that.
(Melancholic instrumental music)
We're never gonna see
you again, are we?
(Melancholic instrumental music)
(Moves to mysterious
instrumental music)
(House club music far away)
[Nick] How much further is it?
[Audrey] I don't know.
(House club music far away)
What is that sound?
[Audrey] I don't know.
Come on, lets just keep going.
(Mysterious instrumental music)
(House club music
getting louder)
[Hazel] The music is
coming from over there!
(House club music
getting louder)
(House club music)
What the fuck is
happening here?
[Audrey] Some crazy party.
Is it fourth of
July or something?
[Nick] We don't have
a fourth of July here,
Not in the sense that you mean.
Some sacred day that
I've never heard of.
I guess it's just in this town.
Well, fuck it!
We gotta find some place
to sleep tonight.
(Salsa music)
(Crowd applause)
(House club music)
(Moves to low-tempo
house club music)
(Anxious instrumental
music getting louder)
[Nick] Hey!
Come on, there's nothing
to be done tonight.
We'll get a boat in the
morning to go to the island.
You can't keep doing
this, lets go!
What's wrong with
you? What's going on?
We have to go, come on!
Hey!
(House club music
drowning Nick's voice)
(House club music)
(Moves to sad
instrumental music)
(No audible dialogue)
(Moves to tense
instrumental music)
(Sounds of struggling)
(Gunshot)
(Aching instrumental music)
(Group cheering)
(Group celebrating)
Hey you guys!
Did you see that I
got in fourth place?
[Hazel] Yeah.
[Audrey] Pretty great.
Yeah, but it wasn't a great
idea to get tanked right now.
We have no money.
We left the jeepney,
we've nothing to sell.
Getting to the island is a...
I got fourth outta
fiddy (mumbling).
Fiddy what?
Fifty, so I got a prize. See?
So I kept going no matter what.
(Audrey throws up)
(Tense instrumental music)
[White shirt bandit]
(foreign language)
(Tense instrumental music)
[Nick] And this is
the magnificent vessel
Which will bear us
across the currents.
(Rey laughs out loud)
[Audrey] Why is
it on the land?
Is it a land boat?
Yeah, well this plus the food
Cost us everything we had.
Come on, we gotta get
this in the water.
[Audrey] Okay.
[Nick] Right over.
[Audrey] Everyone, I just
wanna say a few words.
Okay.
I wanted to, um, say, um...
You Filipinos are awesome.
Now, lets do this shit!
(Adventurous instrumental music)
(Moves to dangerous
instrumental music)
[Joey] (foreign language)
(Dangerous instrumental music)
[Audrey] No, no! Stop!
I can't do this!
All this running,
I'm going back.
Audrey, you're drunk.
It's alright.
I'm just gonna go and
have a word with them.
I'll be fine.
(Courageous instrumental music)
(Gunshot)
[Joey] (screaming
in foreign language)
[Audrey] Never mind!
(Vibrant instrumental music)
[Nick] "I can't
do this anymore".
"I'm just gonna have
a word with them".
"Never mind!".
(Bandits screaming
in foreign language)
(Vibrant instrumental music)
Hey! Hey, guys, where are you?
Hey!
Oh, no! Oh, no, where are they?
Oh, shit!
(Vibrant instrumental music)
(Moves to calm
instrumental music)
[Nick] Wait, this looks clear.
Let's rest here.
Oh, no!
Okay?
[Audrey] What?
(Bandits screaming
in foreign language)
(Blissful instrumental music)
[Rey] The big ship's cast off.
They're gone!
(Hazel screams happily)
[Audrey] Oh, man. No more
crazy motorcycle bandits.
Ah, we're home free.
[Nick] Guys, I am so glad.
And I learned something
from all of this.
Camp fires are just a terrible
idea in this climate.
[Audrey] They're
leaving us alone.
It's plain as day.
[Nick] What is?
[Audrey] Well, they think
That there's something
going on between us.
Ha! Well in that case
Lets call 'em back.
Hey, guys!
- Stop!
- [Nick] What?
- Stop.
- [Nick] What, what, what?
There is something
going on between us.
[Nick] Says who?
I'm wise to your ways,
That you always win
And you do anything
you can to win.
And I'm not gonna be
your tool tonight.
I'm not all schemes
and calculations, Nick.
[Nick] Yeah, you don't really
Calculate anything, do you?
(Melancholic instrumental music)
Nick!
Ten minute rule.
(Melancholic instrumental music)
(Moves to adventurous
instrumental music)
(Moves to tense
(Bandit screams in pain)
[Nick] Hazel! Rey!
Come here quick, I need
you guys right now!
Guys, come on! Guys, quick.
[Hazel] What happened?
[Rey] Is she shot?
[Nick] Yeah, I,
I... Oh, my God!
What are you doing?
[Nick] I just
started panicking...
I didn't think to check
her for anything.
(Sad instrumental music)
We need to get off this island
And to a city to call your
family to come pick us up.
And then we have to, somehow,
Get to an American embassy
to deal with this.
But we've got to act fast,
we don't have much time.
^Lt's been hours! I don't
know how long she can...
We would have if
she wasn't so...
[Nick] Ready?
[Rey] Yeah.
[Nick] Let's go.
Alright, come on.
Woah!
What is it?
It's nothing. I'm sorry.
Okay, let's get going.
(Sad instrumental music)
[Nick] We gotta put her down.
[Rey] What?
- [Nick] Oh...
- [Rey] What's wrong?
[Nick] She keeps moving
and it's weirding me out.
[Rey] If we don't get her
on the boat right now,
It will be night
before we get across.
[Nick] We'll go tomorrow.
(Suspenseful instrumental music)
(Crickets chirping)
(Loud scream)
(Choking)
(Tense instrumental music)
(Loud scream)
(Choking)
(Melancholic instrumental music)
[Audrey] It hurts.
We need to leave now.
[Audrey] I need to go back.
[Nick] Um, what?
[Audrey] Take me back.
Back where?
Okay.
(Troubled instrumental music)
Nick.
I'm still..remembering
how to... talking.
I did more than hit my head.
Here I am still standing.
So let's finish this!
What?
[Audrey] Let's go, we're here already.
[Rey] No, no!
We need to go home.
You need to see a doctor.
You were shot...
[Nick] Rey...
In the head!
What are you?
[Nick] Lay off Rey.
(Speaking foreign language)
[Audrey] English!
We won't follow you anymore!
Come on, let's go.
[Nick] Hey, he's in the right.
It's time to go back now.
Why won't you look at me?
It's hard to look in one eye.
But that's,
That's why we need
to get you, to go,
We need to get you to a doctor.
Where would I go?
Huh?
You don't know
anything about me.
I've nowhere to go but forward.
(Aching instrumental music)
What's happening to me?
You're fixing.
I don't understand it.
[Nick] You don't need to.
[Audrey] All that I know,
All I can pass through
my head clearly
Is to find this place
that calls to me.
You know where it is?
How far?
[Audrey] About an hour.
Can you stand?
(Melancholic instrumental music)
[Audrey] Tell me
what you're gonna do.
Your future.
[Nick] When you
finally see your legend
And you let us get out of here,
I'm flying straight
back to America.
Gonna call my agent, beg
him to take me back.
And then I'm gonna write
on every crappy soap
Until I find something
worth doing.
[Audrey] Sounds nice.
[Nick] It won't be.
[Audrey] What's worth doing?
[Nick] Being famous.
[Audrey] You're lucky.
[Nick] Why is that?
[Audrey] I don't
have a future.
Hey, listen to me.
When all this is done,
you're going home.
And everything is gonna
return to normal.
We're here.
The end of the river, that's it.
Alright, well
fuck it. Let's go.
Get on with our lives.
Wait.
I wanna see it the morning.
In the light.
(Mysterious instrumental music)
(Moves to mystical
instrumental music)
(Moves to blissful
(Moves to suspenseful
instrumental music)
[Diwata King] My dear girl.
You've traveled much too far
on your own strength alone.
Did the humans dare
try to hurt you?
Come.
We've saved that seat for you.
But before you can rest
And know no loneliness
here with your own people,
You must acknowledge,
Understand that your
father was wrong.
Our responsibility
only is to be fair
In doling out the blessed
lives or the cursed ones.
These are the Muses of Luck,
They guide our hands for
Luck alone is fair.
So now, after living with
the humans as you did,
As we had planned for you,
Declare that you recognize
your father's folly.
(Tense instrumental music)
(Vibrant uncertain
instrumental music)
(Tense instrumental music)
(Loud scream)
(Adventurous instrumental music)
(Moves to tense
instrumental music)
(Scream)
(Falling paper)
(Dramatic instrumental music)
(Faded scream)
(Paper falling)
(Adventurous instrumental music)
(Depressing instrumental music)
(Paper falling)
(Moves to rejoicing
instrumental music)
(Moves to jubilant
[Nick] There you go.
Hey, hey! Are you with me?
I'm here, I'm here.
Are you here with me? I'm here.
I got ya.
I saved you.
[Rey] Come on.
(Rejoicing instrumental music)
(Moves to blissful
instrumental music)
(Moves to joyful
(Moves to playful
instrumental music)
[Audrey] You saved me.
So I guess that makes
you the hero now, huh?
You just rubbed off on
me a little, that's all.
(Blissful instrumental music)
I love this thing.
Now, I'm driving it
again, I'm remembering-
- [Rey] -it's a long way back.
Nick, you're some sort
of a writer, right?
[Hazel] Yeah.
We've never heard
you tell us a story.
[Hazel] Yeah, tell us!
This is a little thing
I've been working on.
But before I begin proper,
I do have an introduction.
A hero never falters.
A hero never backslides
or schemes or betrays
And a hero will never fail.
But people do.
They have their weaknesses,
Their deficiencies.
But tell me,
What is the fundamental
difference
Between heroes and
the rest of us?
Heroes are dead.
(Jubilant instrumental music)
(Moves to vibrant
instrumental music)
(Ballad music)