==Subtitle transformation of srt: auess ==
Finally you came
For the person that you kept looking for since this 10 years
Yes, I'm here now.
Happy rhythm
Here is not the final destination
A starting point that just travels
400 years ago
Why does anyone come here to chase one's own destiny?
Do you understand?
Is the thing that you look for really so important?
Have thought
You in Tokyo
Come here to give much trouble by one's own body
To me
What that stone image can be regarded as?
Keep assaulting my soul for a long time
I keep hesitating
Does it really exist?
It is located in a certain place of Europe
It is only a illusion probably
But I have come here
Looking for
What are you looking for ?
I had run into you at that time
Maybe because the music that we listen to is the same
Remember where we seemed in the past to meet
No, may not have such a thing
This may be mere and the same thing flown over at sea
Who are you?
See your close figure
We have already gone to together
I saw you for the first time
I had a kind of indescribable shyness at that time
When foreign country runs into Japanese
I always have this kind of feeling
Run into Japanese, but I am not Japanese
You speak very well
Look like and talk enjoying Japanese from the heart
I think I seems that it is the duckweed
Have no backing, under very contradictory situation, I have spoken the words
Speak to you , make me get rid of puzzledly
I think in this way
Your own thing
Speak a bit more carefully
My own thing
My own thing does not want to say more
Know that runs here and there in Europe
I am such a woman
I really envy you
I have not thought of having persons similar to you life
Have you stayed for a long time in Europe?
What can I say, I have already stayed for several years
8 years, maybe 10 years.
Continue going on
It is really cunning
I have not asked your situation
Begin to leave the continent from here
Begin the sea
This is the end of the west of Europe
It is the title of an emperor's reign found out from map
There was a Portuguese that year
Have found Japan for the first time
In my school-days
In the museum of Nagasaki
I have found a very old map
Have passed for 400 years
That is witness that they come to Nagasaki
There is history of Christianism color
There is that valuable building
All destroy quickly
That picture above
Have brought them to
Considered to be Japan of the earth end
Strong will including pioneer
The impact to my soul is very great
That prototype painted
Must be in a certain place of Europe now
I am perplexed by this idea
Can't free till now
What's the matter with you?
Nagasaki
My father died
In that stretch of miserable land in Nagasaki
But I nothing forget it now
Do not remember what kind of city it is
Do you know where there is such a church?
Do not have
Think where to see to seem that here
What a pity
However, it is perhaps a good thing not to be easy to find
Why say so?
Is it see man missed to keep the same one one year already to seem
Though has not seen that person
I do not understand
I have never thought deeply
You are lying, it is not the innermost thoughts and feelings
Not what I said is truth
So in the past many years, I have walked in the whole travel around Europe
It seems that you do not believe the love
Maybe.
But, you love this stretch of land deeply , right?
So you live here for a long time
I do not understand
I have never really opened one's own heart
I keep sealing oneself
I feel more suitable like this
We all continue for a job
What are you fearing?
I have not just loved anything
Why can't open the heart to me?
Don't be close to me
Are you fearing oneself?
The unlimited heart is very easy injured
You are cheating oneself
It is too kindhearted that just afraid oneself
No
I am very satisfied with one's own life current situation
In such a long time, what do you keep seeing?
I must leave here
Strength of this cathedral that I find
Is it your love? Tell me
Where is that thing?
400 years ago, who brings the civilization to we in remotest places?
I agree on
I will go to Madrid now
If that was produced because of your love
why leave now?
Good-bye, you play here by oneself
Seem to be doing some useless things
No, this is that myself want to do
However, is there many bright remembrance for you here?
I was once injured because of remembering
Will not betray the mankind while remembering
Just people think oneself has been betrayed
I think in this way
Why did you keep following me?
I think too idle
A person has gone on a tour after I have already been tired
Have not I said
If you are lost, I will feel very awkward
Yes, I may get lost
For you
It was a bit different that the travel this time was followed in the past
Perhaps you have ever thought too
When I want to go out, you were still as usual sad
Also saying
Come back as soon as possible, good luck.
Over these 8 years, you have not changed at all
Why have you been here soon?
I have already no longer loved you
No, I do not understand either
What happened?
It seems that someone is assassinated
Have died?
I only know a little Spanish
Spaniards' temper is really very irritable
That girl's elder sister is stabed
Seem that that young man's wife
It is a thing of married woman's adultery
It is not loyal that that man says that can't forgive the wife's
That man is smiling
Say God is looking at him , God understands him
No
You are lying
Is that right?
I do not know their language
You lie to me
No, what I spoke is truth
Why must I compile the story to listen to for you?
Do you have while lying too in order to hide oneself?
It may be my misunderstanding too
I am others' wife too
You say your own thing for the first time
Tell you who are true
Swallow flying in the sky
Want to forget the olive branch that it has ever stopped
A slice of leaf shaking in the wind
This is me
Do you also want to deceive oneself as well as others?
Who is it?
The husband's younger sister
What about him?
He is a nationality of U.S.A.
He resides in a trading company of Paris
Seem that interrogating me
Shall I say his name? No
To me, the name is nothing important
Really a fool
There is awareness, you will not get lost
Do you love him?
I love him very much
It is so all right
Holidays of 6 weeks
Can you see a lot of cities and buildings?
Before beginning the life of the university
This is my only work that can do
That person is too gentle
Even if you and I have loves
He will only look at me with the sad expression in one's eyes
Then he will say that forgive me
Do you understand this meaning?
It is a kind of cruelty to be gentle sometimes
Do you know it is more and more terrible that you lie by oneself?
Nagasaki, Porto, Madrid, Paris
That is only some name of the places
In my memory
Each place just as it is the scenery
When being withered
Can people really totally get rid of the custom of one's own birthplace ?
Where was I born?
Sometimes when I am looking at the plane in the sky , are thinking so
So long as I take the plane , can get back to Japan in 17 hours
It seems that there are my roots there
But I can't go back
Because of
That is a kind of intuition not very reliable
To me, what is Japan?
That is me no the place where we can depend on
Is not it all the same where to go?
I have gone out of Tokyo for the first time
There is no reason
Everybody is after thinking I have reached Tokyo
There must be things to do
But that city had not resumed from suffering a defeat yet at that time
A lot things burnt stayed
Remembering summer there, the sun is very bright
I am travelling alone
Entered a trading company there later
Meet that person there
Later on I fell in love with him.
No,
You do not love him
No way, do you always wander up and down in the street of Paris like this?
Are you Mr.Chuancun?
Yes, I am Chuancun
I call Robert.Fesigerlad
I am a husband of Zhizi, how do you do
Glad to meet you
She says you have ever looked after her when being in Spain
I want to invite you to the family, Zhizi likes too
Sometimes the woman is very homesick
They like staying with native
We are discussing which city is more beautiful
Saboer or Kinoso
There is a characteristic in two cities, can't say where is more beautiful
Saboer has male makings , and Kinoso have women's makings
I can't draw a conclusion before I have not seen
Discuss who of men or the woman have no meaning more outstandingly
The man and woman can like each other
We are discussing the building now
Like determining everything
Only God can give people true love
It is radians that we have now
You are discussing the architectural thing
This has been said by me, it is like a tree sometimes
So can stand a bit longer
Do you agree to the elder brother's idea?
If this is true, it is false
If this is true, other is false
I do not know what you are saying
Do you want to tell me what?
Tell you , we live in one is false world everywhere
False pipeline, the false church
False family, false language
If there are true things
That is God's words
Do you understand he said Zhizi?
Certainly, I understand
Always say in this way too usually ?
Robert is welcoming you
In his unique way
Pen this then belong to I, but a others' one
It is the same things that God sees all these
I think that it is very important to find true oneself
Answers of the spirit are all the same
I have an idea now
Let us see which one of two castles is more beautiful
Saboer or Kinoso
We want to go, he wants to look for an ancient city
It is not the castle
Where?
I do not know
Which castle do you prefer?
Tell me
Do you like living in that castle?
It is a bit better to Zhizi that you want
Sometimes, people need more love
More than what they yearn for
I need love very much too oneself now
Our travel has begun again
It is not accidental this time
I want to go to Italy
Why do you want to go to Noerman?
There are things that want to let you see
Are you joking?
I have investigated within these five days
If the ancient city that I look for exists
It should be in Italy
A lot of building masters at that time all assembled in Florence
That turned round at next stop
Can catch the plane at night
Thing of Noerman that you go
Who else knows?
My husband knows
He is in Paris
I do not have other persons who want to see
In addition, he has not said that let me see others
If the tidewater rises
That church will be stayed in the sea
Want to let me see such scenery ?
Will stay in the sea
But that is different
It is not my church
Yes.
You saw in Nagasaki
It is this church
No, it's not.
My church is very small
Will come into the heart carelessly
Such a church
The things wanted to look for can all be found
I will also go to look for
Not all right
Do not have
You say that your life is a dream, right?
Let to accept oneself
No
I am for proving that came here by oneself
With that person
Have come here while getting married
He loves me
And today
We come here in order to say good-bye
Will not see you again
No way, I can't be like this
I can't meet you again
Not all right
I reach wanting to visit all over Europe before death
No way, when the tidewater comes
The church will stay in sea
That is me
The sun in summer is very beautiful
I work in Sweden now
Are you still in Torino or Florence now?
Have you found that cathedral ?
Today is the day that the 170th commerce meeting opens
Who is it by that white desk ?
There is tea ceremony
When the work is smooth, I am very happy
I am very happy
What is the happiness?
Cathedral that you look for
Should not be here
I have already found
Just before me
Always wind curved and very not all right in the characters
This fact, have no way
The thing that I look for is you
You have left Paris in case of not telling me
Understood at last, to me, the cathedral is you
Really envy you
There are many things that will look for
Are you satirizing me?
No, I really think in this way
I do not have any thing wanted to look for
Can only remember some things
You are talking about your husband
Should have too
It is Japan to have
Have you never remembered me?
You are you
Have not already said good-bye in Noerman?
I am just a scenery in your eyes
No
You may get lost
Disappearred.
Yes.
You yourself
I can have a lost thing
Do you understand me? Not
I do not understand
Only know that the person meeting by chance in Europe
Where are you?
Just here
I am a little tired
Thought you will fly away from my side
Have already reached morning
At night
But very bright outside
It was daybreak originally
There is not the world of shade
The thing that can be seen always lets people think that have no backing
The sun transparent and gives out light
There is not the sun everywhere
I have seen the sun at night
While travelling to the north of reaching Lapplata River with Robert
Sun flickering on the horizon
There are sounds
You have misunderstood
Is that right?
Hope you answer me clearly
You always disappear in front of me
Now in front of you I
Why will you leave alone?
Was all of yesterday dreams?
Yes.
It's a dream.
You are mine
Your tenderness of last night
Almost burn people to death
Today I seem that still live in daytime very much
World before the blast comes
A teenager who puts up the finger
Everything is two people's business
Don't make me painful again
Don't look for me again
There is no thing that can be given to you
It seems that there is anything that was suddenly taken away the samly from my backbone
I am abandoned on the remote path by a person
No, that is not Robert
It is not you certainly
That is myself
I disappearing fall down there
Have another me
Bestir oneself and continue going ahead again
You do not understand me
I want to look for
Cathedral not existing in reality
It can only show your fragility at heart to continue looking for
For you, I should insist on alive
Can tell my you who have only last night
In order to speak the words, I have gone to look for you
You have really left
I have not expected to see you again
Even so, I am still in Copenhagen now
I think I am unfair to you
These that I do not want to listen to you
Do it in this way and hope to have a try of one's own strength
Only a person's words, it is strong that I will become OK
I will make an appointment and meet with Robert in Amsterdam tomorrow
We say good-bye
But please don't misunderstand
Do not say good-bye to him because of you
Did you think I was waiting for this result?
It is all right to talk about, I want to see your husband
Not, OK?
The miserable person is me
By what kind of is your meeting the way to say good-bye to husband?
He is a perfect person
Must be thinking that there is the arrival of this day
Is there love between you?
Like already becoming
Without fate, everything will be finished ?
It is so too to us
Robert was said
The love should take time to test
I will go to see you
I do not think of , do not make me wait
How do you do, can I converse with Mrs.Richard?
I am, who phoning?
Michael, waits for you to be tired
I do not know you
Is it the same greeting?
What has he said?
He says I hope , on the words for him
Hope
He is very amazing
Your language ability is very amazing
What is said?
Hope
Very small hope
Mr.Chuancun
She does not live at our home now
She is in Terfoli Hotel of RomaTeliterni Street
Have stayed for three days in Roma
You must begin to study in Paris by September
The research of sociology is very interesting?
They are thinking of human future
Relics of Roma before 2000
Just in the center of this city
There are people like you
They are missing the future of the city
The passage of time is very cruel
The present thing will be getting bad, disappear
And is made again
I hope you shut up as soon as possible
Why?
I do not want to waste the time to stay together with you
I want to say something
Stand in the middle of this enormous trace
We are just two pieces of insignificant snack
This is that one kind is sad too
You are afraid too, and feel lonely ?
So want to say so much to me
We can get back to Paris tomorrow
It is all right to go back to Tokyo
Choose the place which yourself like
And we will get married
Can't do
You have refused our meet
We meet in may be in the journey
Just in order to look for the consolation of soul
But different now
You are a woman
As a Japanese woman , stand in front of me
To not believing you of the love say these may be of no use
It may be me who is wrong
Live for such a long time in Europe
I have totally become
It must be hard
I also want to ask you a thing
To you, what is Japan?
It is everything
Everything lost already disappears
Why say that disappear
In that year summer for armistice
My mother and younger brother died in Nagasaki
No, all remembrance that I have since borning
All disappeared that summer
Have not thought of getting back to that stretch of land
I have already faced away from it
Even if I tell you the change of Japan is very large
Do not you believe either?
The sun is shining
Now, we are in the passing of time
You are free now, and any relation that I did not have
Hereafter what is to be done?
One lives in Europe
I can't understand the road that you choose
Pay the high cost and freedom got
I myself am too
I do not understand what oneself is doing
You can turn round now
That day
I am when Amsterdam wait for you
That person has said
It is my own hope
It is free from at that moment beginning me
I can't answer at that time
Want to get to your place at once
Though think so , have not taken action
I am sorry
When Robert says those words to me
Will not have thought of you at once in my head
My mood is in a mess
I have asked I am good many times
I like you
So I want and you go one far place very
Very far place
My dear Zhizi
Are you smooth in Roma everything?
I have never worried about you
Dear Zhizi
Are you smooth in Roma everything?
I have never worried about you
But for I who am present, the days pass heavily
Why can understand you with excited heart?
When hearing your application
Being reticent, I have accepted
That can only be because I love you
You have really said that want freedom
Are you free now?
Needn't manage me if you are free
But I
Can't break away from the past of what we have
If you are like this
I will help you
Wish you happiness and succeed
Thought you will disappear from then on
Me while sleeping soundly
Dream you say goodbye to me
By morning
I want to confirm
Use one's own eyes
It is all right to stand up
It is a dream separated form you
I do not want to do
You breathe heavily the slight breath is falling asleep
See I rest assured about these
Not
It is very great happiness
I love you
Present time is very empty for me
Why can't you understand me?
Some words have to speak
That cathedral that you look for
I know , you know too
Prototype of that church
Still in a certain place of Europe now?
You are imagining
That church is still here now
A small village by this Adriatic of Italy
You know these at the beginning
As stubborn as you
That old church
Still stand there now
When I see for the first time
Opposite sea level, the sun is dropping
I have seen
My Nagasaki
I know that must say to you
However, that is only belonging to the cathedral for a person of mine
Do not want to let others know
You sleep very well
I become lively slowly
While looking at the last the setting sun of Roma on one side
Would suddenly think of not meeting you again
If separate now
Can't meet each other again forever
I think I must say to you
Please go to look for that church
No, my cathedral has already been destroyed
The present cathedral is you
I am very satisfied
You can say these finally
It is talents who love me that do it in this way
My cathedral
Have really lost badly
I ran into you that day
If believe it has already been destroyed
Why do you want to go to such far Europe ?
See you for coming
Do you still think now the cathedral is a kind of faith?
Only you are here now, in New Roma
Who has built this new city?
After becoming extinct from Ancient Roma
Extinction is, but some things will not become extinct
It is your love
Thing worked out with our heart
I will let you disappear forever now
Thing disappearing can be retrieved
The words going now should be returned there is still time
Words going now
But I did not go
I do not go
Robert has said
It take time to weigh for the love to want
I always take action according to his words
May be because I believe him
But I am not free now
My time stopped, did not flow
And, I have no time to love
It is said you are in Besili
However, that is not one kind to part
It is not Besili
It is already too late for me to know, but I will also catch up with
Who am I chasing ?
Why must say
And you
Where are you going?
Where?
Where must I go?
Where to go?
The 471st plane of Japan Airlines(JAL)
Guests who want to go to Paris and London
Will do the formality of boarding well soon
Please hurry up
Present I am free
I am free
Have broken away from him, you, I
It is because of loving, it is because of heart , the time
I am free
I have done
Being free, I give me time
Taxi
Summer of 1968