Son las 06:00 a.m.
y hay una mañana de primavera preciosa.
Parece que tenemos '
una gran anticipación de verano.
Y más noticias, tráfico y viajes
para usted en 15 minutos
pero simplemente a caerse de la
cama ahora mismo
aquí hay un franco garantizado
para empezar a moverte esta mañana
Buenos días, cielo. Cómo estás?
Sí, estoy de acuerdo. Cómo estás?
All right, Linford?
Ready? whoo!
Chop chop.
I've got to get back for a delivery.
When are you gonna get a new tracksuit?
- This is vintage.
- It's a relic.
- Well, you need new spikes.
- I'm broke.
Well, nail it on the weekend
and you'll have new spikes
coming out of your ears.
Come on, Linford!
Show her how it's done! Go!
All right, then, what's that time
gonna be on Sunday?
- Under 23.
- That's right, because then we...
- We qualify.
- Exactly.
World Champs, here we come.
Go on, then. Get ready.
Okay.
On the one!
Three, two, one!
Pump it! Push into the bend!
Good!
Bring it home, through the line.
- Still half a second off.
- You want more?
- I got more.
- Well, bloody well do it then.
Stop wasting your breath.
- You're the boss.
- Yes, I bloody well am.
Linford! Get out of there!
Hey! Hey, Shania.
Come here.
Where's that sister of yours?
What? You tell me.
She lives with you, innit.
No, I heard she moved back in with you.
- Well, she didn't, so you heard wrong.
- Is that right?
Yeah, Daze.
Look, I don't have time for this, man.
If Tara knows what's good for her
she will call me. Today, yeah?
- You're gonna tell her that.
- All right.
- Good.
- Bye.
- Hey, make sure you tell her, yeah?
- I'll tell her.
- Sh...
- Don't answer.
I swear, if he calls me one more time...
- Tara!
- Don't start, Shania.
I got enough going on.
That man is driving me crazy.
I swear, if he comes
anywhere near me again...
Are you gonna turn that shower off?
Why have you always got to give me grief?
Hi, baby. Hello, Auntie.
Not You, as well?
Look, please, just for a couple of days?
No way.
Please, Auntie P.
She can stay on the sofa with me
and I promise that
we won't get in your way.
Fine, fine, fine.
Thanks, Auntie.
Thanks, Tyrell. Actually, yeah,
training was all right today.
Yeah, it weren't too bad, thanks.
- There she is.
- Good luck today, darling.
Don't waste the Luck, Mum
It's just for practice.
- Right.
- Just because you've already
been selected, doesn't mean
you don't need the practice
- or the luck.
- Sorry, Dad. Mum...
- Love you.
- Nice to see you, Ellie.
Hi, Lisa.
Hi.
Jane wanted to come and support today.
Great.
How's your mum?
Sorry, Jane.
It's a family tradition.
We always go quiet before a race.
It's part of the preparation.
Right, darling?
Come on, we're starting in a few minutes.
Is that Lisa Temple?
Shania, listen. Focus on your own race.
- Okay.
- She already got her slot.
If you run the way I know you can,
the last one's yours.
- All right?
- Yeah.
You have as much right to be here
as they do.
Now you go and show them that. Go on.
- All right. Take that for me. All right.
- Yeah.
Ana' the next race is the
final' qualifier for the gb sprint squad.
With the World Championships
at the end of the summer,
only one place remains.
The fastest 200-meter time,
sub 23...
- Good Luck.
- ..Wife' take the 5,002'.
6000' fuck to them aft'!
Quiet, please.
On your marks.
Set.
Andrews in lane three, up with the leaders.
This is a fast opening quarter.
- Round the bend. Chapman in the feed.
- Yes!
Andrews is pressuring.
Twenty metres to go!
And Andrews takes the lead!
- Andrews if is!
- Shania Andrews made great time there.
She'll take the final' piece
in the gb squad.
- Congratulations, Shaina...
- Yes!
On a great race.
Joining local hero Lisa Temple...
- Whoo!
...- at the World Championships.
- - Who's that?
Shania Andrews. Local girl.
And has she broken 23 before?
She's been building steadily all year.
Well, considering she missed
last year altogether, I'm impressed.
It looks like Lisa's got a rival.
That will be good for her.
Keep her focussed.
Take care.
Got yourself a winner there.
Sorry, Tommy Southern, GB relay coach.
Brian Johnson, shopkeeper.
Shop... Ah.
I thought you were Shania's...
Well, I give her a hand, you know.
How do you think she
would handle being on the relay team?
Why don't you ask her yourself?
Shania Andrews, Tommy Southern.
- Hi.
- Pleased to meet you.
Ask me what?
I just wanted to say congratulations
You ran a really great race today.
- Thank you.
- No problem.
So, I'm gonna be seeing you at the Valley.
Who was that?
Am I dreaming?
I pinched myself in the changing room.
I actually pinched myself, hard.
It was a big step for you.
You need to keep your times consistent
if you want a medal.
I beat Lisa Temple in a race today.
Did you see my time? Brian, did you
time me? Where was your watch?
- Are you even listening?
- I'm listening but can I scream now?
Yeah, go on.
Whoo!
We're going to the Worlds!
Who's going?
- We're going to the Warlds...
- Well, no, you are.
What? What do you mean?
- You're coming, too.
- I ain't coming.
My job's done.
What? No, listen.
Brian, they'll fund you and everything.
Look, I promised that I'd help you
get in the door and I have.
What? Where you're going, you're gonna
need more than one bloke and his dog.
- Are you serious?
- Yes.
It's up to you now.
Tara?
Yeah.
Tara, I won.
- Did you?
- Yeah. Made the national team.
I get to train with them, and then
I'm going World Champs, everything.
- Really? That's heavy.
- Yeah.
Look, I'm going shop, do you want anything?
No, I'm all right.
I did it, Mum.
- Shania.
- Hi, you all right?
- Hi, good to see you again.
- Yeah.
- How you doing?
- Not too bad. You?
Come this way. Very well, thank you.
Okay, so, our coaching squad will be
making sure you hit your targets.
And we need to get you kitted out.
- Who's your sponsor?
- I don't have one.
Okay. So, you've got your own kit then?
I think we can get you
some better spikes than that.
- Come with me.
- Okay, then.
Stand by.
Knees! Lift those knees!
...dropping your shin.
Don't drop before...
Who's that?
Nobody.
I'm just gonna speak to this new girl,
just go train with the girls.
Hello.
So, how you feeling?
Bit like I'm going to be
arrested for trespassing
but I'm all right, thank you.
How are you?
You know, divorced, stressed, underpaid.
Think I found a lump
in the shower this morning.
This isn't about me.
This is about you.
You're here because you're
the third ranked woman in Britain.
So how about doubling
your chances of a medal?
- What do you mean?
- Relay.
I've got a space on the team
and it's yours if you want it.
Yeah, I've never really
run the relay before.
Same principle as the solos -
run fast, win race.
Yeah, I'm just...
I'm not very good with teams, though.
- Come and meet the girls. Come on.
- All right.
Hey. What are you guys doing
standing around?
We're not standing,
we're stretching, Coach.
Yeah, stretching my arse.
Limber up, please.
Before you do, I want you
to meet Shania... Andrews?
- Andrews.
- Shania Andrews, this is my relay squad.
The fastest girls in Britain.
Rachel, long jump,
Belle and Sarah, hurdles,
Lisa Temple you know,
and of course, the legend
that is Trix Warren, 100 metres.
- You all right?
- I'm Carl, team physio.
Welcome to the team.
Carl will be yours throughout the season.
His brutal touch, your reward
for being a part of the relay squad.
I'll be gentle.
So, what, she's joining us, then, Tommy?
Well, she broke 23 in Surrey last week.
So, I think that's worth an invite,
don't you?
Yeah, we'll see.
Great. Well, we work around
everyone's solo events,
so there's a relay practice
at the end of the week.
So, are you up for it?
- All right.
- Good girl.
In the meantime, have fun, bond.
Love it. Medals. Let's go.
...Carl, can you pass me that?
- Welcome.
- Thanks.
- You all right?
- Cool,
I've dreamed about being here
my whole life, man.
I can't actually believe I'm here.
Me neither.
How about we just start again?
I didn't come here to make friends.
- Okay?
- Fine.
- You must be Shania.
- Yeah.
I hear you haven't got a coach.
Why don't you tag along
with Lisa and I for the day?
Yeah, all right.
Okay, girls, I want to practise
your block starts.
So, we'll run for 10 metres and then
we come back and do it again, okay?
Watch your hands.
Right, it's those first five paces
that really count.
Heads down, weight forward.
On the one. Three, two, one.
Good.
Nice. Nice, Lisa. Right.
Go back, do it again.
Really drive those arms, yeah?
And on the one.
Three, two, one.
Hey!
Hey, what the hell was that?
Come back, do it again.
- Water?
- Thanks.
Barcelona, man.
I've never even been on a plane, so...
Listen, the Indoors
are just a warm-up, girl.
Barcelona's big,
but it's nothing like the real thing.
Look, where do you pay for all this stuff?
Don't worry about it, babe.
It's all part of the deal.
Take as much as you like.
Trix is like the mother goose around here.
Hey! One kid at home's enough,
thanks, Belle.
Girls, are we looking at chicken
or are we eating chicken?
- I'm starving.
- Yeah, I can tell.
Jeez.
What is it with you two?
Nothing.
I just hope we're all as lucky
as she was when it comes to the Worlds.
I'm looking forward to beating you
a second time.
Yes, this one can stay!
I want you guys to go through
the first set of cones.
Take a lane each.
We're gonna practise the walking drills.
Slow, fast, high knees, okay?
You go past me, it's 20 push-ups.
Good work!
Okay, check marks. Let's go!
Mark your lanes, girls.
Hey.
Simple, all you've gotta do
is pass this baton around the track
as fast as you can.
- Simple, right?
- Yeah, simple.
Go!
Call it Loud and clear. I wanna hear it.
H a n d!
Good Speed!
Trix, Lisa, go.
Hand!
Good, Lisa.
Belle, Shania, don't take off
until she hits her mark.
Go!
Face forward, Shania!
Shania, Shania.
Okay, listen, you've got Belle
coming at you like a freight train,
but you hold
until she hits her change-over mark.
Then you fly, okay?
Okay, go.
Trust and timing.
That's all it's about.
Trust and timing. Got it.
- Hand!
- Come on, come on!
I need silk, ladies. Give me silk.
Hey, hey, concentrate, come on!
- Hand!
- Good! Good, Shania.
Yes!
- You nailed it. Wicked.
- Yeah. Wicked.
- Good. Now do it again.
- Here she is, the golden girl.
- Hello there, Mr Temple.
Great to see you, Trix.
How's the season going?
- Going well, thank you.
- Good, we want to see you on the podium.
You will.
Don't worry about it. See you later.
Yeah, take care.
- How's it going, Tommy?
- Yeah, we're getting there.
To be honest, if some of the other coaches
would give me
a little bit more time with the girls
then I think we've got
a real shot this season.
Well, you are the other coach, Tommy.
No offence, but the relay
isn't anybody's focus right now.
I've asked, I have.
All they say is, "If you want
a team sport, go and play..."
- Football, yeah. Thanks, man.
- "...football" Yeah.
Dad, did you talk to them?
- Yes, yes, I've done it.
- Good.
Ms Andrews, hi.
I'm David Temple.
Look,
I'm afraid you're not gonna
be able to share Lisa's coach.
They've built up a routine over the years
and with the Worlds only a few months away,
it's just too close to disrupt them.
- I hope you understand.
- Yeah. Yeah, of course, yeah.
But don't worry. There's plenty
of really great coaches here.
I'm gonna personally make sure
that you get the best one, okay?
- Thanks.
- Okay.
- Thank you.
Wow. Charming, ain't he?
All right.
Well, I would.
The man's old enough to be your...
My sugar daddy?
Now, there's an idea.
You're nasty.
What?
So, what's your story then?
Could you stand over there?
I started out as a runner, 400 metres.
I was a relay reserve in Beijing.
Turn around please.
Extend that leg towards me.
And the other.
Okay.
So, why'd you stop running?
There's a slight curvature.
You might have tight quads.
Can you face me, please?
You seem very good at your job.
Okay. All done.
Strong glutes.
Could you take this to Tommy for me please?
Yeah. Sure.
Good, good, good. Keep that drive,
keep that drive, keep that drive!
- Come on! Change, change, change.
- Stick.
Again, watch that hand...
Yep, YEP...
Carl asked me to give you these.
Who are they?
USA. The fastest.
See how they move as a team.
She knows when the stick's coming.
That doesn't look like how we do it.
That's because they use a downpass.
The stick comes in a downward motion.
Look, just like... that.
Gives you a whole meter of extra distance.
Why don't we do it like that?
Because it's very risky.
Bigger chance of dropping the stick.
Yeah, but if it's faster...
Look, those girls
have been together for years.
You see, they have got silk.
What we have isn't even polyester.
Bye-bye.
- Hey, Trix.
- Hey.
- Good first week?
- Yeah. It's all right.
You know, I don't get it.
So, the anchor, the last runner,
is meant to be the fastest, right?
- Yeah.
- So why is Lisa running it?
You're faster than her.
Well, that's because my daddy
was only a maths teacher.
What's up, ladies? Doing all right?
You lot heard about
this fundraiser on the 15th?
No.
My two favourite kind of people
are gonna be there.
- Fit men and rich men.
I'm gonna find myself a crossbreed.
So what, are we meant to bring a date?
You as well?
What? I'm just asking.
What you laughing at?
Hey, I'm married, babe, not blind.
Yeah, we saw you looking at Carl
with dreamy eyes.
- Please!
- Everybody does.
He's got that whole "boy band" look
goin' on for him, innit?
I'm telling you,
if it weren't for them rules,
I'd have climbed him like a tree already.
...You know what I'm saying?
Real talk.
What rules are you talking about?
No relationships
between athletes and staff.
It's an automatic sacking offence.
Anyway, the Worlds
are more important than that.
- Yeah.
- And, erm, be careful of Lisa.
That girl's been hot on him for years.
Please. She's the least
of my problems right now.
Girl, you're trying way too hard.
Like, why you going anyway?
Do you really think these rich
white people are gonna give you money?
Loads of black athletes get funding.
Yeah, but they don't look like you.
You know, you keep trying to run away
but you've got like Primark
written all over you.
So you are not
who you are in the public arena.
You become more who you are,
the more pr/vats you get.
So I kick back,
play my position and try listen
'Cause there's opportunities waitin'
it's my decision
The scene's getting ugly
And ugliness that's destroying the scene
But I feel beautiful right now
so I get dressed...
Hi, Elise. Can I just have
a few shots? Thank you, that's great.
"Hey, girl.
- How you doing?
Hello.
It's your time tonight.
Yeah, any UPS?
[Ditch the O] and get something stronger.
...Makes it easier to talk to these suits.
Right.
- Who's Trix talking to?
- The money.
If she don't bring him that gold,
probably dump her for a younger model.
No!
I'll get a drink.
We'll be cheering you on to win that medal.
You just keep signing
those cheques, Mr Aldridge.
I won't let you down.
Must mingle.
- Baby...
- We'll be fine.
- Mr Temple?
- Watch your step. Smile.
Okay, thank you. Thank you.
Yeah, thanks.
Thanks.
- Watch it!
- I'm sorry.
- I think you've had enough.
- What?
What, you gonna get your daddy
to chuck me out, are ya?
Excuse me?
Daddy's little girl wanted to run anchor
so Daddy made it happen.
- I'm really sorry...
- You mutt!
Get your hands off me!
What do you think you're doing?
This isn't some
after-school sports club.
We've all worked
our entire lives to get here.
I'm not gonna let you ruin that.
Listen, sweetheart,
I can look after myself.
- Thank you very much.
- Really?
It's the night before a meet
and you're drunk.
What kind of an athlete are you?
I'm really sorry about that.
Shania!
Where you been, girl?
Oi, what are you two doing back together?
Come on, man, she's my baby girl.
I can't let her get away from me, can I?
That's love, innit?
So you gonna join us?
I can't, man. I got a race tomorrow.
- Come on!
- Come on, man!
- Yeah! Yay!
Come on!
Yeah, all right.
- That's what I'm saying!
- Come on!
You're drunk.
I had to be, man, to get through that.
So, what, the party was crap?
Yeah. You was right.
- But this one's better.
- Yeah.
It is.
Be 900111, yeah?
- All right, have fun.
- Will do, babe.
Aw!
Nathan looks so grown-up.
I know. I hate leaving him.
Right, are we all here, guys?
Guess Shania ain't coming.
Well.
Sarah's faster anyway.
- Than Shania?
- Yeah, on average.
- Leave it out, Lisa, please.
- What?
- Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey!
- I'm just saying Sarah's faster.
Not on race day, ladies, please.
Where's Shania? Does anyone know?
Sorry, sorry! Sorry I'm late, Tommy.
I'm sorry.
Whoa!
Smells like someone had a good night.
Okay, what is going on between you two?
Let's just race our own races...
Okay, well, let's do it, okay?
- We really need to go.
- Yeah? Okay, great. Come on.
Guys, let's go!
Set...
What is wrong with Shania?
She's faster than that.
She's hung-over.
You all right?
What?
Look good and run fast, girl.
That's how it works.
Sorry, how you feeling?
I'm just glad it's over.
What about the relay?
Yeah, you better throw up
a couple more times, girl.
That all right?
- Don't start.
- I'm not starting.
Fourth place in that time
with a hangover's actually pretty good.
Come on.
Right, listen up. Come here.
Even though this is an exhibition,
you have to treat it like
it's the real thing.
Okay, now, the longer distance
is gonna suit you two.
We can win this.
So I need good bends
and clean change-overs
all the way, do you understand?
Good. Now let's go out there
and show 'em what we can do.
Let's bring it home, girls.
Boom!
Let's go! Come on!
Athletes, on your marks.
Come on, Trix.
- Come on, Trix!
- Go, Trix!
Silencio, por favor.
Set.
Home straight! Come on!
Belle, come on, come on.
Go, Belle!
Hand!
Knees high, Belle, knees high!
Hand! Hand!
Come on, Shania!
Hand!
What you doing, man?!
Come on, Lisa, run!
Come on, Lisa!
I don't need to tell you
what that was, do I?
No, actually, you know what? I do.
That was shit.
You're the fastest runners in Europe,
but together, you're awful.
- It wasn't all our fault.
- Yes, it was.
You win as a team, you lose as a team.
Shania called too early.
She's just not up to it.
No, it wasn't just her fault, I was late.
Why are you sticking up for her?
'Cause she ain't
a stuck-up bitch like you!
Shania, shut it!
- So what, it was my fault?
- That's not what I said.
I'm sorry, I'm not risking my chance
of a medal because of her.
- Hey, hey, hey! What did I just say?
- Are you dumb, Tommy?
Her and her daddy call the shots
around here, not you!
So if that don't want me
on the team then fine!
Fine. I'm done. I quit.
- Shania...
- Shut up, Trix!
I ain't your little project, yeah?
I hate all of you. I'm done.
Mature, too. Great.
We don't need her.
You sure about that?
Jesus Christ!
Don't give me another injury
to worry about.
Tough day at the office?
Do you know what? I'm a sprinter, yeah?
Solo. No more distractions.
- Lisa's all right, you know.
- Yeah.
Yeah, she's got
a very funny way of showing it.
So do you.
- Patellar tendonitis.
- Sorry?
You asked me why I gave up running.
My knees.
- Carl.
Duty calls.
All right, man. What's up?
Trix, I just want to talk to Shania.
Not now, Tommy.
Please, I'm begging you.
Look, I'm not gonna
force you into anything.
If you want to be on your own, then fine.
But just hear me out here, okay?
That race yesterday, it meant nothing.
It was an exhibition.
But when we get to the Worlds
I'm gonna need you.
Now, the 4 x 100 metres
is where it's at. Okay?
Hey, I told you.
I'm not good with teams, innit?
Now you know what I mean.
Okay.
Whoa! What happened?
Your sister.
Look at what she and her boyfriend did,
letting strangers in our home,
- stealing our things.
- Was it Daze?
Why did I let her stay?
Well, look,
I'll go and talk to him right now.
You do that, but don't come back here.
- I'm gonna look after my family now.
- What?
I've had enough of you both.
- No, look, I can... I can help...
- No!
I don't want you
staying here no more, Shania.
- Please...
- No. Not this time.
Just get out.
Daze, open the door!
Daze!
Who the fuck do you think you are?
Who do you think you're talking to?
Where's Tara?
Look, You know that girl,
she could be anywhere, all right?
What are you lot doing at my Auntie's?
You've nicked stuff,
and you break stuff.
She's chucked me out.
Really? That's bad news, babe.
Don't mess about with me, Daze,
not today, please.
- Tara!
- I told you,
she ain't here, man, stop this...
You know what?
Deal with this madness,
otherwise I'm gonna slap her.
She's chucked me out, Tara!
Well, don't go blaming me.
What? What's wrong with you?
You've got to go and apologize to her
or at least
- pay for the damages.
- Listen, don't tell me what to do, okay?
So, what, you're gonna let me stay here?
No. Daze don't like guests.
- So where am I gonna sleep, Tara?
- I don't know.
I'm not your mum, am I?
Listen, right, it's about time
you stopped messing about
and took life a bit more seriously.
...I got my own life to deal with.
- Mum!
- In here!
- There you are. How'd you get on?
Silver in the 200
and last in the relay.
Congratulations.
Congratulations? We came last.
But you won the silver.
You don't win silver, Mum.
It's a consolation for losing.
And I know you're gonna say
that that sounds really mean
and that I should just
look on the bright side
and try really hard.
...Listen, Lisa...
he won't reject you, you know.
You're still his daughter
whether you win or lose.
Really?
In you go.
- What the hell are you doing here?
- I got kicked out.
- What happened?
- It's a long story.
Why didn't you call? You could
stay at mine. I mean, you can.
Thanks, Brian.
Come on, get a shower at mine.
I'll give you a lift to training.
No. No, I ain't going back.
I quit the relay
and I just want to focus on my solo thing.
Come on, I'll put the kettle on.
It's pathetic, innit?
Sounds to me like you need
a good kick up the backside.
Thanks...
Coach.
Coach?
Come on, Brian. Please, man.
Just until the Worlds.
You do love to do things
the hard way, don't you?
Yeah, you know me.
Come on, then. Tea break over.
I'll see you out on that track.
Yes, Coach.
Right.
Come on then, back to the shop.
No, let's do it again.
Come on. Let's do it again.
It's no use rubbing that leg.
If you're feeling tight we should
go back to that physio of yours.
- Thought it was just me and you now.
- For the training it is.
But we don't refuse help when it's there.
- I don't really wanna...
- I'm not asking, I'm telling.
Hi.
Do you have a minute?
Yeah. How can I help?
It's just my quads they're a bit tight.
- Hop on, then.
- Thanks.
Did you change your mind about the relay?
No. No, I'm back with my old coach.
Just about the 200 metres now.
All right.
- That hurts.
- I'd be worried if it didn't.
I didn't think this was part of it.
I thought you just had to
train hard and not eat crisps.
Yeah, me neither.
I only got into physio after my injury.
Before that it was all about the running.
Yeah, I'm sorry you can't do that any more.
It's all right.
- You can run for me.
- Thanks. Pressure.
Well, you seem to be able
to cope with that... well enough.
Ha-ha, very funny.
I don't miss the pressure.
I'd dream that I was running the race
the night before, every time.
I know what you mean.
In my dreams I just run faster and faster
and it all goes a bit blurry.
Why are you running?
I don't know. Maybe I'm
trying to get somewhere better.
Do you know where that is?
I thought this was a physical.
I didn't ask for therapy.
Well, that I'll give you for free.
- All done.
- Great. Thank you.
This place isn't all that bad, you know.
You just got to give some of us a chance.
What, like you, you mean?
I'm here for my rubdown...
Doctor.
But I can wait outside.
Or watch.
No, I'm joking. I'll wait.
- How long were you standing there?
- Long enough.
You ain't gonna say nothing, are you?
- No.
- Thanks.
Well, I'm fine, thanks, Shania.
Nice of you to ask.
Yeah, it has been a while, hasn't it?
But I guess we've all
been focussing on our events.
I just...
I've been a bitch, ain't I?
- More of an ostrich, actually.
- What?
Sticking your head in the sand
then running damn fast in between.
You need a break, girl.
Just don't get in that zone too early
or else you will be loco
when the race comes.
- Okay.
- Trust me.
Then what are you suggesting?
- I'll see you Friday.
- What? What d'you...
No, no. If I stick around,
you're gonna try and get out of it.
I will see you Friday. Yeah?
- Friday.
- Is that her?
- Yeah.
- You didn't say she was coming.
- Sorry, girl, my mistake.
- Hi.
You all right, babe?
So, this is a girls' night out,
I thought I'd bring some more girls.
Right. Well, we're here now.
Us mums don't get
to do this often. Come on.
Evening, ladies.
Come on.
Time to punch in!
- What?
Belle! What happened to
"a girls' night out"?
- I'll get the drinks.
- Ha-ha! She's off.
Hi.
So, are you ready for the move
to the athlete's village?
I think so. I'm really excited.
And you?
I've won every colour of medal
in this competition,
apart from gold.
Or is that even really winning though?
Or is it just not quite good enough?
Tsh! Sorry, I'm going off on one.
It's all right.
Yeah, I get it.
- I've got to own it next month.
- You will.
Come on.
- What about the drinks?
- We're athletes.
- We weren't meant to be sitting down.
- All right! All right!
No, no. This just isn't right.
Sorry?
A gorgeous girl like you all by yourself.
- Tell us your name.
- Go away.
- Just tell us your name.
- Can't you see my man's fallen in love?
- Come, let me take a picture.
- No.
Bet she's got ice in her knickers.
Don't be so disgusting.
What, you need thawing out, babe?
Belle. Come on, Belle.
Belle, come.
- We're still waiting for that name.
- Yeah, Lisa. Now can I go?
Yeah!
There's some more sisters up in here.
I know what this one wants.
Is it now? You think you're
man enough to give it to me, yeah?
I like a challenge, innit?
- You'll lose, mate.
- I don't know the meaning of that word.
Yeah, I'm sure there's loads of words
you don't know the meaning of, love.
Like "deodorant" and "toothpaste".
... just saying
Come on, Lisa, let's go.
She's fine where she is.
Don't go disrespecting me now.
Why don't all of you just piss off?
Lisa, come on, let's go.
Come here!
Lisa, you really shouldn't have done that.
Come on, let's get 'em! Come on.
My shoes!
- That was so funny!
I wish Tommy could have seen that boy!
Yeah, you did good with that drink, Lisa.
- Just getting started.
- Really?
Girls, where are we going next?
I'm not ready to go home.
Listen, there's a club down the road...
Take me, Belle. Take me.
Take me to the club!
Whoo!
Girls, look.
Okay.
Now I'm sober.
- Okay.
- It's not Long now.
Hey. Sure we can't
persuade you to do the relay?
No, thanks.
Look, I'm a lot more fun
when I'm not in the team, innit?
Yes.
- Home time, girls.
- Yeah, yeah. I'm gonna go that way.
Yeah.
- Miss, see you in a month.
- I had a wicked night.
- See you on the track.
- I'll see you on the track, yeah.
Stay focussed,
don't get distracted by the big lights,
and stick to your training programme, okay?
Come here.
Thanks, Brian, for everything.
You're gonna be a big star.
I know it. Yeah.
Well, good luck.
Thank you.
You know, I wish Mum could see you now.
Yeah, me, too.
Well, come here then.
- Love you, yeah.
- Yeah, me too.
- Well, I guess this is it then.
- Yeah.
Bring us home a medal.
- Done.
All right, see you, yeah.
Ready?
We're gonna need to
get a cabinet for all these soon.
Listen,
before we go
there's,
there's something I want you to have.
Dad, I...
Keep it with you, it's for luck.
Well, it's... It's heavy.
Yeah.
You look like you're going forever,
the amount you've packed.
- Bye, Mum.
- I'll be there to see you.
But don't put too much
pressure on yourself, okay?
Come on, Ellie,
this is what she was made for.
I'm always here for you. Regardless.
Bye.
Excitement is building for tomorrow
as visitors from all over the world
pour into the capital
for the Athletics World Championships,
here in London
Our sports editor sat down with
some of Great Britain's top athletes
ahead of the event
Golden girl' Trix Warren
is hoping that third time's a charm
I can feel it through every fibre
of my being that I'm ready
to go out there and do it.
I mean, I've worked hard for this
and I think this is the year to go in there
and some home with a gleaming medal.
And let's not forget
the new girl on the UK sprinting scene.
Shania Andrews has
made a big impact this year,
and controversially quit
the 4 X 100 metres relay team
after a disastrous performance
in Barcelona.
I just prefer running on my own.
I'm not really used to being in a team
so I think the relay was
becoming a bit of..
Whoo! whoo!
Well, this is it,
the World Athletics Championships
are here in London,
and /{'5 ma/re or break time
for all of these athletes.
There's such
an amazing vibe here in London.
It's great to see a capacity crowd.
We're coming to you live
from the heart of the capital,
and we'll keep track of
all Britain's medal hopes.
I think /{'5 gonna be an amazing week.
We've got big hopes for all our athletes.
Lisa Temple powers
her way into the 200 metre final.
A magnificent start for Temple,
who has big shoes to fill
in these World Championships.
Shania Andrews is right between
Harris of the United States
and Anderson of Jamaica.
- Set.
What a run by
- Great Britain's Shania Andrews.
- Good girl!
Her first World Championships.
Absolutely smashing
her personal best there.
Great Britain
are keeping up with the leaders
at the end of day two.
Can they edge ahead
in tonight's sprint final?
...Focus and concentration
from you, okay?
This isn't about them, this is about
everything that we've worked for.
- Yeah.
- Okay.
Don't let us down?
I'll be right back.
Smash it.
200 metres final.
Introducing the athletes
for the women's 200 metres final.
Lane one...
so here we go, the women's 200 metre final.
We've got two young Britons in there
with the world's best.
We've got Jill Anderson of Jamaica,
Femi of Nigeria,
then Temple of Great Britain.
The brilliant american, Kelly Harris,
she goes in Zane four,
Andrews in Zane five.
Then Kolachenko of the Ukraine,
and finally a French athlete, Rouberre,
out in lane seven.
All quiet, please.
On your marks.
50, ante again, the stadium goes quiet
for this final of the women's 200 metres.
Set...
Temple and Andrews
get away to a brilliant start.
They're being pressured by
Kelly Harris, United States.
Harris first
Harris takes the gold for America.
No medal for Great Britain
as Andrews finishes in fourth place,
just ahead of Temple in fifth.
They'll both be bitterly disappointed
with that
Shania Andrews, a good time.
She placed fourth in 22. 19 seconds.
I'm sorry.
Don't look weak.
It's okay!
It's okay, honey!
This is not your fault.
It's all about him.
He put far too much pressure on you.
Shania!
Wait here.
Shania, wait!
Shania, wait up!
Shania!
Both girls gave
everything. It wasn't enough.
When you're up against
sprinters like Kelly Harris,
I don't think there's much you can do.
But there's still hope
for our female sprinters.
Before we go trackside
for the 100 metres final,
let's take a quick look at what
golden girl Trix Warren
had to say about the race.
Buzzing. Ready. I can feel it
through every fibre of my being.
I'm ready to go out there and do it.
This is the moment
that everybody in the stadium,
everybody all over the country
has been waiting for.
Trix Warren goes head to head
with the world's very best sprinters.
La Toya of the United States
and Grant of Jamaica
could be her main opposition.
Can she get the medal
she's never won in the past?
And now there's a hush
around the stadium before the start.
Set...
Trix Warren falls!
Look at this!
Trix Warren has gone down.
That is terrible.
La Toya of the United States
is gonna win it.
Grant of Jamaica second Jacob in third.
What about poor old Trix Warren?
This injury that's been
blighting her for so many seasons now,
has brought to an and
her final! World Championship.
What a tragic day for this gifted sprinter.
- Lift...
Trix, believe. You're gonna be fine.
- just stay strong like you are.
- She'll be fine.
The news from the 65 team
is that Trix Warren's injury
puts her out of the games.
This injury could spell
the end of her career.
Let's hope that's not true.
I can only imagine
what she's going through...
- I'm gutted for you, man.
- Yeah.
I'm kinda gutted myself.
But it's all right.
I got family waiting for me.
I've neglected them for far too long.
- Yeah, but, Trix, I'm so...
- Don't.
Everyone is so...
So let's just not talk about it, yeah?
Sit down. I want to talk about you.
- Me?
- Yeah.
You ran a good final, Shania.
I'm serious.
You've got what it takes
to be one of the best.
You just got to start playing the game.
- What do you mean?
- Relay.
- No, I'm serious.
- Tommy needs you to take my place.
- I can't, man, that girl, seriously...
Shania, this is your chance.
Don't waste it.
All you have to do is run together
for less than a minute.
Listen, girl, if there's one person
you do not say "no" to,
it's a cripple that has just blown
her last shot at her dream.
What, you think I'm guilt tripping you?
Hell, yes, I'm guilt tripping you.
Promise me you'll go out there
and run that relay for me.
Okay?
Yeah, all right.
That's what I'm talking about.
- Silk, yeah?
- Yeah, man. Silk, whatever.
Ready?
- Bye.
- Bye. You take care.
Yeah, you, too. Look after her.
- Will do.
- See you later.
Trix, thanks, yeah?
Trix is out, yeah,
so I want back on the team.
And I won't let you down, promise.
I've just run my personal best,
so I think I should be back.
I've just been talking to Trix and
she wants me back on the team.
Okay, Shania,
you're back on the team. Go.
Yes!
Thank you, Tommy.
Are you tight here?
You ready, Belle?
You got big shoes to fill.
This is your time.
Now, I know you can do it.
So I've put you on the first leg
because I know you have that power, okay?
Yeah.
All right, here she is. Let's go.
Come on.
Okay. Listen up.
Semi-final. Let's keep it simple.
I don't want anything fancy.
And I definitely don't want anything
between you two, understand me?
Athletes to track, please.
Okay. Let's go. Go fast, go fast.
Let's do it.
- Shania...
- Just please, don't talk to me, yeah?
This is the women's 4 X 100 metres relay.
The first four places will qualify
for the quarter finals.
Here are the teams.
From Trinidad and Tobago...
Proctor, McDonald, Cameron
This is the first semi-final
of the women's 4 X 100 metre relay,
and the big news is that
Shania Andrews has come in
as a late replacement
for the injured Trix Warren.
Now that means that Belle Newman
moves up to the first leg, Sarah Playaga
then Andrews, then Temple.
And they've got to be in the first four
to make it through to the final'.
But they've got strong opposition,
as you can imagine
The Jamaicans are there, too,
Trinidad and Tobago, and France.
They're all very strong teams indeed.
On your marks.
Set...
They're off
Ana' away we go.
The Jamaicans have got off
to a tremendous start here.
Jamaica are streaking away for it.
Trinidad and Tobago are in contention,
but so are Great Britain.
Ifs all gonna depend
on this first change-over.
Hand!
Ana' ifs smooth. 11".? good.
And there go Trinidad and Tobago, too.
A way go Great Britain.
They're still the top three.
Ana' here we go,
in to the second change-over.
That's not bad, but Great Britain seem
to have slipped back to fourth place.
They'll need to make
the next change-over count.
One change-over to go.
The Jamaicans are in front.
Hand!
That looked messy for Great Britain.
Its slow. The French move ahead.
Temple trying to catch up,
but if doesn't look good.
Jamaica, Trinidad, Brazil and France.
Bad luck, GB.
The last change-over cost them dearly.
What a shame. Just one place away
from making the final.
Belle, a quick word.
That couldn't have gone more wrong.
Major disappointment.
A lot of time, effort and money...
- What the hell was that?
- You were too slow!
- That was your fault.
- Yeah, of course it was my fault,
'cause nothing touches
the golden girl, does it?
It's not my fault
your life is a screw-up!
...My goodness.
The British team's emotions
are getting the better of them here.
There's a fight on the track
between the British three and four,
Andrews and Temple.
Hardly appropriate behaviour
for professional athletes.
Flippin"...
But wait! 1"/71 hearing a report
- I will sort it out!
- There's a penalty against the French.
The French team have a lane infringement
in their final leg.
The French have been disqualified
Great Britain are through to the final.
Are you joking?
It looks like you have
a second chance. That's exciting.
Great Britain are back in it now
- She threw the first punch, Tommy.
- I know. I know, David, I saw.
Along with thousands of other people.
David's right.
She's an embarrassment to the team.
No, she's our fastest runner.
Think about how this looks.
We're on the front pages now.
Is this gonna make your CV look any better?
Sorry, what are you suggesting?
It would be a sad end
to a not exactly illustrious career.
Right. So she's off the team or I'm
finished. Is that what you're saying?
We're not saying anything. What's your
conscience telling you to do?
- Is this them or you?
- This is me. You're off the team.
He made you do it, didn't he?
There's nothing I can do.
But you can't take this away
from me, Tommy, man.
What I did was wrong before,
and I know I shouldn't have
done what I did, but I'm sorry, I...
Tommy's decision is final, I'm afraid.
We can't let what you did go unpunished.
You make us all, the whole sport, look bad.
- But I...
- Let's not make another scene, okay?
Okay.
You know what?
Lisa's lucky she's got you.
It's a lot different
from up here, isn't it?
- This seat free?
- No.
- How about this one?
- No, they're all taken.
What you saw between me and Lisa,
it was nothing.
She was upset after the race.
Her dad...
- Well, you know about her dad.
- Yeah, I do.
I do, first-hand.
What am I gonna do, Carl?
I mean, they don't want me here.
They just want me to crawl back
to wherever I come from.
A smug bastard says you're out
and you just give up.
- You're really gonna let him do that?
- I didn't give up, all right?
I was kicked out.
Pricks like that can't always
get their way.
And the Shania I know wouldn't let them.
What am I supposed to do?
He's not exactly gonna
return my calls, is he?
Nah, he wouldn't.
But I know someone who could
persuade him to change his mind.
Lisa.
Come on, we just...
we just scratched each other's eyes out
in front of millions of people.
Yeah, and you also
just qualified for the finals
with the worst relay I've ever seen.
Now imagine what would happen if you
actually ran together as a team.
You said it yourself. You always dreamt
about running to somewhere better.
Well, start there.
So go and get your arse back
on that track where it belongs.
Did you just talk about my arse?
I meant your glutes.
Yeah, it's worth a shot, innit?
Just 'cause I'm listening to you
doesn't mean I've forgiven you.
Come on.
No, you can wait.
I've got a race to run.
...Come in.
I thought you'd left.
Okay.
So, the way I see things, right,
me and you got two things in common.
Yeah. What are they?
One - we both hate each other,
and two - we're both fucking fast.
- So?
- So, I'm saying,
if we get our shit together...
no one can beat us.
I seem to remember you getting
kicked off the team.
Yeah, and we both know
who's behind that, don't we?
Look, I ain't gonna try and pry into
your family business or nothing,
'cause I know if you tried that shit
with me, I'd rip your head off.
But I'm just saying, there does come
a time in a girl's life, yeah,
where she just needs to
stand up for herself
and tell her dad to
just stick it up his arse.
Nobody talks about my dad like that.
- No, and I'm sorry...
- No, it's...
It's okay.
It's a nice change.
- Is that what you did with your dad?
- No.
My dad just left.
- Right. Sorry.
- No, that's all right.
It just means he ain't around
to boss me about like your dad.
All right then, tomorrow, show me
what you got, and we'll see.
Why don't we do it now?
Tracks are all closed.
Come on, man. Get your trainers.
I know somewhere.
- Shania...
- What?
Come on. Trust me.
Again. It's late. It's too late.
Just like the semi-finals.
Just needs marked.
And again.
Too late!
- It's never gonna happen.
- Yeah, it's all right. It don't matter.
We're gonna get this. All right?
Shania...
We can't get our marks right,
but it's irrelevant anyway
'cause you're faster than me.
So let's swap it around.
What?
Fastest runs anchor, right?
All right.
Sure?
Yeah.
Hand.
Whoo! jeez!
Hand!
Boom!
Are you sure you're all right with this?
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
Hand!
- That was it! That was the one.
- That was the one.
We've got it.
- Yes!
- Finally.
- Go for gold.
- Gold 2011.
...Excuse me. Dad?
Hello.
Can I just talk to you a sec?
It's last chance today. You ready?
I've looked at the American stats and...
- Dad.
- Yeah, what?
I want Shania back on the team.
Yeah,
Come over here.
Is this nerves?
No, it's not. We practiced last night
and we're really good.
Don't be ridiculous, Lisa. She's banned.
Yes, I know.
But she's the fastest. We need her.
No, you're faster than her.
No. I'm not.
She's a liability. She's out of control.
- You got Tommy to take her off the team.
- You're better off without her.
So I'm asking you to put her back on.
Darling, I'm just trying to do
what's best for you.
Yeah, then put her on the team.
This is our last chance at a medal.
My last chance.
Excuse me?
It's mine, not yours.
Well, if you'd run
a better race in the 200,
it wouldn't be your last chance, would it?
What? That's the reality. You lost.
So now we can't have
any more distractions or fights.
Okay, this is yours.
I have spent my whole life
trying to please you.
This is my time now.
Dad, either you bring Shania back
or I quit.
- What?
- No, I mean it.
I don't care what you think of me any more.
Win or lose, I am running this race
on my own terms, not yours.
So, how did it go?
I can't breathe.
...What? What!
Lisa, what did you say, man?
Once again, we have a capacity crowd
here at the World Championships
for what promises to be a fantastic
final for the women's 4 X 100 metres...
- Get me another beer, please, babe.
- I'm watching this.
- Go get me another drink, man
- The British team facing stiff
competition on the track.
Can they put their differences aside
and bring home a medal?
We're gonna watch four
British women bid for world glory.
They've had such turmoil
during the championship so far.
Can they deliver today?
Its been a dramatic road
to this final for the British team.
Fifth in the semi-finals,
until the French were disqualified
One more shot, okay?
Yeah, we can do this.
- Hell, yeah, girl.
- Fists in.
Okay. Well, you know...
I did have a big speech prepared
which you've now ruined.
- Had it written on cards and everything.
- Aww!
Okay, okay. You know what?
Just go do it.
- Boom.
- GB, come on.
Come on, don't screw it up.
Oi. What's up?
I've never passed the baton in a race
before. I've always run anchor.
Do you wanna switch?
No. I'll be fine.
- Are you sure?
- Yeah. We're good.
...welcome out the teams
for the women's 4 X 100 metres relay.
Ukraine, Nigeria...
.. Great Britain, USA...
Great Britain start right next to
the favourites, the United States.
And of course,
we've got the Ukraine in there,
we've got the Jamaicans.
We've got the world's
very best relay teams.
What's she doing on the third leg?
She's the anchor.
David, sit down.
On your marks.
Set...
Well, that's a great start
by Great Britain.
Newman is absolutely powering
around that top bend.
Hand!
Superb performance by the British.
Going into the back straight.
This is the long leg.
What a difference a day makes here
for Great Britain
They're absolutely flying
around the top bend.
A great run from Lisa Temple.
Coming towards the last change-over now
Hand!
- Come on, Shania!
- Run, sis!
Heading towards
the line. Andrews gaining!
Ifs gonna be dose!
And it looks like a photo finish!
So, so close.
I'm not quite sure who won that -
the USA, Jamaica, or Great Britain.
What a fabulous, fabulous final.
It couldn't be closer.
- What happened? Did they win?
- The stadium is holding its breath
waiting for the final result.
Ifs Great Britain!
Whoo!
- Yes!
What a comeback
Have you ever seen
anything like that before?
The closest final in years.
Out of chaos they have pulled off
something spectacular.
Its gold for Great Britain.
Darling!
- Dad!
'Darling!
Mum!
I love you!
- Come here!
- I told you you could do it!
Lisa, Lisa, Lisa, come on, talk to me.
World Champion...
- It's amaz...
- Ah!
My God! We did it together.
- We did it!
- We did it.
...Hi, Mum.
Whoo!
Ah!
Boom!
- We love you, Tommy!
- I love you, too!
Go, go, go! Well done!
It feels great.
Today they listened to me.
Swish! Boom! What a great run!
- Linford, get out of there!