- Gymnastics.
- Keep up the good work.
- Sue Allen Baines.
- We're all very, very proud.
- And Nancy Wilson.
In Track and Field --
- I hope you do
as well in the Nationals.
- Joe Ward.
In Gymnastics, Frank Agee.
- All the hard work
has paid off now, Frank.
- Track and Field, Phillip Dandridge.
- I'm very impressed
with your time.
- Swimming,
Lynn Fox.
- You had it
all going for you today.
- And in gymnastics,
- Excellent.
- Annie Rivers.
- Your dad is gonna be very proud of you.
- The Falcon Academy of Athletics
is proud of these young athletes
who will represent us at
the Nationals competitions.
- Excuse me.
We have a little problem.
- What's that?
- They forgot to pack the napkins.
- Damn people.
- It doesn't look like
you need 'em anyway.
- What, do you want
'em to wipe their hands
on the tablecloth?
- Well, I can go to the bathroom
and get some toilet paper.
- Well, do something.
- No napkins?
- Yes.
- No problem,
I'll be right back.
- Thank you.
- Let's sit down, everybody.
- Take this end right here.
Everybody, just grab a piece right here.
There you go.
Take one, Joe.
Smiling.
- What is it, plastic?
- Move your hands.
This should just about do it.
- Ladies and gentlemen, may I
have your attention, please?
Before introducing Mr.
Sam Burger from Tiger,
I would like to take this
opportunity to thank him publicly
for the continued support of our school,
and his invaluable
advice and financial aid.
Now, may I introduce Mr.
Sam Burger, my friend.
- Thank you.
Thank you.
I'm proud to be here again this year.
As a representative of Tiger, I'm honored
to support the great
work that you're doing,
both with your school and for our country.
I have always believed in
supporting the aspirations
of this country's great athletes.
In a democracy like ours,
we know that financial
support for athletics
must come from private institutions,
not government subsidies, like
that of totalitarian regimes.
But most of all, we seek to foster
the camaraderie and brotherhood
that athletics produce
among young men and women.
Athletics is universal.
It goes beyond politics,
race and national boundaries.
It celebrates the brotherhood of man,
the unity of purpose to
strive to the utmost,
to achieve the absolute
potential for development.
As superior human beings...
- Are you sure you haven't
seen my gym shorts and t-shirt?
- Yeah, I'm sure.
- You know what?
- What?
- You forgot to say
goodnight to me last night.
- Is that so?
- Yeah, that's so.
- Well, I must've been tired.
- How can I lose something
in a place this small?
- You know what else you forgot?
- What?
- To say you love me.
- Well, I'll make sure
not to forget tonight.
I know they're in here because
I saw 'em here last night.
- Maybe you're wearing it.
- Sure I am.
- Did you look in the
refrigerator under the cheese?
- That's not --
Give me my things, come on!
- No.
- No, give me my things.
- How could you forget
to say goodnight to me?
- Give me my shorts.
- Nevermind.
- The one I'm after is this.
Look what I got here, huh?
- No.
Now stop it.
- Come here.
- What?
- You say goodnight and I love you.
- Goodnight and I love you.
- How'd it go yesterday?
- It went pretty rough.
Drew's still on my case.
- Why?
You won, didn't you?
- Exactly.
But you know how thick she and Shelly are.
Besides, that's not
what really worries me.
- What?
- It's what's her name down in Florida.
You know she's a full
second fitter than I am.
She's the one I have to
beat to win the Nationals.
- Don't worry about it, babe.
You'll do it.
Now, have Diane give you that
new stuff they've gotten now.
It's helped me out a lot.
- Frank, you know my worries
about all this medication
they've been giving us.
You know, it really could be dangerous.
- Babe, everybody's doing it.
You don't see 'em dropping
dead, do you? Hmm?
- These competitions
are an ongoing process.
To qualify for the Olympics,
you're gonna have to win them all.
Now, you've worked hard, but
you've gotta work harder.
In the Nationals, winners
from all over the country
are gonna be competing against you.
That means you have to work twice as hard.
I'm gonna let you in on my
special secret for success.
Starting today, I'm gonna
add an additional two hours
to your work schedules.
- Oh, come on.
- Let's go to work.
- Some secret to success.
He never made it to the Olympics.
- That's good, Lynn. 53:37.
Take three seconds off that,
you'll break the world's record.
Okay, come on, outta the pool.
Let's practice some dives.
Okay.
Grab the side of the pool, Shelly.
Julie, I want you to set this one out.
Just watch Shelly and Lynn.
You girls ready?
Get set.
Go.
All right, come on, come
on. Let's do it again.
Come on up, let's do it again.
We're training for the Olympics.
Come on, this is no joke.
Gotta get your acts together, you girls.
All right, grip the edge of the pool,
a little more with your toes.
Good, keep your feet shoulder width apart.
Lynn, come on, hit the water flatter.
Keep your head down,
straighter line with your body.
All right? Come on, grab
the side of the pool.
Now, let's concentrate you guys.
Ready?
Set.
Go.
- Let me have your chart, please.
No, very good.
Your pulse rate is 55.
That's excellent.
Sit down.
Look, I'm quite pleased.
I think the steroids that
I had Diane put you on
are paying off.
- I feel great.
- Ah, good, good.
Well, your heart, your vital
organs are very strong.
- Okay.
- Keep up
the good work, Frank.
- Thanks.
- Joe, last Saturday, you
missed your morning examination.
- Yeah, I had something important to do.
- Listen to me, okay? Continuity
Is a very important part
of this whole program,
so don't do it again.
- Okay.
- All right.
Diane, has he had his morning vitamins?
- Yes, Doctor.
- All right, just start
him on the new shots.
- Damn it, Joe. Forget the
accuracy, gimme the muscle.
Here, do it again.
What are you, a ballet dancer?
Keep that up, I'm gonna
have to get you a tutu.
Now, come on, put every
ounce of strength behind it.
See if we can do better this time.
- Not bad, huh, Coach?
- It's gotta be a hell of
a lot better than that.
- What the hell do you want?
That was a damn good throw.
If you think I'm shit, why
don't you just tell me?
- I'll tell you what I think, Joe.
I think you're damn good.
But don't let it go to your head.
- All right, just don't mess
around with the kid, okay?
- Wow.
- Whoa.
- Hey.
You guys seen Sue Allen today?
She's hot.
- Yeah, I saw her out there.
- Say, I had it all working,
I've got to admit it.
- It's a good thing you can't swim,
or I'd be in a lot of trouble.
- Hey, congratulations, that
was really good work today.
- Thanks.
- Hi.
- Hey.
- How's it going?
- It's going terrific.
- What are you gonna do tonight?
- Well, I'm gonna go
back and visit the gym
and work out for a while.
- Work out?
You just qualified for the Nationals.
- Qualified.
Winning there is gonna be
a hell of a lot tougher
and nothing's gonna stop me.
- Well, we're all going out to celebrate.
- Hey, have a good time. Really.
Have one on me.
- See ya.
- Hey, it's great Lynn and Annie
are going to the Nationals with us.
- Together, we'll go to the Olympics.
- You think so?
- Well, I know I'm going.
I'd like you to be there.
- Hey, I'm making the trip.
Hey, Joe, think you'll
make it to the Olympics?
Wanna see my gold medal?
- Yeah.
- Hey Joe. Listen, we're
gonna go out to the restaurant
and have a couple beers,
you wanna join us, huh?
- No, thanks.
- Hey.
- Hey, hey.
- Oh, where's Nancy?
- Oh, she stayed to work out
with the weights for a while.
- Oh, boy, I'd like to lift
a couple of her weights.
- There's enough dumbbells
up there without you.
- Come on, let's go.
- Let's get outta here.
- Hey, wouldn't it be great
if the seven of us made
the Olympics together?
- Yeah, and I'll make sure
you stay away from Nancy
and her weights.
- Hey, I was just kidding about Nancy.
- Oh, aren't you gonna
open the door for me?
That's real sweet.
Nevermind now.
- You seen Nancy?
Can't you stop bobbing up and down
and listen to me for a second?
- No, I haven't seen Nancy.
How'd you like to come
over to my house tonight,
bob up and down on my bed?
- Don't you wish?
- Yes, I do.
- See you later.
- If you luck out.
- I really don't know
what you see in Phil.
You know, he's really an airhead.
- Oh, I'll bring him down to earth.
Well, I gotta go, I'm late for my checkup.
I'll see you later, Poopy.
- All right, see you later kid.
- What are you talking about?
- I think we've gotta go back
to the previous dosage level,
we've gotta go a little bit slower.
- We can't let these
incidents stop our work.
What we're doing is too important.
Sure, there are risks involved,
but need I remind you
that what we are trying to do
is to maximize to the utmost
the athletic potential of the human body.
- Dr. Jordine, they are
kids, they are kids!
They are not Guinea pigs.
- But the East Germans and the Russians
are doing the same thing.
It's only in this country
that we've neglected
the scientific possibilities
of the human body.
And they're winning all the gold medals.
- I think you're being very unreasonable.
- Diane, this is my life's work
and I will let no one stop me.
- Well, I hope you're gonna
take full responsibility,
because I'm not gonna
take responsibility.
- I already have.
Now, you can go back to work.
- Okay, you're the boss.
- So Joe, I heard you tried to
lay Nancy again last night, huh?
- Beat it.
- You watch with that thing, man.
Those things are dangerous.
- Does anybody know where Nancy is?
- No.
- Uh-uh.
- You know, Annie, Dr. Jordine
thinks very highly of you
and he has instructed me to start you
on retardation injections.
He's afraid that your bust line
has being developing too rapidly.
- You've gotta be kidding.
- Doctor's orders.
- What kind of stuff is it?
- Hormones.
- Isn't that pretty radical?
- No, not really.
These Europeans have
been doing it for years.
- Oh, that's it right there.
- Right, you have a
bit of a muscle strain here.
- Oh, that feels so good.
- Now, just relax, okay?
- Oh, it'll be a pleasure.
- Good.
- I'm glad you're one
of the seven winners.
I knew you had it in you.
- Diane, I think I better go.
- Huh, sure.
- Good girls.
Okay, let's call it a day.
All right?
- I'm headed straight for the sauna.
You coming along, Shelly?
- No, I don't wanna.
- See you later, Shelly.
- Bye.
- Guys take care.
- I feel great.
- I wish I did.
- My turns really suck today.
I think I'm having a problem
with my depth perception.
- Don't worry.
You got another two months to work on it.
And lemme tell you,
this is the first time in my life
I feel I have my act together.
- Oh, are you going to
Annie's surprise party?
- I forgot all about it.
I'm going to San Francisco.
- Sue!
- But I have to go up to
my boyfriend's graduation.
We also planned a little party of our own.
- Oh.
- Please explain to Annie.
- Well, we'll miss you.
See you later.
You have a good time, okay?
- Thanks.
See you.
- Bye-bye.
- I just don't understand this.
The whole day's gone by.
Hasn't anybody heard from Nancy Wilson?
- No, not a thing.
- Call her parents' phone.
- Okay.
- I don't like this.
- Weren't you supposed to
drive her home last night, Belinda?
- No, I wasn't.
But how about you, Jack?
Weren't you taking her home?
- No, I did not.
- Come on, guys.
Let's cut it out, huh?
It's a little too late for that.
Goodnight.
- Goodnight.
- Aren't you gonna turn the car off?
- If turn it off, it's
not gonna start up again.
- It's so loud.
Gotta get a new muffler.
- Hey.
- Don't tell me you guys
came back to work out again.
That's what I call masochism.
- No, no, Annie forgot her textbooks.
- God, you're studying again tonight?
- Mm-hmm.
- Don't you ever get tired?
- If I don't hit the
books, my ass is grass.
- Your parents are giving you a hard time?
- You must say something.
- That's what's I'm talking about.
- I'll tell you, her dad's
been giving me a bunch of --
bunch of hassle.
- Been acting like what?
- Didn't approve of the
relationship, or something?
- Doesn't approve of, huh.
- They've locked the doors already.
I've gotta get my books.
- Okay, let's try the windows.
Weren't you supposed to
pick up Nancy this morning?
- Yeah, but she never showed up.
- Oh, Coach Webber
should know where she is.
He keeps all the schedules.
- I asked him, but he said
he didn't know anything.
- That's strange.
- Hey, aren't you coming in with me?
- Ballgame's on the radio.
I'll be in the car.
- Of course
I'll call you, Sergeant,
if we hear anything from her.
Yes, goodbye.
- Thank you very much, Doctor.
- What about this missing
girl, Nancy Wilson?
- Parents called me again.
This time, they filed a
missing persons report
with the police.
- By the way, Sue Allen didn't show up
for practice this morning either.
- What is this, a prank?
- Oh, well, don't worry about Sue Allen,
one of the kids told me
she went to San Francisco
for a boyfriend's graduation.
- We can't have these kids
going off anytime they want to.
Now, it's up to all of you to make sure
that this doesn't happen again.
- Well, here are the files.
- Okay, Annie, but
concentrate on your dismount.
- I will.
Can I speak to your moment, Coach?
- Sure what is it?
- It's my folks.
My grades have gone down around school
and my dad wants to pull me outta here.
- You want me to speak to him?
- Would you please?
- Sure, tell him to come
any time after practice.
- Thanks a lot, Coach.
Oh, by the way, have you
seen Nancy Wilson today?
- No, I haven't.
- Okay, Phil, there you go.
- Good job.
- Good luck.
- Will the
runners for the next event
take their designated lanes, please?
Runners, on your marks.
Get set.
- You can do it, you can do it.
Phil, Phil, you did it!
I'm so proud of you.
- I did it, I did it!
I'm going to the Nationals!
- Let's not keep Coach Webber waiting.
I'm sure he'd probably like to go home.
- Daddy, please try to understand.
- I understand all right.
I understand your grades
have fallen terribly
since I let you join this academy.
- But I can do both.
- You said that last
semester and you didn't.
- I will from now on,
I promise. You'll see.
- You can't take that chance.
We're talking about your future.
- And what about my future as a gymnast?
- How long will that last?
Til you're 25, maybe?
And then what'll you do?
What do all these athletes do?
- Daddy, I don't know about the future,
but I know I'm a good
gymnast. A damn good one.
And if I've got this talent,
I should be allowed to
make the most of it.
Don't take that away from me.
Don't make me give it up.
I have to do it, Daddy.
- This new schedule is really grueling.
- What's the matter, is it
cutting into your TV time?
- I don't have TV time.
I don't even have much
time for Phil anymore.
- What's going on now
with you and your parents?
- My dad and I sort of
reached an agreement.
- That you get straight A's
and break three world records, right?
- Yeah, something like that.
- Well, all my parents care
about is that when I dive in,
I don't do a belly flop.
- Lynn!
Lynn, I've been waiting
for you in the car.
Let's go.
God, why do you stay so late?
- How did you get in?
I locked all those doors.
- The door was open.
Let's go.
- But I locked those doors.
Anyway, I don't wanna leave.
I have to compete tomorrow and
I wanna practice some more.
- This ain't too bad for the 400.
- I was doing the hundred, you jerk.
- Oh, oh.
Hey, listen, even if
you don't win a medal,
I'll still love you.
And I'll even let you
hold on to mine, okay?
- Oh, are you talking about
your consolation prize,
or your pecker?
- Okay, okay, I'll race you. One lap.
- Okay, you're on.
- Let's go.
- Come on.
I'm up.
The winner and new world champion.
Thank you, I love you all.
Thank you.
- That's not fair.
You distracted me and you
weren't wearing your suit.
- Wanna do something about it?
- Yeah.
- Come on!
Try that again, one more time.
One more time.
I'm sorry about that.
- Swimmers up.
On your marks.
- You won, you won!
All right.
- I won.
To the Nationals!
- Where have you been for the last hour?
- I've been out jogging.
- I wish you'd spend as much time with me
as you do with your jogging.
- Shelly.
Come on, what do you want me to say?
- You're supposed to be
one of the best swimming
coaches in the country
and I still didn't win.
Why the hell didn't I?
- I wanted you to win as
badly as you did, sweetheart.
I swear to you.
You still have enough time.
You still have a chance.
- Yeah, if Lynn drops dead.
- Oh, Shelly.
- This was for the Nationals, remember?
And you were supposed to get me in them.
- Shelly, I'm so sorry, darling.
Don't worry.
You're just gonna have to trust me now.
I'll figure something out.
Something will happen, you'll see.
Things...they just didn't
turn out the way I intended.
- Frank, Frank.
- What's the matter, Phil?
- Sue Allen's parents
called my folks last night.
They got the police out looking for her.
And the coaches know all about it.
They haven't said a word to us.
You find that a little strange?
- Why would the coaches keep it a secret?
- That's what's got me worried.
- First Nancy Wilson, then Sue
Allen Baines, now Joe Ward.
This morning, the police came
and I couldn't tell them a thing.
Now, what the hell's going on here?
- Well, I spoke to Sue Allen's
boyfriend in San Francisco.
She never showed up for his graduation
as she was supposed to.
And Joe Ward seems to have
disappeared without a trace.
Frankly, I'm baffled.
- It's unbelievable.
Three of our seven medal
winners have completely vanished
and we don't have the
faintest idea where they are.
- Well, I think this happened
once before in the Olympics.
- Maybe they had an adverse reaction
to some of the medication?
- Nonsense.
I mean, you as the coaching staff
have the responsibility
of watching these kids
and frankly, I'm not gonna mince words,
y
if you can't do it,
look for work elsewhere.
- Ride it up higher.
Don't straddle to soon.
- I can't straddle any later than that.
- You gotta try it.
You gotta be freer, too.
Now, practice your dismount.
You do your dismount, do
it at least 25 times a day.
- Then can I call it quits?
- Yeah, after the 25.
- Cops keep harassing me,
as if I had something to do
with making these kids take off.
Hell, as far as I'm concerned,
they can all disappear.
Bartender, another beer.
Jesus, Diane. Ten years ago,
I could drink a whole case
of this and not be phased.
Now, a couple of bottles and I'm bombed.
- None of us are getting any younger.
- Yeah.
Here's to sawdust in your eye.
I know you've had your
share of troubles, too.
Back in '64, do you know how close I came
to going to the Olympics?
This close.
Damn it.
On my last throw, I just missed it.
- I know, I know Jack.
But you're a great coach now.
Sometimes, helping other
people brings its own rewards.
- Rewards?
Shit.
Diane, in sports, winning is
the only thing that matters.
These damn kids don't
train the way we used to.
Busted our asses, we did, every
minute of every goddamn day.
No drugs to help us either.
"Oh, Coach Webber, I
don't feel well today."
Makes me sick.
- Why, Jack? Are you envious?
- No, of course not.
- So why don't we go to my place tonight
so we can finally make it?
- Make it?
Are you out of your gourd?
- Well, why don't you come over
SO we can at least make out a little?
- What is it, is there a full
moon tonight or something?
- Okay, you don't like
the idea of my place?
We'll go to a motel and see what's on TV.
- The only thing on tonight, Phil, is you.
- Can we at least go out and get a burger?
- Why didn't you say
that in the first place?
- Phil, how could you?
- I got you.
- Happy birthday.
- A toast.
- Dear Annie, as a birthday present,
Coach Webber has asked me to tell you
that he's extending your daily
workouts to 24 hours a day.
We're not gonna let him
get away with that, are we?
- No.
- We're not.
- So,
what are we gonna do?
- We're gonna get drunk.
- What are we gonna do?
- We're gonna get stoned.
- We're gonna get laid.
- Oh.
- You guys have a good time?
- Yeah.
- Hey.
- Thank you.
- Bye.
- Oh, thanks.
- Goodnight.
Bye, guys.
- Oh, say, Annie, are you
going over to Phil's tonight
to do some acrobatics on his uneven bar?
- Frank,
you're gross.
- Frank.
- Damn it.
- What is it?
- I forgot your birthday present.
- Where'd you forget it?
- It's at my place.
Left it on the bureau.
- Oh, really?
- Yeah.
- Why don't we go there?
- You want to go to my place?
- Yeah.
Let's go to your place.
- We're going to my place?
Oh, yes, we are going to my place.
- Put me down, you pinhead.
Sorry, it's her birthday
and we're going to my place, you know?
- Haven't you had enough?
- Uh-uh.
- How many is that?
- 97, 98, 99.
A hundred.
- Why don't you move in with me?
- Phil, you're out of your mind.
My dad would kill us.
You don't know him.
- That's just an excuse, you know it.
You don't wanna move in with me, do you?
- Phil, stop it.
- What?
- I just don't wanna
make my parents unhappy.
That's number one.
And number two, we've
talked about this before.
- Yeah, sort of.
- I thought we agreed that
we wouldn't move in together
until we got married.
- You agreed, I didn't.
- I think it's time for
me to go home, pinhead.
- Hey, hey.
Why don't we compromise, okay?
Why don't you spend tonight here, okay?
- I'll think about it.
How about another glass of wine, huh?
- Glass?
Gotta bring the battle.
Right back.
- Okay, look, I'll do the dishes.
You've gotta get some of this trash out.
- Trash? Okay, don't worry about it.
Trash is out, don't worry.
The trash is history.
- Oh, excuse me.
- Get all the trash out,
didn't you want that?
- Great, this is fun.
What are you doing?
- But dad,
dad I --
- Fine.
Right.
Yeah.
Whatever you say.
Right.
Talk to you Thursday.
- Hi.
- What's the matter?
- Well, I've got good news
and I've got bad news,
and bad news, and bad news.
- Well, forget the bad news
and tell me the good news.
- Good news is I still love you.
- Oh, shit, what's the bad news?
- Bad news is I got accepted
for the tryouts this summer.
- That's the bad news?
- In Pittsburgh, at the
Pirates Summer Camp.
- You've got to be joking.
- I'm not.
- That's baseball and you're a runner.
- I know that.
But my dad's always wanted me
to have a career in baseball.
And so he's talked to this
scout who works for the Pirates,
and arranged for a tryout.
- I thought we were spending
the summer together, Phil.
- I know.
But if I refuse my dad, he'll
never speak to me again.
He's gone out on a limb
to get me this tryout
and I can't just say screw you.
- But Phil, our plans together!
- Annie, try to understand.
- Okay, nevermind.
If that's all our plans meant to you,
I've got some practicing to do anyway.
- Am I gonna see you later tonight?
Fine, forget it.
- Diane, are you ready?
- I'll just be a moment,
I just came to pick up some
schedules for tomorrow.
What was that?!
Jack, pick her up.
- We should go to a hospital.
- No, it won't be necessary.
I think I know what's wrong.
Besides, we don't want any
other doctors nosing around.
Get me a glass of water, please.
Annie, you're gonna be all right.
Did Jordine give you that
new medication today?
- Yes.
- Here, drink this.
Come on.
She'll be fine in a couple of hours.
I'll take her to my place,
she'll be more comfortable.
Keep an eye on her.
Put your arm over my shoulder, come on.
Jack, help me.
- Can I please lie down?
- Sure, sure, sure you can lie down.
Just to the couch.
Take off your things while
I fetch you a comforter
and a pillow.
Relax, you're gonna be okay.
You know, sometimes,
these drugs, they backfire
and you get spasms.
It just goes right through your body
and it doesn't leave a trace.
And it's all gonna be
over with, you'll see.
I'll get you some tea.
Take off your things.
- Hello.
- Dr. Jordine, I'm so
sorry to bother you so late.
Listen, Annie's had a serious attack.
- Are you at the gym?
- No, no we're at my house.
- Does anyone else know about it?
- No, only Jack Webber.
- Why the hell did you tell him?
- I didn't.
He was there when it happened.
- You'll be certain no
one else hears about it.
- Of course, I'll be quiet.
- We'll go over her
records in the morning.
Goodnight.
- Thanks, Diane.
- Just rest, best rest.
- Those photos look so old.
- They are old.
1936 Olympics.
- Really?
- That's my mother.
She won a gold medal.
- Is she dead?
- No, she's not dead.
She's definitely not dead.
My mother...my mother's a
very vibrant lady, Annie.
My mother was famous,
people respected my mother.
You should hope that you
could be as dedicated,
as committed as she was.
I've been trying to be as
good as my mother all my life.
- Sometimes, I wonder
if it's all worth it.
I mean, the constant workouts,
the stress and the pain.
- Everybody's gotta decide
that for themselves, Annie.
- I don't mean I'm gonna quit.
This is my last chance.
Pretty soon, I'll be too old to compete.
You've gotta help me, Diane.
You've gotta help me, please.
- Okay.
Okay, Annie, I'll help you.
Now, just relax, okay? Just rest.
It's all gonna be okay.
- Hi.
I just heard about last night.
Are you okay?
- I'm much better now, thanks.
- Listen, I was a stupid jerk.
I don't know what got into me.
I guess I never really thought it through.
I just wanna make my dad happy.
But you mean more to me
than anybody, or anything.
And you're right,
I'm a runner, not a baseball player.
What do you say, can you forgive me?
- Well, I've got good news
and I've got bad news.
The good news is that I do forgive you.
And the bad news is I might
not let you forget it.
- I'll see you tonight?
- How about tomorrow?
- Okay.
- All right, Frank, this
half of your routine,
hold your moves. That's
what makes them world class.
Give it everything you've
got, you can do it.
That's it.
That's better.
Watch your form.
Push, push, control, control, steady.
Get those legs together.
That's it, go for it.
All right, all right,
dismount. Gimme the dismount.
- Oh, God!
- Frank, are you all right?
- Oh my God, Frank's hurt.
- Don't move, Frank, don't move.
Get Dr. Jordine, or Diane,
and get a stretcher.
- Just relax.
Just try to relax, Frank.
- Oh, shit, it's broken.
- I'm not sure yet.
You're gonna have to have an x-ray.
Jack, help me, please.
I'll call an ambulance.
Take him out on the gurney.
- Okay, guys, give me a hand.
Watch it, easy, easy.
Watch his leg.
- No.
- Easy.
- Frank, are you okay?
- Yeah, Lynn, I'm okay.
- Are you sure?
- I'm okay!
- Listen, Frank, it's just as
bad for us as it is for you.
- Has anybody ever won
with a cast on, Coach?
- Just wait here for the ambulance, Frank.
- Does it hurt a lot?
- Hurt?
I'll tell you what hurts.
I'm out of the Nationals,
that's what hurts.
Don't think about that now.
Okay, I'm gonna go get dressed,
I'm gonna come with you to the hospital.
- No, I want you to stay here.
Don't go, all right?
I want you to keep
working hard, don't stop.
Because you're gonna win for both of us.
All right?
- But what I really want is
for you to be the champion.
- Come on, babe, what you talking about?
You're gonna have to be the champ now.
- Ah, come on, Frank,
something's definitely wrong.
Wait a minute, I'll help you out.
- What are you talking about?
- I'm talking about Joe Ward.
Nobody's seen him for two days.
- Well, let me tell you something,
Joe Ward is weird.
That doesn't mean anything.
- Yeah, well, what about Nancy Wilson?
Is she weird, too?
And Sue Allen?
She hasn't been heard from for four days.
And the strangest part is
nobody's willing to talk about it.
- Oh, come on.
Now, there's got to be
a rational explanation.
- Well, what do you think?
The winners are quitting?
- I think something terrible
Is happening here at the academy.
- Like what?
- You want my theory?
I think they're dead.
- Oh, David, lighten up.
- Go on, go on, go on, come on.
Don't break your knees.
Go back.
- Hey.
- How you doing?
- Not bad, man.
- You ready for Saturday?
- Yeah.
- How we gonna do, you think?
- Not bad.
Keep going.
- Hi, Frank.
- Hi, Annie. How you doing?
- Fine.
How you feeling?
- Not too bad.
I should be outta this
thing in about six weeks.
- Six weeks?
Bum wrap.
- Yeah, should be okay.
Hey, listen, coach, I'm ready
to start training again.
- Why don't you take just a
couple of more hours rest,
then you can go back to work, Frank.
Okay, kid.
- Listen, you guys seen Lynn?
- She hasn't come in
to work out yet today.
- I haven't seen her all day, either.
- That's weird.
You know, I got home
from the hospital today
and she wasn't at home,
and I figured she would've
been here a long time ago.
- She's probably in
the girl's locker room.
- Yeah.
Okay, listen, I'll see
you guys later, okay?
- Yeah.
- Okay, see you later, Frank.
- Should we carry the paint up now?
- Nah, we gotta scrape the ceiling first.
- Diane.
Diane.
- Hello, Frank.
- Is Lynn in there?
- No, she's not.
- Are you sure?
- We haven't seen her yet today.
- Where the hell could she be?
- Oh, I don't know.
I have to go.
Will you excuse me?
- Coach Drew, you seen Lynn?
- No, I haven't, Frank.
- Where'd you get this?
- Belinda gave it to me.
- This is Lynn's watch.
- Yeah, well, I found it
over there on the ground,
so I suggested that Shelly
use it just for a few minutes.
- Yeah, okay, okay.
If you see Lynn, you tell
her I have her watch. Okay?
- Gosh, I wasn't gonna break it.
- What's wrong with him?
- Drew, where's Lynn Fox?
- How did you know?
I was just coming in here to tell you
that she didn't show up
for practice this morning.
- So this is how I knew.
Somebody came in here and did this.
Only the four of us have
keys to this office.
- Hello.
- Phil, Phil, it's Frank.
- Frank.
Where the hell have you been?
- I've been looking for Lynn.
I'm going crazy.
Her parents are worried sick.
They haven't heard from
her since yesterday.
- What?
- Something's happened to her,
I need your help to get into the gym.
- What do you think
you're gonna find there?
- I don't know.
But let's look around.
There's gotta be a
reason why Joe, Sue Allen
and Nancy all disappeared.
- Well, their stuff should still
be in their lockers, right?
I guess we could have a look.
- Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah,
that's at least a start.
Meet me in front of the gym in 15 minutes.
- Okay.
- All right, bye.
- Hello.
- Howdy, it's me.
Listen, Frank just called,
he's convinced something's
happened to Lynn.
He wants to go down and
look through her lockers.
I have to meet him in
about 20 minutes, okay?
- I'll meet you there.
- Right, okay.
I'm leaving now.
I love you.
Bye.
- Oh!
- Frank?
Frank?
- Annie!
- Oh, he tried to kill me!
- Who tried to kill you? Who?
- He's crazy, he killed Frank.
Help me, help me.
Help me.
- Don't worry honey, I saw the
light on in Diane's office.
Diane.
Diane, are you back there?
- Yes, what's the matter?
- Annie's been hurt.
- Put her on the table.
I'll be out in a second,
I'm just getting dressed.
- You gotta hurry, Diane.
She's bleeding awful bad.
- Go and call Coach Webber, Phil.
I'm calling an ambulance right now.
- Okay.
- Phil, don't leave me.
- No, don't worry, don't worry.
- I'm scared.
- You're here with Diane.
You'll be okay, okay?
You're gonna be all right.
- Don't worry Annie, I'll
fix you up in a minute.
You're gonna be fine.
It's just a flesh wound,
but I gotta stop the bleeding, all right?
Don't worry, just hold this here.
I know you must be in a lot of pain,
but I'm going to fetch you something
to put you out your pain.
Hang in there.
Few more seconds honey, it'll all be over.
Annie, I know you're
in here! Where are you?
I am going to have to disqualify you now.
I don't like to have to disqualify you,
but that's what I'm going to have to do.
No!
I can't stop him.
I cannot stop him, Annie.
He must disqualify anyone
who might ever make it.
Too bad, hold me back.
Don't you understand?
I had sacrificed everything.
I have risked everything just to win.
I even became a woman just to win.
Annie, I'm not going to stop now.
I am going to win.
I am not going to stop now, Annie.
Annie.
- Help.