"Reason"
"Chapter 1"
"Gold means nothing,
and so do slivery"
"None of them means anything
after one's death"
- Husband, can you answer it?
- Sure.
Hey boy, no cheating.
It is better to come with me.
What?
A letter for you.
Okay, let me get a pen.
Anybody? No signature needed?
Anybody?
Invitation?
"From now on, you will be in
good fortune for 3 days."
"Afterwards, you will die."
Is it kidding? Nonsense.
Who is it?
Wrongly sent letter
You should prepare the table now,
we can have meals shortly.
Okay, then.
Hey son, let's do it.
Put back to
the management office later.
Wait, please wait!
Why can't you wait a bitt?
Exercise is good for health.
I am arriving.
Hey guy, what happened?
Lift number 3 got problem,
I am going to call the service.
It is lucky that I missed the lift,
or I must be late to office.
I go to work now.
Where are the people?
Wife, what happened?
Husband,
somebody were trapped in the lift.
I know that, I am fine.
I go down by stairs.
Hey, you are smart.
Sure, otherwise
I would be late to office.
It is no big deal
if you are just late for work.
So, what is the point?
The trapped people were saved,
but I found that
they were seriously hurt.
How come of it?
They said that not only
did the lift out of order,
but also the circulation system.
The trapped people could
only be saved after a half hour.
How could it take so long?
It is.
How are those victims?
They looked like dead people.
You scared me.
Miss Yu wants to see you.
Very bad situation.
When did you be here?
Why don't you turn on the light?
I have to hang up, bye.
- Chiu.
- Yes?
Are you here for almost 10 years?
Should be 12 years.
Well, you are
a well experienced staff then.
Yes.
However, the result of your team
is quite poor this year.
Do you realize that?
Actually, all of us
are we working very hard.
However, the market is so bad...
Even my 6 years old son
can understand the situation
Yes, I am glad to hear that.
Even so, don't worry.
We are going to make new plans
for the coming year,
we are confident that
we can have a better future.
Sure I know your capability.
Nevertheless, I have to inform you.
What is it, Miss Yu?
I just fired Chung for you.
Why? He is a good staff.
I passed by a bar
after seeing clients last week,
I saw him having fun in it.
But that was 2:30 pm
and still in office hour,
I can't tolerate that.
So, no begging for him,
I have made my mind.
Regarding you, do try your best,
the company is counting on you
for the next year.
That is really good luck,
I didn't being caught by Miss Yu.
Chiu, are you okay?
Chung, what is your idea?
What do you mean? What idea?
Surely I have to find another job.
I have begged for you,
but she didn't listen to me.
I realized that it was my bad luck.
Everybody knows
Miss Yu is so ruthless.
I will try to ask help
for you in the field, okay?
Okay, thanks for your help.
But I think it won't be easy.
Yeah.
Actually you and me
were together in the bar,
having fun at that same time.
Why did she can just see me
but not you?
You really get a good fortune.
Turn bad things to good.
3 days later you will go to hell.
You got that yesterday,
3 days means the day after tomorrow.
Still not bad.
How come?
You can still have
one more horse race betting.
Yeah, I think so.
I am serious.
I am serious too.
Should you help me to bring
some gifts to the King of Hell?
So I can have a better life
after my death.
Is that funny?
You can give him by yourself
through internet.
Hey bros,
do you really believe that?
It didn't depend on me.
Could you see that?
I got really good luck today.
Are you serious?
There are so many
such bad jokes around.
Did you ever get a message
which asked you to forward
that to 10 persons,
otherwise you would get bad lucks?
Yes, I got it before.
Don't be serious with that.
Hello, my name is Bond.
Madam, it is your drink.
Thanks.
Oh, sorry.
Okay, I can make it.
You are wet.
Should I dry it up for you?
How?
I just live upstairs.
You can go to my home.
Go to her home?
You are too welcome.
I mean I get a hair dryer upstairs.
Oh, it is
a very attractive suggestion.
It is ok, thanks. I am leaving.
It is still early,
let me buy you a drink.
Great!
Thanks and no needed,
we still get beers.
Yes, my name is Juicy.
- How are you?
- Can we exchange the contact.
We can meet next time here.
Sorry that I try to fix it
in the rest room first.
Juicy, is that really juicy?
Can I get your phone number?
Then I can pass to him, okay?
My phone number is...
Are you exchanging contact
with my girl?
Just for a normal friendship.
Normal friendship?
I do like make friends very much.
How about we go out to know
each other much more.
You are too welcome.
Oh, please calm down.
How come of it?
How come I have such staff?
Boss, it is very difficult
to recruit a local right now
in Hong Kong.
By the way, aren't you going to
explore the new market?
What an idiot?
How open mind they are?
I leave now.
Hold it!
- Faster!
- Number 5, 8 and 10.
- There we go!
- Faster!
Okay, they did it.
It's great.
It pushed at a perfect moment
to win that.
Hey, did you win the Tierce?
Hey, man.
What is it? Did you win big?
Or just get the first trio of 3T?
It seems you have got a big winning.
What did you get
for the second trio?
Number 4 with number 2, 6 or 12.
Number 4 with what?
Number 4 with number 2, 6, 9 or 12.
Mine similar as yours.
I get 4 on 6, 10 and all round.
Oh, the second trio comes now.
It is so excited.
Don't hurry, the bend is coming.
Hold it.
Go!
I make it.
I got the second trio too!
Let's cheers!
I got 2 trios already.
Hey bros, did you make it?
It was too hot,
just thousands for these 2 trios.
Thousands are money,
don't be too greedy.
It can't help.
Brother Chiu,
did you follow with that guy?
No, we are just so similar on that.
He is a poor guy,
I just want to remind you
do not follow him.
How poor he is?
You really don't know that?
Oh, everybody know.
He is living in
subdivided unit upstairs.
Did that mean bad fortune?
Let me tell you, his wife left him.
He owes large amount of money.
He is a guarantor for a big debt,
collectors come often
and make disturbs.
So bad really?
Not merely that.
His son got kidney disease.
He has to work and take care his son
at the same time,
he is really poor.
It is really a tragedy,
or is he going to be doomed?
Iced lemon tea.
There is an extra bonus
for this upcoming three Trios.
Millions...
Big pool of bonuses.
- What did you get?
- Sure it is a big pool.
Number 8, 9 and 10
on all around for the final trio.
I got number 1, 8 and 9.
We just got one different.
Maybe either you or me
win the big prize.
It is the final trio!
Can I have a smoke?
Ok, get the whole pack.
Thanks.
It comes now.
Number 8, 9 and 10...
Hold it!
Faster!
Are you kidding?
I really get the fortune,
I win the pool!
- Congratulations
- What a luck, I get millions!
No way.
I got really god fortune
after receiving this letter.
It is not kidding.
So, what does it stand for?
How will be me?
You will die.
How come of it?
When you were in good shape,
did you find any special around you?
I found in these two days.
The better I got,
the worse the people
around would be.
The worst came yesterday,
the man besides me killed himself
after losing all games.
There is an absolute balance
in the universe,
there is gain and loss in karma.
Gaining too much will bring you
great loss in return.
Once your life
can no longer afford it,
death would be the result.
You said you won the 3 Trio?
- Yes.
- What is the amount?
4 million something.
How about this?
Go cash it all out immediately,
then wronged spent them all
within one day.
Cash it all? How wronged should be?
- Do you want to die?
- Sure not.
Then try you best to spend it all
in one day.
In a wronged manner.
It is so easy,
I always can donate it,
share it or even burn it.
Not like this,
it must be in a wronged way.
Do you understand?
How should I do?
Don't waste time.
Cash it as soon as possible,
the working hour will be off soon.
Do you really understand?
The clock is ticking,
you should go now.
Remember to wronge spent them all.
There is gain and loss.
Gaining too much will bring you
great loss in return.
Once your life
can no longer afford it,
death would be the result.
You said you won the 3 Trio.
- Yes.
- What is the amount?
4 million something.
How about this?
Go cash it immediately,
then wronged spent them all
within one day.
It is so easy,
I always can donate it,
share it or even burn it.
Not in this way.
Must be in a wronged way.
Remember that wronged spent it.
What's wrong with you?
Sir, what is the problem?
It is cop. What are you doing here?
- Do you know each other?
- No, we don't know...
Really? So what are you doing?
Just walk around
How come? It is a dead end
How about you?
I am smoking.
ID card please?
- Who get this?
- It's mine.
Open it.
Slowly.
Why is there so much money?
Cash it from bank.
Is there any proof?
I got the receipt
and there was my ID number.
Sir, may I go now?
Okay.
Don't stay too long
with such big amount of money.
I don't want either.
Give me a pack of cigarettes.
- Which brand?
- Anyone.
Here.
- Take it.
- Okay.
You get changes.
Here you are.
When is it now?
You mean what time is it?
Ten thirty.
By this way...
Hey, big boss.
Please feel free to choose.
- I want expensive one.
- Yes?
You only want expensive one.
Ok, let me show you.
Though this one costs
only hundred thousands.
That is very special since it is
the one and only one in the world.
Just watch and no touch.
Must be careful.
You have to pay for any damage.
Let's enjoy it.
You see, I get lots of money.
Yeah.
But, even I buy it...
Oh it is really wronged.
This antique is from Tong Dynasty.
How come you wrongly break it.
You have to pay for it.
What did you say before?
Wronged? Did you said it is wronged?
- Of course.
- Thank you so much.
How much is it?
This one costs 500 thousands
500 thousands.
- How about this?
- 300 thousands.
Are you kidding? It is so cheap.
Is there any much more expensive?
Sure, I get one for 700 thousands.
- Where?
- Here...
This one belonged to Queen Yeung
in the Tong Dynasty.
700 thousands.
700 thousands, so cheap!
- Anymore?
- Sure!
This is our shop's best,
Emperor Qin Shihuang's.
2 million, I give you a discount.
No way!
I want the original price,
not any discount is needed.
2 million is good for me, deal?
Okay...
Is that 2 million?
Go on...
It is almost there.
Let me calculate.
Ten, fifty, thirty...
4.1 millions only.
4.1 millions,
so 300 thousands is still needed.
How much of this?
It worth only hundreds.
Cheap stuffs with low prices.
No, this is an antique
even it got only 3 days' history,
can you charge me by 50 thousands?
Sure...
- That counts for 50 thousands.
- How about these?
1, 2, 3, 4, 5
Total in 300 thousands?
4.4 million will just make it.
Okay, I finally fix it.
"Clap your hands"
"Let's enjoy
this wonderful singing tonight"
"Why? Why? Tell me why"
Give me a pack of cigarettes.
Here.
Okay.
You get changes.
By this way...
It is not for fun,
you will die because of it.
You said you won the 3 Trios?
Go cash it all out immediately,
then wronged spent them all
within one day.
Remember to wronge spent them all.
Mama, I want to keep
all father's belonging,
Sure, I understood that.
I got the same feeling as you.
Mama, I miss Papa so much.
I miss him too.
What is this?
Who send us such bad thing?
Papa got this days before,
it was dispatched
by a man without leg.
What?
A letter for you.
I get a pen first.
A man without leg?
You can't tell lies. I hate lies.
Mama, I am telling the truth.
A letter for you.
"Chapter 2"
"Wife means nothing,
and so do children"
"None of them can accompany you
on the path at the netherworld"
Sir, the thing inside is very dirty.
You should go back home now
and never come back.
- Just go.
- I back home now.
And no rude manner anymore.
What a stubborn stupid.
"Beautiful school girls"
Bye-bye and come next time.
I won't serve woman.
I am Shemale, not woman.
Great, I have never met
Shemale before anyway.
Well, come on in.
Tell you my charges first,
100 dollars for one time
and 150 for twice.
Free of charge
if you can treat me high.
You are really famous
for such cheap charges.
Sure, I am doing for fun.
Really?
No way,
I think you are taking revenge.
Oh, it comes an idiot again.
So, you are not Shemale.
Sure not,
I get bigger breast than you.
Then, what do you want? Miss idiot.
It is that bad guy
did make you suicide,
but his wife is innocent.
That man lied to me.
Don't you know that
my death got two life?
Do you know
what is a perfect revenge?
Make him better to die.
I make her wife a hooker,
it is too good by just killing him.
Indeed, the man has regretted.
I do have nothing to say.
I want his wife to have AIDS.
That is none of you business.
You either terminate me or leave,
otherwise I will kill you too.
What a stubborn stupid.
Miss demon,
do you get hot water.
Don't you need to eat noodles
for extra energy?
I will vomit after exorcism,
so, get something to eat first.
Are you kidding?
How come you an exorcist?
Actually,
that is my family business.
My father said I get the talent.
So, where is your weapon?
Oh, these really are.
The signal is not good.
This China made comes the best.
No need to be expensive.
What are you doing?
This is an apps for exorcism.
So, I lock you up now.
I told before I get the talent.
Hey, Kin.
How have you been recently?
What?
Something in urgency?
Okay, see me in the shop.
Husband, may I ask you a question?
No thinking and answer it at once.
Who is the most beautiful woman
in this universe?
Louder please.
Right, that is your wife, me.
Anybody here?
Husband, happy birthday.
I know that
when you watch this video,
maybe I have been left.
I know you still miss me very much,
but you cannot be sad forever.
Since you look ugly when you cry.
Do you still remember the place
we dated for the first time?
You go there quickly
and I wait for you there.
Ling today accompany me here
to give you a surprise,
so I make a video here.
And try to give you
a very special birthday greeting.
Do not cry, you look ugly when cry.
Yes, my wife.
Do you remember that
you accidentally kissed me here?
Not so accidentally.
Since I knew you want to kiss me,
so I success your wish.
No way, it is not true.
Wife, I miss you very much.
Husband,
here comes another video,
I hoped that
you will not feel annoying.
I bought some good things
for you, Ka-wei.
What is going on, Ling?
Kin, see?
I bring them for Ka-wei.
- It is a very rich mask, see?
- Indeed.
- It sounds good.
- Let us apply it now.
We will see about it.
"Stop laughing,
or you will get wrinkles"
- Ling.
- Kin.
I got Ka-wei's video last night,
thanks.
My pleasure,
I will try the best to help Ka-wei.
I want to get all Ka-wei's videos,
please do me a favor.
Okay.
Kin, I know that
you miss Ka-wei very much,
but Ka-wei got her own ideas
and arrangements.
She tried the best to give you warm
and surprise after her death.
Maybe it is better
to keep patient and wait,
then you can success her wills.
Is that a better idea?
But, husband.
I kind of regret it now,
I didn't feel anything wrong
and having no pain today.
Actually, I should come here
with you by my side.
Because it is so beautiful here,
just like the time
when we had our first date.
But, husband.
I kind of regret it now,
I didn't feel anything wrong
and having no pain today.
Actually, I should come here
with you by my side.
Because it is so beautiful here,
just like the time
when we had our first date.
Because it is so beautiful here,
just like the time
when we had our first date.
Hi, Auntie Yam.
Hey, Kin.
How have you been recently?
What?
Something in urgency?
Okay, see me in the shop.
Kin, what is the urgency?
Auntie Yam, may I ask if you can
communicate with dead people?
Sure, I really get the power.
But wait, who and who
are going to communicate?
You miss Ka-wei really much, right?
Yes, I do really miss her.
Well, the case is,
it will disturb their reincarnation
if you communicate with the death.
The impact is too big and so,
so don't think about that.
Auntie Yam,
Ka-wei got many incomplete wishes.
And she still got many to tell me.
Could you help me?
How is it? Don't kneel.
Unless you will help me.
I hate being threatened.
"Declaration of Love"
"Answering"
Husband.
Here comes another video,
I hoped that
you will not feel annoying.
Husband.
Wife.
How can it be?
Honey, you are so clever.
Fortunately, you left me
lots of video messages.
And auntie Yam gave me
the talisman that can call back you,
we can meet again from now on.
I am so glad that we can
still have mid-autumn together.
Not only that,
but also Christmas, New Year
and our wedding anniversary,
plus both birthday of us too.
Really?
Sure, we can always meet again.
I miss you so much.
I really miss you too.
Hi boss, take a rest.
- Want to have some foods?
- Good idea, I just feel exhausted.
Just you? Where is your assistant?
He said the work is too hard
and quitted yesterday.
So, are you going to hire somebody?
Yes, but nobody apply yet.
Okay, how about me?
You?
Why?
Yesterday Ka-wei accompanied me
in the Mid-Autumn festival.
Ka-wei?
Her footages accompanied me
in the Mid-Autumn festival.
I go to get the forks.
Ling.
Ka-wei told me before that you have
invited her to join your business,
actually she got interest.
Also, I can only survive
with her videos
during this period.
I am impressed with your business,
it helps people.
So, I want to join.
Great, I appreciated that.
Why?
This is a meaningful business,
but I am really exhausted.
Ka-wei told she would like to join,
so...
It will be perfect
if you can succeed her.
Welcome.
Husband, do you remember that we...
Husband.
We...
I am sorry, I am so nervous.
It is okay,
many people nervous liked you
when facing camera.
May I suggest we go aside
and let you practice alone?
Tell me when you are ready.
Nice and thank you...
Husband, I am sorry.
I am really nervous and excited.
Sorry for my cousin's
terrible performance.
It costs you extra time
even for just a simple filming.
No problem,
many people get such camera phobia.
May I suggest that
we get dinner together?
As if for the compensating
of our foolish performance.
Oh no, I got paid.
That is our service and my duty.
That means we can only make business
but not friends?
That's not what I mean.
Okay, may I suggest this?
You may come to my office
2 days later
and have a look of the editing.
Great, I have your words.
"Declaration of Love"
Husband.
Are you happy that
receiving my videos?
"Lee Hui Ka-wei"
- Husband.
- Wife.
I have waited for your video
a very long time.
It would be great if you
had make the video day after day.
If so, we could meet everyday.
Husband,
I have think about it.
I cannot be so selfish.
How come of selfish?
I know you miss me,
but in reality, I have passed away.
You still get your own life
and can't be liked this forever.
Wife, I know what I am doing.
I really need you!
Unless you are not
willing to see me.
No, I want to see you so much.
You wait for me here.
Hurry up, is it okay?
Problem occurs.
It smells very good.
- Make you one also?
- Good idea.
How about we get off work
earlier tonight?
May I suggest we go
to have a movie together.
- Hi.
- Have a seat first.
Alright.
Hi, glad to see you here.
Yes, I have a date with Kin.
But he is still busy.
I see, is that for Miss Wong?
Let me do that.
Okay, I can make that.
No way, how can you
let a girl awaiting you?
Plus, she is such a beautiful girl.
You misunderstood that.
It is Friday night, go and have fun.
Then we leave now.
Bye-bye.
Don't work too hard.
Okay, just go.
"Movie Ticket"
May I suggest you
come on in my home?
Nice, but I have to hurry
for a proposal.
Okay, I get it.
May I see you again?
It sounds like you have
to gain my permission first.
So, is that a yes?
- Sure, I call you after my trip.
- Great.
I have your words,
so don't lie to me.
- Sure, bye.
- Bye.
"Declaration of Love"
You have to promise me
that you will never fall in love
with another woman anymore.
You have to promise me
that you will never fall in love
with another woman anymore.
Or, I will take revenge.
I will take revenge on you both.
Help, help, is anybody here?
You can just phone me
and I take it to the office.
You didn't bother to come here.
Okay, it is in urgency.
Take this one.
Thanks.
Okay.
It seems you and Pik
have come together, right?
Actually,
I am not well prepared yet.
I want to clarify with her recently,
but I cannot approach her
these days.
Oh, today is 18th already?
It is your first quarrel anniversary
with Ka-wei.
Did you get the video mail?
Yes, but it cannot be opened.
Let me see.
- I get some drinks for you.
- Thanks.
Oh no, the file was damaged.
Let me try to recover it.
Alright, take it easy.
You know what?
Ka-wei was specially sweet
when we was filming this video.
You must have a look.
Ling, I have thought about this.
I just can't rely on these videos
for the rest of my life.
Maybe Ka-wei will get the same idea
that letting me back to
a much normal and easy life.
I am so sorry.
You look so pretty
for without the glasses.
How can you still make fun of me?
Ling,
the client wants
a background music from the 60's.
60's?
Sealed with a Kiss?
Did I fixed that lamp yet?
- No, it is still on that table.
- No.
We just bought it recently.
Alright, I will have a look at it.
Let me help.
Just learn about how I deal with it.
Thank you.
Do you get appointment
on Christmas eve?
No.
May we have dinner together?
Yes.
Thanks.
So, is there any...
No, you are
really beautiful tonight.
Thanks.
Husband, Merry Christmas.
Who you are with now?
It is okay, you may watch it first.
No, I have make a decision
that I should start my new life.
On the other hand,
I should not date with you here,
but the heart
is with another girl there.
However, do you think you can
really take easy with Ka-wei?
She will in my heart forever.
But now, I want to start my new life
with the girl I love.
Here.
Cheers...
"Restaurant"
Hi, Mandy.
Hi, Mr Lee.
I cannot approach Pik for long time,
how is she?
Oh, so you don't know about it?
We could not approach her
for a while about 6 months ago,
then we went to her home.
What we discovered that was,
she wounded her face terribly
and stitched her mouth
who just lost her mind.
She is still in the mental hospital.
Husband, it is my birthday today.
Can you accompany me
to a special place?
Sure, but may I ask you
a question first?
Of course.
Do you know this girl?
Negative.
Then, can you help me to find out
why had this girl wound
her face so badly?
Stitche her own mouth
and loss her mind.
Maybe this is a retribution
that she has done something bad.
I don't want to talk about her.
When I saw her in the hospital,
ehe felt terribly scared
once she heard my voice.
She kept on saying
that she won't do that again,
and asked for my wife's forgiveness.
Actually you know everything,
why still ask me?
I want you to tell me
that wasn't done by you.
Yes, it is me.
She and me are merely friends.
Actually, she wanted more.
So, that why you hurt her?
Can we stop conflict
regarding that girl?
I should not recall you.
You were not my wife.
Tell me
if you fall in love with Ling?
We are merely friends.
Aren't you going to hurt Ling.
She is your good friend.
I don't think so.
Or else, she won't trying
to steal my husband from me.
Are you crazy?
We are really merely friends.
We can get an answer soon.
- Hi.
- Ling.
Yes?
I want to know that
if you do love me.
I want to ensure our future,
can you tell me?
Kin, I love you.
Thank you, Ling.
Good friend?
Fine, just another girl
trying to steal you..
Don't you want to hurt her.
She is your best friend,
you can't hurt Ling.
I won't see you again
if you hurt her.
Is there any difference?
You don't love me any more.
For what I lost, no other can take.
Husband,
we got marry for 6 months.
You have to promise me
that you will never fall in love
with another woman anymore.
Otherwise, my heart would be broken.
Hi.
- Ling, where are you?
- In office.
Do not open any
of Ka-wei's video files,
I come back now.
What is that? What do you mean?
I try my best now
to defend and slow down Ka-wei.
Husband.
You have to promise me
that you will never fall in love
with another woman anymore.
Otherwise...
I will take revenge.
I will take revenge on both of you.
I was so stupid that
made you my best friend,
You tended to steal my husband
once I've just gone.
No, I didn't.
Auntie Yam, is that you?
Why do you come across this affair?
It was because of me
that you can still here.
If so, please stay out of it,
it is better for you
by caring no more.
But you are now hurting others.
Auntie Yam.
You treat me well when I was alive,
should we become enemy now?
No, you just stop right now,
and I will help you
for a good reincarnation.
Is that okay?
Auntie Yam,
did you ever truly love someone?
Yes.
How much you can pay for the love?
Everything, but not in your way.
Indeed.
Everything,
including my life.
So, do you think
you can really trap me by this one?
Nobody can help you now.
Honey!
Can you let go of Ling?
You really fall in love with her?
Honey, do you remember
we often played with a joke
that you would ask me
a bunch of questions.
Yes.
Who is the most beautiful woman
in this universe?
No thinking and answer it at once.
It is my wife, it is you.
No longer is, right?
No, it is always postitve
in my mind.
But,
you no longer love me.
Originally, I think so.
But once I see you cried,
I realize that I love you only.
Wife, do you still remember
that I have promised
I won't let you sad?
Yes.
It is my fault.
I can't keep my word.
I am coming to be with you.
Husband.
Husband, do you know what day is it?
Right, the anniversary
of your proposal of marriage.
You have to promise me
that you would love me forever
who never fall in love
with another woman anymore.
Or, I will take revenge.
I will take revenge on you
even if I died.
"Miss Lee,"
"sorry that
I won't take your business."
"Result"
"Chapter 3"
"Fields means nothing,
and so do lands"
"None of the siblings
can escape karma"
Bros, what the special
is of this soup?
Is it kidding? Nothing inside
but just pieces of melon.
No kidding,
It is not just mere a soup.
Many different
kinds of herbs inside,
really good for health.
Really?
So, what is the most
famous dish here?
I will suggest shrimp balls,
it composes of many
different kinds of shrimps.
I see, which will make you
laugh forever.
What a bad joke,
even my son ignores it.
You can't imagine,
Ka-wei loves that.
Right, you are going to marry soon.
Do you need my help?
Sure, may I get your son?
I want a ring bearer.
Sure, leave me
a big red packet then.
What are these turtles for?
For myth believe?
Those are good for health.
You want to eat that?
All animals could be eaten.
Do you really mean it?
Of course, good for your body.
Just trust me.
Your marriage is soon,
eat that without hesitation
and you will get a child soon.
It is mainly for the soup.
So, you must drink the soup.
Well, Kei is late again.
He is used to that.
Among us, I am the only one
who mostly on time.
You just did arrive earlier,
not on time.
Don't talk about this.
Let me suggest,
the beef is also well famous here.
Together with these wontons,
All are custom made for you.
Sure that you are the boss
of this restaurant,
but still no need to
overly promote that.
- Are there any oysters?
- Oh yes, got it.
You are Mom's favor.
Only you could have oysters
in the past,
while Kei and I could only
have radish and cheap foods.
Mama only took you with her
when outing.
Frankly, it was not mine,
but yours problem.
It was because you were very
naughty, simply out of control.
Kei was a good child, right?
But Mama never took him out.
We couldn't just leave you
alone at home,
somebody had to take care of you.
Actually I knew that,
Mama worried that
if all of us were out.
Papa would then do bad things.
So, it was our duty to monitor Papa.
Don't talk about this anymore.
Cheers.
Try this, very good.
I am so sorry for my late.
It's okay, just 30 minutes.
And hotpot dining
is flexible for waiting.
The traffic was really terrible,
I came by taxi immediately
after work.
But roads were jammed,
maybe it was better
that come by MTR.
Sure, I realized that,
so I took helicopter.
But I could only just a bit earlier.
Are you really kidding
with me like that?
Don't bother with him.
- Come here and sit!
- Sure!
Don't save it.
How long do we meet
since previous time?
3 months already.
Really 3 months already?
You are so busy
that cannot feel that, right?
Cheers.
Right, it is you turn
to take the order.
There are already many dishes, why?
It should be enough then.
Please take expensive dishes only.
The boss will pay for that.
What boss?
Chiu got shares here.
Congratulations, Chiu.
You are now the big boss.
Not big boss.
Keung told me that
it will be a good business,
and see if I will join as partners.
So, we just go for
those expensive one.
Don't those cheap dishes.
Yes, we are my brothers.
Try to order as much as we can.
I am going to kill you guys.
Hi Boss,
here come the special order.
Thanks, may you back to work.
This is a very good
and special dish, have a look.
Just frog. How come special?
They are not for eaten,
I just want the urinate.
How come?
Good for man, you know?
You must taste it
and see the impact.
So, do you still go
to the previous job?
Why not? I still have to work hard.
My family gets 3 members.
Your situation
is far better than mine,
You are still single
and get an easy life.
Just okay,
I think Kin is much better.
How could it be?
Is there no need for me
to pay the rent?
Do you know I have to earn a lot
to survive every month?
Unlike you can comfortably live
in the public housing.
Yeah, after sending Mama
to the elder's home,
you can wholly occupy the unit.
Just rent for a thousand something.
I envy that.
I went to see
Papa's gravestone months before,
the color of graphic faded.
What? That was impossible.
I've gone before
and that was still in good shape.
You've been there?
Aren't you still angry with Papa?
Not that case.
After meeting my client last month,
I was just passing by
and have a look.
Just passing by? Just have a look?
Then, what was your purpose
to see Papa?
Asked him for a bless?
That you can earn money for nothing?
It is filial piety,
do you know that?
I really went there.
The color was fading.
So I got some paints to fix that.
Kei, I appreciate that.
We can't change that
he really is our father.
Indeed, I was really angry with him.
Though he was rarely back home,
he always came with chaos.
Yes, you really scared.
Every time he came back, he drunk.
So scared that I would hided inside
the blanket.
Yeah, you would took me with you.
Yes, I really remembered that.
Yes, both you were cowards
at that time.
Weren't you?
Yes, you always got
special response to Papa,
Papa would beat you hard
for your arguing with him.
But why didn't you fight back?
Let him knew what is martial arts.
Yes, Chiu really knew that,
but he applied it behind.
Whenever did Papa beat him hard,
he would held his fist tightly.
I really worried
he would fight back.
As if they had fought
each other at that time,
we would help you for sure.
Why didn't us call police
at that time?
We did it once.
When the cops came
and asked about it,
Papa told them that
he was just a bit serious
in teaching his sons.
So the cops asked Mama.
Madam, how is it?
Mama just repeated what Papa said,
"Nothing, but just a bit serious."
It was useless, no one can help.
Just enjoy our meal.
- Chiu?
- What's wrong?
Why asking me?
What are you thinking now?
It is fine, nothing.
Well, the soup is well done.
Let's have some now.
- Enjoy.
- Let me have a taste first.
Great.
It seems good.
- Have some more.
- It is good for you.
Kei, may I ask a question?
Sure, any without hesitation.
How much you earn per month?
You said that without hesitation,
so don't you answer that?
Or he is calculating.
It is variable since my income
is based on commission.
What is the average?
Tens of thousands.
30 thousands, 50 thousands
or 80 thousands?
About 50 thousands to 60 thousands,
but not a stable sum.
Yeah, really good though.
You are still single
and there is not any family burden,
while the rent per month
of public housing
is just a thousand something.
It is far better than
I got my own family,
while making only 30 thousands
a month.
30 thousands?
I can only make 20 thousands,
yet half of that
is spent for the rent.
Plus I have to contribute
to the expenses of Mom's elder home.
It is just amazing that
I do not get any debts.
Sure you are amazing
and better than me.
You still young, you must have
a better future than me.
By the way,
what do you do right now?
Aren't you changing the topic?
I still get many to ask.
Me too.
Why do you suddenly
get interest on me?
I get nothing change
for these years,
why do you so curious on me?
Just for update.
And, may I ask that...
The elder home for Mama
is chosen by you, right?
Why is it so expensive?
When did you see her the last time?
Can you answer my question first?
Yes, you should answer first.
I got my reason.
Though, I can still answer
that question first.
Mom has lived in this elder home
for nearly 6 months,
I go to visit her every week.
Before going in the elder home,
her body was not good
and even getting worse then.
And I am much busy than before
that I just cannot take care of her.
We knew that
since we got the same situation.
At that time, I have visited
so many o elder homes,
and did many researches of them too.
Finally, considering in all manners,
I thought this one was the best.
The charges is a bit expensive,
but I did ask you before
and there was not any opposition.
No opposition
does not mean I am agreeing on this.
I thought there were options,
but you finalized that
just two days afterward.
And you only notice us after all
those procedures were completed,
should I take Mama away then?
So, Chiu?
I also thought there were options,
but you had fixed that all.
What could I do?
I could only accept that.
I have to contribute
5 thousands per month...
It is not a problem for you
since you make 50s per month.
I can't join any of gathering
or activities with my friends,
and I rarely get meals
at restaurant.
You can tell me
if you get difficulty.
No need to get angry liked this.
Did he get angry?
Chiu is also difficult
with this five-thousands burden.
Do you want some more beers, boss?
No need, thanks.
Kei, frankly speaking,
I really get a difficult life,
and I cannot save even a dollar.
Also, the investment
on this business
was my wife's own pocket money.
Chiu,
I will not know
if you don't tell me.
Should I disclose all of
my difficulties to other people.
However, we are brothers,
so just be frank is all right.
Well, I am not so easy
as you think too.
I lost a lot in the stock market
3 years ago,
I am now still paying the debts.
Kei, are you worrying
I will ask you for money?
I think you over interpret that,
I just want to share
with you my real status.
Will you give
if I really ask you for money?
It depends.
I can give only a certain amount
What is a certain amount?
Tell me what actually you want?
I am just curious about
the certain amount,
what actually that is?
One thousands or three thousands?
Much more than that.
Then what is that?
Ten thousands or thirty thousands?
I can afford ten thousands.
Kei, don't be nervous,
I will not ask money from you.
Yes, don't be worry.
I really want to see each other
with this gathering only.
Chiu, told me
and see if I could help.
You heard before that
our life are really quite difficult.
For me,
I am almost 50 and hardly
get any promotion in my career.
Wages up for only
few hundreds per year.
If my child is going
to study oversea,
I just have to pay for that.
But, could I manage that?
Chiu, what do you want actually?
We want to discuss with you,
we want to minimize expenditures.
You mean...
For example,
the cost of the elder home and so.
Indeed, regarding the elder home...
Indeed, that is really expensive.
Added up with the other charges,
I have to pay 7 thousands per month.
If we change to another one,
we could save only about
one thousand
which is meaningless.
Kei, don't you think
there is really no option?
Options? Should there is any option?
Other options?
I want to know too.
I have discussed with Kin for
long time, but still get no option.
Kei, she is our mother,
and I really want to know your idea
that how to treat our mother.
The grant from the government
has reached the limit.
Then, how much do you want
to contribute per month?
Oh I see, you want to
take Mama out of the elder home.
So, whom will Mom be with?
You or you?
Chiu, can mother
be with your son in the same room?
Of course not,
the room is just too small.
And my wife gets many works to do,
she cannot take care of mother.
Have you ever think it carefully?
Don't you look at me.
My home just gets 200 feet square
and full of things,
it is not suitable for elder.
Kei, have you ever think
carefully before?
The best solution is
fot mother to be with you again.
Originally, she was with you
and you took good care of her.
Plus, the public housing
is under her name.
Honest speaking, you have taken
the advantage for long time.
Ok, I will be with Mom in my home.
No, it is not your home,
but she goes back to her home.
I got it.
Mom will be with me in her home,
do you satisfy now?
Good,
it is great that you understand.
Finally we get the consent,
and we can celebrate with this.
What a good wine,
so let me go to the rest room first.
Clean my body up,
so I can totally absorb it.
Okay?
Fantastic...
How come now? It is so chaotic.
Try to clean it up.
I didn't get chopsticks too.
- And no beers.
- I go and get that.
Why did you stop taking medicines?
Because I can't sleep then.
So can you fall as sleep
after stop taking the medicines?
Yeah, stop taking them
and I can finally sleep,
but still having dreams every night.
Are those the same dreams as before?
I dreamed about my last wife
who then becoming a ghost
and came back for killing.
Then, I also dream about
my big brother and I
attempted to kill our mother
and my second brother.
But, your record said that
you never have been married before,
neither you have any siblings too.
Well, the most important thing now
is for you to relax and take a rest,
Those medicines are here to help,
you just can't stop taking them
whenever you want.
Please believe in me.
Also, you may try going to work
if it is possible to do so.
Doctor Chan.
I dreamed about you last night too.
About me?
May I know about it?
We have had the same apps,
called the Declaration of Love.
"The End"