Attention!
Last year, on December 12th...
...several participants in the bombing of
Clark Field in the Philippines, namely...
...Flight Sergeant 1st-Class Kawata and
eight officers, were shot down.
Though listed as dead,
on January 2nd...
...after the 14th Army Unit's invasion of Manila,
they were rescued from a US prison camp.
At that time in Japan...
...prejudice against those who became prisoners
of war was beyond current imagining.
"Do not live to endure the shame
of being a prisoner of war."
To be a POW meant ostracism, not only
of oneself but of one's entire family.
Coupled with the Japanese mentality,
this created a military force...
...that would die rather
than surrender.
Hence, the focus of the discussion was,
needless to say, the issue of why...
...Flight Sergeant 1st-Class Kawata and the
eight officers did not commit suicide.
Can we not think of a way that they might
live, instead of ways to kill them?
I understand how you must feel.
All eight officers have been publicly
listed as casualties of war.
Hence the situation is quite difficult.
Chief...
if we lose planes,
we can always make more.
But pilots are not made in a day.
Indeed, going down with the ship, exploding
with one's plane, these are beautiful ideals.
However, our Air Corps
cannot fight like that.
We implore you to find
a way to be lenient.
But the conclusion of this incident was
not what Onishi had hoped for.
We should've killed ourselves.
We're a disgrace to the Navy.
We're traitors!
We should've killed ourselves.
I'm going to die...
I'm going to die!
That's enough!
Calm down!
Enough!
Stupid jackass! What's your little
death going to accomplish?
What's it going to accomplish?!
I will die!
One month later, shortly after Chief of
Staff Onishi was transferred inland...
...the eight officers were ordered to launch
a single-plane attack on Port Moresby.
Single-plane attack,
with no other planes as escort.
The command was tantamount
to suicide.
Thank you very much!
It's from the Kawata plane.
What's the matter?
Is that all?
Yes sir.
Note: This is the official war
declaration document.
"We, the Emperor,
ruler by divine providence
of the Empire of Great Japan...
"...hereby clearly and valorously
declare war...
"...against the United States
and Great Britain."
Mere six months after the
start of the Pacific War...
...the western Pacific and Southeast Asia
were under complete Japanese control.
But, after the six-month war of
attrition on Guadalcanal...
...Japan's strategic position
began to deteriorate.
Even the Air Force, which had once thought
itself invincible, had, by mid-1944...
...lost most of the elite pilots that
participated in the attack on Pearl Harbor.
Furthermore, U.S. war industrial output
was six times greater than Japan's...
...and was manufacturing new types
of heavily-armed fighter planes...
...that established U.S. air superiority.
By the summer of 1944...
...having lost Saipan, the critical
defensive bastion defending the homeland...
...Japan's prospects had
become dire indeed.
Allied forces could now attack
Japanese-held territory...
...from multiple staging
points in the Pacific.
What would be their next move?
While Japanese military intelligence
anxiously tried to answer this question...
...a fierce debate raged between
the Allied commanders.
Admiral King emphasized the importance
of immediately invading Taiwan...
...while General MacArthur argued for
the liberation of the Philippines.
The Joint Chiefs of Staff decided upon
the capture of the Philippines.
The Philippines became the focal
point of the entire war.
For Japan, losing the Philippines meant
losing crucial Southern Pacific resources.
In one fell swoop, the enemy would gain access
to Taiwan, to Okinawa, and even the homeland.
The strategy for defending the Philippines
was codenamed SHO-1.
At this stage of the war, it was a battle that
they absolutely could not afford to lose.
Meanwhile, Onishi had been
promoted to Vice Admiral...
...and was Vice Director of the Department
of Air Weapons on the Naval General Staff.
However, the star of the Naval Air Corps
was headed for the battlefront yet again.
The Emperor himself presided over his appointment
as Commander of the First Air Fleet.
We can no longer win this
war with ordinary tactics.
We must use special attack tactics to
destroy the enemy; there is no other way.
I am petitioning the Naval General Staff
to organize " special attack" units.
Therefore, I have come to you, Vice Admiral
Onishi, for a letter supporting my plan.
Please, give me your recommendation!
To turn the tide in our favor, we must not just be
willing to die; it is now necessary that we die.
My firm belief is that we must
make self-sacrificing attacks.
We'll pack 1,800 kilograms of explosives
in the nose, and fly to the target.
From a height of 6,000 meters,
it will enter a dive...
...and plunge into the enemy
at a very high speed.
I'm against it. We can't turn
our pilots into ammunition.
We cannot be so cruel
towards our pilots.
I could never agree to such
disgusting tactics.
Look at this. Accidents happen,
everyday, even here at the base.
We are forced to send our pilots into
battle with only 200 hours of flight time.
To expect skilled piloting
is a dream of the past.
They can take off, and fly to the target
locations. That's about all...
...we can ask from our current
cadre of pilots.
This is absolutely unacceptable!
No matter how bad things are, we can use
our brains to find a better solution.
Please support my suicide-attack plan!
Vice Director Onishi,
why are you silent?!
The demand for suicide attacks
is getting more insistent.
I believe that the Navy must make a
firm decision on how to proceed.
Please give me your opinion.
My opinion?
Well... it'd be easy to order a suicide attack
if a plane was too damaged to return to base.
But to deliberately launch
suicide attacks?
There is no precedent for it in all the
long history of warfare around the world.
I did not come here to debate tactics.
I have come to inquire of the Navy's
decision about the SHO-1 operation.
Are we going to implement
suicide attacks?
I'm aware of the situation.
I'm aware of it. But...
Let's say that we implement
this strategy.
If it is a failure, the effect on military
morale will be catastrophic.
We need the Combined Fleet's
opinion... yes...
We can't decide anything until we hear
the Combined Fleet's opinion.
The question is whether or not
we can maintain discipline...
...if the tactic is employed.
Am I correct to assume, then,
that the Combined Fleet...
...is against the implementation
of suicide attacks?
I am not saying that I am against it.
Only that it needs more study.
We have done all the research, based
on our earlier skip-bombing training.
I believe you are already familiar with the
results, as presented in the report.
Undeniably, the suicide attack
tactic is not palatable.
But if we are going to bring calm
to the current maelstrom...
...then someone... then some,
brave, someone must...
...belt the cat. We need such courage
more than ever before.
Chief. I implore you.
Please decide in its favor.
I just finished the assignment ceremony
at the Imperial Court.
I will be departing for the Philippines
tomorrow morning.
Well done. Come, have a seat.
An enemy B-29 has been spotted,
heading north above Sagami Harbor...
Did it come from Saipan?
An enemy B-29 has been spotted,
heading north above Sagami Harbor...
Most likely.
This war has turned out
just as you predicted.
Like Yamamoto, you were opposed to the
Japan-Germany-Italy Tripartite Pact.
You never took an aggressive stance,
even in the beginning of the war.
You opposed the big battleships, instead
you championed the use of aircraft.
You even advocated changing the Navy
emblem from the anchor to a propeller.
Knowing this, it is cruel of us to send you
off to the Philippines so unceremoniously.
But we need you to do this.
For you are the only man who can do it.
There is one thing that I want
you to understand.
It's regarding the special attack tactic
that is currently being debated by the Navy.
I want you to leave the decision on whether
to use it in the Philippines in my hands.
Needless to say, I will take full responsibility
for the success or failure of the air mission.
Is that acceptable?
The enemy B-29 is still headed
north above Sagami Harbor.
Although no other enemy airplanes have been
spotted, everyone must remain vigilant.
Hey, the evening primrose is about to blossom.
Hurry up and come out here. Hurry.
Come on, you're going to miss it.
Yoshi-e, Yoshi-e.
Hey, mother.
Evening primrose again?
Yeah... so you were listening?
Couldn't help it, I could hear
you from across the street.
We are grateful for your efforts.
Thanks.
Under different circumstances, I would've
been grateful for my promotion...
...but this time it's as if His Majesty
has given me the dagger as well.
I've finally found this. It's not a name
brand, but its sharpness is guaranteed.
Please take it with you to the Philippines,
as a memento from me.
You're going too, you know.
What? I'm going to the
Philippines too?
Yeah. You'll help us
construct an airfield.
Good grief! I'm going from scrounging
to digging ditches?
Driver will come for you at
06:00 tomorrow morning.
Come back here, and don't be late.
Good grief...
Welcome.
Ma'am, it looks like I'll never have time to
find a wife while I'm working for your man here.
Look, it's about to bloom.
It's blooming, it's blooming.
The following morning, Onishi and his staff
departed from Tokyo and flew to Fukuoka.
At Hakozaki Shrine, they prayed
for good fortune in war.
Hey, Hiko-chan, when did you arrive?
Last night. I went to Air Corps and
they said you guys were here.
They told me to bring this to you.
Read it for me.
Yes.
Looks like there was a massive air
strike on Okinawa this morning.
All we know so far is that it was a large
B-29 formation that flew in from China.
That's not right.
What's not right?
It's just a hunch, but they
didn't fly in from China.
I think the attack was launched
from a fleet of carriers.
And if that is the case...
...then building new runways
will be a waste of time.
Then what am I supposed to do?
Wait in Shanghai with Yoshida.
Be ready to leave at any time.
Yes sir, understood.
Onishi's intuition was correct.
General MacArthur's invasion force,
escorted by Admiral Halsey's fleet...
...was headed straight
for the Philippines.
"I have returned...
"...with a colossal fleet of six
battleships, eighteen aircraft carriers...
"...and 700 other vessels escorting
the flagship USS Nashville...
"...carrying 174,000 elite US soldiers,
men who have defeated Nazi Germany...
"...men who are the greatest warriors
the world has ever seen."
"The ocean covered with our ships
as far as the eye can see...
"...and it is with them that
I have returned to Leyte."
"I have returned, indeed. I have returned."
Facing this enemy horde was the First Air
Fleet, with only fifty operational aircraft.
What's that vehicle doing here?
It's got a general's flag. It can't
be Chief Onishi, can it?
If that's Chief Onishi, then Commander
Yamamoto should be with him.
He just arrived yesterday. I'm sure
he's busy making his social calls.
Why would he ever come to a
godforsaken place like this?
Chief!
So what's it like here?
Everyone doing fine?
Yes sir.
The morale is very high.
There's something I need
to discuss with you all.
Why don't we... all go back to my inn?
Yes sir.
All of you know the true
state of the war...
...and that if SHO-1 fails, all is lost.
We must...
...by whatever means, defeat the
enemy's seaborne forces.
And in no more than a week...
...we have to render the flight decks
of the enemy carriers useless.
To accomplish this...
...we will have to load each of our Zeros
with 250 kilos of explosives...
...and send them on suicide-bombing attacks.
I don't believe there's any other way.
What are your thoughts?
Well?
I am only the Executive Officer
of our Air Corps.
I cannot make such a decision
for the entire squadron.
I must wait for Commander Yamamoto to return
from Manila, and see what he has to say.
I have already met with Commander
Yamamoto in Manila.
He said I should treat the words
of the Executive Officer...
...as if they were his own, and that
he trusts in your decision.
Chief. Please give me about 30
minutes to think about this.
Excuse me.
What it is, sir?
It's very late.
Gather everyone in the 10th
squadron together.
Yes sir.
...So I'm waiting for...
Is something wrong, sir?
Coming in!
Everyone's here, sir.
Listen carefully. What
I'm about to tell you...
...must never be discussed
outside of this room.
Today, Commander-in-Chief
Onishi came to see me.
He proposed launching
a suicide mission...
...packing 250 kilos of explosives
into our Zeros.
However...
...I have not given him
my approval yet.
First I want to hear...
...your frank opinions.
I will do it.
Please let me do it, Executive Officer!
I will go too!
I will do it too!
Me too!
I will go too!
Please let us!
You really...
...really want to do this?
It's not a matter of wanting
to do it or not.
All of us have been together since we were
your students at flight school in Matsuyama.
And look at us now...
At Tinian, Yap, and Palau...
...two-thirds of our comrades have been
killed by those Yankee bastards.
We have to avenge their deaths.
Otherwise, we couldn't face
them in the next life.
That's right. We're all going
to die eventually anyway.
So we might as well crash ourselves
into an aircraft carrier.
You'll see. I'll sink an
entire ship by myself!
This is our chance for revenge!
Everyone, let's do this!
Yeah!
Come in...
Entering...
Reporting. The 201st Flying Corps...
...has decided to carry out
the suicide attack.
Regarding the attack planning, please leave
everything up to the 201st Flying Corps.
I'm going to take a little nap. I suggest
you guys do the same.
As you were...
As you were.
Who's going to command
the attack force?
I thought I'd let Seki do it.
Seki Yukio?
Yes... He was one of your students
at the Naval Academy, wasn't he?
Yeah. So... Seki...
Seki will do well.
Come in...
Entering...
Have a seat.
Listen, Seki.
The Chief came to see us today.
It was about SHO-1.
As you know, Admiral Kurita will be
taking his fleet into Leyte Gulf.
To ensure its success...
...we're going to load our Zeros with 250 kilos
of explosives, and launch a suicide attack.
Well, that's the Chief's plan.
We want you to accept the white-feathered
arrow... and command the attack.
Please allow me to do it.
I see...
Come in...
Entering...
We have 24 pilots.
We chose a Naval Academy graduate,
Seki, to command the assault.
"Shinpu" as "Kamikaze" - religious meaning.
Executive Officer Tamai
and I have chosen "Shinpu squadron."
Japan is truly in danger.
Who will rescue us from this danger?
Not the Ministry. Not the Generals.
Not the Naval General Staff Secretary-General.
Not the Chiefs, like me.
It's those who are pure of heart like
children, those who are brimming with energy.
It's only the young who can save us.
Therefore I, on behalf of our
entire nation, implore you.
All of you are already gods.
Since you are all Gods, you are free
from all desires, except one:
The desire to know that your suicide
mission had not been in vain.
However, all of you will be
sleeping for a long time.
So you will not know the answer, and
there will be no way to let you know.
But... I will take care of the rest.
I will bear witness to the fruits
of your accomplishments...
...and will not fail to personally
report them to His Majesty.
And after that... I will come and
tell you what happened.
Please... do your best!
They've given us eight Zeros;
That's unusually generous.
Yeah, I've got a bad feeling about
this. What's going on?
I don't know. They just told us to bring
them here, so we followed orders.
It's probably a gift from Chief-of-Staff
Onishi on occasion of his visit to Mabalacat.
I see... I knew he'd be good to us.
Come in.
What is it?
You won't be keeping me out of the
special attack force, will you?
"Kisama:" roughly "bastard"; can be used both angrily
and affectionately. You bastard... so you know about it?
The Flight Captain and
I are old comrades.
Four planes were brought in today to Cebu
to be used in a suicide squadron.
I'm assuming it's permissible
for me to go too.
Thank you very much.
I will eventuality fail...
...into an ocean a thousand
fathoms deep.
Flowers will bloom on the waves...
above my blue grave.
Huh?! It's the Chief!
As you were... as you were.
All of you, sit down.
Hey...
Yes sir.
Let me have the canteen.
Let's drink together.
Thank you, sir.
What prefecture are you from?
From Shizuoka, sir.
Shizuoka? It's nice.
Yes sir.
We're counting on you.
How about you?
From Fukui, sir!
Are your parents doing well?
Yes sir.
We're counting on you.
Enemy aircraft! Enemy aircraft!
US Bombing raids continued relentlessly
for 19, 20, then 21 days.
When will we ever launch our attack?
I heard that reconnaissance managed
to locate the enemy carriers twice!
How much longer must we wait?
The Chief hasn't given the order yet.
And besides, they're a long way away.
I told him that I'm not letting you guys
go until we're absolutely sure.
So hang in there. Hang in
there just a little longer.
Shit!
Seki...
Yes sir.
Give me a memento,
something to remember you by.
Huh?
It's not for me... the Chief insists.
I understand.
The US submarines Darter and Dace...
...spotted the Japanese fleet off the
Palawan Passage, at dawn on October 23.
Vice Admiral Kurita's armada was spearheaded
by the battleships Musashi and Yamato.
They were the leading actors
on the stage of SHO-1.
Decoy fleets were launched to lure
the enemy away from Leyte Gulf.
Meanwhile, the battleships, with their
massive 46cm guns, crept towards Leyte Gulf.
Their mission was to pulverize MacArthur's
100,000 men when they tried to invade.
Periscope at 90° to port,
distance: 0-5-0!
Ready the depth charges!
Man your stations!
And so, over three days, what may be the last
great fleet battle in history took place.
Enemy attack, 135°, elevation 10°!
235°, elevation 10°.
Open fire!
Fire! Fire!
Ten planes, 180°, fire, fire!
Got him! Good shooting!
Enemy planes!
90° right, elevation 20°!
90°, elevation 20°!
Fire!
Assholes! Screw it! Now I'm
getting really pissed off!
Gunny!
Shit!
The Musashi received a death-blow.
But the Musashi's death
was not in vain.
Admiral Halsey, upon learning of the
Musashi's struggles on the Sibuyan Sea...
...assumed that Kurita's fleet
had been devastated.
Having spotted Ozawa's decoy fleet,
he next headed north to intercept them.
The watchdog had been lured out of Leyte;
Japan's strategy was a splendid success.
Target: enemy ships deployed off
the coast of Samal. Be careful.
Synchronize watches to 7:00...
Fifteen seconds...
Ten seconds...
Five seconds...
Set!
We're off.
Let's go.
Any comments? Just a comment, Captain Seki.
Please don't make a big deal out of this.
It's normal for soldiers to die on the battlefield.
Okay... I'm going to go die to protect my
wife, the person that I love the most.
Entering!
We've received a report about the Shinpu
Shikishima Squadron's mission!
Report to Imperial Headquarters:
October 25, 1944.
At 10:45 AM, the Shinpu
Shikishima Squadron...
...attacked an enemy fleet containing four aircraft
carriers 30nm north-east of Suluan island.
The surprise attack was a success.
Two planes struck an aircraft carrier.
It has been confirmed as sunk.
One plane struck another aircraft
carrier, which is in flames.
One plane struck a cruiser,
it has sunk. End.
Make sure you write, "one plane struck,"
and "two planes struck." Do you understand?
"One plane... two planes."
Yes sir.
Seizing their chance, the Japanese Navy
launched more suicide attacks.
However, the chance for victory
had already come and gone.
Misled by incorrect intelligence, Kurita's
fleet turned back as they neared Leyte Gulf...
...and SHO-1 ended in failure.
The US gained momentum.
They invaded Mindoro island, and
reconnoitered the main island of Luzon.
Then early the next year,
on January 6th, 1945...
...the last five planes of the 20th Flying
Corps, from Kongo Squadron, took to the air.
With no more planes in the Philippines,
Onishi and his men became ground troops.
Enemy planes attacking!
Everyone take cover!
Take cover! Take cover!
Take cover!
Chief! You have to get down!
Chief! Why did you do that?
Well... I was just observing
the enemy planes.
Please don't be so rash.
I know, I know...
Chief. We have orders from
the Combined Fleet.
What do they want me to do now?
There's nothing left to be done.
You've been ordered to move
your headquarters to Taiwan.
What?
The order is effective as
of the 8th. That's today.
Not yet...
it is not yet time for me to die.
Attention!
Fall in!
Chief, please wait.
Please stay with us in the Philippines.
Commander Sata!
It is only because you have been our
commander, Chief... Chief Onishi...
...that we have all gladly endured
the hardships of this war.
Can you acknowledge it?
If so, please stay. I ask you
on behalf of the entire unit.
Stay in the Philippines, and fight
the enemy with us, once again.
I cannot.
Why not?!
Please understand.
If you're going to forsake us, then
I am bold enough to say, Chief...
...that you are a coward!
That's right. You are a coward!
You sent the special attack
forces on their missions.
You stood on the ground in the
Philippines and saw them off.
But now, you're going to leave?
I don't understand it!
Chief. Chief Onishi!
You are a coward!
You fool!
You...
...fool.
You can't fight a war with
that kind of mentality.
Considering the current state of the war, with
the enemy in control of the Philippines...
...their forces are fast approaching
the shores of Japan.
Their air-raids on the mainland are
intensifying with each passing day...
...while our ability to wage war
is in every way reduced...
...and our ally Germany
is similarly beset.
We must admit that our situation
is most precarious.
However, the real war is yet to begin.
The enemy is growing weaker.
Now all Japanese must become special
attack warriors, endure a long war...
...and find every means at our disposal to
kill as many of the enemy as possible.
Then the Americans, who fear the loss
of their lives, will be defeated.
This is the path we must follow
to achieve a glorious victory.
In a battle on land, it is impossible for
one man to kill a hundred enemies...
...but our flying corps is able to kill a ship
and hundreds of its men with a single plane.
We can fight a fight that
is worth dying for.
Victory or defeat is determined
in the final battle.
Even if we are defeated 99 times, if we win
the final battle, then we are the winners.
If we can win that final battle, America
will consider peace with Japan.
The war will be a draw.
And a draw is a win for Japan.
We might not call it a victory,
but it won't be a defeat, either!
The deployment of you fine men of
the Shinpu Special Attack Force...
...ensures that even if the impossible
happens and we lose the war...
...Japan will not be vanquished.
Our strength of will and
lofty spirit are ideals...
...that demonstrate our superiority
over the white man.
But, if defeated without demonstrating
such character...
...Japan would truly be a ruined
nation, a people without hope.
Death is not our goal.
But let us be willing to die...
...so that we can kill the enemy more effectively.
Choose the most valuable way to die!
I know it's short notice, but could you talk
to the suicide troops about the homeland?
The homeland is in shambles
from air-raids.
I can't tell them the truth.
And I can't lie to those who are
about to die. I can't do that.
Please... if there is any way
you can encourage them.
I myself have nothing to say.
I understand.
I'm counting on you.
Though we are not related in blood and flesh,
we still get along, and never want to part.
Chief... How are things back home?
I hear they've been hit
with a lot of air-raids.
You guys are about to go on a mission, so I
won't lie to you. I'll be honest with you.
It's true that it's just as bad back home
as it is here on the front lines.
But everyone takes heart, knowing that you
men are unleashing the Divine Wind.
That's too much. Please don't tell the people
back home exaggerated stories about us.
After all, we're in a war; it's going to be
a good death no matter where we die.
But... for who are you all
willing to die so calmly?
Is it for your country? Or is it
for His Majesty the Emperor?
We don't need to make a fancy statement
with our deaths. Right, guys?
I guess I could say I'm going
to go die for the old man.
Admiral Onishi?
Yeah. He wants to die too, you know.
But we can't let him die.
We have to go before he does.
But please, don't tell the
old man what I said.
Understood.
Hurry up!
Hurry, hurry, please hurry up!
The Special Attack Force can't take off
if the enemy planes come. Faster!
Boss, this is my flight-bento, please
give it to someone who's hungry.
That's for you to eat.
If I get full I'll get sleepy. Then who
knows, I might miss the enemy.
We're waiting for the runway.
What kind of bento do the Special
Attack Forces get?
So that's the last meal.
Originally, the Special Attack Forces
were Rear Admiral Onishi's...
...last-ditch tactic, to be used
only in a dire emergency.
But upon learning how effective it was,
Imperial HQ changed its position...
...and ordered all units to make suicide
attacks whenever possible.
Nobody will understand.
About what?
The... suicide attacks...
...violate every rule of leadership.
"Even after my coffin is buried,
my reputation will be unsettled."
"Even after a hundred years
I will not be understood."
Chief...
Let's get going.
In this way, suicide missions
became official policy...
...and the lives of hastily-trained volunteers
were expended as if they were bullets.
Furthermore, suicide missions became less and
less effective as the US adapted to the tactic.
Target-hitting accuracy, which
was 80% in the Leyte gulf...
...dropped to 50% in Okinawa.
Onishi's greatest fear became reality.
Of the men who were ordered to die...
...more than a few rebelled and refused
to participate in special attacks.
Blame, criticism, and vilification was heaped
upon the father of the special attacks.
Onishi had to bear it, all alone.
Japan's do-or-die counterattacks could not
stop the US march towards the homeland.
Large formations of B29s flew almost every
day from bases in the Mariana islands...
...indiscriminately fire-bombing cities,
large and small, all over Japan.
Eighty-one cities were razed, 2,400,000
houses burned, and 240,000 civilians killed.
It was up to the elite aviators of the 302nd
Air Corps squadron of Atsugi Air Base...
...men tempered in the skies above Rabaul,
commanded by Captain Kozono Yasuna...
...to rise to meet the overwhelming US
forces and protect the Tokyo area.
Hey, one B shot down, confirmed.
Report it for me.
I'm gonna shoot down two
or three more. Hurry!
Yes sir!
Hurry!
Yes.
Slow... slow... stop.
I'll turn it around.
Hey Kaida. My plane's
wing-tank's been hit.
We can't fill it up.
Let me use your plane.
Divisional Captain, please tend to
ground affairs, I'll go do the rest.
Don't get cocky, you're not
that good. Now get out!
I mustn't!
Out you get!
Divisional Captain, you can't borrow
it for free. I'll bill you later.
Fine, we'll have a shogi duel when
I return, so go set up the board.
What did you find out?
Um... We just got word from the Air Defense
Command Post in Yokosuka.
He crashed in Hodogaya.
Who's got custody of the body?
The Third Mechanics Unit is getting him.
You stay here! I'll go check on it!
Kaida!
Hey!
Stop!
Stand down! The ammo's exploding
from the heat. Let's wait a while!
It's like Captain Arai's ghost is here.
Kaida.
I'm sorry. Please pardon me.
It should have been me,
not the Divisional Captain.
Come with me.
You jackass!
It wasn't you that I hit. I hit the God of
Death that's following you around.
The God of Death stays close to weepy
guys. You can't do your duty like that.
The 302nd Air Corps is not a suicide squad.
As long as we're alive, we fight the enemy.
That's our duty. Think hard about how
much the people are counting on us.
You can't afford to cry.
Nakai...
Sir!
Don't offer that sake to the dead.
Let Kaida drink it instead.
Yes sir, I will.
Back to work!
In May, 1945, the First Air Fleet
in Taiwan was disbanded.
Vice Admiral Onishi was appointed Vice
Director of the Naval General Staff...
...and ordered home.
Welcome home.
It burned down very nicely.
I'm so sorry I couldn't
rescue our things.
Where's mother?
She was evacuated to Shimonida in Gunma.
Were you living here all by yourself?
No... my relatives, the Chi'iras, have been
letting me stay with them at night.
I just spend my days here...
...to make sure you could find
the house when you return.
I've wandered here and there,
truly, I've been lost.
It's short notice, but the Vice Director must
present himself at the Imperial Court...
...so could you please prepare
his dress uniform?
Oh no. It's been burnt. Had I thought of it,
I would've run out of the house wearing it.
I see.
I'll see if I can borrow one
from somewhere.
Alright... please do.
Yes sir.
Good job.
I'll make some tea.
Yeah.
Oh... Onishi.
Thank you for all your efforts.
Everyone, my apologies to you all.
Your homes of many years are in ashes,
and it's all the fault of us soldiers.
I sincerely apologize. Please
find a way to forgive me.
I only have a little to share, but...
Rock candy!
Here you go.
Thank you.
Here.
Thank you very much.
Here, Missus.
Here's a present for you.
I can't say that it flatters me.
I can't let the ladies see me like this.
But since it's just the Emperor, who cares?
You look like you've lost some weight.
My countenance has become ugly.
This outfit makes me look like Kiratsune
has become a Vice Admiral.
Where will your next official
residence be?
Nanpeidai, in Shibuya.
Would it be alright for
me to stay there?
You can stay wherever you want.
But not there, not when we're at war.
There are people, parents and children,
struggling to survive.
The suicide warriors went to their deaths
without even knowing family-life.
How then can I enjoy married life?
Yes.
I shook hands with them, with these hands,
and sent them off on suicide missions.
Six hundred and fourteen young men.
Six hundred and fourteen of them...
Meanwhile, the war in Europe
was drawing to an end.
In September of the previous year, Italy, an
ally of Japan, was conquered by the Allies...
...and the fascist dictator Mussolini
was executed by partisans.
In May of the same year, Germany fell under
the onslaught of the Russian Army...
...and the Nazi Fuhrer Hitler
committed suicide.
In this way, Japan found itself catastrophically
isolated, with the entire world as its enemy.
The Army believes that if we had
2,000 special attack planes...
...we could devastate the enemy
invasion force at sea.
But is there any solid
data to confirm this?
Yes sir.
We have results from experiments at Takeyama
Air Base, based on the Vice Director's idea.
If you look at the data and photos,
they will speak for themselves.
Using model No: 25 and No: 50 bombs...
...we tested the effects on the armor used
by enemy aircraft carriers and battleships.
We rammed the explosives into the targets at
the appropriate speed, and the results show...
...that only transport ships could be sunk;
The heavier ships could survive the hits.
Vice Admiral, what is your point of view?
Yes.
Though we can't sink them...
...it's possible to crush their morale
with continuous suicide attacks.
The US military calculates their estimated
losses for each operation.
When their losses exceed this estimate,
they scrap the mission.
That's been their pattern up until now.
We don't know what they estimate their
losses on a mainland invasion will be...
...but if we unrelentingly employ special
attacks, we may convince them to cancel it.
But they will respond by increasing
their control over our airspace.
Our planes would be destroyed as soon
as they arrive at our airfields...
...before they could depart on
special attack missions.
Strategies based on suicide
tactics are unrealistic.
I admit that what you say is well
within the realm of possibility.
Hence, my belief is that we should not
wait for the enemy to make its move.
We must regain control of our airspace
with bold and aggressive attacks.
Regarding this issue, I will have
Divisional Director Terai explain our plan.
Yes sir.
We propose a ground special attack on the
enemy air bases on Saipan and Tinian...
...aimed at destroying enemy
planes such as the B29s.
On a moonlit night, we land airborne troops
using the enemy's own runways.
They will then use mines to
destroy the target planes.
We have already begun combat training for
the mission at Matsushima Air Base.
We already have several factories
working on perfecting the mines.
When can we launch the attack?
Based on the lunar phase and the training
progress of the troops to be deployed...
...our goal is early August.
How can you avoid enemy
anti-aircraft fire?
If we shadow an enemy squadron as it
returns from a raid on the mainland...
...we believe that it's possible to arrive
at the targets with minimum casualties.
Vice Director, regarding this issue, we have a
plea from the training unit at Matsushima...
...to try out their swords on American POWs
in preparation for hand-to-hand combat.
What should we do?
Such a plea, from those who are willing
to sacrifice their lives on a mission...
...cannot be coldly denied.
I am absolutely opposed! We cannot
kill defenseless prisoners of war.
It would be inhumane!
If news of this were to leak to the US
military, it would fuel their morale and rage!
Look at what happened to Italy and
Germany after they were defeated.
We would be accused of war crimes. We would
be getting ourselves into grave trouble.
His Highness Prince Takamatsu
is present at this meeting.
Vice Director, are you saying that it would
be acceptable to implicate His Highness?
First Divisional Director, is that the
way you should speak to me?
I apologize.
Not only will His Highness have
to bear the responsibility...
...everyone in the military
will be held accountable.
However, the First Divisional Director's
views may have some merit.
So we shall reconsider this
matter at a later time.
However, it is defeatist to even discuss
post-war considerations at this time!
I am willing to bet everything on a single
battle, no matter what our situation might be.
And that final battle is the only one that
we absolutely cannot afford to lose.
Winning that battle is the only parting gift
we can give those who have gone before us.
Perhaps some of you have
already given up...
...believing calculations on paper that we
are outnumbered, and that we cannot prevail.
But we must never give in!
We must be thoroughly committed
to this war; never forget that!
Vice Director! You are out of line.
As for the mission proposed by the Vice
Director, continue the preparations.
Today's council is hereby adjourned.
Minister...
Uncle. It's been a long time.
So you're back.
We got a telegram saying to come back at
once. We flew directly from Shanghai.
What is the occasion?
It's copper. Copper.
Copper?
The torpedoes used for special sea attacks
have been duds. Upon investigation...
...it was because aluminum was
used for the main fuse.
We don't have enough copper
to make the electrical circuits.
We asked Headquarters, but they could
only give us 1/16 of the needed amount.
We can't just send the young men of the
suicide forces out to die in vain. Any ideas?
It's Yamashita, entering.
Yeah.
Ah...
Thanks.
Copper... you can find
it all over the place.
Wherever a bomb's hit, you can find electric
lines buried everywhere in the rubble.
Copper electric lines are 99% pure.
If we dug them up, we could salvage
a considerable amount.
I see. In that case,
get on it immediately.
Acknowledged.
By the way, old man...
...the citizens are exhausted.
If the war is going to continue, then
something drastic needs to be done.
His Majesty the Emperor must
directly lead the nation.
He must live in the same way as the citizens
and the soldiers, and fight along with them.
Even the Meiji Emperor went to Hiroshima
during the Russo-Japanese War.
We're all suffering, and yet His Majesty
stays cloistered in the Imperial Palace?
Don't say such things.
Yes sir.
That's not copper! It's no good. Next!
Hey, hey... why don't you
give her something.
Okay.
If you need more workers, you could
get some prisoners released.
I'll put them to good use, you'll see.
That's a good idea.
Anyway, Mr. Seki-ne, your assistance with
the transportation has been very helpful.
As a result, I won't let His
Excellency Onishi down.
Even a gambler such as myself can contribute
to his country. I'm grateful for the chance.
But look, Mr. Kodama. if the Navy needs
help from gamblers, the future isn't rosy.
It's only the citizens who are suffering.
Government administrators and senior
statesmen aren't suffering at all.
That's the problem.
Could you use something like this?
That's a fine Kan'non statue. Young lady,
you should take good care of it.
This is the last of my family's things.
Please use it to make ammunition or whatever you need.
Please.
Young lady, keep the statue. We'll weigh
your good intentions instead.
I don't want any money.
But how is the war going?
Don't worry. The war will end soon.
It'll end, while we're losing?
You people... you are all men! How
could you speak so irresponsibly?
What have we all been fighting for?!
I may be a woman,
but even I want revenge...
Young lady, we're sorry. He only said
that because he felt bad for you.
Not one of us accepts the idea of losing
the war. I intend to die before it is over.
Please believe in us.
Take cover!
Damn you bastards...
come down here!
Mr. Seki-ne! Are you okay?
Are you hit?
Man, what a surprise.
My balls have shrunk!
If it's broken, my woman will cry.
He's worried about his balls at a time like
this. The guy's got nerves of steel!
Hey boss. If you're so worried,
why don't you stroke it and see?
Yeah.
Oh. It's fine!
Meanwhile, day by day, Japan's economy
was nearing collapse.
Not only was the nation running
out of war machines and fuel...
...but even saltpeter, a key ingredient
of gunpowder, was in short supply.
The necessities of life were available
only in the black-market.
Fearing that this ruinous state of affairs
would soon result in a descent into anarchy...
...senior statesmen such
as Kono-e Fumimaro...
...made appeals to the Emperor,
and maneuvered to end the war.
Prime Minister Suzuki, supported by Foreign
Minister Togo and Navy Minister Yonai...
...asked the Soviet Union, which was neutral
towards Japan, to act as an intermediary...
...but instead, the Soviet Union declared
it was abrogating their treaty.
Soviet diplomatic responses
were uniformly vague.
Meanwhile, the military authorities assumed
that an invasion would precede any peace.
However, the resources available
to mount a defense...
...could only be described
as pitifully inadequate.
At the time, these were the weapons
provided to the citizen's militia.
Have a look. He's an example of the
reservists assigned to our unit.
These folks don't have full uniforms.
We have neither guns nor swords for them.
They have no changes of clothes,
so their underwear is infested with lice.
All they've been eating are daikon-
radish leaves and potato vines.
They're falling down sick left and right
from malnutrition and sleep-deprivation.
This is the fact of the matter.
Chief of Staff... are you going to order
these people to fight the Americans?
Navy Headquarters ordered the
activation of the reservists.
Those orders specified what they should be
paid and how they should be equipped.
What else can we do?
Kozono. I truly understand
what you are saying.
However, we need you all
to endure a little longer.
The enemy will soon land
here on the mainland.
At this time, we're preparing
for a decisive battle.
We've increased production, and we're
stockpiling equipment and provisions.
No matter what Headquarters
says, when the time comes...
...I will personally make sure you
get everything you need.
Your troops are essential to me. Believe
in sure victory, and tough it out for now.
Entering.
Commander Kozono.
Atsugi called.
Navy General Staff Vice Director Onishi
has gone there to inspect the base.
Oh, that's right. Nakai.
Yes sir.
I'm flying out from Takeyama,
go get me a plane.
Yes sir.
It's been chilled at 3,000 meters,
so it should be a suitable temperature.
Let's give it a try.
It's nicely chilled. Atsugi's definitely
the place for beer.
Come here for a drink anytime. But I also
want you to hear what I've got to say.
Your Kagoshima accent's going
to turn our beer bitter.
Sorry everyone, but could you
please give us some privacy?
Yes sir.
Guy who came back from Shanghai told me that
there's a rumor floating around there...
...that the Japanese government is asking the
Soviets to mediate for us. Is this true?
I don't have all the facts,
but it's probably true.
They're not even considering
continuing the war.
What are the top brass panicking about?
And what happens when our men,
who risk their lives every day, learn of this?
They might revolt!
I went to the port depot
to argue my case.
But when it comes to properly using
the reservists, and war strategy...
...the old guard aren't
giving it their all.
We'll never win the war with
such flaky leadership.
Vice Director Onishi, let me tell you face
to face. I'm against suicide attacks.
It's not a path to sure victory.
Isn't it a path to sure defeat?
If every person from the Navy, Army, and the
nation fights with everything they've got...
...we could win, without having
to resort to suicide attacks.
That's the only path we've
got toward peace.
It's as you say.
The young men are the only ones who
are seriously fighting the Americans.
Certainly, it's possible that suicide attacks
might not have been the path to victory.
However, if we weren't so totally committed,
our country couldn't rise to the challenge.
If we fight on to the bitter end, our true
character will be revealed to all.
The people will truly understand
what it means to be Japanese.
Only then can we be sure that the next
generation will follow the right path.
If we agree to peace now, the nation of Japan
will have learned nothing from this war.
The young men making suicide attacks
are sacrifices for this cause.
Yes sir, it is as you say, Vice Director.
I've overstepped my bounds.
Please forgive me.
No... I understand your point of view.
The time will probably come when I'll be needing
your help. Until then, look after yourself.
Soldiers must do their very best within
the confines of military law.
If you step outside that, you'll only
bring misfortune upon yourself.
Yes sir. I, Kozono, am yours
to command, Vice Director.
Hey...
Yes sir.
Is that Kaida's mistress?
No, she's been his fiancee
since his school days.
Yes sir.
Your hair's grown longer since
the last time I saw you.
Come on, do guys really pay that
much attention to such details?
Of course. Because each time I
see you could be the very last.
Hey, foxy.
This is what you call "a swan
in a garbage dump"?
Kaida, this is inexcusable! Why didn't you
tell us that you've got such a fine wife?
Hey, slow down. She's not my wife.
She's the younger sister of a friend from
middle school. Show some respect.
No excuses. Enough with
your little tryst here.
Let's go to the gun-room and have
a grand reception. Right?
Come on, escort her.
Please, this way.
Mr. Yoshinori?
Come on, come on.
You've been captured by riff-raff.
Please, come in.
Please.
Come in.
Here, please come in, Missus.
Please.
Now Missus, this is where you sit.
Hey Kaida! You come and sit right here.
Hurry up!
Leave us alone. We don't
want all this fun.
Endure it. We'll leave you alone
after the wedding party.
Wedding party? Quit kidding around.
We're not kidding.
This is for real! Listen up.
You and Miss Terumi absolutely
must get married!
So, with that in mind, look at this.
Cut the crap!
You're making light of
a big life-decision.
But you two are seeing each other, hoping
that you'll eventually get married, right?
I won't get married while
I'm a fighter pilot.
Think about it. What'll happen
to her after I die?
She's only 20. She'll be a widow at
20. It's cruel to even think about it.
So what if you're a fighter pilot,
it doesn't mean you're going to die!
Love is a moment by moment thing. You're
a hypocrite to worry about the future!
Stop your meddling!
This is private!
Hey Missus. No matter what he says, would
you at least accept our good wishes?
It's fine by me...
Miss Terumi, what are you saying?
Okay then, we're on. The shrine is small,
but it'll still be a Shinto wedding.
Everyone, let us be solemn!
Okay, sit down!
Okay, for this couple: Navy First Lieutenant
Kaida Yoshinori and Sada Terumi...
...we shall hold a temporary
wedding reception.
We can't quite do the traditional three exchanges
of nuptial cups, so please bear with us.
What kind of look is that?!
Get over yourself already!
Come on, Missus. You've got
to look happier than that.
Go ahead, Missus.
Silver wings in formation...
At the front lines in the South...
...vigilant sea-eagles guard.
We are the ammunition of flesh
that destroys enemy forces.
We are the glorious Rabaul Air Corps...
Our Navy spirit burns with bravado.
To the South, we see the shining sun.
We defeat the enemy in the clouds...
Mission accomplished.
...And on the waves.
Good.
We are the glorious Rabaul Air Corps.
(Onishi is writing down the names
of dead special attack soldiers)
Chief. The enemy has landed at Leyte;
They're consolidating their position.
Shouldn't we stop launching
suicide missions now?
The Grumman's are pounding our airfields.
If we engage them, we get shot down.
We're short on equipment, and the
skill-level of our current pilots...
...makes them easy prey for the enemy.
They're pitiful. Just pitiful.
As a leader, it's one of my duties to find
beautiful ways for my men to die.
We will continue the attacks.
I believe that this shows the love
we have for our young men.
Hey... Listen up.
I'm not going to kill you.
I'm letting you go.
So fly to my mom on my behalf. Okay?
I'm asking this of you.
Pilots assemble!
"My dearest mother. I, Tsuyoshi,
am finally going off to fight.
"I have only one regret... that I must
leave my warm and loving mother...
"...without repaying the
great debt I owe her.
"Please only praise me for sacrificing
my life for the sake of the Empire.
"My dearest mother...
"Though I, Tsuyoshi will die, my spirit
will continue to endeavor for the Empire.
"Please do not grieve for me. I, Tsuyoshi,
am happy to be part of this glorious act.
"This is what a warrior lives for!
"My dearest mother... Please
live a long and happy life.
"I, Tsuyoshi, will embrace your
photograph in my heart.
"And thus! And thus will
I die a worthy death!
"-Day of attack: Tsuyoshi."
This is Tsuchida, entering.
Alright, come in.
Vice Director, Boss Kodama
is on the telephone.
Yes. Connect me...
Hello. It's me.
We got some important information,
so I'm calling to let you know.
The Soviet Union is finally massing
troops in Russian-Manchuria.
Supposedly there's over
a million of them.
In addition, they aren't equipped
for winter operations.
Because of this, a faction in the Army
has decided to support peace...
...at tomorrow's Supreme War
Guidance Conference.
It seems to be Yonai's faction
that's pushing for this.
I see. Thanks.
June, 1945. The Soviet Union
has conquered Germany.
Using over 1.5 million troops,
4,900 fighter planes...
...and 3,700 tanks, they launched their
invasion of Russian-Manchuria.
At the secret Yalta conference, the US promised
Sakhalin island and the Kuriles to Russia...
...in return for declaring
war on Japan.
Thus the Soviet Union, which was waiting
for the perfect moment to declare war...
...delayed acting on the request to help
negotiate a peace agreement...
...that had been advocated by Former Foreign
Ambassador Hirota and Ambassador Sato.
Please wait until we are graced by
the presence of His Majesty.
Cabinet Minister, I have come
to make a request.
Please advise His Majesty to never, to never,
adopt a path to peace. I implore you.
Mr. Onishi. You are not authorized
to enter this room.
Japan will win. We shall assuredly win.
Another 20 million special attackers, just
20 million more, would guarantee victory!
Get out.
If we all, as a group,
put our heads together...
...we shall, without a doubt, develop
a new plan. I too will think on this.
Please give us some time.
GET OUT!
Mr. Yonai...
Though Mr. Onishi isn't a member of the cabinet,
I believe he has a right to express his opinion.
In the time before the Emperor arrives,
why don't we hear what he's got to say?
Mr. Toyoda...
Come with us.
Mr. Onishi...
if you've got something to say, then speak
privately to me, the Cabinet Minister.
It's most imprudent of you
to come barging in here.
What did you bring that sword for?
What's that sword doing here?!
How dare you come to the
palace looking like that!
Vice Director Onishi. Apologize
for your insolence.
Then say what you want to say.
Please pardon me.
I... merely... want the Cabinet
Minister to reconsider.
Let me be frank with you.
The decision to make peace... has
been made by His Majesty.
It's not that I don't understand
your perspective.
But I will not allow you to interfere
in political matters.
I am well aware of that.
However, Cabinet Minister...
To honor the heroic souls of the thousands
who have fallen on the field of battle...
...at the very least... let peace
come after a victory.
To placate the souls of heroes,
we launch suicide attacks.
And to placate those new heroic souls,
we would have to launch even more.
It would be an endless cycle...
of death and destruction.
But we must still do it.
It is not a matter of how many die.
What I am talking about is spirit.
We must honor the spirit of the Japanese people,
who have shed so much blood, to the very end.
War is waged in the real world!
Spiritual arguments...
...cannot intrude on the conduct
of international politics.
Even now...
...in one region of the country...
...there are reports of starvation
and chaos.
How do you expect us to fight on?
I arranged for you to join
the Naval General Staff...
...because I believed you
were a pragmatic man.
But perhaps my judgment was wrong.
Cabinet Minister...
We all knew that this war was an impossible
one, even before we started it.
We all knew that our steel production and
oil supplies were inferior to America's.
The premise of the war was illogical, and
now we're trying to resolve it logically.
It's a betrayal to the people
of the nation.
Furthermore...
...in the constitution set down
by the Meiji Emperor...
...and in military law, the word
"surrender" does not appear.
Our front-line soldiers fought to
the last man believing in that.
They chose the path of suicide over
the shame of being taken captive.
If the Imperial decision
is to choose peace...
...it would betray the souls of the
generals and soldiers who died in battle.
You are urging... His Majesty
to take the wrong path.
Do you desire the death and destruction of
the hundred-million people of our nation?
I am speaking of our accountability
as a nation.
Of course, the living are important.
But we also must think of the souls
of those who have died.
Otherwise we shirk our
national responsibility.
Cabinet Minister...
...do you feel nothing...
...towards the souls of the
special attackers?!
Such insolence!
I, as Cabinet Minister...
...do not let my personal feelings
affect political decisions!
Cabinet Minister... Director...
please take your seats.
The government's decision to seek peace
was decided upon in that meeting.
But it was already too late.
As Ambassador Sato waited,
the Soviet leaders continued to stall.
In the meantime, on July 16, the Potsdam
Declaration, an ultimatum to Japan...
...was drawn up by the leaders of
the US, Great Britain, and China.
That same day, the US detonated the world's
first atomic bomb in a desert in New Mexico.
As they no longer needed Soviet
participation in the war...
...they wanted complete control
over Japanese territory.
The Soviets sought to occupy Manchuria,
Hokkaido, and the Kurile islands.
Their struggle for control of the corpse
of the Japanese Empire...
...was the opening battle in
the US and Soviet Cold War.
The Potsdam Declaration, which demanded
Japan's unconditional surrender...
...was announced on July 26th by
the US, Great Britain, and China.
Meanwhile, the government, still hoping
for Soviet mediation on Japan's behalf...
...had to placate extremists such
as Vice Admiral Onishi...
...and so the Prime Minister declared that
the Potsdam Declaration would be "ignored."
But the Americans wanted Japan to surrender
before the Soviets entered the war...
...so they unilaterally interpreted
"ignore" to mean rejection.
They immediately launched a B29 from
Tinian island to drop the atomic bomb.
As soon as they learned that the Americans had
dropped an atomic bomb, the Soviet Union...
...immediately declared war on Japan,
and invaded Manchuria.
The Soviet entry into the war meant that
the Americans needed to force Japan...
...to immediately surrender, and so the
atomic bomb was used a second time.
As there was now no hope of negotiating
a peace, early on August 9th...
...the Emperor informed the government
that he had decided to accept...
...the Potsdam Declaration, and the government
immediately sent a telegram to the Allies...
...acknowledging their acceptance
of unconditional surrender.
"The order to cease fire...
the order to disarm...
"These despicable orders are an
attempt to destroy the Emperor!"
"Having lost faith in assured victory...
"...the government and the senior officers
have committed high treason...
"...and have therefore forfeited their
authority to give us orders."
"Therefore, we hereby declare that we will
reject any and all of their commands!"
You bastard!
"Japan is God's..."
Did you actually send that
telegram to all the bases?
Of course. The Army Command Center in Shiba,
Commander Koga of the submarine forces...
...the Army Air Corps in Tokorozawa
and Sayama...
...and Major Masuda's tank force
have responded positively.
This is absurd. This is a declaration of
a coup d'état. Come to your senses!
Chief... From what you have
said, I believe that...
...you are absolutely opposed to accepting
the Potsdam Declaration.
All of us here at Yokosuka should take
this opportunity to stand together...
...and declare to the government that
we will resolutely continue the war!
Kozono, calm down!
The Emperor has made his decision.
It's our duty to obey Imperial commands.
It is you who has to think calmly.
Surrendering is a sinister plot hatched
by the Emperor's aides!
Not true!
Not true! Our "statesmen"
are selling the country out!
Kozono...
His Majesty has said that he can no longer
bear to see his people suffer.
We have three months of rice.
We're out of fuel.
The production of planes
has ground to a halt.
Where do you think we'll get what
we need to continue the war?
Chief. Have you lost your mind?!
Only just recently,
you told us to hang on...
...to keep the faith, and that we had
ample equipment and provisions.
You were the one who inspired us...
...you said that when the time came, you'd
lead us, no matter what orders we got.
If what you said was a lie, then you...
you are a despicable coward!
Fine. If you are going to obey the
government's orders no matter what...
...you should take responsibility for having
led Japan into its present misfortunes...
...and all of you should
commit suicide!
If you do that, I could return to my unit
and convince my subordinates to stand down.
Obey your orders. If not,
we will suppress you by force!
Orders be damned! The Atsugi Air Corps will
take independent action from now on!
Bastard!
First Lieutenant Nakai! You'd better
think about what you're doing.
Go back to your unit and tell
them to stop fooling around.
What do you mean, "fooling around"?
We've sacrificed everything for this war!
How can we just give up now?!
And you call yourselves
professional soldiers?!
That's enough.
Up until yesterday, you boasted to your
men about your faith in victory.
Day goes by, and you
turn completely around.
You quitters are no longer our peers,
no longer comrades in arms!
You are our enemies!
Farewell!
Commander?
Shit.
You have a terrible fever.
It's Malaria. I had a bout of it in Rabaul.
Shit... This is bad timing.
August 12th: the Ministry of
Foreign Affairs receives...
...the American response
to Japan's surrender.
The requirements for disarmament...
...and subordination of the Emperor to
the Allied Supreme Commander...
...strengthens the cause of the
extremist military faction.
Secretary-Generals Toyoda and Umezu...
...demanded a conference to discuss
the American response...
...but Prime Minister Suzuki and Foreign
Minister Togo insisted that it was unnecessary.
As a result, progress towards a cease-fire
agreement becomes stalled.
Vice Admiral Onishi and others develop
a final plan to continue the war.
The cabinet had been in continuous
session for two days.
As night fell on the second day,
they still had not reached a consensus.
Vice Director Onishi is here. He would
like to see the Secretary-General.
Have him come in.
I heard you went to see Prince
Takamatsu-no-miya.
The prince does not think as we do.
He said that in as much as His Majesty
has no confidence in the military...
...unless there is a plan for assured victory,
he would not act as our emissary to him.
He admonished me thus.
For the military to win His
Majesty's confidence...
...we must present him with a
plan that guarantees victory.
There is no other way to
get him to reconsider.
One more month... if we can continue
to fight for one more month...
...I believe that we will come
up with a good plan.
I too will think upon this with
the utmost seriousness.
We need only one more month...
will this be possible?
Minister of Foreign Affairs... is
there anything you can do?
We would have rejected the Potsdam
Declaration if we had a good plan.
The question is, is there
such a brilliant move?
Mr. Onishi is talking about finding
a way out of a fatal predicament.
I have a good understanding
of everyone's points of view.
As to whether we should try to get some
concessions from the Americans...
...I'm afraid that our only option is to
petition His Majesty to make the decision.
Prime Minister. Enemy air attack!
Please go to the shelter.
Your Excellency, please hurry.
Secretary-General.
Vice Director Onishi...
Chief Secretary... can we not
come up with any ideas?
Isn't there any way... that
we could win the war?
Vice Director. Every avenue has been
exhausted. All that remains...
...is for you to rein in the rebellious
faction of the Navy staff, isn't that so?
I see. So you too think that way.
But how... how do I restrain them?
What is the way of defeat that will satisfy those
who have survived, and those who have died?
Mr. Sakomizu.
This war... did not start because
the people wanted it.
It's a war of nations.
It's a war of nation against nation...
...which means that it is a war between
the leaders of nations.
Until now, hasn't Japan fought
to the bitter end?
If His Majesty the Emperor himself
stood on the battlefield...
...along with the cabinet ministers, the
staff officers, and all our men...
...all of us attacking the enemy
with everything we've got...
isn't that the only way defeat
could be endured?
To opt for peace or not, that's a decision
to be left for the civilians who remain.
I believed there would be a final battle, and
that is why I deployed the suicide troops.
The young men of the special attack forces
believed this too. That's why, that's why...
...they went gladly... to their deaths!
Mr. Sakomizu...
How many men, do you think,
died in the suicide attacks?
Two Thousand Six Hundred men.
Two Thousand Six Hundred!
To those men...
Who will go to those men to tell
them that we've been defeated?
At 10:00 AM the next day, August 14th,
the second Imperial Council was held.
The Emperor stated that in order to explain
Japan's unconditional surrender...
...he himself would speak to
the people of the nation.
As the attendees were overcome
with tears of gratitude...
...the decision to end the Pacific War, which
had lasted 3 years and 8 months, was made.
Your Majesty...
I implore you.
Please continue the war. I implore you.
Please continue the war.
Confections given to us by His Majesty.
There's one for each of us.
It was I who had you sent
to the Philippines.
I, Yonai, know what's in your heart
better than anyone else.
As a military man, you have well-founded
reasons for your principles.
However...
...the day had to come, when someone
had to say the war must end.
If... not just the Americans...
...but the Soviets also invade
the homeland...
...Japan would get partitioned,
just like Germany was.
And if that happened...
...then the national spirit of the people, of
which you speak, would also become divided.
Maybe each side would get
turned against the other.
Indeed...
...surrendering is against
the principles...
...of our national policy since the
time of the Meiji restoration.
Perhaps His Majesty's decision
is not the correct one.
But now...
...the issue isn't whether His Majesty,
one man, has made a mistake.
Our priority is to save 60 million
citizens. I'm sure you agree.
I ask you to accept today's Imperial
Decision as a voice from heaven.
But if you insist on continuing
to fight, no matter what...
...you will give me no choice
but to kill you.
I understand.
I will... give up.
Come... Let's partake of them.
It's over.
However, the war of the Atsugi
Air Corps was not over.
Hinomaru Number Eleven, fly to Kisazaru!
Hinomaru Number Eleven, fly to Kisarazu!
Ten enemy Grumman's are bombarding.
Roger!
That day was the final day of combat
for Japan's Naval Air Corps.
Kaida! Pull up! Bring your nose up!
Kurashima!
Kurashima! Bail out!
Bail out now!
We, reflecting profoundly on
the state of the world...
...and the prevailing condition
of our empire...
...have decided that extraordinary measures
are required to effect a settlement...
...and hereby announce to our
good and loyal subjects...
...that we have ordered our government
to communicate to the governments...
...of the United States, Great Britain,
China, and the Soviet Union...
...that our empire accepts the provisions
of their Joint Declaration.
The security and well-being of the people, and
the prosperity and happiness of the world...
Don't listen to this shit!
...Fate has now dictated that we must bear
the unbearable and endure the unendurable.
Now we must work for peace on behalf
of the generations yet to come.
We will always be with you, and will work
diligently to preserve the nation...
...and our heart is gladdened by
your sincerity and goodwill.
We caution you in the strongest terms
to treat each other with sincerity...
...and to accept the tide of events, lest
we lose the confidence of the world.
Let the entire nation work together as one
family, from generation to generation...
...ever confident that the nation
will endure for all eternity...
...but also mindful of our grave responsibilities
and the long and difficult road ahead.
Come together and devote yourselves
to rebuilding the nation...
...cultivate moral rectitude...
Vice Director Onishi... where are you?!
Commander. Commander!
Commander, the broadcast
is finished. Shall I...
No, I'll do the talking.
Commander! You can't. Hey,
bring me a microphone.
Yes sir!
All of you, stay at your stations and
listen. This is Kozono speaking.
You just heard the words
of His Majesty!
Japan has finally accepted the Potsdam
Declaration, and surrendered.
Because of this, I acknowledge that the
Japanese military is to be disbanded.
So now, we begin a war of defense...
...each of us, as regular citizens,
defending our home soil!
Gentlemen! Each of you is free
to decide whether or not...
...you will fight on.
Therefore, those of you who will fight
with me and continue the war...
...remain in your units. Those who
do not, return to your homes.
I believe in assured victory, and will
keep on fighting no matter what!
Over and out.
Yeah! Let's do it!
Yeah! Let's do it! I'm going to
Kasumi'ga'ura to get me a plane.
Come with me if you want!
I'm going to Kisarazu.
Who'll come with me?!
Who'll go get ammo from
the depot in Yokosuka?
Let's go!
Boss...
How bad is the wound?
Sir...
He slit his stomach in a straight line,
then stabbed his own throat.
When?
I heard the groans at dawn,
then saw what had happened.
"Uncle..."
It's me, Kodama.
Hey...
I kept my promise to my men.
I know. I know it well!
Uncle, I know how you feel.
I know it very well.
Do not act as my second.
Tell the military doctor there
to go downstairs.
I want... I want to suffer as long
as possible before I die.
His heart is unusually strong.
I believe it will take several
more hours.
I've put you through much hardship.
Thank you for being there
for me, all this time.
Uncle...
I'm disappointed in you!
I believed that you'd always
be in good health!
I was looking forward to fighting MacArthur
when they land, together, with you!
I've kept machine guns
and grenades ready!
Now... my dream is gone.
I'm going to join you.
Moron!
You won't be worth shit if you're dead.
I called you here because I've
got things for you to do.
Mr. Kodama... Mr. Kodama...
Go to Atsugi and get Kosono
under control.
Tell him to stop his rash
and blind acts...
...tell him I said so.
Also...
...the prisoners of war... those
that have survived...
...they can come back
to Japan some day.
But those who turned to bones on
foreign soil... can't come back...
...so think about what
you can do for them.
His Majesty the Emperor will give
it careful consideration, I'm sure.
We'll entrust it to His Majesty's noble heart,
and the hearts of the Japanese people.
I will bear witness to it.
This car always gets a flat. Hurry!
Yes sir.
First:
Soldier's primary duty is
to be completely loyal.
Those who are born in our nation...
...must have hearts that are willing
to sacrifice themselves.
Indeed, a strong and loyal heart...
Kozono! Listen carefully!
...Is the true measure of a soldier.
I am Teraoka of the Third Air Fleet.
The man you're waiting for,
Vice Director Onishi...
...has cut his belly and died.
...Has cut his belly and died.
...honing his skills.
Surely you must know why Onishi
chose the path of suicide.
Onishi choked back his tears and gave
up his dream of continuing the war.
He chose death, hoping that his
death would end your rebellion.
Can't you honor his last wish?
All the other soldiers that rose up
have now ended their rebellion.
You can protest all you want, but you
can't reverse the tide all by yourself.
Commander... Commander!
Everyone here has decided to accept
Vice Admiral Teraoka's position.
I am giving the command to stand
down on my own responsibility.
Kozono. You've been relieved of duty
as a Commander since the 16th.
The young men that are following your orders
will be tried for treason if they continue.
Treason? You're right about that!
I shall purge the traitors
who defile God's land!
Vice Director Onishi, where are you?
Calm down!
I, Kozono, will rescue you!
Vice Director Onishi!
Calm down!
Calm down, damn you!
Call the military doctor.
Yes sir.
Bring a sedative.
Release the Commander!
Release him, or we won't let you out!
Fools!
If you're going to disobey orders,
cut my head off first.
Nakai.
Executive Officer!
Executive Officer. The guys in the gun room
are trying to escape by plane!
What?!
Move.
Kaida, wait! Listen to me! Calm down!
Talk is futile.
Calm down!
Hurry!
Kaida! Don't go! That's an order!
Don't die! Don't die!
Kaida, calm down!
Kaida!
Missus...
He's at the airfield.
Hurry!
Missus...
Captain Arai... Kurashima...
Long live the Emperor...
Ten Thousand Years!
The rebel officers that flew to Atsugi
were captured and court-matialed.
Each was given several
years of prison time.
Captain Kozono was admitted to Nobi
Navy Hospital in Fujisawa...
...and the uprising at Atsugi Air
Corps was finally quelled.
On this day, the vanguard of the US
occupation forces landed in Atsugi.
Nurse...
Nurse.
Will you please bring
me a drink of water?
Here you go.
Somebody help!
Emergency!
This way... Hey, this way!
Right, this way!
Gentlemen!
He's up there!
We surrendered... Because the
cowardly cabinet ministers...
...fearing for their lives...
...tricked His Majesty the Emperor...
And made him give up!
Get down from there!
Get down!
Gentlemen!
Now is the time for us
to renew the nation!
The surrender must be a sign to us...
...that we must all unite, purge
the corrupt politicians...
...and prosecute the war
as private citizens!
Your Majesty the Emperor...
Please hear my words.
You have erred.
The war was originally declared
by your own words.
Why now have you surrendered?
What the hell!
Bastard!
Bastards!
You bastards!
Who do you think that man is?!
He's been fighting for all of you!
He's Captain Kozono of the Atsugi Air Corps!
Who are you to throw stones at him?!
Your Majesty the Emperor!
You are...
...you are to be pitied!
You do not realize your own error!
You are to be pitied!
The Vice Director's mansion, where Vice
Admiral Onishi committed suicide...
...still stands at Nanpeidai, near
Shibuya Station in Tokyo.
Though 29 years ago, one heartbroken soldier
took his own life, here in this room...
...today, that event has
been totally forgotten.
"To the heroic souls of the special attack
forces I say, you have fought well.
"You have my deep gratitude.
"You exploded into glory as ammunition
of flesh, believing in final victory.
"However, in the end, your faith
did not result in victory.
"I will atone to the heroic souls of my men, and
to their bereaved families, by my own death.
"Next, as I die, I say to all young men that
rash acts only give advantage to the enemy.
"Follow imperial instructions, and behave
with prudent perseverance. Such is my wish.
"Endure, and do not forget your
dignity as Japanese people.
"All sons are national treasures.
"Let them victoriously maintain the spirit
of special attacks, even in times of peace.
"Endeavor to do your utmost to promote
the well-being of the Japanese people...
"...and work for peace and harmony
with all of humanity."