Pedro?
Theo?
Theo, how did you get in?
Can you believe that Pedro
left me waiting...
at the exchange student meeting?
- What do you mean?
- He didn't show up.
I called him up,
he didn't answer the phone.
- He didn't show up.
- So?
Branca, I called you up
and you didn't answer the phone.
I've been ringing the bell for half an
hour, you didn't answer the door.
And you left this door here open.
Theo, there's no way.
You can't just keep coming in
like this, without calling first.
Branca, I'm sorry.
Is Pedro here?
- And you can't have a key anymore.
- Branca, if our only problem...
is me having or not having
the key to this place...
- we were doing alright, huh?
- Yeah, that's not the problem.
I'm the problem.
For me to continue living here, huh?
That's the problem, right?
I brought Zezé's money.
I want you to pay him...
only after he finishes
waterproofing the pool.
- Can you do that?
- Why waterproof it?
The tiles, they'll be delivered
next week, they're already paid for.
- Why tiles?
- Why? I don't know, Branca.
Maybe to cover the hole
out there on the verandah.
I don't know
why you're making a pool...
if we're going to sell the house, Theo.
Because it'll bring the price up,
right? Because we'll make money.
But, maybe the guy who buys it
doesn't want a pool...
- Yeah, he might not like the house.
- Might not know how to swim.
Let's stop around here, please.
I'm tired as hell. We don't even know
if we're going to sell the house.
What do you mean?
You don't seem to understand.
As soon as I find my own place,
I'm leaving.
Do you understand?
- Where were you, son?
- My computer broke.
I took it to get fixed.
We had an appointment today,
did you forget?
You had. Alone.
I had an appointment.
Alone.
It was important for him to go today.
Today was the day...
They have this rule there,
that says the kids...
have to go at least one day.
If they don't go one day...
To be able to pick your city.
You have to go just once.
Just one time.
To guarantee you get Christchurch,
I had to pay.
- Now, he'll have to go next time.
- You paid?
You'll have to go
to the next meeting...
Otherwise, there's no way we
can guarantee you can pick your city.
Dad, I'm not going!
I don't want to!
You don't...
Why aren't you going, Pedro?
Just for me...
The way I see it, I'm
giving him a good opportunity, right?
Am I wrong?
Isn't it something good?
A trip? For you to speak English,
go to the best country
in the world.
If I were a sheep.
Theo, you can't force
something like this...
But, I gave him two options.
On two different continents.
I wish my father had
given me something like this.
It can't always be the
way you want it.
You thought it was
a good idea.
And you're going to decide for him?
- And when is he going to decide?
- When he decides, Theo. If he decides.
You can't just send the
boy off to Australia.
New Zealand.
That's not the issue.
The issue is always
something else, huh?
Yes.
It's always something else.
What's that, Branca?
What's what?
- Theo...
- What is this chair doing here?
It's for his birthday, Theo.
- Why are you doing this to me?
- Nobody is doing anything.
Why are you doing
this, man?
Why this?
What is this, Branca?
- Calm down, Theo.
- What is it?
What is this chair
doing here?
Why are you
doing this, Branca?
- Wait, Theo, take it easy.
- Why are you doing this to me?
- What is this chair doing here, Pedro?
- My grandfather sent it.
Your grandfather?
But, what grandfather, Pedro?
- Listen, Theo...
- Who is your grandfather?
- I'm going to put it in my room.
- Wait, hold it.
Who is your grandfather?
- Dad...
- What grandfather?
- I'm going to put it in my room.
- Hold it, Theo.
Just a second, Branca.
Let me ask him.
- Right, but don't be like this.
- Does he know his grandfather?
Who is your grandfather?
Do you know him?
- Give me my chair.
- Has your grandfather ever seen you?
- Dad.
- Does he know you?
- Let go.
- Hold it. Let me talk to you.
- Let go of my chair.
- Does your grandfather know you?
Hold it! Does your
grandfather know you?
He doesn't know me!
He doesn't know you!
- He doesn't know you!
- You don't even live here anymore!
- Give me my chair!
- He doesn't know me!
- He doesn't know you!
- Give me my chair!
- Stop it, Theo!
- I'll show you all!
- Don't do that, Theo!
- Dad!
Do you want your key?
FATHER'S CHAIR
DOCTOR BRANCA GADELHA
Pedro?
Are you going?
Have they come to
pick you up already?
I'll be back on Sunday, mom.
- Have dinner with me?
- Yes.
Kisses.
Happy birthday!
I got my things.
I'm going.
- I'll help you.
- No problem.
I'm sorry.
- You didn't have to do that, Theo.
- I know, I'm sorry.
Really, you shouldn't
have done it.
Can you forgive me?
Did you know
about this chair?
- Theo...
- It isn't easy for me, Branca.
I know.
Go back home and
I'm not living there anymore...
it isn't easy.
I'm sorry.
Is Pedro up?
Pedro went on a trip.
- It's his birthday on Sunday.
- He went someplace with Levy.
Did you let him go?
He didn't ask, Theo.
But, the exchange program,
I don't know...
I thought it was something good.
I thought that it was
something he'd like,
that was good for him...
good for him to stay
away a bit, on his own...
while we worked things out.
Things aren't going to
work out, Theo.
But, he doesn't have
to stick around and watch.
- I'm leaving that house.
- I'm not talking about that anymore.
- I don't...
- I've already given your key back.
- I never wanted to live in that house.
- I won't go there anymore.
You don't want me to go?
I won't go.
Branca, I made
that house for you.
It was always something
you wanted, Theo.
Let me talk.
I made that house for you.
- Right.
- Branca.
- Theo...
- I made the house for you, for Pedro...
I made the house for us.
- Stop it.
- What's happened to us? Tell me.
- Theo, we've already talked about this.
- What's happening, Branca?
What do you want me to do?
Tell me.
- Theo...
- What do you want me to do?
What do you want me to do?
Tell me?
Tell me.
Theo, let me go.
Theo, please.
Theo...
Hold it, Theo.
- Hi.
- Hi, Theo.
So, I'm going to have dinner
with Pedro on Sunday, at home.
- If you want to show up.
- OK.
I'll go.
How's it going?
Hi, Theo.
Come in.
You've already made dinner.
No problem.
Put it here.
- It's just that Pedro likes...
- Yeah, he loves it.
Do you want to
drink something?
Water.
Thanks.
Sit down, Theo.
I can't figure...
this out...
I don't now...
- It's here.
- No.
There's just one cable.
Looks good.
Yeah, he likes these here...
And the grant?
- Only in September.
- Yeah right, you said before.
Have you decided
where you're going?
I think I prefer Spain.
For your specialty, the
United States would be better, huh?
It's just that in Spain, besides
medical school, there's Spain.
Yeah.
- Pedro's taking too long.
- Did he say what time he'd be here?
- He didn't say.
- Didn't you tell him?
- I just said dinner.
- Let's call?
I've already called twice.
I'm going to call Levy.
Hello, Levy?
Hi, it's Branca.
So, are you guys back already?
What do you mean, "from where"?
Didn't you guys travel, Levy?
What do you mean?
Isn't Pedro there
with you?
Hold it, Levy.
You don't know?
Where's Pedro?
- Renata.
- Hi, Theo.
- How's everything?
- Hi, Renata.
So, Levy?
What's going on?
Pedro told Branca that he was going
to spend the weekend with you.
He didn't say anything to me.
You haven't spoken to him?
He didn't call? Nothing?
- Since Saturday.
- Didn't Pedro tell you, Levy...
where he was going to
spend the weekend?
- No, he didn't tell me anything.
- Tell the truth, son.
- Levy, he said...
- I am.
He told me he was going
to travel with you, Levy.
No, he didn't come here.
He didn't tell me anything.
- No way, Levy.
- Levy...
We hardly talked this week.
OK, no problem.
Listen...
Do you know if he's been
hanging out with someone else?
If he's got other friends?
If he might be spending the night at
somebody's house that we don't know?
- No, Theo. Nothing's changed.
- Listen, Levy, think.
Think a bit if you remember
anything... something...
he might have done
different, during the week.
At school. Nothing?
You don't remember?
- Think, son.
- I don't know, Levy, if you realize...
just how serious this is.
Pedro disappeared.
Do you understand?
He disappeared!
- Branca, Branca. Levy.
- Think back, son.
Anything you remember
might be important now.
There is something,
he asked me for...
he wanted the address to
my Uncle Abrão's store.
- Who is your Uncle Abrão?
- He has a computer store.
He wanted to sell
his computer.
Didn't you say that he wanted
to fix his computer?
Yeah, he wanted to get it fixed.
No, he said he wanted to sell it.
- What are you talking about, Levy?
- No, he wanted to fix his computer.
- He told us that...
- He told me he wanted to sell it, Theo.
He tried to sell
his computer to my uncle...
but he didn't want to buy it.
What did he want to
sell his computer for?
He said he needed money.
Are you sure you got
the right number?
No, Theo. I don't know my own
son's telephone number.
- Call home, see if he's arrived.
- I just called, Theo.
We've got to go to
the hospitals, police stations.
- Make a list.
- He told me he'd be back Sunday.
- So he thought he'd be back on Sunday.
- You're trying to find coherence...
- in a lunatic's attitudes.
- He's just a boy.
- A lunatic, a lunatic. A lunatic.
- He's fourteen. He's a boy, Theo.
When I was his age,
I was at home...
taking care of
my mother, alone.
I was on the beach.
Thank God.
I'm going to call Cynthia.
What Cynthia?
The Secretary of Health.
She can check out
the public hospitals...
we'll check out the private ones.
Cynthia, it's Theo.
I wouldn't be calling
you at home, Cynthia, but it's...
an emergency.
It's Pedro, my boy.
He's disappeared, Cynthia.
Are you OK?
I'm OK.
Pedro?
Pedro? Honey?
Son?
Pedro are you home?
Pedro, call me as soon
as you get in.
Theo...
Hello. Please,
is this Pedro Gadelha's house?
On Catumbi... Street.
What's this one called?
See what it says.
There. This is it.
What's the number.
It's 352.
There.
CENTER FOR ZOONOSIS CONTROL
MONDAY TO FRIDAY
FROM 9 AM TO 5 PM
This is Relâmpago.
He took Relâmpago.
We like to call
after a few days...
to check in and see how
the animal is getting along.
It's just that it might take
a while to adapt to new surroundings.
A horse? He took a horse?
Yeah, a great horse.
He wasn't young,
but still very strong.
Pedro bought a horse?
He adopted Relâmpago.
What do you mean, adopted?
He didn't pay for him,
he took the animal...
with the responsibility
of taking care of it.
It's a system we have.
Where did he take the horse?
- To his house in the country.
- What house?
- What country house?
- He said he was...
- taking it to his country place.
- Pedro doesn't have...
a house in the country.
We don't have a country home.
- If he lied...
- He lied.
If he didn't have the proper facilities
to take care of the animal...
- Excuse me. Let me ask you something.
- that makes things worse, because...
it goes against one
of our basic norms...
Please. Alright, let me ask you
just one question.
Did Pedro leave an address
of this country house?
- That's not necessary.
- It's not necessary...
My friend, how in earth
did you let...
a 15 year-old boy leave
with a horse?
-15?
- Yeah, 15.
What do you mean, 15?
This makes things a lot worse.
What's this?
Pedro did this?
This is false.
Can't you see?
Well, there's so many forms
to fill in...
- so many documents...
- It's ringing. Wait.
If your son falsified this,
that would be fraud...
- It's Pedro.
- If he falsified...
Hello, Pedro? Hello?
Hello, who's talking?
Who's talking?
- Give it to me...
- Hello.
That's my son's phone.
Who's talking?
Hello? Hello?
- Yes.
- What is it, Theo?
You think, or you saw?
What did you see?
- I'm going with you, Theo.
- You go home.
- No, no. I'm going with you, Theo.
- Let me talk.
- Listen, you have to...
- I'm going with you, Theo!
Branca, you have to go home.
- No, I'm not going home.
- Let me talk. Let me talk!
- Let me talk. You have to...
- No.
Listen to me.
You have to go home...
because if Pedro comes back,
if he calls...
I need you to be
at home, OK?
- You have to go home.
- Will you bring Pedro back?
- Are you going to bring Pedro home?
- Yes I am, I'll bring him back.
Bring Pedro
back to me, Theo!
- Please, Theo!
- I'll bring Pedro back home.
- I'll bring him, OK?
- Theo, bring Pedro back to me.
OK, go on. Go on.
Pedro? Hello?
As soon as you get
this message...
Hey.
It looks like an accident, huh?
There are a bunch
of shacks here.
In this community.
Who knows, somebody
who lives here...
might have seen something,
understand?
I wish I could be
more helpful, but...
Good luck. I hope you
find your kid.
Thanks a lot, OK?
Good luck.
Good morning.
- Good morning.
I'm looking for my son,
he's just a kid.
Did you see a boy
come through here with a horse?
No, I didn't.
I didn't see anything.
Thank you.
Ma'am, please.
I need some help.
There was an accident nearby...
either Saturday or Sunday, I think...
I'm looking for my son.
A boy.
A 15 year-old boy,
- maybe riding a horse­
- A black horse?
A black horse, a black horse.
Did you see it?
- No.
- But, it was a black horse.
You said so. Did you see a boy
on a black horse?
I didn't see anything,
but grandma did.
- Your grandmother saw him?
- Not my grandmother, Grandma.
- Where does she live?
- She lives over there.
- Can you take me there?
- But, now?
Now, now. Please.
He slept here, mister.
Like a rock.
- Malina, wake up.
- Malina!
- It's mine! Get up!
You can't do that.
Didn't he tell you
where he was going...
or what he was doing
with this horse?
Didn't say anything, mister.
Here, Quico, give him his bottle.
- Listen ma'am...
- He hurt his leg.
He hurt his leg?
Yeah, and I didn't have
anything for it.
- I gave him some tea.
- Ma'am, just a second.
How did he hurt his leg?
It was scratched up very bad.
Ma'am, could I ask you
to hold it still just for a bit?
Just a bit, please.
Was he alright?
He was alright, mister.
He sleept, woke up,
ate like a pig,
grabbed his things and left.
- Where did he go?
- Only Beto would know that.
- Who is Beto, ma'am?
- Who is Beto? Beto is Beto, mister!
Malina, take him
over to Beto's place.
- But, now?
- Now!
Let's go.
Don't want it, don't drink it.
Beto?
- Beto!
- I'm coming.
OK, this is fine.
- You see that road there?
- That one?
Yes! Follow it.
That's where your boy went.
Horses are made for dirt roads,
not for traffic.
The horse shied.
I've seen lots of folks get killed
by animals on the asphalt.
Didn't he say anything
about where he was going?
Salvador.
He's going to Salvador?
No, Espírito Santo.
Salvador or Espírito Santo?
Salvador or Espírito Santo.
That's it, without a doubt.
One or the other,
both down that road.
Theo?
Everything's OK, Branca.
He's alright. No problem. He's alive.
He's alive, Theo?
He spent the night
at this woman's house.
I met her.
He left early the next day.
- She doesn't know where he's going.
- He's OK?
He hurt his leg...
Just a scratch, a scratch.
I don't know.
I'm going to follow this road here.
That guy doesn't know
what he's talking about.
First he says he's going to Bahia then,
that he's headed to Espírito Santo.
I mean...
We just don't know, man.
- Where is he headed?
- Theo I...
looked through his whole room,
his computer isn't here.
I don't know where it is.
So, send him a message then.
Send him a message, who knows,
he might still have it and...
- he answers.
- Alright.
You find him, OK?
Find him and bring him home.
Hey!
Mister!
Did you see a boy come
through this way on a horse?
- Yeah!
- You saw him?
- Yeah.
- When did you see him?
- He crossed yesterday.
- Crossed to where?
To the other side.
How'd he cross?
I crossed him.
- In that?
- Here.
Him and the horse. Why?
Could you cross...?
Could you ferry...?
Will that thing hold my car?
Hold your car, for sure,
but there's no way.
Why?
- The tide is low.
- No, we can do it.
We can do it. I'll help you.
We can do it.
- No way.
- I'll help you. The two of us...
We'll push.
Can you make it here?
Hold it.
Listen ma'am, it's my son.
The boy is my son. Please.
Bring the boat
over here, please?
Please.
I'll help you, the two of us.
If you push here, it'll go.
Look here.
Back there, if you...
Look. It's shallow here.
Look here, if you...
Mister, it's no use.
If you just help me...
If you help me, we can do it.
It's just a matter of
pushing here, look.
If I put, if I put the pole...
You got a dinghy or something?
Did you talk to him?
He asked me
what horses eat.
- He didn't know?
- No.
Did he tell you
anything?
Did he say where he was headed?
Anything.
He asked me for a discount
for the horse.
He didn't think that a horse
had to pay the same as people.
"Relâmpadu."
- Did he say "relâmpago"?
- Du.
Relâmpago is the name
of Pedro's horse.
Did he say the horse's name?
- "Relâmpadu."
- Relâmpago.
Relâmpago.
Yeah, did you see the horse?
Pedro's horse?
Is this the boy
with the horse you saw?
But horses
weigh more than people.
If it had been anyone else,
I'd charge the horse...
near to what I'd charge for a car.
He was broke?
No, he had money.
Then later, he wanted my cap.
Offered me 20 reais for it.
But I wouldn't sell my cap.
- He wanted to buy that cap?
- Yeah.
- That one there?
- Right.
Want one?
You guys live here
on the boat?
For a long time now.
And that's your boy?
Yeah.
Pedro.
Doesn't look like him.
It's just that he's only...
- How old is your boy?
- Five.
Yeah, five. Five, six...
Younger.
Don't look anything like
the guy on the horse.
He grew up.
Hey.
You can keep the tractor.
Sorry for the trouble, I...
- Where did you get that T-shirt?
- Keep it.
- Keep the tractor.
- That T-shirt belongs to my boy.
- I took it just for this one job.
- Why are you running?
- You can keep it.
- Hey!
- Keep it!
Hey!
Where's my boy?
Where's Pedro?
Are you crazy?
Are you from Town Hall?
Mister, are you from
the Town Hall?
My boy.
- Where's Pedro?
- Let me go, let me go!
- Are you crazy, shit? Are you crazy?
- Where's my son?
- Are you crazy, shit?
- Where's Pedro?
What Pedro?
Where's Pedro?
Pedro?
The kid who
owned this T-shirt?
You are fighting me because
of this fucking T-shirt!
I thought you were
from the Town Hall, shit!
I traded this shirt with Pedro.
The kid came by and traded me
a bottle of pinga for it.
For God's sake.
I thought you were...
He headed that way,
down that road.
Go on after him.
You can catch up to him.
Go on!
They're here, Mrs. Branca.
- What's that?
- Tiles.
What do we do
with the tiles?
WHERE ARE YOU?
CALL HOME
WE'RE DESPERATE...
GIVE SOME SIGN PEDRO...
Good morning.
Did you, by any chance, see a kid
come through here on a horse?
Would you know where I can
find a telephone around here?
Ma'am?
Good morning.
Could you tell me where I might
find a phone around here?
- Telephone?
- Telephone.
A telephone here,
only with Custódio.
- Where does Custódio live?
- Next door.
This house here?
Thank you.
Custódio?
- Good morning.
Mr. Custódio,
my name is Theo, Theo Gadelha.
Your neighbor told me
that you have a phone.
I'm looking for my son, a boy...
who's disappeared. He might have
come through here, on a horse.
Have you seen a boy
coming by here on a horse?
- A boy on a horse?
- A boy on a black horse.
Horses come by here
all the time.
I can't remember
all the colors, right?
Could you lend me your phone,
please?
I have to call my wife.
Is it working?
- What's wrong?
- No credit.
But, it won't be long, Mr.
Custódio. I'll make it real quick.
No, I can't run out
of credit.
My daughter
doesn't like it.
No problem.
This is what we'll do...
I'll give you some money
and you buy some more credit.
No. They don't sell it here.
Where did you
buy this credit?
My daughter.
Your daughter. So we'll give...
I'll even get some more here.
We'll give her more money.
With this, you can
even buy a new phone.
My daughter
only gets here on Friday.
Mr. Custódio...
- I really need your help.
- I can't.
I use a pacemaker.
If there's any problem,
I have to call my daughter.
I know what we can do.
Right, there's no problem.
I'll just make a collect call.
- You know what a collect call is?
- No, no, no.
I'll explain it to you...
Just for you to understand.
The call is collect, you don't pay.
- You know what a collect call is?
- It'd be better not to.
Do you know what a collect call is?
It'd be better if you just left.
- That doesn't make any sense.
- It would be better.
- Are you trying to give me a hard time?
- I already told you mister.
My daughter wouldn't like it.
And I already told you that
you won't have to pay anything.
Are you deaf?
I'm not deaf,
I have a heart condition.
And you can leave now!
I'll leave the money here.
I need to find my son.
I'm really sorry about this.
You can buy a new phone.
Are you crazy?
Come back here!
Hey, buddy!
Stop! Stop!
Come back here!
Come back here, young man!
Help me! Help me!
Help me!
Come back here!
That's my phone!
Stop! Stop!
- Hello, Theo?
- He's OK, Branca.
He's OK. Believe me...
- He crossed a river.
- What river, Theo?
A river... in a mangrove...
He crossed on a ferry.
I talked to the owner of the ferry.
They guy told me that he talked to him,
he had money and he was alright.
He wanted to
buy the guy's cap.
- And he's alright?
- Branca,
I've met two people
who have talked to Pedro already.
He traded his T-shirt...
He's fine. He's getting along.
Find him for me.
Bring him home.
I'm going to take him
home today.
I'm getting close.
I'm real close now.
I'm on a hurry.
Hey! Hey! Guy!
Mister, mister. Please, please.
Could you give us a lift?
We ran out of gas.
- Where are you going man?
- I'm going to Mimoso.
It's a festival,
not far from here.
- And what's going on there?
- Lots of music, lots of rock.
Very crazy.
And guys, like your age,
are going there?
Yeah, basically,
just people our age.
And there are some friends of mine
too. Hold on, let me call them.
- Mimoso?
- It's not far.
You have to go through here.
Hey, man. Are you going to do us
this favor, give us a lift?
- You'll take us to Mimoso?
- Hold it.
Where are you going?
- Where am I going?
- Yeah.
- That's a good question.
- You don't know?
Do us a favor man.
Take us to Mimoso.
It's not far.
- I'm looking for my son.
- What do you mean? You lost him?
I lost him.
But, I'm going to find him.
He's a kid your age.
A bit younger. He's on a horse.
On a horse.
Man, he's going to Mimoso
for sure. The Winter Festival.
Filled with kids our age.
Who knows, you just might
find him there.
- He's in Mimoso for sure man.
- Let's go? Let's go?
- Let's go to Mimoso.
- Let's go guys. Let's go. Come on.
Let's go to Mimoso.
Hold it a second.
- Come on, come on.
- Real quick, man. Not many things.
Go, go, hurry.
Come on, China. Move it man.
There, that's it. Go, go.
- Get in. Get in.
- There, that's all.
Thanks a lot, really man.
Let's go, let's go.
Where are you guys coming from?
- Belo Horizonte.
- BH.
- BH is very far from here, huh?
- More or less.
- Didn't take us long.
- No big deal.
And that car, whose father
does it belong to?
Mine.
And you're going to just leave it
in the middle of the road?
It's all locked.
No problem.
- Nobody is going to steal it, no way.
- I'm feeling bad.
- So you just take it easy there.
- That's what I'm doing.
- Don't hassle me.
- Are you OK?
- He's feeling queasy.
- Poor thing.
Chocolate isn't very good if
you're feeling queasy man.
- You got chocolate man?
- Give it to me.
It's my chocolate.
Want some?
Thanks a lot, man.
Thanks a lot. Really.
Hi. Hi. I'm going to ask you
Just one thing.
Money.
It's because I lost my purse...
and I'll find it, but
it's going to take some time.
And I need a ham and
cheese sandwich right now.
- Ham and cheese?
- Yeah, ham and cheese.
I'm looking for my son.
Man, this place is filled with sons.
Take your pick.
But my son is different.
My son...
My son
has a black horse.
A horse? No way.
I was sure it was just some story.
You mean that he really
did come on a horse?
Maura took a whole bunch...
- of pictures with him.
- Who's Maura?
And you know how it is,
not everything Maura tells me is...
- Where is she?
- At Patrick's.
- Can you take me there?
- Sure.
But can you buy me a sandwich?
Please, I'm starving to death.
I took an acid yesterday
and the festival is today...
What? Don't tell me
you've never done that?
Thanks a lot
for this sandwich, really.
- Stop there, please.
- At this gate here?
I'll open it, you can park
near the trailer.
My bed.
This guy lives here, this Patrick?
Patrick was my French teacher
at school.
- You know São Fernando?
- Yeah.
During summer vacation, he bought a
whole bag of acid and came to Mimoso.
And, a couple bags later,
he's still here.
- Does your father know you're here?
- Here, exactly, I sure hope not.
- Let's go?
- Let's go.
They probably are in the river.
- Patrick.
- How's it going?
- Ça va?
- Ça va bien.
Patrick, I'm Theo.
Patrick. And so?
- The girl...
- Alice.
She told me that my boy slept here,
at your campground.
- And who is your boy?
- Pedro.
Pedro? God!
- How did he do that, huh?
- The thing with the horse?
- A whim. An insane trip.
- I'd like to know that too.
An insane trip.
Is he around? Where is he?
Is he still here?
He left.
This one doesn't work.
Have to take it to...
- He's already gone?
- Yeah.
Do you know where?
He was in a hurry.
Said he couldn't stay.
I even joked around with him.
I told him...
"If you're in a hurry,
going by horseback...
isn't the fastest means
of transportation, right?"
But then I started thinking
to get up...
and leave before the party,
he must have been in a hurry.
- But, did he spend the night here?
- Yeah, he spent the night.
He bunked down in Maura's tent.
The two of them got
real cozy, you know? So cute.
That's Maura.
Maura!
Stop it! Stop it!
You creeps, no!
Go there.
No, no, no.
Take me back.
Man, it hurts so bad.
Maura? My name is Theo.
Pedro's father.
You don't look like Pedro, do you?
Cissa, take me back
into the water, please.
- Help me back into the river?
- Aren't you cold?
- No. My baby is going to be born.
- No.
I want him to be
born in the river.
- Are you cold?
- Can you take me to the river?
Your baby can't be
born in the river.
Yes, he can. I want...
- to have him in the water.
- No, no he can't.
It's too cold.
This girl has got to go
to a hospital, Patrick.
That'd be the São Pedro Hospital.
Two hour drive from here.
No, I'm not going
to any hospital.
No way! My boy is going to be
born here! I want him to be...
- Hold it, Maura, Maura.
- Take me to the river!
Hold it, let me talk
with you.
You can't have
your baby in the river.
You can't do that, understand?
It's too cold.
But I'm right here to help you, OK?
I'm going to help you.
I'm a doctor and
- No. No doctors, no doctors.
- No, no, no. No, doctor no.
I'm Pedro's father.
And look, we're right
beside the river.
The river is right here beside us.
You don't need to get any closer.
OK?
Can you hear the water?
Tell everyone to be quiet,
everyone.
Hey guys, move back.
Move back. Take it easy.
- Let's listen to the river.
- Move!
Can you hear it?
We're right beside the river.
Your baby is going
to be born by the river.
OK?
Patrick.
Get me some towels,
or clean cloth...
- a pan full of boiling water.
- Right.
Wait, Patrick.
Some scissors and alcohol.
That pinga there will do.
- To wash my hands.
- No.
- So, I don't look like Pedro?
- Pedro is better looking than me?
- Yeah. Better­
I want you to open your legs
a bit more, OK?
Just a bit more. Like this.
I'm right here with you, OK?
We're going to do this
together, right?
I'm here to help you.
And now do one more thing.
Open your legs just a bit more.
Can you do that?
I know, it hurts. That's it.
- That's it, right. Just a bit.
- It hurts.
We're going to do this together,
alright? Both of us.
I'm here to help you.
Every time a contraction starts,
you are going to push it, OK?
OK? OK? Right, now. Go on.
That's it! That's it!
That's it, Maura.
Right, like that.
Just like that, right.
Now take a deep breath. Look at
the river. Listen to the river.
We're here together.
Take it easy, everything will be fine.
I'm here with you.
Go on, the baby is coming.
It's coming.
It's coming already.
Go on now,
once again, that's it!
That's it, Maura!
That's it. I can feel his
head right here.
He's coming out.
That's it, Maura.
That's it.
He's right here, he's coming out.
Now breath in deep,
he'll come out the next time now.
The next time he'll be born.
He wants to be born.
- It hurts so much.
- I know it hurts, I know.
We'll do this together.
I'm right here with you.
OK? Let's go.
That's it, right.
Push hard! Harder!
Push hard, go on.
That's it. He's coming out.
There, Maura! That's it!
Like that.
He's coming out. Now!
That's it.
Here, he's here.
He's born. He's born.
He's right here, here.
The garbage truck's here.
Want me to throw this away?
Throw it away.
55 PIRATININGA STREET
SÃO PAULO
MISSING HIM REMINDED ME
OF OTHER THINGS I MISSED
HUGS
YOUR GRANDPA
"My present mug.
And yours, what's it like?"
"I've always thought that the
less you have,
the less you lose.
So, all I had was a horse.
An old horse, not much
good for anything.
But then, my horse died."
Hold it!
Wait! Wait a second!
- Branca?
- Theo, it's me, Branca.
Theo, he went to
his grandfather's place.
Pedro went to
your father's house.
He went to Espírito Santo, to your
father's country place.
He and your father were
sending each other drawings.
They've been in touch,
they've talked to each other.
For a long time now.
Theo, pay attention.
Write it down. Listen, it's...
Ponta Negra, Km 187.
Did you get that?
Theo, this is about Pedro now, OK?
The rest is the rest.
You can see about that later.
Can you hear me?
Get in the car.
I'm taking you to the hospital.
Where's my car?
What were you doing in
the middle of the road like that?
I have to find my boy.
Your boy can wait.
I'm taking you to a hospital.
No.
I'm going to find my son.
- Can you drive?
- I think I broke a rib,
if you have any type of cloth,
a bandage, an old sheet.
You have scissors?
Thank you.
When you find your boy,
take him home.
Don't say anything,
just take him home.
It was him...
My boy, who drew this.
- Your boy?
- Yeah.
Pedro. My son.
Some kid came here,
starving to death. Flat broke.
So I made a deal with him.
- Would you sell it to me?
- No.
This is you here, right?
Yeah.
The kid is good, got talent.
Hey, bro, who do you think I am?
I'm real close.
I think I'll catch him up
in half and hour now.
And how is he?
Is he OK?
I just talked to this guy
and he said that he was great,
I mean, hungry as hell,
and traded a plate of food...
for one of his
drawings, Branca.
The drawing is great.
It's a guy surrounded by women,
you know...
the type you see
in garages, these pinups.
I offered to buy it, but he didn't
want to sell it.
He really liked the drawing.
I'm close. Close.
- I'll catch him up soon.
- That's so good to hear, Theo.
Branca...
I love you.
Kisses.
And this motorbike here?
Want a make a deal?
What's wrong, buddy?
An accident.
Animal on the road.
Pedro.
BEACH
Hi, dad.
Theo.
Is that you?
Someone gave you
a good beating, huh?
A few.
You see?
It's amazing, don't you think?
He draws.
Your son draws.
He's like me.
He's very good.
Yeah, I didn't know.
I'm as deaf as a door.
I can't hear you.
If you want to cuss me out,
it'll have to be face-to-face.
Go on.
I didn't know that Pedro
knew how to draw.
I can't hear you,
I don't understand.
Nothing, forget it.
He draws.
I wrote Pedro a letter...
and sent him a drawing
of my face.
Well, I never thought that
he'd answer.
And he sent me
a drawing and a letter.
I thought he was such a...
so...
So I...
I started thinking...
you have such a good kid
like that, such a great kid...
I imagined
if you didn't think...
of all the things I lost
with you...
and let me be
the boy's grandfather.
He crossed two states
just to meet you.
I don't understand.
I can't hear you.
Pedro rode through
two states on a horse...
to meet you.
On a horse? He came on horseback?
Are you sure? On a horse?
He brought me a horse.
He did.
THIS MOVIE IS DEDICATED TO CHRIS RIERA.
FOR WHAT SHE WAS IN OUR STORIES AND LIVES.