[FANFARE PLAYS]
[CROWD ROARING]
[EXHALING HEAVILY]
[PAPER RUSTLES]
[♪♪♪]
I NOW CALL UPON BERNIE,
THE BELOVED SON
OF OUR BELOVED MIRI,
TO SAY A FEW WORDS.
[PAPER CRINKLING]
I JUST WANTED TO SAY THANK YOU
TO EVERYONE FOR BEING HERE.
IT MEANS A LOT TO ME
AND TO MY AUNT BARBARA.
ANYONE WHO EVER KNEW MY MOM
KNEW THAT
NOBODY EVER REALLY
KNEW MY MOM.
UH, SHE VALUED "HER PRIVACY,"
TO USE HER WORDS,
AND THERE'S A LOT
OF CONVERSATIONS
THAT WE NEVER GOT A CHANCE
TO HAVE,
AND THAT'S A GREAT REGRET
OF MINE,
BUT I DO KNOW THAT SHE LOVED...
HER PIANO VERY MUCH.
SHE PLAYED IT BEAUTIFULLY.
SHE LOVED VODKA...
AND SHE LOVED ME.
I JUST WANTED TO READ
THIS LITTLE POEM
THAT I WROTE FOR MY MOM.
[♪♪♪]
MOM, I DID MY BEST,
THOUGH
YOU ARE NOT VANQUISHED,
ONLY LAID HERE TO REST.
FROM PAIN
TO BREATH DRAWN,
NOW ON
TO A BETTER PLACE.
[VOICE BREAKS]:
SLEEP TIGHT, MOM.
THANK YOU.
THANK YOU, BERNIE.
[CONTINUES SERVICE IN HEBREW]
[RUSSIAN ACCENT]:
EXCUSE ME.
[RABBI]: OH, GOD,
FULL OF COMPASSION,
THOU WHO DWELLEST ON HIGH--
SHHH!
GRANT PERFECT REST--
WHO IS THIS GUY?
SHH, SHH, SHH, SHH.
SHH! SHH.
IS HE WITH YOU?
[GRUMBLING SIGH]
[PAPER RUSTLING]
[CLEARS HIS THROAT]
YOU ARE NOT DEAD,
THE WIND STILL
LIVES IN YOUR HAIR.
IT CIRCLES ME
AND PULLS ME TOWARD YOU.
YOUR EYES ARE NOT CLOSED.
THEY SEE ME
NOT AS I AM NOW,
BUT AS I ONCE WAS,
AND YOUR HAND,
IT REACHES DOWN TO MY COCK...
AND I AM NOT DEAD.
- COCK?
- YES, "COCK."
YOUR BREASTS
AND YOUR VAGINA...
EXCUSE ME, SIR.
OKAY, THAT'S ENOUGH
FROM YOU, SIR.
I AM NOW FUCKING YOU.
THAT'S ENOUGH.
PUT IT AWAY.
THE PAST
IS NOT THE PRESENT--
STOP TALKING.
WE ARE NOT DEAD.
IT'S OKAY.
WE'RE OKAY.
HEY. HEY!
NOBODY WANTS TO SEE YOU
KISS THE COFFIN, OKAY?
[ROARS]: WHO
THE HELL ARE YOU?
DON'T MAKE A SCENE.
YOU GET HIM
OUT OF HERE!
THIS IS NOT APPROPRIATE.
YOU SHOULDN'T BE HERE.
GET OUT OF HERE!
HEY. HEY!
[THUD]
SOMEBODY HELP HIM!
GET THE HELL
OUT OF HERE!
GET HIM OUT OF HERE!
GET THE HELL
AWAY FROM ME!
I HAVE A KNIFE,
AND I WILL CUT OUT YOUR HEART,
AND I WILL SHIT ON IT!
FINE. GET HIM OUT OF HERE!
I WILL
KICK YOUR ASS!
I WILL KICK
ALL OF YOUR ASSES!
SOMEONE, PLEASE,
JUST GET HIM OUT OF HERE!
YOU HAVE NO RIGHT
TO BE HERE.
CALL THE POLICE!
SHUT YOUR GODDAMN MOUTH!
STOP IT! STOP IT
RIGHT NOW! BERNIE!
BERNIE.
THIS IS YOUR FATHER.
THIS IS YOUR SON.
STOP IT, BOTH OF YOU.
WHAT?
YES!
OH, FUCK.
FIRE!
[GUNSHOTS RING OUT]
[MEN GRUNTING IN PAIN]
CAMERA ROLLING.
SPEED.
ANTON INTERVIEW,
TAKE ONE.
IT'S A KIND
OF SURVEY, REALLY.
FATHERS AND SONS,
THEIR RELATIONSHIPS,
AND JUST TRYING TO GET
A SENSE OF
YOUR EXPERIENCES.
BERNIE'S INTERVIEW,
TAKE THREE.
ALL RIGHT, WELL,
MAYBE WE CAN
SHIFT GEARS
AND TALK
ABOUT YOUR FATHER?
CAN YOU TELL ME
ABOUT HIM?
WHAT HE'S LIKE,
AND THAT KIND OF THING?
NOT SO MUCH TO TELL.
[BATTLE SWORDS CLASHING, GRUNTS]
[♪♪♪]
[EXHALING DEEPLY]
[COUGHS]
DID YOU
LOVE YOUR FATHER?
YEAH. OH, YEAH.
I THINK SO.
I ALWAYS FELT,
IF THE WOLF CAME TO THE DOOR,
HE'D WANT TO HEAR THE WOLF'S
SIDE OF THE STORY FIRST
BEFORE HE DECIDED WHETHER OR NOT
TO SAVE ME FROM THE WOLF,
AND IF THE WOLF
MADE A CONVINCING CASE
THAT I ACTUALLY DESERVED
TO GET EATEN,
HE'D SAY, "WELL,
IT'S YOU AND THE WOLF NOW.
I'M OUT OF THIS."
IS THAT HIM?
YEAH, THAT'S HIM.
JESUS.
WOW, THAT'S
PRETTY TRIPPY.
MM-HMM.
SO...
SO, IS THIS LISTED YET?
THE HOUSE?
YEAH, IS IT LISTED?
GOOD, BECAUSE
I WANT TO TALK TO YOU
ABOUT A COUPLE
OF THINGS FIRST.
I DON'T THINK FATHERS
SHOULD HAVE FAVOURITES.
I WILL NEVER HAVE A FAVOURITE
WHEN I HAVE CHILDREN.
I'M SURE IF YOU PUT
MY BROTHERS IN A ROOM TOGETHER,
AND YOU ASKED THEM
WHO OUR FATHER'S FAVOURITE WAS,
I'M FAIRLY SURE THAT TWO OF THEM
WOULD SAY ME.
I THINK IT WAS FAIRLY OBVIOUS
THAT I WAS THE FAVOURITE CHILD.
[GIRLS SQUEALING
AND GIGGLING]
OH, SHIT.
CAN WE HAVE
SOME PICTURES?
ABSOLUTELY.
OH, MY RIDE'S HERE,
SO I GOT TO MAKE IT
QUICK, OKAY?
WHAT'S YOUR NAME?
ELI. E-L-I.
"E-L-I"?
[ELI]: THANK YOU!
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
MIKEY!
HEY. GOT TO HURRY UP.
MY BROTHER. HEY, MIKEY.
SEAN.
I'M HERE FOR
A LITTLE FAMILY BUSINESS.
CAN I GET A PICTURE
WITH YOU?
ABSOLUTELY.
YEAH, YEAH.
HEY, LET'S GET
MY BROTHER IN HERE.
I HAVEN'T SEEN HIM
IN A LONG TIME.
CAN I GET ONE
WITH MY BROTHER?
COME ON, MIKE.
COME ON, MIKE!
COME ON. EVERYONE GATHER IN.
[GIRLS GIGGLING]
MIKE'S THE EXECUTOR?
YEAH,
MIKE'S THE EXECUTOR.
WHAT? I THOUGHT
YOU'D BE THE EXECUTOR.
MIKE'S A LAWYER.
I UNDERSTAND THAT,
BUT YOU'RE THE ONE
WHO'S BEEN WIPING DAD'S ASS
FOR GOD KNOWS HOW LONG.
YES, I HAVE.
AND YOU DON'T GET
TO BE THE EXECUTOR?
THAT'S TYPICAL.
NO, THAT'S FINE.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH, GUYS.
REMEMBER, SEASON FOUR
STARTS IN THREE WEEKS, OKAY?
TUESDAY NIGHTS AT NINE.
SAME TIME.
THANKS, SEAN!
BYE-BYE, GUYS.
HAVE A GOOD DAY.
IS THIS YOUR BAG?
YEAH, THAT'S MINE.
WOULD YOU MIND? YEAH, THANKS.
I GOT IT.
LET'S GET THE HELL
OUT OF HERE.
DOES THAT HAPPEN
ALL THE TIME?
YES.
[GIRLS GIGGLING]
BYE-BYE. BYE.
[SLOW, PLODDING PIANO TUNE
BEING PLAYED]
[PLAYING PIANO]
[SUSTAINS FINAL NOTE]
WOW. THAT'S REALLY GOOD.
YOU WROTE THAT?
[WOMAN]: LAST NIGHT.
LAST NIGHT, ALL
OF HIS OWN ACCORD,
WITHOUT MY HELPING.
WELL, I MEAN, A LITTLE
BIT OF MY HELP,
BUT WHAT HE NEEDS IS THE GRAPHS
AND THE LINES AND THE NOTES.
SO I THINK THAT THAT WOULD BE
THE NEXT STAGE,
IS TO TEACH HIM
HOW TO ACTUALLY WRITE MUSIC.
WELL, I THINK HE'S REALLY
MAKING A LOT OF PROGRESS,
AND I THINK HE'S DOING
AMAZINGLY WELL,
BUT I DON'T THINK
WE SHOULD GO QUITE
AS QUICKLY AS YOU SUGGEST.
IT'S A LITTLE TOUGH
TO TACKLE RIGHT NOW.
WELL, WHAT DO YOU
THINK, JOSEPH?
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
WHAT'S YOUR FAVOURITE
SONG RIGHT NOW, TO PLAY?
[BOY]: WELL,
IN THE BOOK?
YEAH.
PROBABLY "ROW,
ROW, ROW YOUR BOAT."
YAY!
LET'S HEAR SOME "ROW, ROW,
ROW YOUR BOAT," OKAY?
PLAY THAT.
[♪♪♪]
OKAY, WELL,
I HAVE ONE SON,
AND, UH, HE'S A...
HE'S A FORCE,
A FORCE OF NATURE.
[CHUCKLES]
HE'S, UM,
HE'S A BUSINESSMAN.
MM-HMM?
YES, AND HE'S...
HE'S QUITE A BUSINESSMAN.
HE'S DONE VERY WELL
FOR HIMSELF.
[♪♪♪]
[HORN HONKS IN DISTANCE]
SO YOU DIDN'T
HAVE BROTHERS?
SOLO?
PARENTS SPLIT UP WHEN
YOU WERE AROUND 15,
SO, IN YOUR VIEW, UH,
ARE YOU CLOSE
WITH YOUR MOTHER
OR YOUR FATHER?
WHAT'S THE DEAL THERE?
UH, HMM.
THAT'S A GOOD QUESTION.
[♪♪♪]
[BAG THUMPS]
MY BOY!
WHAT'S UP, POP?
HOW YOU DOING?
MY BOY! HEY.
YOU DIDN'T EVEN CALL
TO LET ME KNOW YOU WERE COMIN'!
WELL, A SURPRISE
AIN'T A SURPRISE
IF YOU KNOW
I'M COMING.
YOU GOT A POINT THERE!
DAMN, IT'S GOOD
TO SEE YOU.
YOU TOO, POP. YOU TOO.
SO, YOU, YOU...
YOU COOL
IF I STAY WITH YOU?
YOU GONNA STAY WITH ME?
SON, YOU DON'T NEVER
STAY WITH ME.
YOU KNOW WHAT?
I NEED TO CHANGE THAT,
I REALLY DO. I REALLY DO.
I MEAN, LAST TIME I WAS HERE
WAS WHAT, FIVE YEARS AGO?
WHOA, WHOA, WHOA, WHOA.
FIVE YEARS?
SON, TRY SEVEN.
AHH, THAT WASN'T
SEVEN YEARS AGO.
IT WAS SEVEN
YEARS AGO, SON.
THAT'S EMBARRASSING,
AND I WORK WITH NUMBERS TOO.
[BOTH LAUGHING]
[♪♪♪]
STOP!
STOP! STOP!
EVERYBODY!
I SAID...
SNAP, WIGGLE,
SNAP, WIGGLE.
WHEN I SAY "SNAP,"
YOU MUST SNAP. SNAP.
SO WHEN
YOU STOP THE WIGGLE,
THIS PART HERE
SHIMMERS.
I WAS YOUNG,
I WAS AWAY IN CANCUN
ON A VACATION,
AND I HAD A FEW TOO MANY
WHISKEY SODAS
AND THIS VERY NICE
AMERICAN LADY,
WE WERE TALKING,
AND THE NEXT MORNING, UM,
SHE WOKE UP IN MY ROOM.
WE EXCHANGED BUSINESS CARDS,
I SAID GOODBYE,
AND THEN, SEVEN MONTHS LATER,
SHE PHONED ME TO SAY,
"BY THE WAY, YOU'RE GOING TO BE
THE FATHER OF OUR CHILD."
AND I WAS LIKE, "OH."
CAN YOU DESCRIBE
YOUR FATHER FOR ME?
WHEW, UM...
[CHUCKLES]
HE'S THIS... LIKE,
"GAY" DOESN'T EVEN DESCRIBE.
IT'S MORE THAN GAY.
IT'S LIKE HE'S A FLAMING
BOLLYWOOD INDIAN HOMOSEXUAL...
AND?
HE WEARS TIGHT PINK SHIRTS,
HIS NIPPLES SHOW,
WITH A SCARF,
AND HE DOESN'T STOP TOUCHING ME.
I'D BURST INTO TEARS
IF MY DAD GAVE ME A HUG.
IT'S NOT HUGS,
IT'S LIKE PECKS.
IT'S LIKE, "WHY ARE YOU
DOING THIS TO ME?"
BUT HE LOVES YOU.
THIS GUY
SOUNDS AWESOME.
I KNOW, BUT...
BECAUSE HE
LOVES YOU, MAN.
OKAY, YES,
THERE'S WORSE THINGS.
THERE'S WORSE THINGS,
BUT HE LOVES ME TOO MUCH.
HE KNOWS, RIGHT?
YOU TOLD HIM.
HOW'S HE FEELING?
[SIGHS]:
I HAVEN'T TOLD HIM.
REALLY?
THAT YOU'RE
GETTING MARRIED?
[BOXING BELL RINGS,
SOUNDS OF PUNCHING]
[♪♪♪]
[STARTER SPUTTERS AND STALLS]
[ENGINE FAILS TO TURN OVER]
[♪♪♪]
I WOULD LOVE TO HAVE
SAT DOWN LIKE THIS WITH HIM
AND TALKED ABOUT OUR HISTORY
AND OUR GROWING UP
AND, AND OUR FAMILY,
AND IT'S SOMETHING
THAT WE DIDN'T DO.
WE DIDN'T LOOK BACK.
WE LOOKED FORWARD
AS A FAMILY.
OKAY, ARE YOU READY
FOR MY IDEA?
YEAH, LET'S HEAR IT.
LET'S GET DOWN TO IT.
OKAY.
SO, FOUR BROTHERS, RIGHT?
MM-HMM.
SO YOU'RE TALKING
ABOUT A FOUR-WAY SPLIT?
YES.
RIGHT, GOOD.
LIQUIDATE EVERYTHING.
GET IT ALL IN ONE LUMP SUM,
SPLIT IT FOUR WAYS.
YEAH. OKAY,
AND THEN WE TAKE THAT, RIGHT?
WE EACH TAKE OUR PORTION,
AND THEN WE--
GET THE FUCK OUT OF DODGE.
RIGHT, BUT FIRST
WE PICK AN ELEMENT,
AND THEN EARTH, WIND,
WATER, FIRE, RIGHT?
LOOK, YOU DO WHATEVER YOU WANT
WITH YOUR MONEY, OKAY?
I'VE GOT
SOME VERY IMPORTANT THINGS--
NO, NO, DUDE...
SET UP IN NEW YORK CITY
THAT I GOT TO TAKE CARE OF.
I'M TALKING ABOUT THE ASHES.
STAND BACK
AND WATCH...
I'M TALKING ABOUT DOING
A CEREMONY WITH THE ASHES.
A WHAT?
I'M TALKING ABOUT
SAYING GOODBYE TO DAD
IN A MEANINGFUL KIND OF WAY.
I SAID GOODBYE TO DAD,
AND, TRUST ME,
IT WAS MEANINGFUL.
LET'S JUST MOVE ON.
LET'S GET THINGS
ROLLING HERE.
YEAH, RIGHT, BUT I THOUGHT--
YOU KNOW WHAT?
YOU CAN HAVE
A YEAR-LONG FESTIVAL
OF SAYING GOODBYE TO DAD,
IF THAT'S WHAT
YOU WANT.
OKAY, SO YOU DON'T WANT
TO PARTAKE IN ANY KIND OF,
ANY KIND OF MEANINGFUL CEREMONY
WITH US, RIGHT?
IS THAT
WHAT YOU'RE SAYING?
I'M NOT HERE
FOR A CEREMONY.
I'M HERE TO GET THINGS DONE,
AND, BELIEVE ME,
IT'S NICE TO SEE YOU, IT IS,
BUT NOW I'M DONE,
AND I'M READY TO MOVE.
I GOT BIG THINGS
HAPPENING
AND I NEED TO MAKE
THEM HAPPEN NOW.
YOU CAN LOUNGE
AROUND THE HOUSE
AND PUT YOUR FEET UP IN
YOUR FUCKING BURLAP SACK
AS LONG AS YOU WANT,
BUT SOME OF US HAVE GOT SHIT
TO TAKE CARE OF.
OH, YEAH.
SO DON'T DRAG ME
INTO YOUR LITTLE PSYCHODRAMA.
IF THAT'S WHAT
YOU NEED TO DO--
NO, THAT'S FINE.
THAT'S FINE.
YOU DO THAT.
THAT'S FINE. THAT'S FINE.
THAT'S FINE.
[MEXICAN ACCENT]:
OH, SEXY GIRLFRIENDS!
HEY-EY-EY-EY!
HEY, LOVE,
COME HERE, BUDDY.
ALL RIGHT.
AW, MAN.
NICE WARM HUG
ON COLD GROUND.
NO SHIT, HUH?
IT'S NICE.
WHAT'S GOING ON, GANG?
WHERE ARE
YOUR HANDLERS, BUDDY?
OH, MIKEY?
MIKEY?
YEAH, HE'S HANDLING
THE BAGS RIGHT NOW.
YOU CAME WITH MIKEY?
MIKEY!
PICKED ME UP IN THE OLD
BATMOBILE DOWN AT THE STORE.
NO SHIT, HE'S HERE?
YEAH. I'M GOING TO
JOIN YOU IN A CIGARETTE.
IS IT WRONG THAT I WANT TO
HAVE A COCKTAIL RIGHT NOW, TOO?
IT'S ABSOLUTELY RIGHT
THAT YOU WANT
TO HAVE A COCKTAIL.
IT'S EARLY.
IT'S EARLY. I MEAN...
OUR MAN MARLOWE
OVER HERE
HAS BEEN A LITTLE SLOW
GETTING TO THE LIQUOR CABINET.
"MARLOWE."
I HAD FORGOTTEN ABOUT THAT.
YEAH.
I LIKE IT. I LIKE "MARLOWE."
WE DON'T HAVE TO
PUT ANY WATER BACK IN IT
TO GET THE LEVELS
BACK UP.
NO ONE CARES
ANYMORE. OKAY?
CUTE.
HERE WE GO.
I GOT A LIGHT HERE.
COME ON, COME ON.
ALL RIGHT, ALL RIGHT.
WHEN WAS THE LAST TIME WE EVER
SMOKED A JOINT ON THIS DECK?
YOU DON'T WANT TO ATTEMPT
THE DOWNWARD DOG
ONCE YOU GET
A LITTLE BIT OF THIS IN YOU.
YEAH, ESPECIALLY
NOT ON THE DEWY DECK.
THAT'S MY PROBLEM HERE.
[HACKING]
NO CHOKING.
WALK IT OFF, CHAMP.
GO STRAIGHT
TO THE LIQUOR CABINET.
[LAUGHING]
[SETS BAG DOWN]
HELLO, MICHAEL.
DAVID, HOW ARE YOU?
I'M GOOD. HOW ARE YOU?
I'M GOOD, THANK YOU.
YOU LOOK WELL.
YOU TOO.
YOU'VE BEEN ALL RIGHT?
YEAH, I'M GOOD.
I'M GOOD, YEAH. YOU?
YEAH.
YEAH? GOOD.
OKAY.
UM, THE GUYS DID MENTION,
UH, JUST BECAUSE
I WAS THE ONLY ONE WHO WAS ABLE
TO, YOU KNOW, MAKE IT
TO THE FUNERAL, IF, UM--
I'M SORRY ABOUT THAT.
IT WAS JUST--
OH, NO,
I'M NOT TRYING--
IMPOSSIBLE AT THAT TIME.
YEAH, YEAH, YEAH.
AND LIKE I SAID,
I REALLY APPRECIATED
YOU TAKING CARE
OF THINGS
FOR US...ALL.
YEAH, NO WORRIES.
NO WORRIES.
UM, BUT THEY WERE JUST SAYING
MAYBE THAT WE SHOULD DO A
LITTLE SORT OF PRIVATE CEREMONY,
UM, IF WE GET A CHANCE,
LATER ON.
YOU KNOW, A LITTLE SCATTERING
OF THE ASHES
OR, YOU KNOW,
WHAT HAVE YOU.
OF COURSE. YEAH.
WE SHOULD DO SOMETHING.
OKAY, GREAT.
IS THAT THE WILL THERE?
UH, NO.
NO? OKAY.
NO, THIS IS JUST
SOME WORK.
UM...
DO YOU, UH...
MIND GIVING ME
A COUPLE MINUTES?
I'D JUST LIKE TO...
YEAH, OF COURSE.
SURE. I'LL LET YOU
SETTLE IN.
GET MYSELF TOGETHER
AND FRESHEN UP.
YOU BET.
WE'LL BE DOWNSTAIRS,
YEAH.
GOOD.
DAVID, IT'S GREAT
TO SEE YOU.
YEAH. "MARLOWE," RIGHT?
RIGHT.
I'M SORRY.
IT'S OKAY.
NO, NO, IT'S COOL.
I'M SORRY.
IT'S COOL.
I KNOW. YEAH.
I'M SORRY.
NO, THAT'S FINE.
"MARLOWE."
YEAH.
SO HERE'S THE IDEA, OKAY?
SO WE GET A NICE CAMERA,
BUDDY OF MINE'S GOT
A REALLY NICE CAMERA.
YOU CAN, I'LL GET HIM
TO GIVE THE SPECS,
SO YOU TELL ME
WHAT YOU THINK,
RIGHT, RIGHT, RIGHT.
ANYWAY,
YOU DO A BIG DOLLY SHOT,
COMING DOWN THE TRAIL
INTO THE PARK, OKAY?
THERE'S ME. YOU'RE ONLINE.
YOU FIRE ME A SHOT
WITH THE WEBCAM. OKAY?
RIGHT.
I, QUICK SKETCH,
15 MINUTES LATER,
I FIRE IT BACK TO YOU
AS A JPEG.
"VIRTUAL PARK SKETCH."
ANYWHERE IN THE WORD.
YOU'RE IN NEW YORK CITY
GETTING AN ARTIST PARK SKETCH.
VIRTUALPARK SKETCH.
[WARILY]: OKAY.
THE THING IS, THOUGH,
I NEED A LITTLE BIT
OF START-UP.
I NEED JUST TO GET
A LITTLE BIT LIQUID
OFF THE TOP,
BECAUSE I GOT THIS FUCKING
KILLER WEB DESIGNER, RIGHT?
BUT HE'S NOT CHEAP,
AND IF YOU'RE GOING TO
DO SOMETHING,
YOU GOT TO DO IT RIGHT,
SO I'M LOOKING AT, LIKE,
I'M LOOKING AT, LIKE,
5 TO 7K TO GET HIM...
TO GET HIM, JUST, YOU KNOW,
GREASE THE WHEELS A LITTLE BIT,
YOU KNOW, SO...
ALL RIGHT.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT, YOU KNOW,
WHAT YOU CAN DO, OR--
WELL, 5 TO 7K, YOU KNOW,
I CAN DO THAT, OBVIOUSLY,
I CAN DO THAT FOR YOU,
BUT I DON'T REALLY KNOW
WHAT IT IS
WE'RE TALKING ABOUT HERE.
SO I COULD BE...
LET ME JUST BREAK IT DOWN.
GIVE ME THE PICTURE.
I COULD BE IN L.A.,
I COULD SAY, "HEY, HENRY.
"I NEED YOU TO DRAW ME
IN FRONT OF THE GAZEBO
IN CENTRAL PARK."
THAT'S RIGHT!
SEND YOU A PHOTO OF MYSELF,
YOU, VIRTUALLY--
YOU CAN DO IT
RIGHT ON THE WEBCAM.
YOU'VE GOT A WEBCAM.
BANG! ON THE WEBCAM.
I ZIP UP THE SKETCH,
AND I SCAN
AND I JPEG IT RIGHT BACK TO YOU,
IN THE CENTRAL PARK
BACKDROP.
ALL RIGHT,
THAT SOUNDS
KIND OF, UH,
KIND OF FUCKING AWESOME,
ACTUALLY, MAN.
VIRTUAL PARK SKETCH!
HAVE YOU EVER
ASKED YOUR MOTHER
ABOUT IT?
I DID, YES, YES.
SHE JUST DIDN'T WANT
TO TALK ABOUT IT?
NOT SO MUCH, NO.
HMM.
[SOFTLY POKING AT PIANO KEYS]
[♪♪♪]
"HOUSE OF PUSSY,"
"BLOWJOB,"
"SWEET JESSIE"?
"KINKY FUN"?
YEAH.
HELLO,
I AM LOOKING FOR BLOWJOB.
YES, FROM...
NO! FROM WOMAN! NOT MAN.
I THOUGHT
THE RABBI
WAS VERY DIGNIFIED.
I REALLY QUITE LIKED
THE THINGS
HE SAID, BERNIE.
I GOT TO GET--
[SHRIEKS]: BERNIE,
GET OUT OF THE MIRROR!
DON'T LOOK IN THE MIRROR!
THAT'S WHY IT'S COVERED!
YOU'RE NOT SUPPOSED
TO LOOK IN THE MIRROR!
OKAY, I GOT TO
GET TO THE SCHOOL.
PARENT-TEACHER
CONFERENCE.
WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
YOU'RE NOT GOING.
LOOK AT YOU, YOU'RE COVERED
IN SCHMUTZ.
WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
YOU CAN'T BE
GOING ANYWHERE.
COME HERE,
I WANT YOU TO SIT DOWN.
COME HERE. BERNIE.
BERNIE, SIT DOWN.
OKAY.
BERNIE, DARLING, LISTEN.
YOU JUST BURIED YOUR MOTHER,
YOU MET YOUR FATHER
FOR THE FIRST TIME.
I GOT TO
GET TO THE SCHOOL.
BUT, BERNIE!
TALK TO YOU LATER.
GET-- LOOK AT YOU!
YOU HAVE SCHMUTZ ALL OVER.
IT'S OKAY.
YOU'RE LIKE
A LITTLE OLD MAN.
YES, FASTER. GO.
NO, NO.
DON'T BITE, DON'T BITE.
DON'T BITE. DON'T...
[GASPING]
WAIT, WAIT, WAIT. WAIT.
UP HERE.
SON OF A BITCH!
YOU'RE GOOD, JESSIE!
[BANGING AND THUDDING]
YES. OKAY.
WAIT, WAIT.
NOT YET, NOT YET. WAIT.
BEND OVER.
[GRUNTING AND GASPING]
[SOB RISES]
[ANTON CRIES SOFTLY]
[SOBBING]
[ANTON WEEPING LOUDLY]
SO, UH--
MAN, HAVE YOU GOT
YOUR CREDIT CARD?
SHE ENJOYS, UH,
INTERACTING WITH OTHER STUDENTS
DURING CLASS.
OH, I'M SURE
SHE DOES, YEAH.
SOMETIMES, UH,
A BIT TOO MUCH, PERHAPS.
YOU KNOW,
THEY TEXT NOW,
PLEASE, DON'T TALK
ABOUT THE TEXTING.
I TURN MY CELLPHONE OFF.
CAN'T EVEN STAND IT.
SURE.
"MOM, I NEED THIS.
MOM, I NEED THAT."
YOU KNOW? I MEAN,
"I NEED THIS. I NEED THIS."
BUT "I DON'T NEED YOU."
DO YOU HAVE CHILDREN?
NO, I DON'T.
OH, NO, IT'S LIKE
THE DISPOSABLE PARENT THING
GOING ON.
SURE.
YOU KNOW, I'VE BEEN--
IT'S JUST ME AND HER.
NOW I'M JUST TAKING CARE
OF HER BECAUSE, UH, SHE--
MY HUSBAND AND I
DIVORCED, UH, A YEAR AGO,
AND I'M JUST WORRIED
ABOUT HER, SO...
[AWKWARD PAUSE
ENDS WITH CHUCKLING]
I KNOW, IT'S CRAZY.
"HI! THERAPY 101!"
HI, PARENT-TEACHER.
I KNOW, IT'S CRAZY.
I, UH, HAD
MY MOTHER'S FUNERAL
TODAY, ACTUALLY.
OH, MY GOSH!
I'M SO SORRY.
YEAH.
OH, MY GOSH, YOU, I...
YOU SHOULD HAVE
CANCELLED THIS MEETING.
YOU SHOULDN'T BE HERE.
OH DEAR.
[EXHALES TENSELY]
[SUCKLING]
[WHEEZING SOBS]
OKAY.
WHAT?
JUST SIGN HERE, OKAY?
WHERE?
JUST RIGHT THERE.
YOU HAVE FATHER?
YEAH.
IS HE GOOD MAN?
[CHUCKLES POLITELY]
I AM A FATHER.
YEAH? ARE YOU
A GOOD MAN?
[RESUMES WEEPING]: NO!
[SNIFFLES DEEPLY]
I...
I HAVE SON.
I DON'T, I...
I DON'T KNOW HIM.
WELL, THAT'S OKAY.
WHY DON'T YOU JUST--
JUST GO GET TO KNOW HIM.
RIGHT?
YES.
IT'S NOT TOO LATE.
YOU CAN GO...
GO SEE HIM.
I WILL GO SEE HIM.
[SNAPS RECEIPT OUT]
YOU ARE NICE
GIRL NEXT DOOR.
[CHUCKLES]: YEAH.
[DOOR OPENS, THEN CLOSES]
I THINK
THE KEY TO BEING A PARENT,
AT LEAST A DECENT PARENT,
IS, IS LOVE.
AS LONG AS YOUR KID KNOWS
YOU LOVE THEM,
YOU GOT HOPE.
BEEN A LONG TIME SINCE
YOU'VE BEEN AROUND HERE.
[DAVIS]: USED TO OWN
THESE COURTS, THOUGH.
YEAH, YOU DID.
RIGHT OUT THERE,
THAT'S WHERE I SHOWED YOU
HOW TO DO THAT JUMP SHOT.
WELL, YOU SHOWED
YOURSELF.
YEAH, YEAH.
TOOK A FEW DAYS.
HEY, GUYS!
HEY, BLU!
HOW YOU DOING?
GOOD. HOW ARE YOU?
ALL RIGHT, ALL RIGHT.
WHO'S GOT
THE BIG JUMP SHOT TODAY?
LOOK AT MY MAN.
BANK IS OPEN!
UP IN THE HEEZY!
ALL RIGHT.
LOOKING GOOD, YOU GUYS.
KEEP WORKING ON IT.
HAVE A GREAT DAY.
SEE YOU, BLU.
ALL RIGHT.
FEEL LIKE
SOME SOUL FOOD?
OH, YEAH,
LET'S DO THAT.
ALL RIGHT.
YEAH, WE WERE ALL
KIDS ONCE.
LET'S NOT
FORGET TO PLAY.
[LAUGHS]:
YEAH, FOR REAL.
YEAH.
COME ON, PASS OVER HERE.
OVER HERE.
SHOOT!
[HEAVY ARTILLERY
WITH AIR RAID SIREN]
I'M PROBABLY NOT, UH.
I...
I'M PROBABLY NOT, UH...
A GOOD SON.
I...
BECAUSE I, AM...
YOU JUST CAME IN TO SEE ME,
AND NOW YOU HAVE TO GO, HUH?
DON'T DO THIS.
WHAT IS THIS NONSENSE?
YOU'RE HERE
FOR HOW LONG?
LONG TIME,
BUT I HAVEN'T SEEN YOU
SINCE LAST DECEMBER,
SO WHAT IS THIS NONSENSE?
HOW LONG ARE YOU HERE FOR?
YOU'RE HERE FOR A MONTH?
YEAH.
OKAY, SO NEXT DAY,
THE NEXT DAY AFTER THAT,
WE'LL ARRANGE A LUNCH,
MAYBE YOU CAN
MEET MY FIANCEE.
I GOT ENGAGED.
OH! ENGAGED?
I NEED YOU--
I NEED YOU TO RELAX.
I NEED YOU TO STAY...
I AM SO...
I NEED YOU TO RELAX.
KAMA'S GETTING MARRIED!
OH, I'M SO HAPPY!
MY SON, KAMA!
KAMA SHARMA
IS GETTING MARRIED!
OKAY!
WHAT'S HER NAME?
CONGRATULATIONS.
YEAH, THANK YOU.
IT'S AMBER WILSON.
WE'RE VERY HAPPY.
WE ARE GOING TO HAVE
THE MOST LOVELY WEDDING EVER,
AND YOU'RE GOING TO HELP ME,
BECAUSE YOU ARE HERE.
I WOULD LOVE TO HELP.
OUR PRESENT TO YOU
AND HER FAMILY.
WE CAN DO
THE SECOND DANCE NUMBER.
WE'LL DO IT
AT THE ENGAGEMENT PARTY.
DO YOU MIND IF, LIKE,
I JUST TALK TO MY
DAD ALONE FOR--
YEAH, NO, NO.
WE'LL DO
THE WEDDING PLANS LATER.
YEAH. YEAH.
YEAH, WE HAVE LONG TIME.
OKAY.
SHE WILL MAKE
THE BEST PARTY FOR YOU.
OKAY, I NEED YOU
TO LISTEN.
WE'RE NOT GOING TO HAVE
A BIG ENGAGEMENT.
YOU'RE RIGHT,
IT WON'T BE BIG.
IT'LL BE NOT SO BIG.
WE'RE NOT GOING TO HAVE
AN ENGAGEMENT PARTY.
IT WILL BE NOT BIG
BY INDIAN STANDARDS.
WE'RE NOT GOING TO HAVE
AN ENGAGEMENT PARTY.
DON'T CRY.
MY ONLY SON AND I,
WE CAN'T HAVE...
I CAN'T EVEN GIVE YOU,
LIKE, A SMALL LITTLE
ENGAGEMENT CELEBRATION?
NO, NO. NO,
JUST LEAVE SUTISH OUT!
OKAY, I'LL JUST MAYBE
GO BACK HOME, THEN, HUH?
AND YOU CAN...
YOU CAN CALL ME
AND TELL ME HOW IT WENT.
I DON'T WANT
TO DO THIS RIGHT NOW.
I DON'T WANT TO DO
THIS RIGHT NOW.
WELL, WHEN DO YOU
WANT TO DO IT, HUH?
IF I'M GOING TO CRY
AND I'M GOING TO HAVE
A HEART ATTACK,
IT MAY AS WELL BE NOW
RATHER THAN TOMORROW
TO HAVE TO DEAL WITH THIS.
CAN'T EVEN HAVE
AN ENGAGEMENT PARTY!
FOR MY OWN--
DAD--
[NEHNA]: WE CAN USE THIS
FOR THE ENGAGEMENT PARTY!
THERE IS
NO ENGAGEMENT PARTY!
ALL RIGHT?
JUST SHUT UP.
THERE IS NO--
THERE IS NO ENGAGEMENT PARTY?
THERE IS NO
ENGAGEMENT PARTY. OKAY?
THERE IS
NO ENGAGEMENT PARTY?
BUT BANTI'S PLACE
WOULD BE VERY GOOD FOR IT,
IF YOU WANT IT THERE!
I DON'T THINK "AFFECTIONATE"
IS THE RIGHT WORD, BUT, UH,
BUT A GOOD DAD,
A GOOD SOLID DAD.
I MEAN, EVERYTHING HAD TO BE
EARNED WITH HIM, RIGHT?
THERE WAS NOTHING
THAT WAS JUST GIVEN.
HE WAS A WORKAHOLIC.
I THINK HE WAS SUCCESSFUL
WITH US.
YEAH.
"OUR FATHER."
I THINK THAT'S--
I'M SORRY, BUT I THINK
THAT'S BEEN USED.
THAT ONE'S
TAKEN, YEAH.
YEAH, THAT'S GOOD.
NO, THAT'S ALL
I STOLE.
THAT'S IT.
THAT'S ALL YOU GOT.
I'M SORRY. I'M SORRY.
JUST THE BIBLE.
YEAH, OKAY.
WELL, HE IS
OUR FATHER, RIGHT?
ABSOLUTELY.
"OUR FATHER,
THE WIND,
WHOSE VERY BREATH
BLEW WARMTH
AND RADIANT COMFORT
AGAINST THE COLD NIGHT.
OUR FATHER, FIRE,
WHOSE PASSION
AND INTELLECTUAL STRENGTH
BURNED LIKE
A ROARING FLAME.
OUR FATHER, WATER,
WHO COULD FLOW
THROUGH ALL IMPEDIMENT
AND WHO COULD,
LIKE A MIGHTY OCEAN,
NURTURE AND SHAPE
ALL WHO WERE BLESSED ENOUGH
TO BATHE IN HIS GLORY.
OUR FATHER, EARTH,
SOLID, STRONG, ETERNAL,
WHOSE FOUNDATION AND NURTURING
BROUGHT FOUR TINY SEEDS,
AND TURNED THEM INTO
THE FOUR MEN WE ARE TODAY."
I LIKE THAT,
MARLOWE.
THAT WAS NICE, MAN.
THANKS.
YEAH, HERE.
HERE'S TO DAD.
TO OUR FATHER.
HEY, I DON'T KNOW
ABOUT YOU GUYS.
I THOUGHT MAYBE, UH,
WE COULD, MAYBE EACH, UH,
YOU KNOW...
TELL A STORY ABOUT DAD,
SHARE A LITTLE.
I'M INTO IT!
I'M TOTALLY INTO IT.
I WAS KIND OF HOPING
THAT WE'D DO SOMETHING
LIKE THAT, ACTUALLY.
YOU WANT QUINTESSENTIAL DAD?
YOU WANT DAD AS I KNOW HIM?
OF COURSE, YEAH.
IS THAT IT? OKAY.
SO THIS WAS, UM, RIGHT AFTER
I, UH, QUIT PARSONS.
WELL, YOU DIDN'T
QUIT PARSONS.
I MEAN, JUST
FACTUALLY SPEAKING. NO.
YEAH, I QUIT
PARSONS. I QUIT.
OKAY, YOU LEFT PARSONS.
WE HAD A PARTING
OF THE WAYS.
YES, YOU DID.
I LET THEM KNOW HOW I FELT
ABOUT THE LEVEL
OF THEIR INSTRUCTION
AND ACTED ACCORDINGLY.
THEY LET ME KNOW
HOW THEY FELT
ABOUT MY OUTSPOKENNESS,
AND WE HAD
A MUTUAL AGREEMENT
THAT IT WAS NOT
THE RIGHT FIT FOR US.
SURE, IF THAT'S HOW
YOU WANT TO PHRASE IT.
THAT'S GOOD.
ANYWAY,
I HAD LEFT PARSONS,
AND I WAS HERE,
STAYING WITH THE OLD MAN,
AND, UH, I HAD NOTHING.
I WAS TOTALLY TAPPED, RIGHT?
HE GIVES ME A LITTLE BIT HERE,
A LITTLE BIT THERE,
AND I'M GETTING DOWNTOWN
AND WHATEVER,
AND THEN,
THEN HE CUTS ME OFF, THAT'S IT.
SO I'M STUCK.
SO...
I HAD THAT GUITAR, RIGHT?
YOU REMEMBER THAT '61,
THE RED '61 JAGUAR?
THAT WAS A NICE GUITAR.
BEAUTIFUL GUITAR.
YOU'RE NOT GOING TO FIND
ONE OF THOSE.
SO I SAID, "FINE,
I'LL SELL THE FUCKING GUITAR.
I'LL SHOW HIM,
I'LL USE MY ASSETS."
SO I WENT DOWNTOWN,
WENT TO A PAWNSHOP ON HASTINGS.
TOLD THEM I WANTED 900 BUCKS
FOR IT.
THEY SAID, "NAW,
YOU'RE NOT GONNA GET THAT."
I SAID, "I'M GETTING 900 BUCKS
FOR THIS.
PUT IT IN THE FUCKING WINDOW
FOR 900."
I SOLD IT IN A DAY.
I GO DOWN TO PICK UP THE MONEY,
I COME BACK WITH 900 BUCKS.
I WALK IN,
THE WAD IN MY HAND, I SAY,
"DAD, LOOK AT THIS,
"I WENT AND SOLD MY GUITAR.
I GOT 900 BUCKS.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO GIVE ME
ANYTHING, I'M SET."
YOU KNOW WHAT HE SAYS TO ME?
HE SAYS, "MY LAST COUNT,
YOU OWE ME 750.
YOU'RE INTO ME FOR 750."
HE TAKES 750 BUCKS
OUT OF MY HAND.
MY GUITAR IS GONE.
I SAID, "DAD, CAN'T WE JUST
LET IT RIDE?
I JUST SOLD
THE ONE THING I HAVE,
THE ONE THING THAT--
THAT I HAVE
THAT MEANS ANYTHING TO ME,
JUST SO I CAN
GET A FLOAT GOING
TILL I GET SET UP."
HE SAID, "NO, IF YOU'VE LEARNED
ONE THING IN THIS HOUSE, HENRY,
IT'S YOU HANDLE
YOUR DEBTS FIRST, RIGHT?
THAT'S THE WAY IT GOES."
AND, SO--
SO, THERE I WAS.
150 BUCKS, NO GUITAR.
WOW.
AND LESSON LEARNED, YEAH?
FUCK YOU!
LESSON
FUCKIN' LEARNED?
I'LL GIVE YOU
A FUCKIN' LESSON LEARNED.
LET'S GET DOWN TO THIS,
ALL RIGHT?
THAT FUCKER
WAS ABOUT THE BOTTOM LINE,
WELL, LET'S TALK ABOUT
THE BOTTOM LINE.
WHY ARE WE SITTING HERE
FUCKING EULOGIZING
THAT PIECE OF SHIT?
LET'S FIND OUT
WHAT THE FUCK THE DEAL IS HERE.
WHOA, WHOA.
YEAH, I'VE HAD IT
WITH YOUR FUCKING PLATITUDES.
[MIKE]: LET'S HAVE SOME
RESPECT HERE, HENRY.
TALK TO HIM ABOUT RESPECT.
LESSON FUCKING LEARNED.
I'M PUTTING MY FUCKING HEART
OUT HERE LIKE YOU WANT ME TO,
AND I GET "LESSON LEARNED?"
DO YOU HAVE IT
WITH YOU, MIKEY?
YES, I DO.
WE'RE NOT DOING IT NOW.
YOU WANT TO DO IT NOW?
I WOULDN'T MIND
SEEING IT NOW.
YOU WANT TO DO IT NOW?
YEAH, I WOULDN'T
MIND SEEING IT NOW.
[CHAIR SCRAPES]
LET'S GET IT
OUT OF THE WAY.
I THINK
WE'RE ALL CURIOUS, RIGHT?
I'M HAPPY TO DO IT
WHEN THERE'S A CONSENSUS
THAT IT'S TIME TO DO IT.
IF YOU WANT TO DO IT NOW--
I MOVE THAT
WE LOOK AT IT NOW!
ALL IN FAVOUR?
YEAH, SURE. OKAY.
LET'S GO.
YOU'RE GENETICALLY PROGRAMMED,
IN A LOT OF WAYS,
TO MAYBE NOT EVEN ASPIRE
TO BE YOUR DAD,
BUT THAT YOU WILL EVENTUALLY
END UP BEING SORT OF LIKE DAD.
I DO SEE MYSELF
AS MY FATHER'S SON.
I MEAN, I'M A PRODUCT
OF THAT ENVIRONMENT.
I JUST, I CAN'T BELIEVE
THAT I WAS...
BORN FROM HIM.
YEAH, WE'RE DEFINITELY
DIFFERENT PEOPLE.
DEFINITELY DIFFERENT PEOPLE,
AND I THINK
WE WERE DIFFERENT PEOPLE
FROM THE GET-GO.
YOU COULD HAVE BEEN
ONE OF THE GREATS, MAN.
ANYBODY WHO'S FAMOUS
IN THE MUSIC WORLD, IN JAZZ,
YOU PLAYED WITH THEM,
YOU WERE WITH THEM.
I DID DO THAT.
YOU COULD'VE
HELPED YOURSELF OUT
A LITTLE BIT MORE, TOO.
I MEAN--
I DID WHAT I WANTED TO DO.
THE MUSIC IS ALWAYS
GOING TO BE IN ME.
IT'S ALWAYS GOING TO BE
A PART OF WHAT I DO,
BUT I WANT TO ENJOY
THIS JOURNEY.
THE DRIVE,
AMBITION TO BE THE BEST,
ON TOP AND ALL OF THAT,
I'M GOING TO LET SOMEBODY ELSE
DO THAT.
I MEAN, IT'S A SHAME
THAT YOU DIDN'T, YOU KNOW,
GET RECOGNIZED FOR IT.
THAT'S NOT ME, SON.
WELL, YOU SHOULD
GET PAID FOR WHAT YOU DO.
YOU GOT TO MAKE MONEY
IN THIS WORLD.
THAT'S JUST THE WAY IT GOES,
YOU KNOW?
YEAH.
WELL, YOU MAKING PLENTY.
SO THAT'S COVERED.
THIS FAMILY'S
MAKIN' MONEY, RIGHT?
I DON'T NEED IT,
BUT YOU DO.
DO YOUR THING,
IT'S ALL GOOD
WITH ME.
I WANT TO FEEL GOOD
ABOUT THE DAYS
THAT I'M LIVIN',
AND I'M FEELIN' WONDERFUL
RIGHT NOW.
YEAH, I KNOW
YOU'RE FEELING WONDERFUL,
BUT, I MEAN, I DON'T KNOW
FOR HOW MUCH LONGER.
YOU GOT A DRAFT COMING IN
THAT HOLE IN THE CEILING.
WHAT'S UP WITH THAT?
AIN'T NOTHIN'.
COME ON, WE'LL TAKE 30, 40K,
AND GET SOME GUYS IN HERE,
AND THEY COULD REDO
THIS WHOLE PLACE, MAN.
LOOK, YOU'RE BARKIN' UP
THE WRONG TREE.
THAT AIN'T NEVER
GOING TO HAPPEN.
I KNOW YOU LIKE YOUR HOUSE
THE WAY IT IS,
BUT COME ON, MAN,
IT'S TIME TO UPDATE IT.
YOU'RE GONNA HAVE
TO FEEL ME ON THIS.
I'M GONNA GET YOU
A FLAT SCREEN.
THAT ACCOUNT
THAT YOU TALKIN' ABOUT?
YES.
IT DID HAVE SUBSTANTIAL
SUMS OF MONEY IN IT.
YEAH, $400,000.
YEAH, BUT IT NO
LONGER HAS THAT, SON.
I USED THAT MONEY.
I KNOW THE MARKET
HAS DIPPED A LITTLE BIT.
DID YOU HEAR ME?
I USED IT.
WAIT, WAIT.
HOLD ON A SECOND.
YOU INVESTED IT IN WHAT?
YOU DIDN'T GO THROUGH ME,
SO WHAT
DID YOU INVEST IT IN?
WELL, I DIDN'T NEED YOU
FOR THIS ONE, SON.
THIS WAS A NO-BRAINER.
LET ME TELL YOU
WHAT I DID WITH IT.
WE HAVE A NEW SPORTS COMPLEX
AT THE COMMUNITY CENTRE.
WELL...
SON,
IT IS SPECTACULAR.
ALL THE KIDS
COME THERE NOW.
THEY TAKE BUSES
FROM ACROSS TOWN
TO COME TO THIS PLACE,
BECAUSE IT'S SO NEW.
SON, THEY GOT
A BASKETBALL TEAM.
THEY CALL THEM
"THE BLUES."
THE BLUES.
[CHUCKLES PROUDLY]
COME ON, TOAST THE BLUES.
COME ON, SON.
OH, YEAH, YEAH.
YOU KNOW WHAT?
I WOULDN'T HAVE
BEEN ABLE TO DO THIS
IF IT HADN'T BEEN FOR YOU.
YOU THE ONE
THAT GAVE ME THE MONEY.
THANK YOU, SON.
YOU SHOULD BE
VERY PROUD OF YOURSELF.
WE HAVE TO ACCEPT
THE PEOPLE WE LOVE,
REGARDLESS,
UNCONDITIONALLY.
OTHERWISE,
HOW CAN IT BE LOVE?
WE ALL SAY THAT,
THAT'S AN EASY WORD TO SAY,
"OH, I LOVE YOU
UNCONDITIONALLY."
I THINK CONDITIONS
CREEP IN.
[CAR HORN HONKS]
I AM NOT GOING TO BE
THE TYPICAL
OVERBEARING, OVERLY INVOLVED
EAST INDIAN FATHER-IN-LAW,
OR EAST INDIAN FATHER.
THOSE DAYS ARE OVER, OKAY?
I WILL BE COMPLETELY,
TOTALLY, 100% STANDOFFISH.
WE DON'T WANT YOU
TO BE STANDOFFISH.
WE WANT YOU
IN OUR LIVES.
NO, BELIEVE ME,
YOU DO.
BUT, PUTTING THAT ASIDE,
SINCE YOU DID SAY
I DON'T HAVE TO BE,
I WOULD LIKE TO MAKE--
POINT OUT TWO THINGS.
MARRIAGE IS NOT EASY,
AND THERE ARE A FEW FACTORS
WHICH CONTRIBUTE
TO THIS UNEASINESS.
FOR EXAMPLE,
NOTHING IS WORSE FOR A MARRIAGE
THAN FINANCIAL PROBLEMS.
I KNOW YOU'RE DOING VERY WELL,
BUT IF YOU EVER NEED MONEY,
I HAVE SO MUCH FUCKING MONEY,
YOU HAVE NO IDEA.
WE'RE TOTALLY FINE.
WE'RE OKAY.
I KNOW YOU ARE.
I KNOW IT'S NOT A PROBLEM.
I'M SAYING,
IFYOU EVER HAVE A PROBLEM,
IT'S A WONDERFUL
OFFER.
THANK YOU.
YES. THANK YOU.
VERY GENEROUS OF YOU.
ANOTHER CONTRIBUTING
NEGATIVE FACTOR
TO A YOUNG COUPLE
CAN BE PROBLEMS
OF A SEXUAL NATURE.
OH, NO. NO.
NO, NO.
IF THERE'S A PROBLEM,
YOU KNOW, IN THE,
IN THE, YOU KNOW--
JUST LET HIM TALK.
PLEASE LET HIM TALK.
RATHER THAN ANALYZE IT--
YES?
THEN THERE IS ALWAYS
WHAT WORKS
ALMOST EVERY SINGLE TIME
IS TO SIMPLY
TRY DIFFERENT POSITIONS.
IF THAT DOESN'T HELP,
AND THIS HAS ALWAYS
WORKED FOR ME,
DURING THE ACT OF COPULATION,
EAT BRIGHT-COLOURED FRUITS.
BUT THEY MUST BE SEEDLESS.
YOU DON'T WANT TO BE, LIKE,
GOING, PFFT,
WHILE YOU'RE, YOU KNOW,
WHILE YOU'RE DOING IT, RIGHT?
I MEAN, SOME WOMEN DON'T MIND
THE SWALLOWING THING.
I MEAN, THAT'S YOUR BUSINESS,
I'M NOT GOING TO ASK.
YEAH, I, I, I AM A BIT...
UM, HE EMBARRASSES ME,
AND I, UH,
AM A BIT...
I GUESS I--
YEAH, I DON'T THINK
I'M THE BEST SON I COULD BE,
BECAUSE THERE'S JUST SOME THINGS
THAT I CAN'T GET PAST,
AND I WISH I COULD,
BUT I, I... I CAN'T.
I CAN'T. I'VE TRIED.
AND EVERY TIME I SEE HIM,
I GO HOME FOR CHRISTMAS,
AND I, IT'S TOO MUCH,
AND I CAN'T...
I CAN'T GET PAST
THESE THINGS.
I'LL GIVE YOU AN EXAMPLE
OF WHAT WE DO IN MY CULTURE.
I, THE FATHER OF THE GROOM,
WOULD PUT ON A HUGE, BIG,
BRIGHT, COLOURFUL HINDU PARTY
FOR THE COUPLE
AND THEIR FAMILY.
IT'S SO MUCH FUN!
YOU HAVE NO IDEA, BUT, UM--
WELL?
THAT'S NOT REALLY
WHAT WE WANTED, DAD.
I TOLD YOU THIS.
WELL, IT'S NOT WHAT
WE DISCUSSED, BUT...
AND THE ONLY REASON
THAT IDEA CAME TO ME,
WHICH WE'RE NOT GOING TO DO,
I KNOW,
IS BECAUSE, IN TOWN,
WORKING WITH ME,
FOR THE MONTH THAT I AM HERE,
IS NEHNA KAPUR
FROM BOMBAY.
[GASPING]
ALL OF A SUDDEN SHE SUGGESTED,
"LET'S DO A BIG PARTY FOR THEM."
NEHNA KAPUR WOULD
BE PERFORMING
AT OUR ENGAGEMENT
PARTY?
THAT WOULD BE
SO AMAZING!
ARE YOU SURE
YOU WANT TO DO IT?
OH, I WANT TO!
MAYBE IT'S NOT A GOOD IDEA,
I DON'T KNOW. YEAH?
MY GIRLFRIENDS
FROM CALGARY
WOULD FREAK OUT!
THAT WOULD BE AMAZING!
IT WOULD BE, YEAH,
BUT IT'S NOT
GOING TO HAPPEN, SO...
YOU KNOW, I SUPPOSE
THE ROLE OF A FATHER,
FOR MOST JEWS,
WOULD BE TO...
UH, INSTILL A SENSE OF,
UM, FEAR
AND SHAME.
THERE ARE MANY PEOPLE
WITHOUT HAVE SONS AND DAUGHTERS,
MAYBE I SHOULD HAVE HAD,
LIKE, A DOG?
YOUR MOTHER DIDN'T WANT
A MAN IN HER LIFE.
SHE JUST WANTED
TO PLAY THE PIANO.
UH, A BABY?
I, I DON'T KNOW
IF SHE WANTED A BABY,
BUT I KNOW
SHE DIDN'T WANT AN ABORTION.
SHE DIDN'T LIKE NEEDLES.
BUT, BERNIE,
SHE ADORED YOU.
SHE LOVED YOU VERY MUCH.
LOOK AT WHO YOU
TURNED OUT TO BE.
YOU'RE A GOOD MAN.
SHE MADE ME
PROMISE, BERNIE.
SHE MADE ME PROMISE
ON THE BIBLE
AND ON THE GRAVE
OF OUR MOTHER
THAT I WOULD NEVER TELL YOU
ABOUT YOUR FATHER,
BUT THEN, WHEN IT...
BECAME CLEAR WE WERE
GOING TO LOSE HER,
I THOUGHT,
I CAN'T STAND
THAT YOU WOULD BE
IN THE WORLD
THINKING YOU WERE
ALL ALONE
AND THAT YOU WOULDN'T
KNOW YOU HAD A FATHER.
SO I...
I FOUND HIM,
AND I...I BROUGHT HIM
TO THE FUNERAL.
HE DIDN'T KNOW ANYTHING
ABOUT YOU EITHER.
I'M SORRY
IT HAPPENED THAT WAY.
IT...IT WAS A BAD WAY
TO FIND OUT
WHO YOUR FATHER WAS,
AND I APOLOGIZE.
IT WASN'T SUPPOSED TO
HAPPEN LIKE THAT.
HE SAID "COCK."
YEAH. YEAH, HE DID.
[DISHES RATTLE]
HEY, SON.
HEY, POP.
LISTEN, I WAS THINKING
ABOUT THAT MONEY, AND--
AH, YOU SAID
THE MAGIC WORD.
POKER TONIGHT.
OH, SO WE'RE GOING TO WIN
SOME OF THE MONEY BACK?
I DON'T SEE WHY NOT.
HEY, YOU WANT TO PLAY?
LET ME THINK ABOUT IT.
SUIT YOURSELF.
GUESS YOU HAVE
SOME HIGH ROLLERS COMING, HUH?
YES INDEED.
PIGEONS, ALL OF 'EM.
WE'RE GOING TO PLAY
MOOSE JAW HOLD'EM.
"MOOSE JAW HOLD'EM?"
I'VE HEARD
OF "TEXAS HOLD'EM."
WHAT THE HECK IS THAT?
WELL, IT'S THE QUICKEST WAY
I CAN GET YOUR MONEY,
SO, WE PLAYIN'
MOOSE JAW HOLD'EM.
WELL, YOU KNOW,
WE JUST GIVE YOU MONEY,
AND THEN YOU GIVE IT BACK
TO THE COMMUNITY CENTRE,
SO IT ALL WORKS.
YEAH, I APPRECIATE THAT.
DAVIS, WE COULDN'T HAVE
DONE THIS WITHOUT YOUR DAD.
SO I'VE NOMINATED HIM
FOR ONE OF THOSE
"LOCAL HERO"
AWARDS FROM THE CITY,
AND, FINGERS CROSSED.
YOU WON'T BELIEVE HOW MANY
LETTERS OF RECOMMENDATION...
OH, MY GOODNESS.
AND I THINK--
I'M CURIOUS ABOUT, UH,
YOU KNOW,
JUST HOW THE WHOLE THING WORKS,
AS FAR AS, YOU KNOW,
HE OFFERS UP
A CERTAIN AMOUNT OF MONEY,
IS THERE ANY MONEY
THAT COMES BACK?
WAS IT ALL USED UP?
I MEAN...
WELL, SADLY, THEY'RE JUST
KIND OF BOTTOMLESS PITS,
BUT WE COULDN'T HAVE DONE IT
WITHOUT...
WITHOUT YOUR DAD.
WHAT WAS THE TOTAL COST
OF THE BUILD,
ONCE EVERYTHING'S
SAID AND DONE?
OH, GOSH, YOU KNOW,
I'M NOT EVEN SURE ABOUT THAT.
I THINK IT'S PROBABLY
SOMEWHERE AROUND 5 MILLION.
HERE WE GO.
MOOSE JAW HOLD'EM!
GUYS, I JUST WANT TO SAY,
IT'S SO NICE TO FINALLY
MEET YOU IN PERSON.
WELCOME
TO THE FAMILY, HUH?
WELCOME TO THE FAMILY.
[FIANCEE'S FATHER]:
IT'S KIND OF A WACKY FAMILY,
BUT WHAT THE HECK.
OH! UM,
CAM'S DAD,
I DON'T KNOW IF I TOLD YOU,
HE'S LIKE THIS BIG, CRAZY
BOLLYWOOD CHOREOGRAPHER,
AND HE WANTS TO THROW
AN ENGAGEMENT PARTY FOR US
ON SATURDAY NIGHT.
YOU KNOW, I WAS THINKING
THAT MAYBE IT
MIGHT BE SOMETHING
THAT YOUR PARENTS,
THEY'RE PROBABLY NOT,
YOU DON'T WANT TO GO SEE
SOME SILLY BOLLYWOOD
CRAZINESS AND DRESSES.
HE'S GOING TO CHOREOGRAPH
A BIG DANCE FOR US!
THAT SOUNDS FANTASTIC!
I'D LOVE TO SEE THAT!
WE CAN ALL DO
SOMETHING ELSE TOGETHER.
AND THE SARIS, RIGHT?
I LOVE THAT.
I'VE SEEN THAT IN MOVIES,
THAT'S WONDERFUL,
AND IT'S REALLY
ROMANTIC TOO, HUH?
[LAUGHING]
SURE, WE'D LOVE TO DO THAT!
YEAH, NO,
WE WOULD LOVE TO DO THAT.
AS LONG AS WE
DON'T HAVE TO DANCE.
AND WE GET TO MEET YOUR DAD.
THAT'D BE NICE! I'D LIKE THAT.
SURE.
EVERYBODY'S INTO IT.
IT'S GOING TO BE AWESOME.
[FATHER]: YEAH.
[CASH REGISTER DINGS]
[COIN RATTLES ON TABLE]
SO, SHOULD A FATHER
UNEQUIVOCALLY TAKE
CARE OF HIS SONS?
IS THAT
YOUR SENSE OF IT?
YEAH, I MEAN,
NONE OF US ASKED TO BE BORN.
I MEAN, THEY'RE THE ONES
WHO DRAGGED INTO THIS MESS.
I HAVE THE LAST WILL
AND TESTAMENT OF PETER ADAMS.
"BEING OF SOUND MIND
AND DISPOSING MY MEMORY
AND UNDERSTANDING
AFTER CONSIDERATION
FOR ALL PERSONS, OBJECTS..."
MIKEY, MIKEY, MIKEY,
THAT'S GREAT.
I RESPECT YOU'RE A LAWYER,
IT'S GREAT,
BUT I THINK WE SHOULD JUST
GET TO THE...TO THE MEAT.
SKIP
THE LEGALESE.
YOU WANT
TO DO IT THAT WAY,
YOU WANT TO GET
RIGHT INTO IT.
LET'S GET INTO IT.
OKAY, FINE.
UH, "I, PETER ADAMS,
WILL DISTRIBUTE MY ASSETS
AS FOLLOWS.
ALL LIQUID ASSETS
WILL BE DIVIDED EQUALLY
BETWEEN DAVID ADAMS,
MICHAEL ADAMS,
HENRY ADAMS,
AND SEAN ADAMS."
[EXHALES DEEPLY]
UH, "THE AMOUNT
TOTALLING $100,000 EACH."
EACH! YES!
YES.
"WITH REGARDS TO DAVID,
MY ELDEST SON,
THE AMOUNT WILL INCLUDE
THE SUBTRACTION OF EIGHT YEARS
ROOM AND BOARD,
CALCULATED
AT FAIR MARKET VALUE,
TOTALLING $30,000."
WHAT?
WHAT WAS THAT?
[MICHAEL]: "ALSO TO BE DEDUCTED
A BRIDGE LOAN REPAYMENT
ON LOAN NUMBER 21638..."
LOAN NUMBER
21638?
"SECURED THROUGH
THE ROYAL BANK OF CANADA,
FOR THE AMOUNT OF $60,000,
LEAVING DAVID ADAMS'
TOTAL PAYOUT AT $10,000."
WHAT IS THAT?
MARLOWE, MARLOWE,
WAIT, WAIT, WAIT. WAIT.
I GOT TWO WORDS,
MARLOWE!
LESSON LEARNED.
I'M SORRY, DAVID,
IT'S THE WAY DAD WANTED IT.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND
WHAT THAT MEANS.
WHAT DOES THAT MEAN,
HE'S DEDUCTING RENT?
I WAS LOOKING AFTER HIM,
FOR CHRIST'S SAKE.
I KNOW YOU WERE, DAVID.
I'M SORRY.
IT WAS FAIR MARKET VALUE.
I GOT A TIP FOR YA.
GONNA WIPE A MAN'S ASS
FOR A LIVING?
GET THE CASH UP FRONT.
"WITH REGARDS
TO HENRY ADAMS, MY THIRD SON,
THIS $100,000 BEQUEATHMENT
WILL BE MINUS
THE $75,000 TUITION
AT THREE POST-SECONDARY
INSTITUTIONS..."
HOLY SHIT.
WHAT?
"AND NUMEROUS DEBTS
AND FINANCIAL HANDOUTS
ACCRUED DURING THE LAST DECADE,
LEAVING THE AMOUNT
TO BE PAID MY SON HENRY
AT $4,650."
OH, THAT COCKSUCKER!
ALL RIGHT, OKAY.
"WITH REGARDS TO MY MIDDLE SON,
MICHAEL,
$100,000 WILL BE LEFT TO HIM,
IN TRUST,
FOR MY GRANDSON MAX ADAMS
IN AN EDUCATION FUND."
FUCK. FUCK!
"WITH REGARDS
TO MY YOUNGEST SON, SEAN ADAMS,
HE WILL ALSO RECEIVE
THE SUM TOTAL OF $100,000."
[HENRY]: MINUS?
IS THAT IT? MINUS WHAT?
HE TOOK A BIG, FAT FUCKING LOAN
WHEN HE WENT TO L.A.
WELL...
AM I WRONG?
NO, YOU'RE RIGHT,
BUT I PAID IT BACK.
AFTER THE FIRST SEASON,
I PAID HIM BACK.
I BORROWED 25 GRAND,
TO GO TO L.A., GOT THE SHOW,
AND I PAID HIM BACK.
IT'S FUCKIN' SIMPLE.
THAT'S TRUE, YEAH.
IT'S SIMPLE
ARITHMETIC HERE.
"SIMPLE ARITHMETIC."
[MICHAEL]:
"WITH REGARDS TO THE $94,350
AND THE 90,000 LEFT OVER
FROM HENRY
AND DAVID'S BEQUEATHMENT,
THIS AMOUNT WILL GO
TO THE UNIVERSITY
OF BRITISH COLUMBIA
FOR THE MAINTENANCE
AND UPKEEP
OF 290 KELVIN GROVE."
OH...
WAIT, I DON'T WANT TO BE
A PRICK HERE, BUT--
WHAT DOES THAT MEAN?
WELL, HE'S LEAVING,
ESSENTIALLY, $180,000
FOR THE UPKEEP
OF THIS HOUSE.
YEAH?
BECAUSE HE'S GIVING
THE HOUSE TO THE UNIVERSITY.
ARE YOU TELLING ME
WE'RE NOT SELLING THE HOUSE?
WHAT DO YOU MEAN,
THE UNIVERSITY GETS IT?
[MICHAEL]: THE HOUSE
IS GOING TO THE UNIVERSITY.
WHAT THE FUCK
ARE THEY GOING TO DO
WITH A HOUSE?
THESE WERE DAD'S WISHES.
WHAT THE FUCK
DOES A UNIVERSITY
NEED A HOUSE FOR?
HOLD IT. MIKE,
MIKE, WAIT, WAIT.
WHAT THE FUCK
IS GOING ON HERE?
[MICHAEL]: I KNOW
THERE'S A LOT TO DIGEST HERE.
[MARLOWE]: DID YOU
HELP HIM WITH THAT?
YOU TELL ME THE FUCKING TRUTH.
DID YOU HELP HIM WRITE THIS?
WHEN DID YOU GET THIS?
I'VE HAD IT IN MY POSSESSION
FOR THE LAST COUPLE OF YEARS.
WHEN DID YOU READ IT?
I READ IT WHEN I KNEW
I WAS COMING OUT HERE
TO DO THIS.
YOU DIDN'T WANT
TO GIVE ME A HEAD'S UP
BEFORE I FUCKING
SCRAPED TOGETHER
EVERYTHING I HAD
TO GET HERE?
IT'S WHAT DAD WANTED.
I'M SORRY.
UGH...
[MICHAEL]:
DAVID, I'M VERY SORRY.
[HENRY]: DO YOU KNOW
THE RISK I TAKE
EVERY TIME
I CROSS THE BORDER?
WHY WOULDN'T YOU GIVE ME
A HEAD'S UP?
WHY WOULDN'T YOU JUST TELL ME,
"HENRY, YOU'RE GETTING FUCKED.
STAY HOME."
BECAUSE THEN
YOU WOULDN'T HAVE COME.
THAT'S RIGHT,
I WOULDN'T HAVE COME.
SO WHAT?
[MICHAEL]: WHOA, WHOA, WHOA.
DAVID. DAVID!
OH, HERE COMES
THE CEREMONY.
WHOA!
CALM DOWN. CALM DOWN.
[HENRY]:
TAKE IT EASY, MARLOWE.
YOU'RE GOING TO GET DAD
ALL OVER YOUR BURKA.
I KNOW
YOU DON'T WANT THAT.
SIT DOWN!
I GOT IT, I GOT IT.
DAVID,
TAKE IT DOWN.
I GOT IT.
[HENRY]: SIT DOWN,
HAVE A DRINK.
WHO GIVES A SHIT?
SHUT UP, HENRY!
SHUT YOUR FUCKING MOUTH
FOR FIVE SECONDS.
WHO CARES?
HOLD IT, HOLD IT,
HOLD IT, HO--
SIT THE FUCK DOWN!
FUCK YOU.
OKAY, ALL RIGHT.
ALL RIGHT.
[♪♪♪]
YOU'VE BEEN FRISKY
EVER SINCE YOU GOT HERE.
WHY DON'T YOU TELL ME
WHAT'S GOING ON?
I LOST MY JOB.
YOU LOST YOUR JOB?
AND YOU CAN'T FIX IT?
THAT'S WHERE YOU CAME IN.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
YOU MEAN
THAT LITTLE BIT OF MONEY?
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT I CAN DO
FOR YOU, BUT...
YEAH, I DON'T KNOW
WHAT YOU CAN DO
FOR ME EITHER.
IT'S JUST PRETTY MUCH
BEEN THE SAME STORY,
MY WHOLE LIFE.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
WHAT HAVE YOU
DONE FOR ME?
THIS AN OLD
JANET JACKSON RECORD?
"WHAT HAVE YOU DONE
FOR ME LATELY?"
WHAT HAVE YOU
DONE FOR ME, REALLY?
YOU DON'T REMEMBER
NOTHING I DID FOR YOU?
NO. WHAT? TELL ME.
TELL ME.
SAME AS ALWAYS.
KNOW WHY?
BECAUSE I GOTTA
BAIL YOU OUT.
I GOTTA PAY OFF
YOUR HOUSE.
I GOTTA PAY YOUR TAXES.
I GOTTA FIX YOU UP.
WHY I GOTTA DO THAT
FOR YOU?
I'VE NEVER ASKED YOU
FOR ANY OF THAT.
I KNOW THAT.
YOU WOULDN'T HAVE.
I DON'T GET YOU.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND YOU.
SO MANY OPPORTUNITIES, MAN.
SO MANY OPPORTUNITIES
COME AND GONE.
IF YOU HAD JUST DONE...
ONE THING,
AND FOLLOWED THAT THROUGH
TO ITS COMPLETION,
I--I'D BE IMPRESSED.
JUST ONE THING.
YOU WOULDN'T BE SITTING HERE,
WITH NOTHING,
WHILE ALL YOUR FRIENDS,
WHO STARTED THE SAME PLACE
YOU WERE,
THEY ALL MADE IT.
THEY ALL MADE IT!
ALL OF THEM!
I DON'T UNDERSTAND
HOW YOU CAN JUST SIT THERE
AND WATCH THAT HAPPEN.
YOU KNOW, YOU WANT TO KNOW
WHAT'S WRONG WITH ME?
YOU KNOW
I HAD TO LEARN HOW TO BE A MAN
FROM MY MOTHER,
BECAUSE MY FATHER,
I DON'T KNOW WHERE HE WAS.
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT HE WAS DOING.
HE DIDN'T SHOW UP.
I NEVER WANT TO BE LIKE YOU.
I NEVER...
[CLAPS THIGHS]
I'M DONE.
WAS IT EVER
YOUR HOPE,
AS A YOUNGER MAN,
TO GROW UP TO BE
LIKE YOUR FATHER?
WHAT DO YOU MEAN,
"TO BE LIKE" HIM?
HERE'S VODKA.
WE MUST DRINK
TO YOUR MOTHER.
I WILL START.
[♪♪♪]
[THUMP]
[EXHALES]
[CONTINUES POURING]
[FINISHES POURING]
[POURING SECOND DRINK]
[THUMPS BOTTLE DOWN]
[TAKES A BREATH]
[♪♪♪]
[COUGHING AND HACKING]
[SPUTTERS, COUGHS]
[SNIFFS]
[♪♪♪]
[THUD]
[GAGS AND GULPS]
[GAGS, GULPS]
[THUMP]
[STARTS GIGGLING]
[CRACKING UP]
[LAUGHING SILENTLY]
[STARTS CRACKING UP LOUDLY]
[♪♪♪]
[WHEEZING AND COUGHING]
TO MIRIAM.
GOOD. GOOD.
I'M TALKING ABOUT, LIKE,
A TWO-WEEK-OLD...
[HENRY GROANS]: OHH...
NEWBORN BABY.
MORE SHOW BUSINESS ANECDOTES.
I CAN'T GET ENOUGH!
I'VE GOT IT
SWADDLED, RIGHT?
I'M RUNNING
DOWN THE HALL,
AND I'M BOBBLING
THIS LADY'S FUCKIN' BABY,
WHO SHE'S RENTED
TO THE PRODUCTION
FOR, LIKE, 400 BUCKS
FOR THE DAY.
WHERE YOU GOING?
YOU KNOW, SEAN,
I KNOW YOU COULD GO ALL NIGHT.
I KNOW YOU'VE REHEARSED
A MILLION OF THESE,
AND YOU TROT THEM OUT
AT EVERY OPPORTUNITY, BUT...
ARE YOU COMING OVER
TO HEAR THE STORY?
IF YOU PAUSE
THE ANECDOTES FOR A SECOND,
I GOT SOME QUESTIONS I WANT
TO ASK MY BIG BROTHER HERE.
NO, I'VE HEARD IT.
I SAW IT
ON ONE OF THOSE SHOWS.
RIGHT. [SNICKERING]
YOU'RE SUCH A COCK.
LET ME ASK YOU A QUESTION.
HOW DID YOU MAKE IT
THROUGH LAW SCHOOL?
WHO PAID FOR THAT?
YEAH, WEREN'T YOU
LIVING AT HOME
WHEN, UH, WHEN YOU
WENT TO LAW SCHOOL?
YEAH. WHERE'S
THE TALLY FOR THAT?
YEAH, HOW COME...
HOW COME YOU DIDN'T
CONVINCE DAD TO, UH,
TO TAKE YOUR LITTLE...
OH, BUT, SORRY, THAT WAS
THE TEAM OF LAWYERS
THAT YOU KNEW
NOTHING ABOUT.
OH, THAT'S RIGHT.
A TEAM OF LAWYERS!
DAD HAD A TEAM OF LAWYERS
OVER HERE.
YOU THINK WE'RE BUYING
THAT FOR A SECOND?
IT'S GOT YOUR FINGERPRINTS
ALL OVER IT.
THOSE DEBTS WERE
TAKEN CARE OF A LONG TIME AGO.
WE DON'T EVEN NEED
TO TALK ABOUT THEM.
OH, APPARENTLY WE DO.
ARE YOU GONNA
LOOK ME IN THE EYE
AND TELL ME
YOU HAD NOTHING TO DO
WITH THAT PIECE OF PAPER
YOU READ TO US TONIGHT?
I DON'T BELIEVE THAT
FOR A SECOND.
YOU KNOW
WHAT I'M TALKING ABOUT.
I HAVE NO IDEA WHAT
YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT!
YOU ARE THE ARCHITECT
OF THIS!
YOU THINK WE BUY FOR A SECOND
THAT YOU DIDN'T,
YOU WEREN'T TALKING TO DAD
ABOUT THIS WELL IN ADVANCE?
YOU WANT
TO SETTLE THE SCORE.
YOU WANT TO SEE HENRY
PAY THE PIPER.
YOU WANT TO SEE MARLOWE
YOU WANT TO SEE US
ON THE HOOK, RIGHT?
[SEAN]: WHAT THE FUCK
IS "PAY THE PIPER," MAN?
RIGHT? BECAUSE
YOU'RE A SELF-MADE MAN,
JUST LIKE THE OLD MAN,
AND SO NOW...
IT'S NOT MY BUSINESS, HENRY.
IT'S NOT MY BUSINESS.
YOU'RE GOING TO TAKE UP
THE MANTLE
OF THE GREAT
PROTESTANT WORK ETHIC.
DON'T ALIGN YOURSELF
WITH HIM.
AM I RIGHT?
DON'T ALIGN YOURSELF
WITH HIM.
DON'T STAND NEXT TO THIS GUY.
YOU CAN MAKE THIS RIGHT.
YOU CAN.
YOU KNOW
WHAT I'M TALKING ABOUT.
[MICHAEL]: I CAN'T
DO ANYTHING!
YOU KNOW ALL THE TRICKS.
YOU SET THIS UP
IN THE FUCKING FIRST PLACE!
SERIOUSLY.
WHAT DO YOU SUGGEST I DO?
DON'T FUCKING
PUSH ME!
I SUGGEST THAT WE REOPEN
THE DOCUMENT.
[ROARS]: REOPEN THE DOCUMENT?
IT'S A FUCKING WILL!
IT'S DONE! IT'S FINISHED!
FUCKING IDIOT!
GET THAT FUCKING MESS
OFF, YOU PIECE OF SHIT!
GET YOUR FUCKING HANDS
OFF OF HIM!
YOU FUCKING...
AH! FUCK YOU!
JESUS. COME ON.
PIECE OF SHIT!
WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
HUH, YOU JUST
GOING TO WALK--
YEAH, WALK AWAY NOW.
WHO GIVES A SHIT,
RIGHT?
I'M NOT GOING ANYWHERE!
YOU'RE TAKEN CARE OF.
I'M STANDING HERE LISTENING
TO YOUR FUCKING BULLSHIT!
COME ON, COME ON.
YOUR KID'S
TAKEN CARE OF.
IT'S ALL SET UP,
RIGHT?
[ROARS]: YOU TAKE UP
ALL THE SPACE
IN THIS FUCKING ROOM!
YOU CAN'T SHUT UP!
YOU HAVE BEEN GIVEN
EVERYTHING.
YOU HAVE TAKEN EVERYTHING
FROM THIS FAMILY,
AND YOU KNOW
WHAT YOU ARE, HENRY?
AT THE END OF THE DAY,
YOU ARE A PATHETIC
FUCKING FAILURE!
FUCK YOU.
GOOD NIGHT, MICHAEL.
[DOOR SLAMS UPSTAIRS]
OH, GODDAMN IT.
SORRY ABOUT THAT.
THAT GOT A FUCKING MESSY.
I WAS DRUNK WHEN
I MET YOUR MOTHER.
IT WAS IN, UM,
A BANYA,
UM, LIKE SAUNA.
I WAS DRINKING FOR THREE DAYS,
AND...
I WANTED TO TAKE PISS,
YOU KNOW?
I WOKE UP, AND
THERE WAS THIS...
VISION, THIS...
THIS GODDESS
COMING OUT OF THE LAKE.
SHE HAD SUCH
BEAUTIFUL BREASTS,
LIKE RUBIES.
SUCH BEAUTIFUL VAGINA.
SHE SMILED AT ME.
[CHUCKLES SOFTLY]
WE WENT BACK INSIDE,
AND SHE LAID DOWN ON BENCH.
I POURED VODKA OVER HOT ROCKS,
AND I PICK UP...
BIG BIRCH BRANCH,
AND, LIKE, I BEAT HER WITH.
NOT HARD,
IT'S LIKE RUSSIAN TRADITION.
IT'S GOOD FOR CIRCULATION.
THEN SHE,
SHE BEAT ME WITH IT,
AND THEN WE WENT OUTSIDE
AND WE MADE LOVE IN THE SNOW.
I'VE FUCKED LOT OF WOMANS,
BUT...
I'VE ONLY MADE LOVE TO ONE.
WHAT?
[SNIFFLES]
DON'T CRY.
PLEASE, DO NOT CRY.
[SOBS]
IS NOT GOOD
FOR MAN TO CRY.
[MUFFLED SOB]:
IT'S TOO MUCH.
WHAT?
I CAN'T TAKE THE PAIN.
WHAT PAIN?
THIS IS NOT PAIN.
YOU HAVE NO IDEA
WHAT PAIN IS.
THIS IS LIKE
BULLSHIT PAIN.
THIS IS...
WHAT YOU ARE
CRYING ABOUT?
YOU MUST KNOW
WHAT PAIN IS?
[SOBBING]
HERE,
GIVE ME YOUR HAND.
PLEASE.
[SNIFFLING]
PLEASE,
GIVE ME YOUR HAND.
GOOD.
SEE THIS, HERE?
OKAY.
[CRIES OUT]: OW!
THAT IS REAL PAIN
THAT YOU MUST FEEL,
NOT THIS BULLSHIT PAIN.
YOU WANT TO BE MAN?
FUCK!
ALL RIGHT TO BE HOMOSEXUAL,
YOU KNOW?
YOU WANT TO?
OKAY, LOOK, HERE.
[PUTS KNIFE DOWN]
COME ON.
WHERE IS MY KNIFE?
[FLICK]
[QUIETLY]: GET OUT.
WHAT?
GET OUT.
WHY SHOULD I GET OUT?
GET OUT OF THIS HOUSE.
YOU WANT TO FEEL PAIN?
WHAT IS WRONG
WITH YOU?
YOU WANT TO FEEL PAIN.
I SHOW YOU WHAT PAIN IS.
[BELLOWS]: BE A MAN,
FOR CHRIST'S SAKE!
I AM MORE OF A MAN
THAN YOU EVER WERE.
WHAT ARE YOU
SAYING?
I AM MORE OF A MAN
THAN YOU EVER WERE.
WHAT DID YOU
FUCKING SAY TO ME?
YOU WANT ME TO SHOW YOU
WHAT FUCKING BEING MAN IS?
PICK UP THAT KNIFE.
PICK UP THAT FUCK--
GOOD!
NOW I WILL SHOW YOU WHAT IT IS
TO BE A REAL MAN, HUH?
COME FOR ME! COME.
COME!
I'M READY FOR YOU!
[KICKS CHAIR]
GET AWAY FROM ME!
COME ON, COME ON.
COME ON.
LIKE FATHER AND SON,
WE WILL FIGHT
AND WE WILL FEEL PAIN TOGETHER!
COME, COME.
AHH!
SON A BITCH!
YOU LIKE THAT, HUH?
COME ON,
YOU LITTLE BASTARD.
AH, YOU LIKE THAT? HUH?
HUH? YOU LIKE THAT, HUH?
AH! YOU SON OF A BITCH! AHH!
WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
[♪♪♪]
COME BACK!
[RETCHING]
HEY, COME.
COME HERE.
[WHEEZING AND GASPING]
I CAN'T--
ARE YOU OKAY?
MY HEART, I--
[STABS HIM, BERNIE CRIES OUT]
[ANTON CHUCKLES]
NOW, THAT IS PAIN.
FEELS GOOD, YES?
OH, MY GOD.
NOW WE MUST GET MORE VODKA.
COME. HERE.
GET UP.
ONE, TWO, THREE.
[BERNIE STABS HIM]
AAH!
[GASPING]
I JUST BOUGHT THIS SHIRT.
OH, GOD.
[THUD]
[♪♪♪]
[DOG BARKS IN DISTANCE]
HEY...
THAT WAS GOOD KNIFE FIGHT.
[♪♪♪]
[SIGHS]
[RIFLE BLAST CRACKS]
[RAVENS CALLING,
WINGS BEATING]
NO, NO, NO, NO, NO, NO!
I WANT IT BACK LIKE THIS,
AND THEN I WANT IT HERE, OKAY?
I TOLD YOU
SO MANY TIMES, HUH?
NOW, WHERE THE HELL
IS NEHNA?
HER MUMMY'S HERE,
HER DADDY'S HERE,
KAMA'S HERE, BUT NO,
NEHNA IS NOT HERE.
I'M NOT SURPRISED.
DON'T TELL ME, I JUST WANT TO
FIND OUT WHERE SHE IS.
DO YOUR BLOODY JOB, HUH?
I DON'T KNOW!
SHE DIDN'T TELL US.
YOU SPENT
SO MUCH TIME ON THIS.
SHUT UP AND GET READY, OKAY?
[DIALING]
[♪♪♪]
NEHNA, PICK UP, PICK UP.
PICK UP, OH...
HELLO, NEHNA!
SUTISH AGAIN, OKAY?
NOW, YOU CALL ME
RIGHT AWAY, OKAY?
EVERYBODY'S HERE,
WE'RE WAITING FOR YOU. HUH?
CALL ME BACK.
[♪♪♪]
I'M GOING TO DO IT.
I'M GOING
TO DO THE DANCE.
SUTISH...
NO, NO. NO "SUTISH,"
I'M GOING TO DO IT.
SUTISH, YOU'RE A BEAUTIFUL
CHOREOGRAPHER, OKAY?
DON'T GET ME WRONG.
IF I CAN TEACH IT,
I CAN DANCE IT, OKAY?
OKAY, AND WHAT ARE YOU
GOING TO WEAR, HUH?
I'M GOING TO, I'M GOING--
GO GET ME A SARI.
JUST GO GET ME
A BLOODY SARI, OKAY?
GO! GO, MAKE YOURSELF USEFUL.
HURRY.
BUT WHAT ABOUT
YOUR ARTHRITIS?
NO, NO, NO. NO, NO, NO.
NOT A SARI, A LEHNGA.
THE PINK ONE.
THE PINK LEHNGA.
OH, SUTISH.
GO! SHUT UP. JUST GO!
HE'S LOST HIS MIND.
NOW, LADIES, COME HERE.
MAKE ME BEAUTIFUL.
[♪♪♪]
[LAUGHING]
♪ KAMA, MY LITTLE BOY ♪
♪ MY ONLY PRIDE AND JOY ♪
♪ I RAISE YOU
SINCE YOU A CHILD ♪
♪ I KNOW IT TOOK A WHILE ♪
♪ AND NOW YOU ARE A MAN ♪
♪ MAKING YOUR VERY OWN PLAN ♪
♪ YOU HAD A LOT TO PROVE ♪
♪ MAKING
THIS VERY BIG MOVE ♪
♪ LIFE CAN BE A SWIRL ♪
♪ WHEN YOU MARRY
A WHITE GIRL ♪
♪ BUT DON'T GET SO BUSY ♪
♪ AND DON'T FORGET DADDY ♪
[♪♪♪]
♪ MY DAUGHTER WITH BLUE EYES ♪
♪ I WISH
I HAD YOUR THIGHS ♪
[GUESTS CRACKING UP]
[♪♪♪]
[SUTISH]:
KAMA, WE'RE JUST HAVING FUN.
WOULD YOU GROW UP
FOR ONCE?
YOU MUST STOP.
YOU CAN'T JUST LEAVE ALL YOUR
FRIENDS BEHIND LIKE THIS.
COME. COME ON.
WHAT'S GOING ON?
KAMA, STOP IT!
DON'T TOUCH ME!
STOP IT! WHAT
IS THIS NONSENSE?
ALWAYS RUNNING?
ALWAYS HIDING, HUH?
WHY CAN'T YOU GROW UP?
SHUT UP! SHUT UP!
WHY DO YOU ALWAYS
HAVE TO ACT
LIKE A DUMB FUCKING
HINDU FAGGOT?
[SLAP]
SUTISH? SUTISH...
WHAT DID YOU CALL HIM?
YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND.
NO. YOU JUST
LEAVE ME ALONE.
[HENRY SIGHS WEARILY]
[♪♪♪]
MORNING.
[CLEARS HIS THROAT]
WELL, I'M GLAD
YOU'RE ALL HERE, ACTUALLY.
UH...
HENRY?
I WANT YOU TO LISTEN TO THIS.
I, UH, HAD AN IDEA.
I WAS JUST UP IN THE GARAGE,
I WAS SITTIN'
IN THE OLD GALAXY,
AND IT JUST STARTED,
YOU KNOW,
MAKING ME THINK ABOUT
OUR SUNDAY AFTERNOON DRIVES,
AND HOW THOSE WERE SORT OF
THE ONLY MEMORIES I HAVE
OF ALL FOUR OF US TOGETHER.
ALL FIVE OF US TOGETHER,
ACTUALLY,
AND I THINK THAT MARLOWE'S IDEA
WAS A GOOD IDEA.
I THINK THAT WE SHOULD
HOP IN THE GALAXY,
TAKE THE ASHES,
FOUR BROTHERS,
FOUR ELEMENTS,
FOUR LOCATIONS.
[FLOPS PAPER DOWN]
I GOT A 2:00 FLIGHT,
BUT I'M IN.
I GET TO BE FIRE.
YEAH.
THAT'S A GIVEN.
[EXHALES HEAVILY]
MARLOWE?
IT'S YOUR IDEA.
I'M JUST TRYING TO RUN WITH IT,
WHAT DO YOU SAY?
OKAY.
YEAH? GOOD MAN.
[♪♪♪]
[PLINKING PIANO KEYS]
[HENRY]: GIVEN THAT THIS CAR
ISN'T MENTIONED IN THE WILL,
IS IT SAFE TO ASSUME
THIS IS GOING TO BE
THE PIMP RIDE
FOR VISITING PROFS?
[SEAN GIGGLES]:
"PIMP RIDE."
WHY NOT?
[♪♪♪]
OHH! OH YEAH!
COME ON.
UM, MIKEY,
I THINK YOU SHOULD DO THIS.
YEAH?
YEAH.
ANYONE MIND?
[BIRDS SINGING]
JUST POUR IT?
I GUESS.
JUST DUMP IT, YEAH.
DON'T DUMP
ALL OF IT, THOUGH.
YOU GOTTA SAVE ENOUGH
FOR THE REST OF US.
ALL RIGHT.
[SOFT FOOTFALLS]
[♪♪♪]
[MICHAEL]:
SEEMS TO BE BLOWING EAST.
SHOULD WE TRY THIS?
YEAH, SURE.
ALL RIGHT.
[WIND GUSTING]
OKAY, KEEP YOUR EYES CLOSED.
IT'S IN YOUR EARS, MAN.
THANK YOU.
IT WASN'T QUITE
WHAT I IMAGINED.
IT WAS VERY MOVING.
[QUIETLY]:
I'M SORRY, DAD.
I KNOW...
[VOICE BREAKS]:
AND I'M SORRY I HIT YOU.
I'M SO SORRY.
I'M SO SORRY, KAMA.
I LOVE YOU SO MUCH.
I'M SO SORRY
I HIT YOU.
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
I'M SORRY TOO, DAD. I LOVE YOU.
I LOVE YOU TOO, KAMA.
[SNIFFLES]
I MESSED UP, DAD.
THAT'S OKAY.
WHERE IS AMBER?
SHE WON'T TALK TO ME.
WHAT?
WHY?
[EXHALES HEAVILY]
BECAUSE I FUCKED UP.
[SIGHS WEARILY]
I FUCKED UP.
YOU HAVE TO GO OUT
AND GO FIND HER.
YOU NEED TO GO TALK TO HER.
NOW. YOU NEED
TO DO IT VERY QUICKLY.
CAN'T WAIT.
SHE WON'T TALK TO ME.
SHE WILL TALK TO YOU.
[SIGHS WEARILY]
THIS IS NO LONGER
ABOUT YOU AND I, OKAY?
THERE'S NO APOLOGIES
BETWEEN FATHERS AND SONS.
THIS IS NOW ABOUT
YOU AND AMBER.
YOU LOVE HER,
SHE LOVES YOU.
WE...WE WILL FIX THIS.
YEAH.
[♪♪♪]
[BALL HITS BACKBOARD,
BOUNCES]
[♪♪♪]
PIZZA. LET'S GO.
THIS IS IT.
YOU REMEMBER
THIS PLACE, RIGHT?
UNCLE FATIH'S.
YEAH.
THE YEAR I TURNED 16,
I WANTED TO GO TO ART CAMP,
BUT THE OLD MAN SAID
16-YEAR-OLDS
DON'T GO TO SUMMER CAMP,
THEY GET A JOB,
SO I WOUND UP HERE.
[SEAN]: GET ME
A COUPLE SLICES OF PEP.
[MICHAEL]: LOOK, I GOT
TWO HOURS, ALL RIGHT?
OH, YOU'RE GOOD.
WE GOT PLENTY OF TIME.
I'M HUNGRY
AS SHIT, THOUGH.
YOU'RE VEG, RIGHT? VEG?
YEAH, THERE'S A VEG
IN THERE.
GO AHEAD.
THANK YOU.
YOU WANT THIS?
I'LL TAKE
THE 'RONI.
HERE.
UH...
HE'S IN THE OVEN.
LET'S GO.
WE GOT TO GET HIM
TO THE AIRPORT.
THAT'S YOUR FIRE?
LET'S GO.
WOW.
YOU PUT DAD IN THE OVEN?
YEAH.
[WILD CAT GROWLS]
[RIFLE CLICKS]
[WILD CAT ROARS]
[RIFLE SHOT ECHOES]
[WINCING GASP]
FUCK.
[EXHALES DEEPLY]
[♪♪♪]
[PLAYS "ROW, ROW, ROW YOUR BOAT"
SLIGHTLY BETTER]
[BOY FINISHES SONG]
[BLU]: WOW.
[BLU APPLAUDS]
WONDERFUL.
ONE MORE TIME.
[♪♪♪]
[PATS BLU'S HAND]
[PLAYS FINAL CHORD]
[BLU CHUCKLING WARMLY]
A FATHER IS SOMEBODY WHO...
CAN TELL YOU
WHAT KIND OF MAN YOU ARE.
I THINK THE MOST IMPORTANT
QUALITY FOR A FATHER
IS BALANCE.
TEMPERANCE.
YOU LOVE YOUR KIDS.
I MEAN, THAT'S A GIVEN.
GIVE YOUR KID, UM,
SOME ROOM TO BREATHE.
[♪♪♪]
THE MINUTE I SAW THAT BOY,
THAT WAS MY BABY.
THAT'S ME, RIGHT THERE.
YOU WILL ALWAYS BE
THEIR FATHER.
THEY WILL ALWAYS NEED YOU,
AND YOU, AS A FATHER,
MUST NEVER FORGET THAT.
THE MOMENT YOU DO,
YOU'RE NO LONGER A FATHER.
SHALL WE?
LET'S GO.
[♪♪♪]
WHOO!
OH, GOD!
[GUYS ROARING AND LAUGHING]
WHOO!
[SPLASHING AND LAUGHING
CONTINUE]
I'VE NEVER UNDERSTOOD THIS IDEA
OF THEM WANTING IT
TO BE AS HARD FOR US
AS IT WAS FOR THEM, LIKE,
BECAUSE IT'S SOMEHOW GOOD
FOR US.
I MEAN, IF I HAVE A KID,
I WANT IT TO BE
LESS HARD FOR HIM
THAN IT IS FOR ME.
MY FATHER MEASURED A MAN
BY HIS SUCCESS,
AND...
I THINK I'VE COME TO REALIZE
THAT YOU MEASURE A MAN BY HIS...
BY HIS FAMILY
AND THE WAY
HE TAKES CARE OF HIS FAMILY.
I'LL JUST SAY
THAT I WANTED HIM TO LOVE ME.
THAT I KNOW.
[♪♪♪]
THIS IS FOR YOU.
WAS MY FATHER'S.
I STOLE THAT FROM HIM.
IT IS TRADITION,
MUST BE PASSED ON
FROM FATHER TO SON.
[GRUNTS HIS APPROVAL]
[♪♪♪]
I-I HAD A DREAM ONCE, UH,
THAT I WAS WITH MY MOTHER,
AND...
THERE WAS A KNOCK
ON THE DOOR,
AND I SAID, "WHO'S THAT?"
AND SHE SAID,
"THAT'S YOUR FATHER."
AND I WENT TO OPEN THE DOOR,
AND I OPENED THE DOOR,
AND I LOOKED UP,
AND IT WAS TONY DANZA,
FROM"TAXI",
AND I SAID,
"ARE YOU MY FATHER?"
AND HE SAID,
"BET YOUR SWEET ASS I AM."
SO...
BET YOUR SWEET ASS I AM.
[GUNFIRE]
[BATTLE RAGES]
[♪♪♪]
OKAY, THAT'S NICE.
[CARL BESSAI]:
FASTER, THOUGH.
THAT'S NICE.
COME ON, ANTON.
OH, YOU GOT
GOOD BJ.
WAIT, WAIT, WAIT.
HIPS. GET YOUR
HIPS INTO IT.
WAIT, WAIT, WAIT.
HIPS.
OKAY, OKAY, HOLD UP.
HIPS. HIPS.
LISTEN, YOU'RE TALKING
MORE THAN I AM. OKAY?
I FEEL LIKE I'M GIVING YOU
A BLOWJOB.
YOU HAVE TO BE QUIET.
[LAUGHING]
YES, YES.
YOU'RE REALLY
TURNING ME ON, CARL.
AND...ACTION!
[LAUGHING]