I've talk a lot about her
You might be disappointed
You must like her
I like her...
...everyone courted her
here at the beach...
...she ignored everyone
They all came for her
graduation
We went everywhere
to look for lights
We lit them
all over the countryside
...everywhere...
She was happy
when she saw them
...I'd never seen her
that happy
What did she do?
She said: "Don't ever
put them out"
Go ahead
My heavens
You didn't forget...
Forget?
...just think, it's
exactly 10 years
That's right, come
My son is here...
can he come?
Of course...
I'm coming
I've got large pants
My son Nicola...
grown, huh?
- Yes...
- You remember him smaller
If you look around...
...you'll see weeds
everywhere
See the weeds?
Lots of cracks?
- Look at all those cracks...
- And the shutters?
Let's hurry and
go to the beach
...The professor is there...
He didn't want me
to call you
The people for
the party are here
...are we disturbing you?
Do you remember Vanni,
the cook's son?
Can you give us an indication
or shall I take care of it?
You take care of it
Say goodbye and follow me
Goodbye...
First the Germans arrived,
then the refugees
Now the vacationers
...it's no man's land. Do
you remember how it was?
- And my graduation party?
- Yes...
And the meal?
My mother prepared it
I'd like to see everything
as it was
I slept in that room there
From the walls to the sofas
everything as it was
We're not organized
...I've changed jobs
I thought it would be
a little garden
refreshment party
My daughter is graduating
with an A average!
She's the youngest
in her class
Do you know what that means
for her father and myself
- to live such a moment?!
- We need carpenters,
upholsterers and
bricklayers here
...the war has just finished
and everything is missing
Don't talk to me about costs!
We can't find anything
The professor was against
my calling you
You expect us to think
of everything
...I now have a pasta
factory...
My son is learning now
What did one do before?
Explain that to your son, huh?
If one had to change a faucet
...he'd call the plumber
No...
...he'd roll his sleeves up.
And instead he's making
cream puffs
I had the professor
get up at six
I made him cancel his
appointments and...
...come here for nothing
- It's not our fault
...at all
Your attitude and that of
your son confirms that
If I'd called Silvano,
he'd already be painting
- But he's a lifeguard
- Silvano can do everything
What did you study?
A little of everything
Do you know what
a "degree" is?
graduation means?
Yes...
Well then, explain
it to your father
Graduation means...
...having done well
in school
...and then...
I don't know...
- What should we do?
- Everything!
Did she convince us or
did we convince her?
She convinced us
- How did it go?
- So, so...
Wear a nice English suit
Go get undressed
Give me back my watch
You're downtrodden
No, she cornered us
How was the meeting
after so many years?
She didn't even ask me
how I was
This has to be fixed,
that has to be painted
That's what she said
Did you talk about the kiss?
No...
Does she know about
your factory?
Yes, but... Are the shoes
mine or yours?
Wear something classic
on our next meeting
- Are you finished?
- Yes!
Tie...
...shoes... shirt...
...pants... jacket... and pen
You put these on,
Giorgini...
Giorgini, you're beautiful
...a love...
The "cannoli" burned
- And the cream?
- That's been saved
It's a little bitter
The children is summer
camps eat them
Father be more careful.
Nicola and I are busy
They've come
to collect the rent
You go deliver
- II've got to see your mother
- Say hello for me
- It's me
- I see him
Everything is going well
Mrs. Franchi
wants me with her
Did she come back? Have
you already seen each other?
This morning
The worse they treat you
the more you chase them...
She's never treated
me badly
I must prepare
the whole house
She only trust me and
doesn't talk about prices
Did you accept?
Yes, she always pays
And now...
Take a shower
He's a pig... if you
knew what he tells me
You'll never change
- I've never liked you
- You either
But you used to take me
behind the shed
Why did you marry me?
Because of my father
I've come for those two
you adopted
- One works
- And the other?
- Steals?
- He's getting on
Why did you adopt
those children?
I like them
You had one and
you left him with me
He was too stupid... like you
...he would have grieved me
I'll make a carreer
for Nicola!
Send those two to work for me
The bread comes out good
if the ingredients are good
...and even the day
to come is good
How did it come out?
Good.
We must take that work
I don't agree
They live with your mother
...they are only workers
They must respect you
Are you orphans?
Get on and be quiet
Take the tools
- What are your names?
- Davide e Dario.
I've been told...
that one of you is a smart
aleck... not with me
- Clear?
- Yes...
My son Nicola.
Shake hands
It's rusty
Shall I do it?
Do you know how?
Done
Let's close
No one must enter here
Did you see the weeds?
- See the windows?
- And the shutters?
Who is there?
Who should work?
You...
- Who are you?
- Vacationers!
Vacationers... we
always come here
We're not refugees
The Latin professor
is here for her
Where did you get
the stuff?
Inside...
- How did you get in?
- From the beach
My father will take
care of them
This is a private property
We must work
If the owner comes,
she might fire us
Where shall we go
for the weekend?
- I don't know...
- You don't know?!
Well then, why did
we fight this war?
To have the owners
come back?
- And where will we go?
- There's the beach
Oh! We stay in the desert...
and you here living it up!
Don't sent them away...
Finish eating and then leave
Thank you...
Hurry...
- Let's start from here
- Move
Aren't you changing?
We'll bring everything inside
Let's haul everything
on the cart
Porelli...
...a phone call...
...in an hour from Bologna...
What are you doing here?
I'm waiting for a phone call
For you
Hello?
I can't hear
It's me
Madam...
- How is the work?
- I had to hire
some technicians...
they're not expensive
I'm coming Saturday
...my daughter
is arriving today
Alright
Madaam, may I ask you
a question?
10 years ago, the day
war was declared
...do you remember
what happened?
...I always think
about it and...
- Sir...
- I'm talking!
- With who?
- They've already hung up
- Vanni!
- Sandra!
...it's the daughter...
You've become a woman
They are my friends
They're going to help me
organize the party
He's the son
of the cook
How is it going?
- Fine...
- My friends are curious
Will you be on time?
- Do you need a hand?
- Lf necessary,
we'll even work
during the night
Will they pull out
these weeds?
Of course!
- And the buffet?
- I'd put it under the porch
Who will prepare it?
Them?! Are they
capable of it?
My mother trusts them.
She's known them a long time
The party will be wonderful!
...my father is an expert...
- What do you do?
- In the pastry business
I'm just beginning
I'm sorry about
this new work
It's an experience
- Are you from Bologna?
- Yes... how can you tell?
You seem presumptuous
but actually...
...you're not at all...
like us...
Is he bothering you?
- We chatted
- Keep on working
- He's naive
- No...
He is for his age
...I'm fond of him
because he's that way
I'm grateful to him...
...for being that way
- Are you courting her?
- I'm trying...
- I've got a plan
- What?
To conquer her!
More cakes?!
I don't have meat
Did grandfather
make them?
...They're rancid...
- They taste like fish
- Terrible?
- Lf you close your eyes
they're like fried soles
Try it...
Taste it?
Whatch out... for the bones
- Let's hope Sandra passes
- Of course
I'm very hungry
Will she have
a good average?
- At least a B
- Of course
We have children and cannot
sleep away from home
My sister lives with her
family in Bologna
...we have a bathroom
there... they don't...
...when we're not there,
they wash
That's how we're organized
We thought you'd
leave at dusk
...and we'd come over...
I't's night already and
the children are tired
Alright
- You can stay here
- It's not anything special
Don't be difficult
Bring the mattresses...
only for the children
- And Dario?
- He's speaking outside
Let's call him
II don't think he'll come
I won't pay him
Our mother really
embarasses us
I sslept in a cemetery
Sleeping like this...
...all together like refugees
...just to show that we
go on vacation too
Look here
It's a list of new things
- Who has it?
- As long as you order,
I'll take care of getting it
...it will take
a few days but...
...if your family
is interested
What do you do here?
I work for that
big-nosed man
...the party for a...
I don't know her
but if you want,
I can have you invited
- See you tomorrow
- II can't
- Why?
- I'm busy
If you don't come,
then just disappear
- And the money?
- You'll get it at the end
- I'll think about it
- Think about it
- How is it going?
- You leave me here alone!
- Go to bed
- Goodnight!
You go to bed too
You've changed
since that kiss
Go to bed
Sandra... is it you?
- Yes, it's me
- I thought...
...it was my father
Weren't you busy
this morning?
Put everything back
Sorry I'm late
...I have a radio...
Look for a song
You made it, huh?
It was easy...
- Is my wife here?
- I haven't seen her
My niece would like
to see the works
...without being noticed...
Who is inside?
- IMy technicians
- Send them on the beach
- Now?!
- Now...
Alright...
Hurry up!
Vai, muoviti!
The collaborators are
in the water
While I check the work,
you ceck the car
- Are you staying tonight?
- Yes...
My father's always been
madly in love with her
She doesn't know
Once there had been a
relationship between them
Continue
She must have gone with
him and he went crazy
- You're behind
- A little...
Don't tell my wife I came
There are some bills
Are we spending too much?
I advanced everything
...I have no more cash
- Write an account
and my wife will stop by
- I've already written one
- Write some more
He's got a lover!
That swine betrays her!
That way you've got
some hope!
Forget it...
send me those two
I'm writing down the hours
you worked, not to be wrong...
- For you...
- What is it?
The receipt for your hours
- What shall I do with it?
- Keep it
...in the end you'll have
a nice boundle
- Not bad
- Send Dario over
I know...
...why you want
to look good...
because of what
happened before the war
- On June 10, 1940
- I didn't know that
Right here... in this room
...June 10, in 1940
at six o' clock
I was bringing her some tea...
...She jumped on top of me
and said: "We're at war!"
And she...
Kissed me here...
...here... I've been thinking
of that kiss...
ever since
she could have given it to
her husband, to her daughter
...but no...
She gave it to me
I didn't separate from
my wife for that
I know
there's a big age difference
between ujs
but in life, every one
has a right
...to live a lovely obsession
- A dream
And now she acts as
if nothing happened
...I don't know
what to do
What will you do with
the money you earn?
I'll set up a chewing gum
factory
- How do you make it?
- You take these and cut them
And cook them with water
vapor and sugar
When they're cooked,
you wrap and sell them
But it's poisonous!
No, that's how
the Americans make it
Make a bubble
I can't
Come on, let's do something
Are you crazy?
The Latin professor is here
Sleep...
Dario stopped here.
He had things to do
Go and call him
- He's with a girl
- Your mother gave me
two orphans, not only one
- Where is Dario?
- On the beach
- Does your father know?
- Of course
Dario, you know I have
to take you back home?
I'll go by myself
What where you
talking about?
We were kissing
You'll have one next year
- What?
- A new radio
- Well?
- Let's go
Sandra, bring us
a bottle of water
...They're thirsty...
Sandra's professor
Don Emilio.
Water
We were expecting
you yesterday
Thieves broke into
Nando's store
All the radios
Don Emilio, if you want
to change, go inside
I'll fix you a cold drink
Let's go on the beach.
Here with these workers...
It will be completely
different
Don Emilio, come
dive into the water!
Give the radio back!
Understand?
To the water!!
Help!
- You're way ahead
- We're doing alright
Please be seated
Roberta, do you want
to freshen up?
- Who is he?
- A lawyer...
- Who can it be?
- Maybe a policeman...
Will you bring
the radio back?
- How does it look??
- Fine!
...as long as it's sunny,
we can film exteriors
Shall we go?
The appointment is
for Next Saturday
See you Saturday.
He'll film the party
He's a lawyer but
filming is his hobby
Last year he did a film
on me... in the snow
It will participate in
some competitions
See you Sunday
The expenses
This is the list of what
is left to do
- An orchestra?!
- There will be a tenor
among the guests...
we need an orchestra
I'm here alone
my collaborators only
have good will
I've advanced everything.
I've spent alla my money
...and now I've had it...
You're a little tired
...that's why I come
to see you
Shall we go inside a bit?
Close the door
Here's an installment
It doesn't matter
- You want them all together?
- Yes...
...all of it at the end
- Why?
Before the war...
...many things happened
and some I can't remember
but that afternoon...
...when war broke out...
I kissed you
I didn't remember well.
You said: "We're at war!"
Then I kissed you
Is he good looking?
Who, the lawyer?
He's facinating. Too bad
he's got that idiot wife
Why did you ask me
about that kiss?
To know where I stand
- Here he is!
- Hadn't he left?
One of these days the two of
us must talk about everything
Mother, we're here!
- Who?
- The two orphans!
Shall I take the radio back?
No, I'll do it
We really risked...
Finally...
Ladies should
remain deated
- Some tea?
- In a restaurant?!
- Some tea
- And you?
Nothing
Both of the boys steal
- I didn't know...
- I've taken them
and I'll keep them...
but you should know
Is that all you wanted?
I must tell you...
...something personal...
- Are you afraid of me?
That money...
What for?
I need a loan
- How did it go?
- Fine
We must prepare the party
Nicola must not be like us
...he should make
new acquaintences
You'll ruin him besides
ruining yourself
- What are you saying?
- You ended a marriage for that
...now the company
You made me marry
someone I didn't like
This is the menu
The lady is not responsable
People do not always
fall in love immediately
...at times she's in love
and he isn't
But not with you
Isn't it? Not with me?
It's just an advance
I want to decide the menu
Isn't Sandra coming?
You like it?
- You like it?
- We'll be a nice quartet
...you with her and
me with the daughter
How do you dream
these idiocies up?
At night... I'm happy
only if you are
I can picture the four
of us in a nice car
Dario didn't lose
time with her
They're going together
That's how you do it,
according to him
You don't know how
to treat women
Be careful how you paint
Be more courageous
...don't do anything stupid
- You talk to her
- No...
I'll stay outside
I'm a friend...
...Sandra...
I'm Nicola Porelli
The pastry man on the beach
It's for the orchestra
They're kids from here.
They imitate American music
...I don't know
if you like these
...yes, American records
- Excuse me...
- How are you
How are you?!
We're expecting you
- You didn't have
the courage, huh?
She speaks
in that certain way...
Clear?
They imitate American
music... perfectly
This is a good orchestra?
Maybe
Can you play it all?
We will later
Are you free Saturday?
Yes, also Sunday,
Monday and Tuesday
I'm busy in Thursday
There will be food...
but learn how to play
- Nobody is to wear a T-shirt
- He imitates a horse well
See you Saturday
The whole piece, ok?
He organized the party
He got fired from the hotel
- I quit
- Thet pressed charges
There'll be 70 people
- Stand up dinner?
- Yes
- How many plates?
- Tarts, cakes, etc...
- A family gathering
- I was told
...you have plates
and glasses
forks and spoons
I also have
towels and sheets
You're one of us
Unload boys
The garden
It's modest
The buffet will go
under the porch
...a few tables there...
- We're leaving tomorrow
- About time...
My daughter ran away
...She cried all night...
what a terrible character
She's coming to the party
- She's crazy!
- She said she'd been invited
We want to see
if she comes
...my husband will stay...
We are going back
If you don't mind,
They will stay
I do mind!
Great help!
Guess who's here?
Her!
That's marvelous!
Nice work!
Mother is sleeping here
tomorrow night
My son found an orchestra
Bring up the suitcases
- Excuse me...
- Put them over there
Let's arrange the presents
- Such nice presents...
- Why didn't you stay there?
They're all girls talking
with each other
So what?
...you could have
stopped to talk
...I don't think
she likes you
I'd like you to make
friends like them
...they're well
educated people
If a person speaks well
...they already like them
You must get used
to it... learn
- Shall I go back up?
- Go ahead
Shall I talk to her?
- Try
- And say what?
Something interesting
Who is it? Come in!
- How do I look?
- Very well
- What's your name?
- Nicola!
We finished the works today
Sit down...
This is Lucia, Marisa
and Alessandra
- Are you sleeping here?
- No...
...we're catching
the 8 o'clock train
Go out... I must
try my dress on
You stay
I'm not ashamed of men
You must be used to see
a woman undress
Well...
Where's my son?
Is he saying idiocies?
- No...
- Sure?
You're son is taking
us to the station
- Nicola...
- What's the matter?
- Are you alright?
- Of course I'm alright
Are you happy?
How did it go?
Tell me
She got undressed and wanted
me to tell her nice things
But her girlfriends
were behind the door
I didn't say anything
aand she got mad
She said she's engaged
She apologized
at the station
Did that hurt you?
She wasn't so pretty
undressed
You've got to look
good today, father
I feel fine
- And you?
- Very well
How did the bread
come out?
- Perfect
- Good sign...
...things will go well today
Hurry...
Thanks for the hospitality
Here we are
- What can you do?
- She goes to school
- . And reads and writes
- And you?
I'm a ticket vendor
You clean the bathroom
and you iron the tablecloths
Are you happy "she"is here?
Be careful, the stuff
is itemized
- What is your present?
- I've done enough
Quality merchandize
...Honestly come by...
Even the dogs:
Poodles, setters...
They're difficult to find
Can you find colored
lights, like in a fair?
Yes
Like those of the past
- What's your name?
- Sandra
Same as the party girl
- Do you like Dario?
- Yes
- Why?
- He's handsome
So are you
How will the party be?
After all you've done
it will be marvelous
Sandra's party
Where is the kitchen?
What have you done?
They don't burn?
I feel a nice warmth
Turn them off.
It's a surprise
It's a little modern.
I don't know
- if I can get used to it
- Don't be difficult
- What's written on it?
- "II Castello" restaurant
- And here?
- "Pensione Corallo"
It's stuff from...
If you want I'll take it all away
He's the head waiter.
It's all his
- Read
- "II Capriolo" restaurant
Couldn't you find
something else?
If you want I'll leave and
- take everything away
- No...
Take the writing off
the plates with acid
- Alright, madam
- Madam...
...these are my collaborators
Melloni, the head waiter:
Davide, Dario, the assistants
Mr Zucchi, his daughter,
- the father, my son...
- That's all
I couldn't introduce her
She's a beautiful,
sentimental woman
It's not true!
You're in agreement with
her! You've always lied!
She's a liar and a viper!
You always want
to be right!
The last word
is always yours!
You shouldn't have trusted
people like that. I told you!
Don't change the subject.
That's not the problem!
You're a liar!
You're stingy!
She found everything out
One can never disturb
you. You're a worm
What are you doing here?
Nothing...
Go back to work
- Close the door
- With me inside?
Yes...
She didn't graduate
What?
She said that
during the war
some documents were lost
She swore to have passed
the exams...
but it wasn't true
It must be some mistake
No... she hoped nobody
would find out
- What now?
- The guests will come...
and it will be a tragedy
I don't feel like
cancelling it
and I say this also for you
For me?
My husband says the party
has been poorly organized
I wanted...
something that
resembled my party...
Swear that you won't
tell anyone
- I swear it
- Are you fond of me?
You've always been faithful
You kissed me 10 years ago
...it was something important...
Really? I kissed you?
Are you crazy?
...that's ridiculous...
Who cares
What are we wearing?
We'll rent the clothes
You must be tired...
go to bed
- And the black pants?
- Women look at men
from the waist up
...Sure?
- Yes
Everyone go away.
I must film the titles
Camera, action
Go away. I must
film the arrival scene!
Camera!
Action!
Applaud
Beautiful
Did you iron my dress?
Madame will come
down shortly
They didn't give her...
...the diploma
She had forged the votes
on the register
Some guests have
already arrived
They know, huh?
The professor is coming
right away
And you?
Has my daughter
come down?
There was a surprise
for you
You don't have
black pants?
You're mother
is not coming
because she's ashamed
Go up and smile
Action!
Watch the steps!
Thank you for coming
You can start playing
Like it?
- Is it ready?
- Almost
- She didn't graduate
- I know
They're disgusting
Take it away
Disgusting
They gave them back
Neither Gaia nor myself
took care of things
Eat, they're excellent
- But...
- Action!
They look like asses
The cake!
L'aurora di bianco vestita...
Where did they get
that orchestra?
- And Gaia?
- She's sick
- She was fine yesterday
- Yes she was, but today...
They say she stayed in Bologna
because she was embarassed
I'm sorry for what
happened to Sandra
I'm sorry...
But madam is...
...very upset
- I don't know...
Repeat!
Even the laurel
Let's go right now.
The joke is over
Is it true you never
received a diploma?
The party is marvelous,
anyway
You don't know what
a real party is like
Forgive us...
I'll organize it
the next time
Thanks.
You were wonderful
Not really
They swiped three forks
They took them as souvenirs
We'll take care of the bill
another time
It was a success
- I don't know
- Goodnight
- We're going
- We'll take them to teh train
Be careful with the truck
- Alright
- Goodbye
Thank you
- I'm here...
- We're going
This envelope contains
what we owe you
I don't want it
No diploma, no party
It's true, but you
earned the money
I don't want it...
he doesn't
It's free...
If he doesn't want it,
don't insist
Right
It's the first real present
I'm giving you
I knew from the beginning
that the party was for
you... and I accepted
...you knew that, huh?
Who cares about your
husband and daughter
It was to make you happy
People in love
give presents
Look... there's
a surprise for you
The same lights
as on that day
You remember?
You wanted them turned
on until morning
We can do the same tonight
We'll leave them on
- Finally
- Where were you?
- Are you hungry?
- A little
I only have some bread
...it came out well so
that's a good sign