FIRST TO FIGHT
PATROL LEADER
Guadalcanal.   September 1942.
The war has begun,
but the Marines concentrated
in a narrow perimeter,
have aged beyond their years.
The reinforcements are not
not yet arrived.
Food and ammunition are
ammunition are scarce.
The situation is grim.
Hey, Sarge!
Gunny's coming.
- Hello guys!
- Hi!
Ed Carnavan, what do you think?
How are you, Shanghai?
Ah, it couldn't be better.
Yeah.
I brought you some grenades.
It comes from the heart.
I get that from my mother's side of the family.
Do you need anything else?
Yes, a beer, a woman
and a good shower.
I did order a gallon of sake,
we will have it when we return.
- Good.
- This could be good.
For a gunnery sergeant.
Did you put a fence there?
Yes, Grandma and I have
hung boxes on it
and some grenades.
If they come, we will hear them!
If they come?
They have at least one battalion.
You'd better track them down.
If you're overwhelmed, you'll have to go home.
we will protect you.
Crossing 500m in enemy territory
territory and at night?
Mmm Shout, we'll get you through.
It will be a long night.
Slowly.
Now!
Let's go !
Shoot!
Sarge!
They made it through.
Come on!
Come on.
So, it was tough
last night, Sarge.
Sir.
I said you had work to do.
Yes, sir,
but it was hard to fail.
Yes.
Sorry, sir,
I can't hear you very well.
I understand,
you did a good job.
Yes, so are they.
I suggest you go to the back
take hot food and coffee.
Thank you.
Hey, Shanghai!
Is this all that's left?
Uh, well, it lasted a while,
We need to get older.
Or we get smart,
It tastes like varnish.
No one is forcing you to drink.
That's all there is to it.
Sergeant Connell!
What's up?
Colonel Baseman is waiting for you
is waiting for you at HQ.
He said to bring you there.
I don't have another outfit.
I am only reporting his words to you.
Well, it's done.
Disappear!
What's so funny about it?
Funny?
Come on, talk.
You know something.
No, no! I am surprised,
take your stuff, I'll go with you.
What is it about?
Hey, I don't know anything,
I'm just a gunnery sergeant.
Yes, it's written there,
but you know everything before.
Do you really want to keep the old man waiting?
And I suggest another one here.
Let's take a look.
Yeah, that's good, great.
Colonel, you wanted to see me?
Yes, come on Sergeant, come on.
At ease.
We just refreshed my cup.
I hate it when it starts
to look like a bush.
This is a problem that apparently
you will never have.
How long have you been
have you been a Marine, Sergeant?
More than seven years.
You're going to be thirty, right?
Yes, if I'm lucky.
Sergeant, this war is very
hard for my platoon leaders,
I'm missing four right now.
So, put this on Lieutenant!
I am making you a second lieutenant.
I know it's less
than platoon sergeant
but we all have to make sacrifices.
It's official, the papers
will come from the division.
I don't care, Colonel,
I don't want to leave my group
You see, what you
and what I want,
have nothing to do with it.
Jack, this war has just begun.
Many, or should I say some
say some in the US,
have no idea what
what it is all about.
So, Washington, the High
command, the War Department
would like to know how to
enlighten these people.
In one week,
you will receive the medal
of honor of the congress.
Washington.
They will hang the
medal around your neck,
will put you in a cage, will walk you
walk you through the country
to show the citizens
a hero in the flesh.
What do you think?
Sorry Colonel, I'm not that kind of guy.
I'm not that kind of guy.
Major!
Help him to put on these barrettes.
I hate it when a man
is not in uniform.
This sake rises quickly,
I loosen my leggings
Hey, it looks good on you.
- I want to be the first.
- Ah, stop.
Don't pretend,
you knew it all along.
I've heard rumors.
Ah, damn it! America, do you know
how many single women there are?
I'll try to find out.
I'll tell you.
I didn't really have a choice.
Who needs it?
You did.
I was getting used to this place.
You'll get used to Washington. Force yourself.
Take care of yourself, Jack.
Yes, I will be free soon,
I will be back.
Keep a low profile here.
No one will take my
my beer ration.
- Come on Mike!
- Yes sir.
They call me "Sir".
At the suggestion of your
commander, Colonel Baseman
and recommends to the United States Congress
and approved by him.
It is with great pleasure that I
to present you with this medal.
The nation's highest honor,
that you have deserved by your
services rendered to your country.
Thank you, Mr. President.
Lieutenant, gentlemen,
I assure you that this is
a ceremony that I am deeply pleased about.
And if the dog does not echo
the echo of my feelings,
it's just because he is
Scottish and taciturn.
Now I leave you to the
press, with a warning:
Sometimes they are more difficult
than the enemy.
Lieutenant.
A few questions.
Gentlemen, gentlemen, please!
Gentlemen, they have just
just arrived and are tired.
You can do the interviews later.
interviews later.
Now I would like to say
something on their behalf.
They did not leave their
units with pleasure,
but of course they are
happy to be home.
Tell us why they are at home.
The departure? The war...
Will they go back to the fight?
Not now.
They've had their share.
They will go around the country
to sell war bonds.
I don't understand,
how the war heroes...
Gentlemen, gentlemen, please!
Come on, Jack.
What is your impression, Lieutenant?
Good,
it's good to be home,
I'm just happy to be here.
They could have put some women on the
women in the welcoming committee.
- There will be some on the road.
- But what will I do tonight?
Gentlemen, I'm glad you're ready.
Ms. Sanford.
Thank you, Captain.
- Hey guys!
- Your attention please.
But, how so!
My name is Peggy Sanford,
I will be with you
during the trip.
I will take care of the program and
hotel reservations, everything.
A kind of secretary, or prescription.
Any questions?
I have one: what are you
are you doing tonight?
I'm going to sleep, lieutenant,
just like you,
You will be tired.
We fly to Pittsburgh this afternoon,
then on to Detroit and Chicago.
Here are your copies of the program,
any other questions... about the trip?
No ?  Good.
We will see you in the
in the lobby at 12:00.
Your luggage has already been shipped.
Thanks, and see you later.
What a pretty girl!
Yes, not bad.
She quickly put you back in your place.
Give me some time.
Old Marine saying: "I haven't
haven't started fighting yet."
You're not his type.
- Maybe you are?
- Maybe...
50 bucks says she'll pick me.
A bet made!
Pay now, unless she fell on her head.
has fallen on its head.
You're sure of yourself, right?
- Shall we say $100?
- No. 50 is enough for me.
Thank you, sir.
Are you going somewhere?
Oh. Hi Shanghai.
Hey, good landing.
Ms. Sanford.
You're lonely, I thought I'd cheer you up.
I could cheer you up.
If you really want to make me happy, go back to your
go back to your place.
Look, it's going to be a long trip,
We're going to be together
anyway. I was thinking...
I know what you were thinking, Lieutenant,
no way.
Please!
When you know me better...
Believe me, Lieutenant, I know all about it.
- Oh, please!
- Bye-bye.
Ah, this woman is
anti-American, and unpatriotic.
Well, Don Juan, your turn!
It's the right time.
Are you scared?
No, I'm more of a cautious person.
Hey, we are put in first class.
Our guys in uniform deserve the best.
I'm glad you think that about us.
Excuse me.
- But Lieutenant...
- Call me Jack.
Call me Miss Sanford.
Ouch. Will we work all the time
all the time in Pittsburgh?
You are sent there to
sell war bonds.
Yes, but, always working
makes the warriors sullen.
We could have a little fun.
Don't you know that?
There's a war going on in the distance.
People shooting at each other,
stuff like that?
How about dinner tonight?
Good lieutenant,
at the hotel,
all together.
Excuse me.
How do you want your 50?
In 10s or 5s?
A lot of people together can do
do almost anything.
You can help.
Buy war bonds.
And now, this glorious navy,
Heroes of Guadalcanal.
The pride of the Marine Corps:
"Shanghai" Jack Connell.
Go ahead, marine, it's just
another landing.
Well ... I have some notes here that
I should read it,
in fact I am very afraid to do so
Hello.
I wanted to tell you that
it was a good speech,
I liked it.
One point for me.
No, seriously, it was
almost professional.
When you said
that you were afraid.
I was afraid!
So you've done a good job of hiding it.
There are many things
that I hide well.
Why don't we talk about it
at dinner tonight?
A hot dog.
A cherry soda.
You are persistent.
This is the first thing
we teach at camp:
"Focus on the goal."
Well, maybe another day.
There is not much I can add
to what others have said... . .
- Jack, open the door!
- There's a Greek man with a present.
Jack, this is Ruby "The Riverer".
And Rosie "The Riverer".
Two little women who do everything for
this great country and its noble warriors.
Ladies, Lieutenant Jack Connell.
Welcome to our website.
What are you doing, finish getting dressed.
I have reservations
in an incredible box
probably the worst in San Francisco,
but they serve glasses
this big, um... Arrive!
But not tonight, tomorrow?
Tomorrow we'll be in
Seattle, you idiot.
The place is warm,
and I found two hot irons there.
Sorry, I have other plans tonight.
Oh, come on!
Well girls,
the marines are paying for it.
Ah, it will be a long trip,
we need one for the road.
- Negative.
- Let's see!
It is reserved.
Okay, I'll drink my own poison.
Hey, I'm across the street, just in case.
I don't want you to get
a false impression,
but you are the only ones
in my room.
Hi.
Lieutenant...will you come in?
Thank you. I thought we could
could have a drink.
You thought wrong,
you couldn't be more wrong.
Come on... one little drink can't...
I agree.
But why don't you go
take it with Lieutenant Overman?
I prefer to stay here.
Sorry, Lieutenant, but
I'm not your type.
Do you think that's my type?
You're young, so find yourself a girl and have
a girl and have fun!
- What kind of woman are you?
- I am not a monster.
I am sure you like me.
You don't know anything about me!
You are young and full of life.
Don't tell me that you have never been
you've never been kissed?
Not by some idiot who thinks that a medal
gives him the right to take everything.
Yeah, by a bullshitter who
wasn't taking any chances.
No, he was the most wonderful man
I have ever known.
He had to know how to do it.
What kind of bait did he use?
One thing you couldn't
understand.
A ring and a promise.
And now...
It is not because a guy behaved
as a villain that we should...
He was an ensign on "the Arizona."
Killed at Pearl Harbour.
I'm... sorry.
Behold...the one who failed.
Still trying to win the bet?
I didn't even open the bottle.
Honey, it's all yours.
He said you were mine.
Hey, don't you want to dance?
I dance really well.
I don't know, it's too crowded.
Hey!
What's wrong with you?
It looks like I'm poison!
You are not the poison, I am.
Here, my share, I'm leaving.
Lieutenant, I've been wanting to talk to you
I've been wanting to talk to you...
Here, I'm sorry.
Are you inviting me to sit down?
Thank you.
I think we have
things to say to each other.
- No doubt that....
- I invite you to dinner?
I don't know,
Los Angeles is going to be a tough day.
Lockheed, Douglas, the shipyard...
We'll have to eat!
It's very nice of you to
to take care of my health!
Just a suggestion.
So, a nightclub and
a few dance steps?
Come on, you deserve this.
You really have the
in the ideas!
I have no interest in giving up.
Okay. But no nightclub.
Dinner and a movie, right?
I think I have no
strength of character!
I'll be right back.
All he wants is to finish
this bottle and three others
and water his garden with champagne
rather than the Germans drinking it.
That should make us feel better about the occupation,
isn't it, Mr. Ricky?
You said it.
They're looking at you, kid.
A beautiful song, but
sad like the movie.
Why does everything that is
beautiful must be sad?
Not always.
I wonder who
you really are.
Your past. What you used to say?
What you were thinking?
No questions asked.
It is not forbidden to try to guess.
Guess what?
Why hasn't anyone been there since.
Since "Arizona"?
You can say it, it's in the past.
So?
I won't let that happen again.
What are you afraid of?
Men who may die tomorrow.
Things that need to be finished before
end before they begin.
What else?
What would you like?
Oh, a nice man with a few dollars,
or a reformed one that is more or less intact.
Someone sure.
It could be me.
The war is not over.
For me, yes.
I am a veteran by decree.
I am labeled:
"Hero, handle with care".
You never know what
what will happen tomorrow.
I know what's going on here tonight.
For me... for us.
No, please.
It is also something
you learn in the army...
To be expected.
Allow me.
- Well, good night.
- Thank you.
Jack. Would you like to come in
for a nightcap?
You are forcing my hand!
I keep a bottle for
midnight visitors.
Is it for dwarfs?
You're lucky that
I kept this from the train
I feel like a chemist.
They're looking at you, kid.
- No. Why not?
- Why not?
I told you.
Why?
Is it against the rules?
You can't be serious. It's just...
Just what?
You want me there.
Of course, but that's not all.
I have nothing else.
You are everything I want,
all I need
Peggy, I love you.
I want you to be my wife.
I'm afraid.
You shouldn't be afraid,
that's what I'm trying to tell you.
I am here with you and
I will always be here.
Peggy, love me!
Love me as I love you.
I love you that's why I'm afraid.
I owe you $50!
How long will it last?
Until I get older
and you get fat.
What is it?
It's from headquarters.
Jack!
Orders, that couldn't last forever.
last forever.
They want to keep me in New York,
but it won't always be permanent.
Go on your own to Camp Pendleton.
to Camp Pendleton.
Report to Colonel A.J. Baseman.
He's my former commander.
Commander of the 1st Battalion
Marines and await orders.
What are you going to do?
Train the marines, I guess.
Won't you get on board?
Good, steady work.
From now on, we are part of the
are part of the garrison.
We will have a small
house, a kind of duplex
We will live on the base.
I know you'll like it, Peggy.
I love you.
I love you so much!
If anything should happen to you...
Not today, not tomorrow,
never.
- Hello Lieutenant Connell.
- Good to see you, Colonel.
- Welcome to Pendleton.
- Thank you, sir.
You look good, healthy
in good health.
Does marriage work for you?
Are you already installed?
Like birds in the nest.
Good, good, then we can
get to work.
Colonel, what was the situation like
when you left the guys?
Difficult, the men were exhausted.
The army finally came to relieve them
and everyone went to
rest in New Zealand
Did you get to see Ed Carnavan?
Yes, I wanted to see it.
He asked me to
to tell you not to come back.
There is a problem.
He tries to drink all
the sake by himself.
It's a good marine, the best.
Yes, that's right,
all hands on deck
when we go ashore.
They don't miss anything, do they?
Do you want to come back with them?
No sir, I am happily married.
Why look for trouble?
Some of us never
never get over it.
I look forward to meeting your wife.
You will like it, it is
is wonderful.
No, no, no, let me
make up my own mind.
How about you both come
to dinner at the club with me tonight?
- I take it as an order.
- At 7:00 p.m. sharp?
- We'll be on call.
- All right.
OFFICERS' CLUB
Yesterday morning, it was a very good group.
What do you think?
I think that...
I feel like a civilian.
It's even worse for me,
I am a sergeant at heart.
Ah, excuse me.
Jack.
Yes, Colonel.
My wife.
Wasn't I right?
Report received and verified!
He said you were
pretty, welcome aboard.
Let me introduce you
to the others now.
Gentlemen. Ladies.
Lieutenant and Mrs. Jack Connell.
- I welcome you.
- Welcome to the Pendleton estate.
- You'll regret it.
- I know you will.
You will all have the opportunity
to get to know each other better.
Our table is over there.
Excuse me, would you like to follow me?
- Welcome aboard.
- Thank you for your time.
Gentlemen, what if we put
the pretty girl here, in the middle.
Here.
What would you like to drink?
I recommend the Bourbon
or Rum, because that's all it has.
Bourbon is fine and Peggy
takes it with water.
Three Bourbons with water!
I am curious to know
this whole thing
of public heroes.
So you're being taken on a tour?
To tell you the truth, Colonel, I was
a little scared at first,
but that's what they wanted.
He sold many war bonds.
There's no need to defend him, Ms. Connell,
what he did was important.
Before, he was a good
sergeant with a bit of an attitude.
Now he's a real movie star.
I think you get used to everything, Colonel.
Even to train recruits.
No, don't minimize your work Jack.
the training of men
here is important,
and without these vouchers, we
we wouldn't have much.
But you will have to leave early,
tomorrow morning, he should be
with his group at 6am sharp.
Oh, you don't waste time!
Are you married Colonel?
Yes..., I'm married.
My wife is in Virginia,
in Quantico.
Do you disapprove of officers
having their wives near them?
Well I...  I approve of your presence.
I think it will be a great help.
To a new Marine wife
and has a new marine job.
Success to you both!
Good morning, sir...  Sergeant Kintall.
Good morning, Lieutenant Connell.
Attention ! Company,
this is Lieutenant Connell.
- Good morning, sir!
- Good morning!
What are they doing, Sergeant?
I gave the order to go down the hill,
take position and dig a trench.
With their own means.
Congratulations, that's great.
What's going on here?
That's for one girl,
not for two marines.
Ready to throw grenades!
Remove the pin.
Launch!
Get out of the trenches!
Dear Ed: You won't believe
what I'm doing now.
I train recruits at a rapid pace,
I try to turn real rookies into
into marines in 6 weeks.
It's not easy, we do our best
do our best,
I'm not complaining.
You have the hardest task,
You must take
what we send you
and put your lives in their hands.
Believe me, we would like to do more, but we don't have the time.
more, but we don't have the time.
What I can promise,
is that this group will know
the weapons and procedures.
I would like you to meet Peggy.
She has... Ah, that's a little personal.
Stop it!
Time to go.
Ah, you have run again
in the hills!
Can you tell?
When you kiss me like that.
Should I try again?
Ah!
I find the old "Shanghai Jack".
How was it today?
We sent another group this morning.
And another one arrived this afternoon?
Yeah, just kids.
Sometimes I feel like
the guy from the slaughterhouse
to prepare sheep.
Someone has to prepare them.
I guess.
From Ed?
Yes, I thought you would be surprised.
This is a nice surprise!
Is something wrong?
That's what I was saying...
The kids are good.
They make a lot of effort.
But when we're done teaching them
how to stay alive,
many are no longer.
What we need
is real Marines like you.
Tell me about your work.
It will do me good as an
increase in my beer intake.
He could never get enough beer.
We were compensating.
He sends you his greetings.
You'd like it, Peggy.
Not, if it starts to put ideas in your
ideas in your head.
What ideas?
Jack, you wouldn't be volunteering
volunteer?
Voluntary?
For a change of station.
For a combat mission.
I'm a good Marine,
but I don't volunteer for anything.
I am a big cat with a fairy tale
fairy tale wife.
and I won't spoil our happiness.
I have to be back at
base in 30 minutes.
Did they send a courier
to remind me?
Colonel?
We were about to have lunch,
would you like to come in?
I think that
I prefer to be alone with you.
I have just received the
the last list of the killed:
Ed Carnavan, in Boungainville,
Two days ago.
But no, I just
received a letter from him,
just now.
Unfortunately, sometimes that's just the way things are.
sometimes happen like that.
I'm sorry, Jack.
Jack.
Maybe if I had
been there, I could have...
Don't say that, don't even think about it
don't even think about it, you promised.
Yes, I know.
I promised.
Come on, get a move on Marines!
Get over that wall!
All right guys,
eat this sand, breathe it in,
crush yourself into the ground.
You!
Do you want to lose your head?
Guys do it right!
Don't make me cry!
What's your problem, noodlehead?
Sir, give me a break.
I'll let you breathe this weekend.
You are under arrest.
Come on, get moving!
How long has he been like this?
For two or three weeks, sir,
it seems to be getting worse.
All those who think they are on
instead of working
I want to see you work!
Come on, let's go!
Get moving!
And Slater says it's gotten
worse this week.
Brutal, even sadistic,
crushing these kids to the ground.
And insubordinate.
I requested a report this morning,
He said he would do it when he had
time, that it was crap.
We cannot form
a war council
for a man with a medal
of honor, Captain?
Yes, sir!
"The more you suffer in times of peace
the less you will bleed in wartime".
You have all had your instructions.
This is not a game,
anyone want to try it?
On guard!
If you think you can just crawl away and stay alive
crawl and stay alive,
You have the brains of morons!
You are under arrest!
Lieutenant!
This is going too far.
- Really?
- Did you say?
Look ahead.
These kids walk until they pick up a ball.
they pick up a ball.
If you had combat experience...
- You are not the only one who has it!
- Can you prove it?
Or are you one of those people who sit behind a desk
think they're fighting a war.
Stop!
- They were excellent marines!
- Shut up! You too!
We have to leave, get in the jeep
the jeep and come back with me.
- Yes, sir.
- replace him, Captain!
I have heard a lot
people talking
tell me, what is the real problem?
You've changed, Jack
and not for the better, I'm afraid.
Is it because of
Carnavan's death?
Perhaps in part.
So, I think you're blaming yourself.
Many of us have dear friends who are
friends who are killed.
I know that those you trained are in combat
are in combat and you are not.
Is that it?
Perhaps.
If you want to go into battle,
why don't you ask?
I can't.
Are you afraid?
The colonel knows that this
is not the problem.
So why not
request a transfer?
Peggy is seeing a doctor,
she is there now.
Is it serious?
We are going to have a child.
Yes.
Then it's serious.
However, it doesn't change anything,
you have to decide.
Either you do your job
here or quit.
I will give the orders
when you say so.
I beg your pardon, Colonel,
since when do you
need my permission?
Since you got
that damn medal!
That's all.
Yes ma'am, I will tell him.
- Lt, it was your wife, she...
- Give me another one.
- Yes, but she...
Jack, I was worried,
it's half past seven.
My program is crap?
Or should I punch the clock?
No, of course not.
- Stop telling me the time!
- I'm sorry.
Haven't you had enough to drink yet?
No, I haven't had enough.
I'm not drunk yet.
- Jack, what's wrong?
- Nothing's wrong.
I drink my bottle in my nest,
under the wings of my little wife.
This is not fair.
Don't talk to me about justice,
I'm here, right?
bound hand and foot by my promises.
- Safe and sound.
- jack.
And I am the nanny of a group...
of barely washed-up kids.
Isn't that funny?
Being a marine, then a nanny.
What happened to you?
Nothing, nothing happened to me,
but nothing goes.
I have hot food, clean sheets and
clean sheets and dry clothes.
I am where you wanted me.
Don't you want to know what
the doctor said?
We're having a baby,
another attachment,
another promise to keep.
No, you are wrong,
you're wrong about everything.
There will be no baby!
No, I didn't know that, sorry,
We are young.
If you had told me it was negative...
I'm telling you now,
there will be no baby
and no more promises.
Not even the ones you made me before.
Is it true?
That's right.
I won't hold you back any longer.
You don't know what
that means to me.
You don't know.
I think I do now.
Is it because you lost the baby?
Maybe that's part of it.
But there is more than one way
way to lose someone
When we see him tearing himself apart,
because he can't stand himself anymore.
Let's try to chain it
with a promise,
preventing him from doing
what he wants to do.
What he has to do.
We'll get the baby when you come back.
You have to come back!
I don't want to lose you.
Fourth Marine Division,
Maui, Hawaii
Lieutenant!
- Where is the third "Dog" section?
- On the beach, Captain.
We have a rookie from 3rd section,
Would you mind bringing him in?
- Let him come up.
- Yes, sir.
Bipping, no gymnastics.
Lieutenant, I am Private Bipping.
Let's go!
Get down and lie down!
If the enemy was in front, you wouldn't have
would not have made 2 meters!
Keep your stupid heads down!
Sergeant Tweed!
Don't move!
Tweed, Lieutenant Jack Connell,
the new section chief.
It's a pleasure, sir,
welcome aboard!
Glad to be on board.
Jack "Shangai"!
The men will be crazy with joy.
It looks like you've reached
your first goal,
- I'll leave you with Tweed.
- Very good, sir.
How does it look, Tweed?
It's okay, Lieutenant.
The instructors are veterans,
the guys are tough,
we give them a hard time.
Good. Mason tells me that you
were with the Raiders.
They were good ones.
We were pretty good.
A Marine is a Marine,
you have to be good.
Good, we'll get along.
Assemble, Sergeant.
Come on guys: Gather round!
Meet your new boss:
Lieutenant Jack "Shangai" Connell
You were at Guadalcanal, Sergeant?
Yes sir, Sgt.
Maypole, 1st Marine.
I thought I had seen you before,
I'm glad to see you.
All right, you already know my name,
and I will learn yours.
What you may not know,
is that he is preparing a
operation.
I know that we have been through
difficult times,
but we are going to
harder ones.
When we reach this range,
we will be the best section,
it means work,
real work.
So this is a friendly warning.
Prepare to be drooled on. That's all there is to it.
Lieutenant.
Sergeant Schmidtmer, sir.
I just want to tell you,
we all want to tell you
we are happy to have you
to have you with us.
Thank you very much
All right guys, get up!
Let's go.
Tweed, in a few days,
they will be ready.
They're ready, lieutenant,
they will do their job.
If they fail,
we will not have made ours.
Lieutenant?
A beer?
Come on, come on!
Hey Roy!
Why don't you bring a couple of beers?
It feels weird.
A whole section that depends on us,
it's not like Guadalcanal.
I've never met a lieutenant
who wasn't like that at the beginning.
It is the responsibility
It's like
new shoes,
it takes a while
before they don't hurt anymore.
Look, we have the best Lt.
and the best sergeant in the Marines,
we will be the best
on the beach, you will see.
I like that about you, Sarge,
no false modesty.
What would be the point,
we are good and we know it.
Let's drink to that!
Lieutenant, I was looking for you
I was looking for you, you have a letter.
Thank you soldier.
My wife.
Read it.
Pretend I'm not here.
Is everything okay?
Good for you!
Nothing like a woman to
a good marine on the floor.
Not mine.
That's even why I'm here,
she wants what I want.
Ah!
A woman like I love them.
So there are two of us.
Look Lieutenant, I was just kidding,
when you have someone like that,
it's nice to go home.
Of course.
Do you know "As time goes by"?
- Of course, my lieutenant.
- Can you play it?
Here, just remember
what you have learned.
Run to the beach,
get ashore quickly,
go about two hundred meters
and take the small wood.
If the Japanese do not want to
to give it to us?
Then persuade them.
You section leaders, stay in touch
with me and Tweed at all times.
And when the ramp falls,
disembark at full speed.
And don't get your feet caught in your
your feet in your suspenders.
Are you getting cold feet, Bipping?
Sure, I'm shaking,
I can't move!
You'll be fine, no problem.
Just remember
what you have been taught. Okay?
- Thank you, lieutenant!
- Stay close to me, boy!
Come on! Move it!
Come on, Bipping, move!
Lieutenant!
Come on guys, let's get out of here!
Get up, keep going!
Let's go !
- Maypole!
- Yes sir!
I return to the beach,
the lieutenant is wounded.
Take them to the woods.
Come on guys, hurry up.
Let's go !
Let's get out of here!
Lieutenant!
Or are you injured?
Bipping is dead!
Let's get out of here!
Even if I have to carry you!
- Any sign of the enemy?
- Nothing at all, sir
- What happened to you?
- I don't know.
We landed ... and I don't know anymore.
The beach can be tough.
It wasn't like that on Guadalcanal.
It's not that.
I couldn't control myself anymore.
It happens, I guess.
- Let's just forget about it, okay?
- Yeah.
Lieutenant, it's the captain, sir.
This is Connell.
We have achieved the
first objective, Mr.
Jack, intelligence says
that they are massing at the front.
We are revising our plans.
Come here, I'll fill you in.
Done
Understood.
Done.
Tweed.
We think there may be
a counterattack.
I go back to the PC.
Of course.
I want you to understand,
I'm going back out there to get orders.
Put some barbed wire over there
and stand by.
Yes sir!
All right guys,
put some barbed wire on that side!
- Maypole!
- Yes sir!
Form a detachment
with a few men.
Linch, MacLane, Roy, let's go!
- Miller.
- Yes.
Two scouts there!
Hey! Did you see what happened
to the lieutenant on the beach?
You're kidding, I only saw the sand.
He got the chips.
I've been there too.
Yes, but you are not the lieutenant.
I'm telling you, he chickened out.
It's a good thing the sergeant was there.
This guy got a medal.
Maybe he is nice to his mother.
A hero like that, I leave it to you.
Call the company "Charlie",
tell them to be ready.
You asked for me, sir?
I am very happy that
you are here, come on.
In fact, we have
the plans,
I don't need to tell you
that the hardest part is yet to come.
We'll put ourselves
like this.
Bill's section here,
Robby's here, and yours here,
just on the line that
to the Delman ridge.
Officially it is
is called the 2-3-0 ridge.
The information speaks about caves,
many with machine guns.
We wanted to go around it
and cut it,
but the Japanese prepare a counter-attack
counter-attack on our two flanks,
which means that we will have to
will have to take this ridge.
You'll have to take it, Jack.
There is a rocky spur in front of the
the ridge, you can use it.
Let me know when you get there,
we'll do a barrage.
Start at dawn,
6:35 a.m.
Okay, sir.
Is something wrong?
No, sir.
Look, if you're not up for it...
It's going well.
Jack, this ridge is
of primary importance,
you have nothing to prove,
if you don't feel up to it
we can replace you.
Anything else, sir?
Mortars will support
your progress,
this is all we have.
Any questions?
No, sir.
So, good luck!
I'm a little nervous,
this is my... first fight
This should not be new to you.
Do you have a fiance, boy?
Mmm, yes sir, and very pretty too.
Where are you from?
From Southern Ohio, Nelsonville.
It's nice there.
More than here.
Everything is better than here.
What are you doing there?
Sorry?
At home, with your fiance.
Not much.
Picnics, movies
and we often sin.
For a girl,
she does very well with trout.
I think that's very nice, Lieutenant.
What?
Trying to make me forget about it.
Yes, don't think about it anymore.
Hey Sarge.
On the right.
The company "Charlie".
This is not the "Charlie" company.
Get ready, here they come!
Pass it on!
Here they are. Pass it on!
Get ready!
They are ahead, Lieutenant, they are coming.
Call the PC!
Warn them.
Red Dog, this is Red Dog 2, over.
Red Dog, this is Red Dog 2, come in, over.
Red Dog, Red Dog, this is Red Dog 2,
can you hear me? over to you!
This is Red Dog 2, over to you.
Come on Jack!
Red Dog, this is Red Dog.
Clean them well.
We may need it soon.
You fought well last night.
What happened to the Marine hero?
Are we going to offer him another medal?
- Get your men ready, we're moving.
- They are ready!
Hey Sarge, talk to your coward
tell him it's a pleasure
to have him as a leader.
Do you want my fist
in the face?
Coming from you, that's okay.
We will set off at 6:35 am,
we will go to the rocky spur.
Lieutenant, we need to talk.
Your company's morale is low.
- They will get over it.
- Sure!
It should start with you,
what's the problem.
You can't understand.
Talk to me, I've been in
the body for a long time.
Nothing to do with the Marines.
Stop it!
What's wrong with you?
It's up to me to solve it.
I know how things are
in high places.
We may have inflated
your exploits,
but we don't give the congressional medal
to change diapers.
Why don't you fight?
- You're out of line, Sergeant.
- It's not me, it's you.
A sergeant who does what you did yesterday
yesterday, I'll court-martial him!
Enough is enough!
Get ready to leave.
This is an order.
Yes, sir.
Come on, get ready to go!
- Lynch!
- Sir!
Here we are, Lieutenant.
Delman Ridge.
- Get me Lynch!
- Yes sir.
Go back there and
and get them to safety.
Red Dog 1, this is Red Dog 2, over.
This is Red Dog.
Did you reach the goal?
We have reached the goal sir,
we are waiting for the barrage.
- The artillery is on its way.
- Yes, sir, over.
It doesn't look too bad.
There are Japanese in this
cave and this bunker too.
How to get them out?
This time, do me a favor,
enjoy the show.
- What kind of joke is this?
- Do you want a drawing?
It won't be long now.
It's getting hot.
What happens?
I'm the same guy from Guadalcanal.
It was hard there too.
Just as hard as here.
The ancients were right.
The Spartans.
First, making your way in the military,
and then marriage.
What does that have to do with it?
You are married now,
don't forget it lieutenant.
In Guadalcanal, you had
you had not started a family,
you only had the army.
Red Dog, this is Captain Mason,
answer me, over.
This is Red Dog 2.
Are you able to move forward?
Yes sir, we are ready.
The action moves to your left flank.
After taking the ridge,
wait for the company "Charlie",
they will replace you.
Understood sir, over.
- Have the men move out.
- Yes, Lieutenant.
Did you hear?
Tell the men to move on!
Let's move guys, move!
Do it in order.
We must separate.
Relax, Tweed knows what he's doing.
At least someone knows.
You're in the clear, run!
Move on!
Get moving,
take cover!
Don't stay in the dark!
Go, go, go!
Send shooters to these rocks
rocks to attack the bunker.
Lieutenant!
- They will slaughter them!
- We will be massacred here.
The guys are getting shot,
you have to give orders!
It's not just your problem anymore,
you are not alone.
The fear is on your face
face, admit it!
It's fear! Lieutenant,
why don't you listen to me?
Sergeant, Sergeant what were you
were you trying to tell me?
That everyone is afraid, afraid!
Curses!
It's natural, you're afraid.
But go ahead! Go for it!
Nurse!
Back up, let's get
out of here, let's get out of here!
Don't go forward, don't go back,
these wretches will kill you.
- Maypole.
- Mister!
Take your best men,
on these rocks, go!
Go ahead, you heard it.
On the left, try to
liquidate this cave.
What are you waiting for, go ahead!
Let's go !
With me!
Bazooka!
- You got it.
- Rockets
Ammunition!
Let's blow them up!
Cover us.
We'll keep them busy.
You'll both go.
You two come with me!
Let's get up there.
Let's go!
Hey! Attention, cease fire!
Hey....., he did it, let's go!
- Are you whole?
- I think so.
What do you want us to do now
do now, sir?
Secure the ridge,
put a team of shooters on it.
Okay, sir.
You heard the lieutenant.
Hey!
Here you are.
- How is it going?
- Like a hole in the back.
Did they do well?
They were very good.
You and I can
make a great platoon.
Can be good.
What happened to you...
As you said:
at Guadalcanal I was alone
now I have Peggy,
I didn't want her to lose me.
Okay, good thinking.
Keep it up and you'll be living
for many years.
He deserves the decoration the one who
was afraid, but did it anyway.
Lieutenant Connell?
Captain Mason wants you
on the other side of the ridge.
It's bad out there.
- I'll go there immediately.
- Okay, sir.
All right guys,
get ready, we're moving!
"Short war" Lieutenant!
"Short War" Gunny.
Shanghai...
Are you afraid?
Of course I do!
Come on guys, come on!
And beyond this ridge,
Saipan is waiting to be released.
Then Tinian, Guam, Iwo Jima, Okinawa,
soon sinister and bloody names...
Some men will come back
and some will not.
But the Corps will continue to struggle at
other times for other problems,
always ready when the nation calls,
always faithful, proud to be the
FIRST TO FIGHT.
Translation and S.title
Danielle and J.Y. 13/07/2020