Subtitles by explosiveskull
www.OpenSubtitles.org
We live in Bishop County.
No matter what you do,
somebody knew you would.
People talk in this town.
Somebody saw it,
another person talked about it.
So either you talk
or you're talked about.
So I had to balance
expectations here,
as a girl and as a Christian.
I want to do things, big things,
like those girls in the magazines,
but they call this town
the "fishbowl",
when you climb to the top,
you just slide right back down.
Father says if you want to make
God laugh, tell him your plans.
My father is a good man.
Every time we drive past
a church, he says,
"You think that's just
a coincidence?"
And we weren't even talking
about God or nothin'.
He was a God-fearing man
after mom left us.
We didn't go out too much
after that.
Not even to church.
He didn't like the way
people looked at us.
Father said, "Everything happens
for a reason,"
but I don't think
he really believed that.
I know I didn't.
He would cry for mom like it
would bring her back or somethin'.
We could hear him go through the seven
stages of grief in just one night.
It wasn't long before father
started wrestling with his faith.
Back and forth, back and forth.
He ended up winning.
We're all concerned
about you here at Bishop High.
This is a place where
you should feel safe.
I'm not gonna sit here and say,
"I know what it's like
to be in your situation."
'Cause I don't.
But I will sit here with you
until you say somethin'.
You need to take this seriously.
A Christian education is like
a spiritual piggy bank.
You have an opportunity to find
your faith here and deposit it.
And you know better than anyone else
your age inside or outside these walls
that life is going to present
problems, sadnesses,
even crushing disappointments.
Hmm?
That's why you need
that piggy bank...
to draw from
in times like these.
So I want you
to raise your piggy bank.
Come on, up, up, up.
That's right.
Now, we're gonna shake it.
Go ahead.
Can you hear anything in yours?
That's because faith can't grow
if you don't invest in it.
You ever played Pictionary?
Yeah, okay, great.
Let's do that.
I'll go first.
This is the part where you're
supposed to say what it is.
I need something
from you, Jessa.
You're not gonna be able to
continue in the AP program
unless you begin to participate
in class.
It's been four months.
So who's gonna be there?
Just you and my family.
I think we're gonna have pizza around
6:00, but you can come early if you want.
- I can't.
- What?
My mom says we can't really
hang out anymore. I'm sorry.
But it's my birthday.
Yeah, I know... know, Rachel,
happy birthday.
Miss Simon, now.
Bring your test.
What is that?
My leg.
Don't play smart with me, Miss Simon.
Lift up your skirt.
Excuse me?
Your skirt, lift it.
It's just my boyfriend's name.
I'm not goin' to ask you again.
And how long have you been
dating Benjamin Franklin?
Enough!
I don't know who you think
you're fooling,
but you've got the right sister
to send you to the wrong place.
I'll see you after school.
You can sit down now.
Whore.
Lucy.
If you watch closely,
you can see that God is makin' moves.
You got that bird flu thing
happening and then... and that got...
But we've heard
all of this before.
The world is more populated
than it's ever been.
All those people with flaws,
don't you agree?
I think he's a really
good Christian.
Hey, they laughed at Jesus, they laughed
at Moses, and they'll laugh at him, too.
- Dad, is that Lucy?
- No, no, Carly, no.
- No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no...
- Give her to me, give her to me.
- I wanna see her, please.
- No, no, no.
- Dad!
- Get back inside, honey. Tell your mother.
Mom! Mom!
Mom! Mom, they brought Lucy.
Lucy's dead, mom!
She's dead! Mom!
Uh, thank you. Just...
just give her. Thank you.
Sorry.
Excuse me, uh...
I just drove all the way up
Bishop County.
The, uh...
The flyer says it's a...
there is a reward.
You've gotta be kidding me.
Oh, wow. That is unbelievable
and here's your reward.
♪ Make the memories
That remind me ♪
♪ That how much
You really care ♪
♪ Yes, there's something
About a love ♪
Your total is 16.32.
♪ A love that stands forever ♪
- Thank you.
- ♪ There's something about ♪
♪ Happy birthday to you ♪
♪ Happy birthday, dear Rachel ♪
But don't you feel bad making money
off of other people's suffering?
Like you? Like a doctor,
an attorney, a policeman? No.
I mean, I'm assuming,
uh, you're making a dollar or two
off of this deal, is that right?
- It's a donation.
- It's a donation, okay.
Yeah, but you know what?
$1,000 is a lot of money.
Um, maybe you've forgotten that.
You look like you're doing pretty well.
I drive the same car
I did seven years ago.
I live in the same house
I did ten years ago.
I don't do fancy restaurants.
And this mornin' is the
first time I flew first-class.
So the money isn't for me,
it's for Him.
Every dollar goes to
spreading the word.
I suppose if I were to give you
um, $1,000 check right now,
write this out to, uh,
Ron Peltz.
Oh, I can't forget this. Right.
I have to be referred
by somebody.
I hope you don't mind if I use your name.
Ron Peltz. So here it is.
I did everything the way
you asked me to do it.
Doesn't matter what I've done in my
life, no matter how bad it's been,
who I've been involved with,
the things I've done to hurt other folks,
with this donation and this
referral, if I follow your program,
I can be saved from all this
that you say is coming,
and then I can know God.
Is that right?
Then, and only then
will you recognize God.
You know what, folks?
This might be a good time for a break.
We'll be back
right after these messages.
Thanks.
Have a nice day.
♪ I can't breathe
When you're around ♪
♪ Follow me back
Into the woods ♪
♪ Hear my cry loud as wolves ♪
♪ I can't breathe
When you're around ♪
♪ Around ♪
- Ew, gross.
- ♪ Follow me back ♪
♪ Back where I was before ♪
- I'm so glad I could capture that family moment.
- ♪ And cast the light ♪
- I came as fast as I could.
- ♪ Into my soul ♪
- Well, you know, she's almost finished.
- Yeah.
I gave you the time.
- ♪ Into my dream ♪
- I'm here, aren't I?
Well, you get points
for showing up...
Did you see Becky out there just now?
Was that an accident or...
I mean, I can't stand her.
I know. I know, me either.
She's terrible.
She wears glasses.
She's not into you.
And she clearly totally
wants me.
Catch her staring. Oh, my God.
They're called "tits."
Can you say that?
Let me help you.
T-I-T-S.
What? You can't talk
without Mr. Fluffy?
Do you wanna go cry to your mommy?
Where is your mom?
You're such a...
Oh!
What is wrong with you?
You can go now, Stefanie.
I know you're going
through a lot right now, Belle.
But if this happens again, I'm gonna
have to suspend you. Are we clear?
Are you
stressed out about your future?
You have nightmares
filled with fire, confusion,
bird flu, nuclear war,
apocalypse.
The solution to all your worries
can be found
in the house of the Lord.
But how do you get there?
If you want the key to God's
Kingdom, you must join us,
prepare yourselves,
and your loved ones.
Those who hesitate
will be left behind.
The time is now.
In glory, there is only peace.
But achieving that peace
is pain, is effort.
Though each step may be painful,
we must keep our eyes on Him.
A few steps towards this altar
and you will find rest.
You will find comfort in the Lord,
regardless of what you've done or endured,
as long as you were willing to
take these few steps right now.
The Holy Spirit is telling me
there's one more person.
It's telling me you're scared,
and you're wondering, "Is it me?"
Don't be shy now.
Not in His house.
Please, join me.
♪ Amazing grace ♪
♪ How sweet the sound ♪
♪ That saved a wretch ♪
♪ Like me ♪
♪ I once was lost ♪
♪ But now I'm found ♪
♪ Was blind, but now I see ♪
♪ 'Twas grace that taught
My heart to fear ♪
♪ And grace my fear relieved ♪
♪ How precious did ♪
♪ That grace appear ♪
♪ The hour I first believed ♪
♪ The Earth will soon
Dissolve like snow ♪
Bless you, my child.
♪ The sun forbear to shine ♪
♪ But God that called me
Here below ♪
♪ Will be forever mine ♪
Can we go now?
- How are you?
- Good.
Uh, you know, I called.
And left messages.
I... I didn't hear back.
I... I just wanted to make sure
you and the girls were okay.
Yeah, we're... we're good.
Hmm. Better.
Good. I mean, they're...
they're good girls.
- Yeah, they are.
- Um...
I don't know how to say this,
so I'm just going to say it.
People here still have doubts.
They... they're simple people.
When you don't come forward
to... to accept, to admit,
it's uncomfortable.
They... they just need more time
and it looks like you do, too.
Uh, and I'm... I'm sorry.
It's not personal, but I have to do
what's best for the church, Rick.
But you know where I stand.
Let's go.
Thank you, Lord,
for this meal, for this family,
for these beautiful girls,
for all the things that we have,
and for all the things
that are coming.
- Amen.
- I'll drink to that.
Who's hungry? I'm starving!
- Me too.
- Come on.
- I'll eat.
- Toast!
Have you ever felt
that your life was meaningless?
I did, 17 years ago.
I struggled to put food
on the table,
to raise an upright family,
and then that's when I just fell
into a dark pit
of alcohol, drugs, and despair.
That's when I nearly
lost it all.
But that's also when I found God
or He found me.
I'm not exactly sure.
You have to believe me,
when I heard His voice,
"Ron, my son,
you do have a purpose,
and on September 29th,
I will cleanse the Earth,
house the righteous in Heaven.
You are my knower
and my words are your armor."
Don't you wanna be saved?
Don't you wanna be with
your family together forever?
I could show you how.
And when His trumpet roars,
you'll be exactly
where you need to be.
In Heaven.
So call now 1-800-555-SAVE
for donation.
Only $1,000, you and your family
can access the path.
Hi.
Where are our lunches, father?
It's only $3.
There's always something wrong
with him. What else is new?
We'll just talk about that
later.
Come on.
Just get in the car, Rachel.
Hello, sir.
And there.
exactly 97, 98.
Welcome to Ray's Costumes.
I'll be here if you need
anything or not.
Hey, look at this one.
Give it to your dad.
I'd like to see that.
Maybe you can stop by the house
and give it to him yourself.
Hey. Hey, Henry, come here.
Look at this one.
Playin' up.
Check this out. Ron Peltz.
Right?
Henry thinks you're cute.
Nah, man, you can't do Peltz.
Like everybody's gonna be doing Peltz.
- Okay.
- Be creative, man, come on.
Oh, shit! Firefighter, man.
It's an end of the world
party.
Yeah, and tell like it's
the end of the world, call 911.
- Yes.
- Rachel, yo, check this out.
- Oh, this is so dope, right?
- Yeah.
Come on, come on, we'll get you a
costume, too. It'll be great.
We'll find you like what, like
a lady firefighter or something.
Or like a hot cop.
- Hey.
I just wanted to say thanks
for letting my sisters come.
I appreciate it.
It's no big deal.
Oh, it's perfect.
Oh, my gosh, there's a crown!
What do you think?
I think it looks great.
- Really?
- Yeah.
You like it?
- It's gonna look beautiful on you.
- Thanks.
You hungry?
♪ Now I'm goin' home ♪
As you now know,
on September 29th, the world will end,
but only for some.
God has revealed
five separate steps
to ensure not only your place
in Heaven
but the best seat in the house.
- I got it.
- I can pay for myself.
I'm a guy. It's a date.
I'm supposed to pay.
It's not a date
if there are other people.
Thanks.
But you're the only one
I'm lookin' at.
Yeah, I totally got
the slices for you.
- Oh.
- I mean, uh, on the date, yeah.
- Thank you.
- Definitely.
- Thanks, sir.
- Thank you.
Um, yeah.
- Yeah, that's...
- Sorry. I'll save you a seat.
- Uh, cool.
- That'll be another buck, 50.
Step 1, a 7-day fast.
Only God's love and water will
carry you through this time,
preparing you
for what is to come.
Step 2, seven days of celibacy.
This is not a time
for earthly desires.
Yo... wait,
what are you doin'?
- No, that's...
- Dabbing the pizza.
- That's the best part. No, no, you got to...
- No, no, there's uh...
You got to...
that's where the flavor is.
It's where all the flavor is.
Seriously, try it,
it's so much better this way.
- No.
- Why would you do that?
- Step 3.
- It's pizza.
Purity.
No material stimulation, music,
TV or books, excluding Scripture.
Step 4, women will be prohibited
from having material possessions
that enhance
their physical appearance.
No makeup,
conservative clothes only.
Now, as we speak,
Satan is roaming this Earth.
Lurking, waiting.
Tick-tock, tick-tock.
♪ I'm starting to relate to
A daydream I had as a girl ♪
♪ I'm asleep in a well
And ended up in a hell ♪
♪ I'm not afraid, I'm not afraid
I'm not afraid ♪
♪ I danced with the devil
He said he would save my soul ♪
♪ But a dancer I'm not
A prisoner I have become ♪
♪ But you, you're the warden ♪
What are those for?
There's a party on Friday.
What kind of party?
An end of the world party.
This is funny to you?
The end of the world?
- No, uh...
- Good, 'cause it's happening.
We do not bring Satan
into this house.
Dad, it's just a costume.
Shh. Do not talk back to me.
Princess? Not anymore.
Now, who wants to see mommy?
We're gonna be a family again.
As you see
in your welcome package,
we provided you with brochures
to hand out, to spread His word.
Now, you must sign
five new people
or donate the equivalent amount
by September 29th
if you want to ensure your place
in Heaven.
I'm not doin' this.
As you see
in your welcome package,
we provided you with brochures
to hand out, to spread His word.
Ow, you're hurting me!
Now, you must sign five new people
or donate the equivalent amount
by September 29th...
We'll give mom a hug for you.
If you want
to ensure your place in Heaven.
Anyone else?
Those who don't,
but eventually everyone will believe.
Those trumpets will sound,
and people will vanish,
and the only thing they will see are
clothes falling from the heavens like rain.
I am so sorry.
Can you just give me a moment?
- Rick. Rick!
- Yep.
- What, uh... What is all this?
- We're having a yard sale.
- You're...
- Are you crazy?
- ...welcome to look around.
- Hi, girls.
Can I have a word with you?
Now?
What the hell are you thinkin'?
I have the Smiths coming over.
I have two more showings today.
We talked about this.
We have the house looking great.
You're having a yard sale!
Oh, my God!
Rick, I thought we had
this conversation.
Who's gonna sell this house
for you in less than ten days?
- Jessa. Jessa!
- We're on track.
- You know I've been very patient and very fair.
- Hi. What's your name?
- I let you and your kids stay in this house.
- Oh.
Do you know how hard it is to show
a house with people living in it?
I mean, look at this,
there is trash everywhere.
So this has to look right.
How would you feel, Rick?
My name is on that sign.
I know that doesn't mean anything to
you, but it means a lot to me.
You are makin' my face look bad.
We gotta go.
Got another house to see.
Wait, where are you going?
We haven't even gone inside yet.
Wait, you can't leave yet.
You haven't seen the inside.
The kitchen is to die for and the dining room,
it has a ceiling that is, oh, my God...
- Look, lady.
- So...
We need to go now.
Again.
♪ Satanic cyanide ♪
♪ Get it out of your house
Throw it out, and burn it ♪
♪ It has no place in the house
Of the righteous ♪
What are you doin' in front of my
house, 11:00, on a Sunday night?
Yeah, I was...
I was in the neighborhood.
To go hang with
a friend of mine.
This friend got a name?
Greg.
Greg who?
David.
Well, Greg Davis lives
four doors up on the left.
Whoops.
Whoops?
Joey, if you ever come to my neighborhood
again at 11:00 on a Sunday night,
you go directly
to Greg Davis' house.
Because everybody at my house
is already in bed.
That it?
Did you ever kiss my daughter?
Yeah.
♪ Farewell my friend ♪
Have a good night, Joey.
Tell Greg Davis Mr. Simon said, "Hi."
♪ All that you feel ♪
♪ Nothing is real ♪
You keep opening it like
something's gonna magically appear.
Well, I need to eat something.
You want me to believe that all three
of you have to use the girls' room.
Miss Parker, out.
- Ooh.
- It's an emergency, a lady emergency.
You know, how many times I've heard
those exact words in that exact spot?
Well, we go to
an all-girls' school.
- Grab, idiot.
- Yeah, well, all three of you, not buyin' it.
We're on the same cycle.
- Can't it wait?
- Doesn't work like that.
Go stop it or somethin',
come right back.
And no dilly-dallying.
Why do I have to do it?
Someone has to watch the door.
What's Jessa gonna do?
Pull up her notebook?
I could watch the door.
I'm a good door watcher.
- No, you'd panic and start crying or something.
- Wouldn't start crying.
- And what are you gonna say if somebody comes?
- Someone's coming.
- What?
- It's a little long.
You're taking too long.
Come on, you could've been done by now.
It's peanut butter and jelly.
Great. Grab some for later.
Hi, my name is Rachel
and I live down the street.
Something very bad is upon us, but what we have
to offer could help save you and your family.
Wait, what?
Something bad's gonna happen?
What do you mean?
But it doesn't have to be...
You've probably seen him on TV.
Ron Peltz.
- He was told by...
- No.
No. You have to believe this.
You believe it, right?
Let's do it again. Okay?
Hi, my name is Rachel
and I live down the street.
Hi, Rachel.
What can I do for you today?
Hold on just a second,
darling.
Uh... Uh, hi, girls,
is everything okay?
Not really.
Did he do something to you?
Blink twice if you need help.
Not him, God.
God?
He said He'd destroy everyone
that doesn't buy this.
Um, oh, um, Stefanie,
we've gotta...
Um, we've gotta go do that thing. Sorry.
When I was your age, we used to go to tea
parties, we had all different kinds of teas.
Lemon Zingers, ginger,
Sleepytime.
That's what you girls
should be doing.
I'm Jewish, so I really
don't need this shit.
What the hell is this?
It's to prepare you
for Judgment Day.
No, I don't go to church much.
Well, you don't have to.
You just call this number here and
tell them that the Simons referred you.
That's our name at the bottom.
Ron Peltz. He said that you could
see your husband and family again.
Huh, after 40 years,
the last person I wanna see is my husband.
Just get off my porch.
Is that your father over there,
tryin' to hide behind that tree?
What's the matter with you?
Sending your daughters in here
to do your business?
Everybody hates you.
Just get the hell out of here.
- Let's go.
- Father's gonna kill us.
Is that my nightie?
What? Mine's in the dryer.
- Where's your costume?
- I lost it.
Well, get up.
People are expecting us.
- No, I wanna see mom.
- It's not real, you idiot.
- He's gonna kick me out.
- No, he won't. He won't even know.
Joey's goin' to be here soon,
Henry's coming with him,
he likes you,
and I know you like him.
What if he kisses
Stefanie Fellinger?
She kisses everybody.
All because
you wouldn't be there.
Uh, let's go. Come on.
Dear God,
thank you for this lesson.
The pain is gone.
♪ You were born of a jackal ♪
♪ Can't say that you fought ♪
♪ A battle of tether
To your waist ♪
♪ Riding shotgun into haste ♪
♪ My mom gave me sunshine ♪
♪ You still kick at my heels
Yeah ♪
♪ Who's to say, who's to say ♪
♪ You won't change ♪
♪ The light of the morning ♪
♪ It can bring me to my knees ♪
♪ But so does your cycle ♪
♪ Denial
The darkest of my spiral ♪
♪ And I'm hoping
You're blinded ♪
♪ It could only buy fear, yeah ♪
♪ Who's to say, who's to say ♪
♪ You won't change ♪
♪ I'm not the same ♪
What's your name?
Is this where you take
all your girlfriends?
- Are you my girlfriend?
- You never asked.
- So, you gonna be my girlfriend?
- You can't ask now.
I'll ask in a couple
of minutes then.
- What's in there?
- You'll see.
♪ If you let me sing
I promise to do anything ♪
I promise to be anything ♪
♪ If you let me sing... ♪
I've never felt this way before,
you know?
And he makes me feel
like a real princess.
I don't even need
this dress.
I mean, I could be
wearing anything in fact.
I mean, I should just tell him
that I love him, right?
I mean, we're not even gonna be
here in a week
and like who even knows
if he's going to Heaven?
What if he was in my head?
I have to save him.
♪ Finally caught me, too ♪
♪ Don't leave me alone ♪
♪ Don't leave me alone
Standing here forever ♪
- ♪ Hoping you however ♪
- Joey, stop!
- What are you doing?
- My earing, it was my mother's.
Jesus, gross.
You're a fucking cock-tease.
♪ I'm a little girl ♪
♪ Boiled into a mature ♪
♪ Little piece of work ♪
Father.
Give me another one.
- I'm done.
- Is that it?
- Yeah.
- You're up.
When you get tired,
you need to ask for strength.
you ask for Him strength.
I'm hurting.
Ask Him for strength.
Please, give me strength.
Say it! I am the lowest.
I'm the lowest, most wicked,
most sinful, least-deserving.
Louder.
I'm the lowest, most wicked,
most sinful, least-worthy.
Don't you lock those arms.
Go to your room.
Do this now every night!
So when we compare the Bible with
the literature of the ancient Near East,
um, we'll see not only the incredible
cultural and lit... literary heritage
that was obviously common
to them,
but we'll see the ideological
gulf that separated them
and we'll see how
biblical writers, uh,
so beautifully and cleverly
manipulated and used these stories,
as I said, as a vehicle for the
expression of a radically new idea.
They drew upon these sources, but they blended
and shaped them, uh, in a particular way.
And that brings us to a critical
problem facing anyone
who seeks to reconstruct ancient
Israelite religion or culture
on the basis
of the biblical materials.
Um, that problem is
the conflicting perspective
between the final editors
of the text
and some of the older sources
that are, uh...
Show me you're here.
Please, just show me
you're here.
I'll go to church every Sunday.
Whatever it takes, I'll be good.
Just get us through this.
Help me.
Help us.
Just give me a sign.
Please, just give me a sign.
Hey, shouldn't you be in class?
Make sure you close it
so the smoke doesn't go in.
- Where's Jessa?
- Sleeping.
What are we gonna do?
The same thing we do every day.
And you're not worried at all?
They're just stories.
Do you think Heaven
is just a story?
I don't know.
Mom didn't think it was a story.
Where do you think she is?
Sometimes I wonder how she could
be happy if we're not there.
'Cause I'm not.
I'm not happy.
You're not happy,
nobody's happy.
This house is full of her
and there are days where I...
I can't even remember her face.
I'm sick of wakin' up
and feeling like this.
Do you ever pray for her?
I think about her a whole lot.
Does that count?
Not really.
Okay, I know we said
these, but what do you think?
Do you think these will
go with my dress?
- Yes.
- Yeah.
Yeah, you like 'em?
Come on, Mace, we're gonna be late!
You look fine!
She's not ready yet.
I'm not ready yet!
We're gonna miss
our reservation.
Well, ugh.
You're distracting me.
I'm not even in there!
Well, you're distracting me
with your words.
He said the reservation was at
6:30, but it's really at 7:00!
I made the reservation!
What? He said what?
He said you'd be late!
And you're still late.
Not that late.
Okay, so one last question.
These or these?
Mm.
- Those.
- You got five minutes!
Mm. Okay, look, I need you guys to
please clean up the bathroom for me,
'cause I made a huge mess
and your dad's gonna kill me.
And you, the earrings that I'm looking for I
can't find, because you took them from me.
And I know that about you.
And I love you all.
- Hmm, well.
- It wasn't me.
I left some money
on the counter for the pizza,
and I really don't want you to stay up
really late, and you're in charge. Bye.
- What?
- That's right.
- What? - That's right.
- I love you all!
- Yeah. I missed you.
- I missed you.
- Well, I wasn't gone that long, but...
- Yeah, a real long time.
Um, why don't we just
get our check?
- Oh, here you are.
- Oh, yes, we will.
- 1995, Mendoza Malbec.
- Perfect.
And what are we
celebrating tonight?
- It's our anniversary.
- Oh, congratulations.
How long have you guys
been married?
Twenty years.
Twenty amazing years.
No, thank you, I'm fine.
Okay, she'll have smaller.
No, really, thank you. I'm fine.
No, really, just make it small.
No, really, I'm fine.
I'll just leave
the bottle for you two.
What?
Hey.
Come back to me.
The time has come.
Tonight, He will reveal Himself
to those who believed,
to those of you who believed,
to those of you who spread the word,
you will be rewarded
with eternal life
and will forever be seated
at the right hand of the Lord.
To those unbelievers,
to those who mocked us...
I'm sorry.
There will be no reward
You did your best. We, uh...
we'll head over to Jessup Street?
We already hit that one.
Completed pamphlets and/or
inclusions will be accepted until 11:30 tonight.
- No later.
- Got an idea.
No exceptions.
Come on, girls.
Father. Father, please.
Rick. Rick?
- Take one.
- This is not the way, get out this house.
This doesn't concern you!
Take one, take this.
The only way you're gonna be
saved, this is the only way.
Girls, please,
pass it out quickly.
There is no
soliciting in this house.
You think I'm crazy, don't you?
Is that what he told you
that I'm crazy?
I see it in your stare.
Well, I'm not the one you need
to worry about,
'cause He is coming
and He is coming to reckon.
And you're not prepared,
you're not prepared, you're not prepared,
none of you are prepared!
And I blame him!
But I can prepare you!
I have the golden ticket.
You touch me again
and I'll break off that arm!
- Oh!
- This is my church!
This is my church now!
Now, what you don't realize
is you still have a chance.
You can still save yourselves,
because He is an understanding God.
A forgiving God.
It's all I got.
Right here, just...
just put my name right here,
right... right on the bottom,
just... just take it.
Put my name right there.
And you gotta listen to me, because being
in here is not gonna do you any good.
Not gonna do any good at all!
Now, you got just a few hours to save yourselves,
because at midnight His trumpets will roar.
So if I was you
I would get on it.
You don't get one. Let's go.
What happens
when you die?
I think you get to be
an angel
by being angelic to people
and sharing with your sisters.
How do you think
you would get to Heaven?
If you're helping people.
- Yeah.
- When they need it.
When they need it. Uh-huh.
What if you're helping people when they
don't need it and it's like a surprise?
And nobody knows
you're doing it.
And there's money in a
little bank from me that I'm going to...
when I have a lot of money, I'll give
to poor people that don't have food.
- Oh. That's nice.
- That's a good thing.
- I think that...
- That would be a good angel thing.
I think that that's a
really good angel thing.
Yeah, that's a very
good angel thing.
- I'm scared.
- Don't be.
But we didn't get enough people.
We did our best.
He knows that, honey.
He knows that.
That's what kinda God He is,
right?
Alright, get ready.
Hold on, don't be scared.
Our Father, Who art in Heaven,
hallowed be Thy name.
Thy kingdom come, Thy will be
done on Earth as it is in Heaven.
Give us this day our daily bread
and forgive us our trespasses...
I love you.
Did we not make it?
- Father. No, no, no...
- Just...
- Don't go.
- Wait here.
Father said we'd laugh
about all of this sooner or later.
That Bishop County was too small
of a pond for us big fish.
He said we'd only be here
for a little bit. A week tops.
We knew he wasn't looking for the
perfect house, he was looking for work.
He would always talk about
the houses he saw that day.
White picket fences,
board swings, big backyards.
This one house, you'd love it.
It was absolutely beautiful.
Had picket fences,
a porch swing...
- Yeah, I like it.
- Five bedrooms.
He was a liar.
He was still our father.
Not a day went by where he didn't
try to get past everything.
But like father used to say, "If you want
to make God laugh, tell Him your plans."
Alright, take it down there.
Do it like this.
Hopefully, you'll get better.
I gotta pee.
Hey! What are you doin'?
I'm so sorry, I just, uh...
What, man?
Are you slow or somethin'?
Why are you lookin' at me
like you're stupid?
Get your ass back to work.
That tree is comin' out
of today's pay.
I think you need to walk a little
faster, get your ass over there.
Come on, boy, go.
Get your ass back to work, man.
I'm sure he'll be here
any minute.
What are you doing?
Subtitles by explosiveskull
www.OpenSubtitles.org
♪ You were born of a jackal ♪
♪ Can't say that you fought ♪
♪ A battle of tether
To your waist ♪
♪ Riding shotgun into haste ♪
♪ My mom gave me sunshine ♪
♪ You still kick at my heels
Yeah ♪
♪ Who's to say, who's to say ♪
♪ You won't change ♪
♪ The light of the morning ♪
♪ It can bring me to my knees ♪
♪ But so does your cycle ♪
♪ Denial
The darkest of my spiral ♪
♪ And I'm hoping
You're blinded ♪
♪ It could only buy fear, yeah ♪
♪ Who's to say, who's to say ♪
♪ You won't change ♪
♪ I'm not the same ♪
♪ Ooh, yeah ♪
♪ If you let me sing
I promise to do anything ♪
I promise to be anything ♪
♪ If you let me sing
I promise to do anything ♪
♪ Who's to say, who's to say ♪
♪ You won't change, oh ♪
♪ I'm not the same as you ♪