BLOSSOM PICTURES and kth presents
a GLOWFLY PICTURES and SEOUL
ACTION SCHOOL production
FIST & FURIOUS
Dongjin TV's videographer
Gook-hyun Nam?
I heard you're digging
around for an exclusive.
I got a kickass tip, you want it?
It's about a dirty cop
who took out loans from me,
his name is Ki-man Kang.
Det. Kim, let me ask you a favor.
Lend me some money.
Just for a week, if it's too much.
Don't lie to me, Mr. Park.
I know your bar is doing well.
Asshole, where's my damn money?!
Don't just say no! Hello?
Hello? Hello?
Fucker, pay back the principal
and the interest in a week!
Or I'll fucking kill you!
He was a hotshot cop
who took on big cases.
Then he got hooked on
gambling while on a case?
Right! Then he messed
with a narco units case.
The drugs were made by Tae-hwa Jung.
He's infamous for selling
hybrid drugs in Gangnam.
Kang shot him after trying
to stab him while high.
I don't know who Jung's informant is,
but he heard about Kang's plan.
Crocodile Bird.
Wow, first call in a year.
I heard you went bust with
stocks, it must be true then.
Steal from me?
Cops do something so low nowadays?
I understand.
I'll send you a large one
for giving me this exclusive.
Sure, take care.
Young-dae.
That cop's on the way
to steal our package.
Things got complicated when
a rookie was assigned to Kang.
You got a new rookie partner.
Salute! I'm Jae-ho Yoon!
Det. Kang! Deadline is
tomorrow, don't be late!
What is that?
Det. Kang.
Do you remember me?
The goalkeeper from Gupabal
warehouse 5 years ago.
Det. Kang, are you sure it's here?
We got no warrant,
we could be in trouble.
Open your eyes wide and watch, got it?
See how you lose an ankle
for not cooperating.
Grab him!
Cops!
It's a raid!
Wait a minute.
Detective...
Thank you for saving me.
Could you tell me your name?
I'll pay you a visit.
Just get well, asshole.
I gave up soccer after that injury.
After the academy,
I worked as a patrolman,
and requested transfer when
I found out you were here.
Det. Park said you were the
best cop in Mapo Police.
I lost my touch a long time ago.
So ask for another partner.
But I still want to learn from you
I may be a novice, could you teach me?
Say hi to daddy!
Will you be late?
Yeah, probably.
Honey, say hello to Det. Ki-man Kang!
Hello!
Are you free this Sunday?
It's our daughter's first
birthday, please come for lunch.
- I'll call you later!
- Honey!
She's a bit immature.
But I'll give you an
invitation just in case.
Why are we here?
I'll be right back, standby here.
Yes, sir!
My baby...
Come here, bud.
Kill him!
Grab him! Go!
Son of a bitch!
You bastard!
Det. Kang! Sir!
Just go!
Asshole!
His partner Det. Yoon died on the spot.
And Jung lost his precious lieutenant.
When the narcos raided the place,
Jung was long gone.
Find the switch! Turn the lights on!
We're so fucked! They aren't here!
Find the switch.
Motherfuckers!
The chance of damaging the
brain artery is too high.
Then can he lead a normal life?
I'm not sure...
One thing's for sure, the knife
will stay inside his head.
Until the day he die.
When I got to he scene, Jung had fled,
and Yoon was dead
I found out that they
were working together.
You didn't know, right?
Jung bought him up when
Yoon was a patrolman.
A bag full of money was
found inside Yoon's desk
and he was killed while
trying to steal Jung's drugs.
Who stabbed you, Det. Kang?
Was it Det. Yoon or Tae-hwa Jung?
Det. Jae-ho Yoon
I'm absolutely sure it was Det. Yoon.
Very well.
In Mourning
With the investigation over,
allow me to speak freely.
Don't you think this is too much?
Without much evidence you
put all the blame on Yoon?!
Hey, watch it!
You know Jae-ho,
does this sound like something he'd do?
This is all bullshit!
You can throw him under
the bus because he's dead!
Enough!
Burying this won't turn it into truth!
You know better than anyone!
That's enough, asshole!
Dude, he died because of you,
You assigned him to this team!
How could I have known, you bastard!
You killed him, why did you do it?!
How could I have known?!
He died because of you!
Eun-jae's First Birthday!
I was standing on the edge of a knife.
When I fell over,
the knife didn't lodge
in my head, but my heart.
Can handle this?
Mr. Tipster don't worry about that
just gave me Kang's address.
This is the place.
This is where a man who lived
3 years with a knife in his head.
I'll ring the bell now.
I'm excited to see how he looks now.
Hello?
Anyone home?
I don't think anyone's here.
Where the hell did he go?
No phone number, no nothing.
Why is she pestering me?
Yes, Producer Hong.
Nam, return the camera
and empty your locker!
You're overreacting.
The dip is the cruel part
I'm bringing in a major story!
This one's huge!
- Like hell it is.
- It's a blockbuster!
Don't lie to me.
- Ms. Hong.
- What?
This guy has a knife lodge in his head!
So he's dead?
Nonsense, I'm here to meet him.
- For real?
- Yeah
I'll show you the footages, I gotta go.
Yeah.
She pesters me so much...
Holy cow! Jesus!
Are you here to meet the man here?
I am.
Get him to the mental ward ASAP!
He' screams every night,
smashes everything in sight!
We can't even report him
because we're all scared of him!
Excuse me.
- About this man...
- What the shit?
How long was he like this?
Are you filming me?
When was it? I'm not 100% certain,
but over a year, I think...
Wait, are you Det. Ki-man Kang?
Wait a minute!
I'm Gook-hyun Nam, a
videographer from Dongjin TV.
I heard you got a knife in your head,
did it happen 3 years ago...
You son of a bitch!
Goddammit!
Son of a bitch!
Come at me, let's get this over with!
Fucking hell...
Come out!
Come out, asshole!
Get out of there!
How dare you mess with my pride!
You embarrassed me.
4532...
You've met your match, fucker.
You bastard!
What the hell?
What's up?!
What's wrong with you?
Hey!
What?
What? This?
Give you a shot?
Fucking tell me!
Fuck this...
Goddammit!
Boot up!
Holy fucking shit...
Give me a call.
How did it happen to Det. Kang?
He had a rookie partner,
named Jae-ho Yoon.
He was working for a drug kingpin,
and Det. Kang caught him!
When my husband was alive,
he made this to show the guests.
Det. Ki-man Kang, thank you
for coming to the party.
Since I'm a novice I thought
I'd be a burden to you...
Please be patient with...
Do you always throw
punches instinctually?
It's a good thing I can take a beating,
you could've killed someone.
Are you from North Korea?
Why is it important where I'm from?
Yeah, it's been 15
years since I defected.
Why did you defect?
Yeah, I ask myself that lately.
I should've gone elsewhere.
Family?
When did you start this work?
When I was 20 or so...
I worked for a private detective agency.
It was always about
chasing down affairs.
I did this and that and
ended up doing this.
My life deserves a 5-part
documentary series.
Why am I opening up myself to you?
We're here, this is it.
- Thank you.
- Bye.
- Please come again!
- Okay!
I'm scared because of Eun-jae.
I don't want her to
remember him as a bad guy.
Want me to film you?
You know what happened, right?
What people are saying,
they're all lies, no?
I know it'll be hard, but
try to forget everything.
How could I, when he died like that?
Somebody...
will tell me the truth...
Wasn't that kid adorable?
It'd have looked good
if you hugged her.
It's a bit blunt, but
that's what people want.
Come on...
I just feel bad about it.
Where are you going?!
I had an inkling it'd be here.
You should just forget it.
If you want to live in Korea,
you gotta forget quickly.
Do you still want to report about me?
Sure, I do.
Then start recording, from here on.
Why the sudden generosity?
It'll be my pleasure.
Camera is rolling, you
want to say anything?
I'm gonna make him
confess with his own mouth
that Jae-ho Yoon had
nothing to do with him.
I want everything he says
recorded on your camera
and show it to his family
and beg for her forgiveness.
Where is Jung now?
I'll have to start looking.
Wait, hold on.
I'll need some payment
for taking on such a risk.
Send me your bank info.
Det. Kang!
Who's that?
He'll find Jung with me.
The docs?
Oh, right.
Due to my transfer to homicide,
the only Jung file I got
is a year old.
Yeah? This will have to do.
Please call me when you find him
I'll back you up.
Take care.
Who are those girls?
Overdose victims of Jung's drugs.
This guy is a real villain.
So they were used for clinical trial?
Masseuse, whores, escorts,
they got anyone who needed money high.
The drug's effects were
tested and sold it afterwards.
Wait, wait.
I can't wait to find out how
Det. Kang will investigate this case.
How will you start?
Seol-ran Choi, I'll
have to find her first.
You came without a reservation?
Here.
Pick out who you want to kiss.
Someone like you prefer
girls in high school uniform.
Seol-ran.
Bring her.
What? Bring her?
What the hell?
Shit, I didn't get that!
Dammit...
Who are you?
Song-hwa Han, she ever call you?
Never.
Why are you looking for her?
Why're you looking for my sister?!
You're not gonna get off?
Is she deaf or what?
Just go.
I'm an Uber driver, that's what.
Where should I take you, Mr. Kang?
Wonil district.
Oh yeah,
put this on.
Just in case I miss something.
Piss off.
Fuck, I need the footage!
Christ!
- Drink!
- Yes, boss!
So adorable!
Go cook some meat, asshole.
Sure!
I'm so full...
What's here?
What are you looking for?
Don't look through my stuff!
Pop your trunk
I'm not his fucking minion.
What is it?
Shit, he's got a thing
for making me invisible.
Where are you going?!
Going instinctual again!
Stupid used car!
You stay right here.
Who's that?
What are you?
Why are you here...
You son of a bitch!
You bastard!
What the fuck?!
Where's Jung?
He went to fuck your
mom, motherfucker!
I don't know!
Last chance, spill it.
Where's my sister?
Stop it! Please!
Heuksan Island, he went to Heuksan!
What for?
To smuggle out.
Those addicted to his shit
can't control themselves.
One of them happened to
be a police chief's son
so Major Crime's been on his tail
so he's trying to smuggle
out of the country.
When are we leaving?
Buddy, is he a cop?
Look what he did. He's a thuggish cop.
Where's Mok?
In there.
Det. Kang, should I join you?
Just lock up Mok.
Request support anytime.
Yo.
You must've kissed thousands of guys.
What's it to you?
Do you want to kiss
someone you've just met?
You've never kissed, right?
Wanna do it?
Pay me, I'll kiss you.
This bitch bitches like a rude mofo.
What?
Are you from North Korea?
So what?
Why is that so fucking important?
Goddammit...
I was looking for my sister.
That was the last place
where she worked.
You idiot, you thought you
could find her that way?
What was I supposed to do?
No one wanted to help.
The world is fucked,
no one will ever help!
Very well, I'll give you
half of the package.
Yes, sure.
Boss, you're really
going to China?
Kang is coming to Heuksan.
To kill me.
Why? Scared?
This is good, I wanted to
see him one more time.
I gotta get half of my
knife in his head back
I was curious about that.
What's so special about it?
My whore of a mother
slit her wrist while addicted on drugs.
With this knife.
All alone, I was beaten everyday
by her pimp and fled to Mokpo.
When I was 13.
I told myself I'd never
come back to Heuksan.
How dare those fucking chinks
get me to come back here
Gil-ju.
Yes, boss.
Ask the skipper to have
a few good men ready,
and send them to Kang as my present.
Right away.
But he's not coming alone.
What is it?
Is this how cops investigate?
It's so barbaric.
Want me to buy you one?
Whatever.
Why stare at it all day
when you won't fucking buy?
Is swearing all you're good at?
Swear at me again,
and I'll fucking kill you.
This reminded me of the one
my sister bought for me!
When I first arrived at the orphanage,
boys harassed me endlessly.
They'd hit me, trip me,
pull my hair everyday.
She told me to blow it
whenever they did that.
She bought it for me for that reason.
I still have it at home.
Have some too.
Have plenty.
You loved my mom's chicken soup.
You ate chicken with the money
my mom sold her body for.
Was it good?
Tell me, was it?
Was it fucking good?!
Fucking gimp.
Something smells good!
I baked a sample!
How is it?
Weak ass shit won't impress the chinks.
You'll know once you try.
Son of a bitch!
You fucking trash!
I'm sorry!
Det. Park?
I'm in Heuksan Island.
It won't be easy,
but I still gotta try.
Yeah.
I'll call you when I need back up.
Mister, you okay?
- Are you sick?
- Leave him.
What's wrong?
The headache again?
Are you all right?
Buddy, he's sick, right?
He's got a knife wedged in his head.
What?
You okay?
Why did Jung kill Det. Yoon?
You said they aren't linked in any way
I told you he died while
trying to save him!
So he died because of you.
Right?
You'll kill Jung when you meet him?
He and I will both die.
What are you saying? You can't die!
You have to survive this
and go back to Seoul
I have to film you get
examined at a hospital!
Audience nowadays are
sensitive and experts.
No one will believe about
the knife without evidence!
So we need to have an x-ray shot,
and an interview with the doctor.
Then end with a piano
BGM on your face...
If you're done, get up, let's go.
Fuck, I'm invisible till the end.
Punk ass bastard!
Hey!
DO NOT ENTER
Is there a room?
Granny,
why are you wiping
that pot so diligently?
This will bring us luck.
In a bit, that inn will be mine.
It's all because I've
been wiping this clean.
I see.
Are there any Chinese ships in Heuksan?
None.
There are a few during a storm.
Seol-ran...
You don't have any family?
They all left.
You don't miss them?
I lost that feeling a long time ago.
A feeling isn't a lost item.
It's not something you lose.
You just feel it here,
like an instinct.
Where are you going now?
Fine, I'm used to
being an invisible man.
Take it.
If you meet Kang, do not hesitate.
Who are these bastards?
Shit, we're fucked...
Where are you going?
You stay right here.
I'll come with you!
Just stay here!
It's... dangerous outside.
I bought this just in case.
Use it in emergency.
And when I asked you about
the kiss in the car...
I was so fucking immature
and you know, being dumb,
I'll apologize, I'm sorry.
This is so embarrassing...
Det. Kang!
I don't believe this, where did he go?
Detective!
Why he is always acting alone?
Who ordered you?
Where the hell did he go?
What's wrong?
Hold on, let me see,
where's the shot?!
Where's the shot?!
Hold on, it's okay!
I'm right here, don't worry!
What's wrong?!
Come on!
What is it?!
It's okay, hold on
it's fine, all right?
You'll live through this!
Just hold on!
It's all right.
You're here?
My man will meet you with the
package after killing Kang.
Don't be late.
Are you okay?
So why did you take off alone?
Jung sent these men?
Thanks for earlier.
You actually know how to thank someone?
Take care of Seol-ran.
What took you so long to answer?!
Bring the package to the lighthouse.
If you're not there in an hour,
I'll have you arrested.
Got that?
Mok?
He was found dead
in a container in Paju.
It was a gas suffocation
accident or something.
Det. Park found him.
Feed that bitch and come back,
don't stay with her too long!
Will you stop calling her bitch?!
Her name is Song-hwa.
Jung said he'll leave her
here when he goes to China.
So I'll keep her.
Just so you know.
- Stupid bastard!
- That hurts!
Jung sucked all her juice,
why do you like her?
Throw away her stuff in the storage!
Leave those!
If you touch them,
I'll torch this place!
National ID Card
Gui-su!
Load the booze in the kitchen.
I left my truck running.
Holy shit...
Watch it!
Hey! Hey!
Shit...
What's wrong with this?
What the shit is wrong?!
All right...
Answer, answer...
- Answer...
- The number you are calling...
I don't believe this...
Goddammit!
Is this Mokpo police?
I'm at...
Det. Kang, why are you...
So you've been colluding with Jung.
What do you mean?
Kill Kang then Jung afterwards.
Half of the package is mine.
You little punk.
You were gonna backstab
Jung and take his package?
Fuck...
I was gonna take the package.
Stupid arm...
Boss, they're at the meeting point.
Any contact from Jong-do?
No, not yet.
Are we taking Song-hwa?
They won't give us a boat
if we don't test the drug.
Gui-su!
Sell Song-hwa to me.
I can give you more money.
So sell her to me
I'll give you more money!
No need to raise your voice.
Could I...
do it with her once?
Goddamn fuck...
Song-hwa! Song-hwa!
Song-hwa!
Seol-ran?
What the shit?!
Is she nuts?!
Gimpy fuck...
Boss! Song-hwa escaped!
Get up!
Take this, just go!
Where did she go?
Song-hwa!
Song-hwa.
Song-hwa! Baby! Let's leave together.
Seol-ran!
No...
Come here!
Fucking pervert!
Why?!
Why!
Stop!
Hey! Wake up!
Are you okay? Wake up!
Untie me!
You're awake?
I'll melt your heart
in front of the chinks.
I'll bring back Seol-ran.
He's in Silrak Mountain,
I found Seol-ran's sister too.
Also...
the inn owner and her son,
they're all working for Jung.
My money! My money!
Only Jesus' blood will
wash away my sins!
Only Jesus' blood!
Begin.
Doesn't she look like
she'll get high nicely?
Boss, I left the sample in there!
Find Seol-ran first.
Who is he?
It's not important who he is,
but that he should be killed.
She's just a kid, how
could you do that to her?!
Your accent is weird,
where are you from?
Why the hell is that important?!
I'm from Yanbian, asshole!
Fuck that!
I'm gonna kill you...
Hey!
Seol-ran!
Wake up! Snap out of it!
Fucking hell...
I'm sick of this.
Tell me.
Did you know Det.
Yoon, whom you killed?
Who's the informant
you've been feeding?
Fucker, you know it was Park!
Bastard...
Son of a bitch...
Shit...
Seol-ran, Seol-ran!
Wake up!
Wake up! Seol-ran!
Song-hwa...
Where's my sister?
Let's go see her, I hid her away.
Song-hwa!
Don't want to go to Seoul?
I don't want to go yet.
Gook-hyun!
Thank you.
To the deceased Det. Kang,
Heuksan was an island of hope.
Where were you?
Eun-jae, what's this?
Who gave this to you?
This is Ki-man Kang.
Det. Jae-ho Yoon was framed
and died because of my mistake.
He was a brave cop who
died saving his colleague.
I'm glad his reputation
can be restored.
With heavy heart, I'd like
to beg for his forgiveness.
Baby, who gave this to you?
Nam!
I heard you won't air
the Heuksan cop story.
Think about it again,
it'll be a big hit.