I REMEMBER...
SOMEBODY.
SOMEBODY! PLEASE!
HELP ME!
SOMEBODY, HELP ME!
PLEASE, SOMEBODY!
I'M ALIVE!
SOMEBODY, HELP ME!
SOMEBODY!
HELP ME! PLEASE!
SOME... BODY.
HELP ME!
I'M ALIVE! SOMEBODY.
HELP ME, PLEASE!
Man: I'M MICHAEL.
MICHAEL ROGAN.
WHAT'S YOUR NAME?
IT IS YOU.
ALL THESE WEEKS,
I WAS BEGINNING TO THINK
I WAS THE ONLY ONE LEFT.
NOW I DON'T KNOW.
WHERE ARE YOU FROM?
I WAS BORN
IN RHODE ISLAND.
SCHOOL - DARTMOUTH...
A MASTER OF ARTS
IN ENGLISH LITERATURE.
GAVE ME DICTION
AND A JOB AS A BARKER ON
THE EMPIRE STATE BUILDING.
EMPIRE STATE BUILDING.
WE ARE NOW SITUATED
ON A POINT
102 STORIES IN THE AIR
ON THE HIGHEST, LOFTIEST
MAN-MADE EDIFICE
IN ALL THE WORLD.
BOROUGH OF THE BRONX, BROOKLYN,
QUEENS, STATEN ISLAND...
YEAH, THAT'S WHERE I WAS
WHEN IT ALL BEGAN.
I RAN FOR THE ELEVATORS,
SOMETHING HIT ME,
AND I WOKE UP -
IT WAS ALL OVER.
I WAS
THE ONLY ONE ALIVE -
IN ALL NEW YORK,
THE ONLY ONE ALIVE.
I BEGAN TO RUN.
IT WAS A NIGHTMARE.
WHOLE UNITED STATES, WHEREVER
THERE HAD BEEN PEOPLE,
THAT INFERNAL
RADIOACTIVE DUST -
IT CHOKED AND IT KILLED
AND IT -
BUT THERE COMES AN END
TO RUNNING.
WHERE WERE YOU?
WHERE...
I'M GOING HUNTING.
I GO EVERY DAY.
THERE'S NOTHING TO HUNT,
BUT I GO ANYWAY.
I NEVER HAD IT SO GOOD -
A HOUSE,
FOOD, NO PROBLEMS.
HAVE YOU BEEN SITTING HERE
ALL DAY?
COME ON INSIDE.
DO YOU WANT TO GET SICKER?
YOU SURE
YOU DON'T WANT MORE?
I WANT TO TELL YOU.
I WAS IN THE HOSPITAL.
THEY TOOK ME
INTO THE X-RAY ROOM.
ALL OF A SUDDEN, THERE -
THERE WAS A STRANGE NOISE.
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT HAPPENED AFTER THAT.
WHEN I WOKE UP,
I WAS LYING ON THE BED.
DRINK.
I STILL DON'T KNOW
YOUR NAME.
ROSEANNE.
THE LEAD SHIELD
AROUND THE X-RAY ROOM -
THAT'S WHAT SAVED YOU.
WHY DID YOU COME HERE?
MY MOTHER'S SISTER LIVES -
LIVED HERE.
SHE WAS AN ARTIST,
AND I CAME HERE
ONE SUMMER.
I WAS SO HAPPY,
I NEVER FORGOT.
WHO WAS...
THE MAN IN THE PICTURE?
STEVEN.
HUSBAND?
YES.
DO YOU MIND IF I STAY HERE
A LITTLE LONGER?
I THOUGHT MAYBE
I'D NEVER SEE ANYONE AGAIN.
GOOD MORNING.
I'VE BEEN WAITING
FOR YOU TO GET UP.
I'VE GOT TO GO GET FOOD.
THERE'S A COUNTRY STORE
DOWN THE ROAD.
IT'S ABOUT A MILE,
SO I'LL BE GONE FOR A WHILE.
NO, TAKE ME WITH YOU.
ALL RIGHT.
PEOPLE -
WHERE ARE THE PEOPLE?
THERE SHOULD BE PEOPLE!
STOP THINKING ABOUT IT!
STOP THINKING ABOUT IT.
DO YOU HEAR ME? STOP IT.
NEW YORK, CLEVELAND,
CHICAGO -
WHAT I SAW THERE WAS ENOUGH
TO CRACK MY HEAD OPEN,
BUT I STOPPED THINKING
ABOUT IT.
I'D LOOK AT IT
AND I WOULDN'T SEE IT.
THAT'S THE ONLY WAY
OF THE WORLD THAT NEVER WAS.
NOT EVEN A MOUSE.
THESE COUNTRY STORES -
YOU GOT ANYTHING.
TAKE WHAT YOU WANT.
REMEMBER HOW IMPORTANT
BOX TOPS USED TO BE?
MY MA -
THAT WAS HER BIG DREAM.
TEAR OFF A BOX TOP,
WRITE 20 WITTY WORDS,
AND OWN THE WORLD.
MAIL IT IN
WITH 10 CENTS IN STAMPS
AND YOU'LL GET RICH,
FAT, AND FAMOUS.
HERE, MADAM,
TEAR OFF A BOX TOP.
COME ON.
LET'S GET WHAT WE NEED
AND GET OUT OF HERE.
IT'S GETTING COLD OUT.
I GOT ENOUGH
FOR ALL NIGHT.
ALL THOSE YEARS IN NEW YORK
AND I NEVER SAW THE MOONLIGHT.
I HATED NEW YORK.
IT WAS LIKE
A TRAP HOLDING ME.
WHEN I WAS A KID, WE WERE
SO POOR - HUNGRY POOR.
UP IN THE COUNTRY,
HUNGER IS DIFFERENT.
IN THE CITY,
EVERYTHING THERE,
ONLY A PIECE OF GLASS
BETWEEN YOU
AND WHAT YOU NEED.
IT'S DONE WITH.
ROSEANNE...
WHAT ABOUT US?
NO, NO! UHH!
YOU LITTLE FOOL,
THERE'S ONLY US.
STEVEN!
HE'S DEAD. I'M HERE.
AAH!
STEVEN, SAVE ME!
OH! SAVE ME!
I'M ALMOST OUT OF EVERYTHING.
GET YOU SOME STUFF
TOMORROW.
TAKE ME WITH YOU.
LET'S GO TO THE CITY.
MAYBE STEVEN'S ALIVE.
I DON'T KNOW,
BUT I'VE GOT TO KNOW.
PRETTY SOON I WON'T BE ABLE
TO WALK SO FAR,
BUT I'M ALL RIGHT NOW.
PLEASE LET'S GO THERE
TOMORROW.
WHY DON'T YOU ANSWER ME?
DO YOU WANT
TO KILL YOURSELF AND IT?
THROUGH SOME MIRACLE,
WE'RE SAFE HERE,
BUT IN THE CITY,
HOW DO YOU KNOW
WHAT WOULD HAPPEN
TO YOU AND -
BUT I'VE GOT TO KNOW
ABOUT STEVEN!
ALL RIGHT, I'LL TELL YOU.
HE'S DEAD.
THEY'RE ALL DEAD - EVERYONE.
YOU AND I ARE
IN A DEAD WORLD,
AND I'M GLAD IT'S DEAD -
CHEAP HONKY-TONK OF A WORLD.
WAIT!
STOP! HEY!
I NEVER EXPECTED
TO SEE ANYONE.
BOY, NEITHER DID I.
OH, A YOUNG LADY.
I AM OLIVER P. BARNSTAPLE.
I AM ASSISTANT CASHIER
AT THE SANTA BARBARA BANK.
HOW DO YOU DO?
A MIRACLE -
WHEN WE SAW THAT SMOKE
IN THE SKY
FROM YOUR CHIMNEY.
ANOTHER HOUR, AND IT WOULD
HAVE BEEN TOO DARK.
WAS IT PRETTY ROUGH?
FIRE FEELS GOOD.
YES, IT WAS PRETTY ROUGH.
FIRST GETTING LOCKED
IN THE VAULT.
THE AIR GOT PRETTY BAD.
HE'S A PRETTY OLD MAN.
THEN WHEN I FOUND
THE INSIDE RELEASE
FOR THE TIME LOCK MECHANISM,
WHEN WE GOT OUT,
THEN WE FOUND EVERYBODY,
EVERYBODY HE'D WORKED WITH
ALL THOSE YEARS.
IT WASN'T EASY ON HIM,
EITHER.
USED TO DRIVE ONE
IN THE ARMY -
AND WE JUST WENT OFF,
WENT AROUND IN CIRCLES,
I GUESS.
I WASN'T EXACTLY WHAT
YOU'D CALL NORMAL, EITHER,
FOR A WHILE.
I'D ALWAYS SEEN THE DEAD
IN THEIR COFFINS.
ANYONE WANT SOME MORE?
I AM MOST CONTENT.
I'M FULL UP.
AH.
DELICIOUS
AND DELIGHTFUL,
BUT TOMORROW WE MUST BE
ON OUR WAY, EH, CHARLES?
OH, YES, INDEED,
VACATIONS ARE DELIGHTFUL,
BUT ONE HAS OBLIGATIONS
TO ONE'S WORK.
SIRIUS.
JUPITER.
I ONCE BOUGHT A BOOK
ON THE CONSTELLATIONS.
IMPRACTICAL INVESTMENT.
I NEVER GOT A CHANCE
TO LOOK AT IT.
WE'RE QUITE AN INSTITUTION,
YOU KNOW.
THREE-QUARTERS OF A MILLION
CAPITALIZATION.
DO YOU MIND IF I STROLL OUT
ON THE POINT
AND LOOK AT THE GLORIES
OF NATURE?
ONE MUST ENJOY ONE'S VACATION
WHILE ONE CAN, YOU KNOW.
OF COURSE.
BE CAREFUL, SIR.
OOH, I'LL BE
QUITE ALL RIGHT.
I...
WANT TO SAY SOMETHING.
WHAT I SAID BEFORE,
I DON'T KNOW
IF IT'S TRUE ANYMORE.
WE'RE ALIVE
AND NOW THOSE TWO.
I DON'T KNOW.
Michael: I'VE GOT A PLACE
FIXED UP DOWN THERE.
I THINK PERHAPS
MR. BARNSTAPLE
HAD BETTER STAY HERE
TONIGHT.
OH, NO,
MY DEAR YOUNG LADY.
NO, INDEED.
FOR 40 YEARS I HAVE WANTED
TO SLEEP UNDER THE STARS.
I NEVER DID, YOU KNOW.
IT GETS QUITE COLD
HERE.
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
THERE'S A COUCH.
COME ALONG.
I AM TIRED.
IT WON'T EMBARRASS YOU?
NO.
ON THE WAY,
DID YOU SEE ANYTHING
ALIVE?
JUST A FEW BIRDS.
HE KEEPS TALKING
ABOUT BANK STATEMENTS.
YES, MA'AM.
BEFORE HE GOT SICK,
HE WAS A PRETTY BRIGHT MAN
IN HIS CAGE,
MR. BARNSTAPLE WAS,
BUT WHEN HE GOT OUT,
FOUND ALL THE PEOPLE
HE'D BEEN WORKING WITH
JUST LYING THERE,
WELL, YOU MIGHT SAY HE WAS
SORT OF LIKE A MACHINE
WITH NO ONE LEFT
TO PRESS THE BUTTONS.
WE'LL TAKE CARE OF HIM.
YES, MA'AM.
CHARLES?
YES, MA'AM?
DID YOU HAVE
A FAMILY?
YES, MA'AM.
EXCELLENT INVESTMENT,
A HOUSE.
WHAT'S YOUR HUSBAND'S
BUSINESS?
HE'S AN ARCHITECT.
OH, EXCELLENT.
EXCELLENT.
WE DO A GREAT DEAL
OF BUSINESS
WITH ARCHITECTS
AND BUILDERS.
OUR ESCROW DEPARTMENT
IS MOST EFFICIENT.
DID I FALL DOWN?
I DON'T REMEMBER.
OH, I MUST HAVE
BRUISED MYSELF.
I SEEM TO BE BLEEDING
UNDER MY SKIN MANY PLACES.
I THINK IT'S
RADIATION POISONING.
HOW DO YOU KNOW THAT?
I DON'T KNOW.
I'M GUESSING.
BUT AFTER HIROSHIMA,
THE MAGAZINES RAN PICTURES.
IT LOOKS THE SAME.
BUT YOU'RE NOT SURE.
NO, I'M NOT SURE.
GOOD MORNING.
HOW'S THE LAUNDRY
BUSINESS?
I CAN'T TURN OFF
THE FAUCET.
HOW IS HE?
SLEEPING.
THREE DAYS, SLEEPING.
Michael: CHARLES,
CAN YOU GIVE ME A HAND?
OKAY!
MADAM, I HEREBY TENDER
MY RESIGNATION.
I AM ENTERING THE BROADER FIELD
OF THE BUILDING TRADE.
Oliver: MISS? MISS ROSEANNE?
WHERE DID YOU GET
ALL THIS WOOD?
FORESTRY STATION
TWO VALLEYS OVER.
HEY, THERE'S AN ELECTRIC
GENERATOR OVER THERE.
IS THAT A FACT?
YEAH.
ELECTRIC LIGHT.
NOW, THAT WOULD BE
SOMETHING.
AND THEN MAYBE WE COULD
FIND ME A WASHING MACHINE.
THEN I COULD FIX ME UP
A METER,
SEND ME A BILL EVERY MONTH.
COURSE, I WOULDN'T PAY IT,
SO THAT WOULD FORCE ME
TO DISCONNECT MYSELF.
DID YOU EVER STOP
TO THINK -
A WORLD WITHOUT ANY BILLS.
Roseanne: CHARLES?
CHARLES!
HI.
MICHAEL, CHARLES...
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
HE'S AWAKE,
AND HE WANTS TO GO DOWN
TO THE OCEAN.
OCEAN? WHAT ARE YOU
TALKING ABOUT?
HE SEEMS PERFECTLY RATIONAL,
BUT HE SAYS HE WANTS TO GO
DOWN TO THE OCEAN RIGHT AWAY.
OH, YES.
I THINK HE'S BETTER.
YES.
HOW ABOUT YOU?
I'M FINE.
I'VE NEVER ASKED YOU BEFORE,
BUT I'VE GOT TO,
SO HERE GOES.
WHEN DOES...
I'M NOT SURE.
THREE MONTHS, MAYBE.
DID I EVER TELL YOU
WHEN I WAS A VERY YOUNG MAN,
I ALWAYS WANTED
TO GO TO SEA?
I DON'T REMEMBER
WHY I DIDN'T.
HE'LL BE ALL RIGHT.
CONEY ISLAND.
WHAT DID YOU SAY?
I WAS THINKING
OF CONEY ISLAND
ON A DAY LIKE THIS.
DO YOU KNOW CONEY ISLAND?
THERE WAS PEOPLE,
HUNDREDS OF THOUSANDS
OF THEM JAMMED TOGETHER,
BODY TO BODY...
TRYING TO GET
A LITTLE SUMMER,
A LITTLE FRESH AIR,
AND I WITH THEM.
I STILL SEE A -
WHAT'S THE MATTER WITH ME?
MICHAEL.
MICHAEL!
CHARLES!
LAST DRIFTWOOD
ON THE BEACH.
HOW DO YOU FEEL NOW,
MISTER?
THE LAST SURVIVORS.
I HAVE LISTENED
TO THESE STORIES
OF YOUR INDIVIDUAL MIRACLES.
NOW I'LL TELL YOU
OF MINE.
I WAS ON THE MOUNTAIN
WHEN IT HAPPENED.
THE MOUNTAIN.
EVEREST.
SURELY YOU HEARD
OF OUR EXPLORATION.
NO MATTER.
I ALONE.
THERE WAS A GREAT BLIZZARD.
FOR FIVE DAYS I WAS MAROONED
ON THE FINAL RIDGE.
WHEN I RETURNED
TO THE BASE CAMP
5,000 FEET BELOW,
THEY WERE ALL DEAD.
I MADE MY WAY ACROSS ASIA
TO THE COAST.
AGAIN I WAS THE ONLY
LIVING THING.
I FOUND A BOAT.
I WENT TO HAWAII.
AGAIN A MOUNTAIN OF DEAD.
I FOUND A PLANE.
I DECIDED TO TRY AMERICA.
I RAN OUT OF PETROL
A FEW HOURS AGO.
I CLIMBED MT. EVEREST.
I ALONE.
ALWAYS ALONE.
NOW THERE ARE YOU.
WE ARE QUITE THE COMMUNITY.
Charles: MIKE, ROSEANNE,
COME HERE.
WHAT WENT WRONG?
HE JUST... DIED.
I'LL STAY.
YOU COME BACK FOR US.
NO, I'LL BURY HIM HERE.
YOU TAKE ROSEANNE HOME.
NO, I'LL STAY.
DON'T YOU THINK
YOU'D BETTER COME ALONG?
NO.
CHARLES,
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
HE LOVED THE SEA.
SHE SHOULDN'T BE CLIMBING
UP AND DOWN THAT HILL.
SHE WANTS TO FEED THE MAN.
HE'S NOT THAT SICK.
WHAT'S GONNA BE WITH
ROSEANNE WHEN HER TIME COMES?
I DON'T KNOW.
IF MY OLD FATHER
COULD SEE ME NOW.
WHY?
HE USED TO WAVE THE BIBLE
AT ME AND SAY,
"IN THE SWEAT OF THY FACE
SHALL THOU EAT BREAD."
HOW ABOUT THE BANK?
NO SWEAT OF YOUR FACE?
GOOD MORNING, MR. HARRISON.
GOOD MORNING, MR. ADAMS.
GOOD MORNING, MR. PALMER.
WHAT DID YOU WANT TO DO,
CHARLES?
I WANTED TO BE A TEACHER.
WHY DIDN'T YOU?
LOST MY WAY SOMEWHERE,
I GUESS.
FIRST A GIRL,
A DECENT SUIT,
THEN AFTER A WHILE
I GUESS WHAT I WANTED
MORE THAN ANYTHING ELSE
WAS A LITTLE PIECE
OF SECURITY,
9:30 TO 4:00,
$38.50 A WEEK,
EVERY WEEK.
SECURITY.
WELL, HOW IS
THE AGRICULTURAL PROJECT GOING?
WE DON'T KNOW
IF THE SEED WILL GROW.
WHY NOT?
THINGS ARE SO STRANGE -
NO BIRDS, NO ANIMALS,
SO MANY THINGS
I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
HOW DO YOU FEEL?
FINE.
I THINK I'D BETTER SEE
HOW THE FARMERS ARE DOING.
ISN'T THAT A MISDIRECTION
OF ENERGY?
WHY THIS RETURN
TO PRIMITIVENESS?
THE SHELVES OF THE CITIES
ARE BURSTING WITH FOOD,
A LIFETIME OF FOOD.
MICHAEL DOESN'T WANT
TO GO NEAR THE CITIES.
DO YOU WANT
TO STAY HERE?
I HAVE TO NOW.
I MEAN AFTER YOUR CHILD
IS BORN.
I THINK I WILL TRY
TO GET UP TOMORROW.
OH, THAT'S WONDERFUL, ERIC.
YOU'RE VERY SWEET.
EVERYBODY COME ON!
HURRY.
COME ON!
TAKE IT EASY.
WHAT COULD IT BE?
IT'S GROWING AT LAST.
SO?
PRETTY GOOD
FOR CITY FOLKS, HUH?
CORN ON THE COB.
I WAS A FOOL.
A LONG, TERRIBLE TRIP
TO REACH HERE,
ENDLESS DAYS AT SEA,
ALONE, ALWAYS ALONE.
NOW I HAVE FOUND
MY CIVILIZATION.
AS LONG AS THINGS
KEEP GROWING,
EVERYTHING WILL BE
ALL RIGHT.
YES, I KNOW.
NATURE SO ARRANGES IT
THAT WHEN A WOMAN
IS IN YOUR CONDITION,
CLOUDS ARE LIKE RAINBOWS
AND ALL THE WORLD
IS LIKE A CRADLE.
HEY, THEY'RE ON!
THEY'RE ON!
HOW WONDERFUL...
MUSIC.
I'VE WANTED IT SO MUCH.
WE FOUND 100 RECORDS.
I WISH I COULD DANCE.
ME. YOU SIT.
I'LL DO IT FOR YOU.
IT'LL KEEP BURNING.
THERE'S PLENTY OF GAS
IN THE GENERATOR.
I KEEP THINKING
HOW I NEVER SAW THE LIGHTS.
ALL MY LIFE IN THE CITY,
AND I NEVER SAW THEM.
Michael: VERY NICE.
Charles: AND HERE I THOUGHT
YOU WERE SEWING BOOTIES.
IT IS VERY NICE.
THANK YOU.
YOU HAVE DONE ENOUGH WORK
FOR ONE DAY.
COME OUTSIDE AND TALK TO ME.
I'D LIKE TO FINISH
THIS SEWING.
THAT CORN OUT OF THE CAN
WAS MIGHTY TASTY TONIGHT.
THE BLESSING
OF OUR AGE -
THE AMERICAN
CANNING INDUSTRY,
AND YET IT DEBASED
YOUR TASTE DOWN
TO THE LEVEL
OF BAKED BEANS AND HASH.
I DIDN'T NOTICE
ANY LEFTOVER BEANS
ON YOUR PLATE TONIGHT.
WHEN IN ROME, EAT SWILL
LIKE THE ROMANS.
I'D LIKE
TO GO PLACES TONIGHT
AND HAVE A BIG TIME -
ORDER A DOUBLE-DECKER
HAMBURGER WITH ONIONS
AND A SIDE ORDER
OF FRENCH FRIES
AND A DOUBLE CHOCOLATE MALT.
SPARE RIBS...
BARBECUED SPARE RIBS -
I CAN SMELL THEM.
I LIKE STRAWBERRIES,
STRAWBERRIES AND CREAM.
WHERE I LIVED,
THE SMELL OF TRAFFIC -
FROM MORNING TO NIGHT,
YOU COULD SMELL
THE TRAFFIC.
TELEPHONE - I COULD HEAR
A TELEPHONE RINGING.
A NEW YORK COP,
EVEN A NEW YORK COP
BAWLING OUT A HACK DRIVER.
WHERE I LIVED, THE FAUCET
WAS ALWAYS DRIPPING.
IF I COULD JUST
HEAR THAT DRIPPING...
OF ALL THOSE THINGS,
WHICH WOULD YOU LIKE
THE MOST?
I DON'T KNOW.
KIDS RAISING THE DEVIL
AROUND THE SUPPER TABLE.
I HARDLY THINK
THIS IS THE TIME
FOR NOSTALGIC SENTIMENTALITY.
I'VE BEEN GIVING
A GREAT DEAL OF THOUGHT
TO WHY WE ARE ALIVE.
OF COURSE,
THERE'S A DEFINITE
PRIMARY REASON
WHY HE AND YOU AND I
ESCAPED THE RADIATION.
I WAS AT A TREMENDOUS HEIGHT
AND YOU TWO BEHIND METAL -
THE BANK VAULT,
THE X-RAY ROOM.
AND YET WHAT ABOUT YOU?
YOU HAD NO SUCH PROTECTION.
AND WHAT ABOUT
THE OLD MAN WHO DIED
IN SPITE OF HAVING
THE SAME PROTECTION
AS THIS ONE HAD?
THE ANSWER TO ME
IS OBVIOUS - IMMUNITY,
SIMPLY BECAUSE THERE IS
SOMETHING WITHIN OUR BODIES,
A CHEMISTRY WHICH GIVES US
SPECIAL IMMUNITY
TO THAT WHICH KILLED
THE OTHERS.
I SEE THE DOUBTFUL LOOK
ON YOUR FACES.
THEN MARK THIS.
DURING THE MIDDLE AGES
WHEN THE BLACK PLAGUE
SWEPT ALL EUROPE,
WHEN MEN DIED
BY THE HUNDREDS OF THOUSANDS,
WHY DIDN'T ALL MANKIND DIE?
THE DEADLY ORGANISMS
WERE THERE.
THERE WAS NO PROTECTION
AGAINST THEM,
AND YET A SMALL PERCENTAGE
OF PEOPLE LIVED ON
AS WE HAVE LIVED
WITH THE REST
OF THE WORLD OF MEN
DROPPING DEAD AROUND THEM.
THE ANSWER THEN IS IMMUNITY
TO THE ORGANISMS,
AND THE ANSWER HERE TODAY
IS IMMUNITY
AGAINST THE RADIATIONS.
IF WHAT YOU SAY IS TRUE,
THEN THERE ARE OTHERS.
OF COURSE.
THROUGHOUT THE WORLD,
THERE WOULD BE OTHERS
WHO'D HAVE OUR SORT
OF IMMUNITY.
NOT MANY,
ONLY A FEW PERHAPS,
BUT VERY DEFINITELY EXISTING
AS WE ARE HERE.
SOME WILL DIE FROM
THE LINGERING RADIATIONS,
BUT A SMALL NUMBER WILL LIVE
AS WE HAVE LIVED.
THAT GIVES YOU HOPE,
DOESN'T IT?
YES.
LOOK, THAT'S JUST A THEORY,
AND A THEORY'S
JUST A BUNCH OF WORDS
SET FRONT TO BACK.
BUT A THEORY BECOMES A FACT
WITH PROOF,
AND THAT IS THE VERY REASON
WE SHOULD GO INTO THE CITIES
AND LOOK FOR THESE PEOPLE
WHO MIGHT BE ALIVE.
WE WILL NEVER KNOW
WAITING HERE.
SHE WILL NEVER KNOW
IF HER HUSBAND
IS DEAD OR ALIVE.
TOMORROW WOULD BE
A GOOD DAY TO START,
DON'T YOU AGREE?
SHE'S NOT WELL ENOUGH
TO TRAVEL.
ANYWAY, WE'RE SAFE HERE.
WE DON'T KNOW
WHAT WOULD HAPPEN TO US
IN THE CITIES.
MICHAEL, I WAS THINKING,
WITH YOUR PRIMITIVE MIND
AND TIMIDITY,
IN A FEW YEARS
YOU'LL BE SWINGING
FROM THE BRANCHES
OF THE TREES.
FORTUNATELY, I -
AND I BELIEVE I SPEAK
FOR ROSEANNE AS WELL -
I'M NOT QUITE SATISFIED
WITH THIS RETURN TO NATURE
OF YOURS,
NOT WHEN THE CITIES ARE OPEN,
WAITING TREASURE CHESTS.
EVERYTHING IN THE WORLD
IS THERE FOR US,
EVERYTHING FOR THE TAKING.
AND BEYOND THAT,
WHAT OF THE OTHERS
WHO ARE ALIVE?
I WANT TO GET THEM TOGETHER
IN ONE PLACE.
WHY, SO THEY CAN BEAT
THEIR HEADS ON THE GROUND
FOR KING ERIC I,
THE MAN WHO CLIMBED
MOUNT EVEREST?
MICHAEL, I DO WANT TO GO
TO THE CITY.
IF WE DRIVE CAREFULLY,
I'LL BE ALL RIGHT.
BUT YOU WON'T BE ALL RIGHT.
DON'T YOU UNDERSTAND?
IT'S THE CITIES THEMSELVES,
WHERE THE BOMBS FELL, THE
RADIATIONS ARE THICKEST.
HE TALKS ABOUT IMMUNITY.
HAVE YOU GOT IMMUNITY
TO DEAD PILED UP
LIKE CORDWOOD
WITH THE FLESH
OFF THEIR BONES?
I WANT TO KNOW WHAT'S HAPPENED
OUT THERE, TOO,
BUT MIKE'S RIGHT.
WE DON'T KNOW
WHAT WOULD HAPPEN THERE.
WE KNOW WE'RE ALL RIGHT HERE.
WHO IN GOD'S NAME
ASKED YOU YOUR OPINION?
BUT I'M TALKING TO HER.
AND I'M TELLING YOU
TO SHUT UP.
I HAVE HAD ENOUGH
OF THIS INTERFERENCE.
WHERE HAVE I INTERFERED
WITH YOU?
THAT IS THE QUESTION.
YOUR VERY PRESENCE
IS DISTASTEFUL TO ME -
THAT I MUST EAT WITH YOU,
SLEEP UNDER THE SAME ROOF
WITH YOU.
NOW IT'S OUT.
NO, IN THIS WORLD,
YOU MUST FACE REALITY.
IT IS A MISTAKE HE IS ALIVE.
ALL RIGHT, LET HIM
GO LIVE SOMEWHERE ELSE -
NOT WITH YOU, NOT WITH ME.
DO YOU HEAR ME?
I WANT YOU OUT OF HERE NOW!
DON'T, ERIC!
AAH!
IT'S LIKE IT NEVER WAS BEFORE.
AND GOD STEPPED OUT ON SPACE,
AND HE LOOKED AROUND
AND SAID,
"I'M LONELY.
I'LL MAKE ME A WORLD."
AND GOD SMILED,
AND THE LIGHT BROKE
AND THE DARKNESS ROLLED UP
ON ONE SIDE,
AND THE LIGHT STOOD SHINING
ON THE OTHER.
AND GOD SAID, "THAT'S GOOD."
THEN GOD REACHED OUT
AND TOOK THE LIGHT
IN HIS HANDS,
AND GOD ROLLED THE LIGHT
AROUND IN HIS HANDS
UNTIL HE'D MADE THE SUN,
AND HE SET THAT SUN ABLAZING
IN THE HEAVENS,
AND THE LIGHT THAT WAS LEFT
FROM MAKING THE SUN,
GOD GATHERED IT
IN A SHINING BALL
AND FLUNG IT
AGAINST THE DARKNESS,
SPANGLING THE NIGHT
WITH THE MOON AND THE STARS,
THEN DOWN BETWEEN THE DARKNESS
AND THE LIGHT,
HE HURLED THE WORLD,
AND GOD SAID, "THAT'S GOOD."
THEN THE GREEN GRASS SPROUTED,
AND THE PINE TREE POINTED
HIS FINGER TO THE SKY.
THE LAKES CUDDLED DOWN
TO THE HOLLOWS OF THE GROUND,
AND THE RIVERS RAN DOWN
TO THE SEA.
THEN UP
FROM THE BED OF THE RIVER
GOD SCOOPED THE CLAY,
AND BY THE BANK OF THE RIVER,
HE KNEELED HIM DOWN,
AND THERE
THE GREAT GOD ALMIGHTY,
WHO LIT THE SUN
AND FIXED IT IN THE SKY,
WHO FLUNG THE STARS TO THE MOST
FAR CORNER OF THE NIGHT,
WHO ROUNDED THE EARTH
IN THE MIDDLE OF HIS HAND -
THIS GREAT GOD,
LIKE A MOTHER
BENDING OVER HER BABY,
KNEELED DOWN IN THE DUST,
TOILING OVER A LUMP OF CLAY
TILL HE HAD SHAPED IT
IN HIS OWN IMAGE.
THEN INTO IT HE BLEW
THE BREATH OF LIFE,
AND MAN BECAME A LIVING SOUL.
AMEN.
Michael: HERE HE IS.
HE.
THANK YOU, MICHAEL.
I STILL THINK
YOU SHOULD BE IN BED.
LISTEN, MISTER,
WHO'S THE DOCTOR ON THIS CASE?
THAT'S RIGHT. DON'T ARGUE
WITH A SPECIALIST.
MICHAEL, IS THAT THE BABY?
I'LL GO SEE.
HE WAS SNORING.
HE WAS NOT.
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
I TOLD HIM TO TURN OVER.
ROSEANNE...
WHEN ARE YOU GOING
TO GIVE HIM A NAME?
SOON, I HOPE.
WHY NOT NOW?
THIS IS AS GOOD A TIME AS ANY.
YOU CAN'T KEEP ON
CALLING HIM BABY.
HOW ABOUT GUTHRIE,
OR GLENN, OR LEROY?
YEAH, OR RALPH, OR SYLVESTER,
OR NATHANIEL, OR GUSTAV -
NO.
I DON'T WANT
TO NAME HIM NOW.
I WANT TO WAIT
UNTIL I FOUND OUT AB-
ABOUT HIS FATHER.
DOES YOUR SHOULDER STILL HURT?
NO, IT'S DOING FINE.
WHERE'S ERIC?
HE TOOK THE JEEP
EARLY THIS MORNING,
WENT OFF SOMEWHERE.
I THINK WE BETTER TALK
ABOUT HIM NOW.
HE SEEMS TO THINK THE FACT
HE'S SORRY SETTLES EVERYTHING.
AS FAR AS I'M CONCERNED,
NOTHING'S SETTLED.
MAYBE THE ANSWER IS
FOR ME TO GO AWAY.
LOOK, WE'VE GOT TOO LITTLE
A WORLD LEFT TO RUN AWAY.
WE'RE HERE, ALL OF US.
ERIC'S GOT TO UNDERSTAND THAT
ONCE AND FOR ALL
AND RIGHT AWAY.
AND WHAT IF HE DOESN'T?
THEN HE'S GOT TO GET OUT.
DON'T YOU AGREE?
I DON'T KNOW.
I DON'T THINK IT'S RIGHT.
YOU SAID THERE CAN'T BE
ANY MORE RUNNING AWAY,
AND YOU'RE RIGHT.
AT THE SAME TIME,
HAVE WE THE RIGHT
TO SEND ANYONE AWAY?
ANYWAY, THE WAY
I'VE GOT IT FIGURED OUT,
IT ISN'T ME OR YOU HE HATES.
HE'S RIGHT, MICHAEL.
WELL, THIS IS AN OCCASION.
HOW DO YOU FEEL?
ALL RIGHT.
I BROUGHT YOU
A FEW THINGS.
THANK YOU.
I FOUND A PLACE
OVER THE RIDGE.
SOME WEALTHY MAN BUILT HIMSELF
QUITE A BEAUTIFUL PLACE.
MANY THINGS THERE
WE COULD USE.
WE'VE BEEN TALKING
ABOUT YOU.
OH, IS THAT A FACT?
I THINK I'LL GO IN.
THANK YOU, CHARLES.
THANK YOU FOR THE THINGS.
NOT AT ALL. IT'S VERY NICE
TO SEE YOU UP AND ABOUT.
THANK YOU.
I'D LIKE TO TALK TO YOU.
YES?
I SAID WE'VE BEEN TALKING
ABOUT YOU.
YOU'RE REPETITIOUS.
LISTEN, ERIC,
MAYBE WE'RE THE ONLY ONES
LEFT ON EARTH,
AND, WELL, MAYBE IT'S TRUE
THERE ARE OTHERS LEFT
BESIDES US.
EITHER WAY, IT'S LIKE THE WORLD
WAS STARTING ALL OVER AGAIN.
WE'VE GOT A NEW CHANCE
TO MAKE THE WORLD WHAT -
WHAT EVERYBODY
USED TO TALK ABOUT.
WE'VE GOT THAT CHANCE.
LET'S MAKE THE MOST OF IT.
LET'S NOT MAKE
THE MISTAKES THEY DID -
THE MILLIONS OF THEM.
LET'S NOT BE
AT EACH OTHER'S THROATS.
LET'S WORK TOGETHER,
LIVE TOGETHER...
LIKE FRIENDS.
MAY I HAVE A CIGARETTE?
LOOK, MICHAEL...
WE'VE ALL BEEN LIVING
UNDER A GREAT STATE OF TENSION.
THAT IS MY ONLY EXCUSE
FOR WHAT HAPPENED,
BUT I THINK
IT IS A VALID ONE.
THE TENSIONS ARE OVER.
WHAT MORE CAN I SAY?
I'VE GOT TO FIX
THE ROOF TOMORROW.
WILL YOU GIVE ME A HAND?
OF COURSE.
DO YOU NEED HELP
UNLOADING THE JEEP?
YES.
I'LL GIVE YOU A HAND.
THANK YOU.
I'LL BE WITH YOU
IN A MOMENT.
THAT CRAZY IDIOT.
WHY DOES HE DO IT?
SOME PEOPLE HAVE
TO CLIMB MOUNTAINS
TO JUSTIFY THEIR EXISTENCE.
LET'S SIT IN THE SHADE.
HOW ABOUT YOU?
AREN'T YOU HAPPY HERE?
YES.
WE COULD BE HAPPY NOW.
I HAD SO MANY THINGS
TO SAY TO YOU, I -
I LOST THEM ALL.
ROSEANNE, LISTEN...
I'M JUST AN ORDINARY GUY
WHO HAPPENS TO BE HERE.
I THOUGHT I WAS ALONE, AND...
IT DIDN'T MATTER MUCH.
PEOPLE HADN'T
MEANT MUCH TO ME.
WHEN YOU FIRST GOT HERE...
WELL, YOU WERE JUST A WOMAN...
BUT NOW YOU'RE ROSEANNE.
I THINK OF YOU WHEN I WORK,
WHEN I PLAN -
SO MUCH I...
WANT TO DO.
OH, MICHAEL.
FILTHY SCAVENGERS.
I SAW THEM IN THE CITY.
IT'S GETTING LATE.
IT'S CHARLES.
WHAT'S HE DOING DOWN HERE?
THE BABY!
CHARLES, IS THE BABY
ALL RIGHT?
IS THE BABY ALL RIGHT?
SURE - SLEEPING.
ERIC?
I SAW HIM FROM THE TERRACE.
YOUR DEPUTY DROVE
THE JEEP THROUGH IT.
IS HE ALL RIGHT?
YES.
HOW TERRIBLE.
HOW DID -
ANIMAL.
WE DON'T KNOW WHAT KIND.
WHY DID YOU DO IT?
WHY DID I DO WHAT?
CHARLES WORKED LIKE A DOG
TO MAKE IT GROW.
WHY DID YOU DO IT?
ALL THE FOOD
WE COULD POSSIBLY WANT
IS IN 1,000 WAREHOUSES.
IF THE MAN PERSISTS
IN WORKING LIKE AN ANIMAL,
LET HIM WORK.
I WAS TIRED.
I TOOK
THE SHORT ROUTE BACK.
GET OUT. GET OUT NOW.
I'LL GO...
IN MY OWN TIME.
IT SURE IS HOT TONIGHT.
SURE WISH WE COULD FIND US
AN ELECTRIC DISHWASHER.
WE'RE GOING TO GET
DISHPAN HANDS.
I TOLD HIM TO GET OUT.
WHAT DID HE SAY?
HE SHOWED ME A GUN
AND SAID HE'D LEAVE
IN HIS OWN TIME.
HE'S SLEEPING.
DID YOU FINISH
THE DISHES?
ALL STARCHED AND IRONED.
Roseanne: WHY DIDN'T ERIC
COME UP FOR DINNER TONIGHT?
GUESS HE WENT OFF
SOMEWHERE.
WELL, HE'LL NEVER KNOW
WHAT HE MISSED.
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
WAS THERE GROUND GLASS
IN THE SOUP?
NO.
THAT WAS
A MIGHTY FINE DINNER.
I'M JUST SO FULL,
I HAVEN'T GOT ANY ROOM
FOR CONVERSATION.
GOOD NIGHT, EVERYBODY.
GOOD NIGHT, CHARLES.
WHAT'S THE MATTER,
MICHAEL?
I WANT
TO TELL YOU SOMETHING.
WHAT YOU SAID TODAY
MADE ME VERY HAPPY,
LIKE I USED TO BE.
I FORGOT EVERYTHING
EXCEPT BEING ALIVE...
BEING WITH YOU.
OH, STEVEN.
YES?
IT'S ERIC.
I'VE GOT TO TALK
TO YOU RIGHT AWAY.
I'M VERY TIRED, ERIC.
I'M GOING AWAY TONIGHT.
TONIGHT?
YES.
I'VE GOT TO FIND OUT
ONCE AND FOR ALL
ABOUT THOSE OTHER PEOPLE.
I OWE IT TO THEM,
I OWE IT TO MYSELF.
WILL YOU BE BACK?
YES, OF COURSE,
IN A FEW DAYS.
AND THEN I'LL KNOW
ONCE AND FOR ALL WHERE WE STAND.
YOUR HUSBAND -
IF I FIND HIM,
I'LL BRING HIM BACK WITH ME.
WE'RE A GROUP
OF LIVING MIRACLES.
WHY NOT HE?
YES.
WHAT AM I TALKING ABOUT?
I DON'T EVEN KNOW
WHAT HE LOOKS LIKE.
I'LL GO WITH YOU.
I HAVE THE JEEP PARKED
AT THE BEND OF THE ROAD.
SHOULDN'T WE TELL?
NO. DEFINITELY NO.
MICHAEL - WHO KNOWS
WHAT HE WILL DO OR SAY?
NOW WE CAN GO
WITHOUT ANY QUARRELING,
COME BACK,
AND THERE'LL BE
NO TROUBLE AT ALL.
WELL, OF COURSE
YOU WILL TAKE THE CHILD.
COME.
PACK YOUR THINGS.
I'LL MEET YOU AT THE JEEP
IN 20 MINUTES.
ALL RIGHT?
YES.
GOOD.
OH, I THOUGHT I WAS
THE ONLY ONE WHO COULDN'T SLEEP.
WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
WHAT'S WRONG?
WHAT'S HAPPENING UP THERE?
IT'S ALL RIGHT, DARLING.
WE'LL BE GOING SOON.
I'M SORRY. IT TOOK LONGER
THAN I THOUGHT.
WAS... ANYONE AWAKE?
NO.
WELL, WE ARE REALLY
ON OUR WAY.
IT'S TOO BAD
YOU CAN'T DRIVE.
LET ME SLEEP
UNTIL I WAKE UP.
ROSEANNE!
STEVEN!
STEVEN.
WHERE HAVE YOU BEEN?
GET IN, GET IN.
YOU SHOULD HAVE BEEN
WITH ME.
I TOLD YOU.
THE WHOLE WORLD -
A WAITING TREASURE CHEST.
COULD WE GO NOW?
I'LL GET SOMETHING BETTER.
EVER THINK
YOU WOULD OWN THE WORLD?
COULDN'T WE GO BACK NOW?
BACK WHERE?
YOU LITTLE FOOL.
I GOT YOU AWAY.
YOU DON'T THINK I'M GOING
TO TAKE YOU BACK.
I'LL GET ANOTHER CAR.
WHERE DO YOU THINK
YOU'RE GOING?
GET BACK IN THAT CAR.
COME ON!
STAY WITH ME AS LONG
AS I WANT YOU.
AAH!
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
THERE'S NOTHING.
THERE'S NOTHING!
ROSEANNE!
ROSEANNE.
MY BABY'S DEAD.
IF YOU COULD CRY.
I WANT TO HELP YOU.