FIVE DOLLS FOR AN AUGUST MOON
Let's play a little parlor game,
shall we?
Ah, the rope.
The rope is very important.
We're going to sacrifice
one of the girls of the tribe...
to the great god Kraal.
Our most beautiful virgin,
naturally.
Kraal doesn't give a damn
about these details!
- Come now. Kraal doesn't like to wait.
- Are you going to kill me?
- Yes! But only after much torture.
- Are you serious, George?
Kraal and I have never
disappointed a young virgin.
Oh, so that's what Kraal is!
Jacques.
Now serve our guests.
- George, what's that razor for?
- You'll see.
George, stop it.
You're hurting me, George!
I haven't even started yet.
And your husband's here.
What are you worried about?
You know we all love you.
We chose you out of the whole tribe.
But I'm afraid, George, really.
Please, untie me.
Sorry, it's too late.
- Great Kraal, do you want this virgin?
- George, untie me!
Now I deliver this maiden's lifeblood
to your fire!
All right, friends,
do with her as you will.
Leniency will not be tolerated!
What's happened?
Jack, where are you?
Silence!
Behold the purifying fame...
which draws nigh, sinner!
Prepare yourself.
Nobody move!
Who did it?
Who had that knife?
Doesn't any one remember?
I had it, but someone grabbed it
from me when the lights went out.
- And you don't know who it was?
- I know perfectly well.
Well, who?
I'm not talking, George.
Let the murderer talk.
- They're going away.
- Who?
Over there. Don't you see?
The sailors and the yacht.
They can go to hell.
I don't care.
It's just that I'll be left alone
to take care of everyone.
Including me, darling.
What a bunch of complainers.
For people like them a houseboy
is like a second mother.
Why not leave them then?
We'll hire you, Jacques.
Why the mysterious meeting?
Business matters.
How about being a little more
affectionate, "mommy"?
Come on, hold me.
Does anybody here
understand my husband?
For instance,
why did he send the yacht away?
I'm pretty sure
it wasn't to buy food.
I mean, we are on an island.
That's right. One of us
could get sick or something.
Not much chance of that.
No one gets sick in this house.
George's orders.
George's orders!
Jill, I have a premonition
about this island.
I'm rarely wrong about these things.
Trudy, what are we going to do
about poor little Peggy?
She doesn't like the island.
We'll have to get a different one.
I'm talking about
this mysterious business meeting.
Nice. When are you going
to have a show?
I had one about a month ago.
George set it up for me.
- Why did you marry such a beast?
- All men are beasts.
But George turns into a real charmer
when he starts signing checks.
So you married for money.
Nine million dollars. I would have
married my own grandfather for that.
I'm done.
When are they coming down?
Hi, Isabel.
Do you like wildfowers?
There are lots of them around.
Thanks.
- Won't you help out in the kitchen?
- Me, in the kitchen? Never!
Isabel, aren't you afraid, wandering
all over the island by yourself?
No. Anyway, I think my father
and mother will be back soon.
Maybe even tomorrow.
Her operation was a while ago.
Enough of this, Professor.
We want to buy.
You can name your own price.
We'll give you a million dollars down
here and now.
Listen, you can have a million down
from each one of us, if you like.
I've told you before:
I don't give a damn about the money.
I came here to rest.
Each one of us has in his pocket
a check for a million dollars.
- Swiss bank, made out to cash.
- A down payment.
And you can cash them
anytime you like.
Three million dollars.
I'm just not interested in money.
Please, listen for once.
We want to buy your formula.
What about all your years of research?
Now you don't want to sell?
I'm not sure yet.
I need to give it some more thought.
Please, try to understand.
My best friend was killed
because of these experiments.
I know, but that has nothing
to do with your formula.
- What about my conscience?
- Your conscience? That's a laugh!
You want your name
in the history books.
It'll be there...
the discovery's yours.
Maybe you want me
to throw in my wife too?
That's enough!
I want to get off this island.
Come on, Professor.
Why did you send the yacht away?
It looks stormy, and we haven't got
a harbor for that big a boat.
Never mind. Jacques can take me over
tomorrow on the launch.
And my wife said
this was going to be a vacation!
Help me, Trudy.
I'll bet he's never said no to you.
You're wrong. He doesn't change
his mind unless he wants too.
He's one of a kind.
- I married him for it.
- I know.
He's also a great scientist...
but I'm not about
to give anything up.
I want that formula...
at any price.
Can't you accept the fact
that a scientist...
may want to work for humanity
and not for money?
We crass industrialists work
for humanity too.
We sell things.
We just don't get sentimental over it.
He doesn't sell, he gives.
There's an important convention
in Geneva next Monday.
He's going to announce it there.
Look, you'd better not do
anything rash...
because the three of us don't want
to give up anything, like I said.
Is that a threat?
- What is it?
- I came to get Trudy.
- We're supposed to go for a walk.
- You don't need me, do you, darling?
No, go ahead.
All right.
I won't be gone long.
I just wanted to warn you.
I had no idea it bothered you
so much, Trudy.
I never would have married
if I'd known.
I'm sorry, but I don't believe you.
And anyway, you could always
divorce him.
What for?
What do you care about him?
I can't believe
you married someone...
who could take you
away from me...
No, Trudy, he'll never take me
away from you, I swear.
Well, I see Marie is paying
the houseboy another visit.
- Where? I can't see her.
- There, on the launch.
Jacques, can you hear me?
Darling.
Don't you feel well?
- So what was I telling you?
- That I'm a dirty whore.
That's why I'm taking a shower.
At least now I'll be a clean whore.
Then you asked how I could sleep
with the houseboy.
After all, one does have to do
something for the working classes, no?
Anyway, you were saying
that your wife is very bad.
I'm listening,
if you want to go on.
You see,
I don't care that he's a houseboy.
It all boils down
to a matter of good taste.
WhyJacques, when there are
a lot of better choices around?
- I'm not the jealous type.
- I don't know what the hell you mean!
You threw yourself away
on a houseboy.
Don't be ridiculous.
It was just a pastime.
- If you want to know what I think...
- Dear wife, I don't ask you to think...
only to do something.
Just what the hell
do you want me to do?
A wife should help her husband.
In this case, how?
What you did with the houseboy...
could be of help
in convincing the professor.
And now tell me
who's the dirty whore, you bastard!
If that's your idea
of what I should do to help you...
you can count on it.
I'll be glad to help you out
with all my pals, okay?
That's fine, darling.
Start with George.
Come up to the house.
It's no use staying here.
Who could have done it?
No, we mustn't touch him
until the police get here.
Yes, I know.
If we don't do something about him,
the crabs will take care of it for us.
The police will have
a nice white skeleton to look at.
PoorJacques!
You killed him, didn't you?
I can't figure out whether
you're dangerous or just stupid.
You forget, my dear husband:
I like my men alive!
Hello! Hello!
Save your breath,
Professor Farrell.
Looks like it's out of order.
What's all the yelling about?
George, did you throw
this damn thing out of whack?
It was working before.
Hello. Hello!
Didn't you want anybody
to call the police?
They don't worry me at all.
That's right. You're the big fish
that nobody can touch.
I'm getting out of here.
I'm taking the motorboat.
Come back here!
Professor, where do you think
you're going?
You can't go!
- It's not there.
- What?
You sent it away,
like you did with the yacht.
No, I didn't.
Help me look for it.
Where could it be?
We're the first ones
to put a houseboy in deep freeze.
Jill, darling, stop it, please!
You've got to forget it.
It's all over.
Stop it!
You stop it! Go away!
Just leave me alone.
Jill, you can't go on like this.
Come on, darling, try to stop.
- You want a drink?
- No, thanks.
Houseboys come and go,
but there's always a bottle.
Let me have that.
Death makes me thirsty.
Jill, honey, stop it!
Death makes you feel dirty.
Come on, darling.
You can't go on like this.
I'm going out
for a breath of air.
- Not a bad idea.
- A shower for me.
Come on, that's enough now, please.
You know, you're crying
just like a bad-tempered child.
- Come on, honey.
- That's enough. Stop it!
I don't know
what you're up to, George.
I just know
you wouldn't stop at anything!
You fool! Shut up!
See what you can do with her, Trudy.
You've got a way with women.
I swear, Trudy,
he'll pay for this!
Jill, darling, listen to me.
Don't you know a woman
keeps quiet about these things?
She may even kill a man,
but she keeps quiet about it.
Of course, darling,
that's what we'll do.
We'll leave this place,
whenever you want.
Just a minute.
Come in.
I was thinking.
So far we've done nothing but talk.
Here is one million dollars.
If you decide to deal just with me,
you'll get five more...
and no one will know about it.
You're wasting your time.
I'm not selling my formula.
No need to decide now.
Think about it.
If you want to cash it,
just remember 2-2-3-3-3.
The bank account number.
- Who gave you this?
- Nick.
- Does that mean you're selling?
- No. I'll give it back to him.
Nick, take this back.
I don't want it.
- Give it some thought.
- I'd rather not.
You never know
what might happen.
I'm leaving it on the bed.
Isabel!
What's this about?
Give me that shawl. It's mine.
Sure I'll give it to you.
Wait! Where are you going?
Come here.
- No, please go. Leave me alone.
- Didn't you say it was yours?
Yes.
Take it. Don't be afraid.
All right, now, I want to know
what this is all about!
Professor, what are you doing here?
I came to tell you
I left the check in your room.
Here.
You scientists are all alike.
You refuse to sell a formula
that would make you a fortune...
and you leave a million dollars
lying around as if it were nothing.
Well, it's time to wake up.
A million dollars? Wow!
What's your formula?
An atomic bomb?
No, just a new type
of industrial resin.
You're so different from the others.
- What others?
- Everybody.
Have you thought about how many things
you could buy with a million dollars?
A lot of things.
- What's your name?
- Isabel.
But a million dollars is not
all that much, really.
For instance, Professor...
once you've bought a yacht, a couple
of Rolls-Royces and a nice villa...
your million is gone.
What happens after that,
Professor?
Another formula.
If it isn't Trudy,
the beautiful icicle.
- Want some?
- No.
Well, I do.
I want all of it, every drop.
That's better.
Now let's try something else.
Know something, Trudy?
This is the best formula
your husband has come up with yet.
You are a beautiful woman,
full of passion.
Trudy, a man like me...
and a woman like you.
My hand on your skin.
Do you feel it, Trudy?
I feel I've been looking for you
forever, as though we were...
You don't understand.
You're crazy.
There's been a murder here,
and you expect me to stay calm.
We can't just sit around
and make small talk.
Listen, I don't care
about the six million dollars...
Nick promised to give me today.
Oh, yeah, I forgot.
The good professor accepted
a check from me...
for one million dollars,
as it happens.
That wasn't what we agreed.
I know, but we didn't expect
to play fair, now, did we?
You know damn well.
I left that check in your room, Nick.
Funny, I didn't find it there.
The last thing I expected...
a visit from you.
- Where's the check?
- The check?
I left it here.
On top of your brassiere.
A check in my brassiere... how sweet.
I hope you find it.
Take a look. You're sure to lay
your hands on something nice.
Jack, I'm afraid.
I'm sorry,
but I just can't help it.
You're sure there's no way
to call the police?
That's what they all say.
We have nothing to hide from anyone.
But I keep seeing Jacques dead.
I just know
something's going to happen.
Try to guess what it is.
Only if you're willing, of course.
It's going to revolutionize
the world market!
I swear, if I can't get my hands
on that formula legally...
The ring!
Too bad, Nick.
You want to play dirty,
don't you?
Now, if you were
to go along with me...
and there's still time...
it would be better.
For you, of course.
Who are you trying to frighten?
We're exactly alike,
the two of us.
We're two rotten bastards
cast from the same mold, George.
Never forget it, all right?
- Trudy, I didn't see you and...
- And?
And I got a bit frightened.
You know I'm good
about keeping appointments.
You're so silly.
Everything seems to frighten you.
I just can't stop thinking
there's a murderer among us.
Everyone seems to be waiting
for something that's not happening.
But whoever killed Jacques
might kill someone else.
Trudy, who could it have been?
Don't think about it anymore, Jill.
Let's try to forget the whole thing,
at least for a while, all right?
All right. Forgive me.
I want to show you a beautiful spot.
You'll see.
A gunshot!
The other side of that rock!
Hurry!
Fritz!
- He's dead, Jill.
- Did you hear that? Up there!
Come on.
We've got to warn the others!
Nick! George!
Come here!
Someone's killed the professor!
- They shot him!
- Hurry!
Someone dragged him
into the water. Why?
So that his body
wouldn't be found.
By the way, there's no chance
you made a mistake, is there?
Of course not!
I saw him. He was dead.
And so did Jill. I believe you.
But it's strange.
Whoever pulled him out there
didn't cover the tracks.
So? What does that mean?
It means that whoever did it
was in one hell of a hurry.
Please, let's get back to the house.
I'm afraid out here.
He was in a hurry.
What for?
To get back to the house in time
to be called out to look at the corpse.
You mean one of us?
There's not the slightest doubt.
- What do you want?
- Nothing.
- Just for you to confess.
- What?
We think you know
where the formula's hidden.
But I don't.
He never told me anything.
Not even where he hid my check?
It was for a million dollars!
When I went out,
my husband was sleeping...
but one of you woke him up
and made him go out.
That's the person
we should be looking for.
Why did you go out
in the first place?
- Why did you meetJill?
- That is none of your business!
On, no? I left a million dollars
here on this table...
and I want it back!
Anyone else want to try?
I'm ready.
Have you had breakfast yet?
What's the water like?
Any breakers?
I should take you out and drown you.
That would teach you to answer me.
Right, Peg?
Looks like we're all going
to wind up subzero.
- Am I right?
- You asking me?
Why did it have to be her?
Why did you want me to bring her?
What harm did she ever do to you?
Start talking or I'll kill you!
Only murderers kill.
Jack, where are you?
Answer!
Where are you?
Where the hell are you hiding?
Jack, answer!
Where are you?
Isabel, have you seen
Jack anywhere?
- Would you like something to drink?
- Maybe later.
Look!
Oh, God! Not him too!
Where were you?
- Here he is, George.
- We looked for you everywhere.
Where's Marie?
This time, seltzer water
won't turn the trick.
What's the matter with you,
if I may ask?
I can't stay here any longer.
You must let me leave.
- I'm afraid of all of you.
- Even me?
I don't feel
I ever knew you, George.
I know there's a way of getting
off this island, isn't there, George?
But you didn't want anybody to go.
You kept us all here.
Why, George? Do you realize
the professor would still be alive?
And Peggy and Jacques.
And poor little Marie.
Well, I didn't kill them, you know!
Maybe it was you after all!
What? Stop it.
You can think what you like.
I can't go on!
Nick, may I ask
what you're doing?
Nothing.
Just looking for that check.
And you expect to find it
in my desk?
What are you doing?
Why did you turn off the record player?
What the hell are you up to?
I'd like at least my voice
to stay around.
My name's Trudy Farrell.
One of these three men
murdered my husband.
The first one is George Stark,
the man who invited us all here.
Number two is Jack Davidson...
a business associate
of the aforementioned George Stark.
The third man's name is
Nick Chaney.
I suppose he, too,
does business with George.
One of these three men...
We're all a little upset.
- Why don't we try to get some sleep?
- No.
Why not, George?
You got another one of
your clever ideas? What is it?
We sleep here, all four of us.
- You think so, do you?
- Sounds risky to me, George.
Knight...
bishop...
queen.
Checkmate.
- But not a bad plan.
- Very clever.
Don't you agree?
The murderer will kill us all at once!
Well, I'm not playing.
He won't find me.
Let him go, George.
Let him risk his life if he wants to.
- Nick's gone out.
- Trudy, are you starting that again?
The other two
are still here with me.
It's an obsession.
Each person can watch
over the others.
If the murderer is among us
and makes a wrong move...
He hasn't so far!
we'll find out just who he is.
Will you please stop it!
It's getting on my nerves.
Never mind all that!
I got something in this shaker
you won't believe!
I'm losing my mind!
Trudy, you come over here too.
We can at least
keep each other company.
Strange, there's no one here.
You two take a look upstairs.
If there isn't anyone here,
how did they get off the island?
Unless some friends happened
to pass by and picked them up.
Could be, sir.
There's no one here.
There doesn't seem to be
anyone upstairs, sir.
I'll be damned.
Well, that's all we can do.
My head is killing me!
Do you two feel all right?
George!
We've been drugged.
Somebody put something
in that drink.
It can't be.
I made it myself.
If it wasn't you,
who could it have been?
Who could have put a drug
in our glasses?
Any one of us.
What for?
It was probably meant to kill us,
but it wasn't strong enough.
- Who could it be?
- It had to be one of us.
We all fell asleep except Nick.
- Strange... we're all still alive.
- At least for now.
Shall we bet who dies first?
The dead one wins.
The yacht should be here already.
It won't be much longer anyway.
- What happened?
- It's very simple.
The machine kept on recording
while we were asleep.
- And they didn't see us.
- That's right. It's absurd!
Not only absurd... impossible!
We were here.
Evidently we weren't.
What did you say?
You want us all to go crazy?
So that's your game, eh?
Why don't you kill us
like you did the others?
You're the one who's crazy,
and I was blind not to see it before!
But you're through now.
I'll get you first!
Well! A very interesting
point of view.
I must confess
I had underestimated you, Trudy.
Oh, really? Why?
Do you think thatJack is right?
That I'm the killer?
Sit down, Trudy.
It doesn't matter what I think.
I'm not a man of thought.
I'm a man of action.
Take this, my dear.
It's my million dollars.
I don't think you're crazy,
and money's important, isn't it?
Very important.
I see you're quite clever, George.
You want me to help you?
Just wait here.
All right. I trust you.
Damn it!
It won't start.
- Trudy, Jack, where are you?
- Right here.
I saw what you found,
and you'll be sorry you did.
You know, if you hadn't,
I would have let you live.
Stay where you are.
I'm the one that got rid
of the launch.
And the telephone.
And you killed Nick. But when?
While you and Trudy were asleep.
But we were all drugged!
The sleeping pills
were only in your two glasses.
Why?
So that when the sailors came,
they wouldn't find you...
so they would think
you had gone.
You won't get away with it!
Where will you put the bodies?
I'll hide them in the launch,
and then I'll sink it.
They'll find it!
The water's very deep,
and I have no other choice.
Look, Jack, you said
you didn't want to kill me.
That was my original plan.
I wanted you alive,
to take the blame for everything.
- After all, you killed the professor.
- I did? How do you figure that?
- I killed the others, but not him.
- I didn't either!
- I don't believe you!
- And Peggy?
She had to die too.
She knew too much.
And leaving witnesses behind
would be bad for my health.
Trudy, is that you?
Come in, Jack.
Don't be afraid.
I'm unarmed, as you see.
I heard that you don't like
people around who know too much...
and that you killed the professor,
which was not part of our plans.
I didn't kill your husband.
So if it wasn't George,
it must have been you.
- Now why would I do that?
- I don't know.
There are lots of things
you don't know...
while I know that
you can't shoot me.
I'm the only who knows
where the formula is hidden...
and you find that
very interesting, don't you?
So there's not much you can do
but stick to the bargain.
Just like you, right?
You've already pocketed
two checks...
and if I want the formula
I'll have to give you mine too.
- That's right, Jack.
- Okay.
Come with me.
For all these reasons...
this court finds you responsible...
for the death of your friend
and colleague, Dr. Kruger...
whom you murdered
with the express intent and purpose...
of stealing the formula
of an important discovery of his...
for your own unlawful gain.
You are condemned to be hanged
by the neck until dead.
You're probably a little surprised
that I've come.
Do you understand
how much I love you?
I worshiped you from the moment I first
looked into your sweet, gentle eyes.
I even loved you after I found out
you'd killed that man for his formula.
You believe me, don't you?
I'm not judging you.
You're the only man I'll ever love.
I don't mean to scold you,
but why the pentothal bullets?
And then why did you keep on
with the pentothal?
That's what really did it.
That's what my father does
with animals, to save them.
I didn't know it would have the effect
of making you talk...
and that you would tell that officer
everything you had done.
It was a real piece of bad luck.
How could I have known
about that?
When my father shoots animals
with sodium pentothal...
they just lie there.
They don't talk.
I thought I could save you.
They were going to kill you, you know.
- Thanks.
- That's all right.
You know, maybe you...
Maybe I what?
You could help me.
I'm fat broke.
You spent three million dollars?
No, just two.
Darling, come closer.
I cashed Jack's check
and George's check, but not Nick's.
I would do it but I need
the account number.
They ask you for it.
It's a very simple number.
2-2-3-3-3.
I love you, Fritz!
I'll pray for you, my love!
- Drive to Lausanne.
- Yes, miss. Where is that?
Switzerland.