Toho Co., Ltd.
Daiwa Shinsha Co., Ltd.
Downright dirty!
You all played dirty tricks on me!
My Kotetsu!
Where's my Kotetsu?
Your proud Kotetsu
is here, right here.
I'm falling!
No! I'm being sucked in!
Calm down and stand up!
Oh no...
I'm scared...
Don't you know that
I'm scared of heights?
Why trip over
in a place like this?
I can't see what kind of place
this is.
Don't quibble!
Senkichi-san.
Hey.
Hang in, we're almost there!
I'll do my best.
That hot spring will cure you.
I can't stand this anymore!
Where's my Kotetsu?
I checked it at the door.
I want it back!
Who do you think I am...
Expelled from Osaka
for killing a man,
I'm Senkichi of Kotetsu!
Here's your dagger.
I knew what you were up to
from the very start!
That'll show you. Kill him!
What? He went that way?
You sure?
But you're blind.
Anyway, over there! Move!
Are you Orin?
Why on earth are you here?
What happened between us
was just a one night stand.
I told you to leave!
Otherwise...
Hold on to my shoulder.
Wait a second!
The money...
the money's gonna fall out.
Those bastards!
At least I've managed to pilfer
their door money!
At last...
Hey...
Orin...
Where do you think you're
putting your hand?
On your back.
That, I know.
Right where your hand is,
is Ono no Komachi's face,
on my tattoo.
Her face...
is modelled after my late mother,
who died when I was a kid.
She's beautiful.
And my face looks a bit
like hers.
This hot spring...
In the olden days,
when Kai and Echigo...
went into a long war,
warriors in flight came
to this secret spot...
to heal their wounds.
Your wounds...
I will cure them here.
Oh, ouch!
When I was a kid,
my late mother and I would,
hand in hand,
drift through Shinano and Koshiji,
in the bitter cold of
the blowing snow,
listening to the sound...
of the freezing,
turbulent waves breaking.
My mother was deceived
by my father,
who was a Ronin.
She could never return
to her native Osaka,
and had to die on the road.
With her dying words she
told me to go to Osaka,
where my grandparents lived.
They brought me up.
Senkichi-san...
That's the very first time
that you've told me about yourself.
Isn't it?
I...
despise anyone who does
bad things to women!
Anyone who cheats a woman!
That's why I... you see?
Well, it's my choice...
One night stand or not,
you offered me sincere mercy.
I'm only placing a bet on this
happiness you've given me!
A bet? Gambling is strictly
men's business!
- How dare a woman...
- I placed a bet anyway!
Hono-o no gotoku
('Like a Burning Flame')
Produced by
Tsuneyasu MATSUMOTO & Kyoko OSHIMA
Original Story by Kouichi IIBOSHI
Cinematography by Keiji MARUYAMA
Art Direction by Chiyoo UMEDA
Music by Hajime KABURAGI
Lighting by Haruo NAKAYAMA
Editing by Katsumi KAWAl
CAST
Bunta
SUGAWARA
Mitsuko
BAISHO
Tamao NAKAMURA Akiko KITAIVI
U RA Hiroko SAKU RAMACHI
Makoto SATO Kin SUGAI Goro IBUKI
Tomiyuki
KUNIHIRO
Makoto Ryutaro
FUJITA OTOMO
Tetsuro TANBA Kanbi FUJIYAMA
Tomisaburo WAKAYAMA Kokichi TAKADA
Written and Directed by Tai KATO
They're no better than beggars.
- Just a wasted...
- It's all right.
They might have some.
We are imperialist samurai.
We need funds in order to go to Kyoto
and contribute to the Sonno-joi.
So stand and deliver!
No talking back.
Just make yourself amenable.
Why make a fuss and draw
your sword?
Hey... They're samurai.
I can hear there are
three of them.
Even you won't be able to...
You'd be ruined if you put up
a fight.
Here.
Okay, I know.
Please, take this.
This is all we have.
Oh dear!
Oh dear.
What's that on your back?
Let me see.
Well, urn...
I'm ready to give you
anything you want.
But please,
this is his precious...
A sword, isn't it?
Give it here.
- Give it to me.
- Woman.
We'll take you, to compensate
for the shortfall in our war fund.
And you! We'll slay you
as a precaution.
Come on!
Don't worry,
we'll fill her with pleasure...
before we sell her off.
So get that thing off
your back, quick!
What's wrong?
Sakichi-san!
Please, don't hurt him!
I don't care if you...
Let go of Orin!
Hey...
Orin...
I killed, once again...
I killed a man in Osaka,
and I've been expelled...
from the whole region
for a period of three years.
And that period will be over
this autumn.
And yet...
I messed up, again...
But...
such uncaring,
inconsiderate, cruel,
filthy bastards are unforgivable!
Senkichi-san...
Thank you.
- I'm happy.
- I owe you my life.
It's only natural.
Thank you!
Hey...
- We shouldn't be staying here.
- No.
If anyone should see us,
I'd be in big trouble.
Watch your step.
Don't move.
A clay bell?
I wonder why I picked this up.
Orin...
I give up. You win.
Now that it's come to this...
I too, will bet on you.
I will bet on you and make
you a happy woman, in Kyoto.
Let me carry you there.
Senkichi-san,
the seam on your sleeve
is coming undone.
Let me get down;
I'll stitch it up.
Leave it, I don't mind.
It will look bad.
Let me get down.
Orin.
What is it?
I just called.
MEANWHILE, KYOTO WAS...
A CITY OF SAMURAI ASSASSINATIONS
ON JULY 20,1862,
SAKON SHIMADA, A PRO-COALITION RETAINER
WAS ASSASSINATED BY SHINBEI TANAKA
AND HIS SATSUMA COMPATRIOTS
THIS WAS AN INTERNAL STRIFE.
AMONG THE SONNO-JOI FACTION
ON AUGUST 21,
SEIICHIRO HONMA FROM ECHIGO,
WAS ASSASSINATED.
ON AUGUST 30,
MEAKASHI BUNKICHI WAS STRANGLED
BY IZO OKADA AND HIS
TOSA COMPATRIOTS
SEPTEMBER 23 - ISHIBE POST STATION
- Here they come!
- Where?
Here they come!
TRAITORS
Wait a minute, Orin.
I might need to recite a
jingi greeting...
I'm no good at that.
You've always been a gambler.
Aren't you able to recite one?
No, I just can't.
I'm sorry.
You know...
those phrases are the
same with everybody.
You just have to memorize it.
I don't like it that way.
That's why I never got to
memorize the whole thing.
Oh dear...
Let's go to a quiet place.
You can recite the phrases
while I play the shamisen,
just like singing a song. Okay?
Okay, but not here.
Let's go.
Here.
OGAKI-YA
I am a traveling man.
Excuse me.
Coming!
Ready?
Good day, sir.
Who are you?
What's up?
"May l..."
May I come into your property?
Certainly, please.
Pardon my bothering you.
Just a moment... hey!
Quiet, please!
- Hey.
- Eh?
You interrupted me.
Now, let me take it from
the start.
Please, go back inside.
Hey... Mister.
That's an unusual thing to do.
You've got to let me.
Otherwise it won't...
Start all over again, huh?
How weird!
You ready?
It's alright with me!
Hey.
Who's that talking?
Is that Oburoshiki?
I wonder what that brat is
blabbering about.
Pardon my bothering you.
I shall listen.
Well, I shall listen.
Pardon my bothering you.
I shall listen.
- Oh, boss.
- What?
A funny guy just came.
He asks for your favour.
No way.
I'm about to go out.
Yes...
Here, come in.
Boss. He says...
this is a letter of recommendation.
Hey.
This is Ane-san (boss' wife).
Hello.
What a dirty piece of paper
you've brought me here...
- Barely readable!
- It used to be readable.
- When was that?
- Two years ago.
You idiot!
So, tell me...
You wanted to see me in person?
You want to be my kobun?
- No, that's not it.
- Then what?
The thing is,
Oyabun and Ane-san...
I have a companion here,
named Orin.
I bet my heart on her.
I came to Kyoto in my bid to...
make her a happy woman.
If I drink the cup of brotherhood
to become your kobun,
I will have to stake my life on you,
according to the code of loyalty.
It's not in my nature to lie.
Now, my top priority must be Orin.
Hey. What's your point?
Vending.
Your employment agency runs a lounge
for the workmen, with a gambling den.
Please allow me to sell food there.
I wish to make money that way,
and not by fighting and gambling,
so as to make Orin happy.
Beautiful!
I like your idea -
'to make a woman happy.'
Go for it. Sell food? Great!
Sake, sushi, sweets...
You wouldn't be a kobun...
for Orin's sake?
I like that part, too!
No place to live?
Leave it to me.
Hey, I'm the boss here.
- Are you against it?
- No one said that!
Sorry to interrupt,
but is it a yes or no?
- A little patience.
- Yes.
AFTER THE FIRST MONTH OF PEDDLING
- You idiot!
- Boss!
- A bad guy? How dare...
- Easy...
This is not just your
problem, understand?
I've no patience with guys like that!
Enough of the bullshit!
You little...
- I'll turn myself in.
- Idiot!
I never told you to!
I saw Orin-san in tears of joy,
saying that your expulsion
will be over this fall,
and that you will be free at last.
Your being a wanted criminal
again will devastate her!
Haven't you told us that you
want to make her happy!
Stop doing all the talking,
shut up!
But everyone is grateful
for this killing.
That thug Jagara was
pissing off our guests.
Shut up, you fool!
Please calm down, boss.
What's this...
Got myself ready,
so I've come to...
Later! I'm busy now,
scolding him!
Boss, Oburoshiki is...
on his way to Kishu at your behest.
- Boss!
- Darling!
You took on an assignment to
take care of the huge amount of...
lumber needed to build two mansions...
for the Lord of Aizu Domain,
who has to mobilize all his men...
and set up an office in Kyoto
upon being appointed...
a Military Commissioner.
The Chamberlain himself offered
you this assignment, right?
And you've ordered Oburoshiki...
to go off to Kishu and work
with the local lumber dealer.
Did you forget what you told
him to do?
It's all right.
Hey, Kotetsu!
Don't you ever cause trouble
for our boss and Ane-san!
Nor for Orin-san!
But I heard you're really strong...
What's keeping you? Go!
- Yes.
- Take care.
Hey, Senkichi, you bastard...
Idiot!
Listen, I'll manage the rest,
so forget about peddling and
lie low for now, okay?
- You.
- Yes?
Put your sandals on and take
him to Orin-san...
before leaving, okay?
- Yes.
- Good!
I am very sorry.
What a brat...
Ane-san... I'm sorry.
Move it, will you?
Hurry UP-
Orin-san? Morning!
I've brought you Kotetsu.
Orin, I'm home.
Orin-san.
Orin-san?
Where is she?
Orin?
Orin-san?
Kotetsu-san! ls Orin-san in?
- Aguri-chan, what's up with Orin?
- What's up?
Just now,
seeing you two come back,
my father...
when he opened his shop up,
the watchman on the corner came
to him and said he saw...
a blind lady in goze attire...
heading east,
so father sent me...
to tell you she might be
Kotetsu-san's wife...
- Aguri-chan, when was that?
- Tell me, when was it?
Hey, let her talk!
It was a while ago.
Kotetsu.
Look.
This is the kimono she's sewn for me.
She...
Kotetsu! Wait a second.
Wait.
Look.
Do you know what this means?
- What's this?
- No idea.
Hey, look.
This is a message from Orin-san.
A letter for you.
What's this?
- A tabi (sock).
- Tabi (travel)?
This is a masu (measuring cup).
And this?
Tsuma-yoji (toothpick).
Tsuma (wife) yoji (errands)-
Broken.
Hey! Listen up.
Okay? Now...
Tabi = travel.
Kaetta (upside down) masu.
Kaeri-masu = I'm leaving.
Dorin (clay bell) = Orin.
Wait! Wait up!
- You said east, right?
- Yes.
Awata-guchi.
Keage. Hino-oka.
Osaka-yama. Go, run!
- Orin!
- Run!
Hurry up! Run!
Quick!
It's you...
But Why?
A woman like me ought not
be with you past the fall.
And fall is nearing its end.
You can return to Osaka,
to Shimanouchi where...
your grandparents are waiting,
and be a young master
of Tanba-ya, a wholesale mercer.
Or you can pledge loyalty to...
the Oyabun of Ogaki-ya and
be a member of his family.
It will surely make a man
out of you.
A woman like me can't
stand in your way...
Shut up! You're wrong!
If you leave me now,
what will become of my bet?
I'll have to lose!
I won't gamble!
I promise.
I won't fight, either!
Hey, you!
Nice day, isn't it?
In gambling,
only the bookie makes money.
I know that very well,
from my own experience.
So, let's go.
Oops. Not the bridge.
It'd be a long way round.
Let's go along the river.
I'm hungry, and you?
Roasted rice cake?
Hey. Are they roasted?
They are.
Give me two.
Ouch!
It's hot.
Fresh from the oven.
One bite and the filling will
burn your tongue.
River bank.
River bank, indeed.
Very large river bank.
Quite large, indeed.
A perfect location.
Huh?
BUSINESS RESTART A FEW DAYS LATER
There, bring them down.
Ossan (old man)!
Right there, right there.
- That's all?
- Yes, that's all.
Good job.
Ossan! Are you alright?
Watch out!
Mind who you're talking to.
Ossan.
Now, all we have to do is
to bring in...
those tatami mats and
place them lengthwise.
Quicker than I thought.
You did a great job!
Hey, you.
You sound like you're
building a gambling den.
Sound like?
It is a gambling den!
We'll do good business here.
Grand opening soon!
That's nonsense.
Don't you know that...
this area is within the territory
of Nabari-ya of the Awata-guchi?
This sort of thing could get
you killed,
for violating their territory.
Eh?
Can't believe I've got
myself in such hot water!
Just because I sold you
two roasted rice cakes...
For pity's sake...
Oh, and mind you,
don't forget,
you owe me money!
- I know!
- You pay me back!
All right already, Ossan!
Ossan, don't worry!
By evening,
I'll pay you back double!
Gambling den!
A new gambling den!
It's open now!
What? Gambling?
Where is it?
Go and make money, Ossan!
Welcome!
Here, have a seat.
Please, make your bet!
You're the first customer:
it's your lucky day!
Well, no...
We came to ask you
to make us your kobuns.
My name is Kumagoro Ueba.
My name is Kotaro lroha.
I don't want no kobuns!
We saw you kill that thug, Jagara.
And we both decided our Oyabun
shall be no one else but you.
Use us as dealers and bookies.
No, I don't need no kobuns!
- Please...
- Oh, welcome!
Please, take a seat and play!
Who gave you permission
to do this?
Who's in charge here?
Step up!
- You're the one?
- Come on!
I'm in charge.
You got a problem?
- You...
- You look familiar...
My name is Hyorokudama,
from the Nabariya Family.
Follow me.
Come on!
Clear the way!
NABARI-YA
Oyabun! I'm coming!
Oyabun-san, Ane-san.
I ask for your permission
in my obscure position.
This is my first appearance
in your honourable presence today.
Accordingly, allow me to introduce
my humble self, from Senshu.
I was born in Sakai, Senshu.
My name is Gonji.
I go by the name of
Aka-mamushi ('Red Viper').
The late Jagara the Hairy and I
were brothers in the same family.
I am a person of little account.
From here on, please kindly...
accord me your acquaintance,
and grant me your support.
Even or odds?
Play.
2-5. Odds!
Next round.
Ane-san?
Kotestu.
Come here.
That's territory violation!
Why is that?
I just wanted to build a new
gambling den for the Ogaki-ya.
What's the problem with the place?
Across Kamo river,
the east side belongs to the Nabari-ya,
and the west to the Ogaki-ya.
- And what about the dry riverbed?
- Eh?
Does it belong to the Nabari-ya?
No...
Nor does it belong to the Ogaki-ya.
It belongs to no one.
Hence my choice.
An ideal spot for business.
Look what I made,
just for today.
Heaps of silver coins.
That's clever.
You're right about...
a riverbed belonging to no one.
Boss!
None of your quibbling!
A riverbed belongs to no one.
And it doesn't belong to you!
From the times of Emperor Kanmu,
it has belonged to
the whole city of Kyoto.
A natural landmark of
this capital. You hear me?
Oh.
I will not allow you to
build your dirty hut there!
Tear it down!
And make sure to clean up
the place when you're done!
- Now move!
- Yes!
- Let's go!
Leave!
You're suspended
until I say it's enough.
And don't leave this money
lying in front of me!
Take it with you and leave!
Listen...
Don't you dare step outside
while on suspension,
or I'll hang you upside down,
gouge out your eyes and...
- Understand?
- Yes!
But say...
that brat's such a smart one,
isn't he?
Boss...
This isn't the best time to say that.
What about the Nabari-ya?
With the huge project
commissioned by Aizu ahead,
a conflict with the Nabari would...
You don't have to tell me.
I'm thinking about it.
Kappore kappore
Dance with sweet tea
Dance with bitter tea
Life is hard for a subordinate
Looking for a pretty
lady to come
- Hey...
- Shut up!
What's the matter?
Oyabun...
I can't drink! No more!
Drank too much.
Can't stand up.
Pathetic!
Here...
Go to Miyagawa-cho
or Shimabara, wherever.
I'll make you my kobuns if
you can duly enjoy nightlife.
Oyabun.
Show me you can, otherwise
you're no kobuns of mine.
Eh?
Hurry, go! And have fun!
Hey, Kuma, let's go.
Sorry, thanks!
I'm sorry, thanks!
I'm sorry, but thanks!
I'm so, so sorry.
Thank you for this.
Orin.
Here.
This is all yours to have.
Buy whatever you want with it.
But this is a lot!
I earned it...
for the sake of the Oyabun,
and for yours.
And yet... bullshit!
That nit-picking Oyabun...
But... Orin,
that Oyabun is nothing like...
the ordinary gokudo Oyabuns...
you have around here these days.
He says that the Kamo
riverbanks have been,
from the times of Emperor Kanmu,
natural assets that belong to
the entire city of Kyoto.
He has such a broad vision!
I was totally convinced.
Hey.
If you want to sleep,
I'll make your bed.
Who is it?
Watch out!
Get out of the way!
Wake up!
Someone!
Run to the Ogaki-ya!
Back off!
Brother!
We're going ahead!
Stop throwing stones at me!
Hey, Kotetsu!
Someday I'll get you
and finish you off!
Hey, wait!
Kotetsu-san!
Orin-san!
She... She's dead!
What a cruel thing to do...
They must have hurt...
hurt you badly, right?
You've had nothing but pain
and trouble.
Rain every day and
no sunshine for you.
Kotetsu, you fool!
Such a fool...
Orin...
Orin!
Why...
Why?
Why?!
You've saved my life
once again...
Yet it all had to end
in such a horrible way...
What am I supposed to do now?
Tell me, Orin...
Orin.
You wait here for
a little while, okay?
Kotetsu-san!
Father! Mother!
Kotetsu-san's gone!
I am Senkichi Kotetsu,
from Nijo Daimonji-cho.
Those four cowards who've
just stormed my house...
Bring them here to me!
Wait!
So you're Kotetsu.
I am Shinzo Nabari-ya.
- What do you want?
- Didn't you just hear?
" Stop!
The four who've just come back
from my house!
Three of them have.
They brought back your finger.
The other one,
a traveller who settled in today,
and who was after you in revenge for
his brother Jagara, is missing.
- Now leave.
- Bring me the three who've returned.
I'll slash them to death!
Earlier, I held back,
so they wouldn't die.
But things have changed.
Now I have to kill them.
Changed?
Those bastards killed my wife!
What?
They killed my wife!
I will avenge her death!
Bring them in!
Nabari-ya.
There's been a mistake
on your side for...
having killed this man's wife.
A bad judgment.
Now, I must excuse myself.
Good day, Nabari-ya.
About our earlier negotiations...
- Will you leave the matter to us?
- Yes. I will.
And what about my matter?
What answer have you got?
You are Senkichi Kotetsu.
Listen...
I've got no ears to listen with!
Those three...
You've got to listen anyway.
I am Tatsugoro Shinmon,
from Edo.
I've been accompanying
these Hitotsubashi-sama here.
I am Kojiro Koganei,
from Bushu (Musashino),
on my visit to Kyoto and Osaka.
I am Umekichi Yakushi,
from Yamato (Nara).
I was showing the region
to Kojiro and,
as I was paying a visit
to Tatsugoro's,
we ran into the Ogaki-ya,
who asked us to...
get together here,
although we wanted...
to carry things out in
a discrete manner.
And I believe you should know why.
We will take your
matter in hand, too.
No way!
You'll just have to let us.
Well then, will you bring...
my Orin back to life?
Bring Orin back to life,
will you?
Why don't you understand that
it's all your fault?
What?
Kotetsu...
You were always...
against things that you
truly despised,
or people you couldn't forgive,
and turned into an
angry ball of flame,
swinging around your
Kotetsu sword.
It was invigorating
listening to your stories.
They were beautiful.
But what about this
riverbank gambling den?
What did you find to be intolerable?
Were you angry with something?
It was just a whim.
Out of greed.
Out of ambition.
You almost turned into the kind
of man you despise so much.
But you never realized.
Orin-san died
and proved you wrong.
Didn't she?
It's the first time
that I've see a man...
crying in public without reservation.
Ogaki-ya-san,
this is one hell of a kobun
you've got.
I'm no kobun!
You might want to deny it,
but you already are,
in the eyes of the public.
It's not difficult to understand!
Come on.
Let's go. We'll mourn quietly
for Orin-san tonight,
and hold a respectable funeral.
After that,
you'll take over from Oburoshiki,
who's now working in Kishu,
as a construction chief.
Work hard.
Shed your sweat.
You'll stand on top of the scaffold
at the Aizu construction site,
give the workers a pep talk,
and let your voice...
be heard by Orin-san up there.
But... I'm...
afraid of heights!
If I have to work in construction,
I really can't be a kobun...
Idiot!
FROM THE END OF THAT YEAR
UNTIL 1863
FROM THE END CF THAT YEAR
UNTIL 1863 IN KYOTO...
THE NEW MILITARY COMMISSIONER LIEUTENANT
GENERAL KATAMORI OF AIZU
THE NEW MILITARY COMMISSIONER LIEUTENANT GENERAL
KATAMORI CF AIZU ENTERED KYOTO) WITH HIS ARMY CORPS
THE NEW MILITARY COMMISSIONER LIEUTENANT GENERAL KATAMORI
CF AIZU ENTERED KYOTO) WITH HIS ARMY CORPS (DECEMBER 24)
234 PRO-SHOGUNATE RONIN, THE ROSHI-TAI,
ENTERED KYOTO...
ENTERED KYOTO... (FEBRUARY 23, 186s)
234 PRO-SHOGUNATE RONIN, THE ROSHI-TAI, ENTERED KYOTO...
(FEBRUARY 23, 1863) We finally made it to Kyoto!
234 PRO-SHOGUNATE RONIN, THE ROSHI-TAI,
ENTERED KYOTO... (FEBRUARY 23, 186s)
KAMO SERIZAWA (37)
It wasn't that far.
Kondo-san!
ISAMI KONDO (30)
THE 14TH TOKUGAWA SHOGUN
IEMOCHI ENTERED KYOTO
THE 14TH TOKUGAWA SHOGLJN
IEMOCHI ENTERED KYOTO (MARCH 4)
THE ROSHI-TAI
SPLIT UP
THE ROSHI-TAI SPLIT
UP (MARCH 1 s)
(MARCH 1 s)
ONLY 13 REMAINED INCLUDING KAMO SERIZAWA AND ISAMI KONDO, WHO FOUNDED
THE SHINSENGUMI UNDER THE SUPERVISION OF LT. GEN. KATAMORI OF AIZU
APRIL KYOBASHI FERRY FUSHIMI
APRIL KYOBASHI FERRY FUSHIMI Thank
you so much for your patronage.
APRIL KYOBASHI FERRY FUSHIMI
APRIL KYOBASHI FERRY FUSHIMI She's grown
into a fine lady. How old is she now?
She's grown into a fine lady.
How old is she now?
Sightseeing in Kyoto?
Going down to Osaka?
Thank you.
- Bring some tea!
- Oh, no thanks.
Boat bound for Hakken-ya, Osaka!
AND HERE ARRIVES THE INBOUND BOAT, WAY BEHIND
SCHEDULE Boat bound for Hakken-ya, Osaka!
AND HERE ARRIVES THE INBOUND
BOAT, WAY BEHIND SCHEDULE
This is the last boat for Osaka!
Outbound boat to Osaka!
Watch your step.
Come on, everybody aboard!
Hurry up!
We're leaving now!
Se...
Did you see his sword?
That's a Kotetsu.
Huh?
Push it!
The same as yours, Kondo-san.
Which one's more expensive?
- Oh, mine's longer, so...
- Longer?
Hey, are you finished with those?
Don't take them back to Mibu.
Post them around here.
Oh, these?
COMPETENT SWORDMAN WANTED
- SHINSENGUMI
It's your fault, Kondo-san,
that we have this many left.
Yesterday, and the day before,
in Osaka, you repeatedly said no,
each time I tried to post one.
Of course I did:
I care where they get posted.
It doesn't make any sense
if we don't catch the eyes...
of confident, ambitious men
in these turbulent times.
Hey, look, how about over there?
Nah, I think that house belongs
to the Satsuma Domain.
Then, that's the enemy's den.
Okay. One on the inn next door.
And another one over there.
That'll be enough.
All right?
Hey, wait!
You may have come twice
out of politeness,
but your third time
shows you're in love
The waterwheel on
Yodo river turns...
Orin...
You know where this boat's
heading to?
To Osaka.
Tomorrow, when we arrive,
we'll go straight to Shimanouchi.
This mortuary tablet of yours:
I'll apologize to my grandparents and...
add it to our family altar.
Sir! It's Senkichi-san!
I'm so glad for you, Orin.
Senkichi...
Oyoshi! Senkichi's back.
Ma'am! It's Senkichi-san!
Excuse me.
Grandpa and Grandma,
without saying anything,
placed your tablet...
on the altar,
right beside my mother's tablet.
However...
what followed left me bewildered...
- Senkichi, meet your bride,
Otomi. - Huh?!
Don't you remember her?
That's Tomi-chan.
She's the daughter of
my sister's child.
She's grown into a fine lady.
We wanted her to be your
bride upon your return,
and adopted her in your absence.
Hey, come on, Otomi.
Come sit closer to Senkichi.
Yes, sit closer,
right next to him.
Closer, come on.
Come on.
Please! Someone?
Bring me the calendar.
Darling, we should...
quickly fix a date for...
One moment please! I...
Um... I am still engaged in a...
- large project in Kyoto...
- Orin...
I'm glad I came to Osaka.
Now it's clear to me.
I will bet on nobody else but
the Ogaki-ya boss from now on.
Let Tomi-chan take a husband
and make them your heirs,
I said to them.
Grandpa turned purple.
Grandma stamped on the tatami.
And Tomi-Chan was...
Anyway, I'm on my way back to Kyoto.
Before leaving,
I had to meet my friends.
The best and baddest
of all my friends:
Mizuoto and his wife Otsune.
My second-best friend Heiko,
and his wife Icchan.
Susumu Yamazaki:
son of an acupuncture doctor.
We used to study swordplay together.
He thinks he's as good
as me. Ha!
Nonsense...
I'd beat him three times in
a row in a three-game match.
Um... Who's he?
Must be Yamazaki's junior.
Yamazaki says he brought him,
but isn't he a samurai...?
Are you out of your mind?
The Shinsengumi are never
gonna make it.
As long as it's profitable...
You couldn't be worse!
That's a terrible thing to say!
Orin...
The teapot's empty.
- Goodbye!
- Say thanks to your parents!
It's here.
GODS!
- Ouch.
- I'm sorry!
Kotetsu! Here I am!
Oh, there you are.
Sasaki and I made up our minds.
We've come for a try-out
with the Shinsengumi.
We're staying here for the night.
- Staying?
- Yeah.
- Now the two of us are going
to Mibu. - Two?
Why two? There are three
of you, aren't there?
Huh? Oh...
Mizuoto asked me to
bring that kid to you.
He's Heikichi Kobayashi.
He's been repudiated by his father.
Mizuoto said you can use him
as an apprentice.
What?
He doesn't even bother to ask
and still gets his own way!
Oh, Well.
All right. But this afternoon,
we'll all be out for work at the
Aizu construction site in Kamanza.
Aguri-chan!
Three more tables for dinner, please.
Aguri-chan?
Aguri-chan!
What's with you?
Love at first sight?
None of your business!
END OF PART ONE
PART TWO
If I can't be with you,
I'll die.
I'd even run away with you.
I...
Aguri-chan...
Kiss me on the lips.
Kiss?
That's what you do when
in love, so they say.
It's hot.
Hey. The last moving cart
will arrive. Oyabun, too.
Don't let him see you like that.
But why on earth does Kotetsu...
You know, Kotetsu always makes
objections against...
Sasaki and Aguri-chan
being together.
Why is he so cynical?
Well, he's always been a weirdo,
but...
in order to let them get married,
we'll have to convince him.
Absolutely.
Aguri-chan is an only daughter.
Sasaki-san's quitting the samurai
and the Shinsengumi to marry...
into Yaofuji; the greengrocery
won't be easy.
So, the only person who...
might be able to settle this problem
is our Oyabun,
by convincing Aguri-chan's parents.
Today, I'm gonna make Oyabun
say "Yes".
You can count on me.
- Thank you.
Sorry. Excuse me.
FOR RENT
"We've moved to Sannomiya-cho,
south of Shomen
"- Senkichi & Kotetsu of Aizu."
Watch where you're going!
Aguri-chan, thank you.
Go home now.
It's the busiest time
at your father's greengrocery.
Go help him.
Sasaki-san.
You'd better go, too.
Haven't you got work to
do for the Shinsengumi?
Oh, no. My patrol shift was yesterday.
I'm off today.
We're not through with these.
No! Don't!
Aguri-chan!
Here, Aguri-chan.
Aguri-chan.
Let go of it.
Let go!
Aguri-chan.
Let me take them, Oyabun.
Get off!
Leave the young couple alone,
won't you?
Yamazaki!
Let me tell you something:
You say you've spent all
your savings.
Haven't you found a job
to do yet?
And yet you fool around,
while we're all busy moving.
Are you done with your eating?
All right, then. Listen:
I've been gathering information...
from your conversations
with your kobuns.
What information, stupid?!
How can you...
- Oh, I'll carry it for you.
- Leave it!
The clay bell's missing!
Someone...?
The bell I've kept in here.
Orin's bell!
Hey!
lroha?
Ueba?
Hey!
It's gonna fall!
Fall down and smash!
Someone!
But Why?
How did it climb up here from
the drawer of Orin's dresser?
Someone!
I mean... who did it?
You all know that
I'm afraid of heights!
You bastards!
You're all going to get it!
What... What are you doing?
- Pull it!
- Yes!
- No!
- Hey!
- You do it, quickly!
- Yes!
The ladder!
I'm slipping--
- Oyabun! Please!
- What?
We have a favour to ask concerning
these two. They're in love.
What?
Won't you please approve their
marriage, Oyabun?
And please talk to Aguri-chan's parents
and convince them to give consent.
We beg of you.
Hey, you, too.
- Please! - Please!
- No, I can't!
I'm gonna fall down...
The ladder!
We won't prop it up
unless you say "Yes
You set me up!
- No...
- Kotetsu-san!
I can't live if I can't marry him!
Aguri-chan.
It's only for your own sake.
Because you made nice with Orin,
I don't want you to suffer
like my late mother did...
Not with a samurai!
Sasaki-san...
Didn't you bet your life
on the Shinsengumi?
Then how can you make
a woman happy?
I promise I will make
Aguri-chan happy!
You don't understand a thing
about a woman's feelings!
Kotetsu.
Why don't you just give up?
The... la... cider...
Hurray!
Didn't you hear me?
Gimme the ladder!
...burned down in a fire
Sanjusangen-do Temple
survived this fire
Who stands right behind
you now?
Wait a second.
Over there.
- Hey, Sasaki!
- Kuma!
Come here for a second.
- Let's...
- Yes.
Here we go... hup!
Look, look...
Isn't that it?
Oh, thank you very much.
We appreciate your assistance.
Hey!
You! From the Shinsengumi!
Banzai to you!
Sasaki-san!
Yes?
Just one thing.
Remember...
I really hate those who hurt...
or cheat...
women. All right?
Anyway, her parents say...
they want to meet Sasaki-san,
and are waiting for you.
- L...
- Go. Hurry.
Yes!
A leather cigarette case
from Grandpa.
But I chose it for you.
Sweet bean jelly from Toraya,
and rice puff crackers
from Grandma.
The head clerk said,
after he'd made sure
I entered this house,
he would visit customers...
in Gionmachi or Muromachi,
then go back to Osaka.
Go back to Osaka.
I beg you.
Oh no, I'm not saying you
must leave right now...
I'll find lodgings for you.
Enjoy Kyoto, and...
Grandpa and Grandma
asked me to come here.
- Tomi-chan.
- And get Senkichi-san back.
Tomi-chan.
Out of our way!
Commander.
- Chief!
- Eh?
It's you, Sasaki.
Who's this woman?
Her name is Aguri. She's my...
You're Aguri?
Isn't she pretty?
Tomi-chan.
There's an Oyabun called
Seihachi, of the Ogaki-ya.
I bet my life on him.
I don't expect you to understand.
Call me stupid.
Forgive me.
Working for this Oyabun
is my only...
ll f?
- Even gambling?
- It's still work!
I work under Seihachi,
of the Ogaki-ya.
My name is Kotetsu, of Aizu.
- What do you want?
- I'm not addressing you.
Pardon my sudden intervention,
but this Tome the Helper
is a peddler.
Seihachi Ogaki-ya is,
as you know,
a gambler and an employment agent.
This place is Ogaki-ya territory.
We can't allow these peddlers
to hold any games here,
and bring shame on the Ogaki-ya.
Shut up!
Bullshit!
Wanna fight?
Again, as you know,
the Ogaki-ya is now...
about to complete an assignment
commissioned by the Lord of Aizu.
We were instructed not to look
for trouble with cheap peddlers,
but to have our name disgraced
is simply intolerable.
Sincere apologies
for this incivility...
I'll chop off his head!
Everyone...
Would you please call this game off?
You're gonna pay for this!
- Kill them!
- Wait!
My name is Otatsu,
from Hyogo. I said, wait!
Brother. You, too: wait.
What's this?
- A monogram.
- A monogram?
Oyabun, we already have one,
the Dai from the Ogaki-ya.
I was thinking about creating
another version of it...
Oyabun!
Damn it...
That's it!
Idiot.
- It's all wrinkled...
- But cool!
The Ogaki-ya boss loves sake,
and always asks Ane-san to
fill up his gourd.
He'd go to a place with
a nice view and sip from it,
saying that this gourd is
his only luxury,
then get drunk, right?
It'll suit you too, Oyabun!
- Cut the crap, kid.
- Oh no, wait.
Now that you mention it,
you may be right.
I should ask the boss
to have a look at this.
I'm sorry, Tomi-chan.
I've always been busy
and left you alone.
But I'm glad that a nice lady is...
accompanying you to Osaka.
I leave her in your hands,
Oyabun-san.
Coming from you,
I have to say yes.
It's been 10 days...
since we participated in
that game, but Seihachi-san...
and Oei-san of the Ogaki-ya...
have been hospitably kind to us,
so I feel obliged to respond
in kind to them.
I'll accompany her to Shimanouchi.
Oh no, you can drop her at Hakken-ya.
I've arranged for her pick-up.
Kotetsu-san...
don't you ever feel lonely?
Does it seem strange,
hearing that from me?
- No.
- Really?
On the 18th, when you were
out transporting lumber...
Have you heard?
One hell of a commotion
at the Imperial Palace.
The Sonno-joi allies
Satsuma and Choshu split up.
Satsuma won and chased Choshu
away from Kyoto.
Shortly before that,
on the 13th,
Serizawa from the Shinsengumi
set fire to Yamato-ya at Ichijo,
on account of them failing
to pay him off.
Samurai are all the same:
they seek nothing but trouble.
Leave them be
and they'll devastate Kyoto.
You know, these men left their
wives and children behind.
How about bringing
the whole family here?
Don't you agree?
Not a bad idea?
Urn... well...
But those fellows are all
in a prickly mood,
out on the prowl for women
in Kyoto, like dogs in heat.
Scratch a samurai, and you'll find
a man of flesh and blood.
I'm a woman of flesh and blood.
And you know what?
I fell for you.
If I were a bit younger...
He's also a man of flesh and blood.
You get it?
Yes.
The boat's leaving soon!
Hop on the boat, quick!
This is the boat for Hakken-ya,
Osaka.
Senkichi-san...
You said you hated anyone
who is cruel to women.
Yet you're now being cruel to me.
Tomi-chan!
The boat's leaving now!
AIZU
HEADQUARTERS
Thank you for coming,
and for your hard work
on the construction.
Now, you're sitting too
far away to talk with. Please.
Consider this as a private meeting.
Everyone, come inside.
You know them?
They are Commander Kondo and
members of the Shinsengumi.
This is my first time meeting you.
Vice Commander,
Keisuke Yamanami.
Vice Commander, Hijikata.
- Urn... I'm Okita.
- Oh!
Shinpachi Nagakura.
Genzaburo Inoue.
Heisuke Todo.
Sanosuke Harada.
Then, let me introduce them.
Ogaki-ya Oyabun Seihachi.
His first kobun,
chief clerk Kuniemon.
Second kobun,
chief carpenter Kokichi.
Head of the newly-established
Aizu crew, Kotetsu of Aizu.
Now, we're all set.
We didn't ask the Serizawa
faction to come here today.
Such are the intentions of the Lord of
Aizu, Military Commissioner of Kyoto.
- Please look at it that way.
- Yes.
What the Shinsengumi
needs most today is friends.
To this day, there are...
those of us who would rather
make enemies of people in Kyoto.
- We'll dispense with all that.
- Now Choshu is...
willing to mobilize an army
for their return to Kyoto.
Their radicals, along with...
like-minded expatriates
who've joined them,
and Ronins, have changed
their names and emblems...
and gathered in Kyoto already.
Satsuma is against Choshu,
but you never know what they're up to.
The same goes for Tosa.
So, as a measure of extra
precaution, we...
Are you asking us to work for
the Shinsengumi as spies?
Not at all.
We have members in charge of that.
Look, we want you to be our friends.
- That's all we ask.
- We want friends.
Simple as that.
But it's the most crucial
thing for us.
And in fact, this is also the
intention of...
the Lord of Aizu, Military
Commissioner of Kyoto.
What do you think?
If that's what our Oyabun wants.
We won't say no.
You've just heard our answer.
- Got something to say?
- Yes.
I wish to talk with Kondo-san
in person.
I guess we've been destined
to meet again.
I noticed your sword,
back in the spring,
at Kyobashi, in Fushimi.
So you remembered.
Now that the ice is broken,
please...
I'm ready to listen.
Would you please allow Aijiro Sasaki
to leave the Shinsengumi?
I must beg this of you.
- Of his own will?
- For the sake of a woman.
- Kotetsu-kun.
- Kondo-san.
Sasaki-san is planning to
marry a girl called Aguri.
She is the only daughter
of a humble greengrocer.
She's been living with
her father and mother.
He should be congratulated.
Sasaki has, in this time of turmoil,
set out on an adventure...
and joined the Shinsengumi,
ambitious and proud.
Moreover, he won her heart.
While in the Shinsengumi,
he can't make her happy.
Besides, that ambitious and proud...
samurai and a town girl
will never...
- Ah, wait a second...
- Kondo-san.
Kotetsu-kun...
The Shinsengumi is made up of
human beings.
I mean, we're men.
Men need women.
It's only natural, isn't it?
- Do you mean to defy nature?
- Women...
bet their lives on that nature.
Can a man...
especially a member of the
Shinsengumi, do the same?
- They can't.
- That's what men are all about.
Then what about women?
Listen, Kondo-san.
This girl Aguri...
I can never permit her to be a
woman who would weep...
for all the misfortunes
of the world.
I will swear it on
my Kotetsu sword.
I, Kondo, will never make that
girl, Aguri, a sad woman!
Kotetsu-kun...
Right now, every single member is
important for the Shinsengumi.
We can't afford to lose any of them.
We just can't.
Orin.
All right.
Good.
Let me invite you today.
Well, I'm just a rustic type of man...
but, just now,
the proprietress found
me an unusual girl.
This will be my treat for you.
Now, Kotetsu-kun,
go over there.
Please, please.
<From the last paragraph
of the Noh play 'Izutsu'>
A daughter of a merchant in Osaka,
an acquaintance of the proprietress,
said she wanted to dance for the
customers here, for some reason.
Noh training, I guess.
Sasaki...
Your girl, whom I met at
Miyagawa-cho, Aguri...
I'll make her my mistress.
Be prepared.
- Hey, Mister!
- Huh?
But... Commander!
- We're planning a wedding...
- As soon as tonight!
Aguri is my...
As soon as tonight.
Hey, Sasaki.
- Sorry for being late.
- Thank you for taking the trouble.
Let me get the door for you.
Oh, really?
Well, I appreciate it.
Here you go.
Thanks. It's nothing, but...
- Oh, but you really shouldn't...
- Oh, please.
Thank you so much.
Man, you're in bad trouble.
Chances are, you'll be dead
and that girl will be lost.
If you really love that girl,
you have no choice
other than to desert.
- Desert?
- Yes...
And the time is now.
Right now.
What will you do?
Cling to the group
and hand over the girl?
Time to prove you're a man.
Leave the group and
flee with her?
When Commander Serizawa says
"tonight", he means it.
Your courage is at stake here.
Saeki-san.
Who is it, may I ask?
Senkichi-san...
Well, my husband's not back yet.
The others are out at work.
Please come back
sometime tomorrow.
- What's this? Can't open it!
- What are you doing?
Quick! Hurry, quick!
Here.
Quick!
Cooked beans, anyone?
This house is still empty, right?
No one will find us.
No...
We're dealing with Commander Serizawa.
There's no use hiding.
When did they come?
With Commander Niimi?
Just a while ago,
out of the blue,
saying they'll come tonight to
make her Serizawa's mistress.
- They're crazy...
- No use moaning now.
Go look for Kotetsu-san in Okazaki
or Kamanza and ask for his help!
Well... then... I'll go.
Don't!
I've got no time to waste...
As I said,
I've no choice but to escape.
Sasaki-san!
- Hello. - Otomi-san?
- Yes!
Thank you for the gift,
it was a nice treat.
Well, I wanted to thank you.
I've brought you some boiled sea eel
to add to your dinner menu.
- Wow! Looks delicious!
- Oh, it's not much...
What's up?
Something happened?
Open the door.
Huh?
- Escaped?
- Yes.
My folks live in Hirakata.
They'll hide out there for a while
and think about their next move.
I walked them to Tofukuji Temple.
- They took Toba Street...
- Good! Very good.
Good job, helping them escape!
Serves him right,
that bastard Serizawa!
Anyway, come inside.
This is bad.
He's deserted, right?
Desertion is punishable by
seppuku if caught.
If he tries to fight back,
he'll be slayed on the spot!
"Resignation is forbidden."
That's the rule of the Shinsengumi!
What the hell...
That's ridiculous!
He promised...
How dare he break it!
The Shinsengumi are a bunch of liars!
But Sasaki-san said
his colleague Saeki-san...
advised him that he had no choice
but to escape...
Saeki? Very, very bad...
Saeki is Commander Serizawa's
henchman!
That bastard Serizawa put Saeki up to it,
in order to eliminate Sasaki!
They might ambush them...
I won't let them do that!
I'll run to Mibu to call on Commander Kondo,
as well as Hijikata-san.
- I hope I can...
- I'll make it in time!
No! I'm the only one who's going.
- Oyabun, but why?
- Shut up!
Stupid!
So you just let him go alone?
But it was Oyabun himself who said,
"You've got work to do tomorrow.
- "Follow me and you're fired."
- How important is work?
Work can be replaced,
but human life is irreplaceable!
Someone give me a dagger.
Give it to me.
No, don't!
If you're not going, I will.
Don't.
- What are you doing, Otomi-san?
- No, let go of me!
Get away!
No time to waste! Hurry!
Brother!
What's happening?
Ouch! Where are you going?
You tricked me!
That's foul.
That's dirty!
Shut up.
A rule's a rule.
Give me a sword!
I will die with you!
Aguri-chan!
You're dead!
Sasaki-san!
Saeki!
- Damn!
- Idiot!
Who told you to kill the girl?
Niimi! How could you...
Commander.
Commander!
Let go of me!
Let's go down to Sumizome!
Niimi-san.
Aguri-chan...
Aguri-chan.
Sasaki-san.
Damn!
Kotetsu...
Are you chagrined?
I'll bury you there.
I'll avenge my brother Jagara.
Say your prayers.
I can wait that long.
Deceitful Shinsengumi!
I'll slay you dead!
Oh no, this is Commander Kondo
and Hijikata-san.
Shut up!
Don't get in my way!
They almost killed each
other at the same time.
A Kotetsu...
It surely is a Kotetsu,
but yours is shadowed.
A deceitful Kotetsu!
No Kotetsu can be shadowed!
Shut up!
Hey, you...
When you aim at someone
with a gun,
you'd better take careful aim.
- Kotetsu-kun.
- What now?
The blunder is mine.
Forgive me.
Sasaki... And Aguri...
Please forgive Kondo.
- Please!
- No way!
Aguri...
Aguri.
Aguri!
But Why?
Those two were innocent
and pure.
Like flower buds...
So pitiful...
and beautiful...
Aren't they beautiful?
- Thank you.
- You're wrong.
To hell with beauty.
Thank him?
The most beautiful vision
of a woman is when she...
stays with a man she loves
for life,
and bears his children...
and brings them up...
Brings them up...
But she...
No...
SEPTEMBER 18
SHINSENGUMI
CAMP
Yamazaki!
NOW! Go!
- Quick, draw it!
- I can't...
Come. Quick.
Die!
Beheaded, according to our code.
So, rest assured.
Now... let's go.
NEW YEAR'S EVE
Hey.
What's this?
An arrest, as you can see.
Guess who?
The famous Izo the Manslayer.
Or what's left of Izo Okada,
of Tosa.
Eh?
The pro-imperialist group of Tosa
has had its day.
But now is the time of
the coalition.
He's nothing other than
a murderer now.
A wanted criminal with
nowhere to go.
He changed his looks,
got hooked on women,
gambling...
He was a regular at your den,
he ended up committing burglary,
and got...
tracked down.
His luck ran out.
But how long will you
leave him like this for?
He's freezing.
We're tying up his
female accomplice.
They were naked when
we arrived.
He'll be okay like this,
but the woman needs some clothes.
What on earth...
Hey, Yamazaki!
How dare you tie up a woman!
This place is for passing customers.
She can't be responsible
for every one of them.
- Why are you so...
- Upset? I am!
Beat her up for information that...
you should already have known?
Both the Shinsengumi and
the authorities are pathetic.
I can't take you hurting
an innocent woman like this.
You morons!
All right, all right, I got it.
Release this woman,
will you?
- But...
- Shut up!
I'll take responsibility for this.
- Hey.
- Yes'?
Hurry up! Tell him.
Hurry up, quick.
Hey. Let's get moving.
Hey.
- Stand up.
- Wait!
- Let's go.
- Yes.
What about my position, huh?
Did that come from Kyoto?
- Eh?
- The bell.
I don't know.
Well...
Back when I wandered through...
Koshiji... and Shinano,
I was attacked by...
some robbers who were
Ronins, so I...
Ronins?
There were three of them.
No asking or telling. Nothing.
We got into a fight,
and I killed all three of them.
Actually, the Ronin with this
clay bell was called...
"Watada" by one of his comrades.
It's strange...
I wonder why I told you this story.
- Watada?
- Yes.
I live here alone and
practice this profession.
Please stop by for a while.
You killed my father!
Be prepared!
At least explain!
The man you killed was
Yasumasa Watada,
and I'm his daughter, Naka.
That clay bell was made by
my father for me.
Look!
In the countryside of Echizen,
I lived with my father and mother.
We made clay bells...
and sold them to shrines here
and there to make our living.
- Father became committed to the
Sonno-joi... - And became a robber.
Killed by you!
A man must care for his wife
and children above all.
How's your mother doing now?
My mother... she passed away...
three years ago, worrying about father,
who'd disappeared.
I searched for my father.
Why seek revenge for such a father?
Coward!
Listen...
Your father was a robber
at that time.
He attacked my wife and I.
He tried to steal, to kill me,
yo take my sword, to kidnap
my wife and to rape her.
His acts were unforgivable!
As his child, I must avenge him.
It's unforgivable!
Eh?
- Kill me!
- Shut up!
You know what, Naka-san?
I can't stand that you are
feeling hurt in this way.
I am Kotetsu, of Aizu.
My home is in Sannomiya,
south of Shomen.
I won't run or hide.
I'd rather you... gave up
this profession.
All right?
NEXT SPRING, THE NAME
OF THE ERA CHANGES...
TO GENJI (1864) NEXT SPRING,
THE NAME OF THE ERA CHANGES...
TO GENJI (1864)
The masseur...
JUNE
Are you relieved that
Shinbei's the masseur?
No, I mean the inn, Ikeda-ya...
Ah... Around Same.
- He said he can't earn much there.
- Why is that?
That inn is busy with
samurai these days.
Whenever he's called there,
the customer will have...
visitors who are Ronins or associates,
and say "Excuse me,"
then leave the room to
meet them while he waits.
As soon as the customer returns,
another visitor shows up.
The visitor leaves and he starts
his massage, then another one shows up.
Difficult to make money...
Do you know where these samurai
come from?
From Choshu and Higo and...
Tosa and also a bit of
Himeji dialect...
Senkichi-san, if we head south from
this Togetsukyo Bridge,
past Koke-dera Temple,
Matsuo, and Katsura,
the road leads all the way
down to Osaka.
Senkichi-san...
Take me back to Osaka.
Let's go back together.
Right now.
Tomi-chan!
Or will you take this story...
back to Kyoto,
to alarm the Shinsengumi?
What's your choice?
Senkichi-san, do you love me?
Or hate me?
Tell me now!
I like you.
I like you, but... See?
Answer me!
THE SAME DAY
JUNE 5, 1864
IKEDA-YA INN
- Wait!
- Out of the way!
Why...
Why?
Orin...
I've given my best for
every one of them...
That's the only way I know.
For you,
for Aguri-chan,
for Tomi-chan...
and for this woman.
And yet...
Why?
Orin, the war broke out,
JULY 19, 1864, AT DAWN
JULY 19,1864, AT DAWN triggered by the
Ikeda-ya Incident, the attack of Choshu.
triggered by the Ikeda-ya Incident,
the attack of Choshu.
The enemy sneaked up on Saga
and rushed into the city.
They attacked the Hamaguri-gomon gate
of the Imperial Palace.
Damn it!
The Palace is in danger!
The Shinsengumi are heading
back to Kyoto!
Gather around, Shinsengumi!
We're going back to Kyoto!
Kondo-san...
Are you planning to fight
in the middle of the city?
That's where the enemy is.
We have to fight. This is war.
What about Kyoto?
What about the people living there?
Is that friendship?
Would a friend do that?
Kotetsu-kun, both you
and us bet on Aizu.
That is, on the Tokugawa Shogunate.
We must annihilate its enemies.
That's all there is right now.
Let's go!
An incident later known as
the Hamaguri Rebellion,
the origin of Kyoto's
Dondon-yam
Dondon-yam In Kyoto
Oyabun!
Where's Oyabun?
lroha! Ueba!
Heikichi! Inosuke!
Sanjo
Orin.
My bet...
I might have lost it...
Senkichi-san.
Gionmachi was intact. Come!
With your precious...
If Kotaro,
Kumagoro, Inosuke,
and that kid Heikichi...
were all safe, they would
come back here.
I have to wait for them.
- You insist?
- But...
Thank you, Tomi-chan.
Really.
I mean it.
You know what, Tomi-chan?
When I saw your face,
I had this thought...
You know that I bet on
the Ogaki-ya?
The Ogaki-ya bet on
the Lord of Aizu.
The Lord of Aizu bet on
the Shogunate.
That's why I bet on
the Shogunate...
Somethings... wrong here.
I have to bet on
my precious someone.
And that...
my precious someone is...
Orin.
Is that you, Orin?
- Need some water?
- Senkichi...
Water!
There's water here!
Senkichi-san! Don't!
Where's the bucket?
There go the Shinsengumi!
Oyabun!
Oyabun.
Kotetsu-kun.
Oyabun!
I got it.
Orin!
I will bet, once again!
THE END Subtitles
revised/retimed by lordretsudo