Dr. Muhammad Awais Amin
Nimbus Film presents
A Nimbus Film/Wuste Filmproduktion
Wuste Film Ost/Studio Babelsberg
production
Based on actual events
Do you remember
when they arrived?
April 9th?
I think you do.
Everybody does.
All of a sudden
they were everywhere.
The Gestapo,
The Wehrmacht, Abwehr, SS.
All the German corps.
German Nazis.
Danish Nazis.
They came out of the dark.
They had been
awaiting the day.
Did you go outside and watch?
What were you thinking?
Flame & Lemon
A film by
Ole Christian Madsen
North of Copenhagen, May 1 944
Act with determination.
Execute your plan.
If you stay calm,
no one will suspect a thing.
People will only be looking
at the dead.
At nothing else.
They won't see you leaving.
They won 't remember you...
...at all.
I know I'm doing the right thing.
It's the only right thing.
You see?
Yes...
Lieutenant Ostergaard Petersen
Yes?
Flowers from
Dagmarhus headquarters.
- Ostergard Petersen?
- That's correct.
Shall I sign for them?
No.
You often asked me why.
Why we do this.
Why?
- Don't provoke them.
- Sure.
One good reason:
The Schalburg Corps.
Good morning.
Papers.
No, I don't think so...
Have you seen any papers?
Danes in German uniforms.
Traitors.
Some are experienced soldiers
from the Eastern Front.
Brutal bastards.
Impossible to get close to.
Always in groups.
They are... vermin.
Go!.
The ambulance people help us.
The police help us.
Everyone who 's not afraid
helps us.
Editor Gaust
They've raised the reward.
1 0,000.
- For the both of us?
- Just you.
- What do they know?
- They know you're a redhead.
Get your hair dyed, Bent.
Or wear a hat.
- A hat?
- Or a cap, if you prefer.
That's him.
Another good reason:
Nazi editors who spew their
propaganda through newspapers.
Editor Gaust?
Each has his own reasons.
On the 9th of April Jorgen watches
as the Germans march into the city.
Endless rows of soldiers
make his stomach turn.
He feels sick.
A feeling that persists.
Right up until that day last summer,
when he enters a radio store.
In the back room they were printing
illegal flyers,
and at long last Jorgen meets
like-minded people.
And before long they're involved
in underground activities.
Now Jorgen and a few others
are the only ones left.
Everybody else either fled,
got beaten to a pulp in jail or died.
Shot at the pole.
But Jorgen...
Jorgen persisted.
Smuggling British pilots at night.
Getting explosives to the saboteurs.
He 's eating pills
to stay awake.
Procuring weapons.
Everything.
And he rides with me.
Time?
1 1.25 p. m.
Shot through the back of the head.
Aksel Winther is a police solicitor.
He has access to all the confidential
channels at police HQ.
He is in contact with the British and
gets his orders directly from them.
Last autumn he helped the Jews
flee the country.
Without him there was nothing.
Our chain of command
is quite clear.
- I didn't authorise killing Gaust.
- We assessed that it was safe.
- And we were in the neighbourhood.
- Really?
A signature
for the big shots in Stockholm.
- Some things are on the way.
- What things?
Things that require discretion,
and the utmost discipline.
- You'll like it.
- With Winther...
- It's big.
-...it's always big.
Mother country.
Who else would celebrate three killings
in a place swarming with Germans.
That requires code.
There aren't many of us,
and it's hard to tell who does what.
Once in a while we get together,
but we usually work alone.
That's Bob, a veteran
from the Winter War in Finland.
The schoolteacher called Brains,
expert at getting information.
Big Bear, expert with the ladies.
Always ready to party.
And Little Bear,
great with weapons.
Rumour has it that if they shoot
the man, they also shoot his wife.
The wine merchant sells information
to both us and the Germans.
The Banana, former boxer who
takes part in every operation he can.
Carl, a timid fellow,
but tough if need be.
Heinrich and Teddy, students,
the youngest of us.
Slim, he talks and talks
and never stops. Always about food.
Cap, previously a nun in Belgium.
Has her own group in Kastrup.
The Banana considers it his job
to protect her.
And Jorgen, my friend.
We've been through this.
Stay clear of him.
Karl Heinz Hoffmann.
Head of the Gestapo.
He's the one hounding us.
Hoffmann wants to see you.
Make no mistake.
He's the biggest mass murderer
Denmark has ever seen.
But you already know that.
May I offer you a drink?
Pardon my manners.
Svend Christensen, police detective.
- And your name?
- Ketty Selmer.
- Cheers, Svend Christensen.
- Cheers.
Very nice.
You're married?
Yes.
- I haven't seen you here before.
- I don't come here often. I travel.
- What do you do?
- Fashion design and photography.
I just did a shoot
for Women of the Times.
- Who are you?
- Thank you for the wine.
I asked you a question.
You ask too many questions.
Goodbye, Bent.
"Goodbye, Bent."
Maybe one of the boys said too much.
They would never say my name.
There she is!
Bent, it's a Kraut hotel.
It's crawling with them.
- I'm going in.
- Okay.
If you're not back in half an hour,
I'm going in after you.
Yes.
ClD.
Ketty Selmer?
Nordland Hotel, Vesterbrogade,
Copenhagen
What do you want?
May I come in?
Who do you know?
I design and photograph fashion.
Look.
- Why did you call me Bent?
- It's your name, isn't it?
What do you really do?
- I can't tell you.
- You'll have to.
I'm a courier.
Stockholm-Copenhagen.
I carry letters.
I know the wine merchant.
The wine merchant?
He merely passes on information.
He's just a go-between.
You don't work for a go-between.
I also know Winther.
What do you do for Winther?
You know I can't tell you.
- And that's not why you're here.
- It isn't?
You had something else
in mind.
I don't sleep with married women.
My husband is gay.
My marriage is pure pro forma. He's
Swedish, so I can go back and forth.
Are you attracted to me?
Yes.
Why?
Because you're beautiful.
How old are you?
I'm 23.
Why?
You're young.
Age matters.
Now, leave.
- Ketty Selmer, is that your real name?
- Yes, of course. Why not?
Now, go.
This is my landlady, Lis.
And her husband, Helmer.
This is where I live.
In their basement.
It's a good place.
A good place to wait in.
That's how it is.
Most of my time is spent waiting.
This is Horst Ernst Gilbert, colonel
and editor at Scandinavian Telegrams,
where he spews
German propaganda.
Political refugee. In reality he's
a highly placed spy in the Abwehr.
Closest collaborator is
Hermann Seibold.
SS-Obersturmbannfuhrer.
Head of agents in Scandinavia.
And lastly,
Mrs Elisabeth Lorentzen.
An author. Highly placed in
the Abwehr and a secretary to Gilbert.
Care for some pastry?
And it's real coffee.
- They're Germans?
- German spies!
Yes, but Germans nonetheless.
But the Liberation Council issued
a ban on liquidation of Germans?
It's more of a recommendation.
One that we do not follow.
It's a British order. London wants
Abwehr extinguished in Scandinavia.
Did I get it all wrong?
Isn't our job to eliminate
Danish informers and Nazis?
Yes, but you're in Special Forces,
and you'll do as you are told!
Fine.
- How about you, Bent?
- Perfect.
- But I don't shoot women.
- You don't?
Then you'll do it, Citron.
Or do you also have
a problem with women?
No, I don't.
So, we're shooting
high-ranking German officers.
Then let's get Hoffmann.
We would paralyse the Gestapo.
- There are no orders to that effect.
- You can give it.
No, I can't.
And I won't!
Stay away from Hoffmann,
the both of you!
Bent, don't get caught up
in a conversation with Gilbert.
He has a powerful personality
and a great... spiritual potential.
- Knock on the door and shoot him!
- Yes.
Good evening, Nielsen.
I met a woman last night.
Ketty Selmer.
Did you, now?
Stay away from her.
- Waiting for me?
- Yes.
What do you want?
I need to know
how you know my name.
- Someone must have let it slip.
- Yes, the question is who.
Don't worry.
We're on the same side.
We are?
Is it Winther?
Don't ask me about that
or anything else.
Don't come here again.
It's the last thing I need.
Good night.
I was to shoot this woman.
The one who turned in Finn.
I ran up the stairs.
Knocked on the door.
She opened it.
I was about to pull the trigger...
But somehow she managed to tell me
that she wasn't an informer.
She only informed on him
because he'd abandoned her.
He had promised to marry her,
but he was already married.
She was just a lonely hurt woman.
She stood there
staring right at me.
And I couldn't pull the trigger.
She cried and cried...
I just couldn't.
I wet my pants and ran off.
The following week
she turned in two more.
I swore it would never happen again.
Why couldn't you do it?
I forgot that we're not killing people,
but Nazis.
This one is all yours, Jorgen.
We have to get going.
If you're not back in five minutes,
I'm going in.
Ready?
Editor
Horst Ernst Gilbert
I couldn't do it!
I only got her in the shoulder.
I've never killed before, Bent.
I'm sorry.
- Who are you?
- This is from Police Solicitor Winther.
Legal documents.
- May I see your badge?
- Yes, of course.
One must be cautious these days.
My husband is resting.
Would you like some tea?
"Thank you, Budjonny."
The famous Soviet general.
I educated him myself, Mr...?
Christensen.
Svend Christensen.
After the First World War many officers
tried their luck in the Red Army.
Germany was
destroyed and impoverished.
The Russian officers,
who now fight the German army,
were trained by us.
But I suppose you knew that.
You're here on behalf of
my friend Winther?
Yes, I was to deliver
these documents to you.
Thank you.
Is something wrong with your hand?
Your German is very good,
Mr Christensen.
Thank you.
I used to live in Germany.
My father sent me there.
You're in the resistance.
Well, you're here on behalf of Winther.
Don't be alarmed.
I have no sympathy for Hitler
or the National Socialists.
- You swore allegiance to Der Fuhrer.
- That is a matter for my conscience.
You are a partisan.
That's very interesting.
A soldier without a front.
Are you a good soldier?
Are you prepared to pay the price?
- What price?
- What do you think?
Your life.
You see, there can be only
three reasons for fighting in a war.
Firstly, career opportunity.
It's widespread but does not
produce good soldiers.
You have a fear of dying
and only think of peace.
Secondly, ideology.
Love of the mother country.
That is much more intriguing,
but the dreamer breaks down.
He doesn't have the strength.
He's shallow.
The frivolous and presumptuous nature
of youth.
Unless he's passionate.
Fanatical, if you will.
That makes
for a good soldier.
- And thirdly?
- Hatred of your enemy.
Hate seduces you
into doing things...
you never thought
yourself capable of.
Unless the hatred is caused by
a personal neurosis.
What are you saying?
The neurotic is intelligent
and he has doubts.
If he is betrayed,
his hatred fades,
and doubt sets in.
War does nothing
for the neurotic.
The gentle loving father
is not to be found in war.
Your cause, Christensen,
is legitimate.
Now you must become
a good soldier.
Leaving already?
I suppose it had to come to this.
You're making a big mistake.
Our Father, who art in heaven...
Hallowed be thy Name...
Something's not right.
- What happened?
- Drive!
Hermann Seibold
Stop it.
Easy, now. Breathe.
Bent, you'll be taken
to a private clinic.
When you get an order,
you follow it!
Do you understand?
It's not optional!
- Yes, but Seibold was tough.
- Of course, he's a trained soldier!
Mrs Lorentzen is dead,
and Seibold is wounded.
One out of three
isn't good enough.
Then do it yourself next time.
I'll choose to ignore that.
I was quite clear about Gilbert.
- He's not a Nazi. He admires us.
- You think so?
He'd say anything
to get off the hook.
Gilbert is insanely intelligent.
He knew you were coming.
He played you.
He's been laughing at you all day.
He called up Hoffmann
and they had a laugh!
It won't happen again.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry...
Just make sure
you survive.
I'm meeting Hoffmann in half an hour.
Bent left the documents at Gilbert's.
Hoffmann wants an explanation.
Jorgen...
There's someone to see you.
- Where's Anne?
- Right outside.
We've been looking for you.
You said you'd pick us up.
This is from you.
It's the book she wanted.
- But it's on Monday.
- It's today.
Shall we celebrate?
We usually do.
We can't afford to celebrate.
You bring home nothing,
and my father won't help out,
as long as I'm married to you.
Wait.
Lend me some money.
Come on.
Cough up.
It's my daughter's birthday.
There's that Nazi grocer.
He's loaded with cash.
I'm not a criminal.
Stay away from him.
Little Bear, you too.
Go out and play
with your new yoyo.
I'm sorry.
She's learned how to whistle?
A lot has happened.
I don't know
if I can take this anymore.
Do you understand?
- Bodil, I...
- I'm not going to Sweden!
You have to.
- It's safer.
- We're safe here.
I can't visit you here.
In Sweden I can.
I love you.
It's the war.
This has nothing to do with the war.
You weren't home before either.
I sat waiting then, too.
It has nothing to do with that.
You're not cut out for it, that's all.
You're just not that kind of man.
Stockholm, 3 weeks later
- Are they coming?
- I assume so.
- They're your men, you should know.
- I should, but I don't.
Finally.
Spex from
Danish Army intelligence.
- Flame, Citron.
- Welcome to Stockholm.
Thanks.
Welcome.
Three days ago the Gestapo retaliated
for the attacks on German officers.
Stopped a streetcar and threw eight
hand-grenades at the 29 passengers.
You can imagine the consequences.
If not, then look at the file.
The Gestapo threatens to repeat it,
if the attacks persist.
Pure terror.
Terror that could've been avoided, if
you hadn't started attacking Germans.
I don't know what you mean.
Maybe you can make Hoffmann
believe that your hands are clean,
but we know that you ordered
the assassinations of Gilbert,
Mrs Lorentzen
and Seibold.
I still don't know
what you're talking about.
I act on direct orders
from the British Command.
- And I don't answer to anyone else.
- What the hell are you talking about?
- Are you kidding me?
- What's this about?
This is an order: There will be no
retaliation for the streetcar incident.
All killings, all sabotage
will cease immediately.
The Communist groups
have received identical orders.
We need 50,000 armed men
ready to ambush the Germans,
on the day the Allied Forces land
on the west coast. This is big.
We need peace to establish
these covert groups.
And I need to listen to the 29 victims.
They say only one thing:
Revenge.
From your time in the army,
Mr Faurschou-Hviid...
Leave us!
You must know the consequences
of wartime disobedience.
- Is that a threat?
- Read it as you wish.
We're preparing a big military
operation and neither we
nor the British want it disrupted
by random civilian resistance.
Our goal is to win the peace,
not escalate the war.
I follow standing orders.
- Such as executing Gilbert?
- Among others.
I'll personally call London
and find out who you work for.
Until then you follow my orders.
Is that clear?
- The mother country.
- Yes?
- It's Winther.
Spex is clueless. He thinks he can
run everything from Stockholm.
Are they following us?
- Yes.
- Spex' people?
Spex is a moron. It's the Swedish
Intelligence, SAPO. They're worried.
- About what?
- That you'll shoot someone here.
They don't want trouble
with their German friends.
You're quite famous here.
- Thank you.
- It'll be hard to get close to Gilbert.
The Gestapo has him covered.
He has two guards at all times.
I'll be ready in two weeks.
To do whatever you decide.
- London wants action now.
- Now?
Gilbert is expanding.
He's turning into a serious threat.
- Can the Bears do it?
- They're too noisy.
This requires precision,
discretion and a minimum of brains.
Maybe I can shoot him from the car.
If we can get close enough.
- Too risky.
- Let me. I'll do it.
Don't, Jorgen.
Let's drink to Jorgen.
Cheers!
We're closed.
Alright, what can I do for you?
Do you want to live?
You Nazi pig.
Fill it up.
Eggs, flour, yeast, sugar...
Whatever you have.
I see you have real coffee
for your friends in the party.
Nice apples...
- Is this real chocolate?
- Yes.
What the hell is that?
What the hell do you take me for?
Someone who steals your money?
Do you think I'm a thief?
- Are you calling me a thief?
- I'm sorry...
Thank you...
- Hello, Jorgen.
- Hello.
- You're home late.
- Yes.
Hey, sweetie.
Look, what Dad bought for you.
- Isn't it pretty?
- Thank you.
And a few dresses...
And this is for you.
It should last you for a few days.
Thank you.
Anne, go put on your pyjamas.
I'll be right there to tuck you in.
Jorgen,
I have to tell you something.
I met someone.
Are you listening to me?
It shouldn't have happened.
But it did.
I'm so sorry.
Jorgen.
Please don't...
- Who is it?
- That's not important.
- But who is it?
- You don't know him.
Who is it?!
Answer me, damn it.
Who is it?
Are you afraid of me?
Why would you be afraid of me?
I never hurt you.
Did I ever hurt you?
You'll kill him.
If I tell you, you'll kill him.
It's the only thing you...
Why do you say that?
Why?
It's not true.
Why do you say that?
I love you.
Where did you go?
I just...
I had to...
- Can I try that?
- Of course.
It's more efficient
if you fire single shots.
Aksel asked
if you want to go to Sweden.
- To calm your nerves.
- Did he, now?
- Tell him my nerves are fine.
- Keep it, Jorgen.
I'll get another.
- Thank you.
- Don't mention it.
We can bring it to Japan.
When we're done with the Germans.
We can go to Japan
with the Americans.
- Flame and Citron in Japan?
- Exactly.
- And after that?
- I don't think there is an "after".
Not here. Not for us.
I think we have to move on.
Get up! Come on.
Up!
Get up!
Mother country!
A short while ago the Gestapo
executed three of our men.
Bob, Carl and the school teacher
were all shot at Dagmarhus.
There's an informer in our midst.
They were turned in, for sure.
And an hour ago there were
eight executions at Ryvangen.
Our contact in Dagmarhus says
eight more will be shot tonight.
Hoffmann is striking back
for Gilbert.
The Communists took the opportunity
to sabotage The Rifle Syndicate, inc.
And the Schalburg Corps
just bombed the Tivoli Gardens.
Everything points to more retaliation
and more executions.
Let's have a moment's silence
in memory of our fallen friends.
Soren, are you a bigamist?
What?
Do you get into bed with others?
No. Hell, no.
I'd never do that.
They were my friends.
We served in Finland together.
- Friends inform on friends.
- Shall I shoot him?
- I don't know yet.
- I'm not the one, damn it!
What really happened
at Cafe Lauritz Betjent?
We were celebrating
the invasion of France.
We were at the bar.
Me, Little Bear and Big Bear.
We turn around and see
that Bob, Carl and Brains
are surrounded by Gestapo men.
What could we do...
...other than sneak off?
What say the Bears?
He's telling the truth.
About Cafe Lauritz Betjent.
That's what happened.
Alright, Soren. I'm sorry.
But you know how it is.
Yes.
I know how it is.
I need time, but I'll find the informer.
Keep a low profile.
Vesterbro's in uproar,
so stay clear.
Where were you?
Where were you,
when the uprising started?
Where were you on June 26th
when Copenhagen resisted?
At long last people had had enough.
At long last they're
doing something.
It's getting close.
Real war.
Already, 32 have fallen,
and it's only just begun.
The Communists are fighting.
But we 're just waiting.
Hello, Ketty.
How did you get in?
Today's my birthday.
And so?
Do you expect me to sing for you?
No. I want to take you to dinner.
- Who sent you?
- No one.
Hoffmann just named you
the number one enemy of Germany.
He raised the reward to 20,000
and you break into my room?
The city is in uproar,
and you want to go out for dinner?
- Have you lost your mind?
- Alright, I'm sorry. I'll leave.
You should take care.
Cover your hair.
Here.
- What did you do before the war?
- Various things.
- At one point I was a dancer.
- A dancer?
Where?
At the Apollo.
It was fun.
It wasn't proper, but it was fun.
And I met a lot of people.
That's how I met Winther.
Winther has helped me
a great deal.
- He got me a place to stay and a job.
- He's a great man.
- Do you think so?
- Yes.
- Why do you do it?
- Do what?
Kill so many people.
- Someone has to.
- But why kill at all?
What else can you do?
My father sent me
to Germany in 1 940,
to train as a waiter
and a chef.
The hotel manager was a Nazi.
The chef was a Nazi.
Several of the waiters were Nazis.
I served Nazis every day.
Everywhere.
One of the girls at the hotel
was Jewish, but no one knew.
She kept it secret.
But the chef found out.
He turned her in.
She was beaten to a pulp
before the police came after her.
I don't want that to happen here.
Sabotage makes no difference.
The only thing you can do
is eliminate them. One by one.
Down to the last one.
Was she your girlfriend?
What happened to her?
- And you?
- I don't know.
The war came as a relief to me.
Finally I could do something.
Something right.
I stopped dancing
and started working for Winther.
Conveying letters. Procuring
information and passing it on.
It was fun in the beginning.
But it's different now.
Everything is grey.
I think I just want to survive.
Do you know what I think?
I think we should get out of here.
You have to promise me something.
Don't ever use me for information.
Don't ask me for anything like that.
Don't let that come between us.
- Will you promise me that?
- Yes.
I just wish this war would end.
Why can't I get out of this?
I wish I could leave
and never return.
Where would you go?
To Stockholm.
The war will last
for a good while still.
- But don't be afraid.
- No?
I'll look out for you.
- You will?
- Yes.
My name is Jorgen.
Do you have a minute?
What's your name?
Morten.
I want you to take good care
of my wife and daughter.
- Yes.
- Do you have a job?
- Are you making any money?
- Yes.
Morten, be good to my daughter.
Be very good to her.
If I hear any different...
...I'll be back.
- Is that understood?
- Yes.
One coffee.
You've gotten yourself a hat.
That's good.
- The reward is now 20,000.
- I know.
That could tempt anybody.
Smart move on Hoffmann's part.
- I want an order to shoot him.
- You won't get it.
I have something else for you.
I found the informer.
Unfortunately it's one of us.
Mrs Ketty Selmer Sjoberg.
She is to be liquidated
immediately.
- You're mistaken.
- I am?
I know her.
She's a courier.
- A former dance girl.
- I know all about Ketty.
She's my courier.
She knows everything.
If we don't strike now,
we'll all be shot.
Then why hasn't she
informed on Bent?
Why inform on Carl and Brains,
when Bent will get her 20,000?
You should ask Bent about that.
She's a double agent.
Not loyal to anyone.
Hoffmann cornered her,
and she provided him with information.
And now she's in too deep.
Do you want me to do it?
No.
CONFIDENTIAL
Bent?
What are you doing here?
It's lovely to see you.
Sit down.
Who do you work for?
- Winther, of course.
- Try again.
- Who asked you to draw me?
- No one.
Then why that one?
I was thinking about you.
How come you frequent Dagmarhus?
I need visas.
So that I can travel.
Look.
- Look, visa.
- Who do you work for?
- I can't tell you.
I work for Army Intelligence.
And for Winther.
I traffic documents.
And do different jobs for them.
I follow orders, like you.
You turned them in.
Didn't you?
Why did you turn them in?
- Why did you turn them in?
- What is this?
- How much did they pay you?
- Who's been saying that?
Is it Winther?
He's a swindler.
A thorough scoundrel.
Watch your mouth.
He's under London orders.
- London? They never wanted him.
- That's not true!
- He receives orders.
- Yes, but not from the British!
Let me show you something.
These are all copies of contracts
that Winther made with Gilbert.
I keep copies in Stockholm.
Winther was legal adviser to Gilbert
for years.
They did business together
and made a lot of money.
Serious money, Bent!
But Winther must have realised
that it would be considered treason.
Gilbert was after all
a high-ranking German officer.
So after the war, Winther would be
facing charges of collaboration.
And his close relationship with
Seibold would also be scrutinised.
He would be sent to jail.
This was his only way out.
He had to get rid of them.
Both Gilbert and Seibold.
And he used you.
- They're forgeries.
- No, the documents are genuine.
He's nothing but a gangster.
I know too much, and I have proof.
- So now I'm to be shot too.
- They were German spies.
German spies?
No, Gilbert and Mrs Lorentzen
were in the German resistance.
Seibold was a spy.
But you never got him, did you?
Gilbert was an expert at manipulation,
and he had Gestapo bodyguards...
They weren't bodyguards.
Gilbert was under house arrest,
suspected of anti-Nazi activity.
If Hoffmann wanted to protect Gilbert,
you'd never have gotten that close.
Do you think Hoffmann
cries over Gilbert's death?
- No, you did him a favor.
- And Mrs Lorentzen?
She was Gilbert's secretary
and knew of his deals with Winther.
She was also involved
in the opposition to Hitler,
but more than that she was just
a sweet lady caught between two men.
And Winther...?
Does Winther work for the Gestapo?
No, he just erases his own tracks.
- Is Winther here?
- Winther has escaped to Stockholm.
They've unravelled it all.
Get out!
He was right.
Winther has disappeared. He ran for it.
We've been shooting
innocent people.
Aksel never worked for the British.
Anybody who knew anything
was shot.
- Shut up.
- Only Ketty was left.
- We've shot innocent...
- Shut the hell up!
Shut up!
I sure as hell
didn't kill innocent people.
I shot a German officer,
and a German officer is not innocent.
You come here and tell me he was
in the resistance. Are you stupid?
Winther! What did you expect?
That's rich people for you!
In a nutshell!
They're greedy and full of shit.
You should have shot her
when you had the chance.
What are you saying?
- She's fucking with your brain.
- Watch out!
A girl knows your real name, you fuck
her and "bam", she's an oracle.
- Shut up!
- I'll say what I like.
And I never killed innocent people,
do you hear me?
Why didn't I see it?
Why didn't I see it happening?
He's in Stockholm,
while we're being hounded
by the Gestapo.
Is that justice?
There is no just or unjust any longer.
There is war.
We choose our own targets
and go after them.
- Hoffmann.
- Yes.
Come on...
Go, guys.
- Easy now.
- Where is he?
- In the back.
Flame?
I have a proposal for you.
You leave this place and so do l.
I suspend the hunt for you
for 24 hours.
Go to Sweden and stay there till
the war is over, and this conversation...
...never took place.
Have you considered
the consequences?
If you kill the head of the Gestapo.
- Do you want to survive the war?
- I'll survive.
That would surprise me.
Surviving is not in your character.
You're a fanatic, a terrorist.
They always die.
Tell me...
Do you really think you make
a difference with all your shooting?
Don't you realise you're just a tool
for someone with less pure motives?
I thought you were in charge
of all these courageous activities.
But it was Mr Winther.
How could you take him seriously?
He's so untrustworthy.
And now you want to take over.
You're angry and hurt, and now
the Gestapo chief must die. Why?
What will that change?
We're the same.
I love Denmark.
You love Denmark.
The beautiful landscapes
of North Zealand.
Why don't we cooperate?
You're right. The National Socialist
idea is fine but impossible.
Far too many emotions.
Like an infatuation.
See what that idea
has done to the world.
But think of me
as an opportunity.
I have given up on my ideals.
I must survive.
And I want you to survive, too.
What do you say?
I understand.
Fine.
On three.
One.
Two.
Here come the police,
or what's even worse for you,
German soldiers.
Do you plan to stay here
until you're surrounded?
What happened?
- You got my message?
- Yes.
- You didn't come alone.
- Neither did you.
It's Spex.
He doesn't trust you.
I have a message,
and I'm to return with your answer.
There's a meeting in Stockholm
the day after tomorrow at 1 0.
- What do they want?
- I don't know.
Who'll be there?
Spex and someone
from the Liberation Council,
and Winther.
- Aksel?
- Yes.
He's been white-washed.
I won't be there.
You should, Bent.
You should go and hear
what they have to say.
It's important.
I asked to be the one
to tell you.
I wanted to see you.
- To see that you were okay.
- I'm fine.
I'll let them know
you'll be there.
- Gentlemen.
- You're back with Winther?
No, we're military now.
They pay well.
I'm afraid we have to
confiscate your equipment.
It's an honour.
I represent the Liberation Council.
They call me Raven.
You know Spex
and Aksel Winther.
The Police Solicitor represents
the American Forces.
Interesting.
I'd like to start the meeting
with some good news.
We're on the verge of a breakthrough
in negotiations with the Germans.
Regarding putting an end
to the insurrection.
It's a great victory for the people.
The curfew will be suspended.
- The Schalburg Corps withdraws...
- If both sides stay calm.
Are you paying attention?
Is everyone here aware of
what the Police Solicitor has done?
He's been ordering us to liquidate
innocent people. Old friends.
- People who got in his way.
- What the hell are you saying?
Who's done more to have Denmark
be recognised by the Allied Forces?
- What old friends, Flame?
- Gilbert, German resistance man.
- Ketty Selmer, Danish courier.
- German resistance man?
My boy. The Allied don't recognise
any German resistance.
It simply doesn't exist.
The incident with Mrs Selmer was
a mistake and has been explained.
A simple misunderstanding...
A misunderstanding... I'm sorry.
A misunderstanding?
And in a minute
when I shoot you...
...it's just a mistake.
Can we agree on that?
I...
...admire you, Flame.
But war can be confusing,
as you well know.
All sorts of information
flies all over the place.
The sensible thing is,
to keep your calm.
The Liberation Council knows of
no liquidations of innocent people,
so with your permission,
maybe we can proceed
with this meeting.
- Are you a Communist, Faurschou?
- No.
How would you feel about
a commission?
You'll command 1 0,000 men
in the waiting groups in Copenhagen.
Rank of Captain.
Captain! There you go, Bent!
Imagine that.
Either you'll fight alongside
the British, if the Germans resist,
or you will be fighting against
the Red Army, if it arrives first.
It's about the survival of democracy,
and we'd like to use your name.
- My name? How so?
- We will need heroes.
Heroes to talk about
in schools and associations.
Heroes for public speeches
to huge crowds,
conveying the unselfish and
sacrificing nature of the resistance.
Which you are both
excellent examples of.
- And Jorgen?
- Second-in-command. Lieutenant?
- What rank are you?
- Captain.
Then I also want to be a captain.
No, thanks.
We will no longer tolerate your acts
of random violence. It's unacceptable.
In wartime you kill
your adversaries.
I want Hoffmann.
Then we can talk commissions.
- Out of the question.
- I respect your stance.
But Hoffmann...
- Nothing good will come of it.
- We'll see.
We have other ways of stopping you.
I apologise on behalf of Spex.
That was uncalled for.
These files contain the name
of an informer in your organisation.
- Where are we going?
- Asserbo.
Accept this as a token
of our good intentions.
- Do you have a photo of him?
- No, only name and address.
- I have to pee.
- Me too.
I'm sorry.
And now what?
Now I go and see my dad.
- Has it been a long time?
- Three years.
Wait here.
Birkegaarden Hotel, Northern Sealand
Hello, Father.
A glass of wine?
- Why have you come?
- To see how my father's doing.
Let's not get carried away.
What do you want?
You have many German guests.
The guests choose the hotel,
not the other way around.
- I hear Hoffmann often stays here.
- Head of the Gestapo?
- I couldn't say.
- I would like to talk to him.
Apparently he's a pleasant man...
and intelligent.
And a murderer for the Nazis.
Yes, there is that.
- You always liked them.
- Them?
I admire the German culture and
all the wonderful things it's fostered.
But "them"?
No.
The war must be
a disappointment to you.
Aren't you listening?
I'm just trying to make ends meet.
But you're too young
to understand that.
And with your background
and brains,
you could have done better
than driving around shooting people.
But then again
you became a hero.
Listen.
If you talk well of me
to your Communist friends,
and promise not to shoot Hoffmann
at the hotel, I'll tell you what I know.
Do we have a deal?
Hoffmann comes here with his family
and his mistresses.
And with four bodyguards
at his side at all times.
I'm only told about his arrival
at the very last minute.
Army Intelligence asked me
to get close to him.
I'm merely following orders.
My dear Ketty. Thank you
for last night. You were enchanting.
Your laughter makes me so happy.
Yours sincerely, Karl Heinz.
You're on first name terms.
This is not about us.
It's bigger than that. My work requires
sacrifice. They ask me and I do it.
Did they ask you to sleep with me?
No, of course they didn't.
- You and me just happened.
- Really?
Listen, Bent.
Hoffmann means nothing to me.
You do!
Do you understand?
Now you'll tell me what car he drives
and his route to Dagmarhus.
- And the registration number.
- Don't ask me to do that.
You promised you wouldn't, Bent.
You promised.
Bent...
I love you.
Do you understand that?
This serves no one.
If I tell you...
...will you then come
to Stockholm with me?
We'll go to Stockholm
and never return.
Will you promise me that?
Promise me.
On odd weeks he drives
a small black Opel Kadett.
23 34 5.
And on even weeks a big Mercedes.
44 1 9 3.
The route is unpredictable.
Sometimes Roskildevej,
and other times Vigerslevvej.
It's not Hoffmann.
Oh, no...
You'll be okay.
You'll be fine.
Don't be afraid.
Dearest Bent.
Hoffmann is on to me.
I'm leaving for Stockholm now.
I hope and believe
that you will join me here.
He's dead.
He kept looking at me.
I held him in my arms,
and he kept looking at me.
I could tell that he wanted
to say something but...
...he wasn't able to.
He died before I got there.
Do you still have the police uniforms?
We'll go to Dagmarhus
and ask to see Hoffmann.
We have to.
We'll never get in. Even if we do,
we'll never get out again.
Come, come. Move on.
Next.
Come.
God dammit.
I thought we were rid of them.
Stop! Stop!
Out of the car!
Get out. Can't you hear?
On the ground!
Get into the truck!
Turn around!
Keep moving.
Get up.
Come on!
Faster!
Move!
These two at the end.
Up against the wall!
Against the wall.
Legs one metre apart!
- What's going on?
- They've taken the whole corps.
We're being sent
to a concentration camp.
- Do you have your Baby Browning?
- In my boots.
- And you?
- Yes.
In a second I'll jump the fence,
and you'll run.
See you, Bent.
Get back in line!
Get an ambulance!
Get him out of here!
Water.
- Water.
- Shut up!
- Give him some water!
It's in the back!
Safe house,
north of Copenhagen, October 1 944
How are you feeling?
I'm fine.
Too bad I have to get shot through
the lung to be looked after by you.
There.
- I'm going to jail, Marie.
- Jail?
- I don't think so.
- Yes.
I have to go to jail
for the things I've done.
When this is over...
Do you know what I've done?
No.
It'll be okay.
I'll be back tomorrow.
Watch out, Jorgen.
Oh, no, no...
Go to the basement.
Hurry up.
Open the door!
Can't you hear?
Open this door!
Flame?
Are you Flame?
Say something!
Get some milk!
Stop it!
What do you think you're doing?
Have you no sense of decency?
- Cover them up.
- Yes, sir!
The money order
for the 20,000 kroner reward.
You can cash it tomorrow.
We also found a letter
at his place.
It's for you.
Do you remember
when they arrived?
April 9th?
I think you do.
Everybody does.
I've been thinking
and thinking...
No matter what they say,
I don 't believe it was you.
You're not like that.
Where do we go after this?
When it's all over.
I don 't know.
Can we ever go back?
Can we ever go forward?
Perhaps.
Perhaps not.
At this moment there is only
The Flame.
After the Liberation, Flame and
Citron received a grand funeral.
In the days following the service
their coffins stood side by side.
A few months later Flame's father
passed away.
In 1 951 Citron was awarded the
US government's Medal of Freedom.
It was accepted by Citron's mother.
Flame received the same distinction.
Bodil fled to Sweden where she
gave birth to a daughter, Lone.
After the Liberation she settled
down in a house near Copenhagen,
where she and her daughters
lived alone for many years.
The fate of Citron impacted
the family throughout the years.
After Flame died,
Ketty Selmer moved to Stockholm.
She then settled down in Majorca,
where she died in the mid '90s.
She never spoke of Flame.