Subtitles by explosiveskull
www.OpenSubtitles.org
They
left their old world.
Left everything behind in
search for a land to call home.
But this land does
not belong to us.
We belong to the land.
They called us savages,
demonic creatures
who must be tamed.
They cut off our hair,
abolished our language,
stripped away our
faces, our oneness.
Kill the Indian, save
the man, they would say.
A new suit for every native
to be worn at all times,
even in death.
They captured a medicine man,
a powerful shaman
from the Hawea Tribe.
They chained him,
they tortured him,
they flayed his face.
With his last breath,
he placed a curse
on those chains.
A wicked curse.
A curse that spanned
through the ages.
A curse that sent
forth his spirit
to act in vengeance upon
those who held its chains.
I can't think
you enough, Billy.
Anything else?
Oh, that's off
limits over there.
That's for buyers.
It's just.
This is your stuff over here.
Thank you, Billy.
Have you talked to Moon?
I'm not there yet.
You've had plenty of time.
I have to be 100%.
You'll never be
100%, trust me.
Never stops ringing.
Steve.
Hey.
Yeah, it's a good one.
Its a nice piece, I know.
1939 Washman, I think.
Yeah.
You'll have to string
it up and find out.
I think she'll be good to go.
Okay, well, I guess let me
know when you want to come,
and I'll make sure it's all
out for you and ready to go.
You're welcome.
Hey, what's up?
It's River, I can't get
to the phone right now.
Just leave me a message.
I was gonna make something
that you really like
for dinner tonight.
Call me, please.
I need to talk to you.
Ow.
River?
River!
Work is a distraction
I need.
Work is a distraction I need.
Ow.
What is wrong with me?
Focus.
What are you doing?
I live here.
Not according to our records.
There was no mention of a sexy...
What, sexy what?
Listen, sister, you are
spreading God knows what
over a very sensitive
area right now.
And I would happily cuff
you and take you down...
Hey, you know, have
some respect, gentlemen.
She just lost her mother.
Hey, Moon.
Will you come with me please?
Hey, Bearman, remind me
again why you got suspended?
Was it when you broke
your suspect's collarbone,
or was it the two DUIs?
Or was it both?
It's not worth it.
Hey, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Control yourself,
Officer Forman.
I'm sorry, sir, they
were just harassing her.
You must be Moon.
The way you found
the body was...
Everything about
this is very unusual.
There is nothing unusual
about finding a junky
face down, dead.
I'm done.
River, please.
I swear to God, if you touch
me again, it'll take everyone
in this room to keep
me from killing you.
Will you please just tell
them what they need to know?
It'll make things easier.
I really need you
to keep an eye on her.
Absolutely, sir.
Detective.
What is it?
It's probably nothing,
but there's something
that reminds me of a
case from 20 years ago.
Just keep an eye on her.
Make sure she doesn't
go into to the garage.
- Yes, sir.
- I gotta take this.
Forman, when I get a chance,
I'm gonna take a look at the
files from that old case.
Let me know if
you need anything.
I could look too.
Stay
on this for now.
Yes, sir.
I hope you still like
it with three sugars.
You don't have to do this.
Yeah, well, according
to Gutierrez, I do.
Thanks.
Everyone's
cleared out for now.
I'll let you know if
anyone's gonna come by later.
Should I call your house line?
No, that line's disconnected.
Okay.
Well, seeing as how I
know you won't give me
your cell phone number,
here's what I'll do.
I'll drive up and down
with the sirens on,
and then I'll use the
horn and beep Morse code.
You know Morse code, right?
Hey, you know I still
have that ring that you...
646-555-0470.
What's that?
It's my cell.
That's only for emergencies.
That is all you.
Is there anything else I
can get you before I go?
Cleaning lady?
Yeah, I'll send mine over.
Hey, Moon.
It's good to see you.
Yo, what the...
Nice to meet you too.
You are unbelievable.
I'm just with my friends.
Have some respect for Mom.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, you have
no right talking about respect.
Okay, I'm not getting
high with my friends
and acting like
nothing happened.
I'm not high.
There is a law from like
1800-something that protects you
if you smoke weed
within like 24 hours
of when somebody dies.
I need to talk to you.
I'm right here.
Alone.
My friends can hear
what you have to say.
Don't act tough around them.
I'm not acting.
- Maybe you should.
- Really?
- Yeah.
- How?
Like an adult.
She got you, man.
You're not gonna
take that, are you?
No, he's not.
I'm not wasting
my time with you.
Look, can you please just
come out in the hall with me?
Don't let her control you.
You listen, little girl.
You might be the flavor of
the week, but if you say
one more thing to me, I
will kick your teeth in.
Oh, damn, is that how
they do in New York?
I thought you told us she
was like a poet or something.
I don't know what she is.
Well, I'm gonna grab a drink.
Anybody want anything?
I'll go with you.
Yeah, man, me too.
All this family time is
making me kind of thirsty.
Are you coming?
Let's give 'em a minute.
These are your friends?
Oh, I don't know, maybe I
didn't have a role model around
to help me figure that one out.
Oh, this isn't about us.
Nothing is!
Come with me.
- Where?
- Out there.
You can't, that's
a crime scene, man.
No crime occurred there.
All death is a crime,
think about that.
So deep.
Come on, let's go see it.
No, why?
It just happened,
and we knew her.
And I wanna see, come on.
I'm okay here.
The two of you suck.
Your problem is you
think everything was bad
when you were still here.
It was Candyland!
Every day I came home
expecting to find her dead!
I'm sorry you had to find her.
Who else would have?
Didn't you ever
think about that?
Look, all I'm asking is that
you help me clean the house
so that it can be
ready for the wake.
After that, I won't
expect anything else.
Everything's garbage,
just push it to the curb.
That's fine.
I still need you
to help me do it.
I've got driver's
ed, are you coming?
I'll drive.
Hector and Chrissie
need a ride too.
I'll drop them first.
Let's go.
River, please.
She's so lame.
Come on.
Come on, pick up the phone.
I figured you didn't eat.
No, I...
It's not much, it's
just rice and black beans.
My famous tortillas.
Okay, okay, okay, it's
just a little food.
People start crying
after they eat my beans.
Usually they're fightin'
for their lives,
sittin' on the toilet.
It smells incredible.
That was your mom's favorite.
I can see why.
Thank you, I'll
make it up to you.
Your being here is enough.
Listen, she was clean.
I don't think so.
I mean, maybe she was trying,
but not the way they found her.
She was trying.
Done.
When's the wake?
Tomorrow.
I just want to get
it out of the way.
I figured so.
I can't make it.
I got some buyers in Amarillo,
and I'll be gone for
about three days.
But when I come back,
you, and me, and River,
we're gonna go out.
It might just be me and you.
He hates you now, but
he'll do what I say.
At least he respects someone.
Respect, he just knows
I could kick his ass.
Don't worry about him,
he'll come around.
It's actually harder for him.
Thank you.
I love you, kid.
You call me if
anything comes up.
Everything's gonna be fine.
Now that you're here.
This is ridiculous.
It's not you.
I don't get why she
thinks she can come home.
You're not the only
one whose mom just died.
How could you even...
I know she's a bitch,
but she's going through the
exact same thing you are.
But.
You got a class.
In five minutes.
Do me a favor?
What?
Hold my bag.
I've got something in there
I don't want anyone to see.
You included.
Thank you.
Try to learn something.
Yeah, right.
Come on, where are you?
Whatever.
Once I saw the
truck jackknife,
I realized I had two seconds
to decide what I was gonna do.
So I hit that black ice,
went into an insane 720 spin,
narrowly avoiding being
splattered by that truck.
But that truck driver
wasn't as fortunate.
He snapped his neck right
when he hit that divider.
Any questions?
Miss Wright, am I
interrupting your work?
No, I heard
everything you said.
And what was that?
That you were a stunt
driver or cab driver
or something like that.
You better clean
up your attitude,
or you will be
repeating this class.
And I am the only
one who teaches it.
You can't do that.
There's no test.
All we need are the hours,
and we don't sign in with you.
So tell me, how could
I possibly repeat this?
This is mine.
You can't take that.
My room, my rules.
And I say you can't
have this thing in here.
Douchebag.
Quiet!
What was that, Miss Wright?
River.
River, hey, wake up.
What'd you take?
- Huh?
- What'd you take?
Nothing.
You can be honest with me
about what drugs you're taking.
I didn't.
Then why were you
passed out on the floor?
I think it might've
been the paint fumes.
Is this yours?
Yeah.
It sucks.
It just.
I don't know.
It just came to me.
It really sucks.
It's good.
I'll show you something good.
Hurry, come on.
Come on.
- Why?
- Shh.
Hey!
Hey, hey, I saw you two!
Stop right now or you'll
spend the rest of your day
on in-school
suspension tomorrow.
Come on, guys.
I know you went down here.
The building's about
to get locked up.
I know you're in here.
Hello?
Hello, hello?
If you guys are in here,
give yourselves up now.
Come on.
Okay, open your eyes.
Great magic trick.
After you, sir.
What
are we doing here?
Get inside.
Have a seat.
No, stupid, there.
So you're still not gonna
tell me why we're here?
Winning a bet.
Okay, that doesn't
tell me anything.
Put that on.
Here, really?
You're the boss.
I heard you two
come down here.
Look, if you come out
now, I won't report it.
You just gotta go home.
I heard you two laughing.
Look, I swear, if you two
jump out on me and give me
a heart attack, I have no
choice but to kill you.
Cut it out, guys.
What the hell?
Look.
I don't know who you are, but
you shouldn't be down here.
And the building's about
to close, so you should...
Are you hurt?
Sweetie, it's all right.
Really, everything's
gonna be okay.
Just come with me.
Please let me help you.
Oh God.
What was that?
The voices in your head.
Can we get out of here?
Sure, but first
that thing I gave you.
I'm gonna need it back.
What thing?
You can't be serious.
It's all yours.
Where did I put it?
River?
River, are you?
God.
Ugh, what is that smell?
Weird.
Oh God.
Oh, I can't believe
I'm doing this.
I will deal with you later.
Do you have a warrant?
Yeah, hold on.
Look, it's serious.
I tried calling.
I turned my phone
off, and then I lost it.
Oh, I'm so, so happy you
gave me your phone number.
Hey, I'm actually really
glad that you're here though.
Really?
Yeah, I need you to
help me clean a mouse
out of the workshop.
Oh, no, no, no, no, no.
No, nope.
What do you mean no?
That's not in my
job description.
Pretty, pretty please.
I can't.
I have a mouse thing.
But you're paid
to carry a gun.
Yeah, that's unrelated.
Look, it's just a mouse.
It's already dead.
And it's going to remain
dead wherever you found it.
Well, I know who not to
call when I'm in danger.
You don't even keep
your phone on you anyway.
Look, I need to speak to River.
- Is everything okay?
- I'm sorry.
I need to speak to him.
He's in his room, come on.
In his room, was it?
You two dating again?
Where the hell have you been?
I was robbing a jewelry store.
- River.
- Moon.
River, it's...
Do you love the
sound of my name?
You're just like Mom,
always saying my name.
Why weren't you here?
I could ask you
the same thing.
I'm talking about right now.
It's, what time is it?
It's 1:15.
That's way too late to be out.
I have no curfew.
Had no curfew.
What, you're staying?
If that's what it takes.
If that's what it takes
for what, me having a curfew?
Hey, I hate to interrupt
this family reunion,
but I really need to ask
him about his whereabouts
earlier tonight.
Ask away.
Have a seat.
I'm good here.
Where were you
at 6:45 tonight?
School.
Specifically.
The locker room.
More specifically.
What's going on?
Moon, please.
You know, there's
cameras in the hallway,
so I suggest you don't lie.
I was in the
boys' locker room.
Look, it was stupid,
but whatever.
I didn't do anything.
When was the last time
you saw Mr. Hamilton?
I didn't.
No?
No, not really.
I heard him because he
was chasing after us,
but he didn't catch us.
He...
He almost caught us in
the boys' locker room,
but he didn't.
So I guess I technically
saw him about five minutes
after he dismissed driver's ed.
What were you doing in
the boys' locker room?
Changing into my gym uniform.
Answer him.
I was having sex
with my girlfriend
in the gym teacher's office.
If you need proof
that I was there,
check the file cabinet
next to the door.
Top drawer, behind the folders.
It was a stupid bet Bethany
made with some girl.
What'd you leave there?
Something that would
prove I was there.
I don't know if you can test
semen for time of ejaculation,
but I'd say it was
around seven or so.
What'd you do afterwards?
Went to Hector's house.
Hector Solanos.
No, immediately after
you left the locker room.
You checked the cameras.
Look, officer, my little offense
of mine may be punishable
within the warped
context of school,
but I don't think you
need to involve yourself.
Mr. Hamilton was found dead
in the girls' locker room
around 7:30 tonight,
face down in the shower,
similar to how your
mother was found.
You think I killed him?
I hope it's just
a coincidence.
I didn't kill anybody.
I have to ask these questions.
I have no reason
to kill anybody.
Something is going on.
Feels that way,
but I'm not so sure.
I need you to just lay low
for the next couple of days.
Does this mean
I can cut school?
Yeah, but you didn't
hear that from me.
We have the wake
here tomorrow.
I know, I'm gonna clean.
You should help her.
It's not my mess.
Hey, River.
Look, you gotta watch out.
You don't want people to get
the wrong impression about you.
This?
All this for that organic
food project for health class.
She did not believe you.
I swear to God she did, man.
Oh my God, I wish my
mom was that stupid.
Yeah.
There were like Doritos
all over the place.
Isn't it crazy how there's like
a funeral going on outside?
It's a wake.
Yeah, man, same difference.
You mom was a special soul, man.
Like an angel without wings.
That was beautiful.
I have something for us.
Okay, close your eyes.
Everybody.
Okay, open your eyes.
What do you think?
Cool, man.
What is it?
Wow, you made this?
We needed something that
bonded us together.
For sure, man.
I'm never taking mine off ever.
Even if I take it off,
it's gonna be on, you know?
Here, will you
help me with mine?
The clasp is kinda tricky.
Thanks, Beth.
What do you think?
It's nice.
Just nice?
Really nice.
What's wrong?
I don't know.
Maybe I'm just thinking
about my dead mother.
Thanks.
Can you arrest all these people?
That bad, huh?
I don't know any of these
people, but I hate all of them.
Technically, it'll be
over in about an hour.
Yeah, they're not leaving.
Sorry, everyone.
I never figured out the
whole walking thing.
Where is the casket?
Come on, Hector.
Hey, you can't go.
I can't be here.
I can't let you leave,
not in this condition.
I haven't had anything.
What time is it?
A few minutes past four.
I was out the whole time?
Yeah, pretty much.
Well, you screamed,
you flew backwards,
and then you passed out.
- Great.
- Yeah.
Worked out perfectly.
Everyone left once
you passed out.
Except you.
You know, I was just
thinking maybe we could
go get some dinner somewhere.
It doesn't have to
be anything formal.
It's just a meal
between two old friends
who haven't seen each
other in seven years
and are still officially
boyfriend-girlfriend.
I'm breaking up with you.
That's good, that's good.
So what time am I picking
you up for dinner?
You're a stalker.
As far as the law's
concerned, I'm not.
How about nine?
Gotta make sure it's
okay with my wife.
Hey.
Can I tell you something
and have you not think
that I'm crazy?
Well, I already
think you're crazy,
but I won't think
you're any crazier.
Something really
strange has happened twice
since I've been back.
Strange.
Strange like your living
room being turned into
a rehab clinic.
That kind of strange.
Those aren't even the
worst of her friends either.
No.
I've been having visions.
Like what?
I don't know.
It happens so fast, and
it's not very clear.
But I saw someone being
dragged and tortured,
or at least it seems that way.
Well, it may just be a
combination of jet lag and stress.
I've been hearing noises too.
Well, you probably
shouldn't stay here.
Do you think that my mom's
death and that teacher's death
were too similar to
be a coincidence?
Well, if they're
not a coincidence,
unfortunately your
brother's the prime suspect.
He didn't do it.
Well, then they're
just a coincidence.
Look, I think the best thing
for you is just to relax
for the next few hours.
We'll go, we'll
get some good food,
take your mind off things,
and then we'll figure
it all out tomorrow.
Have there been any
other deaths like that?
I don't know, but I
could look into it for you.
Thank you.
Is there anything else I
can do for you before I go?
No, I'm fine, thanks.
Well, give me a call
if you need anything.
I will pick you up at nine.
Wait, Tyler,
sorry about earlier.
No, it's totally cool.
I'm happy it's officially over.
Now I can finally
start dating again.
Do I like this color?
So you're
talking to me from now on?
I gotta go.
Hello, can I help you?
The wake was a couple hours ago.
You speak English?
Hello, hello?
This is private property.
This isn't funny,
whatever you're doing.
Oh no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Come on, come on,
come on, don't die!
Oh yes.
Oh yes, yes, yes.
Yes, come on, come on.
Do you need anything?
Water, coffee, milk, juice?
Shh.
Oh, I got it, I got it.
It's not that bad.
You sure you want
a Band-Aid up here?
No, I guess not.
You're pretty good at this.
I had to learn.
Mom was always hurting herself.
I'm good with any cuts,
sprains, burns, or bruises.
Thanks.
What happened?
I don't know.
I think I saw something
that wasn't there.
It's all foggy.
It's gonna be for a while.
You hit your head pretty hard.
Yeah, I know.
Have you seen anything?
No.
I'm going crazy.
You're not.
I thought you were dead.
Wishful thinking?
No.
I mean, I still hate you and
I will never forgive you,
but I didn't want you dead.
I'm sorry.
I was a terrible sister.
You had to almost
die to realize that?
- I just...
- I'm kidding, I'm kidding.
I get it.
Honestly, I would've
done the same thing.
In about a year, I would've
shown up at your apartment
and squatted on your
couch for about 10 years.
Really?
Maybe.
10 years?
Undergrad and medical school.
Your grades are
good enough for that?
My friends are
stupid, I'm not.
Speaking of which, I
gotta meet them soon.
We have a project in US history,
and if it is a second late
we drop two letter grades.
But I don't want you to go.
I don't want them coming here.
You'll be okay?
I'm going out with Tyler.
What?
I didn't say a word.
Just be careful.
I don't have to
worry with him.
Never trust a guy who
always carries handcuffs.
Hey, just 'cause we talked
doesn't mean we're friends.
I know.
Hey, keep your phone on.
I don't even have your number.
Yes, you do.
Your code wasn't that
hard to figure out.
Don't worry, I didn't
look at anything else.
See you later.
Keep it on.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Hey.
I called a lot.
And I'm early.
No, I'm sorry, my phone was
on vibrate and I was out cold.
Oh.
It's meaningless.
Thank you.
And we're not
going anywhere fancy,
so you don't have to
get too dressed up.
Okay, just give
me one minute, okay?
And I mean it, the
flower means nothing.
I know, I already
flushed it down the toilet.
Excellent.
So how's it goin'?
- Almost done.
- Good.
'Cause I need you for something.
Give me a couple minutes.
That thing man.
I've got that thing.
This is like some other
world right here, man.
Something beyond everything
that you can't get in stores.
And how'd you get it?
Divine intervention.
You'll know what I mean
when you have a taste.
This stuff takes you
to the next dimension.
What is it?
I don't know.
It's got a couple
different names.
Well, can you
tell us one of them?
Like tequila but
more, so more, man.
Look, even the worm
can't handle this.
This needs something deadly.
Just like the first
time every time.
It will JFK you.
I don't think I wanna ask
what that's supposed to mean.
It will blow your mind.
Tasteful.
It is.
Who's next?
Done.
I need to type this up,
can I use your computer?
Yeah, man.
Just put the right password in.
420God.
Live that motto, man.
Live that motto.
I'll help you.
Oh, I'm gonna
make some brownies.
Oh, they're gonna be so good.
Hey, man.
So everything on
the menu's good,
except for the apps and entrees.
But if you're in the mood
for liquor and dessert,
this is the place.
I got three semesters,
but I don't know.
I wasted everything
while I was there.
You going back?
You know, I can
finish school anywhere.
I might stay and let
River finish here.
I mean, he could go with me,
but I just don't think
it'd be fair to him.
Yeah, well, if you do,
maybe we could eat again
once in another seven years.
Don't push your luck.
Yeah, wouldn't
even think of it.
So I did some snooping
around for you.
Yeah?
Oh, come on.
What?
No way.
You almost done?
20 minutes, tops.
That's a really long time.
It'll take longer if
you keep interrupting me.
Don't you want a break?
Don't you
want a good grade?
I mean, you've been working
so hard, you deserve a break.
I just wanna get this done.
There's other things
that need to get done too.
I should probably...
Take a break, I know.
So there have
been some instances?
Right, right, right.
Okay, a few pockets
of these deaths.
It goes all the way
back to the 1930s.
Now, like I said, I can't
say that any of these deaths
are related in any way,
but there was a small burst
of explainable sudden
deaths, usually with people
that either knew each other
or were affiliated somehow.
Well, okay.
Okay, but the only problem
is they weren't crimes.
But they could've been.
Well, we can only
go off what we know,
and none of 'em
point to someone.
If the first reported
cases of these deaths
were over 80 years ago, then
it can't be the same person.
It's probably just
a coincidence.
I mean, there's just
strange things that happen
that you just can't explain.
But what if it's not a person?
What would it be then?
A ghost.
Moon, I'm trying to help you,
but we gotta go off
facts and reality.
I think someone tried
to kill me tonight.
Hey, little scorpion.
That's not good.
Wish I had a straw.
What about you, man?
What the?
I'm not saying I
don't believe you,
but you got to admit this
is pretty far out there.
Did River see anything?
I don't know, but that
doesn't mean it didn't happen.
Why don't you tell
me about the first time
you started believing in ghosts?
This isn't funny.
Okay, I'm sorry.
I'm just trying to make
you feel less stressed.
By making fun of me.
It's just spilled milk.
I get so crazy.
I have to go pee.
Stay.
And pee in bed?
It's not my bed.
That's so gross.
What if I'm into
that kinda stuff?
Pass me your shirt.
Don't you have work to do?
Just gonna let
Hector finish it later.
I'll sign up
for summer school now.
Hey, I said you're
taking a long time.
It's okay if you're pooping.
I know girls do that stuff too.
Fine, don't talk to me.
I'm getting a snack.
Oh my God.
No!
Bethany.
No, no, no.
Everyone's gotta go
through it, especially me.
They think my dad pulled
strings, which he doesn't.
Hold on, excuse me.
What's up?
They're dead!
Hector, Chrissie, Bethany,
they're dead, Moon.
I don't know how it happened!
I don't know!
Wait, hello?
Hello?
- No!
- What's going on?
River?
What's wrong?
River.
This should cover it.
- Sorry.
- Okay, good luck.
Moon, Moon, let
me handle this.
It's locked.
I'm going around the back.
Just like old times.
River?
She's dead.
I told you something
was happening.
I'm gonna call this in.
Let's find River first.
And do me a favor, stay
behind me this time.
Is it him?
No.
You don't wanna look in there.
Oh no, this
can't be happening.
The chain.
Get the chain.
You okay?
Are you okay?
Just check him.
He's alive.
He's trapped.
What?
I have to get him out.
What are you saying?
Look, I'm gonna call this in.
We'll wait for the...
No, I'm the only
one that can save him.
He's stable.
He's stable, but
he needs an EMT.
You don't understand.
He's not here.
Please just help me carry him.
Okay, Moon, you
don't understand.
This is a police matter.
I'm gonna call this in, but if
I leave the scene of a crime,
I could lose my job.
Please.
This is Forman, badge 1740.
I'm in pursuit of a
suspect on Hartford Street.
There are two, possibly three,
DOAs at 2455 Hartford Street.
Send backup patrol
and EMT, 10-18.
Come on, we gotta get
him to the workshop.
What are we doing?
I mean, is he...
He's fine there.
Okay, this is where
I saw it, right here.
Okay, what are
you talking about?
The thing that's
been killing everybody.
It's because of this.
How do you know that?
Because I've seen it.
Look, can we just
please stop, okay?
Look, we have to get
help for River right now.
Come and get me.
Okay, just stop,
just stop, just stop.
Just sit and stop.
Stop for a second.
Look, you need to be
here with River, okay?
I'll take care of it.
No, you can't.
My God, how do you
know that for sure?
You can't.
Please just trust me.
I'm not gonna let
you kill yourself.
You're all he has.
It has to be me.
I don't want you to go again.
I won't.
I'll take care of
everything, I promise.
I promise.
Why won't you just let
me take care of this?
It has to be me.
Mom?
I'm sorry.
I tried.
What?
To stop.
I know.
Where's River?
I just wanted
us to be us again.
Mom, where's River?
It's all I wanted.
We can't be together
without River.
I tried,
but nobody believed me.
You tried to what?
To warn you.
No, Mom!
Mom!
Moon, Moon!
Bethany?
Oh God, Bethany.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Oh, Moon, come on.
Come on, come on.
He didn't get you.
You can snap out of this.
There's something that
reminds me of a case
from 20 years ago.
My God.
Doesn't make any sense.
Hello?
No, I don't think I'm gonna
be able to get to it tonight.
Nah.
Subtitles by explosiveskull
www.OpenSubtitles.org