Boy!
What kind of music is this?
I've never heard it before.
Cavara.
Is somebody behind you?
Come out.
I'd like to see who's sleeping on the job
instead of working.
Oh. I see...
Carrying on inside my wagon, are you?
Let's go.
Come on.
Such thrash.
Go on!
Did you clean all ze bottles
and test tubes in ze laboratory?
Yes Baron, I did.
I worked ze whole night
to clean up everything.
And why do ze studio look
in such a mess lately?
How could it?
I fixed up all ze things.
You know I like things clean and bright.
How can I work in a mess like that?
When I was study under professor
Blümberg and Fringhs
We had to wipe ze floors for two years.
Before I could stick my nose
into ze laboratory.
But Baron?
You know I believe in your work.
We worked so hard together.
We did everything in ze laboratory.
And I'm so grateful to you
that I could do that.
I know, I know...
Otto.
You've been a very good assistant.
And you brought in some good parts.
That Manus was perfect.
Thank you Baron.
But what we really need now
is ze perfect...
'nasum.'
Yes.
Somezing that will
represent ze finest feature
of ze Serbian ideals.
What do you mean by this?
Serbian ideals?
I have never heard
about it before.
But Otto, you don't understand.
Ze Serbian race
comes in direct descent
of ze glory from ze ancient Greeks!
Oh, I didn't know that.
But...
Where will you find those kind of nose?
In town Otto.
In town.
Oohh...
I remember when I went to school.
Our guvernante was taking my sister
and myself every day to school.
And I saw this creature of ze road.
But we were not allowed to play with them.
Because we were somezing better.
They're peasants.
They told us.
More than once I escaped.
Standing there for hours in ze field
watching zese creatures
Now our studies come finally to an end.
We got a beautiful female.
And I'm sure
among zis town people
we will just find ze perfect...
'nasum'.
Stop now.
Come on.
Let's go.
Come on children. Go on, go on.
Ah! Baron.
You wouldn't believe what a day I've had.
I had to remove the children from
the rotten school in town.
It was you who choosed school, my dear.
Yes, I did like the school.
But I didn't know that those...
dirty little...
Tell me more about it at dinner.
At dinner...
Ohh!
Come on. Let's go.
Still got to be time for us.
Always running off
to that stupid laboratory.
What a mess in this room.
How' you keep your room this way?
I've told you that a hundred times.
What's the point of having beautiful things
if you children do just not care about it.
Look at the dolls on the floor.
We shouldn't be doing this.
You know that.
Now, come on. Take your clothes of and
you put your play clothes on.
All right?
Go ahead.
Now I must tell you something.
I'm very glad that you have left
that terrible school.
The children at this school
are not on par with you.
You are very special.
You are different.
They are jealous and tell awful tales
about your mother and you father.
Olga!
Mm. Some of things they say are true.
When they talk about your mother...
Sometimes they tell things
that are true.
And sometimes they tell lies
because they are jealous.
People who are jealous always tell lies.
Give me the brush.
Madame.
Merci.
I'm goin' to make you beautiful.
You will always have to surround yourself
with beautiful things.
I like the way you look.
And your brother.
I've always...
looked for beauty.
That matter of fact...
I insist on it.
Liver and kidney are removed.
Did you put them in a storage bottle?
Yes I did.
Let's get rid of this useless krank.
Yes baron. Yes.
Ze children should be sent abroad.
Their education will progress
much faster there.
Absolutely not.
They will learn far more from us.
Besides, I don't want
them away from the house.
But it is only in
their own interest.
Mother and Father are coming
to visit us in a fortnight,
and they too, are against it.
You know that very well.
Hmm...
Good God. I'm not looking forward
to their visit.
All they ever do is pry into our affairs.
Trying to arrange our lives.
Erich.
You should eat some soup.
What do you pick on the boy for?
Because he doesn't look
very strong to me lately.
Well, he looks very well to me.
I was just thinking about a few years back.
On a trip I took with mother
to Saint Petersburg
to visit her brother.
When I met that beautiful
Russian ballet dancer...
who journeyed...
after me to Monte Carlo.
As a matter of fact you were there.
You remember you came
with father to the
Hotel de París?
Yes I do.
- Mm.
What happened then?
Mother
took him for herself.
Mother is a very religious woman.
She was only acting in your own interest.
Religious woman?
Why must you always pick on mozer?
I don't pick on mother.
I think she's very selfish.
She left you all ze jewelry,
didn't she?
Father left you all the property.
It was always like that in our family.
Father didn't like me very much either.
Now you have your pick on father.
Didn't he take you to Paris?
Oh, you have to bring that up.
Do you know what I did?
I stayed
the entire trip
in my hotel suite
while he was out with some tramp.
I don't understand.
Why you have to discuss this all
in front of our children?
The children.
What am I going to do with them
now that they're out of school?
Why don't you take them to picnic tomorrow?
Picnic?!
They got you diggin' another one
of these damn holes.
Wonder what they put in 'em.
I don't know.
I just dig them.
You know, I've been wantin'
to talk to you.
About what?
Well...
Are you really serious?
About wantin' to be a...
Monk?
Yeah.
I am.
I wanna live a
cloistered life.
You mean walk around in those clothes
- Yeah.
And pray all the time?
- I will do it.
I've never heard you pray.
I've never ever seen you pray.
Now, all of a sudden, that's what you
wanna do for the rest of your life.
Monks work in the field.
Just like we do.
It's not a big difference.
Yes, but...
Do you know what they eat?
Bread.
With water.
And that doesn't bother you?
Not too much. It's okay.
I don't understand this.
We've been friends all our lives
If you really wanna
be a monk now,
that's up to you.
But you know what you are giving up?
It's okay.
You never come with me
when I go to see the girls in town.
Because...
I want to join the order.
Why don't you come with me just once.
Don't worry. If you don't know
what to do, just watch me.
You'll get the idea.
Okay.
It's a problem with ze fallopian tube.
I have to replace it,
to make it stronger.
What other parts
did you take away from that man?
These, Baron.
Perfect specimen.
Yes.
Seminal vesicles.
But it's too long.
We have to replace part of it.
Prepare it now.
What a hill to climb.
Look!
The shepherds doesn't even care of the lambs.
How sweet.
Come on. Let's build a cover over here and
we'll have something to eat.
Go on.
That's the idea.
No no no no.
The other way
Go ahead.
That's it.
Ohh!
My apples.
They're rolling all over the place.
Come on.
Help me pick the up.
Look. There's two over there.
What's been going on around here?
Put your clothes back on.
And get out of here,
you filthy whore!
It's you again.
I want to speak to you.
Go back to the Barnes you...
And take your friends with you.
Come on up.
What's been going on at my property?
I want to know.
Just watching after the sheep.
And the girl?
She was just passing by.
How long have you been at her employ?
Short time.
And who employed you.
The foreman.
Hm. Yes.
I've seen you before.
You know I'm going to have to speak
to my husband about you.
As a matter of fact I...
think I want to see
you tomorrow morning.
At the castle.
Is that understood?
Yes.
Marika! Erik!
Let's move everything away from here.
Some people don't know
how to behave themselves.
We have to find
the right head for zis torso.
It has to be of a man who has strong way with women.
Who's overriding urges
are sensual.
If we succeed
In finding such a
single minded man
our chances are very good...
That ze male we create...
will fall in love with my
female zombie.
They will mate.
And she will bear me the children I want.
They're going to be a...
true start...
of a new race.
Entirely created by me.
Responding only to my bidding.
But so far...
we have not find a suitable mate for her.
I know where to find such a man.
I've been once to a house in town.
Certain kind of house.
You mean a bordello, Baron?
- Yes.
You, Baron?
Yes, Why?!
You zink I've never been to one?
Ohh...
While I was in medical school.
Most of ze boys
used to go to such a place.
They always wanted me to go with them.
Knowing what kind of good student I was.
Never leaving my books.
Not even for one hour.
And still I was foolish enough...
to want to be accepted in their company.
Once I left my books,
and I went wiz them.
What happened?
It was terrible.
All these over developed women.
With their large breasts.
And shapeless.
And this kind of women
is supposed to give you pleasure.
With their filthy movement.
And dirty talk.
How zis woman even can compare
with a beautiful creation like mine?
Or even with my sister.
To find...
a man who likes to make love to anyzing...
we have to go to such a place.
Who's there?
It's you. Come...
Hi Biba.
Sonja!
- Yeah.
Sonja, this is my friend Sacha.
He's new here.
Why don't we show him a good time?
Are you sure it is in
zis part of town, Baron?
Of course.
I remember well from my schooldays.
Just outside.
Can we go in, Baron?
To go in?
To do what?
You filthy zing.
Of course not.
Excuse me, Baron...
Excuse me.
It's all right Otto.
We'll wait outside.
Why have you never come here before?
I work too much.
You like?
It's one of zose doors.
We watch.
Who goes in or out.
Could they be beating someone?
They like strange zings.
Let me go from here...
No!
Two girls...?
One man...?
He must be very powerful.
Look at his head.
That's him.
That's the man we want.
It's okay. Come in.
Let's go and get ze equipment.
And we come back.
And wait for him tonight.
Come, Erik.
Come.
It's good to see
the children are already in bed.
We've had quite a day at the picnic.
Olga, you've been very overworked.
And you'll be far more than that.
Because now the children
are your entire responsibility
and I think we can do something about it.
Come say goodnight to mother.
Tomorrow morning I'm expecting a visitor.
I would like you to prepare an especially nice breakfast.
For two.
That's him.
There he comes.
But he's not alone.
He is wiz somebody.
He's helping somebody.
Somebody who looks very drunk.
You get rid of ze drunk, Von Otto.
Yes, Baron, Yes.
And leave ze Serbian to me.
Get down.
It's just what I wanted.
It's magnificent.
I knew we would find it.
Otto!
Look at it.
Finally we found the right head
wiz ze perfect nasum.
For my male zombie.
Preparation for the operation
are almost complete.
I hardly can wait for ze results.
I feel certain Baron.
That with your meticulous efforts we have...
You have made it.
Everything will be successful.
Soon here in Serbia, in my laboratory...
perfection will become a reality.
Yes, yes. That's right.
Ze true embodiment of servant youz...
will find expression.
My work is a continuation
Of ze unfinished business
of men on earth.
A furzer refinement.
But zis time it must cost a life.
Your hands are miracle workers baron.
This is a threshold, Otto...
of a creation that will replace
ze worn out thrash...
that now populates
and repopulates that planet.
Their loyalty will be to me only.
I will be ze object of their allegiance.
Listen to ze heart.
Come in.
You wanted to see me ma'am?
Yes.
I'm not in the habit of conducting
business in bed young man.
However, this morning when I...
came out of bed I didn't feel
too well, so I went back to it.
We've been discussing you,
my husband and I.
And we think that your behaviour
on our property is disgusting.
You are acting like an animal.
And we are seriously considering
dismissing you.
I just came to say goodbye.
Collect my pay.
I have to be leaving anyway.
Leaving?
Well, it's.. sort of sudden.
You seem to be Ehh...
enjoying yourself...
yesterday afternoon to say the least.
What is it?
Is it that girl I saw you with.
Is that your sweetheart?
No, she's just a nice girl.
Well then, what is it, because
had I known you would be the person
to do me this kind of trouble
I would not be here wasting my time
and trying to
offer you chance to better yourself.
To give a position in this household.
I'm sorry. It's my friend.
Oh, your friends. You've been telling
your friends you were coming up here
so that they've been running their
tasteless little stories about me.
I never thought that these idiots
could interfere with my business.
No, you don't understand.
It happened last night.
I'm listening.
Well, me and my friend... I had been
drinking and we had been walking home.
And somebody hit me
on the back of the neck.
And dragged my friend into the bushes
and cut off his head.
It's a nightmare.
No. It's not a nightmare
because I woke up this morning
and there was my friend.
He had his head cut off.
I had to bury him
by the side of the road.
Why didn't...
didn't they harm you.
I don't know.
That's a very unusual story.
Have you told anyone
you were coming up here.
No.
- well then...
You're perfectly safe here.
There's no one to spy on you.
No one knows what goes on in this house.
Besides, with murderers
lurking around
I'm going to need some kind
of protection.
I'm sure that if you'd been
sober last night you would've...
Helped you friend.
You look...
strong.
You are strong.
Yes ma'am.
And very good looking.
My husband does not love me.
It's a marriage in name only.
For the children.
For the.. property
Yes ma'am.
From time to time I...
I need someone up here.
Very lonely.
So...
happy they did not harm you.
You want me to stop work now?
Yes.
Beautiful.
We were very fortunate
to find such a perfect torso in one piece.
Incision.
It's superb.
No sign of contusion.
Ready?!
I go in to her digestive parts.
Separate...
Spleens.
Kidneys...
Gallbladder...
Liver...
Remarkable.
After what you went through last night.
What would be my other duties
while in the house?
Well, Olga is to have
full care of the children.
So as of tonight,
you can start serving dinner.
Alright.
By the way...
We have in the castle the most
modern available plumbing facilities.
And I want you to take full use of them.
Every single day.
Do you understand?
Yes ma'am.
Otto!
Level the table.
Soon I will give you life.
New life.
Why are you looking at me.
You filthy zing.
Turn around.
My male zombie
is almost created.
I only need ze blood
Maybe tonight
Soon you will give me
ze right children.
Ze children I want.
Otto!
Help me down.
To know death, Otto...
you have to fuck life...
in ze gallbladder.
I wonder if your father is home.
Why don't you go and look.
Wanna go to the castle?
I'm glad I finally found you.
I've been looking for you everywhere.
But you know that I am always here.
Well, you're not always here.
You could be at the lab, you could
be outside. You could be many places.
Anyway I found you.
It's what I wanted.
I have to speak with you.
About what?
There will be a new person
working around the castle
and I don't want you to be alarmed.
What do you mean?
Well, you are very busy,
the children are out of school...
Olga is overworked.
So I took it upon myself
to hire a new servant.
But how did you find
so quickly another girl?
It is not a girl.
It is a.. man-servant.
A man?
Why not a girl?
You know girls around here.
They're such trash.
And all they want to do is...
steal my jewelry and put on my clothes.
So I adjust for a man.
Kathrine...
I zought we had an agreement.
That no man is working in ze castle,
disturbing my work.
He won't be disturbing you.
I've seen him work.
And I'll keep him very busy.
I hope so.
You can be sure of it.
Where is your husband?
He's busy working.
He works very hard.
He's a very intelligent man.
You can meet him tonight at dinner.
Does he mind you being with men?
I mean, he could get me
in a lot of trouble.
Have me arrested.
Why should he?
He has his work
and I have my privacy.
We have two children.
You.. saw the children
the first time we met.
Did you find them beautiful?
Yeah.
It's the only reason
my husband and I are together.
To bring them up right.
No one has come as close as I.
Understanding the secret of life.
Intelligently created.
My mistakes have been few.
But I learned from everyone.
Let us make certain that ze electrodes
are placed precise as always.
At ze critical energy point.
Apply electricity.
Yes Baron.
Now, start by hand.
I'll handle the brain area.
They move Otto.
Stop ze electricity.
Yes...
And let him down.
Otto, what we're seeing in front of us...
Is really incredible.
It is Baron!
Let's see if they can move.
Arm.
Head!
Look how natural they are.
Look. Their reflex function beautifully.
How super.
Even my own expectations
completely rewarded.
He is so happy for you Baron.
I'm fulfilled.
But not yet.
We have to wait for ze final triumph.
Ze breeding.. and then...
the children.
If there will be only some way
to reduce it,
the gestation period.
How can I wait
for nine months from tonight?
Till she'll bear me ze first child.
I must...
There is even somezings
Science cannot modify.
The honor you do me
to share zis incredible triumph...
is more Zan I deserve Baron.
I take them to table.
Do you approve
of my new servant, Baron?
You are not the only one wiz introductions
to make this evening, my dear.
Otto!
Yes Baron
Show my new guests to ze table.
Yes Baron.
A very handsome pair, Baron.
They're assisting me
in my laboratory work.
They have some interest
in medical problems.
Quite obvious.
Had I known you were so generous
in having couples...
I would not have been so modest
at my own acquisition.
Thank you, Nicholas.
Are you from the town?
I see...
Could they have been
in some kind of accident, Baron?
Not really.
No. I don't want them to eat.
They are not ready yet to eat solid food.
Come here.
There is somezing very intriguing
about your new man, my dear.
Especially to my guests.
What was going on down there?
Do you know these eh...
two new people?
I didn't know that girl.
The man was my friend.
The one that was killed last night.
Well, there you see.
It was a nightmare.
Should've gone and speak to him.
After all...
We're not that strict with our help.
It wasn't...
exactly him.
Well, now you talk nonsense.
How could it be not exactly him
if it is him?
My friend wasn't tall.
He was about my size.
It was my friends head
but it wasn't his body.
You saw how tall
that person was.
Well, he was extremely tall.
What kind of work
did you say husband does?
He's a scholar.
Spends hours in his laboratory.
But I really don't know
what he really does, we...
lead very separate lives.
You must know what he does.
You see him every night at dinner.
Talk to 'em.
A word or a phrase now and then...
Something to do with electrical energy.
But where does he work?
In his laboratory
on the other side of the castle.
No one has access to it.
He had it build seven years ago
with privacy in mind.
Only he and his assistant,
you know, that strange little creature
that's always around him,
are able to go into it.
I should see this laboratory.
It's the only way I'll find out
what happened to my friend.
Mm hm.
You can't go.
No way.
Forget about your friend.
You saw him at the dinner table tonight.
I can't forget about him.
You'll have to.
Besides you can't go wandering
about the castle by yourself.
We have.. better things to do.
Why, Otto, do they seem so
interested in my wife's new servant.
He must have some quality
that attracts them.
He looks familiar to me baron.
Why shouldn't he.
They all look ze same.
Except my Serbian.
He is a true aristocrat of his kind.
He is unusual, Baron.
I always look for
ze noble ideals
and artifacts of ancient
civilizations.
My sister and I are very much alike.
But she...
somehow likes to keep her nose
always in ze gutter.
Jah, jah...
You see how he's all strapped up?
And they're gonna blame me for it too.
You really have to help me
get into the laboratory.
What are you doing
in zis part of ze castle?
Didn't my wife tell you
never to work around here?
No she didn't.
I don't want anybody in zis section.
If you have ze habit
of doing zings on your own
you won't have
your job much longer.
I wasn't planning on keeping it anyway.
Why? Are you going back
to ze farm?
Maybe.
Perhaps that's where you belong.
Yeah.
Otto!
Where are you?!
- Yes Baron.
Come in.
What happened?
I don't know, Baron.
Did you drop it?
- No, Baron, no.
It didn't fall by itself.
I heard no one Baron.
But I clean it for you immediately.
I can't go that way.
He saw me and made me go back.
Is there another way
we can go to get there?
Let's hurry.
Ze medical profession
would love to claim
my achievement as
part of their own.
And call it a giant stride forwards
of medicine.
But they can't.
It is a giant stride forwards for me!
Now her beauty will be appreciated.
Let her down.
Let him rise too.
The brain is controlling
zis massive and powerful body.
Never since Adam and Eve...
history has occurred such a moment
Watch his eyes.
When he sees her womanly perfection.
I'm sure he's never seen anyone
as beautiful as this.
Come.
Bring them close.
Kiss him.
Kiss him!
What are you waiting for?
She's yours!
Touch her!
Kiss him!
Can it be?
Could it be possible that we have failed?
Somebody must have tampered with them.
Somebody must have been in ze laboratory.
Kiss him!
Otto.
It can't be true.
Somebody disturbed our work.
What are you waiting for?
Kiss him!
Doesn't work.
Put them back!
Get them dressed.
And ready to leave.
Wake up.
Come on. Wake up!
What is it?
What are you doing here?
I just had a look
at your husbands work.
What work?
The laboratory. His butcher shop.
How did you get there?
Your children.
They showed me.
They knew the way.
How dare you?
How dare you wake me
up in the middle of the day
when you know
I have insomnia.
How dare you spy
on the Baron's work.
Since when is the lower class
allowed such presumption.
Your husband has
my friend and the girl
in that laboratory of his and
does experiments on them.
The girl is unconscious and my friend
is so weak he can hardly move.
The Baron was once a student in medicine
and perhaps those friends
of yours are sick.
And in need of help.
Sometimes when the Baron finds...
people, that interest him enough...
and that are sick enough, he treats them.
Like his servant.
That servant owes his life to him.
Okay.
I just came up here to tell you in case
you didn't know and wanted to escape.
Escape?
Escape from what?
This is my life. This is my house.
I'm not imprisoned.
Do not interfere with the Baron's work.
Please do not interfere
Things that seems strange to you
are very well planned by the Baron.
He knows what he's doing.
So do I.
And I'm not gonna let it continue.
How dare you speak to me this way?
You're not gonna let what continue?!
How dare you contradict me?
Who are you?
You nothing!
You lowlife.
You scum!
You bitch!
You Filth! You farmer!
How dare you walk out on me?
Somezing went wrong.
- But what?
Maybe ze mixture of the blood wasn't right
You were ze only one
who knew about it.
But maybe someone
got into ze laboratory.
But Who Baron?
The Children?
But they wouldn't do it.
My sister?
My sister. She always
was very jealous of me. Always!
But we failed...
that beautiful serbian female.
Everybody would have jumped.
Everyone!
But maybe that head of that...
creature wasn't any good!
His perfect nose...
His perfect nose!
He had the perfect brain.
He was the king I wanted.
And we failed!
We have to try it again.
Otto, we have to try it again.
I'm going to prove that we can do it.
We wait for so long.
You must help me Erik.
Somebody's spying on me.
Somebody gets into ze laboratory,
talking to my experiments.
I don't like that.
You know anybody who
could to ze laboratory?
Take anyzing away from there?
No.
But tell me about ze new servant of mozer.
Could he go in there
and take zings away?
No.
But Erik, someone must get in there
and take zings away.
Zings are missing.
You must help me.
PLease Erik. Promise that you'll help me.
It's so important to me.
I know it's you.
But I don't know how
he could have done this.
It's all my fault.
If I hadn't taken you to that house
and gotten drunk,
I could have helped you.
He's crazy.
My experiments are disturbed!
And you were ze only one
who knew somezing about it.
And I zought
you were only interrested in sex!
Don't zink I don't know what's going on
between you and that servant.
I watched you!
Up to fathers old tricks?
Shut up!
You're a sex maniac.
Have you been into ze laboratory?
Why shall I tell you anything?
Because I did everyzing for you.
I gave you everyzing
you ever asked me for.
I never interfered
in your dirty sexlife.
Or your friend, did I?
If I should tell you something,
what will you do for me?
Now.
What do you want?
There is something very interesting
in your worklab.
What?
Your new guest.
Does he respond only to you?
Yes.
Would he to me?
Only if I tell him.
Then...
You tell him that I want
to see him up here.
Alone.
Tell me what you know.
My servant is a friend of his.
And right now
he's probably in
your laboratory.
I know where the rest of your body is.
I buried it myself.
We'll come back here with a gun
and make them put you together.
No.
I don't care.
It doesn't matter.
Maybe it'll be alright.
It's still your brain.
Not really.
I never could figure you out.
Breathing is better that not breathing.
No.
I want to be dead.
I'm not sure about her.
But I think it's the same.
No!
Now let's go.
Come.
If she can leave.
You can come too.
Come on.
Where are you going?
We're leaving
and you're not stopping us.
You're not going to leave.
They're staying here.
And you too.
Take him.
He's not taking anybody.
He's coming with me.
Do as I say!
Make him unconscious.
Do somezing Otto!
Catch him!
Get up you fool.
Go after him!
You are not leaving here alive.
You're crazy.
You're not gonna get away with this.
Make him unconscious.
Biut don't kill him.
Or damage his head in any way.
I need his brain for my zombie.
I'm sure it has
the right instincts we want.
I'm glad we got rid of that lowlife.
Certainly made a mistake
about this one.
You were happy with him at first.
Learned my lesson.
Ready for a new experience.
So soon, Katherine
Yes
Is your new man available?
Actually he's prepared.
Come here!
Have you instructed him to do as I say?
I'm ready to tell him what I want.
I hope you'll be very tempered.
What do you mean?
His wounds are not healed yet.
Here! I'll show you.
Touch here.
And here.
But not here.
It's very recent.
I'll bring him back within two hours.
I wouldn't say untouched.
But intact.
I hope you have some success.
You go with my sister
and you do what she demands.
Is that alright with you?
What you want.
But Baron.
Our experiments are too precious
to leave the laboratory
wizout your supervision.
Shut up!
Otto.
My sister did help me.
And I'm very grateful to her.
You couldn't provide me
with the information I needed.
You didn't know
who'd been into ze laboratory.
Yet she could.
So what are you whining about?
My work has been sabotaged
from ze outside.
And zat too many zings
happened today at my laboratory
zat I interfere
in my own sisters amusements!
But Baron...
She will abuse him
or spoil him.
Do him harm.
That's enough Otto!
You are very well aware
of my personal habits.
What is it to him?
Thank you brother.
Why are you standing there?
Get me some chemicals.
As long as the parts are fresh.
We have to dismember him immediately.
So he can cause no problems.
What are you waiting for?
Okay, I'll do it myself, you fool.
Come on!
I'm waiting.
Tie him up and watch him
Put her away.
What a day.
Always he tells me what to do.
Will you do everything I ask?
What do you want?
Everything I ask is what I want.
Come to bed.
Take your shoes of
and get that thing off.
Are you going to stay just like that?
Move closer.
Touch me.
Not like that.
Gentle.
There.
More.
Lower.
Bring your hand up.
Touch me.
Hold me close to you.
Hold me.
Tighter.
Squeeze me tight.
Hold me close.
Ooh.
Not...
Why did you..
Not so.. Close!
I've told...
Stop it. What are you doing?
I cannot breathe!
Stop it!
Stop...
The Baron rewarded his sister
for one days loyalty...
with two hours of company
wiz a mere creature.
For a whole life of loyalty...
I take my own reward.
I have my own rights.
I had more right to ze girl...
than the Baronesse's boy!
Each day The Baron
work into his laboratory...
I work too.
I never had pleasure.
He never finished
medical school, but I...
I have everyzing
learned in ze field.
Not out of books.
And now I know exactly...
how to do it.
You wanna watch me?
I show you.
You are so pretty.
You are so wonderful.
You are such a
wonderful female creation.
Now, I'll get into you.
I have to get in.
She.. She...
She's ruined.
It's not true.
No.
It can't be true
What are you doing to me?
You destroyed my female.
You put your dirty hands on her.
But you went into her, Baron.
Bastard!
I studied how to do it.
I know how to do it!
You don't!
Wiz your filthy hand.
Everyzing...
I cannot put it back.
All the effort and time
I put in it to create her!
All her...
inside is out.
What do I have to do?
To find a new female?
When I took her as a student...
you knew nozing of medicine.
I taught you everyzing!
But zat's happen if you attach people
who know nozing about medicine.
They are too stupid!
It's all your fault.
You had pleasure wiz my wife.
Didn't you?
I watched you.
You enjoyed yourselves.
For a peasant boy!
Oh no.
Oh.
Kathrine.
My...
My wife...
Ze mozer of my children.
You killed her!
On account of him!
My sister...
My beautiful sister.
You killed her.
Kill him.
Kill him!
Listen to my command.
I want you to kill him.
You understand?
He is not your friend.
I'm your friend.
I created you.
Kill him!
Stop.
Stop!
Listen to my response.
Come into the table.
Stop!
Go back!
Stop.
STOP!
It's all your fault!
I make you pay for zis.
You trouble making bastard.
You have put an end to my experiments.
But my work will live on.
I'm not going to die...
In vain.
My work is not...
finished.
But I know I was...
working in the right direction.
I had.. no one.
Just a laboratory.
And a dream.
Ze female is dead.
But he lives.
He will.. show the world...
My genius.
When they...
roll out ze tape...
there can be...
riches...
Perfection.
I wanted...
to...
prove...
I...
don't...
regret...
anyzing.
I...
tried...
My...
best.
He won't be giving you
anymore orders now.
He got what he deserved.
Let me down so we can get out of here.
If I let you down
what will you do?
I'll take you out of here.
I'll take you to a real doctor
Then I cannot let you down.
I must die here.
Why? It's okay now.
He's dead.
I'm more like them than you.
I belong here.
That is terrible.
But there is not life for me.
What are talking about.
I'm your best friend.
You know me before...
But not now.
I must be dead.