FLIES ON THE WALL
TV SURVEILLANCE
Come to my office.
- Sure.
The person in custody won't talk
until we've seen this.
I've read the autopsy report.
Nasty piece of work.
Flemming is on his way.
- How did the interrogation go?
- It's postponed. Grab a chair.
Let's look at this.
It's October 28th today.
It's around 2.30 p.m.
This is a very personal film.
It may never
be shown anywhere.
I want to clean up ...
... in my personal life.
I'm going to
record everything.
I will leave it up to
random events -
- and let the film
take its own direction.
That's all I know ... so far.
So that's a start anyway.
Yeah ... That's it.
SIX WEEKS EARLIER
This is the fourth time this award is
given for a critical documentary.
It was destined that The Third Eye
one day would go to My Larsen.
My Larsen is 33 years old,
a graduate from the Film School -
- she had her debut in 1996
with "The Queen".
A film that compromised
My's person -
- because the tabloids badgered her
for having dated the Crown Prince.
This paper swallowed the bait
and printed a downright hoax.
Hi, My.
Peter?
What are you doing here?
I'll call you, alright?
Congratulations.
My exposed the sect leader
undercover ...
... that's journalism at its best.
My, come
and get the 50.000 -
- that you so richly deserve.
Thanks for the money
after eight years of hard work.
I'll spend them on a boob job
so I can make some new films.
Thank you.
Completely out of sight.
Yes ... Good.
I was in love with her -
- for as long as she'd let me.
That's the annoying
thing about My.
You feel you have
to get her permission.
It wasn't until later I discovered
that she'd never loved me.
But I don't think she's able to.
Something else happens.
She feels flattered.
Then she holds on for a while to see
if she can get something out of it.
She's afraid of something.
Sometimes I'm afraid
that I'll break.
And go into a thousand pieces.
Snap ...
Perhaps because I'm afraid that
there's no one to pick up the pieces.
Should I just talk
or do you ask questions?
I think I'm a good friend to you.
I'm there if you need me.
But ... I don't really feel ...
You're not there
when I need you.
You're hard to get hold of
and you're always on the move.
That's not very appealing.
- I really like you.
But that's how it feels.
It really does.
I'm really hurt by that.
- Your phone's ringing.
We talk about lots of things.
- My, your phone's ringing.
Hello?
- Hi. It's Peter Friis.
Why did you come to the prize thing
and call me now? You need money?
I guess I have to talk to all
my old boyfriends today.
Did you get married?
I want to talk to you.
- Yes.
Hi!
This is our floor.
This is Allan who works with us.
- Hi.
I made some coffee for us.
- Good.
Are you recording?
- I can't believe you got past security.
I record everything.
- I should have washed my hair.
Congratulations.
Your speech was great.
Why did you call me?
- Let's cut to the chase.
Have a seat.
It seems that people around here
are crazy about your films.
We want to hear if you're interested
in doing a film project for us.
You're a spin doctor, Peter.
Too much.
Is this your office?
- I'm the head of public relations.
We want to try to counteract
the contempt for politicians.
Which we in part are to blame for.
Also the Liberal Party has
given the impression -
- that we also control
the media's portrayal of us.
Nothing new in modern politics,
but we'd like to turn it around.
And we want to do it
openly and honestly.
An important message
to send out -
- and something
the voters will understand.
Your job would be
to profile the party -
- in a documentary to be shown
on TV prior to the next election.
We want the documentary to
take place in Ravnskov District.
The important thing is,
you can do as you like.
You have a free reign.
And you will be well paid.
I don't vote for the Liberal Party.
- I know.
But see it as an opportunity
to test your own beliefs.
If the Liberal Party has any
double standards you'll find them.
Why not expose the Liberal Party
for it's own money?
If you pass on this
you're dumber that I thought.
It's political suicide.
I'll make a "nice" film
with Peter and his friends.
So long to Copenhagen.
My ...
Your contact at City Hall
is Helle Tesch.
She'll help you with everything
concerning local government.
RAVNSKOV DISTRICT
Doesn't it smell strange?
I had to brief Balder about you. They
have their own agenda. Or he does.
How much do you make?
Do spin doctors make the big bucks?
You're here to butcher us. I forgot.
Would you turn that off?
I'm not here to butcher any one.
It's purely for therapeutical purposes.
So this Balder has his own agenda.
That's a start.
What's he like?
- He's the may or of Ravnskov.
A new breed of politician and ...
- And ...?
Ordinary, maybe.
An attribute for a politician.
Don't you know him?
- I met him once.
I got the sense he didn't like me.
He's quick to judge people.
Me too.
Balder will insist the film is about him,
so he can keep tabs on you.
He has a soft spot for beautiful
women, otherwise he's a wizard.
I thought that was the
spin doctor, Harry Potter.
How many Harry Potters are there in
your party? All crazy about blondes?
Always jabbering away.
- Are you staying over?
I'll call you, My.
I feel kinda lonely in this suite
you got for me.
Talk to you soon.
Drive safely.
Hello?
- It's the reception.
I wanted to inform you
that City Hall is paying -
- for your use of the gym.
It's open from 6 a.m. to 10 p.m.
Thanks. I'd like to inform you
that there's a strange smell.
I'll be right up.
We thought we were rid of it.
When they built the hotel a fox
got caught between the floors.
And we couldn't get to it.
We've had to wait for it to rot.
When the weather changes
the smell seeps out.
Can't you give me another room?
There's a conference.
Everything's booked.
I'll leave these here.
Just spray if you need to.
Me?!
This doesn't smell any better.
We can just air out.
There ...
Good night.
I'd like a cab to Copenhagen.
Yes, as soon as possible.
I know, I just got here.
Please do as I tell you!
Thanks.
I'd like a cab to Copenhagen.
I'll cut here.
My, we almost didn't meet,
but you changed your mind.
You wanted to tell the truth
about us on TV.
My name is Arne Thorsen. I know the
truth about the events in Ravnskov.
I want to tell my version
of what happened -
- when Ravnskov lost its dignity.
Who the guilty parties are
that should be held accountable.
The account must be settled.
This is my editing equipment.
My, I want you to interview me.
I want you to do it now.
I'm not doing it.
You understand?
A dead fox ...?
Ravnskov District.
I'll do it.
Ravnskov District. Can I help you?
- My Larsen. Svend Balder, please.
He's in a meeting.
- When can I reach him?
Let me give you his secretary.
- Thanks.
Balder's office. Cecilia speaking.
- My Larsen. Svend Balder, please.
Concerning?
I just moved here. I'd like to know
more. Everyone talks about him.
Yes, but he's hard to get hold of.
Go to our website. The mayor
will answer your questions.
Okay, I'll do that.
You must be My.
Helle Tesch.
I was wondering where you were.
I just got here.
- Welcome. I hope I can assist you.
Let me know if you need anything.
- I'll let you know.
Don't hesitate, My.
Just call me.
I'd like to buy you lunch.
I brought some lunch vouchers.
This is yours.
- Thanks.
He doesn't want to talk to you.
Don't wait around for him.
There's a young journalist roaming
around. This is our smoking room.
There's no smoking in the rest
of the building. Do you smoke?
No. Do you?
- No.
This is my office.
That's the mayor's office.
This is your key and your
car is in the parking lot.
Would you sign here?
- Yes, of course.
There you go.
- Keep it.
Keep it ...
I heard that Svend Balder is
in the restaurant.
I'm afraid I can't answer that.
Ask about Svend Balder at City Hall.
Svend Balder?
- Yes.
My Larsen. I'm making the film
about the Ravnskov District.
Well, then the film's about me.
- Fine with me.
They told me it was a man,
but I'm thrilled it's not.
Hi. This is our finance director,
Arne Thorsen.
Nice camera. Is it a Panasonic?
- Yes.
These two fellows are called Anders.
Everyone's called Anders here.
Their field is tourism and activities.
The land of milk and honey.
We're heading for the sauna.
Talk to Helle if you need anything.
But we had an appointment.
- I don't have time.
We're going south for a bit.
See you.
Why should I move here? I have
no kids and I retire in 30 years.
Because you're turned on
by naked men.
The film is about Svend Balder
and he's going to the sauna.
Talk to Helle.
She has a schedule for you.
Unless you want to sweat
with us men.
I'm going to shower.
You said the film should be about you.
- I think I'll ...
Don't you find this awkward
in a film my party is producing?
Like a scene
from the Christmas party.
Should I turn it off?
- Of course. It's too private.
Then do I get to make
a film about you and Ravnskov?
If you turn off the camera
until I am dressed.
The plan is to follow
Svend Balder around.
Granted, he went along with it
because I showed him my breasts.
He felt bulldozed. He's pissed off.
- Right ...
Turn it off.
You can't film in here.
You can't keep me
from filming at City Hall.
I decide who films where.
Turn it off.
Wait here.
We've discussed it.
I told you ...
There you are.
- Hi, Helle.
Hi, Helle.
Is it possible for me to ...
The way I see it you're breaking
a verbal agreement.
It's called a breech of contract.
- Not in my world.
Just because we talk nice to you
doesn 't mean there's a contract.
The syndicate's board
have certain rules.
We can't use you.
We're not allowed to.
But I can offer you a consultant's fee
of 300.000 for renovating the beach.
You're my friend, Svend.
I'm not your consultant.
You know what I mean, right?
It's worth at least 100 million.
Tell me one thing. Your political
adversaries here in Ravnskov ...
Do they know
what you're up to?
Sand and waste
that's never been moved.
All the invoices ...
Do they know about this?
You buying a huge boat and
building a pool in your backyard -
- because you think you have
a contract is not my problem.
I could get some new friends.
- Are you blackmailing me?
I'm just describing
how you treat people.
Did you film this?
Your Liberal buddy
threw me out of City Hall.
Okay ...
Now what do we do?
- Are you asking me?
You're paying me to be here.
Don't you brief each other?
I don't exactly feel welcome.
I don't like it, I have to admit.
And I don't like you
recording me now.
I have to look into this, My.
We'll call off the film for now.
Call it off?
- Yes.
Go back to Copenhagen. I'll call you.
- Are you telling me to stop?
I'm telling you I have look into
whether this is what we want.
We can make a film
somewhere else.
With who?
I'm so provoked by this.
You gave me a free reign.
I'll call you.
I have you on tape, Peter.
Jesus Christ ...
You've reached Peter Friis.
Leave a message after the beep.
Hi, Peter. I just want to
let you know that I'm staying.
You ran out on our agreement.
You screwed me.
You're in the film now. It's actually
more interesting because of you.
See you.
I hear you're interested
in building projects.
Yes. Is that illegal too?
- No, hardly.
Do you know what you're filming?
- No. Tell me.
Let me show you something.
Leave the camera. Follow me.
Unless you're blind without it.
Mogens, I'll catch a ride
from our director.
Pick me up at the hotel tomorrow.
- Okay.
Are you staying
at the hotel tonight?
I have a suite there where I work late,
so I don't disturb my family.
We bought this site
via the syndicate.
It's now called Ravnskov Beach.
The elevated railway will bring
the citizens from midtown out here.
To the Beach Park,
as the architects say.
Like a Mediterranean dream? You're
making a croisette. That sounds great.
Yes ...
It is quite great.
And over here and along there -
- there will be public facilities
with leisure and sports activities.
It's all about the quality of life
in Ravnskov.
We might even move
City Hall down here.
Are your legs cold?
- A little.
I'm sorry about the other day,
when I snapped at you.
I was a bit annoyed
and stressed out. It happens.
But that's over with.
Do you have to work?
- Yes, unfortunately.
Alright then.
Do you know if
your co-workers fear you?
I think so. I know so.
- Really?
But they don't show it.
Fear is a personal matter.
I fear my adversaries too.
- Do you have a lot of those?
Fear keeps you on your toes.
That's how I feel anyway.
Being afraid is fine by me.
Do you have any friends?
- Friends? I don't know.
Are you my friend?
- Me?
I don't think so.
- Oh ...
It takes me a while
to get to know a person.
I'll take my shoes off
in the meantime.
What should we call the film?
- Let me think about it.
We could call it
"The man with the smelly socks".
What? Is it that bad?
- Yes.
Sorry to hear that.
We better turn on the vent.
Hi. What kind of food
do you have?
Can you make a club sandwich?
I think this is yours.
Don't we have other trucks
to pick up waste?
It doesn't have to be dump trucks.
If we can keep
the union out of it ...
Yeah ...
I can't decide on that right now.
But someone else must ...
Yes, exactly.
Yes, that's evident.
Okay, I can't decide right now.
Yes, alright. Bye-bye.
How many kids does he have?
Two, Amanda and Sofie.
I make films too.
Well, it's amateur movies.
But I have a Sony and
editing equipment. I have it all.
Can I show you my short films?
I'd like to get your opinion.
Maybe you can give me some tips.
- Sure.
Are we running late, Mogens?
- We'll survive.
We're getting at bite to eat
with the economic committee.
We like to meet
under casual circumstances.
I know I'm ahead of my time.
I'm not saying it to be cocky.
I sense resistance from people
like you, Siri and Bjorn -
- and pardon me,
but you're lagging behind.
You all know
our collaborators are on board.
So your socialistic
rhetoric is useless.
A journalist wants me to comment
on the syndicate's beach clearing.
Every time I pass him on to you
or Arne you never comment on it.
I said he should wait.
Like the rest of us ...
But you're so secretive, Svend.
- That's an old hat, Siri.
And you know it. Every time you
feel pressured, that comes up.
What happens if we oppose
your proposed plan?
Doesn't that worry you?
- Not again.
What have we achieved,
what are our plans -
- and how do we get there
in the best and least costly way?
Mogens, where's My?
- She had to make a call.
But it was ten minutes ago.
How can you let her film us?
Are you involved with her?
I'm handling this my way.
I'm an open person, you're closed.
We're just different.
That journalist is e-mailing me
about the soil analysis.
Did he talk to Zlatan? Maybe we
should have lunch with him again.
Zlatan ... I'm not taking part
in an environmental debate.
It's not a good time to have
a journalist in our car.
That's what she is,
your film floozy.
My film floozy ...
Get a grip, Arne.
I'm sorry.
Can I film now?
- Sure, we're game.
We're exhausted. Right, Arne?
- Yes, but it was a good meeting.
It sure was.
I have to be careful now ...
... because I ...
... I might feel something here.
Come in.
- Can I film in here?
Go ahead,
I don't mind a bit.
This is where I live.
My wife lives in our summer house.
Or rather ...
Well, it's hers now.
In the past I did
a lot of angling ...
And hunting with a bow and arrow.
That has always fascinated me.
That's a compound bow, but now I
spend my time making short films.
My goal is to
make a real movie.
I really wanted
to be a film director.
That was my big dream,
but it didn't turn out that way.
Let me show you something.
I've attached a camera here.
That way my hands are free to fish.
Cool.
I make the music myself.
There's a lot of waiting -
- but video tape is cheap these days,
so I just wait to hit the jackpot.
But you know all about that.
- What do you mean?
You use a hidden camera, don't you?
- Oh, like that.
You don't hit the jackpot every time.
- No, I guess not.
I'm impressed, Arne.
I was wondering if you
wanted to interview me.
I can tell you about the district.
- The film is mainly about Svend.
He has given up his family,
and they have given up on him.
He's paying the price.
He's lucky to have you.
- I had to pay the price too.
I had to sacrifice my wife,
my home, my family and friends.
I've been married
to him for 15 years.
Some people can't say 'thank you'.
Unfortunately, Svend uses people.
It's horrible to feel used.
'Cause one day you're all used up,
and then you're just ...
Then you're nothing.
I'm sorry. Forget it.
Eat.
Well, you can just interview yourself.
- You're right.
My, I was thinking I could help you.
- What do you mean?
We should collaborate on this.
That's sweet, but I don't think so.
- Think about it.
Let's keep in touch.
Think about it.
Arne, you know what I did to my kids
when they didn't wipe up after a spill?
I took them by the hand,
stuck a towel in their hands -
- bent them down
and made wiping movements.
That's your job. I can't sign it.
You have to do it.
I don't like it, Svend.
- No.
Get over it, because you're the CEO.
Go ahead.
It's a great deal of money.
- Yes.
That's why I need your signature.
Why do you allow me to make a film
about you? There must be a reason.
Do you always obey your party?
No, I think they see me as
a competitor. Somehow.
Why allow you to make
a film about me?
It frightens me a bit and I like that.
I already told you.
Since you're filming our district
I'd like to know more about you.
Yeah. What do you want to know?
- Your height, weight and shoe size.
That's easy,
because I don't know.
Oh ... How do you buy shoes?
My friends say
I'm unappealing.
And my ex-boyfriends say
I wasn't able to love them.
I seem to take advantage
of my friends.
If I talk about myself, I'll probably lie.
- Lie all you want. That's just dandy.
I promised myself I'd find
one little truth about myself.
That's a promise I made.
Then I can call my girlfriends again.
- The perfect self-deception.
How will you honor your promise?
- By being honest and sincere.
Is honesty the truth?
If I'm not honest
then I'm not telling the truth.
I don't buy that.
- Well, I do.
Hi, honey.
How is it going?
No, I'm just sitting here
thinking about you naked.
I don't feel like going to work.
Yes, I will. Bye-bye.
You're strange.
- Yes.
No, you're just stupid.
- Does that make me less truthful?
- Honesty and truth don't go together.
The world is full of contradictions
and I've accepted that.
Although it's painful at times.
I think I've fallen for a man
I shouldn't fall for.
He is ...
I don't know.
He gives me a sense of security.
That's a new one for me.
Smile, Arne.
You're on camera!
Let's dance. Get rid of that.
- Would you hold it, Arne?
He sacrificed his best friend and took
a lover who meddled in our affairs.
I have to follow
Svend Balder around.
He had lost control. He didn't get
that it would all be over soon.
If I had to give career advice
after 35 years experience -
- is would be to forget
one's fear of authority figures -
- and trust your expertise.
That has to be in order.
Numbers can become
the little friends -
- you can go to bed with at night
and wake up with in the morning.
A budget has its own life.
You must learn to befriend it.
The worse part is
when it overpowers you.
You become the boy in the fairytale
with the sword facing the dragon -
- and you have to defend the town
against a fire-breathing dragon.
You're all alone.
You have created it.
You are responsible for your creation.
What do you do?
Good lord.
- Tell me about it.
His books are probably cooked too.
He won't do it.
He thinks we're the bad guys.
But a miracle might save us.
He could sink with his big boat.
- He could commit suicide.
He's been kind of depressed.
He could commit suicide.
Is Svend ready?
- He's in a meeting. It'll take a while.
Then I'll just wait here.
Hi. Who are you looking for?
- Are you Zlatan?
Yes ... Thanks for coming.
Do you have time to talk?
- Of course.
Come on in.
- Thanks. Wow, nice boat.
Are you recording me?
- Are you shy?
A little bit.
I'm not used to being on TV.
I don't know where to look ...
at you or ... Can you turn it off?
Yes, it's done. What do you want?
Why did you call me?
I've spent 15 years of my life
making my business grow.
A business that has supported
my family and many others.
Svend is used to paying off those
who are on his side.
First he buys you,
then he sells you.
Now I'm on
the verge of bankruptcy.
He has fired me
and my employees.
I have a little present for him,
as pay back.
I thought I'd give it to you.
You don't get it.
- No, I don't.
There you go.
Where are all
the forks and spoons?
I forgot everything.
I have cake.
Hauling of waste
Where are we going?
Good question.
I don't really know.
I just thought
we needed to get away.
I have something for you.
I have something for you too.
- For me?
Who should get something first?
Maybe me.
Here.
Did you buy that for me?
- Yes, I did.
I usually send Mogens out for things,
but I had some time during lunch.
It's from a second hand-dealer
behind the mall.
It's really sweet.
When I saw it
I knew it was perfect for you.
It looks really good on you.
So far you've been
a fly on the wall.
Maybe a bit annoying,
but I think ...
It's as if
you've turned into ...
A butterfly.
But what did you have for me?
I saw Sofie, my oldest,
in front of the mirror.
She looked at herself
because she got her ears pierced.
She was very proud.
And I suddenly saw her.
It was shocking, because I realized
I hadn't seen her at all.
I don't know what she's thinking.
I don't see my children.
I know nothing about their homework
or what page they're on in math.
I never help them
with their homework.
I'm grateful my wife
takes care of them -
- because then
I can be a politician.
But if I had to choose ...
The truth is what
everything appears to be.
I've dealt with the truth
and refined it damned well.
Yeah ... I know.
You lie,
you control and rule.
I ought to grill you with
a lot of tedious questions ...
A sugar beet factory is shut down.
I propose we buy it.
My idea is to renovate it
and create new jobs.
All for a good cause.
But the factory was antiquated
and never got underway.
We were stuck with
the beach property -
- and empty buildings
that were run-down.
Svend comes up with an idea.
We form a syndicate
with me as the CEO.
We wanted to build a beach park with
a gym, sailing club and apartments.
We got two European banks,
Konstro in Finland -
- and several contractors
to buy into it.
Our initial capital
was 150 million Euros.
50 million were paid
for site development.
To check the soil for pollution.
The only problem was
we did nothing.
Instead the money
was invested -
- in high profile projects
in China and India -
- and as the years went on
more money came in.
But nothing happened on the beach.
Nothing.
But ...
Svend got the capital
to renovate the schools in the district.
He was a success.
And I ... gave up.
Alright ... Let's sit down.
Sooner or later we'll have to
come clean. We'll do as follows.
As the syndicate's CEO
you'll say you've lost control.
You acted without the board's
consent and you're resigning.
So you take the blame
for bad management.
To cover all our tracks I have to fire
you as the district's finance director.
What are you saying?
- I have no choice.
Listen, Arne. We got a lot further
than we ever dreamed possible.
When things have calmed down -
- you come back and act
as director of tourism.
That's perfect.
Then you can fish all you like.
You can't mean it, Svend.
- We have a huge profit right now.
We can start the clean-up
of the Beach Park anytime.
According to what's dictated.
You come back and get a new job.
People will forget about it.
Arne, don't walk out now.
Stay and listen. Don 't, Arne!
Don't be stupid.
There you go.
Hi.
- Hi.
Why did you fire Arne?
- Who told you that?
Can't you accept the responsibility?
Are you such a coward?
No, but I did fire Arne.
I have my reasons.
Yeah, just blame it on Arne -
- so you can play the grand mayor
who did nothing wrong.
Listen, I did accept
the responsibility.
My responsibility was to fire Arne.
And I did.
Let me make one thing clear.
Don't come running up to my office -
- and lecture me about
what I should and shouldn't do.
I don't interfere
with your little film -
- so don't ever come to my office
and tell me my business!
I have to get that expression
for my film.
Just walk in,
he's at the top of his game.
Can I have a word with you?
About what?
Can we go somewhere?
Bruun at the paper said
I could trust you.
You seem to have better access
to City Hall. You want anything?
Thanks.
Balder ignores me.
The question is whether we are on to
the same story from different angles.
My editor will kill me
if other papers get this story.
So I have to keep a low profile.
But I thought ...
Since you're a film director
we're not really competitors.
No, we're not.
What do you know, that I don't?
See, that's the question ...
Who will spill the beans first?
- You. After all you contacted me.
I'll say environmental clean-up.
What do you say?
Sand and beach.
Then I'll say site development.
- Croisette.
What?
- A new City Hall by the sea.
Is he building City Hall by the sea?
- Yes.
But then he'll mix the syndicate's
and district's economy.
Are you sure?
- Yes.
I'm sure were talking
about the same thing.
As soon as Balder discovers
we're building a case against him -
- he'll make up a cover story.
Who did you interview?
Did you talk to Zlatan Selic?
He's Balder's contractor. He's ...
- I know who he is.
I can't get in touch with him.
Ask him why there aren't
any tracks on the beach -
- after they've transported truck
loads of sand. Ask him about that.
I will.
Here you go.
You look mad.
You want to be dropped off?
Every day is not a party.
- Nope.
You can let me in on your schedule.
We're going to an anniversary.
We have to present a gift -
- to a teacher who has taught
at one of our schools for 40 years.
Then there's lunch at City Hall
with a renovation company.
After that we go to
Vestre Cemetary at 3 o'clock -
- to bury a close colleague.
My primary job is to wait.
Being a driver is just part time.
Then I'll wait with you, Mogens.
The guy in the coffin there ...
I have driven him many times.
He was a good guy. A great
poster boy for the immigrants.
Who was he?
- Zlatan Selic.
I think he had five kids.
What a shame.
Zlatan Selic?!
Hi, My.
Good to see you.
He'll be difficult to interview now.
Can I talk to you? I have ...
- Leave me alone.
I'll call you, okay?
He ...
He went sailing.
He had just bought a big boat.
He was alone and hit a buoy
at full throttle.
My heart goes out to his children.
He should have worn a life jacket.
That's right, Mogens.
He should have.
Who is it?
It's Peter.
Can I come in?
Hi, Peter.
- Hi.
Good to see you.
How's it going?
- Fine.
I just felt cooped up in here.
- Are you recording? Please don't.
I'm not.
I'm glad you came.
My, sit down a minute.
I need to talk to you.
- The film is off, My.
We can't burden the government.
Sorry, but we have to call it off.
- But you already did.
I'm not making it for you.
- No, but ...
We don't want to deal with Balder.
Everything is blowing up soon.
I get it. Ravnskov is not
a model district so the film is off.
Give me your tapes.
- No.
Just in case.
- Why?
Balder is done for. That's how it is.
- And that pleases us.
Does it please you?!
What are you talking about?
I have a check for the amount
we owe you.
Is that why you sent me here?
Am I part of a plan
to rid you of Balder?
I don't owe you anything, Peter.
- No, you don't.
You did yours and we're pleased.
Please go.
Get out.
It'll work itself out.
In a year Ravnskov will have a new
may or. People forget. Life goes on.
Exactly! Then you get a new may or
you can manipulate.
Most politicians are corrupt.
They have fake invoices everywhere.
Balder has made his
own version of our politics.
City Hall is filled with his slogans.
- I want you to leave. Get out.
This is Svend Balder. Please leave
a message and I'll get back to you.
This is Marianne.
Who is it? Hello?
My! Are you still here?
- I'm on my way out.
Did you know Zlatan? Tragic death.
- Yes.
I want you to interview me now.
You promised me.
Another day, Arne.
- You'll forget.
I won't.
I want you to do it now!
I'm not interviewing you, Arne.
You understand?!
Sorry, I ...
This is Svend.
- I'm waiting outside in the car.
I have to talk to you.
- Okay.
What?
You have to do it quick.
You shouldn't come here.
What's up?
You look tired.
- I am. It was a rough day.
Are you involved in Zlatan's death?
Zlatan's death?
No, of course not.
Zlatan was a friend of mine.
I've known him for ten years.
Is that why you're here?
- No.
I don't know what you're
worried about. I'm on top of this.
You're not on top of shit, Svend.
Everyone knows what's going on.
Your party, Peter Friis and the press.
What do they know?
Zlatan called me.
He gave me an envelope
with the fake invoices you used.
I gave them to a journalist.
Why did you do that?
It's got to stop now, Svend.
Hell no.
Your room has been cancelled.
They are not paying anymore.
That's alright. I'm packing.
Should I check you out?
- Go ahead.
I was afraid you had left.
Come with me.
I have to tell you something.
And that is ...
I'm in love with you.
I really am.
That's what I am.
That's how it is.
You heard me, right?
- Yes.
Good.
I don't want you to leave.
I'm stopping.
This is where it ends.
Svend Balder,
I wanted to let you comment -
- on the article we're running
tomorrow. Would you do that?
Yes, I would.
You would?
- Yes.
Alright then ...
How do you explain that the clean-up
of the Beach Park never took place?
And what happened to the money?
I'm not going to defend myself.
I admit that I ...
... have oppressed the truth.
I have mislead the City Council,
the syndicate's CEO and board -
- and I speculated with the money -
- intended for the clean-up
of the Beach Park.
I admit to everything
and I'm resigning.
You're resigning ...?
- Yes.
Make sure you got in on tape.
So you admit to it?
- Yes. You want me to repeat it?
No need. Can I take your picture?
- Of course.
Thanks.
One last question. What happened
to the money for the Beach Park?
All the funds from this speculation
was invested in Ravnskov District.
They were used for renovating
day-care centers, like I promised.
The money stayed with its citizens.
I promise to stay.
When will you get here?
- I'm still at City Hall. I'll hurry.
I'm writing all my co-workers
before it hits the papers.
I don't like it here. If you're not
here soon I'm driving home.
Don't do that. I'll be there in a
couple of hours. Take a nap.
I didn't tell you that Arne was in my
room and made a copy of my film.
Arne? Why would he do that?
- Does Arne know you're resigning?
Maybe you should tell him.
- Arne is no threat. I'll talk to him.
Go to sleep. I'll be at the hotel
in a couple of hours.
Please don't leave, My.
I won't.
I'll wait for you.
Sorry, the door was open.
I just wanted to check.
It's 1.30 in the morning.
If everything's alright
I'll be on my way.
Arne?
What are you doing here?
Are you going hunting?
What is it?
What's going on?
What are you doing, Arne?
Hello!
Is anyone there?
If anyone sees this
they should know -
- that Arne Thorsen
killed Svend Balder.
And he's coming to get me.
This is the end of the film.
I'm doing what has to be done.
The police, the judges,
the syndicate attorneys -
- members of the City Council
and every one who sees this -
- must know what I have done.
I take full blame for it.
When I'm no longer here ...
I want you all to know that if
this young lady had stopped me -
- then you had only gotten
her side of the story.
I want to leave behind
a decent balance sheet.
When you find me
you can see my film.
Arne, you can't change things.
Don't you get it?
You're an ordinary man
who doesn't know what he's doing.
My, is it over?
No, not quite.
This is the end of the film.
I take full blame for it.
You're an ordinary man ...
My, is it over?
No, not quite.
A film by
MY LARSEN
Emergency,
may I help you?
I want to turn myself in.
I've killed a man.
State your name, please?
- My Larsen.
What should I do?
Tell us where you are.
I better get back to her.
- Yeah, you better.
Berggreen, this is for you.
- Thanks.
"Balder admits scam for millions"
Interrogation of My Larsen
November 16th. It's 11.45.
Heading the interrogation
is Mads Berggreen.