♪ We'll light it up
like there's no tomorrow ♪
♪ Hands up
if you want to be free ♪
♪ We'll live it up
like there's no tomorrow ♪
♪ Whoa-oa-oa-ah ♪
This is my best friend
Kaylie Mack.
Confident, cocky, clever--
She's always got
some new idea brewing.
Life with Kaylie
is never boring.
♪ Let's go rave,
come follow me ♪
♪ It's time to taste
some ecstasy ♪
♪ We'll light it up... ♪
This is my other best friend,
Mandy Kim. Five years ago,
she moved here from
San Francisco, lost 30 pounds,
and became the smart, hot girl
that loves fashion.
I love her to death,
and she's not as superficial
as she seems.
Not usually, anyway.
♪ Na, na, na, na, na,
na, na, na, na, na ♪
And that's me. I'm Avery.
I'd say I'm the one that's
more in touch with reality.
I keep the other two
out of trouble--
Well, at least most of the time.
Hey. Hey.
Did you guys see how many
new followers we have?
112 since Friday. 114, actually.
That makes a total of 2,763.
And did you see how many
re-tweets we got yesterday?
People love pranks that
involve authority figures.
Then they're gonna love today's.
What is that?
Ian?
I don't know.
Bro, your backpack.
Great joke, Ian.
Back to the test.
I didn't do it, Mr. Brixton.
All right, laugh away.
Ha, ha, ha.
It's not that funny.
Oh, my God.
This is going to be
great for the blog.
Our followers will love it.
Brilliant. This is perfect.
Send it to me,
and I'll upload it later.
See you tonight, Kaylie.
Come here. You guys
have to see this.
This is awesome.
BeautifulAndLovelyBrides.com.
Mail-order brides.
They're from, like, every
country on the planet.
Click on that one.
Hmm. She's from Latvia.
Nice bikini.
You're a snob.
"Interested in a man
"30 to 60 years old.
"My friends describe me
as creative, shy,
understanding, and cheerful."
Read her hobbies.
"Gardening, housekeeping,
listening to pop
music, and exercise."
This is hilarious!
Housekeeping is her hobby?
That can't be true.
Can you guys imagine
what kind of guys
have to basically order
a wife on a website?
There are how many
women in America,
and none of them will date you?
Yeah, but these guys
don't want American women.
They want women that they can
treat like slaves.
You don't know that. Yes, I do.
Half these women
don't even speak English.
Please don't tell me
you feel sorry
for the losers trying
to buy a wife online.
If you want to feel bad for
someone, feel bad for these girls.
They have no idea
what they're getting into.
There's one in particular
you need to see.
Oh, she's pretty. Yes, she is.
And with her help, we're going
to get a much better look
at these inadequate,
pitiful guys.
Wait.
You faked that? Uh-huh.
This is going to be
our best blog post ever.
All you care about
anymore is this blog.
People love us. We are
getting so popular.
Okay, we're not popular,
the blog is.
No one even knows
we're behind it.
Eventually they will,
if they want to make a TV
show or something about us.
The odds of that happening--
Stop being so negative, Avery.
It's happened to
worse blogs than ours.
Besides, it's fun.
Right? Definitely.
Okay, help me finish setting up
the rest of her profile.
What is she looking for
in a mate?
Someone with a sense of humor.
Yeah?
I'm here for Wanda.
I called earlier.
I brought 300, like you said.
For anything I want.
More, if it's kinky stuff.
Wrong house.
It's across the street.
Oh. Yeah.
Sorry, man.
Gifts for my two besties.
Kaylie, what's this for?
My mom and I found them
when we were shopping,
and they reminded me of us.
I love it, Kaylie. Thank you.
Me, too. I'm never
going to take it off.
We match.
This is our last year together
before we all go off to college.
We've been friends
since the third grade,
and I want us to stay
as close as we are now forever.
I think that's the sweetest
thing you've ever said.
Oh, my God, you guys.
Someone responded to our
fake profile. What?
What a total loser!
He's a computer programmer.
- What's his username?
- "BigJohnny."
Like, as in a big Johnson?
- Or a big nerd.
- Look how ugly he is.
Wow, he's really... gross.
"Hi, Diwata. My name's John.
"I'm 32, and I live in Ralston.
"I wanted to say hi
"because I think
you're very beautiful,
"and we think we both
seem to be looking
for that special someone
to spend our lives with."
"For me, I'm looking for the
right girl who will appreciate
what I can offer and will let
me treat her like a princess."
She'll have to
kiss the toad first.
"My pictures are current.
Please read my profile,
"and if you think you'd like
to get to know me better,
e-mail me back. John."
This is priceless.
We have to respond.
Can't we just finish the movie?
We need content.
Content equals followers.
And followers equals...
Everything.
Let's respond. Okay.
Hey, Diwata.
Um, I've been working
on this for you.
Pleased to meet you.
Now it's your turn.
Fantastic.
Very good. Very good.
Frederick Douglass,
Narrative of a Slave.
Who's read it?
Okay. What was Douglass
trying to tell us about slavery?
Douglass explains how
slavery is humiliating.
Kaylie, I'll take the phone.
No, Mr. Brixton! I
promise to turn it off!
You're my favorite teacher
in the whole world.
Yeah, give me the phone.
You know the rules.
Okay. What was Douglass
trying to tell us about slavery?
Honestly, I hate school.
The idea of doing this
for four more years
makes me want to slit my wrists.
Yeah, but you can't just
not go go college.
Yeah, I could,
if we sell the blog.
Kaylie, I think you're taking
this thing way too seriously.
I've done the research.
It happens all the time.
People start blogs
and YouTube channels,
and they get turned into books
and movies and TV shows.
The way ours is going,
it could happen.
And what if it doesn't?
I just can't do
four more years of this.
Here you go.
Let me know if you guys
need anything else.
I'm Wendy. Thank you, Wendy.
Hoo-hoo!
Damn! She got me
all hot and bothered.
Can we go now?
Not till we've hooked you up
with one of these stunners.
I have a girlfriend now.
Since when?
Here.
She's from Manila. Hot!
How did you meet her? Online.
Super pretty, huh? Yeah-eah-eah.
You should call her up
and tell her to come down.
Oh, she's...
she's super busy
taking classes and stuff.
You should invite her
to the company party.
Yeah.
Are you ever gonna
come get your box?
The delivery guy left it
with me over a week ago.
Expensive software.
Mm-hmm.
I opened it on accident.
I thought it was
something I ordered.
You and me should
get together sometime.
I'll give you a good price.
I have a girlfriend.
How come I've never
seen her, then?
She... lives abroad. Well, then,
you need someone nearby to keep those
pipes working while she's gone.
Can't get any closer
than across the street.
Right? I have to go.
Oh, my God. You aren't
gonna believe this.
What? He just sent
a plane ticket.
Who? Big John,
so Diwata can come visit him.
One-way ticket
from Manila to L.A.
for some ridiculous
office party.
Are you kidding? 830 bucks,
plus a $600 agency fee
that I made up.
Idiot. Seriously?
Do you know what
this means for the blog?
The video we're gonna get when
he shows up at the airport,
and no one comes off the plane?
That's, like, a lot of
money he can't get back.
Who cares? This will make us
the most popular prank
site in the country.
I suppose.
Come on. You're acting
all whiny like Avery.
Have you told her
about the plane ticket yet?
Not yet. Don't say anything.
The way she's been acting lately,
I'm afraid she might blow it.
Uh, Kaylie,
this isn't how we
usually get to the mall.
This is so messed up.
Just tell her.
Wait. Tell me what?
Fine.
We're not going to the mall.
Okay, then where are we going?
Trust me.
This is gonna be awesome.
Flight 477 from Lisbon
has now arrived.
Please tell me
what we're doing here.
Just come with us. You're
going to ruin the surprise.
Oh, my God. That's him!
- I don't get it.
- Big Johnny thinks that.
Diwata's arriving
from the Philippines.
Are you kidding me?
He even made a sign.
Mandy, go get a pic
with your phone.
Maybe she's right.
We shouldn't post this.
Oh, my God.
I have worked too hard
to let you guys ruin this.
Seriously, Mandy,
go effing tape it!
Kaylie, this is
just plain cruel.
Don't feel sorry
for his ugly ass.
Why do you have to
make it worse for him?
I am doing this on behalf of all
women on that mail-order site.
He deserves some girl
that looks like a model?
He doesn't.
Would you even kiss that?
Hell, no.
Look, I don't know why those
girls are on that site, okay?
What I know is that you're
taking this way too far.
It's not okay to just hurt
people so you can sell
your stupid blog and
avoid going to college.
Well, guess what?
3,238 followers
disagree with you.
What happened to you? You
didn't use to be this way.
What way? It's like you don't
care about people anymore.
If they get hurt, so what?
This guy would do
the same damn thing to you
if he was clever enough
to think of it.
Don't think he wouldn't.
He's basically
trying to buy a wife.
So, screw him.
Where are you going?
Home!
It's an airport. I'm
sure I can find a cab.
What's going on? She's
pissed off about the prank.
Just let her go.
This is perfect.
Honey, what just happened? Why
did you just come home in a cab?
I got in a fight with Kaylie
and decided to come home.
From her house?
No, from the airport.
What?
Yeah, uh,
can we maybe talk
about it over dinner?
Yeah, yeah. Of course.
Okay. Okay.
♪♪
Are you alone?
Oh, uh, yeah.
Where's the posse? Not sure.
Avery.
Can I please talk to you?
See you later.
Uh, I have to get home. Please?
I agree the joke was too much.
I haven't even checked the
blog since she posted it.
I feel so guilty.
Does Kaylie feel bad?
She's consumed with the blog.
Look, it's not just that.
You guys had no right
to trick me into
going to the airport.
You're right. I'm sorry.
Why do you go along with her?
She's the reason we're popular.
Who cares about that?
You don't understand what
it's like on the other side.
I do, and it sucks
being the fat kid
who brings kimchi in her lunch
that everybody makes fun of.
Then you of all people
should've known better.
You're right.
She's scared.
You and I are both
going off to college,
and she knows she's
going to be left behind.
What do you think
these are all about?
She can go to college, too.
She just doesn't want to.
Who knows? Maybe
she really can sell it,
and we get famous
and make lots of money.
Stranger things have happened.
You're kidding yourself.
We've all been friends
too long to just end it.
Talk to her.
She cares a lot about you,
and I know you care
about her, too.
Hi, I'm Nick.
Hey, um, oh, come on in.
Nice place.
Can I, uh, sit down?
Oh, sure, yeah.
So, uh, I like to get business
out of the way first.
It's 200.
Yeah. Yeah, uh...
So what did you have in mind?
Uh, I-I'm not gay.
That's fine.
Gay, straight--
Doesn't matter to me.
No, I-I mean I don't want
any sort of sex from you.
I wanted to hire you
for something else.
I'm just trying to
play a little joke
on, on my niece.
I see Trevor accepted
your friend request.
Look, sorry about
the whole airport thing.
It was totally wrong
to trick you into going.
Let's just put it
behind us, okay?
No, I don't want any part of it.
Fine.
Your friendship is
more important to me
than this stupid blog.
I just want the three of us
to go back to the way
we used to be.
Really?
I miss you.
All right.
You have to go to that party
while your mom's in Phoenix.
I haven't been to
a party in forever.
We just went to Justin's party
less than two months ago.
Yeah. Excuse me.
Do any of you have a tissue
in your purse or something?
I got this grease
all over my hands.
I do.
Thanks.
I'm Nick, by the way. Kaylie.
I'm Mandy. Avery.
Hi. So...
why haven't I seen you
around here before?
I just moved here
from Pittsburgh.
That's cool.
Well, so what do you guys
do for fun around here?
You got it?
Yeah. Kaylie Mack.
I'll give you my number, too.
Cool, cool. Well,
catch you guys later.
Nick...
Avery's having a party
at her house this weekend,
if you want to come.
Maybe. Text me the details.
Kaylie, what are you doing?
I'm not having a party.
You have to.
First of all, Mandy,
I saw him first.
No, you didn't. he talked to all
three of us at the same time.
I gave him the tissues,
so I get first dibs.
Guys, it doesn't matter anyway.
Got it.
And...
they invited me to
a party this weekend.
Wow.
What about Trevor? It's the perfect
chance to be alone with him.
It won't be a rager.
Just a few intimate friends.
Please?
That guy is gorgeous!
Okay, fine.
But just a few friends,
and we're not
calling it a party.
All right. Take it easy.
Yeah.
Bye, Mom. Have a safe trip.
Okay.
I will text you as soon as
I get to the hotel in Phoenix.
Okay. Love you. Love you, too.
Bye.
Party of the year.
Stop using the "P" word.
We should do something
for the blog tonight.
Play a joke.
Nothing mean. Right, Avery?
How about we put water
in the vodka bottles
and see who acts drunk
when they're not?
Okay, just no tricks
on Trevor, okay?
Fine. Kaylie?
Okay.
Avery, he didn't show.
Who, Nick? Of course I mean Nick.
He said he was gonna come.
Okay, just text him.
That'll make me look desperate.
So just wait a little longer.
I don't know,
maybe he's running late.
Sorry. Yeah, I just
can't stand her.
Yeah, I know.
Just give her a chance.
She's trying.
You're gonna go
meet him by yourself?
You don't even know this guy.
I know he's hot.
What if he's
a rapist or something?
You can't rape the willing.
I'm just kidding. That's why
I want you to go with me.
And leave the party? No way. Tell
him to get his ass over here.
We can convince him in person
and then come back.
Okay, fine.
Only because I don't want you
to end up dead in a ditch
or something.
Aw, such a good friend.
Let's go.
I guess Avery and Trevor
are together now.
Guess so.
She could do so much better.
You know, you, uh, haven't
shown me your room yet.
I don't think I could just
leave everybody alone.
Oh, come on. They'll be fine.
Okay. Um, I just need to
tell Mandy she's in charge.
Go down the hall, and it's
the last door on your left.
Okay.
Well, then, I'll see you there.
Where is he?
He's in there. Let's go.
Attention, skateboarders
and visitors,
we'll be closing
in about 10 minutes,
so please gather your
equipment and belongings
and make your way
to the front door exit.
Thank you.
Nick!
This is creepy.
I think we should
go back to the party.
I'm getting a really weird vibe.
Let's just check downstairs.
Come on.
No one's here.
Maybe he's playing a joke
on you or something.
This isn't funny, Nick.
Get your ass out here!
We're leaving!
I'm leaving now.
This is effed up.
Mandy! I'll be in the car.
You know what?
You're an a-hole.
Perfect.
Mandy...
Where the hell is she?
The skate park is closing.
What are you doing out here?
I was just texting my friend.
Have you seen her? She was
here a few minutes ago.
Nope. Like I said,
the park is closing.
Let's move it along.
"Went home"?
How?
Move it along.
I'm leaving.
You can go take
your doughnut break now.
♪♪
Three missed calls?
Damn it.
I hate to do it,
but I will call the police
if you don't turn it down and
move the cars... Fantastic.
Hey, uh, sorry, guys.
Party's over.
I don't know
if the cops were called,
so if you're sober, you
should probably leave now,
and if you're not,
then, I don't know,
I'll try and find
you guys a ride home.
So...
out.
Thank you.
What's going on?
What do you think?
Neighbors complained.
Did Mandy come back?
No, I haven't seen her.
Where were you, anyway?
It has to be her playing a joke.
That little bitch!
What are you talking about?
That jerk-off Nick
texted me and told me to go all the
way out to the skate park to meet him
and then didn't show.
Mandy goes with me,
then disappears.
Texts me a few minutes later
and says she went home.
Does that mean she walked?
From the skate park,
that's, like, five miles.
Or maybe Nick drove her home.
Screw her! It's
probably for the blog.
Mandy wouldn't do that.
Nick is probably just an ass.
She wanted him from the start.
I think you should just
go look for her, okay?
I got to get this place cleaned
up and Trevor out of here.
Where's Trevor?
Passed out in my mom's bed.
I'll go kick him out.
Oh, my God!
Look! You pissed yourself!
Go to hell, Kaylie.
What happened? Ask your friend.
Kaylie, you promised
not to play a trick on him.
It's water. He's fine.
I can't believe
I gave you another chance.
You don't even realize
what you did wrong.
Seriously, I'm done.
Just get the hell
out of my house.
You know what?
That's fine with me.
I don't want to be
friends with you either.
You're not even fun
to be around.
All you do is bitch and whine.
It's getting really old.
Do you remember me?
I remember you, too.
I'm sorry! I'm so sorry!
Be... quiet!
I just have one question.
Why did you do that to me?
I don't know. It was so stupid.
Kaylie came up with the idea,
and we thought it would
be funny, I guess.
It was mean. We
shouldn't have done it.
It was Kaylie's idea. I see.
So...
if I had to pick
one person to blame,
that person would be Kaylie?
What are you gonna do to me?
If you let me go, I swear I
won't say anything to anyone.
We'll call it even.
We played a joke,
you played one.
Except this isn't a joke.
This is very real.
The pain I felt at the airport
was real.
And you're soon
gonna understand pain.
I'm so sorry.
We never wanted to hurt you.
I think you did.
I'm pretty sure
it's why you did it.
I swear to God.
We never even considered it.
It was just a stupid thing
for this stupid blog.
It's my turn now...
to be mean.
Oh, that's great, Bunny.
As you know, Bunny
has won $17,380!
What the...
Don't move...
Kaylie.
The problem with
these smart systems
is they aren't that smart.
Sounds convenient, doesn't it,
to control everything
with one device?
Now I control everything.
Please don't hurt me!
We'll give you your money back
or anything else you want!
Hurt you?
All you care about is yourself.
No more pranks, Kaylie.
Your moment of truth is here.
Mandy!
Help!
Someone, help!
Someone!
Help!
This is your fault.
He's gonna kill us,
and it's your fault
because of that stupid blog!
Mandy...
where are we?
I don't know where we are.
Hello?
Avery, this is Brandi Kim.
Is Mandy with you?
No. She was here
for a while last night,
and then she left with
Kaylie and didn't come back.
Well, Mandy didn't
come home last night.
I just tried Kaylie, and she's
not answering her cell phone.
So, they went out to
meet this guy, Nick,
and Kaylie said that
Mandy texted
saying that she was
going home by herself?
Yeah, something like that.
Okay, do you have
any texts from this Nick?
No. Mandy and Kaylie
were the only ones
to get his number.
I think they'd been
communicating over Snapchat.
So, the messages are
probably gone anyway.
Yeah. How did you meet this guy?
He came up to us last week
at the skate park,
and he told us that he was from
Pittsburgh and didn't know anybody.
What day was this? Tuesday.
Oh, I think he actually
might be in a picture
that I took of Trevor--
Hold on.
Yeah, look, this is all I have.
It's not very good, but...
Okay.
Thank you. This'll help.
It's no use.
They won't come off.
Shut up!
Oh! Where are they?
I want to know
why you think it's funny
to hurt someone.
Maybe we should let
Kaylie answer,
since this was all her idea.
My idea? Yeah.
That's what Mandy said.
It was your idea!
We didn't even know you bought the
plane ticket until after she told us.
- Shut up, Mandy!
- Answer me--
Why is it funny
to hurt someone?
We didn't think it was going to
hurt anyone when we started.
It was just fun pretending to be
a fake girl online
and seeing what guys say.
Has anybody ever hurt you?
You've never been hurt.
Do you know what
the word "pariah" means,
Kaylie?
Pariah?
Avery?
It means someone
who's an outcast.
Yeah.
It's someone that...
the beautiful people
treat badly because
they aren't beautiful.
Beautiful like you.
Avery?
Hello?
Rihanne, it's Jenny Mack.
Are the girls with you?
Well, I just walked in,
but I'm sure Avery's here.
Avery?
The police are here. I came
home this morning to find
our security system down,
all the power was out,
and Kaylie's gone, but her car,
her purse, her cell phone
are still here.
And there were messages
from Brandi Kim.
She left them on her cell.
They think that Mandy
was abducted last night.
Avery? She's not here either.
This can't be happening.
I kept thinking...
what would it take to teach
these girls a lesson,
to show them the harm
that their jokes can cause?
Get away from me,
you disgusting creep!
And then I remembered something
my father used to say.
He'd say, "You couldn't
know a person's life
until you've walked
in their shoes."
And when I was little,
I thought that meant
you had to put their shoes on.
And now I realize
that he meant it
in a figurative way.
You are as stupid
as you are ugly.
Kaylie, stop it.
You really are so pretty.
You must be used to getting
everything that you want.
John...
when we played that stupid joke,
you were just some guy online. We
didn't know anything about you.
So that makes it okay?
No. When we saw you
at the airport,
we felt really bad
about what we did.
So bad, you put the video online
for the whole world to see it.
So why'd you bring us here?
So you can sleep with us?
So you can finally experience
having sex with something
other than your hand?
Kaylie...
Stop saying that stuff!
Even though you don't have
control, you think you do.
I'm pretty sure that'll
change soon enough.
John, whatever you have planned,
it's not worth
going to jail for.
The women here,
they think they're
better than men.
All women want
is trips
and jewelry
and nice dinners,
and then they want you
to sleep on the couch
while they sleep in your bed.
How is that fair?
It only happens here.
In other parts of the world,
women are grateful for
everything that you give them,
and they love you
for your personality,
not for your looks.
I told you he just wanted
a female slave.
I did not!
I would've treated
her like a queen!
And I would've taken her dancing
and bought her flowers
and made her breakfast in bed.
I think you would make
a great husband.
But...
you'll never get the chance
if you kill us.
Is that what you want?
A great husband?
Someday.
I'm not gonna kill you.
Then what are you
gonna do, John?
Please let us go.
You'll see.
Did your daughter
mention anything to you
about this guy they met
at the skate park, uh, Nick?
No. No, never.
Well, do you know anyone who might
want to harm Avery or her friends?
No. For any reason?
No.
I mean, Avery's been upset
with Kaylie lately.
They've sort of
been on the outs.
Why is that? Something about
a prank that Kaylie was playing,
some sort of secret blog.
A blog?
Yeah. Yeah, no, yeah, yeah,
I can bring all three--
All three tonight.
Just tell me when and where.
Yeah.
Okay.
He...
Freakin' God.
Mandy,
shut the hell up.
I hate you so much right now.
He's gonna kill us.
I just know it.
I'm not going down
without a fight.
I'll rip his throat out
if I get the chance.
We just need to wait
for the right moment.
It's been taken down.
Well, maybe tech can
roll back the site.
It's time to go.
Wait, where are you taking us?
You'll see.
Please don't kill us.
Please? You're gonna live.
Just a very different life
than the one you planned.
One where girls like you
aren't the one in control.
All right, let's see 'em.
No!
No! Don't touch me!
Stop!
Truck.
Good. The other two?
Where-Where's the money?
We get the girls, and then you get paid.
That's the deal.
No, no, that isn't the deal.
I want it now, and then you
can get the other two.
Unlock the car.
I'm taking the girls.
Be happy you get to live.
Let's go. We got one.
We can't leave Kaylie!
We have to go back!
Two counts of prostitution,
a few minor drug charges.
Petty hustler.
And there are no videos
of him on the girls' blog?
None that I saw.
Do we know where
this guy hangs out?
We're working on it now.
Thanks, Ray. You got it.
Please!
Please! Please...
Schumaker. They found your boy Nick.
He's on his way to the station.
Oh, great. Ray, thank you.
I'll be here.
He's gonna come back
and kill us.
I know he is. Stop.
The detective, she's smart.
She's gonna find us.
What do you think those men are
doing to Kaylie right now?
Thinking about that stuff
isn't gonna help anything.
We need to focus on how
we're gonna get out of here.
Why would they take her?
Her mom has money.
Maybe for ransom?
Those men are sex traffickers.
Was trying to sell us
into prostitution.
That's why I need you to focus on
how we're gonna get out of here.
John, I know you're standing
at the door. Open up.
I have another box.
Just... Just leave it.
I saw you holding your arm.
Are you okay?
I'm fine. Can I have
my box, please?
But you don't look fine.
You're bloody.
What the hell happened?
That looks nasty.
Please go away!
Let me drive you to the doctor.
I can't go to a doctor!
I just need it to stop bleeding
so I can go...
I have to take care
of something.
What do you mean, you
can't go to the doctor?
Were you doing
something illegal?
John, listen.
I've got friends
that can help you.
They don't ask questions,
they don't go to the cops.
What kind of friends?
All kinds.
Anything you need done.
Why don't you tell me
how you got cut?
John, listen. Whatever
it is, I can help.
I need...
I need to find someone that
can get rid of two girls.
Kill them?
Sell them.
I don't want them dead.
I want them sold.
I had a deal with some
guys I found underground,
but it didn't work out.
What do you mean, "underground"?
Tor. Silkroad. Darknet.
It doesn't matter.
They were gonna give me ten grand
apiece, but they scammed me.
If you know someone that can
do that, that can take them,
then I can split
the money with you.
Yeah, I know someone.
He'll want to see them first.
That's, that's fine. I just
want to get it over with.
Where are they?
There're not here,
but I can bring you to them.
Okay.
I'm gonna grab my cell,
call them first,
make sure we can
bring them tonight.
He gave me a couple bucks,
asked me to help him
play a prank on his niece.
So, what else can you
tell me about him?
Nick...
listen,
I think you could use
a friend on the force,
and that's me.
But I need your help.
Or I can charge you
as an accessory.
All right, look.
I met the guy at a
house out in Ralston.
I might still have his
address in my phone.
Find it.
You hear that? Someone's coming.
Where are we going?
You'll see.
Hey, bitch, don't
even think about it.
Don't even think about it.
Let's go.
Come on.
Get out! Let's get the hell out!
Mandy, get her gun!
- Come on, let's go!
- Stop!
Avery!
Come on!
Mandy!
911. What's your emergency?
Hi. Um, my name
is Avery Lindstrom.
Mandy Kim and I
have been kidnapped,
and we're hiding in a
warehouse, I don't know where,
but he has a gun. You said "he."
Is there one person
or more than one?
Shh! He's coming.
He just left, but we're hiding,
I don't know, in some room
or something, I don't know.
Mrs. Lindstrom,
Nick gave us information
on the man who hired him,
so we're checking out
his house now.
Are the girls there?
No, but we're combing the place...
Detective?
Detective Schumaker,
I've got Avery Lindstrom,
one of the missing girls,
on the line.
One of our girls?
Just give me a second, okay?
Don't go away.
Can dispatch put the call through to me?
Copy that.
You're connected, Schumaker.
Avery? Yes.
This is Detective Schumaker.
Are you hurt?
No, and neither is Mandy,
but Kaylie's gone.
Some men took her, and this phone
belongs to a woman he killed.
Okay, honey, now, listen. We're
sending units out to you now,
but I need you to stay on
the phone a little longer.
I'm going to patch you
through to your mother.
Hold on.
Mrs. Lindstrom. Yes?
I have Avery
on the phone for you.
- Hello?
- Avery?
Mom? Avery, honey, are you okay?
Did he hurt you?
No, Mom, I'm okay. I'm so sorry.
Honey, it's okay. It's okay.
It's okay, honey. I love you.
I love you, too.
Is it possible for you two girls
to get out of the building?
We don't know where he is?
We'll try.
Keep the phone on, and if it's
not safe, stay where you are.
Okay.
Keep going!
Avery!
Hey! They're here!
- I've got the girls.
- What is your 10-20?
31225 Industrial Park Road West.
Suspect is still inside.
Shots fired, my location!
10-76 sending in.
Stay down. Help is on the way.
Schumaker. Heidemann. Hey.
Hey. That's how we found him.
Pretty sure it's John.
Can't tell by
looking at his face.
Close-range gunshot
wound to the head?
Self-inflicted.
Give forensics a couple of hours
before you call the coroner.
I'm gonna visit Avery
at the hospital.
Hopefully, we can figure out who
took the other girl. You got it.
So, Avery, you said you
saw two men take Kaylie.
Did you see anything else
in the area?
Did you see their faces?
Avery! Oh, Avery!
Mom! Oh, honey! Oh, my God!
I love you.
It's been seven months,
and no one has seen
or heard from Kaylie.
The police found nothing
in John's stuff
that would tell them
who the men were that took her.
They believe he found them
on the Darknet,
but that's all they know.
Suddenly, everyone was
so interested in John,
who he was,
why he did what he did.
People become
more interested in you
after you do something horrible.
It's so hard to believe. I mean,
the John I knew, he would
never do something like this.
He would never hurt a fly.
He was so shy and kind. He...
This was the last thing
we expected from him.
The media never reported
how we really met John.
They said he found us
using social media.
The reality is, we found him.
We preyed on him.
If you poke a lion with a stick,
is it his fault
for attacking you?
I'm not saying any of us
deserved what he did.
Nothing gives you the right
to hurt someone else,
even if they bully you.
But that goes for Kaylie, too.
She had no right
to hurt him either,
and if she hadn't,
maybe she'd still be here.
♪♪