Subtitles by explosiveskull
www.OpenSubtitles.org
I think
I made a mistake.
Why do you
have to finish it?
You answer me please.
Just answer me.
Why do you have to finish it?
You can't come to your...
To your...
Jess, I
love you most, okay?
Please, someone.
Anyone, if you know anything
about her disappearance.
What's up, minions?
DropTheMike here at the
Pasadena suicide bridge.
How awesome is this?
In 1913, the bridge
was built and since then,
100 people have leapt
to their deaths,
the most famous of
which is Myrtle Ward.
Myrtle Ward is famous for
having tossed her infant
off this bridge and
jumping shortly thereafter
so that they could spend the
afterlife together forever.
Isn't that sweet?
In a remarkable twist
of fate, thick branches
slowed the infant's
fall to the ground
and it landed mostly unharmed.
Myrtle wasn't so lucky
though and people say
that you can still hear
her ghost wandering
beneath the bridge at night,
searching for her newborn child.
All right, guys.
That's it for this installation.
I am DropTheMike,
subscribe to my channel.
I post sick and twisted
new videos every other...
What's up, minions?
It's DropTheMike here.
Some of you sick bastards
have been asking me
for special behind
the scenes extras.
Well follow me this way,
if you dare.
This is my little baby.
Little J Dahmer.
Hey, hey, do your impersonation
of a strangulation victim.
Mwah.
And right over here is my always
effervescent fiance, Jess.
Say hi to the multitudes, baby.
All right as you can see,
Jess is an incredibly talented
artist right over here.
She's also a nurse on the
west side of Los Angeles.
A truly noble career path
if I do say so myself,
unlike yours truly.
Hey, so my followers have
a few questions for you.
Wanna answer them?
Yes, you do.
Oh, come on, come on,
don't do this to me.
Loosecanon99 wants to know
do you approve of
what Mike does?
Ugh,
no.
I haven't seen one of
his films in a while.
They're just unsettling
for my taste, you know?
But he loves what he does and
it keeps him off drugs, so.
So she thinks.
Okay, get out of here.
I got work to do.
Ow!
Ladies and gentlemen and
everything in between,
this is my inner sanctum.
This is where my wicked
brew is concocted
and the witch stirring
the visual pot
is none other than my editor
and occasional cohort,
the amazing Nic.
Say hi to the minions, Nic.
She loves me.
After each shoot, the DP and
I unload all of our video
and sound cards to her
and she has carte blanche
to edit them as she sees fit.
And of course, last but
not deceased,
is my DP, which is
Director of Photography
for your idiots out there,
and very best friend.
The one and only Christopher.
Hey, Chris, turn the
camera around and show them
your ugly mug, okay?
Gotcha, didn't I?
No, this is not Christopher.
This is Fred the Head.
He's great, isn't he?
Okay, Chris, we
can show you now.
We can introduce you.
Okay give me the camera, good.
Separated at birth?
I think so.
You're such a dick.
Stop!
Talk about good head,
right, friend?
Stop, Nic!
God, will you guys
get out of here?
Oh, Jesus Christ.
I'm gonna cut...
What's up, minions?
Okay, really, all
joking aside, I just had
an incredible phone call
with the super popular
clothing store, Haute Gothic.
They just told me that if I
can get 50,000 subscribers
by the end of Halloween weekend,
they're gonna sponsor me
a whopping $250,000.
That is 250 grand, people!
It's incredible.
Okay, so this is
where you come in.
I need you to comment
below and tell me
what horrifying locations
you think I should do
a super scary Halloween
edition vlog, okay?
It's gonna be sick.
If you don't do it, Fred
the Head will be so sad.
Love you guys and
I'll see you later.
DropTheMike out.
What's up, minions?
Bet you're wondering
what I'm doing
in this seemingly peaceful
middle class street.
Sweet costume, dude.
Uh, excuse me,
I'm Michael Myers.
I may look like a troll
doll, but I'm Michael Myers.
Many people don't know
this, but real life
serial killer David
Olmos dumped one
of this many victims' dead
bodies in this street.
It was in this exact spot
that the neighbors found
her dismembered body in a
trash can the next morning.
Oh my God, Chris.
Chris.
She's still here.
Oh, it was too soon.
She was so innocent, it's so...
oh, that feels real good.
Oh, this wig is real itchy.
Anyways, two weeks ago, I
asked you guys to tell me
where you thought
that I should shoot
my Halloween vlog coming up,
sponsored by Haute Gothic.
Shhh.
The response was overwhelming
I couldn't believe
how much you guys wanted to
see me at the winning location,
which is the Lenox Hotel.
Per your requests, I'm gonna
be spending the entirety
of Halloween weekend
there with my crew.
The hotel happens to be where
Night Crawler, David Olmos,
lived and is also where
a tourist, Meghan Kim,
famous for her elevator
video recently met
her untimely demise.
We're shooting the
entirety of the vlog there.
And we have an expert
here to tell us more
about this petrifying place.
That person is.
My friend and haunted hotel
historian, Wallace Fleischer,
author of the book "The
Many Curses of Hotel Lenox."
Please join me in
welcoming the one and only,
the singular sensation,
Wallace Fleischer.
Good evening, sire.
Thank you very much.
I'm not gonna kiss your hand,
you're not wearing a ring.
But Wallace, thank you
very much for having us
into your home today,
we appreciate it.
You're more than
welcome, Mike.
Hi, Chris.
Hi, Wallace.
So why did you write
about Hotel Lenox?
I began to understand
why it was so frightening
after I learned more
about its sordid history.
The Hotel Lenox is
downtown LA near where
Skid Row area is.
They changed the name
of the hotel many times
over the years because of
its very bad reputation,
especially what happened
a few months ago
with the hotel, which
I'll go into in a moment.
It was built in 1927,
there were 123
people who were either
murdered or killed themselves
in this hotel.
Now, the infamous David Olmos.
Ah, yes.
- The Night Crawler.
He stayed on the
14th floor in 1985.
Managed to murder 14 people.
He lured people into his
room, mostly prostitutes,
which then he would dismember.
But not before he had completely
stripped their bodies,
tortured them, and had sex
with their dead bodies.
The neighbors, they'd heard
this humming sound at night
of the electric hacksaw
but they didn't know
what it was for so no
one ever said anything.
Wow!
A devil worshiper.
How cliche.
Yes, that's a
satanic symbol of Babylon.
Follow Satan, you will.
So all joking aside,
could you tell us what happened
to David Olmos?
Well, he cut his
throat in jail.
Wow, I think this sets
the stage beautifully.
I wanna thank Wallace
Fleischer for enlightening us
on the hotel's history.
Thank you very much
for your time, Wallace.
And be sure to keep
track of us as we gear up
for our three nights
at the Hotel Lenox,
we'll be posting
- our vlogs beforehand...
- Wait.
You're not staying there?
You're not
gonna listen to a thing
Wallace has to say, are you?
About not staying
at the hotel?
Are you kidding me?
Dude, it's ooga booga nonsense.
You know, there's no
such thing as spirits,
and ghosts, and blah blah blah.
You do a
vlog about spirits,
and ghosts, and blah blah blah.
Yeah, I also
watch horror movies.
That doesn't mean that
I believe in everything
that I see in them.
I don't know, man.
I don't think we
should do this one.
Seriously?
Are you kidding me?
Give me the camera.
God.
What a pussy.
Look at yourself.
I mean, we have been to
so many different places
where terrible
things have happened.
Are you seriously
gonna ditch the vlog
over one hotel?
This is different.
How?
The other places we shot
outside, we never went in them.
What?
Inside, outside, what
difference does that even make?
I'm look, sorry.
I'm sorry, okay?
No, this is great.
This is exactly why
I keep you around
for this Catholic-y,
pope-y nonsense
that you were raised on.
It's a nice, new perspective.
But seriously, okay,
you were brainwashed
by some pastor, or
priest, or whatever
who had dressed up in their
nice, little robe costume,
preaching these ideas
to you so that they...
It's not made up!
I've seen ghosts.
I've seen evil spirits.
Seriously, chill out, I...
I wanna know, okay?
Just talk to me, man.
I was 10 years old.
I looked in the bathroom
and there's this
kid standing in the doorway.
His right hand,
he's holding this tabby cat
from a noose.
He drops this cat and
it starts running at me
and it's like, scratching
and clawing at my face.
I was blinded but I,
I finally reached
the light switch
and by the time I turned
it on, they were both gone.
I called my mom the next
day and I told her to come
pick me up and get
me out of there.
Wow, dude, that's terrible.
That's the most terrible
fucking story I've ever heard
in my entire life.
I mean, a fucking
tabby cat in a noose
ran at you and attacked
you in the face?
Are you kidding me?
I mean, come on.
Think about this, okay?
It is always when people
are falling asleep,
halfway between
awake and sleeping,
they are ramping into
REM cycle and their mind
plays tricks on them...
What about the
scratches on my face?
Dude, your own fingernails.
Come on, Einstein.
You know, it's nice to
know that the only two people
I've ever told this
to, you and my mother,
don't believe me.
Dude, seriously.
That cat and
that kid were real.
Yeah, okay.
Sure, whatever.
I'm not doing Hotel
Lenox, man, there's no way.
- Yes, you are.
- No, I'm not!
Yes,
you are, all right?
Tune in next week to find
out if pussy Christopher here
grew a pair of testicles.
Shut up, Michael!
Okay, guys.
So pussy Christopher threw a
wrench in the works last night.
Now, I could hire a new DP
for Halloween weekend but
he and I know each others'
work rhythms and we've been
working together
since high school.
So...
so, I'm gonna try
a different tactic.
Danni, that you?
Mike?
The one and only.
What the hell
are you doing here?
Do you got a second?
Oh gentle, gentle, Jesus.
Oh God, that thing
does not work well, does it?
Yeah.
Okay, I gotcha,
I gotcha, I gotcha.
Wow, looking good.
So what are you
doing down there?
You know the sound makes
when you drive a car, that
Uh, sure.
I was recording it
for a friend's short.
- Okay, I see, yeah.
- Don't ask.
Hey, look, I need
you Halloween weekend.
Can you turn that off?
No, I'm a vlogger.
Look, I just need you
to do third camera,
some backup sound.
Okay, what's the hitch?
What are
you talking about?
There's always a
hitch with you, Mike.
Okay, it's in a hotel
that the unenlightened claims
is mildly haunted.
And?
And I need
you to get Christopher
to do the shoot with us.
Oh.
Yeah, no, that's...
Look, look.
Christopher likes you.
Okay, he more than likes you.
Thank you for that.
So you wanna capitalize on our
friendship and his feelings.
That's just great.
Just three
days and three nights.
Okay, I'll give
you scale plus 200.
That means 200 a day.
Okay, send me the details.
Yes!
And a contract.
Of course, always.
Only the best for you.
That's why you're my favorite.
So I just got off the phone
with the Hotel Lenox's manager.
She said we absolutely
cannot shoot there
under any conditions.
The hotel's gotten
a lot of bad press
since the Meghan
Kim elevator video
and Meghan Kim's family
is now suing them.
So I don't know, I guess
I just gotta give up.
Just kidding, fuck it.
As you can see, we've decided
to shoot at the hotel anyways.
So we're packing all of
our gear into suitcases
to disguise ourselves
as tourists.
We're also gonna be wearing
hats and other things
so that people
can't recognize us.
And what's special
about this vlog is,
we're gonna have Nic
on set editing live.
How you feeling about that, Nic?
Oh you know,
absolute thrilled.
Yes, you are.
She's going to be
posting videos throughout
Halloween night so
you've gotta make sure
that you see them before the
hotel yanks 'em, all right?
And we are so excited
to have Danni on board.
Yay!
Hey, Danni, do you really
think that there are
evil spirits waiting in
the hotel, ready to pounce?
Pretty sure the only
thing waiting to pounce
is bed bugs, Mike.
That's disgusting.
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, and
we're welcoming
back into the fold
the one and only Christ-opher.
The only reason I'm
doing this is because
I'm $500 shy on rent.
Yeah, uh-huh, sure.
So Chris, why don't
you tell our sycophants
about some of the amazing gear
that you've brought with us?
We've got a couple
of security cams here,
spy cam, set up with
a button, and hat cam.
Oh, that's sick.
Where's the lens?
The lens is the left
eye of the smiley face.
Oh, that's sick.
If that's not cool enough,
we got a drone packed up
and ready to go.
Oh, no way.
That's so millennial of us.
Hey, Chris, can I borrow
that for my next sex tape?
I heard that.
Everybody, will you
please just be careful?
I don't want any of you ending
up in the ER, all right?
Kiss her!
Shush!
All right, come on.
Oh hey, hey, one
more for camera.
One more for camera.
Come on, come on.
There it is.
Get.
That was a little taste
for those of you out there
who can't get any action,
which is most of you.
Anyways, we're headed
to downtown Los Angeles.
Ooh.
This is your co-pilot, Michael.
We are now entering the first
layer of Dante's Inferno,
please make sure that your
seats are in their full upright
and missionary position.
Hey,
grab my phone charger
out of there, will you?
What the...
Yes!
Motherfu...
I spring loaded it.
Yeah,
tricked the trickster.
Well played, Slim Shady.
But just so you know,
payback's a bitch.
The nice part of downtown's
just two blocks away.
It's feast or famine down here.
Check this guy out.
Nic, give him $50 and
maybe he'll do a backflip.
Jesus!
Ow.
Does anybody know
why they put those gargoyles
on the side of
buildings like that?
It's to ward off evil.
Actually, they are there
to prevent the rainwater
from falling down
the masonary walls.
Wow, Nic.
Throwing out
knowledge sans Google.
I'm telling you,
it's to ward off evil.
I think I'm gonna go with
Nic on this one, buddy.
Sorry.
There she is.
Can you feel the
love, Christopher?
No, it
looks creepy already.
I don't see
any gargoyles up there.
Hmm, not cool.
Hey, do you
guys see that boy there?
Oh!
What the...
Okay.
Hey, dude.
I don't need my
windshield cleaned.
It's fine.
You have change?
I don't have
any change on me.
We don't have any money
in here, I'm sorry, dude.
A dollar's fine.
Dude, you
need to just leave.
I don't have
anything, I'm sorry.
You don't have to be
an asshole about it.
Whoa.
You're the asshole, dude.
I hope you die!
Did that homeless dude
just tell me to die?
Alrighty, my minions.
From here on out,
we are rolling 24/7.
We take a dump, it
better be on camera.
Great.
My ass can end up as a meme.
Whoa!
What's up, dude?
Weird deja vu moment.
Glitch in the matrix?
Yeah.
All right, the same elevator
Meghan Kim was last seen in
before she disappeared.
Creepsville.
Ooh, ooh, ooh.
These are the buttons
she pushed, too.
Hey, why are we
going up to 14?
You'll see.
Here we are.
It's not as
horrible as I thought.
Only the finest for
my fine, fine crew.
Oh, please.
The receptionist
said some of the floors
are nicer than others.
The rest of them...
Rat-infested hell holes.
Yeah, pretty much.
For like low income locals
and backpackers
and such, anyways.
All right, so Nic.
You are in room 1426.
Guys,
give her peace.
She needs to edit.
Break legs, guys.
Literally.
And us.
Guys, we're in room 1428.
Why is he so
excited about this?
This does not
bode well for us.
Well I told you guys
I had a surprise, right?
This is your present.
This is the room where,
where David Olmos lived when
he murdered those 14 people.
You're kidding?
Really?
Dude, there's no way
I'm staying in there.
Yes, you are.
No, I'm not staying in
David's death dungeon.
Dude, that was
like, 30 years ago.
Stop being such a pussy.
I resent that pussy comment.
Why is it guys always
say that when someone's
not being brave enough?
It's not a
question of being brave.
Yes, it is.
As in, they're
female-like, meaning
they're less than
they should be.
It's not a question
of bravery here,
it's a question of
being stupid or not.
Okay, look it.
It's a room, all right?
There is no scientific
data that evil spirits lurk
in physical spaces, all right?
It's what you bring into it
psychologically that matters
so let's go.
Thank you.
Okay, I want to retract my
previous demeaning statement
about the female gender.
Chris, you need to amp
up the pussy power.
Right.
Yeah!
Dude, come on.
Hello?
Nic, can
I stay with you?
I'll set my cot
up in the corner.
Come on.
Come on, it's amazing.
All right, I claim this bed.
You can sleep with
your boyfriend, Mike.
Mm, perfect.
We're gonna snuggle so much.
Hey Chris, can I get
like, an interview shot
of you with the
bathroom really quickly.
'Cause you're a piece of shit.
Ha ha.
Okay, Chris,
how does it feel to stand
in the bathroom where
David Olmos dismembered
all those bodies?
Awesome.
I can take a poop
in peace later.
Thanks, that's all I wanted.
Hey, actually, will
you grab me a water
from the mini bar?
Amazing.
Jerk!
You got me with Fred the Head.
Wait, wait, wait.
Wait.
He's gonna be our
own little gargoyle.
He'll ward off the
evil spirits, you know?
Oh yeah, if anything,
he'll tow them
right to our room like the
Death Star's tractor beam.
You're
such a fucking nerd.
Okay, guys, we
gotta get geared up.
We're losing light so we
wanna get some more exteriors
before that happens.
All right?
Over and
out the door, guys.
What's up, minions.
DropTheMike here behind the
creepy deepy Hotel Lenox.
We are in one of its
many back alleys.
Watch out for the
street juice, Chris,
it's pretty disgusting.
Right here is the
dumpster where David Olmos
would dump his
dismembered bodies.
Sweet, baby!
Oh!
Excuse me, miss.
Would you mind if I interview
you for my documentary?
Mind if I ask your name?
Hey, guys.
Check out our
neighborhood drug dealer.
Oh, shit.
Guys?
Guys.
Oh, okay.
What are you
fucking recording?
Get back here!
Hey who
was that, Danni?
One of your exes?
So funny, I thought
it was your pimp.
Not funny, guys.
Welcome back, kids.
Once again, we're
in the Hotel Lenox.
And right now, I'm
walking down the hallway
where serial killer David Olmos
would sneak to this
very fire escape.
Am I
following you on this?
Yeah, of course
you're following me.
Why are we friends
with this guy?
Are you coming?
Yeah.
Come on.
It's here that David
Olmos would perform
his satanic rituals before
heading out into the city
to find his next victim.
How unbelievably
awesome is that.
Whoa.
Mike, check out this poor guy.
Oh, somebody is not
having a good day.
Toto, we're not
in Kansas anymore.
Bad omen, dude.
Hey, did
you pack the drone?
It's in the pack.
All right, let's unload
the cards from tonight.
Nic'll take care of it
then we can rig our room
with night cams and then
get a good night's sleep
and start fresh in the morning.
A good night's
sleep in this place.
Are you high?
Nut attack.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
So this, my friends,
is a 45nm blacklight
that I got for like $100 online.
It's gonna pick up any bad
energy that might be in the room.
Meghan Kim's coming for ya.
All right.
I think though there's
any blood in here either.
What we need is one
of those ghostbuster lights.
Oh man, look at that
creepy little vent
above the sink.
I bet this is where
they could smell
Meghan Kim's body burning.
Maybe I should shove some
shish kabobs in there.
Oh wait,
hold on a second.
What?
Did you hear that?
Christopher,
I'm coming to get you.
I'm crawling up the vent.
Shut up, Mike!
Dude, there's
nothing in there.
Come on.
How's it going, Nicolai?
Buzz off.
I'm working.
That's my girl.
You know this is gonna
be like trying to sleep
in a graveyard.
Would cuddling
make you feel bett...
Hey!
- Don't touch.
- Fuck, dude.
I thought you were
gonna punch me.
Save room or Jesus.
Danni.
I think little Chrissy
Wissy needs a lullaby.
Know any?
Pwease, Danni?
Yeah!
No, no, no, no, no, no, no!
♪ Rock a bye baby
in the tree tops ♪
♪ And down will come
baby cradle and all ♪
Down will come
baby, cradle and all?
That's supposed to comfort me?
Dude, children's
stories are fucked up.
Wait, that
is really terrifying.
I never thought about that.
Hey, whatcha got there?
Anxiety.
Are you
still on those?
Yep.
I've actually got my
little ambies right here.
This shit fucks you up.
Man, you
guys are a mess.
Fuck you.
Uh, guys.
I know I joke around a lot and
shit but I just wanted to say
barricade!
This is why I
wanted my own bed!
Come to me, my children!
I'm gonna fart,
I'm gonna fart.
- Don't fart!
- I will squash you
with the pillow.
I shall squash you.
Oh, I farted so
bad right on Chris.
Did you set an alarm?
Yeah.
Okay.
Night, guys.
Goodnight.
Mike, get your
hand off of my butt!
Did you guys hear that?
That's not funny.
No, seriously.
Oh fuck, Fred fell.
Oh no.
Hang on, I got it.
That's creepy.
How did you fall, dude?
We're heading down to the
basement where Meghan Kim's
dead body was found in
the back boiler room.
And if that's not sick enough,
we're gonna try out
the drone down there.
Whoa.
Weird deja vu moment again.
You guys didn't get that?
No.
Oh get this, get this.
No trespassing.
Crap, oh seriously?
Oh, dude we need bolt cutters.
Dude, you can't
get through that.
I can figure it out.
Here, take this and set up
the camera over there, okay?
You don't have super powers
by any chance, do you?
I got pussy power.
You're not as funny
as you think you are.
Whoa.
Oh, hey there we go.
I think that I can
fit it through.
You boys struggling
to make something fit?
Ha.
I love you, Danni.
Okay.
You got the picture up.
Yeah.
It's gonna be so cool.
Okay, here we go.
Ooh, that is creepy.
Look at that.
I think I found a new
dream home for me and Jess.
This
hallway on the left?
Wait, go the other way first.
Do you see those?
Oh, that's random.
Huh, it's a cheap
date for Christopher.
Whoa, wait, wait, wait.
Check that out.
Is that a person?
Nah, it's just
another creepy mannequin.
Okay, go back to the hallway.
You're really good at this.
Your fingers are quite magic.
I know.
Those stairs?
Mm-hmm.
Can you go down them?
Descend.
Descend into the dark...
Whoa.
Where is it?
What happened to the feed?
What happened?
Dude, what did you do?
Mike, will you stop?
We have to find this
thing, I have to return it.
Can I help you?
Oh, busted.
I know what you guys
are doing down here.
Listen, I'm a huge
fan of your vlog.
You're DropTheMike
and shit, right?
Yeah, dude.
Nice to meet you.
Wow, thank you for watching.
Yeah, of course.
I love it but, you know,
I still can't let you
in there with all,
you know, all the
electrical boxes and shit.
What's your name, man?
- Tony.
- Tony, nice to meet you.
Mike.
Do you wanna...
why don't you come down here
and say hi to my followers?
What's up, guys?
Tony, you like movies?
Yeah, who doesn't?
Could you ever see
yourself working security
on a big studio lot?
Holy shit, that'd be awesome.
Yeah?
Management, she has a
meeting like, tomorrow night.
I might be able to
snag you a key then.
You can just, I
don't know, like
stick the key in an envelope
and put it through my door.
Yeah, absolutely.
Amazing.
Hey, do you have any
like insider knowledge
about the Meghan Kim thing?
You guys know about The
Elevator Ritual, right?
No, I do not know about
The Elevator Ritual.
Look up The Elevator
Ritual online,
then rewatch the Meghan
Kim elevator footage.
It'll get you
closer to the truth.
Okay, so apparently, there
is a popular Korean game
called The Elevator Ritual.
What is that?
So first, you have to have
a hotel that is at least
10 floors, which lucky for us,
Lenox has more than 10 floors.
Mmm, of course.
Then you enter the elevator
on the first floor alone.
You then go to the following
floors in this precise order.
You go to the fourth,
second, sixth,
second, 10th, and then fifth.
This is fascinating.
Okay, it gets more
interesting, okay?
When you reach the
fifth floor, a woman
is supposed to enter.
Ooh, a woman.
And then you have
mad, crazy sex.
No,
you're not supposed to look
at her or speak to her.
Then you press the
first floor button.
If the elevator
descends to the lobby,
you exit quickly
without looking back.
But, if instead of
going to the lobby,
the elevator goes
to the 10th floor,
you exit and the
woman's going to ask,
"Where are you going?"
You are not supposed to answer
her or even look at her.
What happens next?
Apparently, you enter
the other world.
And what is that
supposed to be?
I don't know but
check out Meghan Kim's video.
See that?
Wait, what
is she pressing?
Okay, so the buttons
she pressed were one,
five, 10, two, six, two, four.
That's not the order
you said, though.
No.
It is the order, just reversed.
My guess is that Meghan Kim
played The Elevator Ritual
the night before and the
night that she disappeared,
she was trying to undo it by
pressing the buttons backwards.
I'm gonna do it so you don't
need to get your panties
in a bunch, you don't
have to go with me
'cause it does say that you
have to do it alone, so.
I hope I come back, guys.
This is wrong, Mike.
Dude, relax.
Yeah, I'm with her.
All right, let's get ready.
Let's do it.
Okay, mighty minions,
it's just after midnight.
I'm all rigged up for
The Elevator Ritual.
I got my fancy little
button cam, a handheld
so we got multiple
angles for you guys,
and in the words of
cinematic thespian,
Arnold Alois Schwarzenegger,
I'll be back.
Don't wait up, kids.
Be careful.
Okay, minions.
We're about to embark
on The Elevator Ritual,
starting on the first floor.
Tony the security guard
totally hooked me up
and shut off the security
camera in the elevator
for 10 whole minutes.
Tell Jess I love her.
Okay, so as the rules mandate,
we're going to the
fourth floor first.
Fourth floor.
Going down.
That wasn't so bad.
Now we head down to two.
I feel like the
world's slowest yo-yo.
Second floor.
Going up.
Number six is next.
Sixth floor.
Going down.
Man, this game is crazy.
Second floor.
Huh, this seems familiar.
Going up.
Whoa.
10th floor.
Okay, so some faulty wiring.
But so far, all is good.
All right, final floor.
Going down.
My heart's pounding
for some reason.
Fifth floor.
All right.
Debunked.
Let's head back down to one.
What?
Let's head on home.
Oh.
You lost, son?
No, no, I'm fine.
Thank you so much.
Okay.
Okay, guys.
Looks like the
Korean elevator game
is indeed a big hoax.
I knew it from the get-go.
Where are you going?
Right there, right there.
What?
Is that the fifth floor?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Okay, right there.
What?
What, that's Meghan Kim, dude.
You didn't say anything
to her, did you?
No, no, no, of course I
didn't say anything to her.
- What?
- I was terrified.
My heart has never
beat that fast before.
It was crazy, I've
never been that scared.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
You hired a look-alike.
No, no, I swear.
I swear I did not hire
a look-alike, okay?
Dude, are you
- messing around?
- Was this you guys?
No, it wasn't us!
It wasn't you guys?
'Cause if it was, please fess up
'cause I will worship the
ground that you walk on.
Seriously, okay?
Dude, this isn't a joke!
Are you kidding me?
Look at the video, that's her.
You know what this means?
It means we're gone.
That's her.
No, no, no.
Dude, this was one
of my fucking fans!
- No, Mike.
- No.
One of my followers
dressed up as Meghan Kim
and came to the hotel
just to scare me.
- Oh, that's amazing.
- No, you're wrong!
I love you guys.
Ugh!
Dude, look at the picture.
That is her.
You're messing with
your life, Michael.
She doesn't look
like Meghan Kim, okay?
Look, we will go compare
it to the footage
from the actual elevator video.
She looks nothing
like Meghan Kim, okay?
You're wrong.
God, I'm sweating so much.
Okay, come on.
Come on, come on, come on.
Dude,
that's the same girl.
That is not the
same person at all.
I could
go either way, guys.
Come on, Danni.
Who's that?
Did you hear that?
What's going on?
Who's out there?
There's nobody out here.
Come here.
Mike,
they just knocked.
They couldn't have
hid that quick.
I don't see
anybody, dude, okay?
It's not like a...
Is anybody out here?
No,
there's nobody here.
Weird.
I don't know.
Who was it?
They ran away again.
I don't know.
Nothing?
What is this?
Another earthquake, Mike?
Dude.
They couldn't
have hid that fast.
It's probably
just Nic messing with us.
I can't believe
I'm locking in myself
in David Olmos's room.
They're really good
at this, it's amazing.
Guys, guys, guys, chill.
It's just,
it's my text messages, okay?
It's Jess, she wants
to Skype with me.
Just, you guys
have a few minutes.
Just relax, I'm
sorry it scared you.
Just chill, okay?
Hey, babe.
How's everything going, hun?
It's good.
Going awesome, how are you?
Yeah, it's really
busy right now.
They asked me to work a double,
lots of injuries, bunch
of drunks and such,
just typical
Halloween Eve stuff.
I can imagine.
Just careful around
those drunk idiots, okay?
I'll let you get back to work.
Wait.
What's up?
I wanted to wait
until you got home
for me to tell you this but
the administration
asked the entire staff
to take a blood test last week,
just usual drug testing stuff,
but they said that they found
something unusual in my blood.
Unusual?
Yeah, it's called
chorionic gonadotropin.
Jesus, what is that?
More accurately,
it's referred to
as human chorionic gonadotropin.
Well what is it?
Is it a disease?
I mean...
I'm pregnant, Michael.
You're pregnant?
Did Chris put you up to this?
No.
I'm completely serious.
I mean, they already
confirmed it.
Babe, we're gonna have a baby.
We're gonna have a baby.
Oh, man.
How does that make you feel?
Uh, my mind is
completely blown, but...
This is fantastic news.
I mean,
I mean, God, it's
unexpected as shit, but...
Are we getting this right now?
Yeah.
Listen, I gotta
go back to work, but
we'll celebrate
when you get home?
Yeah, no, we'll celebrate when
we get home, absolutely.
Love you.
I love you more.
Okay.
Yeah.
Say what?
Oh my God!
That's massive!
Oh my God.
Okay.
You heard it here first.
Wat are you guys
talking about?
- Don't worry about it.
- Nothing.
Oh, that's so...
Danni, are you getting that?
The noise?
- Yeah.
- Thanks.
What is that?
I don't know, dude.
Just chill out, please.
The hotel's like 90
years old, come on.
Trust me, my 90
year-old grandmother
made a lot worse
noises than that.
What is going on?
Danni, did you pick that up?
Yeah.
It sounds like it's Nic's room.
Dude, can you go check on her?
Dude, just...
Please just go over there.
Yeah, camera?
Always.
Hey, Nic?
Hey, do you have that
overnight footage ready yet?
I wanna see how it turned out.
Nic?
Christopher!
I have six new video
cards to download and cut.
I don't have time
for you to be playing
your stupid junior
high school games.
Now will you please
just shut up
and close the door?
Jesus, Nic.
Your nose.
Shit, I'm fine.
I am fine.
Now just give me
some freaking space!
Okay, jeez, jeez.
Ugh, now what?
Hello?
You okay, dude?
Too much wine?
Mike!
Mike, Mike, Mike!
Mike, Mike!
Jesus, dude, what is it?
This guy at the
end of the hallway, his head!
What about his head?
It bent
backwards all unnatural.
What?
Yeah, yeah.
Just completely un-human.
Wait, where?
There's nobody here, dude.
Where did he go?
He was right there.
You think he went
out the fire escape?
It's open.
Are you sure you saw someone?
Yes, I'm
sure I saw someone.
There's nobody up here, okay?
Wait,
wait, wait, wait.
What's that?
Oh, what?
What is that?
It's right on top of...
Oh!
A satanic symbol.
Oh, it's just like the
one that David Olmos
has on his hand.
Wait, isn't this
right where our room is, guys?
Oh, man.
But there's
not even room service
in this hotel, is there?
No, not for decades.
Mike, don't touch it.
Don't touch it.
It's warm.
Mike.
Oh!
Oh, that is so gross.
Oh, that's disgusting.
Oh my God, it smells.
I can't.
There's something...
What is that?
I think it's a tongue?
It's a tongue.
Don't.
Please don't touch it.
I'm gonna do it,
I'm gonna do it.
I can't.
Guys, chill, it's not human.
How do you know that?
Because it's
way too big, okay?
They would have had
to gut Gene Simmons.
Mike, I actually don't
feel comfortable with this.
We should talk
to hotel management.
Call the cops, man.
No, they'll kick us out
and we'll lose the shoot.
Look, this isn't about
ghastly spirits, they
don't exist, okay?
I'm sorry that like, you're
concerned right now but...
Look, don't tell me that
I'm overreacting, okay?
- Dude, Christopher.
- Chris, Chris.
And don't
tell me that I'm losing
some type of control.
Stop, stop.
Watch your step, watch
your step, watch your step.
All right, you've got to
admit it's pretty awesome
that the vlog is
getting interactive.
Interactive?
Yeah.
No, this is demonic.
Dude, if dastardly
demons were real,
then nobody would be
staying in this hotel.
That's what you
don't get, Mike.
It's not about them being real,
it's about you provoking them.
Okay, you need to relax.
Here.
Mama's little helper.
It's way better than
that anxiety bullcrap
you've been taking.
You'll get better dreams, too.
I would advise against that.
Hey, not helpful.
There you go.
Thatta boy.
Seriously, dude,
it's gonna help.
All right, guys.
I mean, that's
hardcore but let's...
Let's head downstairs
and we'll set a trap
for whoever's been
knocking on the door
in the morning, okay?
It's probably the same
DropTheMike follower
as whoever did
this, so, all right?
Yes, can we go?
Agreed.
Hey, Christopher said
your nose was bleeding.
Are you okay?
Nic.
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey.
Talk to me, what's wrong?
What's wrong?
Fuck.
Oh God, you're recording
this, aren't you?
No, no, no, no.
It's just a force of habit.
You'll edit it out later, okay?
Okay, please edit it out.
My God.
Hey, hey, come on.
No, no, no, I just...
Just seems like a
lot of
energies are boiling up
inside of me this weekend.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Hey listen, just
do me a favor.
I want you to get
some sleep tonight
and stop editing
for a little bit.
You can worry about
it in the morning.
No, there's gonna
be too much to finish.
No, no, no, there isn't, okay?
Look, look, everybody knows
we're on a time crunch.
You don't need to make
things as flawless
as you normally do.
I'm sorry, I'm so embarrassed.
No, no, no, no.
Don't be sorry, don't be sorry.
All right, you're gonna
get some sleep, right?
Okay.
All right.
I need way more
subscribers, guys.
Come on.
You've gotta help me out here.
Okay.
Danni, you awake?
Are you sleeping?
Far from it.
You watch Chris's
footage of the headless guy?
Yeah.
That was freaky as hell.
You want?
Everybody's
doing it, right?
Right on.
Hey, guys, so
we're waiting for my
super fan or whoever it is
that's been trolling us
and knocking on the door so
we're just doing a little
stakeout right now.
It's been super interesting
so far so I thought I'd
clue you guys in.
Anyways.
Is that a good idea?
They're just walking
away, it's fine.
Hey, Chris.
Want floor on your food.
No!
What is that?
Stop, man.
You guys are like,
awkwardly close.
You know that, right?
Eh.
Wait.
I don't think I actually
know how you guys met.
Let's see, elementary school.
No.
No, it was...
We met at the
psychiatrist's office.
Yep, we were in the...
No, you're messing with me.
No, yeah.
We were in the waiting room.
I knew you guys were
totally screwed up.
All right, boys.
What were you in for?
I don't know.
Parent shit.
I'll be right back.
Where you going?
I'm gonna give my pee ration
at the urination station.
You know, for a guy who
really likes the sound
of his own voice,
that was pretty weird.
Well, get down to the
good stuff and he bolts.
This would be like, a
really good time to tell me
why you stopped calling
me over the summer.
Are you not gonna tell me?
No.
No?
Tell me.
Okay, okay.
The pain started to
outweigh the pleasure.
Mike, is that you?
What is
that supposed to mean?
Mike, I can't see you, buddy.
You gotta...
I can't see you, it's too dark.
I loved you.
Mike, man, I am so sorry
about everything that happened.
Yo, have you been in
contact with Chris or Danni?
And I knew
that you didn't
feel the same way.
I don't know, I sound like
a Hallmark card right now.
Like a little.
Chris,
you know that you've
always been like,
a brother to me, right?
Mm-hmm.
I mean, when you
stopped calling me, it was
kind of a void for me too.
I don't know, it's a
two-way street, I guess.
Woo!
I just expelled a
foul demon out my ass.
TMI, dude.
So what were
you guys talking about?
Nothing, Mike.
Okay, whatever dude.
Hey, so I was thinking we
can finish up lunch soon.
I don't think anybody's
gonna show up right now
so we might as well.
What the...
I think I know that
kid from somewhere.
You know him?
Hey, kid!
I'll be right back.
Kid, wait up.
Mike,
where are you going?
What do you mean you know him?
Mike?
Mike!
I'm gonna go find him.
Mike?
Mike!
Where'd he go?
Do you see him?
He's gone.
Hey kid, wait.
He's not here.
Dude, I don't know.
We should check on Nic.
No, no, no, no.
Leave her alone, she
was upset earlier.
Is that...
Does that...
What?
Chris?
Danni?
Chris, turn on
your camera light.
Chris!
Danni, run!
Danni, open the door!
Do you have the key?
No, I
don't have a key.
Fuck, fuck.
Danni, open the door.
Okay, okay.
- Wait, wait.
- Do you hear that?
Wait.
Hey, kid.
Hey.
Where do I know you from?
Fold up the tripod.
Get behind me.
Whoa, oh my God.
- Oh my God.
- Mike?
What the hell are
you guys doing here?
What are you doing here?
We thought you were
gone chasing that kid.
How did you...
Did you see Olmas?
What are you talking about?
There was a guy out
there who looked like him.
I was just knocking
on room 440, okay?
Stop messing with us, Mike!
We saw him out there!
Jesus, Chris!
I am not messing with you, okay?
I was knocking on room 440
and you guys answered the door.
I don't know what's
happening, okay?
Check my footage if
you don't believe me.
What happened?
What is this?
I don't know, dude,
leftover drone footage.
No, it's not!
I remember shooting
that drone footage...
Chris, stop yelling at me!
Okay, boys, sit down!
Did you not just see that
guy outside with the hacksaw?
What guy with
the hacksaw, okay?
We got it on video, listen...
I don't care, Danni.
The hallway was empty.
I was just knocking on a
door on the fourth floor
and I don't know what happened.
What were you
doing at room 440?
I was chasing that kid, okay?
God.
Mike, what's in your hand?
Oh my God, what?
Oh my God.
What is...
Oh, that's disgusting.
Can we
please call the police?
Dude.
Dude, chill, okay?
It's probably just...
Give me a second.
It's probably just from the...
from the same animal
that the tongue and the
entrails came from, okay?
Mike, what kind of kid
carries an eyeball around?
Go down and confront them.
I'm not going to confront
a bunch of maniacs.
If we have both
cameras pointed on them,
they're not gonna do anything.
Uh, yes, they could
take our cameras,
kill us, and then
God knows what.
Fine.
I'll call Tony, okay?
And he can help us.
God, this is disgusting.
This is where he led you?
Yeah.
Oh my.
What do you want?
Sorry to
disturb you, ma'am.
Is there a young boy
staying with you?
No.
Are you making a movie?
I love movies.
No, we're making
a documentary.
Has anything strange
happened in your room
since you two
started staying here?
No.
Should there have?
Sorry for
the inconvenience.
No problem.
Have a blessed day.
Joyce!
Shut the darn door!
I don't know, man.
I swear the boy led me here.
I don't...
Hey,
Tony, clean up the mess.
Coming.
Wait, wait, wait, hang on.
Do you have the basement key?
I'll get it to you tonight.
Thank you.
I don't know, guys.
I don't know.
Michael,
is everything okay?
Yeah, yeah,
Wallace, we're fine.
Listen, has anything bad
ever happened in room 440
in the Lenox?
Absolutely.
Kay, what was it?
In the early
nineties, a detective
was called in to
investigate a crime there.
He had a spotless 10 year record
and in the investigation,
he was trying to find
out the reasoning behind
a French couple that was
bludgeoned to death in that room.
He decided to stay in the room,
hoping to lure back the killer,
but he left after three weeks
and returned to his home
in Culver City, where he
proceeded to put a knife
through his wife's
heart three times
while she was asleep and then
gouged her eyes out.
After that,
he drove the kids...
He had kids?
Yeah.
He had two boys.
How old were they?
Do you have a picture of them?
I do but it's in my book.
I'll go get it.
I'm gonna use the bathroom
while he's looking for that.
Yeah, I'll
keep an eye on him.
Well.
Holy shit.
Do you know what
happened to them?
What happened to the boys?
Well,
he took them to the room, 440
and proceeded to
put a knife through his
seven year-old's heart
and gouge his eyes out,
just like his mother.
What happened to
the younger one?
He took off down the stairs,
down to the boiler room.
The father, the
detective chased him.
When he go to the boiler room,
a maintenance man had
been working down there.
And before the detective
could get his son,
the maintenance man bashed
his head in and killed him
with a pipe wrench.
Didn't you know this story?
It's a
Hotel Lenox classic.
Thank you, Wallace.
Mike,
is everything all right?
I gotta go.
I need a minute.
Mike, you okay?
Yeah, yeah.
Stuff like that
shouldn't happen to kids.
Just give me a sec.
Chris?
Whatever you do,
keep the lens up, okay?
Chris, open up!
Chris!
Chris, Chris?
- Christopher!
- Chris.
Danni, the door's locked.
Chris, open the door.
Open the door, Chris.
Christopher, can you open it?
Open it, open it, open it.
Chris?
Are you okay?
Breathe, hey, hey, hey, breathe.
Breathe, buddy.
Chris, Chris, look at me.
Look me in the eye.
Chris, look me in the eye.
You are okay.
Chris, what
happened to your face?
It was the cat.
What do you...
Chris?
There's no cat in there.
- Chris!
- No, come back.
Chris!
Chris, come back.
Dude,
where are you going?
Please?
I'm done.
I'll give
you another $300...
This has nothing to
do with your money!
Get your hand off me!
Chris, it's just one more day.
Danni, I am done, no!
Chris!
Danni, you've got to
help me keep him here, okay?
I'm trying.
Mike, can you put the
camera down please!
Shit.
Chris?
Chris, please come back.
Come on, come on.
Christopher,
where are you going?
I'm done, Danni.
I'm done.
I can't no more.
Chris, please.
Stop, stop, stop, stop.
You can't bail on me, Chris.
You can't on Mike either.
Do you know what
just happened up there?
I can not do this anymore.
Are you sure just didn't like
scratch yourself by accident?
Are you kidding me?
Stop!
Christopher!
I was dragged in
there by something!
There is a reasonable
explanation for it.
Literally everything.
- Reasonable?
- Yes!
You're kidding me, Danni.
No!
Maybe Mike, maybe he
gave you something,
maybe it was those
sleeping pills
and all that stuff
he keeps giving you.
- Maybe it's a hallucinogen...
- This place is wrong,
this place is evil.
And if he's fucking around
with us, then he's evil, too.
I'm done with him!
Come with me.
I can't.
Come with me, I'm
leaving in one minute.
I cannot stay here anymore.
I can't walk out on
my responsibilities.
I can't just leave Mike and
Nic just hanging like that.
Danni.
Something happened.
Please come with me.
I can't, Chris.
Christopher.
Mike, are you serious right now?
Mike, I really don't feel
comfortable with this.
Danni, come on, please?
No, Chris is out
there freaking out.
Like we should really...
we should pack our
stuff, we should go.
Danni, Danni please
just stop for a second.
We can't leave.
What was that?
What just happened?
I don't know, he had
a nervous breakdown.
I am just as freaked
out by it as you are!
Then why can't
we just go, okay?
Did you see what
happened to Chris?
We have to go, Mike.
Yes, I saw what
happened to him!
But we can't leave, Danni!
I'm sorry.
Jess is making the
bulk of our income.
I make very little money off
my ad revenues for the vlog.
And now we have a
baby on the way.
Do you know how
terrifying that is?
I need this sponsorship,
you don't understand.
I need it because if I
can't provide for her,
she's going to leave me.
Maybe not in a week,
maybe not in a month,
but eventually, she's going
to realize that I am useless.
And then she's going to
leave and I cannot lose her.
I can't...
Mike, I really
wanna be here for you
as a friend right now, okay?
But I am not comfortable.
I know, I'm sorry.
Why?
Why this?
Why do we have to be here?
I don't wanna talk about it.
Mike.
Mike, look at me.
It's confusing, okay?
I just...
Things that other people
find disgusting and
terrifying,
there's a disconnect.
It doesn't affect me that way.
It feels good for me to
see those things, okay?
And I know that sounds
twisted but
that's just always how it's been
and even when my
parents adopted me,
they were terrified about it.
You were adopted?
Mike, I didn't even know that.
Apparently,
when I was living
with my birth mom,
I saw something
really disturbing
and I don't know what it was.
I feel terrible
about it but look,
we are so close to finishing.
Okay, we just...
My followers just are expecting
us to go to the basement.
That's the only thing that
we need to shoot, that's it.
Okay?
Please?
Okay.
Thank you so much.
Thank you.
I'm sorry.
Let's try to get
ahold of Chris.
Yeah.
It's crazy to think
how many people just
look across the street,
walk by everyday without
knowing all the shit
that went down here.
Yeah, it's freaky.
Hey, I'm really sorry
you got so scared.
What happened was not cool.
It's okay, it's...
I mean,
there's a reason for
everything, right?
We just gotta figure
out what it was.
Oh, Jesus.
Looks like somebody's
a big fan of you.
Dude, get out of here!
Dude, bye.
Wow, linger much.
Christopher still
not texting you back?
No.
Danni, camera.
Come on, come on, come on.
Mike.
Is that the old lady
from the room we went to?
Oh my God.
Her friend must have
jumped or something.
Oh my God.
Why would she do this?
This is different, I...
Different how?
It's not removed.
It's not like it
is in a picture.
I don't know, it's
just different, okay?
Mike,
Mike, we should go.
Why?
Just, come on.
Just walk.
Guys, get your
camera out of here.
Don't look
back, don't look back,
don't look back.
Please.
Who's following us?
I don't
know, I don't know.
I don't see anybody.
Shit, shit.
Come on, come on, come on!
Come on, come on,
come on, Danni.
Who was that?
What are you doing?
Throwing him off.
Mike, hurry.
There's
the other elevator.
Shit!
Why are we running?
Because he's
clearly after us, Mike.
I think he
just wants to scare us.
Oh fine, if you
wanna hang back and chit chat,
just be my guest.
Where are we?
These are
the low income floors.
Which way do we go?
I don't know.
That way, that way.
They made me do this.
Wait, are you okay?
I'm fine, I'm fine.
Keep going.
Mike, come on!
How do we get out of here?
I don't know.
Danni, Danni, Danni, the door.
Did you see that?
See what?
Mike, come on.
Okay.
Going down.
Oh shit.
Where's the stairs?
It's gotta be
somewhere around here.
Go, go, go, go, go.
Move, move!
Mike, where's the key?
I dropped the
key, I dropped the key.
Please go get it.
Thank you.
No, no, no, no.
Please, please.
Where's the key?
Please.
Christopher!
Holy shit, was
that the guy from the alley?
The drug dealer?
Oh, Chris.
I wanna go home please.
Chris,
thank you so much.
Hey, no one came back for you.
He ran down the fire escape.
You guys okay?
No, far from it.
I'll walk you out.
You coming?
Mike, come with us.
Please come...
I can't, I can't.
Nic's here and the equipment.
I can't leave.
Guys, guys.
Fuck.
God damnit.
Nic?
Nic, Nic, oh my God.
Stop, stop, stop, stop, stop.
Nic, come on.
Nic, Nic, Nic, come on.
Come on, come on.
Come on.
Oh my God, Nic.
What's wrong?
Look at me please?
Bad thoughts.
Okay, okay.
Come here.
No, no, no, no.
Ms. Eply?
It's about Nic.
Jesus, what happened?
Hi, Mrs. Eply, thank
you so much for coming.
I'm sorry, okay?
I don't know what
happened to her.
Honey, honey, what's wrong?
Please talk to us.
Will you drive please?
I wanna sit in
the back with her.
I'm so sorry.
I'm gonna be calling you!
Thanks for bringing her down.
Hi.
Jess.
Are you okay?
Jess, why are you crying?
'Cause I had a dream.
It was a bad dream.
I feel like you're in
danger and I need you
to come home, okay?
Jess, I'm sorry.
I can't come home yet.
Okay?
I just...
There are things that
I have to do here.
What do you have to do?
I need you here with me.
And I...
I'm scared.
Jess, come on, okay?
Please.
You know we need the
money and I can't.
I can work overtime
until I can't anymore.
I just need you to come home.
Stop!
Jess, you should never ever
have to work overtime again
and I can finish here, I just...
Mike, are you kidding?
This is dangerous and I
know that you know it too
so can you just come home?
I don't know.
I think I made a mistake
and I have to finish.
Okay, and then I'll
be home for you, okay?
I swear.
But I can't leave yet.
Why?
Jess.
Come on.
Why do you have to finish it?
You answer me please.
I can't...
Just answer me, why do
you have to finish it?
You can't come home to your...
To your baby, are you kidding?
Jess, I love you most, okay?
No, Mike.
Okay, everybody.
Live feed time.
Making the final descent.
I hope you can
see the feed okay.
It's spotty.
Keep going, Mike, keep going.
Just 330 more subscribers.
Wallace?
Michael.
Oh God, Michael.
Where are you now?
I'm heading towards
the hotel basement, why?
I beg
you, please get out of there.
I found out what happened
to the little boy
who escaped his
father, the detective.
He's the one
behind all this, isn't he?
Behind scaring us
the last few nights.
No!
No, Michael.
What?
The boy was you.
Wallace,
what did you say?
The little
was you.
Only 330
more subscribers.
All right, this looks familiar.
Get in there.
Got it.
Part of me was hoping
that wouldn't work.
This does not smell good.
Oh, there are the mannequins
that we saw on the drone.
Okay.
Guess we're going this way.
What was that?
Oh, there's nothing
in there, okay.
Okay, okay.
All right.
What the hell?
Keep going, Mike.
Keep going, keep
going, keep going.
What is that?
Oh man, the smell is
way worse down here.
The boiler.
Okay.
Here, kitty kitty.
What?
No way.
Is that our drone?
What the hell?
Oh, it's right...
It's right above the vent
where Meghan Kim was.
Who's there?
Hello?
Oh my God, oh God.
Oh God.
Who is that?
Hello?
Who turned that light on?
What was that?
If this is some sick prank,
you're doing a great job.
What the fuck?
Hey!
I know somebody's here!
Who did this?
Shit.
Shit, shit.
No way.
No way, no way, no way.
Who's watching me?
Is that?
Is that Tony's notebook?
Why is this page marked?
Oh, what the fuck?
No way.
No, no, no, no.
No, this can't be right.
Oh, God!
Who's there?
What the fuck?
Who is that?
Hey!
Who's there?
God damnit.
Oh, God.
Okay, okay, okay.
I'm not afraid of you!
Come out here!
Shit, shit.
Okay.
Oh God, oh God.
I'm sorry!
I'm sorry, I'm sorry!
Please leave me alone.
Get out of the way!
No
one's allowed in here.
Hey!
Hey, guys.
Mike here.
I'm sorry about the late post.
I know some of you have
been worried about me.
I'm streaming this live so I
can answer your questions but
before I get to that, I
wanted to show you this.
It seems I broke my hand.
In three places.
The police were
questioning me for hours
about
the body in the boiler room.
I reached 50,000 subscribers,
which I really, really
appreciate you guys for.
I've been trying to reach Chris,
and Nic, and Danni
but they don't respond.
I don't blame them.
I just, I hope they're okay.
And I haven't talked
to Jess either, but
I just, I...
I just don't know what
to say to her and...
I had a lot of time to think.
A lot of time.
And I think the best
decision right now
is to take a sabbatical
from the vlog.
I'm trying to
put this weekend behind me,
think about things.
I've
cut together some stuff from
our trip this weekend.
When I was in that basement,
I was
so alone and scared and I
just kept thinking about
how alone and scared
Meghan Kim must have been.
I'm sorry, this footage is crap.
Nic would have done a much
better job editing it.
But I...
I decided to do a short
documentary like this
on the homeless
issue in downtown.
Just, I need to try
and put something positive out
into the world for a change.
I need to try
to come to terms with what I
know about my birth father.
Which means I might
lose the sponsorship.
But if I do, I mean,
so be it.
Come on, turn on.
Fuck, fuck, fuck.
Oh fuck, fuck.
Jess!
Jess, is that you?
Yo, bitches.
Terrible Tyler here.
And today, I am stoked to find
DropTheMike's actual crib,
where his fiance
was decapitated.
Sick!
And what's even sicker is that
DropTheMike totally bolted.
Cops can't find him anywhere.
How epic is that?
Dude,
it says do not cross.
Dude.
Not anymore.
Tune in tonight where
I try to find out
what happened to DropTheMic and
I'll show you how I got
this awesome artifact.
Like, comment,
and subscribe to my
channel, bitches.
I post new videos every Monday.
Peace!
Subtitles by explosiveskull
www.OpenSubtitles.org