[triumphant music playing]
[drum beating]
[man] Watch your step!
Left, right, left, right, left!
Platoon, halt!
[all] One, two.
-Platoon will advance, right turn.
-One, two, three, one.
Platoon, stand at ease. Stand easy.
Now listen to me, the lot of you…
I'm letting you off light today,
as it's your first day in the Army,
but don't think I'm satisfied, no!
And when I give you the fall out,
don't run away with the idea that this
village is a little corner of Montmartre
because it's not!
You'll find plenty the healthy mind needs
in the precincts of the camp.
There's a NAFI here.
There's a reading room, a games room
where you can enjoy
an invigorating game of draughts.
There's a piano there too
but the manager keeps it locked up
and only lets the key out
to proper pianists.
There's a camp theater
where you can enjoy a wide variety
of entertainment from concerts to films,
all of which you will have seen before.
And tonight, I might add,
they've got a special piece
of resistance for you,
but I won't divulge it for fear
of spoiling your enjoyment.
But, whatever you do with yourselves,
remember this,
you've got a real day's work tomorrow,
so don't go
getting yourselves over­excited.
All right, platoon, attention!
Now, watch this fall out.
Smart turn right, pause of two, three,
and double off the Parade Ground.
Platoon, fall out!
[all] One, two, three. One, two, three.
Go on, double!
[soldiers running]
[trumpet blares]
[orchestra music plays]
[violin music plays]
[audience applauds]
Ah, thank you, and bravo,
Miss Qaalthrop, bravo, ladies.
Just hold it one moment, will you, please?
Thank you, ladies and gentlemen.
Many of you,
rather I should say, several of you,
may have met me officiating
at last Sunday's Church Service,
my first in this camp.
And no doubt you are wondering
what on earth I am doing now in a theatre,
in what I believe was once upon a time
known as a resort of vagabonds.
[laughs]
I don't think anyone nowadays
would describe Miss Qualthrop
and her gallant little band
in quite those terms.
I use the word "band"
of course collectively,
not musically.
Now the fact is that the CO
has put me in charge
of the entertainment here
since Major James
has been posted to Malaya,
and it is my first and very pleasant duty
to thank Miss Qualthrop
and her talented companions
for coming all the way
from Wordington here
to entertain us,
and I think we ought to show them
in the usual manner that in spite of
a lamentably small attendance,
that their journey wasn't, uh… wasted.
Come along, come along now.
Curtain, please!
Curtain!
[audience applauds]
Miss Qualthrop? Miss Qualthrop?
They've gone to catch the bus.
Oh…
I'm terribly sorry, ladies and gentlemen,
but it appears that Miss Qualthrop
and her instrumentalists
have had to catch the bus.
I am sorry, but apparently
there is nothing left for me to do now
but to wish you all a very,
very good night.
[audience chuckles]
The camp seems very
deserted tonight, Corporal.
It's pay night, sir.
Oh? And where does everyone go
on pay night?
I mean,
I'm trying to find out the sort of shows
that you fellows would like me to put on.
-I should try the village, sir.
-The village?
There are several centers
of conviviality there, sir,
if you'll pardon the use
of the expression.
What you're trying to tell me, Corporal,
is that there are several pubs there.
Precisely, sir, yes. The biggest crowd
you'll find in the Rose and Crown.
I'm a non-drinker myself, sir,
but I gather the beer there is better,
according to popular report,
the barmaids too, sir.
Well, I'd certainly choose the place
where the beer is better
not to mention the barmaids.
Goodnight, Corporal.
Good night, sir,
♪ If you don't want the walks
Don't muck 'em about ♪
♪ And take your baby's fingers
Off the slab ♪
♪ They're covered in chocolate
Lovely two-eyed kippers ♪
♪ Take 'em for the pippers
Take a hake or a nice cod steak ♪
♪ Soles and eels for the old man's meals ♪
♪ They're lovely
They're all fresh in today ♪
-Good evening, sir,
-[Chaplain] Good evening.
Taking a squint at the opposition, sir?
Well, I'm prepared to support it
to the tune of a modest pint.
[chuckles] Good evening.
-Good evening.
-Half a pint, please.
-Of what, sir?
-Oh, anything you suggest.
-Old and mild?
-Well, mild will do, thank you.
-Seven pence it is.
Thanks. [chuckles softly]
-Good evening, staff.
-Good evening, sir.
-You seem a bit surprised to see me here.
-Yes, sir.
Well, to tell you the truth,
I was only wondering
what all you fellows did
with your evenings.
-Well, I…
-Yes, yes,
I see all right,
but supposing there were no such places
as the Rose and Crown,
-where would you be then?
-In the Red Lion, sir.
Oh, I can see, Sergeant,
you're not going to be a very
profitable source of investigation.
Cheers.
Excuse me, I've just seen my batman.
-Excuse me… Hello Walter.
-Sir?
I'm surprised to see you here.
I thought at least that you and Jessie
would have been at the concert
to support me, in spite of the music.
Jessie and me,
she's being a bit difficult.
Oh. [chuckles]
Oh, but nothing serious, I hope?
No, just that someone's
been trying to improve her mind.
[chuckles]
But Walter, you must remember
that Jessie is
a very intelligent young girl,
naturally, she wants to…
Oh, Walter, you're not insinuating
that I've been doing that?
Oh no, no, no, come, come, come.
After all, I've only given Jessie
a few good books to read
and advised her
to listen to the Third Programme.
There's nothing improper in that, Walter.
You must remember that young Jessie
has a very enquiring mind.
She never used to have
when she was secretary to Major James.
Yes she had, yes she had, Walter, only
it was probably dormant under the Major.
[sighs]
In any case, Walter, I don't see
why this should lead you to quarrel.
-Well, it has.
-But how, Walter, how?
Well, she wants to know things now.
Oh, I see.
The things presumably
that you don't know the answer to.
Things that nobody knows the answer to.
Oh, I'm afraid you're deceiving yourself,
Walter.
In this fast moving world, there's
always somebody that knows the answer.
Be patient with her, Walter,
but everything will be alright.
[barmaid] Time please.
Come on, boys, drink up.
Oh dear, dear, dear, dear.
I came here to find out what sort
of shows you fellows would like,
now it seems I'm too late.
They won't kick you out yet, sir.
Walter, in my position,
I cannot afford to be kicked out.
I wonder if you'd care
to finish this for me?
I don't really like it.
Walter, I want you with the car
sharp at seven o'clock tomorrow morning.
-Seven, sir?
-Yes, yes.
I'm planning a very full day tomorrow.
Goodnight Walter.
Goodnight, sir.
[slow soft music plays]
Now then. Yes, yes, yes.
-Tea won't be one minute, sir.
-No time for tea today, Jessie.
We've work to do. Good morning, Jessie.
-Good morning sir.
-Get me Major James's theatre file.
-The file with future engagements.
-Yes, but the kettle is on the boil.
So am I, Jessie, so am I.
We're going to sweep out
the Augean stables, so jump to it, Jessie.
Oh, yes, sir.
Good morning, Jessie.
What are you doing out driving the Padre
at this time in the morning?
We've been out since seven.
We'd done the church
and the hospital already.
Sorry if I was a bit short last night.
That's okay. If it'll make you happy,
I'll read a few books.
A few books won't make any difference,
Walter. That's not education.
-Well, what is?
-How should I know?
I never had any education.
-Then what are you talking about?
-I don't know,
being able to talk like the Padre
and people.
Yes, but you're in love with me,
not the Padre.
I know.
But being in love isn't everything,
Walter.
You know, we might be married
for 40 or 50 years
and all we'd be able to do
is to talk about things.
We couldn't talk about
what they're all about,
because we don't know
what they're all about, neither of us.
So we couldn't really discuss
anything sensibly.
Now do you understand?
Well, there's quite a few things
I do know about.
Of course there are.
There's nothing you don't know
about the inside of a car,
but where does that get you?
It gets you wherever you're going.
I don't mean about things like that,
I mean about life
and history and everything.
You can't know about things like that
unless you read about them.
I could get on encyclopedia
and read it through if you like.
Don't be silly, it would take years.
I could get a little encyclopedia,
a potted one.
I don't want anything potted
except the tea.
You can bring that in.
There you are Jessie.
Now, everything in correct order?
Yes, sir.
Too late to do anything
about Saturday, I suppose.
What have we?
Lady Dodd's Company of Thespians
doing Charley's Aunt.
Well, that looks to me rather jolly.
The last time they were here,
they did Quiet Weekend.
-What was it like?
-Quiet.
Well, I suppose we must hope for the best
and make a clean sweep after that.
Now, what have we on the ninth,
the Mordington Madrigal Society
in an evening of plainsong and canticle.
Yes, well, we'll start on them, I think,
while there's time.
What's the number of the secretary?
-Miss Graham. Mordington 69.
-Mordington 69.
Hello, Mordington 69, please.
Forgive me asking, sir, but what are you
going to put in their place?
Hmm? [chuckles]
Let's clear the decks first, Jessie,
and then we'll talk about plans
for the future later.
[door opens]
Hello? Hello, is that Miss Graham
of the Madrigals?
Good morning, Miss Graham,
my name is Paris.
I'm the new Entertainments Officer
at the camp.
[laughs] Yes.
Thank you, very well indeed, and you?
Good, good, good.
Well, it's this way Miss Graham.
I've been going over our program
for the next few weeks
and you know, I find Major James has
rather overweighted us on the vocal side.
Well, I…
I do feel that a certain amount of variety
is necessary in these camp entertainments,
don't you, Miss Graham?
I don't quite follow you, Miss Graham.
Of course, I shouldn't dream of asking you
to do conjuring tricks.
All I was going to suggest, Miss Graham,
was a postponement of your canticles.
When? Well, until I ring you Miss Gr…
Miss Graham, please.
-Hello? Hello?
-[phone dial beeps]
[sighs]
Well, that was…
that was very quickly settled.
Your tea, sir.
Thank you, Jessie.
Now then, what have we next?
Let me see now, Thursday,
the 14th… oh dear.
Miss Qualthrop again and her strings.
Oh, no, no, no.
I do feel that once is enough.
Maxted 74.
Hmm?
No, I think I'll write to her, Jessie.
[gasps]
Lady Dodd is here to see you, sir.
Oh.
That'll be about her program for Saturday.
Show her in, Walter.
Do you know Jessie,
I think we should look on the bright side
and have 300 programs duplicated. Hmm?
No? Oh well, 200 at any rate.
Good morning, Captain Paris.
[Chaplain] Ah, Lady Dodd.
I'm frightfully sorry to butt in on you
at this hour of the morning,
but I absolutely had to.
I don't know how to tell you.
The Thespians have been
overtaken by disaster.
Oh, no, please, Lady Dodd,
not, not for Saturday?
For Saturday and forever.
There's been a rift in the company.
There's…
I don't think I should discuss it
in front of this young person.
That's all right, Lady Dodd,
I'm his confidential secretary.
Well, you know Mr. Burrows
who plays Charley's Aunt?
No, no, no, of course, you don't know him.
But you know Mrs. Phillips who keeps
the cake shop in Mordington High Street
and who plays Donna Lucia?
Her husband is on the Stock Exchange.
He came home the other evening
and found his wife and Mr. Burrows…
Well, I don't think I'll go into details.
Please, please don't, Lady Dodd.
But what on earth are we going to do
for Saturday?
Well, we can't play Hamlet
without the Prince of Denmark, can we?
But I thought you were doing
Charley's Aunt?
That's what I mean.
We can't play Charley's Aunt
without Charley's Aunt.
Oh, yes, of course,
I understand that, Lady Dodd.
And we'd had new scenery painted
and everything. It does seem such a pity.
Of course, I had thought
of something you could substitute.
Oh did you, Lady Dodd?
For Saturday, I'd do anything.
Well then, I suggest you bring Miss Graham
and her Madrigals forward a week.
[Chaplain] Oh.
No, I'm afraid that's out of the question,
Lady Dodd, I just cancelled them.
[Dodd] Oh dear,
they will be disappointed.
Well, now let me think.
The Reverand Hugh knows
the Dickens characters.
A hundred faces under one hat.
Well,
that could or could not be entertaining.
I know, but I'm afraid
he's away at Torquay.
Then, of course, there's Mrs. Prout.
-Who is Mrs. Prout?
-Oh she's brilliantly clever.
She's the wife of George Prout,
the artist.
They're both brilliantly clever.
They live down by the river.
She writes children's books.
-"Zimbo, the spotted Zebra."
-But Lady Dodd,
surely not, not for the troops.
[Dodd chuckles]
Oh, I wasn't thinking of her books.
-She has a puppet show
-Oh.
In any case,
I don't think she could manage it.
She has Professor Mutch the philosopher
staying with them.
Professor Mutch of the BBC?
Yes, that's right.
He's in Question Marks
every Wednesday on the light.
No matter what they ask,
he always knows the answers.
Yes, yes, yes Jessie. But I doubt
if he could find the answer to this que…
Question Marks?
What kind of a program is that, Jessie?
It's a sort of, um… a Brains Trust.
I thought of sending in a question myself.
A Brains Trust?
Why not, hmm? Why not?
Yes indeed, why not?
Jessie, go and tell Walter
to get the car again.
-Yes, sir.
-Lady Dodd,
I do believe we've found the answer
to our troubles.
-Really?
-Where do Mr. and Mrs. Prout live?
Riverside Cottage,
at the corner of Alum Lane.
[gentle orchestral music plays]
[Mutch] You see, a picture
or a piece of sculpture
is budded off from the artist
and it's only when his work has grown up
a bit and becomes a separate entity
that he's fit to give an opinion on it.
Oh, one's constantly coming across
George's sort of dogmatism on the BBC
-and even more complicated for him…
-Jimmy, you really do reason so clearly.
Oh good gracious, I mean to say,
that's my job, that kind of reasoning.
All the same, you know,
if you don't mind my saying so,
I sometimes think you intellectualize
things a little too much.
Well now.
I suppose I do have a sort of tendency
to sublimate emotions and impulses
but into a rationalized
and connected intellectual system.
I mean to say, why not?
After all, we have developed
rationalizing faculties
and no doubt
for some sort of coherent purpose
or at least
as part of an intelligible process.
And you know, after all,
there is a certain satisfaction
in the exercise of one's
more highly developed faculties.
Yes, I suppose so. Yes, I suppose
there is a certain satisfaction…
What I need to say isn't there? I mean
to say take you and me, for instance.
-Oh.
-[Mutch] There you are.
[Chaplain clears throat]
I'm terribly sorry to intrude like this
but I really couldn't help it, you know.
My name is Paris.
I'm the Chaplain from the camp.
-How do you do?
Please, please, please,
don't be embarrassed
If you forgive my saying so,
but it's very, very refreshing these days
to see a couple carrying their courtship
into married life.
Oh, yes, yes, yes,
it's something that occurs all too rarely.
[chuckles]
Look, I haven't come
to pronounce little homilies to you,
I understand you have
a Professor Mutch staying with you?
This is Professor Mutch.
Oh… Oh, how do you do, Professor?
Oh, how silly of me, I ought
to have recognized you from the BBC.
But you haven't spoken yet, have you?
So really, it's quite excusable, isn't it?
[Paris laughs]
And you are?
Mrs. Prout.
Ah, yes, yes, I thought so. And Mr. Prout?
My husband's working
in his studio at the moment.
Oh, but how very fortunate.
I mean, because you see,
I wanted to catch you together,
all three of you, I mean,
of course, naturally.
Then perhaps we'd better go
into the studio.
-Thank you, that's very, very kind of you.
-I'll lead the way.
Oh.
Very, very pleasant morning,
nice and fresh.
[gentle orchestral music]
Fascinating place you have here,
Mrs. Prout, and I love artists' studios.
George, I've brought a visitor,
the Reverend Paris from the camp.
-Oh blast!
-This is my husband George.
Captain Paris wants to see us
about something, so I've asked him in.
Please, please don't stop
whatever it is you're doing, Mr. Prout.
I know that you artists
like to be left alone when you're…
I say, this is a rather ambitious effort
you're at, Mr. Prout.
What's it going to be?
It is not going to be, it is.
Oh, oh really?
George thought of calling it
"Apotheosis."
Ah. Yes, yes, well, why not?
[Angela] I'm making tea,
would you like some?
Oh, well…
Persons of my cloth have a name
for being addicts, haven't they?
[both chuckle]
I'll leave you to talk then
while I get it.
[Chaplain] Oh thank you, thank you.
Thank you very much.
[Mr. Prout] Well, what can we do for you,
Padre?
Well, in a sense,
I'm here to pick your brains.
You see, it was only this morning
that I learned we had three
such celebrated people in the neighborhood
and as we've been rather badly let down
over Saturday's show at the camp,
I thought what a wonderful idea
it would be to get up a Brains Trust.
Oh. So that's it.
Professor Mutch here is paid to do
that sort of thing on the BBC, you know.
Overpaid, but still…
Yes, I know he Is.
I mean, I know he does it professionally,
but I thought for the troops, you know,
it would keep them out of trouble
and get me out of rather a nasty hole.
Yes, I see.
Well, you know, in a way, I wouldn't mind.
But the truth of the matter is, you know,
that there's a great deal more
in these "Question and Answer" affairs
than meets the eye.
Oh, I do really appreciate that,
Professor,
but I thought that with Mr. and Mrs. Prout
here to take care of the arts…
-Eh?
-And one or two other local lights…
-What local lights?
-Well, what…
what meeting would be complete
without Lady Dodd?
What meeting would stay awake with her?
I think it's a horrible idea.
Oh, I don't know, I suppose
in a way it might be possible.
And in 50 other ways impossible.
I've got no brains and Mutch here
is practically an imbecile.
[Mr. Prout chuckles]
[Mr .Prout] Oh, he's no worse
then his stupider, kinder neighbor
in ordinary conversation.
You wait until you see him
before an audience.
-Now, come, come, come, come.
-He seems to think all right in a way,
but there's always some sort of
technical hitch between his thinking box
and his talking apparatus.
I don't think he's got the faintest idea
of what he's saying half of the time.
[Chaplain laughs]
I see our friend here
is a bit of a leg puller, hmm?
I've never pulled anyone's leg
in my life, why should I?
The trouble with you is
you've no faculty for self-criticism.
I was just saying the
same thing to Angela.
[scoffs] You were, were you?
-[Mr. Prout] Listen to who's talking.
-Hmm?
Well, I don't think that self-criticism
is a very common virtue, though, do you?
-Angela! Who said it was a virtue?
-What?
Angela! Where is that confounded woman?
I want my tea.
At least, I don't want it but I need it.
[Angela] Coming, coming.
You've been a devil of a time!
My dear George,
I'm accustomed to your bad manners
but what will Captain Paris think of us?
[Mr. Prout] I know what he thinks of us.
He thinks we're a ready­made brains trust.
-Brains trust?
-Well, yes, as a matter of fact,
I only called in to see whether you
and Mr. Prout and the Professor here
could help us
with a little show at the camp?
Really? I say,
it would be fun, wouldn't it?
Isn't it nice of him to ask us, George?
Nice?
Do you realize, sir,
that I take the profession of Michelangelo
with some seriousness?
Well, of course, I realize that,
Mr. Prout,
but I should have thought
that even Michelangelo could bring himself
now and again
to answer a civil question or two.
-Bah!
-And that's all I'm asking you to do.
You'll persuade him, won't you,
Mrs. Prout?
I can't persuade him to do anything,
not oven to change his underclothes.
[Mutch] I'll persuade him.
Oh, will you?
Well, I don't know
if you'd call it persuasion exactly,
but if I hear him standing on his dignity
as an artist,
something will impel me
to lick the living daylights out of him.
He could, you know.
He used to box for his university
and George is a terrible physical coward.
Well, of course,
if you wish to lay bare the most
secret corners of our private lives
to every Tom, Dick and Harry
who happens to drops in.
Nonsense, George.
The Padre isn't Tom, Dick or Harry.
No, it's William, actually.
And in any case, you said yourself
the world would be a better place
if we all told the truth about ourselves.
Oh, let's all take our clothes off,
shall we?
Angela, show him your appendix scar,
why don't you?
And I've got the most entertaining
birth mark…
Oh please, no. Look, I think
it's awfully decent of you all to consent
to come along and help us.
The show begins at 1930 hours
and I hope you will all join me
in a glass of sherry
in what we laughingly call
"The Green Room" at the theatre.
-Say a quarter of an hour earlier?
-Just a minute, Captain, just a minute.
I mean, after all,
nobody's said yet that…
-They certainly haven't.
-No.
And there's something rather important we
haven't discussed, not so simple either,
something on which the entire success
or failure, for that matter,
of the Brains Trust depends.
Who is going to be Question Master?
I mean to say, you see my point, a good
Question Master has to be a dictator
but not a tyrant if you follow me,
the iron hand in the velvet glove,
you know.
He has to be a diplomat
and a disciplinarian.
In fact, he has to be defending counsel,
judge and jury all rolled into one.
Now who have you got in mind for that?
Well, as a matter of fact,
I…
[chuckles]
You?
Yes, sir, yes, that's… that's right.
Well,
I don't think I'll keep you any longer.
Thank you for a most lovely cup of tea,
Mrs. Prout.
I'll come out with you.
Thank you. Goodbye, Professor.
Goodbye everybody. [chuckles nervously]
See you all on Saturday.
[Chaplain] Thank you.
Now look what you've let us in for.
-Me?
-Yes, you.
And what did you mean by saying
you'd give me a hammering
if I didn't go?
Do you know I nearly believed you?
-Oh, well, I mean to say…
-Do you remember our first day at school?
When we got
to our stinking little cubby hole,
you gave me the thrashing of my life.
I had exactly the same feeling
a moment ago.
-It was most unpleasant.
-[Professor laughs]
I remember you always were
a cocky little blighter.
I probably did you a darn good turn.
[Mr. Prout scoffs]
I spent the rest of the term trying
to think of ways of getting rid of you.
Ha-ha! If it comes to that,
I'm still thinking of them.
You're invited for a weekend
and you stay a couple of weeks.
Oh, well, of course,
-you'll want me to clear out then.
-Don't be an ass.
You amuse me and Angela likes you,
I can't know why.
Probably because I'm not rude to her
in public.
Rude to her in public, me?
Good heavens! Talk sense.
Angie and I are terrific pals.
Oh yes, I know that.
I think in the whole circle
of our acquaintances,
we're the only happy couple
that are legally married.
We're terrific pals.
I don't know what I'd do without her,
confound her.
[chuckles]
Look at her now,
trying to fascinate the Padre.
[chuckles]
Poor little devil,
that's not her line of country.
I think that's why I like her so much.
She's so completely unfascinating.
I'd hate to be married
to one of these disturbing women,
they're as selfish as the devil
and full of tricks.
Angie's is not like that.
She's no Helen of Troy and she knows it
and I know it and she knows I know it.
-So we got on like a house on fire.
-Oh, you do, do you? I mean, do you?
Well, don't we? You know
as well as anyone that we do hang it.
Yes, I suppose you do.
Yes, yes of course, yes.
[soldiers chattering]
All right, men, gather round.
Come on, wake up now.
Now pay attention. There's a brains trust
in the theatre on Saturday
and the Entertainments Officer
wants volunteers to send in questions.
Brown, Buckley, Payne, Moore, Stenning,
sit down and write out a question each
and remember,
nothing about army regulations, pay, food,
personnel, or anything appertaining to,
understand?
Right, now you know your orders.
And when you've got your tracts,
you can decide amongst yourselves
who's going to send in these questions,
but I want a spontaneous response,
you understand?
Otherwise I'll have you all
in the company office, got it?
[lighthearted orchestral music]
Good morning, Jessie.
I've brought the fatigues.
-The what?
-That's what the R.S.M called 'em,
the questions for Saturday.
Put them on his desk
and I'll come in and sort them.
There's a flick on at Mordington
about motor racing in technicolor.
How about it Saturday?
What, and miss the Brains Trust?
What do you take me for?
As a matter of fact,
I'm going to ask a question myself.
-You are?
-[Jessie] Mm-hmm.
-Something I want to know.
-Can't you look it up?
It's something you can't look up.
I can't think what you want
to get mixed up in that kind of thing for.
Because it's very important to me,
that's why.
Well, if I was you,
I'd let sleeping dogs lie.
Of course, you would, Walter,
you don't want to know anything,
even if the world blew up,
you wouldn't ask why.
[chuckles]
Arguing again, you two? Dear, dear, dear!
-Walter, I want you on Saturday.
-Me, sir?
Yes. I want you to look after
the lights and the curtains.
-Do you think you can manage that?
-Well, I suppose so, sir.
Good, I thought that would please you.
Well, well, well!
What a splendid response!
You know, this shows the enthusiasm
for this sort of program.
-Yes, sir.
-Do you know, Jessie,
I think we are going to have a very,
very diverting evening. Now let me see…
Uh…
"Can the Brains Trust tell us
the best way of making homemade gin?"
[chuckles]
Well, I hope we'll do better than that.
By the way, I'm sorry to see that you
and Walter still seem to be disagreeing.
Sometimes I wonder
if we're really suited to each other.
[Chaplain] Ha, why not?
[chuckles]
That's better. Yes, I…
don't understand it but by jove,
it's better.
The way I look at it, sir,
I mean, all Walter can do
is talk about what I look like
and his blooming engines
and his wireless and that.
I don't think we can have questions
about football pools.
Sorry, carry on, Jessie.
That's all very well, sir,
but you know, it's going to wear
a bit thin in about 40 or 50 years,
and you've got to have education
to understand people.
Which Walter doesn't understand me a bit.
He said so himself.
[chuckles]
That's a very good one.
Yes, but Jessie, if you're both
of the same level of education…
-Then neither of you are better off.
-What's that?
I think people should marry
to better themselves,
at least one of them should be better off.
Oh, dear, dear, dear!
That's a very materialistic way
of looking at things, Jessie.
What about falling in love?
I don't know so much about that.
Being in love is all very well,
but where's your guarantee
you're going to be in love
till death do you part?
That's taking a big risk.
Yes, but Jessie,
if a thing's worth doing,
it's worth taking a big risk for it.
That's what my father said,
and my mother and me had to whip round
the neighbors to pay for his funeral.
Hmm, yes, I know but…
Hello, this is your writing, Jessie.
-I know, it's my question, sir.
-What? Oh.
Oh, Jessie.
I think If you don't mind,
I'd rather not open it.
-Why not?
-Because…
Well, don't you see that
if it's a good question and I select it,
well, I might be accused of favoritism,
and if it isn't and I don't,
you will just be disappointed.
So please, Jessie, if you don't mind,
I'd rather you took it back.
I'm sorry, Jessie,
but you do see my position, don't you?
Of course, sir.
[trumpet music plays]
[upbeat music plays]
What on earth is all this?
But Jessie, I ordered sherry.
I asked them to a glass of sherry,
not to a party.
I know, sir,
but everybody doesn't like sherry
so I thought
I'd get something of everything.
-It's on sale or return, sir.
-Oh, is it?
I suppose that's something.
Well, look, Jessie,
put these questions in my table where
I'm sitting. Keep them in that order.
And Jessie,
see that everyone has a glass of
water in front of them, will you, please?
I've already done that, sir.
Good girl, good girl.
I can't think
what he wants this thing up for.
Well, Padre thought something sylvan
would be appropriate.
Is this supposed to be sylvan?
It's all we've got.
It was done for the WRAC pantomime.
-[bass music plays]
-[audience chatter]
It is my very pleasant duty
as question master
to introduce to you
tonight's brains trust.
Therefore, on my extreme left, no, no,
my extreme right…
-Good evening, Padre.
-Ah.
I hope you don't mind Brian
and Penelope coming along
but Lord Dodd has gone to the pictures
and they would've been
so lonely in the house
with only the housekeeper
and the parlor maid.
That's perfectly alright, Lady Dodd.
I shan't take them on the stage,
of course,
not that they don't understand
every word that's said to them.
I am sure they do, Lady Dodd.
Can I tempt you to a glass of sherry?
Oh, I don't think I should, do you?
I mean,
I want to keep my head clear, don't I?
Oh well, perhaps just a teeny one.
Who else is coming along tonight?
I mean, besides Professor Mutch
and Mr. and Mrs. Prout?
Well… I… I've asked Dr. McAdam.
Dear Dr. McAdam. We only have him
for the servants now, of course,
but he's such a nice man.
And then of course, Mr. Byres,
our Member of Parliament.
Oh dear. But he's Labour, you know.
Yes, I know, but after all,
he does represent the constituency.
By three votes after two recounts,
and he wouldn't have got in then
if it hadn't been for that
scurrilous campaign he carried on,
suggesting that Sir John's Brewery
deliberately watered their beer,
which was too ridiculous, judging from
the state of affairs on election night.
Perhaps, that was because most people
went on the whisky, my lady.
Now, we must keep all arguments
for the platform.
Have a sherry, Mr. Byres.
Perhaps you'd prefer beer.
Aye, if there's no champagne.
[laughs]
I'm afraid this is not
the House of Commons, Mr. Byres.
[laughing]
Before we start this confounded nonsense,
I need a drink.
The Padre said something
about a glass of sherry.
I need more than my sherry,
I want a large Scotch.
If you and Jimmy had been back
from the river at a decent time,
we could have popped into the Red Lion.
[chuckles]
[Chaplain] So I told him
he would be able… Ah, Mrs. Prout.
Good evening.
[Chaplain] Good evening, Professor,
Mr. Prout.
-No nerves, I hope.
-Well…
Of course not. Come along now,
I want you to meet your fellow brains.
Lady Dodd, Mr. Byres,
Mr. and Mrs. Prout, Professor Mutch.
-How do you do?
-Now then, let me see, sherry everybody?
-I'd rather have a Scotch.
-What?
Oh. Yes, yes, of course.
This should be an amusing evening and
very stimulating for the troops, I feel.
I mean, so many of them
haven't been taught to think
clearly or straightly or starkly.
I found that out when Mrs. Weatherby
used to take me out to her girls' club.
I mean they simply didn't know
what I was talking about
and I am a simple enough soul.
Hmm, yes, you are.
The difficulty is, of course,
they don't really speak our language.
Yes, yes, there's that.
-[Chaplain] Mrs. Prout, Professor
-Thank you very much, Padre.
Let me see, I do hope Dr. McAdam
isn't going to be late.
It's half past seven everybody.
Yes, yes, I'm aware of that, Jessie,
what's the house like?
It looks half empty to me.
Half full? Oh, well,
that's better than last Tuesday anyway
and I expect there's plenty more to come.
No, I don't think so.
[door slams]
Well, I think we can safely drink
to a most successful evening.
-Oh, thank you.
-[McAdam] I'm sorry I'm late, Paris.
Got called out the last moment.
I haven't had time to change either,
I hope it's all right.
Of course, perfectly all right, the troops
won't mind. Come along now, doctor,
-I want you to meet Mrs. Prout and…
-How do you do?
Mr. Prout.
Lady Dodd and Mr. Byres, you know.
-[Mr. Byres] How do you do?
-And Professor Mutch.
-Who?
-[Chaplain] Professor Mutch.
We'll do well
with the medical questions this evening.
[McAdam] I might have to leave
before the end, you know,
I got a confinement.
I can't tell, she might hang on
for hours, of course, she might not.
Oh dear, I sincerely hope she does.
-[Chaplain laughs]
-[audience clapping]
Oh listen, they're applauding us already,
how very nice of them.
I'm afraid that's an indication
that they want the show to begin,
so if you finish your drinks, ladies,
perhaps we shall take our places.
Will you follow me, Lady Dodd? Thank you.
[audience clapping continues]
Lady Dodd. Right here, Mrs. Prout…
[audience clapping]
-[audience clapping rhythmically]
-[chattering]
[clears throat]
[audience imitating coughing]
Now ladles and gentlemen,
it is my very pleasant duty
as question master
to introduce to you tonight's
Brains Trust.
Now then, on my extreme right without any
further ado is Mr. George Prout,
a very celebrated painter
of oil paintings.
He is indeed a member
of the Royal Institute of Oil Painters,
a very, very distinguished body of men
who paint, uh, oil paintings.
So you see,
if there are any questions about art,
I am sure that he will be able
to deal with them,
especially if they have to do
with oil paintings.
Now, next to him I am very happy to be
able to tell you is
our old friend Dr. McAdam.
-[audience cheers, claps]
-[soldier] Good old doc!
Very distinguished graduate of I believe
Edinburgh University?
-[blows pipe]
-[chuckles nervously]
Yes, yes, Edinburgh University.
And now, you know, I hardly think there's
any need for me to introduce Lady Dodd.
[audience claps]
[chuckles]
Perhaps I'd better spare her blushes
and pass on to Mrs. Prout.
You know, I don't know whether to refer
to her as Mrs. Prout or Angela Kilpatrick
because as such she is the author of many,
many delightful children's books
and is also, I understand,
very, very interested in puppets,
and will perhaps someday give us
a little show. Will you, Mrs. Prout?
Thank you, thank you, thank you so much.
[chuckles, stops]
Thank you. Now next to her,
I am very happy to be able to tell you
is Professor JFS Mutch
of the University of Skerryvore
and the Light Programme.
He is a great expert in mathematics
and is, I understand, one of our
best known collectors of postage stamps.
So, you see, if there are any questions
about mathematics or postage stamps,
I am sure that he will be able
to deal with them.
And lastly, we are very happy to welcome
our local Member of Parliament,
Mr. Joe Byres.
[audience cheering]
We have no politics here
and therefore we are very, very happy
to have him with us.
And now, lets get down
to the business of the evening.
The questions are on anything
and everything.
I've just chosen them at random,
at least, more or less.
Naturally, we've had to bar questions
on politics and religion
and questions showing
ill-timed facetiousness.
I mean, we can't really discuss politics
and religion
in a mixed gathering of this sort
and of course, the CO won't have smut.
-[audience laughs]
-But what's left makes a pretty good lot
and the first is from private JS Dixon.
He asks "What makes cows in a field
run after railway trains?"
Well now, let me see, I think we'll…
I think we'll ask Lady Dodd to kick off.
Come along now, Lady Dodd, what makes cows
in a field run after railway trains?
Well, now, that is a question
I've often wondered myself.
My Aunt was a great friend
of Sir James Barrie
and he used to they were running
to catch any babies
that might fall out of the windows.
I hardly think it can be that myself,
though, mind you,
cows are frightfully intelligent animals.
Ah, thank you, Lady Dodd,
thank you very much. Professor?
Well, I mean to say…
are we entitled to suppose
that they have in point of fact
any reason for running
after trains at all? If you follow me.
Oh, they must have, they must have!
Yes, they, well, I don't know…
I mean, after all,
when one talks about reason,
one's plunging head over heels
into the psychological aspect,
and I mean, after all,
have cows a psychological aspect?
[Mutch chuckles]
[Mutch] I mean to say,
we don't know enough about it.
It may be a simple enough problem
in biophysics,
but we just don't know, now do we?
You see my point?
[Mutch chuckles]
Yes, oh yes, yes, yes, of course!
Of course, thank you, Professor.
Oh, and Mr. Byres.
They get excited by the clatter.
You don't see cows running in a field
where a lot of trains pass,
they get used to it.
Yes, thank you.
Thank you, Mr. Byres. Mrs. Prout?
I agree with Mr. Byres.
I think any kind of vague tumult
is exciting.
I think they run after the trains because
they like the monotony to be broken.
Cows lead very monotonous lives, remember.
I don't agree.
Most human beings
have far more monotonous lives than cows,
and the one thing they hate
is having the monotony broken.
Anyhow, cows don't run after trains.
Oh, yes they do, George.
No they don't.
Anyhow, cows are females.
What's the good of worrying
why they do anything on the living earth?
-[audience laughs, claps] Here, here!
-Now, now, order, order.
Now let me see, Dr. McAdam,
perhaps you will sum up.
What? Well, what was the question?
[chuckles]
Why do cows run after railway trains?
I haven't the slightest idea.
[all laugh]
Well now, I think we've had very varied
and satisfactory answers
to that most interesting question,
and I think the Trust has decided
that it would be unwise
to go too far into the cow's motives.
Well, now the next question
is a very interesting one.
It's from…
from 857643, Lance Corporal Jenks W.
of the Royal Military Police.
[audience boos]
He wants to know "Is civilization in the
opinion of the Brains Trust, a failure?
And what is civilization anyway?"
Well, we ought to get some good answers
to that, eh? Uh… Mrs. Prout?
We'd better answer
the second part first, hadn't we?
Yes, just as you wish.
"What is civilization anyway?"
Civilization surely is the application
of knowledge and experience
to the good of the greatest number
of people.
Oh, is it?
You count a certain number of fatheads
and then try how far
whatever you've got to go round.
That's not civilization.
You can have civilization
if you've got half a dozen sensible men
and a thousand million mugs.
But the mugs have no part in it.
Oh, they haven't, haven't they?
Well, it's high time they had.
Now, now, I'm afraid we're getting
perilously near politics.
Look, perhaps Lady Dodd can tell us
whether she thinks
that civilization is a failure.
Oh, I don't think it's a failure at all.
Look at us, look at the Romans,
look at the way they treated animals
and Christians.
[Chaplain]
Thank you, thank you, Lady Dodd.
Well now,
I think that more or less covers…
Covers…
Oh, you wish to say something, Professor?
Well, well…
I suppose I should say something about it
as it is a matter
I have given
a very great deal of thought to.
[Mutch mutters]
I mean to say, we must start.
I mean this is important, I mean to say.
We must start by having
absolutely clear ideas
about what we mean
by what we are talking about.
I mean to say, you see,
it's not as though there's only
been one civilization in the world,
there have been dozens and dozens.
It's hopeless.
[Mutch chuckles, inhales]
Oh, I could go on about this all night
but perhaps I'd better not.
Oh, no, no, perhaps,
perhaps not, Professor,
but thank you, thank you all the same.
Mr. Byres,
but no politics, mind.
What do you think of civilization?
I don't think much of it.
[laughing]
Well, that's very much the point, anyway.
Now, I think I can say that the
Brains Trust is of the opinion
that there is a great deal
to be said for civilization,
and that there is life in the old dog yet.
-And now we'll pass on…
-[Byres] At the same time, I must say
that a civilization
that is built from top to bottom
on humbug class privilege
and the profit motive
is about as fancy a piece of jerrybuilding
as ever I heard of.
The whole jingbang will come down
with a clatter one of these days,
-you'll see.
-Quite, quite, quite, Mr. Byres.
-And now we'll pass on to…
-I agree with every word you say.
-Eh?
-Every beautiful device we human beings
have invented to keep the gorillas
and yahoos in order will be destroyed.
What do you mean by gorillas and yahoos?
Your sacred proletariat.
-[Chaplain gasps]
-[Byres] Well, I am blowed.
Who do you think you are, anyway?
The Chairman here says
you make your living painting pictures.
Well,
my little girl of twelve paints pictures,
but if I catch her putting on airs
because she can put down on paper
something that looks like a horse
or a chrysanthemum,
I'd give her the thrashing of her life!
[banging gavel]
Please, please, Mr. Byres,
we must get on with the next question.
I never met a Labour politician
who could do anything
but bluster and rant.
Is that so?
Well, if you're asking for home truths,
you'll get them.
And if you're asking for a punch
on the nose, you'll got that too.
Go on Joe, show 'em what you're made of!
Please, Mr. Byres, and please, you too,
Mr. Prout, you're both out of order
if you don't mind my saying so, gentlemen.
-Well, I demand an apology.
-Surely not, Mr. Byres…
Very well, I apologize.
Well, I accept your apology.
[Chaplain chuckles nervously]
Well, well, that is very nice,
that's very nice indeed.
[Chaplain laughs]
Well now, we really can get on
to the next question.
It's a most interesting one too.
It's from Bombardier Benskin,
and Bombardier Benskin wants to know
whether there is any evidence
for the belief that living creatures
exist on the moon's surface?
-On the what?
-On the surface of the moon.
Well, Professor, I think we'll ask you
to answer this one.
Come along now, is there any evidence
of life on the surface of the moon?
No!
-I beg your pardon?
-No.
Oh, but… No evidence whatever?
-None at all?
That seems very peculiar to me.
Yes, well, well…
I am sorry, Bombardier Benskin,
but I'm afraid we just got to take it
that there is no evidence of life
on the surface of the moon.
Pity, though, pity.
Now we'll get on to the next question.
It's from… Private… Private…
Oh dear, it looks like Hezekiah.
It can't be, it's… just a minute,
it's Private JB…
Killigrew.
What… what was that?
Killigrew, Jessie Killigrew.
[audience murmurs]
Oh, oh, it's you, Jessie. Oh…
Oh, that's…
yes, that's very Interesting.
Well now,
Private Jessie Killigrew wants to know,
uh…
Oh dear, dear,
what on earth happened to your writing,
Jessie?
It looks like marshmallow but it can't be.
Is marriage a good idea?
What, what, what, what?
That's the question.
Is marriage a good idea and if it is,
what's the best way to choose a partner?
Oh…
and I thought it was marshmallow.
[chuckles]
Oh well, now then,
Private Jessie Killigrew wants to know
whether in the opinion of
the Brains Trust, marriage is a good idea.
Come along now, Lady Dodd.
Oh I think, it's an excellent idea.
I think that apart
from kindness to animals,
it's one of the best ideas in the world,
except Christianity, of course,
and then,
that takes it all in, doesn't it?
I mean they wouldn't let us get married
in church, would they
unless they thought
it was a wonderful idea?
Thank you Lady Dodd.
Well now, Dr. McAdam,
you've been very silent.
What do you think about it?
Hmm? Oh, I am sorry,
I didn't quite catch the question.
Oh, excuse me, Lady Dodd.
Is marriage a good idea?
I don't know whether it's a good idea
or a bad idea,
but it's an inevitable idea.
Mind you, it's a contract
very few sane people enter into.
Oh doctor, what a dreadful thing to say.
What was that?
I said "What an awful thing to say."
Well, it's quite true. I mean,
if falling In love isn't going mad,
then I've never seen a lunatic.
[both laugh]
Well then, how do you account for the fact
that there are hundreds and thousands
of happy marriages?
Anyone can get on with anybody
if he tries hard enough.
Well, if it's as easy as that,
why didn't you get married then, eh?
Because I never went mad.
[audience laughs]
Thank you, Dr. McAdam.
[both laugh]
Mrs. Prout.
I must have been mad when I married.
Well,
that's a nice thing to say in public.
Oh please, never mind about the public.
Jessie, really, this is rather much
of a good thing!
But I want to know.
-And so do I.
-Me too.
[Jessie] Yes, yes, there's lots more here
who want to know.
But you've got to be honest,
and you've got to be human, see?
Because if you're not with all you know
about the world and everything, well,
we won't learn a thing.
[audience cheers, applauds]
-Jess--
-It's all right, I'll do my best.
I remember when I first met George,
the only thing I thought about him
was that I didn't think his finger nails
were very clean
and he hadn't shaved properly.
To be perfectly candid,
I didn't think you were much
to look at either.
You had a way of flinching
whenever you said anything.
I remember noticing a rather peculiar
and distinctly unpleasant smell.
It's rather difficult to describe.
I don't think you need attempt
to describe it here, Mrs. Prout.
Well, it wasn't a religious smell,
it wasn't a political smell,
there was some turpentine
and some stale tobacco,
perhaps that's why I flinched.
I was out with my puppy,
I remember, and he suddenly started
to bite Mr. Prout's shoes.
-That's how we got to know each other.
-The darling.
-What sort of a puppy?
-He was an Aberdeen terrier.
Oh, there's no love
like a dog's love, is there?
He was a filthy little brute called Sambo.
I didn't like him any better
at first sight than I liked his mistress.
She looked liked a bit of damp seaweed
and she had a cold in the head.
Perhaps it is true
to say I wasn't looking my best.
However you looked,
it wouldn't have made any difference.
We both behaved in an idiotic way
for months afterwards.
-Years.
-And why?
Because we were carrying about
with each other
a microscopic piece of matter
that could neither read, nor write,
nor hear, nor speak, nor think.
It had nothing but a will.
But somehow or other, that will was
able to call out to its neighbor and say,
"Hi, let's get together
and grow into a thing,
which is a perfectly arranged mixture
of Angela and George."
"Right" says the other will.
"The first thing to do
is to make them both mad.
He's a scruffy looking devil
with a face like a gargoyle.
She's a long lanky creature
with a sniveling cold in the head.
Let's make him think she's Venus
and make her think he's Apollo.
Otherwise they'll never be
such darned fools
as to chain themselves together
for the rest of their lives."
-The doctor is quite right.
-Eh?
I said you were quite right.
Well, right about what?
I didn't hear what you said.
What I said was…
Please, please Mr. Prout, not…
not again.
But what I want to know…
-Jessie!
-All the same,
I don't think I was so frightful
as all that!
-Oh yes you were.
-Nonsense!
[audience mutters]
-What's that?
-Oh, well…
Mr. Prout, is that only
what you think of her now
or did you think that then?
I really,
really must put a stop to all this.
But why, why? I think it's fascinating.
[Jessie]
Don't you want us to learn something?
I thought
that's what Brains Trust was for,
to teach us something,
and we've only just begun.
We've seen two people who can get
hooked up for life to each other
but without knowing the least
what they're after.
Oh, it doesn't always work out like that.
I think my husband knew perfectly well
what he was after when he married me.
[Jessie]
Anyhow, that's how it happened once,
I want to know what happens next,
do they live happy ever after?
No one lives happy ever after
but they get on all right.
-Well…
-[Mr. Prout] What do you mean "well"?
Oh, I admit we have our ups and downs,
but personally,
I think we made a darn good arrangement.
I'm sometimes a bit unreasonable,
Angela's never anything else,
but it doesn't take long
to find a modus vivendi.
-A what?
-[Mr. Prout] A way of living.
Oh, but is it the best way of living?
No, by heaven, it isn't!
-What did he say?
-I said it isn't.
It's all very well for George.
He's got somebody to look after
his laundry and do his cooking,
listen to his ravings
and tell him he's wonderful,
but where in the name of fortune
does Angela come into it?
She's got a far better brain than he has
and she's got qualities
to make something of herself,
and she's got something else
that you haven't got,
decent manners
and a capacity for hard work.
And what she's expected to do?
Stand aside like a conjurer's assistant,
waving a handker­chief
and shouting "voilà!"
while you pull a mangy rabbit
out of your hat. It makes me sick!
Yes, but how did it work out that way?
I'll tell you. I'll tell you all right.
It's pure undiluted, unadulterated--
Stop!
Stop. Sit down, please, Professor.
[audience murmurs]
Ladies and gentlemen, it is possibly
a little early to have an interval,
though I must say I think it's high time.
Coffee and soft drinks
will be served in the canteen bar.
We hope to resume in about ten minutes
when I sincerely trust things
will have come back to normal.
Curtain, Walter. Thank you, thank you.
-[audience chattering]
-[flute music plays]
Look, everybody.
I don't propose to hold an inquest
over what has just happened,
nor do I wish to censor anyone,
all the same, I do feel that we…
at least some of us,
ought to reflect very, very seriously
on what has just happened.
-You've said it.
-[Dodd] Yes, indeed.
Well, well, well. A really jolly party.
I say, what was that young woman
in the audience saying?
Come and have a drink, Doctor.
Charming youngster, such a friendly smile.
-Help yourself.
-Made everything seem so matey.
Here, Jessie.
What'd you want to go and make
an exhibition of yourself like that for?
Because I want to find out what happens
to people when they get married.
-Yes, but you don't have…
-I'm not going to get tied up on spec.
On our street at home, nobody's happily
married and I'd like to know why.
You might be living on the wrong street.
Come on, Joe, three pints of bitter.
-You're in a hurry?
-I got to get back to the theater,
there's some fun and games there tonight.
Better than all-in wrestling, no kidding!
Wouldn't surprise me to see a fight
break out in the second half,
-the way things are shaping.
-Go on.
[Dodd giggles]
I'm afraid it's just about time to return,
Lady Dodd.
And may I, may I say just once again
that if we all, all of us
make a really determined effort
to cooperate
and avoid at all costs personal topics,
I am absolutely sure that the whole thing
will go swimmingly this time.
-I shall do my best.
-Yes, I am quite sure you will, Lady Dodd.
And I'm sure we all shall. Now come along,
shall we take our places again? Lady Dodd.
Excuse me, Mr. Byres.
Come along.
[chattering]
What was old Paris talking about?
-Well, he says nothing personal.
-Hey?
-Nothing personal.
-Oh.
-Alright, Mr. Byres.
-Alright.
Lady Dodd, there's… Here it is,
look, there's a question here
about the cuckoo.
Still,
I think perhaps in the circumstances.
That sounds innocent enough to me.
That may be, Lady Dodd,
but my only concern now is to keep
the flag flying until the final curtain.
And I am sure we can all do that. Hmm?
Well, everyone, present and correct
and ready for the fray, hmm?
Right Walter, up with the curtain.
Hold it, Walter.
[audience cheers]
Where's Mr. Prout? Mr. Prout, Mr. Prout!
[audience laughing]
There you are Mr. Prout.
Oh dear, we thought we'd lost you.
Well, now… Ready? Right, Walter.
[audience applauds]
There seem to be lots more people now
than there were at the beginning.
And bad news travels fast.
Well now, ladies and gentlemen,
we've come to the second part
of this Brains Trust session.
[audience cheers]
The first part was, I will not say marred,
but perhaps just a little bit disorganized
by certain,
oh, shall we call them… eccentricities?
[audience cheers]
I think you'll find that a cup of tea…
uh… or… some other…
light refreshment
has put everything all right.
Now the first question
is from Private Slater
of the Army Catering Corps
and he wants to know what is meant
by a "sense of humor"
and how an effective sense of humor
may be cultivated.
Lady Dodd?
Well now, I've always had
a great sense of humor myself
and I have always been very glad of it.
As to cultivating a sense of humor,
I think perhaps the best thing would be
to subscribe to a periodical like Punch
and look at the most amusing pictures.
Thank you, thank you, Lady Dodd.
Now… well, Dr. McAdam.
[Chaplain]
I wonder if you heard the question?
Yes, yes, I'm not deaf.
[laughs]
I'm sorry.
Well, have you any remarks
to make on it, then?
Well, I haven't got
a sense of humor myself. I'm too busy.
[chuckles] Oh, I don't know.
I think a good joke now and again
helps to keep things going,
so long as it's clean.
Some of the things I hear on the BBC
I can hardly believe my ears.
-[Chaplain] Thank you, Mr. Byres.
-Mr. Chairman.
[audience mutters]
Yes, Jessie, what is it now?
Excuse me sir, but you haven't answered
the last question yet.
-That's right.
-[audience murmurs]
But Jessie, you must really try
to control your curiosity.
Mr. and Mrs. Prout are entitled
to some measure of private life.
But I only want to know about marriage.
[audience cheers]
Please, quiet, quiet, please, please!
Really, Jessie, for heaven's sake.
Well, Private Slater, the Brains Trust
seems to think that a sense of humor
is a very difficult thing to define
but a very useful thing to have.
We think you can best cultivate it
by reading suitable magazines
and refraining from listening to the BBC.
Now we'll pass onto the next question.
It is, oh, it's anonymous,
and the question asks "How does
a bluebottle walking on the ceiling
take off when it wants to fly?"
Now that is a most interesting question.
How does a bluebottle
take off from the ceiling?
Who cares?
[audience laughs]
Obviously the person
who asked the question.
[audience laughs]
Well now, Dr. McAdam,
perhaps you can help us?
Oh yes, hmm, yes…
Talking of a sense of humor.
-[laughs]
-it's quite true,
you do come across some laughable things
in general practice.
Doctor…
I remember an old fellow
with a swelling on his backside
-the size of your head.
-[audience laughs]
Doctor, doctor,
we are onto another question.
I had a surgeon in to see him
and we both agreed
we ought to take a wallop at it.
-Yes, doctor, but…
-[audience laughs]
So we did the operation
on the kitchen table.
I must say, the young fellow
made a good job of it,
as neat a piece of work as ever I saw.
Left a beautiful scar.
[audience laughs]
Yes, doctor, you're straying,
we went onto another question.
A pity the old fellow couldn't show it.
[Dodd laughs]
Owing to its situation, you understand.
Yes, doctor, but we're onto
bluebottles now, we're onto bluebottles.
[McAdam] Yes, yes yes.
So we put him into his bed
and as soon as he came out
of the chloroform, he said…
Bluebottles, doctor, bluebottles!
Oh no, no, no, no.
He didn't need a bottle, no, just a whiff.
So the old follow felt under his pillow
and took out a handful of dirty notes
and asked the surgeon what his fee was.
"Oh," says he, "ten guineas."
So the old fellow counted out eight notes.
"Here you are," he said,
"eight pounds, take it or leave it
and if you don't like it, you can put
the swelling back where you found it."
[audience laughs]
Quaint old characters you meet sometime.
-Yes, I remember another time
-Now, the Brains Trust…
No no, please, please, doctor,
another time, another time, please.
Oh, yes, all the same to me.
[Chaplain laughs]
You know,
I wish someone would explain to me
how bluebottles manage to walk
on the ceiling at all.
-No, don't be so darned stupid.
-That'll do.
-[Mr. Prout] What's that?
-[Mutch] I said, that'll do.
Well, upon my word, Mr. Mutch,
I don't see why the devil
I can't pass a remark to my wife
-without you brawling and blustering in.
-He wasn't brawling, George.
Yes, he was.
Mr. Prout, please, please, please.
And Professor, please to you too.
Now, the Brains Trust doesn't appear
to have any positive opinion
about bluebottles,
so we'll pass on to the next question.
Miss Burgess wants to know if Dr. McAdam
can come to her at once.
Oh, what's… Oh dear.
This isn't a question, oh, it's a message.
Oh, it's for you Dr. McAdam.
It's from Miss Burgess, she wants you.
Oh, yes, yes.
[chuckles]
-I'm sorry I've got to run off like this.
-Yes, yes, of course.
It isn't Miss Burgess having the baby.
[chuckling]
She's the District Nurse.
Goodbye, everybody, goodnight. Goodnight!
[audience cheers, applauds]
I'm sorry I've been called away.
Goodnight, doctor, goodnight.
Now then, for the next question…
Mr. Chairman, please,
may I have my question answered first.
-Is marriage a good idea?
-[audience cheers]
Jessie, for the last time,
will you kindly sit down and keep quiet?
But I want to know what happened.
Everybody wants to know. Don't you?
[audience cheers]
Please. Jessie. Jess…
Excuse me, everybody.
I must stop this once and for all.
[audience chattering]
She'll get put in the jug
if she's not careful.
Jessie,
you really must try to control yourself.
You're getting quite hysterical.
No I'm not!
We never had hysterics in our family.
We work too blooming hard.
I just want to know, that's all.
Jessie, but you want to know what?
! want to know what happened.
Everybody wants to know.
[audience cheers]
Please, Mrs. Prout,
it's very important to me.
I don't know, I… I don't…
It's all right, please, don't cry.
Don't worry, I'll take you away.
You take your hands off her!
-[Dodd gasps]
-[commotion]
Sit there. Sit there, Mr. Prout.
Now behave yourself!
I should have warned you that I'd done
a bit of scrapping in my time.
As a matter of fact, I was once amateur
middle weight champion at my university.
I know, I know. Like that swine there,
your only sort of repartee
is knocking people about
like a couple of navvies.
You dare put your filthy paws
on a man like me?
Infernal bullies, that's what you are!
Infernal bullies!
[Mr. Prout sobbing]
Mr. Prout. Please don't cry, Mr. Prout.
Pull yourself together, man.
-Be a man.
-[audience muttering]
I don't know what to do, Lady Dodd.
I just don't know what to do.
But it isn't your fault.
It isn't your fault.
-[audience cheering]
-[Jessie] Be quiet, wait a minute, listen,
I want to say something!
Just a minute. Listen.
I don't want to cause trouble.
I only asked the question
because it's really important to me
and I think it's important
to nearly all us young ones here.
[audience cheers]
Of course we talk about it.
But what do we know?
We don't know anything
and when we ask those
who've been through it,
they put us off with lies and silly jokes.
Some of us never see anyone
who's got any education
from one year's end to another,
so now we've got you here
and we want you to tell us
whether it's worth getting married or not.
So please, Mrs. Prout,
did you choose right or didn't you,
and if you didn't, what went wrong?
[audience cheers]
She's quite right, you know. We…
We ought to answer her question.
No, no. No, I'm sorry.
But I really must put my foot down.
After all,
I am supposed to be Question Master.
Does the Brains Trust wish me
to continue in that office
or would you rather I hand it over
to Private Killigrew?
No. Please go on. You're doing splendidly.
You're quite good enough.
Now look, Jessie. Do you want to come up
and be question mistress?
No, I don't.
Very well then.
I must insist on being master.
I suppose Mr. Byres would say that no man
is good enough to be another man's master,
-but at the same time, I…
-No woman is good enough
to be another man's mistress.
Order, order, order!
Very well then. What do you want me to do?
Do you want me to go on
to the next question or not?
I think the girl should have her way.
After all,
we are supposed to be a Brains Trust.
And if she asks a question,
she's entitled to an answer.
-[audience cheers]
-If this was a political meeting,
she'd get an answer.
[audience applauds]
Very well then, Mrs. Prout,
I think you had something to add.
Well, what is it Miss Killigrew
wants to know exactly?
I just want to know how it works out,
that's all,
marriage, I mean.
Why, I don't really know. You…
You go mad more or less all of a sudden,
but you recover quite slowly
and by degrees.
That's what happened to us. I began by
noticing things about George
that I didn't like very much,
and I suppose that hurt his vanity because
he began to lose his temper very often.
It wasn't the same then, of course,
as it was at first.
But you aren't the same as you were
when you were three years old.
George and I are devoted to each other.
Absolutely.
But didn't you see
any of his faults at first?
But I told you I did. All of them.
Only they didn't seem to matter.
It was as if they belonged
to some other person.
I think it's all summed up
by Lord Tennyson
when he says a friend
should bear a friend's infirmities
and if we've got to bear
a friend's infirmities,
how much more
ought we to bear a husband's?
It's all a matter of give and take.
Oh thank you, Lady Dodd,
and excellently put.
Now I think we can sum up this discussion
by saying that marriage is a very,
very good idea indeed,
if we are prepared to give and take,
as Lady Dodd says.
-Now, we'll pass on…
-But not if it's all on one side.
[audience murmurs]
Well, of course,
it must not be all on one side.
I think Lady Dodd made that perfectly
clear,
and now we'll pass on to the next…
But it is all on one side.
I mean, what the devil?
Oh, I beg your pardon. But look here,
after all,
I know these people better than you do.
I've known Angela for ten years
and George for nearly 30.
Oh, he's a decent enough chap and all that
but he's bone lazy and bone selfish
and as conceited
as a peacock with three tails.
Though what he's got to be conceited about
heaven alone knows.
What I mean to say is after all,
she's got a personality
of her own and what the devil…
[grunts, sighs]
I can't say anything of course.
For some reason or another,
nobody's supposed to say anything
about this sort of thing
until the whole damage is done.
Well, it is done!
And here's somebody
who's had her whole life ruined
by the crass stupidity
of a bone-headed twerp like that.
I mean to say
it's high time someone told him
and I don't care if he knows,
I mean to say…
[audience murmurs]
The Professor is of opinion
that both parties must be prepared
to make some sacrifice
and there must be some give and take.
-Now we'll pass on to the next…
-I beg your pardon.
We'll do nothing of the sort.
[Mr. Prout]
This man has had the impertinence,
to come in and out of my house
like a tame lap dog
and pretend to be my friend.
Now he stands up
at a public meeting and insults me.
I want to know what he means by it,
if he's capable of stringing
a couple
of intelligible sentences together.
I think you can settle that
on a more suitable occasion, Mr. Prout.
I insist!
He's either said too much or too little.
I want to know
what the devil he means by it.
I should have thought
I made my meaning abundantly clear.
I called you a selfish, conceited
bone-headed twerp and I mean it.
You are one. Upon my life,
I don't know how she sticks him.
You keep my wife out of this!
But it's true, George. You are difficult.
That's right.
You turn on me now.
A moment ago, you were rolling your eyes
and telling the whole army
how much you loved me.
[laughs]
But I'm not surprised, it's just like you.
You insist on being treated
as a rational being
and at the same time claim the rights
of a spoiled child.
How can I make a comrade and partner
out of a creature like that?
I should begin
by trying to behave like a gentleman.
I suppose
you call your behavior gentlemanly?
I only discuss terms
with people who know what they mean.
Oh stop, I can't stand this!
Well, as a matter of fact, it's getting
a bit too much for me too.
I'm not in the least surprised, Lady Dodd.
Gentlemen, you must either behave
like civilized beings
or leave this platform.
Certainly, I'll leave this platform
and I'll take Mrs. Prout with me.
You'll do nothing of the sort!
-Oh? And who's going to stop me?
-I am!
[audience cheers]
Are you going to sit there
and hear me insulted?
I can't imagine a woman
with a spark of spirit
sitting still
and hearing her husband insulted.
Can't you, Mr. Prout? It's one of
the few pleasures we poor women have.
If we're talking about insults,
I've been steadily insulted
ever since this thing began,
and by you, George.
And may I tell you,
I've had about enough of it.
You can go on
washing our dirty linen in public
as long as Captain Paris will let you.
I'm going with Jimmy.
I forbid you to do any­thing of the sort.
Why should you? Is he your lover or what?
Yes he is. I mean… Well, he…
He is in a way. I mean… He is.
[audience murmurs]
Do you mean to say
that this has been going on
under my very nose?
Nothing's been going on
under your very nose. Don't be silly.
I beg your pardon, Professor Mutch,
but my wife has just stated
in the clearest possible terms
that she's been deceiving me with you.
[chuckles]
You set great store by your gentility.
Are you accusing my wife of telling lies?
It isn't what you think it means, George.
It isn't at all.
Then, what is it?
At least I'm entitled to an explanation.
Of course, Jimmy and I
are very fond of one another,
but not in that way.
May I ask what you mean by "that way"?
No, sir, you may not.
[audience murmurs]
Steady, Prout.
Excuse me.
I said when I married,
I'd marry the perfect woman
or remain a bachelor.
I was poor
but an artist can marry who he likes.
I was determined to marry a woman
who has graceful and beautiful
without a blemish
with a voice full of sympathy
and talking good sense
and not trying to be clever.
I knew her, I could hear her,
but I couldn't see her.
All I knew was that she'd be a surprise.
Dark, fair, it was nothing to me,
height as high as my heart,
but beautiful she must be,
and honest and gentle and strong.
And look what I married.
He didn't want much, did he?
[audience murmurs]
Please, please go to the Green Room.
I'll see you there in one minute.
Curtain, Walter.
[audience murmuring]
Ladies and gentlemen,
I think I'm safe in saying that
the Brains Trust is of opinion
that holy matrimony is hardly a topic
for discussion before a mixed audience
and therefore, I think we must
draw these proceedings to a close.
I may add that next week,
I am trying to arrange
for a return visit of the…
of the May Savitt Qualthrop
string quartet.
-Thank you, thank you, thank you.
-[soldier] Ladies and gentlemen.
I hope I'm expressing the sentiments
of all present
when I ask you to join me
in a vote of thanks
to our new Entertainments Officer,
the Reverend Captain Paris
for providing us
with one of the most stimulating
and, if I may say so without offence,
one of the most thought provoking
entertainment in the history of our camp.
[audience applauds]
Furthermore, we would like
to ask you, Captain Paris,
Reverend, sir,
if you could make the Brains Trust
a regular feature
of our entertainments program.
And now, three cheers for the Padre.
Hip hip!
[audience hoorays]
Just like him to pinch the car.
-Jimmy.
-What?
-[soft music plays]
-[bus arriving]
Let's catch the bus.
We must get away from here.
I can't stay in the house after this,
-how could I?
-Oh, where are we going then?
Padre, I've been made a laughing stock
tonight and I don't like it.
I'm sorry, Mr. Byres.
It's the last time I'll get mixed up
in this kind of caper.
If only Charley's Aunt hadn't run away
to Doncaster,
none of this would have happened,
would it?
Trouble always breeds trouble, doesn't it?
I believe that fellow Prout
has gone off with the whisky.
Oh, really.
What are we going to do
about Mr. and Mrs. Prout, sir?
I should have thought
that you had already done quite enough
about Mr. and Mrs. Prout.
But didn't you see
Mr. Prout had been drinking?
Yes, and I gather he proposes to continue.
But there'll be a terrible row for when
the Professor and Mrs. Prout get home,
anything might happen.
She's quite right, you know.
I don't believe it's safe
to leave them together.
But I've done my best, Lady Dodd.
I don't see what else I can do.
Well, if they start to fight,
you could part them
and Walter would help you.
Jessie, my job in life is not
to part people but to bring them together.
Perhaps you could do that too.
I really feel we should do something.
I'll tell Walter to get the car.
You know, I wonder if that poor girl
ought to see a psychiatrist.
[conductor] Any more fares, please,
any more fares?
We can go 50 miles tonight
and tomorrow we'll take the caravan
to Cornwall or Wales,
I don't mind where.
But I'm on the air on Wednesday
in Question Marks.
I can't let the BBC down.
Well then, we'll go to London
and park the caravan there.
-What? In Portland Place?
-Oh, don't be silly.
I've got another eight programmes to do,
you know.
Well, we can go down the Thames somewhere
and you can travel up to London every day.
That should be simple enough,
shouldn't it?
Yes, I suppose so.
[soft orchestral music]
Wait, Jessie, who said you could come?
You might need my help.
Yes, she really must see a psychiatrist.
[Mutch] George is back alright.
The lights are on in the studio too.
He's probably in there.
What are we going to say
if we bump into him?
I don't care if we do.
Nothing will make me change my mind now.
-Nothing?
-What do you mean?
-Well, what I mean is…
-Oh, come along.
But ought we to make up our minds
quite so quickly?
-Why on earth not?
-Well, I was thinking of my place,
you see, my house­keeper, she has a
terrible antipathy to any sort of change.
Well, of course,
if you prefer your housekeeper to me.
No, no, no, I don't, my darling but
you see, I can't afford to pension her off
and she's too old to get another job now.
I think if I'm prepared to break up
my domestic arrangements,
you might go a little way
to breaking up yours.
Yes, but as I've explained, Angela,
you see, whichever way we look at it,
-the point is…
-Don't you love me?
I love you with my whole soul.
And I love you too. Don't you see?
We've got to do something about it now.
Yes, but Angela…
Now go and change your clothes
and pack your bag
and I'll do the same.
[upbeat trumpet music]
[tense music]
There's Prout.
See if the other two are back.
[Chaplain] Mr. Prout!
Mr. Prout!
-Mr. Prout.
-[Mr. Prout] Hop it, you!
[Chaplain] Mr. Prout,
please stop behaving like this.
Mr. Prout, will you please
stop drinking that stuff?
It's only making matters worse.
Will you buzz off
and stop poking your nose
into other people's business?
There's no call to be so rude,
Mr. Prout…
Oh, what on earth are you doing here?
I came with Captain Paris and Lady Dodd.
I didn't want to cause trouble tonight,
Mrs. Prout, really I didn't.
There's no need to apologize, my dear,
I should be very grateful to you.
If not for you, I might never have had
the courage to make the decision I have,
so thank you, my dear, very much.
Come along, darling!
Oh, listen, Mrs. Prout, please,
you must wait and hear
what Captain Paris has got to say.
-There is nothing more to be said.
-Oh, but Mrs. Prout!
What on earth are you doing here,
you interfering little brat?
Oh. Oh, Lady Dodd!
[tense music]
[Chaplain] Come now, Mr. Prout,
don't be an idiot, open this door.
If you don't get away, I'll brain you!
I don't think you could do that,
Mr. Prout.
-You see, I happen to be…
-I know,
ex middle-weight champion
of the monastery.
Mr. Prout.
[tense music]
My pictures!
What on earth is George up to?
-Mrs. Prout, Professor Mutch.
-What are you doing here?
At least you will listen to me.
Look,
you can't possibly go away like this.
Forgive me, but all I am asking you to do
is to think it over, to sleep on it,
separately of course, and I'm sure in the
morning you will see that I was right.
Jimmy, don't you realize,
-George must be going away too?
-What?
Well, that's why he's got
all my pictures here.
[Chaplain splutters]
Why, it's obvious, Mrs. Prout,
he cannot bear to be parted from you
or from anything
that even faintly resembles you.
Now, Professor Mutch, look, no doubt
we all have absurd inclinations
and we don't always behave very wisely,
but there is one thing that we do owe
to our self-respect
and that is to play the game.
What game?
Hmm? Well, you're…
you're a public schoolboy,
you ought to know
what playing the game means.
[Angela] Jimmy, we're starting!
I was right. It is George!
-[bus starts]
-[Angela gasps]
This is absolutely ridiculous.
We can't all go away together.
[chuckles]
It might be the best solution,
Professor Mutch.
Don't talk balderdash.
[Jessie]
Mrs. Prout, Mrs. Prout! Mrs. Prout!
-Jessie!
-Thank heavens you're there, sir.
There's a note for Mrs. Prout
from Mr. Prout.
We'd better scramble out now.
Yes, we must, before he reaches the gate.
-Oh, would you mind, please?
-Mrs. Prout.
[bus rumbles]
-Did you say "scramble out"?
-We must be raving mad.
This is a note from your husband.
I don't want to read it.
It may tell us where we're going.
What's it matter where we're going now?
What does matter
is we're going with George.
Angela. Angela, just look at this.
What's it say?
What's he mean?
What on earth does he mean?
ls anything the matter, Mrs. Prout?
What does he mean by "this is the end"?
He couldn't possibly mean…
-Oh, I mean to say, he couldn't, could he?
-Of course not.
He's only doing this to frighten us.
Yes, of course, he must be.
He's obviously going back to his mother.
He did once before,
you told me, didn't he?
-His mother doesn't live on this road.
-Doesn't she?
-This is the Roxborough Cliff Road.
-I beg your pardon?
-It's the road to Roxborough Cliffs.
-Where does it go after that?
Nowhere.
The road ends at the top of the cliffs.
-It's a famous beauty spot.
-[Mutch gasps]
There's nothing there but a shack
that sells postcards and ice cream.
But that's ridiculous. He wouldn't
want anything like that, would he?
Come, come, Professor.
Whatever it is in Mr. Prout's mind,
it certainly is not ice cream!
Well, what is it then?
What on earth is he doing?
[tense music]
I'm quite certain
there's some perfectly simple explanation.
Then why is he taking all my pictures?
Yes, why is he?
What on earth are we going to do?
I said in the first place
we shouldn't have acted so precipitately.
So it's my fault now?
No, it isn't. It's mine for allowing
myself to be dragged into this.
So I dragged you into it?
You did. I wanted time to think it over.
-Think what over?
-Professor!
There's no sense in trying
to shift the blame at this juncture.
-I'm not trying to shift the blame.
-Then what are you trying to do?
Mrs. Prout, both of you,
keep your heads, please!
Do, do, do let us try
and sit down quietly and calmly
and talk this over
like normal human beings.
After all, there must be
some quite simple way
of letting Mr. Prout know that we're here.
Such as rapping on the wall, for example.
Angela, how far are these cliffs?
I don't know, half a mile!
-Half a mile?
-Mr. Prout!
[banging on wall]
[door rattles]
I can hear the sea. George, George!
It's no use, Professor, I've tried.
But I can hear the sea, I tell you!
We shall have to jump for it.
-Come along, Angela.
-No!
-Yes, yes!
-No, I'm not coming!
Don't panic, Mrs. Prout,
not at a moment like this.
If George is going to throw himself
over the cliffs,
-he's doing it for the love of me!
-Oh, nonsense!
No time for mock heroics, Mrs. Prout.
He can hear the sea.
No! I'm staying here.
I'm staying with George. George…
No, no! No, no! No, no! You can't faint.
You can't faint, Mrs. Prout.
Oh, she's fainted.
You can't pass, there's no room.
-Alright, Jessie, you take the wheel.
-Who, me?
-Yes.
-What are you going to do?
You'll see. Leave this to me.
Put her arm round your shoulder and lift.
[Mutch grunts]
That's right. Drag.
-[loud bang]
-[both gasp]
[bus tire squeaks]
Something's happened.
George! George! George!
George, darling, are you alright?
Tell me you're alright. What happened?
-A puncture. What are you all doing here?
-[car tire squeaks, halts]
Deliberately shooting my tires,
what childish conspiracy is this?
George, you weren't really
going to kill yourself, were you?
Kill myself? What in heaven's name
are you talking about?
Then what were you going to do?
Do what any sane, self-respecting man
would do under the circumstances,
get away and do some decent painting
for a change.
But why take all my pictures?
Well, I hadn't got any canvasses,
I was going to clean them off.
-Clean me off?
-Well, I had to paint on something.
Now then, trigger happy,
if you want to get home tonight,
you and your girlfriend
and the rest of you,
then get down and change that tire.
Well, if you ask me, half these problems
would never arise
if more people took a cold bath in the
morning and a sharp walk before breakfast.
Please, may I say something?
Look, Jessie. Listen, I'm begging you,
Jessie, try hard just this once
not to say anything at all.
-Yes, but I just want to--
-Jessie. Now, please.
-Yes, Jessie, shut up.
-What?
Nothing you say now
can make it any better.
Oh, won't it? Well, I like that.
What are you butting in for anyway?
-[Walter] I got my own ideas.
-[Jessie] You have?
Yes, and why shouldn't I have?
I've been listening to a lot of beefing
tonight, hanging on to that curtain,
and what's it all amount to?
Seems to me that it's blokes like me,
blokes that hang around street corners
and hang out with the judies
and bashing around shilling hops
with them.
We're the blokes that got a chance
to find out
what's going on in this world,
better chance than people with their heads
in books half their lives,
getting educated.
There's some things you can't learn
from books,
leastways only secondhand.
And judies is something, in particular,
you've got to know firsthand.
Take what went on tonight.
When you get a lot of blokes and judies
with too much time on their hands,
it stands to reason
you get a bit of square pushing.
I've seen it myself.
Of course, most times it don't do no harm,
it all depends on how bad you've got it.
Look, say a gent gets sweet
on another gent's Judy.
The gent what owns the Judy,
he's got two or three things he can do.
He can go about blinding and belly­aching.
He can clock the other guy
and give his Judy something to remember,
but that don't get you anywhere.
No, the only thing in my experience,
is to sit down over a pint of wallop
and say, "Here chum, how about it?"
There's plenty of other judies
in the world
yapping about, leaving their hair combings
all over the place,
what you want to come
messing around my Judy for?
She takes a bit of getting used to,
I warn you.
And I've got used to her.
If you look at it reasonable,
judies is things that most blokes
can do with, in moderation.
I mean, there's things you've got to do,
you've got to eat, you've got to sleep,
but you ain't got to go running
after other blokes' judies.
You know, I've seen the time when I'd give
the most wonderful Judy in the world
for a plate of bully
and a slice of bread and marge,
so have some sense, chum,
and how about one for the road?
Well, that's what I'd say
if I was in his place.
Well, anyway, I think I would,
you never know, do you?
Walter, I never would have believed.
You know something?
Walter is right. Oh, Walter!
-Come off it, Jessie.
-No, no, honestly,
you see, he's practical.
Now if the Brains Trust
hadn't been on tonight,
none of this would have come out and…
I might never have made my mind up.
You mean you have?
Oh yes, Walter.
Well, thank heaven for that!
I like that, I like that very much!
You've settled everything, haven't you?
That's right. Aw,
everything will be alright, Mrs. Prout,
if you mark time for a bit
and Mr. Prout doesn't go on
whacking it up.
Well, Professor, I think you'd better
stay with us at the hall tonight.
Oh, well, I mean to say…
No, he'd better stay here.
No he had not.
Go on, get in the car now
and don't keep Lady Dodd waiting.
Goodnight everyone.
But Angela, what are you going to do?
I'm going to town next week to have
my hair done in rows of little lumps
like iron filings. I'll feel alright then.
-[Dodd] Come along, Professor.
-Oh yes, of course.
-But Angela, I mean to say…
-Go on, get out!
Goodbye then.
Well, I'll say goodnight to Mrs. Prout.
Goodnight Mr. and Mrs. Prout.
-Goodnight.
You know, I don't think you should have
spoken to Jimmy like that.
I nearly threw his bag at him.
Well, he's a very sensitive fellow.
My goodness, I… Oh, what's the use?
George, must you leave your braces
all over the place?
You know you never wear them.
I hardly think this is the moment
to discuss braces.
No, perhaps not.
George, were you…
really going to paint over my pictures?
I was going to keep the one
in the sitting room.
-[Angela sobs]
-[Mr. Prout chuckles]
You know, there's one thing I want, Angie.
There's not a drop in the house.
I didn't mean that. I want a cup of tea.
I'll… I'll put the kettle on.
No, no, no, no. I'll put the kettle on.
You? Oh, don't be silly. I'll put it on.
No, no, no, my darling, you're tired.
I'll put the kettle on.
But I always put the kettle on.
Well, let's both put the kettle on.
[band music playing]
[coughs]