Director's Debut Award
Best Actress
People's Choice Award
FOOD & SHELTER
Okay, Rocio. So, you live alone
with your son in a rented flat, right?
How many months' rent are overdue then?
Eight months.
How long have you been on the dole?
Three and a half years.
Rocio, do you have any relative
who can help you out?
No, I don't have family.
Are you receiving
any benefits at the moment?
No, nothing.
So, you've no help from family,
and no benefits...
Rocio, what are you living on?
I hand out flyers a few times a month
and I get 20 Euros.
How old is your son?
Eight.
And with your son...
What did you say his name is?
Adrian.
And with Adrian,
any problems? Is everything fine?
Of course, everything's fine.
Why are you asking?
Don't worry. It's just a formality.
Hello. Is he here already?
Crikey, with the morning I'm having.
Tell him I'm finishing up
with a girl now and I'll be on my way.
Right, Rocio, here's how it is...
As a single mother
and in the situation you're in,
on the one hand,
we can apply for a social wage,
which is 550 Euros a month for six months,
and on the other hand
we can apply for food stamps
which is another 120 Euros a month
for another six months.
The problem is,
benefit payments are taking a long time.
Just to give you an idea:
The stamps are taking six months
and the social wage
can take anything up to a year.
That's the only thing
we can offer you from here.
Hello.
What do you want me to do?
I can't be in two places at once.
Yes, that would be better.
Right. I'm coming.
Sorry, Rocio, I have to go now.
The sheet I gave you,
you have to fill out the paperwork,
my number is on there.
Call me if you have any questions
and I'll see to you another day, okay?
Can I ask you a favour?
Sure.
Could you photocopy my CV?
Of course. Come with me.
- Hi, Rocio.
- Hello.
What crazy weather.
It rains,
then the sun comes out...
you can't keep
your hair nice in this weather.
I'll have to go to the hair salon again.
Adrian!
Dani!
They picked us
to play for the school team.
That's my boy! And you too, Adrian?
Yeah. And the Coach says
that we'll be playing against
another school on Sport's Day
at the end of the year.
Isn't that brilliant?
- Aren't you glad, mummy?
- Of course I am.
But you know
I want you to study and get good marks.
Adrian!
What have I told you about puddles?
You'll get dirty!
Stop jumping in them!
Don't get angry, they're only kids.
Right, see you later.
Bye.
- Thanks.
- See you later.
Hello! What can I get you?
A loaf, please.
Can I leave you my CV?
Sure, leave it here.
I can do anything. Shop assistant,
cleaning, whatever you need.
- Thanks.
- No problem.
Come on, Adrian.
Come on, let's get you home
and get those socks off you
before you catch a cold.
Goal!
Adrian, stop playing and have a shower.
One match and I'll go.
Hi, how are you, pet?
Fine, same as always.
- Where's your son?
- There, hooked on the game.
He's getting so big and handsome.
Listen,
I brought you a few croquettes
in case you want them for tonight.
I've just made them.
- There's no need, Maria.
- Go on, take them.
All this food just for me.
My husband, may he rest in peace,
loved his croquettes.
Well, thanks a lot.
I'll get dinner ready.
Listen,
I wanted to say something before I go.
A man came by
asking for you the other day.
A man asking for me?
What did he want?
I don't know.
He asked me if I knew you
and if you lived in the block.
He was a serious man
with a folder full of papers.
That's weird, well, I don't know...
Good evening...
Having a natter are we?
Hi Ani. How's your leg?
Oh, you know.
Some good days some bad.
Par for the course at my age.
I heard about your sister, how is she?
Waiting for the tests she needs
but they haven't given her
an appointment until next month.
Things have gone to the dogs.
Listen, my daughter's father-in-law...
he was sat
in the emergency hospital waiting room.
And that's where
they found him, poor man...
Don't tell me things like that,
it upsets me terribly.
All these cut-backs...
I don't know where we'll end up.
Sure, what do you expect
with all these thieving swines...
Come on.
I'll bring you good luck.
I've two tickets left
for tomorrow with number 83.
- Come on, one for each of you.
- No thanks.
Keep it. If you win,
you can sort out the electricity.
The look of those cables in that window...
It's provisional, woman,
until they come to fix it for her.
Go on, give them here.
I'll pay you tomorrow.
Good luck.
- I hope your leg gets better soon.
- Thanks.
- Good night.
She doesn't miss a thing.
She's not a bad person,
just wants to know everything.
She's a real Mrs. Know-It-All...
Don't worry,
I'll pay for your electricity,
you can pay me back whenever you can.
Go on, keep one.
Fingers crossed we win.
And I won't hold you up any longer.
You'll be wanting to get dinner.
I'm glad you're all right.
Good night.
See you Adrian!
- Bye, Maria!
- See you later.
"The squad trained by Vicente del Bosque
has already got the preparation stage
underway for the European Championship.
To ensure they are in top form...
Adrian, dinner!
...being held in Poland and Ukraine
between June 8th and July 1st,
the 'Roja' is set
to play four friendly matches.
The first will be on February 29th
in Malaga against Venezuela.
The team will face the remaining
three preparatory games in May...
on Austrian soil where
the team will face a 10-day session...
Hello?
...the Spanish squad will face
Serbia and North Korea.
Am I free?
I'm always free.
What time?
Okay, on time.
Bye!
Who was it?
The Marquess, some work tomorrow.
Don't we have any chips?
We're keeping them
for Maria's croquettes tomorrow.
Aren't you eating?
I'm not hungry.
You eat up.
...this will also be the third European
Championship title for the Spanish
Football Federation's trophy cabinet
equalling Germany's record.
The classification rounds
have strengthened
the Spanish team's position
as favourites for the title.
Vicente del Bosque's boys qualified
unbeaten top of their group table,
with a style of football
that sparks envy
and a goal scoring efficiency
that has their rivals trembling. "
Are you tired of not being able
to show off those muscly arms?
The arms are a very important part
of our bodies, and to improve them,
we've created
the revolutionary Super weight.
Super weight
is the first product capable
of doing away with those flabby arms,
toning them up
and making them stronger.
Mum, are you getting up?
It's quarter to nine.
It's really late.
Quick, get dressed.
At last!
What happened to you today?
You never learn, do you?
My kid is sick.
You always have an excuse.
Well, the next time your kid gets sick,
you know what you can do.
I'm telling you, he's really sick.
And today, don't go home until
you've handed out all the flyers.
I'll be back later.
And stop looking so miserable!
OFFER: 6 PACKS
OF SAUSAGES FOR 3 EUROS
Excuse me, do you know if they're
looking for anybody to work here?
I don't think there's anything going.
But if you hear about something,
can you let me know?
My boss runs the show.
Three ninety.
Look, here he comes.
Hey! Listen! I saw you.
Drop what you're carrying.
Rocio!
Rocio, open the door!
...the Minister stressed
that the only requirements...
Are you going to open up or not?
...has ensured that
by doing this, the banks...
Open the goddamn door!
...would be more solvent
and begin lending to households
and as such, the Spanish people
would also reap the rewards.
Nobody takes the piss out of me.
All in all, the bail out to the banks
will be calculated as public debt...
Open up!
You've no shame.
One of these days I'll grab the shotgun
and shells and then you'll see.
If you don't pay me the rent,
there's going to be trouble...
Do you hear me? There'll be trouble!
You'd better be careful what you do!
You're going to pay.
You'll pay for this.
When are you going to pay him?
I have a job interview
this week for some work.
Go on,
drink your milk before it goes cold.
I don't want anymore.
Can I sleep with you tonight?
Course you can.
That way we'll be warmer.
Come on, let's get into bed now.
Fuck!
Hi!
Good afternoon, Madam.
Sorry.
Do you know
if Rocio Gomez Moreno lives here?
Yep.
She lives here.
- She has a small boy.
- Okay.
And do you know what time
I could find her at home?
She's usually around all the time.
But like everybody,
coming and going all day.
Do you want a ticket for the draw?
I have number 51.
No, thanks, madam.
Good afternoon.
Your loss.
Look, there's your friend Dani.
Give me a kiss.
Bye!
- Hi, Rocio!
- Hi!
Are you up for a spot of breakfast?
A few of the mothers have arranged
to meet in the bar on the corner.
I can't.
I must dash.
Now that I look at you properly.
Look at you...
All dolled up today.
No man could resist you
when you scrub up a bit.
Really, you think?
You better believe it.
Look at yourself.
You're a sight for sore eyes.
Go on, come for a coffee...
I've a bit of gossip for you...
I met a Dad, cute and divorced.
Really, thanks anyway.
But I must dash. Another time.
As you wish.
LIMPIEZAS SHERRY S.L.
General cleaning services
Hello, good morning.
The boss has just called to say he's had
a setback and he can't make it today.
Apologies on his behalf and the interview
is postponed until another day.
Another day, but when?
Wait, I hadn't finished.
I also have some good news.
We're just about to close a deal
with a major supermarket chain
and if both parties sign then
there'll be work for all of you.
We'll be in touch real soon.
Brilliant!
I hope they call us.
So, thanks for coming and apologies
for the inconvenience. See you soon.
Good bye!
Who is it?
Is Alfonso there?
Is that you, Rocio?
Yes.
Well, he's not here now.
Not here?
Come on will you.
You talk to her and tell her yourself.
I'm not talking to her.
She can get lost.
Hang on, I'm coming down.
- Rocio...
- Hi.
- Rocio, how are you?
- Fine.
Sorry about the other night.
Since he retired,
Alfonso has been really on edge.
I've come to tell him
that I'll be getting
some cleaning work soon almost for sure.
Yeah, but when, love?
We've been like this for...
I don't know how long.
I'm serious. I've been for an interview
and they'll call me back for sure.
It's out of my hands, Rocio.
My son was laid off as well
and he has two kids.
Things are brutal everywhere
and we need the cash.
You know the banks
don't let anything slide...
I have to go back upstairs.
I'm really sorry, I am, truly.
Hello.
Rocio Gomez Moreno?
Is that you?
Yes, what do you want?
I'm here to issue you
with notification from the Courts.
You're being sued
for non-payment of rent.
I've no idea
what you're talking about...
If you don't want
to accept the notification,
I must say you've been notified
and the notification is available
as of tomorrow in Lower Court
number 5 in Jerez de la Frontera.
You have 10 days to appeal.
All right?
Mummy,
what does "bastard" mean?
Who called you that?
Nobody.
Nobody?
So why are you asking me then?
If I find out who called you that,
there'll be war. Was it Dani?
Forget about it.
It's nothing.
How did the interview go today?
I might get the job.
Mummy, do you know
what I'd like for my birthday?
Football boots. So I can wear them
for the end of year match.
Adrian, you know
I don't have money for that.
Come on, off to bed with you...
And stop asking so many questions,
it's late.
- Paco!
- We're ready to go.
Don't give up Paco, my man,
don't give up.
Don't give up,
don't give up, Manuel.
- Up we go, get your back into it!
- Hard and up.
- Everybody pulling together now!
- Everybody together.
That's the way!
Mummy!
- Mummy!
- What do you want?
When are we going?
In a little bit.
I feel dizzy.
Drink some water.
- Are you dizzy?
- Yes.
You have a temperature.
Let's go home.
What's up?
Nothing, a tummy ache.
Are there any biscuits?
No biscuits, Adrian.
I'd kill a steak and chips right now.
Aren't you eating?
You're going
to end up like a skeleton.
Hey!
Are you feeling better?
Yeah, I'm not dizzy now.
There's no water?
Just what we needed!
They've cut-off our water.
...we'd like to inform you
that at present
you do not have enough credit
on your phone to make a call...
Come on, hurry up!
I'm coming.
Wait, mummy.
Give it here.
Hi!
Where have you been?
You're getting so big.
No, don't ruffle his hair like that.
He doesn't like it.
Sorry, lad.
Go on, go play with your friends.
I've no water.
We don't have water I mean.
Seriously! How's that?
A leak, everything happens to me.
That's really bad luck.
Don't worry about it.
Come and get water
from me anytime you need it.
Thanks.
I'm going upstairs, I'm in a rush.
- Bye.
- See you later.
- Where the hell are you going, kid?
- I didn't do anything.
Adrian started it and he hit him.
That's a lie. He started on me
and he won't let me play.
They're picking on him
because he doesn't have a dad.
He called me a son of a bitch.
Did you call him that?
Bastard!
What?
Adrian!
Get in there.
What have I told you about fighting?
They started it.
It's always somebody else who starts it.
And what about the swearing?
Where's that from?
I'll wash your mouth out with bleach!
Do you know what?
No console for you.
But I was only standing up for myself.
I don't want you fighting Adrian
and that's that!
You know the story.
Off to your room!
Would you mind telling me
what you're doing?
You do know Jerez is full of people
looking for work, right?
Give me the billboard and the flyers.
I've had it!
Please, don't do this to me...
Give them to me now, Christ!
Nacho, think of my kid.
I'm sick of your crap.
Give it here...
Girl... girl!
I'll give it to you for a euro.
I read tons of these when I was a kid.
The memories...
Take whatever you want.
Alright.
Here, for the comic.
Wait.
Here's a tip.
It takes a lot of backbone
to stand here all morning.
Thanks a million.
I have to be careful with the wife.
If she sees them
she throws them out on me.
Okay, see you again!
See you!
FOR RENT
What are you drawing?
I'm coming.
Here, a present for the future.
That's really cool, Adrian!
What is it?
When I'm big I'm going
to look after you and work non-stop
to save up and buy you a really,
really big house...
with a garden full of flowers.
This will be our house...
Here's the pool.
And who's that by the BBQ?
Your future boyfriend.
Me? A boyfriend? Right...
You've got to be kidding...
Well, Dani's mother is looking for one.
Let her look for what she likes...
Do you know what nickname
they've given the mother?
What nickname?
"The scaredicks. "
Why the scaredicks?
Because anytime a guy gets near her
she scares them away.
Hey! not a word
to your friend Dani, do you hear me?
Let's try this on
to see if it's good on you.
Let's see.
Is it okay?
Yes.
Okay,
off to bed, it's really late.
Come up and get water anytime you need it.
Don't think twice about it.
Go on, finish filling it up while I check
the fish and tomato casserole.
Hello, What's up?
But... but what the hell
did they say to her?
And how is she holding up?
Maria.
Maria?
What's wrong?
It's my sister...
My brother-in-law
from Barcelona just called.
They've found something bad.
I'm so sorry.
The poor woman.
If there's anything you need me to do...
You've enough on your plate
to be taking on my woes, love.
Take some casserole with you.
No, no, really.
I've already taken so much.
Go on.
Take it, take it.
That's it.
It's fine.
Adrian!
Stop messing around.
Adrian, stop playing jokes and get up.
Adrian, Adrian, what's wrong with you?
Are you okay? Are you dizzy?
That's it now.
You'll feel better.
That's it.
Are you all right?
What happened to you?
I'll be fine here.
- Thanks.
- You're welcome.
How are things, love?
My leg is killing me.
I've pain everywhere.
What brings you here?
The kid got sick.
Go on, buy a lottery ticket from me
and you'll see how lucky you'll be.
God you're annoying
with the lottery tickets, they never win.
I've handed out loads of prizes
in this neighbourhood,
but recently with things being
so tough, people buy less.
Let's see if things
pick up a bit soon.
You can say that again.
Turn on the TV, for God's sake,
and it's full of politicians robbing,
this one, and that one...
Bunch of useless no-good tykes
who aren't worth a damn.
Where's it all going to end?
Look...
What a shame, that poor girl.
I've known her since she was a baby,
she was a lovely kid, and good,
I remember she had a small boy
and social services took him from her.
Adrian Gomez.
They're calling you, love.
Hi!
Okay. Come in and sit down,
over here on the edge
so I can listen to your breathing, okay?
That's nothing, give it a moment.
Go on, a little deeper.
Okay, now here.
You're a champion.
You have to buy this supplement for him.
It's not covered by the social security,
but get it and give it to him,
one every 12 hours for a month.
He's fine,
there's nothing wrong with him,
just give him a little boost.
And how about his diet?
Does he eat well?
Does he have a balanced diet?
Does he eat everything,
main course, dairy, fruit?
Yeah, the kid eats everything,
he eats well.
All right, but just in case,
we'll run some tests,
that way we'll see how things are going...
blood, ions...
and his defences,
just to check and put your mind at rest.
Okay, so just stop by the desk outside
and they'll give you an appointment.
Okay, Adrian, see you soon and be good.
See you later.
Mum! Mum! Mum!
Adrian! Adrian!
Quiet. A little respect, please.
Bless this food we are about to eat Lord.
In the name of the Father,
the Son and the Holy Ghost.
Our Father,
Who art in Heaven,
hallowed be Thy name.
Thy Kingdom come,
Thy will be done on earth
as it is in Heaven.
Give us this day our daily bread,
and forgive us our trespasses
as we forgive those who
trespass against us.
And lead us not into temptation,
but deliver us from evil.
Amen.
- Good morning.
Today we have fried ham and cheese,
bean stew. Fruit and yoghurt.
That's great.
Very rich, here you go.
- Thank you very much.
- Not at all.
- Goodbye, Rocio.
- See you tomorrow.
Bye!
Adrian!
Come out Adrian.
I'm getting annoyed!
Adrian, come upstairs!
I said upstairs, now!
Close the door.
I don't like you
out on the street during school hours.
Keep still with the ball, lad.
Have you had breakfast?
Yes.
Adrian! Pack it in
with the ball, for fuck sake!
Here.
Hello? Ah...
Hi, Pilar. What's up?
Really.
That's fantastic Pilar,
really and how do I go about it?
The Government Social Welfare Office...
Okay.
And what time are they open until?
Okay, I'll go there now.
Thanks a million, really, thank you.
Adrian,
they've given us a cheque for food!
Come here and give me a kiss.
Tomorrow don't sleep in late
because it's the end of school year party.
- No.
- Can I go with you?
No, no, you shouldn't be going to school.
- Don't you want to stay with Maria?
- Okay.
All right, let's get going.
- Hello.
To pick up the cheque for food?
Your name, please.
Rocio Gomez Moreno.
Gomez?
Moreno.
If you just fill in this form here,
name, two surnames,
ID number and sign here.
Here you go.
Thank you very much.
Goodbye.
...kick out for Spain...
Spain playing.
Short pass to Iniesta...
Adrian...
...ball to Xavi.
Both teams playing
in a very tight space now.
Xavi to Iniesta.
Trying to make the play
throw in to the French side...
This is pretty good...
What did you get up to with Maria?
She was telling me about
when she was a little girl.
I'm very fond of Maria.
She's so kind.
That's very true.
Mummy, why did you tell Maria
that I don't like people
ruffling my hair?
I said that? I never said that...
Here, a little early,
something for your birthday.
Do you like them?
They're great, mummy!
They're cool!
I'll definitely score a goal
with these tomorrow.
Let's try them on.
My boy is going to score
one great goal tomorrow.
Come on, let's eat!
...he's ready to take the corner.
He kicks the ball
into the area... Casillas!
...the French defenders return back
and holds the midfield,
very far forward to try
and stop Spain from playing their way.
Casillas boots it up field...
Mum?
Can I come in?
Mum, what's wrong with you?
Should I call Maria?
Mummy.
Please, if you'd come this way.
Come in.
Are you the lady who called this morning?
Yes.
Please, take a seat, Miss.
I can call you miss, can't I?
Of course.
Okay, I'm going to try and help you,
if possible. Did you bring the letter?
Yes.
This letter enforces a sentence
suing you for non-payment
of rent of a property.
This is from some time ago...
- Your name is...?
- Rocio.
Okay, let me explain, Rocio.
This notice must have arrived
in the post about four months ago
and it's the suit brought against you
by the property owner
for non-payment of the rent.
In cases like these there are
several options open to you.
When the notice arrives you have 10 days
to either make payment of the debt,
abandon the flat or file an appeal,
if you don't agree with it.
So, what happens then?
Well, the term for filing
an appeal has run out.
Which means that the term for doing
anything about it has already expired.
So, then?
What happens now?
Rocio,
there's nothing I can do to help you,
the Courts have issued the eviction date
and that means
you'll have to leave your home.
But, how can that be possible?
Can't I appeal or something?
You've come a bit late.
But you're a lawyer,
you can do something, can't you?
You should have come to see me earlier.
There's nothing we can do at this point.
That's how the law works.
You'll have to be out of the flat
before July 2nd at 10:45 am.
The best thing
is to start looking for somewhere else.
I can't do anything to help you.
I really am sorry.
Charo, could you come here
to show the lady out, please?
Now if you'll excuse me,
I'd better get back to work.
But, isn't there anything
you can do to help me?
I'm on my own with a small boy.
Don't you need anybody,
I don't know,
to clean the offices or something?
Or maybe you know somebody
who's taking people on?
No, I'm really sorry.
Now, I'm afraid
you'll have to leave, please.
Would you come with me please?
Did you see my pass to Dani,
and the goal he scored?
- Have a great summer.
- See you next year.
Bye.
Cheers...
- Bye
- Bye, see you.
Wait here, I'll be right out.
Son of a bitch!
I'm going to fucking kill you!
You're going to throw me out
onto the street!
Take your hands off me.
Let me go.
- Is she mental or what?
- Fucker...
- Are you fucking mad?
- Bastard...
Get lost, fuck off!
What do I do now?
Go on, get the fuck out of here!
You fucking faggot!
Do you thieves want to get
the fuck out of here now, or what?
You fucking son of a bitch!
- Get the hell out of here!
- Fucking...!
Son of a bitch!
Mum, mum.
Are you getting up?
It's nine o'clock.
Have you eaten anything?
Yes, but I'm still hungry.
Come here to me.
What was wrong with you earlier?
No idea.
I've never seen you like that.
I'm like my mother in that way.
When your granny used to get angry,
she had a serious temper...
TODAY, JULY 1ST AT 8:45PM.
SPAIN VS ITALY.
I can't wait to see the football tonight.
If Spain wins tonight,
will you buy the newspaper tomorrow?
We'll see.
Mum.
What?
Can I invite some friends over
this Friday for my birthday?
Maria!
- Hey, Rocio!
- Hi!
I've just been to your house,
to say goodbye to you.
Where are you going?
I'm off to Barcelona,
my sister is worse. She's practically...
Adrian, come here,
for your birthday.
Seeing as I won't be here for it.
- Christ!
- Maria!
It's cool, isn't it?
I'm really going to miss you!
I'm not staying in Barcelona for good.
Okay, I'm off, I have to get a taxi.
Adrian, you handsome boy.
My boy...
I'm going to show the shirt to my friends.
For God's sake,
look after yourself, Rocio, okay?
Okay, see you, Maria, have a safe journey.
- Bye, Rocio.
- Goodbye.
Mummy, what are you doing?
Putting away the winter clothes.
It smells like fire.
What?
Go outside.
Mum,
can I turn the TV on?
The match is about to start.
We can't turn the TV on Adrian.
You're not telling me
I can't watch the final are you?
We've no electricity.
It's always the same.
It's all your fault.
Adrian!
Don't get at me, do you hear me?
None of this is my fault.
No, of course it isn't.
Now I can't watch the match.
I'm sick of it.
Why can't you be a normal mother?
What do you mean?
Dani's mother scares off men
but they don't even go near you.
What are you talking about?
I don't even have a father...
Stop it!
You're acting crazy.
Bastard.
Adrian!
Ball for Xavi Alonso.
Xavi. Xavi to Torres.
Offside.
A little tight that one I think.
Well, well. It's nearly over.
Ball for Italy. Ten and half left.
We can't believe it. It's incredible
but we have too much time.
Careful, watch out.
Spain are back on the attack.
There's Xavi,
he passes the ball to Torres...
Goal!
I'm so sorry, forgive me.
Me too. That's enough of that,
today is a day to celebrate.
You know
things have been really tough lately.
Yeah, you're really acting weird.
I haven't been able to pay
the rent now for a few months.
And the landlord has reported us.
We have to leave.
When, mum?
Tomorrow.
Goal!
You can open the door.
Go ahead.
In my flesh, the nest of shame
The nail grime that claws yearningly
Splinters of my shipwreck
The cuts of the eyes looking at me
In my mouth the wound
The same wingless prayer
The cry that they tread on me
The cowards
I forgot the kisses
The smile and love in words
My frozen hands, locked doors
I walk the paths
Of a world with nothing
I beg for the coat
I ask for crumbs
And life goes by
The flame goes out
In Spain, 526 people
lose their homes each day in 2012.
The unemployment rate currently stands
at 26%, the highest it has ever been.
13 million people are at risk
of poverty or social exclusion
The banking sector was bailed out
to the tune of 100 billion Euros.
So, who's going to bail you out?