♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh
♪ The wish you use
on a shooting star
♪ The single dream
that feels so far
♪ The only thing you
want but cannot have
♪ It's the ending
in the storybook
♪ The chance you
know you shoulda took
♪ Ignored advice
your father gave away
♪ When all that
you're hoping to find
♪ Is the whisper you
can't leave behind
♪ So you try
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh
♪ It's your mother's kiss
on the smallest wound
♪ Her gentle touch
that pulls you through
♪ Standing at your
door to say goodnight
♪ That feeling
when you go astray
♪ Forgotten words that got away
♪ The goodbye you did not
know would be the last
♪ When all that
you're hoping to find
♪ Is that whisper you
can't leave behind
♪ So just trust your heart
♪ You'll get your wings and fly
♪ So you'll try
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh
Subtitles by explosiveskull
No, no, no, this is all wrong.
Forks go on the left,
knives on the right.
Am I the only one who cares
about throwing a good party?
Yes, McKenna,
you're the only one
who cares about the party.
None of us could possibly
care as much as you.
What are forks even for?
Emilyn, that cake
is for the party.
Relax, that's the
keep Emilyn away
from the real cake cake.
Don't worry, I won't let
her ruin the real cake.
That's the let Harper think
she's guarding the
real cake cake.
Aleeda put me in charge
while she went to
the wedding ceremony,
and she said that everything
has to be perfect, so I...
Hey, where do
you guys want this?
Finally,
something done right.
Whoa.
Would you look at the
size of that thing?
It must be worth a fortune.
Or at least a lot of money.
From your first
breath to my last.
Aleeda wants to give it to
them as soon as they get here.
Now, if they show up right
after the wedding ceremony,
the sun should be
directly above us,
so that will make the
optimal placement.
Stop being so smart
and hang it on the rock.
Be careful.
Aleeda spent months on that.
Relax, everything
is taken care of.
Do you think they'll like it?
Of course, it's perfect.
That's
enough admiration.
We still have plenty
of work to do.
Now, what time did Aleeda
say they're coming?
They're not.
I've reevaluated our priorities.
We've wasted far too
much time on them,
so I'm cancelling the party.
What do you mean?
What happened?
Nothing happened.
Fairies belong in the forest
and humans belong out there.
But, Aleeda,
you've always said...
No fairy will have
any contact with humans
from this day forward.
Aleeda, what about your gift?
Leave it as a
reminder of our mistake.
Is that it?
Are we ever gonna
see them again?
If Aleeda says we aren't,
then that's the way it will be.
Now, throw out the cake
and start taking
down the decorations.
My Pop was the most
stubborn man I know.
When I was nine we moved
to the city for Mom's work,
and I didn't wanna leave my Pop,
'cause he was was
my whole world,
but he told me it'd be all right
because if you love something,
truly love something, than
nothing can keep you apart.
I thought he was
just being nice,
but when we got there there
was a computer waiting for me
with a note that said,
"Because I truly love you,"
and a P.S., "As soon as I
figure out how this works,
"I'll call you."
After a day of cursing
and phone calls,
my Pop figured out how to
call me on the computer,
and every day after
that without exception.
He helped
me with my homework,
and he'd send me silly
videos on my birthday.
He'd just listen
to me if I wanted to talk.
He was my best friend, and
I'm really gonna miss him.
The worst part was finding
out that my Pop was wrong,
because no matter
how much I love him,
he can't come back!
Sweetie, wait!
Not having fun at
the party, petal?
It's not party,
Gam, it's a funeral.
Sounds like someone
should tell them that.
How come you're not sad?
Don't you miss him?
The only time I miss someone
is when I'll never see
them again.
Just because you left the farm
didn't mean I wouldn't
see you again, right?
Not really the same thing.
Sure it is.
I believed I'd see you when
your mum moved you away,
and here you are.
Well, I wish we had a
better reason for coming back.
Did I ever tell you
about the time I
helped invent popcorn?
No.
Well, I was at a fair,
and I had bumped
into a fire-eater
who spat his fire
at the corn vendor.
Oh, he was really angry
about losing his hair
until the corn started popping.
Gammy, did you
guys get horses?
Oh no, dear, we
don't have horses.
Oh.
Do you still like horses?
- I love them.
- Ah.
Mom still
takes me for lessons,
but it's inside, so
it's not the same.
I really miss going on
the trails with Pop.
Probably why he
got you this then.
Gammy, but you just...
We don't have horses.
We just have this one.
Hi there.
Careful, honey,
Tanner's fussy.
He's beautiful.
Pop's the only one
who could take him out.
Other tries, but Tanner
knows who he likes
and who he doesn't.
You miss
him too, don't you?
He can see you have his eyes.
I would
never hurt you.
Looks like someone
has a new best friend.
Hey, what are you doing?
Mom, look, this is Tanner.
Isn't he handsome?
Yes, but can you
stay back from there?
Mom, I ride them all the time.
Well, that's different,
this is a farm horse.
A farm horse?
He was Pops's and
Gammy said that I...
Amanda, we'll talk
about this later.
The guests are leaving,
we have to say goodbye.
Come on, sweetie.
Let's say goodbye
to the party guests.
And I will tell you all about
the time that I met Elvis,
Oh, he was very handsome
Thank you.
Condolences from our family.
Take care.
Charlie, thanks for coming.
How could I miss this?
My dad would've been so happy
to see so many friendly faces.
You and
Amanda staying long?
No, we're
just here for the weekend.
I've gotta go back to work.
Sure.
You think you could drop by
my office in the morning?
There's just some
business to finish up.
Sure thing, I'll
come by first thing.
Do you still like
blueberry scones?
I'll
wear my belt loose.
Okay.
- Bye.
- Take care.
Mom?
What is that?
I have no idea.
Can you help me
with the kitchen?
I have to put some stuff away.
Yeah, sure.
Amanda, have you
seen my toothbrush?
Oh.
I don't have one on me,
but there's a spare one in...
What? Why?
Patty, Patty, what
on earth are you doing?
Mom, stay back.
Amanda, call 911!
Oh, for heaven's sake.
- No, no, no.
- Dylan, Dylan.
- Nope.
- Are you okay?
Yeah.
Mom, you know him?
This is Dylan, he helps
me with the day-to-day.
Oh.
I'm so sorry.
Ah, it's my fault.
I thought you'd like
a hot bowl of oatmeal.
Kinda regret the hot
part now, though.
Mom, why didn't you
tell me about him?
Because it's Dylan.
He's always here.
Oh, that clears that up then.
Well, I'm off.
I gotta go downtown
to see Charlie.
I'll be back in a
couple of hours.
Amanda, do me a favor
and make sure, um...
Dylan, or intruder.
You know, I'll answer to both.
Okay, if you can help
Dylan get cleaned up,
that'd be great.
Um, then can I go see Tanner?
No, sweetie, you've
gotta get ready.
We've gotta get to
the airport on time.
I thought we weren't
leaving until tomorrow.
Sweetheart,
you've just go here.
I know, but work called,
and I've got this mess
- to clean up...
- Mom!
Grownup
decisions, Amanda.
All right, sorry about that...
Violent oatmeal throwing?
Yeah, no, it's fine.
It's not fair.
Come on, petal.
It's not that bad.
Oh, no, you guys go.
I'll take care of this.
So while it may look like
they're close sometimes,
I promise they
are very far away.
So neither of you have
to worry about the sun
and the moon crashing
into each other.
Huh, that actually
kept me up all night.
Oh, now I'm sad, because they'll
never get to be together.
Hey, wanna throw the disc
at the edge of the forest?
Oh, yes!
Can I pick teams?
Sure.
Okay, I choose Emilyn!
I was so worried
you weren't gonna pick me.
I felt like the
moon to your sun.
I don't have a son.
All right, let's go.
Losing daylight.
Wait, why do we have to play
at the edge of the forest?
I don't know, just
more open space.
You're trying
to see that girl.
What?
No.
I just think that there'd be
better range for throwing.
Tell me you just
aren't a tiny bit interested.
I knew it.
I'm going to tell Aleeda.
Aren't you curious?
Come on, you of all the fairies.
All you do is study.
Think of all the
things you could learn.
Rules are rules.
Well, what else would they be?
And I'm not
interested in learning
what they have to offer.
Aleeda is quite
clear on this point.
We're not going,
and that's final.
Okay, forget her.
Let's just fly out to
the edge and have a look.
I promise, we'll just look.
I don't know, Cali.
I don't wanna get in trouble.
Come with us.
We'll tell you the sad story
about the sun and the moon.
Nah, you guys go ahead.
Good morning.
Sorry, they didn't
have blueberry.
Do I
look like I mind?
Have a seat.
Still the sheriff as well?
No one else stupid
enough to do it.
I remember when you
first walked in here.
Do you remember that?
I remember walking in
with my little piggy bank,
telling you to draw up a
emancipation agreement.
I
think you called it
an exaggeration agreement.
Coming in here acting like a
grownup at eight years old.
Somebody had to act like
a grownup in that house.
I guess your folks did
beat to their own drums.
Drums?
More like pots and pans.
Well, I won't keep you long.
I know you're a busy gal.
Just a bit of paperwork
to make it all legal.
Thanks, Charlie,
You know, I just wanna get
my mom into someplace nice.
How's that?
Well, I looked at a
few retirement homes,
and I'm not sure it's gonna be
an easy conversation to have.
What?
He didn't tell you.
Tell me what? What did he do?
Just your dad beating
those pots and pans.
What?
I don't understand.
He left me the house?
Why wouldn't he give it to Mom?
I think it was
part of the bigger plan.
He wants to make the place
into a bed and breakfast?
As far as I know,
everything's been done.
What?
Your dad, he worked on
this for a whole year.
He didn't tell you
anything about this?
Dad.
What did you do?
Well, he did
make this for you.
Hi, peanut.
If you're seeing this, I'm
sorry to say, I've gone.
Charlie, I bet you're wearing
that silly green
tie, aren't you?
I keep trying to tell
you, green is off-putting.
I'm leaving you all my ties.
There's only three of them,
but all of them would
be better than that one.
But by now I'm sure
Charlie's told you
about my little surprise.
I'm sorry to spring it
on you like this, peanut,
but we both know that if I tried
to tell you about the idea,
you'd just shut me down
before I even got going.
I know I'm asking a lot of you,
to come on home and
run a bed and breakfast
with your mum and Amanda.
But when I look at
everything you've done,
I, quite frankly, I
couldn't be prouder of you.
My little girl went off
and took on the whole world
and beat them.
And boy, I've loved being
in your cheering section.
But I couldn't just
leave this world
without giving you
and Amanda this gift,
the gift of family,
because you deserve it.
Just say the word if
you want to leave.
Your mum doesn't
even know about it.
Just tell Charlie and
he'll sell the place off,
you go back to your
big city living.
It's your call.
How can I say no to that?
I got her, didn't I?
Charlie, with all that guilt
stuff, I did, I got her.
Well, that's it really.
I've set up everything.
Dylan knows all about it and
can fill you in on everything,
that is if you're granting
a dying man his wish.
I truly love you, Patty.
I always have done.
From your first breath
to my last.
Charlie, how do I
switch this thing off?
Pops.
So?
What do you think, kiddo?
I think I just inherited a
bed and breakfast.
Gammy?
Up here!
Still not big
on cleaning, huh?
Ah, pish posh.
A clean house is a
sign of a boring life.
Well, then this place
is very not boring.
What are you working on?
Well, can't you tell?
It's a sculpture of
you and your new friend.
Am I really that ugly?
If you want to see the beauty,
you have to believe in it.
Well, I believe it
looks like a pretzel.
But it's a very good pretzel.
Oh.
Oh, I have missed you.
Gam, you're getting
clay all over me.
Oh, I am so sorry.
Gam!
Guess you must be pretty
handy with a mop, huh?
Sorry, I'll clean it.
Don't worry about it.
You're gonna have to
save your strength.
For what?
Well, I figure we can
start with the fence,
and then once we're done that,
we're gonna have to repaint
the side of the house.
I think it's gonna stay white,
but like a lighter
shade of white.
Seriously?
Well, it's either
that or the other job.
Well, what's the other job?
Well, somebody's gotta
take care of Tanner.
You know, feed him, brush him,
hang out with him all day.
Really?
Can I, Gam?
He's waiting for you.
Are you sure? I picked out
a really nice shade of white.
And I mopped myself
into a corner.
Morning, Tanner.
Look what I brought you.
That's good, isn't it?
I can't believe I just met you
and I already have to leave.
You know, maybe I can convince
Mom to come back next summer.
What's wrong, buddy?
You wanna go for a run?
Man, Mom would
totally ground me.
It'll be worth it, come on.
I bet Pop took you
out here a lot, huh?
What's wrong, buddy?
I say we just fly
out and say hello.
What's the worst
that could happen?
We can't talk to her.
McKenna said.
McKenna is not the boss of us.
Who knows if she
can even hear us?
Hello, is someone there?
Whoa.
Mind blown.
Look, she's probably lost.
We can't just leave her
out there all alone.
I'm going.
You will do no such thing.
Her timing is awesome.
Why are you always trying
to be the boss of me?
Keep your voice
down, she can hear us.
If she can hear us, then maybe
we're supposed to meet her.
We have no reason
to go out there.
What is that?
Well, now we have
to go help the horse.
No, no, no, wait.
Is that your umbrella?
Yeah.
Sorry.
Okay, let's go home.
I just wanted to say hi.
What kind
of person does that?
I said she could
take care of Tanner.
Uh-oh.
I thought
she'd have fun.
Well, maybe
you should let me decide
what's fun for my daughter!
No, Mom, it's
not Dylan's fault.
I didn't ask if I could ride.
Do you have any idea
how dangerous that was?
What were you thinking?
I just wanted to ride
him once before we left.
Well, we may not
be leaving after all.
We're staying?
Oh, thank you, thank
you, thank you.
For now, Amanda.
I'm going to tell Gam.
Gam, guess what?
I'm still mad at you.
Sorry I couldn't tell you
about the bed and
breakfast thing.
Your dad made me promise.
Yeah, no, that's fine.
You cool off.
I'll chat later.
Gammy, we're staying!
We're staying!
I get to stay here
with you and Tanner!
Oh, petal,
that is wonderful!
Okay, so I'm thinking
that I'm gonna be
in charge of Tanner.
I mean, not in
charge or anything,
but I'm gonna make
sure that he's brushed
and fed and exercised and stuff,
but you have to help me
convince Mom to let me ride him.
Never mind about
the horse, Amanda.
Ugh, that's a lawsuit
waiting to happen.
We need to figure out how to
run this bed and breakfast.
Come on, Mom, he's
not exercised...
Wait, what bed and breakfast?
It's a long story,
apparently part of Pop's
master plan.
He's taken his home and made
it into a bed and breakfast
for us to run.
So did you quit?
No, I took a leave.
They're not thrilled,
but losing Dad seemed to
have given me some leeway.
It's not permanent,
but we'll help Gam get
this place up and running,
and then we have to go back.
Gam, are you hearing this?
Oh, yes, I'm so glad
that you and Tanner
are getting along.
Apparently this is gonna
take longer than I thought.
She'll be all right.
Your Pops really did
set it up for you guys.
Is this really the best
time for you to just jump in?
I'm not really sure you've
shown you have a best time.
What does that mean?
I think you
know what it means.
Look, I'm just trying to help.
I don't understand...
What are
you looking at, Gam?
Looks like my fairy friends
are throwing another party.
She's my daughter.
- Fairies.
- I make the decision.
- Oh my, yes.
- You're not listening.
Can't us
see them there?
Mom, come look!
The forest has fairies in it.
You know, I knew I heard
voices when I was in there.
Mom, please don't fill
her head with nonsense.
Just because you
choose not to see them
doesn't mean they aren't real.
Dylan, have you seen them?
Oh no, I don't
go in that forest.
It's haunted.
That's the smartest
thing you've said
since you've been here.
Amanda, you stay
out of there too.
What?
- No way.
- You wanna hear smart?
I'll tell you smart.
How about you learn to
raise your daughter?
Your daughter knows
- how to ride a horse.
- Uh, hellO, excuse me.
I've seen her,
I've seen her ride the horse.
Of course she
can ride the horse,
- she's had lessons.
- So what's the big deal?
She can ride the horse.
- Just give her a chance.
- Uh, excuse me?
Easy?
It's not that easy.
Stop yelling
at me, I don't...
Hi there.
Uh, I'm sorry to disturb
you, but are you guys open?
Oh, yeah, your dad did
have me distribute those.
Sorry, we're really
in the beginning stages.
But I can take your name and
number and I can call you back.
- I just...
- Yeah, that's fine.
I just need a...
Your name, sir?
Uh, Turk.
Uh, Turk Peterson.
Little Turkey Pete?
Hey, Patricia.
Oh my gosh.
I haven't seen you
in like 20 years.
Yeah, 20 years
sounds about right.
And wow, like, you look great.
Thank you.
You too, you look great.
I see you got your braces off.
Yeah, well, I wanted
to keep them on,
but the dentist said
20 years was overkill,
so what can you do?
Well, your teeth look great.
I mean, not just your teeth.
You all look great.
What are you doing here?
Doesn't your parents
live down the road?
Yeah,
I guess they are
just down there, aren't they?
Uh...
You know what,
I'm just gonna come clean.
I heard you were in the area
and I wanted to come see you.
Oh.
So, um, how was
it riding Tanner?
Isn't it fun doing something
you're not supposed to?
Yeah.
I thought you'd be
alone, and I'm came here,
and everybody was here
and I got all nervous,
and I panicked, and now
I'm really embarrassed.
You know what, I'm just
gonna go, actually, um...
It's fine.
Oh, I'll take fine.
Fine's better than crazy, right?
Yeah.
So, um, would you...
Uh, uh, would...
Oh, right.
Yeah, no, I, I got
stuff I can do.
Sorry, what were you saying?
He's about to ask you
out to lunch.
- Mom!
- No, no, she's right.
She's abrupt, but, uh, right.
So what do you say?
Would you like to go for lunch?
Sure.
That sounds great.
Oh, great, oh, thank
you for saying yes.
Uh, would one work?
- Sure.
- Great.
Uh, wow, I just realized we
keep saying great a lot, um,
- okay, I'll see you at one.
- Leave.
Maybe,
yeah, yeah, okay.
I'll just go.
Bye.
Hmm.
Hey, Turk,
I'll be right there.
Uh, sure thing.
Uh, take your time.
Hey.
I'm taking her out right now.
No, no, I don't think
she'll be any trouble.
Um, if you leave it with me,
I promise we'll start this demo.
Okay, hello, hello?
Oh, um, Ashley, right?
Amanda.
Ah, right, right, Amanda.
Um, I don't know if you heard.
I was just, uh, having a
conversation with, uh, my buddy.
So what are you
planning on demoing?
My
buddy is in a band,
and, uh, I'm producing the demo.
Right, and why would
my mom be any trouble?
You know what, Amanda,
what if we keep this demo
talk between you and me,
and I give you some money,
maybe for a new
saddle for your horse?
Your horse could use
a new saddle, I see.
Mom, Mom!
Oh, no, you don't need Mom.
No, no, you stay
right here, all right.
Hey, hey, come back, come on!
Did I hear Amanda?
Yeah, she said something
about going on a walk,
but not to worry about her
and to buy you something
nice for lunch.
She's a handful, that one.
Oh, I can imagine.
I'll get the door.
Thanks.
Hey, kid, you alive?
Yeah, I think so.
Man, you really
cracked into that branch.
I tried to warn you.
I thought you were a ghost.
Ghost?
How crazy would that be?
You're a fairy.
I bet it was the wings
that tipped you off, huh?
Are you gonna hurt me?
Are you serious?
You're like 1,000
feet taller than me.
Plus you have this giant horse.
This is Tanner.
Hi, Tanner, I'm Cali.
What's that?
Is that right?
Did she really say that?
She's here to do what?
What? What is he saying?
I have no idea.
I can't talk to horses.
Come on, let's get
you all cleaned up.
I must be dreaming.
Nope, no dream.
Come on, my house is
just right over here.
Nothing to see here, folks,
just a giant girl
with a cracked noggin.
Cali, what do you
think you're doing?
Relax, McKenna, I'm
just giving this girl...
Amanda.
Amanda here
something for her head.
You can't just be
bringing aways here.
Aways?
Like away from here.
It's what some of the
ruder fairies call you.
Gimme a second.
You know what Aleeda said.
What do you want me to do,
leave her unconscious
in the forest?
I'll clean her up and
send her on her way.
I'm telling Aleeda.
Nothing personal.
So how long have
you guys been here?
Not sure.
As far back as I can
remember, anyway.
Aleeda and some others
came over on a boat.
Others just sort of
got here, you know?
Bang-o.
Slap this on your noggin.
Ow.
Yeah, it's got a sting to it.
But you'll feel
better in the morning.
Cali, Cali!
Cali, did you hear?
One of the fairies brought
an away to the village!
Hello.
Oh man, the away.
Amanda, this is
Harper and Emilyn.
One of them is smarter
than the other.
Oh, thanks, Cali.
Nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you too.
I like the flowers in your hair.
Thanks, we call them
friendship flowers.
We make them for each other.
You want one?
We'd have to be friends first,
but then we could make you one.
Sure.
This place is incredible.
Yeah, we like it.
That's our place over there.
Since we're best friends
now, you can come over.
You may need to stay
outside, though.
Cool.
The one beside is McKenna's.
Don't knock on her door unless
you like being yelled at.
Which would be weird if you did.
Whose house is that?
That house isn't ready yet.
What do you mean?
A fairy door won't open until
the fairy inside is ready.
That fairy's not ready.
There, see?
Quick, hide in our house.
Uh.
Let me move some stuff.
Told you she brought one.
Yes, McKenna,
hard not to see her.
Cali, explain yourself.
Before you get too
upset, I know the rules.
But Amanda was riding
through the forest
and smacked her noggin.
I couldn't just let
her die, could I?
You risked all of us, Cali.
Oh, please, why are
we so afraid of them?
Girls, that's quite enough.
How's your head, little girl?
Much better, thanks to Cali.
You remind me of someone
I knew a long time ago.
Thanks, I guess.
Tell me, what brought
you through our forest
at such great speeds?
I almost forgot.
There was this guy, Turk,
and he's dating my mom,
and I heard him on the
phone talking about demos,
and then he grabbed me.
He grabbed you?
Well, he tried,
but I ran away.
What they do is
no business of ours.
As much as I see this
pains you, McKenna's right.
We don't interfere
with what goes on
outside the forest walls.
Aleeda, Amanda
might be in danger.
My decision is final.
I have my reasons
for staying out.
I must also forbid any
further contact with Amanda.
Amanda?
That's my mom.
There you are.
We've been worried.
We've been searching for you.
Don't freak out.
What
happened to your head?
We gotta take you
to the hospital.
No, Mom, it's fine.
She helped me.
Who helped you?
Cali, the fairy.
What?
What's wrong?
She can't see us.
What?
She's in between.
Not young enough
to believe in us.
Not old enough
to believe again.
Sweetie, you're
talking nonsense.
- Wait.
- Come on.
I have to
tell you about Turk.
There she is.
Amanda, are you okay?
We were worried about you.
I heard him on the phone.
He's up to something.
What?
I have no idea what
she's talking about.
I don't like this guy one bit.
He tried to pay me
to keep it a secret.
What is going on?
Okay, you got me.
I saw Amanda on the
horse the other day,
and she asked me to
keep it a secret.
I'm sorry, Amanda,
I gotta come clean.
Are you kidding me?
I feel bad.
I see what happened now, and
I just, this is my fault.
He was on the phone
talking about demolition.
Demolition?
You believe me, don't you?
Sweetie, you were just
talking about seeing a fairy.
Mom.
You're unbelievable.
Amanda!
Easy, boy.
Just let her blow
off some steam, okay?
I'm gonna take Tanner
back to the stables.
Thanks, Dylan.
Listen, I'm sorry.
No, it's my fault.
She's under a lot of stress
lately, she's acting up.
No, no, you don't need any
more responsibility, all right?
You have enough on your plate.
You're a good guy.
Aw.
Come on.
I really am.
Ow.
I just, I
don't know what to do.
I just thought I was doing the
right thing by staying here,
but this is all out of control.
She'll sleep it off.
And all this
nonsense with fairies?
I swear, my mom's
filling her head.
Ugh, I haven't even started
getting this place ready.
What am I doing?
Tell you what.
I'll come by in the morning
and give you a hand.
Oh, no, I
couldn't ask you to...
No, it's
already settled.
You're a lifesaver.
Hey, do you wanna
go get some coffee?
Coffee sounds great.
Amanda!
What are you guys doing here?
That's exactly
what I keep asking.
Relax.
We just wanted to
make sure you're okay.
I guess I'm all right.
We talked it over,
and we decided we're
going to help you.
Really?
All of you?
Well, no, not all of
us, but the four of us.
That's better than
nothing, right?
For the record,
I'm not here to help.
I'm here to keep a
logistical record
of the events that transpire.
I don't know what that
means, but we wanna help.
Thank you so much,
guys, but what can we do?
My mom thinks I'm
just imagining you.
Let's keep it that way.
Meet us at the pond.
That'll be our meeting place.
Oh, I've always wanted
a secret meeting place!
Emilyn, how long
have I been saying
we should have a
secret meeting place?
A long time.
High five!
Wing high five!
Okay, see you tomorrow.
See you tomorrow.
Oh, here, I almost forgot.
You made this for me?
Of course, you're our
friend, aren't ya?
For the record,
we are not friends.
More coffee, sir?
Oh, you startled me.
Uh, yes, please.
Sorry, just making my rounds.
Good morning, Mr. Peterson.
Ah, everybody's sneaking
up on me this morning.
Is it the shoes?
You're like a ninja.
I should get a pair like those.
Where'd you get 'em at?
Where is our
money, Mr. Peterson?
Well, you're gonna
like this, 'cause I got...
Finish chewing.
Sorry.
Uh, good news is it's coming.
I know I had a bit of a
rough patch with the dad,
but now I'm kind of,
uh, wooing the daughter,
and I think it's safe
to say without a doubt
that she's probably gonna
sell the farm to me.
So that's good for you,
because then you
get your money back.
Nothing, huh? You're
just like a rock.
You're a hard read.
I don't know what's
going on in that head.
Mr. Peterson,
you and I are involved in
an A, B, and C situation.
A is the borrowing of
my money, which you did.
B is the spending of my
money, which you also did.
And C is the paying
back of my money,
which you have not.
Which part of those letters
involves me listening
to you going on dates?
Well, I see what you're
interested in.
Uh, 'cause I meant like
C, like the letter,
'cause of what,
uh, are you hungry?
They make a mean omelet here.
It's, I don't know what's
in it for the life of me,
but the chickens are
like made out of gold.
Oh, take it, no, take
it easy, take it...
When you first came
to us with this solution
to your money problems,
you said it was,
how did you put it?
In the bag.
But I thought it was, I...
Be quiet.
It's terrible manners to speak
when someone else is speaking.
Sometimes just
things don't always go
according to plan, you know...
Mornin', darlin'.
There's the smile
I came in here for.
Flattery won't
get you free coffee, Charlie.
Well, I can
give you a song and dance too
if you like.
Mornin', Turk.
Morning, Sheriff.
Turk, don't you
want your breakfast?
No, I'm
not really hungry.
Is that
one button or two
that you stole from the village?
Why do you automatically
assume I stole them?
Maybe I found these.
How many?
One.
Looks like two to me.
You tried to kill me.
Under the Order of
Fairy, section three,
any act of violence
against another fairy
shall be considered, whoa!
Now it's none.
And stop accusing
me of stealing.
So she had two in the
sack, but then she threw one.
And then she
threw another one.
Math is hard.
Hi, how's it going?
You're wearing the flower.
Yeah, I made one for Tanner.
I know I'm not a fairy or
anything, so I hope it's okay.
Of course it is.
Wow, good job.
Maybe you are a fairy and
you just don't know it.
Whoa, mind
blown.
All right, I have
it all figured out.
We know he's up to
something, right?
Right.
But since we don't
know what that is,
we just need to
make him go away.
Okay, how do we do that?
I stole a bunch of stuff
from Aleeda to help us.
Come on, we have a
lot of work to do.
Thanks for coming.
There's a lot to do around here.
Oh, I'm happy to lend a hand.
How can I help you?
Well, you can take
this into the stable.
Thanks.
You're a lifesaver.
I really hope this works.
Of course it's going to work.
Sit back and watch.
Whoa, you're a big fella.
Well, you must be
friends with Amanda.
You picked the
losing side, horse.
Whoa, what is that?
Aw, come on.
Oh, you think that's funny, huh?
We'll see if you're laughing
when I send you to
the glue factory.
Okay, I made a bunny ear.
Oh, I
made a rabbit ear.
This should work.
Your chair might be a
little bit more comfortable.
Yeah, I fell.
You all right?
No, something tied
my shoes together.
Don't look at me
like that, all right.
I don't know what it was,
but something tied my shoes.
Nobody ever listens to me.
Listens to you about what?
I keep telling people
this forest is haunted.
What, like ghosts?
Yeah, I've seen 'em.
Bouncing lights,
floating spirits.
Well, that, that's crazy.
That's not, that can't happen.
Yeah, that's my cue.
What was that?
Gonna go.
Where, where are you
going, you leaving?
Whoa!
Yes!
Ow.
And that's how you
get rid of someone.
Whoa.
Turk.
What is it?
What's wrong?
You got
ghosts going on over there.
Ghosts?
Yeah, yeah.
They came right after me.
All right, come over here.
We gotta get you cleaned up.
Come on.
You know, I hate to think it,
but that ghost is
probably Amanda.
She has a unique way
of handling things.
Yeah, well, I don't think
she likes me very much.
Give her time.
Her and my dad
were really close.
Yeah, I suppose it's hard
when you lose someone you love.
Yeah.
He meant a lot to her
Well, I was meaning you.
Mm.
It's been three
weeks and Turk is still here.
You have to
lay your hand flat
or the rock won't skip.
My hand is flat.
Maybe it's too flat.
No, like this, watch.
Hello, are you guys
even listening to me?
Sorry, we're trying
to get the hang of this.
Ooh!
Do you mind?
Why would I mind?
Yeah, you got wet,
you should mind.
She doesn't know herself.
So what if he's going
out with your Mom?
Maybe that will be better.
I just don't trust him.
We have to figure out
how to get rid of him.
So this is why
you come down here,
so you can talk to yourself?
Hey, Dylan, what
are you doing here?
I was going to the apple tree
to get some apples
for the other animals,
but it looks like somebody
here has cleared us all out.
Sorry, that's my fault.
Oh, yeah, that's your fault
for taking such
good care of Tanner.
Kiddo, you've
been a lifesaver to me.
Really?
Yeah.
Your Pops ever tell
you how he got Tanner?
Oh, I love this story.
No, I didn't
even know about him
until I got here.
Well, your Pops and I
were running an errand
because Jean decided it was time
for her to learn how
to play the piano.
Like most grandmothers do.
So we find one, we get it
all loaded up in my truck,
and we hear this guy,
this real nasty fella,
just yelling and carrying on.
Your Pops being who he
is, goes around back
to see if he can help.
Sounds like Pop.
Turns out this guy
can't control his horse.
Figures the best
way to teach him is
to beat a lesson into him.
I'll be honest, I was
ready to do something
I wouldn't be proud of.
But your Pops,
just cool as a cucumber.
Walks right over to this guy.
Did Pops hit him?
No, he looks him in
the eye and he goes,
"You know the difference
between a guy beating a horse
"and a guy getting
beat up by an old man?"
Guy says, "No."
Pops says,
"Me neither."
The guy was so afraid of Pops,
he just handed over the
reins and walked away.
So we ended up bringing
home the piano for Jean
and Tanner for Pops.
And now I think we brought
home Tanner for you too.
Well, anyways, I better
get into the city
for some apples to eat.
Do you need anything?
No, we're good, thanks, Dylan.
All right, well, I'll
see you back at the farm.
Why can't my
mom date a guy like that?
Okay, we have to
come up with a plan.
Now, I was thinking
we attack his money.
Mess with his car?
He'd have to keep
getting it fixed,
and it will cost a fortune.
Or we could hide one of
every pair of his socks.
- That's always a good one.
- Yeah!
You guys do that?
Oh, yeah, that's
a fairy staple.
Kill two
birds with one stone.
What was that?
I said kill two
birds with one stone.
Are the birds like a
sacrifice or something?
Oh, I don't wanna do that.
- Oh, no.
- I don't wanna do that.
You set
your mom up with Dylan.
She wins because
he's a great guy,
and you win because Turk's gone.
Two birds.
Genius.
Come here!
No, no, no, thank you.
You like us!
Admit that you like us!
I'm not one of you.
I'm just here for note-taking.
Tell us you like us.
Okay, so how do we
make my mom like Dylan?
Makeover!
You brought the
fairy dust, right?
Yeah, I nicked it from Aleeda.
She only keeps it
for emergencies.
Do you want me to tell on you?
'Cause that sounds like
the kind of thing you say
when you want me to tell on you.
She'll never even know.
Okay, I'll go hit him with
a blast and put him out.
So what's in it?
No idea.
You don't know what's in it
and you wanna blast him with it?
How much do we use?
Let's try a handful.
Yay, I
solved a problem!
You so smart!
Okay, first things first.
Lose the hat.
♪ Gonna get cleaned up
♪ So I can get down and dirty
♪ Gonna live it up
♪ No way I'm leaving early
♪ Gonna get cleaned up
♪ So I can get down and dirty
♪ Country life has
come to life tonight
Oh.
♪ Gonna get cleaned up
♪ So I can get down and dirty
♪ Country life has
come to life tonight.
♪ Gonna get cleaned up
♪ So I can get down and dirty
♪ Country life has
come to life tonight
♪ Gonna get cleaned up
♪ So I can get down and dirty
♪ Gonna live it up
♪ No way I'm leaving early
♪ Gonna get cleaned up
No.
♪ So I can get down and dirty
♪ Gonna live it up
♪ No way I'm leaving early
♪ Gonna get cleaned up
♪ So I can get down and dirty
- ♪ 'Cause country life
- Yes.
♪ Has come to life tonight
♪ I said country life
has come to life tonight
♪ 'Cause country life
He looks good.
For an away or whatever.
He's waking up.
We did it!
Oh,
someone cleans up good.
What?
Oh, oh, yeah,
I guess I was sweeping.
No, I mean you.
What?
Yeah, you look good.
Bye, Mom, I'm
going to see Tanner.
Amanda, wait.
Gam, who exactly is this for?
Oh, whoever it'll fit.
Did I ever tell you
when I was asked
to knit a sweater
for the president?
He wanted pink.
Lots of secrets, that man.
All right, you ready?
This is pretty amazing.
- Okay.
- Okay, so...
Yeah.
Uh.
It's not as easy as it looks.
Yes, it
is, children do it.
Well, all right,
it's sounds like
you're accepting the challenge.
Okay.
How did you?
And that's how I
got the pickle out.
Wait, was I telling
the pickle story?
All right.
Well, it looks like
I gotta go practice.
Yeah.
You know, I like
it when you do that.
Do what, the coin trick?
Smile.
Is
that for a giraffe?
What a wonderful idea.
Scarves for giraffes.
So it looks like you and Dylan
have been getting along
pretty good lately.
Yeah.
He's a big help around here.
Is that it?
Just a good employee?
Oh, I see where
you're going with this.
What, where
am I going with it?
Yeah, I'd like to know.
Oh, hey.
What are you doing here?
Well, I was coming to see if
you wanted to watch a movie,
but it looks like your
dance card's already full.
What does that mean?
Well, it means lately
you've been pretty busy.
Well, if you haven't noticed,
we're trying to open a
bed and breakfast, Turk.
I don't know what
you're talking about...
Right,
you have no idea.
It's just all in my head, right?
Maybe it's not.
You know what, Amanda, you
stay out of this, all right?
Okay, that's enough.
Everything all
right over here?
Yeah, we're fine.
Thanks, Dylan.
Yeah, thanks, Dylan.
Thanks for getting in the way.
Pardon me?
Okay, you know what, Turk?
I think you better go.
What, are you serious?
Yes, I am, actually.
I think we could use a
little bit of time here.
All right.
You all right?
Yeah, I'm sorry
about all of this.
Well, you should be.
I figured out how to
make that coin disappear,
but I can't make it
come back.
Whoa.
What?
That is amazing.
Mm.
Show me that again, it's...
- Okay.
- Okay, so you went over.
It's not polite to
slam doors, Mr. Peterson.
Oh, Mr. Green.
Uh, wow, you are, you're
really good at sneaking.
Is it my fault?
For sneaking?
Did I not enunciate
the words enough for you
about getting my money?
Uh, no, no, it's not that.
You're really good at
speaking, actually.
Um, I didn't realize we
locked an actual date.
I thought it was
more like, you know,
when someone says something
like soon or whenever,
if it works to get it
back to you as soon...
- Stop talking.
- Yes, sir.
My associates
and I feel it's time
for us to step in.
No, no, really,
please, I'm really close.
I can do this if you just...
Manners, Mr. Peterson.
I'm really sorry.
If you just, I can get
this deal done tonight.
Oh, actually, no,
no, I can't get it.
If you give me five more
days I can get it done.
Just five more days.
Okay?
And then my mom
told him to go.
It really worked!
McKenna,
you're a genius.
As far as records go,
I didn't do anything.
But off the record, I'm
happy for you, Amanda.
Thank you.
This is so great.
Turk is gone and now we
can hang out all the time.
Where is everyone?
They're gathering supplies.
They won't be back for hours.
So, what now?
Celebrate!
Whew, yeah!
Whew!
What is this?
Aleeda.
We were, um, just
showing Amanda here...
Uh, we were celebrating,
because we helped get
rid of the bad guy.
What?
I thought I was quite clear
when I said that we were
not getting involved.
They were just trying to help.
We don't help humans.
Fairies stay in the forest.
Aleeda, I can explain.
You disappoint me
most of all, McKenna.
Say goodbye to Amanda.
You won't be seeing her anymore.
What?
Bye, Amanda.
Amanda?
Wait, is that really her name?
I've been calling her Alanna.
Why did no one tell me?
Bye, guys.
Sorry.
For what?
Being my friend?
I'm not sorry for that.
So I guess this is it, huh?
Hold on.
Here, take this.
We can use it to talk.
You light it up from your window
and I'll make my wings glow
so we know that we're
thinking about each other.
Cali.
I better go.
Hit me up at your window
later so I know you're okay.
Okay.
I thought you were a giant
firefly coming to take me away.
Hey, Gam.
Everything okay, petal?
I got my friends in trouble.
Oh, well, I'm sure
it'll be all right.
In the long run, the friends
who get you into trouble
are usually the best ones.
Did Pops get you in trouble?
Oh, did he ever.
I miss him.
You can't really miss
them if they're still here.
I see your Pop at
the breakfast table,
singing his off-key songs.
I smell him every time
I open the shirt closet.
And look, right over there.
Pop made it sure that you and he
could still go on your rides.
I love you, Gam.
From your first
breath to my last.
Gammy, I made you breakfast.
The toast is kind of burnt,
but at least the eggs are,
never mind, they're burnt...
Gammy?
Can I come in?
You all right?
No.
It's been a couple
of days, Amanda.
Are you gonna spend the
whole summer up in your room?
Maybe.
She really loved
you, you know.
She loved you too.
I know.
What do you say we go
down to the kitchen
and have a nice cup of tea?
And I'll fill it with
sugar just like Gam.
I guess.
Good.
Come on.
What is this?
I think you need to sit down.
Excuse me, I
have things to do.
Can you sit down?
I don't wanna sit down.
What is he doing here?
Sorry to hear about
your grandma passing away.
She was a real great woman.
Yeah, I don't need you to
tell me how great she was.
Amanda, I think
you need to sit down.
Stop asking!
I'm not sitting down.
It's best to do
it quick, like a Band-Aid.
What is this?
You're going home, kiddo.
Mom, you can't.
This is a lot
for you to take right now.
It's really for
the best, Amanda.
Turk, you're not helping.
Let me guess, you
sold the farm too.
What? I was kidding!
Mom, what about Tanner?
I know, but we can get
him a place close to home.
This is home.
It's all good, Amanda.
Your mom sold me the farm.
Aren't you happy?
You get to go back to the city
and see all your friends again.
I don't have any friends.
All my friends are here.
How could you sell this place?
But it was different when
it was the three of us,
but now...
Now what?
Say it.
Amanda.
Say Gammy's
dead, so it's okay.
Say Pops is dead, so it's okay.
I don't wanna fight.
Say you hate me, so it's okay.
Wow.
Teenagers, huh?
Doesn't even look like me.
She knew.
Day one, the
others said it would be
too much trouble to
bring the fairies,
and they'd have to stay behind.
But Aleeda said, "Good
friends don't let
"a little trouble stop them."
Day 40, we've been at the
farm for a couple of months.
There's this boy who
keeps bugging me.
Aleeda said it's
because he likes me.
I just think he stinks.
Pops.
Day 100.
Okay, so, maybe he
doesn't always stink.
He brought me some
flowers today.
I think Aleeda helped
him pick them out,
because yesterday she kept
asking me what kinds I liked,
and today this kid magically
shows up with the exact ones.
Either way, it was sweet.
Last day.
So I guess this book ends with
me marrying the stinky kid.
Turns out he's the most
amazing man I've ever met.
Oh, I have never been so happy.
And I owe it all to
my dear friend Aleeda
for asking me what
flowers I like.
Funny, I haven't
seen her in awhile.
Perhaps she moved away.
I hope she knows
how much I love her.
Thank you, Gam.
Mom, Mom, I have to
show you something!
Hey, slow down.
Get out of my way, I
have to show my mom...
- What's this?
- Stop!
Relax, I'm
just looking at it.
I know what you're doing.
Yeah, what's that?
You used my mom
to get this place.
And when you said demo,
you meant tear it down.
But once I show her this book,
she's not gonna sell it to you.
Hmm, you have it
all figured out.
Did your mom tell you
that she's already
signed the papers over?
- Let it go!
- Hey, hey!
Hey, relax, all right.
Just take it easy.
- You're gonna get...
- What's going on here?
Amanda was
just showing me her scrapbook.
She's actually got
some wonderful drawings
- and pictures in here.
- He's lying!
This is Gam's book,
and it proves that there
are fairies in the forest.
What is going on here?
Look, I found Gam's book,
and Turk doesn't
want you to see it
because there are fairies in it.
Look, there are photos of Gam
and Pop when they were little.
I think it's safe to say
Amanda's seeing things.
Just look.
Look, right there!
Enough about the fairies!
These are just drawings, Amanda.
They're not real
fairies, just drawings.
You just have to believe.
They don't exist!
Look, I'm getting
worried about you.
You're way too old to
be imagining fairies.
I am not imagining them.
What are you doing?
Get away from my horse!
Whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa, relax.
We're doing our job, okay?
What is this?
Turk, what's going on?
I have no idea.
I'd be happy to
shed some light.
Uh, Mr. Green, I wasn't
expecting you so soon.
Oh, I think we've
waited quite long enough.
Turk?
Uh, now,
you see, in the long run,
this is actually gonna
be a funny story.
You're gonna laugh.
But Mr. Green technically
owns the farm now.
Well, most of it, I
still own 10% of it.
Actually, my associates
and I no longer feel
your vision and
ours are aligned.
What?
We've decided to part
ways with you, Mr. Peterson.
Hold on, you can't
just cut me out.
Oh, we can.
In fact, we just did.
You see, the property
is signed over today,
and you said your part would
be taken care of ages ago.
Your wooing took far too long.
Wooing me?
This was part of your
plan the whole time?
I can see how it
looks like that,
but if you give me
a couple of seconds,
I can show you that this
is financially beneficial
for the both of, oof!
Mom, tell
them to let Tanner go!
Not somewhere you
wanna put your hand!
Look, whoever you
are, I made a mistake.
I'm not selling you the farm.
So you can get your goons
and get off my property.
Tsk, such bad manners.
Oh, you're right, I'm sorry.
My mother taught me better.
Pretty please, with sugar
on top, get off my property.
Much better.
Unfortunately, this deed
says that this property
and everything on it is mine.
Tanner?
So pretty please,
with sugar on top,
get off my property.
You can't have him.
Amanda, come back!
Amanda!
Cali, Cali, please,
you have to help.
Amanda, what's wrong?
Some people are here
to destroy my farm.
What is this?
Aleeda, please,
I'm begging you.
They wanna destroy the farm and
they wanna take Tanner away.
I'm sorry.
We can't interfere.
She didn't forget about you.
I know you think she
did, but she didn't.
She always loved you.
She just got too old
to see you anymore.
She would never turn
her back on you.
You always said good
friends never let
a little trouble get in the way.
I guess you were wrong.
Cali.
We're with you, Alanna.
It isn't happening,
turn your rig around!
We're not
going anywhere, pal.
Hey, just take a breather.
Keep calm, everybody.
Come on, I'm sure we can come
to a reasonable solution.
Just calm down.
Well, we need you here now.
Get over here.
Get your kid outta here!
Listen, if I could
control her, I would.
Whew!
Ow.
Yeah!
Ha ha!
Ooh.
I am done!
I tried to play nicely
and do this legally,
but you are insistent
on forcing my hand.
So now we'll do
this another way.
Stop!
Ah!
Fairies!
Fly!
Whew!
Yay, Aleeda.
Ah.
Get back here!
I don't know what games
you're playing here,
but I assure you,
this is the end!
Yes, I think it is.
Who wants to tell me what
the blazes is going on here?
This guy was trying
to burn down the stable.
Is that so?
Sheriff, I think
you'll see here
that I am the legal
owner of this property,
and as such, I have the right
to do with as I see fit.
I guess technically
this is right.
But, Charlie, there
are other circumstances.
No, I'm sorry, darlin',
but if he owned this property,
he'd be within his rights.
- Thank you.
- That is,
if he owned the property.
What?
- I just showed you the deed.
- I know.
These papers say that you do.
But the problem is I'm the one
that did up the deed for
this place, and it was split.
Yes, then the old bag died!
It went to the mum!
She signed, ya backwoods hick!
Fair enough.
Only thing is my good friend
Jean had me draw up a new will,
singing her half
over to someone else.
Me?
Yes!
What?
So you got half the deed
signed, but you need both.
Miss Amanda, you looking
to sell your half?
Never.
Then it looks like
this contract is
what we backwoods hicks
would call null and void.
- Turk!
- Yep.
Get my car.
I'm leaving this
mannerless hole.
I'm afraid that's
not gonna be possible.
You tried to burn this down.
That is attempted arson.
Ow!
They're too tight!
That's for calling my
very good friend an old bag.
Manners, Mr. Green.
Ow!
Won't you come down
to the station too,
little Turkey Pete?
Oh, I'm not very
involved in this, I should...
Oh, I'm
sure there's some kind
of fraud charge
I can make stick.
Come on.
Thank you so much, guys.
You saved Tanner.
What are friends for?
Amanda.
Look at the shooting star.
Are you coming?
What is it?
A new fairy.
Come one.
Amanda,
where are you going?
Why don't we just
stop fighting her
and see where she's going?
Okay.
Just trust me.
You'll love it.
A shooting star means
that a new fairy will
be joining our family.
Let's all welcome
them with open arms.
Guys, I know this is hard
for you, but just believe.
Just try.
I'll try, but...
Whoa.
What?
What is it?
I see it.
They're here.
Let's party!
Yay!
I can't believe it took
me so long to see this.
It's amazing.
They're ready.
Who's ready?
I don't know.
I don't know, this fairy's
never come out before.
They said they only come
out when they're ready.
Pops.
May I have this dance?
Of course.
I love you guys.
From your first
breath to my last.
Subtitles by explosiveskull