FOREVER WITH YOU
What a bright moon... Shit!
Why? Aren't you sleepy?
One day before their release,
everyone feels the same.
You might feel sick and tired of this jail.
You pig! Sorry, but I graduate
from here in 10 years.
Well, good for you!
Be nice to him, he's out tomorrow.
Dude! Hunch your back and get some sleep.
Dude! You can get hurt on the outside.
What can you do?
Since you were in jail,
your fate isn't that great.
Don't worry.
There's someone waiting for me.
It must be a girl
who lies through her red lips.
-I had a girl before, too.
-Shut up!
-My girl is...
-Do you think she's waiting for you?
-Of course.
-Is she your wife?
-That's not the point.
-You really love her.
I'm sure she's waiting.
She's not the one you think.
-You don't know her.
-Is she your first love?
Yes.
-She's my childhood friend.
-Life is the best at that time.
The place I grew up was
such a poor village, even at night.
Everyday late at night
we used to come back to our village.
Ae-ran worked at a bakery until late.
I only had the pleasure of walking
with her at night.
Well,
Bye, bye!
Where do you go every day?
-Won't you eat?
-Why did you cook rice?
I owed Ae-ran again.
You did? Don't do it. Pay it back soon.
Where did you get this money?
Huh?
-You can just use it.
-Let me know where.
-Where did you get it?
-I got some work.
What is that? Gwang-pil
You can't be like your dad,
even if we are starving to death.
My humble mother,
who lost her husband to gambling.
But I was already with Dal-soo.
He was good at playing the harmonica,
so I hated him.
Hey, let's go!
-Dude!
-Shhh!
-How unlucky.
-Why?
-That's all I've got.
-What?
-What about you?
-Huh?
-The one just now.
-Did you come to nothing?
-Dude, let me in.
-Find a good target.
-Shut up and follow me.
I lost my precious money...
-She's poor.
-Let's get the money back to her.
What? Dude, are You crazy?
You must not be hungry to be able to say that.
What's up with him?
He's supposed to be here in 5 minutes.
-He's gone to the bakery.
-Son of...
Why there?
Watch out! He buys Ae-ran gum...
He's very nice to her.
He's making vain efforts.
He said that Ae-ran asked him to teach her
how to play the harmonica.
He was boasting about it.
It looks nice? You wanna try?
-How can I play?
-It's very easy.
I'll teach you.
See, Do Re Mi Fa, huh?
-See. You can do it.
-Yes
It sounds pretty, like your face.
Good. You play well.
You...
Well,
You can play as well? Try it, huh?
Pish!
Why are you getting angry?
-Get away!
-Why are you running riot?
-Pick it up.
-Let's go out, man!
You wanna fight?
You will know your ribs are broken
when you hear a snap.
-What?
-Bastard! Let's go
Oh! What are you guys doing? Oh, my...
What the heck is this?
-Clean it.
-Get away!
-Look at this blood.
-I won't talk to you anymore.
Are you mad because
I played Dal-soo's harmonica?
-Did you really hate it?
-I don't know.
I won't even look at him later.
It must be painful. What a bad guy!
Look at the dust on your shirt.
Did you really like his harmonica?
No! I don't, not now.
Ae-ran, you must be a sleepyhead.
Why?
I feel sleepy too, lying beside you.
Then, go to sleep.
You're not a grown up.
You can't snore like that.
Yes, I am. I have hair on my legs.
-See!
-Oh my!
See, see!
Here you can hang out
the washing and this is...
I like sky blue.
-On this wall?
-Yes.
-I'll get red curtains on the window.
-That would be nice.
-How many sons will you have?
-I don't know.
Who knows, if the person
who will give birth doesn't?
-I don't know, I don't know.
-Oh, it's cold.
What should we do?
Let's go over there!
Oh, it's cold!
Look at that! Our house fell down.
We can get wet here, too.
Let's go under the tree.
-Okay
-Hurry!
It's cold!
-You must be cold.
-No
Why is it raining, bloody hell!
-We won't forget today!
-Right.
Oh, It's cold.
I grew this much more than last year.
-Let me measure my height.
-Sure.
Well,
Look here and smile.
Get closer to each other.
Wait, I have something in my eye.
-Let me see.
-It tickles.
Stay still.
Ah!
-Is it better?
-Yes.
-Mister!
-You can have your picture tomorrow.
I've already taken it. What a beautiful scene.
Your breath can take away a lover's pain.
Dude...
-Look at this picture.
-Well
-It looks nice.
-Really?
-Does it?
-Yes.
-The photographer is weird, isn't he?
Huh, what?
How did you get the picture?
A man like me has enough money.
I know everything.
-You can't hide anything from me.
-What?
You pick people's pockets.
-Hey!
-Yes, sir.
Get me some water.
You'd better feel ashamed, a man like you.
-What's up with her?
-Forget it! I won't talk to you anymore.
Did you tell her?
Tell her Amen.
-So you don't like money?
-Pish!
Tell me you don't like it.
A Wa Yu Wei
O, Yo, Yo Don(Money) money, money!
Money!
Who said I don't like money?
-I thought you were dumb.
-You're mean.
-Got irritated?
-I mean it.
Don't get close to them.
They're like gangsters.
-What?
-You might get caught.
Never do it again?
Why won't you say anything?
A o o o huh?
-Do you get it?
-Pish!
You go!
Hurry, you brat!
Hurry!
It's strange that you entered this school.
First time, I could have gone
to juvenile reformatory for three years.
Had I been patient,
I wouldn't have been like this.
Once a user, forever a custom.
That's because I was too young.
It was 5 months after I went to jail.
That's right.
I went to the interview room and...
Ae-ran!
Such a fool!
What did I tell you?
Look in the mirror.
You should take a look at yourself.
How's my mother?
I'm sure it's hard for her.
How's her illness?
What? Huh?
-She passed away.
-What?
-When?
-A while ago.
Really, huh?
-Mother
-Don't cry.
Mother
How did she close her eyes?
All alone, in an empty room, with nobody.
-Where was she buried?
-Around a grave site...
The seniors in the village took care of her.
I've been busy so I couldn't come to see you.
The bakery was burned down.
Now...
I work at Yonseon-ok.
-What? Uncle Gombo's?
-Yes.
Are you crazy? Why do you work at a bar?
You know my situation.
-Time's up.
-Ae-ran.
Please quit working at the bar, eh?
I see.
That night, I thought
there was no way other than
prison breaking to calm my heart.
And I'd been looking for a chance,
and one day...
Ae-ran! Ae-ran!
Come out!
Hey
Tell the girl that Gwang-pil
-came, will you?
-Yes, sir.
Ae-ran!
Ae-ran! Here.
How did you get out?
I missed you so much.
-Then, you broke out of jail?
-It's all right.
As long as you're with me,
I have nothing to fear.
I wish it were a dream, oh my.
Let's run far away, shall we?
-No way.
-Why not?
Shall I leave you at this bar,
and go back to jail?
What can we do then?
You're the only one that is left for me,
and my mother's grave.
You put lonely me into jail alone...
I'll be waiting for you for a long time.
Forever
Ae-ran!
Where did this girl go?
-Ae-ran!
-Oh, no. Not in here.
-Stay still
-Later...
-It's all right
-Wait for me. I'll be back soon.
Get me some food, huh?
Hey, Ae-ran!
Are you Gwang-pil?
If she's your lover, why doesn't she
come to see you, not even once?
Because she's worried that
I might run away again.
She has been sending clothes
and food every month for 6 or 7 years.
My Ae-ran is that faithful a girl.
Trust is the mother of deceit.
Brat!
She must write a letter,
saying " Keep the faith, love Kim Ae-ran''
Our life has been deceived by hope.
When I get out this time,
I'll become a new person.
-Oho Gwang-pil!
-Yes?
It's a suit sent for you.
Put it on when you are released tomorrow.
Hurrah, guard!
See! She sent clothes for tomorrow.
Ae-ran will not sleep well tonight either.
-Shut up
-Ae-ran!
You're hurting my feelings.
Hey, you should consider a person like me.
When you get out, come and see me.
-It'll be faster to see you again in here.
-What?
No, it's just a joke.
Be happy with her after you get out.
Be happy together.
I'll be here doing nothing.
What a man...
-Gwang-pil!
-Huh?
-Don't you recognize me?
-Oh Sang-moon!
-Buddy!
-Thank you.
You must have had a hard time.
It's all in the past now.
How did you know?
I thought you guys had forgotten about me.
Did you come alone?
Yes.
If any, there's another myself
wearing this priest's suit.
-Let's go!
-Wait.
She must be coming...
-Who?
-You might know her, Ae-ran.
-Ah! Once you met...
-Yes.
She sent me clothes every month.
You never change.
Where does Ae-ran live now?
Huh? What's she doing?
Let's go anyways.
She might not come
because of a personal problem.
Let's wait for her for a while.
She might be disappointed
if she comes late and can't find me.
All right then.
Is this your car?
You must be successful.
-What happened to you anyways?
-The day you were caught...
I went to a catholic church right away.
I confessed all my sins to a father,
and cried all night.
-Then the father led you to...?
-Yes
Thanks to him, I went to a seminary.
My desire to save you spiritually
-made me wear this suit.
-I see.
Without you,
I would have looked up
at the stars of my cursed destiny,
and wandered a street of sin.
I see.
I learned hairdressing at school.
I used to do the hair of higher-ups.
I see.
I made some money,
so when I buy some tools,
I can get a job anywhere.
Then, I can make Ae-ran happy.
I am very confident now.
When we were younger,
I made a promise with Ae-ran.
We drew a picture of our house on the sand.
We dreamt of a beautiful house.
The sky without bars.
A red curtain on the wall.
It's like a dream, but I'll make it come true.
Amen!
-Take a rest.
-Yes.
It's all for you that I come to this holy room.
-Will you smoke?
-No.
I lost the taste. A friend is the best.
If you didn't come,
I'd have nothing to do now besides standing
in front of the gate of the prison.
-Let's drink. I've some western wine.
-Well...
Why did Ae-ran not come?
Today...
I've got this good quality wine
to celebrate your release.
Huh?
I missed her so much.
Before we drink this first shot,
I want you to forgive me
who never went to see you.
It's all right...
Tell me some stories of this world.
-I think I know nothing.
-All right.
Stories in this world are not that great.
The next year you were put into jail,
I heard from a priest that
you were sick in bed.
-In fact...
-Uhm...
My pain was so hard to take,
because I didn't know
what was up with Ae-ran.
The priest also told me that
your illness couldn't be healed with medicine.
After I heard that
-since then I've been looking for Ae-ran.
-What?
But if I could not find her,
what would be right for me to do?
-To a weak man like you...
-So?
It must be hard, but
I just wanted to save your life.
I started writing letters
and sent them in to you
in the name of Ae-ran
who could only heal your illness.
What?
Then, you did everything?
Yes, I did. How miserable!
But can't you see that
this fortunate misery led you
to become a hopeful man for 10 years?
Then, my Ae-ran died?
Huh? Ae-ran...
-Let's imagine that she's dead.
-What?
-For your future.
What can you blame in this world?
You should console yourself.
The more you can't forget her,
the more miserable you guys will become.
-Then, did she get married?
-Yes.
I heard that by accident.
What?
Moreover, she's running a cabaret.
If I could tell a lie to you tonight,
I'd make you happier.
For 10 years,
I've carved this with these 10 fingers.
This is...
Would you take a seat here?
Bartender!
You just looked down on me.
I didn't come here to be treated.
You mean that you don't need me?
Thank you! Spread your wrinkles.
Shall we dance?
What... you're as cold as ice.
Drink it and warm yourself.
Tell the manageress to come here.
Yes, sir.
Is there any place to talk alone?
Wait over there.
Please take a seat.
I apologize for giving you this tedious treatment
It's been a long time.
Are you the manageress here?
Yes!
I'm like a disgraceful queen.
-Please sit.
-Yes.
-Mr. Kim!
-Yes?
Wine, please.
Dal-soo runs this place?
Let's talk about business in the office.
He's an old friend of mine.
Where's his house?
He's here now. Want to talk to him?
Yes.
Tell the boss to come over here.
Let's drink.
Don't you know the wife of Dal-soo?
You don't want to talk about another girl
in front of a lady.
It's all about feeling, isn't it?
-The manageress is calling you...
-Where?
-Over there
-I see.
That guy must be the man from Japan.
Oh, look who's here.
-When were you released?
-Why?
You thought I never came out?
You're good at talking now.
Excuse me.
Good to see you anyways.
I've been busy with business all alone,
so I couldn't go to see you.
I know your obvious tricks.
I guess you came here
to see me bearing a grudge
after you find out everything.
-Then?
-But, hey,
there's nothing you can do for a relationship.
Moreover, it's been 10 years now.
The relationship between you and my wife is
in the past.
Will you abandon friendship for that?
I don't like friends and have no friendship.
Hey! Let's drink anyways.
Excuse me.
I see. Stay here.
Drink with her here.
I have a guest.
Come to my office tomorrow.
I heard that you have found success.
Does your wife come here?
Don't even mention it.
She's always in hospital.
Jimmy! Take good care of him.
Son of bitch!
There's not even time
for laughter in this world.
-Open your mind.
-How old are you?
Why do you work here at your age?
Stop talking about boring things.
You could be handsome without the beard.
-If it's for money, I'll give it to you.
-Jimmy!
Excuse me for a moment.
I'm a guest as well.
Even you don't hate me?
What are you?
You're not scared?
You've got a nice mouth.
You're interesting
since you're from the school.
Son of...
Hey
Mind your own business
and leave him alone.
-What about this hall?
-It's mine.
-The guest is worth 20 million...
-Madame brought him.
-Will you treat him specially?
-First of all, I'll check the conditions.
He's secretly from Japan.
Okay!
It's a piece of cake.
Today you should change
the number of the car.
Dong-il Corporation
-Well...
-Oh, look who's here.
Long time no see.
It's surprising that you've come to see me.
Having fun these days?
-Is this first time since then?
-Yes.
We're going different ways,
so had no communication.
-Oh Gwang-pil was released.
-Yes, he was.
I've been waiting for him the whole night,
not knowing that he came to see you here.
He left earlier.
-Then, where did he go?
-He's changed a lot.
I bought drinks for him,
but he broke chairs and...
Dong-il Corporation speaking.
What? Young-saeng Hospital?
I'll pay the fee today.
-Such an ass hole!
-Who's in hospital?
Don't even mention it.
She's always in hospital,
so I can't handle it.
-I should get going.
-Why? Stay.
-I'm sorry for not helping you.
-It's all right.
What time is it now?
The doctor will be here soon.
Have some food and go.
I don't need a doctor now.
Excuse me.
You've got a scary illness.
Look in the mirror to be in front of a girl.
You need a comb?
It can't brush my unkempt brain.
Good bye.
-Good morning!
-Is that you, Chun-hee?
Yes.
-Feeling better?
-Yes
Why do you bring flowers
all the time? It costs a lot.
You don't even know my hobby.
-What?
-Sis!
When I walk on the street with flowers,
people might think that
I'm on the way to a date.
-Get a boyfriend then.
-Well, it's not that easy.
Last night, something bad happened.
A man came and fought
with the boss' men.
The man was just released from prison.
How pitiful!
-Your injury will be worse
-Please do me a favor.
You know Dong-il Corp. upstairs.
Can you let me know
which hospital the boss's wife is in?
Yes sir.
Oh, well,
I've been waiting for you,
-leaving behind everything
-Don't mention it...
It's humble to say,
but my business is very small,
as you from overseas can see.
If you two have no other questions,
let's make the contract.
-Yes, I see.
-The price is obvious.
Mr. Lim! Thank you for everything.
All right.
-Could you come over here for a while?
-Yes.
You know the guy.
-He went out.
-I should have given him some medical fee.
He looked to be busy meeting someone.
What?
I'll take off.
I've got some work.
I'll see you in the evening.
-I'll buy the drinks tonight...
-Good.
The rest will be sent when the stuff is
taken over, as we promised.
-What time will it be?
-It should be at night.
I'll be waiting for you around 9 in my car.
9 o'clock? I'm coming here then.
You did a great job, madam.
All I did was introduce you guys.
Mom! Are you going somewhere
after combing?
No...
Then, you're not sick anymore?
-Did you miss mom?
-Yes
Tell nanny to get the sweater to put on.
-The weather is cold
-The red one?
Yes.
Mom! Daddy's here.
What're you doing here in hospital?
-You've got classes in the morning?
-Yes.
You must feel better now.
-You have energy to comb.
-Yes.
Gwang-pil came out. He ruined himself.
Such a poor guy.
What should I do?
I should take care of him.
Who will help him to eat?
What?
Why?
You're so mean.
You'll throw him into the depths of misery
just as he gets out.
He must be in pain.
He's following me to trample on me.
But I won't be fooled. Huh, such an idiot.
As long as I don't tell a secret,
he will never harm anyone but me.
Thank you for coming here.
-You came to see her.
-Thank you.
Take a seat here.
Didn't you get hurt last night?
You had me loosen up my muscles.
You drank too much.
-It must have been a hard time.
-I lived in comfort.
What can a man like me do anywhere?
Smoke.
-Is she your daughter?
-Yes. Eun-joo!
Say hello to him.
Time passes so fast.
How old are you?
-Nine.
-Oh, nine years old.
If I went out with a smart girl 10 years ago,
I'd have had a girl like her.
-I should lie down.
-Oh,
let me help you.
-It's too bad you're so weak.
-I'll take off.
Take good care of her.
-You leaving?
-Oh! Eun-joo, bye.
Here's money for your notebook
from this silly uncle.
-Here, take it.
-You don't need to...
-Come on.
-Say thank you to him
-Thank you.
-All right.
Such a wonderful night. Let's get drunk.
-What's your name?
-Lira!
-Lira?
-Yes
Lira... Deliver the scent of flowers to me.
-Besame besame mucho
-Bravo!
-You're such a beautiful woman.
-Why?
You comfort me as much as I feel drunk.
Thank you. I am grateful to you.
I like you so much.
That's what we talk about in bed.
That's an attractive word, very attractive.
But I need more attractive words,
more attractive wine
And more attractive songs
and dances. Madame!
-Shall we dance?
-Okay.
Stop.
A lover who can pray for
an ex-lover's happiness from a distance
is a possessor of real love, isn't he?
Leave me alone.
Let's go into the room.
It's not good if your injury gets cold.
If I heard that you met with a mishap,
I wouldn't feel good, either.
But I endured.
Only he who controls his emotions
can enjoy a peaceful life.
Let's go in from the cold.
Why are you so worried before big business?
-A man is irritating me.
-Oh, that guy from the jail?
It's simple, isn't it?
It's your choice; dump him now or later.
I wonder if that stubborn guy
can be cheated by Lira.
If he weren't,
he should go back to prison.
-What's your plan?
-Let's think about it.
-Here comes the guest with 20 million.
-Okay
Drink with Madame.
-Get him into the river!
-I see.
You brought this here.
-How come you didn't deal with it.
-All right!
If I took it out to the market,
I'd be out of money.
That's why I give you cheap stuff.
There's always a way out, and you're lucky.
You met guys like us.
Every day brings its bread.
-Where're we going?
-Ask the driver.
What?
Such a stupid man!
It's you who did the smuggling.
Let's go to the banks of the Han River
Sis? I'm Chun-hee.
But he's here now.
What?
He wants to know your story.
Yes, he's with Lira right now...
What should I do?
Should I go there?
A corpse from the Han River
turned out to be murdered.
Shit! Why did it come up?
The police are investigating the victim's lD...
Uhm...
He sneaked in on a smuggling vessel,
so they can't find his ID.
What would they do even if his ID were exposed?
Such shameless fellows!
Go and drink at Swallow.
I'll come with you after I go to the hospital.
Something must be wrong.
He goes to the hospital too often.
You're looking for Chun-hee?
Yes. Ask anyone, and they'll call her.
I see.
-Chun-hee?
-All right! Thank you.
Madame
If someone sits beside her husband,
she becomes startled.
How come you trusted that
kind of girl so much?
-What a pity!
-Madame.
What? Ah, such trouble.
All the guests are looking for me.
Excuse me.
-for 5 minutes, okay?
-I see.
Someone wants to see you now.
-Me?
-Yes, it's Ae-ran.
She can't come in here,
so she's waiting in the car.
I don't know her.
Tell her to leave.
Get in.
-I have something to say.
-Go ahead right here.
I'm ashamed to see you right now.
What's up with you?
-You must hate me.
-I don't want to listen.
What will you say?
Nothing.
If you had nothing to tell me,
why did you call me? Why?
Well,
Our stories must have all gone.
Go!
Don't say wicked words and go away.
I don't want to see you, so go.
-Yes, sir.
-You two,
live happily together.
I'll live, until I live,
-But...
- But what?
What? What?
-Wine!
-Whiskey?
She said nothing in sorrow.
She came like a child, but
went back, crying in deep grief.
Let's drink all night.
You must have felt unbearably stuffy.
As you're healed, let's go back home.
If you stay any longer,
a strange rumor will spread.
Right, you're right.
Take me home. Take me...
Though I fall down when I can't sustain
the pain of my body,
God, please help by holding my arms.
I pray.
I've been waiting for you.
-Why are you so late?
-I met her again today
I cursed her to the utmost.
Let's take a rest.
-Sang-moon!
-Yes?
-Is Ae-ran really happy?
-She must be.
No.
There must be a reason
why she'd be with Dal-soo.
-It's all in the past now.
-Unless...
And her daughter is nine years old.
She must be my daughter.
They've been married for 10 years.
If your guess is right,
something serious will happen.
What are you talking about?
Dal-soo believes that she's his daughter.
That's nothing to do with me.
If she were your daughter,
you should consider
why Ae-ran is keeping it silent.
And think about the kid.
And she has to be sorry for her husband.
Would he let you have the girl willingly?
If he would,
It would be harder for you
since you don't even have a house.
It's the girl who'd become unhappy
between you guys.
Stop it.
Don't you recognize me?
We met at the hospital the other day.
Eun-joo, your mom made this shirt for you?
-Yes
-I see.
Who do you like more, father or mother?
-Both.
-I see.
Take it and have some.
It's all right, come on!
-Did your daddy buy you a snack?
-Yes.
When is your birthday?
-October 20th
-What?
Come on, Eun-joo.
-Bye, uncle.
-Hey, Eun-joo!
-Keep going.
-Yes
I hope you can send
Gwang-pil far away.
-I, as well
-It will be appreciated.
-I told him several times, but
-I don't know how to tell you...
It's a big deal anyways.
He should never work
with my husband, never!
-Is he supposed to work with him?
-Yes.
You must be uncomfortable, take a seat.
If he tries to bother me since he hates me,
I'll go to the stake.
But that's not all.
-Do you get it?
-I'll try my best.
The two friends working together now are
beginning a cold war.
That's all I can think.
We could have a bigger problem than that
Please tell him to leave our family alone.
Don't worry about it.
The thing is that
Gwang-pil's thoughts cannot
get past his boyhood age of 18.
As someone's wife,
I know it's beyond my duty, but
if Gwang-pil walks the wrong way again,
I won't be able to take all his sins.
Is there something wrong
with Dal-soo's business?
I don't know the details since he works alone.
Please take care of him and excuse me.
You're too weak to go out.
I'm sorry.
He was in the car all the time,
so I couldn't see him well.
-Detective Park!
-Yes
Let's take a look at these tire tracks
If the government confers orders,
Madame would have five of them
on your shoulder.
You're quite a woman.
-You always find a way out!
-Don't mention it.
You're just saying that since you
don't pay the tax on your words.
Now just give me my share.
I'm very hungry for money these days.
You know well,
as you read the newspaper.
I say that because I know it.
You'll feel relieved after
you bind me to secrecy.
Now you're flinching from us,
because our work's done.
If something goes wrong,
you won't be safe, either.
You must be joking.
Don't worry about me
and watch out for your wife.
Many people visit your cabaret these days.
Let's talk alone.
He has lots of secrets.
Kiss time!
Before we're exposed,
I should change some guys.
Right, my face might be exposed
to the police as well.
It's an stupid answer. Take care of him.
Who? Gwang-pil?
-He's good at it for a long time.
-What's the reward?
-As you ask.
-Then come to my bed.
Ah, you smell like cigarettes.
-Clean your lips.
-What?
You lips are red.
Thank you for your sincerity but
if you try to get Gwang-pil,
-I will object.
-What? Why? Hey...
If I do something bad or illegal,
I wouldn't get my friend
who just got out of prison.
But, now you're just trying to
entrap me without reason?
It is your own business.
whether you do illegal things.
As long as there's some feelings,
how can you and Gwang-pil
work together truly,
since you guys have a grudge
against each other?
Did you come here to make us fight?
How come you want to
make trouble for our family?
Later, you might.. Go! Go away!
I said "go''!
I keep objecting to it for the happiness of
your family and Gwang-pil.
Shut up and go!
I'm sorry I made you mad. Excuse me.
What a bitch!
She should be quiet in hospital.
My sixth sense is just right.
I thought you came.
You've been here long?
-I came here to say good bye.
-I see.
I'll leave Seoul.
Oh! You hate Seoul so soon?
-Come up here.
-Yes
I thought we could become good friends,
but I'm sorry you're leaving.
Thank you for your consideration.
What will you do with your passion?
All I have is ashes now.
Coming to Seoul was a big loss for you.
Please sit.
Where are you going then?
I don't know.
Did Dal-soo treat you that badly?
-I never liked working with him.
-I understand.
I roughly guessed that too.
Thank you very much anyways.
You consider a girl like me, so
came to see me before leaving.
I came here to get drunk.
It must be hard. I know your feelings well.
Can alcohol fill this empty heart?
You should take another step.
Focus on your business or something...
So I plan to
open a small barber shop
after my mind is relieved.
-All I learned is haircutting.
-Though you do that,
they will laugh at you in life.
What should I do with my bad fate?
If I were you, whatever I did,
I would live better before them.
Why are you retreating like a fool?
Stop it. I've been thinking about everything.
I also feel furious to see you that frustrated.
I'll take care of you.
I'll introduce all the stuff to you
that Dong-il Corp. has dealt with
I'm an introducer of it.
I can guarantee good deals all the time.
One condition though...
You need particular passion to work with me.
You should enjoy adventure.
What do you think of my suggestion?
You didn't do it?
The father came and told me what he knows.
-That's what you told him, isn't it?
-Well, you misunderstood something.
-The reason I went to see the father...
-Misunderstanding?
-Then what?
-As for Gwang-pil...
-That's all, honey.
-What?
Don't be so upset, and listen to me.
Tell me! It will be your will.
I don't know why you hate
Gwang-pil that much.
-You feel sorry for him?
-He's such a poor guy.
He's got no one around him.
Why are you trying to send him
back to jail again for nothing?
What? What did you just say?
If someone is guilty,
I'm the one who committed a big sin.
Please consider my situation.
If you feel pitiful
and as if you sinned against him,
go and live with him, huh?
Such a wicked woman.
You went to Sang-moon to tell my secret
because you wanted to live with him
after you got me into jail.
You did, huh? You dirty...
You're not sleepy?
I had a friend called Pig.
He had 5 previous convictions,
but he knew the world.
Why do you reflect on cold memories?
He would tell the same thing to me.
-You're not sleepy, he said.
-So?
He asked me if I wasn't sleepy.
I won't sleep until you fall asleep.
That guy told me that
I'd meet him again in jail soon.
His guess was so right.
To the father...
I've got something to tell Sang-moon,
so call Sang-moon and tell him to come over.
Where would he be now?
I'll make an injection in 30 minutes.
Sis
Doctor!
Please tell me...
I'll do my best, but take good care of her.
The condition is up to the patient.
It's already the time.
We'll be there around 4.
Though I live in Seoul,
I just heard of Incheon.
-It's my first time to go to Incheon.
-You do?
Then, I'll be your guide.
Have you bought stuff in Incheon until now?
My route is from everywhere.
As you will see today,
the stuff from Incheon is the best.
There're lots of ships there.
Incheon? He went to Incheon, I see.
There's no certain information...
When you get it, come back to the office.
I'll contact the police in Incheon.
What about complicity? As we guessed...
Yes yes Okay!
Owing to the confession of the criminal,
the mythical two opposite alibis
turned to dust. The next news is...
According to the authorities,
this morning around 1 1,
the ID of the victim of
the Han River case became clear.
The authorities announced optimistically that
arresting the perpetrator will be
just a matter of time. Next is...
How mysterious!
How would they know?
Is it Swallow?
Call the manageress. She went out?
Shit! I had a bad dream.
Why are you so scared?
-You've got a big body.
-Huh!
Though they know his ID,
they wouldn't know what he's done
since he came from Japan alone
and got murdered in secret.
Excuse me.
I thought he's in.
-Who are you looking for?
-The boss...
-He's not in right now.
-Oh, I see.
Why do you keep coming?
Did he go out with a guy?
-Not at all!
-Oh, I'm sorry.
He's come here for something special.
-He's acting strangely.
-He must have overheard something.
Right, watch your mouth.
Shall we kill him?
Why do you let him in to the office?
Is there a traitor in here?
-Are you?
-No way!
-You?
-Bro, what're you doing?
Son of...
Speaking aloud over a microphone,
you think this is an outdoor market?
Did you hear the radio?
The father came again.
I met him.
Come here!
Hurry!
Never worry! But just in case...
it will be safer if we move the stuff
in the warehouse to somewhere else.
-Right now!
-That's right.
I'll go out to check.
The father is the only dangerous one
since he knows our secret.
If I accede to his demand,
he will inform the police about us for sure.
-Let's get rid of him.
-All right.
Get him.
He will be in the hospital or church.
It was Dal-soo who forced me,
this weak girl,
who was waiting for Gwang-pil.
I swear that I should bring my life to the man
who made me not wait for Gwang-pil.
My husband always told me that I live with him
because I am getting revenge on him.
Am I really that kind of girl?
I don't even know that.
While I live with him,
I found myself feeling attractive
to my family so soon
as if I had become crazy.
That's what a woman is like.
As I heard from you,
I regret myself that regretted you once.
I thought he'd forget me as time passed.
That's what I thought.
But his eyes are the same as
they were 10 years ago.
He will definitely
do something.
Because I know him better than
anyone else, I can't sleep.
Chun-hee!
Open the bag and find the picture in which
he got rid of a pain in my eyes a long time ago.
You can find the picture.
If he sees it, he will know my mind.
-Call her family.
-Okay.
It's hard for her to go through tonight.
-I'll call them.
-Okay
Father! Call him right now.
She must be so frustrated that
-she cried hard.
-I see.
-How are you?
-Oh, hello.
-Then, please...
-I see.
I saw your car, so I was going to meet you.
-Me?
-Yes.
My boss wants to talk about your friend.
I see.
Is Gwang-pil there now?
-Yes.
-Is he?
-Please get in if you are going there with me.
-Thank you. I'm sorry.
Boss!
What is it?
-Can I see your ID?
-Here.
Excuse me.
I'm sorry but please follow me
to the police station.
-Yes, ok. In fact...
-Did you plan to meet the boss here?
Who knows where he is?
He made me come here
and ran away by himself.
Such an ass hole.
-Sir, I didn't do anything...
-Shut up!
If you're that resentful,
I'll let you meet him soon.
Lee!
Gwang-pil, that brat!
He thought I'd get caught as he wishes.
I'm Chief Detective Chung.
Hey, detective Lee!
That's all I know.
-You'll know better after investigating.
-I see.
You aren't even leading him
onto the right path,
Is this Miss Kim?
but using his weakness,
you tried to use him?
-Your voice is nice, huh?
-Stop the private calls!
You just came out of the prison 5 days ago.
How come you're caught in a trap?
Huh? You spiritless fellow.
Detective Kim, take him to jail.
I can see you have no direct relationship
with this case, but
in your psychology,
you've planned to commit a crime already.
-Gwang-pil!
-Sit down!
What are you doing here?
Examine yourself there for days and months.
-What about the gang?
-We're in pursuit.
Wait!
-It could be a rude request, but...
-What is it?
There's a patient who's going to die
and leave her will to Gwang-pil.
I was asked to call him but I was taken to
-the police station on the way.
-You were?
Yes
-Detective Kim!
-Yes!
Get Oho Gwang-pil released temporarily.
Give me your stuff.
Since we'll investigate him later,
please give him security.
Of course.
You should know better
after 10 years in the school.
Ae-ran has fought her pain
and her unfortunate destiny for half her lifetime.
Taxi!
Gwang-pil!
You're late.
-She's gone to the morgue.
-What?
Want to see her for the last time?
Follow me.
Gwang-pil! Gwang-pil!
I know your feelings, that
you informed the police
against me to keep Ae-ran.
Ae-ran