ln the year 2036, 100 years away from now ,
the things to come, l see them well,
The times today, they cease to matter.
It's better to look onto the past,
The world once more will be past a war,
which somebody had won somehow.
AfteM/ards all will claim peace again,
until they're armed to repeat again.
Being victim and part of the national
socialists as well
ou may very well picture for yourself how it
Iools in the middle ofVienna
Austria very quickly developed into
an independent democratic republic.
The social and the Christian democrats,
SPÖ and ÖVP,
proved to be the mo parties to build
one of the most secure,
but also one of the most over structure
nations in the world.
Mid-eighties. The FPÖ, a German oriented,
nationalist party built out of Nazi remains
after WW2, became the third power.
Fourth of February 2000: the beloved
image of the country
ofwaltzes shatters in the face
of the world.
ln 20 minutes the inauguration will be over
and the new government will be functional.
According to article 70 of the federal
constitutional court, l declare you,
Dr. SchÜssel, federal chancellor.
Against his own election promises
and against the outspoken will
of the president, chancellor Wolfgang
SchÜssel goes into coalition
with the openly xenophobic FPÖ-party .
Yesterday night Vienna once again has
seen numerous protests,
demonstrating against the FPÖ
getting to be state officials.
Activists have stormed famous
Burgtheater and Hotel Imperial.
You may very well picture for yourself
how it looks in the middle ofVienna.
The FPÖ-party under the leadership of
Jörg Haider had developed into a
global symbol for Europe's turn
towards the e_reme right.
Stop asylum abuse! Stop the infiltration!
Right now FPÖ
Resistance
Despite being protected by massive squads
of armed policemen, the new government
did not dare to step up the imperial palace
in public, but preferred to enter through
a subterranean passage.
With the inauguration of the new government,
the sanctions against Austria by
all other European Union states
are effective.
With this act the EU threatens
their own member.
A congressman in Brussels states:
Should we wait until they're building
concentration camps again?''
Vienna bemeen 1 1th and 17th of June.
The local cultural institution ,,Wiener
Fesmochen'' invites infamous German shock
director Christoph Schlingensief
as their political statement.
lnspired by the reality TV-show ,,Big
Brother'', he builds a concentration camp
like container right beside Vienna's
opera, the main tourist site of the city .
6 web cams watch melve real asylum seekers
imprisoned there for the entire week.
Via Internet gaming you can deport
these people out of Austria daily.
Kill Europe! Foreigners out!
An event by Christoph Schlingensief
Please love Austria!
Vienna downtown, June 1 1th 2000, 9 P.M.
_.foreignersout.org
The container is coming! A serious situation!
Pick your own foreigner! Give him your vote!
Deport''
Throw mo of them out of the country daily!
Deporting has started!
Christoph Schlingensief: l would like to
use this occasion to explain the rules
of the game: Tonight, only a few minutes
away, a dozen asylum seekers
will be transported into this place.
For the given time, they will remain in
the living room right underneath me,
in mo sleeping containers
and a small open yard.
At the back is a sanitary container
with toilets and showers.
Some of them will stay in here for
six full days.
Every day - dear Austrians,
l am talking to you now-
you will be able to vote for your most
hated foreigner in here.
And by phone and web you will be able
to throw them out of your borders.
The results will be publicly announced
every night at 8 pm sharp.
The concerned foreigners will be driven
directlyto the borderline and deported.
Claudia Kaloff Project manager
of Schlingensief:
The idea was so e_reme to swallow.
Putting real asylum seekers into a
container right at the time of that huge
''Big Brother''- boom!
You just pack them in and the whole
population or half of Europe are able to
vote them out! l just thought: What an
incredible stroke of genius!
Matthias Lilienthal
Dramatic advisor of the container
l guess the worst moment for the foreigners
was, when they stepped out of the bus.
Walking through the screaming hordes of
people. 500 or so.
10 cameras and 30 photographers
opposing them.
An experience l myself had not encountered
before except by watching television.
Leila comes first, please!
Out at the front, please!
Do we make it? Yes?
Anita, read the second bio! Please!
l wish all of you good luck
in the name of Europe!
And now we will unveil the sign, the
soon-to-be motto for all tourists here,
For all those passing by:
Dear Japanese! Dear Frenchmen!
Dear Belgians! DearAmericans!
Please take many pictures of this place!
Please take them home with you!
Show all your relatives and friends
what is going on in Austria!
Show them the future of Europe!
Tell them: this is the truth!
This is the FPÖ!
This is the Krone Newspaper!
This is Austria!
Herewith l declare the event as started!
Foreigners out
lf l just had screamed it,
it would have been different.
lf l scream ,,Foreigners out!'', Then it's
just a somebody screaming ''Foreigners out!''.
You may say, what an asshole
and that's it! l also did that!
But it is something completely different,
when this sentence becomes irremovable
like an election bannerjust standing there.
And you can't do anything against it.
And the entire sympathizers crawl
out oftheir holes and cheer
like freaked out madmen.
Press conference of the ,,Wiener Fesmochen''
Wednesday, June 6th 2000,
Shortly before the event
Luc Bondy - Head of
theatre festival ,,Wiener Fesmochen'':
Good morning, ladies and gentlemen!
We stated it before and l'll be
saying it again clearly:
l do\code(01f9)t feel comfortable to live in the
only country in whole Europe,
where a conservative party
has broken the taboo
to take a party
of the e_reme right
with them to be the government.
And l'm pe_ectly sure,
that the ,,Fesmochen''
need to be a space
for political discussion.
When such things happen, you need room to
openly think about all these procedures.
The way things develop,
the world ca\code(01f9)t afford any individuality.
That's not on the schedule. That's why
those asylum seekers just have to be black.
Have to be drug dealers.
Have to be homos. Have to be assholes.
You just need to be black and - wham! -
That's enough!
Simple key signals!
lf you seriously think about the news,
where UMTS-licences for 99 billion bucks
pass hands daily,
what can the little man with his sorry
wages do of any importance!
There's no relation anymore.
He will just think: ''Hell! There's one guy
in the world paying 99 billion
for that shit.
Maybe with my monthly 1 .OOO l could,...''
But then due to lack of real money ,
he needs a substitutional currency.
And that currency must be
payable in any place in the world.
He must be able to sit anmhere.
To punch on the table, saying:
Black must go!'', so everyone
will get it!
And these are the languages
that are understood very fast!
That's why l'm
completely against the opinion,
that what Jörg Haider does
is an intelligent act. It is not.
lt is simply
a substitution currency.
And even in a married state,
those in the Congo lands
do all belonging to a black.
Todays chosen is tomorrow's trashed one,
if he wants to want another one well
And even body care is no trouble with her.
She needs no silken gown.
No fresh bought hat.
lf she disgruntles him,
he's gonna guzzle her:
Congo niggers live life a pretty way!
Kathi Gruber ''Wiener Fesmochen'' -
productions team:
The container reached from here to
the barrier with bicycles over there.
We need to question, what these drug
dealers have done to our children!
How many families have they ruined?
How many kids have they destroyed?
This must be our direction.
And that's why we, members of the FPÖ,
are the guarantee for every man to live
calm and secure lives in this country:
And l am sure, many have understood,
how cheaply it has been tried to
criminalize the campaigns ofViennàs FPÖ.
Just because they have outspoken, what burns
in the heart of every good V iennese man:
there must be an end to foreign immigration!
Burghart Schmidt, Cultural philosopher:
The political situation,
pinned down in here, was obvious:
For the first time in Europe, a
government was built including a party
party that was fostered and built
on connections to the e_reme right:
Dr. Helene Partik-Pablé
Parliamentary deputy, FPÖ
The FPÖ party never involved itself
with xenophobe politics.
We never said ,,Foreigners out!'' All we did
was to maintain political responsibility!
We always said, Austria
is no country suited for immigrants.
Therefore we need a drastic limitation,
so any civil integration gets possible
in the first place.
At that point it was pledged that
Austria is no immigration country,
despite that this statement completely
contradicts the country' s history.
lt always was an ironic ''bon mot''
to hint at Vienna's phone book,
the kind of names you find in there.
So this broke Austrian traditions
by the same politicians,
who were talking about their
historical commitment.
This is the new way, ladies and gentlemen!
This is ''Foreigners out!'' This is Vienna!
This is Nazi! This is you and l!
This production is given to you by the FPÖ
in association with the Krone Newspaper.
This is a production of the FPÖ,
whohere presents their
up-to-date model for sewage plants!
This is the new we are giving to you!
You may now walk right in here!
Step in, ladies and gentlemen!
Get inside the peepshow!
Pick and watch your very own
asylum seeker! It's absolutely free!
The FPÖ party in association with
Krone Newspaper brings this event to you!
This is the newly opened Nazi film factory!
The pictures that Europe wants will be
produced here!
You are now in resistance,
Iadies and gentlemen!
You also! You are now officially
commissioned to resistance! Yes, you!
l declare you know to the of ficial
resistance at 3:20 p.m. Sharp!
You are now officially commissioned
to resistance! Resistance fighter!
Gabi Kaiba ''Wiener Fesmochen'':
The first mo days were quite peaceful.
Just like we were expecting to happen.
lt was weekend. No work time.
Vienna was sleeping.
Nobody had freaked out yet.
There was no press coverage:
Except the Krone Newspaper.
But theyjumped on it immediately:
Correct. Theyjumped on it.
But only in small at the beginning.
We have been betrayed and sold out
German lessons for foreigners?
Strict actions against loafers
This is a thing that must be
put on the table openly:
behind every bigger movement in Austria,
there is Hans Dichand and
his Krone backing up.
Actionist tries to build
container camp besides opera
German ,,actionist'' provokes in Vienna
Dearest tourists! Please make
pictures! Foreigners out!
Krone Newspaper and the opera!
Send your postcards around the world!
Show them what's happening
in good old Austria!
Land of the Nazis!
Land of the fascists!
Here is Nazi central!
Here refugee camps burn every night!
Here blacks, Africans, all kinds
of people are murdered with ease.
Tourists are o.k.
They are delivering the cash!
They won't be prey to homosexual,
drug addicted blacks anymore!
We got _ustria! foreigners out!
Away with'em!
With transportation cars away!
We're _oin_ to kill 'em all! Heads o_!
Omicial executions in public!
This is the place!
Every day execution of 20 to 30 foreigners!
Cut the heads off!
The square of heavenly execution!
The square of divine execution!
Sure it's easy
to misinterpret the whole thing!
But l have not the least of understanding,
for the whole bunch of peace activists
and those charmingly
sweet resistance fighters.
l just don't get their way.
When l am bugged by something,
when something just doesn't seem right,
l need to disturb the picture,
presented as the wholesome and right one.
The whole container-thing
was a machinery to disrupt images!
We only need Austrians! Nothing else!
This was no voyage to discover how stupid
the Austrian really is!
This would have been idiotic!
We gotAustria!
What was revealed through this form of media
installation, was how this ''dirt plastic'',
as Sloterdijk says, worked to gather
people like a force field.
Like all the dirt that suddenly appears
in the TV ads when the chamois is near.
Houellebecq was here!
And finally here we have her!
A resistance fighteress!
From now on you are a resistance fighter!
We have got 6:30 p.m.!
l officially declare you resistance fighter!
No violence please!
Even if there are some slight Nazi vibes..
There! There! There is something
in the bushes, ladies and gentlemen!
ls there something hidden?
Is there something inside the head?
Does it give you a ring?
Are the eyes flashing
are there strange crosses in the eyes?
l see something! This is film,
Iadies and gentlemen! This is film!
This is the future! We produce the pictures
that Austria definitely does not need!
l know the surroundings of Karajan Square
out of the shopping zone of Kärntner Street
And usually the only hindrance
is the masked opera people,
selling their tickets there, trying to up
the class culture level.
And suddenly we had an
unexpected cross traffic here.
All stops were pulled and it
developed a maelstrom fast.
Two must leave every evening.
Two all the time.
And then?
And the last one will win!
The last nigger carries away 70.OOO bucks!
No Austrian?
You also want in?
Yes! Oh, yes!
Yes? Just go in!
This must be a joke!
Armin Thurnher, Austrian jounalist:
Regarding foreign politics
of that moment the main activity of the
Austrian government was to get
rid of the sanctions. To prove innocent
so to speak. Just at that
exact moment, Schlingensief staged this
event to hold a mirror up towards Austria,
to prove that some kind of guilt existed.
ln a situation when my native nation
is ridiculed in front of the whole world.
When everybody wants to see what
really happens in this country
ls this now a fascist state or not?
Then it is my duty as a responsible
politician. To cover up any impression
of that... Because it's simply not true.
We have violated no convention,
so the European economy can't
put no sanctions up on us!
Now they have
pulled it out their bilateral Asses.
And then they cancelled
all political receptions.
So it's completelyjustified
when our government now takes
it the hard way by saying:
Just a moment!''
lf our government
isn't allowed to negotiate with
Germany, France or Belgium
In preparation of conferences of the
European economy - then we
haven't got enough intellect to do so,
but then we also won't be able
to vote with them and we will need our
expanded share of time
for essential decisions!
Then the whole eastern
expansion process will be put on wait!
And completely right so!
So now we will initiate
an act that is real!
l'm saying it again! This is a
pe_ormance of the ''Wiener Fesmochen ''!
This is an actor!
This is the absolute truth!
The results have arrived!
lt is a man from Iran,
Jahansha Alvandi, who has been
voted out of our country today .
Then security please comes in.
Two of you guys please come in
and carry him away to the car .
Well, that has been the dramatic scheme
of the container.
This container had started like a
picture on the wall.
Then suddenly it flooded the crowds
like the yeast of a cake.
So you were stuck right in there, couldn't
fall over anymore. Enclosed in bemeen.
So you stepped into a movie right at the
moment of filming without a possible reversal
You stood in that film, which was
your very own film.
Not my film. Not the one
of Mr. Schmitz or Mr. Bondy.
Referring to it as a market conscious term,
we had basically built a ,,product'',
that independently perpetuated itself
like a virus in the body
This is the ideal product the
whole economy is searching for.
Which you have to introduce only once and
which then spreads like a snowball system
on its own.
Jörg Haider: We also believe those hundred
thousands illegal aliens in this country
carry no right to remain in this country!
Therefore they have to leave this land by
our will, if they are proven delinquents!
Cause we don't want to breed crime!
Rainer Laux
Head of German ,,Big Brother'' TV-production:
Big Brother indeed was a new kind of
television you really felt it,
this was something new.
It hadn't happened before.
Observing people 24 hours a day,
Watching TV in the TV. It suited very well
at that time to oppose ,,Big Brother''.
With the word of human dignity on your
lips cause you knew it would immediately
be headline, in TV and radio.
lt simply was fascinating!
You could look right into a normal live!
There was a living room, a garden.
A bedroom like in any average home.
A little bit bigger. In a slightly
different style. But principally the same.
And you had the chance to innocently peek
what people are doing.
Morning till night.
24 Hours a day.
The people in this house
were completely authentic.
Though they were in a staged environment,
their lives in there were
completely credible.
Daily German lesson, late forenoon
l had the idea to work with containers
for a very long time.
A container already appeared in one of my
movies, ,,Terror 2000'' in 1992
which featured the visit of a camp
of asylum seekers,
where l realized for the very first time
that 8 people would seriously live
together on 18 square meters
including kitchen hole and toilet outside.
And the ugly news about this pop up over
and over again.
That ,,Big Brother'' hysteria was worth nought,
cause these things had been there forever .
Also that refugee camp beside the opera
was there a long, long time ago.
ln a far more violent and realistic form.
Christoph Maria Schlingensief. Son of a
druggist. Born the 24.10.1960 in Oberhausen.
His artistic method: the subversive
combination of popular narratives like
Big Brother'' with real socio-political
problems.
Since the mid-eighties he creates films
in the German underground scene.
Getting more and more respected
in the art circuit, he expands the
screen into reality in the mid-nineties.
The theatre ''Berliner VolksbÜhne'' is his
permanent home since 1997.
An anarchist TV-talk show and several
public pranks make him a headline item.
But with the real and overpresent
election process of ''Chance 2000'',
an art party supporting social losers,
he overthrows himselfwith the media and
gets trashed as political clown.
The ,,Wiener Fesmochen'' are the first ones
to invite him again to work in an
established cultural setting.
Carl Hegemann, Chief dramatic advisor
VolksbÜhne, Berlin:
ln the beginning l was very sure
this would flop.
l thought this would be too obvious,
too intended.
Everybody would feel preached to, cause
everybody would know
what this whole thing really is about.
And then those would just say:
What the heck! We love foreigners anmay!
And it all would have puffed into hot air!
lt should have occurred to me differently,
cause these Schlingensief-stories always
work the crowd somehow.
But still l was e_remely surprised,
when all of a sudden the whole Austrian
population seriously took part in that play .
The first deported
Vienna embarrassed
Monkey biz theatre
Our country turned cartoon
Certainly,
concerning the themes of xenophobia,
the Austrian media situation, media politics
- he just had to throw a stone into that
water and count the waves.
But how many waves that would be
and how big they would get,
was the thing that really interested him.
and when some others started throwing their
rocks, he as the prime initiator
might have been delighffully thrilled,
what will come out in the end.
He certainly tried to direct in bemeen,
but without an unbiased view
it would have been impossible
to stage this thing.
lf you pe_ectly direct it through
and through, it's D.O.A. from the start!
This is the magnificent banner they keep
hanging here for mo and a half days already!
lmagine: the coalition you have voted for ,
keeps a slogan like this in public
for mo and a half days now!
Since mo and a half days the ÖVP and FPÖ
do nothing to put it away!
How damn stupid this coalition must be to
keep this hanging for mo and a half days!
This is the question we have to ask
ourselves again and again:
Why ca\code(01f9)t we take this coalition seriously?
They have to end?
They absolutely have to end?
In this instant!
Dr. Richard Schmitz
Ex-chief ofVienna's first district, ÖVP:
He is a terribly
skilled marketer of himself!
And there are media believing he will
achieve something really big some day!
lt was like this.
When he was at the Wolfgang-See,
with all those unemployed,
there was nothing at all.
But l was surprised
at the press coverage.
lt was well photographed.
Mag. Heidemarie Unterrainer
Cultural spokeswoman, FPÖ
Schlingensief is a puppet!
You take him out of the dusty agitation
closet and tell him: Hey! You! Do that!
You'll get that mission: Make pictures
ofAustria that pull Austria into the dirt!
Boutique owner sues invaders
Schlingensief storms shop.
It was like a terrorist attack.
Excuse me, but what are you doing here?
Oh, that is beautiful!
But you should have waited!
Please turn off that thing!
Please call the chief
of the first district immediately!
l have kindly requested -you-
to stop filming!
For how long people keep whining that there
is no relevant political theatre left?
People just don't get such stuff anymore.
lt's just blank boredom on the stages,
missing any message connected to life.
This evidently is what links all
Schlingensief-events together.
They invent situations that admit
no clear understanding.
You can't clearlyjudge for yourself
what is happening here.
That's why l completely refuse the idea,
that this was an exemplary
demonstration of fascism.
lf itjust had been that way .
Then people with the ,,right'' consciousness
would have been able to shape up to it.
This method basically reaches
back to Karl Kraus
and what Walter Benjamin
analyzed about Kraus:
That you don't need to comment
to articulate criticism.
lt is way enough to simply cite
what you criticize.
The quotes just need to be placed in the
right position at the right time and place.
Then suddenly a simple citation
becomes self-revelatory!
l simply don't get it,
how they aren't able to understand!
All over the world there is war
and we are supposed to donate!
There is money given to those
who hunger and whoever else!
All over the world there is war
and nobody does something against it!
And here they freak out about this!
Am l stupid or what?
The lady has said it:
all over the world there is war
and people freak out over here,
just because people are deported!
This is fully correct! War is evermhere!
Turks and Yugoslaves!
They are overpopulating us!
This is our problem! That's not their
intelectuals joining us here!
lt 's the waste that's coming up,
who won't even appreciate us!
You can't blame the ones coming!
You have to blame the politics!
This is the problem!
You can't even tell, what you really want!
First the Turks, then the Yugoslavs,
then everybody else is ''the'' foreigner?!
We - are - overpopulated!
Ain't right?
Just look at the schools!
That's bull!
What's your family name?
Duchkowitsch!
Yes, right! Milosevic Turkovic!
OfYugoslavian heritage...
Austria has picked their votes.
The election lines per phone
were used for real
and not the least, so to speak.
Sandra Umathum, Long-term companion
to Schlingensief-events:
After all Christoph just picks up the things
that happen in society anmay .
Everybody knows a ,,Foreigners out!''- Sign!
Everybody knows, there are refugees in
containers out there at any time,
just waiting for deportation.
Perhaps a lot of people see this play
as being cynical,
disregarding the fact that the ruling themes
in media, in society,
cannot be surpassed in their cynicism.
Who are the dirty pigs authorizing this?
l am Austrian! But l am for the foreigners!
My wife is half of a foreigner! In Paris
they say already: Aha! It's correct!
ln Austria there are the Nazis!
Foreigners out, they say there!
Where is the ladder!
l'll be taking this down! Tomorrow?
Please don't submit to this, you all!
Am l free? Do you want to arrest me?
Because l'm protesting,
you really want to arrest me?
What kind of lawjustifies this?
You have got identification?
Kosovo! Shit! Broken!
Dr. Peter Sloterdijk, cultural philosopher:
The age of shock is over!
The epoch has gone, where a cultural
avant-garde could work with surprises
and attacks on an unprepared nervous system.
In Germany we just have lived through
the Big Brother- hysteria,
where an elimination game
became the center of all things.
But as soon you drop that frantic collective
need to have a winner
so you don't cherish the gladia!tor and
you don't cheer the European soccer master ,
but move that mechanism of elimination into
the light, that's where things
start to get thrilling!
There you can see how society daftly
participates in the production of losers!
Because the production of a winner includes
the production of an
uncountable number of losers!
He has said: This is art!
What? This is supposed to be art?
This is a fucking hoax on Austria!
We have not burned down any refugee homes!
Not like in Germany!
We may be talking stupid...
Austrians may be talking stupid...
But we don't burn down any homes
or something like it!
Tomorrow it will be all over the headlines..
Somebody tried to start a fire!
You are helping us?
So l get upset and can't sleep at night!
Because you put something like this up here!
You are an enemy to Austria
and you have to be deported!
This government realizing was not
in the least a democratic act!
Mister SchÜssel has promised before
the election started,
lf he would finish the third,
he would take his party into opposition!
By this he tried to lure those voters,
who for whatever reason
Tried to prevent the FPÖ
entering the government!
Who had voted for Haider
at least knew what he bargained! with!
Who voted for SchÜssel
had been betrayed to the highest degree!
ls this really your only potential?
To articulate any resistance! This is a
sorry ass demonstration of incapacity!
Yes! These are our problems! Not yours!
You don't need to put this up over here!
This is a European problem!
Here no asylum seekers burn
like in Germany!
They are laughing at us in other countries!
Zib3'', midnight news show of ,,ORF''
Tuesday, 13.6.200O
Well, Mr. Schlingensief! The Viennese people
are embarrassed! The tourists are shocked!
We have heard that! We have seen that!
These are the headlines of tomorrow' s
newspapers! and not only of the ''Krone''!
Is this what you wanted?
Provocation is a means for morons!
That's what the FPÖ is aiming for!
With a provocation,
l provoke you and then l just leave.
Different to that the container
also works without me.
You'll recognize that
when you're passing by!
Ms. Unterrainer, you are the
cultural spokeswoman of the FPÖ!
ln a release you are writing,
Mister Schlingensief is mentally disturbed!
Do you feel provoked?
l do not feel provoked at all
by Mister Schlingensief.
But it is symptomatic that provocation
has become a method of cultural politics.
We refuse that. Same as we refuse child rape
violence per se and themes like blasphemy.
We do not consider this as art.
Here art only becomes a disguise for...
What you are doing here is just
spawning public hatred!
Just take your slogans!
You may provoke at your container thing
but not here in ORF-TV
Here at the ORF it is my turn! Not yours!
You have people in the government,
who are responsible for this isolation.
You should try getting elected
as a politician, huh!
Helmut Salcher, ÖVP: You just do your play!
l won't step into that trap!
l won't be acting in your play!
The fear grows! The fear grows!
l have to inte_ere here!
ln this moment, Austria is a
completely ridiculous country.
An absolutely ridiculous,
Iaughed at population!
Tonight there has been an incident again.
Three people invaded the container
for the second time! And there was a little
fire attack right at the front entrance!
What is close ahead of us, concerning
globalization to a high degree
is the danger of technocratic economist
fascism of a complete new kind,
which leaves behind
all its old characteristics.
This could be a form of totalitarianism,
which is completely different.
ltjustifies itself out of the increasingly
Iethal dangers of all the technology
in use as well as out of the globally free
access to the delights of pure economies.
The punch line is: If you really want
all of your consumer pleasures,
we have to completely
control and observe society!
lt had been assumed by Schlingensief, that
the foreigners are just a new currency
for the Nazis. Another idea was, that
the entire e_reme right was just some kind
of business trick. Obviously with Haider,
who just uses it as a market gap.
There is a potential client ship in Austria
that has to be grassed off.
He may catch their votes as result
of a business move:
But yet, that's trivial.
It may be less trivial with all that
xenophobes who bet on that
horse as they keep looking
to realize an idea by doing so,
which hasn't been realized yet:
You just throw that hate-thing into the
market and strive to make it big time.
And if society resists it,
then they'd just let go for the ne_.
Elfriede Jelinek:
We have written a play together.
l somehow got the idea to let them
write down sentences in German.
Sentences they had heard many times before.
So we assembled it together into
a punch-and-judy kind of thing.
l am Miss Heidemarie Unterrainer, M.A.
Tomorrow l will come and eat humans!
Finally l am the chancellor!
l love human beings!
l love Austrian human beings!
l don't want the war!
We need nothing but humans.
We live in Europe with Europeans.
Our biggest wish is to become actors.
Please help us with this possibility.
Thank you!
Everybody wanted to see the product ,,man''.
What had been the actor of a TV series or
Liz Taylor on the big screen way back then?
Now were Mister Smith and that pussy
from the beer pub cross the street
Who became visual as human goods?
They gave you the feeling, that it doesn't
matter how stupid you are, you are worth
at least something.
But then again we could discover
via ,,Big Brother'' and that was a thing
also Mr Laux very painfully had to learn
with the flop of ,,Big Diet'':
The interesting thing in the
product ,,man'' isn't its su_ace.
lt is not to be conceived
as a kind of capital, but far deeper.
Counter-statement by Vienna's mayor
Dr. Michael Häupl, SPÖ: This is not reality.
This is a game. Adangerous
game with emotions. Austria is different!
We are approaching
the deportation of the day.
This night not three will be brought away,
as we had planned. No! Two will be deported!
Today number three is leaving us.
Wole from Nigeria! A black man again!
Austria has voted out a blackie once again!
Look at that consequence!
What a continuous process this all is!
Today the lady from Iraq and
Wole from Nigeria will be gone!
We have reached the fourth day today!
The sign is still hanging!
The coalition can splendidly live with it!
The super stupid Austrians
have voted a super stupid coalition!
That's the way
things look right at the moment!
He shall come out, if he dares to! Who' s
gonna take this down? l can't reach it...
And for the rest it's far too dangerous!
Those Krauts always start these things!
The century of socialism
was a century of crime!
Those who already stay here,
shall remain here...
And they shall have equal
rights to the Austrians.
OtheM/ise there is going to be
a war bemeen us!
We want to have our peace!
The only real surrealist deed possible
is to randomly shoot into a crowd.
lf this is a form of radicalism,
it has worked here in the end.
You could not hear the shot.
But an incredible lot of people
were stumbling around heavily wounded.
Screaming ,,ouch''. Hollering.
The family Garzaner
Permanent guests at Schlingensief-events
Here we have Mario, Kurt and Ilse Garzaner!
You have called us to participate!
Why? What do you have to tell us?
We very much enjoy this event and...
We have accepted the guest patronance...
This is a piece of shit!
Those are all actors!
Kick out the Krauts! Foreigners in!
This is no art! Who's putting up this filth!
This is warmongering!
Foreigners in! Kick out the Krauts!
This is a very significant gesture!
''Our pride is loyalty!''...
...l have no idea at all
where that sentence comes! from!
Aren't you even allowed to raise your arm
nowadays, without being called a Nazi!
What a bunch of morons!
l was pleasantly surprised,
that all these people on the street
started to discuss their politics
in connection to the event.
That really was good.
But when it suddenly cooked up
in the summer heat,
when it turned really hot and aggressive,
l got scared shitless for quite some time.
Just tell me one precise example
Where this Austrian government
since its formation has committed a crime
against the human rights.
Where they have invited any racist hatred!
If you could kindly tell us just one example
in front of these microphones...
But you can't!
You've got right-wing
populists in your government.
There are racist slogans all over the place,
which come directly from this government.
Who afteM/ards just tell:
''Oh my, we didn't say - that!''
Haider is not part of the government!
Is the FPÖ in the government or not?l
But that's bull!
You are one of those artists suckling on
state money and those artists now
scream the loudest in fear they won't get
anything any more!
And that's why this woodshed,
these moron chants...
Does St.Stephan's cathedral please you?
l think St.Stephe\code(01f9)s is a beauty!
Do you know how it was financed?
Possibly...Maybe...Could be...
By subvention money!
Yes. But today the whole art...
Subventions have always been there.
You know?
Yes. But then you can't...
And St.Stephan's cathedral
also still is there!
l only felt scared of these things
happening once on the Friday.
Standing on the roof l thought of a sudden,
the way things happen right now
with all these calls and threats...
lf this really was a movie,
there is place in the story for a sniper
on the other roof or someone
making a drastic example
Everything could have happened.
There could have been an attack at any time.
Everything was possible.
We didn't know at first,
that itjust was butyric acid.
But after these acid attacks,
l mean, they could have used
something really harmful.
Something that leaves
permanent damage on the people in there.
l found his behavior completely
irresponsible to himself.
Standing there fully exposed.
The whole project appeared
to be unprotected from all directions.
You are against foreigners?
Why are you against foreigners?
Ouch!
It can't be the same bottle all the time?
Haider is not an asshole!
President Klestil is an asshole!
l'm inclined to open up a company...
l'm prepared to give work to foreigners
Who carry certificates to live here?
You German swine!
You artist!
This was no real job.
lt was like
living through a war zone, fighting against
the inside as well as the outside.
Amnesty international
would have done itdifferently.
This was no ai-thing!
This was no ,,show me your wounds!''- Project!
lt wasn't that we wanted to get
green cards for all melve of them.
ln some aspects this venture
was swinish to the highest degree!
Gregor Gysi, German politician, PDS
Krauts out!...Krauts out!...Krauts out!
There is no negative energy!
There just is energy!
And now l welcome
our honorary guest Gregor Gysi!
Well, hello to you,
dear Viennese women and men!
Dear guests of the city! Dear friends and
...Enemies!
This signifies our level of tolerance.
Schlingensief is a provocateur.
This is for sure.
and many now heat up to his provocations.
This also is for sure.
But let me state my opinion:
the only real provocation in our time is
that we still have to deal
with late traces of the Middle Ages!
And these traces are any form
of racism and xenophobia today!
This is what we have to leave behind!
Please police!
Viva international solidarity!
Nazis out!
Free the refugees, please!
l really felt scared when
the activists stormed the container.
Theyjust crashed in with that hippie-idea in
their heads: We need to free those people!
They didn't get it, that it was
serious what we played out there.
And then you just could see their urge to
destruct. Sure it is understandable.
We definitely had used
the crudest statements to provoke.
But l was really in fear
that this could suddenly end very badly.
Let them free!
Let us say clear and directly:
1-2-3, let them free!
They were all in e_reme heat.
Those people crashing in.
lt was all just a big brawl of screams and
fighting. You had to keep in the background
You were beaten, torn and pushed.
for not getting punched.
Such a peaceful being like me
l just thought, should l run away?
And the situation was how to get them
down from the roof again,
before it breaks in and 20 or 30
of them have broken legs or worse.
l have witnessed it myself, when the
weekly Thursday demonstration stepped
into the Schlingensief-trap with
their activists completely off the chain.
At once they started to demonstrate
for a clean Austria.
They cleaned Austria
by destroying the revelatory stigmata.
l conceived that as very frightening. That
these people are ruled by certain blindness,
so they cannot see
what they are really heading for .
And that their roles
are immediately changing
when they step into the public stage.
They acted out of the intention
to reconstruct the image of a clean Austria.
Notjust simply some Austria,
but the image of a purified Austria.
So up to a point they acted on
the same level as the Krone Newspaper did,
wanting the same outcome.
Free the people!
The people really are frightened in there!
After the activists were standing on top
and inside of the container
l negotiated that six of them should build
a delegation to talk with the refugees.
Then those six came and held speeches:
We want to liberate you!
We want to bring you freedom!
We are from the anti-fascistic front!
Now they all will be freed!
The refugees have to be
evacuated out of security reasons.
Deportation is murder!
Deportation is killing!
Are they all away now?
The liberation of the refugees has happened!
And it was not the government freeing them!
lt was the population!
Therefore l am thanking all of you! Bye!
Resistance!
lt may be embarrassing
for the Viennese resistance groups.
But the reality is,
that this event had initiated
much more political fuzz then they managed
to raise in mo previous months of protest.
After a furious beginning the demos
had withered more and more.
And no ideas to build the protest
for new were happening anymore.
Does this mean, all is finished now?
Was this the finale?
May we leave some flyers? What's up now?
ls everything over? We insist you come to
the demo ne_ Thursday! The embassy for
weary citizens down at city hall!
Cause we had the container
there a lot earlier!
Since the February 9th!
You just have to come!
We also will be there!
But we have to ask mommy!
This is our new home anmay!
The whole event here was to bug the FPÖ
in the first place, right?
So they would say:
Our flag is parading from such a shithive?
And now those, who are against
this party, pull it all down!
l screamed around like mad:
You'll do the FPÖ a pleasure,
when you're taking that away!
They have become part
of the play without recognizing it.
Or perhaps they even recognized it.
But they never got it, that
this whole event was against the right.
Yes, that was the provocation
like Christoph has said: How long can this
sentence survive in public!
It wasn't really meant that way , right?
Foreigners out!
This was only a provocation... To check out
how long may this keep hanging! And our
government stupidos have accepted that..
Without getting it.
But then the demo gloriously...
Yeah! But isn't it much better to keep
this picture up for a full ten weeks
to oppose the government
instead of tearing it down? It's stupid!
Freedom for the refugees?
When they get out of here,
what kind of freedom,
you think, will be there to find?
They thought you would kill them!
What was on your minds?
They don't know no German!
All that screaming out there!
The hullabaloo!
The fighting all around! They thought,
this would be their end!
Are you the leader of this bunch of
imbeciles? Not one leader's left of them
anmay, ey? Just a bunch of bored idiots,
destroying everything in sight!
Oh, we just wandered down
Ballhaus-Square as as we heard the people...
Deciding to storm the container.
And l just said: let's look what happens!
And then it took eternities until the demo
started marching. And l just said:
l really need to watch this now
and so l went there!
And 15 minutes later the demo
happened to pass by!
The Indians stormed the buildings.
The refugees had fled. The event had ended.
lt would have been
the biggest mistake to do it that way!
Please pull it more towards the middle!
There is a double ''s'' in there!
That looks like SS!
lt's not good for Austria, when people can
see that SS-people are living here!
The SS-insignia are forbidden!
Don't ever let SS be read up there!
They will claim we did that on purpose!
We had to somehow try to maintain
autonomy in bemeen all these positions.
Bemeen the left, that patted on your back.
Bemeen the right,
who wished you god knows where.
lfwe had terminated the event at this point,
we would have played the joker to the lefties
And l don't want to permit
a self-deceiving demonstration culture
the right to the finale.
You just have to wreck that.
ln the morning it was...
l can't even remember what l did that night.
lf l had dreamed at all.
Normally l dream a lot.
But at that morning l woke up and
couldn't even reach my slippers.
lt cracked and crumbled underneath my skin,
like l had completely dried out.
There was nothing in there anymore.
Then l dragged myself back to the square.
And when l arrived there,
pure hell was happening.
The whole thing had restarted.
It was the need of this thing.
lt was this fast breeder.
It was this power plant.
These fuel rods deep inside Vienna itself.
It didn't want to be shut down.
Schröder and Chirac were
kissing all overjust yesterday!
Despite not knowing who's
the bigger one. Who's ruling the EU!
That's because there are
6 billion people on earth...
And only 8 million of them are Austrians!
And the 8 billion permanently
threaten poor little Austria!
14 Countries had to front against Austria.
Isn't that embarrassing?
You may grease that Chirac-guy up your hair!
And that Schröder-guy, too!
This little country Austria.
Barely 8 million inhabitants,
Has welcomed more foreigners,
more refugees and the ilk than Germany!
The ,,provoker'' just drinks liquor!
You should be learning your language, man!
But not your ,,classy'' German!
We talk our talk!
We've been lured enough already!
It's enough all right!
You won't get through language class and
then your citizenship will be terminated!
Cause we're talking on the streets,
l'm talking like a prole!
l'm talking like
my mouth is grown and l say:
Dear colleague, you can
fucking lick my butt hole!
You know what's the Viennese expression for
that? Kiss me in the valley of the winds!
So this is my closing statement
for this long day: God bless Austria!
The way it has been
told since way back then: God bless Austria!
For sure, there were people that said,
it would have been better;
this event had never taken place.
This is clear.
But to prohibit such manifestations
- l don't want to call this art -
would have been far worse than letting
things just go like they were going.
lf the Krone Newspaper
wouldn't have jumped on it,
the whole thing would have
drowned in the public mind.
Due to lack of provocation.
Due to lack of artistry.
l think, the Krone just explicitly
wanted to stake their claims on a clean
and properAustrian super nation.
Like the song in ''First April 2000'':
The sun shines for everyone the same!
WhyAustria is the one to blame?''
The Krone just wanted to make that
point clear, how they dominate the scenery .
And it doesn't fucking matter
if it's a SPÖ or FPÖ or ÖVP:
the Krone is the Krone and
that is the main party of the country .
And whoever buys that paper
in the morning, votes for that party.
And there is nothing to stop that process.
This is the way l believe things to be.
What we normally believe
to be the ruling power isn't.
Yellow press is the
only real party out there.
Foreigners out!'' is a
virulent instigation of the public!
l am sick of apologizing
to my friends from abroad,
that they can read
this ''Foreigners out'' up there!
But you need not to apologize
for something that's true!
Foreigners out! Foreigners out!
You are a fascist lefty!
l reckon the most characteristic development
is, that the FPÖ-people have become
fashionable. They have got the power now.
They are all over the society pages.
They dominate the lifestyle mags.
They are the new idols.
Some years ago it has been just Haider ,
who was that sassily worshipped pop icon,
that bold little chap,
who dares talking back at any cost.
Who bungee-jumps from the highest bridges.
The one fighting
against those with established power.
Now there have grown
a lot more of that specimen.
Daniel Cohn-Bendit, icon
of ''68'' and politician, ''The Greens''
We are dreaming. It's like
back in the fifties.
Art is central again
to political confrontation.
With an artistic idea,
that is deeply connected to reality .
These are real people.
These are real asylum seekers.
Real illegals,
seeking official permission to stay.
Europe has reacted emotionally, because
Europe couldn't imagine how it comes,
that 50 years past second world war
someone like this could openly participate
in a civilized European government.
This reaction of Europe is legitimate
and we would be disgusted
if Europe hadn't reacted that way.
Honorable Mister Haider
we seriously want to invite you to
a conversation with the asylum seekers.
This date would
definitely need your participation
and is of greatest importance,
because it serves the communication
and collaboration within Europe.
Cordially yours,
Christoph Schlingensief
After all we had also
offered the stage to Haider.
The Krone papers completely
shot off range with that.
lt only occured that there
would have been equality of arms.
That was a setting
he could not accept by all means.
Equality of arms for the first time.
And then he chickened out.
You got to believe that:
Haider had chickened out!
The Krone completely missed the point in
saying, this just was leftist group hysteria
the stage also was open to the
right-wingers. Even for the head of them
lt then turned into a propaganda forum for
the left. But it was not intended that way .
lf Haider or Dichand had appeared,
with a delicate certainty
they could have taken over the event
in an instant, within the blink of an eye.
No African has a better life than here!
You liar! Just go to the prisons and look
for foreigners there! Down at Wasa-Street!
Cause they're stealing
and they're living from hash!
Lies! All lies!
When l go to Africa and open up
my mouth, l'll be killed immediately!
You don't need to tell me any truth!
Everyday it's in the papers, what your doing
to the foreigners! Kill em off!
No! That is a lie!l
Every day on television!
That is a lie!l
That is a lie?
That is a lie! Where did that happen?l
In Amica!
What country in _mica?
Yes! In your place!
You don't live anmhere
as good as here!
qou definitely need to learn, my miend!
From you?
Yes! From me!l
Democracy gets burdened very often.
And it is also said very often,
democracy will endure all of this.
l also believe that.
And democracy evidently has endured it.
Also the Austrians have endured it.
But l keep asking myself,
if it's justified to throw another stone,
when Austria is under attack already?
To add fuel to the fire?
And to say afteM/ards:
Oh well, they will endure it anmay .
Democracy?
That means decision of the majority!
Therefore it is completely democratic to
decide by majority to get rid of democracy!
A pe_ect thought by all logic!
But democracy is no formal logical term,
but a term to cover up and
secure certain political social realities.
This is the slight difference.
Straight on time,
the ne_ deportation is starting!
And another one!
And another one! And another one!
All goes down in a pe_ect flux!
We have to rush,
before the demo comes
round the corner again!
Thank god, you buzz off again!
Away to your Kraut brothers!
You won't stop us!
You are the loser!
You are a discontinued model!
Dearest friends! It has become clear now!
The opposition is growing
as the government is dying out!
l also want to be deported!
l also want to be deported! l am Austrian,
but l also want to be deported!
Please help me!
l also want to be deported!
You goddamned bastards!
Everybody talks about well-respected men.
The little ones are for-got-ten.
About big artists, papers write and write
and write. Little men never get in sight.
All raves about the big,
but the little men shtick never gets a kick
Something must happen for the little man!
Without help he won't uncan the can!
He can't help the little man fuzz!
If he could, he would be big like us!
Doesn't the gentleman fit your acting
concept? Could we please hear his speech?
There is no deportation today!
There is no deportation!
This is the real violence!
Your violence!
Deportation is over!
,,Foreigners out!'' is over!
There is no deportation today!
And in bemeen
it all is you, my Schlingensief!
Your touching tender looks!
Your bright children's eyes, those know
no lie when looking onto this world!
That keep looking and looking and wondering,
what still exists out there!
What kind of understanding of art is it
to believe, artjust walks into the world and
completely can alter it
for the good or worse of it.
lf this was the case,
then l am asking myselfwhy politics
haven't replaced art a long,
Iong time ago.
Why haven't politics
gone into art business?
Then all these representatives
can paint a nice picture.
They can tape it
on the ne_ poster pillar.
And l get enlightened
when l'm passing on my bike.
Every problem
in the world suddenly is solved:
No poverty anymore.
No polluted environment.
Just because those
nice pictures are hanging there.
What kind of delusion is this! This is
rubbish! This doesn't interest me at all!
l am interested to invite a multitude
of systems to gather in a dance.
And that dance becomes the picture.
And the picture will remain there!
For six or seven days!
And it still will be there in 10 years
and in 100 years as well!
But if it changes the world or singular
persons is absolutely not relevant! Because
the ones asking for this to happen are the
ones who will never change anything anmay!
Ladies and gentlemen, we are from the FPÖ
and we say: ,,Foreigners out!''
l am inviting all the tourists
arriving here: Photograph this poster!
lt will keep hanging here
for another five hours!
Peter Marboe, Vienna's cultural councilor
and his fascist friends may still come
and take this poster down!
We will not prevent it!
We will wait for him with open arms!
We will even help!
We will not say this work
of art ought not to be destroyed,
cause there is no work of art!
We will simply support the destruction!
Still, five hours are left
and it is thrilling to see what will happen!
Will Europe keep this picture in its mind?
Will Europe say:
Yes. The coalition wasn't even able
to make a phone call.
Just to express:
''O.k.! We want this sentence to vanish!
This is our goal!
We want to take this down together!'' No.
The test is still running.
For five hours.
Then we will all know
what this coalition in Austria really wants.
And at this exact moment
the music comes to an end!
What pathos! What a day!
To me Christoph is no manipulator of society.
Christoph is no ratter piping together
the people with
whatever pictures are at hand.
So that people just say yes and amen
and Schlingensief is our new ''Fuehrer''.
This is not the point.
l am never too sure how many vanities
are to be satisfied with this project.
How much artistic intention is in there?
How much humanism and how much
care compared to the vanity.
l love glamorous people.
Pop culture gives me the kick.
l think it's great,
when they all dazzle and bath in vanity .
lf not, they should work in a bank, you know!
Thank you! It's an enormous
push foM/ard to encounter people like you!
You have to immediately buy a FPÖ flag,
take it into your hand,
walk through the streets and kick a tourist.
This is the method, ladies and gentlemen!
This is for free! Take a FPÖ sticker!
Take FPÖ whatever into your hand
and kick a tourist!
Give him a good smack and
tell him: ,,Foreigners out!''
Just do it!
And then you just kindly run away!
l am demonstrating!
l am against it! Against it!''
That's worth shit today! Resistance is over!
You have to produce contradictions!
Where do you come from?
Indonesia!
Tunisia? Hello! l am from the FPÖ!
Back there are mo Japanese ladies! See?
They both need their faces punched, ey?
lt is evident that the Schlingensief-stories
are e_reme social integrators because they
make it possible to integrate those people,
who are in deep danger to blow their top
and start a large-scale terrorist
or nihilist political act.
Thereby these tendencies get tied to
the comparatively safe art.
And that is why art is so magnificently
assimilated, where it seems
not conforming to society at all.
l am a little therapist here.
A little head doctor in the hospital.
And l am proud of that, to carry my patients
away from their lies for a short moment.
And then we can diagnose together .
And we can judge
if there is recovery possible or not.
lf he was a social therapist,
then this whole enterprise has flopped.
lt hasn't cleansed anything.
Yes, l know, how this is to be understood!
This would mean a battle ofwords.
l conceive therapy as a term
for cleaning up, making healthy again.
But this event only revealed something.
And this is more than we could hope for .
Let's begin. German lesson.
l am sad because l have problems!
l am sad because l have no food!
l am sad because l will be deported!
These are enemies against us!
Who is the bad one and who the good?
That Schlingensief is an asshole!
That's known since a hundred years!
Just look at that name!
He's got v.D. in his brain!
These are some Bavarian colleagues
Whom l am taking for a sightseeing tour.
l told them to really see the town,
We got to go right here!
Here it is great! Here we got a rumble!
Here you get to know V ienna, right?
Yupp, here you get dead drunk
in the right winged students tradition!
That's not us!
The great passion of right winged
students is boozing up, right?
Yes! Correct! So the sorry rest of our brains
will be drunken away!
Just look at that glorious German laugh!
You know the flatheads?
Down at the zoo! Schönbrunn!
Excellent!
That's where you belong! Schönbrunn!
Just look at that ,,Foreigners out!''- Sign!
Who needs that?
ls that an ad for you Krauts?
You Kraut-friend!
You Schröder-friend!
Stoiber stands tall for us!
Haider doesn't stand!
That one can fucking go to hell!
Haider is falling already!
You behave! If he were with you guys,
he'd be chancellor already!
Hitler hasn't made it
over here, remember?
With you Krauts
he was chancellor immediately!
Well, hasn't he got the
Ioveliest name on earth: Schlingensief!
Maybe he just got
the clap in the head!
lt didn't harm him at all.
The opposite was the case.
He now is the big hero in the spotlight.
The ,,Fesmochen'' also weren't harmed.
For sure it meant some damage to the
politicians permitting the whole thing.
Today at Viennese election time for example
you still get mail flyers of the FPÖ,
writing: we would not
have permitted this container!
l am also for you staying here!
You are a Kraut, right?
So please treat us like Austrians! We are
the most peaceful population on earth!
Look! l think you can
judge that from pedagogics!
lf l continuously tell a child
that it is bad, that it is rotten,
it may rebel for a short while.
But if you still continue with provoking it,
then it may finally say: o.k!
Then l am bad and rotten, l guess!
And it will not react to
anything else at all anymore!
That is the case l also see here!
ln every other country you would have been
jailed and executed already!
There you see what country Austria really is!
We are a country of culture, you know!
Listen to Mozart! Go to the opera!
Get the damn back home to Krautland!
Go where you belong, you smart aleck!
Certainly you have witnessed,
what l think is a positive thing.
That mo people that weren't at ground zero
of the event started to seriously
talk with each other.
That also has happened.
Clearly a positive act.
EinstÜrzende Neubauten
German rock avant-garde band
ls tax money paid to remain silent?
l think, taxpayer's money that is invested
into art is there for confrontation!
Charles Ofuedo, Nigerian author:
We all say: Art must be free! Shout it out
all of you! A-r-t m-u-s-t b-e f-r-e-e!
Peter Pilz, Austrian politician, Green Party:
About this container there is huge fuzz.
Not about Rossauer drive
and the Rossauer barracks 1 km from here,
where an artist doesn't stage these things.
Peter Sellars
Theatre director, USA
And when a Peter Sellars suddenly screams:
We need this project in Los Angeles.
Well, then he should do it. But he doesn't.
He just screams and yells it.
And also Luc Bondy, whom l respect a lot
and who unexpectedly discovers
the political fighter within himself, but who
is all but gone right after the project.
Then l have to say:
That's just the way it is!
l won't reproach them for anything.
But the funny thing is:
l had known all this to happen before!
We are now approaching our
final deportation! l don't want to say much,
but to remember you of the container
waiting here at Vienna airport. A container
full of real refugees, seeking asylum.
Waiting for their tough fate to happen.
And this container's not standing just here,
but all over Europe. Evermhere are people,
who are not permitted to stay
in the country they would like to stay in.
And there are a lot of instigators.
People that put sentences up.
Certain sentences
that are said far too easily .
With which people forget far too soon
that they had said them themselves.
Where they play surprised
that they have been said.
To put these sentences into reality ,
to make them real,
was the intent of this project.
And the third one stepping inside the car
is someone that already spent
some time up here with us.
He will also have to leave this country .
And there he goes: Christoph Schlingensief!
Finally he's gone! Thank you! Bye bye!
And now the winner...
the austrian's darling...
Welcome, Ranil Shunta!
You - come - come here!
You - won! From - people! 3.500 bucks!
Give a warm round
of applause to our big winner!
This banner up there is like everything
in life that offers resistance - art!
We are all artists!
The new government raises taxes and cuts
social, cultural and educational budgets.
As a consequence the FPÖ loses lots ofvoters.
The ÖVP in contrast achieves consistent to
increasing results.
ln November 2001 the university of Innsbruck
published a study on xenophobia in Austria:
Out of 2.OOO studied people,
220/o proved strong on xenophobia,
260/o as latent cases.
And 100/o even could be classified
as part of the e_reme right.