Hey, June.
Come have some food.
I think I'm gonna go
watch the fireworks.
You want to go out?
Yeah, I'm gonna go out.
Okay.
Call if you need anything.
Dexter...
How you gonna satisfy me?
Uh, not like that.
Listen Dexter, I gotta go.
Because.
Look, I'll talk to you later.
Bye.
Dexter! You in there?!
You better get some ribs
while there's some left!
No, ma. I'm good.
Fucking mirrors, man.
♪
Ow!
[phone rings]
Hello?
Hey.
Yeah.
On time.
Plaid shirt.
No one is here.
Okay. Cool.
June?
Hi there.
Hey.
My God...
What a wasteland.
My car.
Oh, yeah. Okay.
You okay?
Yeah, yeah...
I used to shop here.
It was a Marshall's. Anyway...
Oh, okay. Well...
Yeah.
Let's go.
So, on the road.
Yeah.
I love driving.
Driving gotta be the most
America thing there is.
You having a good
Fourth of July?
Yeah. It's fine.
Fourth of July.
- Like apple pie.
- Huh?
Driving...
You said it was the most
American thing there is.
Like apple pie.
Oh... Yeah.
We might be able to see
some fireworks tonight.
Where?
It's the Fourth of July...
Fireworks everywhere.
It's illegal here.
Illegal?
That's the other American thing.
What?
Breaking the law.
You know,
we're breaking the law.
We are?
This state still
has adultery laws.
We're having an affair?
So do I look like
the sound of my voice?
Yeah, I guess.
This how you imagined me?
I didn't really
imagine anything.
You look a lot like
I imagined you.
You're a cutie.
Whatever.
I was thinking we could
go see a movie tonight.
Oh, yeah?
What's your favorite?
I don't really
have any favorites.
Come on, you have to have
a favorite movie.
I haven't thought about it much.
I'd have to think about it.
Okay. Favorite books?
You're like an expert.
I feel stupid.
C'mon. Don't be scared of me.
You're not intimidated
by me, are you?
I like Truman Capote.
Minor, minor, minor.
Well, what are your
favorite books?
No. Tell me more of yours.
I was just joking.
I like Truman Capote.
Breakfast at Tiffany's -
that was a great book.
Gore Vidal?
Do you read
any straight writers?
You gotta be proud of yourself.
You gotta believe in yourself.
You say 'I like Truman Capote',
say 'I LOVE Truman Capote'.
Say it with force.
Say it with flare.
Present yourself.
Make people listen.
You gotta come out
from behind that computer.
- You with me?
- Okay.
You need some confidence,
some cockiness.
A little America.
I don't really like America.
What?!
America has done
a lot of bad things.
Who hasn't?
It's just by
wanting to be the best.
Okay. No more politics.
You're making me angry.
Sorry.
I'm gonna give you the most
American Fourth of July
you've ever had.
What do you have
to say about that?
[car engine revs faster]
It's all about excess!
Being big! Being loud!
You with me?!
AMERICA! GOD BLESS AMERICA!
That's better.
Scream something.
I don't scream.
That's not my style.
On the count of three.
1, 2, 3...
I see. Okay.
We'll make you scream
a little later.
You are not coming over.
You're picking me up!
I have work to do.
I gotta be here
when my dad calls.
At a conference in Boston.
[clanging nearby]
Hold on.
Dexter, I gotta go.
Mommy?
What time is it?
Almost there.
Cool.
Sure you don't want anything?
Yeah. I'm pretty full.
When did you eat?
Before I left.
What did you have?
Just, you know...
Hot dog, whatever.
One hot dog?
Yeah.
How are you full on one hot dog?
I'm okay.
So why did they name you June?
Were you supposed to be
conceived in June?
No, I was supposed
to be born in June.
Supposed?
Yeah, well...
I was born in April.
I was six weeks premature.
I was supposed to be
born in June,
so they named me June.
You do a lot of acting?
No...
I've had a few shows,
a few roles. Mostly chorus.
And why haven't you
come out to your parents?
I don't know.
Do you love them?
Yeah. A lot.
I love my parents.
We all do.
So, why don't you tell them?
- Because I can't.
- Why not?
I don't want to. I don't know.
Are you waiting
until you have a boyfriend?
I don't think
I'll ever tell them.
Why?
I don't know!
'Cause I'm the only son.
I know my mom wants grandkids.
I don't really
feel right about...
About being gay.
I don't like that word.
- What word?
- Gay.
- Queer?
- Shh.
You know people here?
I might. I don't know.
It was my dad's idea
to name me June.
My mom wanted to
name me Franklin.
So what do they do?
My dad works for the state,
the Department
of Transportation.
He studies
traffic patterns and stuff.
Helps retime stop lights.
And my mom is
a dental assistant.
You must have
sparkling teeth then.
Not really.
I do love them...
A lot. I just...
Does anyone know?
Well, you.
Me?
Beautiful.
What?
The lights go down.
Like sinking into
a collective dream.
Suddenly, you're anonymous.
You get that sexual charge.
Charge of excitement.
Anticipation.
Danger.
Hold this.
Welcome to Cinemark.
Remember to visit
our concessions stand.
Please silence your cell phones
and enjoy the show.
[phone rings]
Hello?
Hey, baby.
Hi, Daddy!
Happy Fourth of July!
Happy Fourth of July
to you too.
How's she doing?
She's okay. She's asleep.
Okay. Good.
How's the conference?
Quite a spot
on the Fourth of July.
A lot of pride here.
A lot of white pride.
Boston's such a white city.
That's why Daddy loves it.
I stand out here.
You making people mad?
I'm making people listen.
So, yeah,
I'm making people mad.
What are you doing tonight?
Just staying in.
Thank you, for taking care
of your mother.
It's no problem.
I wish I could be there.
You know how much
it means to me.
Where are you? It's loud.
[people chattering]
Hotel lobby, honey.
Sounds like...
Remember when we used to
go to the movies
on the Fourth of July?
Daddy?
Yeah, baby?
Nothing.
Should I call you later?
No, don't call;
it will wake her up.
I love you, baby.
I love you too.
Bye, bye.
Bye.
Dexter, what you doing?
If you wanna come pick me up
for a little while, you can.
But only for like 15 minutes.
Yeah, baby.
Fifteen minutes all I need.
You're so nasty.
Just come, okay?
Alright, I'll be right there.
Bye.
So, why'd you change your mind?
Changed my mind. No reason.
There's always a reason.
So, you can get off
this subject now.
Wow. Okay.
If you're gonna act all bitchy,
I'll take you home.
You'll take me however I am.
And don't call me a bitch.
- I did not call you a bitch.
- Yes, you did.
I said you were acting bitchy.
I wouldn't call you a bitch.
I never call a woman a bitch.
You call
your mother a bitch.
That's my mother.
Alright. Starting over.
Commercial break. La-di-da.
Where you wanna go?
You wanna go to the park?
I don't like the park.
Then where?
You don't wanna
see the fireworks.
Don't wanna go to the park.
Where you wanna go?
Don't wanna go nowhere.
I hate this town.
You told me on the computer
the first night we met.
You said you had a friend
you used to fool around with?
Yeah.
What was his name?
Todd.
Todd... That's right.
How come you don't
speak to him anymore?
I just never really...
Once middle school came,
he started acting weird.
Like a faggot?
Yeah, I guess.
Wearing flamboyant clothes?
Yeah...
And he started
hanging out with all girls.
I wonder what
he's doing tonight?
He's probably out.
I know he goes to Chez.
- The bar Chez?
- Yeah.
And they don't beat the shit
out of him at school?
I guess people
just leave him alone
because he's too weird
or something.
Do people leave you alone?
Yeah, I guess.
I don't really talk a lot.
- Wanna go and see him?
- No!
C'mon!
We're only five minutes away.
I don't want to do that.
So you're not scared
to meet some guy
you just met
on the computer.
But you're scared
to see someone--
- I don't want to know him.
- Why not?
I don't know.
When we were 13,
he was still pretty normal.
I know 'cause,
he used to be on the swim team
and I used to dive.
I wasn't really talking
to him or anything.
We had this swim coach,
and he was
the diving coach too...
I had a funny feeling
about him.
- Fag?
- Yeah.
[chuckling]
What?
No, go on.
I'm anticipating the story.
Go on.
One night my mom was really
late to pick me up.
And I saw Ted give Todd
a ride home in his car...
which coaches, I mean,
you're not supposed to.
It was making me really mad,
like I didn't know what to do.
I decided to give him a call -
to see, like...
Just to see if he was home.
And I don't
know why or anything.
I just said, like meanly, like,
'You're gay, aren't you?'
And then I hung up.
You hung up?
I hung up...
And I never spoke
to him again after that.
I don't know if he knew
if it was me or not,
but I just never...
I hated him after that.
You hated him?
Yeah. I just...
I don't know.
Okay, June...
Where do you
want to go right now?
Where do I want to go?
Okay, just tell me.
C'mon. Just tell me.
This is your night.
You're the young man,
I'm the old man.
Tell me.
Coach Donavan said
he thinks I'm like the best
Division II player
he's ever seen.
Says he wants to
give me a transfer
to a Division I school.
But that my grades
are a little bit bad.
Plus, my record.
But apparently some schools
are still interested,
so, you know, that's cool.
Which schools?
A couple.
Watch this...
Oh, God!
Showoff.
So tell me...
Why'd you change your mind?
Felt like it.
Yeah?
I know I'm a white boy and you
ain't into that kind of thing.
Half white, half spic.
Don't sell yourself short.
Oh!
You're a little bit racist!
I mean, apparently you ain't
into either one.
I never said that.
That I'm not into white boys.
So then tell me...
You think I'm cute?
You think I'm handsome?
You think I'm pretty?
You can tell me. C'mon!
I don't like your questions.
What if I told you...
I think you're pretty?
I'd accept the complement.
What if I told you
I think that you
are beautiful?
are beautiful chocolate.
You just ruined it
by calling me chocolate.
What if I told you
I think you're beautiful -
no chocolate?
Even though it's delicious.
I know you're intentions.
You know that, right?
You know you ain't fooling me.
I don't got no intentions.
I mean, fuck that.
I'm here with you right.
You were saying.
I wasn't saying anything.
You were saying that...
you think that
I'm cute sometimes.
Yeah?
Yeah.
Alright, so then when?
When do you think I'm cute?
When you're smiling
like a little boy.
You think I'm like
a little boy?
Sometimes.
You don't get it...
It's hard to talk to you.
You think I'm stupid,
don't you?
You do.
You think I'm like at home
playing with Legos,
puttin' my finger
up my nose and shit.
You think I'm not
good enough for you.
That I can't understand
your thoughts,
or whatever is going on
in your head.
I got thoughts too.
Watch.
Before the night is out...
you're gonna
tell me your thoughts.
I wish you did want
to see the fireworks.
But you don't wanna do that.
That's okay,
maybe we could stay here.
That's cool too. We can see
the sky get all bright...
Watch the clouds light up...
That's cool too.
I used to love coming here.
Everybody loved me.
Everybody knew who I was.
I played basketball.
I was the leading scorer.
They wrote about me
in the newspaper.
The only thing I didn't
like to do was confession.
I hated that shit.
You believe in God?
I believe in God.
I don't got no reason not too.
I don't know why I wouldn't.
My dad didn't believe in God,
look at that bitch.
He's fat and toothless.
Don't talk about
your dad that way.
Don't tell me how to
talk about my dad.
[fireworks popping]
Some kids gettin'
an early start!
What you kissing me for?
You okay?
♪
You are so warm.
Let's go.
Where?
Your house.
My house?
Why don't we go to your house?
I wanna go. C'mon.
Wait, wait. Come here.
Give me another kiss.
I wanna go.
Damn. You are so warm.
Dexter.
Okay. Okay.
Wait, wait.
Thank you.
I love motels, I love 'em.
Why?
Just do. Just love 'em.
There always here. Always open.
TV. Shower. Phone.
The essential tools of living
in a completely
anonymous setting.
You can re-invent yourself.
And this book...
The greatest book ever.
The Bible is
the greatest book ever?
It's inspired and enraged
so many people.
That's what makes it
the best book.
I hate going to church.
Why do you go then?
My parents go.
We've always gone.
Turn on the TV.
You know, I bet motels
are one of the few places
people feel comfortable
reading the Bible.
Anything on?
Not much.
Turn it off.
I'm just gonna take a shower.
Why do you have to
take a shower?
I want to.
- You nervous?
- No.
I'll put you at ease.
No. I just feel...
I'm not clean.
I feel a little sweaty.
Okay. It's up to you.
I'll just...
I'll be quick.
I volunteer
a couple days a week.
At the University.
I see a lot of kids
in trouble these days.
Sad kids.
I didn't seem that sad
when I was growing up.
We learned to keep a lot inside.
We didn't expect too much.
Maybe that was...
a good thing, you know.
The other day
I was with this man.
And he was very poor.
He was on food stamps
and welfare.
And he's white.
He'd just had it.
He's a little older than me.
Graduated from high school.
But he hadn't gone to college.
And he had a family.
Can you hear me in there?!
Yeah!!
Well, he had a family.
And he lost his family.
He left them.
And he married another woman.
And then he left her too.
And then he stopped
trying to be married.
He wanted to...
be on his own.
He wanted to do
what he wanted to do.
The work that I do -
it's a counseling center.
It's a health center.
I see a lot of kids.
It's a surprise to see
an older person -
especially a man.
And he's there
getting his blood tested.
And as we were talking...
I started to realize.
I started...
to remember this man.
Well, I realized this...
was the first man I slept with.
I remember because he had a scar
on the bottom of his left ear.
It looked like a snake,
I remember thinking.
It was the 80s.
And I was going through
a rough point at that time.
The good thing
about this disease
is that it makes most people
start thinking about sex
instead of just having it.
You know what I'm saying?
Many people start thinking
about the other person
and what they may have
inside of them.
I think....
this disease is the best thing
that ever happened
to gay men because...
in a certain sense
it has made us human.
But I could go on forever
about this.
I'm getting away from the story.
Are you interested?!
I'll stop. I'll stop talking.
Can you hear me?!
No...uh... Keep going.
I didn't bring it up to him,
of course.
I look different.
He wouldn't recognize me.
I started thinking about...
the myths of first love,
first sex.
How for gay boys of today...
their first AIDS test
is the equivalent of
a straight boy
losing his virginity.
What's wrong?
Nothing.
You're all dressed.
Did you shower?
Are you okay?
Yeah, no, I'm fine.
I just...
This is a mistake, isn't it?
- No!
- Let's not do this.
You don't have to do this.
I just...
I don't know.
I'll take you home.
- I don't want to go home.
- What do you want?
I'm sorry.
I'm horny.
You're what?
What do you want, June?
June, June, June...
You are beautiful.
You beautiful boy.
Nah, ma. We're good.
See, I told you
your place was better.
It's a little...messy.
Entré. Entré, madam.
You can sit down if you like.
You saw what
I was talking about, right?
The neighborhood, it's mixed.
What do you mean?
That I grew up in.
We have black people and shit.
You know what's funny, though?
I talk like I'm black, right?
And you talk like
you're a white girl.
I do not talk like a white girl.
What you mean, you don't?
Your mama white?
No! She's black!
Damn, girl.
Why you say it like that?
Like what?
Like you angry or some shit.
You got a nice room.
It's small, but it's cozy,
Little Miss Change-the-Subject.
All these posters.
I wish I was black.
I do...
Sometimes I just
wish I was black.
What?
You alright?
Yeah.
I'm ready to go home.
How come you ain't talkin'?
You're not talkin' either.
You could have taken
the left-over barbecue.
It was good.
I don't eat meat.
Maybe tomorrow you want
to go see a movie?
I have to work.
Where you work at?
Things around the house.
Help out my mom.
And my father's coming home.
You haven't said anything.
Hmm?
You haven't said
anything about it.
Was it okay?
No, um...
Yeah... it was. I just...
- I mean, was it okay?
- Yes. Yes.
I'm sorry that I...
It's okay, June.
Your mother ever let people
come over the house?
She doesn't like it.
I think it makes her sad.
Why is that?
She doesn't want to be reminded.
Of what?
Other people.
I don't understand.
You don't have to.
Damn. Fine.
♪
You okay?
Pull over here.
Why? What happened?
Just do it!
You okay?
You sick or something?
Shut up!
Hey, baby.
Hello? Abigayle?
Hello? Are you there?
Drive.
- Where?
- Just drive, okay!
♪
Time to make a decision.
It's up to you, really.
Okay.
We are going to...Chez.
No!
Oh, alright!
An answer! Emphatic at that!
I just don't want to go there.
- You're scared--
- I'm not!
What's up? Can I come in?
Dexter, my mom is sleeping.
I promise I'll be quiet.
No.
C'mon. I let you come over.
Five minutes.
Dexter, no!
Five minutes,
I promise I'll be quiet!
I'll start screaming.
Your neighbors will think you're
getting raped or something.
You just won't quit, will you?
Help! Somebody help me!
Five minutes.
Don't say a word.
I promise.
[crowd chattering]
Two cokes.
Can we go now, please?
Give me a few minutes--
I did what you wanted.
I'm not scared.
What do I have to
prove to you anyway?
June?
Why don't you say something?
I'm leaving.
- You should talk to him.
- I'm leaving.
Fuck!
Fuck you!
June?
Wow! What are you doing here?
Hi. I'm Joe.
Todd.
- Nice to meet you.
- Likewise.
I can't believe it!
It's so good to see you.
We have some beer and stuff,
maybe you'd want to...
June!
Go away! Leave me alone!
Leave me alone!
What do you want?!
I told you, I don't know!
Well, answer that!
And then you'll know
where you're going!
It's not like I can choose!
It's not like I can choose
to be skinny like that,
or handsome or whatever!
Let me tell you what you want.
Tell me what?!
What you want,
what will make you happy.
You can't tell me
what I want!
You want...a boyfriend.
You want to be in love.
You want someone
sleeping next to you.
You want someone to
stroke your head.
You cry yourself to sleep,
don't you?
You spend four hours
on the computer,
looking for someone to meet.
You want someone
to make you feel real,
someone to touch you.
You don't know what I want!
I'm being honest with you.
I care about you.
Maybe I should go!
June.
Let me go! Let me go!
Come over here and sit down.
Alright.
When I was little...
When I was four.
What's wrong with her?
She's just weak.
Just got weak.
So, she's just weak then?
Yeah.
What about your pop?
Is he cool?
He's a good man.
He loves me, he works hard.
Not much to say.
He travels a lot.
That's cool.
Where does he travel to?
I don't really want
to talk about it, okay?
Alright.
[phone ringing]
- I'm sorry.
- It's okay.
Times up.
I'm sorry.
Can I use your bathroom?
Dexter...
I promise you, that's it.
I'm gone.
Across the hall.
[door screeching]
[toilet flushing]
Oh...
I'm sorry...
I came out of the bathroom,
and I heard a noise over here,
I just...
Fuck you! You fucking loser!
Stop it! Stop it!
I'm sorry!
I'm sorry.
What's this?
It's me, my mom, and my pops -
when I was eight,
after a basketball game.
My dad used to
teach me basketball.
I want you to keep it.
Why should I keep this?
You're gonna miss the fireworks.
I don't wanna go
to the fireworks.
I don't want this.
Thanks.
Hold on.
What?
I got you something.
What did you get?
It's just a little something.
Don't look now.
Okay.
June?
[fireworks popping]
Hello?
Hi, it's me.
I'll be back in a little while.
I'm watching them right now...
with some friends.
Yeah.
[sparkler crackles]
♪
[fireworks continue popping]
What do you want?
Do you want some water?
Go look at
the fireworks outside?
Do you want anything?
♪