¶ MEET ME IN A DOORWAY ¶
¶ I'LL BE PAINTING PICTURES
OF GATES ¶
¶ YOU WERE SO CRAZY
I WAS SO CHASTE ¶
¶ I DON'T KNOW WHAT HAPPENED
TO ME ¶
¶ I DON'T KNOW ¶
¶ I-I-I, I DON'T WANT
TO THINK ABOUT IT ¶
¶ YOU RENDERED ME CONSCIOUS ¶
¶ YOU CUT MY INNOCENT FACE ¶
¶ I'M NOT REALLY BITTER
THINKIN' I'M NOT AMUSED ¶
¶ I JUST WANT TO KICK YOU
'TIL YOU CRY
I LOVED, I REALLY LOVED YOU ¶
¶ I-I-I, I DON'T WANT
TO THINK ABOUT IT ¶
BY SENIOR YEAR, I HAD
IT COVERED, OR SO I THOUGHT.
I HAD A GREAT GUY,
SIGHTS ON COLLEGE, ART SCHOOL,
AND THE DREAM OF LIFE BEYOND.
GOOD MORNING, ARTHUR.
IT'S A DECOY, ARTHUR.
THE AK-47'S IN HER BACKPACK.
YEAH, RIGHT.
YOU TELL YOURSELF TO COUNT THE
DAYS AND PUT UP WITH THE SHIT.
YOU TELL YOURSELF
THESE PEOPLE ARE ILLUSIONS,
PASSING SCENERY.
HEY, SNAP THESE, BABE!
THEY WERE NOTHING TO ME.
I JUST USE THEM FOR MY ART.
NO BLADING IN THE HALL.
I DON'T WANT TO HAVE
TO TELL YOU AGAIN!
OKAY, YOU JOCKSTRAP SNIFFERS,
SAY "CHEESE."
ACTION.
¶ I'LL BE WEARING
MIDDLETON'S LACE ¶
¶ IT'S AS STERILE
AS CHESS ¶
¶ NOBODY'D GUESS ¶
¶ YOU WERE TOUCHING ME
BETWEEN THE LOVE OF GOD
AND SISTER MERCY ¶
¶ I-I-I, I DON'T WANT
TO THINK ABOUT IT ¶
LOOK OUT! COMIN' THROUGH.
¶ I-I-I, I DON'T WANT
TO THINK ABOUT IT ¶
¶ THINK ABOUT IT ¶
MOST OF ALL,
I AVOIDED THE SNARES,
SKATING PAST THE OBSTACLES...
THE WAY EVERYBODY
WHO CAN MANAGE IT DOES.
¶ DING WENT
THE LITTLE GREEN FROG ¶
¶ GUH-DING WENT THE LITTLE
GREEN FROG ONE DAY ¶
¶ AND HIS EYES
WENT AGGH-AGGH-GUNG ¶
OKAY, HOLD THESE SUCKERS
DOWN ON THEIR BACKS.
READY FOR SURGERY.
NAIL 'EM GOOD.
LAST YEAR WE HAD ONE
OF THESE RIPPITS JUMP OFF...
DURING THE INCISION
OF A PULMONARY VEIN.
IT WEREN'T PRETTY.
OH, GOD.
WHAT IS IT, RITA?
I CAN'T DO IT.
- FLAKE.
- GET OFF HER SHIT ALREADY.
HELLO, RITA!
TAKE THE SCALPEL.
EARTH TO RITA.
IT'S SO DEFENSELESS.
FROGS, THEY DON'T HAVE FEELINGS
LIKE WE DO, RITA.
BUT THEIR CARDIOVASCULAR SYSTEM
IS AN EXCELLENT MODEL FOR OURS.
IN OTHER WORDS, THEIR LITTLE
HEARTS WORK A LOT LIKE OURS DO.
YOUNG MAN. YOUNG MAN,
STOP WHEN I'M TALKIN' TO YOU!
WHAT CLASS
SHOULD YOU BE IN?
BUT THEN SOMETHING HAPPENED,
UNEXPECTED.
I FELT IT BEFORE I KNEW IT.
EXCUSE ME.
IF YOU'RE NEW,
PLEASE TAKE A SEAT.
I'LL GET
THE PAPERWORK LATER.
IF I'D KNOWN YOU WERE COMING,
I'D HAVE ORDERED YOU A FROG.
ALL RIGHT, WHERE WERE WE?
CLASS, LET'S CONCENTRATE
ON THE FROG.
ON THE FROG!
ALL RIGHT, LET'S START SLICING
AND THIS AIN'T PIZZA.
WATCH THOSE VEGETABLES.
LET'S ALL SHOW RITA
WE CAN DO THIS.
OKAY?
RITA, ARE YOU WITH US?
ALL RIGHT.
TAKE THE SCALPEL NOW.
WE'VE BEEN WORKING ON THIS
FOR THREE WEEKS.
WE'RE HOLDING THINGS UP.
LET'S NOT WASTE ANY MORE TIME.
I'M GONNA COUNT TO THREE AND
YOU'LL TAKE THE SCALPEL, OKAY?
ONE.
TWO.
THREE.
HEY, LET'S DO IT!
- NO, I CAN'T DO IT.
- COME ON, LET'S GO.
- I CAN'T!
- OKAY, FINE, WE'RE GONNA TALK
IN DETENTION THEN, OKAY?
NO!
CLASS, ANYONE ELSE
HAVING A PROBLEM?
WHAT'S THE DEAL
WITH DETENTION?
HE'S ALWAYS GIVING HER SHIT.
HE'S SUCH AN ASSHOLE.
SO MAKE HIM STOP.
OKAY, I'LL DO IT.
WHAT?
I'M GONNA DO IT, OKAY?
I'M GONNA DO IT,
ALL RIGHT?
ALL RIGHT, CLASS,
YOU HEAR THAT?
RITA'S GONNA DO IT.
ATTA, GIRL.
WAY TO GO.
SHE'S NOW AIMING IT
AT THE POINT OF INCISION.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
WHAT THE HELL ARE YOU DOING,
YOUNG LADY?
HEY, I'M TALKIN' TO YOU!
- I'LL SEE YOU
IN DETENTION ALSO.
- I DON'T EVEN GO HERE.
IT WASN'T OVER.
I COULD FEEL IT...
LIKE A CHARGE IN THE AIR
BEFORE A STORM.
WHAT ELSE DOES HE DO?
HE, UM,
HE GETS REALLY CLOSE...
AND HE TOUCHES MY CHEST.
WHAT'S GOING ON?
RITA'S MAKING UP SHIT
ABOUT MR. BUTTINGER.
I'M NOT!
OKAY? I'M NOT!
HE GETS BEHIND ME...
AND HE RUBS HIMSELF
ON MY ASS.
YOU SHOULD BE GLAD
SOMEONE DOES.
SHUT UP, CINDY.
SHE'S CRAZY.
EVERYONE KNOWS THAT.
SHE'S TELLING THE TRUTH.
HE DOES IT TO ME TOO.
YOU DON'T COUNT, VIOLET.
YOU DO IT WITH EVERYONE.
WELL, AT LEAST I KNOW
WHAT I'M DOING.
IF HALF THE STORIES ABOUT YOU
ARE TRUE--
GIVE IT A REST, CINDY.
LOOK. YOU'RE THE ASSHOLES
FOR LETTING HIM
GET AWAY WITH IT.
NO. YOU'RE THE ASSHOLE FOR
LETTING HIM GET AWAY WITH IT!
EXCUSE ME.
WHO THE FUCK ARE YOU?
GET OUT OF MY WAY.
YOU'RE ALL ASSHOLES.
BECAUSE WHEN THAT SON OF A BITCH
PUTS HIS HANDS ON HER,
YOU SHOULD TELL YOURSELVES
HE'S PUTTING HIS HANDS
ALL OVER YOU.
OR YOU, OR YOU, OR YOU!
BECAUSE HE SURE AS HELL WOULD
IF HE COULD.
SO, WHAT ARE WE
SUPPOSED TO DO?
- MAKE SURE HE NEVER
DOES IT AGAIN.
- HOW?
WE STICK TOGETHER.
GIMME A BREAK.
SO, ARE WE TOGETHER?
GOOD.
WE'RE JUST GONNA SIT HERE, RITA,
UNTIL WE LEARN SOMETHING
ABOUT THE HEART.
YOU KNOW, RITA,
YOU HAVE VERY LITTLE
CONFIDENCE...
FOR SOMEONE WITH
SO MUCH POTENTIAL, TALENT.
WHAT IS THAT?
WHAT IS THAT OVER THERE?
YOU'RE VERY PRETTY.
PRETTY AND TALENTED
AREN'T THE SAME.
WHAT? SAYS WHO?
THAT'S WHERE YOU'RE WRONG.
YOU KNOW,
YOU JUST DON'T APPRECIATE
YOUR VALUE AS A WOMAN.
YOU KNOW, I, I THINK
YOU'RE WAY AHEAD OF ALL
THE GIRLS YOUR AGE. HUH?
VIOLET.
MR. BUTTINGER,
I FORGOT MY NOTEBOOK.
WELL, GET IT.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE,
MADELINE?
- WHAT IS GOING ON HERE?
- DON'T LET US STOP YOU.
GO ON WITH WHAT YOU WERE DOING.
- PERVERT!
- COME HERE, RED.
- THAT YOUNG LADY
IS IN DETENTION TODAY.
- WE NEED TO TALK.
- KEEP YOUR HANDS OFF RITA.
- AND VIOLET.
AND WHOEVER THE FUCK ELSE
YOU DO THIS TO.
- HOW DOES THAT FEEL?
- FUCKING LITTLE PUNK!
THAT'S RIGHT. YOU BETTER MOVE.
YOU BETTER KEEP MOVING.
OR WHAT?
THIS IS OUTRAGEOUS!
THIS IS ABSOLUTELY
OUTRAGEOUS!
I'M A TEACHER!
MADELINE.
MADELINE, COME ON!
YOU DON'T BELIEVE RITA.
SHE'S EMOTIONALLY UNSTABLE.
- I'M NOT UNSTABLE!
- I DIDN'T MEAN IT LIKE THAT.
I'M NOT UNSTABLE!
LEAVE HER ALONE!
NO! STOP!
IF YOU EVER PUT YOUR HANDS
ON ME AGAIN,
I'LL SNIP YOUR LITTLE NUTS OFF
WITH MY TOENAIL CLIPPERS.
ALL RIGHT?
THIS IS GREAT!
BUTTINGER'S SUCH A FUCK!
RITA. RITA.
ALL RIGHT, LET'S GO.
LET'S GO.
GET OUT OF HERE. GO!
COME ON.
CAN YOU GET UP?
NEXT TIME YOU
THINK ABOUT FUCKING
WITH SOME YOUNG GIRL,
YOU THINK ABOUT THIS FIRST.
FUCK!
FUCK! FUCK! FUCK!
WHAT IF SOMEONE SAW US?
OH, MY GOD,
WHAT ARE WE GONNA DO?
WE SHOULD GET THE HELL
OUTTA HERE.
OH, MY GOD, WE'RE IN TROUBLE.
JUST STAY CALM.
WE ARE IN SO MUCH--
WHO WAS SHE ANYWAY?
I THINK WE SHOULD ALL
GO SOMEWHERE TOGETHER.
DOES THIS BITCH ALWAYS TALK
IN EXCLAMATION MARKS?
WE SHOULD ALL JUST GO HOME.
THIS IS GONNA BE
WHAT IT'S GONNA BE.
"IF YOU EVER PUT YOUR HANDS
ON ME AGAIN,
I'M GONNA SNIP
YOUR LITTLE NUTS OFF
WITH MY TOENAIL CLIPPERS."
I SAID THAT?
THE DORK!
SHIT.
MADDY, SWEETHEART,
DID I SCARE YOU?
AH, NO, NO. GET IN HERE.
HI.
OKAY, UH... COME IN.
THANK YOU.
SPICA IN VIRGO.
A JUNE SKY.
HOW DID YOU GET HERE?
I CLIMBED.
NO. I MEAN, HOW
DID YOU FIND MY HOUSE?
YOU DROPPED THIS.
SORRY, IT'S WET.
IT'S OKAY.
UM, DO YOU HAVE A DRY SHIRT
OR SOMETHING?
I'M REALLY KIND OF WET.
YEAH, YEAH, SURE.
THANK YOU.
SO, WHERE DO YOU LIVE,
ANYWAY?
MOSTLY IN MY HEAD.
I'M JUST PASSIN' THROUGH.
THAT'S NOT VERY SAFE,
YOU KNOW.
I LOOK IN THEIR EYES.
IF I DON'T THINK IT'S SAFE,
I DON'T GET IN THE CAR.
HOW CAN YOU TELL?
IT'S A QUESTION
OF REALLY LOOKING.
MAD, PICK IT UP.
LOOK, I HEARD WHAT HAPPENED.
IS THAT YOUR BOYFRIEND?
WHERE ARE YOU?
JUST CALL ME.
I LOVE YOU.
HERE, UM, PUT THIS ON.
THANK YOU.
SO, WHERE
DO YOU GO TO SCHOOL?
DON'T.
I WAS THROWN OUT.
FOR WHAT?
FOR THINKING
FOR MYSELF.
SO, TELL ME ABOUT BUTTINGER.
IS THAT HIS NAME?
GOD, I HAVE NEVER DONE ANYTHING
LIKE THAT IN MY WHOLE LIFE.
I MEAN, RITA VALDEZ
ISN'T EVEN MY FRIEND.
NONE OF THOSE GIRLS ARE.
THAT'S... WHAT'S SO WEIRD.
WELL, SHE IS NOW,
FOR LIFE.
DO YOU MIND?
NO, NO, GO AHEAD.
- THERE'S SOME BEEF JERKY.
I CAN GET YOU SOMETHING?
- IT'S OKAY.
DO YOU MIND IF I SLEEP
ON YOUR FLOOR TONIGHT?
AH, YEAH.
ARE YOU SURE?
MM-HMM.
GOOD.
GOOD MORNING, HON.
YEAH.
ARE YOU GONNA EAT THAT?
I WAS THINKING ABOUT IT.
YEAH.
DID ETHAN STAY OVER,
MADDY?
NO, NO!
IT'S ONLY A GIRL.
WHO IS SHE?
SHE DOESN'T BELIEVE
IN STAIRS?
- WHO IS SHE?
- SHE'S MY DRUG DEALER.
I THOUGHT I LOST YA.
YOU KNOW,
I DON'T EVEN KNOW YOUR NAME.
SHE SAYS THE NEXT MORNING.
DON'T WORRY.
YOU'RE NOT MY TYPE.
OH?
WHAT'S THIS?
THAT'S MY ART STUFF.
IT'S A CAMERA. YEAH.
HMM. RIGHT.
LEGS.
WH-- WHAT ABOUT 'EM?
THAT'S WHAT PEOPLE CALL ME.
I VAULT WITHOUT POLES.
THAT SORT OF THING.
UM, WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
COME ON, YOU'RE GONNA FALL.
I'M NOT WATCHING THIS.
I'M NOT.
COME AND GET IT.
I'M AFRAID
OF HEIGHTS.
OH, HOW AFRAID?
ARE YOU THIS AFRAID?
DOES THIS SCARE YOU?
COME ON, LEGS.
IF IT WAS
THAT IMPORTANT TO YOU,
YOU'D COME GET IT.
- I WANNA PUKE! COME ON!
- COME ON UP HERE.
DANCE WITH ME.
NO WAY!
COME ON.
OH, BOY.
DON'T WORRY, I'LL GET IT.
DON'T WORRY.
LEGS?
DON'T! COME ON.
OH, GOD.
CAREFUL!
LEGS, IT'S NOT WORTH IT.
YEAH, IT IS.
NO!
YOU DON'T--
IT'S OKAY.
OH, GOD.
GIVE IT TO ME.
ALMOST. OKAY.
EASY.
IT'S OKAY.
YOU'RE A FRIGGIN' LUNATIC,
YOU KNOW THAT? GOD!
SO, IS THIS GOOD-BYE?
IT DEPENDS ON HOW MANY
BOTTLES I FIND.
FIGURE I NEED $50
BEFORE I MOVE ON.
NINE HUNDRED AND EIGHTY
BOTTLES TO GO.
I HOPE YOU DON'T FIND
ALL THE BOTTLES YOU NEED TODAY.
LOOK, THERE'S A HOUSE ABOUT
A HALF MILE OR SO UP THE RIVER.
IT'S ABANDONED.
IF YOU NEEDED A PLACE TO STAY,
I MEAN.
THANK YOU.
I GOTTA GO.
I'M LATE.
DON'T TAKE ANY SHIT.
HOW COULD YOU JUST DO THAT
AND NOT TELL ME?
BECAUSE IT'S NOT ABOUT YOU,
ETHAN.
WHY DIDN'T YOU GO TO MR. PARKS?
IF BUTTINGER DID THAT TO YOU,
PRESSED YOU AGAINST THE
BLACKBOARD, GRABBED YOUR BALLS,
WHAT WOULD YOU DO?
THAT'S DIFFERENT.
HOW?
IT JUST IS, MADDY,
AND YOU KNOW IT.
ALL RIGHT, I'D KICK HIS ASS.
WHERE WERE YOU LAST NIGHT?
I CALLED.
I PASSED OUT EARLY.
COME ON,
LIVE DANGEROUSLY.
WALK ME TO CLASS.
I'LL BE YOUR SUBSTITUTE
FOR THE NEXT FEW DAYS.
MR. BUTTINGER IS OUT
DUE TO A MINOR ACCIDENT.
AH, ARE YOU MADELINE WIRTZ?
YEAH.
YOU'RE WANTED
IN THE PRINCIPAL'S OFFICE.
THIS NOTE WAS INTERCEPTED
BETWEEN TWO STUDENTS IN CLASS.
IS THERE ANY TRUTH
TO IT?
IT SAYS WE BEAT UP BUTTINGER.
- THINGS GOT OUT OF HAND.
- SO IT'S TRUE?
- HE GRABBED ME.
- SO SHE BUSTED HIS NOSE.
- WHAT?
HE WAS SEXUALLY
HARASSING RITA.
AND YOU.
THIS IS A
VERY SERIOUS CHARGE.
DUH!
WHAT ARE YOU GIRLS?
SOME SORT OF A GANG HERE?
HMM?
GIRLS WHO RUN WITH FOXES?
THAT SORT OF THING?
SO YOU FIND THIS FUNNY.
OKAY. I AM GOING TO SUSPEND
YOU ALL FOR TWO WEEKS...
FOR YOUR CONDUCT
IN THIS OFFICE AND
FOR ASSAULTING A TEACHER.
I WILL HAVE YOU
ESCORTED OUT.
MR. PARKS, I NEED TO STOP BY
THE ART ROOM, PLEASE.
I DON'T THINK SO.
MY APPLICATION
GOES OUT TOMORROW.
YOU SHOULD HAVE THOUGHT
OF THAT BEFORE.
THAT ISN'T FAIR.
- TWO AND A HALF WEEKS.
- WHAT ABOUT MR. BUTTINGER?
YOU LEAVE THAT TO ME.
HE SHOULD BE FIRED.
THREE WEEKS.
WOULD YOU LIKE
TO KEEP GOING?
¶ UH-OH, WE'RE IN TROUBLE ¶
¶ SOMETHING'S COME ALONG
AND IT'S BURST OUR BUBBLE ¶
¶ UH-OH, WE'RE IN TROUBLE ¶
¶ GOTTA GET HOME QUICK
MARCH ON THE DOUBLE ¶
IT'S ALL MY FAULT.
YEAH, WHY DON'T
YOU KILL YOURSELF?
WHY DON'T YOU
JUST DROP DEAD?
SAVAGE WIT.
DON'T YOU GET DIZZY
CONSTANTLY LOOKING DOWN ON HER?
I CAN'T GO HOME.
MY PARENTS WILL KILL ME.
WE CAN GO TO MY HOUSE
AND WATCH TV.
TV SUCKS, MAN.
IT'S LAME.
I KNOW WHERE WE CAN GO.
MR. PARKS,
THIS IS RITA'S MOTHER...
AND I'M VERY CONCERNED
ABOUT THE SITUATION WITH RITA.
YOU DO A LOVELY MOMMY.
MAYBE YOU WILL CALL HIM FOR ME?
SURE. I'LL DO IT BETTER
ON THE PHONE.
GOOD.
WHERE THE FUCK ARE WE GOING?
I'LL CALL YOUR PARENTS TOO
IF YOU WANT.
YEAH, WHATEVER.
ISN'T THIS BEAUTIFUL?
WHOA!
BET IT'S HAUNTED.
I BET THE GHOST THAT I SAW
WHEN I WAS LITTLE IS STILL HERE.
YOU SAW A GHOST? REALLY?
I SAW A U.F.O.
DID YOU REALLY?
OH! WOW!
WHOA! THERE'S A TREE IN HERE!
WE CAN BUILD A TREE HOUSE.
SO, I HEAR
YOU GOT SUSPENDED.
YEAH.
FOR THINKING FOR MYSELF.
THEN CHEERS.
GET AWAY FROM ME!
I JUST FOUND IT.
WE ALL GOT SUSPENDED
TOGETHER.
MR. PARKS
IS SUCH AN ASSHOLE.
YEAH, HE WOULDN'T LET MADDY
GET HIS AR-- HER ART.
- IT'S MY PORTFOLIO.
IT HAS TO GO OUT TOMORROW.
- THEN WE SHOULD GET IT.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
I MEAN,
WE SHOULD GET IT!
WE SHOULD GO INTO THE SCHOOL AND
GET IT. IF THERE'S A UTILITY
HATCH ON THE ROOF OR BASEMENT,
WE'LL GO IN AND GET IT.
IF I GOT CAUGHT,
I WOULD BE IN SO MUCH TROUBLE.
- SHE TOOK THAT RISK FOR YOU.
- YEAH, I'M DOWN FOR A FELONY.
- A FELONY?
- THIS IS WAY RISKY.
WE COULD BE LIKE
DEAD GERBILS UP HERE.
THIS IS WHERE
THEY PUT THE BAD KIDS.
I DON'T BELIEVE--
I NEED TO GET
OUTTA HERE. IT'S NOT FUNNY.
WHERE'S THE THING?
WE'RE GONNA
GET LOST, WE'RE GONNA DIE.
HERE IT IS, HERE IT IS.
THANK GOD!
THIS IS SO WEIRD.
I CAN'T DO IT.
COME ON.
GOD, PLEASE
DON'T GO ANYWHERE WITHOUT ME.
WE'RE NOT GOIN' ANYWHERE.
WE'RE RIGHT HERE.
OH, FUCK.
IT'S OKAY.
RITA, YOU CAN DO IT.
OH, GOOD JOB!
GOOD GIRL.
SHH, SHH.
COME ON!
DON'T YOU LIKE FLASHLIGHTS?
I ALWAYS WANTED ONE
WHEN I WAS LITTLE.
HAND THIS TO VIOLET.
NOT LIKE
A NORMAL FLASHLIGHT.
LIKE THE ONE WHAT WOULD
SUCK UP THE DARKNESS
LIKE A VACUUM CLEANER.
SHUT UP ALREADY.
I GOTTA GET MY STUFF.
I ONLY KNEW HOW TO DRAW
ONE THING IN ART CLASS.
A PENIS!
OKAY, HERE.
CALM DOWN.
JUST PUT THE STUFF IN THERE.
ONE MORE. ONE MORE.
DID YOU HEAR WHAT
I SAID?
NO, WAS IT FUNNY?
OKAY, HERE IT IS.
OKAY, I GOT 'EM, I GOT 'EM.
I'VE GOT ONE MORE, THOUGH,
SO WAIT.
GREAT, OKAY.
I GOT 'EM, I GOT 'EM.
WHOA!
FRONT DOOR!
LET'S GO.
SEE IF YOU GET IT.
YOU GOT IT.
GOT ANYTHING?
NOT YET.
OKAY, I GOT YOU.
SHIT! THIS WAY, THIS WAY!
THIS IS SIMON.
THERE WAS A SMALL FIRE
IN THE ART ROOM. OVER.
YEAH, IT'S PROBABLY
A CHEMICAL REACTION
TO SOMETHING.
COPY THAT. OVER.
DID YOU SEE THAT?
I WONDER WHAT HAPPENED TO THEM.
I FOUND MORE CANDLES.
YOU AND YOUR FUCKING WEED.
YOU'RE A TEA HEAD.
WHERE WERE YOU GUYS?
WE NEED MORE CANDLES.
WHERE'D YOU GET
ALL THESE CANDLES?
LOOK, IT'S A SHRINE.
WHERE'D YOU FIND THESE?
WAS IT LAYING AROUND
IN THIS HOUSE?
WE'RE LIKE WITCHES HERE.
CRAZY SHIT.
THAT'S RIGHT.
OH, MY GOD.
WHOO.
WHAT ARE YOU DOIN'?
CHECK OUT HER POUCH.
I'M COMMEMORATING TONIGHT.
THIS IS SO
I'LL ALWAYS REMEMBER TONIGHT,
AND YOU, MADDY.
AND GOLDIE.
AND VIOLET.
AND RED.
¶ STILL ¶
¶ FALLING ¶
¶ BREATHLESS AND ALL ¶
¶ AGAIN ¶
FIRE?
BECAUSE IT NOURISHES,
AND ALSO DESTROYS
IF YOU DON'T RESPECT IT.
THAT'S HOW WE WERE TONIGHT.
¶ BESIDE ME ¶
¶ TODAY ¶
¶ AROUND, BROKEN IN TWO ¶
¶ 'TIL YOUR EYES CHANGE ¶
¶ INTO DUST ¶
¶ LIKE TWO STRANGERS ¶
¶ TURNING INTO DUST ¶
¶ 'TIL MY HAND SHOOK ¶
¶ AWAY A FEW ¶
DO IT TO ME.
¶ I COULD POSSIBLY
BE FADING ¶
¶ OR HAVE ¶
¶ SOMETHING MORE TO GAIN ¶
¶ I COULD FEEL MYSELF ¶
¶ GROWING COLDER ¶
HOLD STILL, OKAY?
DON'T BE SCARED.
¶ UNDER ¶
¶ YOUR FAME ¶
¶ IT WAS YOU ¶
¶ BREATHLESS, I'M TOLD ¶
¶ I COULD FEEL MY EYES
TURNING INTO DUST ¶
¶ AND TWO STRANGERS
¶ TURNING INTO DUST ¶
OW.
OH, MY GOD.
IS IT... DONE?
IT'S BEAUTIFUL!
I LOVE IT!
WE'RE LIKE THOSE GIRLS
WHO RUN WITH FOXES.
YOU'RE SUCH A GEEK!
WE'RE LIKE THOSE GEEKS
THAT RUN WITH FOXES.
I'M A RUNAWAY GEEK,
GODDAMN IT!
HEY.
WE'RE SUPPOSED TO DO
OUR PORTFOLIOS.
YOU FORGOT?
NO, I REMEMBER.
I JUST DON'T HAVE MINE.
IT'S NOT AT MY HOUSE.
WHAT'S UP?
HEY.
WHAT IS THIS?
IT'S A--
I GOT A TATTOO LAST NIGHT.
YOU'RE PISSED.
NO! I'M HAPPY THAT
YOU BEAT UP A TEACHER,
YOU GOT A TATTOO,
STOOD ME UP.
HIT YOUR HEAD
OR SOMETHING LATELY?
WHAT'S THE DEAL?
YOU SHOULD JUST DO
YOUR PORTFOLIO AND GET IT IN.
I'LL DO MINE ALONE.
HEY!
WE'RE HANGING OUT TONIGHT,
RIGHT?
OKAY.
WHY DO YOU KEEP DOIN' THIS?
WHAT ARE YOU,
SOME KIND OF FREAK?
WHAT IS THE MATTER WITH YOU?
DON'T YOU HAVE ANY RESPECT
FOR YOURSELF?
THIS ROOM LOOKS LIKE
A DRUG DEN.
I WANT THESE CANDLES OUT OF HERE
BEFORE YOU BURN THE HOUSE DOWN.
DAN, DAN.
WE'RE GOING TO BE LATE.
SO, WE'LL BE AT THE
MEDICAL CONVENTION IN MIAMI.
REMEMBER?
THE NUMBER'S ON THE FRIDGE.
DON'T FORGET TO FEED
THE BIRD, HUH?
OH, THERE'S A GIRL
OR WHATEVER TO SEE YOU.
HONEY, YOU WANT ME
TO STAY HOME WITH HER?
SHE'S 17. SHE'S OLD ENOUGH
TO TAKE CARE OF HERSELF.
¶ TAKING AWAY MY SOUL
MY SOUL ¶
¶ HEY, ENERGY SUCKER ¶
¶ I'M A GODDESS
NOT YOUR MOTHER ¶
¶ HEY ¶
¶ YOUR SOUL IS ¶
I GOTTA PEE!
WHAT'S THAT?
IT'S NOTHING.
IT'S A CUT.
WOULD YOU JUST GET OUT?
GET OUT. GET OUT!
GET DRESSED. WE'RE GONNA
BE LATE FOR SCHOOL.
I'M GETTING A RIDE...
WITH A FRIEND.
SHE DOESN'T HAVE
ANY FRIENDS!
MY STASH.
THAT SHIT CAN KILL YOU.
SO CAN ASPIRINS.
IT ONLY TAKES 60 ASPIRINS
TO KILL YOURSELF.
HEY. PUT THAT MONEY BACK,
YOUNG LADY.
FIRST YOU GOTTA TAKE
THE SAFETY OFF.
PUT IT BACK.
GO AHEAD.
PUT ME OUT OF MY MISERY.
IT WAS JUST A JOKE.
IF I HEAR ANY MORE SHIT
ABOUT 60 ASPIRINS OR ONE MORE
OF YOUR FUCKIN' MOOD SWINGS,
I'M GOING TO TICKLE YOU
TO DEATH!
DO YOU UNDERSTAND ME, HUH?
YES, MA'AM.
HEY, COME HERE.
HELLO?
COME IN.
DID YOU BRING YOUR LUNCH?
NO. HOW ARE YOU?
HI.
SOMETHING TO EAT?
NO.
I BROUGHT CHARLIE DEEN,
THE GALLOPING MACHINE.
WHOO-WHEE!
OH, MAN! FIGURES.
I GOT IT IN SECOND GRADE.
THIS I BROUGHT TOO.
I BROUGHT ANOTHER CANDLE,
BUT IT'S NICER THAN THE OTHERS.
THAT ONE'S MY FAVORITE.
I HAVEN'T DECIDED WHAT I
WANNA DO WITH THIS ONE YET.
WHY DON'T YOU JUST LEAVE IT
LIKE THAT? IT'S NICE.
I DON'T KNOW.
HEY! HEY! HEY!
YOU WILL NOT BELIEVE WHAT I GOT.
READ IT.
OPEN IT.
"DEAR VIOLET,
YOU DON'T KNOW ME.
"I'M ONLY A FRESHMAN,
BUT I FEEL LIKE
I OWE YOU MY LIFE.
"MR. BUTTINGER'S BEEN COMING
AFTER ME LATELY,
BUT HE WON'T ANYMORE.
"I WISH I COULD'VE
BEEN THERE.
"THANKS, THANKS, THANKS.
LOVE, ANONYMOUS."
FUCKIN' COOL, HUH?
YEAH.
¶ LET'S GET FUCKED UP ¶
¶ LET'S DO SOME STUFF
AND GET FUCKED UP ¶
¶ YEAH, TOMORROW WE'LL FEEL LIKE
WE'VE BEEN HIT BY A TRUCK ¶
¶ BUT LET'S GET FUCKED UP ¶
¶ GOIN' TO A COCKFIGHT ¶
¶ BURN, WITCH, BURN ¶
¶ ALL MY STUFF
IN HOCK MIGHT ¶
¶ NEVER EVER RETURN ¶
¶ GOIN' TO THE BRINK
OF OBLIVION ¶
¶ GONNA NEED A SHRINK
TO GET BACK AGAIN ¶
SO THIS IS HEADQUARTERS.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
WE HAVE A LITTLE PROBLEM,
GIRLS.
IT'S CALLED LLOYD BUTTINGER.
WHAT ABOUT HIM?
THIS NASTY RUMOR GOT STARTED
AND NOW THESE GIRLS ARE SIGNING
A PETITION TO HAVE HIM FIRED.
WOW.
WHAT'S YOUR POINT, DANA?
OUR POINT IS
YOU GIRLS STARTED IT,
SO YOU'D BETTER STOP IT.
OR, WHAT, BIG GUY?
OR YOU'LL BE FUCKING SORRY.
IF COACH BUTTINGER LOSES
HIS JOB 'CAUSE OF YOU SLUTS,
YOU'LL PAY.
SHUT UP, DANA.
THAT'S PRETTY BIG TALK, DANA.
YOU KNOW, VIOLET,
I WAS THINKING
ABOUT YOU LAST NIGHT.
THAT'S FUNNY, DANA,
'CAUSE I WAS THINKING
ABOUT YOU TOO.
OH, YEAH, THAT FUZZY
LITTLE HEAD OF YOURS
BURIED BETWEEN MY THIGHS...
JUST BLOWIN' AWAY
AT WHAT YOU LOVE BEST.
WHY DON'T YOU TELL ALL
YOUR FRIENDS HERE HOW MUCH
YOU LOVE THE WAY IT TASTES?
IN YOUR FUCKIN' DREAMS!
DANA, WHY DON'T YOU
AND YOUR LITTLE BOYS HERE...
RUN BACK TO COACH BUTTINGER
AND TELL HIM HE DESERVES
WHATEVER THE HELL HE GETS?
LET'S GO, MAN, COME ON.
SO, IS IT TRUE,
THE STUFF ABOUT BUTTINGER?
YEAH, IT'S TRUE.
HEY, BOBBY?
DO YOU KNOW RITA?
- YOU'RE IN MY FRENCH CLASS,
RIGHT?
- OUI.
OUI?
BOBBY?
I'LL SEE YOU AROUND.
BON SOIR, BOBBY.
GOOD NIGHT.
SEE YA.
I'M SUCH A HOPELESS ROMANTIC.
SO PERFECT.
SO GREAT.
OUI.
IT'S LIKE PANTYHOSE.
YOU HAVE TO UNROLL IT.
LIKE THIS.
OKAY?
YEAH, BUT AM I THE ONE
THAT'S GONNA HAVE TO ACTUALLY
PUT IT ON AND DO IT?
IT'S MORE FUN
THAT WAY.
WHAT ARE
YOU GUYS DOING?
TALKING ABOUT PENISES.
GOD! WHAT FLAVOR?
THIS IS CONDOM 101.
NOW, WE'LL GET INTO FLAVORS
NEXT WEEK.
HOW DO YOU KNOW A GUY'S GOT
A REALLY BIG... "SHLONG"...
BEFORE YOU ACTUALLY--
YOU GET AN EYE FOR IT.
OKAY, SMARTIE.
WHAT ABOUT--
NO, NOT HIM.
HIM.
THAT GUY OVER THERE.
HIM?
VIOLET!
STOP THAT!
THE GUY RIGHT THERE?
VIOLET! STOP IT!
BUSHEL OF POTATOES.
DOUBLE MEAT!
HOW DO YOU KNOW
IF A GUY'S GOOD IN BED?
BY HOW MANY TIMES
HE MAKES ME COME.
¶ DO YOU WANNA COME
INSIDE MY HOUSE ¶
¶ DO YOU WANNA SHOW ME THINGS
I'VE NEVER SEEN BEFORE ¶
¶ I DON'T WANNA TIE YOU DOWN
I JUST WANNA TIE YOU UP ¶
¶ DO YOU WANNA COME
INSIDE MY HOUSE ¶
I WROTE THAT MYSELF.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
I... THINK YOU NEED
TO GET LAID.
I KNOW.
I MASTURBATE, THOUGH.
AM I GONNA HEAR
ABOUT IT?
OH, IS OUR LITTLE BALD ONE
NOT FAMILIAR WITH THE ART OF...
AUTO... EROTIC...
EXHILARATION?
¶ SHE IS MY ADDICTION ¶
¶ SHE IS ADDICTED TO ME ¶
¶ SHE IS THE NEW CONNECTION ¶
¶ SHE IS CONNECTED WITH ME ¶
¶ HERE I GO
AND I DON'T KNOW WHY ¶
¶ I'LL STAY
SI, SI, SI ¶
¶ HER IDEA
HAS TAKEN OVER ME ¶
¶ I'M DANCIN' BAREFOOT ¶
¶ HEADIN' FOR A SPIN ¶
HEY, SMOKE MY DICK,
YOU FUCKIN' WHORES!
FUCK YOU, DICK!
STUPID REDHEAD.
GUYS, I'M AFRAID
OF HEIGHTS...
BUT I'M NOT AFRAID OF GETTING
HIGH.
I'M AFRAID OF AN ISLAND
WITH NO BOYS ON IT.
ARE YOU AFRAID OF ANYTHING?
I'M AFRAID OF LEGS
IN A DRESS.
I'M AFRAID OF MYSELF.
¶ SHE IS THE ESSENCE OF ME ¶
¶ HERE I GO
AND I DON'T KNOW WHY ¶
¶ I'LL STAY
SI, SI, SI ¶
¶ 'TIL I LOSE
MY SENSE OF PRIDE ¶
¶ I'M DANCIN' BAREFOOT ¶
¶ HEADIN' FOR A SPIN ¶
I HAVE BEEN OUT ALL NIGHT...
LOOKING FOR YOU.
GET IN THE CAR.
THE SON--
LEGS, IT'S OKAY.
NO, IT'S NOT.
WHO'S AUDREY?
A FRIEND.
AUDREY'S MY MOM.
HOW?
IN A CAR.
SHE WAS DRUNK.
I'M SORRY.
YEAH, ME TOO.
DO YOU HAVE A DAD?
YEAH,
SOMEWHERE I DO.
MADDY, I'M THINKING
ABOUT MOVING ON
IN A COUPLE OF DAYS.
TO WHERE?
TO WHEREVER.
SOMEWHERE.
DO YOU HAVE
TO GO ALONE?
AH, WOULD YOU TAKE SOMEONE
WITH YOU?
IS THAT SOMEONE SURE?
HMM? IS SHE CUT OUT
FOR THE UNKNOWN?
SOMETIMES THE UNKNOWN
WILL DISAPPOINT YOU.
IF I TOLD YOU THAT
I LOVED YOU, WOULD YOU
TAKE IT THE WRONG WAY?
WHAT DO YOU MEAN
BY "WRONG"?
IT'S JUST THAT
I'M NOT--
AND YOU'RE--
HMM. GEEZ.
I'LL TAKE IT
HOWEVER YOU WANT ME TO, MADDY.
HMM. HMM.
HMM. LOOK.
YOU CAN SEE SPICA
IN VIRGO.
SUMMER'S ON ITS WAY.
MADDY.
HI.
CAN I TALK TO YOU?
I'M SCARED.
DANA AND I
GOT IN THIS FIGHT...
AND HE STARTED PUSHING ME
AND HITTING ME.
I TOOK OFF ON HIM, BUT, UM,
HE'S OUT LOOKING FOR ME.
AND I'M SORT OF SCARED
TO WALK HOME ALONE.
WHY'D YOU COME HERE?
YOU GUYS JUST SORT
OF HAVE THIS REPUTATION.
I WAS KIND OF HOPING
YOU'D HELP ME OUT.
THANKS FOR DOING THIS.
IT'S NO BIG DEAL.
I'D DO IT FOR ANY GIRL.
YOU GUYS REALLY MESSED UP
BUTTINGER.
YOU KNOW,
THEY FIRED HIM.
HE DESERVED IT.
I KNOW.
BUT DANA SAYS
IT'S ALL BULL.
"DANA SAYS.
DANA SAYS."
GOD, CINDY,
GET A MIND OF YOUR OWN!
MADDY, I CAN GO THE REST
OF THE WAY ALONE.
IT'S OKAY.
LAUREL'S NOT FAR.
YEAH, BUT--
YOU SHOULD GO HOME.
WHAT'S GOIN' ON?
WE'LL TAKE OVER
FROM HERE, BABE.
LET'S JUST FORGET IT.
- WHY DON'T WE GO FOR A RIDE?
- YOU WATCH TOO MANY
CORNY MOVIES.
YEAH? WE THINK YOU GIRLS
ARE GETTIN' A LITTLE
TOO BIG FOR YOURSELVES.
OH, YEAH?
WHAT ARE YOU GONNA DO ABOUT IT?
WHAT YOU'VE BEEN WANTING
ME TO DO FOR A LONG TIME.
CINDY KNOWS YOU HAVE.
THAT'S WHY SHE'S COMIN'.
SHE'S A WITNESS.
ONE GIRL'S WORD
AGAINST ANOTHER.
MAYBE THIS IS
JUST A BAD IDEA.
WE'RE JUST GONNA FUCK AROUND.
WHY DON'T YOU GET IN THE CAR?
OOH, WE GOT A FIGHTER HERE.
GET HER IN THE CAR.
FUCK OFF! CINDY!
WHAT DO YOU WANT ME TO DO?
STOP IT! GET OFF ME, DAMN IT!
FUCK YOU! LET ME OUT OF HERE!
LET HER OUT!
TELL THEM TO LET HER OUT,
YOU STUPID FUCK.
LET HER OUT.
COME ON,
GET OUTTA THE CAR.
GET OUT!
LEGS, GET IN.
GET IN. LET'S GO.
GO!
DAMN!
IT'S MY FUCKING CAR!
I CAN'T DRIVE!
YOU GUYS, SHIT!
JESUS CHRIST!
HOLD ON!
OH, GOD! OH, GOSH!
GOLDIE, GO OVER
TO THE RIGHT.
HAVE A NICE WALK,
BOYS!
WHAT SHOULD WE DO
WITH THE CAR?
KEEP IT.
WE DESERVE IT.
AFTER ALL
OF OUR HARD WORK?
SHIT, MAN.
HEY!
COME HERE!
GET IN!
WHAT'S GOING ON?
WHAT'S UP?
- MADDY ALMOST GOT RAPED,
AND WE STOLE THIS CAR.
- WHAT?
OH, MY GOD!
I CAN'T BELIEVE
WE'RE DOING THIS!
LEGS, YOU'RE CRAZY!
WHERE ARE YOU TAKING US?
¶ IT'S NOT WHAT
YOU'VE BEEN TOLD ¶
¶ THERE'S NOWHERE
WE WON'T GO ¶
WHAT'S A BEAUTIFUL GIRL
LIKE YOU DOIN' RACIN'
IN A PLACE LIKE THIS?
- WINNING.
WINNING.
WINNING. WINNING.
- OOH, SHIT! RED LIGHT!
- WHOA!
EXCELLENT!
YES!
- SO WHERE'RE WE GOIN'?
- TO THE BEACH.
LET'S GO TO THE BEACH.
- COPS! LIGHTS ARE ON!
- OINK! OINK!
LEGS, WE CAN EXPLAIN THIS.
- LEGS? LEGS!
- SHUT UP!
LEGS, WHAT'S UP?
TALK TO ME, COME ON.
LEGS, TALK TO ME.
I DON'T LIKE
POLICE STATIONS.
CARJACKING.
RESISTING ARREST.
ASSAULT WITH
A DEADLY WEAPON.
YOU GIRLS FELL IN
WITH A BAD ELEMENT.
I HOPE YOU'VE LEARNED
FROM IT.
I'M GOING TO TURN YOU OVER
TO THE CARE OF YOUR PARENTS.
THEY, BETTER THAN I,
KNOW WHAT'S BEST FOR YOU.
DON'T LET ME SEE YOU
IN HERE AGAIN.
NOW, MARGARET SADOVSKY.
I THINK SOME ADULT GUIDANCE,
SUPERVISION...
COULD BENEFIT YOU TOO,
YOUNG LADY.
- BECAUSE YOU HAVE NO LEGAL
GUARDIAN-- IS THAT RIGHT?
- YES.
AND BECAUSE YOU APPEAR
TO BE THE MOST CULPABLE
OF THE DEFENDANTS...
AND HAVE
A PREVIOUS RECORD,
I HEREBY SENTENCE YOU
TO SIX MONTHS TO A YEAR AT
A YOUTH CORRECTIONAL FACILITY.
NO!
NO, YOU CAN'T
DO THIS.
BE QUIET.
YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND. SHE WAS
JUST TRYING TO PROTECT ME.
THAT'S ENOUGH OUT OF YOU!
NO! WE'RE TELLING THE TRUTH!
YOU'VE GOT IT ALL WRONG.
THEY'RE THE ONES THAT LIED.
THEY LIED! THEY LIED!
CINDY, GODDAMN IT!
TELL THE TRUTH! THERE'S NO
JUSTICE!
WATCH YOUR MOUTH
IN MY COURTROOM.
FUCK YOUR COURTROOM!
YOU WON'T GET AWAY
WITH THIS!
IF SHE GOES,
WE ALL GO.
YOU WON'T! LEGS!
DON'T TAKE ANY SHIT.
NO DATES.
NO BOYS.
YOU HEAR ME?
MAYBE SHE'S BETTER OFF,
MADDY.
LOOK,
SHE'LL BE OKAY.
¶ MMM, YOU ¶
¶ IT'S FOR YOU ¶
¶ ONLY YOU ¶
¶ I DON'T EVEN KNOW
I'LL NEVER CARE ¶
¶ I'LL NEVER BUG YOU
MY PEOPLE, I'LL TELL YOU ¶
¶ WHAT I SAY ¶
¶ I'LL NEVER LIE, I'LL NEVER TRY
I'LL NEVER CRY FOR YOU PEOPLE ¶
¶ I'LL PUSH YOU
PUSH YOU AWAY ¶
¶ YES, YOU LONELY PEOPLE ¶
¶ KEEP ON RUNNIN'
'ROUND MY DOOR ¶
¶ YES, YOU LONELY PEOPLE ¶
¶ KEEP ON BEGGING
BEG FOR MORE ¶
¶ AND I'LL TRY FOR YOU
YES, I'LL DIE FOR YOU ¶
¶ PAIN IN MY HEART
AND IT'S REAL ¶
¶ AND I'LL TELL YOU NOW
HOW I FEEL INSIDE ¶
¶ FEEL IN MY HEART
IT'S FOR YOU ¶
¶ IT'S FOR YOU ¶
¶ ONLY YOU ¶
¶ I'LL NEVER TRY
I'LL NEVER DIE ¶
¶ I'LL NEVER PUSH FOR YOU PEOPLE
I'LL TELL YOU HOW I FEEL ¶
¶ I'LL NEVER LIE, I'LL NEVER CRY
I'LL NEVER TRY FOR YOU PEOPLE ¶
¶ I'LL TELL YOU
YES, IT'S REAL ¶
¶ AND YOU LONELY PEOPLE ¶
¶ KEEP ON PASSIN'
TIME AWAY ¶
¶ YES, YOU LONELY PEOPLE ¶
¶ KEEP ON PASSIN'
PASS AWAY ¶
¶ AND I'LL TRY FOR YOU
YES, I'LL DIE FOR YOU ¶
¶ PAIN IN MY HEART
IT IS REAL ¶
¶ AND I'LL TELL YOU NOW
HOW I FEEL INSIDE ¶
¶ FEEL IN MY HEART
IT'S FOR YOU ¶
¶ BUT OH
I CAN'T NO MORE ¶
¶ I DON'T WANT IT NO MORE ¶
¶ I DON'T WANT IT NO MORE
IT'S FOR YOU ¶
YOUR HONOR, WE HAVE NEW EVIDENCE
TO BE BROUGHT BEFORE THE COURT.
I'D LIKE TO REQUEST A RECESS
TO CONSULT WITH MY CLIENT.
THE COURT IS IN RECESS
FOR AN HOUR AND A HALF.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
JUDGE HOLIFIELD?
YES?
I NEED TO TALK TO YOU
ABOUT SOMETHING.
YES?
UM... I LIED.
HI. CAN I PLEASE
SPEAK TO RITA?
RITA'S NOT ALLOWED
TO COME TO THE PHONE.
THANKS ANYWAY.
MADDY?
YEAH, MOM.
THERE'S SOMEONE HERE
TO SEE YOU.
HI.
GIRL, WHAT'RE YOU DOIN'
IN MY HOUSE?
I DON'T KNOW WHAT
YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT.
I'M AT THE LIBRARY.
OH!
BYE, MOM.
BYE.
WOW!
THIS PLACE IS GREAT!
PULL UP A CHAIR.
WHAT ARE YOU DOIN'?
YOU'LL SEE.
COME ON, BE HERE.
OH, YEAH.
"I PUT MY HAND
IN HIS POCKET--"
"NEVER WANTED MORE
THAN A ROCKET!"
IT'S RED!
MADDY, IT'S RITA!
YEAH, UH-HUH.
CAN YOU TALK TO HER?
HOLD ON.
"BEEN EATIN' ANY MEAT...
AND POTATOES...
LATELY?"
YOU BIG SLUT!
CAN I JUST--
YEAH, TALK TO HER FOR A WHILE.
I GOTTA DO SOMETHING.
I DON'T THINK SO.
OKAY. THAT.
HELLO.
CAN I SPEAK
TO GOLDIE, PLEASE?
GOLDIE ISN'T HERE.
WHO IS THIS?
MADDY WIRTZ.
- IS THAT HER DAD?
- GOLDIE HASN'T BEEN HOME
IN TWO DAYS.
IF YOU SEE HER,
YOU TELL HER TO GET HOME.
WHAT?
MADDY, WHAT'S HAPPENING?
GOLDIE RAN AWAY.
I'M LOOKIN' FOR GOLDIE.
YEAH?
AND WHO ARE YOU?
TELL ME WHERE SHE IS.
GOLDIE, GET UP.
GOLDIE, COME ON, GET UP.
LET'S GO. COME ON.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
ALL RIGHT, ALL RIGHT.
IF I EVER CATCH YOU
NEAR HER AGAIN,
I WILL FUCKING KILL YOU!
COME ON.
COME ON, GOLDIE.
GET OFF ME!
WE SHOULD STAY WITH HER,
MAKE SURE
SHE DOESN'T TRY TO LEAVE.
LEAVE ME ALONE, MADDY!
I CAN'T STAY HERE
ALL NIGHT. I HAVE TO GO HOME.
LEAVE ME ALONE!
WE'LL TAKE TURNS, OKAY?
MAYBE SHE'S HUNGRY.
I, I HAVE SOME CHOCOLATES.
I DON'T WANT THIS.
GET OFF ME!
WHAT DO YOU WANT?
YOU KNOW
WHAT I WANT.
HERE'S SOME PUDDING.
I CAN'T.
FUCK YOU, MAN!
FUCK YOU!
YOU KNOW THAT I CAN'T.
GET THE FUCK AWAY
FROM ME, THEN.
EVERYONE LEAVE ME ALONE!
LEAVE ME
THE FUCK ALONE!
WE DON'T KNOW
WHAT TO DO.
MAYBE WE SHOULD CALL A DOCTOR.
NO, IT'LL JUST
GET HER IN TROUBLE.
GET OUT OF HERE.
I'LL STAY WITH HER TONIGHT.
IT'LL BE ALL RIGHT.
GET THE FUCK OUT!
I'LL STAY.
IT'S OKAY.
FUCK!
WE SHOULD GO.
I'LL WALK YOU HOME.
LEAVE ME ALONE!
MADDY,
I'LL BE BACK LATER.
FUCK.
IN LINE!
LEGS?
SHIT! YOU GUYS!
OH, LEGS!
OH. HEY, LADY.
HI.
OH, THANK GOD
YOU'RE BACK.
HI.
WHAT'S WRONG?
IT'S GOLDIE.
WHAT?
SHE'S UPSTAIRS.
SHE'S SICK.
OH.
HOW LONG HAS SHE BEEN
LIKE THIS?
TWO DAYS.
SHE THROWING UP?
SHE WAS.
LEGS, WHAT'RE WE
GONNA DO?
YES?
WE'RE HERE
ABOUT GOLDIE.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
I MEAN, WHERE IS SHE?
SHE'S IN TROUBLE.
WE NEED $10,000 FROM YOU
TO HELP HER.
SO WHAT IN THE HELL
HAS SHE DONE NOW?
IT'S FOR REHAB.
GOLDIE HAS
A DRUG PROBLEM.
- WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
- SHE'S SICK.
YOU TELL ME WHERE SHE IS
AND I'LL TAKE CARE OF HER.
NO, I THINK
YOU'VE DONE ENOUGH.
I DON'T KNOW
WHO YOU THINK YOU ARE,
BUT I'M HER FATHER.
- DIDN'T THEY SEND YOU AWAY?
- FUCK YOU!
GET OUT OF MY HOUSE!
NO, NOT WITHOUT
THE MONEY.
- WHERE IS SHE?
- NO.
- MAYBE YOU'D LIKE
TO TELL THE POLICE.
- WHY DON'T WE CALL THE POLICE?
WHY DON'T WE CALL THE POLICE
AND TELL THEM
WHAT A LOUSY FATHER YOU ARE?
AND THAT THEY SHOULD
LOCK YOU UP
FOR BEATING YOUR DAUGHTER.
WHAT?
I NEVER BEAT HER.
IS THAT WHAT SHE TOLD YOU?
STOP... BLAMING HER
FOR EVERYTHING!
YOU GONNA GIVE US THE MONEY
OR NOT?
I WANT YOU, YOU AND YOU
OUT OF MY HOUSE.
NOW!
I'M CALLING THE POLICE.
PUT THE PHONE DOWN.
PUT IT DOWN!
YOU GIVE US $10,000 RIGHT NOW
OR YOU'RE COMING WITH US.
- PUT THE GUN DOWN.
- OR WHAT, MADDY?
IT'S NOT LOADED.
WHAT KIND OF ASSHOLE
WOULD KEEP A LOADED GUN
IN THE HOUSE?
- WAIT!
- NO! NOT UNTIL HE GIVES ME
THE MONEY!
COME ON.
SHIT. GET THE KEYS, MADDY.
PICK THEM UP
OFF THE TABLE.
MADDY--
PICK THEM UP, MADDY, NOW!
COME ON, LET'S GO.
- GIRLS, PLEASE.
- MOVE! YOU MOVE!
MADDY, DRIVE.
LET'S JUST TALK
ABOUT THIS.
GET IN THE FUCKIN' CAR.
ALL RIGHT.
LEGS, WE CAN'T DO THIS.
WILL YOU JUST DRIVE?
THIS IS CRAZY!
DON'T CHOKE ON ME,
MADDY!
YOU DON'T HAVE TO OBEY HER,
MADDY. YOU CAN PULL
THE CAR OVER.
SHUT UP!
JUST DRIVE TO THE HOUSE.
WHAT ARE YOU GONNA DO WITH HIM?
DON'T KNOW.
DON'T WORRY ABOUT IT.
MADDY!
MADDY?
- SHIT! I'M GONNA PULL OVER.
- NO, YOU'RE NOT!
I WON'T PRESS CHARGES.
I SWEAR.
I WILL KILL YOU.
I DON'T CARE.
OK-- O-OKAY.
LOOK, WE'RE JUST GONNA
CALM DOWN. OKAY?
I'M JUST GONNA DRIVE.
GET OUT!
WHAT ARE WE GONNA DO
WITH HIM, LEGS?
JUST GET IN.
WHERE'S GOLDIE?
SHE'S IN HERE.
SHE'S AWAKE.
GO UPSTAIRS.
COULD I HAVE SOME HELP?
MADDY SAYS IT'S OKAY.
LET'S GO!
CAN YOU MOVE?
WHAT THE FUCK HAPPENED?
SIT.
COME ON, SIT.
HELP ME TIE HIM UP.
COME ON!
TAKE YOUR SOCKS OFF.
RED, GIMME YOU HAND.
YOU'LL BE OKAY.
I'M JUST GONNA THINK.
OKAY?
HOLD IT ON HIM.
TALK TO ME.
TELL ME WHAT YOU'RE DOING.
WE'RE GONNA CALL HIS WIFE
AND MAKE HER DROP OFF THE MONEY.
- RANSOM?
- THAT'S KIDNAPPING!
THAT'S JUST A WORD, MADDY.
DON'T LET IT SCARE YOU.
YOU'RE WHAT'S SCARING ME.
I'M JUST TRYING TO MAKE HIM DO
THE RIGHT THING.
- NOT THIS WAY.
- HOW?
- HE BROUGHT THIS ON HIMSELF.
- HE IS NOT THE POINT!
WE ARE!
GOD--
WE'RE THE ONES
WHO LIVE HERE.
THEY'RE GONNA FIND US.
AND WHEN THEY DO,
WE'RE THE ONE'S
WHO ARE GONNA PAY FOR THIS.
LIKE LAST TIME?
HUH?
COME ON. THIS IS--
THIS IS FOR GOLDIE.
THIS IS ABOUT
SAVING HER LIFE.
AND WHO WE ARE
TO HER.
IT'S ABOUT WHO WE ARE.
- YOU'RE DOING IT WRONG.
- YEAH? WELL I DON'T SEE YOU
DOIN' IT RIGHT.
THIS IS CRAZY!
THERE'S GOTTA BE ANOTHER WAY
TO GO ABOUT THIS.
- SO WHAT IS IT, RED? HMM?
- I DON'T KNOW WHAT IT IS.
YEAH? YEAH, WELL,
I'M OUT OF IDEAS.
COME ON, LEGS.
I WANT HIM
TO SEE GOLDIE.
HE DOESN'T GIVE A SHIT
ABOUT GOLDIE.
HE'S HER FATHER!
LEGS, SHE'S RIGHT.
YOU KNOW WHAT?
FATHERS MEAN NOTHING!
THEY DON'T CARE.
THEY MEAN NOTHING.
LEGS, THIS ISN'T
ABOUT YOU.
MAYBE HE'LL COME THROUGH
FOR HER THIS TIME.
WHAT THE FUCK
IS GOING ON?
- SOMEONE CALL AN AMBULANCE!
- DAD!
WHAT'S HE DOING HERE?
VIOLET, UNTIE HIS HANDS.
HE'S GONNA BE OKAY.
GOLDIE, IT'S OKAY.
IT WENT CLEAN THROUGH.
WE HAVE TO STOP
THIS BLEEDING.
HE'S OKAY.
IT WENT CLEAN THROUGH.
OH, SHIT!
RED!
IT WAS AN ACCIDENT.
THE GUN WENT OFF.
IT'S MY FAULT.
LOOK AT ME!
OKAY?
IT'S MY FAULT.
GOLDIE,
HE'S GONNA BE OKAY.
WE'VE GOTTA GET HIM OUTTA HERE.
CAN YOU TAKE THE GIRLS OUT?
NO WAY!
- I'LL TAKE CARE OF HIM.
- I'M NOT LEAVING YOU.
NOBODY'S LEAVING.
LET'S GET HIM TO A HOSPITAL.
READY?
ONE, TWO, THREE.
UP! UP!
YOU'RE GONNA BE OKAY.
I GOT HIM.
EASY, YOU GUYS.
PUT YOUR WEIGHT ON ME.
HEAR ME?
UH-HUH.
EASY. EASY.
WHERE ARE YA?
I'M HERE.
GOLDIE,
ARE YOU THERE?
DAD, I'M HERE.
DR. GOLDMAN,
I'VE GOT YOU.
DOWN THE STAIRS.
EASY, YOU GUYS.
EVERYBODY
JUST SLOW DOWN.
EASY.
KEEP HIM STEADY, VIOLET.
KEEP HIM STEADY.
DAD,
IT'S OKAY.
ALL RIGHT. WHOA!
CAREFUL, CAREFUL.
WATCH HIS HEAD.
I GOT HIM.
ARE YOU IN?
OKAY, MOVE OVER.
I'M DRIVING.
WHERE'S LEGS?
SHUT IT.
WE'VE GOT
TO GO!
OKAY, GO!
GO!
LEGS?
LEGS!
LEGS.
WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
YOU DON'T HAVE TO GO.
STAY WITH US.
WE'RE YOUR FAMILY.
DO YOU WANT TO GO
WITH ME?
I'LL TELL YOU WHAT.
I'M GONNA DO THIS, OKAY?
AND WHEN A CAR STOPS,
YOU WON'T EVEN HAVE TO THINK
ABOUT IT.
YOU'LL JUST KNOW
AND YOU DECIDE.
AND YOU JUST DO
WHAT FEELS RIGHT
IN YOUR HEART. OKAY?
I'LL NEVER FORGET YOU.
YOU'RE IN MY HEART,
MADDY.
GOLDIE'S DAD CLAIMED
HE SHOT HIMSELF.
IT WAS JUST STUPID ENOUGH
THE POLICE BELIEVED IT.
HE GOT GOLDIE INTO REHAB,
WORKED THINGS OUT WITH HER
EVENTUALLY.
I'VE TRAVELED SINCE.
HALF THE WORLD.
ART MUSEUMS, BUS STATIONS,
AIRPORTS.
I'VE NEVER SEEN LEGS AGAIN.
THE REST OF US,
WE'VE DRIFTED.
BUT WE EMBRACE WHEN WE MEET,
VETERANS OF A SORT,
BOUND TOGETHER FOR LIFE.
¶ YOU CAN COME BACK
WHEN YOU WANT ¶
¶ JUST KNOW
THAT I'LL BE HERE ¶
¶ I HAVEN'T LEFT THIS STEP ¶
¶ AND WHEN THE LIGHTS GO OUT
I PICK THE ANGEL UP ¶
¶ I ONLY HAVE TWO HANDS ¶
¶ IS SHE HERE ¶
¶ IS SHE HERE RIGHT NOW ¶
¶ DRIVE HER OFF
DON'T BOTHER TO CALL ¶
¶ I'M CHECKING OUT TODAY ¶
¶ ME AND MY CHARMS ¶
¶ WHEN I KISS THE ANGEL ¶
¶ I HAVE A TASTE OF YOU ¶
¶ WHEN I TAKE THE ANGEL ¶
¶ I HAVE A PIECE OF YOU ¶
¶ I HAVE A PIECE ¶
¶
¶ YOU CAN COME BACK ¶
¶ I HAVEN'T LEFT YOU YET ¶
¶ AND WHEN THE LIGHTS GO OUT
I PICK THE ANGEL UP ¶
¶ I ONLY HAVE TWO LEFT FEET ¶
¶ ALL I HAVE IN MY HANDS ¶
¶ ME AND MY CHARMS ¶
¶ WHEN I KISS THE ANGEL ¶
¶ I HAVE A TASTE
OF ME AND MY CHARMS ¶
¶ ME AND MY CHARMS ¶
¶ DOWN ON THE GROUND ¶
¶ YOU CAN'T LEAVE ME NOW ¶
¶ I HAVEN'T LEFT YOU YET ¶
¶ YOU CAN COME BACK
WHEN YOU WANT ¶
¶ JUST KNOW THAT
I'LL BE HERE ¶
¶ I HAVEN'T LEFT THIS STEP ¶
¶ AND WHEN THE LIGHTS GO OUT
I PICK THE ANGEL UP ¶
¶ I ONLY HAVE TWO HANDS ¶
¶ IS SHE HERE ¶
¶ IS SHE HERE RIGHT NOW ¶
¶ DRIVE HER OFF
DON'T BOTHER TO CALL ¶
¶ I'M CHECKING OUT TODAY ¶
¶
¶ ME AND MY CHARMS ¶
¶ WHEN I KISS THE ANGEL ¶
¶ I HAVE A TASTE OF YOU ¶
¶ WHEN I TAKE THE ANGEL ¶
¶ I HAVE A PIECE OF YOU ¶
¶ I HAVE A PIECE ¶