Still in bed?
It's 7 a.m., Max.
Can we get a dog?
Have you seen your room?
Do you want to add a dog
to this whole bazaar?
But one day can we?
I just answered you.
You can't even
take care of your room,
let alone a living being,
let's not talk about it.
The report has been on
Neretin's desk since yesterday.
The meeting is at 10 a.m.
Have a good day !
Do your dishes.
I'm leaving now.
As you know,
my nanobots
are able to grow
and change shape
on command.
Whether to block
a virus that is constantly evolving ...
or to create an organic firewall
to counter hackers ...
or to provide protection
for databases that contain
top-secret information ...
Nothing and no one is more reliable
and efficient than my nanobots.
When will
the field tests start ?
I will be ready
in a few days.
The data will follow
soon after.
Consider your funding to be extended.
Don't celebrate victory too quickly.
We are not sure
that nanobots
adapt as quickly to real conditions
as they do in theory.
Sorry, may I come in?
Come in.
I hope you have a good excuse.
Watch where you walk, loser.
Enough, both of you.
Focus on your textbooks.
Complex nanotechnology.
which can transform endlessly,
the ultimate hacker.
It exists !
And should that interest me?
It can infiltrate
security systems.
It's a
kind of technology ...
alive,
like mercury.
It can hack into banks,
stock market prices ...
This is serious.
Go get Gecko.
The lake is asleep,
just like the forest and the reeds.
As the willow creaked ...
Where's the willow?
Sleep! Sleep!
I had wonderful dreams,
cloaked in white.
In their silver case rested
sparkling stones.
On a carpet
made of grass and flowers ...
I was sleeping,
my breathing
lifted my chest ...
Have you lost your mind, you moron?
Are you drawing my girlfriend?
What is this ?
I will teach you a lesson about staring.
Hold this!
... pure and sparkling white.
The silent and tender stars
fell from the heavens ...
What is going on ?
Skoryk!
Are you trying to set the school on fire?
To the principal's!
Come on, my little ones.
To bed.
I hate
new technologies.
They will send me
straight to a museum.
No museum will want you.
You talk too much.
Sweet dreams my particles
I could easily break
into the laboratory, but ...
this safe ...
It's a state-of-the-art,
fireproof vault
with 5 cm steel walls
and an advanced alarm system.
At that level, I can not guarantee anything.
No...
No, forget your guarantees.
Refresh my memory,
why are you working for me
Because I am the best.
No.
The real reason, clever boy.
That is what I thought.
So bring me those nanobots.
He was drawing all night again ...
And dirty dishes, as usual.
Sorry, darling,
but you can't have a dog.
LOGIN
PASSWORD
The system is ready.
Alert...
Stop !
Don't move.
Strange ...
I do not know this brand.
Did you do that ?
Yes...
Cool.
Your tag is really ... excellent.
Thank you.
Did you hear that?
You're cool !
An idea came to my mind.
What if we separated ...
from our business partners?
All the serious players
have switched to cryptocurrency.
It's a virtual currency,
online
You just have to find
a way to extract it.
A perfect mission for nanobots.
I am a genius !
As promised...
It's empty.
What do you mean ?
What is this thing ?
Where are the robots?
Everyone will know
the name of Myron.
Everyone will respect me.
And will be afraid of me.
With these nanobots,
I will finally have the power!
Read and sign, please.
So, did we do something stupid?
Now you will definitely be handed over
to the the museum!
Shut up you stupid tin can.
What happened?
I did not see anything.
Skyba.
Yes.
A burglar
broke into the lab.
Security agents
chased him, but he escaped.
The police are viewing
the video surveillance footage.
I'm sure it will help us
find our robots.
Or at least the
one who stole them.
No.
These are my nanobots.
My creations.
I know
how they think and operate.
I will find them on my own.
What happened here?
How clumsy you are!
Is that your case?
I said
that new technologies
were a source of trouble.
They are easy targets for theives.
I should hire him
as a security consultant ...
What is that ?
A pulse neutralizer.
It detects
electromagnetic waves,
it can deactivate
any device
and separate nanobots.
Put them in immobility mode,
or turn them off.
Encoding completed.
COMPLETED
Given my budget, I think
my only option is theft.
Theft: taking possession
of the property of others
Society: punished by law
Buddhism: bad karma
Christianity:
ass thrown into the flames of hell
Hey, kid!
Are you stealing from me or what?
Thief !
Alert: nanoactivity located.
Well...
That's weird ...
They could have repainted
over it.
Why would anyone do that ?
It's a work of art!
Hello.
Your brain is producing an excess
of cortisol and adrenaline,
which is increasing
your heart rate.
How can you be here?
You have to calm down.
Start by breathing.
Do like me.
He seems to confuse
breathing and singing.
Maybe I should have begun
artificial respiration?
Can I help you ?
I need to see
the pictures from the last hour.
Are you from the police?
No.
Then I must ask you to leave.
Thank you.
Extracting
surveillance data .
DOWNLOAD
I must be hallucinating ...
To answer your question
about my presence here,
it's simple:
you created
me by spraying me out of the canister
in the form of graffiti.
But it was just paint.
False.
I am made
of microscopic nanobots.
You wanted paint,
so I changed.
You wanted to paint a robot dog,
so I became a robot dog.
I am programmed
to serve my creator.
Your creator?
You created me, Max.
You said I was cool.
Wait ...
So the fight at school ...
It was you
who fought you with my bag?
Your hypothalamus sent
a signal to your nervous system
which I interpreted
as a desire to beat them.
And I helped you a little ...
Wait, and at the store ...
At the store I kept you
from committing a crime
to avoid bad karma
and your ass being thrown
into the flames of hell.
By the way
what is "ass?"
That is what you used
instead of your head!
Not only
do I no longer have any pens,
but I'm going to be in trouble
with this bully, Dan.
- Hide.
- To hide...
is to make sure
that you can't see me anymore.
I can do that.
"Invisible" mode activated.
Hi Dad.
Sorry,
I have an urgent call to make.
Which of us
is more invisible?
The "invisible" mode is working.
Where are you ?
In here ?
Bizarre ...
I really did hallucinate.
Drawing contest.
The grand prize :
one year of training
at Levram Studios.
Today is the last day
to submit your application.
I have no chance of winning ...
So what's the point of trying?
Hey, kid!
Are you stealing from me or what?
What are you making,
my little robots?
Your coffee.
- Thank you.
- Enjoy.
Alert!
Nanoactivity located nearby.
There you are...
UPLOAD
Hi.
This is a cool place you have here.
Say ...
I'm looking for the tagger
who signs like this.
Doesn't ring a bell.
Nope.
Can we play ?
Max !
You created a dog.
So let's do
human-dog activities!
According to my analysis, the park seems to be
full of popular activities.
Max...
But ... you disappeared yesterday.
My "invisible" mode?
You told me to hide.
- Do you want us to go to the park?
- Yes.
- Like that?
- Like that what?
Did you look at yourself?
I thought
you made me look cool.
Yes, it's true.
You're cool.
- It's just that ...
- My tail?
What's wrong
with my tail?
Nothing, let me finish.
It's just that you don't look ...
like a real dog.
I think I understand.
You want me to look
like a real fox terrier, right?
- Exactly.
- No problem.
It is true ?
You can do that?
Yes.
Can we play now?
Yes, we can play.
But we would need a leash.
No problem, Max.
Behave like a real dog.
You promised me.
Anything you want, Max.
My information was correct,
activities at the park
are fun!
Are you crazy or what ?
Don't speak in public!
Someone is going to have
a heart attack.
You think ?
I have an idea.
Max, put this on.
Max, Foxter, here, over ...
So ?
- Very good !
- You're telling me.
Max, what are they doing?
What strange and irrational behavior !
Don't worry, it's nothing.
This is how
dogs greet each other.
Go on, get to know them.
Okay.
So...
Let's see, how to do this ...
Okay.
Sorry to bother you ...
Well.
This is really weird.
Max, something's wrong.
Nobody wants to play with me.
Just like me at school ...
Did you sniff their backside?
Yes.
It's your smell !
You don't smell like a dog.
You are smart!
For a human.
I'll reproduce
the olfactory molecules ...
It worked, Max!
Hello sir...
Nice to meet you.
This is really cool, Max!
It's great to be a dog.
You should try.
You have to
clean up behind me.
I won't touch your poop.
But that is part of the role
of a dog owner!
I don't have a bag.
Use your hand.
They are not even real.
Come on, Max.
- Go on ...
- It's okay.
Come on, Max, pick them up.
Come on !
And here is
an extraordinary discovery:
the very first flying poop!
Make
sure it's mine ...
I've got you !
It looks like mine.
Max ?
What is that ?
Nothing special.
Oh, how cute!
Is this your dog ?
Yes it is.
My REAL dog.
From muzzle to tail.
She's nice...
What is his name ?
Foxter.
His name is Foxter.
Sonia !
We're going to the Art Platform.
See you later.
Bye, Foxter.
Bye, bye
So Max, I perceive
a large secretion of dopamine!
And your serotonin level
is exploding.
Shut up.
It appears that you like her.
I have no chance with her.
Maybe you should
sniff her behind?
It could work.
Max, I have the impression that
relationship problems between humans
are due to their lack of tails.
Why are you so sure you don't
have a chance?
Because she already has
a boyfriend, Dan.
What is a "boyfriend Dan"?
A bully who spoils my life.
She told you
she was going to the Art Platform.
According to my information,
it's a place
where young humans go
to spend
their parents' money.
So what ?
So what...
I may have an idea.
An idea ?
I can't believe it.
Nanobots
have turned into dog.
They are programmed to take
the form of the desire of their master.
If this boy wanted a dog,
that would explain everything.
The most amazing thing is that the dog
seems to lead, not the boy.
It means
that the
artificial intelligence module is working.
No I do not know him.
Hello?
What are you doing ?
I'm investigating.
Do you think you are Sherlock Holmes?
- Look, I'm trying to ...
- Are you trying ?
If I don't get
the nanobots today,
I'll fold you into a small package ...
and I ship you to Timbuktu.
It is very far.
Got it?
What are we doing here?
You will see.
Trust me.
Weird, why do I have the
urge to catch these bubbles?
Max, look,
she's in the crowd.
Is that boy sick?
The one who making
the weird movements?
He's dancing.
I see ...
And wouldn't that be Dan the bully?
This funny behavior
begins to please me.
- Let's move on.
- Hold on.
Congratulations to the winner
of this battle!
Give him a hand!
I analyzed
what captivates the girls.
I know how to
get her attention.
We need a quiet place.
Did you know, your haircut is
called a "bowl cut".
The rest,
you don't need to know.
Children's problems
are so complex.
Here. This is good.
What is your plan?
No, no...
Why not.
Here.
Cool.
Yep!
And the final touch ...
That's it.
According to fashion blogs,
you officially look cool.
Are we going to perform funny movements?
What is he drawing?
Is that you ?
Hi.
Hello.
Ah yes...
So you know the DJ?
That's cool.
If that's the case,
you must know everyone?
So what ?
Maybe you know whose tag this is?
Here,
Is the loser in trouble?
Where is he ?
Give me your phone.
I would love to see the massacre.
Here is his name and address.
Tell him Dan sent you.
That works.
That's it.
It's over for that loser.
That's cool.
Okay, then ...
Okay, well ...
By the way...
Are you the one...
who drew that?
Yes it was me.
- That's wonderful.
- Oh, Wow !
Bye
So that's one of those famous "hugs!"
They are known to be proof of affection.
They are much better
than sniffing the hindquarters.
Did you just make a joke?
I don't know, was it any good?
The nanorobot-dog is learning
to take care of others.
My mom doesn't want me to
have a dog,
then go...
Switch to "invisible" mode.
And now ?
I think we should
tell him the news.
Do it yourself.
It's because of your work
that we have to move.
Max has no friends here
anyway.
A new school ...
Calm down.
Obviously,
it's easy for you!
"No friends?"
You didn't even
ask me for my opinion.
What am I, too much baggage?
A stain on on your pants?
Don't be cheeky.
You don't care about me.
Either of you.
- Hold on.
- Go!
I will be better off without you.
Max.
Max !
No!
Pavlo !
Call an ambulance !
Please!
He could have saved him.
Why didn't he do it?
Boss.
What do you want ?
Answer when I call you.
What is that ?
A handful of nanobots.
Long story, short,
nanobots
took the form
of some kind of super dog.
And then it vanished.
And that's all that was left.
It stinks.
What do we do with it?
Let's ask our scientists
to analyze them.
Yes...
I have an idea.
Have them analyzed.
We will reproduce them en masse.
Tons at a time.
Excellent plan.
Yes.
It's a great plan.
Napoleon!
The test results
are correct.
He can come return in two days.
What do you mean, "evaporated?"
When did you last sleep?
It doesn't matter.
The nanobots have learned
to control their environment.
Impressive, but
Gearz Robotics management is growing concerned.
Are you covering for me?
As long as I can.
How is dad
He had surgery.
Doctors say
he will pull through.
Excess adrenaline
and bile is indicative
of great emotional stress.
- Why didn't you help him?
- Help him?
I saw everything.
You were running fast, you could have
pushed him off the road.
But you wanted to run away!
I only helped you, Max.
Help me ?
My father is in the hospital.
I thought you were my friend
but you...
Do you know what you are?
Max...
Well...
I do not understand.
What do
you mean you can't reproduce them?
It is almost impossible
to reverse-engineer nanotechnology.
And it's also almost impossible
to survive my fist,
but you can try.
- How long will it take?
- A year or more.
A year?
- Where is the boy ?
- What boy ?
You told me about a kid.
Go and get him.
He is just a child.
You work for me.
You do not have a choice.
Your father owes me a debt.
You owe me.
The kid doesn't know anything.
He made a dog
out of nanobots.
Go and get him.
You understood ? Do it.
Go on!
Follow him.
Madame Skoryk?
Hi, son.
Come closer.
You look even worse
than me!
It's my fault.
Max...
I'm
just a freak of nature,
a design flaw.
If you want to move,
then let's move.
I do not care.
I will draw new friends.
You were right,
we should have consulted you.
We won't leave
if you don't want to.
Everybody makes mistakes.
Honey...
Max !
You know, Foxter,
everyone makes mistakes.
It is true.
I'll try to explain it to you.
I know you were trying
to help me run away.
Okay.
I was running away because I thought
Dad wanted to get under my skin.
Is that so ?
What did he want to do
with your skin?
Nothing,
it's just an expression.
Okay.
I ran away,
but I didn't really want to.
Ah!
I don't understand, explain it to me.
Sometimes humans do things
they don't want to do.
But why ?
Well,
imagine you like a girl
and then you pretend
to ignore her.
Why ?
To get her attention.
Humans are
strange creatures without logic.
But hey,
I was created to obey you.
No.
You should make
your own decisions.
When a car is about to
hit a human,
we don't care
what i want.
I should have saved the human?
Obviously!
Human life
is much more important
than my little moods.
I see.
We don't care,
I have to make decisions,
life is more important
than states of mind.
- That's it ?
- Pretty much.
You're cool.
- You too.
- High five !
Max, look!
Sonia?
What are you doing here ?
I heard about your father,
I decided to come.
Honestly...
I'm very happy to see you.
You came...
without Dan?
Well...
He invented the story
that I was his girlfriend,
but
I think he's a moron.
You are not allowed
to park here.
So move it ...
You little smart-ass.
Can you imagine yourself in this car?
Can you imagine us,
both
on an endless highway ...
extending to the horizon?
- Max ...
- That would be great.
Tell her that you can drive.
- Leave me !
- What?
Sit behind the wheel,
I'll drive.
She will be impressed!
You know, I can drive.
It is true ?
You're crazy ?
After all, he asked me
to move his car!
Try to look natural.
How are you going to start it?
Put your hands on the wheel,
tell her
you have magic fingers
and press the button.
Well ...
I have magic fingers.
Let's go.
And now ?
This toy will show us
what it is capable of.
And who are you?
This beauty has horse-power!
Take that !
That was Dan!
Did you see that ?
When did you learn to drive?
And like that ?
This is crazy.
It's ... not that difficult!
I didn't
think you were that cool.
Dating site tip: give
her a compliment.
Thank you.
You are cool too.
Really cool, chick!
Great advice ... thank you!
I am beginning to get tired of you ...
VOICE COMMAND
4x4 black: 0808-AI.
Owner of the vehicle
sought by Interpol.
There are people behind us.
We should let them pass.
Are you ok?
What came over you?
We almost died.
I told you not to
take my orders literally!
How can you be so stupid?
Sonia.
It's not what you think.
You didn't just yell
at your imaginary friend?
No ! I yelled at my dog.
Actually, he is not really a dog.
He's a top-secret super robot.
OUT OF SERVICE SYSTEM RESTART
Are you ok?
No, I'm fine.
I'm from the police.
I would like to see your license,
but I suspect
you don't have one.
This car is not yours,
is it?
My friend asked me
to move it for him.
I know you have something else
that doesn't belong to you.
I'm not sure I understand.
You know what ?
You will accompany me to the station
and everything will become clearer.
We prefer to walk, thank you.
Do I have to drag you there by force?
That isn't a police car.
Keep moving.
Emergency mode ...
Mode...
Do not worry.
I am a friend.
I didn't
mean to cause an accident.
I was trying to slow down
those chasing you.
Who are you ?
Let's say it was I
who gave birth to you.
You can trust me.
He took Max and Sonia.
I was unable to help them.
My nanoconnections
are very weak.
You have to help me
find the kids.
Sorry,
my program
tracks nanobots.
It is unable
to locate people.
Max wears an earpiece.
I made it
from nanobots.
Where is the dog ?
Let Sonia go.
No no no...
What would you want
with such a flea bag?
It doesn't concern you.
He stayed at the hospital.
I personally intend
to snatch him ...
Paws,
tail
and ears.
I will rip it ...
to pieces !
You will no longer recognize him.
Then I will use nanobots
to conquer the world.
Like Napoleon.
If the dog is not at the hospital
as you said...
Let us just say that it is of
interest to you that I find it.
What are you hiding from me there?
Give me that.
Right now.
Soon the city will be mine.
I am on the verge
of realizing my childhood dream.
If the owner of this building
kidnapped them,
Then our chances
are pretty slim.
Is your "invisible" mode still working?
Yes, it works.
But it has bugs because the
nanochannels are interrupted.
It's incredible.
I still can't get over it.
The kids are inside,
we should call the police.
We cannot intervene on our own.
I'm going to record
everything you see.
I will send the pictures
to the police.
You are a
very intelligent human specimen .
Thank you.
I lied.
Foxter is in the car,
not in the hospital.
Foxter,
is that the robot they talked about?
He can make himself invisible.
So it was him that you were yelling at.
How is that possible ?
What is he exactly ?
Some kind of nanorobot, I think.
He can turn
into lots of different things.
He's fantastic.
Can he drive a car?
Yes.
He can drive. Not me.
I'm not cool.
I am a loser.
That's not true.
Nobody would have stood up
to this man like you did.
You really have to be
very brave.
Thank you.
So brave guy,
How are we going to get out of here?
Hi guys.
Have you seen Arcan?
He went out.
He's here, grab him!
INVISIBLE MODE
SYSTEM ERROR
He's there !
- What's the matter ?
- It's that thing!
Get up !
Move!
Help me !
You are useless !
Catch it!
It's over.
Now let's have some fun.
Why won't the robots
change shape
without the kid's order?
They use
their owner's code .
If you want them to obey,
you will need a good hacker
and it will take time
to reformulate all the encoding.
I see.
I have a hacker.
You will do it.
No.
No?
I do not know this word.
I can reformulate it for you:
I will never in my life do such a thing.
I created these robots
for a good cause,
not for you.
Good...
So in three seconds,
the lady will discover
the joys of aerobatics.
One!
Two!
- Three!
- Stop it!
Yes !
We can't give Foxter to them.
You can't imagine
what they want to do.
I have a plan,
but I need help.
What is that ?
No idea,
but she neutralized
the car electronics.
It could be useful.
Good game plan.
How should I encode
robots?
What what do you want them to do?
I want them to turn
into an unstoppable computer virus,
barrier-proof,
to steal cryptocurrency
and to have them obey my orders.
Once I have
all the money I want,
I can go anywhere.
I will be the master of this city.
I will control all the computers.
Everyone will obey me
and be afraid of me.
Nanobots will be
my secret weapon.
At this moment,
no one will dare
to disrespect me.
I get it.
The cylinder must first be removed.
Glass blocks the signal.
Okay, but don't try anything.
Or I'll reduce you to molecules.
Remove the cylinder.
First I must turn off the system ...
Something has to be done.
We are not programmed
to oppose humans.
ACCESS DENIED
Why is it taking so long?
Reprogram this pooch for me!
Max...
Come here.
Do you remember when you said
that I had to make
my own decisions?
I don't want to become a
weapon in the service of this psychopath.
I made a decision,
but I need your help.
Max,
you have to order me
to disintegrate.
To disintegrate?
I can't do that.
Afterwards, you will no longer be my Foxter.
I will always be with you.
It was you who created me.
Be strong.
We will always be together.
I promise you.
I will have you all!
I am sorry...
Disintegrate.
Go get the car.
The cops know
you kidnapped the kids.
And...
I sent a video to the media
showing them the scumbag that you are.
You're screwed.
Find a landline phone.
Call my helicopter!
Max, remember:
I am you
and you are me ...
Are you stupid ?
You are nothing without your little dog!
Let her go!
I would play all day with you,
but I have to go.
Come on!
Get over here!
It's time to leave!
Throw me the ladder!
Max !
Let her go!
You want her?
No problem !
You go, Max.
You are the hero of your universe.
Remember :
I will always be with you.
WIND -
WEIGHT SIZE - DISTANCE
CHUTE
I will break you.
We will see.
Sonia !
Can you teach her to fly?
Look out !
My hero...
Let's go home, my little ones.
I'm sorry about your dog.
He was cool.
He was a true friend.
Yes, he truly was.
Momma !
Max !
Max! You are alive !
How are you ?
You gave us quite a scare!
Come on, we're going home.
Hi.
Hello.
You know,
Gearz Robotics has a bright future.
I really need
a professional
to strengthen
our security system.
Are you interested ?
- Max, can you get the door?
- Hush ...
I have a letter for Max Skoryk.
Here.
It's the contest.
I won the drawing contest!
And a year of training
with a real artist!
That's great.
I didn't know
you entered.
Neither did I.
Congratulations!
Take it, this is for you.
Just for you.
Hi, little fellow!
What are you doing here ?
What are you going to call him?
Me ?
If you can bring down
the city's worst criminal,
I think that you are responsible
enough to have a dog.
So what is his name going to be?
Foxter.
His name is Foxter.
I'm good with Foxter.
It's okay with me.
Come on, Foxter,
We will make you
a real dog!
Subtitles by Theriot@Theriot2020