NARRATOR: The Pentagon,
Washington, DC,
heart and nerve center
of our national defense.
Swamped by the gigantic task
of classifying, assigning and
recalling thousands of soldiers,
man has turned to the machine.
Take the process
of recalling reserve officers.
Department of the army
classification cards
for several hundred
military personnel
may be placed
in the classification machine,
and in the space
of a few seconds
the person best suited for a
specific assignment will be selected.
Once the officer is selected,
the recall procedure
is swift and unerring.
Oh, uh...
Tommy, you got
anything there for me?
Yeah. Here's a telegram,
Mr. Stirling.
Telegram?
I hope there's nothing
wrong with Aunt Ethel.
She's not feeling very well.
Yeah?
Oh, good!
It's not from Aunt Ethel.
It's from Washington. DC!
Gee, who do you know
in Washington?
Oh, connections, connections.
Well...
Hey, I won't go! I won't go!
Bad news, Mr. Stirling?
(STUTTERS) I... I'm a retread!
You're a what?
A retread! (STAMMERING) The Army,
they're calling me back in the Army.
Gee! Are things that bad?
Yeah, I...
Well, they can't do this to me!
They can't do this to me!
If they want me, they're gonna have
to come and get me, that's all!
They're gonna have to come and get me...
(ALARM BLARING)
...No, I won't go!
You wait and see!
You... They won't...
They won't take me! Ha!
You wait and see. I won't go!
(RATTLING)
(HORN BLARING)
(BELL TINKLING)
(MALE VOICE SINGING)
(SINGING)
Hey, Francis! Francis!
It... It's me! Francis! Francis!
(FRANCIS HUMMING)
Hey, Francis!
Hey, Francis, it's me!
It's me, Petey!
Uh... Hey, wait, wait!
Don't... Don't go away!
Wait! Wait!
Francis, I...
Well, I'll be darned!
I could've sworn
you were Francis!
Why, you're not even a mule!
Do you always talk to horses?
Huh? Oh, no, sir,
just the mules.
My bags! My bags! Hey, wait!
Wait! Help me to stop it!
(GROANING)
I... I beg your pardon, sir.
I really, I...
I'm terribly sorry, sir.
(STAMMERING)
I had no idea that you...
That... No, really.
Really, sir...
Why, you're not a sir.
You're a lady.
Fortunately for you.
I... I mean, you're a WAC.
Oh, well... Well, anyway,
I beg your pardon, madam.
Uh, young lady, uh, Captain...
All right, Lieutenant,
you got your laugh.
Uh, but, no, really, I...
That's the prettiest soldier
I've ever seen.
CONDUCTOR: Board!
My bag! Wait.
Porter! Porter! Uh...
Oh! (SIREN BLARING)
Oh! Oh, it's you again!
And your aim is getting better.
Oh, thank you!
I mean, no. No, no.
Well, what I mean is,
well, you see,
the door was closed, I had
to get my bag off somehow.
On my head?
Well, I didn't know it was your head.
Besides, I...
Hey, wait a minute! Hey,
stop the train, will you?
Wait a second!
(SHRIEKING)
Oh!
Oh. (EXCLAIMING)
I'm... I'm very
sorry, madam. I...
Are you all right, Captain?
Oh!
Oh, fine! Just fine!
Now, really, just...
Just an accident!
Really, I... I'm
terribly sorry, madam.
I mean, young...
(STAMMERING) Captain,
I'm really...
I'm very sorry. I...
Oh!
Now, really, I... At
ease, Sergeant, at ease.
Okay, Lieutenant. Okay.
I saw the whole thing.
Well, then you know
it was an accident.
Sure, but you gotta leave the girl
some pride, Lieutenant, some pride.
Corporal McDonald will take care
of your transportation, Lieutenant.
Well, thank you. Oh, uh,
my luggage, though. I got...
Oh, we'll get it, if that WAC
captain hasn't chewed it up.
You're the prettiest soldier
I've ever seen.
Oh!
Ahem!
Just a minute, ma'am.
Uh, I was told I could
get transportation to...
Well, now, please, don't crowd in.
The lady's first.
What happened to her?
Where'd that WAC go? What WAC?
Look, I'm Lieutenant Peter Stirling.
Do you mind?
Yes, sir. Here you
are, Lieutenant.
All in one piece.
He, uh, wants transportation.
KREUGER: Well, give it to him.
Lieutenant, give these to the
jeep driver behind the station.
He'll take you to your outfit.
Thank you.
I thought I'd seen everything.
Papers seem to be in order.
Washington sent him.
George or Martha?
Being transferred in.
PETER: "Off Limits."
Must be a highly
secret assignment.
Sure must be!
All right, sir.
This is it, Lieutenant.
Thank you very much.
I wonder what kind
of work it is.
It shouldn't be hard to take.
Hmm, that's quite
a large female personnel.
Small ones, too.
All sizes. (GROWLS)
Uh...
This organization, is it, uh...
(STAMMERING)
Oh, no, couldn't be.
Is something bothering
you, Lieutenant?
Huh? Well it looks
like a WAC area.
It should. It is.
Oh, is that so?
The WACs! Me in the WACs!
Now, what's...
What's going on here?
(STAMMERING) Now you wait here!
I'm gonna find...
Good afternoon, Lieutenant.
Sightseeing?
I would like some information.
My name is Lieutenant Stirling.
What?
Oh.
For a minute there you had me.
We were expecting
someone by that name.
A camouflage expert.
Well, my name is Stirling,
but, uh, I don't know
anything about camouflage.
Of course, it's not you. You're
Lieutenant Peter Stirling.
Yes, that's right.
We were expecting
a Bunny Stirling,
who is a camouflage expert.
Oh, I see.
May I talk to your
commanding officer, please?
OFFICER: Yes?
Lieutenant Stirling has arrived.
Oh, wonderful! I'll be
with her in a minute.
"Her"?
I told you we were expecting
a Lieutenant Stirling.
Yeah, but not me, you weren't!
Welcome to the WAC.
(GASPS) (MUTTERS)
(MUTTERS)
Anything wrong?
Well, there seems
to be a mistake, Major.
Mistake? What do you mean?
Did the new officer report in?
That's her.
Him.
He?
He's not a she!
Oh. (CHUCKLES)
Good afternoon, Major.
Would you mind stepping
into my office, Lieutenant?
What's going on, Captain?
I was about to ask
that same question.
He's your retread,
Major Simpson.
He?
Lieutenant Stirling.
"Peter Stirling."
Now I understand why our
retread wasn't on that train.
A terrible mistake
has been made.
They sent us a... A man?
Good heavens, I certainly
stipulated I wanted a WAC officer!
I guess the words "overseas
experience" confused them.
Make out a request for transfer
and get him out of this area.
Check Post Headquarters.
They can put him up
until we get rid of him.
Yes, Major.
Well, Lieutenant.
How does it feel to be a WAC?
Now just a minute, this...
This is a mistake!
Uh, isn't it?
I'm afraid you don't quite
fit our physical standard.
Well, naturally not.
A man in the WACs.
What do you mean by that?
Uh, I just meant it's funny, that's all.
The WACs.
If there's anything
funny about it,
it's some of you men
who make it so.
Despite your amusement,
we prefer to think
of women in uniform
as a serious business.
Yeah, but, I didn't mean...
Your masculine ego
refuses to admit that...
That the Women's Army Corps
can serve any place
but in kitchens or for clerical work!
Isn't that so?
I didn't say that.
That's what you meant!
Lieutenant Stirling.
For the moment, you've
been assigned to us.
Thinking it over,
it might be very nice to have
a man around the company.
Yeah, well...
Yes, yes, to help us
helpless women.
As a hardened combat vet,
you'll no doubt put us
poor women to shame,
but, uh, we'll try
to keep up with you.
Now, now, now, really, sir.
I, uh, madam.
I, no, Captain, I think...
I think the WACs are wonderful.
They're... They're just
wonderful in their place.
In our place!
Yes, in your place,
I think you're just...
(DOOR OPENS)
Yes, Corporal Hilstrom?
Post billets
are all filled, ma'am.
Well, Guest Bungalow Six
is unoccupied.
You can put him in there.
Uh-oh. Uh-oh, what
does she mean, "uh-oh"?
Is anything wrong?
No, ma'am, not yet.
But it's a start.
(STAMMERS) What did she mean?
Need I explain? Uh-huh.
Well, Lieutenant, in the
course of your duties with us,
you'll be in contact with
the women of this battalion.
You will avoid any incident.
Uh, incident?
Oh, good heavens, Lieutenant,
you had combat in Burma.
Weren't there any
Burmese girls there?
Oh, yes, yes. They
used to sell us things.
I can imagine. Yeah, uh-huh.
I used to take some
of them home with me.
You did? Oh, yes.
The cutest little wood carvings.
You know, in those little...
Little monkeys that...
You may go now, Lieutenant.
Oh, thank you very much.
Oh, uh, where?
You will be assigned the
duties of a WAC officer.
You mean, I'm a WAC?
Until you've had a change
of assignment, yes.
(STAMMERING)
Dismissed! I just...
Well. A WAC. (CHUCKLES)
Fancy earmuffs.
What am I doin' in the WACs?
MALE VOICE: That's
a logical question.
I... Who said that?
Your old, furry cousin.
1000 pounds of loveable mule
on the hoof. Mmm-hmm.
Well, Francis!
Francis! It couldn't be!
Says you. Well, then it
was you on the train!
Yeah.
Boy, am I glad to see you!
Lieutenant, please!
What kind of an indoctrination
are they giving you?
Oh, I'm in terrible trouble.
Well, that figures.
Me, Peter Stirling, in the WACs.
I'm in and they
won't let me out!
(STAMMERING) I don't
wanna be a WAC!
Oh, simmer down, Petey
boy, that's why I'm here.
I heard the
classification machine
at the Pentagon went snafu
and tapped you for duty
with the ladies
of the Army Corps. Well...
Oh, so that's how it happened?
And it only could happen to you.
Yeah. Yeah, well, you did
come to get me out?
What a fate! Wet nurse to
an upper-class shavetail!
For this I had
to get myself transferred
to the medical research
lab on this post.
I'm checkin' in in the morning.
Oh, that's wonderful!
Wonderful? Yeah!
They needed a guinea pig
to try their injections on.
So, shake hands
with the guinea pig. Me.
Oh, I'm sorry, Francis.
Yeah, but you are gonna
help me out, aren't ya?
Well, I won't be able
to sit for a while
and I hate to stand around
doing nothing.
Oh, thanks, Francis.
Thanks a million!
Oh, Pete, cut that out!
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
What's that? Shh!
(WHISPERS) Sounds like
retreat to me.
For you.
Oh, uh, excuse me. Is there,
uh, is something wrong?
We heard voices. You are
supposed to be alone.
Oh. Well, there's
no one here but me.
That's what we were told.
Oh, uh, believe me,
there's no one in it!
What about this?
There's no one in that, either.
Now, if... If I need
you, I'll call you.
I will. I'll call you.
Francis? Francis! Oh.
(CAR WHIRRING)
That's Bungalow Six, Lieutenant.
Thanks, Sergeant.
But are you sure the OD
didn't say Quarter Six?
She said six something.
I'll worry about it tomorrow
when I'm not so sleepy.
Good night.
Oh, I'm sorry if I disturbed you.
I thought... (GASPS)
(SCREAMING)
Please, don't... Don't scream!
(SCREAMS) Please,
please, don't scream.
What are you doing here?
I really am very sorry. I...
(SCREAMS) Shh!
Help! Help! I... Help!
(SCREAMS) I'm sorry.
(DOOR OPENS)
Alone, huh?
Now... Now I know
what you're thinking,
but it's not so. Honestly!
You'd better come with us.
Get dressed.
Now... Now I know
what you're thinking!
But it's not so, honestly!
Now I know what you're thinking,
but it's not so, honestly.
You can wait outside. I'll
get your report later.
Now I know what you're
thinking, but it's not so...
Lieutenant, I want the truth.
Now, really it was...
It was nothing!
Nothing? Yes.
Two incidents in one night?
Your first night here?
Well, now, believe me, I...
Uh, two incidents?
What was... What was
the first one?
Then you admit
there was a second?
Uh, yeah, no, ma'am.
I just thought
the second one
was the first one.
Well, we won't discuss
the order of your romances.
You were distinctly heard
speaking to someone
before Lieutenant Dickson arrived.
Who was the other girl?
Uh, it wasn't any girl.
It had to be a girl.
There are hundreds of them
stationed in this area.
Nothing but girls.
Not one girl was in my bungalow.
Not... Not one.
What about Lieutenant Dickson?
(STAMMERS) Well, I was
there before she was!
That didn't give you the privilege
of making advances to her.
(STAMMERING) Why, I didn't.
Why, I didn't.
Don't tell me, she screamed
because you didn't make advances.
Yes, ma'am. Uh, no, ma'am!
(STAMMERS) I don't know
what I mean!
If your motives were so pure,
why didn't you
immediately contact the OD
and notify her of the mistake?
Well, I couldn't. The lieutenant
was getting undressed.
You... You saw her undressing?
No, ma'am. I shut my eyes.
Then how do you know
she was getting undressed?
(STAMMERS) I don't know!
I... I just thought she
might be, that's all, I...
(STAMMERS)
Well, uh, you gotta...
You gotta take your clothes
off to get into bed, don't you?
I... Now I'm all confused.
I shouldn't wonder.
Lieutenant Stirling, your records
arrived here this afternoon.
They were very interesting.
Need any help, toots?
What did you say?
Hmm? I... I didn't say anything.
If you get stuck, you can spend
the night with me in the stable.
Lieutenant, you must fancy
yourself a veritable Don Juan!
Who? No, no, not me!
I know your type, Lieutenant.
You get into trouble and try to
talk yourself into a psycho ward.
You've been in trouble before.
Twenty-seven times in
neuro-psychiatric retention!
That's really gold-bricking.
Well, I tried to tell 'em...
I can see right here what
you tried to tell them,
that a mule talked to you.
They didn't believe me.
And neither would [!
So don't pull any of that
mule hanky-panky around here!
Yes, sir. I mean, no, sir.
I mean, yes, ma'am!
For lack of clear-cut evidence,
I will not press charges
against you
but let me make
one thing quite plain,
until you are transferred out,
you are a WAC officer!
You will think as we do
and do as we do.
Everything? Everything!
(TRUMPET BLOWING)
(ALL GIGGLING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
WOMAN 1: Come on! Come on!
WOMAN 2: Come on,
we gotta play...
SERGEANT: One, two, three!
One, one, one, two, three!
One, one!
One, two, three!
Platoon, halt!
Ma'am, C Company is formed.
Extend to the left. March!
Uh, good morning, Captain.
I'm supposed
to report to Company C.
The Second Platoon leader is ill.
You may fall in there.
(ALL GIGGLING)
There?
Fall in.
You are at attention.
Lieutenant Burke,
take over, please.
Yes, ma'am!
Prepare to exercise! Move!
Lieutenant.
Lieutenant! Prepare to exercise.
Move!
(ALL SNORTING)
Our first exercise
is the double
arm swing and leg lift.
Leg lift.
Exercise begins!
Forward, and lift!
And two, and right!
And three, and left!
And four.
Our Don Juan doesn't look so
Don Juan-îsh in the morning.
Oh.
This certainly isn't going to help the
morale of your Second Platoon, Jane.
Oh, that
wouldn't matter, Louise.
Maybe it would be better
to drop the Second Platoon
out of the camouflage
operation entirely,
rather than risk their
making a bad showing.
We can't go in
with just two platoons.
General Kaye and all of G3 know
we've been training a full
company in camouflage.
How would it look
if we admitted failure?
Our cause would be lost
before we started.
Three and four!
And five and six!
And seven.
And eight, and... (GROANS)
What's the matter,
Lieutenant, out of condition?
Yeah. No, an old back injury.
Looks as if a new one
has been added.
BURKE: And four!
Well, you see, when I
took my basic training,
we didn't have to be acrobats.
Oh, I see. You men went in for
the rugged things, no doubt.
Oh, yes. Obstacle course and
that sort of thing, you know,
scale that wall,
jump that hurdle and...
And climb that landing net...
You mean Confidence
Course, Lieutenant.
We WACs don't use it.
Yeah, well, it is
pretty strenuous.
It wasn't meant for women.
BURKE: And...
I'm sure the women
would appreciate it
if you'd show them
how it's done sometime.
Fine!
Maybe I could even get a
few volunteers to help you.
Wonderful. Uh, me?
Yes, you, Lieutenant. Fall in.
BURKE: And four, and five,
and six, and seven.
(ALL GIGGLING)
(WHISTLE BLOWING)
(ALL CHEERING)
We'll show him!
(WHISTLE BLOWING)
(ALL CHEERING)
(ALL GASPING)
WOMAN: Come on, get up!
Get up quick! Yeah!
FRANCIS: Attention!
Fall out!
(EXCLAIMING)
(FRANCIS LAUGHING)
Swimming at this hour of the morning?
Come here!
Francis, I...
Hey, Pete, come here!
On the double!
Francis, that was a dirty trick!
Oh?
What are you doing here?
Haven't you reported in yet?
Yeah, but how I gotta
figure a way to get out.
Yeah, me too.
They've been cutting me to pieces
all morning! (MULES BRAYING)
Oh? What are you
looking at, Pete?
Francis? Yours? Huh?
Flatterer. (CHUCKLES)
Come here, cousin.
Come here. What?
Do you know what Major
Simpson's pet project is, huh?
No. Camouflage!
Camouflage, that's a man's job.
Uh, since when?
Every beauty parlor is a
camouflage installation. Yeah.
Well, I never thought of that.
Neither did General Kaye!
General Kaye? Uh-huh.
Why, you don't mean old Ben
Kaye, hero of the Burma Road?
Yep.
Well, what's he got to do
with all of this?
Everything. He's in G3
at the Pentagon!
And he's trying to booby-trap
the WAC's whole
camouflage training plan!
Yeah! That's why
he suddenly whipped up
this here demonstration!
What demonstration?
A camouflage operation
in the field,
in two weeks.
Major Simpson's WACs against
a company of combat veterans!
And our "Burma Hero" is bringing
along reporters and congressmen
to laugh the girls right out
of their camouflage suits!
Yeah. Yeah.
Now what are
they all gonna think
when they see a man in the WACs?
Francis, I just gotta
get out of this!
Ooh! Easy, boy.
They snuck up on me
with a square needle.
I'm sorry, Francis, I forgot.
They didn't waste any time.
And I'd suggest
you don't either.
Hey!
There's a shortcut to the
finish line over yonder!
Okay.
Now, that wouldn't be fair.
All is fair in love and war.
Get going!
Well, that girl is way
ahead of me, isn't she?
Mmm-hmm, there is the
understatement of the year.
Come on! Mmm!
(GIRLS CHEERING)
(ALL GROAN)
(ALL CHEERING)
Congratulations! Thank you.
Good work.
(GRUNTS)
Are you all right, Lieutenant?
Yeah, I'm... Oh, yeah!
Yes, I, uh...
I just misjudged the height a
little, that's all. Oh! (CHUCKLES)
Oh, well. (CHUCKLES)
Well, that's not all I misjudged.
You WACs are terrific.
(CHUCKLES) You know, I have to admit
that it really wasn't very fair.
You see, Private Wilson
was an Olympic Champion.
Oh. Well, I'm glad to
know that she's human.
I thought she might be
a new secret weapon!
Oh. Here, here,
lean on my shoulder.
Oh, thank you.
I'm, uh, glad to know you
WAC officers are human, too.
What do you mean?
Oh, I thought you were hard as nails.
You're really very soft underneath.
I mean, underneath.
Uh, uh, way underneath.
The real you,
that, that's what I mean!
Well, our complexities won't
puzzle you much longer, Lieutenant.
I'm sure Major Simpson
will expedite your transfer.
Oh, I'm not a bit puzzled.
I understand why
you're all so sensitive.
I suppose General Kaye's attitude
does get you on edge. (CHUCKLES)
What do you know
about General Kaye?
Oh, I sure hope you surprise him
when you have your big
camouflage operation.
(CHUCKLING)
Hey, Captain Parker, I... Captain
Parker, I got a wonderful idea!
Now that we're friends,
what do you say we both go to
the Post dance together tonight?
Huh?
Uh... Hmm.
Francis was right,
every WAC is a woman. Except me.
But it's impossible!
General Kaye just informed
us of the field operation!
No one knows about It here but you and me!
And General Kaye.
The old fox!
I didn't think he'd stoop to it,
but the evidence leads
to only one conclusion!
Lieutenant Stirling was
sent here by General Kaye.
To snoop! Check!
The mistake was no mistake!
General Kaye had Stirling
assigned here by plan!
Very clever of him to send a
spy who looks and acts like...
Like a schlemiel!
Well, if it's fight
the old double-crosser wants,
we'll play his game his way!
How?
We'll try to keep Lieutenant
Stirling here! What?
General Kaye insists
we conduct our
field demonstration
with a full company.
But the morale status of
the Second Platoon is such
that it leaves us
only one course,
to leave them out
of the operation!
But you said he'd raise
an awful holler!
Not if we can blame the condition
of that platoon on a man,
his man!
Send him in!
Lieutenant!
At ease.
Well, Lieutenant, it seems
we have a mutual friend.
Oh, do we? I didn't know.
General Kaye.
Oh, no, I think you're
mistaken, ma'am.
At least, I don't
know him personally.
Well, you knew he was coming here to
review a camouflage demonstration.
Yeah. Well, I, uh, I didn't
think there was any harm.
[, uh, I did happen to mention
to Captain Parker that...
Then you did get the
word from General Kaye?
Oh, no, ma'am. I got it from...
Uh, well, you
wouldn't believe me.
Don't tell me you
got it from that mule?
Why, yes. How did you know?
Strangely enough, Lieutenant,
your answer quite satisfies me.
(CHUCKLING) Oh, well. Oh, fine!
(CHUCKLES)
Lieutenant Stirling,
I have decided to make you
the camouflage instructor for
the Second Platoon of Company C.
Oh, well, I...
Me, an instructor for...
For a WAC platoon?
I'm sure, since you're a man,
you won't have any trouble
whipping 'em into shape.
Congratulations, Lieutenant
Stirling, and good luck!
Man coming! (INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Man coming!
Attention!
At ease.
Some of you women may be aware
that we were to be
joined by an officer
with experience in
combat conditions.
Through some error, Lieutenant
Stirling was assigned.
Until he is transferred,
he will undertake duties
as your platoon
camouflage instructor.
A man in the WAC? What is this?
That's for me!
Take orders from a man?
But he's so cute.
Well, Lieutenant,
they're all yours.
Take over.
(CLEARS THROAT)
I just don't believe it!
Well, it's true! Now, uh...
I'm supposed to whip
you girls into shape!
You're supposed to what?
Well, uh, that's right, I'm supposed
to whip you girls into shape!
Now I want order
and I want discipline.
There will be no
shirking of duty!
Now, when I say "fall out,”
I mean "fall out”!
And when it comes
time to fall out,
we fall out and very fast!
Fall out now, fast!
Platoon, attention!
I said attention!
We are at attention, sir!
You are? Yes, sir!
At ease!
I said, at ease.
I am at ease, sir.
You are? Yes, sir!
Men... Uh, uh, ladles,
now we've all got a job to do.
We've got to be
on the ball, right?
Right. Right.
Let's have a little
close order drill.
Platoon, attention!
Shoulders back!
Suck in your, uh...
(ALL CHUCKLING)
Uh, pull, in your, uh...
(ALL LAUGHING)
Uh, pull out your, uh...
At ease!
All right, fall out.
Fall out!
Lieutenant, we can't fall out
from an "at ease" position.
You always know what's right
when I'm wrong, don't you?
(CLEARS THROAT)
Platoon, attention!
Fall out!
(ALL LAUGHING)
Hey, Francis.
Francis?
FRANCIS: Beat it, bud.
You're bad luck to me.
Where are you? Right over here.
They've made a monkey out of me.
Oh, no. Francis.
Francis, what've
they done to you?
Francis, tell me you forgive me.
Tell me you forgive
me, will you, Francis?
Pfft! Please tell me!
Cut out the monkey business!
I'm over here, Petey boy.
You...
Oh, did you scare me!
For a minute, I... Yeah, yeah...
Why, Francis. Huh?
Hey, what've they done to your...
Please, Lieutenant.
I'm gettin' what I deserve
for tryin' to help you!
One more injection and I'll be
ready to buck for rear admiral.
Gee, I'm sorry, Francis.
Is there anything I can do?
I've often wondered.
I can take anything
they can dish out.
Well, I think we're
both getting a bad deal.
I am officially in the WACs.
Heaven help the WACs.
Now, this is no time to joke.
What're we gonna do? I can't
get any place with those girls.
Maybe they're a little choosey.
Yeah.
Oh, you know what I mean.
I've brushed up on my
manual of arms. Yeah.
My close order drill. Yeah.
Et cetera, et cetera. That
should endear you to them.
Psst! Psst!
Uh-oh! Here comes old aspirin tablet.
Yeah. Who? Who?
(LAUGHS) Have you
got a surprise coming.
Oh, boy.
Oh.
Good morning, you
dear little animals!
Here's some breakfast,
you horrid little things.
(SQUEAKING)
Oh, Aunt and Uncle Wiggly,
a big fat carrot for you.
And Rosalind.
Look what nursie
brought you, a banana.
Well, then you eat it later.
Just take it and eat it later.
Peggy, look what I brought you.
Some nice, fresh peanuts.
Good morning, Lieutenant.
Oh, good morning, Lieutenant.
Here's some...
Oh, no. No, you couldn't be.
No, I'm not! I'm not!
Honestly, I'm not!
No, I mean, uh,
one I met in Burma.
It was in a psychopathic ward.
Huh?
Oh, but that, that was somebody
else entirely. (BOTH CHUCKLE)
Yes, he was always weaving baskets.
Is that so?
Crazy as a loon,
huh? A real idiot?
Oh, the cutest little
idiot you ever saw.
Well. Oh? He talked to a mule.
So of course, you couldn't...
Oh, no, I couldn't. (CHUCKLES)
Oh, dear.
Uh, this mule isn't a
friend of yours, is he?
(LAUGHING) Of course not.
I just came in to see the monkeys.
Well,
no insinuations implied, Lieutenant.
Of course not. No.
Let's see. You poor,
dumb little beast.
No reaction whatsoever.
Here, let's take
your temperature.
Well, now there.
Now, stick it in.
Stick it in that dear little
mouth of yours. Up, up.
There you go.
Oh!
For pity's sakes.
No brains, no feeling.
She shouldn't have said that.
He drank a whole bottle
of alcohol yesterday!
Now, you dear little mule, I'm
gonna start you on your pills.
I hope you take them nicely.
No, I...
The old battle axe.
Pills. Takes a pill
to know a pill! Mmm.
Remember that old saddle bag?
Yeah.
Lieutenant Valerie Humpert.
Do I remember her?
Burma. Yeah.
She nursed me through four
sieges of basket weaving!
Uh-huh. Look, things
are getting worse.
We've just gotta get outta here.
Check!
And your old cousin has a plan!
I knew you'd come up with something.
Natch. Now, get this.
Peel a WAC and you got a woman.
Rank or file, they're females
first and last! Right? I guess so.
All right. You can't win a
woman unless you woo her.
A whole platoon? You want me to
woo a whole platoon? Precisely!
Yeah, but I'm not very strong.
Have you got 30 bucks? Why?
Well, there's a special
sale on cologne at the PX.
Cologne?
It's called, "Night
In the Casbah."
"Night In The Casbah"? You
mean for the entire platoon?
But of course!
You are such a boy!
Now get goin' and check with me!
Woo a whole platoon?
That's 25 to one.
You're the odds-on favorite!
Eh-eh.
Uh-oh.
Oh, no, not that!
(SIGHS) Now you must take your
pill, you naughty little mule!
Take this great big pill,
now! Open wide!
Up with the little mouth.
Now, that's right!
Put it in for nursie.
There, now. Just one big blow.
(SNORTING) (COUGHING)
You all right, Lieutenant?
You... You all right?
Oh, Lieutenant! Lieutenant!
What's this "Night
In The Casbah" bit?
Huh? Oh. It's just a gift!
Are you as innocent as you look?
Well, I really had an
ulterior motive, you see,
I want you girls to like me.
You mean... You mean you gave
cologne to everybody in the platoon?
Well, yeah. Don't you like it?
(LAUGHING) I think
it's wonderful.
You know, if I had a kid brother
I'd like him to be just like you!
(CHUCKLES) I... No...
Oh, Lieutenant! Lieutenant!
(WHISTLES)
Oh, thank you
so much! Thank you!
(CHUCKLES)
(CHUCKLING) (WHISTLING)
Oh, Lieutenant!
You shouldn't have! Now, mmm...
Now, Corporal Hilstrom,
this is against regulations.
Sorry, Captain. It was
just a slip of the lip.
Well, I expect you to be
more careful next time!
Yes, ma'am!
I'll be extra careful next time.
Lieutenant Stirling. Yes, ma'am?
You were out of order. Well, yes. My aim...
My aim is better discipline!
You'd sound a little more convincing if
you wiped that lip rouge off your mouth.
Of course. (CHUCKLES)
I... You know, that Corporal
Hilstrom took me by surprise.
Your life seems to be
full of surprises!
Oh, Lieutenant!
(ALL GIGGLING)
How do you figure that?
Lieutenant Stirling seems
to be trying awfully hard.
Lieutenant Stirling!
There's more to this
than meets the eye!
One, two, three, four,
to the left flank, march!
One, two, three, four.
Hut, two, three, four.
To the rear, march!
One, two... Lift those legs.
Lift those lovely, lovely legs!
And away we go
to the rear, march!
To the rear, march.
Lift those legs!
You're doin' great,
you beautiful dolls!
Embarrassing! Very embarrassing!
Well, don't you think Lieutenant
Stirling is to be commended?
For what? Double-crossing us?
He lifted that Second Platoon
right out of their slump!
And made us a
target for ridicule.
What do you think General
Kaye will say about this?
A man helped us out!
We couldn't do it
but a man could!
PETER: Lift those
lovely, lovely legs.
Ma'am, General Kaye is waiting
for you at Battalion Headquarters.
General Kaye? But he isn't
due in until tomorrow.
PETER: Lift those
lovely, lovely legs!
I'm going to settle that Lieutenant
Stirling's hash right now!
See you later!
KAYE: Major, you might think
that I'm a stubborn mule.
Just because a few of your women
have developed into adequate
camouflage specialists,
it doesn't mean that you can
flood the service with them.
We've known each other
a long time, General,
and I... I'd even
like to think of us as
being good friends, Louise,
but these wild ideas of yours...
Ben, may I have your permission
to speak freely? Yeah.
Just because you believe women are
fit only to be typewriter jockeys
and telephone operators
doesn't mean that
national defense
should be jeopardized!
We've done pretty
well up to now.
You only have to do badly once.
Louise,
you've got a one-track mind and I
consider it my duty to prove you're wrong.
And I find your methods as
misguided as your views.
My methods are beyond reproach!
I've gone to great lengths to
arrange this demonstration.
You've gone to even greater lengths
to disrupt our morale and snoop!
And what?
Why haven't you approved
Lieutenant Stirling's
transfer out of this
WAC assignment?
I don't know what
you're talkin' about.
Who is this Lieutenant Stirling?
And why should you
want her transferred?
Lieutenant Stirling is not a her!
It's a him. A him?
As if you didn't know! Here?
Yes! A Mata Hari
in men's clothing!
Sent here to carry out his
general's orders! General!
Ben, there are many things on
which we don't see eye to eye,
but up to now I have never questioned
your ethics or sportsmanship.
Now, Louise, if you'll simmer...
But the mere fact
that you had to stoop to
this sort of procedure
to try and beat us
is proof of our
superior skill and ability.
Major, it might be
a good idea for you
to use some of your smart
camouflaging on that sharp tongue
when you're addressing
a superior officer.
I'm sorry, Louise.
This is the first I've
heard about all this.
Naturally, if there's been a
mistake, I'll rectify it at once.
Thank you.
Now about the
demonstration, I've, uh,
selected Piney Woods as the area of
operation, if this is acceptable to you.
A male WAC,
how about that?
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Just think, in a couple of days
we might be out of this mess.
You're sure your transfer
is going through?
Well, Corporal Hilstrom
heard it from Captain Parker
and Captain Parker got
it from Major Simpson.
Happy day. I couldn't
stand much more.
What Headquarters is
doing to my hindquarters
shouldn't happen In any quarter.
You know, it's gonna be
hard saying goodbye. Yeah?
Francis? Huh?
Do you think it's possible for a guy
to be in love with a whole platoon?
Never heard of it outside
the Marine Corps.
Once knew a Marine who was
engaged to three women.
Yeah? What did he do about it?
They buried him in Arlington.
Sharpened his heels and drove him in.
(CHUCKLES)
Shh. Shh.
Attention!
Come on, Francis.
No games. I'm tired.
Attention!
Now quit making like a
general, you idiot. (HISSING)
Idiot, am I? I could have you
broken for this, Lieutenant!
(LAUGHS)
A jackass break a lieutenant?
Heh, that's a laugh. (CHUCKLES)
Yes, it's a real yuk.
On your feet!
So you're Lieutenant Stirling?
(STUTTERING) Uh, yes, sir.
Looks like we're gettin' kinda
close to the bottom of the barrel.
Yes, sir. Hmm.
See we hit the Burma front together.
Yeah?
I'm General Kaye.
Oh, how do you do, sir.
At ease, Lieutenant.
(STAMMERING) At ease, sir?
I know how you feel,
coming out of a man's army and
being pushed in with these Suzies.
A male WAC! Yes, sir.
I hear your little tour of duty
has thrown the ladies into a tizzy.
Uh, yes, sir.
Uh, no, sir! Well, I
try to do my duty, sir.
So I hear, and that's what
I want to talk to you about.
Just between us, Stirling, I
don't think you should overdo it.
Huh? I don't understand, sir.
Well, women just don't appreciate
a man's superior skill and ability.
Oh, yes, sir. Oh, not that
it would matter, sir.
I'm not gonna be with
them much longer.
I'm being transferred
out. I think.
Am I not, sir? Yes, of course, my boy.
Of course.
Might take a little time.
I suppose this was a
little advance celebration?
Oh, yes, sir. Me and Francis.
Francis?
Who's she?
Oh, she is a he.
Uh, he is a mule.
Uh, that that's him
over there, sir.
Celebratin' with a mule?
Hmm. Yes, sir.
Personally, I would've selected
a sweeter smellin' companion.
One not so dumb.
Yeah, but he's a pretty smart mule, sir.
That I doubt.
He reminds me of one
I had in my command.
We had just built a temporary
bridge on the Burma Road,
and this stubborn
creature refused to cross.
Held up the whole company.
We never did get across it.
Never? No. The bridge collapsed
before our very eyes into a
raging, storm-swollen river.
Well, maybe he was
pretty smart, sir.
No. Not this one.
He was just ornery, stupid.
Dumbest animal I ever saw.
Well, I'll leave you to
your little celebration.
Yes, sir.
Uh-huh.
Get him!
Come back here, Pete!
I wish you'd make up your mind!
I'm so mad,
I could blow a gasket! Naturally,
I wouldn't cross that bridge.
You mean that mule was you?
Anybody could see the
pulley system was faulty,
the bridge was
bound to collapse.
Francis, you saved
the whole company.
Yeah, but our hero
got a commendation.
Never mentioned me. "Ornery,
stupid." The old goat.
Yeah, yeah, but I don't understand.
Now... Now his voice
sounds exactly like yours.
It was along about
then I decided
it would be handy
to be able to talk,
particularly like a general, and
as long as I was in his outfit,
it was a built-in goldbrick.
Well, it sounds like
nothin' but trouble.
Am I glad we're
getting out of this!
But we're not getting out.
No. Yeah.
What're you saying?
We gotta get out of this!
Hmm, Petey, my boy,
we're gonna stay long
enough to teach that old...
Well, we're gonna
teach him a lesson!
Oh, no, now you can't!
Oh, you're going to become
a camouflage expert.
Not me, I refuse. I just plain refuse!
Let me see,
the operation will take
place at Piney Woods.
Now, we need a map of that area.
Not me! Now you leave me out of this.
I don't want anything to do with maps.
Naturally, this
is top secret, Pete.
Major Simpson won't
even tell Company C
what route they're
going to follow.
Not until the night
before the operation.
Now, starting from Point Able...
Yeah, that's it.
Company C, to be
called the White Army,
is going to try to
move a distance
of 10 miles to Point Baker.
You see it there? Atta boy.
That is, without being spotted
by General Kaye's Blue Army.
Both these points will be
known to us and the umpire,
but not to the Blue Army.
Starting tomorrow, Company C goes
into training on a 24-hour basis.
Yeah, well, Francis, what do I
know about... You'll learn, my boy.
Yes, sir, you'll learn.
Did you deploy your
troops so they can
be identified and
signaled immediately? Huh?
Yes. All right. Show me.
Show me.
Reverse, move!
I said move! Oh, there you are.
Oh, my aching back!
(SCREAMS)
Oh, a moose!
Calm down, boy. That's
just an object lesson.
Camouflage can be offensive
as well as defensive.
I just wanted to drive that
point through your head!
You sure took the long way through.
Mmm-hmm.
Parker! JANE: Oh, good morning.
Jane, did you take
the topographical map
of Piney Woods from my desk?
Well, I wouldn't do that
without your permission, Louise.
Well, someone did. It's gone!
And if that map ever gets into
the wrong hands... Wrong hands!
Oh, you don't think General
Kaye would go that far?
I think he'd do anything
to prevent our success,
him and his male WAC, I...
That's who it was. Stirling!
It must have been our
dear little lieutenant.
Lieutenant! Lieutenant!
As you were.
I won't beat about the bush,
I want that map! What map?
The map to Piney Woods,
as if you didn't know,
and don't tell me you lost it!
Oh, no, ma'am. I've got it. Not that
it would matter, I memorized it!
Lieutenant, report to Battalion
Headquarters immediately.
Go there directly.
Do not speak to anyone!
Yes, ma'am. I mean yes, sir.
I mean, I mean, yes.
Nothing, but nothing must
jeopardize the operation.
Obviously, if he went to the
trouble of memorizing the map,
the information on it has not
yet gotten to General Kaye.
I'm going to see
that it never does.
Send Lieutenant Stirling in.
Lieutenant Stirling.
Sit down!
Lieutenant, I want to know what...
It's not true.
I'm innocent. I'm not
on General Kaye's side.
We want you WACs to win. Yeah, we.
"We," Lieutenant Stirling?
I mean, I. I see.
Oh, no, no, you don't see. Honestly...
I see the map you stole.
I didn't steal any map.
Somebody did. It was borrowed.
Francis wouldn't steal anything.
Francis? Who's Francis?
Francis, he's...
Oh, you wouldn't believe me.
Don't tell me you're going to
go into that mule routine again!
Yes, ma'am.
All right, so there's a mule.
A mule named Francis.
Yes. Spelled with an "I."
Just an ordinary mule? Oh,
no, he's not an ordinary mule.
A mule walked into my office
to borrow a map? Yes, ma'am.
How do you know he did?
He told me.
Oh, yes, I forgot.
He talks, too.
Yeah.
Well, I know it sounds impossible, why,
I didn't believe it myself at one time.
But now you do believe he can talk?
I know it!
And you're willing to stand by
that story, Lieutenant? Definitely!
Good! It makes what I have
to do that much simpler.
(STAMMERING)
Honestly, it's the truth!
I swear, it's...
I swear it's the truth!
Don't you worry about a thing.
We've been through this
before, Lieutenant.
Yeah, and I don't want
to go through it again.
Just like old times, they're
using our treatments again.
Good afternoon, nurse.
And how's our patient? Oh, just dandy.
Just dandy.
Do you still think a mule talks to you?
He certainly does!
You don't have to answer
for Lieutenant Stirling.
You're asking our questions.
That's all. That's all.
Yes, you were asking...
Well, I...
Oh, yes. Mmm.
I'll be right outside, Lieutenant.
(CLEARING THROAT)
Now, this heavy dark mass
represents your mother.
My mother was a skinny blonde.
You said Francis was
like a mother to you.
Oh, no, I said Francis
was like a father to me.
He helps me and advises
me on everything.
And you believe he could help
and advise you in this situation?
You mean you'll
let me talk to him?
I think it can be arranged.
Oh, thank you very much, sir!
Thank you! That's really...
(STAMMERING)
I'm awfully sorry...
There, there, now. Be my
own dear brave little mule.
I know it hurts!
Oh, it hurts me worse
then it does you.
Oh, we got to get
prettied up, you know.
Company's coming. Yes, company!
Now you wait right there
and I'll fix your oatsies.
Hmm, I'd like to
fix her oatsies.
Hey!
Hi, Francis.
Uh, look, I know you're mad at
me but I had to tell the truth.
Uh, did he answer you?
No, he gets this way. Stubborn.
Look, I'm sorry, Francis.
Oh, it's no use now.
He won't talk to me.
No, I'm sure he won't.
Come, Lieutenant.
Now, no hard feelings, Francis.
Come up and see
my paintings sometime.
Hello.
Hello, uh, Francis.
(SCOFFS)
Goodbye, cutie.
Ah! (SCREAMING)
Oh... (SIGHS)
What's the matter?
He spoke to me.
Well, at least I thought he did.
Who?
Francis. The mule!
(LAUGHS) Oh, you dreamt it.
No, no, no, he said...
Oh, he said...
Well, he said, "Goodbye,
cutie." (LAUGHING) Oh, look.
Why don't you knock off for the
rest of the day. Take it easy.
(SIGHS)
Maybe I'd better.
A mule! (LAUGHS)
Cutie! Uh?
(CLICKING)
(SNORTING) (SNORTING)
(IMITATING NEIGHING)
You know something, you look
like a horse too, Major.
(SCREAMING)
You wanted to see me, Louise?
You too? Huh?
Oh, no. It's just a hobby.
Since when?
Since last night.
The mule?
He not only spoke to me, he
sounded just like General Kaye.
Like General Kaye?
Oh, you've got it real bad!
You're one to talk, "cutie"!
Now I've got it all figured out.
It has to be ventriloquism.
Of course!
You mean Lieutenant Stirling.
Oh, I didn't say it was
Lieutenant Stirling. I...
Uh, why I could be wrong about the
whole thing. It had to be Stirling.
But he wasn't even there.
How do we know?
The medical lab is part
of the hospital installation.
All the buildings are grouped together.
(PEOPLE YELLING IN DISTANCE)
Oh, you mean it's another one of
General Kaye's morale breakers?
(YELLING INTENSIFIES)
(ALL WHISTLING)
You gentlemen of the press will
be briefed later by Major Simpson.
From my point of view
I can only tell you
that the operation will start
at dawn tomorrow and finish.
(LAUGHING) before it starts.
Well, what happens
if you spot them?
Do you shoot them down?
Heck, no.
We need them behind
the typewriters.
We're using a kind
of a genteel ammo.
Squirt guns with liquid dye.
That way we can tell which of the ladies
has been spotted and disqualified.
(CHUCKLES) The White Army isn't
going to be white very long.
Major, show these gentlemen
to their quarters.
John?
See you at six in the
morning, General.
(CHUCKLES) You'll be back
in the sack at seven, Jack.
Good morning, Major. I hope your
little army is fit and ready.
(GASPING)
Oh, I...
I thought you were a mule.
A what?
Oh, I mean a jackass. I...
Now wait a minute, uh...
She means a talking mule.
We've both been the victims
of your ventriloquist.
Ventriloquist? Talking mule?
You both ill?
Oh, please, let's not
go through that again.
I mean Lieutenant Stirling.
Oh, Stirling. Yes.
I met him and his mule.
What do you mean
the animal talks?
Well... Well, what
did it talk about?
Well, for one thing, he...
It called Captain
Parker "cutie."
Cutie? Excuse me.
(CHUCKLES)
A real army mule.
(DOOR OPENS)
(DOOR CLOSES)
What did he call you, Louise?
I'd rather not say.
What made you
suspect ventriloquism?
Well, for one thing,
he talked exactly like you.
Now wait a minute, Major.
You may be a woman, but
you're also an Army officer
and there's such
a thing a respect.
But it's true.
He talked exactly like you.
Oh, Major.
No insubordination
intended, believe me.
If anyone's guilty
of such a thing,
it's your Lieutenant Stirling.
Why do you keep insinuating
I have something
to do with this Lieutenant
Stirling and his talking mule?
Well, haven't you, General?
I'll soon settle your mind on that.
Where is this Stirling?
In, uh, in the psycho ward.
What? Well, where's the mule?
In the barn.
I can hardly believe this.
This is too normal.
I'd like to have a look
at this mule.
Hiya, Francis.
Beat it. Get lost.
I just had to sneak
out and apologize!
Amscray, before
they find you here.
I suppose you think I'm a
stupid idiot, don't you?
With you, Pete, that's
par for the course!
Yeah, but I just did
what you told me to do!
I didn't tell you to
mess up the whole detail.
You know how much it means to
me to win this old ballgame.
Well, me too. Well,
we're out of the runnin'.
And that ain't all. Have you
checked your platoon lately?
How could I?
They've fallen apart.
But why? They were
doing so great.
Morale, boy, morale. Yeah.
When they discovered
you were in psycho
and they'd been gettin'
camouflage instruction
from a mental case, well...
(DOOR OPENING) Shh. Shh. Pete.
Hit the dirt.
It's over here, Ben.
Oh, I've had mules
in my outfit before.
None of 'em could ever talk.
Yes.
This is the beast I saw out
near the Confidence Course.
Mangy lookin' creature.
So, you're the
talking mule, huh?
All right, talk it up.
This is all utter nonsense!
What do you mean,
utter nonsense?
(SNORTING)
Hmm-hmm.
Did you hear somethin'?
I heard you talk.
Well, so did I. Me?
It was the mule.
Mule, did you say something?
Come on, speak up!
Are you givin' me permission
to sound off, sir?
Permission granted! Sound off!
Well, to start with,
you're a narrow-minded
fuddy-duddy.
You probably think the top brass
is the machinery that
runs this man's army.
Horsefeathers!
Now, you take these WACs.
Everyone knows that women are here to stay.
But not you.
You've got the idea
they're in the service
just to keep your
memos circulating.
This is the most ridiculous...
Lieutenant Stirling.
KAYE: So, that's it.
Huh! Just as we thought.
Ventriloquism.
You were right, Louise.
On your feet, Lieutenant!
A narrow-minded fuddy-duddy, huh?
Pig-headed, huh?
Yeah, well, no, sir. If you
are, sir, I didn't say so, sir.
Tell him, Francis.
Tell him he's a narrow-minded,
pig-headed old fuddy-duddy.
I mean, tell him you said so.
I've heard enough
from this mule!
You did give him permission
to sound off, sir.
And I sure like the
sound he made, General.
We won't discuss the
opinions of a sick mind.
This boy needs medical care.
Put him back in psycho where
he belongs and keep him there!
Now... Now look
what you've done!
How could you do this
to me? How? Huh, how?
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Yes, Sergeant?
Leemy can't find
her helmet liner
and Cassidy thinks
she's got a fever.
If you ask me, your whole
platoon's dogging it.
Well, we just haven't
been the same
since we found out what happened
to poor Lieutenant Stirling.
Don't you think you women are
carrying loyalty a little too far?
WOMAN: All right, girls.
Come on, now. Let's get busy!
FRANCIS: (SOFTLY) Hey, Cutie.
Captain.
Come on over here.
Come on. On the double.
Back of this truck.
Hey, Captain.
Back here.
Oh, don't be frightened.
Relax.
The next voice you hear
is mine and nobody else's.
Yeah.
The trouble with you, babe, is
that you look like a hot tamale
and act like a frozen custard.
Do you know the best thing
that could happen to you?
Don't answer that.
Lose those captain's bars
for a couple hours!
Act like a woman.
Break a few rules.
You like Pete, don't you? Yeah.
And you want to believe that
he's on your side! Yeah!
Well, he is.
What's more, he could
help this operation.
He could pull that Second Platoon
right into line again. Check?
Well, what're you waitin' for?
Bust him outta that nuthouse
and let's put him into action.
Get goin'.
(CHUCKLES)
Typical.
Once those icebergs melt,
there ain't no stopping 'em.
Can I help you, Captain?
I'd like to see Lieutenant
Stirling, please.
Uh, in... In here, ma'am.
Oh, thank you.
Lieutenant Stirling.
Just a minute...
Well, Captain Parker!
I want to apologize. I know now
it's all a horrible mistake.
Oh, well, it's not
so horrible now.
Captain, the Lieutenant
is a very sick man.
Oh, he's no sicker than I am.
And he's got a job to do!
Your platoon needs you,
and that means the camouflage
operation needs you.
But he's a man! He's also a WAC!
Lieutenant Stirling, I want
you to join your platoon.
Captain, that's against orders.
Orders! This is war!
And you're in the army,
too, Lieutenant Humpert.
And tomorrow we'll be fighting
your battle out there.
But it is against orders.
Lieutenant...
What do you say?
Well, it's orders are orders,
and you heard me tell
the captain, orders.
Oh! (CHUCKLES)
Well!
What you want me to do?
Just anything!
Well, we've got to
smuggle him out of here
past that guard.
Hey, you could lend
him your uniform.
Why, yes. You could lend me...
Her uniform?
A woman's uniform?
He's a WAC, isn't he?
Oh, now wait. Things are going
just a little bit too far.
Well, you want to
help us, don't you?
(STAMMERS) Well, yeah, but I...
Lieutenant, all those
women need you.
Uh, really? Well, I...
Quick! You've got
to get undressed!
Undressed? Yes. Yes!
Well, how much of my uniform?
Uh, do you think just
the outside would do?
Well, I'm afraid what I've
got to put inside won't do!
Hurry. We haven't got much time.
Quick! (STAMMERS)
I don't know whether I
want to do this or not.
Now, really, I...
Give me your bathrobe!
Oh, for heaven's sake.
Now your pajamas. My pajamas?
Here's the robe.
HUMPERT: Yes, and...
And here's my dress!
Hurry!
I don't know whether it'll fit or not!
Oh, that doesn't matter.
He's such a little thing.
And here's the slip.
Yes. Tell him to
squeeze into it.
Here they are!
Okay. Now, if I catch
cold, I'm gonna blame you.
Oh, these are just the tops.
I've gotta have the bottoms, too.
The bottoms, too? Yes. Hurry!
Okay.
Quick! The girls
will be leaving.
HUMPERT: Oh, I'm so cold. Here!
Oh, my. Do you think it would...
Now the shoes and stockings.
The shoes and the... Oh, do I
have to take them off, too? My.
Is it a bird? Is it a plane?
No, it's Superwoman.
Very funny. Very funny.
I'll bet you got me into this.
And trés chic, too.
(LAUGHS)
Oh-oh! Hey!
Oh, why did I ever...
Oh! Spaceship number seven.
I'm getting you
clearly. Mmm-hmm.
Oh, General. Oh.
No, nursie, just your darling
little mule talking to you.
Oh.
(CHUCKLES) You are such a girl.
No, no, no!
Yes, yes, yes!
And no time to faint until we
get lover boy put together.
Well, just don't stand
there with egg on your face!
No, (STAMMERS) I was just going.
Get goin'!
What's taking you
so long, Lieutenant?
Well, it's just that I'm not used to
getting in these things, that's all.
Captain, what're you going to use
for hair on your new sister WAC?
That's right. We've got to
fake a wig out of something.
A wig? Oh, no.
I've got it. Horsehair!
How about it, Francis?
Horsehair? Me and my big mouth.
Well, anything for the cause.
Get the scissors.
Oh, scissors. Scissors!
Yeah. FRANCIS: Come on, Nurse!
They're over here. Here they are.
Oh, there!
Now don't make this
a butch, Captain.
Well!
HUD-huh!
(SIGHS)
Ow! Ooh, you're hurting me!
Oh. Oh, I'm sorry, Francis.
Good night, Corporal.
Good night, Captain.
(DOOR OPENS)
Lieutenant Stirling
is not to be disturbed.
Yes, ma'am.
Whatever you're thinking,
Corporal, it's not true!
LOUISE: Tomorrow we women will
be involved in an operation
that will test the mettle
of every one of us.
You are all volunteers,
and I am grateful for
your efforts and courage.
By tomorrow evening, I feel
sure that we will have proved
that when we WACs say
we can do something,
we can do it.
Good luck.
(INDISTINCT MURMURING)
LOUISE: Lieutenant!
What's the meaning of this?
I'm responsible, Major.
Well, you see, I felt the
urgency was so great...
Well, there wasn't time
to consult with you.
I believe that Lieutenant
Stirling can help us.
You know the low morale
of Second Platoon
and what it'll mean
to have him back.
And I know Lieutenant
Stirling wants to help.
Well, I...
And he still is in the WAC.
He'd better come
through for us tomorrow
or he'll never
get out of the WAC.
Dig up some field gear.
Yes, ma'am.
Woman driver.
Covers on four.
Follow me.
MAN: This is Blue.
I read you loud and clear.
Stand by. Over.
General. Huh?
May I get you an aspirin? Aw.
General, the White Army has taken
its initial position at Point Able.
The demonstration
is officially started.
What happens now, General?
Thank you, Charlie. Well, George,
I'm just an observer like yourself.
Unless I miss my guess,
in exactly 60 seconds
recon planes will be coming
over from Lassen Field.
In 30 minutes, aerial
photos will be developed
and we'll have Major Simpson's
lovely ladies pin-pointed.
Hi. Oh, I beg your pardon.
Be my guest? Thank you.
(CHUCKLES)
(WHISTLES)
Watch out for that gimmick.
Say, you know something?
Those WACs might look
pretty keen in polka dots.
(LAUGHS)
Nothing.
Nothing? Nothing, General.
You don't mean to tell me
that that isn't something?
Well, that's your field
headquarters, sir.
Is it? It is?
(BANJO PLAYING)
(MAN SINGING)
(SINGING)
Hey, uh, that's a might right
pretty dress you got there, Sis.
I've never seen it before.
Glad you all like it.
Sure wish I could read writin'.
MAN: Hey, there, bud!
Hi, there.
Run for it, Beauregard!
They're draftin' again!
Draftin'?
Take it easy, son!
Who we fightin' this time?
Did you see any WACs go by here?
WACs? WACs?
Yeah. You know, female soldiers.
Oh, them! Oh, they...
They went, uh...
No, no. They went, uh...
They went that-a-way.
Thanks. Let's go!
HILSTROM: Okay, girls, come on.
Hey, Captain.
Plane!
Take cover!
They're really pouring
on the pressure. Yeah.
We've still got eight
more miles to go! Whew!
I think maybe we'd better
take the offensive.
Yeah. How do we do that?
Well, let's see.
The idea first is to steal
one of their walkie-talkies.
Oh, I see. And then Intercept
their messages, huh?
Sure. Mmm-hmm. Well, do
you think you can do it?
Well, I'll need a volunteer.
Are there any volunteers
for this hazardous mission?
Well?
Now, look, Francis,
I can't take the chance.
If I mess up this operation,
I'll never get out of the WACs.
All those who don't
want to volunteer,
take one step backward.
The idea is, exchange
one of our walkie-talkies
with one of theirs.
That way we'll be tuned
into their frequency.
Now, this is how you'll do it.
Yeah?
Hey, look at this. What is it?
A gal's comb!
Nice goin'.
We'd better contact
a mobile unit.
Hello, Blue. Hello, Blue.
This is Diamond.
We've picked up
their trail. Over.
Right, sir. Over.
Hey, let's have a little
camouflage discipline.
Sorry.
FRED: Is this your first hitch?
You should know
better than that.
Let's get it out quick
before they see the smoke.
LIEUTENANT: Which way, soldier?
FRED: Well they must've come this way, sir.
We found a girl's comb.
Show him the comb, George.
GEORGE: Here you are, sir.
FRED: It's about time those
WACs let down their hair
and gave us some
kind of a clue, sir.
LIEUTENANT: It might be a decoy,
but I think we'd better
contact field headquarters
and see if it fits in
with the plot map.
Okay, let's go.
Wait a minute, sir.
My walkie-talkie.
Help! Help! They got me!
Well, what do you know?
We hooked the wrong fish.
Francis! Francis, get
me outta here, will ya?
Shh. Easy does it. There.
Lieutenant! Two patrols
are approaching.
What?
That's nice work, Lieutenant.
Thanks.
Mission accomplished.
Yeah, and two enemy
patrols are approaching.
Aah! Come on, let's go!
Aw... Aren't you coming with me?
No, I've gotta untangle
this mess you made.
Gimme that hearin' aid.
Come on. Hmm-mmm.
Oh, hello all units.
This is Blue,
Field Command to patrols.
General Kaye.
Charlie Patrol proceed south
by southeast. Be alert.
Opposing forces
are wearing men's uniforms.
Calling Dog Patrol.
It's General Kaye.
Dog Patrol, proceed
north by northwest.
Be alert.
Opposing forces
are wearing men's uniforms.
Stand by, over.
I gave no such orders.
You know I gave no such orders.
Tell them that...
That's it.
The White Army's tuned
in on our frequency.
They're giving commands
and intercepting ours.
Yeah.
This is our first bit of luck.
Corporal, we're going to
give those WACs some orders
that will cook their goose.
Yes, sir.
Hey, Pete, give this
thing a listen, quick.
MAN: Attention all patrols.
Mmm-hmm. This is Unit Blue.
The White Army is now
bracketed in Zone Twelve.
Deploy east and west
of Hill 1-1-8 to intercept.
FRANCIS: Oh.
That... That must be
this hill right here.
Hey, look, it's not covered!
He probably figured we'd never
dare cross it, too exposed!
That's our answer.
Hill 1-1-8, here we come.
Simmer down, Captain.
This might be a trap.
But it's our only
chance, Francis.
If we're lucky, we'll... We'll
slip right through their lines.
FRANCIS: I'm tellin' ya, Pete.
This could be a trap.
The Blue Army.
It's there. It's a trap.
Francis was right.
Someday you'll believe me.
We'll have to retreat
on the double.
Get Sergeant Kipp. Yes, Captain.
Did I hear you
say retreat, Captain?
What else can we do?
Well we can give 'em credit
for havin' some brains.
They've got our rear
covered and re-covered.
We go forward.
Into their waiting arms?
Into their smoky eyes, yeah.
Right.
A smoke screen.
FRANCIS: You betcha.
Now come over here
and pick my pocket.
All right, come on
over, Captain.
We got the "O" smoke.
Yes, sir.
Yes, sir. Over.
Forward, men.
Ready grenades.
Fire!
Ugh!
Ooh! Happy landin', soldier.
(CHUCKLES)
(GROANS)
Ooh. There's a real
belly-flopper.
I'll scout a bit, sir, for
a way across the gully.
FRANCIS: Well, don't stand there, men.
Jump, jump!
Yes, General. Yes, sir!
KAYE: What... What is this?
Who said that? Who's
giving orders around here?
I am, sir. What's wrong?
What's wrong?
Have you gone crazy?
Don't stand there. Jump. Jump.
Yes, sir!
FRANCIS: Captain! With your men.
What are you waiting for? Jump!
(STAMMERS) But... But General...
Come back here, Captain!
I could you men
court-martialed for this!
FRANCIS: Don't stand there!
Jump, General!
Where's that coming from?
Just a little overdue
payment, General,
on that Burma bridge account.
See you at Point Baker
when the ladies win!
Yes, sir!
After them. Get that mule.
Shoot that lieutenant!
I mean, disqualify him.
If you don't mind some
rough goin', General,
there's a crossing
downhill a ways
that'll bring us out
near Point Baker.
Get in that jeep, soldier.
Oh, General, maybe you'll
need some aspirin now!
Three minutes, General.
Any luck, General?
(HOARSE VOICE) Well, they
haven't reached here yet,
have they?
Well, Major, (CLEARS
THROAT) have they?
No, sir, not yet.
I think I can guarantee
now that they won't.
We've plotted their
line of advance
and got them sewed up
tight as a drum.
About three minutes, your little
dream will be over, Louise.
Aren't you cheering yourself
hoarse a bit too soon, Ben?
Uh, Louise.
You may as well know this.
Your girls are on their own now.
That, uh, little male WAC
has been disqualified by now.
There are still
two minutes left.
Do you mind if I hope
that much longer?
Two minutes.
At ease.
What about that Lieutenant?
Did you disqualify him?
Uh, no, sir. We finally caught
up with this jackass, sir,
but there was no sign of a lieutenant
or anyone else from the White Army.
Of course not.
There isn't one of 'em
within miles of us.
You want to bet?
Who said that?
Mmm-hmm.
You men carry on.
Leave that donkey.
It's a trick.
It's gotta be a trick.
Why? What trick is
there to talking?
Any fool can do it.
(GROANS) Oh.
Unless he loses his voice.
(GROANS)
And that ain't all you
lost, General Kaye.
Look!
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
(CHEERING)
Not a WAC for miles, huh?
(LAUGHS)
Open wide, General.
Wider. It won't hurt.
What do you think
that is, a barn door?
General! We'd certainly like
a few words from you, General,
straight from the horse's
mouth, you might say.
(HOARSE VOICE) And that's the
way you're gonna get it, my boy.
If I can talk through
this throat of mine.
Right over there, sir.
We're all ready for you.
Okay, Fred?
Now it is my pleasure and privilege
to introduce to the TV audience
the man who came
from the Pentagon
to arrange this
camouflage operation.
Ladies and gentlemen, here
he is, General Ben Kaye!
(APPLAUD)
FRANCIS: I'll have to be brief,
because of a touch
of laryngitis.
But having observed
the camouflage demonstration
by this splendid group
of Fort Chase WA Cs,
I must pay tribute to
them and admit defeat.
(WOMEN CHEERING)
A magnificent job, ladies.
Magnificent!
But with Major
Simpson's leadership,
how could it be otherwise?
(WOMEN CHEERING)
I just can't believe it.
A salute to Company C.
The Army is proud of you. Proud!
(APPLAUSE)
You all right, General?
Of course I'm all right.
I want you to arrest that mule.
Have that mule court-martialed...
Mule, sir?
That mule! Get that mule!
At once, sir.
Right now! Get that mule.
(CLOCK CHIMING) (HUMMING)
(SIGHS)
Oh.
Boy, I never had
a general before!
This is really the end.
Let's get outta here,
Lieutenant!